<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FROM NOVEMBER 30, 1900, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS LINCOLN, NEBRASKA PROM NOVEMBER 30, 1900, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1902 i«n. Thb Frkmont Tribune Frbmont, Nib. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Hon. Ezra P. Savage Governor BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. Hon. Geo. D. Follmer, Land Commissioner Chairman Hon. G. W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary Hon. F. N. Prout Attorney General Hon. Wm. Stuefer Treasurer VISITING AND ADVISORY BOARD. Mrs. H. J. W. Seamark, 1030 G Street Chairman Mrs. H. S. Freeman, 1025 H Street Secretary Mrs. E. C. Hems worth 9th and South Streets Mrs. A. H. Weir 518 North Sixteenth Street Mrs. H. H. Wheeler 1525 H Street RESIDENT OFFICERS. Mrg. Sarah B. Sohus Superintendent Mrs. Wm. Faulkner Matron Dr. May L. Flanagan Physician Laura M. Cooper Teacher G. L. Wilhelm Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT. State Home for thb Friendless, Lincoln, Neb., Nov. 30, 1902. KHis Excellency, the Governor, and the Board of Public inds and Building: intlemen: — In accordance with the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska of 1899, page 644, chapter 35, I have the honor to transmit to you herewith the second biennial report of the State Home for the Friendless. Very respectfully, Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus. Ee Home is situated at the corner of Eleventh and South s, in the City of Lincoln, Neb. The Home is easily acces - sible by three different cars leaving Tenth and O streets every ten minutes. The Home for the Friendless property consists of 2.07 acres of ground. On this there are five buildings and a small green - house. The buildings are main and school buildings, laundry, cottage or hospital and barn. The three first-named are brick, the other two frame. The main and school buildings are two stories and basement; the laundry two stories with boiler under - neath. fin Building. — The basement is used for kitchen, storeroom, bath-room, children's dining-room, girls' play-room and wash-room. First Floor. — Office, parlors, officers', employes and old ladies' dining-rooms, two sleeping rooms, also halls and store-room. Second Floor. — First nursery and bath-room for same, three sleeping rooms, girls' dormitory and clothes-room. School Building — In basement, boys' play-room, one wash - room, kindergarten room, and two rooms, one occupied by engi - neer and the other by man-of-all-work. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">236 First Floor. — Chapel, schoolroom, matron's rooms, second nursery, boys' dormitory and wash-rooms for same. Second Floor. — Boys' dormitory and bath-room and four rooms occupied by help. Eundry Building. — Engines and boiler in basement, 2 s, i 40-horse power and "one 35-horse power; engine, rse power; 1 automatic feed pump, 1 coal bin capable of ig one car of steam coal. Krst Floor. — Laundry in which is 1 steam washer, 1 steam ger, 3 steam tubs, 6 stationary tubs, laundry stove, clothes and one dry room adjoining. Second Floor. — Three sleeping rooms for employes. K&gt;ttage of Hospital. — A small building of four rooms and This at present is occupied by two old ladies who require cial attendant; the other half a drug room and a large room uarantine purposes in case of contagious diseases. tirn. — This has accommodation for six cows and four horses ; carriage space. K presenting this second biennial report of the State Home ie Friendless to you it is my desire to state as briefly as pos - the condition the buildings were in internally and exter - on assuming my position March 1, 1901. Kfore the end of the first week the whole sewerage system Led and could only be remedied by the use of most forceful ures. Not knowing what else to do, the city engineer was 1 upon for advice and he kindly came out, brought men and a large hose that was attached to the city hydrant and the obstruction forced from its lodging place and the sewer opened up. Upon opening the man-holes there was found an accu - mulation of coal buckets, tin cans, coal, broken dishes, old shoes, boards, etc., a large wagon load. Since the cleaning out at that time we have had no further trouble with our sewer. The,roofe on all the buildings leaked, the water conductors, down-spouts and tinning rusted beyond repair; the smoke-stack ready to collapse; the laundry floor sinking over the boilers, one boiler needing re-setting; plaster falling from laundry walls and ceiling; the floors of the entire basement in main building </seg>
            <seg id="p005">237 were in a state of decay, broken and unsafe in many places; the back stairs leading to first floor from basement broken so that they fell in; the wash-room was in a dreadful condition, the plumbing was out of order, all fixtures worn and leaking, and the wood-work rotten. Every room needed paint and calsomine. The first floor in this building was in a fair condition, the wood - work needed varnishing, some papering and painting, doors repaired, etc. Second Floor. — The first nursery needed everything except the iron beds. In the bath-room for this department the same state of decay, and the plumbing in as bad condition as the wash-room below. The odor was very unpleasant, not to say unhealthy. All wood-work on this floor was in need of var - nish or paint. The porch from this department — the little ones' playground in suitable weather — needed a new floor and roof. Girls' Dormitory. — In one-half of it the paper was hanging in strips from the ceiling. School Building. — All wood- work needed varnishing; all walls and ceilings either paper or calsomining. In boys' bath - room all the plumbing was out of order, the tubs worn out. The tubs in this department, as well as all others, were the old zinc - lined wooden tubs. The seats in the schoolroom needed repair and black-boards puint. The attic in this building was filled with rubbish of various kinds, old beds and rusted springs, boxes of moth-eaten clothes, and in one corner a large pile of old mattresses and straw beds of every condition. Hospital or Cottage. — Walls needed paper or calsomine, wood-work varnished and plumbing repaired. In all but school building the electric wiring was pronounced in a highly dangerous condition. In the barn the wire went through joists without insulators being used. The vault for the water meter had been walled up with boards and had caved in. The platform for the scales was worn out; the front porch was ready to fall, as were also the steps leading from the back of the main building. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">238 REPAIRS. Main Building. — Roof thoroughly repaired, new tinning, water conductors and down-spouts, new cement floor in entire basement, new plumbing in boys' wash-room, new enamel iron wash-bowls, wainscoting in kitchen, halls, dining-room, wash - room and play-room. New doors were needed. New ceiling in bread room, canopy over range, large steam kettles taken rst Floor. — All wood-work repaired and varnished, paper - one, new plumbing in bath-room, new enamel iron bath- Second Floor. — First nursery, new mattresses for each bed. The mattresses in use were ticks filled with straw. Every bed painted. All wood-work, walls and ceilings painted in nursery, dining-room and bath-room. Linoleum for the floors. New sheets, spreads, blankets, rubber sheets and pads, pillows made over for every bed. In nursery bath-room all old plumbing torn out, new enamel iron tub and bowl put in. A door was cut into bathroom from nursery; heretofore the entrance to same was by going through the hall. The nursery is in good condition at this time and should be the best place in the Home. In hall and in dining-room for this nursery new wainscoting was put in. All wood-work in halls, sleeping-rooms and staircase was varnished and hall papered. Girls' dormitory papered and painted, all beds painted, new mattresses where needed, sheets, pillow cases, blankets and pads furnished every bed and all pillows made over. This department is sadly in need of better bath-room accommodations. As it now is the girls in age from five to twelve have to go two flights of stairs to reach the bath-room in the basement. Ehool Building. — Roof thoroughly repaired. New down &amp; and tinning where needed. In basement in boys' wash - new cement floor, new enamel iron wash bowl and closet, ergarten and men's rooms calsomined. Et Floor. — Chapel and school-room calsomined and var - . Seats in school-room repaired, sandpapered and var - , black-boards painted. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">239 (econd Nursery. — New ticks made, also pillows made over, i bed new blankets, sheets, pillow cases and pads. Gover - i room moved to other side of dormitory ; this was done for sake of better light and heat in the room. Two rooms were ered and varnished. a Second Floor. — In boys' dormitory all beds painted, new ma tress for each, twenty-eight in number, pillows made ove sheets, pillow cases, blankets, spreads and pads furnishec Walls and ceiling calsomined and wood-work varnished. Th other rooms on this floor were papered, calsomined and var nished. In boys' bathroom new enamel iron tubs and closet were put in. B sundry Building. — An entire new roof. In boiler-house one boiler reset, floor raised above the boilers, and stringers n to hold it in place. frst Floor. — Replastered entire room. Moved steam washer across the room to more convenient place. New floor, belts and pulleys for machinery. I:ond Floor. — The sleeping rooms for employes papered painted, which made the rooms habitable and pleasant, iney rebuilt on this building. Cottage or Hospital. — Repaired roof, papered, painted and calsomined. New front porch built. New roof and floor on children's porch. New back steps leading from back of build - ing. New smoke-stack. New range in kitchen. Covers for six man-holes connected with the main sewer on South street, and rebuilding two of the man-holes. New pipes for hot and cold water were laid from the boiler house to the school build- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">240 Appropriations of 1901. wages, first year $13,805.16 Total disbursements — Repairs and improvements . . . 1,681.37 Total disbursements — Cash fund 1,410.45 Total $16,896 98 Average number of inmates for first year 79 Cost per capita based on maintenance, salaries and wages 174.74 Cost per capita based on all disbursements 213.88 Total disbursements — Maintenance, salaries and wages, second year $13,215.22 Total disbursements — Repairs and improvements... 1,254.85 Total disbursements — Cash fund 1.382 05 Total $15,852.12 Average number of inmates for second year 73 tper capita based on maintenance, salaries and wages $ 181.03 Cost per capita based on all disbursements 217.16 L^&gt; AX! *^J..£VLI rwCiTUCVI. •ROPRIATIONS OF 1899. Maintenance Officers Employes Repairs »'unt in treasury Dec. 1900 ursed to April 1, 1901 • $4,347.11 3,651.68 11,034.00 956 67 W, 010. 61 1,010.61 L»P«ed t 695.43 • 77.33 Maintenance Officers Employes Repairs $14,000.00 3,961.62 $6,500.00 2,093.34 $7,000 00 2,131.24 $5,000.00 1,681.37 Disbursed to Dec. 1, 1901. Balance remaining Disbursed to Dec. 1, 1902. $10,038.38 6,682 33 $4,406.66 3,140.00 $4,868.76 3,392.89 $3,318. ft 1,254. &amp; Balance remaining $3,356.05 $1,266.66 $1,475.87 $2,063.71 otal disbursements — Maintenance '» salaries and </seg>
            <seg id="p009">241 Of the appropriations of 1899 there was a deficiency in employes' wages of $183.67. This was paid to the help from the cash fund with the expectation that it would be replaced by an appropriation of the coming legislature. Our cash fund is derived from board paid by parents who desire to maintain the right to their children, and also from the sale of a few cows, old iron, old lead, cinders, etc. MAINTENANCE. Economy has been practiced in every department. We felt it would be simply impossible to manage in such a way as not to have a deficiency in this appropriation, but with the help of the cash fund we have been able so far to have a surplus instead of a deficiency. Great credit is due our matron, as she has watched with diligent care that not anything was wasted in any depart - ment that could be made use of. We have worked on the plan that it is economy to buy good material. Owing to the advanced cost during this period in nearly all the commodities for suste - nance, we have had to do very close figuring. This appropri - ation included the heating, lighting and water expense, which is no small item in an institution of this description. In this fund there was received first year $ I »753-°4 Iursed first year 1,410.45 Balance $ 342.59 lived second year 1,140.58 $1,483.17 Disbursed second year 1,382.05 Balance $ 101.12 IOI.I2 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">242 MATRON'S MATRON'S S REPORT. REPORT. Sewing Done at Home for the F Sewing Done at Home for the Friendless from Dec. I, 1900, to Friendless from Dec. I, 1900, to 1, 1902. Dec. 1, Dec. 1 1, 1902. Sheets 137 Table cloths, new 16 Table cloths, new 16 Sheets 137 Tablecloths, made over.. 10 Table cloths, made over . . 10 Pants, new 7 Pants, new 7 Piano cover i Piano cover 1 Pants, made over 6 Pants, made over 6 Dusting cloths 12 Dusting cloths 12 Dressing sacks 11 Dressing sacks 11 Dish towels 96 Dish towels 96 Shirt waists 5 Shirt waists 5 Large dresses 18 Large dresses 18 Pillow cases 182 Pillow cases 182 Large dresses made over . 2 Large dresses made over . 2 Bolster cases 22 Bolster cases 22 Small dresses 61 Small dresses 61 Pillow cases made over. . . 145 Pillow cases made over. . . 145 Small dresses made over. . 14 Small dresses made over. . 14 Holders 92 Holders 92 Dresser scarfs 19 Dresser scarfs 19 Pillow ticks, new 41 Pillow ticks, new 41 Caps for entertainment ... 13 Caps for entertainment ... 13 Pillow ticks made over. . . 37 Pillow ticks made over. . . 37 Suits for entertainment ... 17 Suits for entertainment ... 17 Skirts, new 19 Skirts, new 19 Wash cloths 27 Wash cloths 27 Skirts, made over 10 Skirts, made over 10 Bibs from old material .... 78 Bibs from old material .... 78 Bedspreads 16 Bedspreads 16 Diapers, new 217 Diapers, new 217 Large drawers 20 Large drawers 20 Pads from old material .... 75 Pads from old material .... 75 Large drawers, made over 6 Large drawers, made over 6 Cushions 7 Cushions 7 Sunbonnets 21 Sunbonnets 21 Large gowns 12 Large gowns 12 Small drawers 12 Small drawers 12 Small gowns 38 Small gowns 38 Skirts, new 16 Skirts, new 16 Napkins 313 Napkins 313 Skirts, made over 10 Skirts, made over 10 Roller towels 64 Roller towels 64 Boys' under-waists 52 Boys' under-waists 52 Short towels 117 Short towels 117 Boys' shirt waists 16 Boys' shirt waists 16 Bed ticks 24 Bed ticks 24 Boys' waists, made over . . 3 Boys' waists, made over . . 3 Mattresses 16 Mattresses 16 Corset covers 8 Corset covers 8 Blankets 78 Blankets 78 New comforts 6 New comforts 6 Neckties 8 Neckties 8 New quilts 6 New quilts 6 Aprons 21 Comforts and quilts repaired 65 Comforts and quilts repaired 65 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">243 FRUIT CANNED FOR THE HOME FROM DVA:. 1, 1900, TO DEC. 1, 1902. Summer of 1901. Summer of 1902 Peaches 97 qts Peaches 185 qts. Grapes 65 qts Grapes 15 qts. Rlackberries 75 qts Black raspberries .... 17 qts. Black raspberries .... 13 qts Red raspberries 20 qts. Plums 30 qis Plums 65 qts. Cherries 3 qts. Rhubarb 20 qts. Currants 3 qts. Strawberries 13 qts. Pears 75 qts. Total 286 qts. Plum butter 40 qts. Total 510 qts. Peach butter 20 qts. Tomatoes 24 qts. Fruit butter, all kinds .115 qts. Total 60 qts. Jelly, all kinds 80 qts. Jelly, all kinds 30 qts. Total 195 qis. Chop pickle 60 qts. Onion pickles 23 qts. Sweet tomato pickle. . 25 qts. Total 85 q's. Tomato sweet pickle . 20 qts. Chop pickle 70 qts. Bean pickle 58 qts. Beet pickle 49 qts. Total 220 qts. Total number quarts of every kind for two years i,3 10 VEGETABLES RAISED FOR THE HOME PROM DEC. 1, 1900. TO DEC. 1, 1902. First Year. Lettuce, 271 h -ads at 1 J^c $ 406 Radishes, 158 dozen at 2c 3- 16 Cabbage, 50 heads at 5c 2.50 Peas, 6 quarts at 8^c 50 Corn, 16 dozen at 15c 2.43 Tomatoes, 2 bushel at 50c 1.00 Beets, 58 }4 dozen at 10c 5.85 Beans, 21 quarts at 7#c i-57 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">244 Second Year. Onions, 84 bunches at 10c per dozen $ .70 Lettuce, 30 bunches at 25c per dozen .62 Radishes, 39 bunches at 10c per dozen .33 Lettuce, 974 heads at ic 9 74 Radishes, 255 dozen at 2#c 6.37 Onions, 51 dozen at 2^,c 1.27 Beans, 246 quarts at 3c 7-3^ Peas, 66 quarts at 8^c 5.50 Cabbage, 75 heads at 5c 3.75 Tomatoes, 49 dozen at 7j4c 3.67 Beets, 20 bushels at 20c 4.00 Corn, 75 dozen at 7#c 5.62 Green tomatoes, 3 bushels at 40c 1.20 $5oi5 Total $71.19 MILK REPORT FROM DEC. 1, 1901, TO DEC. 1, 1902 From Dec. i, 1900, to June 1, 1901, 1973 gals, at i2#c$246.5O From June 1, 1901, to Dec. 1, 1901, 1647 gals, at i2^c. 205.87 From Dec. 1, 1901, to June E, 1902, 847 gals, at 15c. . . 127.05 From Dec. 1, i9oi,tojune 1, 1902, 480 gals, at I2j£c. 61.00 From June 1, 1902, to Dec. 1, 1902, 426 gals, at nyic 33.25 Total for two years $693.67 Mrs. Wm. Faulkner, Matron. IMPROVEMENTS NEEDED FOR THE HOME. I would suggest the buying of the property lying west of the Home and a part of the block where the property now is. A day nursery for the babies or a cottage built on purpose for them. Babies being kept on second floor cannot get out to be benefited by the sun and air as much as they would be from the ground floor. Having sixteen or eighteen children under three years of age at one time, day and night, in the same room, they cannot thrive as they should. We cannot ventilate to suit all ages. We have hard work to keep these little, frail crea- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">245 tures with everything as it should be, the very poorest class of babies being left here to be given away. I would suggest a cottage for them, such as they have in connection with other institutions of like character. I would suggest that a home be built for old ladies, who have no one to care for or support them. These old ladies ought_ to appeal very strongly to us, as it is only circumstances that have made our parents' condition as they are or were. Pie cripples ought to have a home here also, and their home t to be arranged on the ground floor, where they can get y of sunshine and going out and in made easy for them, most cheerful and happy surroundings should be theirs. (the basement we need larger quarters for our store-room, cannot buy in quantities as other institutions in the state, ly because we do not have room to store our merchandise, need also in connection with a larger store-room a large, -in refrigerator for cold storage purposes. In the school building I would suggest the putting in of new cement floors in the basement, and placing steam pipes above the floor. Where they are now the heat is wasted ; if any pipes are out of repair the floors have to be torn up to get at them. I would suggest the tearing out of the wash room connected with the second nursery and throwing that space into the hall, which would give the hall more light. The hall running north and south I would convert into two bathrooms, one for the little boys, the other for the matron, who has no conveniences whatever on this floor. New outside doors are badly needed tthe laundry a new washer and mangier are very much d, the ironing now being all done by hand, and where are at times eighty-five children, it means too much hard for the number employed in that department. tthe cottage new plumbing is needed and bathroom refitted put in better sanitary condition. The steam pipes here are under the ground and ought to be above the floors. The ige needs a new roof. It has been thoroughly repaired but ild be replaced by a new one. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">246 1_«and Commissioner s Iveport. Knew water connection with the main is also needed, the we now have being too small, being only i J^ inch. The sure is not sufficient to throw the water to second floor n we are washing in laundry. New fences where needed. tBoys r present Dec. 1, 1900 . . 43 Girls Adults Total ~~9 83~ M umbef received to Dec. 1, 1901 Returned from homes &gt; 63 16 14 5 4.-. 5 5 fi : "iFE M 61 M 185 — umber dismissed to Dec. 1, 1901 Taken by parent or friends 58 On trial 23 Other institutions 5 Left the Home 1 Found work 43 9 7 16 '"i" 4 "io" 2 Ha 28 umber received to Dec. 1, 1902 . . Relinquished Returned from homes Temporary shelter 42 8 4 1 25 I 2 5 '"25" til 37 25 123 umber dismissed to Dec. 1, 1902 Taken by parent or friends ..." Other institutions Found work 49 11 2 32 9 1 19 "2" 4 42 ' 23 "» umber remaining in the Home Dec. 1, 1902. . . 18 it -1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Average age 71 yrs. 7yrs. 7 yrs. 6 yr«. »4 AGES OF CHILDREN WHEN . DMITTED. 1901 1902 Boys Girls Boys I Girl Jnder one month Jnder six months Jnder one year Jnder two years Jnder three years Jnder four years Jnder five years I six years seven years eight years nine years ten years eleven years twelve years thirteen years fourteen years fifteen years sixteen years 7 4 . 4 -4 4 4 3 7 6 10 11 14 10 4 1 6 4 1 4 5 5 8 5 3 5 2 3 2 1 2 4 1 1 4 4&gt; 2 5 4 6 8 5 4 6 3 3 1 i 4 3 3 Total 61 61 I </seg>
            <seg id="p016">248 Total received during two years, 308. EMITTED 1902 COUNTIES I 0 3 "3 &lt; o go o 03 ■ 3 •a &lt;5 I ■ box Butte !."!!!!!!!! .'. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '. '. Madison NMkoUs'.!!.'!!!!!!!!."!. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 3 1 2 1 1 1 4 1 3 2 • 1" I l" "1" 2' "l* 2 "i 1 r "1 1 '2 "i" ■l r 2 2 5 2 4 11 2 6 8 16 T "2" 2 "3" .... "1" I 1 2 1 45 r l" 2 3 1 81 "1" "2" "i 6 "l" 20" ie "l" 30 2 1 "m" is" 1 I T "1" 2 Sheridan Sherman "4" "5" 6 4 1 "2" 1 3 1 2 "2" "1" 1 4 5 1 9 1 8 4 1 1 2 3 2 1 3 3 3 1 4 1 " .... I .... "l" "l "t" ••-, 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 3 "l 1 "1" -i "f New York South Dakota ....\............. Illinois 4 1 5 3 9 4 — "2" '2" "1" 185 "2" Total </seg>
            <seg id="p017">249 Of the 32 children put out on trial from Dec. 1, 1900, to Dec. 1, 1901, 16 of them were for one cause or another returned to the Home, some of them being replaced two or three times; 9 of them were adopted,7 . tne first homes in which they were placed; 3 of them were taken on agreement, 2 with parents' consent; 1 was taken charge of by the New York Aid Society, 1 taken from the home by his uncle, 1 was given up with the mother's consent, and 1 died. Of the 20 put out during the year beginning Dec. 1, 1901, and closing Dec. 1, 1902, 5 were for various reasons returned, 1 was adopted, 3 taken on agreement, one of these a girl of 14 preferring it; 1 was placed with the consent of the mother, 1 died, and 9 are still in homes awaiting the end of the trial months for action in regard to the future. None of these have been gone from the Home more than three months and two of them have left the past month. Of the number taken by other institutions, 10 were the New York Aid Society children, and were taken by that society; 1 was from the York county poor farm and was returned to that institution ; 3 of the others were Home children who have grown too old for this institution and yet were undesirable to place in families; it had been tried several times unsuccessfully; two of them were sent to the Geneva Industrial school and one to the Kearney Industrial School; 1 was sent to Genoa. One boy ran away from the Home, but was afterwards found, brought back to the Home, and in a day or two was the boy sent to Kearney. Of the 9 adults who were here in the Home Dec. 1, 1900, 7 are still with us and one other has since been admitted. The oldest one is 84 years of age, is perfectly helpless and requires a special attendant. Two of the number are able to go about by themselves, but the others are more or less helpless. We make them as comfortable and contented as we can. They are not without friends, but are homeless. During the two years there were 51 given temporary shelter. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">l^AND COMMISSIONER S ivRPORT. 250 could be found, a great many having one or more children with l i j cm . AGREEMENT. It is hereby agreed between . . . . ' Supt. of the I lome for the Friendless, of the first part, and &gt; town , state , of the second part, that the said shall take one child (sex) named 10 keep and treat as their own child until of age, the child to render what assistance is required of him or her in the Home, provided such requirement is not unreas- onable. For these services the said child is to receive suitable clothing and education sufficient to fit him or her to care for him or herself. Supt. of the Home for the Friendless, of the first part, affirms that the said child was given into the custody of the Home for the Friendless by , he or she making out the proper papers giving child to the Home. TRIAL PAPER. It is hereby agreed by and between , Supt. of the Home for the Friendless, of the firstpart, anu &gt; of the second part, that said , party of the second part, shall take , « child of the age of years, from said Home for the Friendless for the purpose of adopting said child, and if, after four months' trial it shall be satisfactory to both of said parties hereto that said child shall be adopted by said , party of the second part, then said first party agrees to relinquish to said second party and said second party agrees to adopt said child at </seg>
            <seg id="p019">251 ADOPTION BLANK. I, or we, , being first duly sworn, depose and say that I am a resident of county, Nebraska; that I do freely and voluntarily adopt , a child, years of age, the of and as my own and bestow upon equal rights, privileges and immunities of children born in lawful wedlock. PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus, Superintendent Home- for the Friendless : In comparing the present health of the inmates with that when we assumed our duties, we have reason to feel gratified. New bath rooms and plumbing have made decided improvements in the sanitary conditions, while a marked cleanliness and a careful study of the diet have prevented many of the diseases for which for which a physician is often called. In beginning the work March i, 1901, we found fourteen cases of tinea tonsuraus, or ring-worm, and numerous cases of what are commonly called "Institution Sores," and in the first nursery a type of pemphigus. By persistent efforts the former were entirely eradicated, with no return until the last summer, when a boy was admitted with tinae, spreading to three others. In the first nursery the crowded condition during the first summer, which was unusually hot, pemphigus and whooping - cough formed a combination which so weakened them that seem - ingly slight attacks of other diseases proved fatal. As we consider this in looking back over the first summer, as also the fact that nearly every death was in children less than a year old, that the most of them came into the world under most unfavorable circumstances, weakly and diseased, and when we remember the untiring efforts of the employes who cared for them, we feel that not one death could have been avoided. Since November first, i9Oi,only four deaths have occurred, two </seg>
            <seg id="p020">l^AND i_OMMISSIONRR S JN.EPORT. 252 Kem away from the Home, before the children were formally ted. teases of scarlet fever, diphtheria and small-pox, prompt and quarantine with thorough disinfection prevented further d of the diseases. I wish to acknowledge my appreciation of your hearty co - operation and of the help of the assistants so faithfully and wil - lingly given. Respectfully, May L. Flanagan. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">253 a 2 | I e a "3 •a 4 I Bronchial pneumonia 3 Itheria 3 i 1 et fever 2 1-pox 1 ular rheumatism 1 nic rheumatism 1 nic asthma 1 ilitis 12 5 rculosis 1 lure of arm 1 1 mini? 1 inations 84 | 23 Total 1 Number of visits . . Number of prescrii )tions &gt;S •9 I -3 &lt; I Mal-nutrition Hereditary syphilis Gastro-enteritis Whooping cough Cholera Infantum Spasms Spinal meningitis Pemphigus Ptomaine poisoning Endo-carditis Deaths previous to March 1, 1001 Erysipelas Heart failure Bronchial pneumonia Total 5 2 4 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 "i" l i </seg>
            <seg id="p022">254 TEACHERS' REPORT. Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus, Supt. Home for the Friendless : Kouth is opportunity; at the threshold lie all the possibilities fe. Some one has said, "Youth is a book of beginnings, a i without end, each maid a heroine and each man a friend." |^.s men are never so sure of anything else in life as they are the impressions of their youth, we at the Home for the endless try to impress the children under our care that now is time to grow into high purpose; to form resolves that are to :arried out in years to come. Now is their time for forming its of persistence. We try to teach that beginnings are ays easy in any line of life work, but it is only the few who e the persistence to ever get past these beginnings. Kext to beautiful friendships, we teach our children that good :s and thoughts gleaned from our best authors and poets are i prized, and in the course of the past two years we are very proud of tht knowledge they have gotten from memorizing E: of the most noted poems composed by Longfellow, Whit- Bryant, Holmes, Lowell, Shakespeare, Emerson, Riley, low and Field. The children have also been much inter- I in knowing something about the lives of each. One day each week for opening exercises we discuss the cur- t events of the day. The first Friday in each month we have &gt;ricals. The second and fourth Fridays they write to friends, children are taught patriotism to the extent that when a lit— :llow gets up to recite a history lesson as far back as the of 1812 he always tells what we did, and how our flag was ed, etc., etc. The common school branches are taught, the school being graded as well as is possible to do, considering the fact that there is a constant change going on all the time. We have the second, third, fourth and fifth grades, and one boy is doing eighth grade work. B r e have a small library connected with the school where Is procure books each Monday at the close of school. We o have dumb-bell exercises once a day. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">255 (he number enrolled from Dec. i, 1900, to Nov. 30, 1901, 78, and from Dec. 1, 1901, to Nov. 30, 1902, was 86. Aver - daily attendance first year, 39; second year, 36. Number ays taught each year, 193, the school closing two days at nksgiving and five at Christmas. The above is a report for the year beginning Dec. 1, 1900, and ending Nov. 30, 1901, and the year beginning Dec. 1, 1901, and ending Nov. 30, 1902. Very respectfully, Laura M. Cooper. KINDERGARTEN. Our teacher in this department was trained in the Wesleyan University and has been with us almost a year. In this depart - ment are to be found the little ones from four to eight years of age, or until they are able to read well, as this is only for pri - mary work. The average number is about twenty. Specimens of their work are placed on the walls of their schoolroom and attract much attention. They are trained to sing little kinder - garten songs and delight to entertain visitors and receive words of praise in return. (he put poses of this home, so far as I understand and the 3 allow, are as follows : First, to furnish a home for orphans other destitute children of the State of Nebraska. Second, rovide for their physical needs. Third, to surround them wholesome moral influences. Fourth, to give them the ntage of a common school education as far as possible. Is difficult for those living with the work in a state institu - :o say which is the most important part of it, and what has best accomplished. On taking charge of the Home these along which improvement seemed possible presented selves. The home surroundings of the children who come make them particularly susceptible to improved physical ort. They need good moral training and must be started in ectual development. Our efforts along these lines have been rded with encouraging results. We first began with giv - lem good wholesome food, thus building up the physical </seg>
            <seg id="p024">256 nature. We instructed and encouraged them in personal neat - ness, thus giving them some self-respect. Their morals we endeavored to raise to a higher standard, showing them the great benefit to themselves and to all those around them. The school work has developed them to a wonderful degree, giving them a love for the beautiful in poetry and prose, getting them interested in the selections of the authors they liked the best. The time has come when it is necessary to make some arrangements for the supervision of those placed in homes. In all cases where we place a child the right is reserved to have the child returned to the home if it is deemed best during the time it is out on trial. In most cases we have no means of knowing the surroundings and treatment of children except from report and correspondence. No argument is needed to show how unre - liable both may be. Especially is this true for distant parts of the state where all parties concerned are strangers to us. Some person is needed who is connected with the home and acquainted with the character and needs of the children to give his or her whole time to the work, not only to look after the interests of those already placed in homes, but to find suitable homes for Believing that kindly methods and appeals to reason ought to do more than corporal punishment, we use that only as a last resort, and very little has been done. We have very little trouble in governing our children. Ee life of the Home is made to correspond as nearly as pos - to the home life as we find it in most ordinary homes. We upon personal cleanliness, correct morals and manners, and ' as our conveniences admit, habits of industry are taught. SUNDAY PRIVILEGES. Every Sunday morning from ten to eleven we have Sunday school in our chapel, using the same lessons as are used in the city churches. In the afternoon we have Christian Endeavor from three to four. It is conducted by members of the Chris - tian Endeavor societies of the different churches in the city, and a great good is being done. Our children in that way receive </seg>
            <seg id="p025">257 benefit of coming in contact with others than those in the Home, the change in that way being beneficial. I do not doubt that those coming to us from these different societies also receive a benefit. Quite often our older children, accompanied by teacher or governess, attend a near-by church in the evening. We feel confident that any children going away from our Home, no matter where, will always remember the teachings they have had while with us. We have endeavored at all times to employ such help as would benefit the Home, not only in the line of work they were hired ■erform, but in the help that would be given in the upbuild - of the children. We have felt that our work was not only with the children, but with all who were in the Home. We have nineteen employes, whose positions are as follows: Man of all work. First cook. Second cook. First laundress. Second laundress. Third laundress. Boys' governess. Girls' governess. Second nursery governess. Bookkeeper and usher. Housekeeper. Kindergarten teacher. Head nurse. First assistant first nursery. Second assistant first nursery. Hospital nurse. Officers' dining room girl. Employes' dining room girl. Relief. Number of letters written during the biennium 1,103 Number of visitors at Home 3,882 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">258 RULE8 FOR ADMISSION OF CHILDREN INTO THK HOME. i. Children, in order to become inmates of the Home, must belong to one of the following classes: ist surrendered to the Home and thus become its ward. 2d. Orphans or half - orphans. All applications under these two classes shall be inves - tigated by the advisory board and superintendent, and none shall be admitted without such investigation shows destitution enough to require the shelter of this Home. I In case of ability of persons having control of such chil - , said persons shall pay to Home for care, and board a sum to exceed $2.00 per month. A smaller sum may be ged, according to circumstances, at the discretion of the rintendent and visiting and advisory board. Parents or guar - s wishing to place children temporarily in the Home must an agreement that if no compensation is paid for six consecu - months the children will be considered wards of the state may be placed in homes for adoption. 3. No children will be admitted whose parents or guardians reside in states other than that of Nebraska. Applications must be accompanied by written statements from reliable persons stating that conditions are as applicant sets forth. ■ Boys under thirteen and girls under fourteen years of may be received in accordance with sections 1 and 2, of 1, and any rule governing admission to said Home. I Any person desiring to take a child from the Home for &gt;tion or to bring up to maturity, must communicate in per - or by writing to the superintendent, giving a full statement tie circumstances in which the child will be placed if trans - id to his or her care, what position in the family such child hold, what labor will be required, what advantages for ation will be given, what will be the religious privileges training. Also assurance of temperate habits. These facts : be accompanied with good and satisfactory recommenda - or the request can receive no attention. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">259 DUTIES OF OFFKKUS Supbrintendent. — The superintendent shall reside at the Home and have general supervision and control of both the internal and external management, subject to rules and regula - tions provided for by advisory board and Board of Public Lands and Buildings. She shall have the power to engage and discharge the employes, except those provided for in chapter 37 of Session Laws of 1897. She shall keep a record of names of all inmates, with the date of their admission and dismissal. This shall contain as far as possible the name, age, nativity, where from, when received, when dismissed, how disposed of, and in case of death state cause, which last should be certifi - cate of the Home physician. She shall make a written report of all actions in connection with inmates and employes from promulgation of these rules to visiting and advisory board. In no case shall the superintendent and matron be absent from the Home at the same time. Patron. — The matron shall reside at the Home and have :ral supervision of the domestic arrangement of the institu - sewing and dining-rooms, table linen, kitchen and laundry, have charge of all stores. She shall see that the institu - n be in perfect order, all work be done in a proper manner, kbe responsible for the conduct of the help in her depart - t. In the absence of the superintendent she shall assume luties of that office. Physician. — The physician shall have general supervision of the health of the inmates. She shall make daily visits to the Home and oftener if necessary, and shall attend all inmates during sickness. Shall have provided for her a room furnished with hospital and medical supplies, and a bed when obliged to remain at the H &gt;me . Shall make out all requisitions for medi - cal department, and in her absence the superintendent shall see that nurses comply with physician's instructions. She shall keep a record of all patients attended, and report each month through superintendent to visiting and advisory board. She shall thoroughly examine all children before being taken into </seg>
            <seg id="p028">260 Land Commissioner's Report. IHome, and use all precautions to prevent contagious ses. No nurses for either well or sick shall be employed e Home, who are under twenty years of age. I/e wish to express our sincere thanks to the Governor and ;he Board of Public Lands and Buildings for the deep rest you have always taken in the management of the Home, giving of advice and hearty cooperation in assisting us in efforts to build up this Home. To the ladies' advisory board we are indebted for the faith - ful manner in which they have always responded to the calls for advice, help and encouragement given. They have faithfully endeavored to help us carry out the rules for this institution. We wish to express our thanks to all those who have con - tributed to our Sunday school, papers and cards, and to those who have sent magazines, books, toys and candy, thereby showing their interest in the children in this Home. E r e extend a cordial invitation to the tax-payers of the state all interested in the charitable work of the state to visit nd see the workings of the institution. Respectfully submitted, Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus, Superintendent. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>