<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Relation of Low Temperature to Root Injury of the Apple</title>
               <date value="1924-04">1924-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 The Relation of Low Temperatures to Root Injury of the Apple K F. HOWARD DEPARTMENT OF HORTICULTURE THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT. DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. Individual French crab and seedling apple st &gt;cks vary in their ability to withstand cold. Many of them will be killed or severely injured if exposed to 14° F. for 2 hours in an air chamber. 2. The scion roots of most varieties &gt;f apples seem to be hardier than French crab and seedling roots of equal size. 3. Small, young roots are more susceptible to cold than large, older 4. Varieties of apples differ in their tendency to form roots from scion wood. Scion roots are produced by some the nrst year in the nursery while others have none at the end of the third year. 5. The tops of some varieties &gt;f apples are more subject to wintt injury in the nursery than others. 6. At 7 '■* inches depth the temperature under bluegrass sod was from 2 to 7 degrees higher in midwinter than that in a clean cultivated plat. 7. The moisture content of the soil did not greatly influence the minimum temperature that was reached in midwinter at several inches below the surface. The dry s iil, however, responded more quickly than the wet one to atmospheric changes. Freezing temperatures were reached somewhat sooner in early winter in the dry than in the wet soil. In early spring the wet soil remained at or near the freezing point for 12 days while the dry soil had a mean temperature &gt;f 34 F. 8. If there is less injury to roots in a wet than in a dry soil, it is probably due to protection afforded by the m&gt;ist medium and not to higher soil temperatures in the region of the roots. 9. Occasionally the midwinter soil temperature 'if eastern Nebraska gets low enough to kill tender apple roots at a depth of 6 to 12 inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Relation of Low Temperatures to Root Injury of the Apple R. F. HOWARD THE apple tree is subject to many types of winter injury. Macoun (1900) described 10 kinds: Root-killing, bark - splitting, trunk-splitting, sunscald, crotch injury, killing back, black heart, body injury, killing of dormant buds, and winter - killing of swollen buds. These and other types of winter injury have been variously described as being due to: Imma - turity, tender stocks, weakened condition of tree, lack of concentration of cell sap, no soil covering, insufficient soil moisture, and broken rest period. There have been some differences of opinion as to the rela - tive importance of several factors that are known to influence the degree of injury accompanying low temperatures. Winter injury to the tops of plants is known to be in - fluenced largely by the degree of maturity of the wood, as shown by Emerson (1903 and 1906); and Chandler (1918) concluded that a tree which has just borne a heavy crop is more subject to top injury than one that has just had an "off crop" year. In general it may be assumed, from the reports of Goff I 1899). Craig (1900), and Emerson (1903), that root injury is greatest when the soil is unprotected. The roots near the surface of the ground are always injured most. Soil moisture undoubtedly influences the amount of cold »vhich roots are able to withstand without injury. Emerson ( 1903) showed that injury to seedling apple roots was greater in a dry than in a wet soil but he did not record the actual temperatures that obtained in the two cases. He concluded that the more frequent alternate freezing and thawing in the dry soil was probably responsible for the greater injury. Goff (1899) surveyed the states of Wisconsin, Illinois, .Minnesota, and Iowa to determine the effects of the freeze which occurred in February, 1899. He found that the low temperatures of that winter were accompanied in many places without any covering of snow. The injury was more severe to the roots in some cases, while in others the tops were killed and the roots survived. He concluded that root injury was greater where the ground was unprotected by snow or a litter mulch of some kind. In this regard his observations agreed with those made by Craig (1900) , who made a similar investi - gation in Iowa. From wide observations made following the </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 low temperatures of that year it was noted that there was greater root injury to the apple where the trees had been budded on seedling stocks than in cases where piece root grafting had permitted the trees to develop a root system par - tially from scion wood. While the extent of injury was probably greater in 1898-99 than that resulting from any other year, there have t&gt;een sev - eral other periods of low temperatures when winterkilling has been very pronounced. According to Dorsey (1920) the test winters for the northwest have been 1872-73, 1884-85, 1898-99 and 1917-18. Macoun (1918) in reporting upon winter injury in Canada mentions the years 1858-59, 1876-77, 1884-85. 1895-96, 1898-99, 1903-04, and 1917-18 as being the ones when severe injury occurred in that region. A survey of 950 orchards in Maine by Morse (1909) revealed the fact that 24,613 apple trees were killed outright as a result of the severe winter of 1906-07. In many places thruout the eastern ar-d central western states severe injury was noted following tht winter of 1917-18. The experiences of apple growers and nurserymen in the northern states have established the general fact that some varieties have hardier roots than others, and it is believed that the scion roots of most varieties of apples are hardier than those produced from our common seedling and French crab propagating stocks. There is more specific information needed upon the readiness and extent to which different varie - ties produce roots from the scion portion of the graft. It has also been found from practice, Pfaender (1919) and Hansen (1899), that root injury caused by severe freezing may be partially obviated by propagating the apple, for the regions more subjected to injury, upon certain hardy stocks such as the Siberian crab (Pyrus baccata) and seedlings of Red Siberian, Yellow Siberian, Virginia, and Transcendent crabs. Pfaender concludes that French crabs and Vermont seedling stocks are so tender as to be worthless for the north - ern Great Plains section including the western half of North and South Dakota and those portions of Wyoming and Montana east of the Rock Mountains. These hardy stocks have not been adopted as a means of propagating trees for the commercial apple growing sections of the northern states. Their rate of growth is slower than that of most other varie - ties, thus causing an uncongenial union accompanied by a dwarfing effect on the tree. That apple roots will be killed or severely injured when exposed to a rapid rate of freezing at temperatures ranging </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Root Injury of the Apple 5 from 23 to 10.4 F. for a few hours in an air chamber has been fairly well established by Chandler (1913) and Carrick (1920) but there is little evidence at hand to show to what extent these temperatures are reached in orchard soils in mid - winter. Likewise there is very little recorded evidence of the influence of soil moisture on minimum temperatures in orchard soils. Apple roots are probably injured more in a dry than in a moist soil, but there have been few attempts to de - termine whether the greater injury in dry soil is caused by lower temperatures or whether it is on account of freezing in a drv medium. OBJECTS OF THIS INVESTIGATION The principal object of this investigation was to study the relative hardiness of scion and stock roots of the apple, and to determine the extent to which midwinter soil temperatures at various depths are influenced by culture and moisture con - tent. In order to assemble data which would have a bearing upon this problem it was deemed advisable to: 1. Determine the freezing temperatures at which apple stock roots would be killed or injured. 2. Determine the relative hardiness of scion and stock roots. 3. Note any differences in the hardiness of scion roots of various varieties of apples. 4. Determine the rate and extent of scion rooting of differ - ent apple varieties. 5. Determine the midwinter temperatures in an orchard soil receiving different kinds of culture. 6. Determine the rate of change as well as the absolute temperature of wet and dry soils in midwinter. APPARATUS AND METHOD USED IN FREEZING ROOTS The apparatus used in freezing the roots consisted of an inner chamber of galvanized iron 9 inches square and 24 inches deep, a middle chamber of the same material but 15 inches square at the top and bottom, an outer chamber 21 inches square, and a large wooden box 8 inches larger than the largest chamber. Each chamber was covered with a gal - vanized lid. When the chambers were placed in the box the 4-inch space between the box and the largest chamber was filled with dry sawdust. The other two 3-inch spaces between chambers were used for the freezing mixture, which consisted </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 6 of common salt mixed with the proper proportions of ice. The temperature within the inner chamber which contained the roots was found to vary a degree or less at different levels after the cooling mixture had been allowed to stand an hour or more. A piece of cardboard was supported 2 inches from the bottom of the inner chamber on which the roots to be frozen were arranged. In some instances scion and stock roots were cut from the young trees and tied together and frozen. Other series included the trunk as well as the roots. Extra long mercury thermometers graduated to one degree C. per inch were made for recording the temperatures at different depths in the inner chamber. They were from 14 to 30 inches in length and graduated in auch a way that the freezing point on each one was near the top. The volume of mercury in the bulb was large but the column extremely small. In order to take the low temperature readings it was necessary to raise the thermometer a few - inches. The volume of mercury was so large, however, that this process did not change the reading before it could be taken. The error introduced by the fine column of mercury is thought to be small. These thermometers were checked with standardized ones in the chemistry department and the U. S. Weather Bureau office and found to be accurate to within one - half of one degree. Since only a portion of the material could be frozen at one operation and since it was impossible to duplicate the tem - peratures, rates of cooling, etc., for any two operations, it was deemed advisable to use as many varieties as possible in each series. A temperature of 32 F. or lower was maintained in the cool chamber before the roots were inserted. Most of the material was exposed to temperatures ranging from 32 to -4° F. The length of exposure varied in the different series from lVi hours to 4 hours. Upon removing the roots from the cool chamber they were allowed to thaw out rapidly. They were then covered with moist sand in a warm room for 50 to 90 hours. This caused a discoloration in the tissue wherever injury had occurred. Attempts previously made to grow seedling stocks after they had been frozen had shown that the amount or degree of dis - coloration was a fair index to the severity of injury. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Root Injury of the Apple 7 RESISTANCE OF FRENCH CRAB AND SEEDLING STOCKS TO LOW TEMPERATURES Some preliminary trials were made in 1915 with one-year - old French crab and seedling apple stocks to determine their ability to resist low temperatures. The material was bought in early winter from commercial dealers and stored in an outdoor cellar. These stocks were frozen in the apparatus previously described When subjected to a temperature of 14 to 5 = F. for 2 hours it was found that a high per cent were killed. There was no apparent difference in the hard - iness of the two kinds of seedlings. At this temperature some individual seedlings of both kinds of stocks were killed and others were only slightly injured. This difference in hard - iness between individual seedlings was further apparent in the later work when scion and stock roots from numerous 2 and 3-year-old trees were frozen. These results are somewhat in accord with those secured by Emerson (1903), Chandler (1913), and Carrick (1920). Emerson showed that some individual seedlings would be killed at a temperature that would not injure others, tho he did not record the temperature at which injury occurred. Both Chandler and Carrick found that seedling apple roots were usually injured or killed at 14° to 10 c F. but that they were slightly more resistant to low temperatures in late winter than in early winter. In commenting upon the effects of low temperatures on roots of apple seedlings Carrick (1920) states, "One noticeable feature in the apple freezings was the differences in the individual resistance of roots similarly treated and frozen under the same conditions." RESISTANCE OF SCION AND STOCK ROOTS TO LOW TEMPERATURES In connection with a general study of the hardiness of apple roots it was deemed advisable to seek more information than was available upon the relative hardiness of scion roots of a large number of varieties and to compare their hardiness with that exhibited by seedling stocks. This, it was thought, not only would indicate the varieties that would probably best withstand the long dry winters of Nebraska without root injury, but would also give an indication as to the hazard that is taken in using trees that are budded upon seedling stocks. The results secured in freezing seedling roots show that many of them are killed at temperatures that are sometimes reached </seg>
            <seg id="p008">1 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 in our soils at a depth of 12 to 18 inches in midwinter. Craig (1900) in studying the root killing in Iowa following the win - ter of 1898-99, found in many cases that all roots below the union of grafted trees were killed while the roots and the trunk above the union were uninjured. In general he found scion roots to be more resistant than the roots produced from the seedling stocks. In reporting upon the injury in South Dakota for the same year Hansen ( 1899) maintained that the only way to avoid the loss of trees in such test winters is to bud them on hardy stocks such as Siberian crab. His expe - riences with seedling stocks show that they are less hardy than scion roots of the varieties commonly grown in the north. Upon examining some 3-year-old trees in 1900 he found that practically all of the scion roots of Hibernal had been killed by the very unusual conditions of the previous winter, showing that the scion roots of our hardiest varieties are not immune to winter injury. Several varieties of apples were propagated during the winter of 1914-15 by the piece- root graft method. Pieces of French crab seedlings 2 inches long were used as stocks and the scions were about 6 inches in length. The grafts were grown for 2 seasons in garden loam soil. Many of the 2-year - old trees had scion roots one-quarter of an inch in diameter. Several of these trees were taken up in March, removed to a cool cellar, and stored in moist sand. The roots of these trees were frozen April 3-7, 1917 to determine the resistance of scion and stock roots to low temperatures. The trunks were severed near the top of the original scion and the entire root system used. The position in the cool chamber was an upright one, thus placing the scion root r at a slightly higher level than the stock roots. Two thermometers were used, however, one near the bottom and the other 3 inches higher. The temperature in the region of the stock roots was never more than a frac - tion of a degree &lt;*older than that near the scion roots and for the first half of the period of freezing there was practically no difference. The results of this test are shown in Table 1. It will be noted from Table 1 that in general the scion roots of most varieties used were somewhat more hardy than the stock roots. It is also evident that the small roots were less hardy than larger, older ones. It is interesting to note that the roots of Chenango were injured more than Red Astrachan and Northern Spy. Where a rather low temperature was maintained for 2% hours the scion roots of N. W. Greening were only injured while all of the stock roots were killed, and the sapwood above the union was bright but brown in the </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Root Injury of the Apple 9 stock. Fameuse also was hardier than the stock upon which it was grafted. The test with Delicious was a severe one because of the low temperatures that were maintained. Other trees were frozen April 8 to May 4, 1920 (Table 2). These trees were propagated by the piece root graft method upon French crab stocks, and grown under nursery conditions for 3 seasons. They were removed from the nursery in early March to a cool cellar where the roots and a portion of the trunks were covered with moist sand. At the time these trees were dug it was noted that some varieties had produced roots from the scion portion of the graft the first year in the nursery, while others did not form roots above the union of the graft until the second and third years. In all cases the lateral roots from the stock were formed the first season and were therefore 3 years old when frozen. These trees were frozen in a refrigeration room where a temperature of approximately 5 F. was being maintained. All of tne trees included in the 5 lots (Table 2) were cut off at the "ground level," the roots placed in large, open boxes at the time they were exposed to the low temperatures. The injury to the cortex and cambium of the scion and stock was noted as well as the injurv to the scion and stock roots of the various iiieties. will be noted from Table 2 that at the lower tempera- tures used as in Lot 1 the stock roots were injured to a greater dagrac than the scion roots. That scion roots of most of the varieties used are hardier than stock roots produced from French crab seedlings is further emphasized when it is remem - l&gt;ered that the stock roots were in most cases one year older and larger than the scion roots with which they were com - pared. Small roots are injured more than the larger ones at a given temperature (Table 1). In all cases where a small root was compared with a larger one emanating from the same source, the injury was greater in the case of the smaller root. Chandler (1913) comments upon the fact that apple roots were injured more severely near the smaller end but he attributed this tenderness of the root tips to the fact that the small end was produced deeper in the soil. Carrick (1920) after freezing apple roots of different sizes concludes that the resistance to cold is in direct proportion to the diameter of the root. He also found that small roots of French crab and American stocks were injured more when frozen than larger roots of the same kinds that had been produced at the same soil depth. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 Tahi.k I. -Effect of Ion- temprmture* on xcion mui xto*/,- rimt* of tiro- i/tiir-olil treet (Frozen April 3. 1!U7&gt; Chenango 5.3 Chenango Scion roots: Slight injurj (4 tree* i 2:30 19.9 in cambium and cortex; sapwixM 4 :(M) 1 1 Red Astrachan I:M 10.8 Red Astrarhan S&lt;-ion root*: Yer&gt; i3 trees) 5:00 10.0 slight injury to cambium and cortex not injured. Stock roots: All shown, slight injury in cambium and cortex 9:30 14.5 Chenango Scion roots: Cambiurr 10:00 10.2 and cortex injured: sapwood nol 10:30 8.3 injured. Chenango 1 tree 11:00 7.0 1 1 M 6.6 Northern Spy 12:00 6.0 Northern Spy Scion roots: Cambium 1 tree and cortex slightly injured. Stock roots: Small ones killed: sapwood of roots ' , inch in diameter not injured Northwest Greening 2:30 12.0 Scion roots: Injury to cambium and 4 trees) 2:45 6.4 cortex of all: slight injury on some 3:00 3.6 ' 4 inch in diameter. Stock roots: 3:30 2.1 All killed. Original graft: Sapwood 4:00 1.8 bright above union and brown thru- 4:30 .7 out below union. 5:00 .9 5:15 1:60 16.3 not injured ■i:M) l:i.5 Leas than on Chenango. Sapvto Variety Exposure and temperature Fahrenheit ) Remarks r'henango 9::1O 9:45 10:00 10:15 10:30 10:45 1 1 :(M) 11:15 1 1 :•«» 2H.2 20.5 19.2 15.4 15.1 14.0 12.fi 9.7 9.0 , Scion roots: Slight injury in cambium and cortex: sapwood not injured. Stock roots: Slightly colored iii cortex and cambium: sapwood not injured. Original graft : Not injured </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Root Injury of the Apple Yamm I. Concluded. -Effect of low temperatures on sewn ami &lt;/.-. ■/• root* of two-year-old trees (Frozen April 3. 1917) Exposure and temperature Fahrenheit i Variety Remarks hirlev 10:30 14.0 Shirley -Scion roots: Slight injury to root ' s in. in diameter. Original 10:45 9.3 graft: Slight injury in cambium above union; cambium dead below union. Rome Beauty -Scion roots: Medium Rome Beauty 1 1 :00 5.t» injury: slight color thruout sapwood. Plumb Cider rl:15 4.3 Plumb Cider -Scion roots: Medium 1 1 :30 2.3 injury. 11:45 1 Opalescent —Scion roots: Medium in- ■•scent 1 tree each 12:00 .7 jury to cambium and cortex; sap- rm mt 12:45 wood bright. Original graft: Slight color in cambium above union: 1:00 .8 cambium dead below union. Stock roots: All dead on three trees and severely injured on one. 2:15 20.1 2:45 14.7 3:15 13.3 3:45 12.0 4:15 11.7 4:45 11 J 5:00 11.3 Scion roots: Very slight to no color in roots '4 in. in diameter: smaller roots slight injury. Stock roots: Injury in cambium and cortex of all. Kameust trtn 3:00 —.4 Scion roots: Two '4 in. in diameter severely injured; others dead. Stock roots: All dead. Micious 3:15 —.4 trees 3:30 3.2 4:00 5.0 4:30 1.4 5:00 —.4 10:45 12.6 11:15 20.7 11:45 17.0 12:45 14.4 1:15 14.4 1 :45 12.9 Scion roots: Medium injury; small ones dead. Stock roots: Severe in - jury; small ones dead. Patton tree* </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 T.Ull.K \\.—h'tff&lt;t of Itrtr tt lit /unit mix on tttnthiti lit mill tint t l/ftll -tlltl tffts ft n in i-tfrit/t rut i» Miiv 4. 1990 hi Frown April rf injury Scion Stock Variety ™ on BWK Remark Lateral Angina Lateral Original roots KM roots stork LOT I. 1&gt;ATK FROZEN, APRIL .1; EXPOSURE Hol'Ks TF.MI'EKVTl KK T&lt; ' I t Early Pennock Severe Sever* Seek-no-further Severe Killed Northern Sp\ Severe Severe Rome Slight Killed Severe Plumb Cider Slight Killed Killed MoMahon Slight Slight Killed Killed Early Harvest Injured Severe King David Slight Slight Severe Sev Payne's Keeper Injured Injured Killed Kill Bismark Severe Severe Gano Injured Sligh Severe Grimes Severe Severe Givens Severe Sever* Black Twig Slight Sligh Killed U)T II. KATE FROZEN, APRILS; EXPOSURE, 2 Hoi US 1(1 MINI Tf TEMPERATURE To 1.1 t Peerless Injured St-vert Genet Genet Severe Slight Killed Killed Scion roots vt Flora Belle Slight Slight Severe Severe sin Slight Slight Severe Sev Sheriff Severe Severe Killed Tetofsky Slight Slight Sever.- Lyman Sweet Normal Slight Severe S.-v.-r. Normal Slight Severe Se\ Liveland Liveland Injured Severe Severe 3«v« Shockley Injured Killed Killed Injured Killed Killed Collins Injured Slight Severe I^)T 111. DATE FROZEN. APRIL 23; EXPOSURE HofKS TEMPERATURE To 1.1 K Hibernal Severe Killed Florence Killed Killed Killed Missouri Pippin Severe Severe Severe Slight Newton Pippin Injured Severe Severe Willow Twig Severe Killed Killed Charlamoff Slight Severe Injured Mclntosh Injured Injured Trunk injured ir West tit-Id Severe Killed Severe spot Isham Killed Killed Dyer Killed Injured Missing Link Severe Killed Killed Killed Tompkins Co. King Killed Injured </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Root Injury of the Apple 13 liinn scion [root small small I aiw.k II. Continued, h'tf.rt t Degree of injury Stock Ml Remark: Original Lateral Original roots scion roots stock Black Twig Killed Killed Injured Killed Killed Killed Severe Slight Severe n. (irant ("rat \ Slight Killed Severe Severe Killed Killed Severe Severe K Injured Killed Severe T IV I &gt;ATE FROZEN, MAY 4; EXPOSURE. I HuUKS TEMPERATURE. 20.1° TO U°P Injured Normal Injured Normal Injured Normal Severe Normal lialrlw Black Ben Davis Red Astrachan Slight Normal Killed Normal Injured Killed Injured Normal Severe Slight ar o injured Injured Normal Slight Normal Normal Slight Normal \\ Serious Injured Slight Slight Killed Killed Killed Slight Kurr Killed Severe Injured One small miner Pearmair Killed Killed Killed Cral Slight Normal Injured Normal Killed Slight Normal Normal Normal Rorm Klora Ht Nixonite Normal Normal Slight Fameus*- Slight Normal Injured Normal Scion roots Plumb Cidt 1'eerles* Slight Normal Severe Injured Injured Injured Normal Injured Normal Slight Normal Slight Normal Injured Normal Early Harves Champion Tetofsky Senator Slight Normal Normal Killed Slight Lyman Sweet Hyslop Crab Gano Slight Killed Slight Severe Normal Injured Normal Scion roots Slight Slight Slight Normal Normal Slight Normal Texas Red Siberian Crab Giant Geneton Shockley Injured Normal Injured Normal Normal Service Normal Killed Slight Killed Normal Red Romanite Genet Injured Normal Severe Normal Slight Injured Severe Slight King David Normal tf'it of Inn- ti -in /&gt;, nitnrex mi MM ihl tni x fmzi n in refrigeration /&lt;&lt;&lt; l'i&lt;»7..'ii April :!. t&lt;&gt; May 4. l!&gt;20) Large Riil Sibt-riar Iowa Blush Ksopus </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 Tabu: II. — Continued. — Effect &lt;&gt;f loir tern/* nit urrx &lt;&gt;n &lt;&lt;nnbiitn tmd vortv.e of tkree-year-ol&lt;l trees frozen in refrigeration room ( Frozen April 3, to May 4, 1920) Degree of injury Scion Stock Variety Remark* Lateral Original Lateral Original roots scion roots stock roots stock Sheriff Killed Normal Injured Injured Slight Slight Shirley Slight Normal Normal Bismark Severe Slight Yellow Siberian Oral) Slight Normal McMahon Slight Slight Normal Injured Scioi it sma Slight Slight Normal ()kat&gt;ena Injured Normal Injured Sma Slight 'i Grimes Severe Slight Killed Northern Spy Normal Normal Killed Normal Givens Normal Normal Early Pinnock Normal Normal Injured Slight Normal Normal Collins Injured Normal U&gt;T V. DATE KKOZEN, MAY EXP« I KK J Hurt TKMl'KKATl KK Tl&gt; Gano Injured Normal Norma Killed Slight Slight Seven Sever* Senator Severe Killed Black Ben Davis Severe Seven- Peerless Injured Injure* Injured Injured Killet Okabena Severe Slight Injured Injured Norma Norma Norma Norma Norma Norma Champion Severe Slight Baldwin Injured Normal Sev Payne's Slight Normal Rome Slight Slight Injured Kump Slight Normal Giant Geneton Slight Normal Arkansas Severe Severe Severe Severe Sligr Siberian Crab Slight Slight Normal Normal Injured Normal Slight Bismark Normal Normal Slight Slight Paragon Normal Slight McMahon Normal Normal Normal Injured Injured Injured Hyslop Crab Slight Normal Fameuse Slight Normal Normal Normal Slight King David Injured Slight Red Astrachan Slight Normal Early Pennoek Slight Normal Early Harvest Slight Injured Injured Slight Normal Normal Injured Injured Injured Normal Normal Injured Slight Slight Injured Shirley Slight Injured Slight Yellow Transparent Slight Severe Givens Slight Slight Plumb Cider Severe Killed Severe Injured Severe Slight Nixonite Severe Severe Summer Pearmain Injured Severe Romanite Slight Norma Slight Normal </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Root Injury of the Apple 15 I uh.f. II. Conclude*!.- Effect of low temperature* on cambium f tlm&lt; -i/iiir-o/i/ tni x frozen in refrigeration room The scion roots of nearly all varieties, when size is taken into consideration, showed greater resistance than stock roots. Most of the varieties that might be expected to exhibit max- imum hardiness, such as Siberian crab, Walbridge, Yellow Transparent, Bismark, Charlemoff, and Hyslop, had produced scion roots only sparingly and they were small to very small in size. The scion roots of these varieties, however, showed more than average hardiness. In the few instances where the stock roots proved to be hardier than those of the scion, it is supposed that a seedling possessing unusual hardiness had been used. Such varieties as McMahon, Tetofsky, Charlamoff , Fameuse, Early Pinnock, Hyslop, Yellow Transparent, and Northern Spy exhibited more than average hardiness. The degree of injury above and below the union of the original graft was often quite marked. That portion of the tree between the "ground level" and the graft union is desig - nated as "original scion," and it was in nearly all cases hardier than the "original stock," or that portion below the graft union. It was observed also that the stem above the ground level was in all cases hardier than that below the surface, indi - cating a differentition of stem and root tissue. In some instances the original scion was injured more severely than I-W..-11 April t, to May t. 1990) Decree of injury Yarietj Scion St ork Remarks Lateral Original Lateral Original roots scion roots stock Flora Belle Tetofsky LiveUnd West field Opalescent Texas Red Northern Spy Prolific Crab Sheriff York (lenet Shook ley ColHni Injured Injured Slight Normal Injured Normal Slight Slight Severe Normal Slight Slight Normal Slight Injured Normal . . . Slight Slight Injured Normal Injured Normal Normal Slight Slight Injured Severe Normal Injured Slight Slight Slight Injured Slight Normal Slight Slight Normal Slight Normal Normal Scion root small Normal Normal Slight </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 the seedling portion of the graft. This was not true, how - ever, with most varieties that are commonly grown in the north. The greater resistance of the scion portion of the graft in the case of the Wealthy is illustrated in Figure 4. SCION ROOT FORMATION OF DIFFERENT VARIETIES The part that the root system of an apple tree plays in causing fruitfulness, regularity of bearing, adaptability to dif - ferent soils, as well as avoiding damage by insects and dis - eases, has not received as much attention as the subject probably warrants. Very little is known about the behavior of varieties of apples entirely upon their own roots or of the de - sirability of roots of certain varieties as stocks for other varie - ties. In England, Hatton (1920) has found that the Paradise crab as well as the "Free" stocks used so extensively there are extremely variable in their rooting habits. Some of them form a mass of fine, fibrous roots, while others develop long hori- zontal laterals. The vigor of the seedling trees he found to 1* one of the most variable characteristics noted in all of tht stocks studied. This difference in vigor was not very pro - nounced the first year but it was very marked when the seed v se lings were allowed to attain an age of 4 to 6 years. He believes that by selecting stocks which produce desirable roots and then propagating them vegetatively, the uniform root system ten so obtained will probably give much more satisfacto ilts than have been secured when very unlike stocks are used. It seems reasonable to suppose that some of the differences found among trees of a given orchard may be due to unlike root sys - tems, resulting from the use of French crab and seedling stocks of different vigor and rooting habit. It is generally known that some varieties are more suscep - tible to crown gall than others. In Australia and South Africa it is common practice to use roots of Northern Spy as propa - gating stocks in order to overcome injury from woolly aphis. French crab and seedling stocks vary considerably in many characteristics. It has been demonstrated by this investiga - tion and by others that both of these stocks contain individual seedlings that differ widely in hardiness. Furthermore it is known that the seeds from our commercial varieties of apples will not reproduce trees having the same characteristics as those of the variety. Such seedlings when grown to a fruiting age produce trees that differ in habit of growth, foliage, vigor, fruitfulness, season of ripening, quality of fruit, etc. From a comparison of relative foliage condition, vigor, characteristics </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Root Injury of the Apple 17 of growth, and hardiness of French crab seedlings that has been made in connection with this investigation, it is probable that they would show as much variation as American seedling stocks if grown to a fruiting age. In studying the selection of propagating stocks for citrus fruit* Webber (1920) concludes that many of the variations found in the orchard are due in part to stock differences. He recommends the policy of discarding at least 50 per cent of the seedlings when they are transplanted from the seedbed, as a means of securing strong, uniform stocks upon which to bud. Shaw ( 1919) advances the belief that many of the indi - vidual differences among trees of the same apple orchard might be overcome by propagating trees on their own roots or using scion roots of another variety known to furnish a ngenial union. Since this investigation involved the growing of a large number of nursery trees, it was deemed advisable to take de - tailed notes upon the tendency of different varieties to form roots from scion wood. It was thought that a pronounced tendency to root at an early age from above the union would l»e an indication that such varieties might be propagated from uttings or that they could be made to grow wholly from scion (»its by removing the stock portion of the graft after the tees had grown for one or two seasons in the nursery. At the time the trees were removed from the nursery a comparison was made of the various varieties on their tendency to form roots from scion wood. These data are presented in Table 3. The degree of injury to the tops of these varieties as a result the severe winter of 1917-18 is also given. Some varieties of apples, like Missing Link, Okabena, Black Twig, Hibernal, and McMahon, root very readily from scion wood. These varieties and others with this tendency are almost wholly supported from scion roots at 3 years of age. Other varieties, however, like Jonathan, Ramsdell Sweet, Rome, Patton, Northern Spy, Champion, Wealthy, and Ingram, have very few roots from scion wood at 3 years of age. Some of the hardiest varieties of apples, therefore, root readily from scion wood the first year while others such as Wealthy and Patton form roots from above the union very slowlv. The tendency of the variety to form scion roots is appar - ently in no way correlated with hardiness or vigor of growth. In a report upon varietal habits in scion root formation, Shaw (1919) in Massachusetts found marked differences. His trees were 2 years from the graft and in many instances the varie- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 18 n •k &gt;T ,1 rill. — Ti'ht/i mi/ nf •liffei-i'iit i-iir'ntiix tn form si'mn root urns, i;i. mill cowptirtitirs fiardmes* of tops No. To S in i ur &gt;- Variety Trees Winter Scion root formation Re marks 1917-18 45 None Few, small, third year Rank grower. enlarged at unit: N. W. Greening :!M Slight Few »cion roots third year Vigorous growe: 17 Medium 1 8 Slight 14 Slight 1 -1 Slight 5 S None Large scion nati KEu Very few third year Strong grow* largely first year Third year some Small, mostly third year 20 None 30 Slight Medium, first and second Vigorous « year Ming Unk Tendency very great first Tree* almost wh year, more than any supported from h »ther variety Willow Twig I :, Slight Medium first and second vear New Town Pippin Missouri Pippin Medium Slight, third year M Slight 50 None I: Nsjm Few first year First year on fen Medium first and second year •3Sr Severe Few third year Strong g II None Many first year vigorous 16 Medium 21 Slight 36 None Some third year Slock enlarged a Black Twij Perry Kuaset Hibernal First year mostly .-nlarged Some third year St fk -nlargeda 30 None 20 None 36 None Mercer Co. Crab Large Red Siberian Medium second yea 12 Very slight 6 Medium Nun** Some second vear On. Grant Crab Northern Spy 1 5 Medium 2 Medium 8 Medium I* Medium 1.1 Slight 1 1 Slight IS Slight 8 Medium 1 X Severe 14 None Many first year Few third year None Finit year on few SnEr None First year on man First year usual! 3£ Few third year Very readily' flrat year Tapnmt formed First year 5 S%ht 28 Shgh- Some third year Medium second yea Slight Few third year 22 None Few first year Yellow Siberian Crab None Few first year 28 Medium 211 Medium 44 Slight 28 Severe 23 Slight 53 None Mostlv second year Few third year Some first year Few third year Taproot formed Few third year Almost none third year ftanudell Sweet 8gufcfcCr.b Severe Few third year 3 None None 19 Medium 21 Severe 26 Medium 25 None Small second and third year Martha Crab Medium second year First year Few first year . Vigorous grower 7 : Slight 50 None Few first year Few first year 20 Medium 36 Severe . 16 Slight 21 Slight 24 Medium Few second and third year Mostly first year Very readily first year Few third year First and second year Profusely first yemr l-"ng literm 1 S'.me Forma tap i </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Root Injury of the Apple 19 Fable III. — ('(iiicluilol. -T, mlency of different rtirietiei to form Him /■••••/» in /.&lt;&lt;/&gt;,/■//. ,u,d com para tirt luirdinrxx of toj&gt;x ties listed as rooting readily or sparsely from the scion cor - respond rather closely to the observations here given. For some varieties, however, there was a wide variation noted in this regard. There was considerable root and trunk injury to some nursery stock in the central west as a result of the low mid - winter temperatures of 1917-18. From December 7 to 15 of that winter the minimum temperature varied from 0° to 16 F. and for 16 days in January it was below zero with a minimum temperature of - 23 C F. It is possible that the stock roots of some of the trees in this test were injured by these low temperatures, tho no indications of injury were noted at Variety No. Trao Top injury. Winter 1917 18 Scion root formation Remark- 1.-II..W Bellflower Kamadrll Swn-t Vate» Plumb Cider Kut ledge Itino Black Twig (irimes Weatfteld Winewp Karly Harvoi i "h*-nanic.. Tm&gt; Red Spencer Seedlm Salome Yellow Transparent Hurt Summer Fearmain Senator Niionite Hen I&gt;av» Jonathan I &gt;elicious Little Romanm- &lt; tpalewent .Flora Belle L&gt; man Sweet Kepka Malenka Pnev'a S»H*-t . lWh Trtohky Shorkley Roman Stem Kameuae York Porter Mother Red Astrakhan Black Ben I »vi. 9 1(1 22 22 IS 20 10 9 17 27 tl 4 8 15 2 9 6 27 31 50 77 28 4 42 26 n 21 1» ■i:&gt; 19 2 35 23 10 S 25 15 23 23 Sevw*. . Severe Medium S«*V»Tf Sl«ht Medium Slight Medium Medium Slight Medium Slight Svvt*re Medium None Medium Medium Medium Slight Slight Slight Medium Slight Severe Slifht None Medium Medium Medium siirht Severe. Severe Medium Severe Medium Medium Slight Severe Slight Slight Few third ye»r Few third year Few third year Few third year First and second year First and second year Second year mostly Second year, some First year usually Few first year Readily first year Slight third year Well third year None Well third year Well third year None First and second year Few first year Profusely first year Many first year Very few third year Few first year, many second year Few second and third yearn Mostly second year Second year Very few small third year Few first year None Freely first year Few small third yettr Few third year None Mostly third year Mostly third year Few second year Pew second year Few third year Very few third year Many first and second year Readily first year Fibroua roots Vtforotl* grower </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 20 the time the trees were removed. If root injury did occur it may have influenced the degree and amount of scion root for - mation of some varieties. A number of varieties have been propagated by using a short piece of seedling root. When the scion roots are suffi - cient to support the tree, the stock portion of the root system will be removed and the tree cut back and replanted. This seems to be the most feasible method of getting self-rooted trees, tho Shaw (1919) mentions that limited tests indicate that most varieties may be readily propagated by mound layers. Own rooted trees of a number of standard varieties are now being grown. Some trees of each will be budded to other varieties with a view of studying the reciprocal relationship and its effects upon the behavior of the trees in the orchard. In conjunction with the freezing experiments with apple roots, some midwinter temperature changes were observed in an orchard soil at depths of 7'-^ and IO'-j inches respectively. This was done in order to determine whether or not the critical temperatures for apple roots as established by the freezing tests in the laboratory are actually reached in an orchard Ml several inches below the surface during the coldest part of the winter. Electrical resistance thermometers with a balance indi - cator were used in securing the soil temperatures.* With this instrument it is not necessary to make corrections for the re - sistance of the wires leading from the bulbs to the balance indicator, as in the case of the apparatus which measures re - sistance directly. The bulbs used were carefully checked against one another and compared with standardized ther - mometers used by the Lincoln office of the U. S. Weather Bureau. They were found to be accurate to within a fraction of a degree. The soil temperatures recorded ( Fig. 1 ) were taken during January, February, March, and April, 1916. The orchard soil used for this purpose is a medium heavy, upland loam and it had previously been divided into different plats with regard to culture. The sod plat consisted of blue grass which had been cut once each season but not removed. The sod of this plat gave a better mulch than that afforded by the other plats. The clean culture plat had received clean cul - tivation for the past 3 seasons and the soil was bare in winter. The clover plat was mowed once in mid-season and the hay removed. There was very little mulch effect in winter on this •This apparatus was obtained from the Leerix A Northrup Company, Phila - delphia, Penn. Indicator No. K004 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Root Injury of the Apple 21 &gt;lat. The cover crop culture plat had been cultivated until nidsummer for 2 seasons and then sowed to millet. During he winter months the millet afforded a coarse, loose mulch. The small bulbs were placed horizontally at 7 l /i and 10 Vi nches below the surface in each plat. These instruments &gt;vere put into place without disturbing the soil directly over hem. This was accomplished by digging a trench and insert - ng the bulbs in small holes made at the proper depths. The emperature readings were taken at 8 o'clock in the morning ind at 5:30 in the afternoon. The snow was kept removed from the soil immediately above the bulbs. Soil moisture leterminations were made of these plats at approximately 7-day intervals. A composite sample of soil representing the upper 8 inches was used. The moisture content of the sample was determined and is expressed on the dry basis. The daily minimum soil temperatures of the various plats ire given graphically in Fig. 1, together with the mean daily air temperature. The soil moisture content of the different ats is also shown. The temperature variations were least in the sod plat and the minimum reached in midwinter at 7Va inches under the sod was 2.5.5 F. or several degrees above what appears to be the danger point for apple roots. The clean culture plat on the whole responded most readily to atmospheric changes. The clover and culture cover crop plats were intermediate. Fol - lowing the sudden cold weather of early January the clean culture plat not only cooled more quickly but responded more to the low temperatures than the others. When the mean daily air temperature remained well below freezing for several days, however, as in late January and early February, the soil temperature fluctuations of the clean culture plat were not greatly different from those of the clover and cover crop plats. The minimum temperature for this period in the cover crop culture, clover, and clean culture plats, was approximately 19 F. According to the laboratory tests one would not expect any injury under the conditions that prevailed during this period even at a depth of 7.5 inches. * The relatively high temperatures of the sod plat may be attributed to the mulch effect of the bluegrass sod and cut grass. It has been shown by Bouyoucos (1916) that a mulch of either snow or vegetation will prevent excessively low soil Mu&gt;i of the small roots of mature apple trees in this type of soil are below 7.5 inches but above 20 inches. This wax determined by removing the root* of two B«n Davis tree*. 14 yearn old. The noil win removed in 3-inch layers to a depth of S.5 for a radiux of 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">™** * ***** *» z c </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Root Injury of the Apple 23 t n* |5Of- SOD PLAT PCPCCNT M0I5TUIJC-1DAY INTtCVALS -UPPtPOIN MIN SOIL TCMPC1JATUTJE AT DePTH OP 1 INCHES ■ffect of clean culture upon mid-winter soil temperature*. See • A &gt; for mean daily air temperature for these plats. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 24 temperatures even at a depth of 3 inches. The minimum tem - perature in these plats was somewhat lower than that recorded by Woodbury, Noyes, and Oskamp (1917) for an Indiana orchard. They did not have a cultivated plat, however, and their records were for a 9-inch depth. The temperatures at a depth of 10' 2 inches varied in a manner similar to those for 7'v inches. However, when the soil temperature was below freezing it was always from 1 to 4 degrees warmer at the greater depth. It is believed from this that the temperature even in a cultivated unprotected soil seldom if ever gets low enough in this region to endanger apple roots 12 inches or more below the surface. The moisture content of the different plats varied for the most part between 25 and 35 per cent. The temperature of the soil at 7'^ inches is thought not to have been influenced greatly by the moisture content, tho the greater responses in the clean culture plat to atmospheric changes in January were probably caused in part by the surface soil being very dry at I that time. Some very comprehensive soil temperatures havt corded by Perin and Swezey (1903) of this Statioi k temperatures were for depths ranging from 1 36 inches for the period 1891 to 1902 inclusive. They akt by means of special mercury thermometers and fat soil was kept free from snow and other mulch. The Januar; February temperatures recorded by them for 1894. 189 1899, 1900, 1901, and 1902 at the 9-inch depth are shown i Fig. 2. The soil temperatures for 1923 taken a with recording soil and air thermographs are al wr It would appear from the 7 years' records here reported. Fig. 2, that critical temperatures for apple roots wen - reached during this period only in 1899. During February of that year the temperature at 9 inches below the surface re - mained at 11 F. for 4 days. It has been shown that this tem - perature will severely injure or kill apple roots. The records also show that the temperature for this same period at 6 inches was approximately 8 F. and at 12 inches 14 F. At 36 inches the temperature was 31.5 F. The winter of 1898-99 was perhaps the most severe ever recorded in the northern states and it is notably true that apples as well as many other fruits suffered from root injury at that time. MIDWINTER TEMPERATURES OF A WET AND A DRY SOIL It is generally believed that winter injury to the roots of plants is more severe in a dry than in a wet soil. Very little Thin instrument is made hy Julian P. Frifi * S&lt;m«. Maltimurf Marjrl* </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Root Injury of the Apple il: Fig 2 —Minimum soil temperature at Lincoln. Nebraska, for several winters at a depth of nine imhe». (Records for IW, 1X98. 1S99. 1SO0. 1901. and 1902 from report of </seg>
            <seg id="p026">data have been published, however, to show whether or not the greater injury in a dry soil is due to lower temperatures or to freezing in a drier medium. Emerson's work (1903). where he showed that injury was greater in the dry soil, had a rather direct bearing upon this question, but he did not record the temperatures in the dry and moist soils. He con - cluded, however, that the more frequent alternate freezing and thawing in the dry soil was probably a contributing factor to greater injury, tho he stated: "On further investigation it may be found that roots are simply unable to withstand severe freezing or to recover from it unless surrounded by an abund - ance of moisture." Macoun (1907-08) in reporting upon win - ter injury to fruit trees in Canada assumes that plants will be injured more at a given temperature in a dry soil than in a wet soil but Chandler (1913) interprets his own freezing data to mean that the reverse would likely be true. When water was placed in the same test tube with roots, Carrick ( 1920) found that there was some protection afforded against low tempera - tures until all the water was frozen but he also found when soils of different moisture content were placed in the freezing chamber around the roots that there was no appreciable dif - ference in the amount of injury. The difference in moisture content of the plats shown in Fig. 1 was not sufficiently great to determine the influence of soil moisture on minimum soil temperatures. During the win - ter of 1916-17 an attempt was made to determine the rate of change in temperature as well as the minimum temperatures of a wet and a dry soil. APPARATUS AND METHODS USED IN SECURING TEMPERATURES OF WET AND DRY SOILS A large box 9 feet long, 3 feet wide, and 2.5 feet deep was made of tongue-and-groove cypress material. Two partitions were inserted so as to form 3 compartments 3 feet square at the surface and 2.5 feet deep. These compartments were lined on the sides with tin and painted with asphaltum. The bottom of the box was perforated with holes one-half inch in diameter approximately every 2 inches to permit excess water to pass out. The box was placed in the soil so that the top was flush with the surface of the ground, and a covering was made after the fashion of that used for weather recording instruments, to permit the circulation of air yet excluding rain and snow. The soil for filling the compartments of the box was taken in November from the orchard clover plat previously de- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Root Injury of the Apple s </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 scribed. The surface of the soil was scraped free of vegetation and measured to correspond to the measurements of the box. In order to insure the soil being put into the box in the same way in which it had existed in the orchard, a large number of paper bags were used to receive the soil as it was taken from the orchard plat inch by inch. These bags were emptied into the box in inverse order from which they were taken from the field. * The soil was tamped frequently as the box was being filled. Electrical resistance thermometers were placed horizon - tally at depths of 7.5 and 10.5 inches near the center of the 2 end compartments. In order to avoid error due to settling of the soil, wires of known length were attached to each end of the thermometers and allowed to extend to the surface. The surface of the soil was kept at the proper level as indicated by the wires. The wires were insulated from the thermometers by means of rubber tubing. After the thermometers were placed, enough water was added to bring the moisture content to 18 per cent. Both plats contained less than 20 per cent moisture until January 1. when the "wet" plat was watered copiously. (See Fig. :?. ) After this time the moisture content of the wet plat was between 26 and 32 per cent, while the dry plat was allowed to remain be- tween 13 and 17.5 per cent. The moisture (let ■it were made from soil samples taken at 6 to 9 inch ,\ surface. The temperature readings of the soil were made at 8:00 A. M. and 5:30 P. M. The mean daily air temperature was as computed by taking the mean of the daily maximur imum temperatures. It will be noted (Fig. 3) that the soil temperature at a depth of 7.5 inches was somewhat similar in the 2 plats thru - out the period of the test. There were some exceptions to this. however. Following some continued warm weather in early January when the soil temperature in both plats was above freezing, the soil in the dry plat responded more quickly and to a greater degree to the sudden drop in atmospheric temper - ature on January 9, 10, and 11. After this cold period the soil temperatures in both plats not only remained below freezing until early March but responded to atmospheric changes to approximately the same extent. When the weather warmed up in early March sufficient to give a mean daily temperature • A few baim rrprenrntinu the lh-22-inrh surface noil mi -ht be uxed in the box. mined </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Root Injury of the Apple 29 A resistance of M to low t ti V ilurt- mI. scion uninjured above freezing for several consecutive days, the thermometer in the dry plat was more quickly affected by it. On March 9 the dry soil reached a temperature of 37.5 F. and afterwards maintained an average temperature well above freezing, while the wet plat remained at 32 F. or lower until March 20 when it rose rapidly. Thus, it would seem that while the minimum temperature is practically the same in a wet and dry soil at 7.5 inches depth during long periods of extreme cold, a dry soil will be affected more quickly by early freezes and by warm weather in the spring. In this regard Bouyoucos (1916) has suggested that the slowness with which a peat soil warms up in the spring, compared with sand and loam, is because it holds a greater amount of water He thinks it is the latent heat of fusion of ice that causes the delay in the warming of soils pos - sessing larger amounts of water and not the high specific heat of water in the liquid state. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">The results of this test with a wet and a dry soil afford a possible explanation of why root injury is greater in a dry than in a wet one It would seem that the injury in the dry soil is greater, not because the amount of freezing is more severe, but because roots cannot withstand or possibly cannot recover from, the same degree of freezing in a dry medium as ia wet one. To conclude that the more frequent alternate ezing and thawing in a dry soil might cause greater injury tree roots is not justified, because the temperatures at ich this occurs are not low enough to cause any damage. e somewhat quicker response of dry soil to sudden cold uld not account for greater injury, because an atmospheric iperature that would cause a dry soil to reach and maintain ling temperatures would also cool a wet soil to practically same extent. The fact that a dry soil thaws somewhat re quickly than a wet one would not afford an explanation why killing is greater in a dry soil. Chandler (1913) and rrick (1920) have both shown that the rate of thawing has le if any effect on the amount of root injury. Several investigators have found that plant tissue is made more resistant to cold as the concentration of the cell sap is increased, tho in practically all instances succulent or tender parts of plants have been used. Apparently it is not known to what extent, if any, the cell sap of dormant tree roots is more concentrated in a dry soil than in a wet one. Chandler ( 1913) attempted but failed to increase the sap density of fruit tree wood by adding potassium chloride to the soil. The temperatures at which apple roots will be injured and killed are evidently obtained in practically the same degree in wet and dry soils at several inches below the surface of the ground in midwinter. The greater injury to apple roots when frozen in a dry soil can scarcely be explained on the basis of a different cell sap concentration, because a dry soil would tend to cause a greater sap density of the roots. It appears, there - fore, that roots in a moist soil can withstand more freezing without injury than roots in a dry soil because of the protec - tion against injury from freezing that is afforded by the sur - rounding moist medium. DISCUSSION AND GENERAL CONCLUSIONS It may be fairly assumed from the results reported here that there is danger of root injury to apples under Nebraska conditions during certain winters when the temperature is very low. This danger would be reduced materially by pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Root Injury of the Apple 31 viding a protective mulch of some kind. A mulch that will mat down to form a dense covering will afford more protection against root injury when there is no snow than one which forms a very coarse, loose mulch by standing erect. In Ne - braska the presence of snow is not sufficiently regular to be relied upon as a protection. Since the roots of the French crab and seedling stocks are somewhat more tender than scion roots of most varieties, it would seem advisable in Nebraska to use only piece root grafted apple trees until a hardy, vigorous, uniform stock can be found. The temperature goes several degrees lower in midwinter 6 inches below the surface than it does at 12 inches. In the cultivation of young apple trees, where root injury is feared, it ' ould be good practice to throw the soil to the trees in late summer and then work the ground level again in the spring. It has been shown that root injury is greater in a dry soil than in a moist one, tho there is practically no difference in the minimum temperature that is reached during long, cold periods in midwinter. Any method of culture, then, that is adopted should be one designed to conserve moisture in order to assure good growth and to furnish some protection against root injury. More protection would undoubtedly be furnished, however, by providing a mulch, even tho it was only a growth of late fall grass or weeds, than by attempting to conserve moisture by late summer cultivation. Clean cul - ture in early season followed with a cover crop, or a litter mulch of some kind in the fall, is good practice for young apple trees. When apple trees reach bearing age there is less danger of root injury, since the tender portion of the root system is deeper in the soil at that time and because, in the case of piece root grafted trees, of the development of the hardier scion roots. Clean cultivation may be practiced all summer on such trees with impunity, tho it is considered advisable to alternate culture on certain years with a crop that will add humus to the soil. Red clover is thought to be one of the best crops for a bearing orchard in eastern Nebraska, not only because it adds humus and nitrogen to the soil but also because it does not compete as much with the trees for the soil moisture as do many of the other crops. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 199 LITERATURE CITED Bouyoucos, G. J. Soil Temperature. Michigan Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 26, 1916. &lt; AKRK'k, D. B. Resistance of the Roots of Some Fruit Species to Low Temperatures. New York (Cornell) Agri. Exp. Sta. Memoir 36, 1920. Chandler, W. H. Winter Injury in New York State during 1917-18 Proc. Amer. Soc. Hort. Sci. p. 18-24, 1919. CHANDLER, W. H. The Killing of Plant Tissue by Low Temperatures Mo. Agri. Exp. Sta. Research Bui. 8, 1913. Craig, John. Observations and Suggestions on the Root-Killing of Fruit Trees. Iowa Exp. Sta. Bui. 44, 1900. Dorsey, M. J. The Hardiness Problem. Proc. Amer. Soc. Hort. Sci. p 210-224, 1920. Emerson, R. A. Experiments in Orchard Culture. Nebr. Agr. Exp Sta. Bui. 79, 1903. Emerson, R. A. The Relation of Early Maturity to Hardiness in Tr Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. l!Hh Annual Report, 1906. Goff, E. S. Effects of the February Freeze of 1899 upon Nurseries and Fruit Plantations in the Northwt 1899. it. Wis. Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui Hansen, N. E. Root Killing of Appl Bui. 65, 1899. Tree*. So. Dak. Agri. Exp rroN, R. G. Suggestions for the Jour. Royal Hort. Soc. Vol. XLV, Right Selection of Api Parts II and III, MM. k r)l N. \V. T. Winter Injury in Canada. Proc. Amer. Soc. He p. 13-17, 1918. MACOUN, W. T. Overcoming Winter Injury. Proc. Amer. Soo. Hort Sci. p. 15-27, 1908-4)'.*. Morse, W. J. Notes on Plant Diseases. Me. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 164 1909. Perin, S. W. and Swezey, G. D. Soil Temperatures at Lincoln. Nebr 1888 to 1902. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. 16th Annual Report 1903. riNDER, Max. Fruit Growing on the Northern Great Plains. I Dept. of Agri., Bureau of Plant Industry Cir. 58, 1919. rw, J. K. The Propagation of Apple Trees on Their Own Roots Mass. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 190, 1919. Webber, H. J. Selection of Stocks in Citrus Propagation. Cal. Agr Exp. Sta. Bui. 317, 1920. rDBURY, C. G. et al. Soil Management Investigations in a Young Apple Orchard. Ind. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 20f&gt;, 1917. 491-53* </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>