<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00012">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00012</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR JUVENILE DELINQUENTS AT GENEVA, NEBRASKA.  FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER, 30, 1904.</title>
			            <date value="1904">1904</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-28</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

OP THE 

GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR 
JUVENILE DELINQUENTS 

AT 

GENEVA, NEBRASKA. 

FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1904. </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
Hon. Jno. H. Mickey Governor 

BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

Hon. Geo. D. Fullmer President 

Hon. Geo. W. Marsh Secretary 

Hon. F. N. Prout. 

Hon. Peter Mortensen 

OFFICERS AND EMPLOYES OF SCHOOL. 

Horace M. Clark Superintendent 

Lyda J. McMahon Matron 

Lena E. Ward "A" Family Manager 

Nellie M. Curtiss "B" Family Manager 

Mrs. J. C. Wilkins Cooking Teacher 

Laura C. Bock Laundry Teacher 

F. Belle Douglass Sewing Teachor 

Tilla Clark Housekeeper 

M. L. Flick Engineer 

C. E. Argyle. Farmer </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
REPORT. 

I His Excellency, Governor John H. Mickey, and the Members 
of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings : 

Entlemen — I herewith present for your consideration the 
ith biennial report of the Nebraska Girls' Industrial 
ol for Juvenile Delinquents. 

E doing so I desire to thank you individually and colvely 
for your uniformally kind treatment of this insti?n 
and its various interests. 

During the biennium just closed we have had much to 
cheer us, and some things to sadden us; yet withal we are 
&lt;;la&lt;l of the progress made, and are constrained to speak hopefully 
of the future. 

Ilvery effort has been made by the management to observe 
strictest economy in every department, and we can truthy 
state not one dollar of any of our appropriations has 
l wasted. 

While we are as anxious to be economical in the affairs of 
the school as it is possible to be, yet we are not willing to 
allow economy so-called to be carried so far as to hinder the 
work the school is expected to do. 

W« find upon investigation that it is the experience of 
those in charge of reformatories everywhere that it is not 
marly so difficult to secure liberal aid for the maintenance 
of reformatories for boys as it is for institutions for girls. 
And while this seems to be true in too many cases, yet we 
can not complain of anything approaching parsimony in the 
appropriations made for this school. 

K'e have had the best of health among the inmates during 
past two years, as you will observe by reading the physi's 
report herewith appended. 

The work has been carried forward in the various departs 
in a very commendable manner, and the girls that 

Gbneya. Neb., November 30, 1904. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
254 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

have gone out have as a rule been well prepared to care for 
themselves in life's rough battle. 

Ee average of girls proving themselves faithful and doing 
has been about the same as in past years. Not all who 
from our care will turn out as we hope. Yet the per 
of good results is still very high, and we are pleased to 
port 

Our teachers have been very successful in the school work, 
and girls that came to us with a very limited knowledge of 
the very rudiments of an education have been carried forward 
to the seventh and eighth grade work of our district 
schools. For table of work carried in grades see table on 
school work. 

rie matron is deserving of especial mention because of 
interest and intelligent management of the work that 
fallen to her lot. 

Good will and harmony pervades every branch of our work. 
The money appropriated for repairs and improvements has 
been most carefully expended under the direction of the 
state architect, to whom we feel indebted for his courteous 
treatment. 

The entire interior of the building has received an overhauling. 
New steel ceilings have been put on both dormitories. 
Thirteen rooms have been nicely papered. The 
school rooms and dormitories have been freshly painted and 
calsomined. The stairways and halls have been stained, varnished, 
and calsomined as needed. And, as this report is being 
made up, the lower or basement story is receiving its 
final coat of paint, calsomine, and varnish. 

So that we are able to say that not for years has the interior 
of our building been in such a good state of repair. 

In our school work we have kept abreast of the times by 
keeping in touch with the latest methods advanced in school 
work. A new slate blackboard has been placed in the B 
school room, which gives much comfort to pupils and </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
255 

GIRLS 1 INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

As to the furnishings, the old carpets that had seen several 
years of hard service in the office, parlor, and part of the 
hers' apartments have been replaced with good new carpets. 
New shades have been put on all the windows. No 
other furnishings worthy of mention have been added, although'some 
are needed in other lines. 

The industrial classes receive instructions as noted in previous 
reports. Laundry work, house work, cooking, cutting, 
fitting, and making of all garments worn being the line of 
work carried on in the various departments. 

tgood talent for fancy needle work has been developed 
number of the girls, and they can find ready sale for 
articles of embroidery, hemstitching, and drawn work 
ey can find time to do. 

Since our last report we have adopted a uniform for the 
Sunday wear, consisting of white waists and black skirts. 
The effect is pleasing, and the girls seem quite proud of their 
appearance. 

P! have had two good years for gardening, and have 
I all the vegetables we have needed during the spring, 
ler, fall, and winter of each year. Our poultry yards 
furnished us with a good supply of eggs and poultry. 

Kir orchard produced a bountiful crop of cherries, plums, 
peaches during 1904, but for the year 1903 we had very 
s fruit. Our little vineyard produced a bountiful supply 
•apes for both years. 

I/e have seeded four acres more in alfalfa and expect herer 
to produce all the hay needed for the stock we keep, 
?ur report of two years ago we urged the need of a larger 
n so that dairying might be carried on. We are still of 
opinion that an institution having fifty, sixty, or seventy 
[thy, robust girls under its care could very successfully 
iuct a good sized dairy. It would be a source of income, 
would do much toward rendering the school self-Bupport- 

In other words, if true economy is what we are seeking we 
must perforce devise some way for making our institutions </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
256 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

as nearly self-supporting as possible, and with that end in 
what other method seems so feasible as dairying for an 
itution such as this? 

If an investment of $10,000 were made for an additional 
quarter section of land, the appropriation for the maintenance 
could be safely reduced fl,000 a year for the first bien 
nium after the land was stocked. And the next biennium ¦ 
reduction of f 1,500 per year could be made. 

I am thoroughly convinced that this plan is altogether both 
ible and profitable for the state. One very annoying 
slem could be settled by the purchase of land immediy 
adjoining the school, and that would be the disposal of 
erage. We are continually worried over this sewer propion, 
and feel that were the true situation realized the 
ter would be taken up and satisfactorily arranged for by 
coming legislature. 

Ehave but little more to add. You will find annexed 
1 tables showing the work done in the various departof 
the school. 

&gt;ur hundred and sixty girls have received training in 
this school since its organization. 

§ tiring the past two roars we have had seventy under our 
. During the past six months our average attendance 
l&gt;et'n fifty-two. 

We have but little patience with the cry of economy when 
it is carried to the extent of undertaking to cripple the work 
in the only school for the industrial training of delinquent 
girls in our state. 

to the complaint that our population is small we simply 
e to say that we have to contend with influences in our 
k that beset no other line of charitable work. And charalone 
prevents us from incorporating in our reports dist 
references to those influences. 

Ee recommend most heartily legislation that will place 
r the control of the state authorities every institution 
hatever character or name that undertakes to traffic in </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
257 


the unfortunate children of our state. We most sincerely 
trust this matter will receive attention. 

In closing we can not refrain from speaking of the strong 
support given us in our work here by the officers and employes 
of the school. Every one has been so loyal and no 
task has been so hard that it has not been cheerfully undertaken 
to help make the work what it should be. 

Kindness toward the girls has been the effort of each 
teacher, and not one of them has flinched in the face of duty. 

I am truly thankful to each assistant and wish that each 
one may prove as successful in every path of life as they 
have been in their work here. 

Respectfully submitted, 
Horace M. Clark, Superintendent. 

TABLE OF WORK DONE IN SCHOOL ROOM. 

I grade, 18 girls. Studies: Arithmetic, physiology, history, 
civil government, grammar, geography, spelling, 
and writing. 

¦ grade, 8 girls. Studies: Arithmetic, physiology, history, 
geography, grammar, spelling, and writing. 

¦ grade, 14 girls. Studies: Arithmetic, physiology, gram 
mar, history, geography, spelling, and writing. 

¦ grade, 16 girls. Studies : Arithmetic, physiology, gram 
mar, geography, reading, spelling, and writing. 

¦ grade, 11 girls. Studies: Arithmetic, physiology, Ian 
guage, reading, spelling, writing. 

¦ grade, 1 girl. Studies : Reading, spelling, number work, 
and writing. 

Teacher and family manager of 

family A, Lena E. Ward. 

Teacher and family manager of 

family B, Nellie M. Curtis*. 

17 </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
258 


DECEMBER 1, 

RKl'OUT OF SEWING TEACHER COVEHING TIME FROM 

1902, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1904. 

F. Bell Douglass, Teacher. 

Garments and articles made — 

Dress skirts 61 

Shirt waists 74 

Blue dresses 322 

icoats 87 

Undergarments 599 

Night gowns 193 

Aprons 228 

Sunbonnets 36 

Table cloths, hemstitched 3 

Napkins, hemstitched doz., 6 

Tea towels doz., 36 

Hand towels 125 

Sheets 100 

Pillow slips »5 

Ironing sheets 48 

Dresser scarfs, hemstitched 12 

Table covers, hemstitched IT 

Comforts 16 

Garments repaired — 

Dresses 1 4.»0 

Undergarments 2400 

Hose . 260 ° 

Aprons 760 

Tablecloths 18 

Bed spreads 36 

Sheets 60 

Pillow slips ?0 

Comforts 40 

Night gowns 1260 

Girls taught during biennium, 68. </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

259 

HOUSEKEEPING 

DEPARTMENT. 

Housekeeper, 

Tilla Clark. 

Sheets made 50 

Pillow slips 60 

Towels 50 

Tablecloths 18 

Repaired — 

Sheets 40 

Pillow slips 30 

Tablecloths 20 

Girls instructed in house work during biennium, 64. 

LAUNDRY. 

Work done by laundry detail during biennium. Laura Bock, 

teacher. 

Dresses laundered 6,560 

Skirts 4,040 

Drawers v 


Corset covers 5,920 

Hose, pairs 6,420 

Sheets 8,000 

Pillow cases 9,500 

Comforters 105 

Blankets N 

Bed spreads 1,080 

Aprons 3,600 

Shirts and waists 1,140 

Miscellaneous articles $,500 

The laundry work is done by a detail of girls under the 

direction of a teacher. They serve three months in the de- 

Tablecloths , 1,440 

Napkins 5,400 

Curtains 600 

Towels 12,500 

Tea towels 6,480 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
260 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

tail, and during that time are instructed in the various forms 

of domestic washing. Seventy girls have received instruc- 

tion in this department during the past biennium. 

COOKING DEPARTMENT. 

Mrs. J. C. Wilkins, teacher. 

Sixty-eight girls have received instruction in this depart- 

ment during this biennium. 

¦ average of 400 loaves of bread have been baked each 
month, total 9,000 

Cookies 3,500 

Pies 2,600 

Cherries, canned quarts, 400 

Peaches, canned quarts, 350 

Pie plant quarts, 100 

Plum preserves gallons, 5 

Plum butter gallons, 10 

Plum jelly glasses, 100 

Grape jelly glasses, 400 

Grape butter gallons, -•" 

Although owing to our small pasture lot we can only keep 

five cows, we made this season an average of ten pounds of 

butter a week during the season; if we had room for more 

cows we could easily make more butter than we needed for 

our own use. 

From the garden we have produced for the biennium — 

Sweet corn bushels, 100 

Potatoes bushels, 700 

Carrots bushels, 50 

Beets bushels, 40 

Parsnips bushels, 40 

Pumpkins wagon load, 1 

Cabbages heads, 6,000 

Radishes bunches, 2,500 

Turnips bushels, 300 </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

261 

Tomatoes bushels, 50 

Sweet potatoes bushels, 65 

Onions bushels, 25 

And we have in the cellar cucumber pickles. . . .gallons, 200 

Saner kraut gallons, 7.~&gt; 

We raised Held corn bushels, 800 

Alfalfa hay tons, 16 

Nothing that we can use in any way is allowed to waste. 

We have raised during the biennium 70 head of hogs, and 

have tried to make them a source of revenue. 

PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. 

Geneva, Neb., November 30, 1904. 

To the Hon. H. M. Clark, Superintendent of the Girls' In- 

dustrial School at Geneva, Neb.: 

submit my biennial report as attending physician 
e Girls' Industrial School during your administration. 

I am happy to say there have been no deaths in the school 
since my last report and none the previous two years. The 
health of the pupils has been good during my connection with 
the institution. We have had only the usual sickness incident 
to their age. No serious accidents and no malignant 
diseases to contend with. All diseases have been of a mild 
character and readily yielded to treatment. 

I believe the healthy condition of the pupils of the institution 
is due largely to the excellent sanitary oversight you 
have so carefully given the buildings and surroundings, also 
the good, wholesome food, regular hours of eating and sleej^ 
ing, which you have observed in your care for those you 
have had under your supervision. My association with yourself, 
teachers, employes, and patients has been very pleasant 
and harmonious, for which I am very grateful. 

ft will make a few suggestions as I did in my last report 
ich I believe will meet with your approval. </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
262 


Ee first is that a case be put in the hospital where drugs 
be securely locked away, so that there will be no danger 
em falling into the hands of those who do not utkdci - 
L using them. 

The second is that a bathroom be put into this part o' the 
house for the convenience of the sick, while in the hospital. 

Both are not only conveniences, but necessities. 

I wish to express my appreciation of the faithful work 
done by Miss McMahon, the matron. She has been very 
faithful and efficient in the assistance she ban given me in 
my care of the sick. 

Yours respectfully, 

B. B. Magee, 

Physician. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>