<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Co-operative Elevators</title>
               <date value="1921-09">1921-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">tension Bulletin 64 September, 1921 Co-operative Elevators i wn«l fkiiii.ir. in Nebraska— MS THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">I ! I COOPERATIVE ELEVATORS H. C. Filley INTRODUCTION Cooperation is a word which is sometimes used in a very jroad sense to mean any united effort, but in an economic sense its meaning is limited to that united effort which com - plies with certain well-established principles. These principles ivere first applied in 1844, by a group of weavers living in Rochdale. England, and for this reason, true or economic co - operation is often referred to as the Rochdale plan of coopera- i Fh«M weavers were successful from the first. Their plan pread thruout England and other parts of Europe, and to America. Its particular principles have been embodied, in or in part, in every statute governing the organization wrative associations. ROCHDALE PRINCIPLES OF COOPERATION Each member is given one vote and but one, regardless tment or shares held. 2. The payment of dividends on stock is limited to current rest rates and is considered simply as interest upon capital ■tod and not as profits. Profits are divided in proportion to patronage. The first principle given is diametrically opposed to the common rule in stock companies, which bases the voting power upon money invested. In a cooperative enterprise the member are equal, and men, not money, do the voting. In other words, it is an industrial democracy, and each member, rich or poor, has an equal share in the management* 1 he second principle recognizes capital as a servant, not master. It receives a fair wage for the work it does, the same as any other employee. The third fundamental principle is not thought of in the ordinary stock company. It recognizes the fact that the profits of any concern come from the men who furnish the business. Nebi ttutii.n fornn luired "that in all elections for director! [&gt;rporated compan stockholder shall t ave the riRnt to vote na win or by proxy for the numlter of shares of stock owned by him." An amendment il September 21. ISM. r.lievi-« cooperative companies of this archaic provision. I rativt' companies of thin archaic provision, they may now adopt the n, one vote" ruli </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin 64 All expense, including a fair rate of interest on capital in - vested, must first be deducted from the gross profits. Con - servative companies usually set aside a part of the net profit for a reserve fund, and another part for education of the mem - bers along cooperative business lines. The remainder is di - vided among the patrons in proportion to the business which each furnishes to the company. A common practice of cooperative companies in appor - tioning dividends is to pay non-members at only one-half of the rate paid to members. The remainder of the earnings on the business of non-members is placed in the reserve fund. The payment of the dividend to non-members is a very effective method of arguing the economic advantage of cooperation. The payment of larger dividends to members makes membership very desirable, and this in turn is an aid in building up the business. Usually the non-members are not paid their pat ronage dividend in cash, but it is applied as a partial payment upon stock. This is an added incentive for them to become members. These principles apply not only to the organization of cooperative elevators but to the organization of all cooperative enterprises, and their adoption has usually been necessary for success. Following them does not, however, insure success. OTHER ESSENTIALS BESIDES COOPERATIVE FORM OF ORGANIZATION Nearly all elevator companies organized under the Ne - braska cooperative law have been successful. A few havt failed. An analysis of the causes of failure indicates a fairly definite list of factors that are essential to success. Need for an Elevator Cooperative elevators should be organized only where a need exists. Not only must there be grain to sell, but the grain must be owned by the men who wish to sell thru their own elevator. The most accurate method for measuring the desire for a cooperative elevator is by offering an opportunity to subscribe for stock. If farmers really feel the need for an elevator they will buy stock. Desire becomes demand only when backed by money. Ample Capital Essential Farmer-owned elevator companies in Nebraska have an average paid-up capital stock of approximately $15,000, not including surplus. About one-fourth of the companies have </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Cooperative Elevators 5 less than $10,000 paid-up capital. It is little wonder that the managers and directors complain of insufficient capital. Prob - ably more difficulties arise from this than from any other one cause. To build and equip an elevator at the present time that will prove satisfactory to the average community costs from $10,000 to $30,000, depending not only upon size, but upon lo- ition, kind of material used, and type of construction. If an elevator has a capacity of 20,000 bushels and is three-fourths full of grain valued at $1 a bushel, another $15,000 is required. The company may also have grain en- I :irim-r- Klevatu '. Kokeb&gt; , Nebraska. (Operated by Sprugur) ■il IMS: rapacity Hl.otiU bushels: total cost. Including heavy wale and ll'«n: studded construction, galvanized iron covered; bins MM attached. dsivt route, for which they have not received payment in full. Many cooperative grain companies carry stocks of coal, lumber, tankage, mill feeds, and other farm supplies. Where it is expected to do this additional capital is necessary. An ele - vator need not be very large to require at any one time an in - vestment of $50,000. It is usually easier to raise the required capital when the shares of stock are $100 each than when they are smaller. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Extension Bulletin 64 6 Legal Limits to Borrowing Cooperative organizations are usually short of working capital. This has been encouraged in some states by laws per - mitting the financing of cooperative companies entirely upon borrowed money- The Nebraska statutes very wisely provide that no corporation may become indebted at any time to more than two-thirds of the value of its paid-up stock. Revised statutes of Nebraska, Sec. 569 : "Indebtedness Limited. — The articles of incorporation must fix the highest amount of indebtedness or liability to which the corporation shall, at any one time, be subject, which must in no case ex - ceed two-thirds of the capital stock ." If the management allows a current liability to be cor tractod in excess of two-thirds of the paid-up capital stock, personal liability is created. In other words the directors bt come personally responsible for the debts of the company. No board of directors should be compelled to born money upon their own security to finance the business of cooperative company. Such action shows loyalty, but it ca not be considered either a good business practice for th&lt; or a good recommendation for their company. The statutes also provide in section 312 : "No eorporatioi transacting a banking business in this state shall directly o indirectly, loan to any corporation, firm, or individual, includ ing in such loan all loans made to the several members o share-holders of such firm or corporation, for the use and ben efit of such firm, corporation, or individual, more than twent; per cent of the paid up capital and surplus of such bank, bu bills of exchange drawn in good faith against actually exist ing value and the discount of commercial paper actually own* by the persons negotiating the same, shall not be considered a money borrowed." In many of the smaller towns of the state the capital and surplus of the bank or banks does not exceed $25,000. One - fifth of this amount would pay for only 5,000 bushels of wheat at $1 a bushel. The local bank may, of course, dispose of tlu notes to other banks, but this practice can hardly be recom - mended as a permanent policy. Credit Demand for credit sometimes exceeds available funds The firm which has been borrowing to the limit is then in i much more serious situation than the firm which has sufficien </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Cooperative Elevators 7 capital for normal business use. In the autumn of 1920, many cooperative elevator companies were limited in purchas - ing grain by the money shortage. They had too little ready capital. (■ft the Money at the Time of Organization Good business practice demands that a cooperative ele - vator company have sufficient capital not only to construct an elevator, but to buy a reasonable amount of grain. The time to raise the money is when the company is being organized - l/iiless the producers in the locality tributary to the elevator are willing to furnish sufficient capital, the grain business &gt;uld better be left to private enterprise. The Members The members of a cooperative elevator company should nen who raise grain and desire membership in order to provide better grain marketing facilities. It is better if all ire acquainted, as strangers are apt to have little confidence ind cooperation requires the highest confidence Business Done on Cash Basis \ cooperative elevator must pay cash for grain. It should eceive cash for grain, coal, mill feeds, and all commodities (iranting credit to some customers, when others a iank discrimination and cannot be practiced with any cooperative organization. Extending credit is to loaning money and is an accommodation for inks require pay. The business of an elevator com - to buy and sell grain and other commodities, and not &gt;H Accurate Records Kept A cooperative elevator company must keep accurate rec - in order that not only the manager but the board of di- the exact condition of the business. A rs re record of receipts and payments is not sufficient. There must be a record of grain purchases, of grain shipments and sales, a patronage ledger, and a cost analysis. The United States P.ureau of Markets has devised a very complete and accurate system of elevator accounts which is now widely used. It is described in Bulletin No. 811, of the United States De - partment of Agriculture, entitled, "A System of Bookkeeping for Grain Elevators." </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Operate at a Profit A cooperative elevator company should be so operated that it will ordinarily show a profit at the end of the year. The theory some times advocated that it should just pay out each year does not work well. The grain business is hazardous. No manager and no board of directors can foretell when a sudden market drop will find them with a well-filled elevator and no cars. Under such conditions a loss is unavoidable. If the elevator has secured a good margin of profit upon the grain handled during the preceding months, the loss may be balanced by past gains. It is always easier to pay a loss from accumulated profits than to make it up on future sales. Profits are easy to divide. No member objects to receiv - ing a proration upon his grain sales. Earnings upon grain purchased of non-members can be returned to them in part, or used to strengthen the reserve. A loss is not easily pro - rated. No farmer is enthusiastic over a company which fails to pay expenses. He realizes that any loss takes that much value from the stock of the elevator company. A cooperative elevator company must decide upon the margins necessary to pay expenses and secure a profit, and should fix for itself the price at which grain will be purchased. The company which lets its competitor fix the price it pays, that is, which always meets the competitor's pi ice. usually finds plenty of trouble. The members of a cooperative company should know the handling, freight, and selling costs, and the margin necessary to pay expenses. When they know the situation, farmers wiil usually elect to stand by their own company, even tho a slightly higher price is offered by a competitor. There is always the alternative for the members to sell where they can secure the highest price, and pay to their own company a portion of the return sufficient to cover operating expenses. No company can continue to handle grain at a loss, and no elevator company puts up the price to a point where a profit is no longer returned unless it expects to recoup pres - ent losses from future profits. Avoid Speculator Holding grain is a speculative enterprise. This is trut whether the grain is held by a farmer, by an elevator company or by a buyer at the terminal market. The farmer may bt holding the grain because he is not satisfied with the preseni </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Cooperative Elevators 9 price, the elevator company because of car shortage, and the terminal buyer may have purchased the grain in the hope of future rise, — but all are taking market risks. A cooperative elevator company should reduce specula - tion to the minimum. Grain should ordinarily be sold as soon as purchased. In time of car shortage this is impossible. Some companies lessen their risk by the sale of grain for fu - ture delivery, but this affords little protection when the future market is lower than the cash market. \ large elevator providing ample storage room is often f advantage as it permits of shipments whenever cars can be ecured. On the other hand, the elevator company which pur - hases and stores a large amount of high-priced grain is en- Holdretre Equity Exchange crete elevator, built 1919; capacity 35,000 bushels; cost S2\000; .Ir ffice detached gaged not in marketing but in speculation. A year's profit may be wiped out within a few days by market fluctuations. A company owning a large elevator will therefore find it safer to store grain for the growers than to purchase and hold it for themselves. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Extension Bulletin 64 10 Equitable Treatment All customers should receive the same treatment. Grain must be purchased upon a uniform margin and with a due regard for grade. The producer whose grain is of high grade is entitled to receive a better price than can be paid for infer - ior grain. The manager not only should be equipped to test grain but should be able and willing to demonstrate to anv patron why his grain is of a specified grade. Some men whose grain is damp, dirty, or mixed may at first object to this pol - icy, but it will pay out in the long run. The American farmer believes in fair play. The cooperative manager cannot afford to give special favors or special prices. The Management and the Manager The success of a cooperative company depends very large - ly upon the efficiency of the manager. The executive powers of a cooperative association are usually vested in a board of directors, elected by the members. The board of directors elect or appoint the manager and his assistants, and direct the general policy of the company. The directors should make a thoro inspection of the business periodically- The manager should make a report to the board at least once each month. showing the exact condition of the business. For the pro - tection of the manager, the directors, and the stockholders. an audit of the accounts should be made at least once each by some one not connected with the business. The in tax report will ordinarily be made from this audit, so it st meet every requirement of the commissioner of internal enue. The most important task of the directors is thf m of a manager, for upon him devolves, to a largo extent, tl cess of the company. If they elect a competent man t\ of their work is easy. Thev simply hold him responsil the development and execution of their policy. J. W. Shorthill, secretary of the Nebraska Farmers' Co - operative Grain and Live Stock Association, who has had an exceptional opportunity to learn the causes of the mmmm and failure of cooperative companies, emphasizes the importance of securing a competent manager. We quote from him as follows : "The manager of a cooperative organization is the most important single factor in its success. He is the official whom the patrons meet, and their opinion of the company will be gauged to a considerable extent by their opinion of him. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Cooperative Elevators 11 In choosing a manager the first qualification to consider is honesty, the second industry, the third natural business abil - ity, and the fourth business education. All are important, but they are named in the proper order. Experience in the line of business to be handled is a very desirable qualification, but it must come after those named above. "The man whose sole recommendation is that he will work cheap cannot measure up to these nor to such a position. The competent man seldom works for a low salary ; it is not neces - sary. The man who has failed in his own business is not apt to make a success of a cooperative enterprise. The extra sal - ary demanded by a competent man over the incompetent is small compared with the results which he secures. "The manager must give a bond in keeping with the finan - cial responsibility he must assume. The average grain com - pany should require a bond of $5,000 from its manager, and it is preferable that he give a fidelity bond rather than a per - sonal one. "The statement is often made that cooperative companies are successful because their stockholders are loyal. This is true. The reverse is the true statement — the stockholders loyal because the company is successful. Let the company involved or fail 'to make good,' and the members will a ay one by one. The success of cooperative companies sentiment, but to good business methods and to ng. The companies must work continually for bers and new business." GROWTH OF THE COOPERATIVE ELEVATOR MOVE- MENT Phe rapid increase in number of farmer-owned elevators Nebraska is an indication of their success. When the coop- erative law was passed in 1911, there were less than 200 ele - vators in the state which could be claimed as farmer-owned. None of those were truly cooperative, as the corporation law under which they were organized made no provision for the payment of patronage dividends and there was no legal means ti prevent the concentration of the stock in the hands of a few men. Because of the exigencies of the times, most of these elevators had been successful in spite of their poor form of organization. At present we have 465 farmer-owned ele - vator companies. Nearly all organized since 1911 are co- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Extension Bulletin 6b operative, and many organized previous to that time have changed their articles of incorporation and now operate under the new law. The majority of these elevator companies buy and sell not only grain, but various other commodities, among which coal, lumber, mill feeds, tankage, and flour are the most com- PCRCINT commodities. Many other commodities ;ir. mon. More than a third ship hogs and a fourth ship cattle. A few handle hay, posts, paint, salt, and automobile supplies, and order potatoes and apples in carload lots in the autumn. There seems to be a growing tendency for the members of a cooperative elevator company to utilize their organization for the purchase of staple farm supplies. One farmer-owned elevator company did a million-dollar business in 1919 ; three other companies passed the $900,000 mark and many others handled grain and other goods vaiued '--,- COAL •2 n MILL PCIDS .44 "■"• 42 TANKAGE 71 _.. 21 — MACHINERY f7 SALT. - 10 — PRODUCE 8 —TWINE !• — HAY 9 —TIRES 7 _ POTATOES * — APPLES _ 5 SHIP HOGS _. _4D — — _ SHIP CATTLE Percent of Cooperative Elevator » '■■mim ~ N.-I.r; &gt;ntr </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Cooperative Elevators 13 at more than half a million dollars. The average volume of business in 1919, for 185 elevator companies from which we have reports, was $281,000. Nearly 80 per cent of these ele - vators set aside a reserve fund and thus prepared for seasons when the market tendency is downward. METHOD OF ORGANIZATION The organization of a cooperative elevator company is not difficult. If considerable interest is evident, a meeting may he called and a temporary organization formed. At the first meet - ing two important committees should be appointed: first, a committee on membership, and second, a committee on consti - tution and by-laws. Karmfm" Butinc-.** ANttoriatlon. Duncan, »braHka tur hmM !!•!."&gt; : capacity 20.000 bushels; cost, not including flour house rht) M£00; cribbed construction, ironclad; no bins The membership committee should divide up the terri - tory tributary to the proposed elevator, in such a manner that every grain producer will be canvassed. The first essential to successful organization is money, and, unless a considerable number of men are willing to be - come charter members of the company and to furnish ample funds, it is better not to attempt to operate an elevator. ne room detached </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Extension Bulletin 6U Some of the fundamental problems of the organization should be decided upon. The most important of these prin - ciples should be printed on a subscription card, or at the head of a subscription blank. Such a list might well include the following points: 1. The shares of stock shall be $100 each, which must be fully paid for when issued and shall be non-assessable. 2. The business of the company shall be transacted by a board of seven directors. 3. Each member shall have but one vote, irrespective of amount of stock held. 4. No person shall subscribe for more than five shares of stock. 5. Dividends on stock shall be limited to 8 per cent Other net earnings shall be paid in proportion to patronage. If the membership committee find sufficient interest, a per - manent organization can be formed at the second meeting, articles of incorporation and by-laws can be adopted, and the members of the board of directors, to serve until the first an- nual meeting of the company, can be elected. A suggested form of articles of incorporation and by-laws can be secure' from the Department of Rural Economics, College of Agri culture, Lincoln, Nebraska. It is necessary that not fewer than fourteen persons sha sign the articles of incorporation for a cooperative company and those signatures must be acknowledged before a notar public. The state law also requires that a cooperative con pany must have at least twenty-live members All members of the board of directors must be among the signers of the articles of incorporation, better if all men who promote the organization beet i inal incorporators. How to Incorporate The legal steps in incorporating a company are f i iie it-^ai sieps in iiu.-urpurai.iiig a company are iiot ni cult. The following from the Revised Statutes of Nebraska self-explanatory : Sec. 568. Articles of Incorporation — Where Filed. — Every poration, previous to the commencement of any business, except its organization, where the same is not formed by legislative •.•nactmt must adopt articles of incorporation and have them filed in the offk- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Cooperative Elevators 15 Secrt and recorded in a book kept for that purpose, rporations must also file with the county clerk in the mnii unty where their headquarters are located Notice Must Be Published. — Notice must be published in lear the principal place of business for four weeks. jch notice must contain: First, the name tt the principal plan of transacting its business; business to be transacted; fourth, the authorized and the time and conditions on which , the time of commencement and termination of the highest amount of indebtedness or liability poration is at any time to subject itself; seventh, by rporation are to be conducted. Commencing Business. — Any corporation formed actment, may commence business as soon as its poration are filed by the county clerks of the counties, *nd shall be valid, if a copy of the articles ffice of the secretary of state, and the notice required Tionths from the time of filing such articles in Chapter 199: Corporation Notices. Sec. 1 poration notices required to be published by sections of the Revised Statutes of Nebraska, 1913, shall, with publication attached be filed with the county clerk of which such corporation has its principal place of business, from the date of the last publication of such notice, «■ shall be kept on file by the county clerk, properly in- erence ■cretary of State. — There shall be paid to the Secre - following fees: For filing articles of association, in- &lt; in sol idatinn. domestic or foreign, as follows: If the cap - ? 10,000 or less, a filinp fee of $10; if the capital stock is 0.000 but does not exceed $25,000, a filing fee of $20: if ock is more than $25,000 but does not exceed $100,000, a f the capital stock is over $100,000 there shall be a :s additional for each $1,000 in excess of $100,000; for if incorporation for each 100 words contained therein, The "Blue Sky" Law The sale of securities in Nebraska is regulated by a statute known as the "Blue Sky" law. The administration of this law is in immediate charge of the State Bureau of Se - curities of the Department of Trade and Commerce. That the citizens of the state may be protected from the sale of worthless stocks and bonds it is necessary that all companies submit to certain regulations. A portion of the law, as amended in 1921, is as follows: Sec. 3. Application and Authority Required. — No person either as principal or thru brokers or agents or otherwise shall issue, sell, assign, transfer or offer or negotiate for, the issuance, sale, assignment, trans- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 fer or by any means or thru any medium, offer or attempt to take sub- Cptions for or promote the offering, issuance, sale, assignment or lgfer of any securities not specifically exempt from the provisions of this article and within this state, until there shall have been filed with the department of trade and commerce a verified written applica - tion, said application being consistent with and according to the laws of this state and the forms, rules and regulations of said department, and until and after said applicant shall have received from said department a written order authorizing it to proceed with the proposed offer, is - suance, sale, assignment, or transfer of said securities. Sec. 29. Filing Fees. — Every application shall be accompanied by a receipt from the state treasurer for $10 for co-operative companies and all other organizations coming within the provisions of this article, having a capital not exceeding $25,000 and receipt for $25 m all other cases. Each application for registration and license of an agent shall be accompanied by a receipt from the state treasurer for $1 for each agent requesting registration and license. Sec. 24. Violation — Penalty. — Provides penalty for failure to file any statement required or for selling securities (not exempted) without a license. The committee on constitution and by-laws should obtain from the Bureau of Securities forms upon which to make an 6 plication for a permit to sell stock, and this should be filled ; and submitted as soon as the organization is completed, eir approval should be received before the articles of incor - poration are filed with the secretary of state, in order that the company may be assured that their form of organization com - plies with the Nebraska statutes. BUY OR BUILD After the organization is completed the board of direct - ors must either purchase or build an elevator. The purchase of an existing elevator reduces the number of competitors and permits the new company to start business at once. It also settles the site question. As a general thing the elevators already in operation have secured the best available site*,- Many of the earlier farmer-owned elevator companies were unable to secure locations upon the railway right-of-way, and even in recent years companies have many times experienced vexatious delays. The Elevator If it is decided to erect a new building, the directors must decide upon the size and type of elevator best adapted to their funds and needs. A large elevator provides for the storage of grain and so is of advantage in times of transportation </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Cooperative Elevators 17 difficulties. On the other hand as has been already stated the company which purchases and holds grain which it is unable to market is engaged in a highly speculative enterprise, The company which has little storage room is therefore less likely to lose heavily during a period of falling prices The studded construction is the cheapest style, but is not adapted to large elevators. Reinforced concrete is more durable than wood and has the added advantage of being Loomls Farmers' Co-operative Company Klev.iti.r ,t.&lt;i..1 t&gt;M; eapacttjr 4n,onn Imsh.'ls; cost S32,nt)O; material, re n-**d i-oDcrete. Dump has rapacity of 75 loads. practically fireproof. Wooden elevators, whether studded or cribbed construction, should be covered with galvanized iron. Whatever size or type of elevator is built it should be well constructed. A small building which does not leak and is con - veniently arranged will give much better satisfaction than will a larger elevator that needs constant repairs to keep the pit dry and the grain in the bins. Cheap construction in an elevator is extravagance; good construction is economy. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 r h. IC THE NEBRASKA COOPERATIVE LAW Sec. 1. Cooperative Companies.— Any number of persons, not les than fourteen, or any number of cooperative companies, not less tha five, may form and organize a cooperative corporation for the transactio of any lawful business by the adoption of articles of incorporation in th same manner and with like powers and duties as is required of othe corporations except as herein provided. Sec 2. Articles of Incorporation. — Every such cooperativ pany shall provide in its articles of incorporation: First, that the word •cooperative" shall be included in it name, and that it proposes to organize as a cooperative CWCpm Second, that no one person shall own, either directly or more than 4 per cent of the capital stock of the company; pn operative companies owning capital stock in another such cot| in no event or manner own more than 20 per cent of such stm Third, that dividends on the capital stock shall be fixed hut exceed 10 per cent per annum of the amount actually paid th.'i Fourth, that the net profits of the company over and ahi and capital stock dividends or interest, as provided in par distributed as a patronage dividend among the patrons or i employees of the company, or either or both or all, who ■ stockholders or non-stockholders or both as shall ba ip« articles of incorporation in proportion to the value or vc business transacted or service rendered to the company durir for which such apportionment is made; provided, this pr not be construed to prevent the setting aside a part of the surplus fund for the benefit of the company. Sec. 3. Powers. — Every cooperative company which s! under this act shall have power: First, to have succession by name; second, to sue and be sued, to complain and defend law and equity; third, to make and use a common seal and a; at pleasure; fourth, to hold personal estate, and ail suet as may be necessary for the legitimate business of the coi to regulate and limit the right of stockholders to transfer sixth, to appoint such subordinate officers and agents as of the corporation shall require, and to allow them suitab tion; seventh, to adopt by-laws for the management and i ii the affairs of the company; eighth, to purchase, hold, sell, assign or tran: fer the shares of the capital stock of other cooperative companies whk it may own, and while owner of such stock, to exercise all the right powers and privileges of ownership, including the right to vote thereoi ninth, to provide that each individual stockholder may be limited to &lt;&gt;r n vote per person, regardless of the number of shares of stock which may own, at any stockholders' meeting. Sec. 4. Fees. — The fees for the incorporation of cooperative coir panies shall be the same as those required by law of other corporation: And such cooperative corporations shall be required to make the sam reports and filings as is required of other corporations. (As amended. 1921.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Cooperative Elevators 19 Sec. 5. Corporation. — No corporation, company, firm or association which shall not be incorporated as a cooperative corporation shall adopt or use the words "cooperative" or any abbreviation thereof as part of its name. Any person or company violating the provisions of this sec - tion shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and for each day's con - tinuance of the offense fined in a sum not to exceed one hundred dollars Sec. 6. Number of Members. — Whenever the number of members a cooperative company composed of individual stockholders shall be than twenty-five, said company shall terminate and the same shall iissolved without any action on the part of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 PUBLICATIONS OF INTEREST TO MEMBERS OF FARMERS' ELEVATOR COMPANIES NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF MiRU TLTl RE PUBLICATIONS Exteiiswn Circulars: Cooperative Elevator Company No. 1303. Suggested Articles of Incorporation and By -I Cooperative Shipping Company Extension Unlit tins No. 38. Marketing Mixed Grail IMTEIt STATES DEPARTMENT OK AGRICULTURE BULLETIN Farmers' Bulletins No. 718. Cooperative Livestock Shipping Associat No. 919. The Application of Dockage in the Marketing of W No. 1118. Dockage under the Federal Wheat Grade- No. 1144. Cooperative Marketing Department BuOttitu: No. 118. Cooperative Organization Busme-&gt; Me No. 371. Patronage Dividends in Cooperative Gr No. 403. A System of Accounts for Livestock Shipj tions. No. 811. A System of Bookkeeping for Grain Elevate No. 860. The Organization of Cooperative Grain Elev panies. No. 937. Cooperative Grain Marketing Bureau of Markets, Service and Regulatory No. 47. The Country Grain Dealer and Federal ( vision. No. 48. How Northwest Wheat is Grading at the Termir No. 52. How to Take an Appeal. No. 54. How Hard Red Winter Wheat is Grading under Federa Standards. No. 62. Wheat Grade Announcement. U. S. G. S. A. Form No. 90. Official Grain Standards for Wheat Shelled Corn and Oats. Distributed in furtherance of co-operative agricultural extension work Art* of May 8. 1914. and June 30. 1914, Extension Service of The Tniveraity of Nebrnakn College of Agriculture and V. S. Department of Agriculture cooperating. W. H Brokaw, Director of Extension Service r.M&gt; No. 1302. Suggested Articles of Incorporation and Ey-Li </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>