<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Differential Reaction of Strains Within a Variety of Wheat to Physiologic Forms of Punninia Graminis Tritici</title>
               <date value="1926-12">1926-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 39 The Differential Reaction of Strains Within a Variety of Wheat to Physiologic Forms of Puccinia Graminis Tritici T. A. KIESSELBACH AND GEORGE L. PELTIER DEPARTMENTS OF AGRONOMY AND PLANT PATHOLOGY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA DECEMBER, 1926 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">The Differential Reaction of Strains Within a Variety of Wheat to Physiologic Forms of Puccinia Graminis Tritici T. A. KIESSELBACH AND GEORGE L. PELTIER INTRODUCTION Black stem rust of wheat (Puccinia graminis tritici (Pers.) Erikss. &amp; Henn.), which occurs. in Nebraska and thruout most of the wheat producing regions of the world, is of a composite nature, in that it consists of a number of physio - logic forms which- can be determined by their action on different varieties of Triticum species, as shown by Stakman and Levine. 1 The ordinary commercial variety of wheat may likewise be regarded as a mixture, in that it consists of numerous strains, which differ in some more or less important characteristics, as has been frequently indicated in the liter - ature concerning wheat improvement. The object of this investigation has been to analyze such a commercial mass-variety of wheat from the standpoint of the differential reaction of its component strains to a num - ber of the physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici found in Nebraska. The applied significance of such a study would be the discovery of productive wheat strains in a com - mercial variety, which are resistant to a relatively large number of prevalent physiologic forms, thereby reducing the likelihood of severe rust damage from season to season, as it has been determined (unpublished data) from epidemiological studies in Nebraska that the physiologic forms which occur in the field may vary in number, identity, distribution, and intensity in different seasons. DESCRIPTION OF THE WHEAT VARIETY The variety used in this test is known as Crimean C. I. 1435. This is an importation of common hard red winter wheat made in 1900 by the United States Department of Agriculture from Ambracievka, Don Territory, Russia. Ac - cording to J. A. Clark 2 the source of this wheat is some - what different from the source of other Crimean, Kharkof, 1 Stakman, E. C. and Levine, M. N., The Determination of Biologic Forms ot Puccinia graminis on Triticum spp. Minn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Tech. Bui. 8. 10 p. fit. 1. 1922. 5 Personal letter. i </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 39 and Turkey introductions obtained about the Same time. Seed was secured by the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station thru the Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases in 1914. In succeeding tests Crimean C. I. 1435 has proved to be an unusually productive mass-variety. Compared during a 7 - year period with ordinary Turkey winter wheat which has been grown for many years at this Station, and with Kanred, which is a relatively rust resistant selection made by the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station from this same Crimean C. I. 1435, we have the results reported ih Table 1. Table 1. — Comparative performance of Crimean C. 1.10,35, Com - mercial Turkey, and Kanred grown in the wheat nursery 1 during 7 ytars, 1915-1922 Years j 1 duration | | Crimean ' Yield and plant characteristics ol Turkey C. 1. 1435 i Kanred test { Yield grain per acre 3 1 bushels) 7 30.3 _3.fi 36.2 Relative yield grain per acre yper rent I 7 100.0 110.S 119.5 Protein in grain tper cent) 6 15.1 15.7 15*1 Yield straw per care (tons) 7 2.4 2.4 2.4 Plant height (inches) . 7 38.0 39.0 37.0 Lodging (per cenl) 7 18.0 14.0 23.0 Date in head 7 6 3 6 2 6 2 Date ripe ... 7 7 2 72 71 Black stem rc-jt 1 in 1 920 I per rrnh .. 49.0 43.0 19.0 Milling and baking' tests. 3 yr. av.. 1921-1923 Weight ol grain per bushel (lbs.) 3 58.0 57.5 59.0 Crude protein in grain (per «nn 3 14.2 ' 15.4 14.3 Ash in flour (per cent) 3 .45 .45 .43 Straight flour (per cent) 3 63.8 63.3 G4.9 Water used in dough (per rent). .1 63.0 G6.0 65.0 Loaf vol _me (c. c.) 3 1870 1890 1775 Loal weight (i/rnnul 3 480 479 485 Bread color (per tent) 3 97 9S . 98 Bread texture (per rent) 3-94 95 94 'Ten replications ol 6-row nursery blocks each year. In a 3-year average triplicated field plat test, 1921-1923, Turkey. Crimean C. I. 1435. and Kanred yielded 30.5, 32.1, and 33.5 bu. per acre respectively. These are relative yields of 100. 105, and 110 per cent. "Black stem rust recorded on basis of United States Department of Agriculture rust chart published in United States Department of Agriculture Bulletin 1046, by L. E. Melchers and J. H. Parker. The milling and baking tests were made under the direction of Dr. M. J Blish Station Chemist. Because of its outstanding performance among commercial winter wheat varieties, Crimean C. I. 1435 was used as the basis of a selection nursery begun in 1921. A thousand spaced plants were grown and these served as foundation " mother plants." These were tested in plant rows in 1923 with the result that all except the 578 most promising strains were discarded. It is these 578 strains whose individual re- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Reaction of Wheat Strains to Stem Rust action to the physiologic forms of rust is herewith reported. Forty-three additional varieties and strains were tested for their rust reactions in conjunction with these Crimean strains during both seasons. Since many of these are extensively grown hi various parts of this country, their reactions pro - vide a valuable basis for appraising the relative rust resist - ance of these Crimean strains. DESCRIPTION AND HISTORY OF THE PHYSIOLOGIC FORMS OF PUCCINIA GRAMINIS TRITICI The physiologic forms of rust used included p. f . 6, 14, 21, 29, 3, 10, 12, 18, 25, and 32. With the exception of p. f. 14 and 21, these physiologic forms were isolated from collec - tions of stem rust made by Mr. A. F. Thiel, Associate Path - ologist, in charge of Barberry Eradication in Nebraska, Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, United States Depart - ment of Agriculture, and his assistants in various localities in Nebraska during the summer of 1924. Physiologic form 14 was identified from stem rust material collected at Sacaton, Ariz., while material of p. f. 21 was obtained from Dr. M. N. Levine, Associate Pathologist, Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, United States Department of Agriculture, sta - tioned at the Agricultural Experiment Station, St. Paul, Minnesota, in the fall of 1923. During the winter of 1924, p. f. 21 was identified from a number of stem rust collec - tions made the previous summer in Nebraska. However, p. f . 14 has not yet been identified from any collections made in the state. The reactions of these 10 physiologic forms on the 12 differ - ential hosts as determined under control conditions in the Plant Pathology greenhouse, were essentially the same as those listed by Stakman and Levine. 1 In determining the identity of these physiologic forms, 30 plants of each differ - ential host were used. Thus these physiologic forms were pure when used to infect the various wheat strains as judged by their reactions on the differential hosts (Table 2). It will be noted that Kanred is resistant to the four physiologic forms, 6, 14, 21, and 29, while it is susceptible to p. f. 3, 10, 12, 18, 25, and 32. Since the infected plants were grown on an open bench, a recheck of each physiologic form" was made after each set was read. When the rust material was not being used in the "L. c. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 39 greenhouse it was stored in humidity chambers held at a tem - perature of 5° C. and 50 per cent relative humidify. The physiologic forms were again rechecked each time thley were built up from the material kept in cold storage. Physiologic forms 3, 10, 18, and 21 retained their purity on all rechecks both years, as judged by their reaction on the differential hosts. Thru an accident, p. f. 6 and 14 were lost! during storage thru the summer of 1925. Table 2. — Comparative reactions of the 12 differntial hosts to 10 physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis triticfy Variety and reaction! " J_ E _i 3&lt;a — o oo -w w «*e _,■*• .» M to eo o r.* «"_ ""r &amp; __*- PG&gt; 'St . 8°* °0 c" i °° __. „ Uo -=te -rj— oe tSo £n «el ■*© ca £■» I w «© -2 « _,■* H." 6**° "O 3*T JS 10 «&lt;° 5 N m*° S N T5 n -TiT _ r - _ ffu _ _ T3 i_ C3 © .. H _3&gt; 5 P — __ £_J e_J 3_J "-J ____: **___ _o_J C_J •*___ P_J c:_J &gt;, _ W-. J-* C-- w_H - -_ CM a »~&lt; fiM C M C 1 -* 3»H £.2 jo So «u _iu -56 So md usd -So Ed &gt;d 3d I . 6 4 2+ 0; I 2+ 4— 1+ 1+ 0; 3+ 3+ 0; 1 + 14 4 2+2—12+4—4—4—4—4—3+1 0; 21 4 4 0 3+4—4—4—4—3+1— 0; 1— 29 4 4— 0 3 x x x x x 3 0; 0; 3 4 4—4—3 0; 0; 0; 0; 3 3— 0; 0; 10 4 2— 4— 2+ 4— 3+ 3+ 3+ 3+ 3 0; 0; 12 4 4 4—3 4— 0; 0; 0; 4— 3 0; 0; 18 4 4—4—3 0; 0; 0; 3 3+3 0; 0; 25 4 4—4—3 0; 3+1 3+4—3 0; 0; 32 4 4— 4— 3 x x x x X 3— 0; 0; 'Explanation of symbols: 4+, very susceptible; 4 and 4—, susceptible; 8 and 8+, moderately susceptible; 3 — , slightly susceptible; 1 and 2. resistant; 0, norutuscept-ble ; ;. hypersensitive flecks ; x. heterogeneous infection. ISee Fig. 1.) On the final recheck p. f . 12 was found to react at variance with the usual reading on some plants of two of the) differ - ential hosts; p. f. 25 reacted differently to Mindum dnd had a tendency to produce a heterogeneous infection on Kubanka; p. f . 29 produced a few pustules on 2 out of the 30 Kanred plants infected; and p. f. 32 did not produce as outstanding a heterogeneous infection on some plants of the differential hosts as it did at the beginning of the experiment. On the whole it can be stated that the 10 physiologic foriris were pure at the beginning of the experiment but a few stray spores of other forms were found in some few of the phys - iologic forms in the final check upon the differential hosts. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">I II II I I I I HI II II I I I KM* II II II I I I^^^^Bl 1 1 I Fig. 1. — Types of infections produced by the physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici on the various differential hosts of Triticum spp. The type of infection is indicated by the following symbols: 0;, nonsusceptible; 1, very resistant; 2, resistant; 3- to 3+, slightly susceptible; 4— to 4, susceptible; 4+, very susceptible; and X, inde - terminate, as a rule plants that produce this type can be classed as susceptible. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">NEBRASKA AGR. E XP. STATION, R ESEARCH BULLETIN 39 EXPERIMENTAL METHODS i^^wJ^JSTP^ , a pot contein - manner when 7 days ol7 T^ S f. b J ha W d in the ™1 cubated for 48 Ers in . ZE^FT**** seed [ in eS were in - entire lot. A tempore 8 o" SR' J* saturated atmosphere were mSTV - C - and a chamber, conditions rt^S^i^A^*^ platers &amp;pk swsw r ieaf »* ture of about 25" C Two weeks Sr-L^^^ a tem P«a - sru: the p —^ ft^^^-S^!^J^ n^^ errors the personal element by SL^n^ra". and and without regard to the SSJ °m ? Th?. 6 * .i tandard s of infection are illustrated in Fig? Va ™ US no'a^tS wie^Idf tZ^t^A^^ cent of the plants were^nfected a TJw.« lf f^* 1311 50 P er were tested Thus T where eitht ml £°, aI Set of 6 P lants is reported, a total oi 12 2Z ere fle . cks °r no infection year. The second vear inoculated the first made so th^Ta^lS S/S' f ™ were infection is reported the resnlf Z^tZvi 5" - 1 ' Type W or no on 0 f r 5?8 winter of SLS^SSettHLS ted du * n * the 80 of the most resisTan : and 2Hf tv.^ r f dUCed include &gt;n the winter of 1925 26 The mLSf m ° St SUf ?ce ptible ones varieties and strains was tetZt^T c ° llecti °n of 43 addition 15 re P lica?e tS were madJ'Sf £? 8 " In winter of 1925-26 to servo «vJv? i Kanre d during the the results in general All of t£\T n the liability of 10 physiologic forms n 1924-2 5 and IritoiV '' nfected ™' th x^_ and with 7 forms in 1925-26. RESULTS «&amp;XTv4 sSlR^ 0 "™^- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Reaction op Wheat Strains to Stem Rust Table 3. — Comparative reactions 1 of Crimean strains to physio- logic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici Number of strains Physiologic forms Riving 7— . 1 r ; , , 1 identical reactions fi j M 21 29 3 10 12 18 25 32 i r~ ; 16 ! s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s + 5 s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s + 5 s+ s . s s+ s+- s+ s+ s+ s+ s + 2 s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s + B s+ s+ s + . s+ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s + 3 s+- s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s + 1 s s S+ S+ S+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s + 1 S S+ S+ S+ S+ S [ s+ s+ s+ s + 6 s+ s s+ s+ S+ S+ S S+ S+ S + 1 s+ s s s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s + 1 S+ S S+ S+ S+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s 4 ■ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s + 4 S+ 6+ S I S+ S+ S+ S+ S S+ S + 1 s+ s+ s I s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s 1 s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ . s s+ s+ s + 4 s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s s+ s + 1 s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s • s + 2 s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s 1 s s— s s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s + 1 s s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s 1 s+ s s s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s + 2 s+ s s s+ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s + 2 s+ s s s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s + 2 s+ s s+ . s+ s s+ s s+ s+ s + 1 s+ s s+- s+ s+ s s+ s+ s s + 4 ' s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s s s+ s + ■ 1 s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s s + 1 . s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s 1 1 s+ s+ s s+ s . s+ s+ s s+ s + 1 ' s+ s+ s s+ s+ s s+ s+ s s + 1 s+ s+ s s+ s+ s+ s s+ s s + I s+ s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s s s + 1 s+ s+ s+ s s s+ s s+ s+ s + 1 s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s s 1 s s+ s+ s+ s+ s s s s+ s + 1 s+ s s s+ s+ s+ s+ s s s + 1 s+ s s+ -s+ s s+ s s s+ s + 1 s+ s s+ s+ s s+ s+ s s+ s 1 i s+ s s+ s+ s+ s s s s+ s + 1 j s+ s . s+ s+ s+ s+ s s s+ s 1 I s+ s s+ s+ s+ s+ s s+ s s 1 i s+ s+ s s s+ s s s+ s+ s + 1 s+ s+ s s+ s s+ s s+ s s + 2 i s+ s+ s s+ s+ s+ s s s s + 1 s s . s+ s+ s s s s+ I s+ s + 1 ! s+ s— s s+ s s s s+ I s+ s + 1 i S+' s s s+ s s s+ s+ s+ s 1 s+ s s s+ s s+ s s I s+ s + 1 I s+ s s s+ s s+ S S+ I s+ s 1 I s+ s s s+ s+- s s s s+ s + I I S'+ - s s s+ s+ s+ s s s s + 1 s+ s s+ s+ s s s s+ s s + lis s— s s+ s s+ s+ s s s+ 1 s s s s+ s+ s s s+ s s + 1 s s s s+ • s s s+ s+ s s 1 s+ 's . s s s s+ s s s+ s 1 s+ s s s+ s s+ s s s s 1 S+ S 0 s+ s+ s+ s s+ s+ s ■Explanation of symbols: S+, very susceptible; S, susceptible: S — , slightly sus - ceptible; R — ■ resistant; 0, nonsusceptiblc, with or without hypersensitive flecks. (See Fi_r. 1.) </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 39 Table 3 (Continued). — Comparative reactions 1 of Crimean strains to physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici Number " " i of st-ains Physiologic forms giving . 1 1 1 identical I reactions 6 | 14 21 29 3 10 12 18 25 32 I ' 1 oss s+ 1 s s+ s s s s+ 1 s+ s 0 s+ 1 s+ s+ s , s s s 1 s+ 0 0 s+ s s s s+ a 1 1 f s s s+ls s s si s 9 S S S S ; S S S SIS S 9;S s- s s , s s sisis 2 f R S S &gt; S S SSS I 1 s S S SIS S S ! S— S s 1 S-RS ss s sis s s 3 s ss ss s ss s . 1 S S- S 8-8 S S S S S 2 s S S S.S S-SS S s lif S S S , S S S-jS S 1 1 1 S R s- S \ S S-SS s s is S s s s s s s s s 1 8 S S S|S S S 8—3-1 - 1 a s 0 s - s s s s s s is s 0 ss s s-ss I 3 0 S 8 S S S S S S ■ S 2,s 0 s s s sis S 1 [s l.S OS S S 8 8 I S— I S s 4 s s 0 s s sisals 1 s So ss SSSSS 3 0 0 S S S 8 8 8 8.1 3 0 8 0 S S SSSSS ; 0 s os's s- I s s ' a .8 10 ss 0 s ss s s s 13 : s 0 0 s s s s s si * ■■ S 0 n ss s-s sisis so s 0 s ss sss 1 s-o s os ss s si is 0 s 0 S s S S SS 1 S 0 s 0 s s ss— ss 4 s s 0 0 s ss s Is 1 s soo s s s s is ls -s-oosssss. 4 '000SSSSSSS 6 I 0 0 0 S-S S:S;S S S 0 0 0 8 i 8- 8 I S I 3 il s i 1 ° ° 0 S 1 0 SiSS— s I 6(0 0 OS S ' 8- S 8 8 S 1I0 0 OS s s— Is— ss . 4 j 0 0 so,s s s Is! 00 sols s sis S s 1 i 2 s ° s s s 1 s I- I 9 0 , s 0 0 s s sis S s 2 0 S— ( o OS 8|888 i 1 0 s I 0 0 I a- a i s s s 1 1 ° sioios s— sss . I 0 8-003-8 s Is 1 1 ° ' 8- I 0 , 0 s- s- s s s . i or- oo s i i i I I 5 t Zi 2 2 ! s ■ s ' ' 2 3-0 0 '0 If S 8 S S S T IS ° ° s S— S S|S S f- » 0 ( 0 S S 0 8 8 i \ IS o,o a sis s— is s | » i o o s sis s I s- ! i : §— ° 0 0 S 8 8 SiS—S 1 s 0 8 0,8 SS SIS I ! 1 i •__ e«,«v,S^ Pl 1. nat ' 0n °-'. Bymbol8: s +. ve 'y susceptible; S, susceptible; S— . slightly sus - (See Fig. re8,8Unt: »• -onsusceptible. with or without hypersensitive fl«to. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Reaction op Wheat Strains to Stem Rust Table 3 (Concluded). — Comparative reactions 1 of Crimean strains to physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici Number of strains . Physiologic forms giving — 1— i — ■ 1 — ■ 1 1 1 identical reactions 6 14 21 29 3 10 12 18 26 32 202 0 0 0 0 8 SSS S S 30000S— SSSSS 23 0 0 0 0 S S— S 8 S 8 2 0 0 0 0 S S S— S S S 20000SSSS— S3 1 0 0 0 0 • S S S SS— s 1 0 000 S— S S— S S 3 1000SSSSS0S 1 0 0 00 SSO SSS 1 000 0 S S S 0 s s I 1 S— S S— S-rS— s— s s— s— s 1 S Sr-'S— .8— S— S— S— S— S S— 1 S— S S— s— S— s, s— s— s— s— 1 ss— s— s— s— s— s— s— s— s— 1 S— . s s— s— s— s— s— s— s— s— is— S— s— s— s— s— s— s— s s— 1 R— s— s— s— s— s s— s— s— s— 1 S— R— S— S— S— S— S— S— S S— . 3 8— S— S— S— S— S— S— S— S— S— 1 R— R— S— S— S— S— S— S— S— S— 1 0 0 S— 0 S— • S— S S— S— 8— 'Explanation ot symbols: S+, very susceptible; S. susceptible; S — , slightly suscepti - ble; R— , resistant; 0, nonjusceptible, with or without hypersenjitlva flecks. (Set Fir. 1.) pears that these combinations may he classed in 4 general groups: (1) Those that were' very susceptible to all the rust forms tested, comprising approximately 110 strains. All of these developed pustules thruout of rather extreme types as illustrated by Fig. 1, Type 4 to 4+. (2) A second group of about 237 strains gave reactions essentially identical with those of Kanred which had been selected from the same vari - ety, being highly resistant (Fig. 1, Type 0 ;, 1; and 2) to p. f. 6, 14, 21, and 29, and decidedly susceptible (Fig. 1, Type 4- to to 4+) to p. f. 3, 10, 12, 18, 25, and 32. (3) A small group of 13 strains is of especial interest in that they were slightly susceptible to all or most of the rust forms developing, in the main, relatively small pustules as shown in Fig. 1, Type 3- to 3+). It is thought that this type of reaction is espe - cially attractive from the standpoint of selecting resistant strains. They differ from those strains reacting similarly to Kanred in that they show some resistance to all or most of the 10 physiologic forms, rather than being very resistant to 4 forms and susceptible to the remaining six. (4) The balance of the selections, 218 in number fell miscellaneously </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 39 between the first two groups, and varied in their differential reactions . These, as well as group 1, would appear to offer little promise from the standpoint of rust resistance. The data of Table 3 are briefly summarized in Table 4 to show the number of strains giving each type of reaction with each of the physiologic forms, without respect to the various combinations in which they occur. When assembled in this manner it is again shown that the strains fall largely into the two primary groups — a susceptible group and a par - tially resistant group that behave like Kanred. A few strains of intermediate resistance fall under each rust form. Table 4. — .1 summary of the comparative reactions of 57S Crimean strains showing the number giving each type of infection with each of 10 physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici Relative | Physiologic forms bility 6 14 21 29 3 10 12 18 25 32 St 104 62 69 112 91 100 54 80 98 97 S 127 90 87 118 465 425 505 ■ 476 472 468 S— 17 36 22 23 21 53 17 21 8 13 R— 2700000000 O 328 383 400 325 1 0 2 1 2 0 'For an explanation of the symbols see Table 3 and Figure 1. Miscellaneous Varieties and Turkey Strains: — It will be noted in Table 5 that of the 43 varieties tested, five, including (1) Kanred, (2) a long-beak mass-selection of Kanred, (3) Kansas 2414, (4) Kansas 2415, and (5) Tenmarq, give the Kanred reactions, which may probably be accounted for by the fact that they are all related to Kanred. All of the other varieties and selections are relatively more susceptible, and most of them decidedly so. Reliability of Results :— &lt;=In order to have a measure of the accuracy of the results, a series of checks was run in 1925, which consisted of planting every eleventh pot thruout the entire collection to Kanred and treating these as individual strains. Thus we have 15 duplicate Kanred checks whose reactions are reported individually for each physiologic form </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Reaction of Wheat Strains to Stem Rust Table 5. — Comparative reactions of miscellaneous wheat varie - ties and strains to 10 physiologic forms of Puccinia grami - nis tritici Physiologic forms Variety ■ ; — '■ 6 14 21 29 3 10 12 18 25 32 Turkey (Nebr.) »S S— SSSSSSSS Turkey Nebraska 312 R— R— S— S— S— R— S— S— S— S— Turkey Nebraska 60 *S— R— S S S S S S S S Turkey Nebraska 10 Sl+S— S»3 S S S S 3 8 Turkey Nebraska 11 SSSSSSSSSS Turkey Nebraska 6 SSSSSSSSSS Turkey Nebraska 30. «S S— S S S S S SS S Turkey Nebraska 47 S S— SS S S S S S S Turkey Nebraska 59 SS— SSSSSSSS Turkey South Dakota 114 R— R— SSSSSS— SS— Turkey C. 1. 1671 »S»SSSSSS— S— SS— Turkey (Ohio) »SSS+S S S+S S S S Illinois No. 10-110 »SS— SSS*SSSSS Kharkot C. 1. 1442 SS— SSSSSSSS Karmont SS— SSSSSSSS Malakof SSSSSSSSSS Minturki S— S— S S S S S S— S S Minard *S *SSSS*SSSSS— Iowa 404 »S R— S S 3 »S SS S S Iobred »S *S S S— S— S— S— *S— *S S— Montana 36 S*S S SS S S S S S Bacska *SR— S S S— S— S S S 3 Michikot SS— SSSS— SSSS Sherman :.... SSSSSSSSSS RedHussar SSSSSSSSSS Beloglina ". S SS S S S S S 8 S Berkley Rock S+ S+ S+ S+ S+ S+ S+ S+ S+ S + Ridit S— S— S S S S— S S S S Blackhull «S *SSSSSSS— S— S Nebraska 28 SSSSSSSSSS Seward County, Ncbr.t »S S— S S— S— S— S »S S S "Buffalo", Buffalo Co., Nebr.t... *SR— S S S— S— S S S S '.•Manifold", Clay Co., Netir.t ...S SS»S S S S S S 3 "Bulgarian", Polk Co., Nebr.f... »S »S S «S— S S— S— S S S Black Seat . S*SSSSSSSSS CanadaBlueStem,YorkCo.,Nebr.t »S»SS— SSSSS— SS Crimean C 1. 1435 0 *S— SSSSSSSS Kanred... OOOOSSSS. SS Kanred, Nebr. Long beak selection 0000SSSSSS Kansas 2414 000 0 S S S S S 3 Kansas 2415 000 0. SSSSSS Kanmarq SSSSSSSSSS Tenmarq 0 0 0 0 S S SS SS tThese are unidentified varieties of special local farm interest •Mixture of plants yielding different types of infection, but in no instances was a heterogeneous infection found on any one leaf. For explanation of symbols see Table 3. • ".") ■'.- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 39 Table 6. — Reaction of 15 duplicate Kanred 1 checks to 7 physio - logic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici [odd numbered columns show the number of plants inoculated (denomi - nator) and the number subsequently infected (numerator)]. The type of infection 2 is shown in the even numbered columns. Acces- j Physiologic forms sion | 1 , -t number 21 | 29 I 3 i 10 18 25 32 | 1 I 2 : 3 ! 4 5 ; 6 I 7 I 8 9 ] 10 11 12 13 14 0 I 0 i 5 i I 7 3 1 4 18 18 6 ' 4— 18 j 4— 6 3+ 18 4 6 4— 0 0 4 6 2 3 6 1 18 18 8 ■ 41 — * 12 4 6 j 4— 6 4— 6 4— 0 1 5 2 3 5 5 23 - - - — ! - 18 18 4 6 4 12 4— 6 ! 4 6 1 4— I 6 4 ,0 1 12 2 j 5 '| 5 '' 5 34 - - - I - | . - |1 - 18 18 4 18 4 12 J 3+ 6 4— 6 I 4— ■« 4 0 0 6 4 ) 13 3 ■ i 4 45 — ■ — - — I ! _ I - 1 t i_ 18 18 6 4 12 ' 4— : 6 4— 5 | 4— ' 6 4— 0 1 6 2 5 3 i 4 56 — — - — I - I- 1 18 18 4 6 4 12 4— 6 4— 6 4 6 4 2 0 G 2 5 I 4 I 4 I 18 3+ 18 6 4 12 4 j 6 4— 6 4 ! 6 4— 1 0 5 3 j 4 j 3 j ,5 18 i 4 18 6 I 4— I 12 j 4— 6 ' 4 I 6 I 4 \ 8 4 0 j 2 3 12! 3 ; 6 16 89 - '&lt; I - - — I - I - 18 18 I 4 6 4— I 12 1 4 6 4—6 4— 6 4 0 1 '0 6 2 j I 6 I I5| 5 100 \ — \ ■ — — — I - - i 18 18 IS 4 I 12 4 — 6 4 6 4 6 4 i I ' I 0 0 6 15 ,6 4 6 111 — ; — , - — I - — i 18 18 16 4 12 4— i 6 4— 18 4 6 4 1 : 1 ; 0 0 51 2 5 4 4 122 — - |-1 - I - I 18 I 18 I 6 1 4— 12 4— 6 4— 6 4— 6 4 io il 6 5 5 0 5 133 1 - 1 - - _ - _ 18 1 18 3 + + , 6 1 4 12 j 4— 6 4 18 6 4 1 '0 5 2 5 3 3 144 1 - — I - - I 18 3— 18 6 I 4— 12 4— 6 4 6 4 6 4— I 0 0,414 6 3 4 156 — ■ — i I - — I - — 18 I 18 I 6 4— i 12 4— I 6 I 4 18 4— 6 4 l Tbe wheat used was a special "long beak" mass-selection of Kanred. 'See Table 2 and Fig. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Reaction op Wheat Strains to Stem Rust in Table 6. Seven of the checks gave the correct Kanred results thruout. In 4 checks 6 per cent and in one check 12 per cent of the plants gave the wrong Kanred reading for p. f. 29. In 2 checks 6 per cent and in one check 12 per cent of the plants gave the wrong Kanred results for p. f. 21. Of the entire number of 105 reactions with Kanred, 97 were as expected and 8 showed slight contamination. These re - sults indicate the likelihood of some error in the comparisons of varieties and Crimean strains but that in the main the reactions obtained and the principle indicated may be relied upon. SUMMARY The data indicate that there may be decided variation in the differential reaction of wheat strains within a commercial variety to various physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici. The 578 strains selected from Crimean C. I. 1435 and under observation in these tests, contain two groups of strains which offer decided promise for further testing in the field for comparative performance. The strains of one of these groups react like Kanred, while those of the other small group are moderately resistant to all 10 physiologic rust forms. All the other selections are more susceptible than Kanred. In a miscellaneous group of varieties and Turkey strains, none proved more resistant than Kanred. This variety and 4 related strains which react alike surpass all the others in this regard, tho more than 200 new selections from Crimean C. I. 1435 give the same reaction as Kanred to the 10 physiologic forms. For a detailed account of wheat investigations and stem rust studies conducted at the Nebraska Station the readers are referred to Research Bulletins 22, 25, 28, 31, 34, and 35, and Bulletin 201. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>