<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00006">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00006</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>FOURTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Commissioner OF Public Lands and Buildings TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1904.</title>
			            <date value="1904">1904</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-22</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
— OF THE— 

Commissioner 

—OF — 

Public Lands and Buildings 

—TO THE— 

Governor of the State of Nebraska 

DECEMBER 1, 1904. 

GEO. D. FOLLMER 

COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS </seg>



            <seg id="p003">

Geo. D. Follmer, Oak Commissioner 

II. If. Eaton, Fremont Deputy 

Brad P. Cook, Lincoln Chief Clerk 

Robert Harvey, St. Paul Draughtsman 

Frank J. Fitle, South Omaha Bookkeeper 

Frank W. Hollingworth, Oak Bookkeeper 

Maggie Kroese, Hickman Lease Contract Clerk 

Annette dalbraith, Hebron Delinquent Clerk 

Cora A. (Jarber, Red Cloud Vssijrnment Clerk 

Mary F. Holland, Lincoln Vssignment Clerk 

John Lyon, Aurora Stenographer </seg>


            <seg id="p004">
Office of^j 

Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, 

Lincoln, Neb., December 1, 1904. 

BHis Excellency, John H. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska : 
Sir — I have the honor to submit herewith the fourteenth 

biennial report of the office of Commissioner of Public Lands 
and Buildings for the two years ending November 30, 1904, 
together with the reports of the several state institutions 
under the general control and management of the Board of 
Public Lands and Buildings, in compliance with the requirements 
of the constitution of the state of Nebraska, as stated 
in sec. 22, art. 5. 

Yours respectfully, 

Geo. D. Fom.mkr. 

Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

MEETS FIRST MONDAY IN EACH MONTH. 

Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner of Public Lands and 
Buildings President 

(ho. W. Ifanh, Secretary of State Secretary 

Peter Mortensen State Treasurer 

Frank N. Prout Attorney &lt; leneral 

BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS. 

MEETS SECOND TUESDAY OF EACH MONTH 

John H. Mickey, Governor Chairman 

Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Secretary 

Peter Mortensen State Treasurer 

Geo. W. Marsh Secretary of State 

Frank N. Prout Attorney General 

BOARD OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES. 

MEETS FIRST WORKING DAY IN JANUARY, APRIL, JULY AND 

OCTOBER. 

John H. Mickey, Governor Chairman 

Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Secretary 

Geo. W. Marsh Secretary of State 

Peter Mortensen State Treasurer </seg>


            <seg id="p006">
BOARD OP PHARMACY. 

r SECOND WEDNESDAY IN FEBRUARY, MAY, AUGUST AND 
NOVEMBKB. 

&lt; 'liarles Weston, Auditor Chairman 

W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary 

Frank N. Prout Attorney General 

Peter Mortensen State Treasurer 

Geo. D. Follmer. 

Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings 

BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 

MEETS THIRD TUESDAY IN JANUARY, APRIL, JULY AND OCTOBER 

OF EACH YEAR. 

John H. Mickey, Governor Chairman 

Wm. K. Fowler, State Superintendent Secretary 

Geo. D. Follmer Commissioner 

BOARD OF IRRIGATION. 

MEETS FIRST WEDNESDAY IN APRIL AND SEPTEMBER 

John H. Mickey, Governor Chairman 

Geo. D. Follmer. 

Commissioner of Public Lands and BuiMinjjs 

Frank N. Prout Attorney General </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
i 

OFFICIAL ROSTER 1905-1907. 

John H. Mickey Governor 

Edmund G. McGilton Lieutenant Governor 

Algernon Galusha Secretary of State 

Peter Mortensen State Treasurer 

Edward M. Searle, Jr Auditor of Public Accounts 

Xorris Brown Attorney General 

Henry M. Eaton 

Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings 

Jasper L. McBrien Superintendent of Public Instruction </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
NAME AND LOCATION OF STATE INSTITUTIONS 
AND SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE. 

Nebraska Hospital fob the Insane — Lincoln. 
Dr. J. L. Greene. 

Asylum fob the Incubable Insane — Hastings. 

Insane Asylum at Norfolk. (Reconstructed.) 

Not Appointed. 

rRASKA Soldiers' and Sailors' Home — Grand Island. 
W. S. Askwith. 

SOLDIEBS' AND SAILORS' HOME — MlLFOBD. 

Colonel Charles Penn. 

Home for the Friendless — Lincoln. 
Sarah B. Sohus. 

State Industrial School — Kearney. 
B. D. Hayward. 

Gmtf Industrial School — Geneva. 
Horace M. Clark. 

Nebraska Industrial Home — Milford. 
Margaret Kealy. 

State Penitentiary — Lincoln.- 
A. D. Beemer, Warden. 

Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth — 

Beatrice. 
Dr. A. Johnson. 

Institute for the Deaf and Dumb — Omaha. 
R. E. Stewart. 

Institute for the Blind — Nebraska City. 
J. F. Mon 

Dr. W. B. Kern. </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
ESTIMATED EXPENDITURES FOR THE NEXT BIEN 
NIUM, BEGINNING APRIL 1, 11)05, AND 

ENDING MARCH 31, 1907. 

commissioner's office. 

Salary of Commissioner f 4,000 &lt;•(&gt; 

Salary of deputy 3,600 00 

Salary of chief clerk 2,600 &lt;x» 

Salary of draughtsman 2,600 00 

Salary of two bookkeepers 4,800 00 

Salary of lease contract clerk 2,000 00 

Salary of delinquent clerk 2,000 00 

Salary of stenographer 1,680 00 

Salary of two assignment clerks 4,000 00 

Furniture and repairs SM 00 

Telephone and telegraph 2.~&gt;() 00 

Postage 1,000 00 

Stationery and other expenses 60" ' 

Total f29,380 00 

BOARD OP PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

Fuel, light, and engine house expenses f 6,000 00 

trovements, repairs, and care of capitol buildings 
and grounds 7,000 00 

Employees' wages 15.000 00 

Incidentals 2,000 00 

Total 130,000 00 

BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS. 

tinses for serving school land notices, school 
land supplies to county treasurers, etc $5,000 00 

BOARD OF PURCH \SK AND SUPPLIES. 

Expenses for publishing notices, printing, p 
etc 1400 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 


APPROPRIATIONS. 

The estimates of appropriations for the Board of Educational 
Lands and Funds, the Board of Purchase and Supplies, 
Board of Public Lands and Buildings, and Land Commissioner's 
office, as stated, are conservative, and, in the light 
of four years' experience, I believe that the various amounts 
will be necessary to meet the expenses of the current l»i-ennium. 
These amounts were appropriated by the two previous 
legislatures, and there has not been in any case a deficiency 
created, but, instead, a small amount has lapsed to the 
state as an unexpended balance. While I do not believe it 
a wise plan to make a large or unnecessary appropriation, so 
as to perhaps create a demand or a desire to increased expenditures, 
I do believe that a sufficient amount should be 
appropriated to pay the usual running expenses and to meet 
any unlooked for expense that may arise. In the event the 
appropriation is more than necessary to meet expenses, the 
same will revert to the state treasury, as heretofore. 

Iy law it is made the duty of the Board of Educational 
ds and Funds to furnish to the county treasurers of the 
ous counties receipt books, ledgers, blanks, and all other 
plies necessary for them to properly perform their duties 
tive to the collection of interest and rental upon the 
K)l lands of the state and enable them to keep the accounts 
lame uniformly, as well as to meet the expenses of the 
imissioner's office incident to forfeiture of contracts and 
ling of auctions upon lands not leased, and to pay for reraising 
lands as lease contracts expire. I would, there¦, 
ask that the full amount of |5,000 be allowed. 

It will be necessary that an appropriation of |30,000 be 
de for the use of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings 
meet the expenses for heating and lighting the capitol 
lding, for care, repair and necessary improvements to the 
?itol building and grounds. 

Etie Board, during the past two years, has practiced the 
•test economv, but at this time find that the appropriation 
e bv the last legislature is nearlv exhausted. </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
APPROPRIATED BY THE LEGISLATURE 1901 

11 

STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES. 

During my four years" service as Commissioner of Public 

Lands and Hnildinjjs I have at no time used any of the money 

of the state where same was not absolutely necessary, and 

have been able to Met expenses incurred without a single 

deficiency in any department, and at the same time to return 

as lapsed a small balance as unused from the appropriation 

allowed by the legislature. 

I submit a rejmrt of amounts appropriated and egpcadwl 

for each of the biennial periods, also the amount lapsed or 

returned to the state as unused balance. 

APPROPRIATION BIENNIUM 1901-1902. 

FOB USE OF LAND COMMISSIONER'S OFFICE 

Appropriated for office expenses $2,300 00 

Total expenditure two years 1&gt;" V 

Amount unexpended and lapsed to state $ f&gt;21 7»i 

USE OF BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS. 

Amount appropriated $5,000 00 

Total amount expended two years 3,220 4."» 

Amount unused and lapsed from appropriation 
$1,779 55 

BOARD OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES. 

Appropriation made $ 400 00 

Total amount used entire biennium 237 4 1 

Amount lapsed to state $ 16- 

Total amount unexpended and lapsed to state. $2,4&lt;i: </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

BIENNIUM 1903-1904. 

Appropriated for office expenses $ 600 00 

Amount expended 268 14 

Amount on hand December 1, 1904 f 331 86 

Pot postage and postal expenses f 1,000 00 

Amounted expended 600 on 

Balance on hand December 1, 1904 f 400 00 

For telephone and telegraph $ 250 00 

Amount used 177 75 

Unexpended balance December 1, 1904 $ 72 25 

Furniture and repairs allowed $ 250 00 

Used _ 31 14 

Balance on hand Deceml&gt;er 1, 1904 f 21 v 

Total appropriation Commissioner's office $ 2,100 00 

Total amount expended 1,022 97 

Total unexpended balance f 1,077 03 

BOABD OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES. 

Amount appropriated I 300- 00 

Expended 69 70 

Balance on hand December 1, 1904 f 230 30 

BOABD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS. 

Total amount appropriated |4,000 00 

Amount used $ 955 51 

Balance on hand December 1, 1904 $3,044 49 </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
APPROPRIATED BY THE LEGISLATURE 1903. 

13 

Appropriated for reappraisemeiit school lands. . .|1l\im mi M 
Expended reappraising forty-nine counties {&gt;:SM .\ 

6,234 -2\ 

Unexpended balance December 1, 1904 f 5,7Uo T% 

Total unexpended balance, all funds. December 1, 
1904 fKi.o. 

Total unexpended balance four years |12.."»27 :&gt;;• 

The above statement includes all debts contracted by this 

department during the four years, a'nd same will coincide 
with books in the Auditor's office when all warrants ar 

sued against the vouchers on tile there 

The last legislature passed a fee bill, an abstract of which 

is here given : 

For recording lease or contract of sale of school lands. M 


For copy of any instrument, paper, or record in this office. 

Knts for each 100 words, 
r certificate and seal, 25 cents. 

For filing and recording assignment of lease or contract of 

sale of 500 words or less, 60 cents, and 10 cents for each 100 

words in excess of 500. 

For notice of forfeiture of lease or sale contract, 50 c 
For reinstatement of lease or sale contract, 50 cents. 
For recording order of forfeiture, 50 cents for each trad el 

forty acres or less. 

Where news]&gt;aper publication is had, all costs to be paid 

by party redeeming. 

Copies of maps or plats, 40 cents per hour for time re- 

quired for copying or preparation. 

This bill was passed with the emergency clause and signed 

Be Governor March 28, and immediately became a law. 
wing the instructions of this law, this office has col- 

lected as follows : 

¦ field notes, certified copies, assignments, delinquent 
notices, etc.. from March 2ti. 1903, to 

December 1, 1904 $4.4 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

CollecU&gt;d from December 1, 1902,to March 2(»,1903.| 48 85 

¦ived from miscellaneous sources 12S (Ml 

Rental on penitentiary land 1,415 00 

Total collected to December 1, 1904 |6,005 10 

All funds received have been turned over to the State 

Treasurer, and his receipts to correspond are held on lie in 

ill is office. 

I am of the opinion that the income from fees will continue 

to increase from year to year, as: 

1. Hundreds of lease contracts that have run the full 

twenty-five years must be reissued. 

2. A large number of lease contracts will be converted 

into sale contracts. 

3. The work of the department of surveying will Increase 

as the people of the state, realize its importance. 

4. As the state grows older the importance of having cop- 

ies of abstracts of the records of school land, in order to ob- 

tain good title, will become evident. 

It is a matter of satisfaction to this department to know 

that the fees collected will render an income equal to the ex 
M of the Land Commissioner's office, the Board of Educa 
tional Lands and Funds, and at the same time pay the salaries 
of the two assignment clerks, whose work produces the 

iter amount to the total fees collected. 

I would recommend no change whatever in the law unless 

it would be to allow county treasurers a small fee for their 
extra trouble in collecting and remitting same to this office. 

PENITENTIARY LAND. 

The state still holds title to the southeast quarter (S.E. J) 
of the southwest quarter (S.W. +,) and the southeast quarter 
i SB. 4,) of section twenty-six (20), township eight (8), 
range five (5), east; the northwest quarter (N.W. 4J of section 
thirty (30), township nine (9), range, five (5) ; the </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 


I! (E. i) of the southeast quarter (S.E. ) | section thirty• 
(34), township nine (9), range four (4), and the northt 
quarter (N.W. J) of section twenty-eight (28), township 
en (11), range four (4), situated in Seward and Lancascounties 
and containing OTG.Tl acres in all, this l&gt;eing a 
t of the original grant of fifty sections of land by the 
eral government to the state for the purpose of erecting 
¦nitentiary. Although there is no law for so doing, I have 
ed this land from year to year and have collected and 
led into the state treasury f 1,415 as rental for the Men 
m just closing, and have on hand two promissory notes 
1100 each, payable to the state of Nebraska on or before 
first day of December, 1905. 

As the state penitentiary has need of lands for farm purposes, 
I would recommend that the ( 1 onunissioner of Public 
Lands and Buildings be authorized to sell this land and purchase 
from the proceeds lands close to the penitentiary, so 
that same may be used for farming purposes, or to lease same 
for ¦ term of years to the highest bidder, in order that better 
improvements may be placed thereon, and to encourage the 
lessee to take better care of the land. 

There is now in the penitentiary land fund the sum of 
91,415, which I would respectfully recommend that the coming 
legislature, by appropriate legislation. Afreet the State 
Treasurer to credit money received to either the temporary 
school fund or the state general fund. 

KEAPPRAISEMENT SCHOOL LANDS HELD UNDER 

LEASE CONTRA* T. 

Pursuant to the direction of the legislature, which appropriated 
fl2,000 for the reappraisement of school lands, and 
under direct instruction from the Board of Educational 
Lands and Funds, by resolution adopted June 9, 1903, instructing 
the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, 
to take direct charge and to use his best judgment relative 
to the method and manner of reappraising said lands, I have </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
L6 LAND COMMISSION 

lEB'S REPORT. 

•aused to be reappraised the la 

ads of forty-eight counties, 

ftith the following results: 

TABLE OF REAPI 

•RAISEMENT 

COUNTY 

No. Acres 

Old Value 

New Value 

Increased 
Value 

Increased 

Cumins? •¦•••¦¦ 

2,240 00 
9,678 45 
12,34:5 63 
11,205 30 
460 00 
765 20 
200 00 
6,885 05 
620 00 
483 23 
120 0U 
76,789 58 
706 06 
21,209 55 
946 95 
62 00 
40 00 
11,829 00 
16,091 60 
367 00 
9,278 00 
15,432 00 
3,031 25 
8,317 77 
9,458 57 
3,709 73 
400 00 
4,716 86 
26,471 45 
3,231 28 
3,880 00 
295 00 
912 10 
160 00 
5,554 50 
5,718 68 
2,329 10 
670 00 
134 50 
380 00 
603 64 
14,942 32 
2,000 00 
2,328 23 
11,884 38 
1,524 60 
12,402 39 
320 00 

* 

7,720 00 
11,198 47 
17,674 59 
30,649 67 
2,180 03 
5,370 20 
1,400 00 
16,395 18 
1,160 00 
1,885 46 
890 00 
66,752 10 
2,729 79 
15,937 76 
6,979 50 
470 00 
160 00 
33,068 50 
30,627 25 
1,475 00 
14,855 00 
2T),504 00 
15,032 25 
16.840 32 
27,303 30 
10,875 52 
2,800 00 
10,240 32 
56,595 78 
20,551 29 
7,071 20 
1,291 88 
2,367 36 
440 00 
11,228 00 
24,356 04 
12,543 70 
1,985 00 
694 97 
2,280 00 
3,955 48 
32,370 37 
6,590 00 
6,291 42 
8,711 82 
11,823 25 
23,383 60 
1,120 00 

9 29,200 00 
64,652 80 
83,034 18 
51,793 76 
7,890 00 
17,050 20 
7,220 00 
43,900 67 
5,370 00 
16,184 16 
4,390 00 
120,184 38 
11,553 62 
79,508 40 
15,523 77 
940 00 
200 00 
68,044 00 
62,822 00 
9,795 00 
40,788 00 
33,854 00 
26,285 75 
40,497 15 
70,321 30 
41,316 99 
8,400 00 
26,722 61 
167,583 81 
30,111 84 
13,600 00 
5,995 00 
10,121 15 
4,800 00 
47,433 13 
52,803 50 
19,583 70 
11,306 40 
883 97 
12,000 00 
17,672 80 
119,082 64 
37,760 00 
39,221 76 
71,109 11 
27,376 00 
100,227 36 
4,600 00 

S 

21,480 00 
53,454 33 
65,359 59 
21,149 09 
5,710 00 
11,680 00 
5,820 00 
27,505 49 
4,210 00 
14,298 70 
3,500 00 
53,432 28 
8,823 83 
63,570 «4 
8,544 27 
470 CO 
40 00 
34,975 50 
32,194 75 
8,320 00 
25,933 00 
8350 00 
11,253 50 
13,656 83 
43,018 00 
30,441 47 
5,600 00 
16.482 29 
110,988 03 
9,560 55 
6,528 80 
4,503 12 
7,753 79 
4,360 00 
3fi,2O5 13 
28,447 46 
7,040 00 
9,311 40 
189 00 
9,720 00 
13,717 32 
86,712 27 
31,170 00 
32,930 34 
62,297 29 
15,552 75 
76,843 76 
3,480 00 

$1,288 80 
3,207 26 
3,921 58 
1,268 95 
342 60 
700 80 
349 20 
1,650 33 
252 60 
857 92 
210 00 
3,205 94 
529 43 
3,814 24 
512 66 
28 20 
2 40 
2,098 53 
1,931 69 
499 20 
1,555 98 
501 00 
675 21 
819 41 
2,581 08 
1,826 49 
336 00 
998 94 
6,659 28 
573 63 
391 73 
270 19 
465 23 
261 60 
2,172 31 
1,706 85 
422 40 
558 68 
11 34 
583 20 
823 04 
5,202 74 
1,870 20 
1,975 82 
3,737 84 
933 17 
4,610 63 
208 90 

Lancaster 
Nuckolls '. '. '. '. '. '. 
Washington . . . 

323,208 95| 

It 623,735 34l 

l»l,T76,6O0 45l 

If 1,156,584 57 

•0t,8K 1-2 </seg>


            <seg id="p017">
17 

As stated above, forty-eight counties have been reappraised, 
together with numerous reviews of said appraisement, at a 
total cost of f 6,234.24, there being a balance of $5,765.76 of 
the f 12,000 appropriated by the legislature for reappraising 
purposes. 

There are several counties, such as Saline, Antelope, Holt, 
Otoe, Hamilton, Merrick, and Red Willow, which should be 
reappraised as soon as the business of the office will permit. 
The reason that this has not been done is that it was impossible 
to do so, owing to the increase of office work and the accumulation 
of business incident to the reappraisal of the 
forty-eight counties. In the event that the reapprai«ement 
can not be done before the unexpended balance of the appropriation 
lapses, it would be well for the legislature to appropriate 
f3,000 for a continuation of the reappraisal. 

I am convinced that the raise in valuation has fully justified 
the recommendation made by this department to the last 
legislature, and, while the appraisement as made is very 
nearly uniform and equitable at this time, still, in the majority 
of counties, the valuation as placed by the appraisers is 
entirely too low when the true value of the land is taken into 
consideration. The fact that the state had been negligent in 
not appraising the lands every five years, as prescribed by 
the law and as stated in the lease contract itself, caused a 
false commercial value to be placed upon the lease contract, 
and many lessees had sold their contracts to other parties for 
a large bonus, the party buying the contract presuming that 
the state would continue to be as careless in the future as it 
had been in the past; hence, the raise in valuation is very 
gratifying to us, and just to the assignee, from the fact that 
it still leaves a small commercial value in the contracts, and 
the loss will not fall so heavily upon any one person. It 
would be, in my opinion, a wise plan to hay,e this land reappraised 
every five years, in accordance with the intent and 
letter of the law and the reappraisement clause of the contract 
as entered into by the lessee. After the appraisements 
had been received and accepted bv the Board of Educational 

1 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Lands and Funds, this department received many requests 

for review stating that there had been inequality in appraise- 

ment, or that the appraisers had made error that would ma- 

terially change the value as given had they known of the true 

farts or conditions. After careful deliberation by the full 

Board of Educational Lands and Funds, slight changes were 

made in the counties of Franklin, Howard, Jefferson, Bojd, 

JMatte, Pierce, Sherman, and Valley, upon recommendation 

under oath of the appraising board and a review by the land 

department. The changes affect the general total valuation 

but very little. 

INDEMNITY SCHOOL LANDS. 

In the thirteenth biennial report of this department we find 

that the state of Nebraska had not received its full amount 

of land, by reason of loss by Indian allotments, homestead 

entries, and other appropriations of the original sections 16 

and 36, which were granted to the state by the general govern- 

ment for school purposes. After a careful computation by 

a previous administration it was found that the amount due 

the state for above-mentioned causes was. . . . 6,554.51 acres 

Amount confirmed to December 1, 11)02 5,814.75 acres 

Amount still due the state 739.76 acres 

Confirmed during this biennium list No. 3, 

O'Neill district 299.47 acres 

List No. 3, Valentine district 240.00 acres 

Total confirmed during biennium 539.47 acres 

Amount still to be confirmed 200.29 acres 

Total, as per last report 739.76 acres 

The attention of the Interior Department has been called 

to the fact that this small amount is still due the state, and </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
BOYD COUNTY CONTEST. 

19 

we trust to receive confirmation list of remainder at an early 

INDEMNITY LANDS FORT RANDALL MILITARY 

RESERVATION. 

|)n March 3, 1893, Congress passed a law giving the state 
right to Klect from the Port Kandall military reservation 
ds, in lieu of other lands lost in place; provided, the state 
¦cted same from odd-numbered sections, and within oiie 
r from the filing of the plats, in consequence of this law ami 
[er the direction of the state legislature, my predecessor 
cted from this reservation (5,434.48 acres. Up to this time 
18.32 acres have been confirmed to the state, and the en 
•amount continued is under lease contract and bringing 
ncome into the state treasury for the use of the teinjMirarv 
x&gt;l fund of the state, with the exception of 1,318.00 m 
r which there is a contest as to title. The cases involving 
question are now before the supreme court of the state 
their decision. 

BOYD COUNTY CONTEST. 

In my previous report the Boyd county contest cases were 
*n up and discussed in detail; and I again call same to 
r especial attention. Since then little advancement ha* 
i made looking toward their settlement, although the 
ter has been before the Board of Educational 
ds and Funds several times during the past two \&gt; 
a difference of opinion as to the manner of conducting 
cases were had by some members of the Board, and ti 
lions, subject to change from time to time on short not 
*e, little has been done by the Board to effect a settlement. 

The position I have taken in these rases lias, in every instance, 
been approved by the General Land Office of the 
United States, and the Honorable Secretary of the Interior </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

has in each instance upheld my contention and approved the 
decisions of the General Land Office. Therefore, so far as 
the Interior Department of the United States is concerned, 
it has fully confirmed the title of the state to all school lands 
embraced within the Fort Randall military reservation, including 
those in controversy. 

I would say, in defense of the position that I have takrn 
ai the beginning of the contest, that I have honestly envored 
to protect the state's interest in these lands, and 
e resisted every effort made to divert these valuable lands 
place the title thereto with private parties as far as it lay 
ny power so to do. This I have done without malice or 
jntion of injury to the persons who settled thereon. I 
e always believed, and still believe, that these parties are 
?n the land without any color of right, and can not be 
*sified or looked upon in any other way than as tressers. 


The injunction cases of the alleged settlers, which has been 
Umg pending in the district court of Boyd county, have been 
taken to the supreme court of the state, and are now pending 
therein. 

I trust that the decison of the supreme court will fully set 
forth the rights of the state and the rights of the settlers, if 
they have any, in such a manner as to leave no doubt as to the 
ownership, in order that the matter may be closed and litigation 
ended. 

FACTS AND FIGURES. 

I again submit some facts and figures that will carry out 
statements made in my last report that the tendency of 
income from interest on sale contracts is to decrease from 
r to year, and this in proportion to the amount of principaid 
upon school land contracts in excess of the amount 
rincipal received and unpaid, secured by issuing new sale 
ntracts, and that the rent obtained from lease contracts will </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
21 


increase only in proportion to the raise of valuation caused 
by reappraisement of old contracts. Rental can not increase 
from additional leasing of vacant lands, as there are but 
496.28 acres now vacant. 

While the Laud Commissioner does not collect the money 
directly, the policy that he pursues greatly influences the &lt;•&lt;•! 
lections as made by the various county treasurers; but neither 
the Land Commissioner nor the county treasurers cam colled 
more than is due the state, and, if the Commissioner does his 
duty as the law directs relative to notit-e and forfeiture, the 
sum total of any one year's collection can not vary under 
normal condition other than the gradual reduction of ii 

est, as shown elsewhere. 

FIGURES. 

1897-1898 

BIENNIUM 

Rental collected on leases: 

Interest collected on sales : 

May, 1897 f 153,622 77 

May, 1897 f 44,2' 

December, 1897.. 146,239 20 

December, 1897.. 71,8*7 99 

May, 1898 47,441 M 

May, 1898 208,279 35 

December, 1898.. 104,534 65 

December, 1898.. 4r&gt;.i:tl 24 

Total collected. f 208,723 46 

Total collected. f 612,675 97 

1899-1900. 

BIENNIUM 

May, 1899 f 128,877 10 

May, 1899 f 42,726 45 

I &gt;ecember, 1899.. 69,482 08 

December, 1899.. 54,874 SI 

Total collected. f 220,085 75 

Total collected. f 453,695 50 

t, 1900 10~&gt;,409 06 May, 1900 60,10." 69 
¦mber. 1900.. 89,027 2G Detertec, l!M»0.. 62,379 47 </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

BIKNNIUM 1901-1902. 

May, 1901 1 106,203 85 

May, 1901 f 55,988 31 

December, 1901.. 72,081 71 

I &gt;«•• -ember, 1901.. 11,356 27 

December, 1902.. 36,001 06 

Total collected. $33(5,568 40 Total collected. $242,42S 56 

BIRNNIUM 1903-1904. 

May, 1903 f 111,650 98 

May, 1903 $ 111,650 98 

May, 1903 $ 86,065 92 

May, 1903 $ 86,066 !»2 

December, 1903.. 42,791 27 

December, 1903.. 56,34s 4&gt; 

December, 1903.. 42,791 27 

December, 1903.. 56,348 4&gt; 

Ma.v. 1904 112,873 63 

May. 1904 112,873 63 

May, 1904 87,077 88 

May, 1904 87,077 88 

December, 1904.. 30,504 75 

December, 1904.. 30,504 75 

December, 1904.. 78,150 83 

Deeeaber, 1904.. 78,150 83 

Total collected. f 297,820 63 

Total collected. $297,820 63 

Total col leeUHl.f30fi,r&gt;43 11 

Total collected. $300,643 11 

TOTAL INTEREST COLLECTED OX SALE CONTRACTS. 

Biennium '97-8 . . |612,675 97 
Biennium '99-00. 453,695 50 

Biennium '97-8 .. $612,675 97 

Biennium '99-00. f453,695 50 

Biennium '99-00. f453,695 50 

Biennium '99-00. 453,695 50 

Biennium '01-02. 336,568 40 

Biennium '01-02. 336,568 40 

Decrease 1903 to 1904. .$ 38,747 77 

INTEREST ON SALE CONTRACTS DECREASING RAPIDLY. 

FACTS. 

From the above table it will be seen that interest paid on 
sale contracts is decreasing rapidly, and it will be but a few 

May, 1902 122,281 78 May, 1902 78,331! !^ 

I)(&lt;iinber, 1902.. 46,751 10 

Erease 1808 Decrease 1901 
? 1900 fl58,980 47 to 1902 $117,127 10 
Biennium 1901-2 f33fi,568 40 
Biennium 1903-4 297,820 63 

tections— 1897-98, $612,675.97; 1899-00, $453,695.50; 
1901-2, $336,568.40; 1903-4, $297,820.63. </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
23 

PACTS 

K*s until the income from interest upon sale contracts will 
rely cease. 

The amount of money received as payment of principal for 
the past two years is $851,052.15. This amount has Ix-cn 
turned into the state treasury and is now a part of the j&gt;erinanent 
school fund, and, instead of drawing interest as heretofore 
at (5 per cent per annum, it now brings to the state 
hut from 3 to 3J per cent; hence, the interest upon school 
lands will decrease as collected from this department at a 
rate equal to 6 per cent upon the amount paid. During the 
juist two years this department has issued sale contracts uptm 
21,906.38 acres of land which was formerly held under leas*' 
contract, the purchase price of same being $307,42&lt;.». 05, while 
lhis will tend to increase the interest to this extent, it will 
decrease the rental now coming in upon lease contracts to an 
amount equal to 6 per cent upon the valuation as named in 
the lease contracts. 

From the face of the sale ledger accounts I find that IfceM 
was due the state as principal upon sale contracts not deeded 
12,752,335.44, instead of the estimated value of $2,257.27.-). 1 1. 
as given in our last report. Adding to this, $307,429.05, increase 
from new sale contracts issued this biennium, we will 
have a total principal of $3,059,764.49. From this take the 
$851,052.15, the amount received as principal paid upon these 
contracts for the past two years, and we find that there will 
be $2,208,712.34 of principal still due the state from sale contracts 
and upon which interest is received at 6 per cent. Even 
this amount will rapidly decrease from the fact that the contract 
holders have had good crops and splendid prices for the 
past few years, and, if same continues as they have in the 
past, contract holders will rapidly pay off principal upon 
their contracts, and obtain deeds in place. Another material 
element to the continued reduction of principal is that money 
can be secured from loan companies at a much less per centum 
than the regular rate of 6 per cent, the amount that is charged 
by the state upon the unpaid principal, in consequence of 
which many contract holders are taking advantage of this re- </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

duction in rate and paying principal due and taking dettls 
and obtaining loans elsewhere. 

In order to lie more specific as to the rapidity of payment 
of principal, I find that in the Land Commissioner's report of 
1898, on p. 9, the total amount due the state as principal on 
sale contracts was f4,G52,l 23.00. The sum total of all princi 
pal now, including valuation received for new contract - 
sued to December 1, 1904, is $2,208,712.34, a decrease in six 
years of $2,443,410.66 — a decrease of over 50 per cent. 

TOTAL RENTAL COLLECTED ON LEASE CONTRACTS. 

Biennium '97-8. .$208,723 46 Biennium '99-00 . f 220,085 "&gt; 
Biennium '99-00. 220,085 75 Biennium '01-02. 242,428 56 

Increase f 11,362 29 Increase f 22,342 81 

Biennium 1903-4... 306,643 11 

Increase f 64,214 55 

RENTAL ON LEASE CONTRACTS INCREASING RAPIDLY. 

rections— 1897-8, f 208,723.46; 1899-00, f 220,085.75; 
1901-2, f242,428.56; 1903-4, $306,643.11. 

AMOUNT RENTAL COLLECTED YEARLY. 

COMMENTS. 

Es contemplated, the rental upon lease contracts has steadincreased 
through each biennium, due to the fact that 
rly all of the vacant lands in the state have been leased, 
to the reappraisement of lands held under lease contract. 

It is with pride that I am able to report that there is but 
496.28 acres of vacant school lands in the state, and I hope 

Biennium 1901-2. . .$242,428 56 

F— ?116,15U 29 1898 — f 92,572 17 1899 — f 97,6UU 76 
— 122,484 99 1901— 117,344 58 1902— 125,083 98 
1903—1141,414 40 1904-^165,228 71 </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
25 


to have this placed under lease before mj term of offio 

The tendency as to the amount of rental to be received l»v 
tin- state for the next biennium from rental on lands beM under 
lease contract will be to increase in the event that reap 
praisement is had in the counties that have nut as jtA ben 
reappraised, and to decrease in an amount equal to t&gt; per 
cent on valuation of lease contracts that will be converted 
into sale contracts during the coming biennium. In my opinion 
the increase from rental on lease contracts from con 
tinned reappraisement will be of some less value than the 
decrease caused by loss of valuation t*hrough converting I 
into sale contracts; therefore, the income from rental for the 
next two years will remain practically the same. 

It will be noticed that during this administration the .May 
collections of rental are larger than those in December. This 
is due to two reasons: First, that it has been the policy of 
this office to request contract holders to pay a year's rental in 
advance, beginning with the January payment, as this would 
avoid taking the time of the lease holder from his work at a 
very busy time of year. Second, delinquent contract* holders 
are notified from this office of their delinquency immediately 
after the first day of January of each year. This calls the 
t holder's attention to the fact that rental has not been 
paid, and in making payment for the delinquent rental usually 
one payment is made in advance. It can make no dUTUUMC 
to the schools of the state as to whether the apportionment is 
made in December or May. The main question is, how much 
is the total apportionment for the year? At the same time it 
lessens the work of the county treasurers and this office by 
making payment but once a year. </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

PERMANENT SCHOOL FUND. 

The permanent school fund is composed of interest bearing 

Bted States and state securities, registered county bonds, 
state general fund warrants, and was obtained from the 

following sources : 

1. Sale of educational lands. 

2. Fire per cent sale of government lands of the state. 
3. Escheated estates. 

TABLE. 

It will be noted from the table given that the entire per- 

manent school fund is invested: 

IVrinanent common school securities $ 5,767,293 23 

Total interest bearing value permanent 

fund $11,617,483 33 

At the rate of increase as indicated by roippraisement, 
when all lease contracts are raised to a reasonable value, and 
those that are capable of being converted into sale contracts 
are so transferred and fully paid, it will increase the total 
interest bearing value of the permanent school fund of the 
state to nearly $20,000,000. 

TEMPORARY SCHOOL FUND. 

Khe temporary school fund is obtained from the following 
•ces: 

t Interest on permanent school securities. 
Rental on educational lands under lease. 

3. Interest on valuation of lands held under sale contracts. 

4. State school tax of not less than i per cent, nor more 
than 1£ per cent on the assessed valuation. 

Permanent university securities 12(5,1 4."i 21 

Kicultural college securities 331,32(5 TJ 
mal endowment securities tt^25 86 

Tokd securities Prrffcrr 1, 1903 f 6,293,(591 02 

Principal unpaid sale contracts 2,208,712 34 

Valuation lease contracts 3,115,079 97 </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
27 

SCHOOL FUND. 

5. Bonus received as a premium to secure lease contr 

&lt;». Interest on delinquent rental. 

7. .Money received for state licenses, fines, fees, etc 

This temporary school fund is apportioned twice a year 

I i.v the State Superintendent to the different counties in the 

state for the support of the public schools, and is known as 

the semi-annual apportionment. 

This semi-annual apportionment, with local license feel 

and fines, and the direct district tax, which can not ex&lt; 

2.~&gt; mills, compose the ways and means by which the public 

schools of the state are supported. 

STATK Kl»r&lt; ATIONAL LANDS 

Total number of acres acqoired 2,07»i,244.4."&gt; 

Total number of acres deeded 735,951.94 

Amount remaining 

2,240,292.51 

Number acres under sale contract 314.H7 

Number acres under lease contract 1,920,46 

Number acres vacant in entire state 497.13 

Number acres in supposed right of way 107.83 

Number acres paid out, but not deeded 24.". .~&gt;4 

Number acres in contest 1,339.20 

Number acres lost in river 369.00 

Number acres in model farm 1,280.00 

Number acres in city lots 320.00 

Number acres given to Lincoln Hospital for 
Insane 699.04 

Total acres now held by state 2,240,292." l 

WORK OF THE BIKNMIM. 

Number auctions held 57.00 

Number contracts divided 45.00 

Number contracts extended 291. 00 

Number certified copies issued 990.00 

Number reinstatements made 264.00 

Number- assignments recorded 5,626.00 </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
28 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 

Number delinquent registered notices issued. . . . 2,964.00 

Number of tracts of land reviewed 1,292.00 

Number letters prepared by State Surveyor 159.00 

Letters prepared, lease clerk 1,425.00 

Letters prepared, chief clerk, for deeds 2,504.00 

its prepared, assignment clerks 3,365.00 

Number letters general correspondence 15,260.00 

Number individual notices served 28,000.00 

Number acres forfeited 58,853.90 

Number acres reinstated 20,202.78 

Number acres sold 21,902.38 

Number acres leased 90,070.07 

Number acres extended 36,873.61 

Number acres deeded 121,304.81 

TOTAL COLLECTIONS. 

Total rental collected lease contracts f 312,284 89 

Total interest collected sale contracts 352,415 90 

Total bonus and added interest collected 8,246 31 

Total principal collected sale contracts 851,054 09 

Total fees collected 4,413 25 

Total collections for the biennium $ 1,528,414 44 </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
EDUCATIONAL LANDS. 

29 

01 


5 


i 

31 

05 

fUNTY 

1] 
3s 1 

h 

Si! 3 

c a 
SSI 

— 
I 
— - 

a 
s 
2 

Adams 20,480.00 
Antelope 31,400.00 
Banner 26,880.00 
Blaine 25,530.45 
Boone 23,675.28 
BoxButte 40,960.00 
Boyd 22,652.72 
Brown 40,998.90 
Buffalo 30,813.29 
Burt 17,487.88 
Butler 21,687.10 
Cms 19,7aj.98 
Cedar 26,804.36 
Cbase &amp;%280.00 
Cherry 244,104.09 
Cheyenne 106,253.02 
Clay 21,240.00 
Colfax 14,459.69 
Cuming 19,044.70 
Cnster 92,017.98 
Dakota 7,163.19 
Dawes 49,280.00 
Dawson 36,105.15 
Deuel 82,567.31 
Dixon 15,931.20 
Dodge 18,481.89 
Douglas 9,170.23 
Dundy 33,257.01 
Fillmore 20,648.51 
Franklin 20,471.85 
Frontier 34,560.00 
Furnas 25,602.80 
Gage 24,637.31 
Garfield 20,480.00 
Gosper 16,640.00 
Grant 29,000 00 
Greeley 20,475.30 
Hall 19,507.71 
Hamilton 20,487.56 
Harlan 20,400. C9 
Hayes 25,600.00 
Hitchcock 25,494.87 
Holt 87,376.60 
Hooker 26,158.59 
Howard 23,041.44 
Jefferson . 20 484 08 

1 14,600.00 
1 5,4S-2.1&gt;.{ 
I 

3,640.00 
6,997.77 

2,240.00 
18,920.00 
2f&gt;,SSO (10 
25,530.45 
8,314.97 
40,238.00 
21,188.33 
40,904.90 
11,687.86 
700.00 
765.20 
BO. 00 
3,813.36 
31694.52 
243,584.09 
104,602.02 
620.00 
634.43 
85.00 
81,045.98 
1,409.13 
48,787.57 
21,209.55 
81,957.66 
1,156.35 

9,064.76 
722.00 
107.69 
11.00 
11,264.96 
13,924.91 
18,163.10 
18,434.40 
15,551.00 
903.48 
93.92 
451.00 
16,504.02 
11,371.81 
13,692.79 
3,286.00 
3,002.37 
452.43 
6,114.60 
14.06 
9,629.61 
16,754.20 
8,130.19 
1.00 
18,920.00 
4,670.39 
1,362.00 
2,56:2.00 
21.072.81 
560.00 
3,362.00 

6,279.54 

37.80 
83.00 
7,848. -0 
2,662.97 
2,758.80 
1,079.58 
7,440.00 
682.00 
383.06 
1,200 00 
4,075.38 
2,438.45 
5,256.91 
7,606.00 
2,710.49 
40.00 
8.781.00 
M6.60 
5,073.93 
1,7-27.69 
828.45 
080.00 
1,688.51 
3,446.10 
1,920.00 
6,229.20 
3,170.00 
120.00 
4,400.00 

:::::** 

(4) 200 

40.66 "('»)' 3 
46166 '.'.'.'.'..'. 
(6 
en io 
(«) 80 
(») 41 

:::::: :::::::: 
(10) 71 

181.54 
32,576.01 
40.00 
12,355.36 
31,278.00 
16,811.60 
391.50 
19800.00 
8,878.00 
29,000.00 
15,668.67 
3,066.56 
487.56 
8,576.83 
24.852.20 
23,756.65 
84,637.63 
26 038.59 
10,457.39 

'.'.'.'.'.'. (ii)"30 

' '3.00 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 

I 

1,888.10 
12.387.60 
17,922.59 
5,571.80 
193.31 
673.62 
1,658.97 

2,918.53 
4.053.55 
2.077.41 
6,252.06 
554.49 
1.064.60 
1,080.00 
120.00 
7,101.67^ 

i ii 

::::::::::*:: 

"5,482.38 
12,093.38 </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

% 

an 
t jjt; 

- 

COUNTY 

"•3 
IS" 

S"8 
•31. 
r 

11 

i 
a 

I 

Madison .... 
McPherson . 
Richardson . 
Saunders . . . 
Sheridan . . . 
Wayne 
Webster .... 
Wheeler .... 

13,440.00 
18,581.40 
45,662 90 
26,222.46 
36,618.88 
42,893.81 
31,236.84 
97,890.93 
20,480 00 
20,393.28 
24,639.43 
56,320.00 
14,976.21 
11,792.34 
21,019.10 
21,992.44 
20,034.85 
31,523.75 
20,228.60 
20,480.00 
23,655.48 
16,787.68 
25,485.30 
10,400.00 
40,232.40 
20,480.00 
8,988.27 
26,390.99 
25 467.65 
20,560.00 
94,627.74 
20,477.20 
80,972.22 
15,360.00 
20,472.35 
25,600.00 
20,474.88 
13,851.86 
15,360.00 
20,480.00 
20,480.00 
20,474.00 

11,234.67 
8,821.44 
45.00 
413.30 

10,524.09 
24,812.87 
1,776.68 

56O!66 
13,963.66 

7,844.86 
10,573.49 
13,273.76 
18,044.44 
17,056.53 

7,268.32 
6,804.74 
16,514.81 
10,958.58 
1.831.35 
8,230.00 
120.00 
18,520.00 
7,035.69 
23,179.46 
231.11 
17,199.21 
367.87 
1,678.00 
80.00 
8,866.09 
13,011.65 

1,802.00 
4,960.00 
1,079.40 
20 70 
80.00 
10,468.03 
5,090.00 
5,994.20 

mo .'66 
7,555.77 

3,625.06 
HWI.(K&gt; 
7,095.34 
3,418.00 
2,818.32 

7,035.78 
6,435.26 
5,491.57 
4,107.80 
4,452.45 
1,240.00 
40.00 
1,360.00 
1,667.70 
2,843.21 
831.20 
2,757.15 
205.00 
4,426.08 

403.33 
4,796.96 
44,538.50 
25,788.46 
36,400.00 
21,901.69 
1,244.45 
90,104.06 
20,480.00 
19,593.28 
3,120.00 
56,320.00 
3,495.84 
225.65 
680.00 
510.00 
160.00 
31,323.75 
5,954.50 
7,240.00 
1,649.10 
1,721.30 
19,201.50 
930. CO 
40,072.40 
600. CO 
284.88 
360.00 
24,365.34 
603.64 
94,054.87 
14,373.12 
80,892.22 
3,800.00 
2,625.23 
25,600.00 
9,953.51 
1.814.90 

i38.88 .'.'.'.'.'.'.'.. 
;«) 16.00 

~= 

...... CM) i6.43 
34.4OU5) 78.80 
'.'.'.'.'.' U«j "20.66 
I206.66 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 

1 

.'.'.'.'.. im"i'.ia 
40.00 
ji:::::::::::E 

" 4,693 \.&lt;d\ 
4,835.47 

5,814.78 
10,890.00 
10,760.00 
6,526.00 
3.00 
15,680.61 

4,706.59 
1,126. C6 
4,600.00 
8,079.00 
40.00 
3,360.00 

5,875.00 
20,437.00 
1,433.39 

1!!".!!! iw'io'.ab 

I:::::::::::::::: 

2,796,061.97 

1638,628.14 

1261,052.11 

1,893,844.31 

1496.28 

2,041.13 </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
EDUCATIONAL LANDS. 

31 


Total I 89,149. 2l| 47,920 .461 30,865.971 10,342 .3*1 | '20 U 

SALINE 

Lancaster 45,594.24 22,425.35 5,637.39 2,427.66 0)15,103.84 

NORMAL 

Lancaster 12,904.80 10,131.20 2,593.60 80.00 

La 

COUNTY 

• 

k 

CO fj 
•as 
2 &gt;- 
2* 

a a 
II] 

a 
| 

! 

Antelope 1,600.00 449.98 830.02 
Cedar 1,920.00 1,440.00 80.00 
Dakota 330.00 320.00 
Dixon 640.00 360.00 280.00 
Holt 8,322.10 1,720.00 440.00 
Knox 4,480.00 1,680.00 1,360 00 
Madison 2,240.00 760.00 720.00 
Nuckolls 4,916.68 1,206.66 3,558.9; 
Pierce 3,197.67 2,319.44 878.23 
Webster 17,802.58 6,911.71 6,360.72 
Total 45,439.03 16,846.79 14,827.89 

830.02 
80.00 
320.00 
280.00 
440.00 
1,360 00 
720.00 
3,558.9; 
878.23 
6,360.72 

320.0q 
400.00J 

6,162.10 
1,440.00 
760.00 
152.10 

• ••¦•.]•»••••••••¦- 

'MMJli 

"\m '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 

i 14,827.891 

13,763.50| 

.85|. 

AGRICULTURAL COIXX 

AL COIX' 

:ge 

Burt 640.00 480.00 160.00 
Cedar 25,405.47 14,204.21 8,529.58 
Cuming 960.00 960.00 
Dakota G40.00 603.92 
Dixon 2,240.00 1,433.90 676.00 
Knox 33,500.20 14,585.86 12,678.44 
Pierce 10,114.56 4,017.18 4,818.70 
Wayne 15,648.18 11,635.39 4,003.25 

'.'.'.'.'.'.. 
" x.m .'.'.'.'. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.I'.'. 
120.00 (») 10.10 
6,235.90 
1,278.68 
»S» 10.^1 </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
32 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

1. 16.01 acres, supposed right of way, Omaha, Niobrara &amp; 
Black Hills Ry. 

K 1,318.90 acres confirmed to the state, but awaiting reof 
contest. 

t 1,227 acres U. P. right of way. 
200 acres in river. 

5. 3.02 acres held by F., E. &amp; M. V. right of way. 
6. 15 acres principal paid, but deed not issued. 
7. 10 acres paid, but not deeded. 

t80 acres paid, but not deeded. 
41.20 acres in river. 

10. 49 acres in river, and 22.31 acres supposed right of 
way, Chicago, St. Paul &amp; Minneapolis Ry. 

11. 30.05 acres supposed right of way U. P. Ry. 
12. 89.52 acres principal paid, but deed not issued. 
13. 16 acres supposed right of way U. P. Ry. 
14. 10.43 acres principal paid, but not deeded. 
15. 78.80 acres in Platte river. 

16. 20 acres principal paid, but deed not issued. 
17. 8.32 acres principal paid, but deed not issued. 
18. 20.30 acres awaiting decision court in Iowa. 
19. 10.10 acres supposed right of way Chicago, St. Paul &amp; 

Minneapolis Ry. 

20. 10.34 acres supposed right of way Minn., St. Paul &amp; 
Chicago right of way. 

t 15,103.84 acres of Saline land was set aside by the legre, 
as follows: State University and city lots, 320 
; Lincoln Hospital for Insane, 099.04 acres; model 
1,280 acres; Normal school, 12,804.80 acres. 

This department has written to various railroad companies 
(hat have not secured deeds to their lands, and an effort is 
being put forth toward the state receiving compensation for </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
33 


NG 

WORK OF TH 

BI 

CO 

IMON SCHOOL 

ODNTY 

&lt; 

I 

s 

ll 

I. 
P 
a 
HI 

5 • 8 
SI* 

it 
I! 

Box Butte 
praaklta"" 
GaiWld.. '.'.'.'. 
Hamilton... . 
Hitchcock 
Ktva Fa'ha!' 
Kimball 
Lancaster . .. 

2,440.00 

12,058 20 
7,751 40 
1,453 31 
1.572 46 
4,148 02 
5,102 85 
8 890 62 
3.954 63 
5.910 43 
791 80 
8s8 21 
459 10 
1.879 68 
2.130 36 
20,403 86 
8,418% 
245 19 
1,054 98 
263 41 
12.688 97 
7;i5 74 
5,205 49 
4.824 95 
5,7*3 20 
1,267 50 
180 06 
110 94 
2 0.0 59 
45 60 
5.930 26 
X.U".7 'M 
6.290 89 
1.431 76 
4,117 20 
1.002 48 
3633 95 
UN 68 
143 04 
4.32* 92 
3,636 5K 
3.533 33 
13 BM 77 
1.933 96 
5.593 41 
3,061 49 
763 20 
2.087 54 
6.290 80 
3,755 99 
1,629 68 
9,195 47 
1.566 85 
8,761 90 
1 ..596 83 
2,162 23 
1.105 10 
1.757 K8 
2.733 70 
767 10 
M 9". 
2.80K04 

I 4 255 77 
5,614 49 

% 47 30 
M «0 
40 51 
37 53 
80 71 
155 58 
773 98 
103 68 
211 42 
302 
4 65 
I 8* 
39 25 
48 09 
M « 
M ¦ 
1 ¦ 
6 7S 
53 
363 39 
12 72 
132 10 
«6» 
131 9T» 
20 54 
2 8-&gt; 
396 
47 65 
a 
in 37 
327 34 
lit «) 
2 63 
28 29 
58 06 
11 78 
56 96 
44 57 
91 
302 74 
X9 41 
1U98 
341 44 
48 14 
188 11 
34 73 
3 fi6 
38 14 
217 6» 
97 08 
3* (5* 
229 M 
13 40 
168 92 
52 01 
60 53 
22 04 
35 70 
m 92 
5 10 
16 07 
5 22 
32 
28 22 
58 27 
93 ¦ 

$ 15.163 Of) 
3 632 00 

'II 
l.t»«9H 
26,68i 78 
5.ZM 4:1 
9,912 20 
4.13 31 
3S.4S2 55 
15.102 41 
18.52 04 
MB 25 
32,783 Ot 
2.710 69 
21,191 71 
10.519 12 
2S.H5S9I 
15.287 76 
16.240 &amp; 
29,608 12 
10.713 57 
5,344 27 
82.713 66 
6,526 45 
25.793 62 
6,573 0^ 
1,291 79 
2.827 92 
U.445 08 
14,702 04 
11.849 .8 
16,474 98 
12,315 12 
2.S30S7 
23.170 57 
1.014 26 
10,419 15 
22.244 64 
16,724 W 
19 848 93 
4.014 25 
4.110 35 
15.V0 90 
2,157 08 
21.229 57 
28,014 19 
7.06&gt; 83 
33.370 82 
6,987 OS 
5.086 70 
1.752 K 
47.4W S3 
28 279 64 
19 322 63 
1.748 84 
5.101 91 
mm 
1.7VSO8 
12.7a a 
4.1112 90 
35 482 02 
13 207 62 
21.608 5S 

i.680!6(H 
2,160.00 

i,98o!6o 

i,360 66 

"¦5,928O5 

"16,529 OM 
'"ai'oi 

"a!» 

"iiiBW 

"e'ioioo 
'120 low 

4.440.00 
2.127.15 
2.8S0.0O 
130.00 
120. U) 

28 56 
65 00 
9.124 49 
4.307 59 
4.218 11 
1.310 27 
7,761 58 
5T2 24 
38 ! 24 
1,330 56 
r, 636 7X 
5.43rt 01 
s.an 27 
9 l.sii 7rt 
2,922 21 
6S&gt; 
9,840 66 
597 30 
5 198 58 
2,111 72 
1.176 89 
7(19 R8 
2.3x7 80 
3.:kX2 41 
2 257 10 
5.191 13 
3,353 72 
201 65 
5.196 31 

21.246 21 
10.000 00 
13 441 04 
6.450 00 
23.102 50 

3,236.70 
1.430.70 
1.416 W 
680 00 
2,730.00 

'50.66 

i,3'o;6o 

1.00 
3,560.01) 
610.00 
1.701.80 
1,040.00 
1.293.92 

ilooj 

640.00 
80.00 
160 00 
199.92 

198.00 
21.433.10 
4,760.00 
WI.OO 
120.00 
40. U) 
1.240.00 
3.93 
3,840.00 
160.00 
2,720.00 

51100 
22,975 00 
8,790 00 
10.969 00 
7,375 00 
7,052 90 
"ii,'sBz*66 
14 0 1 
19,307 00 
4,278 45 

2,640.00 
2.00 
2,990.00 
276 U 

i'.ixA 

"sao'.m 

1.815 68 
580.00 
160.00 
520.00 
1,850.00 
78.67 
2,080.00 

" 'iio'.iu 

' "io'.om 

11,031 09 
5.078 00 
1.208 00 
4.839 Srt 
8,221 20 
i»» 67 
13.797 00 

i.sbo'ow 

'"iax'.inl 

eo?6cJ 
760.001 

'"Hn'.m 

640.00 
2.2SV3O 
2,006.00 
1,745.10 

¦"jioloo 
80.00 

moo 
40.0d 

2,658 24 
4.911 38 
2.556 75 
6,574 77 
;ss :'s 
298 04 
861 84 
174 96 
6,698 05 
6,210 56 
1,911 97 
6,302 92 
478 55 
97 05 
30 48 
11,047 25 
6.097 39 
5,007 44 

4.068 00 
14.929 01 
14 024 00 
MM ¦ 

i'.m 
13.55 

" 'm.ool 

""»!6m 
13.55 

160.00 
1.16.H us 
1,707.07 
3.280.00 
960.00 
5.03 
207.20 
24O.0O 

¦"isi'oJ 
100 85 

1.400.00 
2,799.06 
aaon 
3,382.16 

3.90 

8 750 00 
18.707 41 
4 3*4 Hi 
24,942 22 

' 56 3.66 

' 2,88 i! 67 

1.146 60 
56 Oi 
27.027 57 
20 «C (M 
5,384 97 

" ia.oiJ 

" 8o!(6 
960.00 

4.S2O.O0 
445.90 
m.» 
2 720 00 
9fiO.«0 
720.00 

4. sir 3i 
• 315 OW 
1,275 88 

'246!6tM 
2.155.74 

47617 
7.125 87 

"i'40306 
13.4S9 38| 

1,078.00 
•» o» 
4.27J.OO 
1 118.90 
2.060.00 

19319 

10.00 

800.00 
80 00 
40.00 
200 00 
80.00 
920.00 

3,548 00 
1030 70 
8.34.' 10 
3.846 53 
4,471 29 

6 435 01 
2 300 00 
H 4!* M 
I.C79 47 
turn 52 

3.'.m50 
l.seo.ool 

8o!6a 

"8!9S6'97 
«,?S5 83| 

22 3US 99 
« 310 00 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
TABLE SHOWING WORI 

: OF TH 

IB BIENNIUM— Continued 

co: 

fUON SCI 

HOOL 

COUNTY 

•a 
V 
¦a 
I 
&lt; 

I 
&lt; 

J 

m 
CO 
02 
P 
B 

III 
Si 0 " 

xa 
a. ¦ 
w 

Red Willow.'. 
Scatu'mnff. 
Washington. 
wJbmv..... 
Wheeler 

2082.60 
1.423.00 
343 30 
12O.00 
40.00 
933.00 
4(1.00 
2 M H 
53.65 
800.00 

160.00 
80.03 
640.00 

"aoioo 

"eooiob 
960.0(1 

79.12 
240.00 
1, .63.56 

* 1 29) 11 
1.659 U 
4.780 46 
1,452 33 
3.657 10 
532 00 
171 61 
721 60 
3,235 36 
993 70 
10.061 09 
6 562 15 
7,645 78 
2.192 41 
1.823 60 
1 240 98 
3,270 0; 
210e$ 50 

i 
i 
i 

$ 5.473 10 
4,497 66 
3.965 80 
1,722 24 
48 00 
2.247 07 
1,964 3d 
5,154 24 
574 35 
2,667 93 
IKS 60 
4.377 64 

$ 29 95 
20 92 
178 45 
2 13 
93 06 
5 40 
97 
17 6S 
127 94 
7 65 
231 58 
147 01 
151 30 
42 ?9 
52 82 
34 18 
41 8' 
28 59 

$ 1SJM Tl 
10, 129 (M 
6i»» 7:( 
2,124 00 
6K) (XI 
7.079 40 
558 00 
18,520 7.". 
921 CO 
5.830 00 

16.912 To 
14.9BI 44 
4!a9S 16 
9.863 87 
2.694 94 
24.414 22 
4.S.X 65 
9.499 28 
10.491 27 
21.377 39 
7.7W7 08 
21,681 26 
21.U46 84 
1275 16 
22.761 18 
11.623 88 
16 057 84 
27 463 02 
4.071 91 
20,101 63 

""40.00 
367.20 

1,181. '4»l 

fiao.'dol 

5,364" 99 

"i6,»6'» 

1880 00 
2 218.30 

"486.06 
410.00 

S.200.00 
20.00 
240.00 
800 00 

" 6,&lt; ; 40'56 
4,720 S4 

13,«O6o6 
15,349 58 

1.886.50 
591.20 
1.K40.IU 
2,119.00 

1960.06 

'iaoi!6o 

562.86 
56i I ! 00 
320.00 

8,284 09 
3.928 40 
1,717 92 

4.430 98 
2 759 36 
5,6i'l 84 
6,8&amp;) 17 
43 36 
4.602 32 

14,998 31 
6,727 43 
10 456 00 
17,r»5 20 

i,952.'37 

'"aa'.ia 

ei 56 
98 1 ¦&gt; 
17 28 

"i4.'r64'hl 

W7.288.23 

15 396.48J 

8». 104. T, 

¦¦MB ¦ 

$289,047 43 

|$7.796 6l|«688.816 68 

$1,282.12S U 

tabl: 

SHOWING WOR 

OF 

THE BIENNIUM— CONTIOTBD 

irvi 

;rsity 

COUNTY 

I 

— 
I 
¦r 

I 

h 
Si 
a u 

h 
V 
a 

"= a 
•o'a 5 
fig; 

§1 

II 

160.00 
lbO.OOj 

800.0M 
400.0M 
80.0M 

4o!oo 

$ 185 00 
2Ti2 00 

8,677 57 
664 80 
97 90 
155 12 

f 585 98 
96 75 
M 92 
224 64 
983 44 
1.398 10 
HI H 
2.757 00 
X83 10 
5,769 03 

$ q 

56 28 
15 13 
1 26 
4 60 

$ 706 CO 
1,000 00 

4.528 00 
2,520 00 
504 00 
850 00 
2.125 31 
12,468 9K 

221 64 
8,245 29 
4.598 03 
1,156 12 
3.266 72 
3.008 41 
20.9S2 30 

596. 59 
1.689.60 1 

isi'.m 

2.68i'59 

' 'ffiTO 

1.418J8 

3 6*. 19 

1.418.18 

,?25.S0 

»6 6t&gt;3 M 

$13,395 92|*147 87 

$24,202 29| $44,410 08 </seg>


            <seg id="p035">
GENERAL COMMENTS. 

Auctions Uave been held in fifty-seven counties during the 
two vears, and I have leased 90,070.07 acres in all. At 
the time of my last report there were 1,339.50 acres of vacant 
land in the state that were capable of being leased. The 
Board of Educational Lands and Funds have forfeited 
&gt;".',. 90 acres during the two years. I have issued lease c&lt;mtracts 
where old leases have expired amounting to 29,880 
acres, and there are still vacant in the state 497.13 acres. 

I also find that lessees are paying their rental mmc 
promptly than they formerly did, from the fact that school 
land leases are more valuable, crops have been good, and 
money easier to obtain. Another fact that is pleasing to me 
is tliat when lands are forfeited they are, in a majority of 
cases, released at an increased valuation. 

1,166 22 661.65 «,200 17 $11,536 20 $ 64 25 $18,128 22 $33,028 M 

LEASE COXTK \ 

EDUCA 1 

lONAL L. 

1NDS. 

TABLE SHOWING WORK 

OF THE 1 

3IENNIUM — Continued 

AGRICU 

,TURAL COL 

cege 

— 

COUNTY 

•s 
&amp; 
8 
I 

— 
I 
¦j 

-3 
3 
: 
o 

s. 

v 
° s 
V 
a 
M 

" - s 
si"" 

¦ 

'.'. awa'.is l.oaiw 
M0.00 
'.'. "iio.U) ".'.'.'.'.'.'. 
¦ ¦ 9 816.69 397.50 
.. 1.313.15 
.. 2,299.13 

w.«a'3M 

M 98 
140 04 
3,222 8* 
999 * 

I 120 96 
9 4«! (O 
14 61 

16 4 1 ". 91 
4.636 49 
«3DX&gt;5 3 

*'*'6S 

I 
I 47 
3 95 
74 85 
29 4" 

t i»m 
i.8uu oo ; 
"¦-'woo i 
58.8.^26 &gt; 
11447 00 I9.i 83 49 

Toe,... 

mm m 

*137 37 

*1IO,461 14 *151,S34 C 

17.762.2M 1,428.07 

NORMAL 

[^ticastcr. 

1398.97 80.no 

$74 40 $3,081 CZ to 21 J9.445 76 112,601 3 

SALINE </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
36 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

SALE CONTRACTS. 

In the roar 1897 a bill passed the legislature taking from 
the market the unsold school lands of the state, but the law 
under which lease contracts were made since May 26, 1879, 
ajid tlie taking effect of this law in July, 1S!»7, pwt the lessee 
the right to surrender lease contract and to take in its place 
a sale contract upon complying with certain provisions ami 
i tiie appraisement of the land at its full value. The law 
of 1897 could not. of course, abrogate this provision. I find 
a number of contracts were issued prior to May 2&lt;&gt;, 1879, and 
under the law which was in effect at the time these 1 
contracts were entered into the right to purchase by V 
not given. It seems to me to be just, under the circumstances, 
that the legislature should make some provision 
whereby these old lease holders might purchase the lands 
held by them as lease contracts for so long a time. They have 
1 upon this land for a quarter of a century or more, have 
builded homes and placed valuable improvements thereon 
under the impression that they had a right at any time before 
their contract expired to surrender the lease contract and 
obtain a sale contract, upon which deed would ultimately 
e. Many of these people have placed every cent that they 
have on earth in improvements upon these lands, and the 
new appraisement has raised the price of same to such a valuation 
that it would be money in the lease holder's pocket to 
purchase. 

inasmuch as these lessees were pioneers of the state, and 
so much toward its material development, I fully trust 
a bill will be passed by the coming legislature removing 
ictions upon all lands held under lease contract prior 
lay 26, 1879, thus putting these old settlers on an equal 
ing with those that took out lease contracts after May 
1879. 

During the biennium just closed I have issued sale contracts 
upon 21,906.: - which have been held under lease 
contracts bearing date since May 26, 1879. It was found </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
37 

GENERAL COMMENTS. 

DpOB investigation that the parties who appraised this land 
were not placing the mine at a price sufficient to warrant 
the state to pan title, but at a value much less than other 
lands of the same kiud were selling for in the vicinity of the 
lamls sought to be purchased. The Board of Educational 
Lands and funds, at a regular meeting, adopted a resolution 
that no lands held under lease contract should be sold until 
they had been reviewed by the Land Commissioner, his deputy, 
or some member of the Beard having authority, and 
i']&lt;in the recommendation of the reviewing party that the 
appraisement was somewhere near its true value. 

In conformance to this resolution, myself and deputy have 
reviewed I,2!t2 different tracts of laud during the past two 
yeafl, traveling thousands of miles by team and train to 
carry out the instructions of th&gt;e Board, and in no case has 
a sale contract been issued without this review. I tind it to 
be the tendency of the appraisers, through sympathy, 1 
influence, or otherwise, to place the valuation at a much 
price than the land is really worth. They do not seem to 
appreciate the fact that the lessee has had the use of this 
land for many years at a nominal sum, and that, by an appraisement 
less than the real value, they are taking the 
amount from the permanent school fund and transferring it 
to the pockets of an individual. They do not seem to fully 
realize, or at least understand, that they are working against 
their own interests, as well as that of the people of the entire 
state by such action, as it increases their own tax by reducing 
the amount which is to become a part of the permanent school 
fund from which the semi-annual apportionment is received, 
and reducing the amount to be paid each year to the school 
children of the state for all time to come. 

If the State Treasurer, the Land Commissioner, or any 
other state officer, would give to an individual an equal 
amount of funds which belonged to the permanent school 
fund, there would, indeed, be, and justly, too, a cry of offl </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
38 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

value one of the greatest dangers which threatens the school 
funds of the state at this time. It also means an immense 
amount of criticism from people who do not understand the 
situation, and does, indeed, work a hardship to this departliH-iit, 
because it is necessary in the majority of cases to report 
adversely upon the appraisement as made by the commoners. 
As an evidence of the facts stated above, I have 
in this office the necessary proofs, and these have been presented 
to the Board of Educational Lands and Funds from 
time to time for their action. Whenever the Board of Educational 
Lands and Funds has rejected an application on account 
that the valuation as stated is not sufficient to warrant 
t hem to pass title, they have, at the request of the lessee, appointed 
three freeholders who live in the county where the 
land is located to act as arbitrators, and to review and reappraise 
the land in question, and in only two instances have 
the freeholders agreed with the previous appraisers, and in 
the majority of cases have placed the value above the estimate 
made by the reviewing party. The fact that this land 
has been reviewed and reappraised has added to the permanent 
school fund thousands of dollars. I would recommend 
that the same system be carried out in the future. In one 
county alone, and upon a comparatively small acreage, an 
increase of |26,000 was made, and then, in my opinion, the 
lands sold did not bring their true value. 

OFFICE FORCE. 

I addition to the commissioner and deputy, the office force 
mposed of a chief clerk, state surveyor, two bookkeepers, 
se contract clerk, delinquent clerk, two assignment clerks 
a stenographer. It can be seen from this report that the 
t of the land office has greatly increased during the past 
years, and that the clerical force has remained the same, 
ill be absolutely necessary for the entire force to be re?d 
in order that the work of the department may be done </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
OFFICE FORCE. 

39 

I lie past two years myself and deputy have done a large 
unt of field work, have held fifty-eight auctions, and rrred 
a large number of tracts of school land that lessees 
converting from lease into sale contracts. We have on 
at this time 1,500 applications for review, which would 
cate that the work for the next two years in this line will 
reater than it has been in the past. This work, as statcil. 
taken a considerable amount of the time of the commis 
er and deputy from the regular office work, and th« 
work has been, to some extent, in the hands of the office 

Et is the duty of the chief clerk to issue all deeds and. in 
absence of the commissioner and deputy, to attend to 
general correspondence, and take charge of the other work 
he office. He has issued deeds to 122,702.88 acres of land, 
has written from his desk 2,504 letters pertaining to 
1 work during this biennium. 

I Che state surveyor performs all surveys upon application 
ere disputes arise between parties. He also makes calcuion 
for the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and 
ildings relative to school land, and performs such work 
is assigned him by the different boards of the state, which 
ong to his department. He also takes direct care of the 
ts and field notes belonging to the state under the direction 
the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. A deled 
report of his work is given elsewhere in this report. 

The two bookkeepers keep the accounts of 65,000 lease and 
sale contract holders. During the last two years they have 
entered upon the school land ledgers 27,000 receipts, have 
registered them, and turned the same over to the Auditor, 
and, in addition to this regular work, have furnished much 
information to thousands of contract holders and various 
county treasurers, which deal directly with their work. 

It is the duty of the two assignment clerks to enter of 
record the assignments and various transfers of lease and 
sale contracts and to record wills, affidavits, and letters of 
administration. During the biennium they have recorded </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
40 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

5,626 assignments, written 3,365 letters of transmittal. and 
have issued sale contracts to 21,906.38 acres of land. 

I he delinquent clerk takes charge of the delinquent m 
its, sends out notices to delinquent contract holders, pie 
» the delinquent list, serves registered notices of lorire, 
reinstates forfeited contracts, makes out the auction 
(, and goes carefully over the 65,000 accounts of the stntf 
lote every account that is behind with the interest or 
al due the state. During the past two years 28,000 first 
ce cards have been issued, 2,964 registered notices serveil. 
several thousand notices of forfeiture have been sent; 
02.78 acres of land have been reinstated, besides the cor(ondence 
which deals directly with this department of 
work. 

Iie lease contract clerk makes out lease contracts, issues 
es of the various contracts lost, divides contracts, and 
» certified copies of the records of the office, extends 
contracts, and, during the next biennium, will hare 
ge of the sale contract work. During the past two jean 
rO.07 acres of land have been leased, 200 certified copies 
xi, 45 contracts divided, contracts to 36,873.61 acres of 
have been extended, 925 letters of transmittal written, 
the work of reappraising 54 counties performed, toer 
with a large amount of information given to the oftiee 

It is the duty of the stenographer to do the work Incident 
to a stenographer for all the departments of this office, to 
copy and file letters, to send out information to bidders for 
the Board of Purchase and Supplies, and, when the 20,000 
and more of letters which have left this department are taken 
into consideration, it can readily be seen that it has been a 
very busy biennium. 

Ee Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings is the 
tary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. 
ill the work of this board outside of the regular board 
ms is done bv the Commissioner and his force. II </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
41 

SURVEYING. 

also .secretary of the Board of Purchase and Supplies, whicb 
\ery three months to open and let the hids for fur 
nishing supplies to the various state institutions. These bids 
an carefully figured over in older to lie sure that some item 
has not been left out, the cost of each item is carefully ¦ 
inized, total inspected, and all compared with the estimate 
furnished hy the heads of the institutions. This takes up the 
lime of the entire office force for several days of each qtUU 

There are many and varied other duties which have to lie 
performed from day to day that are of greal importance. hut 
are only incidental, and it would he impossible to enum« 
them in this report. 

KEL'AKTMENT OF SURVEYING. 

fie statutes of Nebraska •place the government field n 
plats in charge of the Commissioner of Public Lands and 
dings, and. in addition to this, the last legislature passed 
following hill, which was signed by the &lt;lovernor and 
me a law -7ul v I, LM8: 

An act providing for the appointment- of a state sun 
and draughtsman in the office of the Commissioner of Public 
Lands and Buildings, and to prescribe his dir 
li&lt; it cnuctrd hi/ the leffiflatun of the xlate of .\&lt; broak*: 

|«'tion 1. The Commissioner of Public Lands and Build- 
I shall appoint a competent and experienced land 
?r, who shall also "no a competent draughtsman, who shall 
known and designated as the "State Surveyor ami 
ughtsman," to take charge nnder the supervision of the 
unissioner of Public Lands and Buildings of the field 
¦s, maps, charts, and records of the United States suri, 
and to perform such other duties as may lie pi 
he Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. 

¦. 2. The Commissioner of Public Lands and Build 
shall refer to the said surveyor all questions or inquirit 
lating to sir rievances, or disputes growing out of C6B&gt; 
flicting surveys of lands or lots. Said surveyor and drang 
ma;: snail issue and prepare the advice, instruction, and opin </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
42 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

I and issue the same under the approval of the Commiser 
of Public Lands and Buildings. In case a survey is 
tioned for, he shall "perform that duty and report the 
e, with the necessary notes and maps, to the Commiser 
of Public Lands and Buildings, and, when said notes 
maps are so approved and filed and recorded in the office 
he county surveyor of the county in which the survey was 
, shall be prima facie evidence of the correctness thereof. 
[ it shall be the duty of said county surveyor to record 
file said notes and maps in the county surveyor's record* 
he county in which the survey is made. 

Provided, Any person or persons having an interest in the 
lands affected by such survey may appeal therefrom in the 
manner provided by law. He shall also prepare and issue 
under the authority and direction of the said Commissioner 
of Public Lands and Buildings a circular of instructions to 
the county surveyors of the state, for their direction and 
guidance, in the restoration and establishment of lines and 
preservation of corners in conformity with the laws, rules 
and regulations governing the surveys of the United States, 
and established rules of surveying; and for the concise and 
comprehensive preparation and recording of field notes and 
maps of surveys. He shall also perform such other duties 
as the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings may 
require. 

Sec. 3. There shall be paid to the State Treasurer for each 
day the said surveyor is necessarily absent from the office in 
making any survey the sum of six dollars per day for the 
services of said surveyor, and the necessary expenses incurred 
in making the same. All such fees so received to be paid into 
the state treasury for the use of the general fund of the state. 

E4. In case of any dispute among owners of land aris¦, 
or by reason of, any survey of boundaries of lands 
this state; or, in case of dispute or disagreement besurveyors 
as to said surveys or boundaries, the same 
e referred to the said "state surveyor and draughts- </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
SURVEYING. 

43 

I" for settlement, and he is hereby appointed as arbitrator 
*ttle and determine such disputes or disagreements as to 
surveys and boundaries, and whose decision shall be 
1a facie evidence of the correctness thereof. There shall 
&gt;aid to the State Treasurer for the services of the said 
e surveyor and draughtsman in settling and disposh' 
said disputes and differences the sum of six dollars pet 
for each day's services actually performed by the - 
B surveyor and draughtsman, to be paid by the j&gt;;r 
ctly interested in the said controversy, and said sur 
aid boundaries, and said sum or sums of money so reed 
therefrom shall be paid into the state treasury for the 
tfit of the general fund of the state. 

Sec. 5. All acts and pjfrts of acts in conflict herewith are 
hereby repealed. 

Acting under the direction of this new law, I appointed 
and commissioned Mr. Robert Harvey, of St. Paul, Nebraska, 
state surveyor and draughtsman, the same to take effect mi 
and after the 10th day of July, 1903. A large amount of 
work had to be done in classifying, arranging, correcting, and 
preparing the books, plats, and records belonging to the department, 
actual field work in various portions of the - 
in definitely finding obliterated corners and fixing boundary 
lines where disputes had arisen and reestablishing lost corners. 
This, with the regular routine work of the coin 
sioner's office and the services demanded by the Board of 
Public Lands and Buildings, has occupied the entire time of 
Mr. Harvey, and, at this time, we have several applications 
on file requesting his services for field work, which will be 
taken up in their regular turn and receive proper attention. 

The outside work of this department will steadily increase 
in proportion as knowledge of its purpose and importance 
becomes known to the people of the state. In consequence 
of the performance of this field work the fees to be rec« 
will increase. However, the work done for the people of the 
state outside the office, for which fees are received, is incon- </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
44 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

siderable in comparison to the regular work required by the 
l.ind olhYe and the state boards. I attach hereto the report 
of the state surveyor, which will be of interest to the legMatme 
and the people at large. 

(From Mr. Harvey's Report.) 

INVENTORY. 

'•The following inventory was taken of the valuable records 

the oAce pertaining to U. B. surveys of Nebraska, which 
govei nmt'iit, many years ago and since, presented to the 

slate, to-wit: 

4 volumes of field notes of state boundary lines. 

] volume of connections of Nebraska with Iowa and Missouri 
survc* 

rlume of Standard Parallels cast of the 6th Principal M&lt;ridian. 


rume of the Guide Meridian east of the 6th Principal 
ridian. 

I volumes of the township exterior lines east of the Gth 
Principal Meridian. 

97 volumes of the township subdivisions east of the 6th Principal 
Meridian. 

&gt;f the Standard Parallels west of the 6th Principal 
Meridian. 

7 volumes of the Guide Meridians icest of the 6th Principal 
.Meridian. 

K volumes of the township exterior lines west of the 6tlr 
Principal Meridian. 

4 » . -^ volumes of the township subdivisions icest of the 6th 
Principal Meridian. 

tlume of T. 82 N., Ranges 45 and 46 icest of the 5th Principal 
Meridian. 

1 volumes of retracementa. 

!&gt; volumes &lt;»f the Pawnee Indian reservation. 

B volumes of theOtoe and Missouri Indian reservation. 

8 volumes of the Winnefaago Indian reservation. </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
SURVEYING. 

45 

1 volume of the Sioux Indian reservation. 

Eume of the Port McPherson military reservation 
OM of the abandoned Fort Kearney reservation 
al of 700 volumes. 

It was discovered that the tield notes and nia|&gt;s of the 
ey of tlie Sac and Fox Indian reservation had never I 
with the other records, the surveys baring been executed 
* contracts with the Commissioner of 'Indian Affa 
lication was, therefore, made to the Honorable Conimiser 
of the General Land Office for copies of said notes and 
s. The notes were borrowed from the 'Indian Bun 
lie Commissioner, and an excellent typewritten copy was 
llj forwarded to this office. These were compiled and 
id into one volume. 

"There were stored away and on the shelves the unbound 
tii Id notes in MS. the following field notes of surveys, to-wit : 

Survey of the Iowa Indian reservation. 

Bwvey of the Omaha and WinnebagO Indian reservation i f 
1867. 

Survey of the abandoned Fort McPnenon military reservation. 


tnall books of the survey of the '.Missouri River cut 
near Sioux City. 

¦ resuvveys of IV,\ townships in Grant, Hooker, Cheyenne. 
and Cherry counties. 

Survev of 'Ash Island.' in Mei-rick countv 

Survey of an island in T. 11 X., II. 8 W.. Merries: county. 
Survey of an island in Loup River, T. 15 N ., B. 10 W., How- 

ard county. 

tey of an island in Niobrara Kiver, in T. 99 N . Eta. Lfl 
and 19 \\\, Rock county. 

Survey of additional lines and mffatttli IS in T. -V2 N\. K. •"&gt; \\ . 
in 1890. 

Survey of T. 31 N., U. 32 W. 

"Of the above there have been compiled and bound the following 
to-wit: </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
46 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

1 volume of Sac and Fox Indian reservation. 

1 volume of Iowa Indian reservation. 

rlumes of Omaha and Winnebago Indian reservation, survey 
of 1867. 

rlume of abandoned Fort McPherson military reservation, 
survey of 1897. 

1 volume of 'Missouri River cut off,' survey of 1870. 

2 volumes of township exterior lines of nmurtja of Grant, 
Hooker, Cheyenne, aud Cherry counties. 

rl, 9 volumes, which, added to the 700 volumes, m;ikes a 
total of 709 volumes of field notes bound in leather. 

-7&gt; original maps of state boundary lines. 

8 original maps of the 6th Principal Meridian. 

¦ original maps of the connection of Nebraska with Iowa 
and Missouri surveys. 

14 original maps of Indian reservations. 

:; original maps of military reservations. 

34 original maps of Standard Parallels and Guide Meridians 
watt of the 6th Principal Meridian. 

¦ original maps of township exterior lines east of the 6th 
Principal Meridian. 

f original maps of township subdivisions and fragmentary 
surveys. 

»". original maps Ts. 88 and 89 N., Its. 47 and 48 W., 5th P. M. 

f original maps of Standard Parallels and Guide Meridians 
west of the 6th Principal Meridian, 

t original maps of township exterior lines tccst of the 6th 
Principal Meridian. 

rl original maps of township subdivisional lines west of 
the 6th Principal Meridian. 

Total, 2,S86 original maps of government surveys. 

f certified copies of original maps of township subdivisions 
east of the 6th Principal Meridian — bound in 13 volumes. 

4.'t(&gt; certified copies of original mops of township subdivisions 
west of the 6th Principal Meridian — bound in 12 vol- </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
47 

SURVEYING. 

2 certified copies of state boundary lines. 

241 certified copies township subdivisional lines, unbound. 
Total, 1,144 certified copies of original maps. 

5 letter books. 

1 l)ook of instructions to deputy surveyors. 

rok of statements, estimates of surveys, and annual reports. 


2 books of invoices. 
2 ledgers. 

;} account books. 
1 record of surveys. 
1 register of contracts. 
4 books of computations. 

242 duplicate contracts with deputy surveyors. 

f correspondence of the Commissioner of the OtOMral Land 
Office and Deputy Surveyors with the Surveyors Goteral, 
and miscellaneous papers. 

"OFFICE Y\ OKK. 

"A circular of instructions to county surveyors was prepared 
and printed in pamphlet form and a copy sent fee each 
county surveyor in the state. In this circular emphasis was 
given to the subject of the restoration of lost and oblit«i 
corners; the evidence of, and how to find government corners 
which are not marked by durable material, witness tea - 
surface indications; how to divide sections into their legal 
subdivisions, especially the fractional north and west tiers 
of sections of the township; for past experience has shown 
that by far the greater number of questions, disputes, and 
complaints referred to this office have grown out of a lack of 
knowledge, or, perhaps, rather a lack of application of tli&lt;&gt; 
law governing the restoration of corners and subdivision of 
sections. And closely associated with these subjects is the 
question of a careful, intelligent and sufficient examination 
to establish the fact of the non-existence of corners, before 
proceeding to restore or reestablish lost or obliterated cor- </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
48 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

"In order to explain certain matters relating to the - 
eminent surveys, it is often Decenary to refer to the correspondence 
of the Commissioner of the General Land Ottce, 
an&lt;l deputy surveyors witli the Surveyor General, and to lender 
this more accessible ilnd convenient it was assorted and 
rearranged. The field notes of the resuivey of thirty nine 
•iships in Grant, Hooker, Cheyenne, and Cherry counties 
¦ filed in manuscript, and consist of 3,760 pagea &lt;¦,{' descriptive 
notes. These have been examined and compared 
with the forty six accompanying mapfl to insure strict con 
fortuity therewith. 

Irhe leather bindings of many of the older volumes of Held 
¦s are greatly damaged by use and deterioration of the 
her. Ten of those most seriously injured have been rend 
in order to preserve their contents and render them 
icealile. Numerous requests for information regarding 
ind surveying have been referred to this department, 
er by mail, wire, or in person. Such requests have reed 
special attention, and all have received answers to 
r iuquiries, excepting one, which, for want of the neces• 
data, has been referred to the proper department at 

"Complaint! have been received by the Commissioner from 
is of school lands in townships resurveyed in Grant, 
kei\ Cheyenne, and Cherry counties, that the ijoverniiient, 
¦\iiis did not survey school sections Li and M from the 
original corners found, but from new corners, and 'surveyed 
out" claims of settlers within the original boundaries of certain 
school sections, thus causing a loss of land to the lessee 
and the state. 

"The matter was referred to this department for information, 
and upon examination of the field notes it was found 
that the snrveyin&lt;; deputies had not been required to survey 
said sections from original corners found. The position was 
taken that inasmuch as the state by t lie enabling act \\ 
donee of the government, of sections ir» and 86 when sur- </seg>


            <seg id="p049">
49 

veyed, and subsequent camgnrnkmtd legislation, departmen 
tal decisions or inst rut-t ions could not deprive it of these 
vested rights, and that the deputy surveyors should have 
turn required by instructions to survey school sections 1 ?» 
and 36 from the original government cornel's when found. 
The facts as ascertained we#e reported to the Commissioner. 
In the matter of supplying applicants with certified copies 
of field notes and maps, this has been attended to as promptly 
as time and the work of the office would permit. It fre 
ipiently occurs that applications for field notes are a&lt; •&lt; -om 
panied by special requests for copies of the 'Sped*! Instruc 
; ions' issued to the contracting deputies, and also the requirements 
of the printed manual governing them in the execution 
of certain surveys. Frequently the reports of special exam 
inations in the field by the inspectors of surveys, the correspondence 
of the deputies, and even that of the Commissioner 
of the General Laud Office must be examined to secure the 
necessary data, all of which requires time and considerable 
research, and it emphasizes the necessity for continued effort 
to place all of the records of the office in the l&gt;est possible eon 
dition. in order to make them not only valuable, but available 
and convenient for ready use. In addition there has 
been the general work of supplying the office force with such 
information as may be required from the maps and field 
notes; also of furnishing drafts of special surveys and allotments 
pertaining to the state lands, and such other duties as 
have been required by the Commissioner. Recently there has 
been commenced, under his instructions, the construction of 
r of maps of the different state institutions to show the 
location, description, when and how acquired, and the exact 
it umber of acres of each tract of land set apart or acquired 
1&gt;\ the state for their use. This work has not yet been com-1 
CU. </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
50 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

"FIELD WORK. 

"Before the law providing for the appointment of a state 

surveyor and draughtsman and prescribing his duties, became 

operative, applications were received by the Commissioner 

requesting the services of the state surveyor to settle con- 

troversies over disputed lines and corners. These were re- 

ferred by him to this department for adjustment and, to- 

gether with complaints received to date are tabulated below, 

giving&gt;«the name of complainant, location, time required, and 

the per diem charged and paid to the Commissioner of Public 

Lands and Buildings, together with other field work required 

by the Commissioner for the benefit of the state. 

tl, M. B. Trussell et al., T. 25 N., R. 26 W., Cherry 
county, 9 days |54 00 

No. 2, County clerk of Wheeler county, 5 days 30 00 

No. 3, County attorney Greeley county, 2 days 12 00 

No. 4, John Reis, Scotia, Greeley county, 1 day 6 00 

f5, Casper H. Meier, lot 3, 16-11-8 W., Merrick 
county, 3 days 18 00 

§6, Theo Seivers, S.E. I S.E. } and lot 8, 16-10-9 
W., Hall county, including examination in March, 

3 days 18 00 

No. 7, August Jeudes, by his attorney, M. H. Weiss, of 
Thayer county, 3 days 18 00 

fS, Geo. Mulligan, North Loup, Valley county, by 
his attorneys, Clement Bros., 6 days 36 00 

No. 9, W. B. Green, North Loup, Valley county, $ day 3 00 

BIO, John Brennick, North Loup, Valley county, 
3 days 18 00 

No. 11, Geo. Mulligan, North Loup, Valley county, 

1 dav 6 00 

No. 12, W. E. Meagley, supt. Santee Indian agency, 
Knox county. 

No. 13, W. If. Parker, Cotesfield, Howard county. </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
SURVEYING. 

51 

"ORDERS RECEIVED FROM THK COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LAM'S 

AND BUILDI 

tl, To survey fract. W. } N.W. 15-7-10 \\\. south of 
M. P. R. R., for Hastings Asylum 4 dftjl 

t2, To run levels for new buildings at Norfolk Asylum 
2. la\s 

t3, To survey foundations for buildings at Norfolk 
Asylum 2 (bn &gt; 

t4, To survey fract. E. | N.W. 15-7-10 W., for Hastings 
Asylum - daj i 

t6, Preliminary examination of road W. \ 16-20-8 
W Sdayi 

HISTORY OF COMPLAINTS AND ORDERS 

Complaint No. 1 was filed by M. 15. Trussell et al. of Ch&lt; 
county, alleging that the county surveyor had ignored Umg 
recognized government cornel's and established new corners, 
causing uncertainty and doubt as to the identity of their 
boundaries. I left Lincoln on the evening of Septembc 
'.. and began to survey September 30, returning to Lincoln 
October 9. During the seven days of work fifteen 
eminent corners were found and perpetrated, out of twenty 
two for which search was made. The principal corner in 
dispute (4, 5, 8, and 9, T. 25 N., R. M W.) was found at the 
foot of a bank or terrace, and near the edge of a swamp. It 
had been covered up for many years by the fallen walls 
sod house, and overgrown with rank grass. There has ' 
no appeal from my findings. 

Complaint No. 2, filed by the county clerk of Wheeler 
county, was for the purpose of settling a dispute between adjacent 
land owners in order to enable the county to locate a 
road on the line between sections 31 and 32, T. 22 N., R. 11 
W. This survey was begun August 13, 1908. It was claimed 
at the time that there was not an authentical government 
corner in the township. The original survey was made in 

r5, To survey fract. N. of B. ft M. K. R. in W. £ 
N.W. 15-7-10 W., for Hastings Asvlum 1 «1m\ </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
52 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

1 and 1872. The surface of the country is rolling and 
sandy. In three days six of the seven corners for which 
search was made were found, some on the slopes of the sand 
hills, and others on Hat ground, or in small basins. All of 
the parties acquiesced in the survey. 

OmpUini No. .1, made by the county attorney of Greeley 
ity, was on account of a dispute growing out of a county 
road located by the county surveyor. This dispute originally 
grew out of the action of a county surveyor establishing the 
corner of sections 15, 10, 21, and 22, T. 18 N., K. 11 W., in 
the bottom of a ravine, several years before. Some of the 
adjacent land owners claimed that the original corner stood 
on the slope of a hill about two rods away. The contro\ 
carried into the district court, appealed to the supreme 
court, tried the second time in district court, and taken under 
advisement, when the trial judge died. The accrued ¦ 
amounted to about $500. The survey was begun August If, 
on my return from Wheeler county, and resulted in finding 
the original corner in dispute on the slope of the hill, about 
40 feet east of the corner located in the ravine by the excounty 
surveyor. The total cost of the examination to the 
county was $."58.50. I returned to Lincoln August 17, and 
have not heard of an appeal being taken from my findings. 

"Complmint No. J/, filed by John Keis of Scotia, (Jn-eley 
county, was a dispute over the location of the original corner 
¦ it ions 21, 22, 27, and 28, T. 18 N., H. 12 W., alleging 
that the county surveyor had ignored the existence of a corner 
which had been long recognized as the original, and had 
established a new corner about three rods west. On November 
12, 1903, I made search for the corner at the place pointed 
out to me as the generally recognized corner. Although the 
ground had been mutilated by road grading and previous 
digging, evidence of a corner was found, but this was not considered 
conclusive as to its original character. However, Mr. 
8, who owned the N.E. \ of section 28, elected to stand on 
his right of adverse, peaceable, and uninterrupted possession </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
53 


by himself ami grantors, for more than twenty years, to establish 
his title without the intervention of further surv« 

I .'om plaint So. .7 was tiled by Casper II. Meier of section 
T. 11, li. S W., Merrick county, alleging t tint la- was 
lessee of lot 3 of said section, and eomplauung t hut tlute 
river had washed away about one-half of said lot, and 
; he ought not to be made to pay for the same. On March 
ind 30, 1904, I surveyed the lot, and, from the data ob 
ed, calculated the area and found it had been mli 
ii 3»&gt;.95 acres to lt&gt;.17 acres, a loss of 20. 7S a&lt; r 

"GompimiHt BTO. (&gt; was lied by Tkeo Seivers, the lessee of 
the S.E. I B.E. •, and lot 8 section Hi, T. 10, B. !&gt; W., Hall 
county, alleging that the IMatte river channels had washed 
away a large tract of land, and that he OVght not to be made 
to pay for the loss. On August 16 and 17. 1964, I subdivided 

KS.E. $ of said section Hi, meandered the banks of the 
mels, and found the area ;&amp;lt;» be t&gt;4.M anvs, a loss of - 
s from the original amount. 

•nnplaint \o. 7, tiled for August Jeudes of Thawr 
county, by his attorney, M. II. Weiss of Hebron, alleging that 
lie was the owner of the S.W. { of section t, T. 1, II. '¦'&gt; W., 
containin&lt;r LB1JM acres, and that his neighbor on the N.W | 
had 141S.S(&gt; acres by government survey, and that, thiouuh 
the action of surveyors and neighbors, he was wrongfully de 
privetl of several acres of his land. On June 30, 1904, I made 
a preliminary examination of the matter in dispute by running 
a random line from'the northwest corner of amid section 
6 south to the Kansas Nebraska line, and found the distance. 
by my chaining, to be 1.72 chains less than six miles. pra&lt; ti 
¦ ally agreeing with II. E. Headley. county surveyor, who prorated 
hi* distance and established the corner of sections 1. ti. 
7. and 12, and the \ section corner between sections 1 and ti. 
by measuring off his calculated distance from the aorta 
coi nir of section t'». The examination showed that the farms 
( f l(»0 acres were each practically 40 chains, or half a mile 
li ng north and south, from the Kansas line, north •" 
to where Mr. Jeudes' fence had formerly been placed. But </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
54 


he had permitted his neighbor on the N.W. \ to move his 
e south to the \ section corner set by the county surveyor. 
The owners of sections 7 and 12 claimed their S.W. and S.E. 
corners, respectively, to be a stone set by a private surveyor 
ut eighteen years ago. The distance from this stone north 
to the corner of sections 1, 6, 7, and 12, established by Mr. 
illey, was about seven rods too short, but the owner of 
W, } of section 7 had claimed his north line to be about 
u rods north of said corner, and had held peaceable possession 
for more than ten years. Mr. Jeudes was ? therefore, 
caught between these two opposing systems of measurement. 
and wrongfully made to lose several acres of valuable land. 
A copy of my field notes and maps were sent to Mr. Jeudes' 
rney, who has the matter under advisement. 

f'omplaiiit Wo. 8, filed for Geo. Mulligan, by his attorn 
lent Bros, of Valley county, alleged that the south side 
east end of the N. £ S.W. }, section 4, T. 17 If., B. 13 W.. 
in dispute, and requested a survey by the state surveyor. 

"The survey was begun July 12, 1904, and found that the 
principal cause of dispute was over the location of the original 
\ section corner on the south line of said section 4. Previous 
to this time, two county surveyors, acting jointly, had 
decided that the original corner was lost or obliterated, and 
reestablished it. The line was examined by the county surveyor's 
successor and the work affirmed. Afterward, a private 
surveyor reviewed the work and established another \ 
corner more than two rods distant from the first Having 
&gt;ured the entire line, and having heard the representations 
of the parties, I concluded that the original corner was 
still in existence, and proceeded to make a thorough examination 
for the same. After one day's search with six men, we 
found it in the middle of the traveled road, more than twenty 
from either of the corners heretofore established, as de- 
Wed. Original corners were found at the N.W. and NJS. 
corners of the section, and the \ section corner on the east 
line. Tl tion corner on the north line having been destroyed 
by a wagon road, was reestablished. This enabled </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
55 

SURVEYING. 

tto subdivide the section into quarters, and the S.v. 
N. \ and S. \, by running a line east and west through 
center as required. I am informed that the disputant* 
i put their fence on the line so established. 

"Complaint No. 9, filed by W. B. Green of North Loup, Val 
ley county, alleged that the county surveyor had, in the surv.v 
of the line between sections 8 and 9, T. 17 V. B. IS W . 
established a section corner between said sections about t \\ &lt;&gt; 
rods west of the original corner, and that he ignored and infused 
to search for the same. At the close of the survey under 
complaint No. 8, on July 16, I proceeded to make an examination 
of the matter in dispute. Mr. Green contends 1 
that there existed an original corner; that he had known it 
for thirty years; that, while yet plainly to be seen, he had 
driven a red cedar stake in the corner. At the place pointed 
out I removed the earth to a depth of about 15 feet loi 
feet wide and 1£ feet deep, and found the original wit 
pits, and midway between was the mark of the original post. 
About one foot northeast was found a red -cedar stake as described 
by Mr. Green. I perpetuated the corner at the j 
indicated by the mark of the post. The adjacent owners acquiesced 
in my decision. 

"Complaint No. 10, filed by John Brennick et al. of North 
Loup, Valley county, alleged that the county surveyor had 
established \ section corners on the four sides of section 9, 
T. 17 N., R. 13 W., and subdivided the section therefrom, and 
that since the original J section corners had been found on 
the north and west lines there was a dispute in regard to the 
J corners on the east and south lines, and requested the I 
surveyor to settle the controversy. I began the survey September 
12, and, after a half day's search, found the original 
\ section corner on the south line, at the edge of a pi" 
field, where it had been plowed over for thirteen years. It 
was more than two rods distant from the corner establiby 
the county surveyor. After a half day's search the 
inal section corner on the east line was found at the 
of a plowed field, where it had been plowed over for twenty- </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
56 


Kr years. The section was then subdivided into quai 
I the N.W. I and S.W. i divided into E. } and W. i, as 
uired. The parties in dispute acquiesced in the surve.\ . 

"Complaint No. 11, filed by Geo. Mulligan of North Lou p. 
Valley county, alleged that the county surveyor, in the sur&lt;&gt;f 
the line between sections 31 and 32, failed to find the 
original corner of sections 5, 6, 31, and 32, of townships 17 
and 18 N., range 13 W., and had established a new corner, 
and requested the state surveyor to settle the dispute. At 
the close of the survey of section 9, under complaint No. 10, 
I proceeded to make a search for said original section corner. 
The point claimed as the location of the corner was under a 
wagon grade about 18 inches high and at the edge of a slough. 
The grade was removed, and at the bottom, which was the 
surface of the original ground, was found the decayed point 
of the original post and the four witness pits to the corner. 
The corner was perpetrated with durable material. This corner 
was eight feet south of the corner established by the 
county surveyor. All of the adjacent owners conceded the 
(&lt;»iner found to be the original corner. 

'out plaint Wo. 12 was recently filed by the superintendent 
of the Santee Indian agency, Knox county, who complained 
of a dispute between the Indians and white settlers on account 
of a conflict of boundary lines, and requested that the 
state surveyor be sent to make a survey. This case is held 
in abeyance awaiting action, looking to a joint survey of pnrernment 
surveyors and this department. 

Eotnplaint No. 13 was recently filed by W. M. Parker of 
ifield, Howard county, requesting a survey of section is. 
! N., R. 11 W., on account of a disagreement with tlie 
ty surveyor. This case is still pending. 

En all of the above surveys, excepting Nos. 5, 6, and 7, the 
notes and maps have been sent to the county surveyors 
e respective counties for record. 

Knhr Xo. 1 was received October 16, 1903, from the Coinoner 
of Public Lands and Buildings, authorising a SOT&gt;f 
the fractional A\ . i N.Y\ ion 15, 1. &lt;, K. 10 </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
57 


t South of the M. P. 1{. II., Adams county, for the purpose 
itabtiaaing the boundary lines and ascertaining the area 
¦eof, preliminary to the purchase of said tract l&gt;y the state 
the use of the asylum at Hastings. Nebraska. The work 
I)erformed October 17-20, 1903. 

1&gt;nl&lt; r .\ o. 2 was received from the Commissioner DtCf ¦ 
38, 1968, to run the preliminary levels at the Norfolk 
, to enable the architect to draw the plans for the four 
buildings to he elected. The work was performed he 
her 29 and 30, 1903. 

t Order No, ¦&gt; was received from the Commissioner IYhru-11, 
1904, to survey the fractional B. 1 N.W. \ section ir&gt;, 
N., IJ. 10 W., Adams county, for the fmTfOWK &lt;&gt;t estabing 
tJie boundary lines and ascertaining the arcii of 
t, preliminary to the purchase thereof by the state for 
use of the asylum at Hastings. The work was \)utwmvi 
ruary 12 and 13, 1904. 

t')rdcr A'o. -) was received from the Coinmissio'iier March 
1904, to survey the lines for the foundations of the four 
bttildillga to lie erected at Norfolk Asylum, according 
lie plans of the architect. The work was performed March 
.nd 18, 1904. 

••O/v/rr No. 5 was received from the Commissioner Jul 
l ( .t04, to survey fractional \Y. \ N.W. ] section IS, T. 7. 
H. 10 W., Adams county, belOBging to Win. Kerr, lyiag south 
M. P. H. 1{. and north of the I?, ft M. H. ]{., for the pvpOK 
of establishing the boundary lines and MC f rtalliiag the 
thereof, preliminary to purchase by the state for the uthe 
asylum at Hastings. The work was performed on Julv 

"Order No. 6* was received from the Commissioner November 
14, l!&gt;04, to make an examination of a county road running 
across the YV. ] section K"&gt;, T. 20, K. 8 W., BOOM 
county; also of the practical)ility of a road along the 
line of said section 16, and to make an approximate estimate 
of the cost of constructing a passable road tor ordinary 
travel. After examination, November 1"&gt;, and report made </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
58 


that the road as traveled followed a ridge through the S.Y\'. 
i and a part of the N.W. J and was a permanent damage to 
the land ; also that the route for a road along the west line of 
the section was practical and could be made passable for 
ordinary travel by the expenditure of $195 for 1,320 yards of 
grading and the construction of two culverts. 

ilt will be seen from the history of the foregoing comints 
that the greater number have been caused by the 
ure of the local surveyors to make a thorough and exstive 
search for the original corners established by the 
ernment surveyors. It seems to have been taken for 
nted by surveyors that the government corners were either 
or obliterated, as investigation into the conditions set 
h in the complaints shows that very little, if any, search 
made by local authorities for original corners. 

It was to correct such indiscriminating and unsafe meththat 
particular stress was given to the subject of 'lost 
obliterated corners and their restoration' in the pamt 
of instructions recently issued from this department, 
i has been taken to distribute these pamphlets among 
owners particularly interested in restoration of origgovernment 
corners, as well as to local surveyors in the 
'. Carelessness or ignorance of this subject is inexcusin 
the surveyor, as it is a source of endless litigation, 
one of the objects of this department to minimize this 

"The original field notes and maps of government surveys 
of the state are on file in this office. Each county should have 
on file at the county seat a copy of the entire field notes of 
said county for general use, and to assist its surveyor in making 
surveys. 

"This department is ready at all times to assist surveyors 
with information or suggestions on all subjects that pertain 
to land surveying, and especially the restoration of lost and 
obliterated corners." </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
59 


BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

E chairman of the Board of Public Lands and Buildii 
ire to report to you, and through you to the legislature. 
e disposition of the several amounts made by appropriaby 
the legislature of 1903 for the various slate iustituaud 
public buildings under control of this Hoard. 

I he legislature of 1003 made an appropriation of fl5,»Hin 
the purchase of additional land for the asylum for chronic 
me at Hastings. After duly advertising for propo 
Board, on October 9, 1903, purchased the E. i S.E. i 
'-10, containing 80 acres, at the price of $3,2."&gt;0, and &lt;&gt;n 
ember 7, 1903, purchased part of the W. | N.W. \ L5-7-10, 
taining 50.51 acres, for $2,454, and on March 20, 1904, 
chased part of the E. i N.W. \ 15-7-10, containing 70.37 
m, for 93,298.59, and on July 25, 1904, purchased part ti 
\V. } N.W. i 15-7-10, at the price of |l,000, making the 
il acreage of land purchased 221. til acres at a price of 
102.59. There was $6 expended for advertising for bids, 
ing $4,991.41 unexpended in this appropriation. 

I in appropriation of f 100,000 was made by the legislature 
I 903 for the erection of new buildings at the Hospital for 
Insane at Norfolk. After advertising for bids, the Board, 
February 20, 1904, awarded contract for the erection and 
rpletion of an administration building and three cottages 
said institution to the Capital City Brick and Tile Co. 
the sum of $96,975, said company having submitted the 
est and best bid. The buildings, at the time this report 
i made, were rapidly nearing completion, and, when finjd, 
will be a credit to the state. 

The legislature of 1903 appropriated $4,000 for the erection 
and completion of a commissary and quartermaster's buildand 
$2,000 for the erection and completion of a laundry 
building at the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home at Grand Island. 
The State Architect was instructs by tlie Hoard to secure 
liids on material, and on July 29, 1904, having secured the 
necessary bids, the State Architect was instructed to &lt; 
and complete said buildings, at a cost not to exceed $5,921.67. </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
60 


I lie legislature of 1903 appropriated |20,000 for the erecof 
a hospital building at the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home 
lilford. After having advertised for bids, the Board, on 
il 7, 1904, awarded the contract for building said hospital 
I. T. Ward &amp; Co., for the sum of 18,090, and afterwards 
le a change in the contract, it being deemed necessary to 
in stone facings up to the water table at a cost of $735. 
t amount was added to the contract price, making a total 
19,425. 

The legislature of 1903 appropriated f 13,500 for the erection, 
completion and equipping of a joint hospital for Soldiers" 
and Sailors" Homes at Milford and Grand Island, and 
$ 13,302.21 of this amount was used for repairs at the Soldiers' 
Home at Milford. 

The legislature of 1903 appropriated $2,500 for the purpose 
of installing an electric lighting plant at the penitentiary. 
After having advertised for bids, the Board, on October 
13, 1903, awarded the contract to the Western Electrical 
Company for the amount of $2,435, and this institution now 
its own lighting plant, which furnishes perfect light for 
the whole establishment at a cost greatly reduced from the 
amounts paid under the old method of renting lights froaa 
the city. There was also appropriated by the legislature of 
1903, $80,000 for the erection of 240 steel cells and sewerage. 
The Board, after having advertised for bids, on May 12, 1903, 
awarded a contract to the Van Dorn Iron W T orks Co. for 156 
(tils for the amount of $69,030, and on March 9, 1904, 
awarded a contract to the same company for 84 cells of the 
same kind, at a cost of $9,982. These cells are now all in 
place and, with the excellent sanitary sewer system installed, 
give ample room for housing the inmates of the institution 
in a comfortable manner, and giving to the state one of the 
and most up-to-date prison services in the country. 
There is a balance unexpended of this appropriation of 

She legislature of 1903 appropriated the sum of $26,000 
the completion of the administration building at the peni- </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
61 

APPROPRIATIONS. 

tentiary, and the sum of $5,000 for furnishing 1 lit* same. I he 
Board advert ised for bids for the completion of the building, 
and on March 10, 1903. awarded the contract to H. T. W 
¦&gt;. for the sum of $23,500. The electric wiring of this 
building and other necessary expenses not under contract to 
linish tlie building exhausted the remainder of the appropria 
tii n. The Hoard advertised for bids for furnishing this building, 
and awarded contracts to several parties, which on 
traits were completed and the building furnished in a mat, 
tasty and substantial manner, with a balance of $30.54 of the 
appropriation unexpended. 

There was appropriated by the same legislature $3,000 for 
building and furnishing a convicts' kitchen at the penitentiary, 
and f 6,000 for repairing the west building. The P. 
authorized the warden to secure contracts for the material, 
which he did, and, under his supervision and that of the Stale 
Architect, the kitchen was built and the west building was 
repaired, some necessary furniture was purchased and installed, 
and there remains a balance unexpended of these 
funds of $1,621.15. The kitchen is built separate and away 
from the main building, and is connected with the com 
dining room by a tunnel, through which the food is conv&gt; 
in ¦ car on tracks. By this means the odor arising from the 
kitchen is kept away from the main building, and there has 
been excellent service for feeding the prisoners instituted. 

The legislature of 1003 appropriated f 2,500 for the erection 
of a cold storage plant at the institution for feeble-minded 
youth at Beatrice. After having advertised for bids for same, 
the Hoard, on April S, 1004, awarded the contract for build- 
Mid plant to Louis Werner for the sum of $2,500. 

There was also appropriated ?l,000 for the building of an 
addition to the kitchen at this institution, and, after having 
advertised for bids for same on March 9, 1904, the &lt; on' 
awarded to ltutherford &amp; Hickman in the sum of ftl 

The legislature of 1903 appropriated $3,000 for the 
of a Public Comfort building at the State Fair Grou </seg>

            <seg id="p062">
62 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Bids were advertised for, and on July 21, 1903, a contract 
awarded to Campbell Bros, for the erection of the same 
for the sum of #2,735, and the building was erected and ready 
for use during the state fair of 1903. 

The legislature of 1903 appropriated $1,885 for improving 
the water plant at the Capitol building, and $1,200 for resetting 
the boilers at the power plant at the same place. After 
having advertised for bids, the Board, on May 20, 1903, 
awarded the contract for these items to Joseph Burns for the 
sum of $2,89."). The work was done, and is a material improvement 
to the water supply of the building. 

There was appropriated at the same time $1,000 for the 
-t ruction of an underground ammunition storage house 
muection with the office of Adjutant General at the Capitol 
building. The State Architect has the plans and specifications 
for same under way, and the building will be pushed 
ompletion as soon as practicable. 

ment steps, to replace the old wooden ones, have been 
tructed at the northwest corner and on the north side and 
on the west side of the Capitol grounds, at an expense, as per 
contract, of $2,536.59, the same being a part of and being 
iv from the $7,000 appropriated for the care and repair of 
the Capitol building and grounds. These steps add greatly 
to the appearance of the grounds and are much better ;ind 
safer than the old ones. 

There was $10,000 appropriated by the legislature of 1903 
for paving Sixteenth street between H and K streets, and H 
•t between Fourteenth and Sixteenth streets, surrounding 
sides of the Capitol grounds and in front of the Governor's 
mansion. This work has been satisfactorily done, 
and the expense was paid in the amount of $7,320.92 on November 
19, 1904. 

The legislature of 1903 appropriated $5,000 for the construction 
of a barn at the Hospital for Insane at Lincoln. 
The superintendent of the institution was authorized by the 
Board to procure bids on material necessary and to use as </seg>

            <seg id="p063">
63 

RECOMMENDATIONS. 

much institution labor as possible in the construction. In 
accordance with his instructions, the superintendent procured 
bids, bought the material, and completed the barn, and 
all of the appropriation was expended. 

(ie members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings 
ng the biennium just closed have given their attention to 
administration of the different state institutions as 
;ly as their other duties would permit. They have urged 
1 the superintendent in charge of the institution to keep 
in the appropriation made by the last legislature, and 
iake no expenditure where not necessary. Each superinent 
has been pleased to cooperate with the Board, and 
reports of these institutions, as given elsewhere in this 
rt, are, indeed, gratifying. 

The large and varied amount of work demanded of a 
of the state officers who composed the Board of Public Lands 
and Buildings, in addition to this supervision of the various 
institutions, is such that it is impossible for them to look 
into the details of the management of each institution as 
much as should be done. It is made the duty of this Board 
to examine into the condition of the buildings and gr&lt; mi in Is. 
the manner of conducting the same, as well as to examine the 
accounts and records of all the institutions, and to report 
quarterly their findings to the Governor. As this can not be 
done directly by the full Board, I would recommend, as in 
my former report, that the coming legislature pass a suitable 
measure, directing that the Board of Public Lands and Buildings 
appoint a state accountant, who shall have power to investigate 
the management and the books and records of the 
several institutions, to act as clerk to the Board of Public 
Lands and Buildings, and the Board of Purchase and Supplies; 
to take an inventory of the supplies on hand in each 
institution quarterly, so that the Board may act more intelligently 
upon the estimates for supplies, and to check up the 
vouchers drawn upon the various funds in payment for the 
supplies furnished these institutions. This would relieve the </seg>

            <seg id="p064">
64 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Ete Board of the* necessity of acting apoa matters that 
e before them that they are unfamiliar with, and would, 
ted, be satisfactory to the Board and th&lt;^ superintendents 
barge of the state institutions, and, in my opinion, would 
lit in a great saving to the state. 

AN IMPORTANT RECOMMENDATION. 

I wish in this report to call the attention of the legislature 
to the fact that in the vaults of the Land Commissioner's ofare 
the books and papers which affect the title of nearly 
three million acres of state lands, the deeds to the various 
state institutions, two and a half million dollars' worth of 
s given by different individuals, made payable to the 
state, for the purchase of lands held under sale contract, the 
school laud abstract books, school land ledgers, in which are 
kept the accounts between the state and her contract holders; 
the records of the various boards, the government plate and 
field notes, and a large amount of invaluable correspondence. 
These are kept in pasteboard boxes ou wooden partitions, or 
upon wooden rollers resting in wooden frames. If the state 
Capitol should burn, I feel that these records would all be 
royed, and, if once destroyed, the loss would be incalculable 
to the state, and it would be impossible to replace them. 
The cost to the state to replace the abstract books and school 
land ledgers would reach into the thousands, and at the same 
time cause the state administration and the people who hold 
B and sale contracts an endless amount of trouble and, 
perhaps, litigation. 

I would, therefore, recommend that the legislature take imiate 
action and have placed within these vaults steel fixtures 
instead of the pasteboard boxes and wooden frames. 
While the cost of samfc will be considerable, the importance 
of the change can be readily seen upon a passing investiga- 

In the vaults of the Secretary of State's office, upon similar 
frames and same kind of boxes, are kept the original laws. </seg>

            <seg id="p065">
RECOMMENDATIONS. 

65 

these should be replaced by steel fixtures, the same as recommended 
for the Land Commissioner's department. 

CONCLUSION. 

i desire at this time to express my appreciation to the 
erintendents and other officers in charge of the various 
itutions of the state for their hearty cooperation, for their 
lifest interest in keeping within the appropriations, for 
r careful expenditure of the state's funds, and for their 
ly courtesies extended to me during the past four years; 
their management of the institutions on a high plane withfriction 
or scandal, and at a cost that is, indeed, gratifyto 
every one who has any knowledge of institutional life. 

twish to express my gratitude to the several state officers 
vidually for their hearty support and courteous treatment 
ing my term of office. I desire to thank them one and all 
their many acts of kindness in the discharge of my official 
lee. 

I would especially desire to express my appreciation of the 
able assistance rendered by my deputy, H. M. Eaton. His 
work has been done in such a thorough and conscientious 
manner it gives assurance that the people of the state made 
no mistake in electing him as Commissioner, and that the 
business of the office will in the future be in good hands. He 
has, indeed, been most faithful and competent. 

I sincerely thank the members of my office force for their 
ilty to me and for the prompt and efficient manner that 
work with which they have been entrusted has been perned. 
With this, I close my four years of service as Comnoner 
of Public Lands and Buildings. The work, in the 
n, has been pleasant, and I have used every effort to cont 
the business of the state in a business manner. I can 
say I am fully satisfied with what I have been able to 
&gt;mplish, but I feel that great progress has been made in 
ing care of the work that comes before this department 
iall with pleasure submit the progress made and the work </seg>

            <seg id="p066">
66 

LAND COMMISSIONER b REPORT. 

done in my department to the kind consideration of the people 
of the state. 

GEOHGE D. FOLLMEK, 

Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>