<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Common Intestinal Roundworm of Swine</title>
               <date value="1922-06">1922-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, JUNE, 1922 CIRCULAR NO. 17 THE COMMON INTESTINAL ROUNDWORM OF SWINE Ascaris lumbricoides ) H. M. MARTIN DEPARTMENT OF ANIMAL PATHOLOGY AND HYGIENE The large intestinal roundworm of pii^s is u very common parasite, ami is probably jut-sent in every bqg raising district of Nebraska. l'j&gt; until the last few years the true nature of this parasite was unknown. Little did we realize the actual harm done liv this worm: l&gt;ut tliru the scientific inveatimtiooi of Stewart. Hansom, and others we now know that this parasite causes heavier |mm to the breeder and feeder of swine than any other now common in Nebraska. I'ntil the recent work by Stewart &lt; 10UM918), it was con -idered an estalilished fact that this worm had a direct life ln-torv: that is. that the eggs were passed in the feces of the host (pig or man), and after they developed to the infectious stage (with a small worm within the shell) were swallowed by a suit - able ho&gt;t ( pig or man ). and upon reaching the intestines emerged from the shell and there developed to maturity. Stewart's work, however, showed that the life history is not so simple as was generally supposed. He made the discovery that if rats and mice aiv fed eggs that have developed to th&lt; infectious stage the egg- will hatch out in the intestines am the larvae will wgntt out of the alimentary tract and trave to the liver and lungs by the blood stream, undergoing consider able development in the meantime. He further observed that the larvae do not remain in the lungs but migrate up the trachea ami can be found in the mouth, and upon this observation suggested that the saliva containing </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nebraska Experiment Station, Clients 17 2 the larvae might probably contaminate food eaten by human beings or pigs and in this way act as an intermedi - ate host. It whs hiter Ob - served l&gt;v Stewart that the larvae pass: up the trachea and down the esophajpw into the intestines. ultimately passing out of the intestine-. in the droppings without undergoing any material changes in size or struct in-.-. Similar experiments con ducted \&gt;y Stewart i&gt;:i [&gt;ig&gt; failed to reveal definite proof that these animals become infected by swallowing A - caris eggs. He therefore of fered the theory that rat - and mice act as iiiterniedi.it.' lio-t- in the life cycle by con - taminating food eaten by human l&gt;eings and pigs with the droppings containing larvae that have passed thru the lungs and back into the intestines. The more recent work of Ransom and his aaweialM does not confirm Stewart": - theory that rats and mice act as intermediate hosts in the life cycle of this parasite. They have shown definitely that this parasite undergoes its complete life cycle within i suitable host, as the pig ami presumably man. Their in - vestigations also show thai the Ascaris larvae migrate thru the lungs in guinea pigs, rabbits, sheep, and gouts as well as rats and mice. Pig. 1 -Ffm.1. Aaearis duaacted. Half natural sis*. I. inUttin. ; U. utanu : 0. OTary- </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Common Intestinal Roixdworm or Swine 3 DESCRIPTION OF THE ADULT WORM The coloring in the fresh condition is reddish-yellow or grayish - yellow; the body is elongated and spindle-shaped. The male measures from 6 to 11.5 inches in length and about Y% of an inch thick: the |&gt;osterior end is conical, bent hooklike. The internal organs consist of ( 1) the male genital organs (the much folded, threadlike structure, the testicle; and the white, elongated, COne - sha|&gt;ed body, the seminal vehicle) and (2) the intestine, which M of a yellowish-brown color due to its contents, extending almost the entire length of the UkIv. The female measures from 8 to lft inches in length, and about Ms of an inch thick: the posterior end is conical and straight. The internal organs of the female COIlsitSt of the reproductive organs (the much folded, threadlike structure, the ovaries; and the Uterus or egg sac. a white structure which divides into two i. ranches that extend thruout the greater part of the posterior two-thirds of the body) and an intestine which is similar to that of the male. tit has been estimated that the reproductive organs of one 11 -grown female worm in the intestine of a hog may produce main as *0.000.000 eggs. DESCRIPTION OF THE EGG OR OVUM The egg is small, oval in shape, with a very thick, transparent &gt;hell and an external albuminous coating which is very irregular in outline. The eggs are 50 to "."&gt; microns long and 40 to 58 microns wide. Abnormal or unfertilized eggs also occur. They are dis - tinguished by their elongated ovid form (80x45 microns). The -hell b very thin and smooth compared with the fertilized ones and their contents consist of a granular mass filling the entire sbrll. Eggs dejMisited by the female in the intestines of the host U« in an early stage of segmentation. Segmentation progresses during the passage of eggs thru the intestines to a certain point, and if the eggs are not promptly eliminated from the intestines of the host segmentation ceases and development of the embryo does not continue. Because of the inhibitory effect of the body temperature, it is necessary that the eggs pass out of the intestines of the host to develop to their infectious stage. Development of eggs outside the animal body is chiefly influenced by temperature, moisture, and oxygen supply. At low temperature, development </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 NEBRASKA Kxpkkimkm Station. Ciri i i.ar 17 i I i i» very slow, mill if low enough it diflcoacintMH entirely. ~&lt; time required for full format loll (if tilt" MBbryO IHilY lie t'li few da\&gt; to month- or even Will-. in A. Martin (1913) found Velopinent of the Asraris epjjs tliiit a considerable number of tun* would contain ftillv ilev &lt;l:iv&gt;. mill tliiit practically all tlie optimum temperature foi to !&gt;.• about ■&gt;■&gt; C. Uan-mii f&lt; Awcaris »'&lt;:«:- k«'|&gt;t :it thi- temi 'loped embryoM at the end of iiiupli-ti- their developatenl tri n'l ti th ii montli. The author ha&gt; foillnl tliiit a (OlMtlci alll' 1 Illlll ejrjr- incubated at room teniperature (-1 ('. i contains developed embnoi iit tin- mhi of fourtwil rttys ami thai all were completed within two motith.s. I 1 Iii Hit' iiliM'iii'i' of iiioistm Fio. t. — Aacmrii ejetn Enlarged 500 times, a ilea.l »t*nle egg : h. ette t dy to invade the pifr. nr freshly from the uterus ; e ripe, infective etrK with larva. development i- ii extreme drynei — in;i\ ilextroy th«" «'^j-'- entirely. The moistiirt' required i- eery little. I'..-- in lftl« found thai A-.mii- ea^ |&gt;liie«&gt;il on gtmtm ~li&lt;le- Mini left eXDOHcd 1&lt;&gt; ll|V — -till ill India till ■X week- contained actively motile ciiilu\ o- Mt i In- end of that time, it i~ certain thai under most climatic conditions there i- -.iitticH'in OMMHture in the -oil or wherever the pgK* biv • I i-&lt; &gt;| • | &gt;•■• 1 wlicn eliinihiitt'il from the !io-i to mahle them to tlevelop mi I.;i-i intermittently and perhaps ntntinuallv. llic c^rjr&gt; will rettisl freezing; Mini may retain their \i;il&gt;ilit\ after u-in^ in ti 1( - mil (Nrbnwki) over winter. Axari- t'jr^r- iin- extn'inely resistant to cheniicalu and are not killed by tin* ordinary disinfectants. Tin' author t' i . 1 that tli&lt;-\- will live in -J per rent formaldehyde (3 part- of !'• |mt rent tormaluehyde gma in water ;i- obtained in commerce and '■&gt;"' j »a rt - &lt;&gt;f watrr) for &gt;i.\ and ;i half ninnth- Mini nrohaltlv Icmirer. The "*•* ■..» ■■■•&lt;• II ■!&lt;• 1 1 '•'■'Illll Illl'l I'iMIF » I'Ml^l'l. 1IH" 6 c </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I iik (iiMMiix Iktmtwal Rot niiwiirm of Bwna 5 Mind egpa t&lt;&gt; live in 1 per cent corrosive sublimate. 1.5 |mt cent itric acid. 1() |mt rent iron sulphate (copperas), (&gt;.."&gt; j&gt;er cent i*:*iitin) |HMiiiiiiijranatt'. Id per cent formalin, and 10 per cent iriatic) acid for ;i con-nleralile tinn AVENUE OF INFECTION I In- &lt;■&lt; minion entrance of infection under natural conditions doiilitcilly liv tin- swallowing of ejrj^s containing fully de - &gt;ed emlnvo-. The |&gt;n— iliility of natural infection in otlltT imiot !»' excluded entirely. Ransom has shown that when i V-cari- &lt;-jr&lt;r- containing fully developed embryos an* inoculated -kin tliev will hatch within a few days and that the later appear in the liinjrs. reaching the same stage of ii — t . . . —^ 1 1 it- 1 1 1 that they would in :i similar time if the e«r&lt;r- wen HATCHING OF ASCABIS EGGS \\ lie A -cans efQgM oontaininf( fully developed etubrVOB are tliev pass thru the stonnich unhatched I altho hatching «1|. till t |Min^ till II lilt 7"&gt;l &gt; 'I I I ll ' I I Hllllill' II' &lt; I I &lt;• I I I I' ' I I •( I &lt; Mill - tomach ninv -onietiines OCCW) illltl |ia» I Ml t(l the Slllall •-. where the\ liejrin to baton within a few hours after r me swallownl. The »'&lt;jr&lt;rshell is not digested l&gt;y tlie di - uice&gt;. hut the emhrvo i&gt; released liv a -|&gt;lit in the I'll which It PDW1JBM liv Its own etTolt-. epjpx max hatch not only in animals wliciv they can tn maturity, hut in almost any mammal that -wallows -urn and Foster have found that a ft'W fJi^S will hatch mix laboratory method- in almost any medium, including - neutral or alkaline media, not only at l&gt;ody tern it lower temperatures. The largt majority, how i -- —^- — j -.._.. — nt hatch out-ide of the animal body, altho the emliryo - wilhill tile eirj.' max remain alive and active. LARVAL STAGE OF THE ROLNDWORM (Ascaris) MIGRATION OF LARVAE IN BODY OF HOST The newly hatched larvae of Ascaris measure about 0.2 to Illl. ill Ifllffth. Ill the liver tliev may reach a len&lt;rth of 0.»i Larvae in the lunp- may &lt;;row to a ienjrtli of 1.0 to 2.4 nun. The larvae, after hatching; in the -mall intestines, burrow ntn the intestinal wall, from then being carried to the liver uc al»o quite ivr-istaiit to the ordinary chemicals. Vosliido :i\'c readied t lit* infective Hta*p. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Xkbraska Kxi-khimknt Station. Pi III f 17 i I I by the portal circulation, when they aiv distrihnted thin tl orjran l&gt;y small bland vessels. Thev may pas- lliru the liv very rapi.llv or may lx&gt; delayed for ■ time. From the liv they u re carried by the hepatic veins into the vena can tl from there into the rijrht heart. The larvae are carried fro tlic right heart to the lun&lt;_'s by the pulmonary art. ■tie-, irhe they remain for a time. In the hill-.'- thev filter tile air Nil Hi and after further development and growth. Veaehin&lt;r a l.iurt 1.0 to -J.4 nun., they pa* OH into the -mall intestines by of the bronchi, trachea, larynx, pharynx, taophagiiM, and Mom Here they heroine fully developed in their proper ho-t (ma ,\ pig). Some larvae evidently do not remain in the lini" a short time. Imt return t&lt;i the hear! by the pulmonai are carried to all parts i»f the body in the jrnieral &lt;-iiv in eircnla linler normal coinlitioii- it "i - it 1 11.1 \ ii- -i||&gt;po-ci| iui&lt;lei&lt;r&lt;» at lea-t two molt-, the tir-t molt M the time orsh.n-tlv afterward-, thr hitler molt appareiitlv liefo reach the stay,, at which thev migrate from the I t intestines The larvae in the InngH may ranch a length of times the length of the newly hatched - ami ran !„. _,.,,,, |, the naked eye if first isolated from lung tissue 1&gt;\ the micro-cop. The body is almost Uniform in diameter thruout; it i- attenuate slightly at the anterior end and gradually from about the Im jrnimnjr of the posterior third of the body backward t&lt;&gt; the regio of the anus, the tail being conical. Ill the living larvii tin- tmfkmgm is .listin.tly \i-il»le. located ■am ma and ("mm have found larvae in the heart, iiinl lung* -,t&gt; early ■» Heventeen hours after feed A few l;ir\;ic ui;i\ 1 1*) li' t-;! fried tn the I'ijrlit the wall- of tin- -mall intestines by the lymphatic without passing thru tlir liver ur (»v penetrating t textinal wall into the ahduaiinal ra'vitv ami from ilif diaphracni into the thurkcic i-avity bimI paininj; tlu- lun*&gt;. However, the tw« routes l:i-i nu-ni i i u h -&lt; I garaed a- cumnMHi path- of migration. DESCRIPTION OF LARVAL siai.K ' lit' ni'wlv liMiclicd l:i!'\;\c mi" Illicroscopk 1 in - JM-twecn (KJ and &lt;&gt;.:', mill, in length. The diameter i i^ lii'iirlv liniforui thntotit: the head and tail arc .-, anterior portion of the body i- rery rlear and free 1 lie intestinal cell* contain nianv small, vellowish-brov </seg>
            <seg id="p007">I'm. Common Ixtkstixai. Rocxdwoui &lt;&gt;k Swwi i :■ ri of the body, structure arising The intestine is a yellowish - at tin- posterior BM of the I i&lt;i the anus, a short distance i i i- -.-.-11 in the tunics of artificially infected pig. Enlarged Mll.KATIM. LARVAE LESION'S c Al SKI) BY larvae can iiMiallv l&gt;e demonstrated without (lifticulty. As a rule the lllllfTs are more OT leas edeinaloiis. In more severe eases there air pmenl nianv hcniorrliajjric patches rajying from pin |M&gt;ints to those of con&gt;iileral&gt;le ~i/.e. «rivin&lt;r the lim&lt;rs a mottled ap|&gt;ear - iinct'. The brOOobi and tmcliea often contain a frothy substance, which i&gt; MOBMtimn Mtained with blood. In the extreme ('«&gt;**"&gt; the l inning l)!i&lt;kwar al organ affected is the lun&lt;r. Ransom and m.l alteration* in the liver. l'lic lt'-i&lt;&gt;n&gt; in l4ie limjrs varv jriviitly in their intt-nsity, uding it | '&lt;&gt;ii ilic -H-vtiitv of the invasion. In mild cas»H, ■ ;nv MmII. bright-red lu'inorrliafric spots in which the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Kxpkkimkxt Station. Cikci lar 17 entire limps nniv be involved, an- •rivatlv swollen, rdenuUou.s, ex - tremely heinorrhajjic. dark reddish-brown to a reddwh-Uack in color, iiinl firm likf liver tissue. In these tMH MM frequent ly finds a blood-stained, frothy discharge from the nasal nnrminfT and the larvae can Im- demonstrated with ea-e from almost anv part of the luiifr*. Tlie symptoms vary irreatlv of larvae migrating at one time small i ii im I &gt;t-r of larvae migrate visible symptoms. In case- where only a very ;ii one time, there mav be no mixed liv the migration of .\M-;iri&gt; lurrae are a iliiiiacifiistic jerky breathing oomiuonh know 11 a- "thumps.*' rapid breathing, roughing, low of appetite, emaciation, usually an elevation of temperature. Thi- max reach KM! I-'. l&gt;ut doe- not commonlv remain at a high level for anv ••re-it length of time a- i- comnionlv -ecu in DOC cholera ami I tlie pneumonias, due to other c:iu-e- -and usually di-a| entirely within four or Hve da vs. Their i- generally a thrifty ■ppea.ranee ami interference with growth survive a severe inrittioiiuf llie lunjr- by A-cari- larvae 1 entirely recover and fail to grow and dVvrlop at a nori mid in this wav cmhf heaw kuMex In addition to t pi«Ts involved acquire an im waiwd susceptibility to inte infections. RELATION OK AGE TO WORM INFESTATION lloffs may U'coine infested at any ■gv. Init th birth up to two week- old i- the most dangerous perio very susceptible up to four month- old. After foui the danger of infestation is relatively -mall. The condition found in pijr- may also apply t is. children are more comnionlv infected with A-cari- t METHOD OF CONTROL The method of control i&gt; tittioil. without question that of Mai The h'r-t euneotial i- to mm- that the piy^s are farrowed under pro|&gt;er conditions. They should Ik* farrowed in a pen that is .-o constructed as to have the floors liuilt of an impervious material (not dirt floors), which will enable one to thorolv i-lean out ill litter and filth by wrapinf the Boon and -ide-. After the litter has all been removed by sorapinjr. the pen- -hould be well SYMPTOMS really, depending upon tin* miiiiiIm'i The mo~t common gynipton Tin- l&lt;&gt;-&gt;('~ h\ dciitli iirt- comparatively Mil </seg>
            <seg id="p009">I in: Common Ixtkstinai. Roindwoum or Swixk 9 d witli -tronjr. hoilinj^. l\c -olution (lye solution can Ik - •(I in mii iron kettle, in or do* bv pen-). The hot water ■-troV t iikI the lye will di-.-olve and help removi - ng iin- not artificially heated, the cleaning 111 rax done in (be fall before freezing, as ii i&gt; practically to properly clean pen&gt; in eold weather. Farrowing pen- should not 1m&gt; occupied bv other pi«r- be- fi anil time of placing; sow in pen to farrow. ■ed in tlie clean pen- I few day- liefore farrow 1 they are well cleaned 1&gt;\ washing with MM] uove all mini and din that i&gt; usually prwen 1'he udder particularly -hoidd lie wa-hed. I an- taken, there is very little danger of ill. i into their mouths from the udder of the mm It ■-injr. Th* dirt on an tine leaned udder mav contain nianv thai the young pigs may get hundred*, thousand*, or fective ejrjr- with the first few mouth f ul- of milk. r farrowing, tlie hows and Hhould not be permitted t mi infected or contaminated soil ( |&gt;ermanciit hotr lot-). &lt; i — - j» - — ■ '- of ten da\&gt; or two week- tlie mw and her litter arc i-ture. Tin- stow can be moved in an ordinary crate. which may lie hike*! up to the door of the jm-ii way by a team of bane*. I'he |&gt;i;r&gt; mav Ik- carried tall box on top of the crate. 'I'he &gt;ow- mav be removed a&gt;tnre after I he weaning of the pi«r* lint the litter -hoiild they are at lea-t four months old. Hie pasture should Ik- one which ha- not DM used con- &gt;jr- lint a Held that baa Keen under cultivation nal rotation of crop- and -own at the DfOpBT me forage crop. Tin- pasture should be free of I'lic drinking water should be clean ami in«r fountains, and the feed given in se!f-feeder&gt;. I'lic colony bouses -hould be M i-onstructed that thev may oved from one pa.-ture to another. l'hi.- sjrste lay be applied to aprinaj or fall litter-, altho - farrowed very early in the sprinjr may have to be kept lilt e famwing pen- for more than two weeks, and late fall may have to he taken off pasture and put in winter (piarter- Ii are more or Ie— contaminated with infectious e&lt;r&lt;r- before pip w hi tin- pijr- are four month- old ink that are constantly naed by kaga should Im&gt; so arranged that the bogs may he changed every year or two to fresh ground. The old yard should Ite plowed under and a crop sown which </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nkhkaska ExrnUMEJtT Station. Ciik i i.ar 17 will permit h Hrm surface to lie reestalili-lied before u-iuir aira for liojrs. II(»&lt;r yards should be located where propel I l.i iti i can l&gt;e secured: Imt where natural drainage iis impossi Mill mud wallows. Ms these me a No a rery prolific mure? of III iulniiiiisteiin^ oil of chenopodiiim. H« administer ins two ounce- of cantor oil and follow i liv one ilnnn of oil of rhenopndiuin (Or swine wei| &lt;lred pound-. Tills dose of oil of I'hellnpodilllll 1 - licient for hirifer animal-, tho the done of mi increased to three or four ounce- for larirer animal ones the dose can lie reduced iii proportion in tmriv castor oil should not Im- les- than one ounce for an\ Iii concludinf. the writer desires to sty that n "or Ascaris is of little use. as it increa-e- the defrree 'oiitaiuination liv epp, in tliis way inflTaiiinjt the da Vscaris pneumonia thru large numbers of migrating larva do the greatest amount of harm, and durinir the peril reatment i^ absolutely useless Hi i . Wlllc 1 Wh, may Ik 1 matted to. The ranfa nhouH b* free from roainx with worm egga ;ll "l "ihrr riiitwmr producin|? f.-ictm (four {rniins of nntonin and two .u i iv r. \ i &gt;i r. &gt; i Tin' practice &lt;&gt;f tivntin&lt;jr Iio-jt~ with various remedies t\ &gt; i - removal of A&gt;«-ari- from tin- intestines i&gt; i vrrv common | «-ediii-e. Tin 1 miit'ilic* im»t ii-rd ui ivmiiimi'inlril »re hirpentiiM*. ■ Illlllll iltlll CmIoIIII'I. illlli Oil l)f l'llCII(&gt;|&gt;IMllll)ll. \\ lien lio&lt;jr~ aiv in he HvHti'il for worms it i- al\\;i\~ I io withhold food from tin-in for twenty- four hours licfnrc ininisterin&lt;r the draff. Turpentini- i&gt; I &gt;i-^t ppvvn in milk. Tin- rvtjttiral a mi tlit* driiL r sbowld he lir-t -jiakcn up with a small ainonm warm milk, after which tin- mixture van be m • l&lt; ]&lt;-&lt; J t&lt;&gt; the n offered to the hofs. The ilosf nf turpentiiH 1 is fnmi nnr-hili one diain for i'Vitv liniiilred pounds of I i v ■■ weight. I !ii~ in inent -lionld lie repeated daily for thrre or four da\- in • oession. Santonin ami i-aloincl. liemy: in powder form, ai'i' le — - aide t" lie pvcn in liquid mixtures. For even htindriMi | of live lio&lt;r we &lt;ri\c ci«jrl it grain* "t' santonin and five i.'iain- calontel. Tlie-c dni^rs are lies! prepared Ip\ I&lt;m-«I ilruiriri ili^jieiised in cnpsiile form in doses -nilalile for lit'tv - 1 &gt;&lt; &gt;u 1 1&lt; 1 | ■ t I" -■i ■ :i i i ni I VI -I -II III l&gt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p011">i&gt;i:m CM Swixi 11 EFERENCES Animal Parasite- of Man 11 ■s I Hit' V in tht* Life History VJIli i of A c u i&gt; iiciin . Vci Am iciiliiu \\ in.&lt; Cii M farm- i- la !«■ mired iilt iiM'ilniin~ tu -wine Hlcil In. i|&gt;!»emenl Kb ';iri*. 1913. Washington Waris Kim-.. Journal of I'a </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>