<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00040">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Studies of Prarie Hay in North Central Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1932-03">1932-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 60 Studies of Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska P. D. KEIM, A. L. FROLIK, AND G. W. BEADLE Department of Agronomy LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MARCH, 1932 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Summary \ Page Introduction .'.'.'""..'."'" ' ** Review of Literature Location, Extent, and Topography of the- Area. : ....."" g Drainage i oils •• T: — i-lIZZZSiZZII o General Plant Life Conditions 10 Base Stations ■ Methods " ■ „ . • 12 Ground-water Level ....:.... Native Vegetation ; Rel^vtefeK^l.°L^ etatiOn t0 tHe DePth °* '^ i"'S»nd - Seeding Tame Legumes and Grasses in the Native Hay Meadows or, Seeding into native meadows ......"....: .jj, Leguminous species .' &#132;_ ' ' Medium red clover (Trifolhim pratense ij.............. ;n Mammoth red clover (Trifolium pratense perenrie L.) S4 Alsike clover (Trifolium hybridum L.) " - i5 Sweet clover (Melilottis alba Desv.) Z1...1." . " 3(5 White clover (Trifolium repens L.) '".""... " 39 Graminaceous species .1 '. ".',' Timothy (Phleum pratense L.) 40 Redtop (Agrostis alba L.) .....IZZZ«ZI!Z 42 Kentucky bluegrass (Poa pratensis L.) ...»....I."!...1"!1"^' 43 Management of native meadows seeded to. cultivated forage plants 45 Effect of the cultivated forage plants on native vegetation 47 Relation of protein content to the structure of the vegetation.;...... 48 Scientific and Accepted Common Names of Species Mentioned 52 Literature Cited 54 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY Studies were carried on during four years, 1926-1929, in the native hay meadows of four counties in north central Nebraska, the import - ant prairie hay producing section of the state. The counties included were Holt, Rock, Brown, and Cherry. A general discussion of the topography, drainage, and soils of the area is presented. The ground-water level lies near the surface in most of the Elkhorn valley region and many of the sandhill valleys. The water level comes nearest to the surface during the months from March to May. Follow - ing this, there is a gradual lowering during the summer. It reaches its lowest level during the period from September to November, after which it rises gradually. It varies within a range of about three feet throughout the year. Rainfall and subirrigation water play an important part in the yields and structure of the native vegetation of different communities. An intricate relatiGnship exists between the depth of the ground-water level and the botanical structure of the native vegetation. Data are presented to show the change in vegetative structure and yield in a number of meadows including numerous stages in succession beginning with the hydric Phalaris-Polygonum (reed canary-grass — smart weed) associes and ending in the xeric Stipa-Bouteloua (needle grass — grama grass) community. The natural plant communities are divided into five general types with respect to production of prairie hay. These are: (1) wet areas, Spartina (slough grass) type; (2) bluestem areas, Andropogon furcatus- Sorghastrum nutans (big bluestem-Indian grass) type; (3) drier areas of the blue stems, Sorgkastrum nutans-Andropogon scoparius (Indian grass-little bluestem) type; (4) transitional areas between the bluestem type and the typical successional vegetation of the sandhills including the Stipa-Bmitelmut, (needle grass-grama grass) climax vegetation; and (5) typical successional vegetation of the sandhills. The botanical structure and yields are given for a number of meadows representing each type. The economic aspects of each of the five plant communities are considered. A number of introduced, cultivated forage plants can be grown suc - cessfully in the native meadows, but only under conditions of subirri - gatibri. The range of adaptability of each species with respect to the depth of the fluctuating water level is discussed. Medium red clover (Trifolmm pratense), mammoth red clover (Trifolium pratense perenne), alsike clover (Trifolium hybridum) , and sweet clover (Melilotiis alba), when seeded into the subirrigated native meadows markedly increased the yields and crude protein content of the hay. The first three are to be recommended as worthy of further dis - tribution, but the last should be used rarely, since it produces hay of undesirable quality during the second year of its growth unless the meadows are harvested unusually early. White clover (Trifolium repens) is not recommended for the native meadows because of its slight beneficial effects on yields and the difficulty experienced by hay producers in mowing it. White clover, because of its stoloniferous habit, may be utilized profitably in subirrigated pastures. Timothy (Ph.leu.rn pratense). and redtop (Agrostis alba) increase yields and are valuable as supplements to the_ introduced leguminous species. These two grasses serve to increase yields where legumes are not desired. Kentucky bluegrass (Poa pratensis) does not affect yields </seg>
            <seg id="p004">nl?ive n ve C g o etet"on 0f *' tHme SS COmpared with thatofX The cultivated clovers brought about a small but sicnificant increase tive growth. Cultivated grasses gave negative results in this respect </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Studies of Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska ' F. D. KEIM. A. L. FROLIK. AND G. W. BEADLE = During five years, 1924-1928, Nebraska ranked first among the states in the production of prairie hay. Approximately 2,500,000 tons were grown annually during this period (Table 1). In acreage utilized, wild hay ranked third among the field erops of Nebraska. As a forage crop in the state, prairie hay ranked first in acreage, but second to alfalfa in produc - tion. • . The purpose of this bulletin is to report studies made of the botanical structure and yields of the native hay meadows during a period of four years, 1926-1929, in the most prom - inent prairie hay producing section of the state. Four coun - ties in. this area, Holt, Rock, Brown, and Cherry, produced 29.1 per cent of the prairie hay crop of the state in 1928. These studies are divided into three parts: first, the rela - tion of the depth of the ground-water level to the botanical structure and yield of vegetation; second, the structure of the more important plant communities contributing to the production of prairie hay; and third, the effects of seeding tame or cultivated legumes and grasses upon the yield and quality of native hay meadows. REVIEW OF LITERATURE Pool (8) briefly summarizes the papers of a number of workers who reported on the vegetation of the sandhills of Nebraska prior to .1914. This paper outlines and discusses in considerable detail the environmental conditions and the structure and classification of the native vegetation Keim and Beadle (7) carried on studies during 1925 and 1926, and Frohk (5) during 1928 and 1929, most of which are incor - porated in this paper. Beadle (1) prepared a key to aid in the identification of the more important graminaceous consti - tuents of the prairie hays of Nebraska by means of their vegetative characters. Brouse (2) has reported on the suc - »n'| T £ eS ? nitS?" Ttfc 1 "^ 1 " I "" 8iblc throush the «o-opcration of the Hay Feed mlt^A^cX^ &amp; SEBMLfr^jffiEE^ UV-'bSA meadows; to James Rooney, former student in the Collece of Agriculture fo? carry - sluartfo f ''T Si* 1927 . : i a J? d tO Wm - KrOtter of the Krotter Lumber c" of btuart for furnishine office and laboratory space • Formerly graduate assistant in the Department of Auronomy, now National Re - fo?n7a '" Beni?tlcB at Californi a Institute of Technoloay at Pasadena. Call- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 1.- -Annual production of prairie hay and other impor- tant field crops in Nebraska, 1924-1928 l Crop Acreage Production Corn I 8,910,400 " 214,381,200 bu. Oats : 2,505,000 68,800,800 bu. Wheat 3,223,200 55,299,800 bu. Barley 277,400 7,646,200 bu. Alfalfa • 1,274,000 3,051,200 T. Wild hay... :. 2,808,200 2,486,800 T. Sugar beets. . 1 74,600 933,800 T. 'Compiled from the United Stales Department ofAgriculture Yearbook. . cessful seeding of medium red," mammoth red, and alsike clovers into the subirrigated native meadows, of the sand - hills. LOCATION, EXTENT, AND TOPOGRAPHY OF THE AREA These studies were confined to Holt, Rock, and Brown counties and that part of Cherry County lying east of the one hundred and first. meridian (Fig. 1). An extensive area of sandhill terrain to the south and west of this area is very similar. The Elkhorn River, with a number of tributaries draining fully 50 per cent of Holt County and the east central section of Rock County, flows through a prairie plain which is. known as one of the leading prairie hay producing districts in the United States. This subirrigated region is approximately 90 miles in length from its headwaters to the point where it -111^'. LJ -^ ■ LEGEND . \ £&amp;2Z1l. mL_ \k I J**r^M(t FitlDiTATXM* COUNTY SCATa 7_ SwjiT*" U"t *£- row * * **'*■ *Q*£&gt;— -471 Ii/iWplI - rewvvfffinM^ A^^rnr. 1 * K S? v*~ aiJf H* js I I ' i — /f«y ffjf e«*«' &gt;. \ Vy rock ~^"^7 &gt;&lt;^Sr:^ Fig. 1. — Map of the four counties under study. The X's in Holt and Cherry counties indicate locations where detailed studies were made. This map was partly reproduced from one prepared by G. E. Condra of the State Conservation and Survey Division. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska leaves Holt County. It has a width of one to two miles in eastern Holt County and of several miles in the western part of the county The five creeks emptying into the Elkhorn River are imbedded in subirrigated valleys which are from ?n ten Th 6 milCS in Width and frOm 15 to 30 ™"S The topography between the creeks in the southern part of Ho t County is notable for its continuity of sandhills, among winch are numerous valleys, frequently subirrigated (Fig 2) mSiT 3111 ," 01 '* 11^^ ? rOm the river i£ * an intermingling of LS-i? aDd , mWaSh pla i" 8 ' a northeastward projection of the sandhills, and an area of high plains along the northern part of the county. A great deal of the land north of the Elkhorn River can be devoted to cultivation. The projection of the sandhills in the northern part of the county s comparable rhir. enVironmental as P ects to the sandhill area south ofthe *t Fig. 2.— General soil areas" of the four counties under study The soil area md.cated as outwash includes both inwash and outwash plains Rock and; Brown counties are for the most part covered If | a ssacSksa ?mS </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Rock, and Holt counties. It flows through a deep, narrow valley, and accordingly furnishes a small acreage of arable valley land. The entire sandhill area, as outlined in Figure 2 and re - ferred to in the preceding paragraphs, is characterized by rolling hills and knolls. The intervening topography varies from small depressions to extensive valleys. These often reach the proportions of one mile in width and three to four in length. Hundreds of these valleys are of sufficient size to permit the free use of haying machinei-y on the largest scale. DRAINAGE Condra (3, 4) discusses the drainage and water resources of the sandhill area. Pool (8) in a study of the vegetation outlines in considerable detail the streams of this area and discusses the sources of water and characteristics of the drainage system. Since the production of hay is confined largely to the Elk - horn valley and the sandhill area of the four previously named counties, the consideration of drainage is restricted to these. As the soil is' sandy over nearly the entire area, most of the rainfall enters the ground as rapidly as it falls. There are, howeveiv small areas of heavier soil. The amount of run - off is very small, and the meager system of surface drainage - ways can carry it away. Even these streams are fed largely by springs and underground drainage. The Elkhorn River, with its five large creeks. Clearwater, Cache, South Fork, Dry, and Holt, drains most of the sand - hill area in Holt County (Fig. 1). The sandhill area north of the river is largely drained by streams flowing into the Niobrara River. Similar areas in Rock and Brown counties have a meager system of streams. The headwaters of the Elkhorn extend into the eastern edge of Rock County. The Calamus River, with a few small tributaries, drains the southern portion of the latter two counties. The Ainsworth Table, in the northern part of Rock and Brown counties, con - sisting of a heavier, less porous soil, naturally accounts for the more numerous streams in that area. These streams flow into the Niobrara River. The streams in Cherry County are more uniformly distributed than those in the other three counties. The North Loup River and Goose Creek drain the southern portion of the county in a southeastward direction I he northern two-thirds of the county is drained by several large streams, namely, the Steer, Gordon, and Schlagle Creeks,- which empty into the Snake River - and finally into the Niobrara River. . : ■ " lk " </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska With a meager system of creeks and rivers in this section of the state, it is evident that of the hundreds of valleys only a limited number are drained by surface drainageways. Accordingly, many of these valleys are drained by an under - ground system. Some of this water finally appears in streams, lakes, and marshes. Much of it, however, remains as underground water for prolonged periods. SOILS The discussion of soils is restricted to the sandhill area and the Elkhorn valley. The ridges of the typical sandhills are composed of dune sand. The soil type invariably changes from a fine, sandy soil to a fine, sandy loam, and only very seldom are such heavier types as silt loam present (Fig. 2). Soils of the Valentine series predominate in the valleys among the sandhills. This series is represented by sand, loamy sand, sandy loam, and fine sandy loam. The sand and loamy sand lie in parallel arrangement to the basins of the larger valleys and cover the entire valleys of smaller propor - tions. The larger valleys are covered with a sandy loam or fine sandy loam to a depth of five to ten inches. There is usually a subsoil of sand. Stratified layers of a clayey sand occasionally lie in the upper two feet of the subsoil. Whenever a valley is poorly drained or, as in some in - stances, contains a lake or a marsh, soils of the Gannett series are often found. These are somewhat mucky and contain a heavy accumulation of organic matter. The adjoining higher topography, subject to overflow, is most frequently repre - sented by the Cass and Sarpy series. These two merge into occasional areas of the O'Neill and Sparta series. The latter four soil series are present only in irregular, scattered areas throughout the sandhill region, while the dune sand, with the Valentine series in stabilized depressions, constitutes the bulk of the soils. The Elkhorn valley proper has a diversity of soil types, as contrasted with the monotonous appearance of the sandhills. The topography of the valley is relatively uniform but occa - sional knolls and even sandhills are sprinkled over the terrain Alluvial plains border the river to its headwaters and to a more limited extent up each of the five creeks. The Valentine series is the most important type of soil lying under (the hay meadows. Valentine sand occupies ex - tensive areas) along the outer borders of the valley as well as along the outer borders of the valleys of the five tributaries The sand frequently merges into heavier-textured soils namely loamy sand, sandy loam, and fine sandy loam, which </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 are also members of the Valentine series. Representatives of the O'Neill and Sparta series occupy some areas on the lower levels where the Valentine series is not usually found. How - ever, extensive areas of the alluvial plains lying between the Elkhorn River and the coarser soils adjacent to the sandhills on the southland between the. river and outwash and inwash plains to the north are of a distinctly heavier texture, fre - quently having the characteristics of a mucky silt loam. The surface soils vary from six inches to three feet in depth and usually cover a sandy subsoil. The subsoil strata occasionally have layers of a heavy soil approaching the clay type lying above the sand, and more often stratified profiles of a clayey sand. Numerous intermittent streams, marshes, and even ponds have heavy subsoils, characterized by a large accumu - lation of organic matter. The Gannett series is the most common in the lake and marsh areas. The Lamoure and Wabash series, accompanied by more effective drainage, occupy scattered areas adjacent to the Gannett. The Cass and Sarpy series are common over the valley and second in importance only to the Valentine. These are largely l-epre - sented by those soils in the textural group between line sandy loam and very fine sandy loam. The Cass and Sarpy series occasionally merge into the Sparta and O'Neill. Members of»other soil series may be found occasionally, in localized areas over the district. Riverwash occurs in a few small areas adjacent to the channel of the Elkhorn River. GENERAL PLANT LIFE CONDITIONS Lying in the open, grassland topography of the Great Plains area, this region is notably conspicuous for its continuity of herbaceous vegetation. The annual precipitation is about 23 inches in eastern Holt County and 18 or 19 inches in Cherry County. Table 2 shows the mean monthly and annual rain - fall at three stations dm-ing 1926-1929. The normal monthly rainfall is included for comparison. The seasons of 1926 and 1928 were below normal in total precipitation, the 1927 season about average, and 1929 decidedly above the average. A new normal for the annual precipitation was adopted at Valentine in 1929. This is 18.34 inches instead of the previous mark of 22.49 inches. Most of the rainfall comes during April, May, June, July, and August. . Even though subirrigation plays an important role in the tonnage of hay produced, as will be shown later, the rainfall materially affects yields. A considerable acreage of the hayland is situated too high to be benefited by the underground-water level. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Table 2. — Mean monthly and annual rainfall in inches at three stations 1 w Deviation K Year Jan. Febr. March April May Juno July August Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Annual from M ' normal O'NEILL, HOLT COUNTY . . &gt; Normal 45 .62 1.31 3.08 3.11 4.15 2.60 2.72 2..10 1.09 .75 .70 22.88 1926 95 T: .67 .1.1 2.71 3.12 2.23 5.82 3.06 .77 1.39 .80 21.98 — .90 S 1927 .10 .34 3.9:1 7.00 2.B8 1.25 2.10 4.66 1.28 .41 .47 .71 24.93 +2.05 -^ 1928 10 ' 1.89 1.13 .02 3.01 2.51 1.74 .94 ■ .87 2.93 1.54 T 16.68 —6.20 1929 65 .86 1.98 3.82 5.80 3.27 3.59 3.01 1.94 3.02 .911 T 31.90 +9.02 Z NEWPORT. HOCK COUNTY § Normal 50 .58 .95 2.04 ' 3.52 4.18 3.90 3.17 2.12 1.67 .59 .66 23.88 S 1926 54 .11 .30 .17 2.30 2.83 2.25 ' 6.52 1.45 1.60 .76 .81 19.64 —4.24 * 1927; 79 .30 2.35 6.05 3.17 2.12 1.23 2.83 .87 .91 .58 .70 21.93 —1.95 1928 .06 .43 1.78 .18 2.32 3.01 2.71 .70 1.64 1.63 1.46 .04 15.96 —7.82 O 1929 51 1.25 2.60 3.68 2.39 4.02 4.40 2.11 4.65 2.63 .94 .15 29.33 +5.45 H . • ... VALENTINE, CHERKY COUNTY Normal .52 .63 1.20 2.32 3.33 3.81 3.40 2.82 1.79 1.32 .73 .62 22.49 £? 1926 1.42 .06 .82 .39 2.37 2.18 2.34 3.05 .77 .89 .90 .45 15.64 — G.85 C, 1927 55 .47 2.59 3.78 4.29 2.97 1.72 1.73 .48 1.73 .59 1.30 22.20 —0.29 ~ 1928 .26 .38 2.00 .55 1.62 3.35 3.76 2.00 .78 1.63 .69 .66 17.68 — 4.81 i-y Normal" 48 .55 1.02 1.85 2.82 2.87 3.01 2.17 1.30 1.10 .56 .61 18.34 .... M 1929 1.13 1.03 2.56 1 2.44 3.08 3.69 5.49 2.60 2.10 3.01 1,17 .41 28.91 +10.57 jg ■Taken from U. S. D. A. Weather Bureau, Summary of the Climatological Data for the United States. &gt; «T "trace. W ■A new normal rainfall average for Valentine was established in 1929. R </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 The mean annual temperature is about 47°. The daily maximum and minimum temperatures have a much more pro - nounced effect on the welfare of the vegetation than the annual temperature. There are wide fluctuations from cool nights to the frequently hot days of the summer months. The sparsely covered sandy soils of the hills respond readily to these daily extremes. These wide fluctuations are much smaller in the heavier, more moist soils of the valleys which are covered with a dense growth of mesic vegetation. BASE STATIONS The towns of Stuart and Valentine served as base stations. Stuart, in Holt County, is located in the heart of the Elkhorn valley prairie hay district (Fig. 1). During certain years more wild hay has been exported from this point than from any other town in the state. Extensive studies were carried on here and extended also to Atkinson, Emmett, Inman and Chambers. The town of Valentine provided a suitable station from which to pursue studies in typical sandhills. The de - tailed work was carried on within a radius of about thirty miles to the southeast and to the southwest. In addition, general field observations were made in numerous localities throughout the four counties. METHODS The quadrat method, used extensively by plant ecologists, was found to be the most satisfactory method of conducting the studies. The clipped quadrat proved to be comparable to actual haying operations. Each quadrat was one square meter, a standard size used by ecologists for herbaceous vejre - tation. A series of either five or ten quadrats was considered rep - resentative of a section of either a native community or one mixed with cultivated plants. In taking yields on adjacent seeded and untreated areas, the quadrats were paired bv being placed within three feet of each other so that variations in vegetation and soil were reduced to a minimum. The vegetation was clipped with a pair of sheep shears at a height as nearly comparable as possible to that of a mower. It was noted, however, that the tendency was to clip somewhat closer to the ground than is customary in haying operations. This close clipping became a necessity under cer - tain conditions when a botanical study was made of the native vegetation. Certain plant parts such as the collar and ligule °l the leaves, which are frequently necessary in identification of. individual species, were often so close to the ground that close clipping was necessary. It is also apparent that nearlv </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska 100 per cent of the vegetation is recovered by hand clipping, while a considerable percentage is lost by ordinary commercial methods. The weight of the vegetation was determined on a moisture-free basis and the yields in nearly all instances cal - culated to a 15 per cent moisture basis. Determinations of the depth to the ground-water and the identification of soil types were made by boring with either a 11,4- or 4-inch auger near the quadrats. The 4-inch auger was the more satisfactory where the permanent water holes were opened, while the smaller auger worked very well for boring temporary holes and for a study of soil types. The crude protein content was used as a rough index to measure the feeding value of the vegetation. The limitations of this criterion should be noted; nevertheless, it serves a useful purpose in a study of this nature. Nitrogen determ - inations were made by the Kjeldahl method. The percent - age of nitrogen multiplied by 6.25 gave the percentage of crude protein in the hay. . GROUND-WATER LEVEL The depth of the water level has a profound effect upon the structure and yield of vegetation of hundreds of acres of land in this section. Because of the porosity of the sandhill soil and the high ground to the west, the rainwater accu - mulates and forms a ground-water table. It often covers some of the lower valleys, with the result that lakes and marshes are formed. Figure 1 shows the numerous bodies of water throughout the area. Among the larger units are hun - di-eds of smaller lakes, ponds, and marshes, too numerous to be located on a map of the scale used. That the water table was near the surface of the ground in hundreds of other valleys, was verified by visits to a large number of localities. The tall prairie grasses, rarely to be found in this section of the state except where the ground- water level is close to the sur - face, afforded a reliable indicator. Many borings supported the fact also. The depth of the water table fluctuates from season to season and from year to year, depending largely upon the amount of rainfall, evaporation, source of water supply and drainage. The volume of water in the lakes and marshes fluctuates accordingly. Condra (3, 4) states that there are fluctuations in the size and depth of the lakes during wet and dry years. He concludes, also, that many bodies of water are intermittent in character because of the rise and fall of the water table, so that the number of ponds varies from year to year. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Permanent water holes were made in a number of meadows in the Elkhorn valley in order to note the seasonal fluctua - tions of the ground-water level over a period of one to three years. TABLE 3. — Depth of ground-water level during three years, 1927-1929, at a number of field stations located in the Elkhorn valley, differing in respect to dominant type of vegetation ' ■__ Station 1, Stuart Station 2, Stuart Station 3, Stuart Station 4,. Stuart Spartina Spartina Spartina michauxiana Andropoeon michauxiana michauxiana Andropogon furcatus furcatua Hole No. 1 ' Hole No. 1 Holes No. 1, No. 2 Hole No. 1 Dale | Inches Date \ Inches Dale \ Inches Dale | Inches 1927 ■7/7 34 | 7/ 6 . 36 1 7/ 9 33 1 44 7,21 38 8/10 36 8/10 42 ' 8/10 40 ' 46 8/10 41 8/19 29 I 8/19 31 8/19 31 42 8/19 35 10/21 26 10/21 . 27 | 10/21 28 ! 31 10/21 28 1928 ' 6/ 5 24 6/5 16 • 6/5 20 26 6/ 6 24 6/28 13 6/28 12 6/28 13 • 22 7/9 23 7/ 9 15 7/9 26 42 7/9 32 8/7 34 8/ 7 . 38 8/ 7 35 42 8/10 32 9/14 19 9/14 32 9/14 33 35 9,14 3G •■ 11/24 8 11/23 ■ 6 16 11,25 19 . ' 1929 - 4/19 0 4/19 0 4/19 0 4 4/16 3 7/ 3 26 7/3 16 7/ 3 21 29 6,27 " 28 .. 7/8 13 7/19 2 7/19 4 7/20 11 21 7721 18 8/3 18 8/3 22 8/3' 24 31 8/3 27 9/13 18 9/13 12 9/13 17 21 9,'13 £0 : | , . ; Station 5, Stuart Station 6, Stuart Station 7, Inman j S ition 8, Emmett Andropogon furcatus Andropogon furcatus Andropogon furcatus Sorghastrum nutana Sorghastrum nutans Andropogon scoparius Andropogon scoparius Holes No. 1, No. 2 Holes No. 1 , No. 2 Holes No. 1, No. 2 i Holes No. 1. No. 2 Date I Inches Date | Inches Dale \ Inches | Date \ Inches 1927 6/28 23 37 6/27 29 33 6/15 40 30 I 6&gt;25 44 44 7/11 26 40 .... 7/23 47 41 7^25 52 54 8/19 27 41 8/» .21 34 %',\\ tl 28 S/17 48 §0 10/21 23 30 10/20 14 26 10/20 42 36 10/20 50 54 . 1928 6/6 19 23 6/ 6 1 21 24 6/5 39 37 I 6/ 5 46 I 42 6/23 17 25 6/28 20 25 6/14 37 35 1/4 i? 40 7/9 . 30 M ■•■ 7/1 ° ** ■.:** |/ J 32 42 8/7 32 34 8/8 43 4i 8/i6 63 57 ,V,&amp; 22 3 k 9/W 3I 32 9/M 41 4 -» 9 /l 4 6 3 B9 11/23 27 29 11/25 17 25 11/23 46 32 11/23 51 63 1929 p i i si i £ si I i w " ? 8/ 3 35 35 .... 8/13 42 42 8/13 35 31 ...; '.[ '.'. 8/14 6i 65 9/13 29 42 9/13 19 26 9/13 45 38 9/13 43 41 'McaaurDments given in inches from surface of ground to water level. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska The results are presented in Table 3. In some instances readings were taken in only one hole (No. 1), while in other cases they were made in two holes located close together It u i -■ L T noted that in s °me meadows, Station 3 for example holes No. 1 and 2 represent areas varying in depth to the ground-water level. Accordingly Spartina miehauxkma (slough grass) dominates in the vicinity of hole No 1 while Avdropogon furcatus (big bluestem) dominates that of hole ..f A transition occurs in the relative percentage com - position of the two species between the two water holes ,_ From an analysis of Table 3, and from general observa - tions, the following conclusions are drawn. The water level SET Voir St - tO S? s^face during the months of March to May. Following this, there is a gradual lowering during the summer. The transpiration of the vegetation is a flctor n the recession of the water. The water reaches its lowest level during the period from September to November after which it rises gradually. If the summer has been dry there will be no appreciable rise until October or November; con - versely if considerable rain has fallen during the summer TZ^fvt ah \\r n - heein , t0 rise in August "or September.' The rapidity of the rise and recession is governed accordingly The water table fluctuates about three feet throughout the Within this annual rise and fall are temporary fluctuations a direct result of local rainstorms. For example on Julv ?q' 1929, at Station 1. (Table 3) the water levels witWntwo inches of the surface following a three-inch rain on Ju?y 13 Readings taken prior to and after this date, July 3 and August 3, respectively, show the water level at one and one - half to two feet in depth. A number of days were necessarv for an adjustment of the water level necessary Stations 1 and 2 (Table 3) represent a considerable acreage of valley land producing largely midland hay, with a dom inant growth of the tall prairie grasses. Stations 4, 5, and 6 represent a considerably larger acreage of valley topog - raphy producing over 50 per cent of the total tonnage of prairie hay of this region. Meadows of this type Tvllucl the most desirable hay. Hay land with a water table at thl depth indicated for Station 3 is not uncommon and invariably furnishes the connecting link between the two types of veS at T^STiiT^-fl^ 1^- T, he ve * etati ™ at sSch statins as 7 and 8 is modified to a smaller degree by the ground-water level because of the greater depth of the latter. An extensive acreage of hay land has the ground water at such depths Is </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 those at Stations 7 and 8. Areas of this description lie be - tween the land ideal for hay production and the xeric, roll - ing topography of .the hills and knolls. NATIVE VEGETATION According to Shantz and Zon (9), this region lies on the western edge of the tall grass (prairie grassland) area. The climax vegetation of the area should be a mixture of tall and short grasses, generally recognized by the plant ecologist as the Stipa-Bouteloua (needle grass-grama grass) association. Because of the limited rainfall and the relatively high evap - oration ratio the habitat cannot support a closed cover of tall grasses. The latter are sufficiently thinned so that the shading effect may not entirely eliminate short grasses, which therefore occupy restricted areas among the more mesic taller ones. Contrary to the usual intermingling of tall and short grasses, which is typical of the climax vegetation, only relics of this association are found. Two factors have had a pro - found effect upon the vegetation and have altered it beyond recognition from what the climate would designate. One is the unusually favorable conditions in the valleys, brought about by subirrigation. The subirrigated meadows of the Elkhorn valley are a westward extension of the subclimax, tall-grass prairie of eastern Nebraska. The vegetation of many of the subirrigated valleys of the sandhills is compa'r - able in its botanical composition to that of the Elkhorn valley. A second factor, unfavorable in its reactions upon climax plant communities, is the coarse texture of the soil. This causes rapid percolation of the rainwater with the result that much of the moisture moves rapidly below the feeding zone of the roots. This manifests itself in the type of vegetation capable of meeting the rigors of a soil with a low moisture equivalent. Furthermore, these soils are subjected to fre - quent periods of high winds. Therefore plant species char - acteristic of developmental communities constitute the plant cover and the climax has not been attained. As described by Pool (8) , a number of developmental com - munities occur, representing in various degrees the extent to which any particular area of land has been stabilized and made favorable for plant growth. The discussion of the native vegetation is divided into two phases: (1) a study of the relationship between the struc - ture of the native vegetation and the depth of the ground - water level and (2) a study of the structure of a number of typical hay meadows, representing the more important plant communities contributing to the production of prairie hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska RELATION OF STRUCTURE OF VEGETATION TO THE DEPTH OF THE GROUND-WATER LEVEL In order to discover the importance of the ground- water relations in determining the structure and yield of the vege - tation of the native hay meadows, a series of quadrats were clipped in a number of meadows in which there was a typical gradation from the wet areas with a high water table to high ground with a low water table. Differences in the depth to the water table are often accom - panied by differences in soil texture. Invariably there exists a gradation from the heavier soils of the valleys to the coarse - textured soils of the hills. The valleys support a more lux - uriant cover of vegetation than the uplands with the result that organic matter has accumulated in much larger quan - tities than in the higher habitat. Subirrigation water, then, is the primary factor which causes the differences in the cover of vegetation, but the varying degrees of textural and organic matter content of the soil also have some influence. A study showing the correlation between the yield and composition of the vegetation and the depth of the ground - water level is presented in Tables 4 to 10, inclusive. The com - parative yields per acre and the relative percentage of each Table 4. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent moisture) of a native meadow and the relative yields of component species in relation to depth of ground-water level three miles west and five miles north of Chambers, July 1U, 1926 Depth to ground-water level (inches) Botanical species" 44.0 47.0 52.5 slTo 62.5 tj. , . .. P' c &lt;- P- d. P. Ct. P. Ct. P.ct Phalans arundinacea 47.5 1.0 Spartina michauxiana 4.3 4.5 Triglochin maritima 6.4 8^1 """" Polygonum muhlenbergii .... 7.7 0.4 Calamagrostis neglecta 34 '5 " " Equisetumjspp 13 . 7 j^g " gg ; 54 Agrostis alba 23.0 215 Panicum virgatum .... 6.5 15 Sorghastrurn nutans ' .... " " 14J7 jj'y ~A2 Petalostemum purpureum .... .... . . . . " 4*6 Andropogon furcatus ' " g'g fa's Andropogon scoparius " n'a Vo Sedges and rushes 33.0 81*7 2o!6 3o!8 Miscellaneous grasses. 0.5 .... 15.7 8.6 9 3 Miscellaneous forbs" 0.6 6.1 3.2 2 1 4 6 Total yield (pounds) .... 3259.4 2383.1 2469.2 2045.6~ 1411.5 1 For a list of common names see page 52. ■ * 1 Forbs are all native species other than Brasses, seders, and rushes. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Table 5. Stmcture and yield per acre (15 per cent moisture) of a native meadow and the rela - tive yields of component species in relation to depth of ground-water level three miles south of Stuart, July 20, 1926 . 2 ■ Depth to ground-water level (inches) . g Botanical species w 24.0 27.8 28.5 36.5 38.3 44.3 68.0 80.0 84.8 90.3 W P. el. P.cl. P.ct. P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P. el. P.ct. P. el. P. el. Polygonum muhlenbergii 14.6 8.2 4.8 22.3 •*. Phalaris arundinacea 76.2 .... 1.4 .... — y Alopecurus geniculatus 0.6 ■ • • .• Melilotus alba 6.5 .... .... 1.0 ..;.. 1.1 .... • ; g&gt;. Spartina michauxiana.. , 20.9 46.8 4.2 \ .. j, Hordeum jubatum •• 0.2 .... ■ . Phleum pratense -..- *■■" '•&amp; &amp;•* '■•'■ ••■■ td Calamagrostis neglecta .. . 0.8 W Andropogon furcatus — °- L &lt;J-° i°-^ •■•■ ■•■■ •■ w Sorghastriim nutans ;... ..... ! 5 -V °-° 3 -' — ■ — •■ g Taraxacum taraxacum •.••• 6.1 .... Equisetumspp '. , .... 0.5 1.0 1.1 1.0 g Elymus canadensis .... .... 10.6 O.b .... .... Andropogon scoparius .... ...... ■••■ 10-o »4.l 48.7 21.3 .... CO Panicum virgatum : • • • — | -. — "•! 0.5 .... .... c Bouteloua oligostachya and B. hirsuta : .... •■•• •■ 30.6 87.8 r Stipa spartea and S. comata . . • ■•■- •■■:•• ••■ 26.6 6.3 W Artemisia gnaphalodes ....: •• — "•" •■■• -. Sedges and rushes 2.0 89.6 73.6 1.6 2.0 0.6 0.2 6.2 6.7 2.7 .Z Miscellaneous grasses ,,.....! .... 0.6 .... 5.4 0.2 .49.1 2.1 37.2. 4.7 2.2 Miscellaneous forbs ....... j M 0.7 10^ ,;■■■/ ■ 3.7 0.7 . 3.7. 2.9 .... o ~Total yield (pounds) 1 4644.7 s 5348.7 [5467.4 5230.1 J2253.2 1997.7 1681.1 1083.1 1406.1 1480.8 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">. Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska of the more important native grasses, forbs, 1 and cultiva - ted species, whenever present, are given. The miscellaneous grasses and forbs are included under the two headings, respectively. The sedges and rushes are grouped under one heading. Table 6. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent moisture) of a native meadow and the relative yields of component species in relation to depth of ground-water level, Valen - tine Substation, July 30, 1926 Depth to ground-water level (inches) Botanical species ; 47.2 55.1 65.7 66J9 67.7 . j , Pcl - P-et. P.ct. P.d. P.ct. Andropogon furcatus.-. 59.6 62.4 38.5 35 5 Sorghastrum nutans 11.8 7.2 12 6 16 9 Panicum virgatum 1.1 0 7 0 7 0*3 3 6 Agropyronspp 0.5 1.3 l".7 o!2 08 Equisetumspp 0.9 .... 1.2 10 3 0 Andropogon scoparius. .■ 2 4 34 8 219 7*4 Elymus canadensis l'_2 Stipa comata ... oo'o Bouteloua spp ' ' jjfi R Calamovilfa longifolia ' Jg Koeleria cristata ?'| Sedges and rushes ig.4 i6i ' 2A 5.5 ' 6 7 Misce aneous grasses 2.8 6.2 4.7 17.6 53 Miscellaneous forbs . . ' 4.0 3.6 2.2 1.0 11 Total yield (pounds) 3806.1 2695.0 1689.2 ~ 1812.5 1528.7 The structure of the vegetation is 'closely correlated with the depth to the water table in any given area and period of time. In a meadow of the type presented in Table 6 with the water level at 47.2 inches on July 30, the Andropogon furcatus-Sorghastrum nutans (big bluestem-Indian grass) type of vegetation predominated. In the same meadow, where the water level Was approximately 20 inches farther down, the more xeric species, such as the Stipas (needle grasses) and Boutelouas (grama grasses) were controlling The bluestem meadow yielded 3,806.1 pounds of hay, while the drier habitat yielded only 1,528.7 pounds, 2,277.4 pounds less. ' . A more detailed illustration may be found in Table 5 In a habitat with the water table at 24 inches, Phalaris arund - macea (reed canary-grass) dominated with an appreciable quantity of Polygonum muhlenbergii (perennial smartweed) In situations where the vegetation was 90.3 inches above the ground-water level, Bouteloua oligostachya (blue grama) and 1 Forbs arc all native species other than Brasses, sedges, and rushes. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Table 7. Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent moisture) of a native meadow and the rela - tive yields of component species in relation to depth of grounds-water level five miles north - east of Simeon, August_j^l926 ■ Depth to ground-water level (inches) g" . ■ Above ?8 Botanical species 27 0 30.0 33.0 33.0 36.0 36.0 42.0 51.0 57.0 60 g P. d. P. d. P. d. P. ct. P. d. P. d. P. tt. P. d. P. d. P. d. &gt; Polygonum muhlenbergii 12.6 1.9 41.3 1.8 4.8 0.6 M Phalaris arundinacea : 0-3 0.3 19.1 ... .... •*&lt; Stachys palustris . . . . 0.5 4.6 1.1 3.5 5.0 .... .... y Srartina michauxiana 2.3 .... .... l.o .. ... dlamagrostisneglecta.. • •• 48.0 10.0 .... 5.7 10.6 W Hordeum jubatum ■■•• 1»-| \-\ ••■• &gt; Mentha canadensis }•* *•" „"„ ■•„■. ■•-•± :•; Agrostisalba.... 1-2 ™ 31.8 72.4 5.7 1.1 W Agrostis hyemalis «... &lt;&gt;••» : M Trifoliumpratense... ■,■•• ' •••■ °- d ••■■ •••• •••• •■■• a Andropogonfurcatus ,. •• 2.6 40.5 30.7 .... Panicum spp. other than P. virgatum ■•■. • J -' 2 «•* •••• z&lt;a ■••• o Agropyron tenerum ■•• £•« • f* ■■: ••• W Sorghastrum nutans ■■ • • • ■ • ■ ■• ■ l °-° l °-* • wx Equisetumspp.... ........ ..... 3.7 7.8 1.5 6.6 W Panicum virgatum .■■ ••■■ 3 - 4 0.3 2.1 9.3 C Elymus canadensis •■ ■■ «•« -x y.;. r; Andropogon scoparius : - 3 - 0 b7 -° 1^-° S Koeleria.cristata ■ ■•• ■•• °-J %i % Calamovilfa longifolia ■■•■ • ••• °- 9 9 °^ Z Bouteloua hirsuta :??•? at Andropogon hallii — '•• i'i ° Total yield (pounds) 1 6082.5 3513.5 1 4378.1 3021.4 3858.4 2394.6 2835.8 2124.0 1438.8 986.7 ; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska " ■ Table 8. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent moisture) of a native meadoio and the relative yields of component species in relation to depth of ground-water level three ■ __rnues_west of Simeon, August 2, 1926, •!■ ' ' ' ' ' ['. ■ . ;:•■ ' '■'. ■ ' ~ Depth to ground-water level (inches) Bptanical species 36.0 40.0 48.0 52.0 Above 60 Polygonum muhlenbergii .... "8.3 ° \ ° ' ' Ct ' P ' cL Stachys palustris 1.8 . ] " Mentha canadensis 2.1 '■■'". Spartina michauxiana. ... . 36 0 44 Equisetumspp. :.;...... 0 .3 17.V | iile h'.O "H Calamagrostis neglecta .... 22 I 1 2 Andropogon furcatus .... io!o 52^ iiiio 60 Sorghastrum nutans ■. . . 26 9 111 29 8 Panicum virgaturn lo'.o 0.3 \&amp; "ii Glycyrrhiza lepidota 27 Andropogon scoparius '"' "' oi'v ' o Vh Koeleriacristata.: K'.V H s? Eragrostis trichodes i' 7 %'i Bouteloua hirsuta 2'J Stipa" comata . .'. ■ %'n Calamovilfa longifolia • o"o Sedges and rushes 47.5 22.3 i2.8 i2 0 72 Misce aneous grasses 2.0 1.8 0.3 2 7 04 Miscellaneous forbs 1.9 5.0 | 4.5 4.6 2L2 Total yield (pounds) .... 5030.7 2178.3 2631.8 1674.8 1417.8 Table 9. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent mois - ture) of a native meadow and the relative yields of com - ponent speces in. relation to depth of ground-water level Jwo and one-half miles south of Stuart, Jtdy 15, 1927 Botanical .pocies 25.0 25.5 30.0 39.0 jlG.O 60.0 60.0 80.0 Polygonum muhlonborglt . . . ?#&amp; **&amp; ■ "' PcU P ~ Ct ' P ' «• Phalaris arundinacoa 5.9 .... . " " * ' ' * ' "" * ■ * ' • Hordeum jubatum " 6[5 " " " ' " * * " " " Phleum pratense vht'k qir kh'/i ' e'o '-no "" MolilotuSalba I" fgj 31 ; 8 *f* §| »» ■■•■ Andropogon furcatua 114 tit iJ; ,„ J'2 Sorghastmm nutans ■ aoi ,i'a i}"n Elymus canadensia ../. "//' ■■ f2"| ™-% "-0 Agropyron tenerum " **" ; q g Sporobolus cryptandrus . ', ii'o " "•" AWi Koclcria crisUta "" ki 3 ?-? i,^ 25i: Panicum virgatum ..' ] °- 8 i'S 2 " 7 "•» Andropogon scoparius " T% i"i •••• Boutelona oligosUchya and ....... ... 4.u b3.3 4.T B. hirsuta Stipa spartea and S. comata ...... """" t Sir? Sedges and rushes 14.3 4.9 17 j s.i 16.9 ibi "" 25 Miscellaneous grasses in o K ,c 1« «« MUceUaneoua forbs 2.4 3.5 Y." I* H $ H H Total yield (pounds). .. 3521.9 3872^ 12623.4 19S7.9 1712.5 1767^ 1939.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 10. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent mois - ture) of a native meadow, and the relative yields of com - ponent species in relation to depth of ground-ioater level two and one-half milse south of Stuart, June 21, 1028 n . , Depth to ground-water level (inches) Botanical species f 1 : 7.0 7.0 18.0 '20.0 28.0 32.0 | 47.0 62.0 . /'• &lt;■!■ /'■ &lt;■&gt;• P. rl. P. &lt;■/. /'. ct. /». rl. I /'. rl. I'. rl. Dasystephana spp 1 1.3 • 34.3 .! Polygonum muhlenbergii . . . B.3 33.8 10.1 Phalaris arundinacea 50.8 24.9 Alopccurus geniculatus 10.2 1.1 * 1.6 Phleum pratense I.I 50.5 28!i 10.7 6.2 1.8 Stacnys palustris I 0.9 .... Spartma michauxiana . . .... 12.6 1.7 .... . . .]' Equiselum spp .... 1,1 .... . . * * ' ' ' ' Hordeum jubatum .... 2.7 4.3 .... ! Andropogon furcatus : 2.0 27.1 109 | ii 3J Melilotus alba • .... .... 0.7 3 jj • 37.9 23.6 13*8 '.'." Sorghastrum nutans : . 6.4 7.5 3.9 6 3 Poapratensis 5.8 9.7 18.0 3o!s -Spornbolua cryptandrus 1 1.4 3.7 8.1 1.2 20.1 Elyraus canadensia .... I .... 3.2 6.9 0.5 Koeleria cristata. . . . .' j .-. ; . .... 4.1 1.6 ' 0*3 [ i's Panicum virgatum .... | .... ./..' . o.S OH ' Andropogon acoparius I 1.8 30.3 8.2 £tipasparteaandS. comata .... .... I ...-. .... .... ;ji;j Bouteloua oligostachya and B. hirsuta .... I . ( • 79 Serigcs and rushes 19.1 .5.9 I 15 J 10.9 ]i'.7 i 20.9 i :u 18.il Miscellaneous grasses '.... . 02 01 01 18 Miscellaneous forbs I .... | 3.9 11:0 0.5 ] 5.0 8".6 4I2 Total yield (pounds). .. i 4067.3 1 2479.7 13470.4 i 1776.6. 1728.5 I 1254,'J 1557.1 648^4 Bouteloua hirsuta (black grama) occupied the soil to a nearly complete exclusion of other species.- Detailed studies of 8 areas (Table 5) between these two extremes show a complete transition from the Plwlaris (reed canary rgrass) type of vegetation, through the Spartina (slough grass) area, the Andropogon (bluestem) zones, namely, Andropogon furcatus (big bluestem) and Andropogon scoparius (little bluestem) and finally the Stipa (needle grass) and Bouteloua (grama grass) communities. The yield of vegetation gradually varied from 4,644.7 to 1,480.8 pounds per acre. One needs only to analyze the seven tables to see the direct relationship between water level and the corresponding changes in. structure and yield of the vegetation. Since the depth of the water table fluctuates throughout the season, a direct comparison can scarcely be made between the data of the various tables, but the close relationship is easily noted. STRUCTURE OF THE MORE IMPORTANT PLANT COMMUNITIES CONTRIBUTING TO THE PRODUCTION OF PRAIRIE HAY The composition and yield of the native vegetation varies greatly in both the sandhills and the heavier soils of the Elkhorn valley. These differences are nearly as pronounced </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska in the plant communities harvested for hay, as in those of the entire region. Hay producers and feeders are necessarily concerned with the types of native meadows. The type affects very materially both quality and yield. This variation in botanical composi - tion has been recognized in a commercial classification of prairie hay, as presented in the Handbook of Official Hay Standards, pages 15 to 18 (6). A study was made of the more important plant communities in order to determine what common native species are contributing to the prairie hay crop. These communities are classified under five general types, although other less important communities, including intermediate types, occur. Meadows producing the type of vegetation included in Table 11 are classified as Midland Prairie, according to the U. S. Official Hay Standards. Meadows of the types present - ed in Tables 12 to 15, inclusive, are termed Upland Prairie. The latter class provides for a wide inclusion of species. Meadows producing midland hay (Table 11) are scattered as irregular areas, varying in size from a few square feet to tracts of many acres. These communities are found in valleys and in depressions along streams, ponds, marshes, and other bodies of water. The midland areas frequently occur in Table 11. — Structure and yield per acre' (15 per cent mois - ture) of two Spartina michauxUma (slough grass) mead - ows ' ■ Meadow number and . date of harvest Botanical species 1 2 July 9, Aug. 10, 1928 1929 P. el. P. d. Spartina michauxiana 5.5 20.9 Phalaris arundinacea 13.1 1.9 Calamagrostis canadensis .... 21.5 Calamagrostis neglecta .... 13.1 Puccinellia airoides 32.0 0.5 Phleum pratense 18.6 1.9 Poa pratensis .... 10.3 Hordeum jubatum 0.5 0.3 Alopecurus geniculatus 0.3 Agropyron tenerum I. 0.1 Sedges and rushes. ! . 19.7 17.5 Forbs 10.2 12.1 Total yield (pounds) 4581.5 3307.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 TABLE 12. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent mois - ture) of a number of Andropogon furcatus (big bluestem) meadows ■ ,■'■■-, ■'■'■'. ■ Meadow number and date of harvest Botanical species 1 2 3 4 July 1, July 6, June 15, June 23, 1926 1926 1927 1927 P. ct. P.-ct. P. ct. P. ct. Andropogon furcatus 41.6 17.9 15.2 29.2 Sorghastrum nutans 2.0 41.6 8.8 9.5 Andropogon scoparius .... .... 6.6 .... Panicum virgatum 2.1 2.0 .... Other Panicum spp .... .... 2.7 ..... Spartina michauxiana 4.9 0.9 .... 5.3 Koeleria cristate 3.2 .... Elymus canadensis 0.1 0.6 .... Sporobolus spp '. 4.0 .... Agropyron smithii • 2.5 .... .... .... Phleum pratense 5.0 6.4 14.5 16.9 Poapratensis 0.3 15.0 2.3 Trifolium spp 1.9 3.6 Sedges and rushes 10.8 13.2 11.6 19.1 Miscellaneous grasses 2.9 6.5 5.2 6.9 Forbs ; 27.8 5.0 17.3 13. Total yield (pounds) 1008.2 2087.0 1471.3 1744.0 5 6 7 ' 8 Botanical species June28, Junel5, June29, June30, 1927 1928 1928 1928 P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Andropogon furcatus 45.7 20.0 16.5 40.5 Sorghastrum nutans 0.2 4.4 4.3 0.1 Andropogon scoparius .... 13.2 .... Panicum virgatum 2.8 0.5 1.0 Other Panicum spp. .... Spartina michauxiana 3.4 4.0 2.2 Koeleria cristata 1.2 Elymus canadensis Sporobolus spp .• 1.0 .... .... .... Agropyron smithii .... . . . .' .... .... Phleum pratense 9.3 7.6 ! 18.3 9.2 Poa pratensis. ; 0.7 13.4 2.1 6.6 Trifolium spp. .. 21.1 Sedges and rushes 15.1 4.8 16.7 17.3 Miscellaneous grasses 4.3 13.2 8:5 8.8 Forbs .-... 17.5 21.4 8.4 14.3 Total yield (pounds) 1592.9 . 1346.8 1920.2 942.3 bluestem meadows. Such communities are a result of a water table at or near the surface of the ground for a period of a year. This may recede to a depth of two to four feet during its lowest ebb. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Praikie Hay in North Central Nebraska TABLE 13. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent mois~ ture) of two meadows, characterizing the drier habitats of the Andropogon furcatus (big bluestem) meadows ■ Meadow number and date of harvest 1 2 Botanical species June 24, June 27, 1927 1928 P. ct. P. ct. Sorghastrum nutans 19.0 20.5 Andropogon scoparius 16.2 20.2 Andropogon furcatus 2.1 5.6 Poa pratensis'. . : 39.6 32.7 Agrostis alba j 3.8 4.0 Melilotus alba ■ 5.7 Phleum pratense 0.3 Sedges and rushes 4.4 0.9 Miscellaneous grasses 5.0 2.8 Forbs , 9.6 7.6 Total yield (pounds) J 1420.7 1065.0 Spartina michauxiana (slough grass), the most important midland grass, together with the sedges and rushes, makes up a large percentage of this type of hay. Phalaris arundinacea (reed canary-grass) and Calamagrostis spp. (bluejoint) also add materially, with other species contributing in much smaller quantities except in occasional meadows. In meadow No. 1 of Table 11, Puccinella airoides (slender meadow-grass) made up 32.0 per cent of the total vegetation, which is un - usually high under average conditions.! Other species of grasses frequently contributing to the strictly midland meadow, although often not classified as such, are Panicum virgatum (switch grass), Alopecurus genicvlatus (meadow foxtail), Hordeum jubatum (wild barley), and the tame species, Phleum pratense (timothy) , and Poa pratensis (Ken - tucky bluegrass). The sedges and rushes composed 19.7 per cent of the vegetation in meadow No. 1 and 17.5 per cent in meadow No. 2 (Table 11). Native forbs made up 10.2 per cent arid 12.1 per cent of Nos. 1 and 2, respectively. Most of the native hay is recognized as upland prairie, according to the federal standards. Ai great deal of this hay comes from meadows of the bluestem type. The blue - stem grasses, Andropogon furcatus and Sorghastrum nutans, are the most important grasses (Table 12). Andropogon scoparius (little bluestem) often predominates in the drier situation of the bluestem meadows (Table 13) . Other grasses frequently present but not as important as the bluestems, </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 are Panicum spp. (switch grasses), Agropyron spp. (wheat grasses), Spartina michauxiana (slough grass), Ely m us canadensis (wild rye), Sporobolus spp. (dropseed grasses), and other grasses of minor importance. The sedges and rushes (Table 12) made up from 4.8 per cent of the vegeta - tion in meadow No. 6 to 19.1 per cent in meadow No. 4, while in the drier situations (Table 13), this group of plants made up 4.4 per cent and 0.9 per cent, in the two meadows, respectively. The forbs constituted 27.8 per cent as a maxi - mum in meadow No. 1 and 5.0 per cent as a minimum in meadow No. 2 (Table 12). In the drier habitats these per - centages were 9.6 and 7.6 respectively (Table 13). The types of communities discussed thus far have developed under conditions where subirrigation played an important part. In addition there are those communities which are in no way affected by the ground-water level because of its great depth. These meadows may be recognized as two groups: (1) those characterizing the typical sandhill top - ography and (2) the intermediate types between the bluestem meadows and the sandhill terrain. The intermediate meadow types are usually either an advanced successional stage of the hydrosere of the valleys or xerosere of the sandhills. In other instances these are stabilized communities under the prevailing climatic conditions of the heavier soils of some 6T the uplands. The intermediate meadow types have been referred to as the Stipa-Bouteloua ( needle • grass-grama grass) meadows, since these two generally include the dominant grasses (Table 14). These meadows could appropriately be referred to as the climax vegetation of this region. Other grasses often grow - ing with Stipa spartea (porcupine grass), S. comata (needle grass), Bouteloua oligostachya (blue grama), and B. hirsuta (black grama) are Andropogon scoparius (little bluestem), A. hallii (sandhill bluestem), Koeleria cristata (June grass), Calamovilfa longifolia (sand reed-grass) Sorghastrum nutans (Indian grass), Sporobolus spp. (dropseed grasses), and Panicum spp. (switch grasses). The sedges and rushes con - stituted from 2.3 per cent of the vegetation in meadow No. 7 to 9.7 per cent in meadow No. 2 (Table 14). The forbs con - stituted from 9.3 per cent of the vegetation in meadow No. 1 to 37.6 per cent, in meadow No. 6. The bunch grass meadow type, often referred to by the hay producers, was included under the intermediate meadow type. Meadow No. 3 (Table 14) containing 28.5 per cent Andro - pogon scoparius (little bluestem), may well serve as an illus - tration of the bunch grass community. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Prairie Hay in North Central i Nebraska Table 14. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent mois - ture) of a number of Stipa-Bouteloua (needle grass — grama grass) meadows Meadow number and date of •' harvest Botanical species 1 • 2 1 3 4 July 2, July 28, Aug. 3, Junel6, 1926 1926 1926 1927 P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Stipaspp.: .: . 20.4 11.8 2.3 18.8 Bouteloua spp 30.2 33.9 12.8 1.2 Andropogon scoparius . .' 10.2 j 28.5 27.6 Koeleria cristata . 6.8 4.6 5.2 1.8 Caiamovilfa longifolia 2.9 3.4 14.3 Andropogon hallii 3.3 13.7 2.0 3.0 Sorghastrum nutans 0.9 2.8 Panicum spp • 2.1 .... 0.8 Sporobolus spp. ..... 3.5 4.4 .... Sedges and rushes 8.2 9.7 8.4 3.4 Miscellaneous grasses. . . : . 5.6 6.5 22.3 Forbs. 9.3 1 19.3 15.7 18.4 Total yield (pounds) 1325.3 1183.7 1232.7 959.0 ~~~ ~5 i (5 7~ Botanical species June 16, June 16, July 10, 1927 1928 1928 P. ct. | P. ct. P. ct. Stipaspp 31.2 14.4 33.6 Bouteloua spp 12.6 2.3 15.8 Andropogon scoparius 18.8 19.1 13.4 Koeleria cristata 6.2 2.4 2.3 Calamovilfa longifolia. ....:.... 2.5 .... 3.7 Andropogon hallii 0.6 j 2.1 Sorghastrum nutans .... 1.3 .... Panicum spp .' 0.8 14.1 1.2 Sporobolus spp .- " .... .... 2.3 Sedges and Tushes '. 3.2 3.9 2.3 Miscellaneous grasses. 13.2 2.7 4.9 Forbs 11.0 37.6 20.4 Total yield (pounds) . 1236.1J 697.7 452.1 ■Air dry basis calculated to 15 per cent moisture. A considerable acreage belonging to the intermediate type is cut for hay each year. Because of low yields (a quarter to a half ton) and the high percentage of forbs, an undesirable constituent in hay, these plant communities form the marg - inal hay land. In years of high prices | or heavy rainfall, a larger acreage of such land will be cut for hay than in years of low prices and unfavorable growing conditions. Even though a considerable acreage is cut each year, this type of </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 hay does not comprise a very large percentage of the total hay crop because of the low yields. The last meadow type is the vegetation of the typical sand - hills. This is discussed primarily because such areas exist and not because of their importance. It is seldom harvested. The more important species are Calamovilfa longifolia (sand reed-grass), Bouteloua spp. (grama grasses), Stipa spp. (needle grasses), Sporobolus t spp. (dropseed grasses), Andro - pogon scoparius (little bluestem), A. hallii (sandhill blue - stem), Panicum spp. (switch grasses), Koeleria cristata (June grass), Sorghastrum nutans (Indian grass), Festuca ovina (sheep fescue), Redfieldia flexuosa (Redfield's-grass), Muhlenbergia pungens (blow-out grass), and other minor grasses. The vegetation of thi-ee meadows of this type is analyzed in Table 15. The sedges and rushes composed from 1.4 per cent in meadow No.. 3 to 14.3 per cent in meadow No. 1. The percentage of forbs runs high, as indicated by the range f rom 28.2 in meadow No. 1 to 31.3 in meadow No. 2. The sedges and rushes are an impoi'tant constituent of prairie hay. They reach their greatest prominence in the TABLE 15. — Structure and yield per acre (15 per cent mois - ture) of a number of meadows characterized by vegeta - tions of the sandhill succession types Meadow number and date of harvest Botanical species 1 2 • 3 Aug. 2, \ July 16, Aug. 9, 1926 1928 1929 P. el. P. cl. P. ct. Calamovilfa longifolia , 15.6 37.3 48.8 Bouteloua spp 25.3 4.6 1.3 Stipa spp 3.4 4.8 7:1 Sporobolus spp. 4.2 3.4 2.7 Andropogon scoparius. :.:.... 1.4 ' 2.8 1.9 Anriropogon hallii . . '....-. . 5.5 0.1 1.4 Panicum virgatum : 0.8 3.4 2.7 Other Panicum spp .' 0.8 .... 0.4 Koeleria cristata 0.5 1.0 Muhlenbergia pungens .... .... l.j' Redfieldia flexuosa ■ .... 0.4 Sorghastrum nutans 0.3 Festuca ovina .... . . o.l Sedges and rushes i 14.3 3.4 1.4 Miscellaneous grasses 0.2 7.6 Forbs : 28.2 31.3 30.9 Total yield (pounds) 1214.3 916.3 1391.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska midland meadow. and gradually decrease as drier situations are encountered. Approximately 18 per cent of the vege - tation in the midland meadows was of the sedge-rush group (Table 11). This percentage was reduced to approximately 6 in the upland vegetation of the drier habitats of the sand - hills and other higher ground. The prominence of the native forbs, on the other hand, works in the opposite direction. It must be considered that individual meadows and areas of the same type vary widely in their relative percentage of forbs. This may be illustrated in Table 12 where the forb content varies from 5.0 per cent in meadow No. 2 to 27.8 per cent in meadow No. 1. Thus a trend of differences may be noted in the forb content of the various meadow types. In a general way, the midland mead - ows contain approximately 10 per cent as the one extreme to 30 per cent in the sandhill vegetation as the other extreme. The bluestem meadows, making up a large percentage of the prairie hay producing acreage, are considered by the hay producers as the most favorable when both yields and quality are desired. A subirrigated Andropogon furcatus (big blue - stem) meadow producing a good growth of bluestem grasses and a comparatively small percentage, 5 or less, of forbs is an excellent hay meadow. Although numerous meadows of such description may be found, many bluestem meadows are either inherently low yielding or contain a heavy growth of forbs. The midland meadow, nearly always yielding a good tonnage of hay, produces a product which is commonly coarse and not as palatable to livestock as bluestem hay. The time of cutting affects materially the quality of this type of hay and such meadows should be harvested sufficiently early to prevent a heavy growth of stemmy hay. The dry land and sandhills yield small quantities of hay per acre. Yields of one-fourth to one-half ton per acre make it difficult for a hay producer to realize any profit on his in - vestment. Furthermore, upland hay of this kind usually con - tains sufficient foreign material to grade either as No 3 or sample grade, according to the Hay Standards, and conse - quently sells decidedly lower than good prairie hay. SEEDING TAME LEGUMES AND GRASSES IN THE NATIVE HAY MEADOWS The possibility of seeding a greater acreage of the native hay meadows to one or more of a number of cultivated leg - umes and grasses suggests itself as a practice worthy of further study when the beneficial effects of earlier local seed- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 ings by the hay producers are noted. Many acres of sub - irrigated native hay land have been seeded to one or more of these cultivated species. There are thousands of acres in native grassland which could be profitably seeded. Studies were conducted during a period of four years, 1926-1929, to obtain data on a number of cultivated forage plants and their effect on the yield and quality of these native meadows. The legumes employed were medium red clover (Trifolium pra - tense), mammoth red clover (Trifolium pratense perenne) , alsike clover (Trifolium hybridum) , white clover (Trifolium repens), and sweet clover (Melilotus alba). The grasses were timothy (Phleum pratense), redtop (Agrostis alba), and Kentucky bluegrass (Poa pratensis). Bluegrass and, more especially, white clover have been seeded only to a very limited extent artificially but are nevertheless present in many meadows because of their prolific methods of propagation, namely, by seeds and vegetative organs. Other forage plants such as the brome and orchard grasses have been seeded but to a very limited extent. The phases under study were (1) the distribution and abundance of each of the species, (2) the effect on yield of the native hay meadows by seeding the cultivated species, (3) the adaptation of each species with respect to environmental conditions, especially moisture relations, (4) the effect of the cultivated species on the native vegetation, and (5) the re - lation of the structure of the vegetation to the quantity of crude protein as influenced by the introduction of the culti - vated forage plants. SEEDING INTO NATIVE MEADOWS The term "seeding," as used in the following discussion, includes any practice ranging from broadcasting the seed on the meadows with no previous seed bed preparation to the other extreme of drilling the seed on land in which the sod has been plowed and pulverized. Since much of the soil is sandy, care must be exercised in not destroying the vegetative cover too completely or the soil will blow to such an extent that the seedlings will not become established. A great deal of the hay land is subject to such precarious conditions. Some of the land, however, is of a decidedly heavier texture and pro - vides a much better seedbed for the cultivated plants during the period of early establishment if the sod is partially de - stroyed through disking, plowing, or other tillage practices. Under such treatment, a sufficient amount of native vegeta - tion remains to protect the soil against severe blowing and rapid desiccation. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">'. f. Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska A second factor is expense. Some hay producers cultivate very little of their land and, consequently, have a limited amount of tillage machinery. A minimum amount of capital in machinery and labor must be expendedj on a crop such as prairie hay, wh|ch usually furnishes a low| return per acre. Another advantage of leaving the native sod in a fair con - dition is that if the seeded crop fails to establish itself, the land in the following season will produce a crop of prairie hay instead of weeds, as would be the lease if the native grasses were largely or entirely destroyed: Those cultivated species which may he considered worthy of further distribution are under average conditions capable of producing some seed, as well as a crop of hay, provided the vegetation is not harvested too early. Milch of the seed is scattered over the meadows during haying operations and aids materially in reseeding and perpetuating the stand. In those years when seed production is low or a failure, or the seedlings fail to become established, sufficient native vege - tation remains to insure a crop of hay. LEGUMINOUS SPECIES The five cultivated clovers under study, since they are mem - bers of the legume family, have two commonly recognized characteristics which deserve mention. Other factors being equal, legumes from a feeding standpoint are much more desirable than grasses because of their higher percentage of protein. Legumes also prove beneficial because of the nitro - gen which they add to the soil. Medium Red Clover. — Medium red clover is grown the most extensively of the cultivated forage plants. Red clover and timothy were among the first forage crops seeded in this section by the pioneers. Approximately 50 per cent of the meadows of the Elkhorn valley, where the! ground- water level does not exceed four feet at its maximum depth, contain red clover. The clover varies from a small | percentage in some fields to. over 50 per cent in others. The jdistribution of red clover in the sandhills is not nearly so general, although many fields were noted in certain valleys. A summary of four years' data shows that when red clover constituted 51.7 per cent of the hay by weight, the meadows yielded 706.9 pounds or 34.7 per cent more hay than adjacent meadows that were only 11.9 per cent clover (Table 16). The results reported for 1927 indicate a loss of 10.4 per cent as due to the presence of clover. These yield's were taken in a meadow containing largely clover of first year growth. Even though the yield was decreased somewhat, j the increased feed - ing value compensated for a small loss in total yield. During </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 16. — Effect on yield of the invasion of medium red , clover in native meadotvs — 1926-1929 Clover content Yield per acre by weight (15% moisture) Year Date Heavily Slightly Heavily Slightly Increase harvested invaded Invaded invaded invaded due to clover area area area area ■ - Percent Percent Pounds Pound* Pound* Percent 1926 6/29 66.-I 22.6 2787 A 1818.6 968.7 53.3 7/ 6 54.9 1.3 2741.1 1664.4 1076.7 64.7 Average 60.7 12.0 2764.2 1741.5 1022.7 59.0' 1927 7/14 26.5 6.5 2437.8 2722.1 -284.3 -10.4 1928 7/ 6 58.9 26.2 3596.4 2567.9 1028.5 40.1 1929 7/ 4 65.7 1.7 2038.0 976.0 1062.0 108.8 7/29 75.8 fr.l 2942.6 1211.1 1731.5 143.0 8/ 1 40.3 1.7 1532.1 J 143.9 388.2 33.9 Average 60.6 2.8 2170.9 1110.3 1060.6 95.5 1 4-year average £1.7 11.9 2742.3 2035.5 706.9 34.7' 1 Percentase based on average of yields. its second year medium red clover brings about marked in-, creases in yield. Red clover can produce two crops of hay in one season under the environmental conditions of the subirrigated valleys. It is the only desirable tame forage crop plant which can be thus utilized. An illustration of what may be expected when two crops are harvested during one season is given in Table 17. The second crop contains a higher percentage of clover and, consequently, is more in demand, particularly by dairymen. The second growth may be utilized for hay or be permitted to seed. This crop usually seeds prolifically and serves as a good means of thickening the stand. A very limited acreage is utilized for the production of two crops in one season. This is due largely to the fact that most of the hay land does not contain sufficient clover to sacrifice Table 17. — Yield of tioo cuttings in one season of two native meadmds supporting a heavy growth of medium red clover — 1929 _____ Clover content Yield per acre Date of cutting by weight (16% moisture) Meadow ■ ■ — — — • — ' — — : — *- number First Second First Second Total First Second cutting cutting cutting cutting Per cent Per cent Pounds Pounds Pounds 1 6/26 8/8 415 59.6 2373.9 1146.4 3520.3' 2 6/27 8/7 38.2 70.4 3081.2 1763.9 4845.1 Average 39.7 65.0 2727.6 1455.2 4182.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">..- Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska the yield of the native vegetation, which is essentially what happens when the meadows are harvested early in the seas - on. However, the practice is worthy of encouragement, par - ticularly jn the Elkhorn valley, provided a field contains a good stand of clover and is cut sufficiently early to permit a second crop of clover to seed. Medium red clover can be grown only in those meadows in which subirrigation is important. The upper margin of the successful establishment of red clover in relation to the depth of the water table is given in Table 18. The upper clover margin was determined under conditions where the clover had seeded and established itself j under natural con - ditions. The water level at these stations would reach a maximum depth of 40 to 45 inches, which is usual during the months of August and September. Red clover can be grown only in those meadows where the ground-water level does not reach a greater maximum depth than four or five feet. Another means which may serve as an! index of success in establishing a cultivated forage plant is the structure of the native vegetation. Generally speaking, any subirrigated meadow supporting a closed cover of Andropogon furcatus Table 18. — Maximum depths to ground-water in native mead - mvs at which medium red clover was successfully estab - lished 1 . ■ Readings Station Date •! : 1 2 3 J4 5 Av. Inches Inches Inches Inches Inches Inches . 1 7/17 32 34 33 [30 32 32 2 7/17 33 24 40 36 27 32 3 7/25 38 32 32 33 36 34 4 7/25 32 33 31 33 33 32 'Five readings distributed over a distance of one-half mile were taken at each station. (big bluestem) and Sorghastrum nutans [(Indian grass) may be successfully seeded to medium red clover. The midland meadows dominated by Spartina michauxiana (slough grass) and species of similar habitat requirements often have the water table at or above the surface of the ground for a pro - longed period during the winter and spring months. Such a condition is usually fatal to the clover. ! Occasionally under more moderate conditions, the clover will thrive well.' Areas of land supporting a mixture of the bluestems and midland grasses usually provide ideal conditions for clover. When the vegetative coyer contains such component species as Andro - pogon scoparius (little bluestem), Stipa spp. (needle grasses), </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Koeleria cristata (June grass), and other plants of the drier habitats, successful seeding of red clover is impossible. Even though the clover may germinate and grow in these habitats, it would not, under average conditions, be able to survive the summer drouth, where subirrigation water is not available. Medium red clover should be a popular forage plant among the hay producers and livestock feeders. Its ability to thrive in meadows with a deeper ground-water level than alsike, its capacity under average conditions to outyield alsike and white clovers, and its higher feeding value and palatability as compared with sweet clover make it the most desirable of all legumes. Mammoth Red Clover. — Mammoth red clover resembles medium red, and is hardly distinguishable from the latter by the farmer. A few hay producers have seeded it in prefer - ence to medium red because of its higher yielding qualities and its longer life, but its distribution is limited to scattered local seedings. Table 19. — Effect on yield of the invasion of mammoth red clover in native meadoivs — 1928-1929 Clover content Yield per acre by weight (165? moisture) Year harvested Heavily Slightly Heavily I Slightly ~ due'lTdm-* invaded invaded invaded invaded area area area ) area i&lt;w&gt;r -,-&gt;i P "»Z" P'reenl p,m«,h Pouml. | Pound* . p t r cent 1928 'J2* - r &gt;2-2 5.1 2557.4 1728.1 • 82!).O 18.0 1929 Vlk\ 44 - 2 ■'•&gt; 2 137.6 i J538.5 I 599.1 i 38.9 VZl 48 ' 8 *■* 2280.1 ■ 1559.4 I 721.0 ! 48.2 \l™ "••? °-5 39S4-6 HKl.fi , 2828 0 848.0 V%k SS-I l A 4760 -' 1710 - (i 3048.fi ! 178 :r 7/30 77.2 2.9 3097.9 1192.1 1905 8 1S9 9 Average 61.1 2.0 3252.1 1432.1 iSlSE? \ I27.S 2-year average 56.7 . 3.6 2904.8 i 1580.4 !■ 1324.4 : RfTsi l Percentage based on average of yields. A two-year summary shows the extent to which a good stand of mammoth red clover can increase the yields of native meadows (Table 19). Meadows with clover to the average extent of 56.7 per cent outyielded adjacent areas with 3.6 per cent clover 1,324.4 pounds, or 83.8 per cent. Large increases in yield may be expected with mammoth red clover under favorable conditions. Mammoth red and medium red were seeded in adjacent plats in a subirrigated meadow in 1927. Good stands were obtained. When harvested on July 26, 1929, the mammoth plats yielded 3,432 pounds of hay, as compared with 2,766 pounds for the medium red plats, or 24.1 per cent in favor of the mammoth clover. Its greater yield was due largely to </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska . ' . ■ - . ■ ■■.-.. ■• ••• ■ its greater height. Mammoth clover had an average height of 30 inches, while medium red had an average height of only 20. The first crop of medium red had matured seed and the second growth Tiad reached a heightj of 10 inches among the Oid plants when the first crop of mammoth red was just nearing maturity. Mammoth red can be grown on any sub - irrigated meadow that will support a good growth of medium red. Mammoth red, under average conditions, will outyield medium red when only one crop of hay j is harvested during the season, but the latter has an advantage over the former when two crops are cut. Although most of the meadows are not harvested until the cultivated plants have matured seed, mammoth red is less likely to have matured seed than medium red. This is especially true in those jmeadows which are mowed early because of a high percentage of clover. The question of the cultivated forage plants maturing seed at least every two or three years is pertinent for the continuity of a good stand in the native meadows. Under comparable con - ditions, mammoth red grows taller and more stemmy than medium red. Seed of the former is more difficult to obtain and retails at a higher price. When only one crop is harvested during the season and cutting is delayed sufficiently during some years to mature seed, mammoth is slightly superior to medium red because of its higher yields and its longer life. Alsike Clover. — Alsike clover grows in small quantities throughout many meadows, but it is much more limited in distribution than red clover. Recognizeid as well adapted to poorly drained, wet soils, alsike has been seeded largely in areas of that nature. It is usually found in those meadows which are subjected to low, wet conditions for prolonged periods during .the spring and early summer months. During the course of haying operations, the seed is disseminated to higher, adjoining ground, but in the drier habitats alsike grows less luxuriantly. It reaches its greatest prominence in the wet meadows. . Meadows containing an average of 43.0 per cent alsike, as. compared with adjacent untreated areas with 6.9 per cent, yielded 1,174.3 more pounds of hay, which is an increase of 37.4 per cent (Table 20). The average yields of both ths seeded and untreated meadows are high, jespecially when com - pared with those of the red clover seriesl This is due largely to the fact that the reported yields were taken in midland or upland-midland mixed-hay meadows where growing con - ditions are very favorable. . </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 20.— Effect on yield of the invasion of alsike clover, in native meadoios — 1 926-1 929 Clover content Yield per acre Date by weight (15'.o moisture) Year harvested Heavily Slightly Heavily Slightly - dueTo'clTver invaded invaded invaded invaded "ca area area area _1D26 7/2 y 'nT_^^J^]gjr^^ 1927 7/ 6 •"' 3.4 5058.2 3695.0 1363.2 36 9 Average 38.3 8.1 3843.5 298G ;, 1 j gj£| g|-« 1929 Vnl ir 8 - 3 - B 3785 - 4 2904.1 siil 30l 4-year average 43.0 I (i.9 4313.4 3139.2 I IlTui a7 , 4 i •Percentage based on average of yields. Alsike clover produces the greatest yields in those meadows which have the water table near the surface during a period ot each year. It also grows well in. those bluestem meadows that support a dense cover of native grasses and which con - tain a small percentage of wet-meadow grasses. In the blue - stem meadow alsike cannot be depended upon to increase yields markedly. Good stands can be obtained, but the vege - tative growth is never so aggressive as that of red clover Alsike grows poorly in the upper limits of the red clover range. Alsike produces hay of good quality, slightly superior to that of red clover because of its finer growth/ It is better adapted to the wet meadows and will often thrive where the red clover varieties die. Alsike will serve its most valuable purpose in the midland and the upland-midland m uf y meadows - I* cannot compete with the red clovers in the bluestem meadows. Sweet Clover.— Since fully 90 per cent of the sweet clover growing in the meadows is the white-blossomed bien - nial type, the discussion will deal with this species' onlv InrW If h as been disseminated in many fields in the fclkhorn valley. It was originally introduced as a desirable leguminous plant for upland, sandy soil and to a limited ex- Jf'VS subirrigated valleys. Because of its heavy seed - ing and the fact that it usually matures seed prior to the harvesting of hay sweet clover is not only perpetuated in the seeded meadows but invades adjacent hay fields. It may be WlS W°S° CCaS ! OnaIIy &amp; S0me ? f the valle y s of the san d- SfaSSS^U. ons where jt is so cons p icuous </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska Table 21. — Effect on yield of the invasion of sweet clover in ■ native meadows — 1926-1 929 . Clover content ■ Yield per acre by weight (15% moisture) Date ■ Increase Year harvested Heavily Slightly Heavily Slightly due to clover invaded invaded invaded invaded area . area area area Percent Percent Pounds Pounds Pounds Percent 1926 6/29 89.2 13.2 5435.3 1258.1 4177.2 332.0 1927 7/13 56.8 7.7 6071.9 4414.2 1657.7 37.6 1928 7/17 ■ 72.9 0,0 6107.8 1934.4 4173.4 215.7 1929 7/11 45.3 5:0 3982.9 2650.8 1332.1 5oli 8/7 46.0 3.6 2937.5 2016.1 921.4 45.7 . Average 45.7 4.3 3460.2 2333.5 1126.8 48.3' 4-ycar average 66.2 6A 5268.8 2485.1 2783.8 112.0' 'Percentage based on average of yields. Data collected over a period of four years and summarized in Table 21 show that sweet clover increased the yield 2,783.8 pounds or 112.0 per cent on the average in those areas which were 66.2 per cent clover, as compared with adjacent areas which were 6.3 per cent clover. All the yield data were taken in meadows where the clover was largely in the second year of growth with the exception of the cutting of August 7, 1929, which was first-year growth. Good to medium stands of sec - ond-year growth of sweet clover will produce marked in - creases in yield. A dense growth of first-year sweet clover will increase yields appreciably when cut during the latter part of the growing season. Numerous hay producers discriminate against sweet clover because it is coarse and unpalatable during the second year. The first season's growth does not meet with disapproval as readily, since at this stage the clover produces a reasonably palatable feed and increases considerably the protein con - tent of the hay. Since sweet clover has spread considerably, it is meeting with disapproval in many instances. Many hay producers are trying to eradicate it. The most feasible method would be to mow it- as close as possible to the ground, either during the .first season or just prior to the blossoming stage of the second year. During these stages it makes a hay of finer quality and higher feeding value than it would if cut at a later stage. Sweet clover mowed during its first season is handicapped •the following year. The severe competition of the native vegetation greatly hinders growth. Mowing prior to blossom - ing prevents seeding and, consequently, the clover stand will diminish rapidly. The detrimental effects of early harvesting as compared with late harvesting, .June 21 and August 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 22.— The comparative effects of time of cutting upon the succeeding year's yield of sweet clover in a native meadow, June 23, 1928 nucive Date harvested Yield per acre (15 per cent moisturej previous year Sweet clover Other vegetation ' Total Pounds P.ct. Pounds P.ct. Jw7«~ June 21. 1927 380.9 18.3 1698.0 81.7 2078.9 August 1, 1927 1856.4 55.4 1494.4 44.6 3350.8 of the same year, are given in Table 22. This meadow con - tained a heavy growth of both first and second year clover A relationship of this kind is common in the meadows where the clover has been seeded and has reseeded naturally The response of the vegetation as affected by the time of'cutting - during one season is reflected in the yield the following vear 1 he adjacent plats were again harvested during the latter part of June of the second year. A decrease of 79.5 per cent in the weight of sweet clover and 38.0 per cent in the total vegetative yield was brought about in the second vear's wXlL™ v, f q^ adrats in June, as compared with those harvested in August of the first year Early harvesting decreases, the yield of native vegetation as well as the yield per acre during the year of the earlv clipping. The effects, of this early clipping are carried over swrot clov°i "* y6ar ' Meadows ma y thus be cleared of Sweet clover, with respect to adaptation, can be seeded over a more extensive area than any other cultivated legume Although materially benefited by subirrigation, it grows com - paratively well in the uplands if the plants withstand the xeric conditions until the roots are established in moist layers Sttnn, A 80 * Th i« r , eatest difficulty is the precarious con - 55 w- a^ eSUl TT O^ P rolon &amp;ed high winds, the soil dries and blows readily. Under mesophytic conditions sweet clover SbteidSK 111 ?- ? d0 +l s poor i y on meadows with the *85 It SSS ? ?r,2 tI°°fi. Of th . e J , surface f °r any prolonged period. It seldom inhabits the midland meadow and often does not thrive well in the upland-midland mixed-hay meadow DrSS? t77 presents a com P lex P^blem in the" native prairies. It is commonly regarded as a weed since the vSrand^ro^H^ has /° , marl &lt;et outlet, is difficult to har! Itocic mJ «^ £ f 7 9f *°", ly f air 3 Uality - Certain local liv^ - stock men say that sweet clover when harvested rather early </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska in the season makes a roughage of medium quality. The animals readily consume the leaves and a large percentage of the stems where they have access to the hay continuously. Wherever the red and alsike clovers may be successfully grown, they should be grown in preference to sweet clover. Even though local feeders may utilize hay mixed with sweet clover, its extent should be carefully guarded, for adjacent fields may be readily contaminated. Livestock men can utilize sweet clover where the more mesophytic red and alsike clovers will not grow. The heavier-textured soils with no subirriga- " tion provide the most suitable areas for the use of sweet clover. If there is danger of contaminating hay meadows used for a cash crop, sweet clover should never be intro - duced. White Clover. — White clover has been introduced into a number of pastures but as far as can be ascertained, no efforts have been made to seed it into the meadows. Occa - . sionally it. is found in meadows, having come in from adjoin - ing pastures through vegetative propagation and livestock droppings. Even then it occurs only in small patches. Table 23. — Effect on yield of the invasion of xvhite clover in native meadows — 1 926-1 929 Clover content Yield per acre by weight (15 1 ;; moisture) Date — Increase Year harvested Heavily Slightly Heavily Slightly due to clover invaded invaded invaded invaded area area area area Percent Per cent Pound* Puumh Pountln Percent 1926 11 7 :■ 22.9 0.0 1616.4 1502.9 113.5 7.6 1927 8/10 15.3 5.8 4166.6 3618.4 548.2 15.2 192.8 7 12 . 19.2 -5.0 12651.9 2554.3 97.6 3.8 1929 7 20 15.6 0.4 2984.4 2752.8 231.6 8.4 1-year average 18.3' 2.8 2854.8 2607.1 247.7 9.51 .j Percentage based on average of yields. The increased yields brought about by white clover are summarized in Table 23; meadows that contain an average •of 18.3 per cent clover outyielded adjacent areas with 2.8 per cent clover by 9.5 per cent. The stand was fully as good as in any of the yield studies made in connection with the other species of clover. This clover, because of its low growth, is incapable of producing as much hay as the others. It made up only about one-fifth of the total vegetation (Table 23) . White clover grows comparatively well in all bluestem meadows. Its range of adaptability resembles that of red clover. It usually grows well in the pastures developed from </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 areas of the midland meadow type, but does poorly in the midland hay meadow. This is due largely to shading by the tall native grasses, which is more severe than moderate or even fairly close grazing by livestock. White clover is of little value in the native meadows. An increase in yield of more than 10 per cent can seldom be pro - duced. It is difficult to mow, especially in dense stands. As a result, it is little used. Its stoloniferous qualities are of merit in pastures, but of little value in the hay meadows. GRAMINACEOUS SPECIES Grasses increase the protein content of hay only through increasing yields. In many instances the cultivated grasses are harvested in a late stage of maturity and the percentage of protein is frequently, lower than that of the native vege - tation, which is in an earlier stage of growth. Consequently, the introduced grasses should not be used as substitutes for, but as supplements to, the legumes. In a few instances hay buyers prefer hay free from legumes, and in such cases cer - tain species of tame grasses can be used advantageously to increase yields. .. Timothy. — Of all the introduced grasses and legumes, timothy has been disseminated most extensively. It makes up various percentages of the hay in many of the subirri - gated meadows, of the Elkhorn valley and in the valleys of the sandhills. Only a few meadows produce hay containing as much as 50 per cent of timothy by weight, but many have from 1 to 10 per cent. Just as red clover has proved to be the most popular legume among the hay producers, timothy ranks equally well among the grasses. TABLE 24. — Effect on yield of the invasion of timothy in / native meadows — 1029 Timothy content Yield per acre Date by weight . (15'; moisture) Year harvested Heavily Slightly Heavily Slightly due "o'timothy invaded invaded invaded invaded area area area area Percent Percent Pouiirln Pound* Pnmiilt Percent 1929 7/12 54.9 6.4 2863.4. 1968.0 895.4 45.5 The yield data on one meadow in. 1929 are given in Table 24. Plats heavily seeded with timothy outyielded the adjacent lightly seeded area by 45.5 per cent. The yields for a three - year period of a typical upland-midland mixed-hay meadow, heavily invaded with timothy, are given in Table 25. This meadow also contained an appreciable amount of red and </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska Table 25.— Yield of an upland-midland mixed-hay meadow lieavily invaded with timothy — 1927-1929 Year Date Type of native vegetation Timothy content of other Yield harvested by weight vegetation per acre Pounds Per cent Pounds Pounds 1927 7/ 9 Andropogon furcatua Spartina michauxiana 1721.1 53.4 1502.7 3223.8 1928 7/13 Andropogon furcatus Spartina michauxiana. . . . 1916.2 56.5 1475.5 3391.7 1929 7/19 Andropogon furcatus Spartina michauxiana. ... 1884.7 52.7 1690.6 3575.3 ■ . Average..... 1840.7 54J2 1556.3 3396.9 alsike clovers. The timothy constituted 53.4, 56.5, and 52.7 per cent of the total vegetation during that period. A meadow yielding over one and one-half tons of hay per acre as consistently as the. one referred to in Table 25 should be the aim of every producer. The water table readings taken over a period of two years in the meadow indicated in Table 25 are given in Table 26. With respect to adaptation, timothy is very similar to red clover. It thrives well in any good bluestem meadow support - ing a closed cover of vegetation. It is somewhat better adapt - ed to the wet meadow than is red clover, reacting more nearly like alsike clover in this respect. Even though partially or en - tirely submerged during brief periods in the winter or spring months, timothy resumes normal growth the following season. Its upper limit of adaptability is nearly identical with that of red clover. Timothy is of considerable value to the hay producers and consumers desiring hay free from legumes. It is the most satisfactory grass for increasing yields. It can readily sup - plement native vegetation as a feed. Where legumes are de - sired because of the higher feeding qualities, timothy can Table 26. — Depth of the ground-water level at various dates in a medow producing the type of vegetation presented in Table 25 — 1927-1929 1927 • 1928 192 9 Holes No. 1. No. 2 Holes No. 1. No. 2 Holes No. 1, No. 2 Date Inches Date Inches Date Inches ... ■■ .. 6/ g 20 26 4/19 0 4 • • • • 6/28 13 . 22 7/3 21 29 7/9 33 44 7/9 26 42 7/20 \\ 21 8/10 40 46 8/7 35 42 8/3 24 31 8/19 31 42 9/14 33 35 8/ 6 26 30 10/21 28 31 11/23 6 16 9/13 f? 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 27. — Effect on yield of the invasion of redtop in the native meadotvs — 1929 Redtop content Yield per acre Date by weight (1S% moisture) ■ Year harvested Heavily Slightly Heavily Slightly dueio'red'top invaded invaded invaded invaded ' area area area area Percent Percent Pounds Pounds Pounds Percent 1929 7/10 73.1 11.1 2025.5 1190.5 835.0 70.1 ■ _'_ 7/10 77.5 . 7.4 2068.0 1319.1 748,9 56.8 Average 75.3 9.6 2046.8 1254.8 792.0 63.1" Percentage based on average of yields. still be used advantageously as a supplement. Possessing the desirable qualities of heavy seed production and perennial growth, timothy will readily perpetuate itself in a subirri - gated meadow if harvesting is delayed sufficiently during occasional years to permit seeding. Redtop. — Redtop grows in small amounts throughout numerous meadows of the Elkhorn valley. Approximately five per cent of the subirrigated meadows in this area con - tain a heavy growth. In the sandhill valleys, redtop domin - ates the situation only in an occasional field. It was originally seeded into wet meadows because of its adaptation to poorlv drained, wet soils. The comparative yields of seeded versus untreated plats of two meadows are given in Table 27. The seeded plats con - taining 75.3 per cent redtop yielded 63.1 per cent more vegetation than the adjacent plats with 9.6 per cent redtop. Table 28 shows what may be expected where a good stand be - comes established. Redtop is adapted to a wider range of environmental con - ditions than any of the other cultivated species under study with the exception of sweet clover. It does reasonably well on Table 28. — Yield of three native liay meadows heavily in - i . vaded with redtop i ■ • _ ' — Y f ar h. Da t A TyPC Ot " atiye gelation Uedtop content oTotner Yield | narvested by weight vegetation per acre Paundm Percent' Pounds Pounds 1927 7/12 Andropogon furcatus 1374.7 54.9 . 1129.2 2503.9 1929 7/ 5 Andropogon furcatus I Spartina michauxiana . . 1678.1 63.6 959.2 2637.3 1929 7/6 Andropogon furcatus 1940.4 77.7 557.3 2497.7 Average '. . . 1664.4 65.4 881.9 2546.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska low, poorly drained meadows, pairing advantageously with alsike clover in this respect. Besides, it will grow in areas with a lower water table than either timothy or red clover. It is occasionally observed on high ground, where subirrigation is not a factor in plant growth, provided the soil is not too coarse. These areas generally have been found in depressions and swales where considerable run-off accumulates before the water penetrates the soil. Only in rare instances would timothy and the true clovers grow under such conditions with - out subirrigation. ; The chief difficulty with redtop in the native hay meadows as viewed from a hay producer's standpoint is that after the blossoming period it matures rapidly and soon reaches a stage where it becomes unpalatable to livestock, and materially reduces the market quality of the hay. Timothy is much more desirable from the standpoint of palatability. Wherever timothy will grow successfully it should always be utilized in preference to redtop. The latter may be utilized profitably as a supplement with legumes to increase yields in low, wet meadows, and may be seeded in a pure stand in drier habitats beyond the timothy range. Kentucky Bluegrass. — Kentucky bluegrass was orig - inally seeded into the wet meadows to partially replace the tall, coarse native grasses and, consequently, produce more desirable hay. It also proved to be well adapted to the sub - irrigated pastures. Because of its heavy seed production dur - ing the early part of the growing season and its stoloniferous qualities, bluegrass has spread profusely in the Elkhorn valley and in many of the sandhill valleys. A large percentage of the meadows contain at least a small amount, while in many bluegrass is dominant. No data are presented to show the comparative yields of adjacent plats containing a heavy and light growth of blue - grass. Harvesting at an early date, at the optimum period for cutting bluegrass, would indicate favorably increased yields. Bluegrass blooms and produces seed in June and grows very little after that. Consequently it is surpassed in yield by the native vegetation as the growing season advances. The extent to which bluegrass may take possession of a meadow is shown in Table 29. The first three cuttings of 1927, 1928, and 1929 were taken in the same meadow. The depth to the ground-water level on several dates over a period of two years is given in Table 30. When harvested on June 25, 1929, this meadow was 73.3 per cent Kentucky bluegrass, 5.8 per cent timothy, 2.1 per cent redtop, 2.5 per cent Hordeum jubatum (wild barley), 1.4 per cent Andro- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 29. — Yield of two native hay meadotos heavily invaded with Kentucky bluegrass Year Date Typo of native vegetation Bluegrass content . of otner Yield harvested by weight vegetation per acre Pounds Per cent Pounds Pounds 1927 7/20 Andropogon furcatus 2564.7 95.1 132.2 2696.9 1928 6/21 Andropogon furcatus 1554.2 81.9 344.2 1898.4 1929 6/25 Andropogon furcatus.,... 1587.8 73.3 579.3 2167.1 1929 7/ 1 Andropogon furcatus ■■■ Spartina michauxiana.. 1436.6 67.9 678.9 2115.5 Average 1785.8 79.6 433:7 22J9.5 pogon furcatus (big bluestem), 1.2 per cent Spartina michauxiana (slough grass) , 0.4 per cent Panicum virgattim (switch grass), 13.3 per cent sedges and rushes, and 0.1 per cent forbs. The vegetation harvested from the upland-midland mixed - hay meadow on July 1, 1929, shows an invasion of bluegrass to the extent of 67.9 per cent of the total vegetation. The native vegetation characteristic of an upland-midland mixed - hay meadow consisted of 4.7 per cent Spartina michauxiana (slough grass), 2.8 per cent Andropogon furcatus (big blue - stem), and 2.1 per cent Sorghastrum nutans (Indian grass) with traces of Panicum scribnerianum (Scribner's panic - grass), Hordeum jubatum (wild barley), Panicum virtgatum (switch grass), and Muhlenbergia racemosa (wild timothy). The rest of the vegetation was as follows: sedges and Pushes 8.6 per cent, timothy 8.8 per cent, redtop 0.1 per cent, and clovers 3.5 per cent. The water table readings in 1929 are given in Table 31. Bluegrass will grow on any subirrigated land that will sup - port a stand of red clover and timothy. It thrives especially TABLE 30. — Depth of the ground-water level in a meadoiv pro^ during the type of vegetation presented in the first three cuttings in Table 29 1927 1928 1929 Dale Inches Date Inches Dale Inches .. 6/5 20 4/19 0 . . 6/21 18 6/25 21 7/25 27 7/9 25 7/20 12 8/10 29 ,' 8/7 27 .... 8/19 20 9/23 22 9/13 i6 .... ._. 11/23 13 ..... </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska ■ - • • Table 31. — Depth of the ground-water level in a meadow pro - ducing the type of vegetation presented in the last cuttina of Table 29 -. Hole Hole Hole ■■' Date Number 1 Number 2 Number 3 T , , Inches Inches Incites July l t ... 31 . 22 25 August 12 34 26 28 September 13 ... 1 22 18 18 well in meadows producing upland-midland mixed hay, and does reasonably well in any big-bluestem meadow. It will grow in a somewhat drier habitat than timothy, is about as drouth resistant as redtop, and usually grows luxuriantly in the midland hay meadows. The invasion of bluegrass into native meadows has brought about a number of complications. It matures during the month of June, and cannot produce the quantity of vegeta - tion that the native species which utilize nearly the entire growing season can. In addition, bluegrass, because of its early maturity, usually lowers the palatability and the com - mercial grade of hay, since the meadows are seldom cut at an optimum stage of growth for bluegrass. This has made blue - grass unpopular among the hay producers. Many wish to eradicate it. Breaking and cultivating the meadows is the only feasible method. It is of of no value in the meadows. It can be used advantageously . in subirrigated pastures but even under such conditions care must be exercised in its use as it may invade adjacent meadows. MANAGEMENT OF NATIVE MEADOWS WHICH HAVE BEEN SEEDED TO . CULTIVATED FORAGE PLANTS Brouse (2) discusses the methods of seeding tame forage plants into the native hay meadows. Consideration must also be given to the perpetuation of these species. Since most of the introduced cultivated forage plants are perennials, they continue to live a number of years. The longevity of the in - dividual plants under conditions of subirrigation has not been established. It is of utmost importance that certain practices be followed after a stand of the cultivated species has been established in a meadow. The tame plants should be permitted to reseed at least during occasional years. All the species under con- </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 sideration will mature seed under average conditions it allowed to reach maturity. Although they are highly variab e Ssii &lt;? pacit y&gt; e y. en the Poorest seeders such as red clover wall produce a medium amount of seed. All of the cultivated ltf S Z &amp;t l r&amp; Se f f rlY in ,, the , SeaS0n ' hence the meadows need not be cut abnormally late as compared with the optimum time for mowing wild hay. Red clover is capable of producing two crops in one season, and the first crop should be cut sufficiently early to insure the maturity of the second, which, is the more prolific seeder. If the tame species have o"vPr U th %Z°? °l seed &gt;, considerable quantities are scattered over the field m harvesting the crop for hay. Raking and bucking the hay are especially valuable in this respect m ,IS e n AV r0P T ay , be fed to livest ock, which will return Srnirt t f&gt;f Seed . in dro PP\»S s - Th e manure should be re" turned to the meadows. as a light, top dressing, or, preferably the livestock should be fed on the meadows Lastly the hav tSSKhS "* ° r *&amp;* to bein^ to iivestec?. The resulting seed crop may then be returned to the meadows These practices mil aid materially in perpetuating a stand years^TSefXv^' 1^ 1 S° a ? ificial Periodic seeding! in later price of seed 1S expensive because of the high Since the cultivated forage plants develop iflowerinjr stalks comparatively early in the season, the time of cuttinj should SuaHtT^Q^T^^ in ° rder t0 produce h " ofgoo quality. Quadrats in two meadows supporting a heavv grovvth of tame hays were harvested on thS difffrent dates Augusf pTable S y&gt; T G , midC ! 1 f V July ' and the St PartS August (Table 32). The yields increased rapidly until the TAB^f/ Z }-— Effect of time of cutting on yield of two subirri- Sni-W29 Vlead ° WS heaVibj iUVaded W^ t™ef°"cwc VegeUMon Yield per acre (15',' moisture) , Meadow No. 1 . Meadow N o 7z~ Timothy . p - &lt;*• P • &lt;*■ I', ct. l&gt;. ct. - p.ri. p.et r«"op. ::::..::: 48 - 7 5 ?- 7 53 -? •«•« &lt;&amp; Medium red clover ...... ' Vsa '".Vi °- 1 °-l AUikedover 'H 1 ii "- 6 0.5 1.4 "07 Sweet clover 9 - 8 ?•? 7.2 •' Whitedover *" ; '---' 0.4 " r Vi -^S^Ske^r--^^ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska middle of July. Thereafter the increases were not nearly so marked. The quality of tame hays will decrease materially after the first of August. Consequently, meadows with a high percentage of tame hays can be harvested to the best advan - tage during the latter part of July. This date of harvesting should be delayed as the percentage of tame hay decreases. The earlier harvesting of native meadows that contain culti - vated grasses and legumes will facilitate materially the hay - making progx*am. The hay producer requires from two to eight weeks to harvest his crop. If a part of his hay land is seeded to cultivated forage plants, the harvesting of these areas may be started comparatively early, while the harvest - ing of the unseeded meadows may be delayed until the season is more advanced. EFFECT OF. THE CULTIVATED FORAGE PLANTS ON NATIVE VEGETATION The native species, although in competition for nutrients, light, and space, have reached a stage of equilibrium in these subirrigated valleys where comparatively little change is tak - ing place under the prevailing climatic and soil conditions. When undisturbed, the native vegetation produces the maxi - nium quantity of hay. The repeated mowing, however, causes it to suffer from the often untimely harvest. Haying begins about the first week in July and continues until the last week of September. The result is that vegetation is cut in all stages of 'growth from an early period of vegetative develop - ment to full maturity. Upon the introduction of the cultivated plants, severe com - petition with the native vegetation results. The cultivated species are capable of retaining their prominence under favorable conditions. Reseeding of the cultivated plants is necessary in at least occasional years. Any condition un - favorable to native vegetation, however, gives the cultivated vegetation a decided advantage and accordingly a greater as - surance of establishment and perpetuation. Untimely har - vesting of the native vegetation for prolonged periods leaves it in a weakened condition. Tillage operations of any kind may be used to diminish the activity of the native vegetation. Their effects depend upon the severity of the tillage of the sod. Table 33 summarizes! the yields of native vegetation in adjacent quadrats. The quadrats in one instance contained a heavy growth of one of j the five clovers, while the adjacent quadrats had little or no clover. The native forbs were separ - ated from the native grasses, sedges, and rushes, so that the effect on each group of plants might be noted. The reduc- </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 Table 33. — Effect of the associative growth of cultivated legumes and native vegetation on the yield of the native vegetation Clover content Native grasses, sedges, Native forbs and rushes . Yield per acre Yield per aore ■ Clover Invaded Check ■ Reduc- ■ Reduc - quadrats quadrats Invaded Check lion Invaded Check tion quadrats quadrats in yield quadrats quadrats in yield P. ct. P. ct. Lh.'. Lbs. P. ct. Lbs. Lbs. P. ct. Medium red G1.2 10.9 646.7 903.6 28.4 .50.0 56.2 11.0 Mammoth red 62.6 3.9 731.4 1054.3 30.6 30.3 41.9 27.7 Alaike 40.7 6.6 .1368 .3 1639.5 16.5 52.6 86.5 39.2 Sweet 55.1 3.5 1382.6 1655.6 16.5 47.3 54.4 13.1 White 20.4 7.9 1062.4 1373.7 22.7 29.4 16.1 .... tions in yield of the native vegetation by the various clovers are not comparable, because the quadrats were taken from different meadows. The yield of the native grasses, sedges, and rushes, when growing in the presence of the clover, was reduced 16.5 per cent in the case of the alsike and sweet clovers and 30.6 per cent in the presence of mammoth red clover (Table 33). The native forbs also yielded less when in competition with the cultivated species. The reduction in yield "ranged from 0.0 per cent in the presence of white clover to 39.2 per cent in the presence of alsike clover. RELATION OF PROTEIN CONTENT TO THE STRUCTURE OF THE VEGETATION The quantity of crude protein in the hay was used as a criterion to show the additional beneficial effects of the culti - vated forage plants upon the prairie hay. A comparison between the component vegetation of quad - rats harvested in areas containing a heavy growth of one of the cultivated forage plants under study and of the. native vegetation of adjacent quadrats containing little or no culti - vated forage plants is shown in Table 34. All the tame plants are considered. The effects of the individual cultivated plants are not directly comparable, since they were harvested in different fields. They are comparable, however, to the extent that they were harvested at nearly optimum periods from the standpoint of the cultivated forage plants and under similar conditions with respect to subirrigation. The cultivated' clovers contain about twice as much pro - tein as does the native vegetation in its leafy stage of growth, with the result that the quantity of crude protein will be in - creased twice as rapidly as the increase in vegetative yields brought about by the clovers. In one instance medium red clover increased the yield of a meadow 143.0 per cent and the total amount of protein in </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska Table 34. — Vegetative yields and average percentage and pounds of protein per acre of the component vegetation liarvested in quadrats located in native meadows with a heavy groivth of one of the cultivated forage plants, and of the vegetation in adjacent check qtiadrats (moisture - free basis) ' ■' M Increase of Invaded quadrats Check quadrats invaded over . ' check quadrats Vegetation — 1 1 : • Vegeta- Vegeta- Vegeta - tive Protein content uve Protein content tive Protein yield . yield | yield yield :-Za«. I Pi el. i Ll&gt;*. Lbs. J'.d. i Lb». P.ct. I P.ct. ■ • HARVESTED JULY 29, 1929 Medium red clover 1896.4 '13.89 257.72 52.6 13.59 : . 7.15 Alsikn clover 2.1 .12.11 0.33 1.8 12.31 0.22 Alfalfa .'. 9.8 12.69 1.24 13.4 12.69 i 1.70 Timothy...... ': 50.8 4.88 2.48 59.8 4.19 j 2.51 Native. . 541.4 8.03 43.47 901.8 7.63 i 68.81 Total .:...! 2501.1 12.20" 305.24 1029.4 7.81 •' 80.39 143.0 279.7 HARVESTED AUGUST 1, 1929 • Medium red clover 525.4 13.59 71.40 16.9 13.59 2.30 Native 776.9 7.28 56.56 955.3 7.31 69.83 • Total. . | 1302.3 9.83 127.96 972.2 7.42 ! 72.13 34.0 77.4 HARVESTED JULY 26, 1929 Mammoth red clover 2H80.3 12.00 322.84 4.5 12.00 0.54 Abike Clover 141.8 13.09 18.56 11.6 13.09 1.52 Timothy. ....:..... 17.8 5.97. I 1.06 22.3 4.66 1.04 Native 537.0 8.69 46.67 949.1 7.75 j 73.56 Total.. 3386.9 11.49 389.13 987.5 7.76 , 76.66 243.0 407.6 HARVESTED JULY 25, 1929 Mammoth red clover,.. 803.7 14.66 117.82 14.3 14.66 ! 2.10 • Alsike clover 10.7 11.59 1.24 i . .-. Timothy. .79.4 5.13 4.07 99.0 4.28 4.24 Rcdtop 32.1 5.78 1.86 16.9 4.13 i 0.70 Native 891.1 7.38 65.76 1175.7 7.00 82.30 White clover 1-8 16.06 0.29 Total 1817.0 10.50 190.75 1307.7 6.85 89.63. 38.9 112.8 HARVESTED JULY 24, 1929 AUike clover 1096.3 13.72 150.41 56.2 13.72 7.71 Red clover 68.7 14.81 10.17 61.5 14.81 : 9.11 ! Timothy 407.6 5.31 21.64 555.7 4.91 27.28 Redtop 58.9 4.88 2.87 53.5 4.69 2.51 Native. 9:15.9 7.72 72.25 1142.7 7.72 88.22 Total . I 1 2567.4 10.02 257.34 .1869.6 7.21 134.83 37.3 90.9 HARVESTED JULY 23, 1928 AUikeclover ... 671.7 13.70 92.02 40.1 13.70 .5.49 I Timothy 170.4 4.6:1 7.89 198.0 4.81 .9.52 ! Redtop 11.6 6.22 0.72 1.8 6.22 0.11 ; ■ Native 1344.2 7.28 97.86 1500.3 6.80 102.02 i. Total 2197.9 9.03 198.49' 1740.2 6.73 117.14 26 .3 69.4 HARVESTED JULY 11, 1929 Sweet clover l»t yr. | 68.7 17.56 12.06 70.5 17.56 12.18 Sweet clover 2nd yr. 1466.4 12.59 184.62 41.9 12.59 5.28 1 Red clover 8.9 14.63 1.30 8.0 14.63 1.17 {..', Timothy 175.7 5.25 9.22 ' 225.7 6.03 13.61 J... Redtop 4.5 6.78 0.26 J Native. 0 1665.4 7.44 123.91 1902.6 6.97 132.61 J Total.. 3385:i 9.78 331.11 2253.2 7.34 165.31 50.2 100.3 I </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 ■ ; Table 34. — (Continued) \ . j j „. • Increase o[ Invaded quadrats Check quadrats invaded over Vegetation . -— . check quadrat. Vegeta- Vegcta- Vegeta - tive Protein content ti.vc Protein content live Protein y' eld yield yield yield . Lba. P. ct. | IJu. Lbs. | /&gt;. cl. | /„/,.,. /&gt;. ct. I', ct. HARVESTED AUGUST 6, 1929 Sweet clover 1st yr. 1148.9 15.72 180.61 61.5 15.72 9 67 Red clover 38.-1 16.38 6.29 23.2 16.38 3.80 ■" Timothy 43.7 6.25 2.73 44.6 4.50 2.01 Native 1265.7 7.19 .91.00 1584.2 . 6.5:1 103.45 '..... Total 2496.7 11.24 280.63 1713.5 6.94 118.93 4577" 136.0^ HARVESTED JULY 20, 1929 White clover 396.9] 16.06 63.74 1 9.8 16.06 157 Red clover I 6.2 15.41 0.96 Alsike clover I 1.8 15.41 0.28 Timothy 851.0 5.69 48.42 611.0 5.88 35.93 Redtop 25.9 6.28 1.6*1 2.7 6.28 0.17 Native 1264.0 | 6.56] 82.92 1709.1 6.28 107.33 '.'...[ '..'.'... Total 2537.8 I 7.71 \ 195.71 | 2340.6 6.25 | 116.24 sTT aJjTs" HARVESTED JULY 12. 1929 * Timothy .. 1337.1 4.80 61.18 107.0 4.80 5.14 ' Red clover 6.2 14.53 0.90 0.9 14.53 0 13 Redtop 7.1 4.81 0.34 Native 1083.8 6.77 73.37 1564.6 6.B8 104.52 '.'..'.. ■Total 2434.2 5.70 138.79 1672.5 6.56 109.79 '48.6 | .Z6A . HARVESTED JULY 10, 1929- Redtop 1264.9 8.03 101.57 108.8 8.03 8.74 Timothy 0.9 4.80 0.01 .1:8 4.80 0.09 "" Red clover •■ 1.8 14.53 0.2ti Native 455.8. * 9.72 41.30 900.0 9.28 83.52 Total 1721.6 8.48 145.91 1012.4 9.15 '92.61 70.1 &amp;f.(T HARVESTED JULY 10, 1929 Redtop 1344.2 7.63 102.56 1 79.4 7.63 6.06 Native 413.9.. 8.66 35.84 1011.9 9.72 101.27 .'.'..: '._.... Total I 1758.1 r 7.87 138.40 | 1121-3 9.57 I 107-33 56.H 28.9 'Percentage determined from average of vegetation and protein yields. the hay 279.7 per cent; in a second meadow an incx-ease in yield of 34.0 per cent brought about an increase of 77.4 per cent in the amount of protein. Mammoth red clover in two meadows increased the yields of hay 243.0 and 38.9 per cent and of protein 407.6 and 112.8 per cent respectively. Alsike, sweet, and white clover brought about similar increases in the yield of protein. Timothy, redtop, and Kentucky bluegrass mature much earlier than the native vegetation, with the result that the former plants contain a lower percentage of protein than the native vegetation, which is in an earlier stage of development. However, since the cultivated plants increase the yield de - cidedly, the quantity of the protein is increased but not as markedly as the increase in vegetative yields; </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Prairie Hay in North Central. Nebraska * Table 35. — Effect of the associative grotvth of cultivated clovers and native vegetation on the protein content of the native vegetation as compared with the protein content of adjacent native vegetation growing in the presence of little or no cultivated clover x j Woipht of clnvnr , in total Protein content of native vegetation vegetation Date I Cultivated forage , — : : harvested plant . ! Increase Seeded 1 Check Seeded Check —— j quadrats | quadrats quadrats quadrats Actual Percentage I /'. rl. P. cl. P. c.t. P. rt. P. cl. P cl 8/ 1 '29 Medium red clover ..... 58.9 1.9 7.28 7.31 7 2,1/29 I Medium red clover. .... 73.8 5.1 8.03 7.63 ■ .... Average......' ■ G7.4 3.5 7.6G 7.47 0.19 2.54 '7/26/29 Mammoth red clover ... 79.6 0.5 8.69 7.75 7/25/29 j Mammoth red clover .. I 44.2 1.1 7.38 7.00 ...... ..... Average 61.9 0.8 8.04 7.38 0.66 8.94 7/2.1/28 Alsike clover 30.2 2.0 7.28 6.80 7/21 29; Alsike clover.. . '. . 42.7 3.0 7.72 7.72 .... Average 36.5 2.5 7.50 7.26 0.24 3.31 Sweet clover • ■ 7/17/28 Second year growth 72.1 0.0 7.95 6.89 7 11/29 Second year growth 45.3 5.0 7.44 6.97 8/ 6/29 [■ Flnit year growth 46.0 3.6 7.19 6.53 .," ")" Average... 54.5 2.9 7.53 G.80 0.73 10.74 7/20 29 White clover 15.G 0.4 6.56 fi.28 0.28 4.46 7 12 29 Timothy 51.9 6.4 6.77 6.68 0.09 K35 7/10/29 Uedtop ....:.. 73.1 ll.l 9.72 9.28 7 10/29 ! Kedtop 77.5 7.4 8.66 9.72 '.'.'.'. '.'.'.'.[ ! Average , . ..'. . . 1 75.3 9.3 9.19 | 9.50 -0.31 ■Each result is based on a composite sample of five or ten quadrats. A meadow yielding 45.5 per cent more .hay as a result of a good growth of timothy also yielded 26.4 per cent more pro - tein. Two meadows yielding 70.1 per cent and 56.8 per cent more hay respectively as a result of a good growth of redtop yielded 57.6 per cent and 28.9 per cent more protein. The cultivated clovers brought about a small but significant increase in the protein content of the native vegetation as a result of associative growth (Table 35) . Although the results were not positive in all instances, eight out of ten meadows showed increases in the protein content of the native vege - tation. One meadow containing red clover gave negative re - sults and the vegetation in another meadow containing alsike clover showed no changes with respect to protein content The results with the individual cultivated plants are not com - parable, since they were harvested in separate fields. Medium red, mammoth red, alsike, sweet, and white clover brought </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 about increases of 2.54, 8.94, 3.31, 10.74, and 4.46 per cent respectively in the protein content of the native vegetation. Although the increases in some instances, such as red clover with 2.54 per cent, are not significant, the average positive results in the case of every clover species indicate positive favorable changes in the protein content of the native vege - tation. Cultivated grasses indicate negative results in this respect. Under field conditions, in many instances, the native vegetation growing in the presence of the clovers had a darker green color, was more spindly, and of greater stature than native vegetation growing in adjoining areas which were relatively free from the clovers. This was especially true in situations where the native vegetation grew in the presence of such tall plants as the sweet and mammoth red clovers. The increased protein content of the native vegetation may be the indirect result of limited photosynthesis in the leaves due to shading. Accordingly, the limitations of carbohydrate pro - duction would result in ah increased percentage of protein, even if there were no increase in the total quantity. There also exists the possibility that the nitrate content of the soil was increased by the legumes. This factor may have affected the protein content .of the native vegetation as has been reported by other workers for cultivated plants. SCIENTIFIC AND ACCEPTED COMMON NAMES OF SPECIES MENTIONED CULTIVATED SPECIES Legumes - . Medicago sativa L ; alfalfa Melilotus alba Desv sweet clover Trifolinm hybridum L alsike clover Trifolium pratense L.... .'...medium red clover Trifolium pratense perenne L .......mammoth red clover Trifolium repens L white clover Grasses Agrostis alba L redtop Phleum pratense L timothy Poa. pratensis L Kentucky bluegrass NATIVE SPECIES Grasses Agropyron smithii Rydb .' western wheat grass Agropyrcm tenerum Vasey slender wheat grass Agrostis hyemalis (Walt.) B. S. P hair grass Alopecunis genicnlatnit ~L meadow foxtail Andropogon ftircatus Muhl big bluestem Andropogon hallii Hack sandhill bluestem Andropogon scoparius Michx '. little bluestem </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska Bouteloiia hirsxita. Lag .". black grama Boutelmta oligostachya (Nutt.) Torr blue grama Calamagrostis canadeneis (Michx.) Beauv bluejoint Caldmagrostis neglecta (Ehrh.) Gaertn ....pony grass Calamovilfa longifolia, (Hook.) Hack sand reed-grass Elymus canadensis L wild rye Eragrostis trichodes (Nutt.) Nash '..... hair-like love grass Festiica ovina L '. ."..; sheep fescue Hordeum jubatum L .;. ..wild barley Koeleria cristata (L.) Pers June grass Muhlenbergia pungeus Thurb blow-out grass Mnhlenbergia racemosu (Michx.) B. S. P wild timothy. Panicum scribveriannm Nash Scribner's panic-grass Panicum virgatum L switch grass Phalaris tviindinacea L reed canary-grass ■ Pncciiiellia airoides (Nutt.) Wats. &amp; Coult..... slender meadow-grass Rcdfieldia flexnosa, (Thurb.) Vasey ...Redfield's-grass Sorghastrutn nutans (L.) Nash .' Indian grass Spartina, michauxiana ' Hitchc slough grass Sporobolits cryptandiiis (Torr.) A Gray sand dropseed Stipa comata Trin. &amp; Rupr : needle grass Stipa spartea Trin porcupine grass Forb. i Artemisia gnaphalodes Nutt , prairie sage Dasystcphana spp ; , •. gentians Equisetum spp •• horse-tail Glycyrrhiza lepidota Pursh wild licorice Mentha canadensis L wild mint Petalostemum jmrpurottm (Vent.) Eydb purple prairie-clover Polygonum muhlenbergii (Meisn.) Wats perennial smartweed Stachys palustris L hedge nettle ! Taraxacum taraxacum (L.) Karst • dandelion Triglochin maritima L ....; arrow grass 'Forbs are all native species other than crosses, sedges, and rushes. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 60 literature cited 1. Beadle, G. W. 1927. Identification of the More Important Graminaceous Constituents of the Prairie Hay of Nebraska by Means of Their Vegetative Characters. Unpublished Master's Thesis, University of Nebraska. .2. Brouse, E. M. . 1930. Clover in the Subirrigated Meadows of the Sand Hills Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 241, 12 pp. 3. Condra, G. E. 1915. The Development of Nebraska's Sandhill Areas. Ne - braska State Board of Agriculture, Ann. Rpt., pp. 279-299! 4. . 1930. Conservation of the Wild Life of the Sandhill Lakes. Legislative Reference Bureau Publication, The Nebraska Blue Book, pp. 434-436. 5. Frolik, A. L. 1930. Ecesis of Exotic Cultivated Plants in the Native- Prairies of North Central Nebraska. Unpublished Master's Thesis, University of Nebraska. 6. Parker, Edward C, Seeds, K. B., and Hosterman, W. H. 1928. Handbook of Official Hay Standards. Government Print - ing Office, Washington, D. C, 48 pp. 7. Keim, F. D., and Beadle, G. W. 1926. Prairie Hay in Nebraska. Unpublished Report, University of Nebraska. 8. Pool, R. J. 1914. A Study of the Vegetation ofthe Sandhills of Nebraska. Minn. Botanical Studies 4:189-312. ■ 9. Shantz, H. L., and Zon, Raphael. 1924. Natural Vegetation — Atlas of American Agriculture Government Printing Office, Washington, D. C, Part I Section E, 29 pp., illus. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>