<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00013.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00013.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TWELFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE DEPARTMENT OF BANKING SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE INCORPORATED, PRIVATE, AND SAVINGS BANKS OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR 1903 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE STATE BANKING BOARD FEBRUARY 15, 1904.</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">k OF THE DEPARTMENT OF BANKING SlIoWINU THE CONDITION" OF THK INCORPORATED. PRIVATE. AND SAVII BANKS OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR If' M UMITTEI' TO THE GOYEItNoK A N 1 ' FHK STATE BAN IN(. HOARD FEBRUARY 15. I!** BY YORK. NKKI NEHRASKA KBWSPAPEB OIOS PRINTKRS MM E. KOYSE. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002">DEPARTMENT OF BANKING OK THE STATE OF SEBRASH.A HOAHD. Auilitor of Public Acconnt", President Hon. Ciiaklek Westox. Hon. Piter Mobtk-- Hon. f, X. Pboct, State Treasurer Attorney General etTetary E. ft EXAM! 1.. V. Haskell, Wakefield Fkei&gt; Whittf.m W. D. Haktwelu Pawnee City K. K. Kmmett. A. N. Dodson, Cliief t'lork Fraxk Smith, Stenographer &gt;re. Ix&gt;ntr Pine Arapahor </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Tiik State of Nkbkaska. Dki-aktmknt ok Bank: Lincoln. February 15. Iitn4. \ The HonoraJtle* Charl** Wtxtun, Auditor of Public Account*. Peter Morten* n. State 7 Mkmkkks or tiik Static Bahkiwo Hii.vkh Sirs: Pursuant to the provisions of sec. 8a of ehap. 8 of tlic* Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, for the year l'.'O:,, the twelfth annual report of the department of banking covering the period beginning November i6, 190S is suhmitted herewith. tnd ending November 17. 1 During th&lt; Three hanks have reorganised Six have changi'd from private Nine have nationalized. and reineorporated, to incorporated banks, Seven have sold to and been succeeded bj other hanks. Six have gone into voluntary liquidation, paid depositors in full and quit bminOM, One has been closed and placed in the hands of I re&lt; One has changed its name and location. Forty-two new banks have been chartered, thirty nine of which were incorporated and three were private banks, with an ag - gregate paid in capital of $340,000, Three private hanks have been rechartered 1. Broken Bow — Bank of Commerce September. 12, 1608 2. Osceola — Osceola Bank February 4, !!"•:'. 5. Stroinsburg — Stronisbnrg Bank December 3, 1902 I" His Excellency ■/&gt;&gt;/,n II. Mirk, tj. Governor t*k" /•'. .V. Prout, Attorney Gen RKolNiANIZED AND liKINnililDRATKH HANKS. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 CHANGED FORM PRIVATE TO TNCORI'ORATED HANKS. 1. C'ortlaud — Bank of Cortlaud Julv 88, 1903 2. Glenville— Bank of Glenville April 1, 19&lt;»H 3. Odell— Bank of Odell August 3, 1903 4. Springfield — J. D. Spearman «fc Co October 8, 1903 5. Virginia — Citizens State Bank June .'!, 1903 6. Wood Lake— Wood Lake Bank . Mav 2»&gt;, 1903 STATE BANKS WHICH HAVE NATIONALIZED 1. Atkin illagher Ar Co December 1. 1902 2. Beemer — Farmers State Bank 3. Cambridge— State Bank of November 24, 1902 larks — Merrick County Bank September 1. l'.'&lt;»3 5. Crawford— Bank of Crawford August 1»&gt;, 1903 &lt;&gt;. Genoa — Nance County State Bank June 30. 1903 7. Mitchell— Mitchell Valley Bank November 1. 1903 8. Stuart — Stuart Bank \K Wisner —Citizens State Bank July I, 1903 HANKS THAT HAVE SOLD TO AN1&gt; BEEN BUOCKBDKD KY OTHER BAHKfl DURINIi THE YEAR. HANKS THAT HAVE SOLD TO AND BEEN SUCCEEDED BY OTHER BANKS DURING THE YEAR 1. Dixon — Dixon Bank sold to and succeeded bv tin 1. Dixon — Dixon Bank sold to and succeeded by the Dixon State Bank September 1. lHt&gt;3 •2. (iordon — Maverick Bank sold to Sheridan County Bank January 10, 1903 S. Hantiugs — Adams County Bank sold to First Nation - al Bank June 1, 1908 4. Milligan — Nebraska State Bank sold to and succeed - ed by Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank June 15, 1903 5. Pawnee City — Pawnee County Bank sold to and suc - ceeded by National Bank of Pawnee City. .January 13. 1903 6. Reynolds — Bank of Reynolds sold to and succeeded by Farmers Bank of Reynolds April 8, 1903 7. Sutherland — Bank of Sutherland sold to and succeed - ed bv Sutherland State Bank March 17, 1903 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">IAKV OF THE STATE liANKIM. 5 BANKS WHICH HAVE GONE INTO YOLINTARY LlojIDA- IION. PAID DEPOSITORS AND Ql IT I! DIRING THE YEAR. 1. Archer — Archer State Bank ... March 83, 1903 2. Edgar — (lay County Bank .April 19«»:'. 3. Elm ( First Bank of Elm Creek. . it. l!»02 4. Fairmont — Commercial State Bank . 5. Grafton— Bank of Grafton December 30, 1903 ♦&gt;. Sidnev — Bank of Nebraska January 16. HANKS WHICH HAVE P.K1 -ED AND PLACED IN THE HANDS ()K RECEIA DURING THE YEAH. Verdigre — Bank of Verdigre January 21, HANKS THAT HAVE (HANGED THEIR NAME Dl RING THE YEAR. Aiioka— Anoka State Hank changed its nan* County and moved to Butte. NEW BANKS INCORPORATED AND CHARTERED 1. AiuKWorth — Citi. 2. Amherat Fanners State Bank.. . .Apri Anselmo — Anselmo State Bank... ..April 4. Atlanta- Atlanta State bank January 31, 1'.'": 5. Barneston- Commercial State Bank Febrii; '-'0:'. «. Craig — Frrmers State Bank July j 7. Davev — Farmers State Bank.. .. JulvJ 8. DeWitt- Home State Bank ... . June 4. | '.). Dixon — Dixon State Bank September 12, I'.hi:: 10. Eddyville— Eddyville State Bank. M 11. EdiHon— Bank of Edison October l'.». 1J»O3 12. Edgar— Clay County State Bank February 18. Exeter— Exeter State Bank June »i. 1903 14. Fairmont — Commercial State Bank Mai 15. Fairmont — Fairmont State Bank April 2."». IJM)3 16. Farwell— Farwell State Bank . Februarv '.•. 1903 17. Goehner — Goehner State Bank . </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 M Al. KKl'i'KT OF THK 1&gt;. Harvard— Harvard State Bank Mav 1*. 1908 18. Hershey — Bank of Lincoln County .July 16, 19&lt;»3 Hubbard— Hubbard State Bank May 23, 19o: J , 21. Martinsburg — Martinsburg State Bank October 3, 1903 Maxwell— Maxwell State Bank October l'.i. 1903 Milford — Farmers and Merchants Bank. . . March 25, 1903 ■24. Milligan- Farmers and Merchants Bank .June 15, 1903 •2.".. Odell -Hinls State Bank September Is, li»U3 2«. Oconto-- Oconto State Bank February 24, l'.tO:*. 27. Octavia- Octavia State Bank February lit. 1903 •2^. l'lattBinoutli- Plattsmouth Savings Bank July 1, 1903 •_".'. Primrose -Primrose State Bank July lti, 1WA 80. Republican City Commercial State Bank June 2:S. 1903 31. Spriugriew Springview State Bank .... September 25, 1903 32. Sterling- First State Bank January 2s, 1903 Sutherland -Sutherland State Bank March 17. 1903 34. Tamora — Farmers Exchange Bank July 1, l!»0« 85. Verdel — Farmers State Bank May -20, 1903 ?&gt;&lt;&gt;. Vesta— Vesta State Bank February. 14, l'.to:! 37. Wabash— Farmers State Bank September 12. 1903 3&gt;. Whitman - Whitman State Bank April 25, 1903 8». Wisner— Wisner State Bank April 20, 1903 NEW PRIVATE HANKS CHARTERED I)IRIN(. THE YEAR. 1. Garrison -Bank of Garrison March 25, ll»03 2. Reynolds Farmers Bank April 10, 1908 3. Springview- Citizens State Bank October 1!». 1903 s&gt; CHARTERED BUT HAD NOT COMMENCED ItCSINESS NOVEMBER 17. 1H03. 1. Fairmont Fairmont State Bank April 25, lt»&lt;»:i 2. Maxwell-Maxwell State Bank October 19, f903 8. Stockville-Stockville State Bank June 23, 1902 PRIVATE HANKS RK( IIAKTERED 1 . Kagle -Bank of Eagle May 4. 1903 •2. Exeter -Wallace &amp; Co. Bankers Mav 20. l'.»o:! I. Udell— Bank of Odel! A L908 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 HKCAIMTI'LATION Number of banks reporting November 2."&gt;. 1H02 47'.' Number of banks chartered but had not commenced busi November 15, 1HU2 Nmnljer of banks discontinued since November 25, l'.»02. . . Number of banks organized since November 25, I'.»u2 42 Number of banks reporting November 17. li»03 Number of banks chartered but had not commenced busim November 1 7. 1908 3 During the year there has* been but one bank failure among the banks uuder state supervision, viz, the Bank of Verdigre, of Verdigre, Knox county, Nebraska, a small concern with a capi - tal paid iu of $5,000.00 and with deposits amounting to $16,915. - 8l, organized in September lM»y. This bank was closed and taken charge of by State Bunk Examiner Fred Whittemore on January 21, 1903, ami subsequent - ly placed in the hands of Receiver Harry A. Cheney, of Oreigh - ton. The sole ownership and management of this bank had only a few months prior to its failure passed to Mr. L. 1 man. The causes of the failure were incompetency. negligence ami utter disregard of the state banking law on the part of the man - agement. Mr. Messnian is now awaiting trial in the district court of Knox county upon a criminal charge for unlawful conduct in the management of his bank. U«reiver Cheney's last report shows dividends paid to tie tors amounting to 7T&gt; par cent. The following statement shows the bank's resources and liabil - ities, as compiled by examiner in charge. Fred Whittemore, at the date he took on: </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 TWKI.KTH ANNUAL KEl'OKT OF THE STATEMENT Resource?. Loan- hedule) $17,730 -53 ledule) Overdrafts (see schedule ) 1,109 ill Hanking House Furniture and Fixtu 1.500 no iid FixtOff Current Expenses and Taxes paid 100 24 &gt; paid 1 terns (see schedule) 21 00 Casli +45 52 Deficit... Total, -y.. 034 08 Liabiliti Capital stock paid in $ 5,000 00 .Surplus Fund .550 00 Undivided Profits :W0 90 Due to Banks 3,207 32 Deposits ]ti,915 81 Totals - 034 03 In the following tables will be found summaries of the re- sources and liabilities of all bauks in active operation under state supervision compiled from reports submitted in respoi calls from the department (four iu number) during the vear, and summaries of the condition of the incorporated, private am! ings banks on November 17, 1903, compiled separately from re- ports submitted, also an abstract of the reports of the condition of the national banks of the state on November 17, 1903, as compiled by the Comptroller of the Currency: </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SE( KETAKY OF THE STATK HANKING BOAKD 9 ABSTRACT OF THE CONDITION OFTHK STATE. PRIVATE. AND 8AYING3 BA THE STATK OF NEBRASKA. AT THE CLOSE 01 HCH 1 - 1W». TOTAL NDMBIR OK BANKS REPORTING. 484. Re»ouree$. Loans on real estate securlt ( )tlier loans and discounts Overdrafts Stocks, securities: judgments, claims, etc • "&gt;■ »n* 34 Due from national, state, and private banks and ban'- 171 43 Hanking house furniture and fixture! ( )ther real estate Current expenses and taxes paid 43-"&gt;. - Premiums on bonds, etc •"&gt;. 1 - Othei 11 Cash reserve In banks Total Jl To Capital stock paid in Surplus fund ITndiTided profits I Dividends unpaid Deposits subject to check Demand certificates of depi - Time certificates ot deposit s and bills rediscounted 117. 17*; lo Hills payable Total </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 TWELFTH ANNIAI. KKl'ORT OK THK AB.-1EAC -I OF THE, CONDITION OK THE INCORPORATED STATE, PRIVATE. AND SAVINGS BANKS OF THE STATE OK NEBRASKA. AT THK CLOSE OF BU8I- NE8SJUN1 9, IMS. TOTAL NUMBER OF BANKS REPOR1 ING. «H. Resource*. Ixuuis and real estate security . * 4.049.030 MO ( )ther loans and discounts 28,042,767 14 ( Kerdrafts :»3.o:.4 VI Stocks, ncurities, judgment*, claims etc I&gt;ue from national, state and private banks and hankers.. 10 Hanking house furniture and fixtures 1,410,061 •'&gt;!• ( Mlier real estate 374,U"&gt;1 82 Current expenses and taxes paid "&gt;24.810 44 Premiums on bonds, etc :&gt;.3"&gt;3 «■'&gt; ( &gt;t!ier assets *23 3* Cash reserve in banks J.44&gt;3,704 29 Cash reserve in banks 2,4&lt;&gt;3,7O4 2« Total - 7 W» Total " 1 7 H!» Liabilities l.ialrilit Capital stock paid in I 7,970,250 0O Capital stock paid in I 7,976,250 0O Surplus fund 1.401.- Surplus fund 1 .401 . - I'ndivided protits 1 I'ndivided profits Dividends unpaid 1_\'&gt;11 in Dividends unpaid 12."&gt;11 \\&gt; I &gt;eposits subject to cheek 21 ..Vt.'i,331 05 I &gt;e posits subject to check 21 .;VCi,331 05 Demand certificates of deposit 4.8."&gt;3,373 4'&gt; Demand certificates of deposit 4.8."&gt;3,373 4."&gt; Time certificates of deposit 10.270,037 0»&gt; Time certificates of deposit 10.270,037 0»&gt; Due to banks K86.4O7 79 Due to banks tiW.407 79 s and bills rediscounted .V..34(&gt; 3&lt;&gt; Bills payable 102.W1 4X Total WM.tW.717 W» </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 METBKTABY oK STATE IS\NKIN&lt;. K«'.\K1&gt; ABSTRACT OK THE (. ONDXTJON OK THE INCORPORATED 8TATE, PR D 8AV- INGS RANKS on HK STATE ok NEBRASKA. AT THE CLOSE OK H SEPTEMBERS. 1«&lt;B. TOTAL NUMBER OF BANKS REPOR TING, 4M. Re iu&gt; i Loans on real Other loans and discounts &lt; Herd rafts Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . 11 Banking house furniture and fixtures 1,411,507 &lt;* Other real estate Ul :&gt;3 Current expenses and taxes paid 4Th.*,3'J tn&gt; Premiums on bonds, etc otlier assets Cash reserve in banks 1,V&gt;1. Total Liabilit :&lt;•». Capital stock paid in Surplusfund 1.427.*97 9."&gt; Individed profits 1. Dividends unpaid Deposits subject to c-lieck Jl.Ti^.342 *• Demand certificates of deposit —\u ]n Time eet ificates of deposit Due to banks 711,142 4&gt;* Notes aiui bills rediseounted ."► 1 41 Hills payable Total </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 TWELFTH ANNUAL KV THE ABSTRACT OF THE CONDITION OF THE STATE, PRIVATE ANI&gt; BANK-, OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA, Af THE CLOSE OF BUSINE*, NOVEMBER 17, 1KB. TOTAL NUMBEX BANKS REPORTING. 501. Rttourcei. e security I Othei '+3 07 Overdrafts 4.12,!«4 00 Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc »&gt;71,312 07 Due from national. id private banks and bankers . 8,340,2.V&gt; 4+ Hanking house furniture and fixtures 1,410,801 14 Other real estate 343 45 Current expenses and taxes paid Premiums on bonds, etc I, OP - not otherwise enumerated 92,0 rve 2,507,888 91 Tot ;il M8.«72,1M 54 Liabilities Capital stock paid in .1 B,018,100 oO Surplus fund 1,486,277 19 Undivided profits . 1. 93.1, 471 43 Dividends unpaid 12,244 00 Individual deposits, subject 1o check _. Demand certificates of deposit Time certificates of deposit 10,311. &lt;»04 1« Due to banks &lt;i47,: - and bills rediscounts 11W.O73 10 Hills payable 307,151 58 Total M8.972.11W 54 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 RPORATED BANKS. AltSTRACT OF REPORT OF CONDITION OF INCORPORATED BANKS (451 IN NUMBER) OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA, AT THE CLOSE OF BU8INE9! NOVEMBER 17,1903. Resources. Loans on real estate security * 3,121.322 13 &lt; )ther loans and discounts 32 27 Overdrafts 421,355 71 Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc 443. 1 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers.. 7,441.032 74 Hanking house, furniture and fixtures 1.317.K43 s*&gt; Other real estate Current expenses and taxes paid ~&gt;33,014 47 Premium on U. 8. bonds - not otherwise enumerated Cash on hand 2,290, 15H 71 Total t43, 949,72 i 7« Liabi Capital stock paid in $ 7,215.000 00 Surplus 1,295,217 IV* Undivided profits Dividends unpaid J44 im Individual deposits ; subject to check Demand certificates of deposit 4,x."&gt;8,314 71 Time certificates of deposit 9,479.889 4o Due to banks «39, - Notes and bills rediscounted 1»&gt;4.615 10 Bills payable 278,340 34 Total W3.949,723 7ti </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 l'BIVATE BANKS, ABSTRACT OF TB« REI'ORT OF CONDITION OF PRIVATE BANKS (41 IN NUMBER) OF THK iTATE OF NEBRASKA. AT THE CLOSE OT BUSI SnVEMBES 17, 1#B Re»ource». Loans on real estate securitv ♦ .105.474 59 Otlier loans and discounts 2.083,281 7". Overdrafts 31.(538 29 Stocks. securities, judgments, claims, etc 23.989 95 Due from national, state and private lmnks and hankers . 736.895 til Banking house, furniture and fixtures 109.420 24 Otlier real estate 46,536 7 ti Current expenses sad taxes paid 43.053 95 - not otherwise enumerated 17.548 29 Cash on hand 158.507 22 Total ♦ 3.7.V».:{4») iio LiabiHtit*. Capital stock paid in ♦ 592.190 00 Surplus fund 114.5(50 0(&gt; I'ndivided profits 148.1 Deposits suhject to check 1.637.230 85 Demand certificates of deposit 458." Time cert iricates of deposits 734.4.'J2 32 Due to iKinks 7.770 84 and hills rediscounted 34.458 00 Bills payable.... -1124 Total * 3.75»i.34ti 65 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 SAVINGS HANKS. AR&gt;TRACT OK TUB CONDITION OF 8AVISU8 HANKS (8 IK NL'MBEK). OK THI 8TATE OF NEBRASKA AT THE CLOSE OF Bl\- MU EMBER IT, 1908 Ketourcet Loans on real estate security Other loans and discounts IV .029 (V&gt; Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc 204.199 I« Due from national, state and private lwuiks and bankers.. 162.327 iw (tanking l&gt;ouse. furniture and fixtures Other real estate 4ti 49 Current expenses and taxes paid 3.49 I'remiums on D. S. honds and securit ies Cash on hand 74 9* Cash items 1.575 12 Total 29 13 Li ibilitiet. Capital stock paid in Surplus fund I'ndirided profits Deposits suhject to check Demand certificates of deposit 12.704 tut Time certificates of deposit Total 129 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 ABSTRACT OF REPORTS MADE TO THE COMITROLLER OF THECIKRENCY. SHOWING THI CONDITION OFTHENAT - IONAL HANKS IN THE STATE OF NEBRASKA (INCLID - IHG OMAHA ANDLINCOLN) ATTHECLOSEOF Ml SI NESS ON THE 17th DAY OF NOVEMBER. 1903. NIMBKK &lt;&gt;K HANKS REPORTING 1*. Resources. Loans and discounts -Wo. W. 193 1 1 ( Merdrafts 652.354 &lt; 2 honds to secure circulation 4.767.570 00 l»nds to secure deposit 1.X60.000 00 Other honds to secure I*. S. deposits 11.500 00 I'. S. bonds on hand 40.910 00 Premium on 1". S. Ilonris 2ti9.«&gt;«3 37 Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc 2.573.967 76 Hanking house, furniture and fixtures 1.736.323 64 Othe! -.tv and mortgages owned 474.190 23 Due from ot her nat ional hanks . 3.016.996 3"&gt; Due from nd bankers 1.029.149 4!» Due from *. 081.445 25 Internal revenue stamps IS 68 Checks and other cash items 658.403 41 Exchange for clearing house 935.806 48 s of other national hanks 383.53100 Fractional paper currency, nickels and cents 20.547 49 Specie 3,351,466 84 Legal tender notes 2.7.VJ.690 00 Five per cent, redemption fund 237.763 5»i Due from V. S. Tieasurer 11.109 70 Total -"-.537.61437 Liabilities Capital stock paid in $10,390,000 00 Surplus fund 2.418,950 00 Cndivlded profits, less expense 1.460,442 83 National bank notes outstanding 4.756.632 50 Due to other national banks 6.637.185 00 Due to state and private banks and bankers 6.774,860 30 Due to trust companies and savings banks 315.345 7."&gt; Due to approved reserve agents 19,460 96 Dividends unpaid 5.024 50 Individual deposits 43.495.615 47 deposits 1.563.264 73 Deposits of I*. S. disbursing officers 264.603 85 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Notes mikI bills ri'discountefl 43. i Hills payable Other liabilities Total '4 37 Below is ii statement of total deposits shown bv t! tins department in incorporated, private, and savings hanks under state supervision, as shown by annual reports of such including the total amount of di in hanks placed in the hands of receivers in the respective jean: By comparison of returns from the 601 hanks repoi November IT. 190S, with those &lt;»f a year ago r \ed that there lias been an increase in number of reporting hanks • and a net increase of s-_'. &lt; .t4T,"Tn. l»; in The increase of the principal item- Loans and discounts *1 -Ii and due from hanks . ;t-_\o&lt;;. The sources from which loanable funds were augmented during the year were as follows: Capital sto&lt; Barplni and undivided ]&gt;rotii- Tlie items of notes and bills redisconnted and bills were reduced to the extent .tu.25. The total amount of d&lt; ted in state ban (i"3.S s 2.24 to the credit &lt;&gt;f 11&lt;"&gt;.4S4 di 2 » KAK h» i in 1892 18»5 1896 1898 1899 1!KK) 1W1 1902 1903 $ 71,007 1» -M7i 79 197 1,1" 144.:&gt;OT 34 !O (Mi ■r&gt; &lt;tl 10&lt; 19o.770 70 16.9! $-J4 18.0" I 14 II 1^ 37,0- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 TWELFTH ANNL'AI. KKI'oKT "K THE $318.27 to the credit of each depositor at&gt; against 97,618 deposi - with an average deposit of $353.45 each a year ago. Amount of average deposit per capita of entire population of the state based upon the last cen .67 as against $32.27 a year ago. The amount of deposit per capita of entire population of state in national ban igainst $61.88 a year ago. Amount of deposit per capita of population of state in all banks of Nebraska $'.«&gt;. 00 as agai ir ago. Average reserve held by state banks 29.95 per cent, as against ' per cent, a year ago. Legal requirement is 15 per cent. A\ e national banks percent, of total deposits in available funds 33.65 per cent, as against 34.35 per cent, a vear ago. Notwithstanding the ii a deposits shown by the returns of November 17. 1903, over that of a year ago this item readied the maximum for the year and the high water mark during the existence of state bank supervision on September 5, 1903, when total deposits amounted 101,448.47' Detailed reports of the condition of the several banks in active operation on November 17, 1903, and the reports of the condi - tion on December 81, 1903, of banks placed in the hands of re - nce July 1. 1 ( .K)1 will be found on following pagi this report. A recent decision of the district court of Platte county render - ed in a case wherein Peter Phillips was plaintiff and Louis Halm a director of the defunct Platte Valley State Bank of Bellwood, was defendant, emphasizes the recommendations contained in my former annual reports with reference to the responsibilities and duties of bank directors. I desire to repeat that I would recommend such an amendment to the state banking act as will make it compulsory for any one before becoming a director of a state bank to be a subscriber to apital stock to such an amount that their own interests will demand the careful investigation and supervision of the af- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 fairs of the institution that should be exercised by its board of directors. The decision just referred to is significant of the personal lia - bilities to which directors are subject by neglecting their duties in the management and control of the affairs of their banks. They owe it to thfimnlTOi as well as to the deposito a careful and strict supervision of the affairs of the institutions with which other peoples money is entrusted. A copy of the report of the eaec as published in the Lincoln Trade Review follow In district court at Columbus, Platte county, an important decision was handed down last week. ••The court instructed a verdict for $; the plaintiff in the suit brought by Peter Phillips, a Butler county farmer, against Louis Halm, a director of the Bell wood bunk, which failed in .January. 1 ( .M&gt;2. Halm ha- I 8 published n the previous month certifying the bank to be in &gt;und condition, and Phillips alleged that upon the strength of th port he deposited in the bank during the months of !)• 1901, and -lunuar.-, 1909, sums of money aggregating i The testimony of Mr. Halm went to show that even had be cited due caution in keeping posted on the bank's affairs, hi not the only one misled by the artful work of the men responsi - ble for the failure, and among others were practical bush The case has attracted able attention throughout the .state and will probably b One of the questions in - volved is the extent of responsibility of bank directors in the act - ual business management of bank affairs, and the pit - diet is one to make directors duly cautious in the future about placing their names to instruments purporting to be a true report of the condition of their bank Through examiners' reports and otherwise the attention of the department has at different times during the past year been call - ed to cases where purchasers of banks operated by individuals </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 ami partner* are continuing tlie business under the chart to the original owners. The right to succession of such banks was questioned by the trtment and a case in point was brought to the attention of the Attorney (General with a request for his official opinion in the prem i Bv that official s opinion rendei ii\ of which follows, it is observed that the pure ' banks operated by individuals are not permitted under the law to continue the business under chart I to prior owner. In my opinion the hum would hold good in the case of the transfer of the interest of a partner or partners operating an unincorporated bank. State of Nebraska, Office of Attorney General E. Royse. 1 tarv of the State Banking Board Lincoln, Nebraska Dear Sir: I ha\ I'd vour letter as follows •■ It appears from a recent examination of a private banking institution, that the owner of said bank died some four jo. His son states that the bank was willed to him - self and his brother, who have since been operating it, but that the details oi rring the same to them, have urried out. Th fl the identity somewhat ob - scure and pn n as to who is responsible for the liabilities of the bank. '•In the event of the death of the owner of a private bank. who, if anyone in your opinion, has authority to continue busi- If in your opinion this bank is not being conducted with proper authority, what steps should be taken in the matter at this time! My opinion in n !o your inquiric- 'How A banking business in tl bv a Lincoln. March 31, 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 IAKV Ot III ..\KI&gt; state bank without a charter from tl banking board. Under section 5, ehapto inpiled Btatutea, an individual person may obtain a charter to do a banking business. When an individual procures a charter, it authorizes him alone to do a banking boi tid when he dies, the righl I net the enterprise under the charter is at an end. A private individual who conducts a bank is not a corporation and his entorpr on the same footing as to succession as that &lt;1 in the bus banking. A corporation may coml banking business until the end of the period fixed b &gt;rter, but the death of an individual banker terminates the right to carry on the business authorized 1&gt;\ the charter. The prin 1 as been stated as follow "It is sufficient to mention one indispensible character; - corporation to show that an individual banker cannot be one; and that is, its principle i i and perpetuity for the ]■• of existence assigned to it by Itor A pr inker under the act to authorize the business of banking, and tin ions acts amending the same, has no more the chant poration than a merchant, a lawyer or an other indivjdi immJord, s /&gt;W&lt;.. i V. ) The business of banking by au individual, bv wl lame it may be carried on. 1 intents and purposes, hU and individual affair, as much as any other trai la- mav be engaged.'" hi r. Ha The same rule \ in Hallrtt &gt;■. It fiari It is therefore clear to mv mind that au individual bank not a corporation. The legatees under the will of I the bank in question have no authority to conduct a banking buei - l&gt;v virtue of the charter issued In my judg - ment they have been conducting the bank in violation of law, and I am of the opinion that the bank should b they immediately </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 according to the provisions of the banking act Very respectfully, F. N. Trout . 1 Horn ' y General. Numerous applications having been made to the department by banks for instructions how to proceed to extend their coporate existence prior to the expiration thereof, a communication was addressed to the Attorney General by the Secretary asking his opinion as to whether or not the corporate existence of a bank operating under the laws or the state can be legally extended by amending its articles of incorporation. A copy of his written opinion in answer thereto follows: State of Nebraska, Office of Attorney General Lincoln. February !♦, 1HU4. £. Royse, Esq., Secretary State Banking Board. Lincoln, Nebraska Dear Sir I have received your letter making the following inquiry: "Will you please favor this Department with your written opinion as to whether or not the stockholders of an incorporated bank operating under the laws of this state, can, by resolution or written consent, with the approval of the state banking board, prior to the termination of its corporate existence, legally extend its period of succession by amending its articles of incorporation, and continue under the charter previously issued by the state banking board '." Under the corporation act of this state the first of the enumer - ated powers conferred by statute is 'Ho have succession by its corporate name.'" Compiled Statute*, ek. VI. mc. I !\. The notice of incorporation must state "the time of commencement and termination of the corporation." 1 Compiled Statutes, ch. Jf&gt;. tee. 111. The statute further provides: </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 ••Every change in the above matters shall be recorded and published iu the same manner as the original articles are requir - ed by law." Compiled Statute, eh. I'J, 8&amp;- . / It is apparent the statute contemplates that corpora 1 shall have succession; that the articles of incorporation shall the time of commencement and termination of the corporation and that the articles of incoi poration may be changed. I have been unable to find in the constitution or statutes anv limitation upon the period of existence of the corporation. The qu&lt; of fixing this period has therefore been left to the corporation it - self. Having power, as shown by statute, to fix the peri' its existence, it may extend such period bj amending its articles of incorporation, since it is to have succession by its corporate name. It is apparent however that this power to amend the articles must be exercised before the original term has expired. I am therefore of the opinion that the stockholders of an in - corporated bank mjiy, before expiration of its chart' ;d its corporate existence by legal and valid amendment to the original articles of incorporation. F. N. Prout Attorn?!/ Of Through the courtesy of Hon. W. (i. Hastings, member of the Supreme Court Commission of Nebraska, I am permitted to incorporate in this report a paper read by him before the ka Bank' &lt;iation at Lincoln last October, entitled, ••Kr cent Legal Decisions of Interest to Hankers, " as follow The task of preparing a 20-minute paper on recent legal di of interest to bankers requires first of all a determination what ones shall be included. The legal i - in Eng lish speaking countries reported since July. 1909, nunil thing orer 18,000. Of these a little more than one in a hun - dred are digested in the Current American Digest under the of -'Hanks and Banking.' 1 The cross-references, however. Yerv ri'sjii'ftfully </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 uliug hare to do with about three tin nanv more, particularly those under the title of "Bills and Vat But is one at liberty to assume that legal decisions of int ■ to bankers are to be found solely under that head and its e The banker was surely a citi/.eu before he embarked in his present but Surelv like other citizens, he feels that our government, that universal guarantee of all his rights of per - son and property, which alone renders, not only his business, but his domestic tranquil it v and comfort, possible, is an interest above that of the busin f. Of the 486 reported cases, dec by the United States Supreme Court, at its last annual term, only three are indexed under the head of ••Hank and Banking." Earl&gt; Sup. C't. Ii. '2bi. 1&gt; V I . S. 4 -2. was a ease holding that the fact that a bank was insolvent at the time of a transfer of stock in it, if not known to either party, would not of itself render the transfer fraudulent. Eastman vs. Stat&lt;' of Iowa. 23 Sup. Ct. Rep. 2 _'2O. held an Iowa statu - te forbidding the reception of deposits by any officer of a bank while knowing it to be insolvent, and fixing a penalty for such action, to be void so far as an attempted application to the ] dent of a national bank was concerned. It was held that the Iowa legislature was powerless to prescribe anv conditioi which the national banks should receive deposit* and that a con viction of the bank's president on this Iowa statute was void. It ield to be "not competent f&lt; legislatures to intei whether with ho- dlv intentions, with national banks or their ottio the ]&gt;owers bestowed niion them by the general government." The other case. 1S°«. I". S. 242. 2:'&gt; Sup. C. B I, Kankin vs. Fidelity Insurance &amp; Trust A: Safe ijiany. is a holding that the pledgee of national bank stock, which he took a collateral security fora loan, is not cli with the personal liability for the debts of the bank which is imposed upon their stockholders "unless he has become the al owner of the shares in fact or has held himself out to be •vuier, ti ping himself to deiiv hi- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 ltv. 1 hose are all tht 1 cases which arc thought u of tlif Supreme Court reporter to directly concern hanks and banking, but at the same term of the Federal Supi ;irt it held in Hawaii vs. Maukichi that the pro -titution with reference to trial by jury have no applies to tilt* Hawaiian Islands, and by the same reasoning they would have none at least bv virtue of their own effect, and in the ice of congressional legislation in the Philippine Island Porto Rieo. Following this decision, as it was bound the Supreme Court of the Philippine Islands held that the I stitution was not extended over Paris, and that they were like the Hawaiian-, simply subji • the legislation of Had thi- tntional no interest for bank&lt; If the popular ideas of the luxury with which bank' travel are in any -ion of I mrts in the Pullman Palace Car Company vs. Match would certainly be of intc The banker would wish to know whether his aluables were insured agaii ly theft while In 'j", v ~ ng the privilege ;. in one of the compa The urt holds that tl h implied contract of insur - lt flatly repudiat* ;thority of our state in the one which is cited to uphold such a liability. P ill In oinpanv vs. I,. I'KoMI'T I A - which directly concern bankers have within the past 3 the Supreme Court of N and among these i&gt; Kdmiston vs. Ilerpolsheimer, 92 N. VV. 138; this i- Supreme Court and resulted each time in a holding that a check must be presented on the day after it d. if all pa! in the ■ longer at the holder's risk. Herpolsheinier &amp; Company batl ceired a check for s -_ &gt; Ol».tc ) on the Merchants Bank in payment of their account against .1. H. 1 1 and 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 next day with the American Exchange bank. The latter bank did not present it on that day, but put it in the clearing house. The next day was Sunday and the day following Decoration day. and on May 31st the Merchant** Bank failed to open. Consequently the check could not be presented; nothing was ever realised out of the Merchants Bank. Herpolsheinier «fc Co. sued Edmiston for the amount of the check and recovered judgment in the dis - trict court on the ground that their action had been in accordance with business usage; the Exchange Bank had placed the check with its others in the clearing house and in ordinary couisc of business it would have been presented on the .Hist had the Mer - chant! Bank opened that day. The district court held that this usage of business was sufficiently established to excuse the fail - ure to comply with the general rule that checks must be prt ed on the day following their acquirineut if the drawee bank is in the same town. In the Supreme Court it was conceded, as it must be, that the general rule requires, where all of the parties reside in the same place that a check be presented not later than the close of the next business day after it is received or the hold - er must bear any lows which occurs from its non-presentation. It was urged, however, and the authority of the Supreme Court of Pa. cited, that the real rule is that the holder has a reason- able time within which to present his check, and if he does pre - sent it within such a reasonable time he will not be chargeable with loss by reason of failing to get it then- sooner. It was onceded that in the absence of any special circumstance making a further delay reasonable the one day rule prevailed; but it was urged that where the usage of a clearing house was well estab - ished and must have been well known to all of the parties, and it was the ordinary ami usual business agency for the presentation of hecks, all checks should be held to be drawn with such usage in "iew and compliance with such usage should be considered sufti - •ient diligence. The court declined to accept this argument and after two hearings decided to abide by the one day rule not - withstanding the earnest and brilliant argument in the dist </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 KCRKTARY OF THK 8TATK ing opinion of Judge Sedgwick. The rule adopted by the court in simple and clear at all events. It is that if you are in the name town where the bank is you must pr&gt; k on the day you get it or the next. If you carry it longer you take the risk of a failure of the bank. This decision will hardly result in preventing the adoption of the clearing hoi igent for the presentation of ch&lt; Sooner or later it is probable that such u nized as reasonable bee nearly universal Checks will be presumed to have been drawn with such usage in view and the delivery of a check be held tantamount to an e\ mi- - sion to use such a method of presentation. I.VIILK INSTRUMENTS LAW It is to be saiJ that the negotiable instruments law which been adopted in so many oT the states, and which the Banker's '■iation of Nebraska so ably championed at t li • of our legislature, provides for a reasonable time for the pn tation of checks and drafts and was drawn with a view ing such extension of time where presentation through a clearing house as an established method. If in no other way we hope presently to have this change introduced in Nebraska by means of a negotiable instrument law. Another case in which the Nebraska Supreme Court found it necessary to deal with a much disputed question in banking law Hoffman vs. American Exchange Bank, 90 N. W. Rep. 112. Hoffman was disbursing agent for the executor of an Elizabethtown, Pa. One of the heirs was Peter W. Bruhaker. Two dividends had been paid him and a third was ordered. Hoff - man could not find Brubaker at his former address. Inquiries were unanswered. Finally a letter came asking for li and requesting that it be sent to Lincoln. Hoffman made ceipt and release of further claim for the money and sent it to Lincoln to !&gt;• ary public. In due time it came back to Eliza! with the name of Peter Bra baker and purported to have been acknowledged by him before Walter A. Leese a notary of thi&lt; citv. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 THR Hoffman purchased a draft in Elizabethtown payable to his own order, endorsed it to the order of Peter W. Hrubaker and sent it to Lincoln, addressed in care of Walter A. Leese. It was d by the American Exchange Bank for a person identified by Mr. Leese as Peter W. Brabaker. About eigbjt month* later the real Peter W. Brubaker turned up in Elizabcthtown, l'a., and wanted hi* money. Confronted with the cancelled draft, he at once declared that he had never been in Lincoln in his life ami that at the date of the transactions in Lincoln he was at work on a farm near Evansville, Indiana. This he was able to substantiate. and Hoffman was compelled to pay him. Then Hoffman brought suit against the American Exchange National Bank for the amount of the draft, claiming that it had been j&gt;aid on a forged endorsement and the right of the money was in himself. This contention the district judge. Homes, re - ain. He said that Hoffman had negligently supplied an ii with tlie means of defrauding and should himself bear the Hoffman took the case to the Supreme Court where it was twice heard. Our court was not full v satisfied with its first con- clusion that the distrct court was right and granted a re-hearing. This resulted, however, in the same conclusion. It was decided that Hoffman having himself procured the false Brubaker to ex - ecute a n id having himself in response to the release sent the draft to the impostor, could not complain of any bank for doing precisely as Hoffman requested to be done, and paving the money to the swindler. One difficulty in this and simiiar cases is to distinguish it from i here the swindler perpetrates one fraud on the maker of the draft and another on the purcl the numer - ous instances where a loaning agent gets a draft sent him for some imaginary borrower, endorsee the draft himself in that bor - oame and gets the money on it. In that case the bank !&lt;■ draft has to make good r wner. It is </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 not paving the money t&lt;&gt; an n intended by the remitti have it. A different deception is successfully practiced on the paving bank from that which i against th&lt; therefor the hank cannot shelter itself behind his error. The case of Logan vs. The Nebraska Mnline l'low Company, 92 N- W. Rep. 128 and 83 N. W. Rep. 112S. first decided in October, l ( .t02. »nd again on rehearing in March, together vrith the Federal Court cases which were passed upon while it ing on and which were finally held to determine it. are of ; est to bankers perhaps more than to most citi cerned with titles and the validn depending upon them. It is a holding that conditional sale with one who becomes an adjuged bankrupt, where the &lt; record, are void as against his trustee in bankruptcy. The ! Company lias -old some *2.^M) worth of pi taken his notes for them and by the contract title should until the notes were paid and if the purchaser became his right of | n should cease at one. became due the purchaser tiled a voluntary petition in bankru The l'low Company at once replevined the The tr in bankruptcy was appointed about a month later and ed in the suit. The contract had never been placi The district court held in accordance with the only Fedi then decided. In re New York Economical 1'rintii p C. A. 1 ;&gt;.'&gt;. that the title remained in the Plow Company and that the trustee's rights were subject to the company's alt! the contract was not of record. The trustee appealed tl our Supreme Court. While it was pending four cases cided in the federal, circuit and district coi a trustee in bankruptcy had all the rights of a levying en in possession and that his titli k and ta ofthe date of the tiling of the petition in bankruptcy us, In re l'ekin I .50C.C A. '2~&gt;~. wa^ in ' VALIDITY OK COXTR </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 from this state. The Federal Supreme Court meanwhile, without deciding this express question as to the trustee's rights against an unrecorded contract, had held in Mueller vs. Nugent, 22 Sup. Court. Rep. 269, 184 V. S. 1. that the filing of a petition in bankruptcy was a caveat to all the world as to the insolvent's property and equivalent to an attachment or an injunction. It was held, therefore, that the trustee could hold the plows and the manufacturing company could only prove up its claim on the notes against the bankrupt's estate. Another case of interest and of importance to any one holding or giving guaranteed commercial paper in this state is the very recent one of Lemmert vs. Guthrie Bros., 96 N. W. 104H. The defaulting maker of the note in question was a firm of bankers, but the only point determined in the case is the extent to which the guarantor of payment on a note is relieved by a failure to notify him of the principal's default. Guthrie Bros, had for ac - commodation guaranteed payment of a machine note of Meek it Briggs, bankers and brick manufacturers of Superior. The ma - chine company sold the note to one of its own officers who laid it away and went off to Europe. It was not found until sometime after his return when it was eighteen months past due and Meek ft Briggs had failed for something like *lf&gt;0.000.00. Suit was brought against Guthrie Bros, and they defended on several grounds, one of which was the failure to notify them of the non - payment of the note by Meek &amp; Briggs, who at the time of its maturity were entirely solvent. This defense our court pro - nounced good, following the great weight of authority, though some late cases, and one of them in Nebraska, hold that one who guarantees the doing of a specific thing at a specific time must at his peril see that it is done and no notice is necessary to fix his liability. In the case of a promissory note, however, it seems much more just to hold that a reasonable regard for the guarantor's safety is required of the payee and that he must notify the guarantor within a reasonable time or the latter will be dis </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 charged to the extent that he is damaged by failure to get the Dotice . HPANY A KAN K The case of Hamilton County Bank vs. American Loan A Trust Co., i)2N. W. 139, had for its main question simply, was the American Loan &amp; Trust Company a bank? If it was, its stockholders were under the liability to double the amount of stock held which is prescribed against bank stockholders in the Nebraska State Constitution (Sec. 7, Art. II bi. It was found that the articles of the corporation provided for making loans, buying and selling commercial paper, borrowing money and is suing its own obligations for it and receiving money on deposit and executing trusts. It was found to have done all I things, and sold exchange on other cities as a part of such busi - ness. This was held to make it a bank though it called itself a loan and trust company and although it transferred it* deposits subject to check to another organization made up largely of its own officers, The American Savings Bank, when the pn banking law of this state went into effect. The articles of incor - poration set a limit upon its indebtedness, but expressly ex ed deposits from such limit. The court holds, adopting the opinion of Judge Kirkpatrick, that it was a "banking institution" within the meaning of the state constitution, and the stockholders liable in doable the amount of their stock. Of the recent cases relating directly to banks, many are meiely a reiteration of familiar doctrines. In the case of Falls City State Bank vs. Wehrli, 83 N. W. Rep. 994, the bank had agreed with a customer, Miller, to advance him money to buy a carload of horses, he to turn in a draft with his bill of lading when he shipped the horses. He turned in his draft and it was paid before some of the checks for the horses were presented. The bank applied the proceeds of the draft in part to the pay - ment of an old claim against Miller and refused to honor a check given by him to Wehrli for a horse. Wehrli sued for the amount of his check and was given judgment under the rale of </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 our state that the payee of a check has an action against the drawer if the money is still there. Of the cases in other courts than the Federal Supreme Court and that of Nebraika, there ie not much space to speak. Many of them are of much interest. The Missouri case of the First National Bank vs. American National Bank. 7"2 S. W. 1&lt; &gt;."&gt;&lt;♦, is an interesting example of the legal doctrine that estoppel cannot confer power. The American Bank had agreed, in return for certain accommodations, that a draft drawn upon one of its cus tomers should be paid. The National Bank act does not authorize such a use of a national bank's credit. The First Na - tional carried out its part of the agreement, but the court held that no estoppel arose which prevented the American Bank from pleading its want of power to make the agreement. The First National Bank was denied a recovery. The California case of l'nllen vs. l'lacer Co. Bank is of much interest in this state. It illustrates the difficulties which are liable to arise in applying two separate doctrines of the law. There is a tloctrire in this state that a check operates as an as - signment of the fund ou deposit if there is one, and gives the holder a right of action againet the bank, as we have seen in Wehrli's case. It is also a doctrine of our law that a gift is not completed till the thing is delivered. In the California c check for *1,(MMMM) was given by a lather to his son with a re - qnest that it be not presented till after the father's then expect - ed death. The father did not die until ten months later. The morning after his death the son presented the check and it was paid although the bank's officers were aware of the Baker's death. The administrator sued for the $1,000.00 on the ground that having knowledge of the maker's death, there was no au - thority iu the bank to pay the money on the check. The trial court held tl at the bank was not bound to pay the money again. The California Supreme Court so held at first in one of its de partments. A rehearing before the whole court in bane was ob - tained and finally the doctrine that there must he a completed gift </seg>
            <seg id="p033">to carrv title was held to prev&amp;il. The bank was con pay the money again to the administrator. Probably in I the rule that a check is an assignment of money actaally in the bank to the makers credit when it fa presented, would beapp but if the bauker knows that the maker is dead, it will In- to refuse payment. The case of Crocker Woolworth National Bank ad a Hank of San Francisco, 73 l'ac. Rep. 4.V). decided by the preme Court of California, July 14th, last, is of deep iuten members of the Clearing lion-' On December 9th, 1896, the Hank of Woodland sold to A. EL 1 &gt;ean a draft for $12.&lt;&gt;0 on the Crocker Woolworth National Hank in San Francisco. On December 17th, with its date changed to December 13th and its amount raised to Dean deposited this draft, bearing his unrestricted end.. in the Nevada National Hank. He got only a provisional c on his pass book for its amount. The same dav the Ne Hank put it in the clearing 1 Section with an cud ment such as the clearing house rules required --pav tin clearing house only" and with no other restrictions. It m cepted with other clearings by the ('nx-ker Woolworth I'. The next morning, the 18th. Dean drew out the money by &lt; on the Nevada Hank and left for parts unknown. Tin Woolworth Bank on January 1st, sent its statement to the Hank of Woodland and were- at once informed of the raised draft. January 3rd demand was made on the Nevada Hank for the inonev and return of the draft otfered. It was refused ami suit begun by Crocker Woolworth Bank for the inonev. The Cali - fornia Supreme Court ret allow the recovery of the nw It says that the payment was assented to by the drawee for fif - teen days and until after the Nevada Bank had paid out the money and the latter is not liable. It had failed in no duty and the law would leave the parties as they were. This result seems so contrary to the general sense of ji, fair dealing that if it is the law then the clearing house should </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 change its/riles. Tlie draft was preseir te Nevada Hank bearing general endorseaieat. There was nothing to apprise any one t li nt the latter bank claimed to be only an agent. Of &lt; • if there had been any one paying the draft, would have under - stood tiiat the Nevada Bunk would not be liable after it paid the money to its principal. Of coarse, too, the drawee \h presumed to know the signatwi indent. It is not ordinarily Lined to know whether drafts have been raised in amount. This draft the Nevada Bank was handling as owner. In present - ed procuring its payment as owner the latter bank in ordi - nary bu&gt; aouUI be understood to assert the genuineness of the draft. If such a result does not follow from a clearing tation, then the rules of the clearing hi tion should be- changed to make it ■ We lia\e wen that with all the bnisness they do, all of it in volving credit on one side or both of each transaction, the- bank - i-h. contribute little more than a hundredth part of the litigation of the English speaking world. The tor their comparative immunity from litigatioi the rules of law and the decisions of the courts on this topic so exactly follow the current opinion and - if justice of the bankers themselves. They and the lav harmony. This last decision, like that of Herpolsheimer &amp; &lt; Kdmiuston. tion and it should be either changed by tin' courts or its effect ren rule of the clearing hou- In conclusion I thank the members of the Banking Board for their com aent, their prompt and careful deration of all ma bmitted for their adjudication. their valuable counsel and timely advice in the administration of fairs of the department. To the bankers of ■ I acknowledge my grateful ap - preciation of their tion in maintaining the efficient :n by their cheerful compliance and prompt acquiescence in all rules and instructions issued by the department, and their manifest interest in the promotion of state bank supervision. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">BECRBTABY OF 35 IK'l the I par tin I acknowledge- the faithful service of the State Hank Exanii '•s, the prompt and efficient performance of the di. rned in. their lovaltv to the interest of the department appreciate the valuable services of the members of tli. tineiit force, the efficient and systematic manner in which v have disposed of the greatly increased volume of office work. Very respectfully submitted, E. ROYSE, - te Banking Board </seg>
            <seg id="p036">• </seg>
            <seg id="p037">KWIHG COWDITIOH OW BAHKfl PLACID IN THE H\ )K RKCK1VKRS SIB&gt;K jUKXT TO JULY 1. 1901. WMVO DECEMBER :il l!"03. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">5 g g : :|tl EJ : : . 2§ to • ■ as co . ' Hm • •* «. : » : • eg© • S | • 5 — r- • oc • • 30 I- IO • 94 • ■ t- TO • — ■ i-T— r ! «T • • of «» ■ •» • : • O r- (M r» «f jm go -r I «w utm*- i - m -^ f- • OC * ' 30 Q© T ■ • ■ *H 40-0 O3 wm • r *XJ i-T— r ! m • • a» «T • • • pJ • • .... . .iO • " - -as • • C4 • • •■*■ - : : : 8 S "S §2 : : : 5 § :R &lt;o m • • _ o in ■ to •» ' ' '• m &lt;* '• no t o — &lt; oo : ~5 ~ o o CM o _ O ; re Q » s^ * © • in o: •* Q i- r: • — • &amp;l -r ■» O^ ; e*f -o" of • ■ 8 i- s ■ r^ • &lt;• ■ «• OS -* ■ 2 r^ »O • OS ss — ' • oT ■ «e - 3 57 as a 0C TO C-» t- \ 8 a g i i IS : *• «&amp; • • • • t ~r i &gt;m «o — x « o I 1 o~ I — -f«o "J 2 O Q «" Tr-i:o*l » — « r- CD C -f O I !• &lt;O &lt;C aOOO'^C '35O "~ "~ "— ■*j»Q--r^t-!- o; r: r r- l~ O 1" O C^ Ctr: — i-^-Hm* :*: O . . . . • • i II !i z e : § : f B a : * : *i s| IS I | \l\\t 1 1 !l !» If \ »1 8 S *l I til 1 If •§ii- ~-s o ljit t E o "• E i o 1 ' «2og«S.»3SS*l« 1 = 52 S 2 | = = 5 5 2Sx «««j CM IO X -T C — r •* «» 5£33S5|5 ■^ q -r * i r- O **■ ~ P4 * -r o •^ i _ . r- to a: ro r; &lt;o -t r: * 'TOO OC ~ a — — i o </seg>
            <seg id="p039">r « i i- ?i - 5 ~i T Z- — &gt;o r- -* — r- O r * «o &gt;a £ n i n -^ - ! M m ■ r. J H A x 1 3 •■: ? S s &lt; i r-" — 1 fr -*- X &gt;• ,1(1 f&gt; x 1 ■ &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p040">1 i rt x i — ' 9&lt;O • • i- - o rt • •r-ia • • im — - ■ o ■ • r- — -3 "So o — ■ -: So ■ »(-5r: nSn ■a t-o») a» o.Not ; c^J = •" -o; O~* x — 11 ti M M i I • (-4 i i ? * I s i i O i S 1 js « i S I * z -15 ■ B 5 o ?! ■Si Q 1 COM OS S IM ?» 3". U5 -I- 3S e^-^«ot- o im — t- 3oir-ee M MNr- ©"«O" «5 ■* CM • " CM (X CD ""CM I B • o :x -5 m — « — i-rt « r- — — r- n j O — » KCOU3 91 -r tr ■+ r- O r^ ■» -* — r- — Sao — to -* m ■ : ■ s ■ i : 2 . : : : S : . : : : : 2 o . iii if r ! = s j B Nil ; « : : : S»o« I ; Hi! I : : : o | £ H *1 iflJ ijijif] iii i : : ; s ; i ! j M | ] U • 1 1 1 ! I e |U j j j I Mi ||! I : i|§ i ! 3 i ; I ; : ■ i E!!ljj!ji{jj ° t : : « i i ] I I : 2 : : : ill iilJH i HUH i IaSSH= jot 8 3» "&lt; .3 £ S || |=|l=a ■ S 2 S </seg>
            <seg id="p041">= 5 32835 2?, c s. ■' H 25 x •4 s r- t-~ •■: &gt;-: n ■» a ; i M ! II Ml \\Ush i i 1 1 ■ a B 5 5. 5 * : - ft = S H a • i| 3 1 1 ll \i\n\" 2 a J x ■&lt; aa *• ! : ! I III 1 jjj j : : : : • : f | S . m m fill ! * 3 - — - T : . i : ■ : ■ s fife i| ■ | Il ;i Ii i g=f= SB q 5 • ■ — ■ s3 3 8e ___^ z — - - — -z. i i 1 B C * . Iff ;l! ' 1 ill = -2 .-a « O 2. 1 '-j! 2 i </seg>
            <seg id="p042">— m 3E at n 9 r- = CM -CM oc ■ I- C. — CI Or- m * 94 CO 1&gt; 8 S3 •CiO ' - «3 • -r i- IN 3 u m • I i I I s O S M I k » I y - i &amp; j * I * I* I* , tt«r: cr — m -i — : — C= — — — ■ ? i — Ml i a-. — — — ?i -r - _ - : : : : : i I ;! II : i 1&lt; i * : - 5 5 S-li i = S S III | e-S 5 « • a B "^ = £ * I O U Sm : U T3&lt;r :n- -5 vr.i- ~ Z. _ — " - c - I — • : i ■ i ■ t ~ ; : : — : ~ - - n« i j I i M i i|! fii I i-iil I III :=ss t :5§5 i i j j : 15! i |f;-| sjlf ! » I </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 i?i;z; |$ i2&lt; = o 3 i - r - • I :! •M — S - in » — ' — &gt;d e*T I - I I * 3 I S 1 c c I OS 2 p ° ft - h C M H H - a. as O 2 8 I : : : i '. '. ' S I U i it &gt; i — • : : I : : i m si! - • — = u - -»■ - pill! i — </seg>
            <seg id="p044">IH : i|- 1 I 1 ■ • : : : | § 2 3 i € I g I ■ o S 1 1 1 git?: to I s I i Z s t * s LU !; = ■ = I % I S O 0 i" fe S I e 4 &gt; I 8 | a : I ; I a *• ■*O3 33 i-i O ■"" • oc o '" &gt;c o en -r — 3". &gt;O O O M m^h c x; ?&gt; — oa o r- r&lt; S3 S" 1 s -* i- — •0 &gt;r — &lt;«• «» I* T. . : . b • : : : £ . . ; ; . k II ill i : : :|i : : : :*; S \ : : c c "S • : ■ 5 e - • : « t 111 j {Mill! I : • • I 1 - 1 1 i - 1 i - lil If BO &lt; - p ... : ! : ': : i : I : : : ; : ■:•!:::&gt;:: : i "i [ 1 1 i | i j* ; j M ::::.: 3 :: : : : ::::.: S :: : : : I : . '. '. . '. w . ' ' o . : • t I U : : : : : :l : : : 1 1 k 1 I | .. : ■ I : 1 I : 1 ■ i Ss :V|j|=l::« H |ti&gt;i 1 ; I ! • S : « e -- « -f : -s : : « : | : iiifli! S| l!lli a .ll|lill-j s siSillils8:{3i Sjaoo- .a Jaxi^K J gSESS jos3o!»« 'ISII §s3ss r ss </seg>
            <seg id="p045">&lt;J •r oocof « "OMOCO OS Tl «o~ oo ion 10 c 5C O — ?l OS iC"**t •a - - 3 ; ; ijj : ■ £ '■ : si is "i I iHli? 1 ItllHI I lil:; a l 1 S2* ® o §2 385133 -S3 IS z : i u : : : S : ; 8 | i \ \1\ i iis 8 I a a -&gt;» s s — - — s &lt; — 1 2 3 £ H £ - _ z 2 ; S | 5 — - ! ■ - » * : U ! :I_ 1| 11 i : Si ■ £3 Z s " -9 - - III 3 U r _ t s i - ri x n *■ «• ~ 7 T T 7T: : : . • ■ • -x — ? S B % — - a = - ■ . a • • 2 : : : a E S : : : 9 5 3 * : . : 1 : ■ ■ ■ i. : : :f = Ji|l! -II llilifi 1 - 3 3 - 3 2 y r. &lt; r. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">I* ■ 1 ■«; • &lt; j -Z • • ■ - o • -r • c: ■ f^ * n '■ OS IC — ir- iS 30 «* • O35 • SS : 2g : — CO era &lt;O « 10 90NM O O6 ' .« ■ 00 - . a, 10 • 1 — St. - M I- e r- a 35 « cm -r t- co • • ■*- «• • • ;8 ■ »o • Ctt PS : S • Is 1 • I X - - - - M O E j - --r^ra.mr-MJ &lt; - -.c — — -r i ~ - ef "; si « » ■ I j =" : : C ■ * }! 1 - III : ; if j : i.-a :f ; : | j : :| I s i|| = ;• I i I I : ' tlill! hi'! Ill i i 1 f If I Jl|i III |i|| II i i ijil I $ j ? — c fasEE i&gt; «o |« o ; ■ «&lt; So " ?* fi*. ■» * 000 00 se: _ . „ • </seg>
            <seg id="p047">•a "v 1 _ I* _ a — C5 r. M J -J 9 3t O v. o 3 1 r~™ — . * " — " •+333 ~ - saiaer- r- -f — t:h-i- — ~ r r - — — -r'_-_- g a ■*• • : : : : T^ ": : : : — TT I ■ • - j £ % z .* :: * j 8 6 ■" f • 1 1 - : .i = 5| I 3 S Si : « : E = a » : 3 &gt; ; a Hi 3 7 _ « — - i a v : ; ; — ; &gt; » _ 2 — ■ a = a ■c r : — - ~~ — • _* I J : j : . . CO • : a : • : • -s * = ; - .? : ® "c : m • — — Hi " § 111 i ; 1 i M !i If s H = -i I g i IS ||f f * II </seg>
            <seg id="p048">* X n tn ■ 8 : :|8 9 ; i -t- . . *r - «o I «e » ■ • «• i-i- }J ■ -T • • -r O 5 ; r- • • r- &gt;~ &lt;~. ' m ■ ■ re '~ ci • ; .;' • ■ m &gt; f • I ■ -r a. o E &gt; 1 5 • &gt; 1 2 2 - ill! liu | 5 s 5 I £ i H 1 k 2 i &gt;• V ■ r- — SC © C e*'* — r i rT — ' - i -r — • I s ■mi-: i- «o « I - *M I- I— I- 1- zr'i- ?i &lt; 1 1 I Mil : : : s I ': ill I if I Nil ! I I :i:| £ :i if ;!{{ !| iss-sia --all i i!MM !Jll"ili l |i ii § 1 1 1 if il a </seg>
            <seg id="p049">[AKV i'l- Til 49 r „ Tl X 1- I o rrs ~ f _ i\ i a * • -« j&lt; s: • * - 9 ■ R 5! ; 3i I 'A • k ■ k; ■ a -t I ! £ * ? - a E l«fi S v i 1 5 ?l * a I-S = S ■ a i° 5 I Z ' r - - B * * &lt; &lt; -&lt;; 30 r-: rj nil / r / -* y' ¥ = * « x 33 * -"" &amp;C I * 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p050"/>
            <seg id="p051">STATEMENTS r OWING THE CONDITION OF THE SOI INCORPORATED PRIVATE AND SAVINGS HANKS IS THE STATE (&gt;I HBASKA AT THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS NOVEMBER V. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 IT. \'M liBII.ITlE k paid in 1.061 OB ileposit Tin- Hank of Aiuswortli Ainsworth hi A I iinpav • </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Ainsworth Citi/ itc Bank Kankii ■ ■ 46 M) Alexandria. 'auk State Bank ulria xaudria Alexandria. ■ els ■* - ■ ml pri and pri- i ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Allen Allen StaU- Bank r No. 3. (Incor; ..President V. W. McDonald \V. K. Stativ 'ir.ii 17, tiWSL. U8OI f 67. 1U* M LIABILITY 1.IAK1MTIE' ♦ 67. 1U* M it -t'x'K paid in it -t'x'K pahl ill upai'l .... hi paid IiicliviiluHl .: •J3..M1 :« 3.511 :« he houM furniture and fl\- 3.100 UO i if house furniture and :- ■ -&lt;R 91 3.100 UO - - r«ml rsUte. - real estate "nses unit tuxes paid ■ -nil national, slate am) mi tuxes paid and bankers ll ■ . I&gt;wfrom national, slate and pri- in ted. vate tanks and bankers. '.sand ttemiof exchange. .. cash on hand :Tt W vate bmik&gt; and bankers. . 4.475 10 '100 00 uem» of ev 771 W I 79.916 «6 I 7S.916 «6 Totml | 7S.HI8 M Total I TV- Alma The Bank of Alma (Incorporated) r Statement. N'ovhiii 17. I'.KW. KlfWII land uns - judini' L1AB1L1T: I 1AIIII.ITIK • • •k |i:ini in •k paid in f :*' land nn- I ■'•oi Ul *,m * I Mil Ul liiini'nts. Mr * 3.4iT W :::::::::::::: - .iMets 4U.494 37 i!".«M S7 house furniture and 6\ Qg houw furniture »nd ti\ [»'nieo and taxes paid 1.W3 47 Demand &lt;•. V&lt;S TV nd certificate* of depo^ »&lt;S m »,4»7 16 »,4»7 18 -■n~e&gt; and taxes paid l.MU 47 rl other bond* and w.-uritl.- Premium on V.S. and other I • and iM-urities. ■ bank and private 1&gt;. Uf, «S ttf&gt; 9a ■mil bills n Hills pavabta ... Kill- ]&gt; Total oa«li on hand and il Innks </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 Alma Alma The Harlan The Harlan 1 tv Hank County Hank - John Krenou V ice-Piv- ..'.!! ashlar .jniin i VIUBII IT, I ' LIABILITIES C»pi Stated I I YMBKK IT, I'."" HHOKM | 41.411) «u BISOUKX'I LIABILITIES % 41.411) «u Overdrafts, ■ecored and SW 6ti On'nlmfts, serurtil ud SW 6ti ■ ■hums, etc • ■ -•17 W. tjm i»i vw dm - • m m 1 oo it od ttwrittw nod Mcunti6» inte«l Iwuks II banki 15.613 «R * 5K.2W CI « .&gt;.-MM II f ■*• .1* HI ■ .1* m Alvo Incori* (i P. Foreman C. R. Jonliii ... (i P. I Statkm VH1II The Farmers" and Merchant*" Hank NTATKHSV hemu si f.» Luauiai Overtir tuilun^f- l|-&gt; vs j -'.■8 IT claims etc liomU Other asset* ; KankinK liou«- furniture ami fix I *»&gt; ?' lures .. Other real &lt;-»t»t&lt;- Current i'\u000es and taxes paid 8X7 72 ' 'atliier'* &lt;■ Premium od 1 .8. »nd ■ ami *ec*urites pri- e i.n tik. u iid l»nk !; - . ...... liank I 11 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 The r ipst Hank of Aine M. J. Jol Btatimf.wt, Novembkk I.I t Illl. 1 IE: JO anil fly c Amherst T1k&gt; Farmers' Suite Bjmk T. B. i . L. !!■ - Statkmknt. Novembf.i: II 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 Anselmo i harter No Incori. Frank II. Young President I . I. J. Toole\ J&gt;jvid i 'hristen . . . I rank It. Youn HIE1 LIABILITIES l and .li-c. - ture« v i te I ' Ansley Tin State Hank HI. II. .1. I i 'I ■ TATEM llw.-l. The Ansflni. Bank liond- other Mtel lUnkinsj hou&gt;&lt;- furniture sod D\ Other r ittta .nd pri irniture mid - </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Arapahoe The Arapahoe State Bank Charter - S. M. I 1. Yx&lt; HTATEJIENT. NovHBEl 17. 1SI03 ■M UUBimi U&gt;mu» .. I SI.7U -k p»iil in overdrafts. secured ami unsecured 2.10J fll 2.0 0 Oil •■nt&gt; .441 SH clain ttondi Indiviciiuil 'i»'[* oiliir »«m-i« check 'ik house furniture umlfK- Demand certiflcnti's of ilfp..&gt;ii •• ■ WO I Hi '.■»le»U(e ... . . • iivsan.l I;. 800 I M ' • lliUs. . .. . tc banks mid h»»M - i«T.k- u.mx m (114.830 40 | Arcadia The Stato Bank of Arcadia Arcadia The State Hank of Arcadia Ctinrtir R*. II. Iiioirporiited ■ iriited li.M K II. I. Kin*' R. .1 K II. L. Kin* R. J. K -•■■.Men I ■^ll»T STATf.y vain 17. ISXt! iMtnm November 17. IMt LUB1LI1 ♦ W.1KJI 1(1 ick paid * i »nri uiiieciirwl .v; )ii Surplus fund A00O m he house furniture aud 8\- Drmandi-ertilcatMaf &lt;hpo«it ... 1" l.iwii no -use* and taxes pi. - out staadini; .nut- and IK 85 bane - OH IkAQQ ft Ao QQC il^OIH l&gt;aiik- T..U1.... * W.4I1 S3 • 80.411 S3 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 Arlington The Arlington State Hank r.i II. W - Stitmi »BK1! ! ■ E8OI-KCX4 I.I A 111 $: i nd iMiwi'uri'ii .. . - licments I!.-. liking houae, fiirnitiire and Hv W7HW Ml tures ■ i nil pri hum ;ind banken iture. . . M|H fP«l|l IlilN i • Ashland The Farmers" and Merchant*" Hank ii p-lllmril W. A K ■ii. Jr 8TATMEKT, SlU K y BUR it. 1MB Rt-UJKrE LIABIL1TIF. Mfti.llS 14 • ) and anieruTOl - | • Honds. . B.000 00 9.UU0 IK) liankiiiK Iioum- furniture and Hx- tute« 10.000 00 uses and lazes paid Premiui and »e&lt;-uriti«'s an. I teakan i.xv; 15 items n national, state and pri- '.nnks anil ImiiKs Total ♦4S7.II4 3» ToUl </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Ashton The Bank of A&lt;hton ■ Stuemknt. Novembei RESOURCES LIABILITIE ■ J The Atkinnoi Hank Atkinson STATEMENT. NOVEMBER I.1AB1LITIE M i &lt;-I'-ti;fti </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 Atlanta The Atlanta State Bunk \ IT. \\. u. i I NovEMBEl: VTEMENT RES&lt; LIAIIII.IIIK I ■ IT. ■ - • Auburn Thi' Nemahu County Hank ATI KENT Noveii i ■;»i&gt; 1 ■ •.. ■ ■ ■ m }S </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 TWELFTH ANN! A! &lt;&gt;K THK Aurora Aurora State Bank Cliarit-r Nn. IT. 1; V. Ol v Statement, N vkmbkk IT. 190S. ml discount 1154.761 04 Capital MO.-W paid in ebwk . ' rs.seoiired and u i "-'.MM ■ ' I'',- ' *• i i'*r ,■. nats aud i.-ix 1.730 ix Premium on U.S. anil oth. I luniks and securities banks :md iwnk'TS Due from nni tonal, state and pri- • liscounltil TOtoba th«Hk - fash Total |:r#,Sfi7 18 $■-• .:- H Avoca The Bank of Avoca nnlt .loin I .Ino. O. Knwlan&lt;l STATEMENT. NOVEMBER HI. 1903. HE8UI K( K&gt; RK8OI ' I «1.8 LIABILITIES LIABILITIES Iakiii.-miiiIiIik lOJIill «k paid In t V).O - &lt;k paid iii ? 10.&lt;&gt; Ovirdmfts.swiirediind unfwcured I n mi unsecured 2 2.816 67 «16 87 clainis rlaiiui, aw cheek :37 ft&gt; Itanking house furniture mnd lir - ture* iioo 00 ■ re»l estate 1.000 00 Itanking house furniture and lix- DHkEaiwn r .-,-. - r.l. p- - • .Vh-j ( H l^ii.jin.i .-. rtifi.-.t. — f .1. + - • .Vh-ji .Vi tnie» 2.0P0 00 33,«2S 15 33,«K 15 il ■ -tale 1.000 00 Currant ex[XMise» and tales paid l.SW M Currant expenses .i ml iutoi paid 1.2W M Una to national U. Premium on U.S. and other !«&gt;od» and aecurities Premium on I and securities Doe to state »od print.' tank! 1 'Unt&lt;Hl Doe to state aod private l.ank 814 M Due from national, -i.iw and pri - vate banks and bankers 31,440 71 Cash items 61 4 m Due from national, state and pri - vate bankt and bankers 31,440 71 :ited Bills payable Bills p»&gt;.il. lianp"... :« «» &gt;f exclianu- :« «» 4.0MO4 &lt;a.h 4.08604 I1U4.H0 10 IKM.fXM *&gt; LIABILITIES t "j.tKn no turn m }l &gt;ll&lt;1&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p063">• 63 Axtell The Bank of Axtell barter V rpunted tfatdaat j It. K. !!■ ' Statement. Novembeb 17. i;«ci . . * «r«) . Honda. Other llankiiii! Imii-f furniture iiiil flx - tam 5.ow oo ; • Other r «7? 88 I ' I'mnmin oa I". s. anil other boada Cash i' -'88 and bmner-. Due from national, state and pri- ■ « Bancroft The Bancroft Bank I'urn.-r A. (■. /.utilt'- .. ■ STATEMENT, NnvimiK UISOURI ES LIABILITIES n&lt;) ilix-i.unt* IH6.SM 9B I Overdraft- ■.."•urid »nd untecuml Stocks. securities. ludun *&lt;«i hi in laim- Other assets ch«k •tanking house furniture and Us- Demand check -•■ill estate . - expenses and taxes pa .S. andothi and aecurities 37 So and baaften Cash items Due from national, state and pri - vate banks and hankers T» «t Kill* |.i» 13. l he&lt;-ks anil 'lange. -lion hand 2.954 56 }l;li&gt; ;h» m I Tola I </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Bancroft i jn- (^ iti/A'ii8 l&gt;;mk of liancroft Charter s-.. 2:.;. Incorporated. Charter No. 23. Incorporated Yard President I E. T. Rice (ashler lilenkiron. . President I r. u. Manoa Assistant Catl.ier Ward Ward. ... . President I E. T. Rice Blenkiron. Vice- President I r. H. Maims Statement, November 17, 1903. RESOURCES Ull Assistant C&gt;»t.ler Statement, November 17, 1903 KISH'K. ES I IABIU11K- Loans and discounts . (144,764 11 Capital stock paid 1 Loans and discounts ... f 144,764 11 Capital stock paid In J 3n ■ 8urj. H.UOOOO uverd rafts, secured and uuse- afts, secured and uuse- -iu- fund ll,U06 00 eared . . eared , , Hi V I, ■.*.'.&lt; *5 Stocks, scoutities jud^mei claims, etc . . Stocks, seourities, judgments, claims, etc .... uai depjeils subject to check i cates check Bonds -e furniture and nailing house furniture and eg of ii(im 64 6,000 Ou Its.... entaU' »n»« and taxes : 648 50 Due to national bai * ashlers checks to national baukx Pruniui: - and oilier i«nds and i^ecurities ■tmte and private banks and bunkers items and hills re-discount mi' from national, state and payable '..... private bnnk»and banker* ' hecks and iten t of exchange l ■■■Hi casn on hand Total .. (Ml Total Barneston The Bank of Barm Charter No. 21. Incorporaied I ■ 'lent | A. I' ''ashier Vice- President | c (i. spencer Assistant C Cashier Statement, S'. ■. kmhkk 17, 190: RE8OIBCE! ii I 1 .: Loans and discnair i k paid in $ .\000 00 100 0U 811 20 unpaid ... Overdrafts, secured and unse- cured It* 63 Stocks, aecurities, judgments, claims, Bonds ml deposits subject t Other assets . . Dnmi Baiikinfc house furniture and deposit Other real niitfttimling national banks i state and private hn Premiu 1 &lt;-sh items ediscounted Due from national state and private bank Checks und Total cash oi </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 Tin- I ! &gt; &lt;i 1 1 k Barneston ■ 1I..W* LIABII &lt; N Hartley 1 $ 5 - »4T </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 The S ink of 1 Charter No. 26. Incorporated J. D. Bray ton. President II. I. Artcs iHi-hlT I.. L. Biaylon \ AasiMant i «1jii: iTATEMKNT, KOTIIIBEH 1 LIABILITIES l.oausand discount* J i xl itock paid in $ 5 000 00 i aud uuse- 500 (H) 041 71 •2,500 (H) Ifmaata, ■ 447 19 - SW7 05 re mid ending e banka unted Bills payable Mtional. state and bankaaod s and Items of exehai Tlie CoiiimtTcial Hank C i. after No. 701 I G A. i President | A. O. i-milh X J. ait vi sliitr Statement. November 17. 1903. LIAB1LIT1E t 14,354 U «fi», secured aDd un- «tock paid i^ | 5.0C0 Ci ■ 7S4 » I 5.0C0CI ■ urn. deposits subject to other a - 'Uj furniture and iepotit.. MM ■ft o/UeiK.- I 661 64 - real estate 'lit standing . ai'i anal hanks 1 other and securi Due to state and private banks and hankers Noirs and bills rediacoun'.ed u aod Bills payable pra ichanre Total "lolal. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">8 El H t AKV *»K THE STATE !• &lt;&gt;y KI» 67 Battle Creek The Battle (reek Valli-v Ba Battle Creek The Battle (reek ValU-v Bank Charter No. 27. Incorporated. ..President j Geo. Breci let .. C»«hl«r Vice-I're«ldent ST.vr r.MHEi: 17, l'Xtl. Charter No. 27. Incorporated. Charter No. 27. Incorporated. Herman Hogrcfe I Herman Hocre Prf-ident j Geo. Brechler ... Cashier F. H. 1. VIee-1're F. H. L. W111U VIce-1-n ST.vr r.MHEi: 17, l'Xtl. Itatf.-m i VEMBEB 17, 190B BISO! S DCkpair :iU, BE I.IABILITII II1IIIIM Capital stock p« S 40,000 00 andc &gt; I 40,000 00 ti. claim?, etc Bonds Bonds otber asset? 'ther asset v.-har &lt;o.; i" Tot II Battle Creek The Citiz&lt; te Bank Charter No. 1 ■". W llich i'resi'li-nt H. Barn*a teklM eh l'retid T. L. W CMBKr LIAB1LITIE and. apital stock paid in ■9 J rnent* ■)ihur asseta Banking house furniture and ixiun Other real entatt Current *xi*nses ami taxes paid Premium on V. 8. and other bnnds and securities state and private banks and banker !.U1^ re-disconr.t( J-J7 20 terns Dne from national. &gt;t-te and ite banks and bankers heoks and hems of exchange Total cash on hand a: from i&gt;ank.« IS, 388 16 - Banking house furniture i - her inks ' ate and 5,000 OS l.wo oo </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Bayard Thi- Bank of Ba IiicorpuraU'-: u-Li.-r Mary I -tant i ashicr tlATEMKXT JVKMKrR IT, lyft LUBILITII Hnd difcou: 111 -ec- claims. Honds «■ &lt; &gt;ther ass*- It . demand rertuicates of de| ■ uie furniture and privaif Tot» Tota. Total Ba/ile Hills The Bank of Bazile Mil Charter Ni Incori Geo. A. Bron - dent I Walter Brown tent Cashier S-TATKM TMBU liabii.it: TRMHEIt ABII.ITIf paid iu «&gt; • i\M secured ill I end i] ■ •in - - and ••I1VSH1..1 til' (inks mnted. re-disconi m nationn I&gt;ue from natioi mul ankg and bank' - )«nis and bankers . C««h 1 . Cuali 1 . Charter J. \V. ■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 Beatrice Tin- 1'iiion State Bank i A. M. kliM . \v. ||. || TATEM' BE$&lt;" see ..... ... Hanking house, furnilur l!:mWir '. ' ■ &amp;: 17 __ im — Beaver City Beaver City The First BtSte Hank The First State President ■nt I IV. - LIARI j claims, et.' .... claims, etir M.bl&gt;" I II !;,•■■■ r- •'.-,■.. ' ■. ■ I 1 ™. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 • Beaver Crossing XI Bunk of Beavei M. \\ . Warner I . II. Diuierv Statcv U..tm:- i il lwnk&gt; - ami hunk'-" r, hand - UC.107 41 1 The State Hank of Be&lt; Bee i T. II. \ l iheb 17. 1U03. IUI &lt;Mber mmiii'".'.".'.'. ".'".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '.'.'.'..'.'. .'. 1.081 75 » ::*: ti </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 occmcr Tlit- Beemer State Hank TEMINT. NoVEJIHl ICES LIABH.ITIE | Belden Tlie Belden Bank h I'r. r. a. &gt; TiTEV I.1ABII ITIE f 'S paid T </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 Tin- Hank of Belt: 1 Belgrade p. n. ; Statement, Ngvehbek KEBOl'RCES 1.I1BI] HIE I ;tH.»» iture »n&lt;l llv- 4.1 . ■ bank pri - 973 ■ 1.4&gt; 41 Bell wood Tlio Bank of Bell wood Statement, November LIABIL T1F. RESOURCES ■ ill (6 "MM M H.J9S « m m n IB ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Belvidere Hank of Belviden (hartf- Incorporat* President i: ph A. i KKCM 3 tt] LIABILIT overdrafts. swur*- stocks. si •■ stock- el liond- &lt; tth«r ■ | Ifankii ruiture ami ture« ... Other ■ pa id Hue from national, state and pri : Hum iniur.iKii siaif :ina pri - rate banks and blinkers ex- -t» ■ Benedict The Hank of Benedict ch:ir TATEMf ■VKMBKI ired 1*1 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 [Jenkelmsn The Hank of Benkehnan • liar'' \V. I! K. K 3VIMBKR 17, 1WI3 KENT - T Tlie Citizens Bank of Bonnet Jo... I Statement 'IBEK 17. 1S«&gt;: l.lABII.ITIK I It I I'.'.'..'.', bsr </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Bennington Tin- Mangold &amp; (.laiult Bank rcti 1 t i ■ Berlin Bank -if' Berliu r K. I.. Hi STITKMF.Sr, NOVBXBKR KEM&gt;OBCE, I.I. IB iud lix- iiMi ami taxes paid ■ ■JH &gt;U .. ♦ 84.771 » I I </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 Bertrand Tlie First State Bank 11 &lt;:n \\. K , Statement, November ■ 1»UH ■■ I.IAR1LIT1E I | .. ...* - 1*1 1« . k I108.S17 83 ! &gt; Btaden The Exchange Bank of Bliden &lt;rs!«l N. B. Hall STATEMtNT ' I.IABIL1TIK I M ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p077">• The Banking II . .Mr-. II M. i EMBF ( &lt; The Blai Bank r. w . k&lt; i i * </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Hioomfield The Fanners" and Merchants' State Bank nhier nt ! i Statement. S ■v km i; Kit 17, 19a:. I-1ABILITII: • k paid in I 10. (i 17.713 8U • -o ami - MM :&gt;t Bloomfield Tlio Citizens Hank STiTEMlM I.IAB1LITIE - «X) (JO ■ and fix- ■ MH ffi bank • &lt;m tnm aatioasl. 7 411 -J4 . Hi! i- 1 fi.5i3 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 Bloomington riie Franklin County Bank I". A. lllurk l'r We I' H. V. Kirkhriil. W. Mack Statemist. I KESul T." r II I FIE 1 ix- Bloomington ate Hank - I - H. ml fi\ - ■■" ■■ 2.807 S3 Kills |&gt;a\ftl- </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 THE 1 Blue Spring. Tin- Him- Springs State Bant Chart Incorporate \V. W. !i - on .'.""".. As's'iVta'nt i Statement, ■ !UK-U-Bi ES IABM.I1IK Loans and d t ! Ill l and unae- riiiture and vea paid SankM item« ■ Iwi Total Boelus The 1 5tate Bunk c a ii L B. K I ant( STATEMENT BIL1T1E } - : ta subject t i ml tare and bank xinted ite and T.ital from 44 ( </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 Boone Nell ! Ihirri STATKM : 17. I Hi. LIABII.1TIKH i IAII11 ITIK Mu -~els ,ssels .... paid 1 '• :u:» mi vri i ti ■ iTi' - of de|K»3it.. l.lW) OU .He b ■ ithmal. - - payable Total ciish oil h»nd auil due from hanks LOT Total ciish oil h»nd Hint dm' from 1.07 Bradshaw TIu- Btete Bank Bradahaw Bradshaw K I STATUS' J securllw- rlsim .'00 hi furniture and flx- .id. ■ I other i«&gt;nds i in I mi&gt; 16 il banks •• bank </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Brainard Tin- Bank of Brainanl Charter No :* Incorporated -.sident A. K smiili afhier Vice-1' Assistant Cuhie: Stitkmikt, November 17, 1H03. V.KSO1HF.S LI A HIM 1 IE* and discount* stock raid in ( lu 000 (K »nd uo»e- 1..S8B 45 (00 Oil is 4,840 81 10.000 00 jadgmenta. s tal.]ect to chart useti -of deposit. :-»f&gt;hJL't um furniture and of deposit. . estate lading 'wiand tuxea p id - ami other miks ■ivate banka ' ankers . . . bonds and sei urities . . 14« »T items. discounted Bills ]■■■ l.inooo ToUl. ■ ■ »».' Brewster Tlit- International State Bank Charter No. &gt; Incori ; Mfhier ial Lushier Statement, N VEMBEl: LIAB1LIT Loana and di Capital strK-K paid i: $ 5.0TO C -red and 87 WW I -its subject to assets us; furniture and t&gt;-s of deposit nt s'aii'lin- estate expellees and taxes paM hanks *. and other ■ • - Due to state and private banks and backers 40 00 - and bills redlacounted &gt;itional. state at ■! Bills payable - chanire. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 Bridgeport Charters &gt;rporated. Pr*Mden Viee-1'residem Statement, November 17, 1903. Charter No. orated . . Pnxidenl ...Vice-I'residen Statement, N v km iik u 17, 1903 KESOi I.I Rl MAIll: Loans and di- I *I stock paid Loans and*! J *1 stock paid in 00 00 Overdrafts, secured and un - red Overdrafts, secured and u »• cored ■ Stocks, securities, judgmenti, ciaims, eic ■ Stocks, securities, judgment!, ciaims, eic Bonds Bonds other assets other assets Banking house furniture and tlxtu Banking houae furniture and tlxtut. ■ ot.er real estate - 47 ot.er real estate • urrent expenses and taxes paid • urrent expenses and taxes paid Piemium on U. s and other ul ;■&gt;. :ui:iiii on U. ;■ and other in and | ■ and securities bonds and neon Cash In Cash iie Due from m ate and ! Billspaya private ha; Bills payable Hue from lia private han Ker» ... Check.- Checks r Toial &lt; To 1 a. t Bridgeport The Valley State Bank Tin.- Vallt-v Bauk Bridgeport Charter No. 696. Incori orated. rreaHtnt .1. L. i're»ident EMBER 17. Charter So, ■ cor: orated eiiient S \ t.HP.KR 17, 1 MtNT KESOI LI LIABILIT1E I.iun&gt;» » -kpaid .ck paid i: | 'J,30u (0 O\erdr»fts, swcured and on - seen- 101 St.xkp, securities, judgments, claims etc Other assets Other assets Kki kin-' bouse furniture and .■lines and taxes paid 21 i nal b s. and other ue and li and securities lur from national, st-te and .•r \Ht- hanks and bankers ... Checks and iiems of exchange . Total caih on hand an I dn&lt; from ban: Total </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 TWKLFTH ANNUAL KKI-OKT OF THK Bristow The Brixtow State Bank Charter No, *&gt;. Incorporate*! Pre*i&lt;1 K Mo- - , ... Ca«faier . Vice-President \--i»t»nt Cashier CTATEMKNT NOVEMBER 17, 1903. U8OCBCU LIABILITIES Loans and dlacoui .., } ifi * ij Capital stock paid in i overdrafts, secured and uns-ec- • Surplus fund cured MB OB j Uudivlded profits VjS Jl Stocks, secniities, judgments, , Dividends unpaid claims, etc 1810(1 Individual deposits subject to Individual deposits subject to check 2* V4 Individual deposits check subject to in&lt; IM Bonds Bonds Other asset* Banking Mouse furniture and Other asset*... ales ot deposit i Demand certificates ot deposit i ■ eates of deposit Banking houae furniture and fixtures 1.880 12 icates of deposit fixtures 1.880 12 Other real esia Cashier's cheeks outstanding Cashier's checks outatnndi Other real esm- Current expenses and taxes paid 2.075 40 Premium on C. 8. and other • 'urrem expenses and taxes paid 2.075 40 Due to national bank- Due to national banks Premium on C. 8. and other bonds and securities Due to state and private banks and bankers Due to state and private banks and bankers . . bonds and securities Cash items Due from national, sttte and private banks and bankers.. . Checks and items of exchange Total cash on hand and due Cash items Notes and bills re discount' Notes and bills re 'discount' Due irom national, sttte and private banks and bankers... Bills payable Bills payable Checks and Items of exchange Total cash on hand itnrf ■ l&gt;ank&gt; S,5» SB Total * 25,151 22 from l&gt;ank* x.SM SB Total Total Total $ 35,i5i ■•&gt; J Bristow Charter No. 8K8. Incorporated John ftuaw President ■ ashier Kdward Renanl Vice-President V&gt;si«tant Cashier Kenan! . Vsei«tant Cashier Statement, Novkhber IT, 1903 \ BIKOl'h LIABILITIES Loans and discounts .' aid in ; Overdrafts secured and unse - cured... divided profit* Stocks, securities judgm&lt; Tills tinpaiil. claims ttc - idual deposit! subject to Bonds it I Demand certificates if deposit. Peinaud certificates c f Other »s-t-i« Other assets Banking house furniture an4 Hankiuc home farnitnre and lUtnrp* eatate . . l&gt;en*e&gt;and taxi-»p«iil I. WO 79 Time certificates of deposit 12, ■ andlng . Time certiticates of deposit 12, tandtnK . Due to national banks - real estate l&gt;en«esand taxes paid 1.930 74 Doe to national banks i state and private banks and banker* and bills re-discounted, Premium on V. S. and other bonds and securities Premium on U. S. and other bonds and securities mate and private banks and banker* Cash items Cash item- Notes and bills re-discounted. Due Irom nation- Dae Irom national, stat^ and private banks and bankf- 'M u*i bills payable. . . . bills payable. private banss and banker- (.'here- ■&lt;37 87 Check :&lt;37 87 Cash Cash Tlie American Exchange Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p085">85 V OK Tl NKINi Brock Tla- Hank of Brock John Vont \ J itiunt, Nornui ; i lAi-.iLi r;». at 76 9 06 &gt;:.,,,. I- - object 3.0BO 00 • Premium on I . . v.iie banks and bankers 13.96 M 4.886 49 t «4.*5 Broken Bow The Broken Bom Bank i State v 1 IAHI1.1TIE' - ' r Imnks </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 Broken Bow The Bank of Com men Broken Bow W. M. 1: Prescient I C. .1 KM ..President lent I State*' mu LI.VBTi Loan* ami dlaoou 1 12,886 10 Loan* and dtac ■&gt; Stocks, securities. judgments. ela'imi, etc . . . .' 177 16 Bonds ?.V&gt; 61 ■■* hmue furniture and . ,•« iai IIM pmil :fr M :fr M Total I 3».1«6 73 Total I asi.HK 73 ToUl ) Bruning Brunlnj The German Bank V:llllU&gt;- In Hrilllllii:. k lSruimii:. W H silent | A. • W. il -ideut | A. ■ STA1 EMBER 17 190S. Statem tiHts 17. 1903. LIABII.IT I.1AKII.ITIK I 02.4% II 161 11 Loans anil f A2.4X3 11 &lt;i.000 i 161 _• tioute furniture and flx- king house furniture anil r real e»ui. nv«&gt;s and taxes ]&gt;aiil i ud oilier !► -ps and taxes paid ■ Total from 7.719 65 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 Bruno The Hruuu State Bank Rerm Suiijum. N&lt; F. MM K.I. RESOURCES ABILITIES - f i; i Hi claims, etc . Mtti.T JUMMt* other a Ha il kin tun &lt;t*h il Brunswick The Brunswick Bauk States KCKS ; I .IAHII.M 1 IABII.ITIE I '•tl**-k Ikmttn.i cerul • •• - ' |. ,.,-■- -nitun 1 »nd flx - -nitiire and flx - paid - :li&lt;l Hll'f ■ .........•.•• .nd other h. • •» |.ri- vat6 l&gt;i»iik« mid bankers vRte fattnks snd b«n Total cash on hamt and dm- from lmnk&gt; M«« I) * lK.SaSOB Total * !C.WB0« </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 Burchard liank of Huivhanl eriu.m. STATIMIHT, NcVF.MBKR l.l&amp;Hll.iriE: "* SO mire and i!\ I.HKit --ill - i i*i. i--r mi pri- vate I. *t.iM 87 Burr Tlie German American Bank STATKJIINT. NOVEMBKIt RCSOCBCKS I.IAMlL HIS M si i'W 5S •-■ '•»&gt; i &gt; i i -HI &lt;U . </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 &lt;'harter No :t. Incur \\. L. V November • :&lt; EJ LIABILITIES -counts ... * - tils. secured and Kond&gt; other »»».-i- . llankinsr houx- furaiiure and Ii\ ture« -WS iai other ri-.-il estat paid rbouds &gt; n hand and ilue from mk&gt; Butte Tin- Citizens State Hank Iw-orp I' .1 M. Wjmt Statem ■' red f»l IT ! »&gt;' »■ .•r.aei 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 Kutte The Bank of Bovd County Charter Klmer ' 'TATEMEST, tMKtl: I.lAKIl.lTlt. Loan- * 25,628 65 '.'11 91 lion.K _• house famltom - - * Butte The P&gt;ank of Butte Butte - 1 State* i till.]! 17. ' LIAR): ekker I I.IABIMTIE - •■tines and I ft -&gt; " I </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 Byron The Farmer*' and Merchant*' Hank W. I) &lt; . \V I RESOUKCK1 I 12,778 63 IW 30 ,-. ml fix tures ■ t« Cairo Tlif &lt; tate Hunk m 8T»T«3CE!«T VEMBKR KMOOBCM LIAI1M.ITIE 3W Ken Hid flx- ■ nses nn&lt;l v:.ie lian-s • ♦ Si'.rifi in </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 THK Callaway The Seven Valleys Hank i ST \TEMt.vT NOVEMBER IT. !'.«&gt; LIABILITIES B ■SOURCES :k ]&gt;aid in | 11.300 00 - aml.iiv * 38.W9 6! &lt;«J0M - 337 U1 31.1W « !ix - 1.000 00 fix - I. 000 00 1 TKX 34 30 J (« l.THS 34 IW nft iw m 1U0 IK) Out* to NMIM pri\aT»" b:i ' ■■ - I 52.M9 71 I M.BW Callawar The C'iillawav State Hank ■ha*.. II. All) ii -TATKMtM. November 17, 1U03. I.K-. L i. I l.IA»ILniKS S M mm • r 23,8» 6» -■»« 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 i OF THK n &gt;AKH Campbell Tin- Bank of pbt'll n. Henry Ound Pr«- II II. C. K. (iuiiil \ i 8TATKXBHT. NOVEMBER 17 IHU3. KES. Ll.lHILITlh i ■ ■ ■ Ih-i ■■■ • furniture unil fiv- IHk- U&gt; ttate m s vat.- banki and !&gt;.. Carleton The (it itt 1 Bank T. P. I. iTATKM LIABILITIB: RKSOl'RCK LMU8 M tl - &lt;H» • I ;.■!:.-- XCt |«iil snrt te bank lisooiinted. v:ltl&gt; liHIlk- ;u« l fr«un SI Total ... f «n.&lt;*0 01 ... «M .IMI ill </seg>
            <seg id="p094">Carroll The Farmers" SvMv Bank L. Lui State * ivtmr.Hi 17, 190; LIABILITIES - ! '" »50 71 Mil irnilure and 1.700 00 M ■ ■ ■■...'....'. vate t* i S70 * Cedar Bluff The Bai iar Blutf R. H . K CmMr • shirr STATEMBNT. N'OVIKBII 17. !'.• I.IAB1L1TIF 1136.730 9) I 15,900 00 41.031 flp 3.500 00 II7.0M 40 H o ■ 1)0 nt'&lt;l rate bai 7,018 53 *' 77.4*3 7C </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 ITATKMINT. N I I Mill 1TIE t flx- I..VO IKI i I Cedar Rapids The S. S. Badlej Compauv p \ EMBEi: ■ : ■ '. :u it boml H)5 00 ■ •llliiTS » | </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 Cedar Rapids Tlie letlar V alley Bank ( hurt, r Incorpoiaie&lt;l President | esident I A. I,. TiK-k.r .Ir .( „ Assistant Oel.ter Statement, November 17, 1MB. RKIOl'Ri K8 LIABILITIES Loans and discounts » ;»,618 40 Capital stock paid In f lu.iaw 00 Surplus fund -'.000 W Undivided profits i ,'is "4 Dividends unpaid Overdrafts, secured and unse- sureU 4U IV stocks judgments. Individual depwits subject to check "I he- Matt* Demand crrtiflcate* of deposit. . B»'&gt;kii :irniturc and eg o ( deposit ttxtui ... -'.(BO 00 certified &lt;hecki lime certiti ates of deposit .'.' !i,07H fixture* -',(100 00 otber real e«tm other real e*tat&lt; . H -h(f i s cnecks outstanding Cashier's checks ontstan.linir ..' ......... Due to national banks Current expenses and taxes i Current expanses and taxes ; OS 42 Due to national bank- Premium on U. kt. and other bonds and securities Premium on U. S. and other ! Due t,i state and private banks bonds and securities and bunkers . . Due ti&lt; state and private banks and bankers Cash Items Motes and bills re-iisrouiVt .i Cash Items I M14- from national, state and nid Mils re-itiscount '■! Due from national, state and , navable private bankr and banker* 14.578 14 Bills payable private banki- and bankers li Checks and items of exchange. Checks and itenis of exchange. Total casn on band 4.:«X&gt; &lt;* Total $ 64,6I« 20 ' Totn . } W,61« 20 Total casn on band 4.:&lt;96 W Total . Total | Mfi\ Center Center Tlie Center State- Hank Tlie Onter State- Hank Charter No. «65. Incorporated. Charter No. Mo. Incorporated. r&gt;. T. &lt;■ President I II. 1. st.'is., n rashitr r&gt;. T. • President &lt;;. E. 1 Vice-President I Assistant ( Vice-President Statement t-KMBKK. 17, 1S03. KMRKK 17, 1903. RBHOCBCBS LIABILITIES REHOCBCB8 Loans and discounts $ H.tfSU &lt;%) ' h(.,i«: -t-i k pni.l in $ ti.OOO 00 Uverdrafts, secured and unse 528 46 furplu 1 * fund cured vided profits stock-, •ecuritira, judgments, Utrldemis unpaid claims, etc - idual deposits subject to Stocks. s*i unties, judgments, claims, etc mis unpaid lual deposits subject to Bonds Bonds Other assets Other assets -ates of deposit Demand rertiricates of deposit lime nertilicate&gt; of depoar. "&gt;«&lt; W Banking house furniture and lime rerliiicate- of deiKMit .. fixture* ifle&lt;l check! Banking house furniture and M'- Other real estate AOO 00 other real A00 'er's checLi&lt; outstinding Current expenses and taxes paid i national banks Premium on bondx «nd securities Due to state and private banks and ban kers &lt;' .sh items Due from national state and Notes ami bills re-diacouuted •livable private banks and bankers.. Checks and items of exchange 1.718 W </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 ( itv Hank Central City Thi' Farmer Bank I. \\. Yi II I ;il other Imml *' 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 Central City Tlie PiatH- Vallc- Bank ;'Oraie&lt; I Hthier ■ ' MltKB 17, 1 &lt; Hpitni stock i-hiiI In - Cubital stock |&gt;ald in J L'0.000 0 JO (Km IN 4 judgments. ,l\|i»ifl Other as- - ir ni lure and andlng • nks private banka aid bankf- ■ te aud Bill! payable ToUl.. Ceresco Tin- State Hank i C harter No. • , shier ant c i shier J 41,ti I o-erjiM d ami un- Ki«nt», -.ts subject t :iS* I leposit.. lrniinre and • it standing \eepairt anks d other -late and private banks Hnker8... . inted . tc and ■ ruble ■ M h Total . . | . </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 Chadron A. W. 1. Prfsidei. A. vt. kiukii President I C*«her lce-1'reslden .» nt cashier rint Cashier IT ATE M VKxr.EK 17, 19(M claims, etc claims, etc Bonds Bonds Other assets.... itber asse iratesof d&gt; Banking house furniture and fixtures Banking house furniture and fixtures A.400 Qluer real estate :id taxes paid im on U. 8. and other and necuriiies ationd, suite and .'t'lant-Hiii biuken f ox.hansre . I'.iils payabl Bills payable . Chambers State Hiinl. orated. EMBER 17, l'J a ■mil u her MMli ■ house furniture and xtur Other real estah I standing Hi tanks. Current expenses and taxes paid Cash items m national, st-te and private banks and bankers Bills i- checks and items of exch f The Citizen's Baiik Charier No 87. Incorporated. RESO ' lunm r.oansandd I ockpaidin Overdrafts, secured and un- •roured -, securities, judi'menU, Ek», securities, ju lims etc ITeminm on U. S~. and other bondu «nd securities and banktr </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 Tilt' ( lliipill&amp;ll 13llllk Charter No, 6H5. Iocorporate-1. Yiee-1' resident mt r»t HC«S LIABILITIES Loans «nd discount* Hal stock paid io $ rafts, secured and an us fund eunw i n.livid.-ii profits. V. Stock- ,-ticit unpai claim*, ' Bonds Other a«et* Other assets Finkimr house furniture and Hxturei. -TOM ■ck&gt; outstanding • iirrem expenses and taxes paid Due to na! i Dne to state find private bank' iii'i other Cash Items. Notes h hi, sute and •Table Total cash on hand Total $ 3»,nH| Total Chappell The Commercial Hank Charter Inoori- Mdent | II i Boikds other «s-ets Dema t. ■» Bunking houte furniture and rlxi - real emai. enaetand taxes p«iil ». and 01 boada and securities ise furniture and Time • national banks ■ »t8te and private ba and bankers. . . . and bills re-discounted.' real estate &gt;en*esand t»- national l.anks. and other securities stMtc and private bank and bankers. . . . Notes and bills re-disV&lt; l&gt;ue from national, si private banks and bank) - ra nationn Bills payabl Bills payablt private banks and bank' Tot«; Total Total t KL~l, T..M tTATI.V 'IIIF.R IT, l'.KW ami hankers.. Checks ami Items nf cxcha- Maeni 11 liabilit: Loans and discounts 5 id in uumm Overdraft, secured and un»e ■t to </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 The Farmer Hank of Cli&lt; ■ i«a il bunk &gt;- l Clarkson The Clarkson State Bank ri n . </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 Uatonia file Farmer's Hank of Ciatmiia rharur .. ::::.:■■ £5| f:. 1 President I T Statement. Xovembkk 17. I9(H. Statem&gt; EXBKK 17. :i«i:i IUC8OI I BESIJI m E I.IABII.1T1F. I4O.80U 13 J *J I I ■ ■ ■ se furniture and iz- ■ -. rt»ie S uw::: nd !t&gt;i« p^id C«hJers! Due to n»tlrm«I I • ■atMan &gt;»nd itenu of exchange... 2,957 54 Totl »l IM.8W 14 I Total . . ; Clay Center The Commercial State Hank H. l: McDowell Pr. State* &gt;ike» it. ioo*. ltE"ii| Rl F* I.IAB1I ITlf f WS.496 19 tMnk " </seg>
            <seg id="p103">K. r»yi. TATEMtVT N KMBKI RESOURCES AB1LITII urwUnd mer -■ : -", furniture and fix i 1 •t Imiul^ ■ri- The Bank of Codv ] * Statement. &gt;' KVHKl: Loans ami Loam and clis..mni« J I M ■ • 1 ;■.!■•:- Otber assets ruitiire and niilure am: paid 1.0C0 90 d other Ihjii.1 - nid other !&gt;• </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 Coleridge Tin* Connnei it&lt;- ltank (.. Bri.; ptatemest, November it. iwb. RIHOl'BCE: 1.11BILITIE - :»\ 46 and fl\- 6 Bills ' Coleridge Tlu- Coleridei Bank NOVEMEKi: .. .. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 Colon Colon The Stan- Bank of Co The State 15 P. ii •n - STATKJIKNT, XOVEMBKKlT Statkjiknt. x.j\ kmkkk 17. mo RESOCEU'ES 1 RESOCRCRS LIABILITIES ind discounts -k paid .tid discount*. -i' furniture and II mlture and real estate .. CorM-nl \cs p.i id ml other bond&gt; slate :i nd prt- ... ex- !: trom 'p&gt;n nk- VrOiutnMis h \\ TATEM I i.i m: lint \&lt;\ utli.r ;' II ll Ulllk- I ' </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 Comstock The Comstock Stato Bank Charter iwniBju r. i: .- \ •'■-•■ N'OVEXBE EB IT. 1903 ITATEXENT I.IARU.IT1E and unta" - BmmI*. MM 12 house furniture torn ] I 21 t&gt; Concord I IH' (&lt;&gt;ll tt' Ptilllk I'HIll Statement. Ndvemkek IT. 19U3 LIABILIT1E .... :t.wn * A0n 111 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 !»Kt KKTAKV OK THE STATE BANKIN Cook The Farmers" Bank of Cook ■ TE»I^ I RESOIRCE1 ABILITIES Banking house, furniture and ti\ him1 securities .... Due from mm - The Cordova State Bank 1*. II. Cpdik Statiment, Sovembkr IT. 1903 RESOURCES LIABILITIE I lUiikini; house furniture l.tiUtl 0» i Itlit-r r- and pri vate Iwnh- ■ f exchan </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 Cortland The Mauk of Cortland Clmrtrr II. li Bui V A. llurlii tTUIV tIKKi: IT. 11" i ltKSOLMil £S LIABILITIES | M Ml (HI M H 34.064 • -■■ MX- M I ■ »&lt; OB Crab Orchard Tin- Bank of Cml&gt; Orchard kit. .hi r o". \". I ?TAT«MIXT. NOVEMBKI. MABILI'I ' I ill I.IABILIT1E! RESCH I-.K-C 1 ■ i ■' : ! I Bx- flx - 880 «• SOT bS 880 «• ■ .71 41 &lt; - </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 Craig State Bank : \ L. Mi-I'l i St.it** V EM BE I I hunk- and Innt ii Tin 1 Formers ite Bank ATKME^ KMP.n: IT. 1MB I Hx :!«• w </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 The ( uinim : ate Bank Crawford ■ »n Statement. November IT, 1901 IABIL1TIE l.li.l ns IKI 16 tl | I Creighton The Security Hank \V. li \\ . A. M.1IF.1HNT. NOVEMBER IABILITII . I'lX - .. • *M',1I» » </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 jiltOll Creighton The Bank m r&lt; A Statkmint. RESOl'ltl I» lix- pri- I t To'. i Creston Tlic Bank &gt;TATEM I in -•■&gt; and tax i </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 Creston The Citizens' State Bank Chart ' ncorpoiKicl ■. ■m CaM.ier Statement, November 17, 19ft KRt80CB('M ns and discounts J overdrafts, secured and uuse - sar* 1 ; -, jndgmei .nu house furniture mid rurrent exp»n*fs»nd taxes Premium 01 bonds and wr unties t/ush itein&gt; i'ui from national, stnte aud id bankers (heel 'littnl caBU on ha r Iniik- Total .... RISOl-R' E8 MAHii.n LIABILITIES- Loan* an&lt;! discounts J &lt; paid In i k paid In »lt! »ubjei ■ overdrafts, secured »nd uu§«- Mued . judgments, ■ cbeCK ftiruiti: I'emni ■ her rea •-•.ISM 04 Other rea iii'Jinir » a*h aud private banks and linkers rediscount current exp«"n«-!&gt; and taxes ■ • I national banks Premiun '1 oilier bonds and &gt;••■•• u riiies aud private banks and linkers &lt; hsIi items •• disoonnt?d i'ui from national, siir private l.«nk- and banker! ... syable «he-» 'littnl ca«ri on band ant Total State Bank Crete Tlio Crete Charter .■rated. T II V &gt; -tnntC Ca» kl VHMKKK IT, : gTATEMIST, X VEMBEK 17, 1S03 VB1I.1TH Loans and ■liscoui ■ use - cure'1 use- cure • •, judgmo ■ judgments, Individual deposits subject ti&gt; ch~&lt;k .. itutividuHl deposita snbiect to ch-ik .., other aaaeti .. e posit Banking nouse furniture and rniture and - nit»tindlng tr uuf.tin.llni; Oth&lt; other i Current ex[ieii«*- j*ld inties ■ ■ • Current ex[ieii«es ami taxes paid ■ national banks to national banks .... ,■- state and private bank and hankers to state and private bank- and hankers ... • an. I bills re-ilm-oui payable and bills re-discounted Mi national state and Due from national state and private l&gt;anks and bankers... . ayab'.e private l&gt;anks and bankers... '■-■ Checks hi. Checks hi. </seg>
            <seg id="p113">( Culbertson The Calbcrtsou Bank Dm. Curtis State Bank &lt;&lt;( Curt I U '' »&gt;!•• . ■ - ■ . o.».,j . i ji i »ut ,1 ■ . . ■ ihiiks </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 Dakota City The Bank of Dakota Citv Charter No. 116 i-rivat Cathier Viee-I Assistant Cathie: JTATEXKNT, NOVBMBEB 17, 14&lt;Ki REXOimcKS LIABILI1IKS LIAHILI1IES Ix»ns mnd discount* f 91,271 «o Capital Mock paid io | 10.000 OU rafts, secured and uosr- burplus fund Capital Mock paid in | 10.000 0D UurplUK fund Individed protits Individed profits &lt;se go btocka securities, judgments, - securities, judgments, Dividends unpaid ... Dividends unpaid clali Individual deposits subject to ia subject to check 106,614 00 Other ass* (» ... Demand certificate* of deposit. 2,130 00 Other assets. Demand certificate" of deposit 2,130 00 Banking house furniture and fixtu Banking house furniture and Time ceniflcates of deposit I Time certificates of deposit . tft Certified check* Certified checks • -.her real estate • -.her real e&gt;ute - Caahler's checks out standing Caahler's checks out standing Due to national banks .... Current expenses and tax** p^id 1.219 00 Due to national banks nt expenses and tsxee p. id Premium on l\ s. and other bonds and securities Premium on l\ s. and m Due to state and private banka bonds and securities and bankers • ■ ... Notes and billMe-discounted miii national, state and Bills payable private banks and bankers O 00 , s and items of exchange . Due to state and private bank* and bankers items and I. iH- re-discounted m national, state and Bills payable. private banks and bankers .. #930 00 ■ ami items of exchange 3,1185 45 3,085 45 Total I128 848 90 Totn IUMM H Total. Total |USJ O«nbury The Bauk of Danburv Dan bury CharterNo.il" Incorporate I resident I I ashler int Cashier tint Cashier Statiment, Novfmbek 17, 1903 *E«)] LIABILIT I.nana and I l.'.OCOCO Uverdi'i -d BDd un- 1.665 "6 rities, judgment*, sits subject to ■ ■ -it.. :««*-, us. 1 furniture and iy M xespaid 1.3KI 90 ~. and other bond* and and bills rediscounted Hue ft Li- a; ! &gt;87 SV I S.V. ."w </seg>
            <seg id="p115">IAKY OF TIIK STATE BANKINU UUAKD 115 Dannebrog Charier No. Hv Incorporated. Prriiident IP- Cashier Viue-l're-ldeni | I. J. Hansei Assistant Cashier it I T. J. Haiueii issutant Cashier AMUUnt Cashier State mk VKMI1EK 17, 1903. VKMI1EK 17, 1903. LIABILITIES Capital stock paid ia 00 00 resources RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts ! Loans and discounts I Capital stock paid ia 00 00 i/0o M&gt; I'ndivided profits ... 106 S3 Dividends anpai overdrafts, secured and an - red trails, secured and un - ■ jm wj iiOO M&gt; I'ndivided protils .. 106 S3 Stocks, securities, judgments. claims, etc Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc Dividends anpsi Individual deposits sul j ct to mid cerllficalesof depoelt -posit JS- • out standing 1 banks .. ate and private banks and '■»!; -and bills re-discouuted Individual deposits sui Bonds other assets...'.'". nitier assets ificatesof depoelt . &lt; Banking house furniture and Hanking house furniture and t.xtures - real estate • i.m-r real estate it standing Due to na:.ui. .1 banks 1 urrent expenses and taxes paid i - mm on U. 8. and other bonds and securities 1 urrent expenses and taxes paid •■ • - and other bonds and securities • ■■ and innate banks and ' and ' i C«*h Its - an national, state and Hte ban«&gt; aoa binker- ■.ems . aid bills re-discouuted &gt;n national, slate and private banki- aoa b inkers ... Bills r Totnl i Toia: Eenport The Jeuning Bank Davenport l':i nk Charter No. MB. .... President • - STATEMENT, J ). I neon orated. Incori orated. President ; I W. i' ashler 11. 1. • not Cashier W II -liier II B. \ssistaot Cashier AssisUot Cashier November 17 1903. LIABILIl i I -lock paid in ;ud MBER 17 19C tTATIMEST r.Ksumt RKflU KCES LIABILIT1E; s and discounts I .V'.ifti W I and discounts J nl Mock paid in o eplmfts, secured and an- drnfts, lecured and an- Banking house furniture and ng bouse (uruiture and SOU 00 .00 00 xiure r real estat t.'ut exienies and taxes paid t.'iit exienies and taxes paid im on U. B. and other &gt;nal banks &lt;&gt;nftl : hii-s Premium on U. B. and other - and securities M bank •ids and securities - ■ in national, -t-.it&gt; and anks and ban Ut s and items of exrhange. . &gt;n liauil. . items discounted in national, stite and banks and bankers - and items &lt; The Dannebrog State Bank - • securities, judgments, claims elc 3S,a»«8 - </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 KKl'OKT &lt;&gt;V THE D«vey Tlio Farmers Bank Charter Incorporated . nt casr M EXT KMBFK RES.'l'RCES IABILITIE; Loins and diKoai *id in : and untec- - cureii igment ■ re «ml .-state &lt;!urrt nvate tanks ! Ca*li Total Daw son The Daw on Bank Charter No Inoorpo rated ■ KHBER IT, 190 : UABILIT UMBER IT, 190; I.I.I ItlUTIf Loan* and id and u Loanx and k imli] i 11 Overdrafts secured ati'i judgmentu, rniinre an4 nee furniture *n4 estate -l.M-l.MIl.'. U an kg ankers 'la and strurii.es .. .. iud bills re-discounted i anil bills re-discouir it» and payable i </seg>
            <seg id="p117">The -letierson * Haul' r State v K&gt; B1LITIE kh iai m c &lt; i : Uecatur The Bank of I &gt;• i .t&gt;lti**r ATKX- ■MW1 ■ 1 1 »e» and U 1 ■ -'.••• -.» and i 3..VJU 00 a; </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 Deihler Charter No. 586. Incorporated ITesident I Vice-President ..." it I ..." Abstain c'»shier ..." A»si»t»nt Cashier Statimf.- Statement. NOVEMBER 17. IMS. Xovembkk 17. IMS. lUMum » MNVMH BESOFRCES LIABILITIES , Loans and discounts *!.=&gt;. 1T« 70 Ixmns ami discounts Hr&gt;.f7G TO ro CupiUl «I.N-k pa 1. 1 ai .' $ II .tends unpaid Mflratf- of and li'tnk- r- ■I in ." | Hii Overdrafts, lecund and auseeorad Overdrafts, lecund and unsecured Stocks, securities. Judgments Stocks, securities, judgments claims, etc ., m i claims, etc Honds Hondt Other assets Other assets * 790 U lUnkinu house furniture and fix- llankiDK bouse furniture and to - tuns . .... 8.300 00 tures 8.300 00 .ies of deposit Other Ml esUle Other real estate. CMHttipMRt and taxes paid 1.210 SB nt expanses and taxes paid 1.210 86 Premium am D. S. and other bonds aad securities IT* niiuin .mi I . s. and ••ther l&gt;oii&lt;i, aad »ecurit ie» te bank Cash items Cash items Due from national, state and pri - vate banks and bankers. sand itfn. Uuefrom national, state and pri - and bank" ' Checks Total cash on ban « iMuik m 02 ToUI $ ',5.«4 70 Total ea \ l*nks IMM 02 K Tola .$ 75 «••» n. ToUI ,'t 7(1 i ToUl I De Witt The Fanners" A Merchants' Hank Statement. Novembeb 17. 190». I IAHII.ITIK! Loans and * 50.4*8 7:i - k psiil in f J0.000 0* landunsei'i i» - 4.1SH claims, etc fw im rlaiin - ., a i(j deposi' ■iiiture and ft.5flO 00 - real estate. peaaaa »i taxes paid n 45 to nntional - - bank 1.781 W vate banks and baahi. &amp; "ill) 19 The State Bank of Deshler Krert Dam ro^vr C. II. I </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 DeWitt hitrter is Presider. I ' \V. KlhMf STATMB&gt;T. NmyEMRIK ■saoDncBS ■saoDncBS LIABILITIES • »i 60 lABILITin l.«&gt;:in&lt; and | !:i,wi ar $ 1 SI.H8J V7 Stocks. •«■&gt;• I".*."/./.'..*.".".".'.'. ""im'i*t riiitureiind Hx- .'.'.'.'.'..'.'..'.'.'.' '"imii :v, H ■ furniture and flx- &gt;an* • 3.3U8 W ■ 3.3W no Tiww pakd -"•-•urlt ie» -"•-•urlt ie» ■ Bill* pny;i 92 n &lt;asl, ,J3 S8 : I :».T5-: HI Diller The IVodK State Bank A. 11. ri&gt;lm»i, Prnldrat I. M. Ravnit.nd Vic STATEMST. EMBEB IT. IMS. Hunkiiie house faniiture and Hn- _ \«s paid 736 40 .1...].]...^. ........ Rrlts Ln«n» si J i &gt;ii'' to -itrttt' . re I priv :itf . i " k ■ &gt;anks and t «n k**rs 30.401 00 ( 'hecV I </seg>
            <seg id="p120">The- Dixon Bank Dixon 8tatim£KT, November i i tmi.niK * 41.i ... no ■ Bill* ! liVU ate Bank Dodge Statement, November 17. 18CS. UHOOBCXa LIABILITIES .- 1.T2S 10 &gt;« Kills p ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 Dodge Oo&lt;lge The 1 int.- Hank STATEMENT, XOVKMBh Si A 1 KM ! EXIIt&gt; - RCES LIABILITIES LIABILITIES . furu - &gt;:S p.i id . • 0*6 &lt;• Doniphan The Hank of Dooiphao Doniphan • -~ v z~ ' , : -u;--, - TATEH &gt; K HP. Kit IT. 1M3. VKMV.KB IT. 191 LBCE8 ABILITIES LIABILITIK ud ilemsof ■ Ifl W &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 Dorchester The D&lt; te Bank Charter No. 130. tarn .1. H. dark A. H. Kenyon W. P. STA I EMBER IT, 1903 KE«H I.IAlill.lTIE* Loan* :iim1 Discounts * &amp;»,»» 78 rafUjacurad and nnteenred Stock*. Mcoritie*, jimJiti- ■ Bonds. Othrrauets -niture and 11 x- Ihin:nnl aartifcatai of ilpposit :*« i&gt;T" 4..VHI (Ml :iM'Saml t.i f.ri- MM *l!fi.&lt;)!8 76 , fU'l Douglas Hank of Douglas ■no ftaa Hani Statehent. NovintK LIABII-ITIE: ■ '7 44 "«7 15 1 1 mil H\- 7SW It - •■iiwi »nd ti 6.ST5 61 itnted .y»blf &gt;n html i; </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 Du Bois (;. 11. lviton President A . H. l"ehou Vic STATE* f rbsourcei LIABILITIES Loam and discounts | 57.(«6 24 M 7* claim*, etc. ... 130 00 Hankii ..- tures • - i - Due fro i Tatc httin-s and bu i n,tH 1 1 I :•■• M ; i Dunbar Henry W. Knise Hans V. Ai. -iiient | Statbmiwt. Novcmbicb IT. l«B &gt;nd tlx- H.u. k -nitiire and flx- (urrent expenws and tuxes paid i,t8S 04 I lid otlwT I" ...... m nation:. (urivni exiienwx and taxes |m id 1,0t! 04 and Mrnrit &lt; - ial hank! ■ niebum and tor 10.S7B »» iyal&gt;le TotRl &lt;-ash nn hamt 7 107 43 Total ••ash on hand 7 107 43 Tlie State Bank of Dn i m k The Dunbar State Hank RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and I ' wf ■ ■ - </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 at Statemeht, November IT. 190: RESOURCES LIABILITIES . . * 60,205 8r&gt; $ 10 1'lt nirt fix- • •oi) oo hand and due from - Eddyville Tin- Eddvvilk- State Bank STATgy I.IABILiriK * 12,0»7 33 M s«0 H i :il I ...iiU (V 291 tl t ttjm ii </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 mk of I - Btatem RF I The Chiv County State Bank j flx- - --■ i </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 Edison The Bank of Edison Cli»r m. Incorj- M iller President ;pc P. Smith i - V Statement, 17, 1903. LIABILITIES rid discmin: .. I 1,4» 40 Capital stock paid in I 5.000 00 I Oveidn judgments - subject to K house furniture and rivate banks led 144 15 2.307 74 I 16,(O6 54 Elba The Elba State Bank maaoi ■ iwd *2 49 LIABILITIES "0 00 • . furniture and fix- lix- bank "40 16 * M.I7OS4 * .... ■ . banks </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 KTAKV OK THK &gt;TATK BANKISi- 1K1ARH Elgin The Elgin State Bank ChnrterN". IS 1 .'. I Win. H. I mour Pr- ■ s. Hutmun Vi' Statkmknt. November IT. 1908 -ITIB9 BI8OCRCII -'•.mills *1. | ■_•-■.«». ,.) 1u»l dep«-i'- subject l^.mls " furniture and fix . 186 :o nits auillKinklTs ... 23.8K » &gt;a\ tb i 017 * Total Elk Creek •ate Hank it iTATEMh viMBin 17. 1SW LTABILITIZS ' IK' p bonds </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 Elkhorn Elkhorn ( Lb: Priva .1. M B VENT, NOVEKBIB 17, 1903. ABIL1T1K Loans ainl d i and uiik- . :ts»j Tot»l iV Mfichunts" Bi Elm Creek The Farmer Charter mil ( gTATEMINT, SOVKMBEK ' PI unse ■ : &lt;1ep&lt; epoatt l .se furniture and andlng tebank ite and privH' Checks ban </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 Elmwood riie American lank stmrk TATEXENT. XoVEM *"•"" LIABILITIES ■ .'(» 1 ,- ,,- ... " . .... (mm 1)»iik 1 Tlie State Bank of El wood Imrtcr K&lt; Win. Kirr Vi c N Statement VEXBER IT \\4K{ LI VB. t 62.2TT 10 il stock paid in... .&lt; "*»! " «a; 87 s • furniture and flx- 3.80000 34.879 IS Demand 2.MM m ■ n-.es and t»\es paid. 'I other bonds "cks outstanding. -'a re and pri- e banks vate bmnlcs and liankcrs 0,788 03 Check* and items of exchange md bills re-disonunted. Bills payable Total cash on hand 2.549 34 Ui a Total | hi Total </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 Emerson Tho Farmer Bank (. ham r Xo it in casbier K.P. llaa AisUtant Cathie: STAIKM VIM BEE 1 a nil I Limn* s-iil .liM-i.uctit $ tecured and ni judgments. use lurniiure and unted Total J151 403 60 i T«UI 1151.4 Emerson Tin* German American Bank I barter No. J80 Incori •hie »ui v i slue 'TATIMENT, XoVEMBIK IT, 1901 LIABILITY k paid i:. t ali», secured » 1,83S&lt; S3 - • -its subject to Mt. . us furniture and • tisea and tuxes paid i nationnl banks i other -late and prlrate baufcg and bankers 100 67 1 n-h nems - and bills rediaconnted Due from national, state and , ayable private banks ar.d bankers Cberks and items of exchange C«sti Total . | Total </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 Eu *tis Eustis The Fanner* The Farmer ■ State Bank n&gt;o rated. Bank nrterXo Incorporated. D»vi. Preskl. Diviil II Preskl M. v\ ashler State me st, S Statement, X 'VKMHEl: 17, . LIABILIT rk p»id in V KM HE 11 17, 190;! KKSOIRCES RESOURCES Loans and discounts t k paidia . overdrafts, secured and on - ■. securities, judgments, claims, etc ■'■■&gt;'('■' .*."."." ng house furniture and and taxes paid B. and other ds and aecuriiies ■ o oo me and ties, judgments clai lse furniture and and other and sec hue Hills payable ■ iiwing Chart. TATEMEST RESOI-Ri Loans and'! { | Overdrafts, aeeured and un- I uber assets Banking bouse furniture and . .. . Other real estate i standing : al Hll.i Current expenses and taxes paid Premium on U. s. and other and prirate banks and banker^ bonds and securities Cash items Due from national, state and Bills payable private banks and bankers 3.286 7V Checks and items of exchange &lt;Jash Total Total . rhe Ewiiiy; State Ba bi'.okf, securities, judyruentB, claims eic Bonds '**&gt; 11*1 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 TWKLKTI Wall;. ( o., Banker Exeter Charter No. II \v»ll«o« Owner ushier Vice-Fr. Assistant Cashier :TATIJIENT :.H\ EMIIF.R 17, liW KISOCKCE8 LIABILITIES Loan* and discount- ni stock paid in ooo OO Overdrafts, secured and ui. cure - mis unpaid Stocks, seem Hies judgments, ts mbjei't to claims, etc onds Bonds ■ues ot deposit ha kiin.- houae furniture and tlxtures of deposit. real estate andin Current expenses and taxes i&gt;aid ,. ite tanks »mi other ida and securities X les and b.lis re-dlseounted.. &lt;'*-( i •e and private i "hange *liKj,31S SB Total .. m Total Exeter Charter No. 74 Incorporated W. H.Tmytna President I C. U. Eeka Cashier Vice-Presldent | lnt casaitr Statemekt, Novkmbeb 17, l»03 BESOUKCEB LIABILITIES Loans and discounts ? 1«,783 50 Capital xtock paid in limmmi Overdrafts secured and unae - curv. 23 77 Overdrafta secured and nnae Surplus fund us fund ::::::;■■■ ■™ w curwl 23 77 Undivided profiu.... .^.g ui Dividends unpaid ..'.".. Undivided profits w. Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, ttc Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, ttc Dividends unpaid. Individual deposits subject to i-heck ] &gt; 8J0 00 Individual depositi'iDbject'to Bonds Bonds i-heck ] ' 8J0 00 nemand certificates °of 'ditDCsiti -j.'wn 00 Utber «s ets Other «sct5 Demand certificate* 'of 'ditDCsit! i.'so* 00 BankiDg bouse furniture and BankiDg bouse furniture and fixtures 3,870 00 Time cert.Heate« of drportt Time certificates of deposit. . lixtures y,870 00 Certified cnecks Certified cnecks Otber real Miatv Otber real estate Cashier s checks oimiandYnK Cashier s checks outntandlnii ' Due to national banks Current expenses and iaxesp«id i2X aj Curren t expenses and iaxesp«id i2X aj Due to national banks Premium on U.S. and other bonds and securities Premium on U.S. and other bonds and securities Due to atnte and private banks »nd bankern.... Due to state and private banks and bankers Caan items. Cash item- Notes and bills re-discounted .' '. '. Notes and bills" rWdiscounted: Bills payable Due from national, state and private banks and bunker? .. 5,336 73 Due from national, state and Bills payable. "" private banks and banker? .. 5,(86 73 Cbet-ks ar.d items of exchange 14 64 Checks ar.d items of exchange 14 64 Cash 4,8W»7 Total... 31,318 80 Cash 4,8W»7 Total 31.318 80 The Exeter State Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p133">133 Fair bury The Harbine Bank Charter ;!, &lt;i. \V. Huuseii President II. P. II ■ L. M.Kldridsre Vi.- Statement, Novembeb 17, 1SW3. BKSOUBCES LIABILITIES i and discounts «n6.5.»4 09 Overdrafts, seoun-d and unsecured 1,940 94 Capital stock paid in 160.000 00 50,000 00 idedpronu fc,40B It .vi.i.ni mi securities, judgments claims, etc claims, etc ■ -«■!» - UMU... iighouie, furniture and fix- nghouie, furniture and tl\- 132.308 S8 10.W7 85 10.WT 85 rrcmlnute use* and taxes pnid 491 US ind other &gt;» t expense* and taxes [.aid 491 US ies '..... nnd tecuritiM ' Dim- hi &lt;t»ip tad private tanks »mi linkers 73.711" m Due to stale and private banks Cash .III 00 Total. »81,37« 48 ToUl I5CI.376 W Fairbury Charter No. l.V» HKln.h I. M.B ashler I.. VV. I ..,,t I K. H AS!' uhitf Statmint, Notehbkr 17, 1903. KEMUKi ■ LIABILITIES -and discounts *H5.IS4 90 Ovenlmfts. secured and uusmiml lit 13 ck paid in &lt; ri\000 00 1&amp;.0WW 4,803 S3 Di&gt;i(J |f,tH mi judgments claim- i r.uoo oo ■ ■ Hanking house, furniture and ti\- &lt;1.7» W ...... TlllW cert I f1**.i t*'-* "f 'It'JloMt Other real estate mi m peatM and taxos paid «6a ml bonds aud - Due from national, state and pri- prirate bai S3.110 IB rate l&gt;anks and bankers ... i »* SO Bills payable -8B6* Tota! rids unpwi'i 17,100 00 •»««-, pri- hills re-ili&gt;' vate banks mid bankt-rs .... W.K44 U3 ! HUN (unable The (loodrich Bros. Bankiu. </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 Fairbury The Fairburv Fairbury The Fairbury Savings Bank Charter No. 155. .rter No. 155. !.!■ L. \\ L. W. (• E. F.. ' Vic ST1TIIE' STATEMENT. X ITEHBKB 17, 1908. LIABILITIES - k paid in $ I. ITEMBEB 17. IS«W. ■MM* B18OUBCE8 1.HB1MTIE . . . ltt,8ZS 46 !...„„, ami dtaem IK.8ZS M I k p»id in $ l.'.50O0O BoJbT. .' ng bouse furniture and tl\ Mb. ..*!*..... &gt;oi paid l'remi l&gt;ue from dm and j&gt;ri - und ..Hiikc-r Total | yi ind pri- . Uash ToUl . . ...19 ..$ »:.o;i (« Total | yi Fairfield The Citizens" Hank K. .1. I T. I". sbi\ Statement. Notiibib 17. 1008. LIABILITIES Loans and rtbnwtl . I W.86T n il stork paid in t 40.000 00 OTerdrafu. sei-un'J ami unsecured ... 8.U9843 IninM, Bonds »»eU UankinK house furniture and Demand .-..rutlrates of d&lt;-i«j-iit .. i-_&gt;n|&lt;i.v&lt; a.ixa 28 ()ih.-r real wtala ....... iui iki ixes paid «*k* out st. 1 1 erbondi ■ bauk&gt; 6.S33 98 1 1 .ii QflV ftl </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 Fairmont The Farme State Bank Krank v Statement N. EXBER 17. 19O 1 RESOURCES -.•ure&lt;taii&lt;1 un&gt;.iure&lt;l W :i rr -. -X ml item fl.WM'.i 35 Falls City I.R.I Vic Iain Statement. Ni F.MBKK IT. 1903. F.MBKK IT. 190S. LIABILIT BESOl'RCES I.IABII.IT1F. $-.' ■ Other assets tnc bouse furniture ami real estate - and taxes paid ind other l» and Meuriu-.s ii hand ami doc ' banks 1U6.000 W : assets g bouse furniture and fix- real estate -f &gt; ami taxes paid ■ Total cash on run. I idiI due fnmi ius.oeo so LIABILITIES .... ... The- Richardt nty Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 Falls City Tin- Falls State Bank Charter No. 159. W K. lk&gt;rrington . ■ ■lit I W A. (ireenualil. .shier \ STATEMENT, NOYEMBKK IT. IWU3. BESOUBCES I.IAHIL11IE I^ians at* discount- *1.- ■il stock paid in « 50.000 00 nd 5.000 00 « 50.0UO 00 - dand unsecured 1.108 S3 claims, etc Bond* Konds. V1.797 73 Banking bouse furniture and (Ix - 13.200 00 Banking bouse furniture and fix- I*&gt;man&lt;i ••pniH.-ales of deposit .. !'.W II fled checks V.'.V.' 2.000 Ui 13.200 00 ifled cheeks &gt;«i0 (Mi niei and taxes paid 2.378 58 iws and taxes paid J, 378 59 1^ toV.no^al'hai. k - " " '.'.'.' Cash Cash items ■n national, state and pri - rate banks and h Due from national, state and pri- . 1U.U00 00 rate banks and hankers . . 10.000 00 Check! and items of exchange . . t 'hecks and items Total oaab on faaad and d Total each oa hand am: banks W,0W 12 lwnk&gt; H.0W 12 ToUl 1159.553 12 Total 1159,583 12 ,, }15*,,t«3 i; {159,503 li Farnam Fariwm The State Bank The State Bank Charter So. 701. Incorporate*! . Charter No. 70S. Incorporated Hugh Ralston ....President Hua-h Ralston President I L.W . Kalstmi L.W. Kalstim J. ij. Kelly Vice.Premldent | Assistant Cashier J. ij. K. Vice.l»re.ldent A»U' STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 17, 10U3. KS8OUKCM LIABIL TIES Loans and &lt;i t 35.231 44 &lt;-kpaidln • 5,000 00 533 38 s . &gt;• , - ■ ' judgm&gt; 3.043 ."2 Bonds . .......... Other MM** is* furniture an4i S.44O 4« 1 .000 Ou uses and taxes paid 1.0OS 06 Do«- Doe to state and private banks ■ onal. stale and pi V " ... &gt;&gt;nks and baak»r (hecks and items of n hand $.881 W&gt; Tot: </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 Farwell Tlie Farwell State hank Charter So. Tl». Incorporated Prwiirtent A . Aniit^nu ubiei ITATEMSNT, NOVEMBER IT, 1903 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans ■ ■k paid in. "WOO rafts.saeurrd and un»&gt;Mired Maaki Maritto*, idgaMaM n :, m ltond» other assets Kmiknm house furniture and flx- ] rrul estate Kr bonds I -\i oq hanit and iiiie fnun - vv.i 18 ■ I eMH Filley Tlie State Bank of Fillev t'harter No. 618. Incorporated. \\ P.Xorcr H.H.N'ir ' iTATEMENT. N IVEMBKR IT, 1(02 LIABILIT1E • * &amp;.0WM * yam m • .-ured and ansccurro \6i H ClHIli HornU ■ subject to - Hanking bouse furniture and Ox Kll IK &lt;**&gt; mi | Mill ud other bond) ■ &gt;) banks * J3.WI II </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 Firth The Kirtli Bank Charter I. 11. Krtn Wra K STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 17, 19« HSOUBCES I.IABILITIE Lout .hi * 64.864 t»j 54 15 mil 11 \ 4.S6-J X $ 84.864 36 Firth The Citizens' Rank i Tresident w :.ililll Stated I IVEXBEK 17. !S«t UAR1I.IT1E Loans ■ i I 61 30 1.HS3 HO &lt;50 tr T » </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 Ft. Calhoun The Washington County Hank Ifcnrv Ri\ LIABILITIES fl.-il Kank ■ &gt; Due from national, st.ite anil pri :md bnnker- • Franklin The Franklin State Hank &lt;■ hi F. M. il TATIMEUT, NC HMOOTM FS LIABILITIES I.IABII 1T;K Loam am! I &gt; •&lt;) ■» i Cap . I s.nm OS ■■•OS - asset ltank -uiture and fix- .H\ du ■ '■uses and &lt; **U m.n </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 The Franklin Exchange Hank Charter Xo. 163. Incorporate! F. E.Garrat! U. .1. Murray Cashier Assistant ( iint Cashier Statement. November 17, 1908 LIABILITIES LIABILITIES KUOCBCCB BESOUKCES Cfc paid ill J15.000 00 Loan! and I 50.693 21 . . t 50.603 21 c-k paid ill J15.000 00 614 yi 614 l Jl :«0 00 Sloe* a. weurltiea, Judgm&gt; Ml f«i Ml fiii leposits m 26.480 it -•■..490 2J .... e furniture and nx- -nit lire and Hi - ;.iid 142 Tt pri - 800 00 (79 50 Dai . (79 so .&lt;« ou tmraa 5.000 01) 26.799 OU !.Hid 142 97 : . . . e banks anil hiif in Mattaad private baaki ■ml ■ nited I 14.1U6 97 ,V:ilil- Cash 4 Cash. Total . | 75,613 JO Total. I 75,613 40 Total t i5.«13 40 Total % 75,613 40 Fremont The Security Savings Bank L. D :. F. II. Kfc-li -^usurer A -sistant Cashier Statemint. November 17, ]s«i. resources LIABILITIES Loawaaialf'-inn- «l^.'.202 :»7 1 in t li.&lt;X« 00 3.080 0B - judgments. Mond- . .V. 5C«I M _■ liou-c furtiiture and Hi IVmand oertiflcii 3.857 50 • id 619 22 inding \1 :.■:■■ ■ ,-.- I .i ■.■!». ■ 6fi pri- Bills ]&gt;:. 16.»41 5.1 - and items of exchanc . . ' $140,906 SI ■ra:i"l. </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 Fremont Char) t Statement. November Statement. November 17 iMt. LI1BILIT *18l.0OB 71 I s I oo UK, 103 60 ■ The Merchants" and Farmers' Bank Merchants" and Farmers' Hank .rterNo. t*«; ■ No. 68fj K. II. Fergus ufciar Statement, November 17. 1S03 Statement, November 17. 1903 HF.nOI'Ri I LIABILITIES Loans ai 1 1 34,908 57 f ii.K.I .»! 9S5 Oh - II. WO 74 ect to Hanking house furniture and fix- flx- 6,102 00 IS 05 8,102 00 Other real estate paid '.*9 ' expenses and taxes paid ■'-'-■ TV #. C»ah items .'.'.III'.]']''/.]] 9»' in &lt;l pri I P«- -»nd bills re-discounted.'.".." vate banks and banters 20.435 75 Bills payable Checks a nd items of exchange Total cash on hand CMS 6.HW! (1 ToUl 1161,838 «7 Total *W.*3S m </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 Tin- Bank of ( » and v dandy ■ Statement. November 17, 19(X LIABlLtTIB! ■ ... f 38,884 M INI isseti ■ "■..'"* .... • Tin* Ban Garrison Statement. K iVEXBEK 17. 1903. LIABILITIES vember 17. 1903. ■ LIABILITIE ■ , . - - vatc bttnks . inted. I'.'ink* '.u86 80 ToUl »1&lt; ToUl I </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 &lt; Geneva The ub' Bank a V\ \ KMilKIt IT, !'.« 1 - i&gt;ty « J a Geneva Tin' ( il KMBRl: LIABILITIES ; | m ■■-i.r | ; </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 lerin * The Bauk of « iharter N... 1T2. Incorporated iharter No. 172, Incorporated President | • President i't'T M&lt; Cashier « Vice-President I Assistant C.tl.iei Assistant C«tl.ier Statement, Koykmbir 17, 1903. Statement, November 17, 19a KR85CKCM UABIL11 KF.SICIN E8 LIABILITIES Loans and discounts ( 90,308 87 Overdrafts, secured and unae- Dana and discounts 180,306. Ic paid In $ ■ &gt;i(u, secured and unse- ls'mu ek paid In - 241 3 i . . judgments, . judgments, - lbjecV to Othe- "awe"" . .'.'.'.'.'. '. '.'. '.'."'.'. '.".'. 6.064 * erenu«* stamps check «•&lt;»'• • osit" -e furniture and a Mm: house furniture and ixtui ... «.at; exp.nw.and taxes M ballks •W W ■ and taxes i if (H to national banks r" a ' uni !• ami private banks 'Hi'! private banks and linnkers ... ••■■ • H*n items. ... 5 .=■■ ills rediscount^ . - discounted l'i:. from notional, state and n. from national, state and Kill- nm-.n,. -and bankers ... 8.383 i2 B»ispa&gt;«Dlt; Ol tM-hl: Total $134,1:16 30 ! Totn . HM.1M 31 Bills payable ■v- and bankers X.333 i Kks noil lten s of exchai 4. WO n Total JI34,i:« 30 ! Total |lSi,13t 11 :«,1 (iermantown ermantown The Bank of (ieriuaiitown The Bank of iermantown Charter So. Charter So. 17::. Trivaii - 1'reoident | asbiei Priva President I Cashier Vice-Preaident | Vice-President I -lant Cashlei •nt Cashif r Statement, Notembek 17, 1S03. Btatimint, November 17, 1S« »SOn&gt;CES LIABILITIES unmcu I.IABILIT1E Loans and discounts | 2f&gt;.~!2 &lt;w nans an. 1 discounts | 2S,rt2 62 CapiUl sto-k paid in | 6.P00 0C i npital -to -k pniii in * 6,000 00 Overdrafts, -ecured and unse- verdraUs, secured and unae- plus fund Surpliis fund cured 1.102 42 Vnoivided profits.... w.i ■&gt; cured . 1.182 42 ided profits ... i*:; ,oeks, securities, judgments, l)lviden&gt;is unpaid Htooks, securities, judgments, claims, etc ends, unpaid claimii, i Individual deposits subject to iual deposits subject to ch- I iw oo Bonds ahdwarntnU Other assets .... onds aiid uarranU ch- - m&gt; I* ther a«set« nnd certificates of deposit 2* Demand certificates of deposit -X .- Banking house furniture and ankinir bouse furnitnre and Time nertificates of deposit . Tiint' of dtjioait fixture- :,900 00 fixtures 2,800 00 lertiBed checks !fil checks Other real estate ther real estate ... Cashier's checks outstanding.. Cashier's check? outstanding.. Current ezpenoes and taxes paid urrent expenxes and taxes paid Due to national banks Due to national banks Due to state and private banks and bankers Premium on 0. S. «nd other bonds and securities.. remium on V S. »nd oilier Due to state and private banks bonds and securities and bankers ('ash items RSh items Notes and bills re-discounted.. Notes ami bills re-diseounte.i Due from national state and ue from national state and Bills payable Bills payable private banks snd banker* . 25,27! 06 Thecks and items of exchange 3,045 88 ToUl </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 'hvk. Pr&gt; James Halloway Vice-Pr*- . STATF.V kmhv.h IT. 1SKJ3 i.iiHii.iTir t lli.iii«i 80 Other assets Ti!'i- 1 -rrt:li.-Ht.--Mf ,|^,»,m&gt; Ottinr RMtl «U* '.&gt;:iid Doe to national Unks iini urivue bank « bmaks &gt;ud bank 3.113 61 Tlie Exchange Hank II I Flint l'r. - I. \. Kirk. is Kirk Statimejit. X Vt.MKKR IT. IOCS RESOURCE! LIABILITIES [imT mi Msaoutit- t 41 12s 33 Capltmlstoek paid in... ! O0 uo m urines, jm i:raeni-. claiEis. etc i.roflU Uivi.ten&lt;1» BBpHi;''.!!!""!!!"" .... .. . ■ furniture and fl\- il depotiU tut M no Other real estate Iivmanil IWillfcaf id deport ■ id. I.HT7 US ■luslct of d&lt; ; d other bonds - Due to ntt i.'.n». banka &gt;-• VMI Dui- from n:iti..n:i! *t:itp iinl |iri- and ba nluand bat 11.180 «3 Checks and items ■ i ' nted. Hills payable •ash on hand J.OTU 11 Total f M.0W 17 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 (ii liner Bank of Bromtk'ld Charter No uhler tisirtant Ca»hier Statev mbf.b 17, m stock tuid in I - anels ruiture and i ■ »nd i tiki and • :ems of ex&lt; ToUl Gienvtlle Qienville k of iville adhier i .in &lt;-nibier Statev VEXBKR 17. 1903. LIABILI1 tal stooic piid i:. f ;-.'.oco CO iabii.it Loam aii' Lomm Capital stooic piid i:. ; m 00 :its t :its t re and ■ us ■ funr taxes palii :ial, state act! xclianre .'«t( (HI e«Utc DuetosM ate bnnki and bank ■c'discountt' : -late and piiratebanki and banker- ate acd em M hanre . Tot al Tot al </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 *.jocnnci* Tlie Goehner Hank Char ■ rated :::::::::::::::::viii-\ &lt;*•«•• lahiwr 8TATF &gt; VKMI1ER 17, 1908 RE I.IABILIT1» Loans and d. j i and un- i a] stock pa: : 1b i i ihi q r Its, see 1 - and sccur. siate and In ami i. inkers and it* Ciordon Jharter So ated. I.: vi Overdra I m ".re and n£ houw ■ &gt;m national. st-.te i" banks and ban hecks and iiemiof exchani: </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 Qraf Charter No. «6. •orated ,rmf Owner I J. O ashler Vice-President | Assistant Cashier bTATEMENT NOVEMBER 17, 1903. BBBOCBCES BESOCBCE8 LIABILITIES IABILITIEB Loans and discounts * 24 004 04 Loant and discounts I 24,004 04 a I stock paid in I 5,000 00 al stock paid in I 5,000 0» 1 Overdrafts, secured and u: cured 1,347 88 Overdrafts, secured and uu&gt;ec- HurDlu- cured 1.347 88 - Dividends unpai&lt;1 profits l - Stocks, secuilties, judgments, claims, etc Stocks, secuiitles, judgment!., claims, etc Dividends unpaid. . Individual deposits nil check Individual deposits subject to check . Bonds Bonds Demand certificates ot deposit 336 10 ■incites of deposit Other aaseU Other assets UMier mkw Banking house furniture and fixtures Banking house furniture and fixtures of deposit. of deposit Other real estate Other real estate .'Cks outstanding hecks outstanding.. Current expenses and taxes paid ■.i«i r Current expenses and taxes paid ime to national banks Hue to national bank- Premium on V. 8. and other bond* and securities Premium on U. S. and other bond* and securities Due to state and private banks and bankers One to state and private banks and bankers Notes and bills re-discounted. . Cash Hems Cash items N&gt;tes and bills re-discounted Due from national, st«te and Due from national. Mite and private banks and banker* .. ..412 59 ; syable Bills payal private banks and bankers . . . Check* and Items of exchange Check* and items of exchange ToUl $ 30,64 » 49 Total ... Urafton The Graf ton State Bank Charter No. 662. Incorporated Krank W. Sl'an President I Harry K &lt; ashler W. A Vice-President I ... taiit Cashier Statement, November IT, 190. KUOUKCES RESOURCES LIABILIT. LIABILITIES Loans and disconnls I 39,877 05 Loans and discounts $ 38,877 05 Capital stock paid in . . 10 (JUO o» CapiUl stock paid in ... 10 000 o» Surplus fund . ' W Surplus fund . ' W Overdrafts secured and unse - cured . Overdrafts secured and unse - cured Undivided profits ....' i v&gt;4 i Di»Idenrts unpaid.""!"!.""." Undivided profits i v&gt;4 is Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc Di»idends unpaid Individual deposit! subject to check Individual deposits 'subject to check Bonds Bonds cnecK Demand certificates' 'of deposit! o.rti fl a rt c n Sk?. of . . depo€U - ■ • ■ i8 - 7 * m Demand certificates" 'of deposit! Other assets .... Other assets Banking bouse furniture ana fixtures 1,000 00 Blinking house furniture an* SemneT caecf," ". . "^ \ \ [ 18 ' 7S8 TO fixtures 1,000 00 Otber real estate Other real estate Cashier s checks outstkndini;'" Cashier s cbecks'outstandVn'g'" Due to national banks Current expenses and lazes p»id 1.99183 Current expenses and taxes p»id 1,901 8S Due to national ban ki... " "" Premium on U.S. and other bonds and securities Premium on U. 8. and other bonds and securities Due to atate and private banks and bankers... Due to state and private banks and bankers Notes and bills re-discounted.' «'a»h item* lM ■ Cash Items KW ■ Notes and bills re-discounted.' '.'. Due from national, stato and private banks and bankers .. 'phis of exchange Due from national, stato and private bants and bankers .. Bills payable ..'.'.'.'."' Bills payable. items of exchange Total cash on hand nnd dtie from ban 12,519 07 hand nnd &lt;! 14,519 07 Total 56,524 47 Tola; T^n~7 Total f SUUl 47 The Bank of Graf </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 S fc.^ *K KT A K \ iJY T 'UK 8T ATK H A N K I N Grand Island The Graud Island Banking Chart' J. W. Thompson ITMulenr (,. H. Bell Statement Nc iveiiii IT. 1W)3. ZESOURCE) LIABILITIES Loan* and dUcout -"'"■SSSSraE- Bonds - UHU... ng boose, furniture and flx- MWS 35 .- hoaw, furniture :imt Ox 30,fMB &lt;M Time certificate! of de|- «,S11 51 Time certiflcate* of rt3,Sll 51 -00 00 » 'ert j' ■ -rial banks &lt; urrt-nt expenaa* and taxe* paid urrent « ! Premium or Premiui and bank' 1.000 00 I.OOD 00 and pri - vate ba .. 11.371 Ofi pri - 1I.S71 Ofi )60 R ilUcounted -"-dlacounted :)60 *7 Cash Total r3M.U»i W Cash Total ISM.UM 80 Totu ISM.UM 80 Total S3M.0M 90 Grand Island The Commercial State Bank Charter No. 607 II. B. Sie«»rt resilient K D. I) Vice- President C H M«Mfc V -MsUnt (Ja*hler TlT£«i:\T, NOTXVBEB 17. l«03. LUIIL1TIKS 9 M.5&amp;4 7¥ • k paid in t :».«» 00 1.344 W I&gt;1\ Kifll.l- iillp ml m^count uid fl^- tnrea 1.000 00 . uses and ta\ Pn-mtni ■■•■ national, stato and vat« ImiiksaiKl In hanire .. 170 14 ivable u.eao -it t*l itock paid in 1100.00* M Mfc :::::::.::::::■: SSS leodi unpHiil </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 Qreeley The Greeley State Hank Garr\ Treu .T. K Statim ivembkr 17. 1903. LIAB1LITIE Loans urn! HIS I •*" H, NU .red 900 00 ilm aud Bx- 1.300 00 4.300 00 i '■s paid ■ 'bansc. . . • ) Ores ham The Farmers" and Merchants' Hank ucorporated iJpiu I .1. K. Han i.-nt | C. II. Uavittoon it, 100: ■ UMS and dU.-u.ints 172,171 lemeau, I' I&gt;u*- fr..Tll"l.;llic,ii:.i iKi'ilks ',".'.'.'.'.'.'. ii.'iol MM mi T"t-il Total </seg>
            <seg id="p151">151 Static i E8OCKCB ABILITIE ,«• i. M I The I Bank .1 ATKVt IIABILITIE .... 111(1 Hi tl k- :ilM i &gt;:i fjl </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 TWELFTH ANNUAL KKI'uKT «'K THE Guide Rock The Bank of Guide Rock Chart" ■ \\ T. ■ M. Ik. uilli. , .-.hier Statement, NOVEMBER it. \»a. RESOURCES LIABILITIE1 Loans ami discount- I 47.4*8 75 1 in 115,000 00 mserured 97 83 profits Stocks. u-meiits. idedproBU 3,828 50 na bouse furniture and flx - tans . MM mi i n.-utesof deposit .. I.UT0 OR t &gt;th»T r»*al «*statH ixei paid M ■ it standing ... and securities .... Due to ttatr te bank ind pri- Billi payable 34. 309 01 I %.7I5 HI Halgler igler The Empire Loan ft Trust Co. II W. Ouolaii r. Dun,:, i President I \V . II. Lamed.. .. \\ . II. Larm-il Cashier \ I Attistant ■ Assistant Cashier Statement, November 17. 1903. Statement NOVEMBKB 17, 1903. RESOURCES resources liab1l tif.g * 15.5W7 39 .idin t 445 30 . * 15.507 3» 445 30 •■j, judgments, 1.153 84 U id&gt; I " - m fi _ in .u-&lt;' furniture and fl\ .«• furniture and fi\ 74! OU «,105 SI 4«1 37 and pri - .ankers.... uited. livable .' (W0 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p153">153 Hallam The Hallam Hank Charter No. ,'&gt;13. Incorporated. OartaMd Kip President I -ent I i;.H. Kulma'k \&gt; - Asiiitant C:iihwr Statement, November IT, imi. RESOUBCE« LIABILITIES Loans and discounts I. ck paid in. t 5.000 M (ts.sacured&amp;nd unsai-ured Stocks, securities, judgments. S*t 10 MM ■ Honds 1. 0411 mi ject to other asse ■ Hanking hem-- furniture and ti\- '■■»t."« .if d. tures 1.500 00 nt eipenM* and taxes paid 1.348 8S IT»... . v:ite bfiok&gt; and bMiik- -' hand anil li UMt 11 ■ ♦ tkMt w Hampton The Bank of Hampton I! llouslil Pn-5 ITATIMENT. NOVEMBEB LIABILITIES Kt-lKiK t." ««' 0* M 1 .040 21 0M« 3.UII 98 ■ furniture aud fix- 1.300 00 y.300 00 ad taxes paid i.l other bonds ■ 1 1 !•» 101 «S rirate hanks vate bauk» h Ml 1.1 lyafeli i 3.0*) SM l-.W.rt.* ik . </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 Tin' 1 1 aid v Bank .'barter No WO. 1 \\ II : . !&gt;T*Tf - \'i\ EVP.KF1 I.1AK1I.IT1E . - " - |II*U3I 01 I Marrisburg The Banner Countv Bank A STATK»C!«T. NnvIKlEK 1.1AB1MTIK i nx- 710 83 -'iKvuaiiri lain paid 1 II imilkk :ttn1 ' </seg>
            <seg id="p155">155 Harrison A ATKHt • BEH 1 BESOUKCE ITI ES Umii- I Hanking h&lt; ft.110 47 - Hartington The Fir- I'.ank ■ Statement, November RK.-OURI ES LIABIMTIE W.C5I &lt;XS » w.owm Moots, f- ;( rfM 17 r asset "furniture and tix- :«n9e« and tnif- [&gt;:n&lt;i 1 1 ▼ate banks and bun. V «O • Total i </seg>
            <seg id="p156">156 Harvard The I nion State H;uik Charter No. IMS. Incorporated P. li. I pdike Presid«nt I F. Kuenueih Cashier S II. l: President ] W. II A»-i»t»nt Cashier Statement. November IT, IMS RESOURCES RESOURCES *lfvj.3!5 79 LIABILITIES LIABILITIES ■It paid in $ 25.000 00 Capital stook paid in $ 25.000 00 Loau» a . 115-2.315 ?9 ;o« «o 1.500 00 704 » 1.500 00 led profits net 704 W 704 m 8.UJSC0 -ndMinpaiil 8.0KCO to 58.248 10 - N it urc ami fix -nitureand flx- -t i rtcatei of depo.it . . 13.8*1 OS -t ideate* of depu- -u a; fiS.9O6 08 •'- banks 11JHI « I tana uiMkBd Uzes p«iil ■ ■u«rs and taxes paid ind other bo ' ioi 9J ;iml pri - 1(L*OU «5 It'S bull Mi y-i i 1,515 « van- banks ■ MLMO S6 .jalil.- n li.'iml .. 0.4M :«i Total rash on hand 6.4*8 W ToUl . $184,331 16 ToUl 1184.381 16 Total I1H4.331 18 $1X4.331 1« Harvard The Harvard State Bank Incorporated ■(••iii I M. Wfil M. K. t ant Cashier statement. November 17, 1903 KK-l'l 'Hi K- LIABILITIES ill 77 !:,n uur.- and til' 1.093 p5 and lixiur 1,091 K Utlicr n*al est: ■ .... mil 531 42 531 42 it standini; Hiding le banks anted al banks and fecurities I utAie and pri- ■ bank and pri- anted Bills payable &gt;«IO 00 Tut., f 63.9J0 m Billi payable l»nk&gt; I(3.&lt;M» 41 Iwnki... . It5.«4» 41 * 83,«WM $ S3,&lt;M fl» ToU&lt; ♦ 63,930 m Iudin f J5.000 00 tlu.Hcand &gt;diI m b, judgmth 6«1 l« imt, etc lft.847 7« </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 Havelock The Farmers" and Mechanics" Bank liartcr Xi I. [mor W. K. .lolniMii, 1'r. ■ I 11 K G. G - Statement. Xov ■ MBER 17. 11*13. RESOURCES LIABILITIES s UN ■« ': . :iK house furniture and ti\- 3.501 Due fr i&gt;ri - ■ ami Items ofeichanoi 3,706 31 ■ ami Items ofeichanoi .',,i 9i a M 3! *l 17.340 61 • HIT *1 17.340 51 • II Hay Springs The Farmers" and Merchants' Hank Hay Springs The Farmers" and Merchants' Bank I). T. Taylor Hopper.. Inr llop|»r. I). T. Taylor. S. E. Taylor i'-nt ! Statement, Kovkmbkk 17. 1903. Statement, November I KF-SOlBlBS LIABILITIES I 1S.30B 64 I S.IWI 00 ir«l . MM) (&gt;0 ItO Other assets • \t.tU U Banking house furniture and fix- Uem.. l.fltVi 00 otli.rreal esUt&gt; .'.'.'."..'.'.'. and banker*.. ' luii on n rom 1S.8M ll </seg>
            <seg id="p158">158 T iHf KL.Fl H ANN I A Ij KK "OK r ' • r I I) K May Springs The- Northwestern State Hank Charter Statement, November 17, 191 LIABILITIES ■ ;&gt;«i'l in iM &gt;« I ■ bank I "- i Hebron The Tlmver County Bank W II ( IABILITII • ■ I MM is I </seg>
            <seg id="p159">Memingford The Hank STATEMENT. XnVEMBER r. ! X I I Henderson III I! «\ M » </seg>
            <seg id="p160">160 KTH ANNUAL KEl'dKT &lt;&gt;r THE Henderson The Farmers" and Merchants' Hank &lt; harter No. 708. Incorporated Jacob I. Kr.»-kcr President I .1.1. 1 Cashier MfeW Vice- President 1 D. .1. Kroker Assistant Csti.ier Assistant Caol.ier Statement, November 17, VM RLBOEKM RE.80CBCU I.IABII.II L1ABIL1TIE Loans and discounts % 35,353 77 Loans »ml discounts I 35,353 77 . ; stock paid in t 10,000 00 al -i..i k paid In t lu.iU) » i Overdrafts, secured and unse - sared .... . '!&gt;" n jjhiu in « iu,«iuu iv Overdrafts, secured and unse- nured .... i Stocks, securities, judgment*, claims, tic 8U&gt;cks, securltie*, Judgments, claims, etc n-sunips ln.ii.i !'.n dfi&gt;»its lubject to cbf 3.SS1 30 In.ii.i !'.n deposit*, subject to check ■Mtasjastsjsasa Iiemind ( irtificates of deposit.. I 'en .!e« of lieimsit.. : »ies vl deposit .. 11,1 % house furniture and »■ kltii house furniture and lilt - of deposit . . 1S.1 i6CkS Other real eitati- Other real eiUti- i »-hin s cbecks ontxauding i »-hin s cbecks outstanding Current exp»nsrs and taxes psid Current e-xp-nse a ami taxes psid lint- to nstional banks I nit- to national bank - slate aod private banks and hunkerfl .. .... rediBCOunted .. Premium on U. S. and other bonds and securities Premium on U. s. and oiher bonds and securities iatc and private banks ■aikers Cash item- Cash items Um from national, state and •• discounted l&gt;n- from national, state and private liHnk-aml bankers C 250 78 Hills payable private bank* and bankers Checks and iten.sof excha: Checks and iten.sof exchani,'" 1 Total &lt;*ai&gt;li ou hand... i»h ou hami Total . . f IM* 36 I Total Total ... S 4- » «, The Plateau Hank Herman Charter No. WC,. l'riva Ch»s.P. Clir .. . President Vioe-President Assistant Cashier Statement, MBKK 17, isoa MABILITIE8 REsorai es ■il stock paid in $ SI. 000 00 Loans and discounts . . $10»,:&gt;M 3S (ivcnlritft-, secured and unse - cured 3.155 53 Stock*, securities, judgments. Surplus fund I iimvided profits 3.111 Dividends unpaid Individual deposits subject to claims, etc Bonds and v P'-mand certificates of deposit 1.0H 00 Other assets Banking house furniture and fixture- 4.900 00 lime ct-rtiticates of deposit 22.963 17 ;ied checks Other real estate kmw 7i Cashier's checkr outstanding Current expenses and taxes paid Due to national banks Due to state and private banks and bankers l.BI &lt;t Premium on U 8. «nd other bonds and securities Notes and bills re-discounted.. H.tfel 00 c-sh Items ' -SI! 1MT1UB. ■ Due from national state and Bills payable private banks and bankers... 4.061 80 Checks and items of exchange 114 M check C«*h </seg>
            <seg id="p161">161 Hershey The Bank of Lincoln County ' r Hickman The Bank of Hickman LIAB1L1TIE I : 1.H36 » ; m ... inn id . mil fl\ MLW MO (W iVitti »^ 43.500 t."i 1121. II </seg>
            <seg id="p162">162 TWELFTH REIH'RT ofr The Franklin Co Bank of Hildreth Hildreth Charter No. *» In Cathier AisUtant Cathie: Statement, Novkmbeb 1", 1 LIAHILIUES LIABILIUES RKSOUBCES RKSOUBCES la] Hock pal&lt;] in I ■Ml stock pal t .iOOO 00 Loans snd discounts I ■ Loans ami discounts rsfts, secured and u: red and ui y -3' y -3' &gt; judgments. urities, judgments, deposit* subject to «te* of deposit. ate banks ■ li maud rertiticates of deposit Other uueli % house furniture and - assets u-e furniture and j ties of dcpos - real estate ■ nwBaml tsxespid - and o •1 sei urities ,p«eaand tixeap&gt;id e banks and bankers - and other itnd seiurities and bant. bills re-discounted. . . Mini bills re-di«counted Billi payable ltemi | Billi payable ■ Total Total t / of Hol brook i r|&gt;orated. Holbrook Hol brock Tiie Bank &lt; Tiie Bank of llulhrool Charti Cashier Cashier B ut cashier sant casbier iTATEM I vembkr IT, 1903. LIABIL1T aid i:. t S.OCO CO i "ch. EMBK ,1*1! I Loans and ii red and un- Loans and di ■ v. pan ed aDd un secured : * :«&lt; n Stocks, s» ents, . iras, etc ... r assets - Hssets H ■use furniture and tnnkiiK' huuse furniture and er real eKtato . xpen^es and tfl\ - bond" and securities b items .... it itanding standing - real estate : expenses and ts banks ■itional banks. .. •• and private banks and private banks rs ". and bills rediscounted ! bills rediscounted Dae from national, state and Dae from national, state and payable i hc&gt; mo . ■&gt; . </seg>
            <seg id="p163">163 The First State Hank harterN i -i corpora ted I - :\\\\\\"\\""::::. vi ATEMENT, NOVEMBER 17, 1908 IABIUTIES SKrSSSS -andnn- ' P* iJ in » I an red and u aret e )ther tts?t g house furniture ■ :1 est« uuer real estitc «nd^&lt; e liir Homer Bank Cisbier « it IT 19 LIABILIT1I; | 8g.90&gt; 01 O\erdrHfts, aecured and un- '•ick paid i ii rt -eourities, judgment!, ■laiins «lc ., ; ■ Banking bouse furniture and ix'urrs real estate • s and taxes paid 1.48S 30 Premium on U. 8. and other -iHte and prirat and bankers bonds and securities Cash items ■discounted Dm- from national. stVte and Bills payable private banks and bankers i Checks and item* of exchange '.'. </seg>
            <seg id="p164">164 I.FTH ANNUAL KKI'olM OF THK Hooper Tlie Dodge Countv Bank ■.iit Cashier -lant Cashier 3VKMBFK IT, LIABILITIES Ual stock paid in !us fund I profit* l)i\iden&lt;ls unpaid tVKM lil M8OUECB8 RESOlRrEP LIABILITIES Loan* and discounts &gt;:&gt;» or Loano and dlscoui. . $233, tee ff lal stock paid in ov.nlmfts. secured and ui. cared . . ov.nlmfts secured and untec- Surplus fund - - Dividend! unpai Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc Stocks, secuiities, judgmi - claims, etc Bonds Bonds Other assets oil if r assets... BatikitiK House furniture and Hit BankiiiK house furniture and fixtures .. Other real estate Other real estate becks outstanding ' h.-cks outslandi: - 1 private links Current expenses and taxes pai'i .m on C. a. and &lt;■; bond» and securities ... rurrent expenses and taxes paid &gt; nutiomil banks &lt;im on 0. ». and bonds and sec arities and private banks ■ nd baiiK re-discounted.. Oa*h items Oaah items 8 re discounted.. Duu trom national, stite and private btnks and lan«- Duu from national, stite and BilU payable BilU payable private btnks and hankers Checks and items of cxchan- Checks and items of exchange U. 440 86 Total «X),45S 10 Total .. W&gt;ti,t Hoskins Incorporated ..Vice-President . , ailt cashier Statement, Novkmbir 17, 19O? Loans and discounts i Overdrafts secured and unse- Stocks. Hcarlties, judgments), claims, ttr Bonds Other as'c! Wt ■ Banking house furniture and Otber real es'atp Carreni expenses »nd JUO 19 •i»l banks.... Premium on U. 8 and other ■ • an&lt;i priTa'te'banV bonds and securities Cash item!- and banken Nntes and bills re-discoi- ' .d.' u national. st&gt; Bills payable T.408 07 Charter No. Jl .l«rr\ I&gt; a.-tiier ■ant Cashier Tlie Hoskin's Btate Bank Charter No. 5tq Presiden lubilit: ek paid in „ „.. m Xuralus f n 1 1 ' l Girted proflu ts subject to Denm Time certificates of dcpoalt 21.027 m KlldlDK ".! </seg>
            <seg id="p165">165 v In* Hank of Howe ■ TATEJIt VEXBEIl IT. i'.-ll. LIABILITIES - uuo w .on ™&gt; ■ - • ■ T um I turn n t r:.«i IT tiowells The Colfax ■ ATEM&gt; E»BER 17. 190! I I Mill 11 It. ill *t - nd pri- &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p166">166 Howell* (•resident I Statement, November 17, 1908. REHOl'RI ES I.IABI1.1TIK Loans and discounts IKI tin- rafts, secured and unset' •:•:::::.:::: -niliiro :iik1 fix- 11.100 - real estate. 13 Ml nta* and tales paid ier bond -tate and pri vate b "" 2.261 *7 Ll ! Hubbard The Hubbard State Bank r &gt;o, T43. Im-orporated David I luis . '■ State v I.IABILIT1E * 7.000 00 - . ■—ik o furniture and fix- - real estate r ' &amp;t m sow • ■ ■ t 21,632 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p167">167 Hubbsll The Iluhbi'll Hank Statement. N YEMBER BESOURCE LIABILITIE! 5 - ■ Oth-T rva Total i-as.li cin h»i I Humboldt Tlie State Hank " A \ I State m I ; lAini.iriE I .... I) md Bx- »M 33 r bonds I. MOM Total </seg>
            <seg id="p168">168 The Hank of Ottis ct Murpliv Vtkinson Statimekt, November 17, 1903. RESOURCES IAB11.1TIE: ■ ind pri- » 000 OU The Bank of Hyannia Myannis Statement, Novembeu liabil.tik ll Im .. 'It* t 35 - </seg>
            <seg id="p169">169 SECRET A K Y OF T 1 N K I N t Imperial The Farmers" ami Merchants" Hank ■»r No Ineorperat ill Ei LIABi: • ■ ' irsiture and Indianola The State Hank ,N . D St.it im VEMBEB IT. Idti- LIABILITY ;:RCE9 ... * OS.*'' I M.M It M -.■ furniture and 111 -niture and flx - nd other li. T&lt;mhI cash on hnnd and buki </seg>
            <seg id="p170">170 Inman Tlie Inman Hank STATE V DYEBBEB 17, 1S«J IAHII.IT1K • I urn ;&gt;tid y.i 1.806 74 •■ furnitim- .... ul estate ■ banks and I ■ Ithaca The Fan ate Bank Statkjiixt 1 IAHII.ITIK ■ J '.CB8 'i mil B\- 1.882 Ot&gt; : ' S02 81 '•MB CO Totai I 57.199 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p171">171 Jackson Tlio Hank of D, Kean ATEMEXT RESOURCE LIABILITIES Bunking bouse, furniture and fix » Wl : Jansen The State Bank NOVEMBER i Statement, RESOURCES LIABILITIE I F «id in * (T.«(1K lioiui Bank &gt; : Mx - tures and pri ~ '.i'4 »a5.38S11 ! Tot, I «.3 s ■ M I </seg>
            <seg id="p172">172 Johnson 1 lie* r iirrncrs 1»ihik or joik Incorporated Statkmmt. November 17. 1SW3 LIABILITIES REPOUKi ES « HO.S23 88 ( is ;v m - liturcand flx i6.s«jfi 4. - s . r.o.ir. \* :• Johnstown The Citizens" Bank !. II" STATE v UABii.rnt. • $ s. 9f&gt;l ■( )■&lt; «I 30 ■ ■ i2.ws n . I 38.980 61 I tt,SM ''.I </seg>
            <seg id="p173">173 luiian The Bank of .lulian Statement. November 17. ltW3. Statement. November BMW rf.s LI ABII-IT1K ■ « '&gt; II -•■ furniture ami fix tix - 630 I- &lt; - ■ Juniata Jumata Bank of Jmiiata Bank K M B K I 1 7 HM lit! .... til 1. 1(00 (X RESOt'Bl ES !!:■ i- k hilt house furniture -mil fix ■ -. .... ,■ 'e bank H i^&gt;» * </seg>
            <seg id="p174">174 Kearney The Farmers" Bank Charier i LIABILITIES ■ - . | ■ -. be nk- kenesaw Exchange Hank t State mint ■ ABILITIES 5 M . I Tot»l ! </seg>
            <seg id="p175">175 The Farmer- Bank iTim RI9OCBII » t Kimball Bank of Kim ball - ■ ud ti\ ?«8 333 01 anks anil Im ; : Mi Kills i»vat rtln s&lt;) </seg>
            <seg id="p176">176 Laurel The Fanners Bank c hart. Incorporate 'dent i cashier Assistant i KMBER 17 ] uaooacH - LiiBii.n LIABILITIE Loans and discounts -ed and nnae - Loans and discoun! k paia In i 2C,cK)( ■; paia In | i 2.6B6 X to -ed and unse- judgments, check 'ificate* of deposit. . 500 0 ■!ificate«of deposit.. 30(1 and use furniture »nd -^ and taxes paid 1,1 anding ■id taxeti'H i oiher and private bank: bond* and hecuritiei im ■ ■ buv from national, state and private bank- and banken l nyable buv from national, atate and private bxnk-and banken l Ckn-kl in ■ | h-' i- it: • I. 171 49 71 49 | Total.... • * 9S.SS0 31 Total... - I »«,8S0 31 Total Laurel The Laurel Bank i ■TATEMINT, NOVEMBER 17, 1S« LIABILITIES I.IABIL1TIE BESOUtCES RISOUtCBS Hi stork p»id In I I Hi stork paid in I I i" fund .. - unpaid .... tual deposits subject to Mies of deposit l • -indlng . Loann and ditcoain liacounta I -ecared and unae -oiured and unae - ■ •«, judgments, l&gt;rofit!« unpaid If menu, 1ual deposits subject to is of rtepi - nueta .... ■lire and re and ■th fS.OOO c^ _ • other real estate Cashie Htidlng niher real ••« and uxe« paid taxes paid to national hanks to national i.aiiks . .... mi ■ and private banks and bankers Due to state and private banks and bankers ... KM H 565 JI M 21 Notes ami bills re-discount &gt; Notes ami bills re-discounted Due from national state and private banks *nd bankers . r'hecks «nd items of fx&lt;h«nee Due from national state and private banka »nd banke - k-i »nd items of fx&lt;h«nBe [i In nrl and iIiip from Total . . »ia3,S» » Bills payable »&lt;U 00 Bills payable n In nrl and iIiip from ... ai.sau :*■ Total |153,nW 3K Total |l j3,.tW M Total *153,iW9 Chart. </seg>
            <seg id="p177">177 SECRETARY OF THE 8TATK BANKING B' Lawrence Tlie State Bauk of Lawrence Charter ■r»tiil Mlorf Jolm O. Rilov Vice-Pretideut | .lay ' Statement. Nothbeh 17. 19U3 LliHll.lTIK&lt; $ 4O.3W 60 • .il Mock ph.,1 iu 877 U -. judgment to -ndt unpaid Konils Otlier assets ml depo«it~ liankiux '...■.&gt;#■ furnitur - '-erUfleatet of Jn 034 113 Ui ■ : . state and (!►.' 1 58.1*3 7e | Lebanon The State Bank .1 W.flupp State m LIABIL1TIE ! Capital p»iu in I Hunk in rnitunr her bf te bank </seg>
            <seg id="p178">178 Leigh - A I'.ank Charter No. H In&lt;-orporau Cashier Assistant Cashie: VBEB 17,1903 RICdO- LIABILITIES 0 t ' stock paid in .... . I ■ &lt;-uiired and uuse- »r in I ure and . ■ :e bank hankers.... discounted - Total lota Leigh I harter No. - 'resident | \ Cashier ant Cashier TATKX MBKR IT, IJO LIABIL1TIK ].o»n" k paid ii. | lo.OCO CO .0.. IK) • us ■ furniture and real eitat? tea paid ». and other bonds and securities -tate and private banks and bankers fills - and bills rediscoanted liue from national, state and d l«olcers . ayable Total.. | </seg>
            <seg id="p179">1 ATS BA N 179 Lewiston The Hank of Lewigton Charter No icorpo rated. ... cashier Vice-1're-;. tatem: MBER 17, 1903. RESOURCES &gt;BILITI«S Lotnsand discount- ! rafts, secured and I irities, juUgmt etc deMMita m Bonds assets ing house furniture - re»l estat - s and taxes paid iiu on US and other ■* bonds and sccr Total i Lexington The L nk Lexington Chari- Char Hted. oted. E. Da' li. Da I VlocPret tTATEMEKT, NOVEMBER 1", I KEB0UBCE8 LIABILIT1B8 B. Darr . .. a: IATEMENT EMBER 17, 19C KE8OUBCE LI IP ialO 00 r:ifU, KC 3, judgme claims etc Banking house furniture and fixtures necks r real estate •cksout Mk urrent exiitnses and taxes paid national banka Premium on U. 8. and other ■ and securities state and private banks and bankers items discounted •n national, sttte and private banks ar. ijable - and item) of ex 14,936 43 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p180">The State Bank Charter No. 401 Incorporated. ...--pi: ».: nsiilent I C. Vice-Prenldent [ A. Cashier ink Assistant Cashier bTATEMENT NOVEMBER IT, 1903. BESOCBCES LIABILITIES Loan* and discounts I 5-.«.7S6 80 Capital stock paid in i ju.OOO 0» Overdrafts, secured and untec- Stocks. secuihies, judgments, Surplus fund 4.080 00 eared 510 15 ludivided profits *71 bi Dividends unpaid claims, etc 2* 00 Individual deposits subject to check . 51.1B 46 ■sseu w house furniture and es a.80C 00 eal estate.. ; expenses and taxes paid V7\ 16 Dems ates of deposit KS4T «4 - of *|» ir «r 31 Cashier'!' (becks outstanding Due to national banks Premium on D. 8. and other bonds and securities Due to state and private banks •nd bankers : . Notes and bilis re discounted.. Cash items Due from national, st«te and Bills payable 1IC irum U1UUUA1, nnic buu private banks and bankera . . li.lw v&gt; Checks and items of exchange. Cash I. mo hi Total 191,493 14 Total » M^H -i Tlie American taring! Bank Charter No. 500. Incorporated President I 1. Cashier ..Vice-Prwident I .... tint Caabiet Statement, November IT, 190.!. RESOURCES LIABILITIES UMns and discounts |M .ck paid in rafts secured and unae- rplus fund rndivldeil profits..!. l nniviaea profits Dividends unpaid .] Stocks, securities, judgments, Bonds ami SS.90B 33 - Individual deposits so check i iii' r. of deposit ??I^ Banking house furniture an4 ..vrr. :::: Uom« «32 M Due to nationafbankV! Due to state and private bank and baukers l&gt;en«ea and taxes p»id 1.488 15 Premium on U. 8. and other bonds and securities... M H Notes and bills re-discoi- Bills payable rash items... Due from national, stat" ami </seg>
            <seg id="p181">SECRETARY OK THE STATE BANKING It. The Farmers' and Merchants' Hank Chmrter Xu. 620. Incorporated. t.. w. President I H. R. K. r fainter I. I". KunkliiHiM-r A. H. J»&lt;|i idem | L. I -'»nt CukM L. F.. \\ Statement. Novembeh IT, 1901 lESOt R( K3 LIABILITIES Ixwus ami d . t 7O.6M 75 Cspii iin » sti.ooo oo : - . f i ». set- ured and udkc u i rndivlded profit * IT-muim on C. S. and other bondi il bank* ■ ■■ banks i -- ia ■ dUoounted. vktcbankci uyable . - rtn.i itPin - .■ .' crtT It » »»h 7.7« 38 Total. iuum «6 $181,300 til i Tlio Bank of Comim-rce Charter Mi. Aim er Casktar Stati November LIABILITIES ■ Capital stock paid in ♦ .WOO* « idgments rlaims, etc - .10 hanks flR.0l» 47 -:a!.- and pri - vate banks and dm - 9.WV IW Bill- payable l»nks &lt;.iit:9Si 66 •■V ludgm. 11, 90* IT 16.400 00 Individual i*set» • - ni; house, furniture and Ox- '." &lt;•» 4.BM 3J 9.7ST .16 - realetute - expense* and taxes paid 11,0- i.oon w ■ Bccount </seg>
            <seg id="p182">•1., ite Bank Vlce-l'resi' Stat&gt;: ■I UKR IT. !'.««. LIABILITIES I ■cured and unsecured Ml 52 .... :*&gt;( 4S Bankinc house furniture and flx- . ■ re» 3.000 00 •uncatet nt depnv »«. ofdepo.it *..■!.«. (M 'and bui«i paid Pn-miuni n r.s. asdotlMt l&gt;onds Duf t.&gt;ii:iti..nall«nkv :inJ pri - vate bat. \- and oanken. " tmnks - s »nd Item - «... bank! 11.951 27 Total % 7i,im 02 Tlio Farnieis" A Merchants" Bank Charter do. 017 Incorporated O*o. Hau ITetident | Chaj . STATEHINT, NuMIKEt ir. iu(H. T IAKII.1TIES 4 dtoooaate t M.337 5S - danduns*. v» 23 securities, judcmonts. -•k paid in f 10.000 00 Siirplu- 1.(176 35 1 .ject to W,tfl 08 furniture and fli- um 33 1 estate xpenae* and taxes paid 702 H i ml other bondi -late and p- Bills pi rate bmnki a°nd i«iTk'er!,"' no 74 CJbecks and iteniB of e&gt; r 1 .5A4 00 C'aah 7»6 5J Total I 63.P73 M Loans MM) l-« 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p183">The Farmers' and Merchants' Bank ■ ■ Statement, NOVEMBER IT, r, i«OT Litchfield The Litchtieltl State Bank Incorporated John Terhune Pr nt ' Harry Terhnne Stitiukt, 'BIB IT, urn I.IABILITISS BB8OIBCB8 Uui and % 17.«W a8 ir»Ml 298 M I ill t 2U.0UU 00 r*s. Otber auets Hankiuii house furniture and li\- 2.30000 real' pstate 150 00 and Uxes paid 1.583 3D tit -utinlii _■ i on I'.S. and other bondii and securites i Bin intuit * ii national. - :md bankers 3I.U0O i\ s and items of eschanite ... IT m J.TaB 05 STATEMENT. XlVMBEIt 17, IiHn. KISOCRCEB LIABILITIES Loans ... f • 'ier bonds and securities pri- ■asli on liant ami due from 12,1 17 64 Total ICT.Wsl DM t'&gt; ll;it l"&gt;IUll ltUtlk&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p184">184 Chan 246. l'rivat. f'resid.'iit I PredLehmkiihl it Frank Lehmku HeaUir Frank !..■!. mtul. Stat«meiit, November IT, 1808. BISOl'RCIS 1.IAB1UT1E- I,.aiu anii.:i~" m.-- I 3O,S*S X I in | 8,000 00 418 7» - se furniture and fls- 1.406 40 HE Ui 391 93 Due to national banks ■■ bank and bAiikers Itrr 66 and pri «,7i7 08 i and item- j ... 3.8M 14 • * I ;.H9 * The Farmers' State Bank Charter No. 551. Iiicor|K)rate&lt;i. \V. A fashM-r AMlit Statement. November RES* &gt;C RCK9 I.IABIL TIKS Loam and duc»unt&gt; * \i Sir; fifi i in * 5.000 00 U-, etc MM l« flx- ilratate i 1 nited. - </seg>
            <seg id="p185">185 Long Pine The Browu County Bank Charter No. A I neorporated . President I Vice-President | - Win . Glover. Statement, November 17, 1903 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts f 31 .:. ok paid in. flO.MOOa Overdrafts. secured and unsecured 1.1M OB securities, jiidfmenti. ■ claims, etc rt»i m&gt; Konds &lt; tther assets Kankine bouse furniture and fix- . real estate nt expenses and titiei pnid l.(B7 34 1*0 «) * frl I Hills payable n hund ■ « 4».OM 58 Lorton The Hank Lorton Tlie Bank of I.' uhtor III'. Anilers. III'. Anden&lt; '■ Statimk Statement. N JVEMBKR 17, 1003. LIABILITIES C»p . •10.000 00 1VKMBKR IT, IM3 msoukcm .W 5:t M m ■ rniture and fix- LIABILITIES RESOURCE Canil I 'IO00 secured and unsecured i.un W :«». «i Mm « Wt Vt I-. I- -c furniture and fix i Table itebanksai 1 : -'&gt; ' I 3I» 38 t ■.«■ M ■ I other bonds -tatp and pri- - and bankers lie :&gt;ii&lt;1 prlTkte bauks </seg>
            <seg id="p186">186 Louisville The Bank of Commerce Louisville Clm- i. H. v STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 17, 1H03 XoVKMBEK STATEMENT 17, 1903 KEKOl'KCIS LIABILITIES I.IAKI1.ITIK' Loans mil iiiiw 4SK 33 Sur r - .... &lt; M :&gt;:t 1,171 ..; ... 4 1.. 61 fU - 3.500 00 aOOOO (&gt;ruh.-l ••■■•*- ' 6 ;;,.» :•! $ 82,3»4 S3 * 82,»1 33 ; Loup City Loup City The First Bank of Loup I r No. 280 Incor: rtpr No. 280 Incorpor - Statbheut Novmini IT. IMS ■MOCBCn I.UBII.ITIH Loans and I &gt; Overdrafts.secured and uiiMeurad 1.0* SI &gt;iid»iinui" Wmmtf •;t.(w 2o ii« houae furniture aid Ix- rl iOratr* ol d^p. ,»»4 28 3.JO0OU \e% paid 1 in «5 i ml other bonds and t«cariti&gt;'-. iud private banks and bancrrs Sotet and bills re-div vale 1 2,?«6 (W Other rtalt . . 6,185 77 Total. Total I11S.95O T8 </seg>
            <seg id="p187">187 S E&lt; ' K ET \ll\ ■ ■ r III!-. * '. \ i h H A N K 1 N &lt; * i. ' \ \i: &gt; Lushton The Hank i&gt;f Lu K. .1. \\ LIABILITIES ; I BnniN II :. MO M * • i; «i i i I i Lynch The Hank of Lynch lii'V T]n iraii'it I;. II. llarr.- ■.amlwrs. . ■ Statkheht, Hovehbrb 17, 1903 KMOOBCEa LIAHIL1TIE Loans and Di- ■ Capital *tock paid in 364 ;-■ - ■ - T.(O8 10 lionds 7.0SS 10 Other UieU &lt;)th«r aswt Hunkiiu: house furniture and tix - real estate &gt;it expense* ami taxes paid Banking house furniture and flx- turn - real eatate nt expense* ami tasei paid Premium on iier bonds and - Premiui, and " national b*ulc&gt; inks bank* &lt;'*ah Due from national, state am . vai* ban'.!' * * and items of exchange... iikI. state Mid prl- v»ta banks ■ 2.018 94 tems of «!X' Cash 3,088 47 Total •tt.MiMS Total •tt.SttM »1« ■ ... </seg>
            <seg id="p188">188 Lynch The Ponca Vallev Bank r\.i. 601. Incorporated fa-hl.T Assistant &lt; bTAtlMfMT. NOVEMBER 17, IMS, RESOUKI ES » 90,211 78 RESOUKI ES LIABILITIES LIABILITIES Loan aaddlwoiints * .-ji.-at 7S f 15.000 00 -.•ure&lt;t and uBMenicd m .-i ~= upaitl. is subtevi Individual depoaiU subteri _• house furniture and tix- igbouie furniture and tix - pitM . Hnil ]&gt;ri- tuna \X) 17 S30 17 .Hid miu) ! 00 &lt;•&gt; .„.. .. 13,825 4-&gt; ToUl $ «6.SM «6 Total $ Sfi.ft.Vl 66 ,1 $ 96..W6 «fi f IUM Lyons The Farmers' Bank .. .' .Assistant I State* int. November IT. 1003 RESOURCES LIABILITIES I117.0W 54 k paid in t 6. (1 00 00 ... ■ ; ilgmenu. 7.58O S»2 tl5S,T«6 10 ■ ■rated. •intnn- an- I &gt;e ma i id &lt;•• ■•- li-844 UO lilies and taxes paid 4.9W SW ants mm - paratilp IS.OOt) l»l v» 91 : i i-atw of .iepo.it . »»4 UO </seg>
            <seg id="p189">BKCRKTAK E 8TATK BANKINif HOAKI&gt; 189 McCook V. Krnnklm W. It. Wolfe , . . . President I a i Vice-President | .... Btatemmct. November IT. 1H03. BBIOl'BCF.8 LIABILITIE ■..unts II in I 00. 00 &lt;iiIht assets tin ii k i til.' house furniture banks IT.MI :t« T McCool Junction statement, N RESOI'Ri K &gt; Ml SO The Citizens" Bank of McCook Charter No. 276. li»:or; Mded pntflu plain tup . d^^^^l i&gt;n- The^Blue^Rh er Bank flx- ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p190">190 McLeai I Sank ficLean T. M. I ABILITIES I«iil in . - 4.00(1 00 - The Madison StaU- Bank nadison art hier Statement, November 17, 1903. LIABILITIES KFSMI 111 F. ... ll63,il6 80 . .ii.asM li.-. I4JM •) </seg>
            <seg id="p191">191 Madrid , . v Statement, November u i « "l i « The Madrid ■ STATh' :MBKI&lt; KES. f * 1 m w * </seg>
            <seg id="p192">192 The Magiii't State Bank i barti-r No. 448. Incorporated President I [.O.Woolil ra*liier 11. K. *»&gt; Viee-Prwident , .....'....'.'.".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.AtiiiiiinictilAtr STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 17, 1903. RISU'Rc II ■aMTOCM LIABILITIES LIABILITY Loans and discounts I in, 571 W6 Loans and discounts I in, 571 !&lt;s Capital stock paid In * 8,0 Capital stock paid In * 8,o Surplus fond Overdrafts, secured and unse - sured.... »7 PI Overdrafts, secured and unse - sured.... »7 PI Surplus fond iiied profits t'nihvKted profits !......'.'!!!.'...' jit 5 Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, tic Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, tic Dividends unpaid ........... In.ii.idua depisits tubject to Dividends 11 npaid Iniii.idual depMits tubject to check fi,7M ]y cheek n,7« )« Othe' assets Othe^ assets l&gt;em«nd certificate* of deposit.. 177 («i Demand certificate* of deposit., trr («l Banking house furniture and rlxti ... 1.180 00 Banking house furniture and flxti ... 1.180 00 Time eertinViites of deposi H9 00 Time certinViites of deposit '.'. * 419 00 Certified checks Certified clieckt other real e»tati' other real e«at&gt; &lt;'a-hier's checks nnt»-anding i a-hier '» checks nnts'anding Current exp*ns«*s and taxes paid Current exp*»ns«*s and taxes paid Due to national banks Due to national banks Premium on U. &gt;. and other bonds and securities bit. paid Premium on U. H. and other bonds and securities iut. paid Due t&lt;&gt; state and private banks and Imnkers Due t" state and private bank* and bankers Cash items K * Note« and bills re-Miscounted Notes and bills re-discount'-'! Cash items 21 ■ B11U payable Bills payable Due from national, state and private hunk- and bankers Line from national, state and. private tmnk- mid bankers Checks and iten.s of exchange rherks and iten.o of excha: Total cash tui liai pom Total cash on hsnti 2.342 1« Tota J .• Total Total .... I 22.6W »7 Total I Malmo »' and Merchants" Bank Charter No. Vice-Presidrnt | Statement, Sovkmber 17, 1S0I REKOl'RCE! LIABILITIES Loans « It paid in $ •ocured ar. . in Bond- 9W 00 Other assets . Banking house furniture and WC Oil hecks • :ml taxes paid lo national banks Due to state and private banks and banker- terns. ii'l bills re-discounted ntional state and private banks it' ayabie ! </seg>
            <seg id="p193">193 ¥ irleys Hank Stati i ahi i i • Hlif llxnl llu Cli Martinsburg Tin- Martinshnra Bank u \i- o ! j Bank Olll Cur I'mi . ;" |ii. • i hand anil </seg>
            <seg id="p194">194 Mason City itv Hanking V fafhier \»-i.-:n- LI A 111 raid in ! Loans t ■i :»1 X :gmeDt re and 'H - me and Items of exc rUywood The State Hank of Mavwood I lian B»hier -:;t ■ shier LIABILITII I.liBll* I. ? :..0CO CO • l»i - ■ &gt;. and o' :*'•• Kiid private banks ae aid Mills payable IffS . Total </seg>
            <seg id="p195">iiei . A.ovllltl : IE! I ) cl 1 .- a r, Meadow Grove Tin ■ ■ N ai w r&lt;4 . , „ &gt;;ber r«a •■-■■•' LI ks ant </seg>
            <seg id="p196">196 TWHLFTH AN The Bank of Memphi Memphis Charter No. 6o». In Urnt I fTATEMFNT !&lt;OVElIBr.R IT, 1908. ai-hier .-President ant Cashier -lant C» t-T ate* I embrk 17, UK tBB8OCBCI8 LIABILITIES D« and dlscouir : 'apiia' stoat i»id in } o c Overdrafts BESOUBCIB I U'.U.ITIF Loan, and discount I in | Overd rafts 106 Stork*, -erniities, judgmr Wurnlu- 106 77 .Mo - Stork*, -erniities, Jadgmt- mu A. ' '.'.".'.'.'. 1.745 20 Individual deposits mbii Boixlv liS* iiK- houae furniture and Na* iuse furniture and and in .... [■en^esanu I ■! H ■n^es and t 386 56 i aecarities ate banks re discounted.. aional, stite and ,al, st^te and 1 bankers. . . 4.172 c iii'l liankers. . . 4.1" ■ ■ Total » JS.MB 98 hW $ tt&gt;a Total J -•:&gt;.*» 93 ...|f Menw The Bank of Merna Merna The Bank Charter No. »». Inform President | S K. Warrick .. Viee-Presidei.t . ..•;.; ,.•!?" ant Cashier Statement, Nuvkmber 17, 190: RC«8 L1ABIUTIE Loans and discounts .' i61 50 10.00000 afla secured and nnse - cuiv 18 08 "10 00 Stocks, securities judgments, - ■« depoait...; i house furniture and 100 00 banks l)ue iV t " te and P'i«t«'b«nW bondi and securities and bankers.. Notes and bills re.discV &lt;r d.' Ca-h i 13 10 Bills payable m national. 8tat" an&lt;l • ban., andb-nker* M.771 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p197">197 Merriman K. M. Kiiller Z. I . lla\i- \ LIAHIL1TIE R&gt; ' 2M in .;, a ■ .-■&gt; ■ d liand n , t f i I 47.540 13 Miiford The Nebraska State Bank Milford Tin- Nebraska State Bank ■ &gt;hier \TKHf iVEMBEl! I; LIABIl 1 HKII.ITIE 1 ■ ■ I « 1.39&lt; ; ... &lt; T»l </seg>
            <seg id="p198">198 I in.* r armor* ;in&lt;l Mllford ....* Him Hank of Millard Millard ... ■B. - </seg>
            <seg id="p199">M Tin- Bank of Miller i a </seg>
            <seg id="p200">200 Milligan The Farmers 1 and Merchants 1 Rank •••••' auionz ' c Statemewt, November IT. 1903. BISOUBCE9 LIABILITIE: .{3,912 74 -niture am: 3.500 00 II ■ ... » 45 The Minatare Hank Mlnatare Statement. Notem LIABILTIK8 resources * Ml ■ furniturt' 1,919 88 - .... $w io 818 80 ■ f 25.378 94 </seg>
            <seg id="p201">201 Minden The MiiKli-n Kxchaiiirc Bank ■»nt i asbwr Statement, November IT, 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES &lt; &gt;»erdraf tsswurwl and unsecured an nk eiii-ii rto TDitur e 'I pri- x- I Tin' Munuwi Stato Bank harler Ni \. \\. I TATEMI KMI1KK 17. IWf RESOUBCBI LIABi; ur«i u ■ ml other Ik 1 i </seg>
            <seg id="p202">202 Tin- Hank of Monro* Monroe e : ■ Morse Bluff Tlu- Bank of Morse Blutf AB1I.ITIF. i h lilh Oilier rp </seg>
            <seg id="p203">Bank oi U:: • « Murdock Tlie Bank of M unlock y KMBKRI ' - </seg>
            <seg id="p204">204 Murray Tlie Murray State Bank &amp; Incorporated F M - STATEMENT, NOVEMBER IT, 190I LIABtLlTIEl RESOURCES -■ ■ IN N I 31.610 '.&lt;* !Nap«r The Bank of Naper Btatkmint. November 17. 1903 « I.1ABII.1TIK: * 8.467 43 141 '.'I k paitl in '00 00 III . . 6.782 85 rniture and fii- 111 30 tndin ■ $ lt&gt;.S6f W </seg>
            <seg id="p205">205 Tin- Peoples 1 Bank ■ liforil \ F.MV.y.. BESOl'I S - , &lt; Tin.- Citizens Ban!- ...... TATEMENT, NOVF.Ml' RESOl'Ri I II. fix I ■ 'I I: 811' I T </seg>
            <seg id="p206">TWI RT OF TH The Napooi Han rsaponei State m x v &gt; Tlie Farmers' Bank Nebraska City Statement, s . kmbkk .■ ■ - - i: .: flT. / y </seg>
            <seg id="p207">Nehawka ,a Bniil A « &gt; * Neligh ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p208">208 Nelson The Commercial Bauk i barter Incorporated .l.Wehri &lt; ashler •mt Catl.ier Statement, November 17, 1903. - i.iabi; u paia in Lotus and d Overdrafts, secured and unae- sured mts'Mi o national banks ■Utte and private banks rediscount and 1 bankers v 1 1 _ . . i h-' k - han- 1 Total The Bank of Ni-maha rsemaha Charter «. Q ....... Pi .CaHlii Ca« Statement, If Of Ml Ml 17, 1903. ITATEMIXT, XOVKMBEK 17, 1901 MM I.IABIL11 P«' d »" * 5 -°°&lt;! ed .nd unse- '■'"" &gt;use furniture I uf d«po«n ... standing.. t expenses and taxes paid 'onal banks 1, ,, -T. ■ to state and private 1&gt; and bankers ... .... - ami Mils re-diacooii! »ml Mils re-diacounted Bills payabie I tems 1 -iMl 1 it'lU* Due from national state and Due from national state and Bills payable ale banks ond bankers ... T.UII 11 ki ond bankers... 'M\ 11 in of exchange M 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p209">A • auk i.. i i • '« i»t V ♦1 </seg>
            <seg id="p210">210 THE Newmm Orove The Newman Grove State Bank Charter No. ■ Cashier Vice Aisirtant Cashie: Cashier MBKB 17, 1903 RESCH LIABIUTIE Limit and discount* I ■ : s:.uk paid in : k paid i ■ ■ - id u dgment- ■•l'l judgments. rniture and lire and id tuxes p id •xes i' discounted ' Total .■ Newport Tin- Rock Count Bank Charter No P. II. ! . Hthier ■ at i.i.sbier Statement, November .1AB1I.ITIF. I.. .mm ai'-l d ired anl un- it) Cd 1,134 88 ila mi,ri- IndivMiml deposits subject to check «1 ?it.. 4 tHnklni.' hous- furniture and - real eotate s and tHxt'Kpsi'l femium on D. ". and other ■ind securities . . Due to state and private banks ''a«h uems and bills redlscounted I'ue from national, state and Bills payable private banks at ri bankers . 3.BM 50 rberks and it&lt;-ni of exchanre I 34.M0 «1 . </seg>
            <seg id="p211">&lt;&gt;K 211 Newport The Newport Bunk icorpo rated Dan H.Uaims Ca«hi«r AT F.ME NT X VEMRER 17, 19a RF LIABILITIES J and V n ng house furniture »ud !&gt;i*es pnM &gt;'l other a taxes r ate a te hai; &lt; tncl items of exehani a Total Nickeraon Tin Nickerson Char atid. Chan. 'iratid TATEXENT N KMBKR17. 1903. EMBER 17. 190: KESOIRCE9 LIABILIV t'RCI LIARILITIE: Loansanddi- S rk paid in Loans a- I O\er&lt;irHfts, »ecured ami un- O\erd rafts, lecured and un- 8u&gt;&lt;-k«, securitiuE judgments, claims etc (•i&lt;;pk», securitiet iudgmer claim- Bond- Oiher assets Other asseta Banking bouse furniture and xlures, Other real eRtatt current expenses and taxes p«W 6W0 67 One to nutional bank! Premium on U. S. and other bonds and securities "tale and private banks ankers. Cash items &gt;nd bill?, re-discounted Due from national, sttte and private banks and bankers. . . . .yable - and items of exchange. . </seg>
            <seg id="p212">- 1 rWKI.KTH ANNIA1 , ,y Tn ntoormt Ban rar ChH I -T«nt I • .-T.ITEMKS VEMBE IABILITI1 iai«ii» ana aiscoi I iu Immn i rTrruraiw, secured and uiue&lt; »ck». secuittiM, judgif Rial nit AnnHa 'use lurnl: i p i 'lfpi f kl outstanHi n«egan(l taxes paid I &gt;an I ■ and s«ciir 111! t ,1 e and Check &gt; an&lt;1 it.-,,'!. IO1I1 .. T 'uruen Tin- liank of Nord&lt; «harter No. ■Istmiit Cm. I MI'.KI: lAjmun anu aiscontus I irt 2W fl .,ltv nil ,,r...( .!...( i'% tri'iiHus lecurea ana unie - rnnvi 2 lii.iLWf fnrnitiiVa' "««"j i '"»[»•« «jf &lt;]' ; .«] I miture an* 1..VK) 00 ■ \pmar-mmna lai »imi ... Vlit" K&gt; HU&lt;] ll^tn- * - - Tosiu' iobje •■ tanks hi ii •,«! L-r.r. </seg>
            <seg id="p213">213 North Bend The Hank of North ■ • &gt;- i i North Loup The Fanner- A i nd U&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p214">214 North Platte Tin' McDonald State Hank President I \v. 11 T Statkjiist. X mm 1.1 IKII 1TIE Los ns and d t22A,HW J i Komi- ■•■ furniture anil flx- IT ■ real estate. ■ ii-s lie bar vateb. Oak Tlie Bcroggin vV Co. Hank 803 I'rin State m LIABI1.1T1E Lohii- and H*0 57 nil !i\- 1 100 (Ki - real ritate 3ft!fi Si S 07006 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p215">215 \ 1TKSBK e«iiKi: RESOCIUE9 ABILITIE ? a ■«• OakJale Tlu 1 An: Bank I'r f . irt'd ITi U6 M »; turns ■ BH </seg>
            <seg id="p216">216 Tlu- Farmers' and Hank Oakland o Statement, » (VEMliKR 17. 1WW IIAKIMTIE.- ■i- The Bank of Wells A Trinil)orn Oakland Statement, novembek LIABIL TIKS besodbcks &gt;]&amp;(! </seg>
            <seg id="p217">217 &gt;l. K.l'a MUKK 17, v E.SOl'HCJSI ABILITIES «&gt; • ired Igme i m b: X n Octavia The Octavia State Banl EMBKR 17. ;». . liai; I i.OM| Jt,*l KAI 8(6 urines ■ M i« .... t ii.ftW 34 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p218">218 M ,, t v Irnt Arthur Hi, ;■ i&gt; win i h.k. - I Uury ST4TE»£VT 1.1 .' Loan* ud Dtioon 15! ,e f urn il ure ":ili(i fl\- T5o 43 ler lx)inl ■ WU in M ."r .... tsi Odell The Hinds State Bank The Ilimls auk Udell ■Ii»&gt;. N K «. II 1MB IUMHM * 16.318 O.( I |,., | ., r , ,| ISO 1M •ise furniture »u«l «s- III- Due ' re-aueomneu ... II. 167 58 Ollirr 116 110 f U.W t I4.4W 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p219">219 OgaUlla The Exchange Bank Mn. II WT« - RESOURCE ■ t araw ■«&gt; vicuritie ST 150 OU .'in INI | Ogalalla The First State Hank - M. Macl J. r. ' Statement, s VEMBKR KESOURCC 4P.ii.itif; Loaus aud Di • ■ 66 lturc aud fix- ■ Total c«sb oc bauil l«nks ToUl * M.8S0 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p220">220 Ohiowa The Bank of Oliiowa Incorporated bTAIEHENT. NOVEMBER 17, 1SHB I.IABIL1TIK 455-iu flip. 184 M The Citj Savings Bank Omaha STATRMIST. NOVF.MBKH MABILITIE »I.MW1 ,«. - ill- " ImnK i </seg>
            <seg id="p221">221 Tin- .1. L. Brandeis A: Sons. Banker N \ . I). ! Krai II II Bra States i it&gt; s ■ ' y ( &lt; ; horn iv Bank R Hx x rit &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p222">222 MAI. KK THE Tht- Exchange Bank Ong IT, 19« STATEMENT. N( I.1AB1LITII Ko.tWO 00 • . - State Bank Orchard Tlie Orchard \. K 11 LIABILITIES • i in &gt;«&gt;•• m u&gt; 712 'S&amp; MM '306 86 ■ - and fir- . 500 0U ■ lei paid 1.W0 M t«Bkl bank 1,500 00 MM M 5 -jT.yKi </seg>
            <seg id="p223">223 Tin- &lt;&gt;nl Bank A1KMF.V » * - I Orleans Tin- Bank of Oi NOVEMBER • I ■» ■ ■ - nnk*T </seg>
            <seg id="p224">224 THE « Osceola The Osceola Bank ihartei ■■ I- K , lllt C.bl.ier it Cn.-I.l Statement, Statiment, November 17, 1M I I HIM. I k paid In ohecK. xsir 17, 19C ■RIM 'RIM IAB1I.ITIES Loans and di -ed and diim - Loans and discounts : k paid In I Overd'H I nnsc- 8 took - ■ check ii» &gt;kii and 10.SU0 eittt. •&gt; banks m rnl -e-di»countsd Total . . - 5 Osceola Tin- P.i:nk of Polk Countv Chart. ' H stanu Stat«m«nt, KOVKHBKR 17, 1S03. ■ SILITIE J 36,971 !ifl slo"k pi. f (X Oth*r asMts . ■ :se furniture and lepout ii real estate ■ hack! aoding and taxes paid ivate banks national state and ul» re-di»&lt;'' . of exchange Total </seg>
            <seg id="p225">225 The Secaritj State Bauk B. Di P .".'.'.'. v'i. M.A. I Static* YEHBKR IT. i.«L I MB ■■' ... .; i»i no 3.0W.I artnta kMks and U,,i i.om *j *~3™rTn I • Osmond Osmond Tllt , p arlners - Statt . Bank The Farmers" State Bank &lt;\ \. K f\. Kl-- L. Manten H. M C I.. MirjI.T, State v 1 KMKKK 17. !'.«« LIABILH ... I 63,ig8 B | (.'aplul stock paid in &lt; m^m s ■ -uHure'and flx'-" „ .. 1,227 W 1,227 «0 - a lid I </seg>
            <seg id="p226">KLKTH ANNUAL Kl TIM The First State Banl Uvertoi Charter No. W\. Cathie I'HUI AuUtint Cuhi MBEB STATE1IEN1 LIABILITIES KKSOUBCK! 1 li'rtW II 1 i uuse laments, ).t .■.!■&gt; ftl use lurnilure and ve» P'id ate b H inted Total Ha Overtoil Charte V' nt i .Hthi*r ITEMEXT. NOVEMBCI ! . _, . J -ecured »Dd un- - .l&gt;jeot rnilure and liscounted. "It..- PoUl . I 41.806 06 I I </seg>
            <seg id="p227">227 Oxford xiie Commercial State Bank C*M rporated. r St *- t R 17, 1903. RMOtBCES LIABIUTUS red and uii- '«w W RF IABIUT1IS • ml disc aiseU.V.". ".'.'.' ' furnilure js is a and ■ Page ( hsr . 1903. ES I "0 0T • ■ • i « r UQ- -. wcuritiee, ja.igmentii &gt;&gt;use furniture and aen K»i k:n_ bouse furniture and uouse lurnuur' ■ i 16 . ■ [ rj 1 &gt;£l)ses rt 1) ' 1 !fi\t'S PR 1(1 ' urroi-" -1 mj tftxcspftid ' ntiOD»l. ■«tVte'»nd ile hanka and I'H *^ 3 D«nM i </seg>
            <seg id="p228">228 TWELFTH AN" THE Palisade Tlie Frenchman Valley l.ank Charter No. del : -orated m ashier Viee-Presideiu Assistant Cuhier S-TATKMKNT NOVEMBER 17, 1U03, ■MM Loans and dlscoun: | LIABILITIES hi stork paid in flOOOO 00 Surplus fund Overdrafts, secured and untec idfd profit* ii,4 cured .... 3&amp;; U3 Stocks, secuiities, judgments, claims, etc Dividends unpaid Individual deposits sul Bonds Htes o! de of deposit Other assets Banking house fnrnlture and flxtures Other real esiale SOU 00 nndinir "urrem expenses and taxes paid &gt; national and other bonds and securities -tmo and private banks Notes and bills re-dUe&lt;v Cash Hems m national, stite and ■ayable private banks ami bankers . ".1.214 OB Checks anil items of exchange ToUl » 49,6*4.66 Total... I Palmer The Palmer State Hank Charter No. 521 - .. ;; ... President III. I. Teiupltn ('ashler Vice-President | '.■.'.".■ V.' '.'.^ Asaistiut Caahicr Statement, Novkmber 17, 1903. REBOURCIS I.IABII.ITIK Loans and discounts J 51,968 &lt;W a! stock paid in luooOOO . Overdraft! secured and unse - cured 36 73 a , .. ided profits. . s ,7«i Di»iden.i.« tmpaid... Stocks, seruritie-, judgments, ual deposit! subject to check Bon.l- '•Beck 39 j97 58 Oemaii 1 « of dercsit. 2.8B8 51 -t paid on &lt;ie - lepoait.... Bnnking house furniture and fixtures Other real esi.it. l&gt;ue to national banks. Curren t expenoes and taxes p*id 1 ,382 92 Due to state and private bank and bankers Premium on D. B. and other bonds and securities Notes and bills re-dUco,.' ' &lt;rd .' '."" Bills payable " H"h items. Due front national, state and bai&gt; 9,691 76 ToUl 65,49f;7: </seg>
            <seg id="p229">229 Palmyra The Bank of Palmyra Chart. - H. («tron President I .1. H.Cat- Cathier U Knvart.... \ |t.ti D. - Statement, N &gt;v»bib IT. 1903 mouicn LIABILITIES 14 73 C«| ISO 47 J.IKM) HI rxi a Hond ibject ■ assets Hank irniture at.'- lUr.k 1 - * 'M I ]&gt;aid • ri ■ •■- ■ Dm from u ■ and pri- I ■ Check » 5.801 IT , $ 95.410 15 I | 95.410 15 ♦ 95.411) I .'5 U.i IS — P««ma Tin- Bank of Panama Panama 1Ch:i &gt;li»ll I'rvsident i John T. Mitrsliall ithiei Charter Ho. 323 i I Statemint. Novexber 17, 10O3. Statement. Novehbek 17, 1903. IIWICIU M IIABM.ITIEt ? 5B.SS IB CapiUl stock pa .... f HIUUD CO I lABII.ITIEt ■Hcurwiandiinsw W 3S Surplus 1 st.«'k~. ■Mntw, judgment* Unohrldrd Dividenils uupti I I i' I IV H 111. I "sets rnitureitnd flx- IVm •, 71* 00 Hanking house, furniture and fi'x- MM M 3,.&lt;)M 43 ad. am no 1 C. S and other &gt;es • asb in-ni. .. »,„( pr i vm te Iwnks und pri* and httnkers ■••inks Hud teakers ... I ... Chsoks .'iiui itpnj*uf SKBkaBfli payable Imnks ,n -ft </seg>
            <seg id="p230">230 FT II AN S 1MKI &lt;&gt;V P«piiiion Tin- Banking Home of A. \V. ( I'm I.IAB1I.ITI ' 1(, , . ■ rniture an.: 5 f Bank Charter Incorporated 111 I ! lit | o. M. I Stati - kothbbb.it, ltioa. L1ABILITIE UMI,. * 87. 466 UJ , sa m </seg>
            <seg id="p231">231 of r R VI! II. IT IK t ha Petersburg Tli Petersburg itizen State Bank ■ Bank ATElll- HA t , t 30.41 I M'"-k-. uri'i"-. luct^inents. .... Other assets ....... — furniture aud ttx- tutw 2 - Oili.-r n-al .■sta 1 ,T3;J 63 1,753 63 - bonds .ud otlii-r 1&gt; I </seg>
            <seg id="p232">232 r hi I!tp5 Hank of Phillips Chart iM. Incorporated 'lit | Ham CashM-r Btatemkjct, November IT. 1MB. BIIIOURCES I.IAKII.1TIE!- Loans and t 2K.018 30 d in I 5,000 OS I0U00 6 unsecured 1,083 JS IflUUU Judgment* claiii; Indlviil iture nut II \- 1.M0U0 &gt;1 estate - l&gt;ank asd pri a.m ti I.5SB 1» Pierce The Pierce State Hank Charter Mo SM ■■■ratol M. Ichi • Pmfctaui Statehkkt. November 17. I9C3. ■aaooBCEs I.IABIL ■T1K» f»«.701 7* • kpaidlll * S.UO0 00 1.4MW 1 irnient&gt;. 5.5U « • ftx - "200 09 4.1M m W.775 36 2.4M 75 i- bairin 13.747 «B '..".'.' 4.596 7J . . I1K.M0 * I13R.»46 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p233">233 SEG'KKTART OF THK STATE BANKING BOAKD Pierce The Pierce Coiuitv Bank Incorporated. President I .t»bi*r VIM rilMiiil I A».Ut»nt i .ubur 8TATEM EST, S'OYEMBER 17. RE^OL'ECBI LIABILITIES ti-oi'Rc n LIABILITIES Lo»o» andducoum* (145.130 53 overdrafK.Keuradaod uo9*&lt;-ured MM Stock- bs, judgment*. I...»ns anddiacoui: ... Jlt.i.l:. .-k paid in . «..(«» i«i -k paid in. KR.000 ill DTerdmftt.Meuradaod uo9*&lt;-ured t ■jntui H Stock- bs, judfBkeni*. 7.(W 91 ins, eii- Kond- npai.1 Hnnd^ ■ nther »s«*ts nther »ss«m- Kankine huuse furniture aod ffv l i.-tn k. i ii L.' huuse furniture and (1\- - «0 90 8.3» 00 .-v).IKl 3D ■ • ■ 42 96 . banks itatennd pri- viite li ink- and bunk- - ■ ■a m •■&lt;■■ — Plainview PUinview The Farint • Hank The Far Bank - K. C. II ilcnl I M !'. J). ( .-ill I II.L.B 11 - 1). tore Statement. Novimbkb 17. IMS. ITATIMIKT. KOVEMBKB 17, 1963. BESOUBCN LIABILITIES flffT.OCl 83 ... RESOURCES LIABILITIES tltiT.OtU H KVOW W iiioram 2.5M « - * w - J.M6 49 * on * im •I »M H 64.4)0 M re mil flx - 7.0H 90 7.0H 80 H».I7« 4* P«h1 1,344 « ■ nun .iDil Um paid 1,*M « ml other be '"•■uriiiat ! ■ :•■■&lt;! private bo -•'-diieounted ME»M »il!» ixiy.il.le H.OCO Cn Bilh payable S.000 CO 'W6 75 8.406 47 ji'.jt i::. .-.' </seg>
            <seg id="p234">. Tin- Hank »»f Plainvie i K. V -&gt;!.■ STATEMEN VIMBE . ' -'- &lt;xtu r*. t Mb. * • )U ■ Platte Center The Platte Countv Bank i;. ii - VnVEMHKI! M ENT. .1 IHIMTIk- ■ - '. ' ~ ■ jiiMT mmm '• /iimt n*:ti i" 'r . 1 M 84 MM... </seg>
            <seg id="p235">The Hank of &lt; i Char ATESF V Plattsmouth The Plattsmonth Savinm Hank \V II. N \y 11. - STATEW LIABI! I) linnd Other ii Banking house furniture and fll- ;3« uo » r j» 0 Che.k Total </seg>
            <seg id="p236">236 Pleasant Dale The First State Bank Charter Incorporated J. H. Mern -mm Cashier T. H I Assistant Cashier STATEMENT NOVIMBIB 17. 1903 LIABILITIES RESOGP.r ES S N000 00 t 30.514 !M M 110 ; II "I HI - II "I HI Iudiviriuai 30.106 82 tix- ww on Mm 2.80001' m« ■ 846 3R I'll- • ■ • .-.-k- il -i miling.... &gt;ii&gt;1 hank- •■ bank ■ 1 tmnjre (J«&gt;l 3. ; i &gt; l-lfl.210 30 : IWWa $ 49/J1U 30 J iV.H0 30 Pleasanton Pleasanton The Pleasanton iState Bauk -■rated. A. H UraiiiMf 1- L. iir.-in, Assistant I Statem ikt, November it, 1903 REKOUH('El&lt; LIABILITIES ? 20.6* 48 rt in $ 10. "TO 00 1.300 l»l ■ • l.o:«l M '■ - iilca»«.of depo»: -mju (Xi 1.000 00 of depoait M.677 60 &gt;es and taxes paid Due to state &gt;- bank ■ and i.n- ■ 3,577 94 </seg>
            <seg id="p237">237 Plymouth The Bank of Plymouth ■ Statement. .November KESOURCE8 ARII.ITIE S KomK \ arrant I in ilk: '■"■•- -J.nOO 00 ■ IK US' Dm- froi It'. MM) T :v&gt; Ponca T1k&gt; Bank of □ Countv Private K.K. IIh'-h*.] K.li. Halstead".'.".'. .'.'.'.'.'.'.". .'.'.'.Vv'ii-i iTATEMENT, NOVEMBEK I RF.aOURi K" LIABILITIE ■ its tlW,*0S « ■ ;re&lt;l hbS 74 I ■&lt;»! « Storks. s&gt; 721 SO llnmls !!.!!!.! llimkni^ lioime furniture »nd flx- 7.WW 20 . .'.".I"""""" and pri «' eb " » '"•""••■ .'.'.'. ..... 4.1 74 Ot « 58JS0 </seg>
            <seg id="p238">238 Ponca The Security Bank of Ponca LIABILITIES ftO.OQO DC ks Ponca te Ba \v. i BILITIE 4 I Ik TutAl { </seg>
            <seg id="p239">Prague The Farmers' 1 and Merchants' Bank Preston ■ ■a </seg>
            <seg id="p240">240 Primrose The Primrose State Bank President I II. J Cannier Vice-President i lant Catl.ier Statement, November 17, 1903 RESOURCES RESOl'Rl'ES I.IABILI1 I I.IABILITIE: Loans and discounts I It, I Loans and discounts IK 1 Capital *tock i aid lu J m fund Capital stork i ni&lt;l in f 5,0 Overdrafts, secured and uiik - sured .... 1SI 04 Overdrafts, secured and uimv Surplus fund sured 1S1 04 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 262 ■Xi IU Stocks, nei unties, judgments, claims, etc Ids house furniture and Stocks, necutities, judgments, claims, tic t« subject to check cbeck '.;*.&gt; HI l&gt;em«mi rertiflcaiex of depot! t . i Demand ri-rtilicates of deposit l- house furniture and lime certiti uln of deposit lime certiti uln of deposit ' , . •" 4«3 mi (tvi ■ Certified check*.. Certified (heck" real eitnU 1 - real eitnU' &lt; ashler s eneeks oiHk andint i a'httr'K cnwks oiHk amiii: ntexp«naesand taxes ]&gt;aid •'•' T4 ntexp^nsesand taxes i&gt;«id •'•' T4 l&gt;ue lo natinDal tmnk ' aud private banks and hankers re-&lt;li»count l&gt;ue to natinual banks Premium on Bd other bonds and wcuriiies Premium on U. S. and oilier bonda and aecaritles and private banks and hankers N&lt;ite« and bills re-discounted .... Cash items Cash items B.lls piyable Due from national, state and private bunk.- and bankers . l.KJg W 1/u. from national, itate and private bunk.- and bankers . 1.20P W Cherts and items of exchange. Checks and items of exchange. i ... . i TotaJ t W.S01 P5 Total . * l«,301 U5 Total '&gt; Total I kagan Charter No. ■■lent I AH.. c.nhier . Vice-Preaident | Assistant Cashier Statimcnt, November 17, 1903 RESO V ECES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts I Sl.iv.; i: CupiUl pto"k paid in $ V 000 00 Mirplvix fund OverdraftH, secured and unse- cured . 4.8* 72 ided profits stock k. securities, rants lilvldfiius unpai&lt;i Individual deposiu snbject to Bonds ch»ck ir.641 81 Demand certificates of deposit Other assets Hankinc house furniture and lime certificates ol deposit fixtures Bed checks Other real estate Cashier's check* outstanding • 'urrent expenses and taxes paid Due to national banks Due to state and private banks and bankers . . . dish items Notes ami bills re-diacovnted Due from national state and Bills payable private banks und bankers Checks and items of exchange 346 o0 Wl 65 Total J83,2«28 Total ... ,. . | M. MS 21 Charter N&lt;&gt;. 752. Incorporated The Hank of Iiaean </seg>
            <seg id="p241">Randolph Bill) .' II </seg>
            <seg id="p242">24-_&gt; * : Ravenna Ravenna » • </seg>
            <seg id="p243">a Red Cloud r • * </seg>
            <seg id="p244">244 Charter A ABILITIF Loans and dli ...... lid in . mid other ■ate La ,te and iRnan* Republican City The Republican City Bai LH Til I.I bM Mil rdrafis iine- sments ""* bank ■le ba Eal.'stat" h - inn and b«nkeT - ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p245">Republican City »■ Reynolds Tlu- Farm. ik of U&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p246">Rising City Bank ■ ' </seg>
            <seg id="p247">1 I- Roger </seg>
            <seg id="p248">TWEI "IE 248 The Citizi-ns" ! Rushville Rushville • </seg>
            <seg id="p249">V • - Kuskin I • </seg>
            <seg id="p250">250 5t Paul &lt;afh i NOVEMBER 1 St. Paul i </seg>
            <seg id="p251">• 1 ( ( I </seg>
            <seg id="p252">252 5aronvl|l e The Farme Iiicor l The Banking 11 V. Koldn 5chuy!er H </seg>
            <seg id="p253">W . II. S Statkmi ■ « Scotia The Hank * fix lit T"t«l </seg>
            <seg id="p254">The Iitjl Bank Scottsblulf Scribner A Kill r i s ji </seg>
            <seg id="p255">a a </seg>
            <seg id="p256">256 Shelby I'.aiik -hell) Chart ItH'ort ! d uuie- - ■ i-i private banks :lem« .itional, state and k-and ban ihany Total . . r's Hank Shelton 1 i epoait nte ba le mid T.)lali-H ToUl J </seg>
            <seg id="p257">Shelion I a. » </seg>
            <seg id="p258">; Ch«rtiT 'TATEMEST. NOVEMBKI! AB1LITIE « 1 k l»iu». &lt;-u !l\- niers' 1! . n I </seg>
            <seg id="p259">arm* te Bank Charte rated. •shier WarrrnHui.- AnUUnt Cashier Auistant i ./« fcTA E*ENT, N'OVEMBEK 17, 190i RESOURCE LIABILITIB Loan- am i Capital (lock paid in I Overdrafts, secured and un - secured -~ fllO'l Bu.ekf, securities, judfrment*. claims etc - assets . . . t'.rk», aeouritlee, claims etc Rftseta Banking bouse furniture and Banking bouse furniture and her re:. Current excuses and taxt J Premium bond* and securities bonds ■ Cash items .. Cash itemi I&gt;ii" from national, stite and private banks and banker - .s and items of ex&lt;hn Due from national, st private banks and l&gt;ar - 1 » rated Ca«hi«r er ) MBCR17, !-•' K ans an&lt;! I k paid in erdraftb, secured and e furniture i -in;.' and ,e ban k </seg>
            <seg id="p260">260 Silver Creek The Silver Creek State Hank Silver Creek Charter Ma Chan ...Assistant Cash AissUtaut Cash .-TATEU I.IAB1LITIE b»ourc» KESOURCIB Loan* and * 01.584 00 d and ui; Loan* and d and un oflu " judgments, etc Bit.. paid I aher State BanV Snydet Char'. ABILITIES *?u iSSSS 1 * atih unVe- 3.H» judgments, ' &gt;anks and private bank and I'tiui i other ii' &lt;fd Cash i asn i ' , national, stat- and private banks ami hanker .. M" To..!... »»l </seg>
            <seg id="p261">- :;: </seg>
            <seg id="p262">262 The Sj&gt;akliiiL Bank .1. H Sullivai State h ivekber 17, 1SU3. L1ABII.ITIE Loam and &lt;li&gt;o i ? .... infaM ■ m no 4 1 ..atd M -.1 l»Dl and haulers nnd pri s • J Spencer Tin- Boyd Couiitv Hank lew | y.v - i l&gt;ark&lt;*r ir.KK IT. 190! IABILITIE p:ii-l in • llon.U - real e*laie 1.115 56 </seg>
            <seg id="p263">263 Spencer Corn Ex Bank \ nrorp Stated i KISnCRCE ! ■ - -til l.r [i ( I-. Springfield W.II. !• I' ;"l&gt;t- Mies and I ,i m m u i </seg>
            <seg id="p264">264 ( o. Bankei lit V MBER I Statimkkt. ARII.ITIE Springview </seg>
            <seg id="p265">'Shier </seg>
            <seg id="p266">266 TWKLFTH AN'\ THE Stamford The Stamford Bank Charter No. 388 Incorporated I'resnt. ashier -tant oaihier Statement, Novembek 17, :903. ■ EBOCRCE8 LIABILITIES Loam and discoun: Overdraft*, secured and un- ities, judgment*, "■Ik mi, etc -its subject to «&lt;■■(« us - furnliare and tp«It real estate it standing "3 and taxes paid I* &gt;'* inal hanks frernium on D ". and other and securities Due to state and prirate bunLi » itera &lt; H-n i 49 88 ■ if and -ers . . . ■ lianre (.Mt y&lt; Total $ JV.OXW 17 Total ( Stanton The Citizens' Bank State i BE8OCKCZS LIABILITIES Loans aurl disonn Hi.". •&gt;•:! 4; H..111I- 1.761 tUTM real MUM . m&gt;* paid and securities... 387 a 327 » 3*7 a» . vat* Urn- and twi «.H3l&lt; 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p267">267 Staplehurst The Hank of Btaplehnrat Statem RE&gt;"U ■ Steele City Tlie Exchange Bank TATEHKNT. NOVEMBER ' - LIABILITIES m- ■ ■ • f Hank r } 10.667 88 I </seg>
            <seg id="p268">268 ftfl^MHMMI Stella i'.iiuk « ■ m </seg>
            <seg id="p269">Sterling Ail'* r &lt;l 11111'!"* v\ « !l I Sterling t </seg>
            <seg id="p270">270 Iloughtou Bros.. Banker Stockham STATEMENT, NOTEMBKE 17. 1803. RESO! LIABILITIES " ! Slll.J' " furniture and fiz- |h tes paid M 5 19 I The Union lank Strang • fix- : </seg>
            <seg id="p271">271 Stratton The Commercial Banking STATEM r.es LIll',: J • &lt; I) ■• J s Stromsburg Fanners' vV &gt;!«• A k pa T&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p272">272 L.ll. TATEM1NT, K iVK.MHt Loans and ' &lt;l and uuse ire and ■ . Ban Stuart -lock paid in Loaus i igmenti vale banks i TcU </seg>
            <seg id="p273">273 The Se surity Bank a.ldox ■ I V L. Johns R W Jol Statement. N embek f 26,482 98 il Mock pa i &lt;ioo (in Bond Other ;i Hh ti k ini» Ik fixturt - . ■■ bank hi ted ■ ' Surprise The State Bank W . H 'TATEJtf LIAR! I 31,08* 58 ck paid in r 00 00 tX 13 lumen Hills paya Checks and items ofeichan - nnd items of*ich»ne&lt;&gt; Hills JM\:&lt; Total cash on band and dtif from \ish on band :m i rhif from b«nki 21,199 82 banks .. 21,190 82 ToUl .... $ W.S70 go ToUl | M.670 80 clHins. etc • ■ . ... . 1.70000 ! Banking house furniture and flx- atewft l Mn l.«50 00 810 97 i 21 30 Din to state and private banks and pri- i&gt;anks and bankers </seg>
            <seg id="p274">274 The Sutherland State Lank A \\ iTATEV nid (lx- ... ! 68 \ The Ban! : Koto Oi _ i. </seg>
            <seg id="p275">275 Jhart. •rated Pretirte Preside ATEXE.VT iVKMBKR R Loans and discount? ; J Overdrafts, secured and un - claims e Overdrafts, sec Other assets Banking bouse furniture and «*&gt; ■■ i ei!«nw&gt; and 'taxes Dairf I . inks Bank 1 ii esta Cash items Due from national, tl al and t.a T0U1 l»» I Tota Tota til Table Rock Thc . Stat( , Bank of Taljle Rwk Table Rock Charter No. WB. Incorporated. iirterN atecl. ' a»hi«r CMhltr tihier 8TATEMKNT, NOVEMBER 17, 1908. ATEMEK MHER 17, 19a mraocucES lunm RE LIABILITII oans and discounts I Caiiital stock pa: ,« m . securities, judgments, ,es, jU(. claims, eic claims, cic ion. Is Bonds ueiwiii miLjf Other assets... , Banking house furniture and ■ ■ uep««ii Mxtures ber real estate (. &lt; urrent exj&gt;ensesand taxes paid ?ieraium on U. 8. and other bonds and securities.. F - items Notes and bills re^discounted Bills payable mi national, state and private l&gt;anka aDd bankers . :«• -««nJ it«mg of exchange ' ta on hand </seg>
            <seg id="p276">276 TWELFTH ANNUAL KKl'OKT OF THK Talmage The Bank of Talniage Charter No. 410 HiTinMii Arend* .. ( a-lner .1 11. Dannie .Vice-Presideiit ; Cbn- i Assistant Cashier Assistant Cashier TATEMF.NT NOVEMBER 17, 19a BM0URCI8 LIABILITIES I.o»n» and discounts fllfi ai stock paid in |2fl 000 00 OviTilraftn, secured and nn;ec - cnrei tfurnlus fund 10.000 01) 1'udivlded profit* i'.OBS Stocks, securities, judgments, claims, etc Dividends unpaid individual deposits subject to check v\ arrants Other assets Demand certificates of deposit Time &lt;ertificates of deposit Hanking i" furniture and fixtures S.900 00 Certified checks Other real estate Cashier's checks outstanding Uue to national banks Current expenses and taxes paid 21* 95 P-emium on C. 8. and other bonds and securities Due to state and private banks and bankers . Cash items N &gt;tet and b 11s re-discounted. Due from national, stite and Bills payable private binks and (.ankers . 15.034 03 Checks and items of exchange. Total |143,7V . Total Ill $143,79-: iJl Tamora The Farmer)"' Exchange Bank Charter No. M President I L A Sandlieri: Cashie Cashier Anna C. Sandberg Vice-Presideut I Assistant Cashier Statement, November 17, 1903, REROUKCKS LIABILITIES Loans and discounts % 6 T.S 15 Capital stock paid in Overdrafts secured and unse- 1.61? 90 cured — siirDliis fund Undivided profits 107 40 Dl»ldend8 unpaid Stocks, tecaiitles, judgments, claims, etc Individual deposit! subject to Bondsand warrants &lt;-heck 6,494 37 Fher as-ets. interest paid on de - ■ • Demand certificate* of deDcsit s of deposit.... 2.721 «5 BankiDg house furniture an* : 1 ■ ■ ■ - fixtures 1.538 00 Other real es'ate Due to national banks. Currem expenses »nd taxes p«id M H Due to state and private banV and b«nker» Premiuti on U. 8. and other bonds and securities Notes anil bills re-disco r &lt;k3. &lt;'a«h items Bills payable. Doe from national. stat» and private banns and hanker; .. Checks ar,d items of exchange Total cuh onlund aud d banks 4.04S 96 Total 14,t»« </seg>
            <seg id="p277">277 Tekamah The Burt Countv State Bank Charter .rated. ic.l.. Adan - - Statement. N vexber 1? BESOl LIABILITIES I..MU.- ..ii. I discounts I1I9.62S t SMOOOOi * MM ix) 1.7l« other a . Ti&gt;i»1 c&amp;fli od hand an&lt; • I.HI Total : Thiyer The Bank of Ti w K. J. W i * ii Statemext. November LIABILITIES . 1 I*y.48'2 53 .... t i judgiuents Otll.T :l&gt;~-' 1.ISW 30 - private bank </seg>
            <seg id="p278">278 The uf ord id Bank Mullen Statmevt. N iVEXBKi: ? I) tm\ pri mkt mul Imi Total I Tilden Tlie Tilden State Bank Charter iVKHIlKR IT. 1903. LIABILITIES Statement. N iVBXBEt IT. 1903. 1.1AHII.ITIK LOHIIS Hll.l Cii-C.iil . S118.1»S 07 Loans Hinl disco I1I8.1M 97 t M.000 I.4M) i:*l 07 laments. tie* of deposit .. II ite banks lUnldur house furniture and fix- iture and fix- 7,000 00 7,000 00 - nil e«Ute - real esUtc ■ banks OMh Mhm ............. '" SO 30 SO 30 ■&gt; and pn Notes and &lt; I S6 43 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p279">riie Elklioni v Bank LIABILITIES I Tin' Peoples' Hank - MM *» re and fix m ji C&amp;sii </seg>
            <seg id="p280">280 Tobias The Citizens' Statf Bank WO. Inc"ri»irale&lt;l ikiT STATCatlfT, : STATMElfT, November 17. 1903. liabilities ill in ( 20 November 17. 1903. BES0URCE8 BEOOVBCEa I 61 - jyfi 16 LIABILITIES .. t 81 .881) 67 1 in ( H&gt;. jyfi 16 iture and tlv -uiture and fli- M4 49 31.414 49 6.0C1U UO paid unl privati- ban) r&lt;»! i * i' ■ * i' ■ t 91.313 28 .31 Trenton The Collett State Bank Statement, November 17. IM'3. ■wncti LIABIL TIE «KI IW ll I.6NM .W il banks 14 45 :md pri in ted. hanfce - I ll . ♦ 46.306 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p281">281 Trumbull The Bank of Trumbull Charier No. SMC Incorporated. w Aliiitin't duhte AliiiUnt I '.nhiar TATBMENT, NOVEMBER 1 RESOURCE! l&lt;« ill ■ red m w Bond other Kankii furnitur' • estate illll b: I Ulysses The First Bank of l"l\ Um. II II. M VEMBKK RKS.iURIK LIABII.ITIE JI78.068 31 irw - t house furn ■ i&lt;»ak» h? $-38,111 i&lt;5 </seg>
            <seg id="p282">282 THE Unsdllla The Bank of Unadilla Charts .-&gt;rate&lt;l ['resident C'aahier M :int i .-.sluer Statement, K&lt; iVKMBKK 17, I*). AP.11.1T1 K Loan* and discoui I Kiaitk, aecured aod n red ■•"&gt;.' H Si.x-ts. securliies, jud. &lt;-U ins. ■ . tniikln:' hout furniture and ■ :i'1 tHze«paid 'auks -. and other -itien nraie bauki l&gt; rnliw ute at,d ire Total . I Total $ 7J i » TJ Union The Bunk of Union A Statement. November 17. 19(«. RESOOCE! ABILITIES Loans and ■ II hi 11.4&amp;7 I m .;■ Oilier reul &lt;&gt;*txte ■ Cash items ■ 15.MS2 12 . Total rash on hand f M.W M </seg>
            <seg id="p283">The Wiiuloiii Bank A « -X » The Upland Bankiaf Incorporate* - ;tatkment. November REi&gt;nCK&gt;'K [ABILITIES Loans and disrnun- 343 aim A«i 00 othi'r asset Banking house furniture and fix- 1 - - • '■■»••&lt;. and Uxes p»id 1.138 87 and sccurtnBB M.M8 2 r </seg>
            <seg id="p284">284 The Merchants Bank: Utica Pun int. RESOURCES Loans and diieoui. Statement. November 17, J9« November 17. 1903. LIABIL1T: » 30,000 00 ■ rvil &lt;H&gt; . MM ■ vwo on . I8.WI 73 LI S 7i».33H L-; Utica The Utiea Bank Ltica ■ » STATEMENT. NOVCMBER 17, 1U03. BESOCBCKS LIABILITIES Loans and &lt;: I 14.287 01 din ( Htatemeht. November 17. iyo3. BESdVBCES Loans and dtouo— » . * 14.207 01 3.7V7 * 100 00 100 ■ I MO 00 ••n»« »wi 1,111 57 I •■ bank tte banks .. U 45« 5! I 174 40 _••■ . . I 174 40 Tl 50 O^i I C^ 1 v t 68 781 01 ' </seg>
            <seg id="p285">285 Valentine Frwl \\ hit J.W. Btetl ..I Statement, Novf.mbkk 17. 1903 RESOUR&lt; E LIABILITIES Loans :i s $ . | ■uretl :in&lt;l tin S claims, etc Knnds Warnin llan km- houw furniture mid fix 1 I ■■ * ' 10 d Di her bond Cash M04 i* Total $i3U Va'ley AH. N TATEIIEST, N v em lit: it 17, 19*1: LIABILITIES - ■ ■ "■••curpti ftnd u nsd.' up' 1 ! 1 liiti'rest paid _- house furniture and S.S33 W H tonal, state and pri - and bankers ems of exchange . . . hand and dur from ui national, state and pri ▼ate banks and banker- ■ - :ind items of exchange «sh &lt;&gt;n hand and due from banks ».KH&gt; f S» 53 Total i ae.f-ei u Total i ae.f-ei u Total ToUl t S6.8M 11 The &gt; aleutiiK Bank ■ - \k* paid ■ Tlie Va te Bunk ■ JOO !■-. p.-iiil. 1,309 Wd I 898 0i il hanks inks .... </seg>
            <seg id="p286">286 V Mas .1. P Statement. N F.MFKK K IABILUIE ■ •• IKI (I DO k 1111 ■ . Ill Verdel The Fanner State Bank v Statemint, N VKMHKIl RESOl'IltEl ■ Homls Kid flx- D | private bank Jl .*y M ToUl </seg>
            <seg id="p287">287 Verdigre The Kn tv Bank LIABIi $ I .« t \ sl.iar ~l.i*r ATCM! ««iis» .. f »,K»a6 (lid ui.se- .. • a and ta.vt- Preir; s I t---ts.li ite Due from iintional, state and ate Iphiu- a-id bankers hange </seg>
            <seg id="p288">288 Charter No. President ! KC.Rul'a.... Cashier . Vice- President l Assistant Cushler ut Cusbler STATEMENT, NOVEMBER IT, ISO: Statimikt, November IT, 1S03 MMmea KBSOCKCIS I LIABILITIES !1I.H2(M Capital -to-k paid In } 5 000 00 unse- ad 166 profits .... LIABILITIES Loans and discounts } Overdrafts, secured and unse- Loans and discounts J u.rt.'i 54 Capital -lok tal -tok paid iti J 5 000 00 Overdrafts, secured and unse- rind cure runts 166 30 1 .017 securities, it*! runts • m unpHiil ! Inal deposits subject to - unpaid deposits subject to Bond- Bond- ch Other Oth&lt;- .... D&lt;-mai&gt; : !«•■ furniture and LVma f deposit LVmai .» of deposit mi «) niture and e and deposit . ... .1431 30 1.450 30 Certified chec . IM n I ■ rtlfl. i bet U real estate real estate . ••■n»es and taxes paid natioi Cashle outstanding - outstanding.. • n»es and taxes paid M Si • paid 6S8 37 Due to national banks • national banks I acct. -i paid acct ie and private banks - -htc and private banks and hanker* and bank. «n.l Mils re-discounh and imiihiT C»sh items C»«h items votes and htl ■ ri'l Mils re-discounted Due from national state and Bills payable private banks mid banker I 63 Due from national state and e and Bills payable I 63 Bills payable private banks und bank' Checks end items of exchange Checks and items of exchange ToUl I19.S0I 74 Total liana I19.S01 74 Total $19,901 T4 12* 96 Total II9.WI 74 I Total $19,901 74 Virginia The Citizens' State Ba Virginia The Citizens- State Bask Charter No. 745. llHXMJKm The Citizens' State Bank Charter No. 745. Incorporate Charter No ■4! AW S AW Nickell ... Cashier Cashier lent I M V. Aaalitant Cathie: O.O.Tb' M V. &gt; Assistant Cashle: Statement, November 17,1903 ram, Novembeb it, 1903 lint, November 17,1903 KKROUBCES KKROUBCES I LIABII.I IBS 21,5* IS Capital s'ock paid in | 500000 Siirpiis Innd Ml 54 prolits .. 907 » LIABILI IBS Loans »nd discounts ji,5..y H Loans ind discounts MJWH Capital s'ock Capital s'nek paid in | 5 000 00 nvt-rdrst ■.-. kecured and uuse uwrdnif ■.-. tecured and u us In ml ttarpins Innd i. roli :s .. 90? oared.. ill 54 Ml to I rities, jodgments, - t«-arities, judgments, nents, mpaid clai dual d lual d'pesits subject to check 36.402 Di-mand certificate!) of deposit. . i*,3U idual deposits subject to B»nd&gt; check Bonds Other assets Demand certi Other assets 1&gt;&gt; maud certificate!) of deposit ■•.'■£*) IS :«U 15 li.-mk -niiure and fix Time cerlitics nd fix Time cerliticates of deposit 1 .000 00 MB 00 Certified checks Caahter's checks out standing . . li:i nk int' hiuisp furniture and fix Time cerliticates of deposit no 00 3fV- ■ XH 00 Certified chec Certified checks Other real estate Cashier's che Other real estate. cashier's checks out standing Currentexpennesand t*xea p &gt;id 71170 current expentwsand ttxes p dd 74170 Due to nation spirt 74170 One to national banks Due to national hanks Premium on U. S. and other and securities Premium on U. S. and other Duetostnte : bonds and securities aud bankei other Due to state Hid private banks aud banker* Notes and bills le-discounted Due to state Hid private banks aud bankers Cash item-, Cash item* Notes and bll Notes and bills te-discounled Doe from national, state aul Bills payable private banks and bankers ... lfe.363 30 Col. to Doe from national, state aul e aul Bills parable Bills payable private banks and bankers ... 16.36130 sr« ... I*. 363 30 Col. to be credited and remitti ■ Checks aud items of exchange . 133 :s6 Checks aud items of exchange . 133 36 mm*.. 133 :« 1.IM64 I43«!3»8e toui *42,&lt;ae m C»*h 1 362 di 1 362 di ToUl 1-12 830 00 Total . ToUl ! 12 639 60 Total utm The tate Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p289">289 8KCRKTAKV 01 BANKIN W abash The Fan tate Bank i&lt; o. rtiom (&gt;»n r State v ivixbib 17, 19U3 HCWI LIABIL1TIE ■ Other assets I LM I 1.600 I liHI tivt Oih. t - Due fn &gt;m '■h«'l hang* fIMM 04 ! Tlit- Farmer*" it Trailers" Bank K. .1. Wight '■e-Pre»Went Statement. November 17. 1903 LIABILITIES Lcinl Capital stock paid in ; I iM III ••O proBti I l id other bonds : tnd other bonds : statp and pri - 50.599 W Cashier's checks outstanding. . . . : private batnkt -t.it.- and private banks ind pri :ks and l»nkers 50.599 «6 'fins of exchange M)4 .-: - and items of exchange 694 It C«ih 1.972 40 Cash . 1.972 40 .9 RESnCRCES $ -I Intlh Banking house furniture and fix- chock . 1.600 00 ass 21 • </seg>
            <seg id="p290">290 TWELFTH ANNUAL EEl'ORT OF THE Bank Wahoo The Citizens A LIABILIT1E *101.: ,.. &gt; ■nd priviti Tin. 1 Farmers' A Traders Hank Wakefleld * IV Math K. H. ' Statement. Novembeh IT. ISM liabi: i in I WO00 i] m &gt; w» •■ 993 "5 11,411 26 anil tt\ ... io.ooo oo </seg>
            <seg id="p291">BANKING 291 Waterbury The Waterbury Bank Charter No. 609, i -ated. President Cashier 1&gt;. resident UsisUDtCn ATEMEST N VEXBER IT, lA ¥ LIABILIT1E I 21,0: )ans ant I ."..no M Oven) rafts, aec u uu in 4Ui Stork*, securities judgment*, claims eic - assets use furniture and real estah- ' Stockt. secur: gmenu, v 1 le furniture and her real estatt it standing nal banks standing Current ex|*jnses and taxes paid 1.4 ,i banks Current expenses and taxes paid !■)■.•;■ Premium on U. S. and o Premium on U. S. and o anki bonds and BecuritieB Cash items Due from national, stite and private banks and hankers rut 1 from national. sNte mid private banks and haiiK O necks and items of e ■ Checks and items of ex- |f( ti'i Total I » Tott . t Waterloo The Citizens" State Bank Waterloo The Citizens" State Bank Charter No. nlu. Incorporated. Charter No, u. Incorporated ■ President I H. B Vice-l'residpRt | Statement, November 17, 1903. resources liabilities Pre: tident I 11. B. \V ildeat I v Caihi.r Vioe-1're: N VKMBEl: RESOir.CKS LIABILITIES Loans and discounts s atal atock paid in Loans and discounts : al -lock pa: Overdrafts, secured and on- Overdrafts, secured and an •t-oaxed 80 1 -. securities, judgments, securities, judgments claims, etc 233 80 ; In Individual deposits subj.it to Bonds Fiber assets ■ •ertineatesof de; inking house furniture and leposit r real estate .. lias;., current expenses and taxes paid 868 .V naiionxl banks Piemium on U. 8. and other Due t &gt; state and private bunks ■» of deposit Other assets g house furniture and rixtures Oilier real estate cashier t standing urrent expenses and taxes paid Ml H ' naiion-il banks state and private bunks bonds and securities .. and banker!) 7*1 U0 items ind bills re-discouuted lme from national, state and private bank- aDd bankers Bills payable. checks and items of exchange Total cash on band and il banks Total </seg>
            <seg id="p292">292 The Wauneta Falls Bank Charter No. 443. Private. viaw Pre- ('a.-)iier Vice-Presideut | V. K. MoCullura Assistant Cashier Assistant Cashier bTATCMENT NOVEMBER 17, 1903. BISOUBCK8 LIABILITIES Loan* and discounts I 12 Overdrafts, secured and mat Capital stock paid in 4 C.600 0C Surplus fund -titicates of deposit 119 eo Other asset* Other assets rtiticatea of deposit nu eo Banking house furniture and Hmiknii: Iiou»e furniture and fixtures ] icatesof deposit. ieatesof deposit. fixtures 1 . Other real estate ierks &lt;ii checks heekt outstanding.. tonal liauk - ■late and private banks Other real estate hecks outstanding.. 1 national banks Current expenses and taxes paid 3.S12 67 Premium on U. 8. aDd other Current expenses and taxes paid 3.312 67 Premium on U. 8. aDd other bonds and securities -tan- and private banks mid bankers bond- and securities Cash items mid bankers and bills re-discounted., .ayable Cash items Notes and bills re-discounted.. Due- from national, tttte and private binks and banker*... Due- from national, tttte and private btnks and bankers .. BilU payable Checks and items of exchange Total ■■■ Cbeckn and items of exchange Total baai Hi 91 banes. ToUl »3»,T78 12 Total Total Total 139,778 li *39,778 12 t Wausa The Fanners State Bank Charter No. 44 1 Incurp T. A AnthoDV Cashier 1 • my ,. » a- ; K. \V. Hiir&gt;t Vice-Presideut Assistant Casl Assistant Cashier Statement, Novemher 17, 190" BCSODKCIS LI ABILITIES Loans and discounts (I77 0CS84 Capital stock paid in $ ?o,000 0C Overdrafts secured and un*e- .us fund i&gt; cured 3,119 36 cur. 3,119 .16 Undivided profit.". Jt'.as 80 Undivided profits, 3i.62S 80 Btocki, securities, judgments, claims, • ' Stocks, securities, Judgments, claims, ftc Dividends unpaid Di»iden&lt;ls unpaid... Individual deposits subject to check 45.891 15 Individual deposits subject to Bonds and warmi Bonds and warrants check 45,«B1 15 Demand rertitieatei of deposit. 2..W7 go Other ..s-ets. iTitf rest paid on de - posi: Other nssets. interest paid on de - posits Demand certificate* of deposit. 2.5*7 00 "ates of deposit.... 100,804 89 "ates of deposit.... 100,804 89 Bunking house furniture and fixtures 2,781 » Bunking house furniture and fixture* 2,781 » IH'raanil iiccniuts Otber real eaiatc Other real eaiatc Due to national banks 174 75 Due to state and private bank Due to national banks 174 75 Curreti t expenses and taxes p«id 4:'.i 00 Current expenses and taxes p« id i'.'h ■ Due to state and private bank and banker* Premium on U.K. and other bonds and securities Premium on U.K. and other bonda and securities and banker*. Notes and bills re-diseon &lt;?d Cash items Caiab items. Bills payable ... 5,000 00 Doe from national, state and Due from national, stat" and private banks and Sunk |3S 82 private banks and banker* .. 23,433 82 k s ar.d items of exchange 1 .342 48 is dr.d items of exchange 1.S42 48 uh on hand 9.061 30 -ash on hand 9.061 30 To'«l S 217,181 29 To'al I 181 29 Total f 217.181 29 t 217.181 29 *j&gt; i iui ni la, MTimu anil UUWI'- nuil'ius 1U11U care: iivldi-d j.roflta I Stocks, securities, judgments, . Dividend! unpaid claims, etc Individual deposits eubject to narr«uis Mk ■ i17 w </seg>
            <seg id="p293">Wausa * Charter Kdwanl R iilent I (,. II i:-.,:ir.l. . . Cashier li. E. Lund;: re i • STATEMENT. X VIMBF.R 17. 1901. BESOUI LIABILITIES l in t 20000 00 Lin 0::0 'i&gt;i f&lt;: in I 9.8*9 06 ri (a- ■ • Waverly Charter X. H. M*r I STATEJIENT. N BOIIVBi )&gt; 1 IAHII.ITIK 100 00 • ■urwianii n 97 BO . . --w ...... . u . S and other ■ Iter m national, state and pri- - in national, state and pri- vate banks and bankers ... 34.188 18 ■•• hanks and bankers ... 34.188 18 : items of exchanu - ind items of exehsiiL- Hi!!- payable Tutsi cash on hand 3 M3 W Tota % til .MM 16 Totalcanh on hand Total t til .MM IB I ta bank The Bank of Waverh claims, etc r :i*sets Sn.Mt W ng house, furnitu- 9 age 45 1,501 1 e\pen»es and t» 418 59 </seg>
            <seg id="p294">294 Wayne Tlu' Citizens" Hank STATh 1AR1LITIE8 Loan- lUliklii K.000 00 Duefroni national stati- and pri I } I Wayne The State Hank of Wayne State v LIABILITIE Loans ai . f 113.945 26 I in 180.000 00 1.549 (II _ &lt;M In* ml ii\- 7.1 '.'. .... bank* ! iCSOiti </seg>
            <seg id="p295">I !C vOU III » ! * HINT. SO ABILITI I ■ i I *ton Bank itak K STATEMENT. N.i\ KMKKI. ■ IAB1I.ITIE lix- I v&lt;« V ni « </seg>
            <seg id="p296">296 TWKLFTH ANNUAL KKI'OKT OF THE West Point The Nebraska State Bank IiK'orporatei ■ NOVEMBKR 17. 1908. STATEMENT, RESIH KCF.S LIABILITIES I...»ns aiidJi-&lt;-..iit.i- IU7.SMM 130." *6 ■ lo.two uo : 400 00 if \%&gt; 1,000 00 ■■• furniture and flx- 1.400 00 1.400 00 ind pri- Uills. imyul. • I The Whitman State Bank Whitman ■ ■ I A.I'. SmitL Assistant I Assistant CashU-r Statement. November 17. ltcs. KESODRCE8 LIAB1L.TIKB * t iO.IXXI 00 wa m , ... 14.1*45 i«i - furniture ami Bx- 2. Other real Mtate .. J.SSD 4rt ■id 170 18 •r bonds U l»nks mted. 13.6S8 16 cuh 1,178 01 </seg>
            <seg id="p297">297 Whber The Bank of Will Wliber harter 0. R Hopkins \ U. R Statement. November IT. 1W3. TATIMENT. N iVKMKKR IT. 1W3. RESOURCES LIABILITIES ■ RESOURCES LIABIMTIE ■ u Hank tur.-- 6.60C 00 - » Dm , • 11(1 (tU. Itauk* liank t 5.861 13 -«1 44 WHcox The State H.ink of Wilcox The State Bank of Wilcox WUcox Charter It* 156. Ineorpora .Prmldent I Charter Ka tM neorporated President I Vice-l'r A«si»tin; i iilu«r » Statement, November IT. RESOURCE* LIABILITIES 8TATKMF.ST, NOVEMBER 17, 1903 RESOUKCES Loans and d I 43.W1 39 Loans and diseoun - ... ( 43.061 3» Ovrcirufts sacuralaud unscrurad Overdrafts. Mcurad mid unsei'ured 1.9U1 Stock- e&gt;, |MilKmeii'&gt;. :*3 ■ lion&lt;i^ other assets Hanking bouse fuxoiture and fix tures 2.T0O 00 Other real estati &lt;!0 00 Cur i-nt expenses inid 880 73 r hoods private bank 3» 00 ,iat*» and pri- THte bunks s HitU p $ * - ■ V v 1 "i f SI. 183 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p298">298 r \\ K I . r I Wiisonvllie The Wilsonville Hank Wilsonville Charter No. 507 Charter No. B Preside Cashier Preside Cashier \ ant^aahier Statement, Novkmbck IT, 1903. Statement, Novkmbcr IT. !90: RESOURCES LIABILITIES LABILITIES Loam and diseou rafik, secured anil un- Loam »nd discou . J 4O,K«8 7X Capital stoct paid i:. $ 10.0CO CO raft*, secured anil un- paid i:. $ 10.0C0 Gt 1.030 1.03895 05 I Stocks, securities, judgment*. Stocks, securities, judgments, clams, el. Individual deposits subject to da mi 1 ii-I i vI-Iiih . deposits subject to check check » Oiber Hsvts Oiber as«-U... ,f deposit. . 11 ' s of deposit 11 nankin* hous- furniture and eposh tixi Dankiui? boua: furniture and de|&gt;osu fiXlUT' ■tending 1 1 standing. . xtional banks and tiixea paid 1182 - and taxes paid i» uional banke. . ■«. and other | private banks - and other - Due to state and private banks Ankers - 1 n-h items - and bills rediscounted i ■ and bills rediscounted .... Due from national, state aiid privs - 16,.S65 06 Due from national, state ai.J l»ue from national, state aiid . payable . . privs - I6,n65 06 Cheeks mi xchan«e 1'rivati ankers Cheeks an xchanre Total |«MHU Total !• Total | 08 11 I Total f Winnetoon Winnetoon xiie First Bute I'.ai.k The First State Bank ■ ■ rp-iraied • - f»ESt. KtfSJBI BESOCRCES W1ILITIES J H.-kV MENT. • &gt;'■ re and flx - iiid 10 4&lt; ■ - 1 1 estate .id Ml '■" • Total cash on hand « *Mt» I 1 53.906U 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p299">299 The Merchants Statement. November V ur. Tin- Wi- 'r Bank I'f' ATKMKST ABILITIES HK8OURCES Ix»ns $ KM n) lUnkin 731 ;■ * </seg>
            <seg id="p300">300 TWELFTH ANNIAI, KKI'OKT &lt;&gt;K THE Wolbach The Wolbach State Bank So. «t&gt;3. Statement. November IT. ]9O3 LIABILITIES I ill $ 10.000 00 I KM 00 1.M4 3C 18,386 18 LIABILITIES RESOCRrES RESOURCES ♦ -7.329 07 i.WS «6 ♦ -7.329 07 i in $ io.ooo oo KM 00 l.VU 3C • i, )lld|[lll' 1.S44 3S lrt.:i«f, Hank I t!c real e«Ut« "iis&lt;&gt;s and taxes paid •T.n* IT I !■ ... ;il estate :ii(l 4D6 17 te bank •ate and pri- pri - »W TO 9M TO nd 2.38! 96 nd 2.38! 96 t 35.687 76 ,1 t 35.687 76 $36.887 76 The Wood Lake Bank Wood Lake P. &lt;'h«i M M .1 .rkl-r... hier Statement. November 17. 1903 RESOURCES LIABILITIES t 27 nor tie ired Hi M k yaiit in I mi :4 ■.'.:*»; ii ■hool Warrants -e furniture ebeok . 30,946 30 as&gt; in 3 000 00 :&gt;67 85 Oth«-r reHl estme ".'.".".' .'.'.'.".'.' '.'. • and taxes paid 1,106 27 - banks Hid pri- ■ ills re-discounted rate banks:, 14.426 01 Hills )&gt; -and Items of exchaiii: 74 76 1.860 00 t 4C&amp;M 70 </seg>
            <seg id="p301">301 • 1 Wood River The Citizen Bank Ini'i \V. W. MitcliHI Vi Statement, Novembkk I". IS* LIABILITIE RESOURCE I&gt;. i.lt n.iii.i Warran Hanking bouse furniture and iix- n(l taxei | ' ••• bank -,-. ,.■ . ... f-hw-k C«*h al »I(#.I5» Wymore Tin- Wvinon- Stiitt.' Bank . Mt It . Andersou \ iTATEMENT. NOVEMBKR IT, 190. LIABILITIES RESOURCE I25.0HO no nscouni S 51.471 TO | red 1,3') Hi «i ■ lgmet us, etc i subject to It. .II' 1 .- -sets Interest paid 4OI«&lt;* Hanking house furniture aud 3&gt;«&gt; OU j uid pri - ;iiiW&gt; and banker. ImnKe doe fron bank^ 3.181 55 Total $ 88,l&gt;- t 88.0M9I </seg>
            <seg id="p302">302 Yutan Tlie Bank m Cashier A t nt t Statement. November 17. u«&gt;:. ate. KCS8 I.IABILITIE f5».ll2 » lid in »1 - !iX- • 1,500 00 "... bank 3.14 J |7 </seg>
            <seg id="p303">GENERAL INDEX A ill State F-!;iuks, June 9. 1» Abstract all State llai id Private Banks, November 17, IS .... 17. 190j ional Ha National Ban mber IT. ve Aver;: I! Banks reorganized and rein d Banks from V ited Bai i changed from l'i •■ Banks Nationalized... t Hanks National! Hanks sold to and - ; Ha ; Hanks gone into Voluntary liquidation Hanks gone into Voluntary liquids) Bank- 1 in hands of Hani Banks that have changed their names Banks that have changed their names Banks (Incorporated) chai Hani- Banks (Private) chartered ... &gt;\ Hani. Banks chartered but had not commenced In - | Hanks chartered hut had not commenced hi - I Hanks (Prlva Comparisons Comparisons 1&gt; - nuniljei IT- is its iiiiii) (mount peicapita . . 1« ipreme Court) Failed Hanks (caus ; ( p </seg>
            <seg id="p304">304 R pitulation Stati i .inks in tianda of Bee </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>