<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00048.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00048.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Second Biennial Report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings and of the Secretary of the Board of Education Lands and Funds to the Governor of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1920-12-01">1920-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWENTY-SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Commissioner OF Public Lands and Buildings AND OF THE Secretary OF THE Board of Educational Lands and Funds TO THE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1920 By DAN SWANSON Commissioner of Public Land* and Buildings and Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds 1920 THE BEACON PRESS LINCOLN, NEBR </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">STATE OFFICERS 1919-20 Samuel R. McKelvie Governor P. A. Barrows Lieutenant Governor D. M. Amsberry Secretary of State D. B. Cropsey Treasurer George W. Marsh Audito' Clarence A. Davis Attorney Genera! Dan Swanson Land Commissioner W. H. Clemmons, Died January 9, 1920 State Superintendent John M. Matzen, Appointed January 15, 1920. Victor E. Wilson, Resigned Oct. 1, 1919 Railway Commissioner Thome A. Browne, Appointed Oct. 1, 1919 H. G. Taylor Railway Commissioner Thos. L. Hall Railway Commissioner STATE OFFICERS 1921-22 Samuel R. McKelvie Governor P. A. Barrows Lieutenant Governor D. M. Amsberry Secretary of State D. B. Cropsey Treasurer George W. Marsh Auditor Clarence A. Davis Attorney General Dan Swanson Land Commissioner John M. Matzen. State Superintendent Harry L. Cook Railway Commissioner Thorne A. Brown Railway Commissioner H. G. Taylor Railway Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p004">COMMISSIONERS OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS OF NEBRASKA F. M. D*t1« _ 1877-1880 A G. Kendall 1881-1884 Joseph Scott 1885-1888 John Steen 1889-1890 A. R. Humphrey 1891-1894 H. C. Russell 1895-1896 J. V. Wolfe _ _ 1897-1900 George D. Follmer 1901-1904 H. M. Eaton 1906-1908 E. B. Cowles 1909-1912 Fred Beckmann 1913-1916 G. L. Shumway 1917-1918 Dan Swanson 1919-1922 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">COMMISSIONER'S OFFICE 1919-20 Dan Swanson Commissioner G. E. Emery Deputy Commissioner T. A. Boyd Chief Clerk Bert R. Anderson Bookkeeper Metta I. Loeber Recorder and Delinquent Clerk Cecille M. Hanna Stenographer DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING Robert Harvey, St. Paul State Surveyor E. B. Corning, Loup City Deputy E. C. Simmons, Pender Deputy B. W. Benson, Central City Deputy W. S. Scott, Lincoln Deputy Dan A. Nippell, Antioch Deputy </seg>
            <seg id="p006">' </seg>
            <seg id="p007">COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Lincoln, Nebr., Dec. 1, 1920. To His Excellency, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor: Sir: In compliance with the constitutional requirement, I have the honor to submit the following report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, who is also the Secretary of the Board of Educa - tional Lands and Funds, for the biennium beginning December 1, 1918, and ending November 30, 1920. IMPROVEMENTS During the past two years the following improvements were made: Replacing underground light wires running to the Lincoln monu - ment, and to nearly all lighting posts on the Capitol grounds. This was a needed improvement as the grounds had been poorly lighted for several months. Repairs in the Senate Chamber for the purpose of bracing ani holding the walls and staying the ceiling. Repairs on the roof of the State Capitol covering the greater part of the roof and gutter. This was another improvement very much needed as the roof was in bad condition, allowing leakage whenever rain or snow fell. ESCHEAT LANDS During the present administration the State became the owner of the following escheat lands and lots: East Half of the North East Quarter of Section 13, and the North East Quarter of the North East Quarter of Section 24, Township 20. Range 36, West of the 6th P. M., Arthur County. West Half of Section IS and the North West Quarter of the North West Quarter of Section 19, Township 20, Range 35, West of the 6th P. M., McPherson County. Lot 7 in Block 1, Town of Phillips, Hamilton County, Nebraska. RENEWALS OF LEASES ON SCHOOL LANDS HAVING IMPROVEMENTS By an Act of the Legislature approved April 17, 1919, lease holders of lease contracts dated after July 8, 1897. are given the right, at the pxpiration of their contracts, to apply for new contracts, and if the bid of the lessee shall be equal to the amount bid by any other person, the lessee's bid shall be accepted. If a higher bid is made by a person other than the lessee, the value of all the improvements on the land shall be appraised by the Board of County Commissioners or Supervisors, as the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT case may be; such appraisement to be made within thirty days after the acceptance of the bid, and, after being signed, shall, within five days, be filed with the county treasurer of the county in which the land is situated. Either the lessee or successful bidder may, if he is dissatisfied with the appraisement, appeal therefrom to the District Court of the County in which the land is situated. NEW LAW The constitutional amendment which provides that no lands now owned or hereafter acquired by the State for educational purposes shall be sold except at public auction under such conditions as the Legisla - ture shall provide, becomes effective January 1, 1921. This annuls the law permitting the sale of lands held under school land lease contracts dated prior to July 9, 1897, or the sale of lands under irrigation. If the present session of the Nebraska Legislature should conclude o sell all the educational lands belonging to the State when the leases xpire or are cancelled and forfeited for nonpayment of rentals, I would recommend the lands be appraised for sale purposes by the chairman of he County Board of Commissioners or Supervisors of the respective counties together with the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings r his representative ; the land to be advertised and sold at public auction to the highest cash bidder for not less than ninety per cent of the ap - raised value, the purchaser to pay 25% in cash and the balance to be secured by a sale contract running for twenty years at 6% annual nterest I would recommend that all city lots and small isolated tracts of land be sold to the highest bidder. The State now owns a number of such lots in Lincoln and Kearney, two lots in Auburn, one lot in Phillips and a fractional lot in Sidney. REVIEW OF APPRAISEMENT When a lease holder makes application to purchase, the land in question is appraised by the County Board of the County wherein it is located. This valuation thereupon becomes reviewable by the State Board to determine whether the appraisement is adequate or otherwise. I have reviewed 19,069.03 acres in twenty-six counties, and the appraisement made by the respective County Boards was increased $52,100.25. The pur - chaser paying the expense of the county officers appraisement, the in - crease in review is net, less the small costs of review by the Commis - sioner of Public Lands and Buildings. MINERAL LEASES bBy an Act of the Legislature approved April 9, 1918, a Law was sed to provide for the prospecting for, and development of minerals, roleum, gas, potash and other valuable substances found in public </seg>
            <seg id="p009">INVENTORY OF PERSONAL, PROPERTY 9 lands and waters of the State of Nebraska, and from lands heretofore sold or conveyed by the State, in the conveyance of which there had been reserved mineral or other valuable substances above enumerated. The terms upon which mineral oil prospector's leases may be issued shall be to the highest bidder and one-eighth royalty in the case of pe - troleum or gas. In case of potash and other substances, trie leases issued shall be to the highest bidder and the royalty shall be not less than five per cent in addition to the bonus or amount of such bid. During the bienuium, forty-five mineral leases have been issued covering 24,240 acres of land located in the Counties of Cherry, Dawes, Deuel, Franklin, Garden, Sheridan and Sioux. During the last two yearp the State received $9,447.04 royalty for potash, which is the first royalty for minerals of any kind ever received by the State. INVENTORY OF PERSONAL PROPERTY During my administration an inventory of all furniture and fixtures belonging to the State, located in the State Capitol and Governor's Mansion, has been prepared. EXCHANGE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS During the administration of my predecessor, application had been made by agents of the United States Government for an exchange of educational lands within the Federal Forest Reserves for other lands of equal area and value of public lands within said Reserves, and the Leg - islature, by an act approved April 19, 1917, authorized the Board ot Educational Lands and Funds to make such exchange, and that the lands exchanged and the lands received therefor should correspond in value at not less than $7.00 per acre. In pursuance thereof, my predecessor examined certain lands in the Reserves of Cherry and Thomas Counties, and during my term a cor - rected list of 5,316.55 acres were selected in a body in the West end of the Reserve in Cherry County, and a list of 3,642.08 acres in the East end of the Reserve in Thomas County have been selected and approved by the Registers of the Land Offices in Valentine and Alliance. These lands have been duly advertised and are now awaiting the action of the Interior Department at Washington, D. C. RE-APPRAISEMENT OF LEASED LANDS During the biennium the lands under lease in twenty-two counties have been re-appraised and the new valuation approved by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. This increases the yearly Income of the State $102,975.84, and this increase is for the benefit of the educational funds and helps every school district in the State. The appended table shows the counties thus affected. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Harlan 39,280.05 124,895.80 85,615.75 1 5,136.95 Johnson [ 7^019.98 37.249.75 3o!229.77 : l!si3.79 Keya Pana 53,086.67 Keya Paha 53,086.67 130,429.34 77,342.67 ' 4,640.56 130,429.34 77,342.67 | 4,640.56 Otoe 6!550.00 ! Otoe 6,550.00 ! 18,630.00 12.080.00 724.80 18,630.00 12.080.00 724.80 PUtte „ 6,720.00 ! 26,300.00 19.580.00 ! 1,174.80 PUtte 6,720.00 26,300.00 19.580.00 ! 1,174.80 Pierce 58,500.00 Pierce 58,500.00 ] 160,800.00 102.300.00 i 6,138.00 26,955.00 15,375.00 I 922.50 160,800.00 102.300.00 i 6,138.00 Richardson _. 11,580.00 Richardson 11,580.00 26,955.00 , 15,375.00 I 922.50 Sarpy 1,821.48 Sarpy 1,821.48 18,207.80 16,386.32 i 983.18 18,207.80 16,386.32 983.18 Saunders 280.00 I Saunders 280.00 500.00 220.00 13.20 500.00 ; 220.00 13.20 Sioux 101,794.73 Sioux 101,794.73 146,054.43 44,259.70 2,655.58 146,054.43 44,259.70 2,655.58 ScottB Bluff 14,837.36 Scotts Bluff 14,837.36 42,824.68 27,987.22 1,679.23 42,824.68 27,987.22 1,679.23 8,860.00 1 3.420.00 ! 205.20 Stanton 5,440.00 Stanton 5,440.00 8,860.00 1 3.420.00 [ 205.20 20,629.12 ! 5,859.05 351.54 Webster 14,770.07 Webster 14,770.07 20.629.12 ! 5,859.05 1 351.54 Wheeler 30,640.00 Wheeler 30,640.00 156,580.00 125,940.00 7.556.40 156,580.00 I 125,940.00 ! 7.556.40 Totals $883,003.83 $2,599,267.83 $1,716,264.00 $102,975.84 COUNTY Old Value New Value Increase Yearly Increased Rental oone oyd uffalo nrt iase lerry ►mwBon *©€icy $15,599.83 73.270.58 46,176.77 2.100.00 51,659.88 237,685.13 75,511.30 28.680.00 $31,697.72 116,249.54 93.850.91 12.000.00 310,802.51 906,883.23 171,940.00 36.928.00 $16,097.89 42.978.96 47,674.14 9,900.00 259,142.63 669.198.20 96,428.70 8,248.00 1965.87 2,578.74 2,860.45 594.00 15.548.56 40,151.89 5.785.72 494.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">APPROPRIATIONS, 1919-1920 11 s In o 2 t- to in r- 1 in ih m h Pi ■* 3&gt; t- » M O t-; » O5 3&gt; O) 7&gt; in u? co » OO ■i ■a I I ■ I CO 00 o — a&gt; is o in CD O3 — «c in eo AtfilflN oo o in o » v pi w o in in -« « n id h H eo oo in 00 00 Ol on o ■» in »■« — I ■ : 1*4 ci c : in |» I |a : t^ oo i : : © — : : m o M °? us ia ia ■ a |s ! o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o o IO O O Iff O O O o o o o o o o o o o io't-" § o o o &lt;e i-T 111 » to ■» : : *? : t- : t* : o : s* i oo : » s n ri ia M i-l p4 «-; O 00 CO •» • f I ■ • I • • 1 ill! I I ■•a * o « I ■ % * • .11 . j= ■J oo O : js i. • ;««o «£ : o : t I -o S - - § . H ■ ! 1 jSiS£|£ *| I | ije;s**g •£« ;| S ill I- "S g S-g I SirJlbliiii 1« •&amp;§§ a s « s • E t% e o u m X </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT RECEIPTS OF THE DEPARTMENT FOR THE BIENNIUM Rentals on lease contracts j 675,806.24 Interest on sale contracts _ 263,242.03 Bonus and added Interest. 14,672.27 Principal on sale contracts 575,443.11 Fees, December 1, 1918, to November 30, 1920 7,060.97 Total receipts for the biennium $1,536,224.62 rABLE SHOWING FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS, NOVEMBER 30, 1920 „......,. _ . . . Total Actpk Total Acres COCNTT Total Acre. Total Acre. Under Sale Vm*m Lea»e ln- Aniuired Deeded Contract Contract claxKifleil Adams 20.480 18.600 1,080 800 Antelope 31,400 17,840 3,000 10,560 ZZZZZ. (Univ.) — 1,600 1,360 40 200 \'Z'Z Arthur 25,720 25,720 S»nner 26,880 320 1,280 25,280 Z... B &lt;»ine 25.530.45 160 880 24,490.45 l ZZZZZ. Boon ® 23,675.28, 19,303.50 1.637.53 2J15.77 "l's'is Box Butte 40,960 762 160 40,038 1. Boyd 22,652.72 4,390.78 7.450.87 1M11JT _____ Brown 40,998.90 556.40 397 «t,t« H Huffalo I 30.813.29! 22,067.32 1 1,560 7,173.'70 UUff Burt ! 17,487.88 j 16,667.88 440 W 180 (Agr. Coll.) 640 640 Sutler 21,687.10 1 21.161.90 C-M 19,733.98 I 19,513.98 Cedar | 26.964.36 25,885.36 (Univ.) — 1,920 1,520 (Arr. Coll.) \ 25,405.47 23.837.56 Chase 33,280 1,585.48 Cherry 245,169.21 2,701.23 Cheyenne 43,840 853 CUy 21.240 20.580 Colfax 14,459.69 I 14.078.26 Cuming | 19.044.70 | 18.924.70 (Agr. Coll.) 960 960 Custer 91.017.98 20,093 Dakota, 7,163.19 5,768.81 818.05 510.83 (Univ.) ...... 320 320 (Agr. Coll.) 640 603.92 36.08 1.400 7.451.60 1,038 Dawes 49,280 892.43 46,987.57 Dawson 36,105.15 1 20,945 7.683.55 25 14.692.50 43.12 744.40 54 Deuel 16.800.70 1.027.08 Dixon 15,931.20! 14,722.80 410 (Univ.) I 640 640 (AgT. Coll.) ! 2.240 2,187.77 40 12.23 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS 13 TABLE SHOWING FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS, NOVEMBER 30, 1920— (Continued) Total Acres Total Acres COl'XTY i Total Acres i Total Acres I'mler Sale I'nder Lease i I'n- Acquired Denied Contract Contract classified 18.558.58 18,467.72 90.86 I 9,160.23 8,918.69 40 62 139.5 Dodge | 18,558.58 18,467.72 i 90.86 I Douglas 9,160.23 8,918.69 4&lt;i n 139.54 33,257.01! 772.56 240 32,244.45 Dundy I 33,257.01 772.561 240 32,244.45 Fillmore 20,648.51 20,648.51 20.488.51 160 ' 20,488.51 160 ' Franklin 20,471.85 20,471.85 ! 10,211.73 3.693.76 6,566.36 10,211.73 3.693.76 6,566.36 Frontier ! 34.560 34,560 7,478.50 5,280 21.798 3.51 7,478.50 5,280 21.798 3.50 Furnas I 25,602.80 25.602.80 '• 10,732.42 4.150.78 10.719.60 4,150.78 10.719.60 Gage 24.637.31 24.637.31 24,422.81 214.50 214.50 20,480 1,281.58 720 18.478.42 20 Garfleld 20,480 Garden 63.926.61 63.926.61 1,821.43 3.771.39 58.329.10 4.6! 4.69 Gosper 16.640 16.640 11,522 2,998 2,120 11.522 2. 9HS 2,120 30.845.68 3.805.68 911.46 26.120 8.5 911.46 26.120 Grant ' 30,845.68 3.805.68 8.54 20,475.30 | 12,035.30 2,440 6.000 12,035.30 2,440 S.000 Greeley | 20,475.30 Hall 19.507.71 19.507.71 16.808.25 213.25 2,486.21 16.808.25 213.25 2,486.21 Hamilton I 20.487.56 20.487.56 20.480 7.56 20.480 7.56 20.400.69 12.699.86 3.116.91 4,555.42 28.51 Harlan 20.400.69 12.699.86 3.116.91 4,555.42 28.50 Hayes I 25.920 25.920 753.31 1,584.59 23.582.10 Hitchcock .... 25.494.87 25.494.87 1,729.22 51 23.714.65 II Holt 87.536.60 87.536.60 7,852.02 6.960 72.724.58 6.960 (Univ.) ! 8,322.10 8,322.10 2,880 1,522.10 3.920 2,880 1,522.10 3,920 Hooker 26,127.53 26,127.53 120 26,007.53 120 26,007.53 Howard 23,041.44 23.041.44 15.733 2.161.89 5.141.52 5.0: 15.733 5.03 13,440 13.076.67 363.33 363.33 Johnson 13,440 Jefferson i 20,484.08 20,484.08 17.887.93 1.667 929.15 1.667 Kearney ! 18,581.40 18,581.40 14,360 880 3.341.40 _ 14,360 880 45,662.90 2,357.10 5,018.64 38,204.64 82.5: 82.52 Keith ! 45,662.90 Keya Paha.... I 26,382.46 26.382.46 910.85 1,160 24.311.61 910.85 1.160 36.618.88 699.22 640 35.255.54 24.1 35,255.54 24.12 Kimball 36.618.88 699.22 640 Knox 42,893.81 42.893.81 25,230.62 5.187.66 12,475.53 25,230.62 5.187.66 12,475.53 (Univ.) 4,480 4,480 3,440 200 840 840 (Agr. Coll.) 33.491.20 33.491.20 28,921.47 , 4,170.73 399 399 31,236.84 29,790.37 i 680 764.45 2.0 Lancaster 31,236.84 764.45 2.02 30,775.22 1,331.16 673.64 9.42 (Saline) .... i 32,789.44 (Normal).... | 12,804.80 12,724.80 80 Lincoln I 97,892.89 14,924.99 10.497.50 72.370.20 100.20 614.89 2.505.11 17,360 Logan 20,480 Loup 20.393.28 930.65 818.30 18,644.33 320 2 SOO Madison 24,639.43 22.119.43 (Univ.) 2,240 1,600 480 160 McPherson .... j 31,092.63 840 30,252.63 Merrick I 14,976.21 11,846.62 520 2,609.59 46,872.80 3.06 Morrill 62,677.58 4.623.46 11,178.26 11,493.49 40 323.05 85.80 Nemaha 11,942.34 Nuckolls 21,049.10 20,089.10 520 440 1.023.42 117.10 (Univ.) 4,881.68 3,741.16 21.412.44 320 260 Otoe I 21,992.44 80 Pawnee i 20,034.85 19,754.85 200 65.13 160 31.298.62 Perkins 31,523.75 16,308.60 2,280 1,640 Phelps | 20,228.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">t LAND COMMISSION s'ERS REP( &gt;RT TABLE SHO /ING FACTS RELATIV ANDS, NOVEMBER 30, VE TO ST i, 1920— (Coi tn EDU itinued) ATIONAL COUNTY Total Acre* Acquired Total Acres Deeded Total Acre* Under Sale Contract Total Acres Under Lease Contract fn- classifled (Univ.) ...... (Agr. Coll.) Red Willow.. Richardson .... Saunders Scott* Bluff.. Sheridan Sherman Washington .. Wayne (Agr. Coll.) Webster (Univ.) 20,480 3.197.67 10,114.56 23.655.48 16.787.68 25.485.30 10.400 40.232.40 20.480 8,988.27 26,314.29 25.467.65 20.560 94.472.07 20.477.20 80,972.22 15,360 20,472.35 25.600 20.453.62 13.849.86 15,360 15.648.98 20.480 17.803.48 20,480 20,480 13.800 2.798.31 9,194.56 22.486.38 15,705.68 8.139.50 9,510 2.280 20.360 8.624.39 25.914.29 6.458.34 20,440 3.092.87 10,807.72 530.40 13.960 18,374.35 9.30 14,712.09 12,090.26 15,000 15.638.64 17,913.87 14,970.33 923 19,526.61 1,200 399.36 400 80 160 4,739 320 3,240 5,480 520 1,089.10 922 12,606.80 570 34,712.40 120 284.88 40 10,854.56 80 88,094.20 6.350.52 78,092.22 360 418 25,590.70 2,290.88 780.30 79 360 8,148.75 40 3.285 3,318.96 2.349.60 1.040 1,680 6 3.450.65 882.40 360 96.au 2,120 1,512.34 2,000 80 440 1,320.81 17.557 873.39 10.34 6.13 Totals .... 2,977,767.30 1,185.324.70 196,049.69 1,594,920.67 1,472.24 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE STATES SCHOOL LAND 15 THE STATE'S SCHOOL FUND The temporary school fund is derived from the following sources: Interest on permanent school funds, rentals on lands under lease, interest on balance due on lands sold, bonus received as premium to secure lease contracts, interest on delinquent rental and interest and money received for licenses, fines, fees, etc. This temporary school fund is apportioned twice a year to the different counties in the state for the support of the public schools. The permanent school fund is derived from the sale of educational lands, escheated lands, and 5% of the purchase price of government lands sold within the state. This fund is invested in interest-bearing bonds in amounts at present as follows: Appended to this report will be found tables showing the acquisition and disposal of the educational lands of the state, and the work accom - plished in this department for the two-year period. I have also attached hereto the rules and regulations now governing the lease of educational lands which may be of interest to prospective lessees. A table of the fees charged in this department is also shown. Very respectfully. DAN SWANSON. Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. Common School * 1 iv,iua,votj.ou f 1U,1VJ|VUU.OU Agricultural College Endowment... 633,236.18 633.236.18 Jniversity - formal Endowment 261,533.40 261,533.40 81,900.00 81,900.00 3essey Endowment 5,485.00 5,485.00 Total $11,151,220.44 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 LAiSD L. (J AI Al i bol O^ lliFV b filial UKT ■ ! I 5 axaNX t* tc x t* n ic e* o t^ t-_ te «" i-i ' © cm" onxnn : ; : ; | I I * **J ! i ilisi I i i s as t- V w te ci S cn&lt;-« ~- ,_ •*« © tn t- m ION Xr- Ng&gt; AtCO riu*^ iciccn w t- n t- x •&gt;»■ m © m ■» w iexi-,e * VlOlOH kOuH r-i 00 00 nil nil iii I I I I : • i i : i i ft ft | I II I IS 13 I nil Isisi Sii ocutos octcdC o be US&lt;co w &lt; a: £ w -r. cZ i I ! VHAM3 NMr-^O co l~ ce V o t^^'Oo^^' li: M U3 » N O V DC O O^-^-C» tt V r^ t&lt; K t- ri «&lt;f OOnn o i • ill I I I I I m : : : : i I I I I I V I I* I I 1 : : : : : ■*• ; : : « i I ! ! i ! H I I I I 1 : : : : : I • I ■ fell I I M&gt; I I IT I I &lt;v : ■ ~* ! • t • S f ' "o : "3 : : "5 i "o i i 5 ! W ! I I I • I «&gt;,£ i « g i C — p i ' c — 2 : ' iiiii ills i o 5 Lc73 c c c bi ce c i i fi t- -r I T | ■ c CO ■I. I "~ o &gt;&gt; J I y. C ■ a * </seg>
            <seg id="p017">WORK OF THE BIENNIUM 17 Si BD S o : in h : : : : : : x » : I ) { »s :mx» :O"ror&gt; :m : : : :»^s» : :©» :w Hm I f-i : : : *i : f-i ::: ::om:::;;:o:; : II ; : x eo I I I I I j co;: ; ;; o I I ioo I iaOH i i i i i :o«© : :eo ios i io SI I so eo I j o m juooq; ':**■ ; : : : itj : : : t— : «-o ■« • i • • ® : £* ©o : :o : © © © : i-* © © © © :© :© :©«©©«© :© •O &lt;*■ e* : :w : &lt;© &lt;© :ooooo-*« : ■*• :© : cj -v &lt;e « c© :oo cj r-» : : co : o&gt; os : co n •*&gt; : e* : : *-» t- t&gt;; cm : &lt;J Z rH ! CO * •* U3 t- X N t* t* h C O L! C « C f C » - N ft M f 1 5: M j *• "^^ 1^5 OO t^* 0^ t^5 j QO P^ ■ Li!^ t- t-^^* n f Hri C^tA ; L_ oo iooooo^oooooo :oooo :O'»-om^ :o oq :&lt;= ?°. °. c :^ c^'^ l^^ l&gt; ! c i &lt;=s . i'-?^ 0^ : *-^ "? °. °i :°. SS „" ixih ;oufioiootTVSct- :w--'»' :&lt;CNAie« :« ■!? — ■ I r- © : K a n &lt;e « r- M si a oc b- a : co to aq :n«(- s m« : eo gfl &lt;i n°« i ■■* eo O3 ei «c i-T ci V «Ht&gt; : pi ei pi V eo i £5 3 j j I I UJ Z Z LJ m 2V - - — a &lt; * BOS © C — — * ■»^' :iemi:r-Nnr-iex5ii:r-8i5Nj)»x?! ; via :» taw ioid^v^niav^nrinvxuivhdd : x ri \ ei 30-^* :Mior4?ot^ot-Of-t!0 t~ » urn h N m :»?o :^^ m ia : i-iiieoeoi-i m»i-i :o :i-i Ul I -f o : :r-eoacMr--&lt;rcoQ&gt; coo f xn ;c*3O3^r«0u3 ;ia HH* co m* cs m wt •• I io I »J U. o a: o ■ 0 oe&gt;0'«&lt;ocoao'vt-'4-'V9VOiao&gt;accoooooao«c ;«e (caqiaor-M^ooqooiflqb-wioaifiocct-NaN : co tA n m in* t* n n a o t- « '^ « 1-1 n oe M a rn -f r* : ei 55 E o o !!!:!!!: i : i i !:!: i !!: Mi ! 4 ! !^ ! ! ! is i J I i I ! ; Qi ■ : ' * h I ' I * I I hi • • 53 ■ • • ■ * illlsss s jHjsJsg|st Infill | &lt;&lt; &lt;kbb eonncBou uuooouufl 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT ! : I I I I I I : : - ■ - :::■♦: » : » : : : » : is! :=&gt;oo:oc:oo-r:»o: [• I : : » : i : : : : » » d :wo :*»s : s m : : : x : :pirtH :h« :h : to m : : : : : : :::::: : : _c : : : : : : *° I I I I I I I I ! ! ! I I I I I I I I I I • I © ao : ; . 11 o : :o :oo© : o us © io o : :oo ;© : Io m : : : : : : i-h : oo ■»■ to itknnx : :n« ;■* : le* « : an :»io(t&lt;» i ;«« :• : |h I I I I I I I i i i III I io : : o : «o ■* e m :co oo © . . . os oj : . t- : c ps us n :&lt;* to oo: et-e ■ :&lt;b iddnerie :t^oio©io loo loo Io « ps m t :t- : h x n xm :nxxor- :oooo : -^ oo :«o nMd : r- y m h : us « x m »o : ■* : oo [ 1-4 j I co x — :oo&gt;CNt&gt;uit-x«not&lt;u3nNaao«ieuinui t-Nt&gt; :aMKTSN«e«N«ir-o«naHus«»VHi(i usoo :««ffixxfiic«ctoniflffiXO'-i-v--oc!axt- ut XX j flH tClflf^^NwftlflOOOin O O -&lt;f M X OS A t-" o as i t^ n m* ui t- c v n d n' o n &lt;c ta n V » NH CQlO^"^e0fie0i-l!-l!-ir-U3 N i 18.8 ft.* 1 O ot-n i : :o :o — tooooaeoceoo :oo :oo :o qtOH : :o loocqcoocsio — oci ;oo — — j o ciiex : i i i-&gt; icicusacowxcecn :•■ I o • iao u3hh : : : oo lOoscMKccricKC : t ir: :mv i ih t-_ « [ «c : : h io «&gt; is » i- « i" M « M : ""I *". I * * • "^ -V«e-Vi us w ia* us os «' « «' : ic r- t^ t v« — — — ci : ih i f-i 2 V III tnx :© :lO^st-^^^J!C^c-»w^-^o&gt;-lp-^^^0^5lflr"^5'r »rJ S I r-i :Nlfi»lSaON39iNN3iN ' 00 N t-^ » O IO »&gt;ot~ : :»9 os»x&gt; x*mnioa&gt; usnexxsis M rH fH t- IO i-l m IH i-HONNMi-CN to •*• o :oo : o o »— weaooejoiwocj : *-i o&gt; o us o o o hOn JON ;«-»tCr-tCC'-WXQCC» jNICVNM NO oe «c ui Inis ios^ei^moosNrJW^ia i &lt;e ri t- oi to t- ■» os O! «D :«n :exMt-t-c»t-f knk :ic««cnae f-&lt; e» o&gt; ; rn : m cr--»»«icri-.T : io c&gt; © ri_ m c 5 eo us o&gt; : : :en :eMO*N»»ox««»»io»»0" octfiia &gt; j jo-* j^Ni-aeNngoN^tt^e^n^nh; MNr. : : too :teootciaiat-nxn t- a o ci t- f- x M«'V i t^ i OS © « i-i OS N V CO P3 t-~ I-* PJ IO t-" N* ■«■" t-" 1 1 Mj | J i 1 1 J 1 1 ( J 1 1 1 i i ' M J j [iiIhitiftlillhiJilElJIii </seg>
            <seg id="p019">WORK OF THE BIEXNUM 19 si ■ tl — 9:: :: : : so *a :::::::: i :©»&lt;■»•* i is : isec i iriais i : : so &gt;•&gt; »r » so : :sm i '*-*m : :ir3»^" : : ; : cj w m i-i ■— : ; : ei n m ; : q e« ; • i-t j I M •• to j I * OT j ii tiii i i I I I I i I i I i i Tt^ ; : : : : i : :© :::::::: : oo I I I • I I I ! ! — r z - i I ! ! :oo ~ : 1*4 : : :on«qo : : : : :toto :ao : -r i *4 : : ■ : : r-i-uie : : : ; :mh : :m ;io : i i I j : ; i j ; : j ! ! ! j I I ! ! •o c 1 I Si I ; : ; N CO oo : : : us : . &lt;e ioo io :oeoonou)N io i :o« :e&gt; :©o :oo&gt; :«ooo :m :«CMO-»co-r^-«&gt; ;oo : :m« :«&gt; :t~oo :ooeo :n« :h :ian» nnnn : :un ;h :h ;nw ©4 r* ; I : o I N t- N V CO p- W M &lt;C W « 00 N IO O W H r&lt; N O «C t^ O » 30 ft OC W 1 US N C4 t&gt;* Ol UJ O* U) U3 N 01 H i-*' QO* O V H U) N N V *-^ N ci l£3 »— OO i is.! *£ a j iooooooooocoo-^co :o :ooo :© :oo :oo :oocooooooomou5&lt;d :o :oot^ ;o :uso .o© ■xoinxNtCMCifiXNc'n :©" iooooo iod :ci© :ci^ :o»M^naosOr-io^voo :^« : x oo ta :c&gt; :^-«o :■*•*■» ■ t«T H i-J V N OS i-' W ri t»" « I 94 \ r* V ©' •&lt; ! «^ ! * (• ■a -a - - — 00 &lt; CV so eo riH ; m to mm : US o :usia«ou;o«nM looi-itcoooioNOOMMtoooo to !iaiae«io&gt;&gt;HNa :eauit-xieocM o » i» n n » a N jrtiSH 1 t-' locin Inn to 1-4 co n g &lt;00&gt;i-lN&gt;-ie&lt;50»O©N^"O©MeCOOU5O0300ON©«0'«»'OO h;«&gt;nr&lt;ICnNN«eiI)O^II&gt;nieM«TK*OrlOOatliNIO lOMfii-iOr-'mMOt-^N^MOOrti-iooVMNOCttNmrJNJ- W t* » H H W O) O» M OO t» CO « b- OS N » IO » IO » H t* * Ifl US r- N ri G4 H &lt;D M h-' ri r4 CO H rt « 00 H N «O t-^ N t-1 U5 CO OC r-l f-l r-l z B o u 1 1 1 1 j 1 1 ii j 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 i 1 1 1 1 1 i 1 1 lltlliSI *"* liillllllflili : : : : _; • ; • i : : : : i i : i i i IJ I e A l I I I I I ii If el sitlilt i tii^iiHi s fii </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT i i it 1 111 ! I I 11111 ! ! 9 i a i \% |t| ; is i Is ! H I |N I I I I I 1 ": i i i I I i ! I I I ! ! I ! 30 06 a -a ;©; ioloioi loo: lo! :&gt;-i: : o : &lt;c : ■* : :»■«■! :«: i^ ;e« irt j j • ; ; ; ; j : • • • • • ill ill • s U3 ~- Cl c I ii n a&gt; o : : : :oooooo :ooooooirioooo :o : ioo^o : oc m ec x :«aoaivMnt^on :c^ : :&lt;cco«c "«(• T ; os&lt;-icsc*M&lt;e ;^&lt; 1 : o- c^ -^ „ wf I M r4 1-1 i i-J : • : ill CO °i iri 00 cm" ■♦ ancffi*ftN^M0)O«owNxt^v«aiflu;v(0M'r HHCeCtDOlNXt-MNOt-HteiONOsat^n^^rvO (Offl^oCfDoot-t^Miootciflojfct-^'ainooir.Noiwft »-" o&gt; o o n a&gt; 00 a&gt; n cj o »- eo o m «r-ai«F-Ni-cin9i Hto vioifl c4 r- t ia n si * V oa la •— ■ 00 c£ 00 us 00 10 ■ ■I •» l_ ■ 000000 : o o © o .1 r- o o O o o o :ooo© ;oooooo :sohoisn«okno9 : o © o e !22 O0 ° o0&lt; ' :«6io«i^»'»ei ; io«6 iao'tboo" ;■♦■•» 10 »-— ; :«Neionr-»N^F-Bx :hnoS Nna°Nr&lt; • ec o* c&gt; o* « &lt;e t-' 1— ' m ! •» ei e« « 1-1 .1 N N e* 1-1 : 11 1-1 f— 1 CO ■ ■ 2 v - - - Ml Q B - nn *»iot-H !-!■* lio^'rojo^-r^oo-*' :oc-30*o pi £g 5 000000010 iiooaoiOfHox :ooococenc »«|NCt-e» :*x--o»«iioinr- :k»SS&lt;i&gt;vx "SS'ISSSiS™ it-mioioiOi-i^rtM ! n us ui 0 n o h r-100 : c: 03 r- 9) V O 30 C : !C Ol N M L- o: r- » «h ■■ I A rt'VlOrtM i*N W P4 n" V9 o ci CO (O si iSSS 0 ." 500 '"" 1000 '' 0 ©"'©*©©'*^ 1 '* : © o» t- e* :iCC»*»XOQIlC^Ch;«)M0tN0llOU! : o 00 O «5 : *" *. 1 ". N . ". * * ri*r-ia*»oo»Mec : ic *■ i-« tn ««»«» V &lt;e «e n hhnn : 1-1 o» «c o 00 10 r- •- t c I I I I I I I I j j I I I I I I } I I I I I i f I i~ i ii 1 i I I I I I j I I I I I I j j ij ll 1 1 I I HI! hi!!! 1 - £. — — — K V. V. 'S. &lt;S. X V. « CC X E- E- &gt; g£ &gt; &gt;&gt; m </seg>
            <seg id="p021">LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS 21 RULES AND REGULATIONS PERTAINING TO THE LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS The following paragraphs are intended to answer a majority of the inquiries made by lessees and purchasers of Educational Lands as ■well as many questions asked by county treasurers. The state seldom has any unleased lands, and then only at or about the time auctions are held as described hereafter. These auctions occur generally but once each year at the offices of the various county treasurers. LEASE CONTRACTS The Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings may at least once in each year designate a day and hour for offering in a public manner, at the office of the county treasurer in the respective counties, lease con - tracts on all of the educational lands, which may be subject to lease in that county at the time of such offering. The same shall be subject to lease at an annual rental of six (6) per cent on the appraised value. Provided, that if two or more parties desire to lease the same land, the officer having control of the auction shall lease to the person who will pay the greater amount of cash bonus in addition to six (6) per cent on the appraised value as annual rental. Lease rentals are due in two installments, January 1 and July 1 of each year. If not paid within six months after due, the lease holders are declared delinquent and notice is sent them if their postoffice addresses are known; if unknown, advertisement is made in a newspaper. Ninety ilays after date of such notice lease contracts are declared forfeited and are subject to auction thereafter. (See Fees.) Delinquent lease holders are not permitted to bid at the sale of the lands they have forfeited, but at any time before the land is actually put on the auction block they may reinstate their leases by paying all back rentals and penalty fees. (See Fees.) All school lands under lease are subject to appraisement every Hve (5) years, if the Board of Educational Lands and Funds so elects. The holders of lease contracts executed prior to July 9, 1897, are given the right, at the expiration of said contracts, to make application for and receive new lease contracts upon said lands, and they will not be required to compete for the contracts, and the rate of rental will be the same as stipulated in the old contract; Provided, that all of the rental due on the old contracts has been paid. Leases dated on July 9, 1897, and after (at the expiration of twenty - five years from the first of January next following date of lease) are not subject to renewal excepting upon the terms and conditions pertaining to new leases. Lessee may surrender the premises or re-lease them under ordinary competitive conditions, he being entitled only to the movable improvements on the land. Owners of school land lease contracts made subsequent to July 9. 1897, shall have a chance to renew their lease if their bid is as high as </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT any other. If another bids higher than the lease owner, he gets the lease; the former lessee will be paid the appraised value of his improve - ments thereon. The appraisement shall be made by the County Com - missioners within thirty days after the acceptance of bid. LThe amount of school land authorized to be leased, direct or by wal, to one person is limited to 640 acres. SALE CONTRACTS A lease holder whose lease may be converted to a sale, desiring to purchase the lands described in his lease, should apply to the county clerk in the county in which the land is located, to have same appraised by the county board for the purpose of sale. Such appraisement shall te subject to review and approval by the Board of Educational Land? and Funds, before the same shall become effective. Upon the sale of any lands on which full payment is not made the Commissioner of Public and Buildings will issue a sale contract running for a term of wenty (20) years, showing the land purchased, the amount paid, the mount due and the time when the interest and principal are due, and n the payment of such amount, according to law, the purchaser or his assignee shall be entitled to a deed to such land. The contract holder has the privilege of making payments on the principal at any time and in any amounts, which should be done just on or before January 1, thus reducing the interest for the ensuing year. The owner of a sale contract may, at any time, pay any portion of the purchase price thereof to the treasurer of the county in which the and is situated; Provided, all interest at that time earned and due has rst been paid; and when the principal is paid in full, other than at the rst of the year, interest upon the obligation having been paid for the ntire year, the county treasurer receiving such principal payments may refund to the payor, out of any interest money then in his hands, the interest so paid in advance in excess of the amount earned and due at le time said final payment is made. Refund receipts are furnished by the Land Commissioner for this purpose. All unpaid principal on sale contracts draws interest at five (5) per cent per annum, payable annually on January first of each year, in advance. Sale contract holders making final payment to county treasurei should also surrender their contracts, that same may be forwarded to Land Commissioner with receipt showing the full payment. NOTES The Board of Educational Lands and Funds meets on the second Tuesday of each month. No assignment of a school land lease or Bale contract is valid until recorded in the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build - ing i, and will not be recorded if any interest or rental is due at the tln-.e said assignment is offered for record. The original sale or lease contract must be sent in with the assignments or the latter will not be </seg>
            <seg id="p023">LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS 23 recnrded. The contract will be returned with the recorded assignments. When a subdivision of not less than forty acres in any contract is assigned, a new number is given the assigned portion on the ledger account, and a certified copy of the original should be given to the assignee. When assignments are made as above, the original contrar' must be reduced and the interest or rentals as the case may be &lt;s adji iited to the new conditions. Whenever a lease or sale contract becomes lost or destroyed, a certified copy of the same may be procured by filing an affidavit of lost contract. Such copies may be used in lieu of the original for the pur pose of passing title. When interest on a sale contract or rental on a lease contract is no paid when due, county treasurers will collect "penalty" interest at 7 per cent for the time purchaser or lessee has been tardy in making such payments. Improvements on leased land, and the owner's equity in land under sale contract are subject to taxation. County treasurers are requested to send in school land receipts at least once each week. Sometimes tardiness in this particular leads to considerable unnecessary correspondence and occasionally to delin- quencies being charged against contract holders who are not in arrears. but whose receipts have not been sent in to the Land Commissioner's office. Lands escheating to the state under the alien act are appraised and leased in tne same manner as educational lands. If lessee shall be in default of rentals for six months, or if purchaser shall be in default of interest for one year, county treasurers shall collect delinquent notice fee as set forth in table of fees under heading of "For Notice of Forfeiture." FEES For the issuance of a lease or sale contract, each 40 acres J0.50 For recording assignments, for each contract assigned 50 For recording affidavit of lost contract 50 For certified copy of a contract - 75 For recording any instrument, each 100 words 10 For notice of forfeiture of lease or sale contract 50 For reinstatement 50 For recording order of forfeiture, where redemption is made before auction, for each tract of 40 acres or less 50 Where publication in newspaper is required in lieu of ordinary de - linquent notice, the actual cost of such publication is charged where redemption is made. For copies of maps or plats, each hour's work 40 NOTE— Fees payable to the state should be remitted by draft or money order payable to State Treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING Robert Harvey, State Surveyor and Draughtsman The duties of the State Surveyor and Draughtsman were defined by he Statutes of 1903. which placed in his charge, under the supervision f the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, the field notes, aps, and records of the United States surveys, conduct the corre - pondence relating to surveys, grievances or disputes growing out of conflicting surveys of lands or lots, to prepare the advice, instructions nd opinions, and issue same under the approval of the Commissioner; nd to issue a circular of instructions to County Surveyors of the state or their direction and guidance, in the restoration and establishment of nes and preservation of corners in conformity with the laws, rules and egulations governing the surveys of the United States and established rules of surveying, and perform such other duties as the Commissioner ay require; and in the case of any disputes among land owners arising r by reason of any survey of boundaries of lands within this state, or,, case of dispute or disagreement between surveyors as to the survey f boundaries, when petitioned for, shall be referred to the State Sur - eyor, who is made the arbitrator to determine and settle such disputes y making the necessary examinations and surveys to settle the same. nd whose decision shall be prima facie evidence of the correctness ereof. The law provides for an appeal to the courts from the decision of the State Surveyor in making such surveys, by any person having an interest in the lands affected by the survey. The law also provides for the appointment of deputy state surveyors who are competent and experienced land surveyors. Field notes and maps of surveys made by the State Surveyor or deputies are to be reported to the Commissioner and if approved by him. they become a part of the records of his office and a certified copy thereof is sent to the County Surveyor of the county where the survey was had, to be recorded in his office. The per diem and other expenses of the survey is to be paid by the parties directly Interested in the survey, and when made by the State Surveyor there shall be paid to the State Treasurer the sum of $8.00 for each day of actual service performed; but when made by a deputy he is entitled to receive the sum of $8.00 for each day's service and his neces - sary expenses. Eight dollars per day is the statutory charge for field Correspondence relating to surveys is constantly increasing and daring the biennium 2.246 letters have been written, besides information given in a large number of telegraph and telephone messages and personal calls from county and private surveyors and land owners. The second issue of the circular of instructions to County Surveyors published in 1914 Is nearly exhausted and the increasing demand for </seg>
            <seg id="p025">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 25 copies is an indication of the favor in which it is regarded. In a few months the third edition will be called for and the issue should be large enough to not only supply surveyors and engineers who are' frequently called upon to make land surveys, but every judge and lawyer in the state. Lawyers are often consulted by land owners as to their rights in disputed surveys, and it is the experience of this office that very many are sadly deficient in accurate knowledge of the laws and rules govern - ing land surveys and especially of resurveys. It has been of valuable assistance to many attorneys of the state who have secured copies and studied their contents. What we have said in previous reports regarding surveys made by private surveyors and "locators" and by many County Surveyors who have not thought enough of their surveys to record them, is being con - stantly exemplified in the range country as to their pernicious effects in provoking and encouraging disputes among the land owners, and especially between the early settlers and those of later years, who allege that the early settlers selected the more desirable lands and either ignored or destroyed the original corners and hired their own surveyors or "locators" to run lines and make corners in imitation of the original to fit their holdings, which they now claim to be the corners of the Government surveys. In territory where the Government surveys were poorly executed and so poorly monumented that in a very few years they became so nearly obliterated and dim as to be no longer recogniz - able, locators ran lines from distant initial points or known corners and made corners in imitation of the original without regard for accuracy or intention to commit fraud. These lines generally inclose more land than the sections are entitled to, thus causing excessive deficiencies in the neighboring sections, causing great dissatisfaction. Now when attempts are made to search out and identify the original surveys or to restore the lost and obliterated corners by pro-rata measurements, sur - veyors are confronted with the claim that these "locators" corners are those of the Government survey, although very plain to the experienced surveyor in this line of work that they manifestly lack the ear marks of the original corners. In making surveys by this office every effort is made to find the original corners and when that cannot be done, then to relocate them by the best evidence that can be obtained as to their former location, and ill the absence of better proof to pro-rate the measurements, according to the Government survey between the nearest known corners. The Government is still engaged in making resurveys of townships in the western part of the state and during the biennium has not com pleted any work. During the biennium, there have been received from the General I^and Office at Washington, D. C, the following records of resurveys. to-wit: </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Resurveys — Exterior lines of Township 28 N. Range 14 W. Township 20 N. Range 19 W. ■ Township 20 N. Range 11 W. Township 25 N. Range 21 W. Township 26 N. Range 21 W. Township 27 N. Range 21 W. Township 28 N. Range 21 W. Township 25 N. Range 22 W. Township 26 N. Range 22 W. I Township 27 N. Range 22 W. Township 28 N. Range 22 W. Township 25 N. Range 23 W. Township 26 N. Range 23 W. Township 27 N. Range 23 W. Township 28 N. Range 23 W. Township 25 N. Range 24 W. Township 26 N. Range 24 W. Township 27 N. Range 24 W. Township 28 N. Range 24 W. ■ Township 25 N. Range 25 W. Township 26 N. Range 25 W. Township 27 N. Range 25 W. Township 28 N. Range 25 W. t Township 18 N. Range 26 W. Township 19 N. Range 26 W. Township 20 N. Range 26 W. Township 18 N. Range 27 W. Township 19 N. Range 27 W. Township 20 N. Range 27 W. Township 18 N. Range 28 W. Township 19 N. Range 28 W. Township 20 N. Range 28 W. Township 18 N. Range 29 W. Township 19 N. Range 29 W. ► Township 20 N. Range 29 W. Township 21 N. Range 43 W. Township 27 N. Range 33 W. Township 25 N. Range 44 W. Township 20 N. Range 48 W. Resurveys — Subdivisions Township 28 N. Range 14 W. Township 20 N. Range 25 W. L Township 27 N. Range 33 W. Township 29 N. Range 37 W. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 27 Township 21 N. Range 43 W. Township 23 N. Range 43 W. Township 25 N. Range 44 W. Township 29 N. Range 48 W. Townships 25, 26, 27, 28 N. Range 17 W. Townships 25, 26, 27, 28 N. Range 18 W Townships 25, 26, 27, 28 N. Range 19 W. Townships 25, 26. 27, 28 N. Range 20 W. 7th Standard Parallel N. through Ranges 13, 14, 21, 22, 23.24 3rd Guide Meridian W. through Townships 19 and 20 N. Survey of Tract No. 39 in Sections 6 and 1. T. 21 N., Sees 31 and 36, T. 22 N. Rs. 35 and 36 W. Survey of Ash Island in Sec. 2, T. 16 N. R. 1 E. Re-establishment of a portion of the original surveys in Tps. 32 and 33 N. R. 7 W. and extension survey in Tps. 32 and 33 N. R. 7 W. MAPS Resurveys — Township 28 N. Range 14 W. Township 21 N. Range 21 W. Township 22 N. Range 21 W. Township 23 N. Range 21 W. Township 24 N. Range 21 W. Township 21 N. Range 22 W. Township 20 N. Range 25 W. Township 27 N. Range 33 W. Township 29 N. Range 37 W. Township 26 N. Range 44 W. Township 20 N. Range 48 W. Tract No. 39 in Sees. 6 and 1, T. 21 N. and Sees. 31 and 36 T. 22 N. Rs. 35 and 36 W. Survey of Ash Island in Sec. 2, T. 16 N. R. 1 E. Copy of original map of T. 25 N. R. 5 E. Supplemental Plat of Sec. 7, T. 25 N. R. 7 E. showing sub division of Lot 6. Indian Allotment .No. 582. Supplemental Plat of Sec. 3, T. 25 N. R. 9 E. showing sub division of Indian Allotment No. 599 — Solomon Grant. Supplemental Plat of Sec. 15, T. 1 N. R. 17 E. showing Kickapoo Indian Allotment No. 96 — John Lasley. Supplemental Plat of Sec. 9, T. 24 N. R. 39 W. segregating and showing designation and legal area made fractional by claims of H. C. Damaree and Wm. Buffington. INDEXING GOVERNMENT SURVEYS The indexing of the original maps of Government surveys is -com - pleted and nearly all of the original field notes. There remains the </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT ndexing of the field notes of what is known as the "Alt" and "Dixon" Resurveys in Grant and Hitchcock counties, T. 30 N. R. 32 W., Ts. 21, 2 and 23 N. R. 47 W. and T. 8 N. R. 29 and 30 W. There is a large accumulation of field notes and maps of resurveys made since 1907 that re not classified and arranged for binding which cannot be done until he Government has completed its work of resurveys which is expected within the next biennium. GOVERNMENT LAND GRANTS The special grants of public lands to the state were for Agricultural College, Internal Improvements, Public Buildings, Saline and University, n the last report I told of this office having been called upon by the Government to furnish a statement of the number of acres the state tad donated to railroad corporations. In compiling the statement many iscrepancies were discovered; deeds were issued upon the basis of the sts of lands selected by the Governor before some of the lists had been approved by the Secretary of the Interior Department, which de - cribed thousands of acres which were never approved by the Secretary, consequently the state never had title. The disposal of the Public Lands according to the plats of survey. The areas of tracts in the Govern - ent Clear Lists very often described a lesser or greater acreage than hat of the plats. The state deeds made jnany like errors. These deeds re on record in this office and are intended to be copies of the original eeds issued, but there were found incorrect descriptions, duplications and omissions as shown by comparison with the Government Clear Lists and the original deeds temporarily loaned us by railroad companies, and correspondence with County Clerks and Registers of Deeds. Some of the ompanies have lost their deeds, claiming they have been destroyed. The work of discovering and correcting any errors in the statement furnished the Government has been conducted to the present time and from the best obtainable data, 501,154.60 acres of the Internal Improve - ment lands have been conveyed, leaving 160 acres which were trans - ferred to the Common School by Legislative enactment approved February 20, 1883. AID BY COLORED PLAT8 The work of coloring all tracts of special grants to the state has been completed and the number of acres granted according to the plats of survey written into each tract, and in the grant for Internal Improve - ments the area of the tracts according to the plats of survey is written as the amount granted by the Government and conveyed by the state. The independent checking of these plats agrees with the present findings of the total amount conveyed. These colored plats number about 250 and altogether make a volume of 268 pages which has just been re - ceived from the bindery. During the progress of the work of coloring the tracts of the grant of twenty sections or 12,751.05 acres for public buildings for Legislative and Judicial purposes the T^Wtt of Section 2, </seg>
            <seg id="p029">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 29 T. 9 N. R. 8 E. was described as containing 318.87 acres instead of 158.87 acres. The tract was sold to W. P. Enry, July 13, 1871, for |3.55 per acre but the deed included the SW&gt;4 also and the sale amounted to $1,120.00. The records of the U. S. Land Office show that the entire W% of the section belonged to the state by virtue of the grant. The approved Clear List of the grant on file in this office shows that only the NW% was granted. A certified photographic copy of the state's selection of lands in the Nebraska City land office was procured from the General Land Office which showed that the NW&gt;4 and SW*4 were selected and certified by the Register of the Land Office as subject to selection. A certified photographic copy of the original Clear List approved February 17, 1870, was then procured from the General Land Office showing that only the NW^i was approved by the Secretary of the Interior. A letter was then addressed to the Commissioner of the General Land Office inquiring if the Government had patented the SWVA. to whom and date, and on the 11th of last month a reply was received that the state had selected the SWV4 of Section 2, December 27. 1867. but that in making up the Clear List February 17, 1870. the NW*4 had been described as containing 318.87 acres, inadvertently omitting the SWU from the description, and as there was no adverse claim against the tract, the office purposed to prepare a Clear List embracing said SW% and submit it with recommendation for approval, and within the last few days said approved Clear List has been received, thus perfecting the state's title. It is one of those curiosities of land transferring that the tract should ".opear on the records of the local U. S. Land Office as having been pat - ented to the state, sold by the state, transferred the second time, entered upon abstract books, passed upon by examiners of titles without dis - covery for nearly fifty years. Table of Land Grants Actually Conveyed Land and Water Ares-s of the State by Counties During the last biennium, I began a compilation of the land and water area of the entire state by townships and counties from the records of surveys. The land areas are taken from the statement of recorded number of acres in each township plat, and in many cases the water area is also Acres Agricultural College 89.459.68 Internal Improvement _ 501.314.60 Penitentiary _ 32,039.55 Legislative and Judicial _ 12.751.05 Saline 45.597.24 University _ 45,439.93 Total 726,602.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 LAND COM MISSION ER S REPORT recorded, otherwise the areas have been calculated. The water areas are only those of the meandered lakes and streams. Streams less than twelve rods right angled width, and ponds and lakes not meandered are not considered in the calculations. The work has required the handling of more than two thousand plats. The following is a tabulation of the land and water areas by coun- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 31 gj C X OS § 2? »• gj C X 111 »»XlOMMt-*»«et-«r"»»lOt-NOOr&lt;31»r&lt;^t- OMXt^3)t-vnOMfliv31H^'-ClXVW?)3;0(0 3', in« w»N*H90i&gt;«Nt-a»ui&lt;raMat.r&lt;i&gt;x«aN«xv lOxt't^t'VOiANA^iotat^xdHiAvtaiANnov^ia Ht-x«nu9»«isxcQHNN»nt-NXHiHannt&lt;Na lflWt-U3in«MXia*NOCr-IJ5X(C(CXOON^ffi«NOOOlfl Ho6tdtecdNdcitA^'cou3Avc4^'Ai-4tdtc^ i nt^u3U3nci -foOi— fliin*!floNffi-xO)t-OXL'3irft'rfXfflvffiu;(fi M . 1 * N . ". T M . f". *. ". 1 •* T. &lt;e&gt; . °i °. "1 •* "^ "^ "? ""I M . *t T ■* *1 o h n t-' n « « i«' u fi e ei V ui n «' »' e t&gt;" t»" »' 6 ui ui « o» &lt;e »u)»t-io*»*«NF-t-ioi"r-*&lt;e»!eeiot-o&gt;iaxo» nis««v«ent&lt;ien«nv&gt;sxt&lt;nNn&lt;cnx«Nnn Ifl p _J I is : : : as : :at-n»xox ■« : : o :nu : &lt;e &amp;&gt; m co , co : : :c* : :mooxx ato :oo : : t- :offl : a w cc i- » : : :eo : :nMxt&gt;-rN« :n : :oo :mu5 :t»^oi eo : :ia ; :ou3«umN« | »• : :ao : oe :^««ift Id : jMNiirN *t^-oo :^* : :o '. us us :Veooie4 Ir^C^r- 1 I V4 1 I f-( I ISO 1™t il ic : : : n ; ivnt-oioMO :ia : :oo :xo :&lt;-&gt;oon o : : :t-; : : « n « o « o » :w : ;«c ;oo ;noo« - 1 ! ! : c : :cni-crit^M :&lt;e : I to :x c : d x *- x C4 : : ; c i : : o u: n r&lt; n n t- : m : : to :ooia : n n o&gt; &gt;a e&lt;i : : :to : :t-Nte«Ntcn :t : :o&gt; l 1 *^ : N . "I o I ih : ■ t-^ N to t-' V to : os ! : «e i eo co : ti n e x" III II Ml I I x I i iflt-Np-t^VlOr-N5vaCOX5«*NWV»NWONX WXXiflOMt-NXNXXlfiiflV^lfll'lflOSNKlflLCMB 30xnt*Musn^ &lt; x9&gt;«Nb'^NVor-^a)OViAiH9)^ i ia Xt* »®N*i-xt-MN^xxTM3)5iat-Oh-xtc3ixnr-r) I 3 «t-OONOlOOOOONrtM»HNW«t-NOf«eiOO&gt;P5Nt-Nt- HOOrH03nf«U5t*«CO«NOOWWVNVlOMfl30lfl(DC i-« C^ C© N C* * M O &lt;O N t» IO 00 M OJ tD CD «O 00 W O * M fll fli N V_ ©' h" n »•' t-* h «* o w • 90 n « o w a • • o r»" « »' us n © co" ao egiO^-*--^'&lt;*&lt;OOQb-«DCOCCCO-*«U300t"COC^CO«Di-'00«©MCOeO co m o o liiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii II • i I !• I i I i I I I M I ! I I ! I I ! &lt;&lt;&lt;SBOCBBKBC!.UUUOUtt^CCCCCC </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 111 — = = ro»Mio»:'Oio»©M:'0'— t~as:&gt;5»©:e3s©;eiooo:o©;e» ▼ v^x^xteHnsf-^r-nt^N^iaNNsiot^NAic^ (-•-xtDNnNiflCiflxXF-y. ?it"-r:r; -r- ar-sie^t^o»xeaisosxisnu;n«vNe»eii:M oidtbiA^eiai-vncoxVf-td^'rHdiat-'^iateteiawoitb nftioiaAt^XNia^t-tatOiAiotvt-vr-iOionifiMt^Ari 8 *° U &lt; tl o J eio-xxwexc. e-t-inc»nexTu:t-n«c)i-(cc- is « is « oo &lt;e r^ t- N &lt;c eo t~_ «e in w«aoaee«« to oo © © in r^" x oo x « o* oi o t- od i-«* t* « ai t«" r- o* us »■" t- a o o" t- t^ V n r-X«(CM!CTratCfl;r-{Cli;*tCX«'*«W«f«C51r-n i-4 m I e. net : us ; oo : t~ ■♦ ec :««■»•♦ :na&gt; in : :«n« : oo os oo :cm : m : r- e-&gt; &lt;— : t~ n ■* ;ten : cc : :«■«■-»■ : t- :« :oo :■•(-« :*»mm :«c«m :« : :»oort :eo os oo :U3 : in :«t-o :c&lt;cc* :ce : in : : w © : m r^ao : oo : in : *— © N : •— a; oo -^ :coos :ud : : oo r- ■* [few oi ei :c4 : w I i-i f-i ' : »— ci t-^ co i ■• : os : : ci in : © : e* i-c : ■♦ : c* III i I ! i i i is «e© :oo :«c :r-eotM imccoin :■♦« :co I mooo :« t-;N :© :« :oo^;© i^ 0 ? • "1 • : e i t^°; : T oo oo :«e •• : in cs ©' • t^ ©' cc ci : oc in : •» ! : cc cs «i : c-i w^ :« :r- :e»ooco :©cos© :■»» :ih : :ccaw : oo « oo :oo :c4 :&gt;o&lt;Si-i :r-ReiM :ao : &gt;-i : : oc &lt;o -r : ci w « :« : e&lt; ! eo ao V n :m"io : w i :i-'«n : eo I i HNO^^iHONt*4|A«oc4nifliaiflnx^Mt«MNia^&lt; Mpir-[-r-HIOr-l-»»t-»Mt-SrtON»^^ri»t-lON naiaioo!t-xeio*i-iOiainiot-t-*t-ioionio3^o)'; ■ I ■ I I »i-»»»iONt--»5i t-oir-icweot-ooixnoanx »np&lt;b;«rlOO;ifiOrHt-OUSanb-a««K;n*IAN»N n o « is x « i&lt; n us 10 n o « u: e x a « » is n k k n a u o « T-^r--oo«©c«&amp;ooost*«©oO!-«fc--^^io*-rt-^c&gt;"-^i-rado'oot-*eC'*«o I c 0 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 II I! ! ! II II II i I II I II I ! II II ! I Illilllllllllllllltlll I I I I I I I I I I I I I I i I I I I I I I I I I I in ||Ji I i • iiii yi Kill s 'll kit 111, I It] IllJ'l 1 |l|5!|l|llll?l!llill|| illl </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 33 2^- ri*ONX»N»iaor-ia»»*Nf-riH*n*xfMX^ran O*t-Mh;Mpi«ONH^ia'fr-XN«NNhlflX»X3J^O«C XLAu3u3X&gt;4a^^«^io»«xicu)v^i&gt;u:c&gt;aN^t-u3«ioc ci rt" pi ci n* 3 c o o ee u |l IS I t-iOJN'fMa^io^otei-amcouj^ifl^hir-xosiiWioqM^ tet^eo6^'t^6xN'oi*T-r-©ia«!iacJo i it^oidir;&lt;e&lt;ccwNt^ i^ i oci&lt;ce&lt;:OHNt&gt;xu:Nu:coc^MX&gt;- i 0)OMx fN^OlXNNLlMp-T-- N K X * W tC tf If. M C. r- » O3 &lt;C t C f* t»" x" cc n x' w « r-' «' t-" © &lt;c w «5 t-* o* ©* ai &lt;c t*' x" a* « w t-* « t*" c VL^wtoifltfir-cixccccc t- tc -r tc v » l: l*. t tc l: (X t- tc t- c f 1 totococo^eccootciNn^'NkaeccovNvcotonr^^'^'nLaeceo :ao : oc : : &lt;*• as cc as eo : :o ; oj « m - . p: re c : :io : :^» :io : :cioot-oooeo : too ;xn^«v ir-cor- : :cs : : lt2 : ic : : o w &lt;c o : :ia : n in ei t ci : c ta x : : *r : :t» :r» : invAOCoto : : fh :ioo)Tan :t^t-«c : :«© : : rH : 05 : : * r- 05 ec «o w : :o : us w co x : •— -r oc : : ci : ici ici i :^io^6h« : :cc iiocoeot^oi :co&lt;coi i \ ■+ i :io; [HH P :^t IN A I I I I I 111 : ill : o : t- : :w«t-f-&lt;e»-' : :© :ioio^r»o&lt;c :oc^-i— : : t- : \m : eo : : t- ic m r- © c : : i— j oo os « w a ;oono : | m : '. ci ■ — ■ i ! co ia u: u: n te : id : co &lt;P i— ■*»* oi : x v to : : oi : : oa :o : ; t-o r- os oo : : ia : u) tr. n n o&gt; : n : : e* : : eo : os j ; «o r* rn ia o ci : : oq : os^ r^_ m os t- : r- ■ b- : : t- : :co i^« : ! 10 to 10 tc h u; : ico : oi n" V «-* I 06 d : !ci : : w i i i *^ *** *~* I : « Xh»»OOO35e:NXNOS*O»«-r-C^CCXttr'5f-i^ 0- lO^HOOMiariXNiflt-rtMi-tX^NI'KXCp-CNNMlOw 2 O^XOXh-Wt»t-»Ot-n3jnNXr-L5HONVM3m;ifiNW 2 ©Nt^^^ntOXOX^XtO^rtXtOXiAIAA^t-iOnOlTXW _. (et^ujdniooi^i-dNVHnte^cjtH^oix^tcxN^naiM r* *rtt-t*!Ch*«OH^©t"i-ieoxwt"t*Mf-v©t"N*NN?c»» x iq id irt x ifl vr w 10 » v x ir: u: w t- u: c ir; m 1- t- c r c c I N l-i pi* C-J CM ■ NWrtNNNOlflONVOWNOirHlOf- H N « W 06 W f © f- f I'tfiNCMXhOOCJCWftWNWtCWMNNXCC; tfCCX" * X * O 00 frl W N U5 CO OC ©« t i" X IO CO M f N « f O h- O5 «C (O © i-&lt;" eo* x* 10 n x* ©* h&gt;" n tc «c V tc w co" t* ©" to t»" &lt;-■" icac»-*cse4f-&lt;bVo fN«ccifiC©oxin«ooi'CT«CMt-WL i :vtCL':t-cct-«CN .r-, iflwweouieoeooJNNNWNioeoeo^wteotteow-f^eoioweo C in" ~* pi h9 H 5 o o IIIIIMIIIIIIilllMIIIMIMM i I I I I I I I I I I j I I I j j i I I I I I I il I'M ■■ II |i J|l ■ !l!!illiillilleli!2i!lililiii </seg>
            <seg id="p034">ill ~ — c 3i&gt;x»x»nsu:xo ce : »»M?if-3iNft«f-in c- : Nsxr-9iniox«3&gt;a i-c : ifl^-Nf-*Nt-Mxa« © : «t-ex«aooso«t-; r^ . 9Ot»^-3St*9S^'t^C^t' © ! * io c- m ia m * io us to » : t^ i c- I •% •o 1 m jlj O "- 1 »«ioef-c«r.MNt-t- o&gt;^"cioico'^©odVcooJ rt IO C4 lO to O V O A C4 « (C Cft V h- V P9 0C 00 00 V t-ceinmteinootccc«0 co : s i o&gt; : © i : ia ; en : 1 I o u c J \ £ m ■I* : : : t- ■• eo : eo : : e» : co oi oo ; co : : o&gt; : : :t-ON : r- : : M : : : o&gt; co oo : os : : © :eian IfS : : to ! «c ■♦ o&gt; ; ei ; ; «c : OO 00 to — ce co co eo oo © t- CO in oo «e r- e e # &gt;&gt; I ■o s ■ I \ : : : oo c cm : a&gt; : |« :nooo ■ : : to :«oi^ : o i fl : : j - — : as : : «c :n«« 1 1- : j i-« I »*« \a ! i-J i : V III I j j io : p : ci i in : t-H : e&gt; ! t- : t-. : hi O a &lt; ! o | ■ I N©3SMl-lr"l4Or«»©r* «&lt;if »is»«isiaio oo : — • co : eo : o ! co : oo : &lt;e ! t- I I !| -2 O5 O5 C &amp;* 22*"- d ° &gt; !» P OS SSI* ££-°£ - - £ *" Pill e»»Me-icooot^-*co't^ «i«M«r-o oo ©_ o&gt; i-i «e &lt;c" o&gt;* o" V od co" «c oo* oo © © t- in C- »H ©"©" t- r- &lt;-• eo si" ■I i ■&gt;»■ ::::::::::: : i i i i i i j i i : ! i M I M M I I ! i : I ! i i . : I Nj If I- II : 1 t ■§■§■2- 8 m c T. E I I </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 35 Platting of Examiners Reports of Government Surveys During the last year I have drafted all of the reports of Special Examiners of Government surveys East of the 6th Principal Meridian that have been found in the archives of the old Surveyor General's Office, on a scale V4 inch per mile, showing all corners examined in black with the notation of corners not found or condemned in red ink. It was the rule for the Surveyor General to appoint special agents or deputies to examine surveys and file written reports of their findingu. A large number of these are on file, but they do not cover all the surveys east of the Principal Meridian and it is possible that some were lost before records of Nebraska Surveys were transferred to Nebraska, when admitted into the Union in 1867. These reports are very interest - ing and important as they show the idea of the Department as to the future value of these reports and of the examinations. The special agents were assigned the contracts to be examined and received per diem wages and their expenses. The method of procedure seems to have been standardized which was a fatal defect. Throughout the entire file of examinations, great stress was put in the character of the monu - ments and witnesses and very little attention as to the course and length of the lines. If the monuments were within the requirements of the printed and special instructions, the surveys were accepted. If not, they were condemned after about one-sixth of the lines had been ex - amined, yet these reports are of great value and when re-surveys of lines are applied for to settle disputes, they are consulted to obtain informa - tion as to the character of the surveys at the time of examination. The reports of examinations West of the 6th Principal Meridian have not yet been drafted. Rebinding Field Note* and Reports Lack of funds has prevented the rebinding of many volumes of field notes of original surveys, whose bindings have deteriorated through use and age. There are alsn about one hundred re-surveys of dHpute'l lines by this Department which should be bound as early as possible. The Kansas-Nebraska Base Line When the Government turned over to the State in 1867. the field notes, maps and other records of surveys in Nebraska, a barren copy of the notes of survey of the Base Line were included, in general, with - out information as to who were the surveyors, their assistants, the list of names of assistants, their oaths, and oaths of the surveyors and Surveyor-General's approval. There should be obtained a certified copy of the entire survey and all of the history pertaining to it. It has been reported to this office that the iron monument set in 1855 on the West bank of the Missouri to mark the initial point of- the 40th Parallel or Base Line has fallen down. The matter should be investigated and if so, it should be permanently restored to its original </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT position. It is also reported, by one of our deputies, accompanied by photographs, that the monument erected in 1869 to mark the inter - section of 25 degrees West of Washington, D. C. and the 41st parallel of X. Latitude, which is the southwest corner of Nebraska and the Northeast corner of Colorado, is falling down. It should be re-set in a permanent foundation to prevent future displacement. Field Work Applications for examinations and surveys to settle disputes, are by law made to the Commissioner and referred to this department. On account of the increasing demands on the time of the state surveyor, most of the field work must be executed by the regularly appointed deputies, under the direct instructions of the State Surveyor. It has thus far been the policy of the several Commissioners to comply with the law in the appointment of deputies who are experienced surveyors and who have made a study of the subject of retracement of lines and identification of corners. The Department of Public Works and County Commissioners have largely drafted the available competent surveyors and engineers, so that we have found it very difficult to retain some of our deputies and to find others who were experienced in land surveying and capable of handling the complicated cases submitted to this office for solution. Our deputies are nearly all County Surveyors and High - way Engineers and it is difficult for them to find the time to make surveys for this department. The result is that we are unable to meet all the demands that are made and are consequently considerably be - hind. The construction of State and Federal roads has added to the work of the department in the matter of requests for examinations and re-surveys to settle disputes over the location of original corners along roads that are being constructed. The lack of funds to defray current expenses to enable the State Surveyor to go into the field to direct and instruct new deputies in searching for and identifying original corners has prevented the appoint - ment of more deputies and has greatly retarded the work. Our deputies complain that they have to use their County instruments and tools in making surveys for this office, and that the County Boards are reluct - ant to give permission for such use, and have asked that they be furnished the necessary equipment as furnished the Board of Public Works. As no appropriations have ever been made for instruments for this office, the department has been unable to comply with their re- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 37 During the biennium the following surveys have been made or par tially completed, to-wit: No. of Location Survey Name of Applicant of Survey 221 Wilfred E. Voss Dakota County 222 W. L. Little, suspended — land sold Howard County 223 Wm. P. McCormick Keya Paha County 224 Jas. E. Rice &amp; E. H. Boyd Garden County 225 Richards Keene &amp; Co Cheyenne County 226 N. E. Ellerson Thayer County 227 J. A. Ludwick et al Saunders County Hi W. W. Alt _ Cherry County 246 George Bellis Knox County 247 Arah H. Hungerford, et al — discontinued... Dawes County 248 Robert Blacklock, et al Greeley County 249 Luther Woolbridge, et al Greeley County 250 A. J. Cook, et al — not completed Valley County 251 A. S. Blakeslee — not completed Valley County 252 Carrie Nelson — et al, not completed Lincoln County In September, 1919, it was reported to this office that a Mr. A. H. Adams had been sent by the General Land Office to survey out certain claims in Townships 27 and 28 North, of Ranges 39 and 40 West in Cherry County, and was then engaged in the work, and had surveyed out a claim in Section 36, T. 28 N. R. 40 W. I was immediately instructed by the Commissioner to go to the locality and examine the condition of the alleged survey and interview the surveyor, if possible, dn reach 229 Otto Weiderander Lincoln County 230 231 Geo. Sinn Thayer County Nels Hawkinson HitchcMik County 232 W. D. Troxel et al Hitchcock County 2.33 Andrew Kewitt— adjournment awaiting evidence _.. Lincoln County 234 Oscar Warp Lincoln Courty 235 John Husa et al Thayer Countv 236 Victor Grudzinski Sherman County 237 John C. High, et al Stanton County 238 William Neidfelt Merrick County 239 Cheyenne County, examination of resur- vey by county surveyor Cheyenne County 240 John Bredehoft, et al., York County 241 John C. Bredehoft York County 242 W. E. Kelso and 19 others Kimball County 243 244 245 Mary Ahlert, et al — suspended Hayes County Stephen E. Johnston Lincoln County Harlan County Harlan County 246 George Bellis Knox County </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT ing the Survey Post Office which is only a half mile east of said Section 36, I was informed that Mr. Adams had completed his work and had left the country. I found upon examination, from maps of resurveys of said townships and from settlers that a line of corners had been found several years before extending from the Southwest corner of T. 28 N. R. 40 W. East into R. 39 W. representing the South boundary of T. 28 N; Also thai another line of corners had been early found extending from the South - east corner of T. 28 N. R. 39 W. known as the "Log Chain" corner, and extending westerly into R. 40 W. and crossing the line between Ranges 39 and 40 about 108 rods North of the township corner on the first line marked "T.- P. Cor." in diagram, and established the Southwest corner of T. 28 N. R. 39 W. about 160 rods West in Section 36, for the line representing the South boundary of T. 28 N. R. 39 W. and then continued the line one mile farther west. The records of survey of T. 28 N. R. 39 W. show that this town - ship was surveyed by G. E. Kentner in 1882 from the line run from the "Log Chain" corner at &amp; base, and that T. 23 N. R. 40 W. was also surveyed by the same party in 1882 from the South line as a base, as indicated by the original corners found in each township. The settler in sections 1 and 2, T. 27 N. R. 40 W. claimed that his "Kinkaid" homstead was short, therefore Mr. Adams surveyed out of Section 36 and SH of Section 35 about 420 acres as a part of the "Kin - kaid" claim in Sections 1 and 2, T. 27 N. from the corners made on the North line. The State owns the S^ of Section 35 and all of Section 36, amounting to 960 acres and have been under lease for many years. In the resurvey of 1916 by the Genearl Land Office, the corners found on the South line in Range 40 were perpetuated with regula - tion iron posts with brass caps, with proper description stamped thereon, and the corners on the North line from the "Log Chain" West to the line between Ranges 39 and 40, were perpetuated in like manner. Mr. Adams in his survey of claim lines perpetuated the Corner at "A" in diagram, with iron post and brass cap as a corner to Section 36 and Tract No. 99. He also perpetuated the half mile and mile corners on the next mile West with iron posts, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 39 As I expected to find the surveyor, I did not take with me an in - strument or tape line to make measurements, but from the examination and maps of resurvey which I hare been able to obtain, the portion sur - veyed out of the school lands i3 approximately represented in the annexed diagram. School Sections 36 and S'^ofi 36 No person lives on the school lands in Sections 35 and 36, but they are enclosed with a wire fence and pastured by the lesee, D. M. Gourley, who lives in Section 14. The South line of Sections 35 and 36 runs along the South edge of a beautiful valley which is several miles long East and West, and about half a mile wide, and is valuable farm land and if the claims are allowed to stand they will cut the heart out of the entire school tract. Immedi - ately on my return I filed my report with the Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 L.A.N1J CuMMloblUNER o RcsPkjRl In the matter of the contention of the state and the Krause estate over the amount of potash brine pumped from the "Krause" lake, is in Sections 15, 16, 21 and 22, T. 26 N. R. 45 W. but mostly in the S% of Section 16 of which the Krause estate owns the S% of the S% and the State the N% of the S%. Therefore to determine the area of the lake bed owned by each of the parties, the lake was surveyed by Deputy State Surveyor D. A. Nippell, under instructions. In order to do this it was necessary that he make the necessary retracements to find the original corners of adjacent sections to determine the boundaries of Section 16. Excepting a short distance at the West end, the lake has a clearly de - ned water line and the shore was meandered as close to the water as onditions would permit. There is a small island near the West end hich was also meandered, the surveying crew passing over on the dry bed of that part of the lake to the island which lay partly in the estate and partly in the school land. The island's total area was deducted rom the lake's total area and the portions lying in the respective tracts ere deducted therefrom. Complaint was made that the survey was incorrect, on account of it having been made during high water and therefore took in too much land, especially at the West end, which did not have a clearly defined water line. I was instructed to examine into the merits of the complaint, Eich I did in February, 1920. I spent half a day examining the survey the shore lines with Mr. Nippell and half a day with the representa- B8 of the Krause estate, especially with reference to the West end. The lake bed here was covered with several inches of water and a thin ice on which boards were laid to cross over to the island. A photograph was taken of the flooded lake bed between the island and the shore to show that the survey was not made during a time of high water. My conclusions were that the survey was not made during a period of high water and that it could properly have included more land at the West end of more or less saturated lake bed, but that the surveyor had exer - cised his Judgment in choosing a mean line between low and high water and altogether the survey was favorable to the estate. LOn both of these trips to save expense, I examined several tracts of ool lands, for which applications for sale had been made by lessees and reports made with diagrams showing conditions. No fees were charged for any of this work. Fees The only income of the department is derived from fees for filing of Applications for surveys, examination of the field notes and maps of surveys made by the deputies, per diem of the State Surveyor for field work and copying of field notes and maps of surveys. There have been received the following fees which have been paid into the State Treasury, </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 41 Filing Applications for Surveys $ 25.00 Examination of Notes and Plats of Surveys 220.25 Copying field notes an&lt;i plats 67.00 Certified copies of records 9.00 Total *32i.2d Oregon Trail By Legislative enactment the State Surveyor, Secretary of the State Historical Society and Regent of the Daughters of the American Revolu- tion were appointed a commission to mark the Oregon Trail through the State. The death of the secretary of the Historical Society in 1917, wai activities, the control of the railroads by the Government which pre- vented free shipment and general unsettled conditions have prevented the completion of the work. The inclement weather during the present month has prevented the placement of the last of the monuments. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>