<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00074.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0074.0004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Ninth Biennial Report OF THE Board of Control OF Nebraska For the Period Ending June 30, 1931</title>
               <date value="1931-06-30">1931-06-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Ninth Biennial Report OF THE Board of Control OF Nebraska For the Period Ending June 30, 1931 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">3 FOREWORD The Board of Control of Nebraska herewith transmits its Ninth Biennial Report of the seventeen institutions under its jurisdiction, for the period beginning July 1, 1929, and ending Tun&lt; - -30, 1931. J The term of Carrie A. Hirss expired June 30, 1929, and Nellie T.enson of Silver Creek was appointed by the Governor to fill the vacancy. During the period covered by this report, changes have taken place m the management of six institutions. J. O. Moore, Commandant, Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Mil - ford, resigned. . Ivan S. Gallant of York was appointed to fill the vacancy on August 20, 1929. J. J. Carlisle, Commandant of the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Grand Island, resigned, Ivan S. Gal - lant was transfered from Milford to Grand Island, and on March 10, 1930, Charles F, Jackson of Lincoln was appointed Comman - dant of this institution. At the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Mrs. Florence Crist, Superintendent, was transferred, at her request, to the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, to fill the position of Matron, suc - ceeding Mrs. Hannah Buck, resigned. Mrs. Effie J. Mou.len was appointed Superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children on September 1, 1930. Dr. J. H. Matthai resigned, and m his place Dr. F. A. Alcorn of Haxtum, Colorado, was appointed Superintendent of the Or - thopedic Hospital, Lincoln, on February 24, 1931. .Dr. J. Blame Babcock, Superintendent of the Hastings State Hospital at Ingleside, resigned, and Dr. G. E. Charlton, Superinten - dent of the Norfolk State Hospital, was transferred to Ingleside. Dr. J. C. Nielsen, Assistant Superintendent at Norfolk, succeede 1 Dr. Charlton. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Some permanent improvements have been mack 1 during the - liicnnium, the more outstanding of which follow: Institution for Feeble-M hided, Beatrice J? 125 .()()().( Hi Girls' Training School. Geneva &gt; -10.000.00 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Grand Island 1(H).(IO().(MI Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside -10,000.00 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney : (i. ).()()( 1.0(1 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln ". 35.(MX).()!) Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 100.000.00 State Penitentiary, Lincoln ' 50.000.1 X) X'eliraska Industrial . Home, Mil ford -15,000.00 Xorfolk Slate Hospital. Xorfolk „• KK).(KKUK). School for Deaf. Omaha "W. 000.00 Reformatory for Women, York 6.000.00 Reformatory for Men. Lincoln 20.500.00 In addition to the foregoing permanent improvements', ap - proximately. $3f&gt;2.s(X).{X) was spent on general repairs t:&gt; the vari - ous institutions. A new steel water lower, capacity 60,000 gallons, was built at the Lincoln State Hospital at a cost of 56 .000.00. while at the State Penitentiary the power equipment was improved by the ad dit ion of a steam turbine, a generator and boiler at an approximate cost of $5K.000.00. We are grateful to the legislature for the appropriations which made it possible to make these improvements. There is a crowded condition still prevailing m a number of our institutions, and this can be overcome by appropriations to meet the emergency. In the tables which follow, it must be borne in 'mind that items of salaries an 1 wages are included under maintenance m all in - stances, excepting m the case of the Hoard itself. Capital outlay represents permanent improvements to realty and equipment.' We extend thanks to officers and employes of the institutions for their efforts to bring about better conditions for those committed to their care. We also sincerely thank Governor Weaver for his many manifestations of interest and cooperation m our work. Hoard of Control. ■ K. T. WESTERVELT. Chairman, H.S.THORPE, ..NELLIE G. BEXSON. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NEBRASKA STATE INSTITUTIONS {H S. Thorpe, Chairman Nellie G. Benson W. \i. Hagcr O. R. Slmtto, Secretary Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Beatrice Dr. J. A. IJurford, Superintendent Girls' Training School Geneva Miss Lena E. Ward, Superintendent ♦Nebraska Soldiers and Sailors" Home Grand Island Ivan S. Gallant, Commandant •I lasting* State Hospital ' Inylesidc Dr. G. E. Charlton, Superintendent State Industrial School Kearnev K. V. Clark, Superintendent Hospital for Tuberculous Kearnev Dr. L. T. Sidwell, Superintendent Lincoln State Hospital Lincoln Dr. I). G. Griffiths, Superintendent ♦Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln Dr. I l '. A. Aleorn, Superintendent State I 'enitentiary : Lincoln \V. T. Teuton, Warden Nebraska Industrial Home Mil ford Miss M. Evelyn Meyer, Superintendent •Ivaii S. Cullunt was appointed I'omnmndniit, April Ist, 19.50. to succeed .1. J. Carlile. *or. (i. lv. Cliarllon was Iransfirrtd friini the Korkfolk Stale Hospital mi March 24th, 19.11 t«i till the vacancy resulting from Or. J. Blnillv l!a l)i-i ick's resignation^ *l)r. I". A. Alcorn was appointed on February 24th, \')i\, to succeed Dr. J. J. (Jerkfiis who had heen made superintendent tin January Ist. V&gt;M. Dr. J. 11. Matlhai having resigned. ■ 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">♦Nebraska Soldiers and Sailors' Home Mil ford Charles F. Jackson, Commandant Nebraska School for the Mind Nebraska City N. C. Abbott, Superintendent *. Norfolk State Hospital , Norfolk Dr. J. C. Nielsen, Superintendent Nebraska School for the Deaf Omaha F. W. Booth, Superintendent State Reformatory for Women ....: York Dr. Alma J. Chapman, Superintendent *Nebraska Home for Dependent Children .'. ; Lincoln Mrs. Effie J. Mouden, Superintendent ■ ■ State Reformatory for Men '. Lincoln A. W. Miller, Superintendent . ♦Charles F. Jackson was appointed Commandant on March 10th, 1930 to fill a vacancy caused by the transfer of Ivan S. Gallant from Milford where he had been m command since August 20tb, 1929, having succeeded J. O. Moore. *Dr. J. C. Nielsen was appointed to the superintendency March '24th, 1031, to fill a vacancy because of the transfer of Dr. G. E. Charlton to Hastings State Hospital. *Mrs. Effie J. Mouden was appointed to the superintendency September 1. 1930. She succeeded Mrs. Florence E. Crist. 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 INMATE POPULATION There arc seventeen institutions under the control of the Hoard, ;m(l at this time, June 30, 1931, the inmate population is 7,136 as compare:! with an average of 6,691 for the hiennium ending m 1929, and 6,547 for the hiennium just prior to that. The following table will be found of interest as showing the population of the different institutions during the past two bienna : Average population T , biennium ending Lwpsl number • at any one June 30, June 30, time m past I').*) 1931 hiennium Institution {or Feeble-Minded.... ' 858 881 983 Girls' Training School ■ 1% 184 198 Soldiers' Hume, Grand Island ' 258 247 304 Hastings State Hospital 1.383 1,4n9 1.492 State Industrial School : 200 212 ?34 Hospital for Tuberculous 107 121 151 Lincoln State Hospital 1.14.3 1.157 1,170 Orthopedic Hospital 99 92 110 State Penitentiary... 700 741 779 Nebraska Industrial Home 77 77 ' 93 Soldiers' Home, Milford 13) 121 151 Nebraska School for the 81ind.... 46* 45* 52* Norfolk State Hospital 899 928 943 Nebraska School for the Deaf K&gt;s* 189» 201* State Reformatory for Women.... 49 42 48 Home for Dependent Children.... 104 .111 117 State Reformatory for Men 2H7 388 423 Total (&gt;.f.91 7,005 'Average during school terms. . Note: Attention is called to the fact that, m considering the question of maintenance, the figures [representing the "Largest number at any time m past biennium" should be used, for the reason that help, equipment, teachers, etc., must be adequate to care for the maximum population. This, fact is unfortunately often overlooked by those m authority. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 SUMMARY OF EXPENDITURES OF STATE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Salaries Operation Furniture Imp. to v rixcd STATE INSTITUTIONS and and and Bldgs. and J&amp;L- Land c.f'V) n-° Ul - f " r Per Cent Wages Maintenance Equipment Grounds Rui 'd'ngs Charges A— Institution for Feeble- Minded $103,66875 $267,664.83 $11,304.73 $.32,454.02 $118,147.78 $1,730.44 $534,970.55 9.4— A B— Girls' Training School 45,246.26 84,604.75 2,363.84 23,985.67 38,847.35 .. 195.047.87 3.5— B C— Soldiers' Home, Grand Island 95,460.14 172,755.74 4.254.55 4,582.32 00.715.31 10.00 376,778.06 6.6— C D— Hastings State Hospital 243.825.16 41it.173.18 21.7W.78 59,963.77 33,704.57 . 3,969.00 773,399.46 13.6— D E— State Industrial School 64.401.71 131.149.32 3,697.54 7,126.58 968.00 207,34315 3.6— X F— Hospital for Tuberculous .... 63,402.30 97,819.33 5.180.83 5,053.36 53,360.85 ... 226,816.67 4.0— F G— Lincoln State Hosptal : 227.607.04 396,812.19 8,074.28 20.255.92 30.065.61 ...: 2,023.92 684,839.86 12.0— &lt; ; H— Orthopediic Hospital 70.499.44 107.311.75 2,984.51 9,559.18 99,873.25 . 290,228,13 5.0— H J— State Penitentiary 226,696.12 201.W8.38 61,174.87 23,734.01 54,419.02 12,588.04 670,521.34 11.7— J X— Nebraska Industrial Home .... 21,990.77 35,031.35 3.876.28 4,491.82 42,131.24 150.01) 69.50 107,840.96 1.8— X L— Soldiers' Home, Milford 43,411.68 87,716.73 4,937.30 7.872.47 34.00 143.972.18 2.5— L M— School for the Blind 34.383.08 43,105.62 603.41 5,70679 83,888.90 1.4— M N— Norfolfk State Hospital 178.108.91 265,847.88 14,329.22 54,376.81 06.179.04 1.820.00 610,661.86 10.6— N P— School for the Deaf 100,861.33 83.549.10 11.543.59 21,997.63 92,169.49 310,121.14 5.4— P . R— State Reformatory for Women 14.832.07 32,805.22 4,176.92 9.243.17 6.371.91 1,345.25 68,774.54 1.3— R S— Home for Dependent Children 30,734.76 71,359.47 1.989.08 2.943.94 941.24 .. 0.217.69 117.186.18 2.0— S T— State Reformatory for Men .. 111,65375 168.142.70 12,688.25 3,141.16 19,124.57 &#132;, 7,810.13 322.560.56 5.6— T Total $1,676,784.17 $2,747,757.54 $174,942.98 $296,578.62 $787,152.13 $150.00 $41,585.07 $5,724,951.41 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 POPULATION AND PER CAPITA REPORT OF STATE INSTITUTIONS Ju'.y 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Number I Aver . a 6 c Number Avera S&lt;: Average Average Average Average 1931 ur "? g 1931 , ( . lunl ? g t0 T biennfum per month per month 01 biennium ■ bicnmum employee ' __ A— Institution for Feeblc-Miiidcd 072 881 72 76 11 $406.00 $10.92 $4,319.53— A B-Girls' Training School 179 184 26 25 7 702.52 29.27 1. 883.26 -B C-Soldiers 1 Home, Grand Island 229 247. 78 76 3 989.36 41.22 3,864.53 -C D-Hastings State Hospital ........ 1.468 1.469 IS2 162 ' 9 433.7 18.07 9.856.33-D E-State Industrial School 206 212 39 39 6 89973 374 2,683.40 -E F-Hospital for Tuberculous !. 139 121 57 54 2 1.31/. 2s j4.89 2.641 Jb-F G— I incoln State Hospital 1.170 1,157 158 153 8 320.66 21.69 9,365.63-G H-0 Cedk Hofpit'i 101 92 58 52 2 1.900.88 79.20 2.937.48 -H I— State Penitentiary ' 769 741 76 76 10 712.71 29.6&lt;&gt; 6.781.00 -J i^r.iM&amp;nESr: M 77 II 10 8 Ml M 6 916^-K 1,-Soldiers 1 Home, Milford 107 121 44 42 3 1.0/9.34 44.9/ ./62.// '-I. M-Nebr School for the Blind* .. 48 45 25 26 . 2 1,542.4fi US J^f-W-M N-Norfolk State Hospital 935 928 116 109 9 4/3.22 1 ./2 7.203.;6-N P-Nebr. School for the Deaf* .... 190 189 53 55 3 %4'W 4O ; 21 456777 -P R-State Reformatory for Women 36 42 10 11 4 1.144.34 47.68 ;MJ-9»-R S-Home for Dependent Children 95 111 22 2i 5 988.42 4 18 1223.84 -S T-State Reformatory for Men .. 399 388 44 35 H_ /33.24 30.^ 3,913.94 -1 Total _ - 7,136 7.005 | 1.071 1.024 | 6_J $020.17 $25.84 $06.549.95 ♦Average during school term </seg>
            <seg id="p011">ESTIMATED VALUE OF LANDS, BUILDINGS, FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT, AND IMPROVEMENTS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS June .31), 1931 Lands ! Buildings STATE INSTITUTIONS' ofwres ' [S July 1 j ,- , fesMv 1 J 'Purnhare | Equipment j Total owned | Value 1W » to jdnc ValuC [1929 t« June 30. R3l I'O. l'J.il j ■ | | ■ ' A— Institution for Feeble- Minded 519.41 ■ $107,566.00 | ?184.10 | ?716,132.00l $38,390.25 i §71,901.831 SW4, 174.18 —A B— Girls' Training School 70 Ki.325.05) 80.76 I 189.209.00 ■■ 14,236.15 16,276.40 2.36,127.31 — li C— Soldiers' Home. Grand Island 640 : 114,671.00 '.07.21 459.(125.00 1 13:301.7.3 21.207.76 608,812.70 — c: D— Hastings State Hospital 623 180.335.00 13.980.29 j I.IJSJB6HOI §1,612.65 125.W0.56 286.688.59 1746.943.09 —D E-State Industrial School '.112 112,215.00.: 205.394.00..- 17.221.19 »M 370,fi48.88 -E F-Hospilal for Tuberculous .W 33.900.001 | 225.ft35.tt) 17.277.43 .V).^7.A) .1A.W0.1.S — F G— Lincoln State Hosptal 640 128.123.00 1,3.406.77 1 944^10.00 | 85.745.2'&gt; 1.v;.265.03 UW4.053.09 — G H— Orthopedic Hospital .3.70 2V.118.UU | 700.00 210.303.tW 1 9.716.69 11.313.71 261,151.40 — H J— State Penitentiary 416 ■ 85.346.1)0 , 12.000.00 452.ff16.00 -O.i.'l') 13.4'JOJS 135.890.54 699.915.98 — .1 K-Ncbraska Industrial Home 57.58 7,805.00 •. . W.i')4.0(l 6.642.47 i 7^f2A§ 121.W.12 -X 1.-Soldiers 1 Home, Milford 41 12.2.30.011 1«&gt;4.525.00 \V^,~ I f,V?H^ ?&amp;$!, f, "A M— School for the Blind 10 i .3.650.0a 1 ■ 122,5,35.11')! 12.1 ( &gt;1.14 19.153.60 157.529.74 — M n-noS sLteHospkai ::::::: as i&amp;mmoi : ■:: 82i5jBiH ; ; mmm s^fh-^^-N P— School for the Deaf 2i . 75.2 W.0 1 .) 16.620.95 415.256.0:) 1 .' :. '24.590.88 49.912.56 .iB4,/ 09.39 — P R-State Reformatory for Women 119 .38..354.00 1.(1.36.35: 94.345.0t&gt; 3.337.75; 5.582.77 1 12.4.36.f,5 J 55.092.52 -R S— Home for Dependent Children 49 .39.603.42 i 56.078.1)!1| 8.W.9.34 :■ 3.192.81 107.743.57 -S T-State Reformatory for Men .. 161.64 | 68,504.00 I 235,572.00;.: , |- 8.623..V ■ I 20.8.34./8 333.a34.3.i -1 T ota l ~ 4,«)7.39 SI .217.178.4J I 55K.M6.43 1 $6.577.61 3.04 1 55.443.59 | $488.994 36 $1.095.105.77 }S'J.-t42.951.61 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Report of the Institution for Feeble-Minded Beatrice, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED BEATRICE, NEBRASKA OFFICERS J. A. BURFORD, M. D. - - - ... Superintendent A. O. SKINNER, M. D. - - - ■ . Physician WILLIAM POLLOCK - - .... Steward NELLIE MUMFORD - - - - . . Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established \ jgg^ Number of employes June 30, 1931 72 Number of inmates June 30. 1931 &lt;)/2 Highest number of inmates at any one time 953 Per capita cost per month $16.02 Number of acres owned 519.41 .Number of acres leased 61.50 Number of acres under culivation 326.50 Value of lands and buildings, furniture and equipment $934.174.]K Principal industries : Farming and stock raising. Visiting days: Every day from 7.A, M. to 7 I. M., excepting Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays. I I■; . . The parent, husband or guardian of "any person committed shall, if financially able, pay the actual cost, which shall not amount to more than $40.00 per year for clothing and incidentals; other - wise the county shall pay. Statements are rendered the first of December of each year showing actual expenditures. At any time an inmate is discharged, the balance m the fund will be returned. 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">To the Govcnior ;in&lt;l the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I herewith submit the Twenty-Third Biennial Report of the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded for the period ending Tune 30th, 1931, During this period, we have received 224 new inmates and have discharged 95, 56 by death and 12 after sterilization. 27 inmate:; have been discharged while on parole. The sterilization law was pending the decision of the courts for almost two years, so thai only recently have we been able to do sterilizations. The number of these is small, as but few of our inmates are m condition for Operation and discharge. On June 30th, 1931, we have 972 inmates m the institution and 88 on parole. Many of these paroled are home on short vacations, and practically all of them will return by September Ist when our school starts. During the biennium, a new building with capacity to house 21C&gt; inmates has been opened for boys, and 75 boys have been transferred to this building from the stone cottage.' The stone cottage has been remodeled, and we have received and placed m this cottage, 80 girls. We now have room- for 75 males, but quarters for females arc practically filled. In our last annual report, we asked for an appropriation of $150,000.00 for a girls' cottage, but, on account of the general financial depression and the necessity for economy m building, the Legislature felt justified m appropriating only $55,000.00 for this purpose. It is thought that, with the lower cost of labor and building material, we may be able to get a serviceable building for this amount, and so we are going along with plans for a building to accommodate 120 girls. It will take practically all of the appropria - tion for this building, leaving but little for equipment and nothing 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">lor tunnels or steam lines. However, as we. have plenty of pipe on hand, it is my judgment that these lines should be laid m tile conduit until an appropriation can be made for tunnels. Request was, also made for an appropriation of $15,000.00 m order to remodel the girls' brick cottage, but. for the same reasons as stated above, this was reduced to $12,500.00. P,y employing our own labor insofar as possible, it is thought that we can make the necessary repairs to this building. We plan to proceed at once with reshing - ling the cottage and the roofs of the porches which are leaking very badly, and other repairs will be made as rapidly as possible. Later, terrazzo lloors will be built, but it will be neeessarry to complete the new building m order to make a place for the girls before we can finish remodeling and repairing the brick cottage. It is our intention to place m the new building, girls of the higher type, and m the remodeled building, girls of the lower type. When this is accomplished, we will have relieved the congestion m even - department and should be able to accept all applicants both male an 1 female. The appropriation of $12,500.00 makes it possible for us to increase the size of our bakery, and laundry which have become inadequate as the institution has grown. This will be the first improvement m the laundry m 15 years, .and the bakery, with its orginal equipment, has done service lor 11 years, while the pop - ulation of the institution has grown from five hundred to more than one thousand. The following improvements have been made during the biennium : Construction of a new greenhouse which was very badly needed. The building of an addition to the hay barn, 32x56 feet, enabling us to store more hay and providing more feeding space for our dairy herd, and an addition to our dairy barn, 18x80 feet, with concrete lloor and feeding troughs. Feeding stanchions were added so that we now have room for 45 cows. Our smokestack has been overhauled by expert workmen ; all joints were repointed and the stack made 15 feet taller. , This has noticeably improved the draft and, together with other improvements made, has greatly increased the efficiency of the heating and power plant. I am confident that the saving m fuel will soon offset the 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">cost of these improvements. Old brick tunnels have been rebuilt or strengthened. Small and inadequate steam and water lines have been replaced with larger ones. All pipe joints have been welded, thus saving fittings and making a permanent installation. Our electric wiring system has been completely overhauled. Three main leads of large wire have been installed from our switchboard to supply every part of the institution with current. These have replaced numerous small lines, thus eliminating line loss, and I have a letter from the lowa-Nebraska Light and Power Company, commenting on the fact that, although we have added a garage, a large poultry house and a three-story building, as well as motors for pumping, etc., our monthly bill for current is less than before. One of the outstanding things done during the past vcar was tlie completion of our water system for irrigation and for fin. 1 protection. A 0-inch cast-iron water main extends from P.ear Creek to a point near the administration building, a distance of 2()00 feet. We have a dam ai the creek and a large body of water from which to draw. This water system is entirely independent of our regular well. A 5-inch centrifugal pump near the creek pumps about four hundred gallons per minute for the irrigation of about forty acres of alfalfa' and garden. Permanent lire hydrants are located at convenient points, and we have a large steam pump at the boiler house to furnish pressure, so, with an abundance of water and with ample pressure, we are well C(|ilipt m case a lire should occur. The stone collage lias been remodeled, a new roof having been pul on and new stone porches built. New lloors have been laid, terrazzo downstairs and maple upstairs. This cottage was m very bad condition, but it is now one of the best buildings we have and should need no attention for years. New floor have been laid m the two south cottages for hoys. A part ol the old boiler-house has been converted into a garage to accommodate -4 trucks. Heretofore, our trucks bail been kept m indicated garages, and so were hard to start on winter mornings. Just recently, we have built a 12-stall garage for employes' cars. Most of this work was done with material on hand and with our own labor. During the past year, we built a laving house for our poultry. 20x110 feet and absolutely up-to-date m design and construction. 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Our school continues to be the center around which the institu - tion is built. 250 boys and girls are doing work m the school proper Many others are receiving training m the various departments. Close check is kept on these boys and girls, and they are encouraged to do the things for which they seem best fitted. In the school proper, we are teaching everything from kindergarten to, and in - cluding, fifth grade work. A few are able to do work m the sixth grade. Industrial art. music and physical education are highly important departments, inasmuch as they take an active part m the preparation of programs and entertainments which are given throughout the school year and which serve to keep up the interest of the pupils and provide entertainment for a large number of our population who are not privileged to take part. We have a motion picture show one night each week to which 500 are taken and a dance one night each week m which 100 boys and girls take part and many others attend as spectators. We have church service each Sunday morning at nine o'clock which is attended by 500 of our people. Our institution has grown so rapidly that we are now con - fronted with the necessity of enlarging our school building. We find it necessary to divide our pupils into forenoon and afternoon groups. Many of these should spent! more hours m school. Then too. our auditorium is small, so that we are compelled to limit the number attending programs, a considerable number being deprived of this privilage. In our next annual report, recommendation - will be made for enlarging our school building and improving our facilities for teaching. In concluding this report, I wish to thank our officers and the heads of various departments whose faithful performance of duty and cheerful cooperation m conducting the affairs of the institu - tion have made possible our achievements. I wish to express my appreciation for the keen interest the members of the Hoard of Control have shown m this institution. Their understanding of our problems and their willingness to advise and assist m solving them have been an inspiration to me. • " Respectfully submitted. .1. A. HURFORD. Superintendent. 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Total fur Hicnnium ! . M. F. T. Present at beginning of period....: -144 ,5'j(l 8.54 Admitted for first time l.W 85 224 Readmitted _j 4 .5 7 On parole at beginning of period (.(I 26 Wi ( )n escape ;.t beginning of period 4 0 4 Total ' : 651 504 1.155 Discharged from Institution 10 1 Died at Institution :.. 35 21 50 Died while on parole 0 2 2 Discharge while on parole 27 5 .52 Remaining on parole at end of period 47 .50 77 Discharged on escape 4 0 4 Remaining on escape at end of period 11 0 11 Total •. '. 125 58 IS.? Remaining at Institution at end, of period 526 446 °72 Total on hooks at end of period ; 584 47&lt;&gt; 1.060 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Bicnniuin M. ¥. tT Under 5 -. ". 12 7 1" 5 and under 10 .54 IS 52 10 and under 15 28 21 4" 15 and under 18 _. M 8 38 18 and under 25 _.. 14 14 28 25 and under .35 '&gt; ° 18 .55 and under 45 7 7 14 Over 45 5 1 &lt;&gt; Total 139 85 224 i </seg>
            <seg id="p019">TABLE III— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Biennium M. R rT | in B lc -v ■ 138 ~82 220 Separated _ . () 0 . 0 Married , _ j 3 4 Widow or Widower 0 0 0 Total I _ 139 224 TABLE IV— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Biennium _ M. F. T. Able to read and write 48 ?6 74 Unable to read and write Z......11....Z 91 59 150 Total •—•■•- — ■'• -.. 139 85 224 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Biennium M. ~~F\ tT Nebraska TI — — ; — U. S. other than Nebraska ~ £ Vi, z\ Russia ~ 34 I' S3 Switzerland : ; . ' ' { n Unknown ...: i - ' ~ o 5 13 Total : ■ ■ 139 85 224 TABLE VI-PARENTAGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Biennium 1 M. F. T. Both native born o? i^ . ., Both foreign born _. "" " " ,q l ii -Mixed ; -" y ,* &amp; Unknown _ ....Z!.*Z1".'.~Z!!! 22 17 3&lt;) Total '- - ■•• 1 39 85 224 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">TABLE VII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR THE FIRST TIME AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT THE END OF BIENNIUM Total for Actually remaining Bicnnium at Institution M. F. T. M. F. T. Adams 10 1 6 5 11 Antelope 12.? &lt;) S 17 Banner Oil oil Blaine 0 0 0 0 1 1 Boone : 1 3-4 8 - K 16 Box Butte 2 0 2 2 1 .5 Boyd 12.? 14 5 Brown _ 0 0 0 2 2 4 Buffalo : 2 2 -1 13 f&gt; V) Burt 0 2 2 5 7 12 Butler 0 0 0 10 &lt;&lt; U. Cass .- 3 0 3 13 S 21 Cedar 112 ft 2 8 Chase 112 13 4 Cherry , 0 0 0 .5 14 Cheyenne .-. _ " 11 2 3 5 Clay _ 10 1 4 4 X Colfax 1 0 1 . 6 1 7 Cuming 3 0 3 ') 1 10 Custcr I... 1 2 .V 10 21 31 Dakota 3 0 3 11 2 13 Dawes '. L 10 1 5 4 9 Dawson : 10.1 369 Dixon 0 11 3 4 7 Dodge 112 16 4 20 Douglas 45 IN '&gt;3 135 85 220 Dunciy 10 1 2 2 4 Fillmore 2 0 2 7 4 11 Franklin 0 0 0 3 4 7 Frontier 0 11 5 16 Furnas .-. 3 0 3 • . 5 4 ') Gage .. 6 5 11 24 25 4 ( .&gt; Garfield :. 0 11 0 2 2 Gosper 0 11 12 3 Grcely ...112 358 Hall 5 0 5 11 4 15 Hamilton :_ 0 0 0 0 11 Harlan 2 0 2 4 2 6 Hayes 2 0 2 2 13 Hitchcock 0 11 3 0 3 Holt 2 13 4 6 10 Hooker 0 11 Oil Howard 10 1 3 2 5 Jefferson _.... 11 2 4 7 11 Johnson 10 1 2 3 5 Kearney 0 0 0 112 Keith _.. 0 0 0 2 1 3 Keya Paha 0 11 2 13 Kimball _ 10 1 112 Knox _ 11 2 4 9 13 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 TABLE VII— COUNTY OP RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR THE FIRST TIME AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT THE END OF BIENNIUM .(Continued) |&#132; M. F. T. M. J. r. ' Lancaster: j 7 9 if, 47 4,, &#132;',.{'. Lincoln , 2 1 .1 '111 &gt;0 Logan ....; () 0 0 10 1 '-°UP 0 0 0 10 1 £ adison 0.1 1 5 X 1.1 derrick 2 0 2 7 4 11 Morrill _ ■__ 0 0 0 Oil Nance 000 0 &gt; j Ncmnliu _ _. 1 1 ± H 12 20 Nuckolls 112 12 7i T« &lt;""e 2 1 .1 8 (1 U Pawnee 2 1 .1 S ■ ■ 8 11 Perkins :.... (10 0 2 15 I'helps 0 2 2 5 1 s I'ierce (I (I 0 ,"j '1 1 Platte 114 7 .1 10 Polk 2 0 2 2 1 \ Keel Willow 0 0 0 I 5 (, Richardson .1 2 5 10 10 ?0 Rock 0 0 0 .2 I ' ~&gt; Saline 0 .1 .1 ~&gt; 7 11 Sarpy 2 0 2 7 0 ■ 7 Saundcrs 2 .1 5 ' 4 7 11 Scotts Hluff 1 0 1. .1 4 7 Scward .' 2 2 4 5 4 0 Sheridan _. 1 0 1 !l 1 4 Sherman 2 0 2 2 .1 S Sioux 0.2 2 0 2 2 Stanton 0 0 0 &gt; "^ 5 State Wards 0 (I 0 112 Thaycr 0.1 1 ,S \ '■ &lt;) Thomas 1 0 1 2 0 2 Thurston 0 11 S 11 19 Valley 0 0 0 7 .1 10 Washington 2 0 2 7 1 10 Wayne 0 0 0 1 ? 1 Webster 0 11 .3 3 6 Wheeler 10 1 '1 1 York 10 1 2 4 6 Total 139 85 224 ~~5K4 476 1.060 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">TABLE VIII— HEREDITARY INFLUENCE Total for Bicnnium '" - M. ~. tT Hereditary taint denied ,~p yj i 01 Father and mother feeble-minded 17 jo 77 Father or mother insane r, 5 "J] Father or mother intemperate ](, 7 ■?■$ (fraud parents insane ...'.....'.'.'. 4 1 5 Parents blood related 4 1 5 L'ncles, aunts or cousins feeble-minded 0 u 15 Brothers or sisters feeble-minded 18 13 31 Brothers or sisters insane I) 1 1 Unknown ' 26 7 33 " Total '. ]f,2 90 252 TABLE IX— CONDITION OF THOSE DISCHARGED FROM INSTITUTION AND WHILE ON PAROLE (DOES NOT INCLUDE DEATHS) Total for Bicnnium '_ ' M. R t7 Much improved \ U 1 12 Moderately improved _ 6 17 Slightly improved 8 2 10 Unimproved 7 18 Total 32 5 37 TABLE X— CAUSE OF DEATH.- DIED AT INSTITUTION Total for ■ Bicnuiurn _____■■ Ml ~~^' T - Acciclvnt ' 2 0 2 Acute Mania I 1 0 I Apoplexy : .11S.ZZZ.......\ (13/ Itrouchitis ' - ] 0 &lt; Carcinoma 1 1 i Kiiteritis 1 d f •Kpilcpsy g 1 ](, (iastric L'lcer 1 0 1 Heat Prostration 3 (I 3 I lydrocephalus 1 2 3 Influenza 10 1 Mela not ic Sarcoma 0 1 1 Mitral Rt'KiirKitatioii .....!.!.. Z.! 0 2 2 Myocarditis 2 0 2 Nephritis 1 0 1 Pneumonia 3 4 7 Pulmonary Emphysema 1 2 3 Suicide ...' 1 0 1 Tuberculosis 5 5 10 Unknown Chronic Disease 1 0 1 Total 35 21 56 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">TABLE XI— PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN INSTITUTION OF THOSE WHO DIED AT INSTITUTION DURING THE BIENNIUM ENDING JUI 1 "! 30, 1931 Total for Biennium _____ _ . M. R tT I. ess than one month 2 0 2 1 to 6 months 2 3 5 - 6 to 12 months 2 0 2 1 to 2 years 2 0 2 2 to 5 years 7 4 U 5 to 10 years 9 y k, 10 to 20 years 10 4 14 20 to 30 years : 0 3 . 3 Over 30 years 10 1 Total : 35 21 S6~ TABLE XII— AGE OF THOSE WHO DIED AT INSTITUTION Total for Biennium M. F. t7 Under 10 3 3 Z 10 and under 15 2 2 4 15 and under 20 ; 12 0 12 20 and under 25 4 3 7 25 and under 30 5 3 8 30 and under 35 _ _.. 1 1 2 35 and unded 40 ;.. 1 3 4 40 and under 45 , 0 1 1 45 and under 50 3 14 Over 50 ,. 4 4 « Total 35 2T 5fT 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">TABLE XIII— AVERAGE NUMBER OF PATIENTS EMPLOYED Average Number Employed Population Per Cent : — ~ — ■ — — — — — - — : — Average Employed In Ward Outside Ward Aggregate M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. ¥7' T. U. FV "FT" During period ending June 30. 1931 : 142 14 1 283 139 125 264 281 266 547 473 408 881 59% 65% 62% TABLE XIV— RATIO OF EMPLOYES TO PATIENTS Ratio M. F. T. Number of physicians, including Superintendent .' 3 0 3 Ratio of physicians to patients _ 1 to 294 Number of nurses, ward attendants and supervisors (day) .._ , _ 9 19 28 Ratio of same to patients . L .. .... „ 1 to 32 Number of nurses and ward attendants (night).— _ „ , 4 6 10 Ratio of same to patients" __Ito 88 Total day and night nurses, ward attendants, and supervisors 13 25 38 Ratio of same to patients _ _ _ 1 to 23 Total officers and employes _ _ _ _ 36 49 85 Ratio of same to patients _ _. 1 to 10 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY, on hand June 30, 1931 Number Value Cattle (,7 $6,700.00 Chickens 710 706.00 Ducks 5() 45.00 •ii'cse 34 ■ 47.50 Hogs 144 1,942.00 Horses ! 8 400.00 Mules H) 1,360.00 Turkeys 20 60.00 Total j $11,260.60 FARM PRODUCTS, July.l, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total Produced Total Disposed of T . ota ,' °" !»"* ; J_^™&gt;™ | Measure \ aluc Mcasuro Va|||u Alfalfa i 321 t. $3,852.00 261 t. $3,132.00 60. t. $720 00 Corn 5.700 bit. 4,560.00 5.700 lui, 4,560.00 Knsilage \ 243 t. 2.430.00 243 t. 2.430.00 Oats ! 2.404 1m. 961.60 2.404 hu. 'JOl.OO Oats, straw ' *)&gt;/&gt; t. 88 50 29'/, t. 88.50' '. Potatoes 2.000 l)u. 2.400.00 2.000 hu. 2.400.00 Wheat 1. ?&gt;2 l.u. &lt;X)4.40 1.292 bu. 904.40 Wheat, straw ... 8 t. 24.00 8 t. 24.00 Total $15,220.50 $14,500.50 $720.00 DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 39j 1931 Total _ Produced and disposed of Measure Value I--KRS , .-. 8.429 doz. $ 2,107.25 Milk 704.892 lbs. 21,146.76 Total • $Z?,254.O1 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July I, 1929 to June .30, 1931 Total Produced and Consumed Measure Value Asparagus 3,500 lbs. $ 245 00 Beans, string 0,500 lbs, 13000 Ueets 25,000 lbs. 1.000.00 Cabbage 120,000 lbs. 2400 00 Carrots 35.000 lbs. 1 050XK) Cauliflower 11,000 lbs. 660 00 Corn, popcorn 600 lbs 24~00 Corn, sweet 70,000 lbs. 2100 00 Cucumbers 18,000 lbs. '36000 Lettuce 18,000 lbs. 90000 Melons, musk 35,000 lbs. 700 00 Onions, green 30.000 lbs. 1200 00 Onions, dry 55,000 lbs. 2,750 00 Peas, green 8.000 lbs. 560 00 Parsnips 11,000 lbs. 330 00 Peppers 3.000 lbs. 300.00 Potatoes, sweet 25,000 lbs. 1 250 00 Pumpkins 18,000 lbs. 18000 Radishes „ 35.000 lbs. 700 00 Rliubarb _. 145,000 lbs.' 5.800'(H) Spinach 22,000 lbs. 880.00 Iomatoes ' 79,000 lbs. 1,580 00 Turnips 75.000 lbs. 1500 00 Cherries 1,548 lbs. 139 32 Strawberries 1,984 lbs. . 238.08 Total value ! ' $26.976.40 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">Report of the Girls' Training School Geneva, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p029">GIRLS' TRAINING SCHOOL GENEVA, NEBRASKA OFFICERS LENA E. WARD Superintendent SUDE B. WARD - - - - - . . Assistant Superintendent ELLA GOSSIX .... Secretary J. IUXBY. M. n. - - ... Physician Miscellaneous Statement fjirls ami Hoys' Industrial School founded IS-7'J-lS'Jl Kstablishcri as Girls' Industrial School .-. 1,S«&gt;1 Number of employes June 30, 1931 26 Number of inmates June 30. 1931 \J) I Holiest number of inmates during bicunium I'M Per ea]&gt;ita cost per month ■ $ 2').2/ Number of acres owned : '. 70 Number of acres leased _ 25 Number of acres under cultivation ;. '.' 5,s Value of lands and buildings, furniture and equipment : ; . $2.%.127.. : il i Principal industries: Gardening, dairying, 'sewing, and canning. Visiting &lt;lays : Every day except Sundays ami 1 lolidays, S :30 A. M. to 1 1 :30 A. M. and i :30 P. M. to 4:30 P. M. Admission to the school. is by commitment by court of competent jurisdiction, and girls arc required to remain until they are 21 years old, unless sooner released by parole or otherwise. 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control nf Stale Institutions. - Lincoln, Nebraska. It is with pleasure thai 1 submit, for your consideration, the nineteenth biennial report of the Girls' Training School at Geneva. 1 he past two years have been years of unusual progress! and improvement. The general conduct and health of the girls have been very good, and their progress m educational and vocational training most satisfactory. For the first time m the history of this school, we have been able to give personal supervision to paroled girls'. Last February, a field secretary was employed to devote her entire time to this work. We were successful m obtaining a woman trained and experienced m dealing with unfortunate girls, and. while she lias been employed Inn a few months, a great deed of progress has been shown by reason of her acquaintance with conditions m the state. We were much m need of additional quarters for colored girls. This need was cared for during the biennium by the building of "Paul Lawrence Dunbar Cottage" which is now Occupied by thes;. - girls. Our -supply rooms, kitchens and living rooms have been re - paired and needed equipment and furniture added. ( kir new poultry plant, built during the past biennium. was constructed and equipt m accordance with the ideas of one of the best authorities. Xew tire equipment, m every building, and additional water lines and fire hydrants have been installed, insuring better tire protection. Heating and pipe lines have been taken out of the ground and put into concrete tunnels, thus adding years to the life of the pipe. Pipe lines now make it possible to supply our gardens and lawns with water whenever needed. Besides the betterments outlined, many minor repairs an.l im - provements have been made to grounds and buildings during the biennium. In closing, 1 desire to express my deepest appreciatation to the members of the Hoard of Control for their cooperation and counsel, and 1 wish to thank the members of the staff for their loyal and help - ful support. Yours respectfully, LENA E. WARD, Superintendent. 29 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June 30, 19.31 Present :it beginning of period 178 Admitted lir&gt;t time •. ..................." 125 On parole at beginning of period 21 Returned from transfer 3 Total on books for the period .327 Discharged from institution 57 Discharged while on parole 49 Died ?.. \ 1 Transferred to other institutions 7 On parole at end of period 34 Total leaving institution _ _ _.. 148 Total remaining at the institution at' end of period 179 Average number inmates during biennium 184 TABLE II— COLOR AND AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 \V. Q T7 Under ten , 1 0 1 Ten years and under twelve '. , 0 4 4 Twelve years and under fifteen 28 5 3.V Fifteen years and under seventeen 59 6 65 Seventeen years .-. 22 0 22 Total ._.._.. no 15 125 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">TABLE lII— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED " '. FOR FIRST TIME Total for . Bicimiuni I'irst grade : 2 Third grade 5 Fourth grade ; 2 Fifth frraclc ~, Sixth grade ■ 17 Seventh grade 18 Kighth grade : 26 Ninth grade 29 Tenth grade 14 Klcvc'iitli grade 5 Twelfth grade : 1 Total [ p$ , j . . TABLE IV-j-CAUSE FOR ADMISSION OF THOSE ADMITTED , I FOR FIRST TIME mm *__ i ' Total for Bienniuin Delinquent unclassified 125 Total 125 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME j " . Total for I Bicnnium Nebraska ! fis Other States than Nebraska : 54 Canada j , 1 Unknown :~c. 5 Total L: .: 1 125 ; 1 , I TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Bicnnium United States both parents 91 Foreign , 10 Unknown 24 Total ; 125 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">TABLE VII— PARENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED- Total for Bicnnium Parents both dead ' 3 Father dead 17 M other dead _ . _ 26 Parents living together 46 Parents separated 31 Unknown _ 2 Total : 125 TABLE VIII— AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED Total for Biennium Age at death of father : Under ten years 1? Under fifteen years : : 3 Age at death of mother : . Under ten years 22 Under fifteen years 6 ■&gt; Fifteen and over 1 Total ! 44 TABLE IX— COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF GIRLS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Total for Biennium Biennium Adams 2 Jefferson , ] Booue 3 Lancaster 14 Box Butte 3 Lincoln 3 Buffalo 2 Madison 2 Cass 1 Merrick 3 Chase 1 Morrill : 1 Cheyenne 1 Nemaha 1 Custcr 1 Pierce 1 Uawes : 3 Platte 1 Dawson 3 Polk 1 Dodge 4 Red Willow 3 Douglas 43 Richardson 3 Dundy 1 Scotts Bluff 3 Franklin : 1 Sheridan 3 (iage 2 Thurston 1 Hall 5 Valley 1 Hayes 1 Webster 2 Holt 1 York 1 Total _ 125 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">''■ TABLE X— PAROLE STATISTICS Number &lt;m parole July 1, 1929 I 21 Number paroled during hiennium , 7.? Number returned from parole' during biennium j 11 Number discharged while on parole during biennium 49 Number on parole July 1, 1931 .54 .'■ • LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On Hand June 30. 19.51 Number Value Cattle 25 ' $2,563.08 Chickens 2,024 71.5 ..55 Geese .55 .51.75 Guineas 35 18.25 Hogs : 44 574.0(1 Horses 2 200.0(1 Total : $4.100.4.5 DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCE July 1. 1929 to June .50. 19.51 Total produced Measure Value Kgg* .' 6.252 doz. $9.57.80 Milk : 215,426 lbs. 4,079.10 ■Total \ $5,016.90 FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total Produced Measure Value Alfalfa 18 t. $180.00 Knsilage 25 t. 90.00 Pasture 75.00 Total |_ $345.00 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Produced and Consumed ■ Measure Value Asparagus - - 413 lbs. $80 10 Itcans, dried 900 lbs. 36.0(1 Jeans, green 250 bu. 402.03 »cet* ; - 150 bu. 150.00 I arrots 51 hu "ii (HI &lt;-.«&gt;ni 650 doz. 97.50 Cucumbers ;_ _ 4,155 |b s . 166.20 Knhl-Kabi 528 lbs. 2640 l-cttuce 1.500 lbs. 45J)0 Onions, dried 6,516 lbs 195.48 Onions, green 620 doz. 62.0(1 "arsnips 60 lbs 3.00 Peas _ _ _ _ 3,567 lbs! 214.56 Poppers _ 32 lbs. 3.20 Potatoes 887 bu. 1,650.50 Radishes _ * 1,104 doz. 55.20 Rhubarb 1.709 lbs. 102.54 Spinach 300 lbs. 24.00 Tomatoes 442 bu 44200 Turnips _ 300 bu. . 300.00 Strawberries .*._ _„ 105 qts. 21.00 Total value $4,127.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Report of the Soldiers and Sailors' Homes GRAND ISLAND AND MILFORD, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p037">NEBRASKA SOLDIERS AND SAILORS' HOME GRAND ISLAND, NEBRASKA OFFICERS IVAN S. GALLANT - Commandant A. M. SALAK - - - - . Adjutant J. M. TR1PLETT - • . . . Physician NEVAU. CUMMINGS - . - - - - . Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established '. ] gg/ Number of employes June 30, 1931 7y Number of inmates June 30, 1931 229 Highest number of inmates during bicnnium 304 Per capita cost per month $ 41.22 Number of acres owned 640 Number of acres under cultivation 400 Value of lands and buildings, furniture and equipment $008,812.70 Principal industries: Farming and gardening. Visiting days : Visitors are welcome every day. Honorably discharged soldiers, sailors, marines and hospital nurses, who have become disabled by reason of military service, old age or otherwise, from earning a livelihood, and are dependent upon public or private charities, are eligible to membership in the homes. Wives and mothers of ex-soldiers, as well as the widows and mothers of those who died in the service, who have. reached fifty years of age and are unable to earn a livelihood, are also eligible. The amount of pension an applicant receives has no bear - ing in determining his right to membership. Applicants for admission must also be bona fide residents of Nebraska of at least two years' standing. Applications are made to the county board of the county of residence on blanks furnished by the county clerk. 36 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. It is with pleasure that I submit my first, and. the institution's twenty-second, biennial report, for the period ending June 30. 1931. During this two-year period the new adniinistr.it inn building has been erected and two new boilers installed. A new grinding room and granary were also built. Two parks were made and over three thousand shrubs and plants set out on the grounds. A new gate-way was constructed, and the old iron lamp-posts mi tin - grounds replaced with concrete posts. Pershing .Hospital and the Lincoln liuilding were painted on the outside and redecorated inside. The barns and outbuildings were all painted, also the chapel. The parkings were curbed up and shrubs and flowers planted m them. A nursery with several hundred young trees and shrub:; was starterK The frame house south of the hospital, known as the ■'adjutants house" was remodeled, modernized, and the grounds landscape 1. Through the kind cooperation and assistance of the Governor and the Hoard of Control I feel that the institution is becoming l better equiped to take care of Nebraska's war veterans and their wives and widows. Respectfully submitted, IVAN S. GALLANT, Commandant. 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">38 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OP POPULATION Period cndiiiR June 30, 193] , M. F. "FT Present :»t beginning of period 78 jlO ]88 Admitted _ 40 47 $? Readmitted , U 7 m On furlough granted before commencement of this period 54 153 207 Transferred from another institution 112 Returned from transfer 2 1 ■« 3 ' Total _. 186 .319 505 Discharged (honorably) _ 31 ■ \\ 4? D 'cd • 29 40 69 1 ransferred to another institution _ 10 8 18 Dropped _ 6 i 2 8 Total '. - _. 76 61 137" Total membership _ 110 258 368 - ()n furlough at end of period 35 104 ■ 139 Total in Institution' 75 154 229 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 . -M. ~¥. T~ Under fifty 16 0 16 Fifty and under sixty „ _ 7 8. 15 Sixty and under seventy '. 5 10 15 Seventy and under eighty ■.. 1 12 13 Kighty and under ninety _ 11 14 25 Over ninety : 0 3 3 Total „ _.. 40 47 87 TABLE III— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 M^ K T7 Single _ 13 0 13 Married _ 18 10 28 Widowed _ „. 9 37 46 Total ; _ 40 47 87~ </seg>
            <seg id="p040">TABLE IV— OCCUPATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1&lt;)31 ■ T - Barber i 7) i Blacksmith ZZZZZZ 2 () &gt; Carpenter .' ' - 1 n 7 E«* ::::::::::;:.:::.::. { !i Farmer •- (, 0 f, rireman- j 0 , Housewife .........JZZ'Z'Z'ZZZ. ' 0 47 47 Laborer • ■ 12 0 12 Newspaper man ] 0 j Painter , ; j () j Salesman ; , j 0 . Soda clerk ' j q , £ etired - ......Z.1ZZZZ. 6 0ft None • 6 0 6 Total - - -■■ ~40 47 W TABLE V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30. 1931 ' M. R T~ United States .'. 7T 7^ Canada ] [ZZZZ o 1 1 Denmark i n J England : ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZli \ \ \ France j 0 j Nova Scotia ..._ 1 n i k™&gt;* - •■•■:•-:::::::::.:::■•■ \ g \ Total - - - 40 47 87 TABLE VI— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF PERIOD Total for period jLT^ ■ M. F. ■ T. M. F. T. Adams.... 0 3 3 H 2t 3S~ Antelope 112 2 2 4 Boone 2 13 0 3 3 Box Butte 0 0 0 12 3 Buffalo 0 4 4 4 14 18 Butler 0 0 0 0 11 Cass 0 0 0 2 0 2 Cedar — : 10 1 10 1 Cherry — 0 0 0 10 1 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">TABLE VI— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF PERIOD (Continued) Total for period A " Rc ™ ai "j" g . June 30, 1931 M. ,F. T. M7~ F. t7~ L ; ia &gt;- () i i ~ o 3 3 &lt; olfax Oil 044' t'uster ■ 0 (I 0 J • 5 8 Dawcs I) 1 l 1 12 Dawson 10 1 0 3 3 Dodge 112 3 2 5 Douglas : 11 (, 17 13 2 " 40 Dundy 10 1 0 0 0 l'lllniore 0 0 0 0 2 2' Fnii.klin 0 0 () 0 3 frontier 0 (&gt;• 0 0 1 \ Pumas 0 1 1 &gt; \ '• 3 •iage 0 0 0 3 3 "(, ('.arficld 1 0 1 3 7 10 ■ (Jrceley 0 11 0 11 Hall ..: V) 14 33 27 54 HI I familton 0 2 2 2 7') Harlan 0 0 0 0 3 3 Hitchcock 1 0 1 () 0 0 Holt 0 0 0 14 5 Howard ;.... 0 11 0 5 5 Jefferson 0 0 0 112 Kearney ; .&gt;. 0 0 0 0 11 Keith ..". , 0 0 0 . 1 2 3 Knox 0 0 0 3 5 k l.ancaster 3 0 3 1 . 8 ■ ,. -9 . Lincoln 112 0 0 0 '-"tip 0 1-1 0 0 0 Mernck 0 1 1 0 4 4 •N'ance 10 1 10 1 Ncmaha 10 1 Oil Nuckolls 112 0 2 2 Otoc 0 0 0 2 13 I'helps 0 . 0 I) 1 4 5 Plattc 0 2 2 0 11 1'olk 0 0 0 0,1 3 l^ock Oil () 1 1 Saline 0 0 0 Oil Sarpy 0 1 1 0- ■ '• 3 ■■ 1 Scotts Hluff 10 1 3 0 3 Si-ward ....; 1 12 1 •&gt; ? Sheridan 0 I) 0 0.1 1 Sherman 0 0 0 0 1 1 Thayer 0 0 0 1 2 ? Valley 1 1 2 4 3 7 .',',',' Washington 4 3 7 8 13 21. Wayne _ 0 0 0 0 3 - 3 '■ Webster 0 2 2 2 4 6 Wheeler 10 1 0 1 1 York 0 3 3 18 0 Total. 54 5d 110 110 258 368 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">TABLE VII— NATURE OF SERVICE ON WHICH ADMISSION IS BASED Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F\ rT War in which enlisted : Civil 20 45 fiS Indian -. () () () Spanish American IS 7 25 World _ If, 4 20 Total , ~54 56 110 Division of service : ' Artillery 2 1 3 Bombing Squadron 10 1 Cavalry 3 5 8 Casualty Department * 1 1 2 Chemical Department 112 Depot Brigade 2 0 2 Engineer ...-. : ' 1 ~ . Ciraves Registry Service 1 0 1 Infantry 38 47 Ka Medical Department 2 U I Quartermaster Corps i 0 1 Navy :■■ ' " \_ Total : — 54 56 110 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 TABLE VIII— STATE OF ENLISTMENT Period ending June 30, 19.31 m. x t7 Colorado ; ' ' 2 0 2 Illinois : 7 15 2' Indiana '. 2 } 5 Iowa - . j ' (l jf, Kansas _ _ 2 13 Massachusetts 0 j ". Michigan u ] 1 Minnesota ] j 2 Missouri v _ 2 3 5 Montana 10 1 * cbr: Vl k a : ._1."ZZZ 17 ■ 10 27 New \ ork ; _ 2 2 4 North Carolina 10 1 Ohio _ 7 5 j 2 Pennsylvania ...". _ j 2 1 South Dakota 1 i\ \ . T . .................. — 1 1/ 1 \ ermont .::t 112 Virginia 2 1 3 Wisconsin _ 1 4 S Total _. _.. 54 56 i7o~ TABLE IX— AGE OF THOSE WHO DIED Period ending June 30, 1931 - ■ Ml R t7~ 50 and under 60 j j 2 CiO and under 70 2 5 7 70 and under 80 _ 1 10 11 NO and under 90 _ „. 21 23-44 90 or over ; 4 1 5 Total 29 40 ' 69 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">TABLE X— PERIOD OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE WHO DIED Period ending June 30. 1931 ■ u. v. r~ I.ess than 6 months .-. 2 4 6 6 months to 1 year 3 4 7 1 to 2 years 16 7 2 to 5 years 6 &lt;) 15 5 to 10 years 7.8 15 10 to 20 years 8 6 14 20 to 30 years 13 4 30 to 35 years 1 0 1 Total '. 29 40 W DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCE July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total Produced and Disposed of Measure Value Milk '. _ __. 568.807 lbs. $14,451.97 Krks 10,765 doz. 2,150.37 Total : • $16,602.34 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On Hand June 30. 1931 Number Value Chickens 2,600 $1,300.00 Cattle 71 8.875.00 I logs : 228 2,280.00 Horses ; 12 1.200.00 Mules 2 125.00 Total ...: $13,780.00 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total Produced __ Measure Value Alfalfa 690,000 lbs. $3,215.00 Barley 256,176 lbs. 2.809.20 Barley, straw 300,000 lbs. .300 00 &lt;-.ane 70.000 lbs. .380.00 1 &lt;""" 197.400 lbs. 2.595.00 Knsilage 480.000 lbs. 1.200.00 °ats .31.040 lbs. 582.00 Oats, straw 20.000 lb.i: 20.00 Pasturage 795 00 R.ve : 108,304 lbs. 1.012.50 Rye. straw ; 250.000 lbs. 250.00 Sudan K rass 16,000 lbs. 40.00 T "t"l •; J2.418.920 lbs. $13,198.70 GARDEN PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total Produced Measure Value Beans, string 1,248 lbs. . $124.80 }\™\ s ' ■■ 9,735 lbs. 186.60 .al&gt;l&gt;aRe 74 , y ,, )S ]27M Larrnts : ; 18,830 lbs. " 237.90 lorn, sweet : : ; 5,520 ll )s . 1.39.20 Cucumbers , 12,7.32 lbs. 209.55 1 ettuce (,,036 l| )s . 343.00 Onions 18,753 lbs 670.82 Parsnips 22.000 lbs! 825.00 Peas 1,320 lbs. 92.40 Peppers '_„. 354 || )s . 17.70 Potatoes 90,240 lbs. 2.645.20 Potatoes, sweet '.. .... .3.575 lbs. 131.25 Kadisbes : 5.885 lbs 168.45 Rbubarb '. .3.540 lbs. 103.00' Squash l.]()0 lbs. 110.00 Tomatoes .-. 29,715 lbs. 466.92 Turnips ; 9,460 lb.s. 142.70 Total 247.462 lbs. $6,741.57 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">SOLDIERS AND SAILORS' HOME MILFORD, NEBRASKA OFFICERS CHARLES F. JACKSON - Commandant THOMAS SWEARINGEN - ... Adjutant J. G. MUIR, M. D. .... Physician FLORENCE CRIST - - ... Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established : ... 1X95 Number of employes June 30, 1931 44 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 10/ Highest number of inmates during biennium 151 Per capita cost per month $ 44.97 Number of acres owned 41 Number of acres under cultivation '. ;; Value of lands and buildings, furniture and. equipment ..., : $2(&gt;8,477.O7 Visiting clays: Visitors are welcome every day. In the hospital, visiting hours 2. P. M. to 4 P. M. 1 lonorably discharged soldiers, sailors, marines anil hospital nurses, who have become disabled by reason of military service, old age or otherwise, from earning a livelihood, and are dependent upon public or private charities, are eligible to membership in the homes. Wives and mothers of ex-soldiers, as well as the widows and mothers of those who died in the service, who have reached fifty years of age and are unable to earn a livelihood, are also eligible. The amount of pension an applicant receives has no bear - ing in determining his right to membership. Applicants for admission must also be bona fide residents of Nebraska of at least two years' standing. Applications are made to the county board of the county of residence on blanks furnished by the county clerk. 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. It is with pleasure that 1 submit my first biennial report. During the past bierinium the veterans of the Civil War have dropped from the ranks quite rapidly. However, veterans of the Spanish American and the World War have more than taken their places. The general health of the members has been very good. They have been much pleased with our efforts m trying to make the grounds and buildings more beautiful. This has done a great deal toward their contentment and happiness, and the result has been better health. We have continued our work of redecorating the rooms, and most of them have been redecorated. The painter is now painting the exterior of the Roosevelt Hospital which will add much to its appearance. We have also redecorated the office, and we have a new fireproof vault for the safe-keeping of many valuable papers consigned to our care. ' Awnings have been placed on the hospital and the Sherman building, and the porches on the hospital have been screened, adding greatly to the comfort of patients during hot weather. We have installed natural gas m our kitchens and the power plant. The experiment has been more than satisfactory m regard to cooking; how successful it will be for heating can only be learned after we have gone through the winter. We are building a new, up-to-date chicken house. This was our first year m the chicken business, and we have been quite successful. During the beinnium, we have been confronted with the problem of water shortage, our wells one mile east of the institution having gone suddenly dry. We are now testing wells at a depth of two hundred feet, right near the stand-pipe on the home grounds. If the test proves successful, and it now gives promise of so doing, we should be able to replace the old wells at a much lower figure than the cost of the original wells. Sincere thanks is extended to the Governor, the Hoard of Control, patriotic organizations and the officers of the institution who have helped to make the past biennium the best ever. Respectfully submitted, CHAS. F. JACKSON, . Commandant. 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">47 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending Juno 30, 1931 M. F\ T. Present at beginning of period 40 54 &lt;J4 Admitted for first time _ _ •. 43 50 93 Readmitted 8 3 11 On furlough at beginning of period 25 03 88 Transferred from other institutions 3 2 5 Total : 119 172 Zn" Died in Institution 16 22 38 Discharged 24 7 31 On furlough not returned during period 36 76 ■ 112 Transferred to other institutions .'. 2 13 Total 78 106 184 Remaining at end of period 41 66 107 Total membership, June 30. 1931 77 141 218 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 M. R T. 30 and under 40 8 0 8 40 and under 50 2 0 2 50 and under 60 10 7 17 60 and under 70 .. 7 5 12 70 and under 80 . 6 15 21 80 and under 90 6 20 26 90 and under 100 .... 4 3 7 ' Total : 43 50 93 TABLE III— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 U. F. T~ S^guTT.Z. . 28 0 28 Married .'. : 10 6 16 Widowed 5 44 49 Total : i ■■■ -■ 43 50 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 TABLE IV— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 19.51 ' _| M. F^ T. United States other than Nchraska 35 . 45 80 N'ebraska 4 3 7 Bohemia \ 2 0 2 Canada ; fl 1 \ Kngland ..: 0 1 1 Germany 1 0 1 Poland :. 1 0 1 Total .......... ;. I 43 50 93 TABLE V— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 ■ M. F. T? Chiropractor 1 0 1 Farmer 10 0 10 Housewives : 0 50 5(1 Laborer 31 0 31 Plumber 1 0 1 Total : ! 43 50 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">TABLE VI— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending .June 30, 1931 I M. F\ T? Antelope 0 1 T~ Boone 10 1 Hurt : _ 112 £ IS . S • •-■ I..""". 0 1 T D«'«lBe , 0 1 1 Douglas 18 lo 28 Furnas , 0 1 1 (•api -. ■&gt; j = Haii ■ ::::::::: :::::.. t 2 3 , 0 1 ] Lancaster y&gt; 15 77 piatte : :...'..".'"."."."'. 1 1 2 Richardson 112 Saunders : 0 4 4 Scward : ,. ....V..V.........I 3 6 9 Thurston 112 York 2 0 2 Tota ' Ai 50 93 TABLE .VII— NATURE OF SERVICE ON WHICH ADMISSION IS BASED ■ . . Period ending June 30, 1931 . - . \ Males War in which enlisted: •Civil _ 8 Spanish American 15 World War 19 Indian War _ 1 Total ! 4I Division of service: (a) Volunteers 29 ( b) Drafted 14 Total ~ 43 (c) Artillery '... . \ (d) Infantry 40 (c) Cavalry 1 ( f ) Navy , 1 Total ; 43 49 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">TABLE VIII— STATE OF ENLISTMENT OF MEN ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 Males Illinois 4 Iowa 4 Kansas 2 Nebraska . ?5 oi,io ...: : ;.... , Pennsylvania 2 South Dakota : : 1 Wisconsin 2 Wyoming -. 2 Total : 43 TABLE IX— AGE AT DEATH Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. . t7 Ml and under 70 0 0 q 70 and under 80 _ 0 y 9 .Sfl and under 90 ; 14 12 if, ')0 and under 100 ". 2 1 .? Total 16 22 38 TABLE X— PERIOD OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE WHO DIED Period ending June 30, 1931 . M. FV T\ Less than 6 months _ _ _ 3 S 8 From 6 to 12 months "', 10 1 From 1 to 2 years _ _ 0 11 From 2 to 5 years : _ _ _.. 12 11 23 From 5 to 10 years _ _ „_. 0 3 3 From 10 to IS years _ _ 0 2 2 Total _ _ 16 22 38~ 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">TABLE XI— CAUSE OF DEATH I Period ciicliuK I June .30, 19.31 ; ; ! m. f. tT Arteriosclerosis \ 1 ? 3 Carcinoma 13 4 i crcbral hemorrhage 5 4 o Cirrhosis of the liver 0 j j Chronic nephritis 3 14 Krysipelas 0 1 1 Fall ; ; , 0 2 2 Uaiigrenc, I 0 T I Influenza I) 1 1 Myocarditis I 0 ] Pernicious anemia 10 1 Pneumonia 1 2 .3 Prostate growth 1 0 1 Thrombosis, of the leg ;. 0 1 1 Valvular heart disease 2 .3 5 Tola! ...: H, 22 38 LIVESTOCK On Hand June 30. 1931 Number Value Horses .: _ ■ 2 ? 150.011 • l»Rs 22 500.00 Cattle 18 . 1,600.00 Chickens . &lt;J40 [■ 564.00 Total I $2.814.01) GARDEN PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total produced and disposed of Measure Value Tomatoes 3,000 lbs. $ 60.00 Rhubarb ■. 4.000 lbs. 160.00 Potatoes 4,000 lbs. 80.00 Cucumbers 4,000 lbs. 80.00 Peas 100 lbs. 7.00 Turnips 500 lbs. 10.00 Onions, green 100 lbs. 4.00 Tota 1 $401 .00 FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 I Total produced and disposed of Measure Value Oats 6,400 $80.00 Alfalfa : ..; 16,000 96.00 Total : „ $176.00 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p053"/>
            <seg id="p054">Reports of the State Hospitals AT HASTINGS, LINCOLN, AND NORFOLK, NEBRASKA Including the Eighth Biennial Report of the Board of Examiners of Defectives </seg>
            <seg id="p055">HASTINGS STATE HOSPITAL INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA OFFICERS G. E. CHARLTON, M. D. - - - Superintendent WALTER E. KELLY. M. D. - Assistant Superintendent and Physician DORA M. JUDKINS-DAVIES, M. D. - Staff Physician C. R. LAIRD, M. D. ----.- Staff Physician H. H. STRETTON. M. D. - - - - Staff Physician JACOB PETERS - - - ' Dental Surgeon E. J. CAMBLIN - - - - - - - - - Steward LIBBIE G. THOKDSEN - - - - - - - Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established 1887 Number of employes June 30, 1931 '. 182 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 1,468 Highest number of inmates during biennium 1,492 Per capita cost per month !? 18 07 Number of acres owned 62.i Number of acres leased ■'. .0 Number of acres under cultivation 840 Value of lands and buildings, furniture and : equipment $1,746.9 KUD Principal industries : Farming and stock raising. Visiting days : Every day, 1 :00 to 4 :00 P. M. Admission to the hospital for the treatment of mental diseases is had only through commitment by the insanity board in each county, consisting of the clerk of the court, a physician and a lawyer. 54 </seg>
            <seg id="p056"/>
            <seg id="p057">To the Governor and the Roard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I have the honor of presenting herewith the Biennial Report &lt;&gt;f the Hastings State Hospital, which covers a period from July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931. As only four months of this Iliennium came under niv charge as Superintendent, 1 find it rather difficult to give a full and complete report. As a matter of record, Dr. J. P.laine Habcock resigned the Superintendency of this Institution March 10, 1931, and by your order, Dr. W. E. Kelly, the Assistant Superintendent, was placed temporarily m charge. I took charge of the Institution March 2&gt;. 1931, being transferred here from the Norkfolk State Hospital. During the Kicnnium, Dr. H. H. Stretton was appointed a member of the Medical Staff January 24, 1930. Dr. W. S. Yager resigned from the Medical Staff May 31, 1930 and Dr. C. K. laird was appointed to fill the vacancy June 5, 1930. Dr. C. \Y. Parks also resigned October 14, 1930. The continued increase m our population is a matter of rancern. The situation. is not peculiar to this hospital; it exists m ninny local - ities. Congestion has long been a perennial problem with which we have to deal. Statistical surveys conducted m various localities show mental disease and disorder developing at a rate m excess of that expected from the growth of population. The number of pa - tients with mental disease being cared for by the U. S. Veterans Bureau Hospitals is, approximately, twice as great as those with :physical ailments. Many reasons are described for the rapid growth m the number of patients coming to state hospitals. Some of them are economic conditions, more familiarity with improved methods of care and treatment now afforded, and the enlightenment and a greater dif - fusion of information concerning care and treatment. There has 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p058"/>
            <seg id="p059">also been a change of attitude on the part of relatives. Less reluc - tance is shown on the part of the newer generation to send relatives to an institution of this type. Family physicians show a greater interest m more familiarity with psychotic cases, and advocate early hospitalization, so that medical measures may be applied to the • incipient cases. The old idea of "insane asylum" has largely been replaced by the newer concepts. The great number of mild or benign cases of mental aberration admitted is encouraging, as they are amenable to treatment and usually are granted early parole. Staff meetings are held at frequent intervals, usually twice a week, at which time patients are brought up for diagnosis and a full description of their cases. These are illuminating and very benefit cial factors, and they serve to bring out many important points to stimulate each one to better work and more alert mental reactions. The patient benefits very materially, both mentally and physically. As a rule, this same procedure is followed before releasing a patient on parole. This distributes responsibility and gives the' advantage of advice of other members of the staff. Progress notes are made from time to time, as these enable us to establish contact with and determine the patient's condition. Any - one wishing to know about a patient's condition can ascertain the facts easily. It is regrettable that continuous records have not been kept as consistently m the past as we should like. So much of this work has not been done, due to the lack of time on the part of the physicians. There is a dire. need of an extra doctor on our Medical Staff at the present time. As a matter of treatment, Occupational Therapy is very import - ant. Many patients prefer to be occupied rather than. to remain idle on the wards, and those who are at all physically able are engaged m some work on the farm m the industrial buildings, or m some of the numerous activities m and about the hospital. Employment is given that is best suited for the patients' abilities. Visitors are always cordially received and conducted through the hospital. Relatives are encouraged to call, and mental ailments are frankly discussed with. them. We feel that these contacts will dispel fear and apprehension and leave a more friendly feeling for the hospital. Good will and a kindly attitude are as important m public as m private institutions, and these ideas are inculcated among our employes. 56 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">The general health of the patients and employes has been excelent. No epidemics or serious illnesses have occurred during the past two years. Religious services of the different denominations are held every Sunday afternoon, and all those who desire are encouraged to attend. The Ministerial Association of the City of Hastings appoints a minister to take charge of this work, and he usually has charge of the services a month at a time. Ground paroles are coveted privileges. Freedom of tin - grounds is granted as much as possible, as the liberty to come and go at will is much appreciated and encourages good behavior, as well as giving the patient confidence m himself. I wish to make grateful acknowledgement to the staff and the hospital personnel for their loyalty and allegiance to the hospital and the interests of those, m their charge. We also wish to extend thanks to the Board of Control for courtesies extended and help given throughout the period. Respectfully submitted, G. E. CHARLTON, Superintendent. 57 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">58 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June 30, 1931 ' M. F. T~ Present at beginning of period '. _ 852 593 1 445 Admitted for the first time 308 202 510 Readmitted 33 2 6 59 ( )n parole at beginning of period 113 38 151 On escape at beginning of period 18 0 18 Total 1.324 859 2,183 Died in institution ; 186 08 284 Discharged from institution ."." ]7 3 20 Tranferred to another institution . 3 () 3 Died while on parole .' ;....... 2 0 2 Discharged while on parole 113 79 \t)2 Died while on escape 10 1 Discharged while on escape 22 0 22 On parole at end of period '. ._.'.«.~ZZ 104 67 171 On escape at end of period 20 0 20 T"t"» 468 247 715 Total remaining in institution June 30, 1931 856 612 1,468 TABLE II— NATIVITY OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending ]ww 30, 1931 Fl T ' United States • 24K 174 422 'V lstr j :i 1 0 1 Canada 5 . ? 5 Czeclio-Slovakia ■ 4 T 5 Denmark ZZZZZZZZZ 6 2 8 Kngland : 2 0 2 Germany , 15 7 2 n H. . .* . !•' / _U ollaud 10 1 ' rc J ai «' ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ 1 34 tal &gt;' - : ■ : i 0 3 Jugo-Slavia 2 0 2 Mexico , ] 0 j Norway j j 2 £ oland Z'ZZZZIZZZZZ." 1 0 1 Kussia ; .4 g Sweden ■ j] 2 13' Switzerland 3 1 4 Unascertained l...".".Z.."...\. 3 5 8 Total •■'■ ■• :.. 308 202 510 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">. TABLE III— CITIZENSHIP OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. Citizens by birth _ . 248 174 422 Citizens by naturalization _ _ _ 24 10 34 Aliens - _ 10 0 10 Citizenship unascertained 26 18 44 Total _ .'.._ 308 202 510 TABLE IV— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 M^ ¥. t7 Adams ... v \(, 20 36 Arthur 112 !|;'»» cr : - 10 1 Blame 2 (I 2 Box Buttc .' _ 4 4 k Buffalo .. . .. 15 in ?^ Butler _ _ _ _ 1 2 3 Chase _ _ _ 2 2 4 Cherry 1 o i Chcvennc - .. 3 4 7 Clay ._ _.-. - _ 13 5 ]8 Colfax .' 3 2 5 Custer _ 16 5 21 Ouwson .—.... Ci 1 7 Douglas _ 57 14 71 Dundy _ _ _ 3 (&gt; &lt;) Fillmore - _ 6 17 Franklin _ 3 4 7 Frontier '. .". 2 0 2 Furnas 3 7 10 i ! 59 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">TABLE IV— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS (Continued) Period endin}* June 30. 1931 ■ M. R T\ *Jage _ ; \ j - t.ardcn y \ 7 (airfield ' , ,. ? (f reeky ~"~ 5 5 8 ( ,i°1P cr r ■ ZZZ: 2 I) 2 HamiH^-zz::::;:::: ! 9 1S , 2 | Marian ™" " ~ \ i U Hayes zz::::::iz::::::z:::::::""" 1 o * Hitchcock i , c Howard ;. Z"""ZZ"._..ZZI!~ZIZI 12 3 Jl'ffcTSOll ; _ o C Kearney Z!Z!Z!"ZZZ . 4 2 r. Keith . 1 i s Kimball ZZZZZZ " 4 0 4 J &lt;n " x .........r 3 0 3 Lancaster 7 4 11 Lincoln "" 3 5 i '•"e ;i » ZZZZZZZZZ 1 0 1 Limp 1 n 1 McPiicraon } ,, Mcrrick ZZ ■ 6 7 l\ Morrill ZZZIZZZ"ZZZZr 4 15 Nance ■ 3 • 2 S N'uckolls ZZZZZZ 17 8 Perkins 0 2 2 Phclps -•—■... "■«« zzzzzzzzzz: S. ■ § . 1 Polk 4 2 6 Red Willow " 11 c . -if. Richardson . 12 1 Scotts Bluff ZZZZZZZZZ Z. 7 9 16 Sherman ZZZZZZZZ 5 2 7 Stanton j JJ i Thayer ". n i n in Valley "" '? " c^ tcr ■ : ZZZZZZZZ s s 10 ork 11 4 15 Total - -.. 308 20l 510~ 60 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">TABLE V— PSYCHOSES OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. t7 Senile psychoses _ 22 13 35 Psychoses with cerebral arteriosclerosis 68 27 95 (iencral paralysis , 17 3 20 Psychoses with cerebral syphilis 1 0 "l Psychoses with Huntington's chorea 2 0 2 Psychoses with other brain or nervous diseases: ....... (a) Paralysis agitans 1 0 1 (b) Other diseases 7 ] 8 Alcoholic psychoses : : (a) Acute or chronic y 1 10 Psychoses with other somatic diseases: (a) Post-infectious psychosis 1 1 2 (b) Exhaustion delirium 13 4 (c) Other diseases or conditions Oil Manic-depressive psychoses: fa) Manic type 16 18 34 (b) Depressive type _ 16 16 32 (c) Other types 8 2 10 Involution melancholia 2 1 3 Dementia praecox (schizophrenia) 66 60 126 Paranoia and paranoid conditions 6 7 13 Epileptic psychoses 3 7 10 Psychoncuroscs and neuroses : (a) Hysterical type 11 2 (b) Other types " : 1 0 1 Psychoses with psvehopathic personality 2 3 5 Psychoses with mental deficiency 15 8 2Z Undiagnosed psychoses - 26 24 50 " Without psychosis : (a) Epilepsy without psychosis 6 3 9 (b) Alcoholism without psychosis 10 1 (c) Others 10 2 12 Total 308 202 510 61 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">62 TABLE VI— AGE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 - iA. ¥. t7 Under IS years _ 3 1 4 15 to 19 years 11 7 18 JO to 24 years _ 29 17 40 25 to 29 years _.. 20 10 30 30 to 34 years _ 21 10 37 35 to 39 years _.: 19 22 41 40 to 44 years _.. 21 22 A3 45 to 49 years _ _ 23 \7 40 50 to 54 years _ _.. . 25 14 39 55 to 59 years _ _ 18 15 33 00 to 64 years 17 14 3\ hS to 69 years ., _ 23 10 33 70 years and over _ _ 77 30 107 Unascertained 112 Total 308 202 510 TABLE VII— DEGREE OF EDUCTION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T, Illiterate 12 3 15 Read and write 15 17 32 Common school _ 227 131 358 High school - _ 30 39 60 College 13 7 20 Unascertained _ 11 5 10 Total .„ _.. 308 202 510 TABLE VIII— ENVIRONMENT OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 - M. F. T? Urban _ 160 151 311 Kural ..:._ 132 40 172 Unascertained „ _ 16 11 27 Total' 308 202 510 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">63 TABLE IX— ECONOMIC CONDITION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1031 M. F. tT Dependent '. ;...„ ~^\ 3J8 Marginal 4,, &gt;, 7S Comfortable 44 ?4 68 Unascertained _____________„ 7 "2 9 Total 308 202 510 TABLE X— USE OF ALCOHOL BY FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 ' ' f M- F~ T. Abstinent 224 1&lt;M 418 remperate : OS 4 (,&lt;) Intemperate L y j ] () Unascertained _ 10 % i ]j Total ■ — 308 20! 510 TABLE XI— MARITAL CONDITION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 M. ~. T~.~ .^"S 1 ? : : H2 46 188 ;\' a 7 IC(1 , loo 93 199 Widowed 33 31J y, Separated '. 12 \-&gt; 24 Divorced ... Z'l... 13 12 25 Unascertained 2 0 7 Total - - 308 . 202 510 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">64 TABLE XII— PSYCHOSES OF READMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 U. ~. 77 (icneral paralysis : 0 1' 1 Alcoholic psychoses ; 10 1 Manic-depressive psychoses 11 14 25 Dementia praecox 8 6 14 Paranoia and paranoid conditions .'. 10 1 Kpileptic psychoses : , 2 13 Psychoneuroses and neuroses 1 ' ' 0 1 Psychoses with psychopathic personality :... 112 Psychoses with mental deficiency 2 1 3 Undiagnosed psychoses ; 6 1-7 Without psychosis : .... Oil Total : ,. 33 26 59 TABLE XIII— CONDITION OF THOSE DISCHARGED Period ending June 30, 1931 Ml -F. T? Without psychosis 7 3 10 Recovered 27 25 52 Improved _ 107 45 152 Unimproved _ „ 11 9 20 Total „ 152 82 234 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">TABLE XIV— CAUSE OF DEATH Period ending June 30, 1931 M. ¥. T\ Epidemic, Endemic and Infectious Diseases : Erysipelas 4 „ 4 I uberculosis of the respiratory system 12 14 ?6 Purulent infection, septicaemia ..." 3 0 ~3 Other infectious diseases 1 0 1 General Diseases Not Included in Class I : Cancer and other malignant tumors 6 5 ]] Diabetes 1 j ■&gt; Other general diseases 5 0 5 Diseases of the Nervous System: Cerebral' hemorrhage, apoplexy 12 5 \7 General paralysis of the insane 10 1 11 Other forms of mental disease 5 3 8 Epilepsy • 7 18 Other diseases of the nervous system (1 7 13 Diseases of the Circulatory System: Endocarditis and myocarditis 31 30 o j Other diseases of the heart 0 2 ~&gt; Arteriosclerosis 4C cj 55 Other diseases of the circulatory system 1 1 2 Diseases of the Respiratory System : Bronchitis 0 j j Bronchopneumonia .,.....-. U &lt;-, J7 Lobar pneumonia j2 f, \r Other diseases of the respiratory system (tuberculosis excepted) .". 2 1 } Diseases of the Digestive System Diseases of the pharynx and tonsils 10! Ulcer of stomach and duodenum 3 () 3 Hernia and intestinal obstruction 1 () 1 Other diseases of intestines 2 1 3 NiHi-Vcncral Diseases of Gcnito-Urinary System and Annexa : Nephritis 3 1 4 Other diseases of kidneys and auncxa .; 0 I 1 Diseases of the Skin and the Cellular Tissue: 0 1 1 Gangrene ; 0 1 1 Other Diseases not Included in Above Groups: External Causes : Suicide 2 0 2 Other external causes, while on parole and escape 2 0 2 Total IK'J 'ffl 287 65 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">66 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On Hand June 30, 1931 Number Value Rattle 141 $11,690.00 Chickens 3,532 2,119.20 Ducks 47 4230 Hogs .372 5,354.00 Horses . 24 • 2,285.00 Mules 10 1,125.00 Turkeys 118 236.00 Total . $22,851.50 FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Measure Value |! arll - v 1,355 I'm. $ 077.50 lirooin-ciirii 0,5(M) !l». . 437.50 , 1 .'"" .-•,-. - 8,504 l)ii. (.,803.2(1 torn fodder _ 52 t . 200.00 \," r " Vi : ', RC ■ 6S0 '• 0,500.00 jay, alfalfa ( ,15 ,. 7,380.(M) I lay. cam; ,, t M)m lay, prairie ; f4 t . . 57c qo I lay, soudan grass ]32 t. 792011 I )ats ,- ■'• 0,900 liu. 2J(t2Al) &lt;): &lt;t lia.v 40 t. 400.1H) Oat straw ..., 147,. 441.(M» K.ve : , 502 liu. -505.80 Rye straw 05 t . 1.5( U)() Straw, lianvy = 30 t. 15.00 &lt;J4 |,u. 01.10 \\ lii-at .straw : 20 t. 20.00 T"t»r : $27,791.50 DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1029 to June 30, 1931 Measure Value I--egs ~ _ _ 22,060 doz. $ 5,515.00 Milk - - 1,202,107 lbs. 36,063.21 Total _ : „ __ . $41,578.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">GARDEN PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Produced and Consumed ' Measure Value Aspa ragus 8,721 lbs. $ 610.47 Beans, lima : 5,740 n )s 2 29.M) Hcans, string 21,705 lbs. 43410 Beets „ 46,499 lbs. 1.859.96 Cabbage 123,680 lbs. 2,473.60 Carrots _.. 22.081 lbs. 662.43 Celery 1,015 lbs. 101.50 Corn, sweet - _ 134.095 lbs. 4,022.85 Cucumbers &lt;),820 lbs 196.40 Rgg plant _ _ _ 2.295 lbs. . 137.70 Greens, turnip 4.830 lbs. 48.30 Horseradish 820 lbs. 49.20 Kobl-rabi 7,274 lbs. 290.96 Lettuce _ 22.170 lbs. 1,108.50 Melons, musk 15.380 lbs. 307.60 Melons, water .'. 6,260 lbs. 6260 Mustard 3,880 lbs. 116.40 Onions, dry _ _ _ 43.030 lbs. 2,151.50 Onions, green _ 45.805 lbs. 1,832.20 Parsnips : 43,940 lbs. i,318.20 Peas 7.125 lbs. 498.75 Peppers '. 7,125 lbs. 712.5(1 Potatoes J 529,560 lbs. 10,591.20 Potatoes, sweet 1 5.340 lbs. 267.00 Pumpkins ; 14,800 lbs. 148.00 Radishes , 18,970 lbs. 379.40 Rhubarb _ 27,465 lbs. 1,098.60 Salsify 7,200 Ib». 216.00 Spinach 4,820 lbs. 192.80 Squash 18,735 lbs. 374.70 -Swiss chard 6,960 lbs. 348.00 Tomatoes : _ .. 127,257 lbs. 2,545.14 Turnips 98.240 lbs. 1,964.80 Total '. $37,350.96 ORCHARD AND BERRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Measure Value Grapes 1,360 lbs. $81 .Ml Peaches 3,720 lbs. 74.40 Plums _ 1.000 lbs. 40.00 Strawberries 475 lbs. 57.00 Cherries :. 796 lbs. 71.64 Total : '' $324.64 67 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">LINCOLN STATE HOSPITAL LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS D. G. GRIFFITHS, M. D. - Superintendent R. H. SPRADLING, M. D. -" - Assistant Superintendent T. K. JONES, M.D. - - - - Staff Physician P. L. SPRADLING, M. D. ..... Staff physician MARIE L. GROTE, M. D. Staff Physician J. R. HELMS - Steward STELLA CLAY - . . Matron Miscellaneous Statement Kstablished 1870 X umher of employes June 30, 1931, : •■ 158 Xumber of inmates June 30, 1931.. 1,170 I fighest number of inmates during biennium 1,170 Per capita cost per month $ 21.69 Xumber of acres owned 640 Xumber of acres leased ; 215 Xumber of acres under cultivation '. 825 Value of land and buildings, furniture and equipment : $1,334,053.09 Principal industries: Farming, gardening and stock raising-. Visiting days : Every day except Saturdays, Sundays and holidays, 1 :00 p. in. to 4 :00 p. m. Admission to the hospital for the treatment of mental diseases is had only through commitment by the insanity board in each county, consisting of the clerk of the court, a physician and a lawyer. 68 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions Lincoln, Nebraska. I hereby have the honor of submitting the Micnnial Report of the Unclon State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, for the period cover - ing twenty- four months, from July 1, iy2o, to June 30, 1931. The medical staff remains as it was two years ago, with tin - exception of Dr. I). (). Swanson who came m November, V) 2-) to take the place of. our dentist. Dr. William I. Rotton. Dr I- I Spradling was appointed by the Hoard to take the place of our .staff physician. Dr. A. R. Hornbeck who died at this Institution August 2, 1930. The members of the staff have manifested a keen interest m their work and efforts directed to the restoration of patients through modern treatment have been quite vigorous. The following reports and statistical tables comprise the Biennial Report, beginning July 1, 1929 and ending June 30. 1931. The population of this hospital on the first day of July, 1929 was 1146, 581 male and 565 female. Gain : Admitted for the first time — 380 males and 172 females making a total of. 552. Readmitted— 62 males and 36 females, making a total of 98. Returned from parole and escape— 88 males and 70 females, making a total of 158. Loss: Died m Institution — 115 males and 70 females, making a total of 185. Discharged from Institution— l 92 males and 10 females, making a total of 202. .Escaped and paroled— 2l2 males and 179 females, making a total of 391. Transferred to other Institutions— s males and 1 female, making a total of 6. Total loss during period 524 males and 260 females, making a total of 78A. The sewing room and the various domestic duties about the institution provide occupational pursuits for our female patients. The sewing room performs a most useful function m the manufac - ture of clothing and bedding for the institution. The carpenter shop, shoe repair, mattress shop, furniture repair, farm, garden, engine room, laundry, chicken house, dairy, greenhouse and lawn provide occupational pursuits for our male patients. We usually have about fifteen patients m the art room who do fancy work, furnishing the Institution with table covers, etc. They 69 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">make from thirty to thirty-five pieces a month. We have a show - case m tile center office contaning fancy-work made m the art room to he sold to the public, and we also take many pieces to the Stale Fair for display and sale. Patients are happier and m many instances actually ■ improve mentally by reason of having certain tasks to perform. We regard industrial pursuits as one of our most potent therapeutic agents. While the last Legislature was m session we found that our engine room, was m very had condition, and the Hoard was kind enough to procure for us a $15,000.00 special appropriation. How - ever, when this work was completed, we found that up until July. 1930 we spent besides this $15,000.00 appropriation, ?19,0M.(X) from our general maintenance fund, increasing per capita cost, but now our engine room is m very good condition. With an appropriation made for that purpose, a stand-pipe has been erected near the wells up on the hill, replacing the old stand - pipe which has been torn down. To one end of the hospital building, we have erected an ell. which accommodates thirty-four female patients. We have been able, as our tables will show, to send a great many patients home, either completely recovered or at least so much so they can remain m their home environment for some time. This has been due, of course, to the surroundings, the entertainment and care which are a part of the treatment of mental diseases. An appropriation of $30,(XX).00 was made by the last Legisla - ture to repair and improve the main building and attempt to make it more fire-proof. We have $10,000.00 to buy land south of the present pump house m order that we may obtain water for this institution' Refor - matory for Men for which we furnish water; ?8,000.00 to run pipes down here and put m fire hydrants. I wish to thank Mis Excellency, the Governor, and the Honor - able Members of the Hoard of Control for their courteous consider - ation, for the confidence, the kind assistance' and advice they have uniformly extended to me throughout the year, and 1 also wish to express thanks to the officers and employes associated with me who have been loyal and faithful during the biennium. Very respectfully submitted, D. G. GRIFFITHS, Superintendent. 70 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">71 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period endinu June 30, \&lt;&gt;M ; K~ T. Present at hcRi'iining of period 5X1 51,5 1 i4(, Admitted for the first lime ,suo 17} '$$? Keadmhtcd Yi2 .Ifi &lt;ix On escape at beginning of period 17 0 17 On parole at beginning of period i5 ,w 7.5 Total _ 1,075 sil l.K8d Discharged from institution ]»2 10 202 Died ill institution ; 115 70 7^5 Transferred, from institution 5 1 (&lt; Died while 011 parole 0 4 4 Discharged while on parole KM 10(1 20.5 Discharged while on escape o 0 f&gt; On escape at end of period I 1 ) 0 ]&lt;) On parole at end of period -48 4.5 &lt;&gt;1 total ; j AHH 2J« 71d Remaining at institution at end of period j 5N7 58.1 1,170 TABLE II— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June .?(). \&lt;).\\ ~S\. V. T. Nebraska ; :.... 15S SI) 2.W L nited States other than Nebraska 156 7,? 2*&gt; Austria 1 ] 7 Belgium "(I 1 If Bohemia 7 1 N Canada" _ 1 0 ] Czecho-Slovakia 1 0 1 Denmark : .'. _.;.... 1 ? .1 England _... _ 2 T S France _ 0 1 "] Germany , o 5 ]4 Hungary _.. 0 1 ] Ireland ; .5 d Italy ; _..„._.„..„.___„ 2 (I 2 Moravia ; ' 1 0 T Norway 0 ] ] Poland ; 1 1 2 Russia ._ .1 2 5 Syria ; ....„..........."" 1 I) \ Sweden : 5 1 6 Unascertained ; ....!.„..."!" 28 1 2') Total _ 380 172 552 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">TABLE III— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OP PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR THE FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, l'«l ■ M. !■'. ~ T. Adams .■ , Hoonc 'i I, , •I- »««•-• ::::::::::::::::::::::: 1 [| lirown 9 i, i Buffalo ' = V t '!»« I::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: ,', j • ? Lass _ _ 12 ' 1 14 Cheyenne i ( *J i c.ifax "~~;~; , " ■ Cuming \ , , Custcr _~..™_™.'ZZI 5 | 7, Dakota ',, ,, , Dawson ; _ 0 i Dcuel ...................'....." i o i " od Bf - 10 7 17 ?"V Klas - 84 55 I.W I:' 1 ""}™ ■ i o i I'ranklm 2 0 2 frontier ;. . . 10 1 !;urnas ..., ZZ. 2 0 2 a S c - - • -- 16 f. 22 ! ra "t 3 0^ Hall _ _._ _. 6 1) () Hamilton q j j Harlan _ 2 0 2 Jefferson . 2 0? Johnson _ 2 1 3 Kearney ' 0 1 1 Keith 1 ' 1 2 Knox - 2 0 2 Lancaster 75 57 U2 Lincoln 3 0 Madison 2 0 2 Mcrrick _ _. 2 0 2 i Nemaha k j 10 i Otoe I \\ \ \l ■ : Pawnee _ 4 -j 7 Perkins '................' 1 i&gt; 1 pixips : I::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: \ I \ Pierce 1 {) 1 Platte : 40 4 ! Polk 2 0 2 Red Willow 101 I Richardson ;. 9 7 ■ H&lt; Saline _ __ __ o e 11 Sarpy 1 - fi 0 6 - Saunders _ _ 9 S 14 Scotts Bluff : 4 0 4 Seward _ _ \ jj 5 lf) Sheridan . 2 0 2 $| anton ZZZIZZ. 101 ia &gt;' er • 213 Thomas j 0 1 Thurston Zl. 9 0 &lt;) I X allcy - : " 2 0 2 Wayne ? n 9 Webster ZZZZZZZZZ 3 0 3 Total _ _ ■ion 170 ceo 1 ■ ' "I 72 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">TABLE IV— CITIZENSHIP OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period endiiiK June 30, 1931 AT K~ tT Citizens by birth _ 312 151) 4(&gt;2 Citizens by naturalization _ 8 .S lT Aliens '. '4 12 Citizenship unascertained 52 15 U7 Total 380 172 552 TABLE V— PSYCHOSES OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30. 1"«1 M. V. T. Psychosis due to arterioclerosis 6 0 (1 Senile psychosis \ 41 14 55 Manic depressive psychosis _ 37 4 n 83 Dementia praecox '. 48 67 115 Paranoia ; 3 &lt;j 12 Huntington's chorea 0 1 1 Imbecility 5 6 11 Paresis .............ZZZ. 32 8 40 Kpileptic psychosis :. 7 4 11 Alcoholic psychosis 1 () 1 Feeble-minded 8 4 12 Psychosis with psychopathic personality 2 1 3 Involutional meloncholia 112 Psychoneurosis •. ; 2 0 2 Traumatic psychosis ■. 10 1 Cerebral syphilis 10 1 Inebriates ...'. 165 9 174 Without psychosis ', 5 0 5 Undiagnosed 15 2 17 Total 380 172 552 »4 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">TABIE VI— RACE OF THOSE ADMITTED. FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30. 1931 ; KT FT "tT African '. \ : 8 7 15 Austrian 2 13 Bohemian - 11 (, 17 Canadian 11? Dutch 1 0 1 Knglish ; ..... 3 2 5 French : ....."..........."..""" 0 T 1 Uerman id n 31 Hungarian ; I) 1 1 Irish (, 0 (, Italian _ 2 0 2 Jewish 2 0 2 Norwegian , 0 1 1 Polish 2 1 3 Russian ;.... 3 2 5 Scandinavian ; 9 4 1.5 Slavonic 10 1 Syrian : ........"........... 1 0 1 Mixed _ _..„ 2&gt;&gt;&gt; 10(&gt; 335 Unascertained 7&lt;J 28 107 Total M) 172 5lF TABLE VII— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June .50. 1931 M. F. tT Fifteen to nineteen years _ 10 4 14 Twenty to twenty-four years _ 22 9 31 Twenty-five to twenty-nine years 25 16 41 Thirty to thirty-four years _ 34 ih 50 Thirty-five to thirty-nine years _. _ 56 31 87 Forty to forty-four years _ 50 21 71 Forty-five to forty-nine years _ _ 43 24 67 Fifty to fifty-four years _ 35 11 46 Fifty-five to fifty-nine years _ _ 21 7 28 Sixty to sixty-four years _ „ 2S 12 35 Sixty-five to sixty-nine years _ 20 10 30 Seventy to seventy-four years , 18 4 22 Seventy-five to seventy-nine years 3 3 6 Ejghty to eighty-four years 4. ■ 1 5 Eighty-five plus 1 1 . 2 Unascertained _ _ 15 • 2 17 Total _ _ 380 172 552 74 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">TABLE VIII— DEGREE OF EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June .30. 1931 , ____ M. F. T. Illiterate . _... 7 |T~ Read and write ....:.......".". I ~ if, i7. -i-&gt; Common school .... &lt;,,.. ..,, ,,, High school ::::::::;::;::: ; 2 O ™d ?$ College ■; ; Z™ZZ ~~ 25 0 4 Unascertained ."_" |j , '^ Total _ .380 \72 552 TABLE IX— ENVIRONMENT OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June .30, l'J.31 m! ¥. t7 \! rb ™ ■■ ~218 \V) 337" V' ral : : 1.38 44 182 Unascertained ; 24 9 33 Tot:l1 - 380 172 552 TABLE X— ECONOMIC CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30. 1931 _^ M; P; tT Dependent 2 11 &lt;)i «)•&gt; Marginal _ " f,U &gt;\ f»| Comfortable „ ™ "4 of SS Unascertained _...".""1".™ 30 8 38 Total • ~380 172 55Y" TABLE XI— USE OF ALCOHOL BY THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 M. R T~ Abstinent _ . cja 1T7 95a j^ P cv aic :::::::::::z:::z:::z:z £ i ?l Intemperate . „ 198 10 208 Unascertained _ 22 14 36 Total - • '- 380 172 552 75 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">TABLE XII— MARITAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. Single 116 45 161 Married 186 X2 268 Widowed '. 26 31 57 Separated ,. : 12 « 20 Divorced 27 6 33 Unascertained 13 &lt;• 13 Total : :. : mo 172 TABLE XIII— DISCHARGES OF PATIENTS CLASSIFIED WITH REFERENCE TO PRINCIPAL PSYCHOSES AND CONDITION ON DISCHARGE Period ending June .30, 1931 Unimproved Improved Total M. V. T. IZ F\ tT M. F\ T. Constitutional, psycho - pathic inferiority 0 00 101 101 Feeble-Minded 0 0 0 .94 13 9 4 13 Dementia praecox 2 8 10 25 20 45 27 28 55 Manic depressive 3 2 5 26 48 74 29 50 79 Paranoia 0 0 0 13 4.134 Paresis 2 0 2 9 1 10 11 1 12 Alcoholic psychosis .... 0 0 0 2 13 2 13 Traumatic psychosis .10 1 2 0 2 3 0 3 Senile psychosis 0 0 0 8 6 14 8 6 14 Epileptic psychosis ...... 1 0 1 2 4 6 3 4 7 Inebriates . 0 0 0 202 12 214 202 12 214 Without psychosis 0 0 013 14 3 14 Undiagnosed 10 1 .303 404 Unascrtained 10 1 2 13 3 1 4 Total .' 11 10 21 295 101 396 306 111 417 i 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">77 TABLE XIV— CAUSES OF DEATHS OF PATIENTS Period ending June 30, 1931 ! . - \ \I. ¥. T7 General Diseases : Influenza : 3 , , Gangrene ......Z..ZZ.ZZZZ! ? (\ ■&gt; Cholecystitis f i 2 Septiccmia 10 1 | Tricuspid regurgitation ....ZZZZZ..Z 0 ? ? Carcinoma .'. 2 '] ? Ostco-sarcoma ■—•.—• .^ Acute alcoliolism 3//........... -10 4 Angina pectoris [ II 7 Nervous System: General paralysis of the insane 8 1 &lt;J Apoplexy (cerebral hemmorrhage) 14 5 iy Epilepsy ..: 12 { 2 ?A Bulbar paralysis 0 T "l Encephalitis 1 0 1 Circulatory System: j • Acute endocarditis 2 () &gt; Chronic endocarditis Z..1....... 11 () n Actue myocarditis ZZZZZ. 1 2 3 Chronic myocarditis 0 9 '() Acute cardiac dilation 8 5 ' 13 Pscudolcukemia " 1 j) 1 / Aortic stenosis _ 0 1 l Arteriosclerosis' ; .......™.'..."... 1 0 1 Respiratory System: Pulmonary tuberculosis , (, 15 ji Bronchial pneumonia 4 \ ~^ Pneumonia j &lt;l '. I.obar pneumonia ZZZ.ZZ. 10 1 Bronchial asthma 1 0 . Tubercular pleurisy 1 ( , 1 Dicestivc Sv'stem : Cancer of the. stomach 1 (l 1 Tuberculosis of the intestines 2 0 2 I Chronic enteritis ZZZ.ZZZZ1 0 1 T Acute Kastro-cnteritts 0 1 « 1 Appendicitis ...ZZZZZZZ. 2 0 &gt; ; . Peritonitis 0 1 T (ienitci-Urinary System: Acute nephritis () I , Chronic nephritis Z.ZZZZZ" ~&gt;\ h '7 Diabetes mellitus "ZZZZZ ~1 1 2 Tutal ■ : 115 70 185~ </seg>
            <seg id="p081">DIPSOMANIACS— TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June 30, 1931 M. ¥. TV Present at beginning of period _ lfi 0 16 Admitted for first time K&gt;5 0 174 Readmitted 39 2 41 Returned 5 0 5 Total 225 11 236 Discharged 182 10 192 [Cscapcd 10 0 10 Paroled _ 19 0 19 Died in institution 5 0 5 Total ,. _ 216 10 226 Total remaining at end of period .„ 9 1 10 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 \T F! T. Thirteen to nineteen 1 0 1 Twenty to twenty-four 7.1 8 Twenty-live to twenty-nine 12 2 14 Thirty to thirty-four _ 21 0 21 Thiry-fivc to thirty-nine 32 4 36 Forty to forty-four : 26 0 26 Forty-five to forty-nine 27 (I 27 Fifty to fifty-four 19 2 21 Fifty-five to fifty-nine 5 0 5 Sixty to sixty-four 4 0 4 Sixty-five to sixty-nine -• 3 0 3 Unascertained 8 0 K Total '....■ 165 9 174 78 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">TABLE III— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 3d. 1931 ' U. F. T\ S/ns'F : ~&gt; 2 W Widowed jj -&gt; ](. Divorced ™.™"I"™""~™" ." ™ 20 0 1) Separated ; 11 1 p Unknown ~..~."1"~!1"ZZ1_.I.__3 8 0 8 • Total -■ Ui5 9 174 TABLE IV— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 ' ■_ ~M. F. T7 Primary 2 0 ~2~ Comtnou school . inn ! no HirIi scliool . p (, CoHcge .....-..."Z™!'ZZ;™Z 12 () 12 Unknown 10 0 jo . . T "tal ;. u,5 i) 174 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June Ml I'm .\T F. T. Nebraska _____ ___ ~^ _&gt; United States other than Nebraska ~ (&lt;&gt; 5 r&gt;7 ei e" : :.:;;. u o u Unknown ; ' jj () |j Tut;il Hi5 t) T7T~ 79 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">80 TABLE VI— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. Harbor 6 0 6 Bartender 1 0 1 Blacksmith 2 0 2 ■ Butcher 1 0 1 Carpenter 1 0 1 Cattle buyer : 2 0 2 Chef '.. : 4 0 4 Clerk , 5 0 S Clerk of the District Court 1 0.1 Dentist 1 " "0 1 Electrician : : 1 0 1 Engineer 10 1 Expert Accountant 1 0 1 . Farmer Ift 0 If. Gardener 10 1 Housewife 0 5 5 Huckster ', : 1 0 1- Janitor 1 0 1 Jeweler 10 1 Laborer 27. 1 28 Lawyer 1 0 1 Lineman - 1 0 1 Mason 1 0 1 Mechanic .3 0 3 Merchant 5 0 5 None 2 0 2 Oil Station Attendant 2 0 2 Painter .... 5 0 5 Pharmacist 3 0 3 Physician '. .' 3 0 3 Plumber '. 3 0 3 Printer 1 0 1 Kailrond Car Inspector 1 0 1 Real estate 1 0 1 Salesman .'. _ 16 0 Id Secretary 1 0 1 Shinier 1 0 1 Station agent 1 0 1 Stenographer 0 1 1 Stockman 1 0 I Store owner .1 0 1 Switchman '. •. 1 I) 1 Tailor 1 0 1 Telegrapher 1 0 1 Tinner 1 0 1 Truck driver 2 0 2 Veterinarian 10 1 Well driller ..' .-. 1 0 1 Windmill worker 1 0 1 Unascertained 29 2 31 Total 165 9 174 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">TABLE VII— COUNTY OP RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 . M. F. T. Adams ; 3 jj Bikiiic 10 1 Box Butle "_ 1 0 1 Brown 2 0 2 Buffalo 0 1 7 Hurt 0 1 1 Lass :. 1 0 1 Cheyenne : 1 0 1 Colfax 3 0 3 Uiming 1 0 1 Luster ; 5 1 &lt;-, Dakota 6 0 „ Dawson [ 3 0 3 Dcucl : "...".'"""".' I (I 1 Dodge '. 1 0 1 Douglas 2.5 1 24 Killmore .: 10 1 Franklin -2 0 2 Frontier ""ZZ"S/.'.'..."."~. 1 0 1 Pumas '. 3 (i 3 (Jage I .5 0 3 Grant ; 3 (i .1 (ircely fi 0 6 Hall ". (&lt; I) (&gt; Harlan " '"' 2 &lt;&gt; 2 Jefferson- "'"" 1 0 1 Kearney .: Oil Keith : •"" 1 1 2 Isnox 2 0 2 Lancaster 15 2 17 Lincoln 3 0 3 Madison 1 0 1 Merrick "" 2 0 2 Nemaha 3 0 3 (Itoc 5 1 (, Pawnee 3 0 3 Perkins ... 1 (I 1 Phelps 2 0 2 Pierce 1 0 1 Platte 4 0 4 Polk ., 10 1 Red Willow "Z~ZZ •' ° ' Richardson' 4 0 4 Saline .....Z.. ' - 0 2 Sarpy ; 5 0 5 Scotts Bluff ' 4 0 4 Sheridan 2 0 2 Stanton 1 (I 1 Thaycr 10 1 Tlmrston 8 0 8 Valley "" 2 0 2 Wayne 2 0 2 Webster 3 0 3 Total ; 165 9 174 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Produced and disposed of ____ . Measure Value A'lalfa : 300 t. $ 3,600.00 Corn 3,500 b u . 2,800.00 I-.nsiIage 1,000 t. 10,000.00 F'xlrtcr 25 t. 75.00 Hay, oats, alfalfa SO t 600.00 Hay, timothy 30 t . 360.00 Oats „.... 9,722 bu. 3,888.80 Straw, oats _ 110 t. 330.00 Straw, wheat 40 t. 120.00 Sudan grass 30 t. 270.00 Wheat 2,044 bu. 2,235.40 T »tal ....: $24,279.20 DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Produced and disposed of . Measure Value !"-KK s - 5.500 rloz. $ 1,375.00 -Milk i&gt;50,000 lbs. 28,500.00 . Total . $29,875.00 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY July 1st, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Number Value £**"&lt;•' : hi $12,425.00 \ hickcns 2,720 1,632.00 pucks 1,420 1.278.00 Hogs 71 1.245.00 I torses 27 3,996.00 Mules 5 925.oo Sheep 17 525.00 Total $22,026.00 82 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">83 GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to Juno 30, 1931 Produced and disposed of Measure Value Asparagus \ 3,800 lbs. $ 266.00 Beans, string 33,000 n.s. 660.00 Beets ....: , , 41.500 lbs. 1,660.00 Cabbage ." 21.000 lbs. 420.00 Carrots 50,000 lbs. 1,500.00 Cauliflower : 14.000 lbs. 840.00 Celery ; 4,000 lbs. 200.00 Chard, Swiss 43,000 lbs. 860.00 Kohl-rabi 12,100 lbs. 482.00 Cucumbers 35,000 lbs. 480.00 Kgg plant 10,000 lbs. 960.00 lettuce _ 13.800 i| )s m)m ""! ons ■ -. 32.000 lbs. 1.600.01) Onions, green , 27,5(M) lbs. 1.100.00 Parsnips 51,000 )|, s _ 1.530.00 Peas , 31,500 lbs. 2.205.01) Poppers 4,500 i| )s . 315.00 Potatoes 288,000 lbs. 5,760.00 Potatoes, sweet 16.300 lbs. 815.00 Pumpkins 2.100 ||, s . 21.00 Radishes _ 18.700 lbs. 374.00 Rhubarb 88.000 lbs. 3,520.00 Spinach 12.400 lbs. 496.00 Squash 100 lbs. 2 00 Tomatoes 98,000 lbs. l,%0.00 Turnips , 50.400 lbs. 1,008.00 Turnips, green 3.000 lbs. 120.00 Apples : 2,000 lbs. 60.00 Cherries : 21.600 lbs 1,944.00 Grapes 18,500 lbs. 1.110.00 Total . $32,958.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">NORFOLK STATE HOSPITAL NORFOLK, NEBRASKA OFFICERS ). C. KIKLSEN. M. I). - - . - ' - - - Superintendent C. C\ DULMMONI), M. I). ...... staff Physician S. \V. SHKLTON, M. I). Staff Physician \V. \V. DA VAULT,. M.D. - . - - - - - Staff Physician A. J. GUTZMER - - Steward R. E. ANGEL - - - - Domestic Supervisor Miscellaneous Statement Established 1885 Number of employes [une 30, 1931 116 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 „ 935 Highest number of inmates during biennium 943 lVr capita cost per montii $ 19.72 Number of acres owned 615 Number of acres under cultivation 435' Value of land and buildings, furniture and equipment $1,200,214.09 Principal Industries : Stock raisiny, farming and gardening. Visiting Days : Every day, except Sundays and holidays, between I) :00 A. M. and 4 :00 P. M. Admission for treatment of mental diseases is had only through commitment by the insanity board in each county, consisting of the clerk of the court, a physician and a lawyer. 84 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of.StnU' Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I have the honor of presenting herewith the twentv-lirsi biennial report of the Norfolk State Hospital, covering the period from July Ist. 1929 to June 30th, 19311 It was the privilege of the undersigned to be appointed Superintendent of the State Hospital of Norfolk, Nebraska, on March 24th, 1931, following Dr. G. E. Charlton's appointment of superintendency of the State Hospital at Hastings, Nebraska. Recently, Dr. W. Slielton of ("mill. Alabama, and Dr. W. \V. Davault of Cape Girardeau, Missouri, accepted positions on our staff as residents m psychiatry. The position of medical director is still vacant. The health of the patients during the hiennium has been ex - ceptionally good, taking into consideration that the wards are not only filled to capacity, but dangerously over-crowded, but due to the complete cooperation of the employes and physicians this condition has not endangered the general health of those m this institution. During the past year the, construction of a new receiving and hospital building was started, but so far has not been completed because of lack of funds. It is our hope that funds will be available m the .coming biennium to enable us to finish this building. When this building is completed, we will be able to receive, and intelligently treat, new women patients, but our male wards will still remain crowded more than a hundred over maximum capacity. The effect of this over-crowding is readily seen from Table 3. It has reduced our recovery rate of male patients fifty percent. In former years, recoveries were about the same of both males and females. In the biennium of 1925-1927, the proportion of recoveries of male and female patients was 1.07 to 1.0, respectively. In 1927-1929, the proportion of recoveries was 1.20 to 1.0, res - 85 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">86 pectively, but m the biennium of 1929-1931, the figures are reversed, being only .5 to 1.0, respectively. The various activities of our patients m- the institution have been functioning to the greatest degree of efficiency, taking into consideration that we are laboring under adverse conditions to which many state institutions are subjected. Improvements have been made to the extent that our funds permitted, and, m this regard, I think particularly of the Occupational Therapy, the beauty parlor for the ladies, the attention paid to our outdoor activities, and greater personal freedom. I wish to express my sincere appreciation of the cooperation of the county officials m our district, and also of the interest of those State Representatives and Senators, who have visited our institution ami contributed to our patients' welfare. In particluar, do I want to thank the employes and physicians of this institution for their interest and cooperation and the Hoard of Control of State Institu - tions for their help, advice and trust. Respect fully submitted, JUUL C. NIELSEN, Superintendent; </seg>
            <seg id="p090">87 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June .50, 19.51 M. F. T. Present at beginning of period _ 4S2 4.5.5 915 Admitted for first time .: 78 11.5 191 Readmitted , 1(1 19 2&lt;) On parole or otherwise absent ill beginning of period 29 47 76 Total '. , ■. 5&lt;)9 (&gt;12 1,211 Discharged : Recovered (, 14 7Q Improved -. 24 39 03 Unimproved .' 5 4 ij Transferred to other institutions ] d ] Died ...._ , 4S m 112 On parole or otherwise absent at end of period ... ,57 71 Total 118 15S 27(&gt; In institution at end of period I 481 454 935 TABLE II— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, IW1 M. F. 77 United States _ t&gt;2 94 156 Canada , J 2 2 4 Czecho-Slovakia I 1 4 5 Denmark I 1 2 3 England _ | 2 I) 2 Germany _ _ 5 6 11 Hungary : (I 1 1 Ireland _ 1 (I 1 Scotland _ 0 1 1 Sweden _ _ _ 2 1 .1 Switzerland _ _. 1 1 2 Unascertained _ 112 Total '. _ _ 78 11.5 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">88 TABLE III— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE Admitted for All remaining First Time June 30, 1931 M. F. T. M. i! t7 Antelope _ .3 3 6 16 19 35 Hoonc 5 3 8. io l? 22 Box Butte 0 1 1 0 3 l' B«y«l 0 2 2 11 * 4 15 Brown 1 2 3 10 11 21 Buffalo _... 0 0 0 0 3 Hurt 5 5 10 21 10 Vl Butler 0 11 o 1 I Cass . 0*0 0 0 1 I Cedar 4 0 4 14 22 36 c .' lcrr &gt;' 14 5 17 13 30 Cheyenne _ 0 0 0 112 Clay 0 0 0 Oil Coif ax 2 4 ' 6 ' 15 17 3? fuming ..„. 4 5 9 10 17 27 C.uster _. 0 0 0 2 -0 2 [Jakota 6 4 10 12 V, 2K iJawcs _ „ (1 4 10 12 12 ?4 Dawson 0 0 0 1 1 ~-&gt; Deuel _ — 0 0 0.101 &gt;' x ,°» 0 2 2 13 13 26 Dodge 0 11 7 7 14 !?°U8las 5 28 .^ 86 87 173 l-ranklin _. 0 0 0 0 1 1 K*Kc 0 00 10 1 (ircclcy 0 0 0 0 11 Hall — 0.0 0 0 1 1 " oIt , 7 1 8 ' 29 17 4f. Hooker _ 0 0 0 0 0 () Howard 0 0 0 1 2 1 Keya Paha „ _ 0 3 .3 5 2 7 T Knox ; 7 4 11 28 18 4f. Lancaster _ 0 2 2 2 3 5 }I adi ?°» » — - 2 8 10 27 25 52 Mcrrick „ ...._ 0 0 0 10 1 Morrill 0 0 0 3 14 Nance _ 0 0 0 6 3 9 Nemaha 0 0 0 10 1 Nuckolls 0 0 0 0 2 2 Pierce 2 5 7 14 14 28 P«»«e -- 1 4 S 20 21 4l Polk 0 0 0 0 1 1 Rock _... 13 4 2 5 7 Saunders 0 0 0 0 0 0 Scotts Bluff 0 0 0 10 1 Seward — _ — 0 0 0 0 11 Sherdian 2 6 8 5 16 21 Sherman _ 0 0 0 2 11 ■5!°"? - 2 0 2 7 3 10 Stanton 3 0 3 ' 15 13 28 5, nr P- v 0 0 0 0 0 0 Thaycr 0 0 0 0 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">89 TABLE HI— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE (Continued) Admitted for All remaining First Time June 30, 1931 M. F. T. M. F. T. Thomas Oil 02 2 ''"''""ton _ 5 3 8 18 3 21 Washington 4 3 7 23 16 V) Wayne i 0 1 1 , 10 10 20 Wheeler 0 .0 0 1 0 1 Tota » - — • 78 IU V)T 481 454 935 TABLE IV— PSYCHOSES OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 . m7~~r t. Traumatic psychoses 7? T? ■», Senile psychoses Z.™ZZ™Z'.'Z 7 7 fj Psychosis with cerehral arteroiscierosis o &lt;t k (jfiieral paralysis D 2 &gt; Psychosis with cerehral syphilis 0 1 T Psychosis with other brain or nervous diseases 3 0 ; Alcoholic psychosis 0 1 \ Psychosis due to drugs 0 1 j Psychos-is with somatic diseases '. 0 8 8 Manic-deprcssivB psychosis ; " 8 20 '8 Involution melancholia 1 ~S ~(, Dementia praecox.... (schizophrenia) 21 32 S? Paranoia and paranoid conditions 0 2 2 Kpileptic psychosis 4^7 Psychoneuroses and neuroses 1 !} 5 Psychosis with mental deficiency 2 5 7 [.'■(diagnosed psychosis 10 1 Without psychosis _ 4 4 8 T " t:l1 ■ : ~78 U3 V&gt;T </seg>
            <seg id="p093">90 TABLE V— RACE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending Juno 30. 1931 M. F. T. African (black) 0 . S 5 American Indian — 38 46 84 English : S 3 8 Herman - - " 21 30 Irish . A 2 h Scandinavian --- 4 4 8 Slavonic 3 ■ 15 18 Oilier specific races 0 2-2 Mixed : •&gt; "12 21 Race unascertained ft. 3 9 Total — ~~78 113 191 TABLE VI— AGE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30. 1931 M. F. T. IS and under 20 years '. 0 4 4 20 and under 25 years '. 10 3 13 25 and under 30 years &lt;X 7 15 30 and under 35 years 6 17 23 35 and under 40 years " 26 32 40 and under 45 years ~ 5 15 20 45 and under 50 years " 7 13 50 and under 55 years 4 '&gt; 13 55 and under 60 years 8 8 1ft fiO and under 65 years ' " '•' 65 and under 70 years '. 5 4 l J 70 years and over 13 7 20 Total — 78 113 191 TABLE VII— DEGREE OF EDUCATION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 • M. F. tT Illiterate - : 1 f 5 Read and write J I * Common school - ■ »' 86 153 High school 5 14 19 College - 16 7 Unascertained - 0 ; _2 2^ Total _ _ - 78 m 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">TABLE VIII— ENVIRONMENT OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June- .30. 1931 m! R t7 Urban ,. 30 71 loT K"™1 _.. 48 42 90 Total 78 113 l&lt;n TABLE IX— ECONOMIC CONDITION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 J M. F. T. Dependent 41 (l0 m Marginal 2 (&gt; 24 50 Lomtortable \\ 29 40 T °t"' ■«. : 78 11.3 l&lt;;i TABLE X— USE OF ALCOHOL BY FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 19.51 ' m! f\ t. Abstinent ~»5 |^j | 73 I emperatc _ 9 1 j0 Intemperate 4 4 8 T °tal 78 H3 V)T TABLE XI— MARITAL CONDITION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Period ending June 30, 1931 \l. R tT Single : 1. ~34 22 5fT Married _ 22 60 82 Widowed _ _ _ 14 19 33 Separated „..„ _ 3 7 10 Divorced _ . 5 5 10 Total _ _ 73 113 i9i 91 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">TABLE XII— CAUSE OF DEATH Period ending June .30, 19.31 . ' M. F. T\ Epidemic, endemic and infectious discuses: Tuberculosis of the respiratory system... 1 ] ? Tuberculosis of other organs 0 ] 7 Other infectious diseases ; 0 i ■ lieneral diseases : Cancer and other malignant tumors „. i _, Tumor (non-cancerous) .... ii i , Diabetes Z.ZZZZZZZ ,, Other general diseases I I , Diseases of the nervous system: .Meningitis (non-epidemic) I 0 . Cerebral hemorrhage, apoplexy - j^ j () (ieneral paralysis of the insane ; 5 2 7 Other forms of mental disease j) j j Epilepsy , 1 ? 4 Chorea () j ( Other diseases of the nervous system 10 1 Diseases of the Circulatory system: Endocarditis and myocarditis ; K 1 o Angina pectoris , 1 () j Other diseases of the heart ! j • d j Arteriosclerosis ....'. 0 j I Diseases of the respiratory system: Brouchopneumonia 1 7 8 I.obar pneumonia ' J2 7() Other diseases of the respiratory system (tuber - culosis excepted) ....' 1 12 Diseases of the digestive system: . ■ I leer of stomach and duodenum 0 n q Other diseases of stomach (cancer excepted) 1 0 j Hernia and intestinal obstruction j q j Other diseases of intestines ..._ 0 ] j [iiliary calculi ,.;.,., j 0 1 Other diseases of the liver 3 0 3 Other diseases of digestive system (cancer and tuberculosis excepted) 2 1 3 Non-veneral diseases of genito-urinary system and annexa : • Nephritis &gt; j &gt; Diseases of bladder jj j j Diseases of bones and the organs of locomotion (tuberculosis and rheumatism excepted): 12 .3 Other diseases not included in above groups: 0 4 4 External causes : . Suic!dc ■-..•- 0 3 3 Total ■ 48 64 112 92 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">TABLE XIII— AGE OF PATIENTS AT TIME OF DEATH Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. 20 and under 25 years |j j j 25 and under 30 years 7 { \ 30 and under 35 years "' 2 2! 35 and under -40 years 7 1 7 40 and under 45 years 4 4 u 45 and under 50 years 4 4 u 50 and under 55 years 5 5 i () 55 and under 60 years 3 7 ] () 60 and under 65 years _ 2 5 7 65 and under 70 years '. ", j (( 70 years and over j x 77 Total 48 r&gt;4 112 DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS __________ . July 1. l&lt;)2&lt;) to June 30. 1931 Total Produced and Disposed of Measure Value f.KRs ; 10.&gt;4o d..z. $2,561.5^ Mllk - 1,755,173.3 His. 52/iSS.2() Total - ~~$55.21670 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On Hand June 3(1. 1931 Number Value Chickens 1,75(1 $ 1,OSO.(K) Cattle 125 13,l9o.o:i jl°B s 73 1. 200.00 {ivw 3 75.00 Xlulcs 14 l.OO(UK) T " lal I $ld,5I5.OO " FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total Produced Measure Value £ or " 9,462 hu. $7,569.60 Kiisilagc f,ys t. 6,950.0(1 Hay, alfalfa , 261 t. 313200 Hay. pra.rie m , f)2UK , " als • 5,134 bu. 2.O53.M) Rye 3.380 bu. 3.042.00 Mraw : 134 t. 402.0(1 Total -■ $23,770.20 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">94 GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Total produced and disposed of Measure Value Asparagus 1.646 lbs. $ 116.22 Beans, string 10,505 lbs. 210.10 Beets 14,560 lbs. 582.40 Cabbage 63,654 lbs. 1,273.08 Cantaloupe 1.220 lbs. 24.40 Carrots 27,875 lbs. 557.50 Cauliflower 1.658 lbs. 69.40 Celery 425 lbs. 42.50 Corn, pop : 505 lbs. 20.20 Corn, sweet '. 30,600 lbs. 918.00 Cucumbers 16,642 lbs. 332.84 Egg plant 1,190 lbs. 65.75 Horseradish 340 lbs. 68.00 Kobl-rabi ' 450 lbs. 9.00 Lettuce , 7,364 lbs. 368.20 Melons, musk _ 5,470 lbs. 109.40 Melons, water '. 44.620 lbs. 446.20 Mustard, green 140 lbs. 2.80 Onions, dry 22.955 lbs. 1.147.7.=; Onions, green 26,182 lbs. 1,047.28 Parsley i 325 lbs. 81.25 Parsnips 9,950 lbs. 309.50 IVas 6,585 lbs. 460.95 Peppers 2,432 lbs. 243.20 Potatoes : 217,560 lbs. ■ 4,351.20 Potatoes, sweet :. 20.485 lbs. 1,024.25 Pumpkins : 12.550 lbs. 125.50 Radishes : 25,156 lbs. 503.12 Rhubarb 3,365 lbs. 134.50 Rutabaga 6.841 lbs. 136.82 Salsify «70 lbs. 130.00 Spinach 10,035 lbs. 401.40 SquasUi 6,600 lbs. • 132.00 Swiss chard 1,185 lbs. 23.70 Tomatoes 64,498 lbs. 1.290.06 Turnips - 25,344 lbs. 506.8H Apples 60,075 lbs. 1,801.25 Cherries 1,070 lbs. 96.30 Currants 785 lbs. 62.K0 Gooseberries - 275 lbs. 22.00 Uranus 2,790 lbs. 167.40 Plums 2,910 lbs. 116.4(1 Strawberries '. '.. 500 lbs. 60.00 Total $19,591.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF EXAMINERS OF DEFECTIVES D. G. GRIFFITHS, M. D., Chairman. Superintendent, Lincoln State Hospital. Lincoln, Nebraska J. A. BURFORD, M. D., Secretary, Superintendent, Institution for Feeble-minded, Beatrice, Nebraska G. E. CHARLTON, M. D. s Superintendent, Hastings Slate Hospital, Hastings, Nebraska J. C. NEILSEN, M. D. Superintendent, Norfolk Slate Hospital. Norfolk. Nebraska F. A. ALCORN, M. D. Superintendent, Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln. Nebraska 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions. Lincoln, Nebraska. We submit herewith the Kighth Ilienniaj Report of the Hoard ol Examiners of Defectives, covering the period beginning July 1, 1929, and ending June 30, 1931. Since the decision of the District Court of Gage County, con - firmed by the Supreme. Court, that provisions of the Sterilization Law of 1929 were unconstitutional insofar as they applied to inmates of other institutions than the Institution for Feeble-minded, all meet - ings of the r&gt;oard have been held at the latter institution. The table on the following page is a summary of the actions taken by the Hoard at the meetings held during the biennium. The Hoard has adopted and followed a conservative policy m dealing with applicants for sterilization. No patients have been sterilized without the consent of the relatives and the consent of the patients themselves. Authority to sterilize has not been given m any case until after careful consideration of the personal and family history of the pa - tient, and the Hoard has been convinced that the patient was capable &lt;&gt;f "bearing or begetting offspring, that children born or begotten liv such inmate would inherit a tendency to feeble-mindedness, insanity, degeneracy or criminality, that such children would probably become a social menace and that procreation by such inmate would be harm - ful to society." Respect fully ' submitted, D. G. GRIFFITHS, Chairman, J. A. IiURFORD, Secretary, G. I£. CHARLTON, J.C.NIELSEN, F. A. ALCORN. 96 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">3 PATIENTS COMING UNDER OBSERVATION OF THE BOARD OF EXAMINERS OF DEFECTIVES FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING JUNE 30, 1931 Authority given Authority given : Number for sterilization to parole or dis- , . . . . _ , Sterilized -ic - examined before parole or charge without Actlon dtfcrrcd Total cording to law discharge . sterilization ■ M. F. T,. M. F. T. M. F. T. ' ~~M. F. t7 ~AL F. T. ~m! F. T. Institution for Feeble- ■' " " „ m'! ldcd 5 = ■■•■• ■» » 25 11 13 24 0 0 0 0 1 1 11 U 25 5 8 13 Hastings State Hos - .pte] "•= - ;•■•■ 000 000 000 o o o 'o o o 000 Lincoln State Hospital &lt;) 10 19 8 7 15 0 3 .? 1 0 1 ' 9 10 19 2 11 Norfolk State Hospital 0 0 0 0 0 0. 000 000 000000 Tot" 1 20 24 44 ! 19 20 39 [ 0 , 3 3 j 1 1 2 ~JS 24 44 7~"~&lt;j 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p101"/>
            <seg id="p102">Reports of the State Industrial School Kearney, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p103">STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL KEARNEY, NEBRASKA OFFICERS R. V. CLARK ... Superintendent F. R. DICKSON - - - Assistant Superintendent K. L. HART. M. D. Physician S. \V. BISSELI. - - - - - - Steward MRS. MINNIE ALBRIGHT - - - - Matron \V. A. DANKOKTII - - limit Officer Miscellaneous Statement Hoys and Girls' Industrial School 1879-1891 [established as Stale- Industrial School fur Hoys 1891 Number of employes June 30, W.il 39 Number of inmates June 30. 1931 2()'i Highest number of inmates during hicnuium ....■ 23-1 I'er capita cost per month $ 37.49 Number of acres owned (A) 2 Number of acres leased : 110 Number of acres under cultivation .^BB Value of lands, buildings, furniture and equipment $370,648.88 Principal industries: Farming, stock raising. Visiting- days: Afternoons from 2 to 5, excepting' Saturdays and Sundays. Admission to the school is through commitment by court and is confined to sane boys under 18 found guilty of crime (except homicide), or boys under 16 who are beyond parental control. l&gt;oys are required to remain until 21 years of age unless sooner released by court order or paroled by the superintendent. 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p104">To. the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. The State Industrial School has received, during the present Inennium, commencing July 1, 1929, 338 ho vs. Discipline of the school is based on the merit system. Kadi boy is required to earn 18,(XX) credits, when he may lie paroled. The better his conduct, the more painstaking he is with all iutitution duties, the more honest . effort he puts into his studies, the more quickly he earns his credits, and the sooner he goes into the world l.i enjoy liberty and happiness. I'.ach boy is thus able to deterinin--. lo a marked degree, the number of months lie shall spend m ibis institution. Some boys earn the credits m nine months, others require eighteen months. Honesty is fostered by offering each bo\ 3,(HX) credits for truthfulness and trust-worthiness during bis slaw School work is outlined by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction. We make use of three rooms m teaching first to eighth grades, and we have another room for high school work which includes the ninth and tenth grades. A fifth room is used for the teaching of commercial subjects, such as typewriting, bookkeeping and business practice. The boys do fanning, tailoring, shoemaking, printing, painting, mechanical work, laundering, carpentering, cok - ing, broommaking and baking so that they might learn these trades. Half the day is spent m the school rooms, the other ball" m training for different vocations. •We have a 25-piece band. An accomplished band-master trains and conducts this group of boys which provides music for evening concerts, chapel exercises and all special occasions, giving cheer and happiness to the boys. 18 horses, 8 mules and a tractor furnish power for farm 'activities. The teamsters pride themselves m caring for, driving and working our horses. Our line farm of 572. tillable acres and the equipment provided are valuable to boys who grasp the op - portunities of agricultural life. It is a pleasure to interest boys from the city m farming, with the possibility that they will leave 101 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">the congested communities to enjoy the simple country life with its sunshine .and fresh air. Sugar beets are our most valuable crop. This biennium our net receipts from the American Meet Sugar Company' of .Grand Island have been, $4,382.61. Our farm has produced 6,221 bushels of potatoes, supplying the tables of both boys and officers. Spotted Poland China hogs have been raised so that our tables have been supplied with choice, fresh pork. Resides, hogs have been sold to the amount of $7,717.34. We are proud of our dairy herd of 120 Holsteins. We have been provided with milk, cream and butter, and milk and cream have been sold to the amount of $10,914.24. Some Holsteins have been sold, netting the school, $2,199.47. ( )ur poultry houses and yards are filled with fine while leghorns, 3,158 to be exact. During the biennium a lot of fresh eggs have been enjoyed, and the boys had chicken dinners on Thanksgiving Day, Christmas and the Fourth of July. $1,300.13 worth of eggs have been sold. A market improvement has been made m poultry raising at the institution. The sanitary condition of the school is very good. Simplicity and cleaniness is the aim of those who pride themselves on the appearance of institution property. Most of our boys have been healthy and strong, and we have had no deaths. It is a pleasure to note the improvement m the physical condition of boys after entering our school. Moral training is uppermost. It is our. endeavor to see that boys lead pure lives. Sunday schools are held m the cottages on Sunday mornings, and chapel services are held each Sunday after - noon m the gymnasium auditorium. Ministers address the boys and urge them to lead Christian lives. Heartily do 1 thank my faithful, conscientious co-workers, the citizens of Nebraska, the judges and the executive officers who have encouraged and helped us m this great work with Nebraska boys. Honorable members of the Hoard, sincere thanks do I express to you for your systematic aid, your encouragements and your kindnesses. Sincerely yours, R. V. CLARK, Superintendent. 102 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">REPORT OF PAROLE DEPARTMENT This report covers the period from December 17th. 1930, to June 30, 1931, and concerns mostly the- hoys who were paroled during that time. Tin- majority of returned hoys was paroled prior to December, 1930, and several had been out for more than one year. Of the boys paroled, 67 were m the school for the first, IS for the second, and 3 for the third time. 7 were paroled by order of the Hoard Pardons and 18 were below normal mentally. -1 hnys arc - in other institutions for crimes committed since parole. It has been difficult to find homes for the younger boys who could not be returned to parents or other relatives, inasmuch as the general depression has made families unwilling to. take another to care for. Farming and industrial conditions being bad, not many of the older boys have been able to obtain work. However, several have been placed m good homes where they are doing very well, even though the wages are only board, room and clothing. We now have on file as complete a history of each boy m the school as it is possible to obtain, and this data has been of great help to us. Many 'county, officials, as well as welfare agencies, through - out the state have been enlisted as willing aids to the parole de - partment and are giving valuable help m making home investigations and m supervision of boys on parole. Our parole officer aims to make as thorough an investigation as possible of family history and the causes of commitment of every boy and visit each -boy on parole as often as possible, at least once m two months. Home investigation is made, either by mail or by the officer m person, m each case before a boy is released on parole. Carefully checked monthly reports from boys on parole serve to keep the school m close touch with each boy as to his conduct. Considerable time has been, spent m pursuit work, with a result that nearly all escaped boys have been returned, and the school has a satisfactory account of those not returned. During the six-month period, our parole officer has traveled 4,191.6 miles by automobile and over 530 miles by train, trolley or bus, and following is an outline of work done : 103 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">Roys paroled .■ -. (White 78: Negro 6: Indian 3: Mexican 1) 88 Returned for violations 23 Returned for relocation , 3 Recommitted .; 3 Discharged as of age 50 Discharged to the Court 1 Home investigations made '. .• 63 Other investigations, complaints, etc 35 Visits to paroled boys '. 60 Location of Paroled Roys: Returned to parents 64 Returned to others 24 Returned to Omaha (Douglas County) : 26 Returned to Lincoln ( Lancaster County &gt; 3 Others counties .". . 44 Out of the state 15 Occupations of Paroled Boys: School boy 26 Farmer . ; 26 Hotel worker „ 2 Printer. ; 1 Miscellaneous 15 Unknown _ 12 Conduct of Paroled Hoys: I )oing well ;.... 32 Doing fairly well : ;. 15 1 )ning badly , 6 Unknown 7 First report not yet received 12 Sincerely yours, R. V. CLARK, Superintendent. 104 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">105 table i— movement of population Period eliding June 30, 1931 Present at beginning of period ioj Admitted: • "" For the first time o-to Readmitted ZZ"'"'"""'""'"""~" ° Returned from parole during biennium % On escape July 1, 1929 "" 37 Returned from transfer to another institution i ............ ' 1 T °tal '. 568 Discharged : Reached majority .-. _ o Transferred to another institution " 1 Discharged paroled during the two years""""""" 308 On escape July 1, 1931 47 Total : , 362 Remaining at institution at end of period 206 TABLE II— AGE AND COLOR OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 ' \ W. C. ToUd Under ten ;. 7~~ 9 Ten and under fourteen '"""'""". 2 7 } 25 Fourteen and under sixteen {JO ]j) of) Sixteen and under eighteen ', - &lt;jn &lt;j 107 Eighteen and under twenty-one """"""!"'."" 6 1 7 T " t:i1 "213 25 23iT TABLE III— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 Below and including third grade p Fourth grade _ j^ Fifth grade .....".""~..."..Z!!. I 20 Sixth grade Z.~....Z...."Z 45 Seventh grade !..""..~"""!! 34 Highth grade [ j# High school , 65 Finished high school !"'".."!!!!" 1 Total - ~ 238 </seg>
            <seg id="p109">TABLE IV— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending ' June- .30. l')M Nebraska ; ; _.. 1,37 United States other than Nebraska 95 Total native horn 232 Uanada 4 Mexico j Poland " 1 Total foreign born (&gt; Total ! , ~ 238 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30, l'»31 United States both parents 156 Foreign 33 Mixed ., 4n Unknown .5 Total : j 2.W TABLE VI— PARENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED I Period ending j June 30, 1931 Parents both dead .' 17 Father dead 37 Mother dead 17 Parents living together 11.? Parents divorced 14 Parents separated -.V) Parents unknown 1 Total .' 238 106 </seg>
            <seg id="p110">TABLE VII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED DURING THE BIENNIUM Total Adams ; N Antelope 3 Box Butte , i 3 lirowu 1 Buffalo ZZ.ZZ.ZZ.Z! ( t Burt ; .' ' " 3 Butler :. '. 1 Cass 2 Chase ; » 2 Chcycmic 4 Clay ..._...r.Z 2 Custer 7 Dakota ...- ZZZ 1 Dawcs 1 Dawson ? Deuel : : .....ZZZZZ..ZZ.ZZZZZ.Z! 2 Dodge '.' 4 Douglas hi 1 Dundy • 3 Furuas ■ 2 &lt;Iage ■■ : ■ 7 Marian _5 Hayes \ Hithcock 3 Hooker *j Howard j Jefferson j Johnson 1 Keith ZZ1ZZZ. 1 Knox (, Lancaster 13 Lincoln ZZZZZZZ. 2 Madison 3 Merrick ZZZZZZ 2 -Vlorrill ZZZ 4 Nemaha (, otoe .....ZZZZZZZ!!.""!! 4 Pawnee : 1 Pheips- : ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ! 3 Pierce .: 2 Platte j Polk 2 Red Willow ZZZZZZZlZZZZZ 8 Richardson ZZZZZZZ!! 8 Saline Z!!!!!Z!!ZZZ 1 Saunders 3 Scotts Bluff _ ZZZZI.'.ZZZZ.Z 10 Slierman ZZZZZ. 1 Thayer ZZ.ZZZZ.Z 2 Thurston .'...'. • i Valley ZZZZZZZZZZZ. 2 Washington ? Wayne f Webster , York ZZZZZZZZZZZZZ 3 Total 238 107 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">TABLE VIH— CAUSE FOR ADMISSION OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June- 30, 1931 Incorrigible ] Theft ZZZZZZZZZ 13 Breaking and entering 18 Forgery ; 9 Uurglary 4 Raijc ........................ 1 Petit larceny 1 Airto theft 16 Delinquency _ 168 Felony 5 Total . 238 DAIRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30. 1931 Total produced and disposed of Measure Value ■W'k 593,415 ll)s. $17,802.45 '••KKs 18.231 doz. 4.557.75 Total •• — ■■ - .' $22.3f&gt;0.20 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On Hand Juiu 30, 1931 | Number Value i-*»«tle j 120 $l(U3Ti7 Chickens I 3,158 1,894.80 Hogs , , I ,W3 2,277.95 Horses 26 2.750.00 Rabbits 119 119.00 Total j $17,372.92 FARM PRODUCTS July 1. 192") to June 30, 1931 • Total produced Mi-asure Value Alfalfa - 685 t. ?8.220.00 Barley 4.392 bu. 3,074.4') Barley straw 1-45 t. • 435.00 Beets, sugar 715 t. 4.382.61 * »rn. far 3,924 hu. 3.139.20 Kn.silage 415 t. 4,150.00 Pasture , 486 a. 1.588.00 Total $24,989.21 108 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July 1, \&lt;)2) to June 30, l'&gt;31 Total produced and disposed of , : Measure Value Asparagus 4.4W |l',s. $ ,?14&lt;H Beans, string ,, m) Uls , , ()()() Beets, red ; ;. ,,,270 ||,.,. 250k) Cabbage i().t(&gt;5 lbs. oOMO Cantaloupes 2(1.170 lbs. 40340 Carrots s,0&lt;«) lbs. 15' 70 eler - v 7.050 l| )s . 352.50 Corn, sweet , w.uuS || )s , )K ,, f)i; Cucumbers * O.4S5 lbs. l«&lt;/7&lt;» JjeB Plant 2 iO7 5 |, )S Ul( ,; 5() Horse. radish 275 lbs. 16 5o 'f'fuce -. 10.180 lbs. 61080 Melons, water 52.1'X) ||, s . 52I &lt;)U Mustard greens 2,665 lbs 7')&lt;)5 Onions, dry 1 1.-105 ||, s . 570*25 Onions, green ; K...W8 || )s . ( ,5 5 &lt;,'&gt; Parsnips , 1,500 n, s 4^ m \ Peas 3,765 lbs. 2(..5.55 Poppers n.150 lbs. 184.50 Pumpkins M.M30 lb.s. 148 ,i() Potatoes, Irish ,?(W,480 Il&gt;s. 7,H)&gt;&gt;.U) Potat.ies, sweet 12,8()fi lbs. o4() M) Kadislies » 8,2.?() ||, s . lwa , Khubarli 8.').?o lh s . 178 Mi Sajsify 470 ||, s , i-t.10 Spmacli 3,271 lbs. 130 84 • s '|uash 18,810 lbs. 376 20 Swiss chard 2.075 lbs. 6? 25 Tomatoes 61,5'JO lbs. 1,231 8(1 Turnips Ct,7'Xi lbs. 135 80 Apples _... 51,050 lbs. 1,531.50 Cherries 2.IW2 lbs. 18828 1 urrants 1.121 lbs. 8'J.68 (.ooscbemes 2.750 lbs. 220 Oi) '■■""I"-* 8.8W lbs. 533.40 Plumbs : 1,030 lbs. 41.20 Strawberries 4,410 ||, s . 529.92 T «t ;i1 ■■ ■ ?20,l 1 1.32 109 </seg>
            <seg id="p113"/>
            <seg id="p114">Report of the Hospital for Tuberculous Kearney, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p115">HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS KEARNEY. NEBRASKA OFFICERS L. T. SIDWELL. M. D. - . - - Superintendent HARRY C. SMITH. M. D. - --.- Assistant Superintendent T. 1.. HAVI.UKK. M. I).. . - - - Assistant Physician S. II. IJOLKJACK - - - - - - - . Steward I.OUISK-C. SKIHKI. - - : - ■- - - - Head Nursi- ANNA M. STAUB1TZ - - - - - - - Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established ;..... 191 1 XumbiM- of employes June 30, 1931 57 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 139 Highest number of inmates during biennium 151 Per capita cost per month . ; ' $ 54.89 Number of acres owned 37 Number of acres under cultivation 17 Value of lands, buildings, furniture and equipment ". $316,390.13 Visiting days: Every day excepting Sunday, 11 to 12 A. M., and 4 to 6 P. M. Admission : A full and detailed report is required from a practicing physician of the state, made to the superintendent of the institution. The expense of the patient's examination is borne by the county of residence when not otherwise paid for. "Pay patients" may be admitted provided there is room for. them. 112 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions. Lincoln, Nebraska. I herewith present the Ninth I'.iennial Report of the Hospital lor Tuberculous for the biennium ending June 30, 1931. During the biennium our hospital has been lilted to capacity most of .the time, and a part of the time we have had many on our waiting list. Our new wing which has thirty beds for women was opened last November. Until a few weeks ago all of our beds for women were filled, and there were some applicants waiting. During the warmer months a larger number of our patients find it possible to take care of themselves at home and desire to take vacations. For this reason, our population now is slightly under wiiat it has been. and all women applicants have been accepted. Recently we have had more men applicants than we could accomodate. but Our number of applications for men now has been reduced to ten. However all our beds are filled. There have been no outstanding happenings during the past two years. Our institution has m a number of ways shown im - provement and is growing larger. On the whole, results obtained have been as good, if not better, than m previous bienniums, and, although our population is larger, the number of deaths has de - creased. 1 believe the physicians of the state are taking more interest m our hospital, ami during the .past year we have received a few more early cases than previously. On April 30th of this year we held a meeting for physicans at the Hospital m conjunction with the Nebraska Tuberculosis Association, one hundred physicians attend - ing. In order to keep up the efficiency of the institution, we have kept close track of conditions and have made many repairs and replacements. In addition to those mentioned m last year's report, we have accomplished the following: 113 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">The pavilion has been reshingled with asbestos shingles, the beds m the pavilion and hospital have been recastored with a large - hospital type castor, a new wooden floor has been laid on the boys porch at the pavilion and a terrazzo floor m the hospital kitchen and an electric refrigerator installed at the east sun kitcTien and a small one at the stone building. There has also been $500.00 worth of furniture and rugs purchased lor different parts of the institution. A Kent floor machine has been added to our equipment, a large vaccum pump for our heating system installed m our heating plant, and new llues were put m our hot water heater. At the present time we are building an addition to our greenhouse, doubling its capacity. This is entirely home made and will be of great benefit m raising more vegetables and flowers. We have installed a small merry-go-round aiid built three old fashionde swings for the children. The material for a concrete vegetable cave has been purchased, but construction on it will not be completed for a while. We have continued to look after numerous small repairs as needed. Painting has been kept up. Our land has been used to the fullest extent m raising garden I ruck, potatoes, sweet corn, hay and other farm products. The ministers of Kearney still conduct services without re - muneration each Sunday. The college Y. W. C. A. has given a program once each month. The Industrial School continues the weekly band concerts during the summer months. Several musical organizations have given concerts. The World Theatre has ad - mitted our patients free of charge on an average of about every two weeks for a number of months past. The bookstore and other agencies handling magazines have given us their unsold copies. Many individuals have done much for different patients. For all of these tilings and others that have not been mentioned, 1 feel es - pecially grateful and am sure the patients have received great en - joyment as a result of these contributions. In concluding this report 1 desire to extend to the Hoard my thanks for the splendid co-operation given this institution during the past biennium. 1 wish also at this time to express my ap - preciation of the continued loyalty shown by my co-workers. Respectfully submitted, L. T. SIDWELL, Superintendent. 114 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">115 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June 30. 1931 M. F. T. Present at beginning of period 44 5j 95 Admitted for first time ■ P4 14? */, Readmitted ; • ]k 14 p On parole at beginning of period '; 10 "]9 _ Total 195 217 412~ Discharged: Apparently cured 7 , Arrested ,| f 7 j Apparently arrested '. ,^ ,„ f' Quiescent \% '* •]" Improved U * f Unimproved • ;, -° UlccI ; . ?*j 1 / 1^* Unclassified ""." ' T ( . !,}' Ji Not tuberculous 1\\3"'.".'.'"".' () V i 1 On parole at end of period ] 4 i Total -^ 135 T« 27T Total remaining in institution at end of period 60 79 139 TABLE II— NATIVITY OF PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME ' Period ending June 30. 1931 . u7 r t7 Nebraska _ i 41 L mted States other than Nebraska 47 47 94 Austria 0 -&gt; -, Czechoslovakia 3 0 3 Denmark . j q j England "~"~ 2 0 "&gt; Germany _ 2 0 5 Greece 2 0 ~&gt; Italy ' 1 j ~? Mexico _ ] 1 j Poland • ZJ....Z.1..~..~.Z~Z1. 0 6 (i Kussia '. : 1 0 1 Scotland 10 1 Sweden 3 4 7 : Total - - 124 142 266 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">TABLE III— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR THE FIRST TIME AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT THE END OF BIENNIUM Total for Actually remaining . Bicnniuiti at Institution M. F. T. 117 V. T\ Adams ,i (, y ? ? 7 ! 5oo »&lt;: • 1 0 1 10 1 ! rc '"V • 2 0 2 1.01 '"ffalo : 7 U 13 5 16 " r ,t 12 3 0 1 1 Uutler ;. 1 i 2 o 0 0- , l .; lss ; - 2 13 0 0 o S laj ; - - 2 ■ » -5 o o o Luster 2 4 0 0 3 .1 !^ :lkot:l (ill 0 i i uawson 3 4 7 ? 5 £ ix ,°" --■ 2 13 o b n P od ec io l o o o Douglas ,U 3S 71 1' '7 V) Franklin ; .. 1 0 l 1 ~q " j Furnas 0 11 0 0 0 (■age 10 1 2 0? ( ' n 7, k '" ° 11 0 0 (» Hall 2 13 13 4 Hamilton 4 0 4 3 0 3 Harlan 0 0 0 . • 2 0 • ~&gt; Holt 0. 1 1 T 0 T Howard 3 0 3 0 0 0 Jefferson 2 1 3 . 2 1 3 Kearney 0 11 0 0 0 Kimliall 2 13 2 0 2 Knox 1 3 ' 4 1 2-3 Lancaster 8 V) 27 &lt;J \l 2(1 Lincoln 3 0 3 0 0 0 McPlicrson 1 0 1 0 0 ' 0 Madison , 2 5 7 14 5 Merrick :: o 1 l 0 q () .Vance 1 2 3 2 0 2 N'emaha 10 1 0 0 0 Nuckolls II 2 2 0 1 I Otoe 5 2 7 11? Pawnee 10 1 1 0 T Pliclps 1 1 2 0 0 0 Pierce 12 3 0 \ \ Plattc •&gt; 3 6 13 4 Polk : 13 4 0 () () Red Willow 0 11 0 1 1 Kichardson 10 1 Oil Saline 3 2 5 112 116 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">TABLE III-COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR THE FIRST TIME AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT THE END OF BIENNIUM (Continued) m- T. tT £ TT" Saunclers s . i ? ? „ j . Scotts Bluff 2 J 4 o &gt; , •jewnrd i I 2 « I T Sherman 0 2 2 Oil ? r ' a - vcr • I 0 2 1 (I 1 riiurston 5 « l.i 1 5 , ,\" n £¥ 0.1 i i, (, u Washington 112 0 0 0 Wayne 112 112 cl ? stcr 3 1 4 ,3 1 4 or k 0 4 4 0 11 Total 124 142 266 «P V) 13&lt;j TABLE IV— AGE OF PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME For Period Ending June 30, l'-tfl M. ¥. T 5 to 9 years , 77, 77 10 to 14 years % , }'' 15 to 17 years ZIZIZZZZ 4 ,, 7 18 to 24 years ■ 2 C, 51 25 «° 34 years ; ™; 3rj 4&lt;J - y 35 to 44 years 25 25 i() 45 to 49 years ; ....,...". ~7 12 V&gt; 50 to 59 years 1? 7 Id «) to 69 years ZZZZZZZZ 6 1 7 Total : 124 142 26fT 117 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">TABLE V— CIVIL STATUS OF PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME . Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T7 Single _ _ 61 54 115 Married 52 08 120 Widowed _ 3 9 12 Divorced 8 8 16 Separated , _.... 0 3 3 Total _ 124 142 266 TABLE VI— EDUCATION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30. 1931 M. F. T. Primary 3 7 10 Common school 73 . 78 151 High school 37 46 83 College or university 10 10 . 20 N'one II 2 Total 124 142~ 266~ TABLE VII— RURAL AND URBAN DISTRIBUTION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30. 1931 Country villages and towns 32 37 60 Cities of 1.000 and under 5.000 33 25 58 Cities of 5.000 and under 25.000 ." 19 23 42 Cities of 25.000 and under 40.000 0 0 0 Cities of 40.000 and under 100,000 '. 7 19 26 Citie"s cif 100.000 and over : 33 38 71 Total ..: 124 142 266 118 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">TABLE VIII— PROGRESS OF DISEASE OF PATIENTS "'■ • AT ADMISSION Period ending June M). V)3\ : m. ~ t~ Incipient \ j j Moderately advanced ...; 57 (l y j 74 Far advanced 41 jo 7! • on-tulierculous | 0 2 &gt; Chronic fibroid 1 ]^ 97 Tota! : - I* 12-1 1-12 2o~ TABLE IX— SHOWING PROBABLE SOURCE OF INFECTION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, l')31 ' m. T. r~ Sources not known 5f, 5] JJJ7 Previous infection of other members of the patient's family ■. 27 52 7&lt;) Onset following influenza 15 21 V, Pneumonia ; 7 o "j^ Overwork _ 7 4 lj Severe cold 437 Previous infection of other persons with whom patient lived or worked 2 2 4 Onset following operation 2 13 Nature of occupation 3 0 3 Onset following childbirth ■ () ] "j Whooping cough 0 1 I Car accident 1 0 j Total ■ -'- 124 142 266 119 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">TABLE X— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30, 1931 JiT fT~ T~ Attendant .: : 0 1 1 l!;ikcr : 1 0 1 linrliiT '. 2 0 2 Bindery . 0 1 1 Boilermaker 1 (I 1 Bookkeeper 1 1 2 Box maker 10.1 Bus hoy : 1 0 1 Carpenter 1 I) 1 Cashier = 0.1 1 Chauffeur 1 0 1 Chef 1 0 1 Civil engineer ; 10 1 Cleaner &amp; dyer 1 0 1 Clerk 7 -4 11 Cook 2 1 3 Dentist 1 0 1 Dredger 1 0 1 Klectrician 4 0 4 Klevator hoy 1 0 1 Farmer '. 29 0 29 Foreman 1 0 1 Horseman : 10 1 Housewife 0 72 72 Housework 0 9 &lt;J Insurance salesman 2 0 2 janitor '. 1 0 1 Laborer 24 0 24 Laundress 0 2 2 Machinist ■. 1 (I 1 Mason ! 1 0 1 Mechanic 2 0 2 Merchant 1 0 1 Miner : 1 0 1 None 1 4 5 Nurse 0 3- • 3 Packer .0 1 1 Painter 3 0 3 Plumber , 1 0 1 Radio manufacturer 10 1 Railroad station agent 10 1 Salesman 4 0 4 Sailor : 1 0 1 Section foreman : 1 0 1 Stenographer 13 4 Student 13 30 4.' Solicitor 1 0 1 Tailor ." 1 0 1 Teamster , 1 0 1 Teacher _ 0 3 3 Telephone Operator 0 3 3 ■» 120 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">TABLE X— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED (Continued) Period ending June 30, im _J , M. R tT Telephone repairman 10 1 Typ^t LZ'ZZ™. o i i \\ artress 0 2 2 Welder • ........."".I". 1 0 1 Total 124 142 26f) TABLE XI— AGE AT DEATH ', Period ending June 30, 1931 m! F. T~ Under 15 years , 1 ] 2 15 and under 20 years 1 (I T 20 and under 25 years .". 5 3 8 25 and under 30 years 5 1 () 30 and under 40 years .,"""'" 5 5 10 40 and under 50 years 4 4 50 and under 60 years ......'." (&gt; 2 8 'i0 years and over 2 I) ' Tot;i1 2&lt;J 16 45~ POULTRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 Produced and Consumed Measure Value K BB S .' 3.038 doz. $759.58 Total $759.58 FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 . Total Produced - Measure Value Alfalfa, hay ~ J7 $24.00 MlUct ; 2.'/. t. 27.00 Total - • $51.00~ 121 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July 1, 192&lt;J to June 30, 19.31 Produced and Consumed Measure Value Asparagus 40 IDs. $ 3.50 Beans 1.098 lbs. 21.57 Beets : 2,910 lbs-. 116.41 Cabbage 9,839 lbs. 196.78 Cantaloupes 225 lbs. 4.50 Carrots 7.157 lbs. 214.71 Cauliflower 309 lbs. 18.64 Celery (bunches) 500 300!) Chard : 1.880 lbs. 75.20 Com, sweet : _. 13,694 lbs. 380.82 Cucumbers 1.476 lbs. 29.52 Kgg plant 1,126 lbs. 67.56 Lettuce &amp; Chinese cabbage _,.... 5,2-46 lbs. 262.30 Onions : ; 13.686 lbs. 659.87 Parsley 500 lbs. 30.00 Parsnips _ ., 3.480 lbs. 104.40 Peas 932 lbs. 65.24 Peppers ; 720 lbs 72.50 Potatoes, Irish ". 6S.5K0 lbs. 1,371.60 Potatoes, sweet 1,930 lbs. 96.50 Pumpkins 4.100 lbs. 41.00 Radishes 1,020 lbs. 20.40 Rhubarb 895 lbs. 35.80 Spinach : .....; 7,220 lbs. 288.80 •Squash 650 lbs. 13.00 Tomatoes 16.992 lbs. 359.84 Turnips : 6.240 lbs. 124.80 Apples : ;.. H27 lbs. 24.81 Grapes : 300 lbs. 18.00 Total : : $4,748.07 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On Hand June 30, 1931 : Number Value Chickens ftjs $ 77,59 H °ES 10 " 79.OO Horses 2 225.00 Total $381.50 122 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">Report of the Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p127">ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL , LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS F. A. ALCORN. M. D. ' . - Superintendent 11. \V. ORR, M. D. - - - - Orthopedic Surgeon FRIEDA TENFOLD, R. N. - - Superintendent of Nurses GLADYS FOREMAN - - ... - . Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established . . 1905 Number of employes June 30, 1931 , 58 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 101 Highest number of inmates during biennium 110 Per capita cost per 'month 79.20 Number of acres owned 3.76 Value of lands and buildings, furniture and equipment 5261.151.40 Visiting days : Every clay from 2 P. M. to 4P. M. Application for admission must be accompanied by statement from a physician describing the condition of the patient. As preference is given to indigent cases, a statement is also required as to the financial status of the patient or his relatives. Examina - tion expenses, as well as those of transportation to and from home, and cost of clothing must be paid by patient, his. friends or relatives, or by the county. 124 </seg>
            <seg id="p128">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. ', The thirtenth Mennial Report, covering the operations of the Orthopedic Hospital for the period ending June 30. 1931, is herewith respectfully submitted. The Orthopedic Hospital was created by an enactment of the Legislature of 1905 and on October Ist of the same year the hospital was opened for the reception of patients. During the first part of the present year, 1931, the new fireproof annex unit was completed, and on February 10, 1931, the patients m the old original building were transferred to the new unit. This has a capacity of liftv-two beds and is so constructed that the patients can get the maximum of fresh air, both night and day, and sunshine. The basement lloor houses a very modern and well equipped kitchen, a reconstructive swimming pool, a massage and physiotherapy room and an enter - tainment room. The main lloor has a partially equipped diet kitchen, two well lighted wards, two large bathrooms and several private rooms. This lloor and one above have porticoes on the south exposure so that each bed m the ward may be wheeled out and the patients may enjoy a restful night's sleep m the open air. The same may be used for direct sunlight exposure during the fore - noons: The second tloor is an exact duplication of the main floor. The operating and x-ray units on the top lloor have not been m use for lack of equipment. Through the efforts of the Hoard of Control, the kind and considerate legislatures and others concerned, we now have funds to go ahead and eqiup this new part which will soon be functioning an appreciated by all. Today, lite hospital stands as proof of Nebraska's pioneering and is, m its present service to our citizens, a monument to our great state. 125 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">The purpose of the Orthopedic Hospital is that of correction of twisted little bodies m children, prevention of deformities, and it stands as a help to the medical and surgical professions of our state. Those are admitted whose -parents or caretakers are unable to stand the tinacial burden of prolonged private treatment. Tables appended hereto will give a very comprehensive idea of the scope and magnitude of the work being done. Application for admission, examination, and possible treatment is made to the Superintendent of the hospital direct. This consists of two blank forms which are supplied by the institution. One of these forms calls for information relative to the financial state ot parents or caretakers of the patient m mind. This statement is - sworn to before a notary public. The second blank is one that must be executed by the physician m attendance prior to admission and calls for data relative to birth and general history of the patient from early babyhood. It also requires a medical description of the deformity and history of the possible cause with a statement from the physician relative to prognosis and his tentative diagnosis. Xo charge is made for the hospital service nor the medical or surgical procedure, if such is indicated after careful observation and examination of the patient. However, parents or caretakers arc required to supply adequate clothing and meet the expenses of mechanical appliances if these are indicated. Owing to a number of applicants on the waiting list at all times, it is necessary that application blanks be executed and sent to the superintendent prior to bringing the patient to the hospital. 1 f blanks are found satifactory, then the superintendent makes an ap - pointment and goes over the patient thoroughly with a view to treatment and admission if this is indicated. The hospital stands ready at all times to give free consulation to physicians throughout the state and will give every help to solve perplexing problems thai we all must meet and can be handled out of the hospital. The patients while under treatment m the Orthopedic Hospital are given the advantages of continuing their school work, and classes are conducted each day m all grades up to and including the eighth. The work is outlined by the county and city boards of education. The teachers are all registered and duly accredited with both the county and city boards of education. On completion of the eighth grade, the pupil is permitted to take the examinations of the county 126 </seg>
            <seg id="p130">for admission to high school. It is pleasing to state that m 1927 we had thirteen such graduates, and m the past years we have had several pupils that, while being treated, finished their work and passed the high school requirements by examination. It is a well recognized fact that the minds of our little cripples have to be given first consideration, for without an easy aivl well occupied mind the' work from a medical and surgical standpoint is handicapped. As it was considered that the running of a nurses' training school m connection with the hospital was a financial loss, the irain - ing school was discontinued. Graduate nurse supervisors and nurse aides were employed to do the work previously done by the student nurses. As this change has only existed since February, 1931, we do not at present know its final outcome, m a financial way. However, it is more sati factory from the standpoint of the patient's care and the amount of work done. During the past few months' Mrs. Thelma Swift, Rcgisterel Nurse, has been added to the payroll to take charge of swimming and muscular constructive exercises for those who need it. The swimming pool is a decided benefit to many and, particularly, to those after effects of infantile paralysis. Mrs. Swift is assisted m the swimming pool work by Miss Irene Wallace, masseuse. Mr. H. F. Willcss has been employed as part time technician m the laboratory. The aim is to have dependable and efficient la - boratory service for all patients m the hospital who need it. Certain routine laboratory tests shall be required for all patients who enter the institution. In rendering this report, it is gratifying to the present manage - ment to herein state that the recommendations made m the last annual report were favorably acted upon, and as-a result a splendid annex unit is now occupied. This unit replaces the old original building which through the past eight years has been a menace not only to life itself, but has inhibited work m the highly specialized line of citizen rehabilitation. The new building with its added fa - cilities is one of the biggest steps forward m this work. This improvement will bring the Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital up to the very peak of institutions , of its kind and will be second to none m its physical equipment and facilities for handling the work coming under its jurisdiction. 127 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">The work of the past two years is clearly outlined m the tables herein incorporated and needs but a few commentaries to bring to mind the salient points that need stressing. It will be noted that during the last two years several patients, who have been here more or less for long periods, were discharged. The long term of their residence was due m several instances to the tact that home conditions were such that no care could be given them, and they, being helpless, were at the mercy of the state for a short period of custodial care until such time as satisfactory home conditions could be brought about. At the time of the present management's taking office, several patients were found to have been inmates for a long period, due. to inability to discharge them. In the admission of patients it is very necessary to watch and examine carefully the applications, for many of the requests are for patients needing only custodial care, and, once received, they cannot readily be shifted. If the institution were purely custodial it would take but a short time to fill it with the hopeless, and this would be a detriment to the work for which the hospital was erected. People many times think the hospital is a home, and it is always necessary to remind the laymen, as well as the physician, that this is an acute hospital and m no way a home for the unfortunate cripple. It is the desire of the present management to have as quick a turnover as possible m the hospital. Therefore, as soon as we have done all we can for a patient, we dismiss him, and make room for others who are m need of constructive treatment. It is only by this plan that the greatest number of deserving patients can be benefit - ted. During the past two years repairs have been maintained throughout as far as limited funds were available. The wear and tear is great, for children are careless, and through their residence the buildings suffer heavily unless constant vigilance is kept and repairs made when needed. The old original building is m a very deplorable state and is not much more than a tire trap. It is hoped the day will hasten when it may be torn down and a suitable school building erected m its place. The laundry plant is m poor condition and the attendant in - forms me that he has repaired it so often that it is almost beyond 128 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">repair We are m the hopes that it will keep going without a major breakdown, necessitating a delay m operations. The employment situation has been very satisfactory m that we always have a nucleus of old employes who function well and without their understanding and continued loyalty the institution' would be markedly handicapped. In many positions the personnel undergoes a great turnover m a year, and this is m great part due to the salaries, the average man or woman only using the position as a stepping stone to tide them over until a better and more lucrative position affords itself. This can - not well be eliminated until we begin to realize that belter salaries bring better help and makes the institution position a profession ratiie than a side issue m the employment situation. To the members of the Hoard of Control, we owe much for their kindness and wise counsel. They make the effort worth while with their every cooperation, and whatever success this report in - dicates is, m a greater measure, due to their ministrations through - out the period. Respectfully submitted, F. A. AI.COKX, 1 Superintendent. 129 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">130 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June 30, 1931 M. ¥. T~ 1'icM'iit at beginning of period 43 53 96 Admitted for first time 90 93 183 Readmitted '. 19 39 58 Returned from parole 28 12 41) Total 180 197 377 Discharged: Cured ...., ." '. .■ 51 53 104 Improved 70 73 149 Unimproved - 5 12 17 While on parole ; 10 1 Died v : 3 2 5 Total 136 140 27o~~ Total remaining in hospital July 1, 1931 44 57 101 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 M. R tT 1 and under 3 mouths 2 0 2 .i and under (t months 0 0 0 ii and under 12 months ._ 2 3 5 1 and under 2 years &lt; 3 1 4 2 and under 5 years- 14 5 19 5 and under 10 years 24 15 30 10 and under 15 years 25 3(1 55 15 and under 20 years 13 28 41 20 and under 25 years 4 ' 7 11 25 and under 30 years _ 2 13 30 and under 40 years 0 1 1 40 and under 50 years 1 2 3 Total ., 90 93 183 </seg>
            <seg id="p134">131 TABLE III— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 ; M. F. T. Total ■ ■■ 90 93 183~ TABLE IV— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending • . June 30, 1931 ■ m. ¥. t7 None 90 ™ jj. Kindergarten 'IIZIZZZZZZIZZZI 0 0 0 1st to 4th grade t« i#. ii 4th to 8th grade ~ J 7 [ t&gt; '],, 8th to 12th grade 23 31 54 High school _ 4 rt , () ColIc Kc 0 1 1 T "' : '' ■ : ■ &gt;K) 93 183 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 ' ~~M. R tT Nebraska . .....". ~. ~~^ 8fl m U. S. other than Nebraska 7 7 14 Total ■■ 90 93 183^ </seg>
            <seg id="p135">TABLE VI— COUNTY RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME AND THOSE REMAINING ISiennium All Remaining Total for June 30, 1931 M. F. T. M. F. T. Adams '. 1 i 2 0 1 1 Arthur (I 0 0 0 1 1 Maine 0 0 (I Oil Box Butte 0 2 2 1 12 Brown :. 0 0 0 10 1 Buffalo (Ill Oil Burt 0 1 1 0 0 0 Cass 0 3 3 0 2 2 Cumins 0 11 0 2 2 Custcr ■ 0 11 0 1 1 Dakota 10 1 112 Dawcs 2 0 2 0 .? .? Dawson 0 1 1 1 1 2 Dcucl ; II 0 0 0-1 1 n&gt;od K e 1 2 3 0 2 2 Douglas 2 (&gt; H 3 2 5 Dundy 0 2 2 0 11 Fillmoro 0 2 2 0 11 Franklin 2 0 2 2 2 4 Frontier 0 2 2 0 2 2 Pumas 0 3 3 13 4 f.ace 3 4 7 2 1 3 Garden .....: 0 11 10 1 (iosper 0 3 3 10 1 nreclcy 0 11 0 11 Hall ..1 0 1 11 1 2 Hamilton II 1 1 0 11 Marian 4 0 4 0 0 0 Hitchcock 112 0 0 0 Howard Oil (III lefTers.m 112. 101 Johnson ..: •' o 3 10 1 Kcarncv '. Oil 000 Knox " 1 ' 0 0 o Lancaster . 44 ]') . n3 11 7 IK Lincoln (Ill 0 0 (I Madison 112. 112 Mcrrick 1.1 2 1 0 1 Morrill : 10 1 10 1 Nance • •? » .? (Ill Nuckolls 12 3 0 2 2 Otoc 3 2 5 3 0 3 Pawnee 0 11 0 0 0 Perkins 0 2 2 (111 Platte 3 14 0 11 Polk _.. (Ill 2 13 Red Willow Oil 0 0 (I Richardson Oil 0 0 0 Saline - 1.01 0 0 0 Saumlers 3 1 4 2 3 5 132 </seg>
            <seg id="p136">TABLE VI-COUNTY RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME AND THOSE REMAINING (Continued) X otaI - for All Remaining Dicnnium j ullL . 3^ 193] . . ' M- F. T. M. F. T7 Scotts Bluff : 0 3 3 ~ " — Scward (I 2-2 1 , Slicrman 1 -&gt; , ' ' ■Tjwr : J f f W=,- :::::=:::::::::::■ . I •• . &gt; . ffcsr:::::::::::::::::::::: J j .5 | i! I | ■ ; | . T " t:&gt;1 --■ W ".? 1.S3 44 57 101 TABLE VII— FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND THOSE REMAINING Total for Biciuiium A ," remaining June 30, 1W1 . M. I?. T. 2KL F - T - Abscess 1 1 , „ — JJ — Amputations 2 0 2 0 n A " c&gt;1 ". i:i ■-:■.■ ! 0 I ,) 0 Antcrui polio 1 &gt; 5 0 &gt; " Appendicitis 5 ,,- ■ ,", „ * - Arthritis J 2 -1 5 ■ 1 J Ascia ' s : • ■ nil il 0 0 Uoiycd legs 1 (I 1 ,1 „ „ Broken arm 1 0 1 ,1 „ „ B . ur ». s : •••■; 112 (I (I Carcinoma of intestine (I 1 1 (1 0 n Cleft palate 1 1 7 0 II ,1 Club-foot ,... 5 4 -7 " 2 I Club-feet 1 1 Z . (I ~&gt; j Club-feet and hands 1 (I 1 I 0 7 Congenital deformites (I () (I (» 1 1 Curvature c&gt;f spine 112 Oil Deformity of hip 1 1-2 000 Ear trouble 0 11 0 0 0 Mat feet _ 2 2 4 ■ 1 2 " Fracture ankle 10 1 1.01 elbow 2 U 2 0 0 (I „ h «P. - 112 0 0 (I tibia I 1 0 1 0.0 0 „ " .. wrist 2 U 2 ()()() Harelip (Ill 0 0 (l Infection 111 toe 1 0 1 () () 0 Injury to clavicle 10 1 0 0 0 Injury to hand 10 1 10 1 Injury to leg 2 0 2 0 0 0 Influenza 0 11 0 0 0 Lateral curvature of , ■ s P i " e .... 0 2 2 0 0 0 Legal Sterilization 0 8 8 0 0 0 Little s disease ; 0 11 0 1 1 133 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">TABLE VII— FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND THOSE REMAINING (Continued) Total for Biennium A T U rc ??. ai 1 n o i " B . June 30, 1931 \T F. T\ M. R f! Mastoid (i l l 0 0 0 ■ Mongolian idiot 1 0 1 1 0 I Muscular atrophy 10 1 0 0 0 Nerve injury 1 0 1 0 0 0 Operation on old incision 0 11 0 0 0 Osgood-Schlatter's disease - 0 11 0 11 Osteomalacia 1.01 1 1 2 Osteomyelitis 5 4 ') 5 4 &lt;J Paralysis due to injury -011 (111 Paralysis, infantile 14 &lt;; 23 14 \\ 25 Paralysis, post anterio 0 1 1 0 0 0 Paralysis, spastic 2 4 6 14 5 Peiitonitis 1 () 10 0 i) Phimosis 1 () 1 (I (I o Poliomyelitis 1 ') 10 17 8 Pott's disease ..' (Ill !&gt; 0 0 Rachitis 2 0 2 10 1 Scoliosis 2 5 7 2 5 7 Spinal hifida (Ill 0 2 2 Spinal paralysis _ 0 1 1 .0 1 1 Talipes varus 3 14- 1 0 1 Tonsils hypertrophied 15 6 0 0 0 Torticollis 12 3 0 2 2 Tubercular foot 10 1 10 1 Tubercular hip 7 2 '■&gt; 5 16 Tubercular knee (Ill 0 11 Tubercular peritonitis 10 1 (I 0 0 Tubercular spine :.. (Ill 0 0 (I Total «.'D »3 183 44 . 57 101 TABLE VIII— CAUSE OF DEATH Period ending June 30, 1931 ' id. ~F. tT Carcinoma of lejf 0 1 1 Heart case : 1 () 1 Peritonitis _ 1 () l Tubercular peritonitis 1 (J 1 Tuberculosis of the spine .' 0 1 1 Total ....: .3 ~2 5~ 134 </seg>
            <seg id="p138">' TABLE IX— AGE AT DEATH Period ending June 30, I'm _ __ M. F. ~ T. 10 years and under 15..... ] Jj j IS years and under 20 . ..." 0 2 2 20 years and under 25 .'. Z.Z.... ...Z..Z 2 0 ' Total 3 2 r RATIO OF EMPLOYES TO PATIENTS June 30, V)M Period ending . mT[ '""iT" ~T"~ Number of physicians including the superintendent o 0 ■&gt; Ratio of same to patients ■„ ZZ.Z. ~\ :5().S 0 1 :5u i •Number of day nurses 0 1&lt;j j (&gt; " " Ratio of same to patients .....'"'. o 1:5.32 I :S X&gt; Number of night nurses o 3 3 Ratio of same to patients 0 1 -33 67 1 -?3 6" Number of officers and employes 12 46 58 Ratio of same to patients \ 1:8.42' 1:2.19 1-174 •Does not include gra-luate nurses. OPERATIONS DURING THE BIENNIUM ENDING JUNE 30, 1931 M. K. T. Surgical operations 11' ill 9 4- Surgical dressings ZZZZZZZ 1.243 940 2.183 Plaster dressings 2 \U 207 4?3 X-ray pictures 18S , 28 3U Mechanical appliances 30 23 53 135 </seg>
            <seg id="p139"/>
            <seg id="p140">Report of the State Penitentiary Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p141">STATE PENITENTIARY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS W. T. FF.NTON - - - - - - Warden D. G. KAVANAUGH - - - Deputy Warden MRS. FRONA LOCKAKI) ..... Matron WILLIAM KIRBV - - - - - - Steward \V. LANGFORI) " . - C"lii«?f Clerk 1!. A. FINKLE, M. D. - - Physician Miscellaneous Statement Established : 1869 Number of employes June 30. 1931 , 76 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 769 Highest number of inmates (luring biennium 779 I'er capita cost per month $29.69 Number of acres owned , 416' Number of acres leased 360 Number of acres under cultivation 606 Value of lands and buildings, furniture and " equipment .' $699,915.98 Principal industries: Manufacture of work shirts and fibre furniture, farming, gardening and stock raising. Visiting days: Every day except Sundays and holidays, 8 to 12 A. M. and 1 :30 to 4 :00 P. M. Commitment by District Judge. Persons committed to the Reformatory for Men and the Reformatory for Women for felony, may be transferred to the Penitentiary on order of the Board of Control. All transfers, however, from the Penitentiary to either Reformatory emanate from thd Board of Pardons and Paroles. 138 </seg>
            <seg id="p142">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I hereby present to you my biennial report for the period from July 1, 1929 to July 1, 1931. Our population on July 1. 1931 is 754 male and 15 female, making a total of 769. We have employed at the present time about 4(X) men making work shirts, work pants and lumber jackets; 35 men making fibre and over-stuffed furniture; 100 men on construction work, dairy - ing, stock raising, farming and gardening. The remainder of our men are employed as engineers, coal shovelers, cell house men, cooks, waiters, porters, mechanics and general utility men to carry on the work at the institution. The 15 women are employed m making dress shirts, work shirts, and garments of different kinds for the other institutions. We have just completed an addition to our inmates dining room, making ample room for feeding our men. We have also under construction a large auditorium m our prison yard which will be completed about December Ist, capacity 1000. We will then commence work on our new cell block m the east wing which when completed, will accomodate 312 inmates. We have a prison night school nine months of the year with an enrollment of about 200. Our religious work is carried on by Reverend Maxwell, our prison chaplain, and Reverend Quinn as volunteer Catholic chaplain. Our recreation consists of picture shows on Sunday afternoon, baseball games on Saturday afternoon, yard privileges, etc. Our prison library is cared for by one of the men and is well patronised by the inmates. In conclusion I wish to thank the Honorable Board of Control and His Excellency, the Governor, for their kind consideration and administration m the affairs of the institution. 1 also wish to extend sincere thanks to my co-workers for their loyalty and cooperation. Respectfully submitted, W. T. FENTON, Warden. 139 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">140 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. On hand beginning of period ; 720 10 730 Admitted first time 32i) 15 335 Readmitted ?89 4 293 Returned from parole 7 0 7 Returned from escape 4 0 4 Returned from transfer (, 0 (, Received from transfer 10 0 10 Returned from reni-md 2 1 3 Returned from parole violator : 1" 0 19 Order of Court 0 0 0 Total recovered 3^ 1,407 Released: ~~ Kscaped 2 0 2 Djscharged 4f»7 10 477 Uied 7 ] X Order of Court ,5 0 3 Transferred ,808 Paroled : IL'ZZZ.! 132 3 135 Remanded 4 1 5 Kxecuted 0 0 0 I'urlonghed and discharged .-. 0 0 0 Total released ' 623 15 ■ 638 Remaining at end of period 754 15 769 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. 14 to 16 years 2 0 2 16 to 18 years 4 0 4 - 18 to 21 \ears 47 2 49 21 to 25 years Sl'ZZZl'Z'Z 96 2 98 2s to 30 years 119 4 123 30 to 35 years ZZZZZ 106 4 110 J3 to 40 years 7 O 3 79 40 to 45 years 00 1 61 45 to SO years ; 53 1 54 50 to 5a years ; 17 0 17 55 to 60 years 14 1 ]5 60 to 65 years .....ZZZ... 16 0 16 (&gt;3 years and over y 1 10 Total - 619 19 638 </seg>
            <seg id="p144">141 TABLE III— RACE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 . M. F. T. Indian ; ' 9 q y~~ Negro '■ .._„_! 39 3 42 White 571 16 587 Total ■ 619 19 638~ TABLE IV— EDUCATION OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 KT F. T\ •! rimar y • 21 0 F~ Common ... ;.. 303 I-5 4(H) High school 14,5 4 147 College or university 15 ■&gt; 17 None I..;. 47 0 47 Total 619 1&lt;J (M TABLE V— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 AT ¥. tT Single 270 i, 27(7 Married 2S7 &lt;; Widowed 37 3 40 Divorced 25 1 20 T" 1 " 1 ■ 619 J9 63)T TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 . *l. i^ tT United States: Alabama 4 0 4 Arizona 2 0 2 Arkansas n 0 f, California „ _ 5 0 5 Colorado 13 0 13 Georgia „ 3 0 . 3 Idaho 2 0 2 Illinois _ _ _ 19 2 2? Indiuna :.........."........""L....7 10 0 10 '»wa 03 Q (,3 </seg>
            <seg id="p145">TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED (Continued) Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. Kansas 39 o 39 Kentucky 7 18 Louisiana 2 0 2 Maryland 3 0 3 Massachusetts 2. 0 2 Michigan _.. 7 0 7 Minnesota 3 14 Mississippi : : 1 0 1 Missouri 56 3 50 Montana 1 0 1 Nebraska 226 8 234 New Jersey , 5 0 5 New Mexico 1 0 1 New York 10 0 10 North Carolina '. ; 3 0 3 North Dakota 1 0 ! Ohio . 12 . 0 ■ 12 Oklahoma :...... 17 0 17 Oregon 1 0 1 Pennsylvania 8 ' 0 8 South Carolina : 2 0 2 South Dakota ;. 8 0 8 Tennessee : : 5 0 5 Texas ; 14 3 17 Virginia 2 0.2 Washington 2 0 2 West Virginia 1 0 1 Wisconsin 3 0 3 Unknown : 3 0 3 Total A 572 18 590 Other countries: ■ Canada .: 4 (( 4 Czechoslovakia .' 5 0 . 5 Denmark 2 0 2 England 4 0 4 fiennanv 6 1 7 Cireecc .'. 10 1 Holland 1 0 1 Ireland 1 0 1 Italy _ .-. _.. .. 2 0 2 Mexico _.. 11 0 11 Norway 1 0 1 Rumania 1 0 1 Russia _ :. 4 0 4 Scotland ...: 2 0 2 Sweden : 2 0 2 Grand total _ 619 19 638 142 </seg>
            <seg id="p146">143 TABLE VII— COUNTY FROM WHICH COMMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 ' M. F. T. Adams _ 7^ Z 77" Ameiopc : , :;:..::. 15 4 ° 0 ls 4 Blame : i „ 7 Boone , _ , ' Uoyd ] „ " " utTaI ° r • - • 13 () |J Burt : 7 „ '*, B«t&gt;« - : I d I Lass n 1 ... ;..:..;;;;;;;;;:; [ » ' &gt; &lt;-. lcrry - - 8 2 111 Cheyenne 5 „ s (-lay 5 „ V £°lfax : 1 „ \ &lt;-U'"'"K : 5 0 5 &lt;-"f cr : ; 5 0 5 P akot:i 3 0 J " awes • ■ 3 0 ;? D aw! l on ■■ • 13 1 14 £9" el 2 0 2 ?&gt; x .°" : ■■ - .• 3 (I 3 Dodge 11 1 1 , Douglas 117 5 122 gjMKty 7 0 7 I'lllmorc • 1 (I I Franklin _ _5 0 Frontier ] 0 "• C'uriias i) (| (J y.^c : ,1Z"ZZ 11 2 ,., darden ; 3 0 (Jarfield 1 0 1 &lt;i ra "' ......'..zz; 1 0 1 l.reeley ■&gt; () , " a11 .,- •&lt; . IK 2 i) Hamilton K 0 « Hqrlan , : 404 Hays 5 ,1 j Hitchcock 1 n 1 Hou : Z-ZZzzzziTz: 2 [1 ] Howard , .404 Jefferson ZiZZZZ 13 0 13 Johnson C o f) Kearney 4 0 4 Keith , 4 0 4 Kimb.ill % n • Knox 5 0 S Lancaster Z'ZZZ! (A 2 &lt;*, b in s? ln • is o is Madison , &lt;; () (J Mcrxick 5 0 5 Morrill _ , 7 0 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p147">TABLE VII— COUNTY FROM WHICH COMMITTED (Continued) Period ending June 30, 1931 m! f\ t7 £ :mcc , 3 0 J~ Ncninha „ 5 0 5 Xuckolls _ „.„ 3 0 ? "toe _..: 16 0 i fi 1 awncc _ _ a n a 1 ......................................... 1 ■ U *t 'helps SOS 1 4 ..................................... if t , ■"lcrcc 3 0 3 Platte .-. 8 1 y Red Willow _ _ ]j 0 13 Richardson : ,. 12 0 12 Saline _ _ 3 0 3 Sarpj- „ 0 " r , Saunders _ 15 1 U) Scotts Bluff ;. 15 0 J5 Scward „ 3 0 • 3 Sheridan 12 1 13 Sherman 3 0 3 Stanton \ 0 1 Thomas a 0 ■ 4 Thurston : _.. 7 0 7 X? n ?y ••■ 202 \\ ashington ; _ _.. - 2 0 ' Wa&gt; ne ■ 3 0 3 \\ ebster 3 0 3 Yor k 1...L... 2 0 2 Total : 6iy 19 (,38 TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 m! F\ t7 Auditor 1 0 1 liarber 12 0 12 Hanker 10 0 10 Baker 8 0 . 8 Beet worker 1 0 1 Bootlegger 1 0 1 Boiler maker 4 0 4 Bookkeeper 5 16 Blacksmith 2 0 2 Butcher , 5 0 5 Brakeman 1 0 1 • Bell-hop 2 0 2 32 0 32 Lenient worker : 3 0 3 Ovef : 2 0 2 Carpenter 14 0 14 144 </seg>
            <seg id="p148">TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED (Continued) Period ending Jinn: 30, 1931 . . I m. ~ 7. Cabinet maker 3 0 3 Chauffeur : 4 0 1 Car maker : , 10 1 &lt;&gt; rk ...'.'".'."."'.'. 9 0 9 I utility treasurer 10 1 Car repairer j 0 j Car checker j 0 I Hoiler-cleaner 10 1 Cleaner &amp; presser j 0 j Construction worker 1 y I Comptometer ;...... \ y ( Uraltsmau , j lt I Deputy game warden : •] 0 I Dairyman 4 0 Klcctrician : $ d v. Kngineer ' 4 (l j Klvyatur operator ] d j gamier 143 0 14.5 I'lroman : 11 u u I* lour packer 1 0 j Kactury worker . j 0 I Jiroccr ; 1 „ , (■arageman 3 0 5 Housewife U Housework 0 j Insurance : a 0 4 J-?borer ; !.5I 0 lM Lineman JO' Linotype operator : I 0 J Laundry 0 „ ,, 'v lw &gt;v r . •- = .. 1 0 1 .Machinist 7 0 7 ili&lt; 1 1 ••-; .'...".ZZZ. I) 1 1 Aleclianic &gt;4 0 Musician 4 0 "4 Movie operator 1 0 ] Miner ; 2 (I ' Minstrel t 10 1 Molder j d &gt; N'urseryman 1 I) i *"»«-• 5 0 5 Oil-man ; &gt; | 0 | Ofh'ceman ; ■ j D 1 Painter j 2,i I) 23 Plumber -. 7 0 ~~ Porter • ....".Z'Z'J U (I U Pipe-fitter ■ f 4 (i 4 PuKilist I 1 |) 1 Poultry hatcher ' \ 0 ] Piano finisher -. I ] 0 \ Pumpman ] 0 I Pressman ] d I l'lastervr I 1 0 1 145 </seg>
            <seg id="p149">TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED (Continued) Period ending I June 30. l'tfl ~nT I". T\7 Rancher , i | I) 1 K'ailroadcr ... d I) 6 Roadhuildcr I II | Real estate 4 n 4 Restaurant . . I I) 1 Roofer ' J&gt; (I z Salesman , IK (I IK Steel worker I ll I Shoemaker 4 0 .| Storkmaii 1 || ] . Sie.'im-pipe titter I 11 I Ship rinser ........ I II 1 Saleswoman 11 I I . Seeilman *.. . 10 1 Stonecutter I 0 I Stenographer 2 (I 1 Sawmill worker : 1 II I Swilelilioaril operator 1 (I I Stiiileut . in 1 Tailor . .i II ' ,i Tractor driver ...'. 2 I) Z Veterinarian 10 1 Chocolate dipper (I 1 I Waiter ;... 4 0 4 Waitress () 2 2 • Trucker ; U 0 13 Total ! 619 19 638 TABLE IX— RELIGIOUS PREFERENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED I Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T~ Protestant 31,2 16 378 Catholic , : 141 3 1-14- Jewish 4 0 4 Not reported _ 112 0 112 Total : 619 19 63R TABLE X— CONVICTION OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June .30, 1031 M. F. T. First time 311 12. 323 Second time .". 202 6 208 Third time : 75 1 76 Fourth time ; '. 27 0 27 Fifth time , 4 0 -J Total 619 19 638 146 </seg>
            <seg id="p150">TABLE XI— CHIME FOR WHICH COMMITTED IVriiul ending June .ill. I'M] ■ " M. ~. T^ Assault 2 0 2 AccesM iry before llu- fact : n ] ] ')&lt;&gt;"", i o 1 7 .Assaull lo rob ■. -4 I) -I Assault in rape d (l (, Assault tn wound 5 0 5 Automobile stealing .if, (i ,;&lt;, Altering check •. I II 1 Aid and abetting burglary 1 (I ; Attempted hank rohlicry .'. • 1 I) 1 liigamy , 2 II 2 lln-akiiiK j:&gt;il 4 n 4 I Sank robbery i ]-) u ).l Breaking and entering : 7\ 2 7,i llurglary _;ii 2 -12 Chicken stealing ; 21 !i 21 lattli' stealing i fi II r&gt; I'arr.vinj; concealed weapons : 4 li 4 Cnitd'aling tnariguaiia I ] 0 I l.'alf stealing 1 n 1 Deserting family ', i j 0 j ICscape from custody ]H 11 10 Kscape from prison 4114 KinlH-zzlemeiit i2 11 1 • Decoying minor child from home 1 II 1 l-'«irgcry 117 5 \&gt;2 False pretense 4 0 I'clouious assault . ? (I 1 1 iiand larceny 2&lt;~ .1 2~&gt; Horse stealing 2 (I 2 Hog ..stealing : 12 11 12 Highway rohbery , 0 5 !»«-"«■■*! ■ &lt;&lt; (i o Iiistilhcient funds .- (I $ Illegel operation 0 1 1 Intent tn rol&gt; 7 (j &gt; Kidnapping-child stealing .} 0 3 Larceny as bailee S 0 1 |- arccn &gt;' , •■» 4 (I 4 Larceny trom person 4 0 4 Manslaughter 5 1 „ Malicious destroying of property 2 0 2 Murder first degree 3 1 4 Murder second degree 1; 0 ij Misapplication funds 2 0 2 Non-support ;. 1 0 1 Non-payment of alimony .' 1 0 1 Xo fund check ]? 0 12 OhtainiivR money false pretense 2 0 2 Obtaining property under falsn pretenses and grand larceny .., •. 1 0 1 Rap*; -. ■ ......'l."..".'Z.'.3Z.'Z y 0 ■) Pandering I 0 ] Robliery : : 54 n 5J Kecciving stolen property 7 0 7 147 </seg>
            <seg id="p151">TABLE XI— CONTINUED | . Period ending June .5(1. V&gt;M . ; \i. i". t7 Receiving and concealing stolen cattle .... ' 10 1 Removing mortgaged property I j 0 ,j Receiving and concealing stolen property '..... 0 1 1 Sliooling to wound : ,' 2 0 J Shooting to kill ,! ; ' (I 5 Statutory rape , '........! H II H Stealing j 5 (I 5 Selling mortgaged property ', i 2 0- 2 Slabbing m kill ami wound '.. • ' 2 (I 2 Siiclmiiy i : ' ,$ 0 ,j Stealing and reccving automobiles j . l II ] Violation of lit|uur laws .. 20 1 2\ Violation of hanking laws ,? 0 Violation of suspended sentence , I ] [) \ Kidnapping for purpose of rape : ,? () 3 Tii kill and wound I 0 1 Total ! : fil'j 1" (,.?8 TABLE XII— TERM OF SENTENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June .10. I'm M. F. T. Life i 7 1 S 110 years : | 1 0 1 50 years 2 0 2 -10 years .5 0 .? 35 years ; 1 0 1 25 years 5 (I 5 20 years 17 0 17 2.? years 2.0 2 15 years 14 0 14 12 years 1 0 1 1-t years : 1 o 1 10 years 26 0 26 11 years 1 0 1 5 years 4 0 4 7 years ;. 21 0 21 /'/■ years s 1 0 1 6 years ; 7 0 7 5 years 48 1 4'^ 4 years : ;..... 17 - 0 17 V/. years 2 0 2 iVi years ■. 2 0 2 .? years 05 1 6Ti 2','j years 7 (I 7 2 years 5«&gt; 2 61 2 years, 11 mouths I I) 1 I ywir 115 7 122 1 year. 2 counts (consecutive) : 1 . II • 1 Wi \cars l.j ||' 1.1 1 year 4 months 1 (I 1 1 year 5 mouths 2 0 2 I year 2 months 1 0 ] 5 months : 2 II 2 7 months 10 1 148 </seg>
            <seg id="p152">TABLE XII— TERM OF SENTENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED (continued) Period ending juiu- 30, 1&lt;)31 _ M. F. T. 10 months I (| | '■ """"jis .zzzzzzzzz &lt;■ » ( , 10 iiiuiitlis tn 1 year : Z \) &gt; &lt;&gt; tn IK months I 0 T 6 inmitli.s t&lt;i 2 years \ 2 0 2 1 year to 1 year 1 clay ~Z {) ~&gt; 1 year 3 months (I 1 year to Mi months 7 0 7 1 to \Y&gt; years 7 {) &gt; 1 In 2 years 30 ? 1 to 2 l /i years. . 'j () ' ? 1&lt;A to.? years '"ZZ. \ . o "i Wi to 2 years I 0 j J I" •' vt ' ars Z.ZZ'Z".'Z.'.Z .n 3 m 1 to 4 years 2 0 2 1 to S years ;. r " „ " 1 tn fi years 2 I) &gt; 1 to 7 years ]j I q J '" '" &gt;; cars ZZ'IZZZZZZZ. 12 o 12 1 " i &gt;;"••»« : .5 I) 5 2 " 5 &gt;' cars fi (l o 2 to 7 years -&gt; „ , 2 to 10 years I (I 7 7 t&lt;i 10 years 1 0 I 5 to 5^" years "ZZZZZZZZZZZZ 1 ■' ' ' 0 1 12 to la vears i n i ttl * i \i i 2 to IS years 1 (I l ' •] V 5 , yc:irs ........ZZZZ. 5 (I 5 • t(1^ &gt; cars ■• 1 (I 1 .5 to / years ? 0 i .? to 15 vears I (j 7 •] «" i° &gt; iars ...;:'.■.;:":"".";::"::::;":::: 303 4 to (1 vears 9 &lt;&gt; , • ... A, 1/ £ -I l&lt;i 10 years j 0 I 5 to 7 years ! 2 0 &gt; 5 to- 17 years ;. , j y T (i0 years, 10 counts 5 years, 1 count 10 vears .............. 1 0 1 6 to 7 years ,. I 0 ( 2 counts 3 to 4 years each (conscctivcj 2 0' 2 counts 10 years each (consectivc) 1 0 1 4 to 5 years : .........." 2 0' Total ~619 19 638 149 </seg>
            <seg id="p153">GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July 1, l')2') tn Jink- M), V&gt;M Total Produced and Consumed | Measure Value Asparagus ! l.(H)() lbs! $ 70.01) Ueans I 10.000 ||,... 201100 f'l-i-ts : i 11.500 lb&gt;.. 4o0.0l) iicrts. .stuck 50.00(1 ll)s. 1 .01)0.1 II I I'alilKiBB ■ .- 1150.000 lbs. .5.000.00 1 'am its 110.000 lbs. ,U(MMI!) ( &lt;ini. sweet ..: 44.000 Jlx. 1 , .120.00- Cucumbers 42.000 ll&gt; . ,S4ll(|ii Dill 1..300 !l): U0.00 Kiiiil-rabi 11.000 lbs. 44000 lettuce ;. 22.000 li)s. l.WIMMl Melons, musk • 23.500 lbs. 470.0(1 Melons, water I S5.000 ll». S50.00 Onions, Krecn :.... 85,(HKI His. 5.400 Oil Onions, dry 120.000 lbs. ',.0(10 011 Parsnips : ln.500 Ib-. 4^5.1):' 1'eas : I 22.000 lbr-. 1.5)0.IIH lVpi'ers : 4.(M)0 |l&gt;«. 4(10 00 I'otatoes 144.1XH) Jb.. 2..SSI ).(;;! Pumpkin : K().(Kli) lbs. KO(I.OI) l\;i(lisbes 24.0IH) lbs ■ 4.S0 0II Kluiharl) .ll.oiHi lbs. 'MO.di Spiiincli 15.000 Ib.-. Nio.Oli Squash 45.OIK) lbs. 'Mill 1)1! Tomatoes -....(l40.(MM) lbs. i",«S0.0(l Turnips : '. S0.000 lbs. |.d(10.00 tlierries d20 lbs. SS.KII (irapes : 11 OHO Ib.. uiiO.oo I'ears | 44(1 lbs. 44.00 Plums ! l,2f&gt;0 Ib-. 50.40 K'aspberries 1.200 lbs. 144.1111 Strawberries '. 1S.0II0 lbs. 2.1MI.OII Total value :.. ?.Vi.l7'J.2o 150 </seg>
            <seg id="p154">FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1&lt;J29 to June 30, 1931 Total produced , Measure Value ;;' rIl&gt; &lt; ! 1.750 hu. 052.(10 •■'"^ I 30 t. 270.00 ,." nl .-•:•■-: ■■ ; 4,700 hu. .1.760.00 Corn unshi-llccl ; ! 2 .7(M) Im. 22r&gt;0(K) l ;-" s , i , la 8« i 245 t. 2,450.00 ,/ ; " s . ; : I 5.85(1 Im. 2.340.00 Straw, barley | ,, t 22()( , g ra *' I "5 '• 1^5.00 Dira»,.r\c r , in fin r ;' w - wl '-« . i&gt;o I 4 iao Ullt "-" rt^Jo l&gt;u. 5,037.60 T..tal value ....: $19.S80.M) LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On hand IVriod cndinR June 30, \')M Number Value '. : .' t . tl 1 t ' 'II Sl.rkllKiu Chickens _.;. 2Jo; 1 ,_4.2ii \}."\ sr - 11 '..'5.011 •\'."''' s 7 55(llMi F 'K S ; *)A 1.555.01 Total value SSoSl^l DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to Imif 31), 19.11 'J'otal Produced and (."unsullied Measure Value {■ : .KK S _ 4.435 do/. $ 1.108.7:5 • Mllk 0.237 cwl. 18,711.011 Total value $i^81&lt;775~ 151 </seg>
            <seg id="p155"/>
            <seg id="p156">Report of the Nebraska Industrial Home Milford, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p157">NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME MILFORD, NEBRASKA F OFFICERS M. EVELYN MEYER - Superintendent \VM. SANDUSKY, M. D. - - - Physician CORA A. TOWNSEND - - Steward and Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established 1887 Number of employes June 30, 1931 11 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 93 Highest number of inmates during hiennium 93 Per capita cost per month $31.16 Number of acres owned 37.58 Number of acres under cultivation 18 Value of lands and buildings, furniture and equipment $121,434.12 Principal industries : Gardening-, poultry raising, canning and sewing. Visiting days : Thursdays, 2 to 4 P. M Applications for admission are made to the superintendent and no information is given out as to the name or identity of an n.pplicant or inmate. 154 </seg>
            <seg id="p158">T&lt;&gt; ihe Governor and the I loan! of Control of Slate Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. li is with pleasure that we submit for your consideration the twenty-third biennial report of the Nebraska Industrial Home. During the past two years we have been pleased with the im - provement the girls have made, not only m the work accomplished, but the manner m which they have responded to the training m tin - different lines of work. Most of the j^i i"l s have found something that has interested them to such an extent that they desire to follow it up when they again take their place m society. Many have the impression that the majority of our girls are those who have had no education, but, referring to the tables at the close of the report, you will find that out of the 114 girls received, 79 of them have had either eighth grade, high school or college work. 63 of the the girls came to us voluntarily. 40 were committed, and 1 1 transferred from other institutions. At the present time we have 35 wonderful babes. We have found permanent homes for 58. 51 per cent of our girls have kepi their- babes, and so we have fewer adoptions. The general health of our wards has been very good. Last year we had a few cases of measles among the girls and babes; this year we have had the chicken pox. Considering the number cared for, we think our mortality rate is very small. ( )f the ln&lt;S under our care, we lost live. 1 girl and 4 babes. 'Die population as the biennium closes is larger than it has been since the spring of 1927. The following improvements have been made during the bien - nium : Enclosed walk between two main buildings; new roofs nn nurseries, sleeping porch, laundry, store-room, coal-house and bughouse, and we have contracted to have lire proof roofs on both barns. The icehouse was reconditioned and converted into a root cellar and store-room. The east side of the north building 155 </seg>
            <seg id="p159">was re-stuccoed, parts of both buildings were redecorated and a few new furnishings bought. The' water tower lias a new lop, and lias been cleaned and painted inside and out. The sil:i was covered with a concrete covering, and the shute . was rebuilt. A cement porch was built m front of our laundry. A modern hospital huliriing is under construction and will be ready for occupancy about October Ist. 1 feel very grateful indeed to the members of the lioard of Control for their wonderful co-operation, consideration, and the confidence they have shown at all times. I take this opportunity to express my gratitude to each of my co-workers for their support, loyalty, and untiring efforts m helping to create a homelike atmosphere for those who have been given In us fur care and protection. Respectfully submitted. M. FAT.LYX MKYI-.K. Superninleiideiit. 156 </seg>
            <seg id="p160">157 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period cndtiiK Juno 30, V&gt;3] _____ M- ' "~V. T. I'resent at hcRnming of period ' if. =r Adults: "■ " Admitted for first time . I o 105 ,,.&gt; Transferred from other institutions ."."". 'i 0 11 jj ' r " tal ' : Id W) Ts5 Infants: Horn -} _j (J 1() , Returned from transfer to another institution .... ..." 1 0 J Tfltal ■'■ • '... 54 4" juT Crand total 70 2 1K 2NS . I &gt;iscliarRcd : Ailults : 111 due course _ „ l; , ,„ 1 ratisferred to nther institutions :. (17 7 I'.'i-.lr.l ' •"-i :::::::::::::::: J } \ . T " t "' : " ; - • - (» UKI "l(K» Infants : Djscliarged with mothers ; 22 IS III I )ischar(-i'il without mothers 5 5 Id In temporary homes \&gt;) \u .55 Transferred to other institutions -1 &gt; u "ied ". ......Z.ZZ (I A -I Tula I 50 45 &lt;)5 *l'"tal removals .! : 5() ,_,- ,,,- Tnlal reniaiiliiiK in institution June .«). l').M 20 7.? U&gt; TABLE II— AGE AND COLOR OF ADULTS ADMITTED Period i-udiiiK June .^0, l').?l : \V. C. T. I'nder II years . .j (l I 1-1 and under. Id years II 1.1 l'i and under IS years • 2o o &gt;' IS ami under 20 years 1 '{T 20 and under 12 vears TV 1 \u jj 1 , ,- ■ 1/ 1 iii J.H. and under 2.i years ' 7 0 7 .15 vears and over * X 0 Tl " al j 101 U HI </seg>
            <seg id="p161">158 TABLE III— SEX AND COLOR OF INFANTS BORN IVrind ending June. M). 1'Ml Ml ]-\. ' T. While -4(. 44 '«) I'nlnri-il : 7, 5 12 Total ". 5.5 4') 1(12 TABLE IV— EDUCATION OF ADULTS ADMITTED I IVrind i-ndiliK I June 30. 1"3I - w. c tT Third grade , 1 0 1 I "mirth grade .' 2 0 2 I'ifth Rrailc .? ii .? Sixth Krndc fi 4 10 Si-vrnili Rraile H&gt; 1 11 l-'itihtli Kradu '4 .&gt; .?/ Iliiili scliocil 42 5 47 lc.llfj.i- .? 0 .5 Total 101 13 114 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF ADULTS ADMITTED IVrind ending June 30. 1931 \V. C. T. Nebraska 7&lt;i 4 80 I'niled Stales nlher than Nebraska : 21 ') M) ISolu'inia 1 II 1 Ireland 1 0 1 Kussia '. 2 0 2 Total 1(11 13 114 </seg>
            <seg id="p162">TABLE VI— PARENTAL CONDITION OF ADULTS ADMITTED Period ending June M). l'J.il W. C T. Both parents dead . • 5 .? S KnthtT dciiri 1-1 .1 17 Mother dead 1') .i 11 Parents livillf! j 5H -1 &lt;il Parents separated ' : i "11 1 l.i lias slep-fatlier [ K 1 'I lias step-mother .. .'. : S 1 ') I'llkllllWII ; | 3 0 .1 TABLE VII— AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS OF ADULTS ADMITTED Peril id ending June .it), I'Ml | \V. C. T. Hum after father's deatli 1 1 1 .\ne at death of father: L'nder 1() years II) .? l.&gt; 1(1 and under 15 years 'i 1 7 15 years and over : : 1 (I 1 Atfe at death of mother : L'nder 10 years .' 15 1 17 10 and under 15 years : j h 1 X 15 years and over | .! 1 5 L'nknowu .' ,i (I .&gt; 159 </seg>
            <seg id="p163">TABLE VIII— ADMISSION OF ADULTS FROM DELINQUENT OR DEFECTIVE HOMES Period ending June .it), 1"31 \v. c. t7 I Vchlc- Minded: l-'utlu-r : il (l (i Mother ". : ;.. I) (I 0 llulli parents [) li ll llriitlivr (l o ll SiMer (I ll il Insane : I'iltlltT . .. : .' : 2 (12 Mother 1 (I 1 Moth |i;ir«.-nts .". (I n (I ISrolher (I 1 1 Sister ■. : II I) II l)eliiii|iicitl : I'iUliiT ... 12 -I l'i Mi.llier : ! 7. 0 7. Until parent:. : ' 5 1 It Itmllu-r : : 3 I) i Sister. ... : ; I l.i &lt;l U I ukiKiwn j 112 Total : | 44 7 51 TAULE IX— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF ADULTS ADMITTED Period eliding June .?(&gt;. 1&lt;).H ' C T. At limnc • IS II IK Clerk 3 I) .? I'nnk 1 1 2. Domestic 41 2 4.? l";ict..ry 10 1 Laundry . . 2 0 2 Maid ..'. : '. -... 0 3 3 ( Illice work 1 0 1 racking hottse * 1 0 1 School «irl ; 26 7 33 Telephone operator '. 1 0 i Waitress ' 5 I) 5 Working in creamery 1 0 1 Total _ 101 13 114 160 </seg>
            <seg id="p164">TABLE X-COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF ADULTS ADMITTED IVrinel rndiliK .lime .5(1, iv.ii . ■_ . w. c. tT Adams I , " ~~ ar ■■■■. ■ " i &amp;^zEE : BS 5 - '* Hiilf.il.. I " 1 iturt :"■". ■; • " - ; Uuilvr : » 1 lass . ' " I Chaw . - " -i Cherry .... • 7 &lt;&gt; 2 Clay ' : I II 1 Cul'fax ■'■■■ • - " Ctistrr ' I 11 1 Dawis ; I " 1 UllWM.II ■■' ~ - (l -' biMlm- ■ ;. •; I" .| Killiiiorfc ■ ' ■■; " !•■ i-vankiin ".' ."......r ; 1 " ' I'Viinliur (t 1 G:. K c ::.: ■• i » 1 (Jariicld ' "'"' , " - ; llauiiltou " I •lhirlan .] ; : " I Hitchock .. , 11 I Holt ■■ " 1 Jefferson ~. ] |J - ; Kearney ZZ I &gt; 1 Kciti. : ;z:zz: I i ,\ -, Lanca.-,tcr I ,r " Lmcoln ' i l ? ' "' Madison ;;; : ■ ' " &gt; Merrick -1 ° Morrin ;;;;;: f Nemaha % \ Nuckolls ■- • f " - otoe -ZZZZZ ' } \ Pawnee Rcii Willow ""■ i ' I- Rid ;.ulson \ " -' Saline ZZZZZZZZZZZ '\ ! \ Saunders J ' Scotts Bluff ZZZZZZZZl I Sherman i ! ; Sioux I ' Thaj-er Thurston Washington' , Webster v -&gt;&lt; -= • :::::::::::-z::::::::::;;: ; J _ ;[_ \_ T " tal ; nil "u iT-i 161 </seg>
            <seg id="p165">162 TABLE XI— PROCEDURE FOR ADMISSION OF ADULTS Period ending June 30. VJ3\ \V. C f! Voluntary application 62 1 6.3 1 Irerec i»f ( '&lt; »urt : Delinquency U) 1,0 4(1 Transfer : : ;...;.. n 2 ii Total 101 l.i 114 TABLE XII— CAUSE OF DEATH Period ending JniR- .50. I'M I 1 M. F. T. ! \\\ C. \V. C. \riik enteritis probably strcptocoeeicosis . 0 0 10 1 Acute jinlioinyclitis 0 0 1 0 I I 't'ciuaturiiy and immaturity 0 0 2 0 2- Suffocation (accidental) 0 0 1 o .1 Total o 0 5. 0 5 TABLE XIII— AGE AT DEATH Period ending I " June M0, 1931 I XL F. ' T. W. (.'. W. C. I'mii-r six inonttis 0 I) .? 0 .? Under one year 0 0 1 0 1 l'.if?litiTii years 0 0 1 0 1 . Total : 0 (I 5 0 5 LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On hand i June 30, 1'tfl Number Value Tattle ! 3\ $2,732.80 lliickens :.. 75.; 452.40 I Ings \ 37 l%.00 I lorsis ■. 2 225.00 Total $3,606.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p166">DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS July 1. V&gt;2'&gt; in June .id. I 'Ml Tula] produced during liicniiiuni Measure Value Kkks ■ ... 5.151.1hz. $1.28775 Milk , 2&lt;&gt;1.W2.4 lbs. 7.857.07 Total .. | $&lt;&gt;.I44.82 FARM PRODUCTS July I, 1«&gt;2'J tu Jiiik- .11). 1'Ul Total produced iluriiiK bieiiuiuiu Measure. Value Alfalfa 7.5. t. $ 54.511 Kii-.il;i«i- 1,11 I. .ilHMIIt Pasture l.ttMNI TulJil ,. , $1,402.5(1 GARDEN AND ORCHARD PRODUCTS July I. Pi*) in Jiiik- Ml. 1'Ml Tutiii produci'd and comsunuil Measure Value Appk-s , .' 388 ll.s. $ 11 .M llciiim, striiiR '. 7f&gt;'&gt; His. 15..W Ucvts ?.'&gt;'»! ll&gt;s. 15S.-I-1 I'aliliiiKu '• - l-' w -' "&gt;!*■ •'''•«'• Cautaliuipe .' 5d lbs. 1.12 Tamils 1.588 ll&gt;s. -I7.M Cherries 22(1 ll.s. 10.8(1 I',,,-,, ; JJIM) Ills. ')').(ll) Cm-unilieis .'. 728 His. 14.5d Krr Plant : His. 14.M Kndivi- ..:..- - : 174 His. 871) Lettuce 821 ll.s. 41.05 i )iii,in* ■ :.................: .V'4S ll.s. 1K2.4I) Parsnips M)5 His. 18.15 Peas 77 ( &gt; His. S4.W IVl»pe'rs 8(1 ll.s. K.Od 1'ntatoes 2.5.82"^ ll.s. 47I..5S Kaclishcs 42S lbs. 8.5(1 Nlmbarb 'H*l lbs. MM Spinach 2'»4 ll.s. 11. 7(. Tomatoes 11.140 ll.s. 222.W Turnips 4.22d lbs. 84.52 Ti.tal $1.577.&lt;&gt;5 163 </seg>
            <seg id="p167"/>
            <seg id="p168">Report of the Nebraska School for the Blind Nebraska City, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p169">NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA OFFICERS N. C. ABBOTT - Superintendent KI-FIK B. MlTAKLAN'D .-,-•--.-- .Matron L). D. STONECYFHliR - - Physician Miscellaneous Statement Established lS/.i Number of employes las! school ilay of biciiiiiiim • 2^ XiimluT uf inmates last school day of bk-iiiiium I:'. Iliyiicst number of inmates during bieiiniiim ;■&gt;! I 'or capita cost per monlli $ol.J7 Number of acres owned 10 Number of acres under cultivation ."&lt; Value of lands and buildings, furiiiliire and equipment , $Kv.5&gt;2 l &gt;.7'4 Visiting days: School days from S:fKI A. M. to o :4(.l 1*. M. The institution is open during the school year to such bona - fide residents of Nebraska as are of suitable age and capacity who by reason of their disability cannot attend the common schools. Clothing, transportation to and from school, and support during vacation periods must be paid for by parent or guardian. If the parent or guardian is unable to pay, or if the pupil is of school age and indigent, the county shall pay such expenses. 166 </seg>
            <seg id="p170">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln. Nebraska. 11l this report I have the honor to tell you of the progress of the school during the biennium from and including July 1, 1929, to June 30, 1931. A harmonious and successful bienium this has been as indicated by the fact that our personnel m control of the school lias remained unchanged. Kxpcricncc means much m giving the very best lo those of defective vision, or without sight at all. Klindncss, on the whole, due lo many meliorating cireniiislances, is decreasing over the .whole world.. Yet there is likely never to ''"in 1 » lime when such ji stale as ours will not need lo provide tile specialized instruction which Xcbraska offers here. World figures show that the frequency of blindness (this in - cludes, also, such defective vision as lo prevent the securing of an education thru common schools) is al the ratio of three males In Iwo leinales. Furthermore there are, under normal life, three blind persons lo ten deal". In oilier words, when onr school enrolls 61') pupils, it would lie expected thai (he School for the Heal", serving the same area, would have on ils lisl 2(K) pupils. ll is interesting lo note a comparison of the percentage on the sex basis for the Iwo years: •Male Female Total First 3H 27 57 Second 3K 21 y) Average .VI 2-1 58 In the first year, lilt- nit id works out — &gt;2.(&gt; and -17.4, a much larger per cent of girls lli.in usually happens. In the second, il is far different -64.-1 and 35.fi — which is an extreme, m the other di reel ion. L!ul when the average is si ruck, we find it 55.. i and 31.7, which conies very close lo the (&gt;0 and -10, which is almost standard. The chief use to which Ihe appropriation of $15,(KN).(N), granted by the recent special session of the legislature for repairs and re - placements, should be a complete overhauling of the buys' wing of our building. This is the orginal building of the. institution, con- 167 </seg>
            <seg id="p171">strucU'd Tor less than $1(),(HK).(X), almost Ml years ago, li include., a lliircl Moor dormitory for older biiys, a second lloor iliii'niilorv for youngsters, a first lloor used fur industrial ami recreation rooms and a basement with waiting rooms and storage aeoomodatioiTs. Xew doors, easements; floors, windows. plumbing, stairways an. l balustrades are sadly needed. Tin- remainder of the fund may well lie expended for plastering, painting, plumbing, display cases, books, and apparatus. The whole building should In- screened whenever funds will permit. The following purchases and improvements during the bienuiuni stand out : 1. Xew boilers, which have proved most satisfactory. 2. The large radio for chapel use. 3. Pavement tlmiout the grounds. The last bit was finished over the northwest corner just as the biennium drew to a dose. 4. Splendid merry-go-rounds for boys and girls. 5. A large kitchen range. (i. A school bus. 7. Kleven new typewriters, m exchange, for used ones. 8. A iarge frigidaire. 9. Three la,rge dissected maps of Kurope. South America and North America, 10. The old building, originally constructed as a gymnasium, converted, as far as first lloor is concerned, into an industrial build - ing. Six large rooms have been divided out of the large ground lloor where our excellent teacher. Mr. Clark Bruce, and his boys will be offered a fair chance to g:&gt; on under encouraging conditions with tuning and piano-repairing, netting, caning, brush-work, mat - making, broom-making, reed and fiber work, weaving, door-sprill 1 ; construction and other lines as they may develop. The Lions Club of Nebraska City and the whole International organization, having work with and for the blind one of its primary objects, have been of vast help to us m our work. To the Hoard of Control lor help and encouragment, I extend thanks. .Most respectfully, ' X. C. AIIOTT, Superintendent. 168 </seg>
            <seg id="p172">169 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION ■ Period ending • Jinn- 30. 1931 __ ~m. v. tT I'lfsi-nl :il (-1..-.I- cii' scliiuil Iitii). Juiii- 111. l')J&lt;&gt; .12 |9 51 Admitted fur lirsi linu- : it, &lt;) 25 Ueudmitted ,5 D "Vj (&gt;n v.ic.il i.ni ;il llt'f&gt;iiiilill)&gt; nf period ... .. 10 1 'l'"'i'l -■ : _ 52 2K 81) I itschiir.m'N : &lt;ir.'idii;iU-d 7 1 S lliiinir.ilil.v discharged ..- 5 4 ') "i«-«l (I 0 0 l.iil school fur nlliiT ri-asuiis * 11 4 15 'l'"l»l 2S «J .U I'nstnt ;it the close- n"f scIhki! term, Jiiiu- 10. V)M 2-) l'J 4S TABLE II— AGES OF PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending Juno 30, 1931 ■ \l. F. t7 l r uiir years Oil l'"jvo years : 1 0 1 Six. years 1 2 .? Seven years 112 Nine years 1 0 1 .Ten years 1 0 1 Kleven years , Oil Twelve years 1 0 1 "Thirteen years 1 0 I Fourteen years 2 0 2 Sixteen years Oil Seventeen years 10 1 Twenty-two years ! 0 11 Thirty years 1 0 1 Thirty-six years 0 11 Forty-two years 10 1 Forty-seven years 2 0 2 Sixty-one years , 0 11 Seventy-three 10 1 Seventy-seven .. 1 0 1 Total 16 9 25 TABLE III— NATIVITY OF PUPILS ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. Xrhraska [ 10 4 14 L'nited States other than Nebraska 6 4 10 Sweden ..:. 0 1 1 Total : 16 9 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p173">TABLE IV— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF PUPILS ADMITTED DURING BIENNIUM Period ending June .50, 10,51 ■ j iu^ F. T. IliilT.ilo ' (i 1 ] l '" 1 " 11 ; ZZZZZZZZZ' i o-i I) ( .utKl:is ..: ; 4 ,5. 7 I* r:mk I in 1 I) 1 !&gt;:'" - : :.::::::::::::::':::- i „ ! Kiifix Oil Lancaster , &gt; &gt; a £ !lllCi ; ZZZZZZZZ] I • i) 'i \enialia 1 II I nine .'!'.'.'.'.'.'.".'.'. ....... "I ' . 1 i RiclianlMNi " y II I Seward ' i 0 1 I Thayer 1 ' (| I W.'iyiu , ; i &lt;l j T " ta i_-;; ••■ , j U&gt; '&gt; 25 TABLE V— AGE AT WHICH PUPILS ADMITTED BECAME BLIND IVriml i'ikIiiik June .ill. 1'Ml m. i^-; r. rnkniiuii -&gt; ,| &gt;~ CfiiiKfiiital : ZZZZZZ'Z 3 1 T\ I'nder nne year ; . lit One year..'. ZZZZZZZZZ (I 1 1 rimr years : [ I &gt; l - "ive years 2 II ~&gt; Kitflit years , 1 () IK&gt; -"••"■••= ZZZZZZ. i ii i I'.leven vears I n t *p • * " i I welve years 11' Over twenlyiine years . j &gt; T " l:i1 17 }7 170 </seg>
            <seg id="p174">TABLE VI— ASSIGNED CAUSES OF DEFECTS IN PUPILS ADMITTED ■ Period imuUiik • June .?(), 1&lt;U1 ■ J - M. ~~~^' T. Congential 7 r~ 7 Malpractice ... ■ .' i \ ', i-&gt;H zzzzzzzzzzzz. ! f •; funeral breakdown 1 (I T Inlluenza anil infantile paralysis () i Accident ', -&gt; () , lilaucoma T (I T Pressure mi optic nerve ■. 1 () i I'ltuitarv tumor ■ ,, . J It i u i i nknown j . ( ""taracts ZSZZZZ'.'ll ■ ~&gt; (. I Scarlet fever ' ; f ,, 'J Tl&gt;t;i1 - ~, &lt;) Ji ■ TABLE VII— EXTENT OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED . ' Period ending June .10, l'J.il ■■ . J.M. ~ |.\ T. '" tal ■ (i i &lt;) ' r " tal "if, •&gt; 25 171 </seg>
            <seg id="p175">TABLE VIII— DISTRIBUTION OF PUPILS AT THE CLOSE OF THE SCHOOL YEAR &gt; . Distribution Literary Department — ■ — — First grade « .( 11 Second grade 6 17 l-ourlh grade 2 0 2 Fifth grade • II ■} -3 Sixth grade , ,. . .1 .t &lt;&gt; Seventh grade .' I 7 High School Knglsli literature 2 1 .i American literature 2 4 &lt;&gt; Chemistry 3 &lt;&gt; .' Kcoiioiuics : II 1 1L I'lane geometry 3 4 7 Solid geometry 2 (I 2 Ancient history ; 2 4 (&gt; Modern history : 2 It 2 Psychology ....'. 3 5 S Salesmanship 4 -t M L'lignidvd 4 5 ') I'raillc reading 27 15 42 llraillc writing H&gt; 4 2(1 Typewriting _ 4 ') \3 1'iano 11 1.1 24 Chorus, advanced ." 8 10 IS Chorus, primary 12 8 20 Girls' ensemble 0 12 12 Hoys' ensemble 8 0 8 Orchestra 22 10 32 Violin 12 5 17 Cornet 8 1 " Other instruments 10 2 12 Primary industrial 3Z 14 4n Broom making 10. 0 10 Piano tuning 5 0 5 Mat making 10 0 10 Chair caning .■ 3 I) 3 Brush making 10 0 10 Art curd weaving 10 0 10 172 </seg>
            <seg id="p176">Report of the Nebraska School for the Deaf Omaha, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p177">NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF OMAHA. NEBRASKA OFFICERS FRANK \V. IJOOTH - Siip.riiilrmlrnt A. Mil. IX TKKNTIIAM - - - Matron MARY A. CHR1STOFFF.RSKX - - - Secretary Miscellaneous Statement Kslablished , IWi'i Number of employes, June M), \')M 1... 51 Number of pupils, June 30, l'.Ml :....• l'tii I Holiest number of pupils dining hiennium 201 I Vr capita cost per month $10.21 Number of acres o\vne&lt;l .^.i Number of acres under cultivation Id Value of lands and buildings, furnilure and equipnienl $5K-1,~n i ).3 l &gt; Visiting days: School days from 8:1)0 A. M. to 4:15 I'. M. Sundays, all day. The institution is open during tin- school year to such hona fide residents of Nebraska as are of suitable aj^e anil capacity who by reason of their disability cannot attend the common schools. Clothing, transportation in and from school, and support during vacation periods must he paid .for by parent or guardian. If the parent or guardian is unable to pay, or if the pupil is of school age and indigent; the county shall pay such expenses. 174 </seg>
            <seg id="p178">To the Governor and the Hoard of Control of Slate Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. • I beg l&lt;&gt; submit iliis die Thirl v-lVrst I'.icnnial Kvporl of the Nebraska School for Ihe heaf, covering the period of its activities from | nl \ 1. \&lt;)2'&gt;. to June M). |«WI. The school was started m the year 18d9 by a deaf man named William 11. French, lewlve pupils being m attendance during the year. In the &lt;&gt;2 years dial have intervened ii|&gt; to the present, 1205 deaf children have partaken of llie school .benefits. ( )l" this number, I'll are slill m school, leaving I 175 who have come and none, (aking with them die educational benefits the school has conferred upon I lu-id. becoming, for (he majority, iiuliislrious, lax |iaviug, home keeping and family rearing citizens. The school's* aim is lo restore lo society those who without education would In- a perpetual burden on society and charity, and il .accomplishes (his aim as is m evidence m the standing dial our former pupils maintain -m their home communities. The lalesl slalislics show dial Ihcre are 2(H) schools for deaf children m the United Stales, (il of them being public residential schools. 117 city day schools, and V) private, or denominational schools, fhe.se affording educational privileges m the 15.1.i0 pupils attending them. I lie ratio ol die. deaf lo (lie hearing m the general population is approximately- one m two thousand, and naturally this rati'.i prevails among children of school age. Prom (A) to 05 per cent of deal persons were born so, die remainder heiiig made deaf I&gt;\ diseases, eerebrospinal meningitis and scarlet fever being the most prevalent causes. Improvement m medical treatment is gradually reducing the percentage of those made deal" by disease, but con - genital deafness seems outside the range of prevention methods of treatment. Seemingly a matter of inheritance m many cases, it is advised that the congenitally deaf, if they marry, male with hearing persons, or with those adventitiously deaf. &lt; &gt;f the 190 pupils m school at the close of the term on June 13, 152 were taught orally, thai is, they were being trained lo speak and to read the lips while pursuing the various studies m the school 175 </seg>
            <seg id="p179">murse. Tlic remainder, or 38, were taught manually, that is. through use of the linger alphabet for purposes of thought com - munication, language m written and printed forms being used m all classes, whether oral or manual. The aim of the school is to teach pupils the Knglish language, and this by using it. m one form or another, m all cases of need for thought expression : this again to lit them lor the life they are to live among people using the English language and depending upon it for communication purposes. Pupils are now admitted to the school at five years of age. Three grades are given to kindergarten and preparatory work, followed by twelve grades — primary, intermediate, and advanced — bringing the pupils to their graduation at about their nineteenth or twentieth year. IJv the above system of classifying, our grading numbers are brought more to correspond to those m use m the public schools, thus making them more readily interpreted by parents with hearing children m the various grades. Our industrial department gives training to tjie boys m carpen - try and cabinet making, painting, printing, and gardening; to the girls, m domestic science, domestic art. and house keeping. The new industrial arts building, recently completed, will, we anticipate, make possible greater accomplishment m all lines of industrial train - ing. The new power house, when equipped and m operation, will give a much improved service m heating. The Legislature has made appropriation for a new dormitory. This will provide fireproof, up-to-date sleeping and living quarters lor pupils now occupying rooms of old type, unsafe construction. A new laundry building will also be constructed, the same being provided for by the Legislature. Future needs m the way of improvement of the school plant include the completion of the iww school building by adding th - final unit planned, this to enable the removal of eight classes still occupying rooms m the old school building. This removal will enable the carrying on of school work more effectively as a whole under one roof. I he school has also need of a modern hospital to replace the present building, which is ah- old residence building, with meagre equipment. Ihe addition of the new school unit and. of an up-to-date hospital building will make possible the removal of the old school 176 </seg>
            <seg id="p180">house anil of the present hospital, leaving space for construction m the future or a new administration building, with dormitories, etc., to replace the present building of old-time, unsafe construction. In conclusion I wish to thank the Hoard of Control for the interest it has taken m the work of the school and m the upbuilding of the plant. Also I want to express appreciation of the faithful service of the teachers and officers who have contributed so much toward the success of the work. Respectfully submitted, F. W. I'.OOTll, Superintendent. 177 </seg>
            <seg id="p181">178 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period viidiiiK June .50, 1&lt;&gt;M ' M. K. T. I'tiMiu ill close of .school term, June 15. 192" 11» so \')&gt; Admitted : • For first lime '. _&gt;X 22 SO "Readmitted, 10 S in Total Kimilliiu-nt : 150 no Hi) DischarRfd : (■raduatcd « g ]7 Left school fr&gt;r other reasons 55 IK 5^ Total KViiiovals 4,5 rj 7() I'ic-miiI at the close of school term June 1.5. |0.?l 107~ KJ I'll 'Includes pupils who had previously attended this school. TABLE II— SEX AND RACE OF PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME IVriod ending June .30, 1').51 ' ~~M. V. T, ) Vh i' c ■ '■ - 2fi 22 iT llllll; '" ■ 2 0 2 T " l;lls 2S 2l 511 </seg>
            <seg id="p182">TABLE HI— AGE OF PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period (■nclillK June 30, 10.? 1 . . ; i m- f. t. •5 year* j 5 , - '• &gt;; cars ; a 3 7 7 years -. . r , / S years ZZZI """" 2 i •&gt; years ZZZZZZZZ ""■ 3 2 s Id years ..: L ZZZZ. 2 ' 4 11 years L ' i 5 ; 12 years ...! ZZZZZ \ f, « " vcars I I) 1 14 vears i ,, , If. years Z ■&gt; \ .., • 1 0 S 15 years , () j , Totals Yz 5() TABLE IV— NATIVITY OF PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ciiditiR June 30, 1931 M. F.~ T. K;' l " r ' ul " : 0 i ~ IHllKliK „ j , Iowa Ill {jj a " sas : .~-.zzz;zrzzz"; o 1 i Missouri 0 I j Montana j 0 . Nebraska ; -&gt;\ i- &gt;,. Oklahoma , Z.Z3ZTZ 1 (I 1 South Dakota- 2 0 1 Z™™ ..zzizizzzrz oi t Virginia 0 j , Totals _ 28 22 50 179 </seg>
            <seg id="p183">TABLE V— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OP PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Period ending June 30. 1931 M. F. T, United States, both parents _ _ 21 13 34 Foreign, both parents ._ 4 6 10 Foreign, one parent : _ 1 2 3 L'nknown _ _.. 2 13 Totals 2? 22 SO TABLE VI— AGE AT WHICH PUPILS ADMITTED BECAME DEAF Period ending June 30, 1931 M. F. T. CcniKcnital .1 . ; JS yi 27 I'nilrr 2 years _ 4 15 I anil under ,\ years _ „ __ 12 3 .i and under 4 years 11 2 4 ami under S years 0 1 1 5 and under f&gt; years 1 n 1 &lt;&gt; H'"l under 7 years ; 3 14 ~ and under X years 0 2 2 8 and under ') years 0 1 I II and under 12 years 0' 1 1 II and under 15 years . 1 0 1 L'nknown : . 2 0 2 Totals . - - 28 22 S0~ TABLE VII— EXTENT OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED Period cndiiiR June 30, 1931 M. I". TT N'o hearing .'. _ [&lt;, f&gt; %* Partial lirariiiR ]| X l'» Considerable hearing 1 2 .! Totals 2K 22 5(1 180 </seg>
            <seg id="p184">TABLE VIII— PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME HAVING DEAF RELATIVES Period ending June 30, 1931 ■ M. F. T. lliis sister and cousins de;if j 0 j~~ lias parents and sister deaf ] 0 1 lias grandfather, parents and uncle deaf ZZZZ.'Z.. 0 I 1 lias sister and brother deaf 12? Has lirolhcr deaf ZZ ".'.'■ 0 1 1 Has sister deaf ZZZZ. 1 0 ] Has parents, brother and sister deaf 1 0 1 Totals _ j Jj~ TABLE IX— CLASSIFICATION OF PUPILS BY ORDINAL YEAR IN SCHOOL OF ALL PUPILS PRESENT JUNE 13, 1931 Period ciiditiK June 30, 1931 ■ . M. V. T. !: irsl -y p . ar •■•' * : 13 7 2ii Second year 8 , ? 2 , Third year „, ,, -,, Kpurth year „ „ , f| l :. 1 " 1 ' year ( , (x x , IX "' &gt;*•« 10 7 17 seventh year- f. ir lo KiRhlll year ...-. ZZZ'ZZZZZ K 4 1 " .^ llltl I 1 &gt;;«■•»«■ io a u lenth year y I Mleventh year * * ZZ.ZZ": '&gt; 3 1 » Twelfth year 5 j J t Thirteenth year ZZZZZZ. 4 5m Fourteenth year _ 2 0 » I'iftcenth year ZZZZ[ T 0 I Totals I 1Q7 M |g() 181 </seg>
            <seg id="p185">TABLE X— DISTRIBUTION OF ALL PUPILS IN SCHOOL JUNE 13, 1031 IVriml cud inn Juno 30. l'tfl ~M. l\ 'FT Kindergarten A 7 2 o Kindergarten I! 4 5 1, First Knulu ""'.'.'."■ 5 3 K Sri-uml grade A n n j.| Second grade H .-. 5 ,s U Second grade C .... 5 5 |ii Third grade A , 11 (, 17 Fourth Krfitk'.A •. (&gt; &lt;) It iMHirtli grade 15 ...i.ZZ.ZZ..... '■ III if. I'lflh grade _ _ 5. 5 10 Sixth grade A ' 8 3 11 Sixth grade B 7 r, \t, KiRhtli grade 1 _ 7 3 10 Ninth grade 4 SO Tciith grade _ .'......'..'1..Z 11 1 12 Eleventh grade 8 6 14 Totals 107 83 190 1 ■ ' 1 TABLE XI— ASSIGNED CAUSES OF DEAFNESS IN ALL PUPILS REMAINING AT END OF SCHOOL YEAR JUNE 13, 1931 - Period ending June 30. 1931 j Abscesses _ _ 3 3 J, / Brain fever and small-pox . '] 0 1 cold : : ; " j , , Congenital 66 49 115 Earache and adenoids 1 0 1 Erysipelas 0 11 Fall -™_...ZZ!ZZZ1" 0 1 1 Flu and whooping cough 10 1 Inflammatory rheumatism .~Z.T.ZZ7 10 1' Influenza _ ' 5 (, \\ Malarial fever 10 1 Measles Z/.'.~'.'.'.'.ZZ '.'.'".'.'.Z'.".'. 2 1 3 Measles and pneumonia 10 1 Pneumonia 0 11 Scarlet fever , ; 14^ Spasins ....""Z!™"."'."".™ 0 1 1 Spinal meningitis : 12 ,S 21) Sickness 3 0 1 Whooping cough 2 2 4 Unknown ; S 11 T" 1 " 1 " 107 ki 1 9li~ 182 </seg>
            <seg id="p186">TABLE XII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF PUPILS IN SCHOOL, AT THE END OF THE SCHOOL YEAR, JUNE 13, 1931 Period ending June 30, 1931 ; M. ~. ~'l\ Adams ? .. T~ Ulaiiic 1 ii l dihiik' zzzzzzz lil IJtix liuttc I n i Huffalii " \ uurt ;;;;;; : A -, 3 , nuticT :::::z::zz: " ,, 1 y**?, :zzz: 2 o i ( hast: i 9 t Cherry ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ.: 4 3 7 C hcyciinc 1 n I l; !&gt;- ■■ •• zzzzzzzz: o i i -^. olf: ! x 1 0 1 C liming ■,. () , , K u ? tor Z~. 2 0 2 IJiikota : I . 2 Dawson '. ' q 2 2 DtucI 0 1 T Dod™ ; zzzzz i I \ Douglas 33 22 55 I'lllmore : q j 1 Franklin j , Frontier ..„....-. .ZZZZZZZZZ 0 T 1 •. urnas :■ 4 1 5 : : 'B C • 2 4 0 •I'osper .1 1 o , "I'".,;' .' ZZZZZZZZZZZZZ I 0 T I h'liiiltini 11' 'J'^ 1 " 1^ : 1 0 I "" •: 3^6 '"ward : , „ j JllllllSOll I q 1 [y-""'^- ZZZZZZZZ 1 0 1 : :. 1 0 1 SI1I1X l 0 1 Lancaster 7 2 9 '••'"" : - ZZZZZZZZ 0 1 1 M;ultsi)ii ■_ Oil 183 </seg>
            <seg id="p187">TABLE XII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF PUPILS IN SCHOOL AT THE END OF THE SCHOOL YEAR, June 13, 1931 (Continued) Period emiiiiK June .?&lt;), i".U ■ , \l. P. T. Murrill 0 j Naiic; 1 ii i Neinulia .;. j 1 &gt; N'uckolls 2 2-1 Perkins I) • I 1 Phelps ■'..■"Z.Zl I) 1 l ff« te - ; 11 1 1 {^ ••; : 1 0 1 Richardson ' 2 1 .1 Saline 0 ; Sarpy ; .....ZZ'.'.'.'.'.'.".Z" (I 1 1 Sannuors I 1 _' Scotts Hlnff -Z.1.11ZZZ......1..Z 2 1 ~&gt; Sherman , T 0 I Stuiitcn 10 1 X ha &gt;' cr ; ""'.™'.r.'.'.'.' 2 -I (. \ alley 1 o j Washington 5 2 7 St;:te &lt;if Wyoming ] J ,; Totals ; |07 K.5 l««| 184 </seg>
            <seg id="p188">Report of the State Reformatory for Women York, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p189">STATE REFORMATORY f OR WOMEN YORK, NEBRASKA OFFICERS ALMA J. CHAPMAN, M. I). - - - - Superintendent LORA I. WADHAMS - - - - - Matron. K:ist H;i!l KLI.KN )(. K1KKNRAKV .... Matron. WVst II.ilI Miscellaneous Statement Established '. 1020 Number of employes June 30, 1931 10 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 36 Highest number of inmates (luring biennium 4S lVr capita cost per month $47.6S Number of acres owned 119 Number of acres leased . 20 Number of acres under cultivation 10'' Value of lands and buildings, furniture and equipment .' $155,092.52 Principal industries: Farming and stock raising-. Visiting- days: Fourth Thursday of each month; A female of fifteen years or upwards (who is not feeble - minded or insane), convicted by any court or magistrate, on charges i»f petty larceny or immoral conduct, may be sent to this institution for indeterminate sentence and is subject to parole by the Board of Pardons; provided that no such parole may be granted while the inmate is afflicted with venereal disease. When the crime commit - ted is a felony, the convicted woman may be sentenced to the Reformatory but is subject to transfer to the State Penitentiary for infractions of the rules in incorrigibility. 186 </seg>
            <seg id="p190">To the Governor and tin- Hoard of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. 1 have the honor of submitting the heinnial report of the Slate Reformatory for Women, covering the period ending lime 30. 1931. We feel that we have made progress the last two years. Our new tile barn has been built to replace the one that was destroyed by lire. New terrazzo lloors have been put m West Hall, also new furnaces m both Mast and West Malls. I'.oth buildings have been painted on the inside. We have a new washing' machine and a small mangle that ar. - run by electricty. The front lawn has been landscaped by Mrs. Homer King— a lily pond built, flower beds made and many trees set out. This adcU much to the appearance of the place. The care of the lawn and garden gives a desirable occupation m connection with our health development program. The Legislature allowed us money to buy land to the east of us. Most of our land is m corn, alfalfa and gardens. Our Poland China hogs furnish us meat and are a source of income to us. Our herd of pure bred Holsteins are doing line. We have enough milk and make our own butter. I hope U&gt; put m individual drinking cups m the barn. I would like a milking machine because, while the girls do well, the constant changing of milkers does not make for the maximum production of milk. Every six weeks we have a change of detail so that each girl may learn different kinds of work. All girls go to school an hour after breakfast.. A great many of them have had little schooling. A marked improvement is seen m their letter writing. The State Library Commission sends us books and a number of monthh magazines. People of York have given us much reading matter so that pur girls are well supplied. We have a sewing class, and it is our aim to give instruction m plain sewing so that the girls can sew for themselves when they leave here. We also make garments for other state institutions. We have a loom on which we make rugs. Our exhibit at the State Fair is made up of the fancy work ill me by the girls.' Upon being admitted, each girl is given a careful examination 187 </seg>
            <seg id="p191">iii order to determine what treatment to give. Almost nil the girls need treatment, and m even' case there is improvement, many gaining from ten to forty pounds. ( &gt;nr mothers and babies have ail done well. Regular Sunday services are held. These are conducted In - different ministers each month. The girls prepare programs to entertain the inmates and officers. In the evening they embroider and read. During the summer ihev play ball, skip rope and throw horseshoes. When a girl leaves the institution it is difficult 10. find work for - her. In times of depression the demand for girls m homes is less. Their downfall is often due to improper home conditions, and many times it is better to make a fresh start m some other place. From the time of her admission to her release, a girl is given individual study so as far as possible to help her prepare herself to become a good citizen when she leaves hen-. 1 he morale of the inmates has been good, and they have been willing workers. I wish to express my appreciation of the loyalty and cooperation of my helpers and the constructive help and encouragement of the Board of Control. Respect fully submitted. ALMA J. CHAPMAN, Superintendent. 188 </seg>
            <seg id="p192">189 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending •_ June Ml I'M I Present at beginning of period .JO Admitted fur the first time HI Readmitted .,..: .j Return from parole &gt; Returned from transfer 7 On parole Julv 1, 1 929 .| On escape July 1. 1929 ".'..'....'.'... '"""'.'.'.'.'.'.'.. 1 _^ ''*"tal ,. \ ; j u ij Hied in institution j Discharged from institution My Transferred to other institutions 4 Released on habeas corpus \ j Releasetl on respite -. ;. j "On escape July 1, l'Ml ZZ.ZZ.Z....... ,i Discharged while on parole \\ On parole July 1. 1&lt;M1 ..... 1 Total ]_y Remaining at close of period ,Vi TABLE II— AGE AND COLOR OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 1931 \V. C. 17 Under 1 year 12 2 14 14'and under 10 _ j f 4 16 and under IS 2^ 0 M 18 and under 20 20 2 1' 20 and under 22 : IS I) 7,s 22 and under 25 "!."".'.'.'...™!1 ') 2 II 25 and under .10 (, Jj (, .iO and under .15 5 1 I, .55 and under 50 7 0 7 T »t ; 'l ■ 103 ii TIT </seg>
            <seg id="p193">190 TABLE HI— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED 1'iriixl ending . June Ml 1°3I Dahivs it First grade ...: Z...ZZZZZZZZZZZZZ. \ SiTuml grade ? Fourth grade &gt; Fifth grade ; ; .»Z..ZZZZZ'ZZZZZZZ ■ 5 Sixth grade ■; Seventh grade \ ZZZZZZZ. 5 Kighlll grade ZZZZZZ. 35 Ninth grade j J{ Tenth grade ; ; "ZZZZZZZ S Klevcnth grade : '^ Twelfth grade : , J. One year college '1 Two years college I College graduate j Total j j . TABLE IV— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending i June 30. 1931 liahies 14 Divorced y Married '. 55 Separated ' j Single ; ZZZZZZZZZZ 4&lt;) Willow $ T "ta 1 HI TABLE V— CAUSE FOR ADMISSION Period ending ■ ■ June 30. 1931 Adultery „ Automobile theft j Arson "l Aiding and abetting a felony 1 I 'allies with mothers '. ].j liurglary . i I'onspiracy to violate Mann Act ' 1 (onci-.iling stolen property ; | I'linnnnn prostitute , 5 I)fliui|uent 1 l)clini|uent and veneral disease . &lt;, l-jirgery ' . ( I'oruication h'alsely issuing a Certificate of Deposit 1 Intoxication . 5 Larceny '. [ "j </seg>
            <seg id="p194">TABLE V— CAUSE FOR ADMISSION (CONTINUED) i IVriiid ending . June .id. V)M M;iiiil;iiuiiiK ;i disorderly house ■/. I ] Vagrancy i 7 Vagrancy and common prostitute : 1 Vagrancy arid vcncral disease ,$,s Venereal disease K Violating Harrison Narcotic Act 1 Violating Prohibit ion Act | .? Violating White Slave Traffic Act j 1 Total 1 Ul TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending ' - June .?(). 1931 Alabama 1 Colorado .' , ? Idaho 2 Iowa •? Illinois 2 Kansas '. 5 Missouri .'. 8 Minnesota 2 Montana 1 Nebraska : 69 New York 1 Oklahoma 6 Texas 1 Vermont , 1 Wisconsin 1 Wyoming 2 Total ..:... |~ 1 1 1 TABLE VII— COUNTIES FROM WHICH GIRLS WERE ADMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 Adams 2 Antelope .-. - 1 Boyd . 1 Buffalo , 3 t&gt;ss : :;■ 1 C heyenne 3 Custcr 3 Dawson ; 3 Dawcs 1 Dcs Moines, Iowa 1 Dodge 3 Douglas 5 Kant St. Louis, Illinois 1 rillmore " 1 l"t. Smith, Arkansas 1 I'urnas ' 1 Hall t i loit ; ;.". . i 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p195">TABLE VII— COUNTIES FROM WHICH GIRLS WERE ADMITTED (Continued) Period ending June 30, 1931 Jefferson 2 Johnson I Kaw City, Oklahoma 2 Lancaster . 25 Madison _ 2 Mobile. Alabama i Morrill : .~Z""""~".ZZ 1 Nance j Neniaha &gt; otoc .zzzzzz... i Pawnee I Phclps 1 Platle \ Red Willow • ZZZZZZZZZ.' 1 Kichard-on • i Scotts Bluff ZZZZZZ - 3 Scward ; \ Sheridan Shrcvespurt, Louisiana , 1 Thomas | j Tliurslon Webster j York ]2 Total ■ ! TTi TABLE VIII— PHYSICAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending . June M), l'«l y Committed with syphilis 23 Committid with Ronnrrhea 24 Comniitied with both "7 Committed free from disease 57 ' r "ta' -..) III TABLE IX— PARENTAL CONDITION Period endiiiK "" ■ June 30, 1931 Never lived together 12 Both parents dead 7 Mother dead 15 Father dead ..• 20 Separated Jj Living together : 28 T " tHl 1 1 1 192 </seg>
            <seg id="p196">LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On Hand June 30, 1931 Number Value £' ttIc • 46 $2,335.00 J"K S 87 500.00 '4°. r ? cs '■* 225.00 &lt;- hickcns 325 12O.(K) Tfltnl $3,180.00 DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS July 1, 1029 to June .50, 1931 Total produced during bicnniuin Measure Value M'lk 515.246 ll.s. $6,304.92 1-KKs &lt;WI ,|, 1Z . UK.&lt;)2 Total value : $6,423.8-1 FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS July I. |029 In June 30. 1031 .Total produced during hiennium ' ■ Measure Value g**»* •. ■ ,. 5 \^. $ 7AM~ p can&gt; 60l.ii. 82.0(1 Larrnls .| [,„, 5 ()( , &lt; ahlviEc : (25 lbs. 9.51) . 1 '••.'"cc IIS lbs. ll.5(i '•Onions 5k | m . 7500 P^as ...: : 50 i, lt . 5d0(i l'nlHliu'.s »S(I hu. 310.00 Toiualiics 115 |,,,. 115.00 • Swift cum : 75bii. 75.0(1 Corn ■ 1.150 Int. 685.00 Rnsiluiw 2IHI t. 1.000.00 Alfalfa 115 t. 1.205.00 Tnt.ll .' | $3.6.?0.00 193 </seg>
            <seg id="p197"/>
            <seg id="p198">Report of the Home for Dependent Children Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p199">NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS MRS. EFFIE J. MOUDEN - - - - - Superintendent E. \V. HANCOCK, M. D. - - ... . Physician MARIE IKU.H.LAN - - - - - Field Worker . K. C. MUL'UEN - - - Steward Miscellaneous Statement Established 1909 Xumlicr id' employes June 30, \')^\ 22 Number of inmates June 30, 1931 0.5 Highest number of inmates during liieunium . 117 I J er capita cost per month $41.18 Number of acres owned 4y Value of latvls and buildings, furniture anil equipment $107,743.57 Visiting days : 9to 11 A. M. and 2to 5 P. M. - Dependent or neglected children under eighteen years of age. and of sound mind, may be committed to this institution by the count}-, district, or juvenile court. Temporary inmates not regular - ly committed, may be admitted to the Home at the discretion of the Hoard of Control, but. the care and maintenance of these must be paid for by either the parent, guardian, or count}'. i 196 </seg>
            <seg id="p200">To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions. Lincoln, Nebraska. It is a pleasing to present herewith the I'.iennial Report of Hie Nebraska Home for Dependent Children which covers the period from June 30, 1929 to June 30, 1931. Our work m the Home is to care for children committed to onr institution after! the local and state welfare departments have been unable to adjust them m any other way. Our fust consideration, after a child comes to us is the welfare of that child. We are located on a tract of ground which is beautiful m every way with trees, shrubs, grass and llowers. Here the children find peace and the rest fulness found only near to nature. Those who have studied the situtation' realize the effect this has upon children uprooted from home and planted m a new surrounding. Our children at all times are under the supervision of a regis - tered nurse, who has charge of our nursery. Dr. X, \\\ Hancock, a child specialist, is our physician. A child is examined upon entrance to the institution, and any defect or ailment is acted upon at once. Dr. J. \Y. Tjhomns, specialist, cares for the tonsil lectomies. eyes. ears, lilting of glasses, etc. The Orthopedic and University hospitals care for our hospital cases. We feel that this medical care has been most effective and praiseworthy, as we have had only two deaths m the institution during the biennium. These were both premature babies who had come to us m a weakened condition. Dr. M. T. Sommer cares for the dental work of our children. Mental testing is done by Miss Clara Slade of the Lincoln Public Schools, and by J. McV. Hunt of the Psychology Clinic of the University of Xebraska. Our staff of workers are chosen because of their special ability to work with children. Our children attend the public schools. We do feel the need of an opportunity room for special ability to work with children. Our children attend the public schools. We do feel the need 197 </seg>
            <seg id="p201">of an opportunity room for certain types of children, but believe it Ih'Uit for the most part that they attend the public school. This gives them a normal outlook m their relationship to the world. The corps of teachers m the various schools which our children attend have given us the finest cooperation which we appreciate very much. The children attend Sunday School, church and young people's meetings m the various churches near our Home. To the pastors, laymen and teachers m these churches, we wish to express our appreciation for their interest and loyalty. Our children have received the most kind attention from various clubs, civic. organizations and business firms m Lincoln and out m the state. Christmas was made a time of joy, and many things m a recreational way became possible because of these organizations. We owe much to the thoughtfulne.ss of many individuals who so kindly remembered us. To these organizations and individuals, we are indeed grateful. We have our older boys on our forty-acre farm northeast of I'ethany. Here they have hogs, cows, horses and chickens which are cared lor by the boys. They raise rabbits for their. own remuner - ation. Those who remain m the Home for some time attend high school, securing work upon adjoining farms during vacations. Tin - problem of several so called "unplaceable"' boys has been worked out on this little farm. Now they arc with good, substantial farmers, and each year a savings is banked against the day when these boys become of age. On our farm a man and his wile care for our boys, giving them supervision as needed. Here we have worked out most completely the cottage system, a system we would very much like to be able to work out m all the other departments. With iiiir children living m the institution, we have been able to study them most carefully. The supervision given each child by the workers has helped him overcome many of the little habits which made it hard for him to adjust himself, and our physician and nurse have been able to correct and overcome physical defects. As a re - sult of this, Miss Uouglan, our field worker, has been extraordin - arily successful m placing a very large number of children m adoptive and free homes, with a small per cent of returns. The large number of placements In her credits makes her rank near the top of the list with others m similar work. 198 </seg>
            <seg id="p202">We need a work shop for the boys, laundry equipment m cln our laundry, &lt;&gt;ur buildings arranged to earn nut mure eflVclivelv the cottage system, a small hospital unit and rooms lor segregation upon arrival m order to work more effectively and economically. I wish to express my deepest appreciation for the attention and kind consideration given to the Home for Dependent Children hv each member of the Hoard of Control during the past biennium. 1 wish to extend thanks to Urs. E. \V. Hancock and J. \V. Thomas for their interest and cooperation m our work. Tn aH the. staff and employes 1 am deeply grateful, as 1 realize that only by their fine loyalty and labor has it been possible to make this a home rather than an institution. Respectfully submitted, EFFIE J. MOUDEN, Superintendent. 199 </seg>
            <seg id="p203">200 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending June 30, 1931 \T ¥. t7 Present at IwRinning of period 5-4 -4" 103 Admitted : First time „ (,') 80 . 14" Readmitted 0 I) (I Returned from parole and vacation '. ol 82 1-1.? Returned from transfer to other institutions 21 5 2fi Returned from escape' .1 0 .5 Total _.. 208 216 424 Died in institution „ 0 2 2 Discharged from institution _ 21 20 41 Paroled and on vacation 109 148 257 Transferred to another institution 1° -4 2.? (•".scaped from institution .'. 6 0 &lt;&gt; Total 155 174 ,?2" Present at end. of period 5.? 42 °5 Total under jurisdiction of the Home 275 22d 51)1 Returned from trial homes in which placed before beginning of period , 48 5.! nil Placed in trial homes and not returned during the period % 11" 215 Returned to parents or friends , 18 ') ■ 27 Adopted „ v.. J8 4" &gt;)7 Died : 0 .j .! Attained majority 27 2.5 50 Discharged by transfer to oilier institutions 15 Id M TABLE II— AGES OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June M). 1 •&gt;.{ 1 xi7~ i^ ~t7 I'nder 1 mouth 15 1.! 28 1 and under 2 months : d 2 S .$ and under 6 months .1 4 7 6 and under 12 months 2 2 4 1 and under 2 years ., ■ ,1 ] (, 2 and under 5 years _ 10 ].| 24 5 and under 10 years '. 21 '21 42 10 and under 15 years 8 1° 27 15 and under 18 years 1 &gt; $ Total : (,i) KO 14" </seg>
            <seg id="p204">201 TABLE 111— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June 30, 19.31 ' M. I*. T 7 3rd gra&lt;je .... . I I3 . "' &amp; 4th grade XZZZ j I '.', 5th grade " * s a 6th grade ■" X 2 ? 7th grade " "Z" " V ,, .;; 8th grade „. T " ~ — /. ? •&lt;» Above the 8th grade ■■"""'Z'"~~~""~'~''""~' (J q ,, T ° tal -■ ffl K0 »./ TABLE IV-SEX AND RACE OF THOSE ADMITTED Period ending June ■)(). l')M — . ; m^ i--. tT White ~ ~ ; Negro '"' ' '"' Mi - d _jj i ft I^Ln^z^ m xi) |.|.) TABLE V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED Period emliiiK June .!(). I&lt;U| 1 ' M. K. T. Nebraska [ Tj ~7. TT^~ United States other than Nebraska .'.'.' '. , -' ' .,. " '■ 1 .» ,i T 1 "* 1 ; ~&gt; m TuT TABLE VI-NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED I Period ending June .?(J, 1931 '■ M. F. t7 United States, both parents 7, Tp~ Foreign, both parents ... n i Mixed ' ' Unknown ! : ' ' L 1 " , (l / d l.i Total ■ ■•■■'. ~^ 51 TvT </seg>
            <seg id="p205">TABLE vn— PARENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED Period emliiiK June- .«), V&gt;M \i. R T. Both parents dead : 0 0 0 Father dead _ 7 n U, Mother dead _ ,{ (,■ i&gt; Parents living together \ 11l v \t&gt; Parents divorced _ 4 2 ■ v Parents separated ]« vj .\~, Stepmother '. '. ii ~&gt; j Stepfather „ 2 1 Parents living hut not married 25 Z&gt; -IS- I'uknown 0 1 1 Total m m ii«&gt; TABLE VIII— AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS Period ending June .1(1, l').?l \i. ¥. tT Age at death of father: L'nder 10 years 5 7 ]j 10 and inicler IS 2 2 \ Age at death of mother: Under 10 years _ 3 5 jj 10 and under 15 years 0 11 TABLE IX— ADMISSION FROM DEFECTIVE OR DELINQUENT HOMES Period ending June M). IV.II -m. l. r. Feehle-mindcd : leather 3 3 (, Mother _ 3 2 5 Brother _ „ _ 0 1 1 Sister ...„_„ 4 1 a Both parents „ 0 0 0 Insane: Father „ 1 1 2 Mother _ 2 (1 8 Both parents : ; () () 0 Delinquent : ■ Father ] _....; „.... n 13 ?4 Mother ; _ _ 15 21 Mt Both parents _ y 17 2fi Unknown 1 2 .5 202 </seg>
            <seg id="p206">TABLE X— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF PERIOD Total | All remaining For Period i Junt- 30, 1&lt;M1 _j __j M. r. T. M. K tT Attains 2 .} 5 3 JT" AnlL-lopu 4 2 1, .? 1 .4 Boone s .i 2 5 (I 0 n Box Hut it- 5 ■ 1 fi 4 15 g°«* 115 1 it 1 Buffalo 1 2 i 1 &gt; ( Hurt ; 1 ,f 4 1 2 \ « a&gt;s II (i (i 2 (1 -&gt; IVdar : (I (] o 1 0 I 1 Iwrry 0 0 0 ■ .{ () • t-lay , Oil 0 0 it ' UHter : i 1 -| &gt;, „ { IJawcs 10] I (l 1 Haws.iii 2 " II 2 0 |) 0 Dixim -4 15 1 (I 1 Dodge (10 0 21 \ DouKla.s .1 II (1 1 7 Diindy 0| I II 1 ! f-'i II mori- II (| |) 1 (I 1 •jane : { .) i, 11 0 0 darlifld I I 2 I 1 II 1 Hall 0 0 0 I) 1 1 Hnrlan : (I 0 0 1 (I 1 Hayes 0 0 n 0 2 » Molt (I 0 0 2 11 2 Ji-fferson : 000 11^ Koya Paha (I 11 (I 0 fi Lancaster..'. 21 .?2 5,1 ') ]« 27 Madison 0.2 2 0 1 1 Mvrrick '. 0 1 1 0 0 „ Ncmalia ■. 112 0 0 () Nuckolls 0 2 2 0 1 1 Oloc : 2 0 2 0 0 0 Pawnee 0 ■ 1 10 1 1 Pierce 0 I) () 10] Platte 0 2 2 Oil Red Willow 112 0 11 Richardson 112 0 0 0 Sarpy Oil 01] Scotts Bluff 1 0 1 1 0 ] Scward 12 3 2 1 .? Sheridan Oil 101 Thurston _ 0 (I 0 0 1 1 Washington 10 1 0 0 0 Webster .; (&gt; 5 11 1 (I 1 Vork 0 1 10 0 0 Total 69 80 14&lt;) 53 42^ 95~ 203 </seg>
            <seg id="p207">204 TABLE XI— CHARACTER OP ADMISSION i Period ending June 30, 1931 U. f! T? Permanent — by decree of court 67 77 144 Temporary — by contract: With parent 1 0 j . My order of court ; 13 4 TABLE XII— DISTRIBUTION OF CHILDREN I •■"■ • : — : Period ending June 3(1, 1"31 . M. F. ~ In institution ; 55 j2 0.5 In other institutions 2 0 2 On contract 0 0 ' (1 lu trial homes 21K ' 184 402 r-scapi'd : 2 0 2 Total 275 226 5o7~ TABLE XIII— APPLICATION FOR ADMISSION Period ending June 30. 1031 Application for admission jjg Permanent rare 209 Admitted \jtj \ Males (j9 \ Females (JQ Not admitted ft) Parents persuaded to keep 5 Family homes secured under parents super - visiuii q Referred to' court 44 Sent to other institutions 10 Aged people — information iiiul advice niven ... ' 1 Temporary care _.. 130 Admitted 5 Males '.ZZIZZZZZZ'.'. ' 2 • Females 3 Not admitted 125 Parents persuaded to keep 15 Family homes secured under parents super - vision : 0 Placed with relatives 0 Family homes secured ' 0 Referred to court 10M Applications withdrawn ] </seg>
            <seg id="p208">TABLE XIV-PHYSICAL CONDITION OF CHILDREN ADMITTED Period ending '_ June 30. V)3l Normal, physically Sulinorinal. physically : 1 71 Normal, mentally ' .71 Subnormal, mentally '......] w, Knlargcd and diseased tonsils ™ Knlarged adenoids " ( , Defective eyes Defective teeth ..ZZZZZZZZZZZZ. i'o Defective ear I Hare lip and cleft palate .., t P.iFalyzed limb _ , Mowed legs .........'..;." i Clubbed feet i ..............."....... 2 Hernia ... -&gt; Syphilis ZZZZ'ZZ'Z'Z'Z'Z'Z 2 (ionorrhoea '.".".'.'.'.'"..".".. 2 Bisexual ZZZZZZ". 1 ICpileptiforni , ICczema ZZZ. ■ 1 Hirth mark — large one on face i I [ydrocephalus | 2 l : iulernourished "• Mild rickets ""'" ', Severe rickets ZZZZZ'. ■&gt; Premature birth : 'ZZZ T Malnutrition :.............•... ! TABLE XV— APPLICATIONS TO TAKE CHILDREN Period ending June 30. 1W1 ] ■ . AT R T~ Habies ; nTJ TT1 ~ Older rl.ildrei. ,?? 232 Colored children ZZZSZZ j 7 i? Applications withdrawn '.ZZZ 14 \) if Anplications investigated and rejected IS 4J «5 Homes investigated and child placed . 10&lt;J 147 2 S6 205 </seg>
            <seg id="p209">tABLE XVI— FIELD WORK DURING PERIOD ENDING JUNE 30, 1031 Period ending June 30. 1931 Traveling: Number of miles by rail and auto : . . • - Rail 3490 Auto „.. 28,769 Total .■ : 32,268 Children : Placed in homes for adoption , 1 40 47 87 Placed in free homes, work, and vacation 69 100 169 Returned from homes _ _ '■ 57 73 130 Removed from homes ....: _ _ 4 9 13 Transferred from one home to another 1 4 5 Left homes in which placed 1 0 1 Visits to children 313 330 643 Homes : Number of visits to homes in which children have been placed 299 311 610 Prospective homes visited . 130 158 288 Special cases investigated 15 21 36 Schools visited _ 127 120 247- 206 </seg>
            <seg id="p210">Report of the State Reformatory for Men Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p211">STATE REFORMATORY FOR MEN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS A. \V. MILLER - - - - Superintendent H. \V. JESPERSEN .... Assistant Superintendent DR. B. A. FINKLE - - - - - Physician CHAS. SI EH - Steward C. R. PHILLIPIPI Educational Supervisor Miscellaneous Statement Established 1 921 Number of cmpolycs [uiK-30, 1931 14 Number of inmate's June 30, 1931 , 399 Highest number of inmates during biennium 423 l'er capita cost per month ;. ■ $311.55 Number of acres owned •. 161.64 Number of acres leased 605. S Number of acres under culivation •. ' 690.8 Value of lands and buildings, furniture and equipment equipment $333,534.35 Principal industries : Farming, gardening, stock raising, and industrial trades. Visiting days: Every day excepting Sundays and holidays.' Hours, 9 :30 A. M. to* 1 1 :00 A. M., and 2 P. M. to 4 P. M - Any person not less than sixteen nor more than thirty years of age at the time of conviction of a felony for the first time may be scntened to the Reformatory instead of the Penitentiary when in the judgment of the court the person is capable of reformation and the sentence is compatible with the general welfare. 208 </seg>
            <seg id="p212">To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I have the honor to submit to you the fifth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Reformatory for Men, covering the period from July Ist, 1920 to July Ist, 1931. " The population of this institution has shown a steady increase during the biciiniijm, beginning this bicnniiini with a count of .500 inmates and closing with a count of ?&gt;&lt;)&lt;), with a high count of 42.5 at one time. A change of officers has taken place since our last report. Air. H. W. Jespersen succeeded Mr. 11. I". Scheidcler, resigned, as As - sistant Superintendent, with Mr. Charles Young being appointed to the Captain of Guards position vacated by Mr. Jcspcrsen. Mr. \V. |. Shrake was appointed Day Sergeant; Mr. Charles Sieh continues as Steward, as (hies Mr. Claude \V. I Toward continue as Night Sergeant, and it is my pleasure to report that these men and other employes of this institution have made honest efforts to continue the good health and conduct of the inmates, and to them commenda - tion is-due for the splendid record made during this biennium. Examination of Table No. V contained herein shows an increase m two extremes. We received 41 more men this biennium than we did m the last that have had less than a fourth grade education, and an increase of 11 men over the number shown m our last report who have gone to college or university. Our grade school is progressing splendidly under the leadership of Mr. Cal. R. Phillippi, a most competent man who is devoted to his profession, and we feel very fortunate to have him as the principal of our school department. This biennium we are farming on a much larger scale. All of this work is under the direction of a genuine farm boss, Mr. 11. C. Marshall, who is constantly teaching fanning m a most practical manner to the men assigned to his department. We have under -cultivation nearly 700 acres and expect a fair crop from each tract. Mr. Marshall also has charge of our live stock department, and with the assistance of Mr. Joe King, has brought great improvement m this department. Our several shops are proceeding along lines as heretofore 209 </seg>
            <seg id="p213">reported, and it is our pleasure to announce that we expect to have a first-class automoible license plate manufacturing plant m full operation before the next biennium closes. The Legislature provided funds with which we will rebuild our detention building, construct a new water reservoir and install a block of 63 cells all of which will mean much activity and thereby create an influence which will be very beneficial to our already good discipline. We have just finished building a residence for the Superin - tendent which was provided for by our 1929 Legislature. This building cost $8000.00 and was built and finished by the inmates under the general instructor, Mr. George Davison (Mr. Davison's son assisted m the laying of brick, and an outside tinman installed the guttering). To Mr. Davison, too much praise cannot be given, for, under his supervision, inmates built and installed a structure m a first-class workmanship manner. All the electrical, plumbing and heating work was installed by the inmates under the supervision of our engineer, Mr. Charles Munis, a most competent man. The decorations for this residence were done by the inmates under the supervision of Mr. C. L. Walker. Directly after finishing the superintendent's residence, work was started on an employes' building consisting -of three apartments with main dining room and kitchen. $12,5(X).00 was allotted by the' l') 2') Legislature for this building which will soon lie ready for occupancy. It has been the custom to conduct a regular chapel service each Sunday for the entire population of Ihe institution, securing 1 1 it - best speakers available, selected from the many prominent' pastors of the different churches of our city. We have found this plan most satisfactory. From time to lime we secure as speakers business men who have made a success m life, and this offers the inmates something tangible m the way of right living. Often we have women as speakers wlio bring to the boys messages which cause many of the audience to wipe away a tear and make resolution anew to strive for the better things m life. 1 am pleased to report thai these regular chapel services are cheerfully attended by our inmates, and many young men hear new ideas expressed which have a marked bearing on their future conduct. Mass is attended every Saturday morning by those of the Catholic faith, and we desire to express to Bishop Kucera our appreciation for assigning 210 </seg>
            <seg id="p214">Father Quinn and Father Killian to carry on this important work. To Father Quinn ami Father Killian, I shall ever feel indebted for the punctual service rendered this institution every Saturday morning. The First! Church of Christ of Lincoln holds morning services here each Sabbath, and many of our young men attend services. We also express our appreciation for their regular appearances and the wholesome services rendered for our boys. The young people of the Union College deserve much credit for the inspiring programs and talks presented to our inmates through the winter months. For the past several years Reverand H. Erck, University Pastor of the Lutheran Church, has taught a bible class at this institution each Monday night through the fall and winter months. Reverand Erck lias given quite generously of his time, energy and money to bring these services to the high standard maintained. The officals of this institution and many of our young men appreciate Reverand Erck very much indeed. The health of the population of this institution continues to be good. With plenty to do and good wholesome food to eat, clean recreation and rest, these men should be, and are, healthy. We have had three deaths this year which makes four deaths and one suicide since the beginning of the institution almost ten years ago. Dr. 1!. A. Finkle serves as our. institution physician and to him should go the credit for this excellent showing." Even though he has had some serious problems presented to him m sickness, by his advice and attention those suffering soon return to their duties appreciating the services rendered by the good doctor. Basket, volley and base-ball, horseshoes, running and jumping are the outdoor sports indulged m by those inclined m the hours set aside for this purpose. We encourage ami prepare contests between inmates m order to bring about a better understanding among them, also teaching them self-control, besides getting them m action which makes for their better health. Heretofore we have enjoyed movies provided us by the large film corporations through the kindness and activity of Mr. Charles Shire. Mr. A. 1-:. Eaton of the American Distributing Corporation of Omaha also furnishes us with films gratis, when it is impossible for us to secure them else - where.- The movie is fast changing, the silent film almost a thing of the past, and inasmuch as we have no sound equipment, we expect to have few movies hereafter. We regret this very much because 211 </seg>
            <seg id="p215">our men prize their movie privilege, and the discipline of the institu - tion is better maintained by granting movie permits. The fact that this institution is not surrounded- by a high stone wall but with a ten foot woven wire fence offers many of our in - mates an opportunity to speculate on their chances of a get-a-way, and we are pleased to state that, while we have had five men leave our custody m the last two years, only one of them went over the fence and soon afterwards, even though he had gone to Canada, re - turned of his own accord. The general conduct of an institution is no better than what the men make it who are m command. . Without disregarding the in - mate, the protection of society must be our first concern, and, m dealing with these men sent here for reformation and protection of society, great consideration should.be given m the selection of the men who are employed to guide and govern these charges because the discipline of the institution is but the reflection of the influence of those who .daily control the activities of the inmates assigned them. The discipline of this institution is good, having little trouble with the inmates. We endeavor to have a flexible program along reformatory and educational lines, and our employes, whether guards or tradesmen, are expected to be on the alert to offer good whole - some advice and report to the office any. case where extra effort is needed to restore m the inmate confidence and self-respect. We find that efforts along these lines bring excellent results which continue long after the inmate's release from this institution. To name each of the employes and tell of his sterling qualities would make this report too long, hence we will state that the employes of tin- refor - matory are men of good character and are making honest effort to assist those m charge to have the institution function as it should. In closing, , l wish to express my sincere thanks to the Hoard of Control for all official courtesies and considerations so generously accorded me. To His Excellency, the Governor, I express my ap - preciation for the wonderful spirit displayed toward the men brought before him at the regular monthly meetings of the Hoard of Pardons, and Paroles and also for the many official courtesies extended me and the officers of this institution. Respectfully submitted, A. W. MILLER. _ ( . ■ Superintendent. 212 </seg>
            <seg id="p216">213 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Period ending . \ June .50. 1931 Present at beginning of period Zl Admitted : For first time ' 579 Returned from parole !ZZ!" ~7 Returned from escape "..."..'.'..'.".... 8 Held for parole board 1.............. • 3 T " tal • ■-■...^......^ ::::::::::^^ ::: .. 913 Released : Escaped r Discharged ,.? Died ■ 34^ Paroled : ZZZL.J 1 14? Released to parole board ZZZ ~ 2 Transferred to penitentiary .4 Commuted and paroled ...'. ".".....Z"Z 2 Total - ~ 514 Total remaining June 30, 1931 ~399^ TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period endiiiK .._ . June 30, 1931 Fifteen and under twenty years J(~j Twenty and under twenty-live years 269 Twenty-five years and over ZZZZZ 97 Total ; ;...: j^j </seg>
            <seg id="p217">TABLE III— NATIVITY OP THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 Alabama '. : 1 Arkansas , 4 California 3 Colorado ''■ Connecticut .. ...' 1 Florida : 1 Idaho 1 Illinois : 19 Indiana ...: '■ 3 Iowa - -'7 Kansas 3n Kentucky '. " Louisiana 2 Maine 2 Maryland .-. 1 Massachusetts 3 Michigan : 7 Minnesota '" Mississippi 4 Missouri _ •"' Montana 4 Nebraska 22 1 ) New Jersey 2 New York '" Nortli Carolina ' North Dakota 3 Ohio :._... 7 Oklahoma - IS Oregon 2 Pennsylvania *• South Carolina 2 South Dakota : 10 Tennessee _ f&gt; Texas 12 Vermont _ 1 Virginia 2 Washington - _ 2 Wisconsin ; f f Wyoming 1 Canada 1 Central America 1 England 1 Italy 2 Mexico : 9 Russia 3 Sweden , 1 Not given ■... 9 Total .' 529 214 </seg>
            <seg id="p218">TABLE IV— RACE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending ■ ■ June 30, 1931 White 7^ Negro JZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ 24 Indian ...!...... jn Mexican ZZ.Z'Z— 12 Total JJ2I) TABLE V— EDUCATION OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending . June 30, 1931 None _ j Primary (to 4th grade) ~ 40 Common (5th to 9th urade) me High school „ ' ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ 152 College or university ir Attended scliool for deaf ..~..Z.ZZZZZZZ'.i 1 Total _ 5^ TABLE VI— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending . June 30, 1931 Single _ Married iiu. U. . . t - HTJ ldowed j Divorced ?,, Annulled ZZZZZZZZ 2 Common law wife ZZZZ.ZZZZZ.. 1 Divorced and remarried ZZ..ZZZ ZZZZZ 1 Separated ; ZZZZZZZ. i Unknown , T " t;tl -. ■• ~ 529 215 </seg>
            <seg id="p219">216 TABLE VII— COUNTY FROM WHICH COMMITTED Period ending June .ill. 1931 Adams „ 14 Antelope ZZZZ "J Boone • 4 Boyd .' 1 Box Butte ZZZZZZZZZZZZZ! ' ■ 7 Brown .3 Buffalo 14 Burt ■ 3 Butler ZZZZZZZZZZZZ 1 Cass ZZZZZZ... •* Cedar .' f&gt; Chase ' 7 Cherry ZZZZZZ... 1(l Cheyenne 17 ciay ZZZZZZZZZZZ! 2 Cuming 2 Custer ' 4 Dakota : ZZZZZZZZZ!!!"!!! - Dawes .".!".....ZZ.Z.ZZ ' Dawson S Deuei z:zzzzzzz;zzzzzzz - Uixon 2 Dodge ZIZIZZ1ZZZZZZZZ1!Z! y Douglas 67 Dundy ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ™ l Fillmore ; ZZZZ. Franklin 3 Frontier ...„ 3 Furnas ..ZZ.ZZ.ZZZZ". •' Gage ZZZZZZZZZ &amp; Garden ZZ..ZZ.Z....Z. " Gosper _ 2 Greeley 5 Hall ; 9 Harlan ; ..ZZ"."."'.™™"!!" •* Hamilton _ _ ZZZZZZ....... •* Hayes _ _ ;. ZZ. •* Hitchcock 3 Holt ZZZZZZZZZZZ 4 Howard .....................ZZ...... 3 Jefferson ;. Z.Z.Z.Z 5 Johnson '. 3 Kearney .'. "...]._ 6 Keith .'. ZZZZ... ■&lt; Keya Paha ......Z.....ZZ.Z.Z......Z..Z". - 1 Kimball 10 Knox !.....Z....!!!..~!!!!!1!!!!!.~ s • ' Lancaster .ZZ..Z.Z....."... 41 Lincoln \ 10 Logan ......"....." |. Madison 1 McPherson ~i!!!™!!!Z".".!Z!!"." I </seg>
            <seg id="p220">TABLE VII— COUNTY FROM WHICH COMMITTED (Continued) Period ending ■ June 30, 1931 Merrick ? Morrin iczzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz 6 Nance j Nemaha ZZZZZZZZZZ 8 Ntickolls c otoe z!!zzzzzzzzzzzzz 3 Pawnee 2 p^ip* ■ zzzzz:zzzzzzz:zzz: i Fierce i Platte Z H Polk : ■■■ 7 Red Willow ZZZZZZZZZZ! 14 Richardson 7 Rock j Saline ...Z........ 7 Saipy !.!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 4 Saunders 9 Scotts Bluff L .™.._.Z!!!ZZZZZZZZZZ 23 Seward 4 Sheridan Z!Z! 10 Sherman Z..ZZZZZZ 1 Sioux _ ZZZZZ 1 Stanton ; I Tliay.cr 9 Thomas ; 1 Thurston „... ' u Valley ZZZZZZZZZZ! 2 Washington 4 u ..... ............................................. -i Wayne 2 Wehster ZZZZZZZZZZ!! 3 York ".!!..!!! 3 Total _ 529 TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 Actor , 2 Automobile painter 1 Barber ■ q Baker ZZZZZZZIZZZZZZZ" 8 Banker 1 Bank cashier 1 Bookkeeper 3 Blacksmith : """'_! 1 Breaking horses .". ;.. 1 Boilermaker apprentice I Butcher '. 2 Beet worker ; j Bridge construction ....: j Cabinet maker ; _'__' 2 Carpenter _ J2 Carpenter apprentice .-. , 1 Chauffeur _'. 3 Clerk ■. _ 10 Concrete contractor _ j 217 </seg>
            <seg id="p221">TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED (Continued) Period ending June 30, 1931 Cook ... ID Crane operator 1 Clothes presscr .. 1 Concrete worker 1 Chemist, sugar factory . 1 Dairyman 2 Kgg candler .- 1 Electrician 4 Farmer ; 173 Fireman fi filass cutter : 1 Iron worker 3 Interior decorator 1 Ice cream maker ..'. 1 Jockey •. 1 Laborer 110 Lineman 1 . Laundry man _ 1 Mechanic '. -44 Machinist ; 7 Miner : &#132;.., 3 Musician : 4 Mason 1 Newsboy 2 Nursey man ..., 1 Negative cutter movie lahratory 1 Optician apprentice 1 Painter 1.5 Plumber 4 Plumber helper : 1 Plasterer 2 Pipe fitter 1 Porter 1 Printer \ 4 Kadio operator 1 Radio mechanic 2 Rancher ' 5 Salesman (&gt; Shoe shiner . 1 Steam fitter 1 Steel worker .{ Student 1 Steeple jack ; ; 1 Stenographer 1 Steam presser .• 1 Shoe maker : 1 Tailor _ 2 Truck driver 14 Teacher 2 Terra cotta worker 1 Tinsmith ;..... 1 Undertaker apprentice 1 Waiter 2 Window trimmer I None given 2 Total ; ■ 218 </seg>
            <seg id="p222">TABLE IX— RELIGIOUS PREFERENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending ' June 30, 1931 Protestant 7^ Catholic ZZZZZZZZZZZZ in No preference """""'.'." 2.? Total ; ~ j^~ TABLE X— CRIME FOR WHICH COMMITTED Period ending June 30. 1931 Aiding and abetting breaking and entering i Arson \ Assault ZZZZZZZZ'ZZZ. ? Assault, felonious 2 Assault with intent to do bodily harm 4 Assault with intent to murder 1 Assault with intent to rob &gt; Assault to rape ...ZZZZZZZ. I Attempted automobile theft i Auto theft 'ZZZZZZZZZZZZ. 60 Auto theft and breaking and entering 1 Bank robbery I Bigamy : ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZl 1 Breaking and entering ,... &lt;)S Breaking and entering and burglary ..Z.ZZZZZZZZZZ 3 Breaking and entering and larceny ZZZZZZ. 1 Breaking and entering and parole violation 1 Breaking and entering and theft 7 Breaking and entering, stealing and concealing automobile ; ' I Breaking and entering, carrying concealed weapon and possession of burglar tool 1 Burglary i&gt; Burglary and larceny IIZII~ \ Burglary and grand larceny I Carrying concealed weapons ; ? Chicken theft 33 Causing death while Unlawfully operating motor vehicle ; . y Concealing stolen chickens \ ' Disposing of mortgaged property \ Embezzlement \ Knticing a minor child from home of parents 1 •orgery .... ' ; 10(&gt; l-orgery and uttering forged instrument .... 3 (jrand larceny "" 41 tirand larceny and parole violation 1 Grand larceny and possession stolen propertv 4 Issuing no fund checks ' 3 Jail breaking j Larceny , ]..."...... 0 Larceny as bailee _ 2 Larceny from person ..ZZZZZZZZZZZl'. 2 Larceny and receiving stolen propertv 1 Murder " -, Obtaining money under false pretense 2 219 </seg>
            <seg id="p223">TABLE X— CRIME FOR WHICH COMMITTED (Continued) Period ending Juno 30, 19.31 Parole (bench) violation 4 Rape, forcible ....:• 4 Rape, statutory 5 ReceiviiiK stolen property ■ 1 Receiving stolen goods and breaking and entering 2 Receiving .stolen cattle 1 Ueimivinv mortgaged property 1 Robbery .'. .' 32 Seduction • 1 Shooting with intent to kill and wound 3 Selling and disposing of mortgaged property 1 Stealing cattle '. ." 8 Stealing and receiving stolen automobile 10 Stealing geese 1 Stealing grain 1 Stealing hides 1 Stealing hogs _ 1 1 Stealing saddle 1 Stealing hogs and chickens 1 Stealing wheat ....'. $ Theft 4 Wife desertion .'. 2 Wife and child abandonment 2 Wife and child abandonment and non-support 1 Total 529 TABLE XI— CHARACTER OF PARENTAGE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June 30, 1"31 Father dead 116 Father unknown 15 Father dead and mother unknown 7 Father unknown and mother dead 7 Mother dead : 45 Mother unknown _ 3 Uoth parents dead ' 46 ■ Both parents unknown ■... 7 iioth parents living 283 Total '52&lt;) \ 220 </seg>
            <seg id="p224">TABLE XII— PHYSICAL AND MENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending - ; '_ June 30, vm General health : Sound ,,. Diseased ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ 98 Total g2^ Mental state: ■ Sane ,„, Sub-normal V,. Feeble-minded '. ZZZZZZZ. ' 2(l' Total ...._ - ~J^ Diseased : (lonorrhea „ syphilis ZZZZZZZ &gt;1 Acne f. Hernia 3 - Heart Z'ZZZZZZZZZZ i? Hearing defective ' ' 7 Coryza ', Phymosis i Pyorrhca ZZZZZZZZZ • SS Pigeon breast '_____" "'-. Scabies ; ] ZZZZZ1 i'^ Teeth very poor : 1,2 Tonsils enlarged ._ .ZZZZ. «7 Venereal warts , V r inceuts angina 1 Varicocele ..........".... 2 Eczema f Epilepsy .Z.'Z.'ZZZ % Partial paralysis """ P Hydrocele ...'. , ...."""." f Hypo spadis : Defects: ' Blind one eye .'. Leg deformed 5 Ami stiff f Artificial leg '.ZZZZ!. i Deformed hand i Deaf and dumb : , Sunken chest 2 221 </seg>
            <seg id="p225">TABLE XIII— NUMBER OF CONVICTIONS OF THOSE COMMITTED Period ending June .50, 1931 First time 281 liencli parole 26 liench parole and detention, home ........ 1 Bench parole and jail 2 Industrial school, 1 term ....: 25 Industrial school. 2 terms 11 Industrial school. .? terms 1 Industrial school and jail 9 Industrial school and reformatory 6 Industrial school and penitentiary 1 Industrial school and work house 1 Industrial school and detention home •: ' 1 Industrial school and lieneh parole - 3 Previous reformatory : K Previous reformatory and penitentiary .5 Previous penitentiary : 1 Detention hoiiie .! Detention home and jail 2 House of correction 2 Juvenile school 1 M Hilary prison , 1 Work house 1 Previous jail record , 139 Total 529 TABLE XIV— TERM OF SENTENCE OF THOSE CONVICTED Period ending June 30. 1931 4 months : . 2 5 months 2 (i months 6 It months to 1 year 3 • 9 mouths ; " 1 10 mouths to 1 year 2 1 year flat " :... 184 1 year anil 1 day 3 1 year to 1 year and 1 day .....' 2 1 year to 14 months 1 1 year to 15 months 2 1 year to IX months d 1 in 2 years 4.5 1 year to 30 months : 1 1 to 3 years ; 52 1 to .i years (&lt; months ... ; 2 I to 4 years 4 1 to 5 years 9 1 to 7 years ■ 6 I to 10 years .....", 20 1 to 20 years 12 15 months flat :.... 5 15 months to 4 years 1 18 months flat 12 18 months to 2 years 1 222 </seg>
            <seg id="p226">TABLE XIV— TERM OF SENTENCE OF THOSE CONVICTED (Con.) I Period ending June M). \&lt;)M 18 to 30 months j 18 months to 3 years _l 18 months to 5 years &gt; 2 years flat : iT • Jtn.i years n 2 to 4 years ZZZZ. 7 2 to 5 years * y M) months to 4 years &gt; 3 years flat ; 3 to 4 years .? to 5 years ..._ .5 to 6 years : ; .? to 7 years "j .5 to 10 years 7 .? to .30 years I I ■? years Hat 5 to 10 years I 7 years flat 8 years flat ( 10 years flat i 17 years flat '. ""™.!™.!"ZZZ 1 Total ; ~~ , 2 ,j TABLE XV— DURATION OF IMPRISONMENT OF THOSE DISCHARGED AND PAROLED Period ending ___^ June 30, l'Ml Less than 6 months ,. 7^ 6 months to 1 year ZZ" 100 1 year to 18 months ,«. 18 months to 2 years ™!-"™Z!ZZZZ! US 2 to .? years v7 .? to -4 years Z"ZVZZZ...ZVZZV.Z.Z % 4 to S years : &lt; T " tal . *~ 4KK 223 </seg>
            <seg id="p227">GAREN, ORCHARD AND FARM PRODUCTS July 1, 1929 to June 30, 10.S1 Total produced i Measure Value Asparagus ..............".!........„. 87.? lbs. $ 87 JO bw .K &lt; -i 13,242 lbs. 264 84 Carm sT* 8 ' 703 Ibs ' 34SA2 Carrots | ]9814 , b 3y62^ Cauliflower 456 , bs ° 2 °^ , L . orn - field 7,724 lbs. 3862 Corn, pop ,c 4 .. Yn ia Corn, sweet 18 735 hs' 1«7 « \f* " Ia "J. 1 722 lbs. 3776 r X tUCC •. 5,681 lbs. 227.24 " k r- V, - 85 lbs. 3 40 Onions, Bermuda ■ 4 25 lbs 127S Onions, dried .'.....IZ."™ 12,162 lbs! " 18Z43 Omons, green 1 2 978 Ibs 259 J6 P ars "'P s 3,931 lbs. 78^2 , c:is ■,.; 5,686 lbs. 284 30 Vpncrs /MaiiRo 21 Ibs. 147 V;"'! slu i s 6,483 lbs. 324.15 ' &lt; . ll "!" irb -■" ! 12,183 lbs. 121.83 £«! sif y ••• 155 lbs. 4.65 5^»» h 1 6,565 lbs. ' 131.30 -: : : 3, 471 , bs , 04 A , Swiss chunl 2.265 lbs. 45 311 rnmatocs. Rtvcn 2.W5 lbs. ?&lt;&gt;0S I "iiiatocs. ripe 26,267 lbs. 3'M0() Turnips ; i il76 „,, ,, 7fl \\ .•ilerntiloiis 3«.W!) lbs. 570 58 }-.iw«tic« :... 3,527 lbs. 15871 ••rapes 261 lbs. 10.44 M7'u r "' s • 7&lt;J8 "&gt;«• 1197(1 •^ lf 'i lf:l "! 194 t. 2,590.00 Barley 1,130 |,u. 51? 55 r " ■ 8.674 bu. 5.357:00 ;l . ls , ■ 2.772 bu 914.10 ,"'•'."'. lls . 1,641 bu. 2,106.00 'rairic •&gt;•'&gt;■ m 1. 4« 0 .00 '&gt;- vi ; 120 bu. 86.40 Sudan grass ; ,„ ,. ]{)0 . (h , VVIuat :.. 570 bu. 342.00 T " tul - '■ ■ : $17,959.45 224 </seg>
            <seg id="p228">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY On Hand June 30, 1931 ' , , Number Value S " •■ " $1,255.00 iy"' le 47 3.422.22 2 2: iljg Total ■ ■ -, I $6,924.62 DAIRY PRODUCTS j Total produced and * disposed of Measure Value £?'£ ■• K'1.017 1l.s. 4.859.01 tggs 2309 doz. 512.37 Total j $5,395.38 225 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>