<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00020.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00020.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report OF THE State Veterinarian OF THE State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">Biennial Report OF THE State Veterinarian OF THE State of Nebraska, K&gt; Dr CHAS. A. McKIM, State Veterinarian 1908 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">term ending November 30, 1908 4* biennial repor, of ,1... Office of^Xril^ Z Respectful &lt; HAS. A. McKIM, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">STATE VETERINARIAN Since rendering the third biennial report &lt;m November :to. I'.MKi, the wort of this department has more Than doubled in amount, until at flic present time it is an impossibility for ■M man to properly take care of it. nr begn to answer alt the calls or reqnesto made upon him to go and examine animals supposed to 1m- raftering from contagious, infectious, transmis- sible diseases 1 ooaM remain out on the road constantly, from month to Ik; able to keep the tield work do *.. the necessary office work Iifh, ami then probably only in fairly good shape, but tc dd suffer. »pondenee devolving upon the to the Itch or Scabies of cattle I The great amount ol mw , especially that pertainin ires nearly half the time ■t the men in the Held as £ the Veterinarian to property will 1k&gt; explained later I Two years ago 1 tried to impress apoa the memben of lvogislature the imperative need of a larin-r appropriatiai the Assistant Stale Veterinarians, the present amount al - tl lieing only $200.00 a year for the salary, thi* is not more one-sixth of what ii should be. tit is not a question of increasing any Htants are allowed $5.00 per day for il nly when </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 for the state to employ tin- lore often than it ran &lt;&gt;r doe it vvniil.l generally U- i saving i,, the State hi do bo, us ill, pmtw iirc-.-sin f,,r the Deputy State Veterinarian to reach »tor i him ii w nit til.- n-.. mi CXIH'llS would In- onlv ;, t';iir iiiiniM-nsHrii hi law under which ill lui* |»n.vi«n to lie very excellent, eaxil.v iin.U-rxtood. forceful an. rv excel Icnl i rcetiil an in in. .-i etw« nu U- enforced without trouble, and I wuiild in favor thai it U- retained a« far a&gt; |NM«ibk&gt; with i f.-v in uhwI i-:i&gt; ( - eiin In* enforced without trouble, and I would . -li;i r lire •- which ti mid iMrcuiiiHtaiieeK haw proved are essential In ill.- tir-i |,| ;1 .-.- I w.-iild m-,. that Sr.-iio,,^ i am | 2 ( 'l«»l"'-'- »■ l»0" C piled Statute* of N'ebnwka be m, cfannp, '"■ |v niil . v '"■ rrwiteil ;i Live Stm-k S ; ,uiiiirv Board, coil sislinj; ..1 five iikiiiImi- ;i|&gt;]M.inl,..l liv the Governor, emeh in s,-i-\, terui of Hve vears, Ihi) in sn,-], » n v rhal one member vril annually. Tlnv.. ,,f ibe iuetiiU*iN -li ;l || 1,,. Hnandallv in wl in live sfnek .in I i wo |»rn&lt;-ticin» v&lt;&gt;teriniirian ! «, ;;r;nlii:,t,- for a term of I'd in uf ■ r«-iihirl\ itrpiiiizeil mid n-,-,,i..,ii/.,..| Veterinary Collep- iii/.cl N'eteriiiarv ( U '"•" v:l&lt;- '&gt;' 'wnw "ii ill'' Uml the \Am-v lx&gt; till,.,| by a|i|M»inr Ii ! th. nu-iii from ili,.-hi&gt;- tu wkieb r.-tirin^ nniuU-r Im-Io,,-^. The Board -ImiiI.I have the |M&gt;wer to iiiij.^iv &gt;u.-li | l( -l|, M Ii men: which I he Boanl should have the |n»wer to iiunlov &gt;ucli h n tnnls neeemarv ind mm exenitive iiffiwr who shall he the Stair illim:m '"■' ■ uiemher of the Board, and who shall be a it Hii.ls nece^;irv and mii executive officer who sliall he tlie Stat. inarian n..i ■ uiemher of the Board, and who shall be ■ irra.iiuiir .,t ■ reprulariy »r|raniatl and reco|Eniae&lt;l V r eterinary Ii &lt;lioiil,| determine whai MHnuenMtioo the executive graduate ..t i repilarh ..i--:iiii/e,l and n-e. ,-11 i /.,•,! Wterinan It should determine wh Acer shall receive and gttcfa other aalariea or expeaaea Deseman Acer shall reeeive and »nefa other xalariea or expettwa aeaoman i-&gt; tli.- .•.irrviiiii ,,n of tj»e work, but tht&gt; I,,,.-,,-,! &lt;),.., ,1,1 ,...,...;,.. inl slionld n-cei\ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">rh [Jo I should have power in make *uch rales an hIs needed in carrying on the work of the office. rimls needed in carrying on the work of the orti&lt;-&lt; of thi' present law. doubt le«8 was drawn, having Section 1 L of the preseni law. doubtless was drawn, having teaser a&gt; Glanden in horses and other very naa ases a&gt; Glanders in horses and other verv tna kgeroug diseases, but is probably uh&gt; extreme ii probably too extreme in i it might Ihh-ohic necessary to enforce ir in such sarv to enforce ir in such iie« in cattle, so it might !&gt;&lt;• well to amend it in s ahit might 1h- well to amend it in lit apply to less dangerous diseu rgently ask that Section 6 !«• amended that rh» owner c.t' an animal which musi In- destroyed can lie compelled imal which must l&gt;e destroyed can !«■ compelled e carcass of the animal so destroYmi as directed lie animal 30 destroyed as directed ■terinarian. &gt; \ion rendered by ilic State's Attorney Genera v the Stale- Attornev Genera lie says: "In our opinion it is doubtful it' the IVputv oar opinion it is doubtful it' the Depntj us the authority to enforce an order made l&gt;&gt; nfoiee an order made bv \« ! him requiring tin- owi the owner of a diseased or infected animal ti used or infested animal the carcass thereof." h. m.-elt' or to dispose of the carcass thereof." Nor do the St; • Statutes make it the duty of the Depot destroy any snob animal- or to dispose of theii the dlltv of tilt- Depim nimal- or to dispose of their i i&gt; a matter that must be remedied. h a In- reiiM'di iggesl some sucli addition as this: Any \tenot addition a- this: Any iterson owning or having in charge anv domestic animal that ban died ng in charge any domestic animal that has diei i account of disease or by accident, shall immedi ise or bv accident, shall ininiedi 11 k 11 carcass thereof in the ground, so that at leas he car in the gronn hat at least 1 1 will be over the carcass, or cause the same '• iss. or cause the sam&lt; will I med by tire, shall sell, offer to sell or give away such i si I— Im ta lv limed bv No person shall sell, offer to sell or give away such earea ih. i\ died or was killed on account of diat»mi, bcm Wilt illed on account of disease, nor a was ■ aloni; any public road or upon land not his own road or u|»&gt;n land not his own son •V tl I w« d also lecommend tliat tlie Mallein test for Glanders horaet or when the clinical symptoms are ahwciii be in expo: Vet </seg>
            
            <seg id="p007">6 providing for the State Farm work through the State I niver a&lt;-c&lt; |.ir.i m reliable ami truthworthy itn&lt;l thai when ued by the Deputy State Veterinarian and a satisfactory r*-acti«n take* place that he have the power to destroy such annual forthwith. Would also urge the same in regard to the Tuberculins tesl when used to determine the existence of Tuberculosi* in cattle In the event of a Live Stock Sanitary Board IxMtig pro - vided the appropriation for the office should he made in one amount and the expenditure of the saint' left to the discretion of the Hoard, but disbursements by vouchers audited the same as other claims by the State Auditor. For the carrying on of the work durinir the next liiennium. 1 would estimate that not Mian |S5,000.00 lx- provided. File office lnusi have the full time of an office clerk or stenographer, and be kept open at all times, as there are manv callers who are disappointed if they find the office olosad, ;i- i - necessarv under the present arrangement. In preference to the present plan of appointing veterinar - ians in practice as assistants, to receive compensation only when engaged in .state work. T would recommend that at least one or better, two assistants giving their whole time to the work be provided, it will add greatly to the usefulness and efficiency of the work. There should l&gt;e a good standard microscope provided for the use of the office, and nexvssary supplies. Fii carrying out the duties of my office during the past biennium. I have traveled by borh ! of -20.00(1 miles. itn ,| ♦,000 miles. rail over the state in the neigh by wagon road Boniethini&gt; iiki I have found that a «oo&lt;l leal of misunderstand i iii! in regard to mv office, manv c mfoundinc it witli the office of Animal Pathology at the State of t lie iiH-inhers of the la*l [*eiri Experiment Station, even la i ure having the impresriimi tlia </seg>
            <seg id="p008">I irian. The office* are distinct and entirely -i.-pararc as t'ar us an \h- and are of great assist Peters, the ahle representative "»f the Depart \niiiial Pathology, and myself, and I am glad here the State Veterinarian, in luce the needed hope* ili liiain icin his ,,ff ;l|i|&gt;ro[il Following I will give a brief account ot' the iliseases &gt;&gt;t tin -i&lt;K-k of the state, which I have lx-eii called upon to invosti pate during the | tist two vf-ar farcy, on account of the ax - and the great monetary loss rheir being deprived of the if Qlanden and Farcy among i li. u counties ol iik- state, in t ceived, l&gt;ut npoB investigation leaves onlv 23 counties of the in n 11 which h iiuc in. counties where the disease has f animals, which have died or Following are th( existed together with a nun killed in each on accoi K'inc; affected Traded Ha l(P|H.rl Off tantfar NTN Antelope Box Bnttt Boone . . 1 9 1 il ilic U-&gt;t of relations I am triad to &lt;a\ r aasistaiut and h&lt;I rect ilii- error which ha* (•landers -Farcy IKir*i and foremost, Glandei &lt;&gt;f the- same within the rt«t&lt; c owners thereof, and ;\]~&gt;&gt; i EMme, lia rsts. mill fiin jther i-niiirtk fonnd to I* </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 K ' rt R&lt;r|K&gt; Off til 1 1 il Buffalo B»rt : , Butler Cedar \~, I Cbwe &lt; Iherry 1 (.'llllc 1 CoJfax 4 Coming 1 ■ ••■ in i Dakota I tawes I tawsoii 1)ix "" 1 1 Dougia* F laiikliii i; Frontier Furnas ,; .&gt; i 1 1 le y m 4 Hauiiltoo 4. H«rf*n 14 ] lla\ es i lliichccM'k 17 Hooker Howard 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 Pah t Lincoln | Mcl'herson Madison 1 Saum 13 1 1 ■21 llt*por iz Richardson Bluff Sheridan Sherman SUnton Washing Wayne . Webster Wbeeler Y-trk were trade*! "tf 1 &gt;\ on •nan v &gt;it tln-f animals </seg>
           
            <seg id="p011">10 original owner wh prosecuted by tlic victim of the tr action ami damages recovered. In Duster county &lt;&gt;ne party wa- prot&lt;ecuted for In ( luster count y one i&gt;ai w;i- iir a quarantine established by myself, in this ease thr a i|iiaraiiiiiic established by myself, in this case three hors h. wen run nut of tin- state, tlir party pleaded guilty were run oui of the state, tlii fined $50.00. I he seven canes killed iu I&gt;"\ I &gt;iif t«- eounty were tin.-.! $50.00. I'lic seven faxes killed in Box Untie &lt;•&lt; &gt;un t \ w&lt; slii]i|ici| iniu the state from Montana by g railroad po firm aad billed to Grand Island. The shipment &lt;&gt;[' i-H tirin and hilled to (Jrand Island Rtop|ied at Alliance Seven hexd wire ile8tmyed, am Rtop|ied at Alliance. Seven In in^ re-acted I" tin- Mallt-in teal were bold under qua ran I ina re-acted to tin- Mallein te&gt;t were held under quarantine. () i-i-(|ucsi ,it' the State Veterinarian .. fColurado ilm-c Im allowed U&gt; l&gt;c taken hi (Vilitradn hihI |(Ihc*h| mi : i ran. ( owner*. I In- shows the ueed "t an itnler or |&gt;rut*lauiation owners I hi- shows tin- n&lt; mi; the importation of any horses nr other animals un mi; the importation of any horses or other animals link uniiils unless tliev are accompanied with a ceriiticaie nf health from iLe Star&lt; ■re accompanied with i certificate of health from i Veterinarian, i»r hi- ap«ents of the mate from wbenee tl Pbere arc a number &lt;it' horses under quarantiu at time, which ghoald l«- carefully watched. K&gt;|&gt; \ eierinarian. &lt;&lt;v his ggent* r&gt;f the -t ;i 1 1 ■ from whence thev com&lt; There are a number of li&lt; laianliiie at tin prestml time, which should Ik- carefully watched. rZg]iecially ilii- true oJ ih&lt;- seven head hi liiitte in Bfivd eountv, a tlii- i rue of the -even head »l liinie in IJovd count v, 8i»»l whicl are under the directi »f the (fmntv sheriff an- under the ilireeti &gt;1' ilu- cfmnty sheriff. Theae ca-e- g»vts a strong re-action in the Mallein because iliev ili&lt;l im.i show sufficient clinical lesions r stv the owners, thev i»l&gt;jecte&lt;l to the destruction of tlu 1 he annuals were directlv ml lively exi n advance)! stages of elanders ;iinl without donbi will scm.ik •i- later break down. Lei it lie understood thai glanders and farcv are one and he same disease, differing only in that the Term glanders an Kto the disease when the seal of it i- in the internal '.rgai nirs. nostrils or air tul&gt;e» and thai farcv or cutaneous irlan&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 ii [' e\t&lt; ' J'lia 1 1 V oil tile skill ot IN*' rs applies when tin 'I'l* animal in both forms, for while the &lt; »i 1 1 v l»e mi the skin, internal Hie term glanders ai risible symptoms in farcy maj esions exial tlmuirh thev mav n \h- evident .1 (Jlandi he I. ilv Cut V in it i ii nt U' immune, if this were n llcirse~ left. Some h there would lie few i Ulandera may he chronic and slow in development i&gt;r acute rauidlv fatal. 1 lie svinptoma of the disease rarv, al first rlnre may Ik' a bleeding at the n«&gt;se without apparent eaaae, a 'otigh mav or mav nut !*■ present, which mav \h&gt; mistaken for the •otiffh &lt;&gt;f heaves, sudden welling of one hind lei; mav take j^aee Modules will appear either in nostrils or on skin, as the •ase mav 1h&gt;. later on. these will form characteristic ulcers, break ind irive off a dirty, wnher colored, sticky discharge, Bometiinft* treaked Fhese ulcers ma\ heal and when thev do so leave a char aetoristic permanent star or frost-like scar, to be followed by a fresh crop of later on. In nasal glanders as a rule the sub-maxillary lymphatic glands will be found enlarged, painful at first, then they become hard, painless and more or less adherent to adjacent tissues. They rarely if ever suppurate. The animal loses condition even if on good feed, become: K'lv fatigued, as the disease advances the coat of hairbeeoaM hard and erect. itutional ilixeMe, affecting ii atnl irimir;i nitr. anil is tlul cilickili&gt; st-cill to Ik- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 A IK VKTKH1XAKIAX S A horse mav have I a) en UMlers ;ii 111..111I1S before rlic disease will manifest iis. -If. ( iiiim noi arise spontaneously bat the animal mug) have been exirfwe. ■lirectly to a bone suffering from the disease or with ili&lt; barge which ha- been de|*wit&lt; sllcll ill \ illll other horse mav ooiiie in contact with ir. I'll. miuon i'dei that other di^-ii-c- a- diKteni|ier or &lt;-;i i ;i i-i-h may r a\ ers, it nut properly treated i- ern&gt;m -. for wit rs, it not properly frea t" rli&lt;- genii of glandeni ii pan mrt iln *»; bow i" rli&lt;- ir.-rni of glandeni ii ran not ■!•• *,; however. ;i bo suffering from -n.-li above . I i-&lt; ;i~. -~ if ( .x|mmp«I tog suffering from nucli ilic more readily &lt;-.,in rae) it. Phc mattiT ni (■iiiii|».-ii&gt;iii i"ii for Imrm;* destm I lie matter ..f &lt;-,»iiii&gt;eii.sali«.ii fnr Imr.-e- &lt;le&lt;i r.ivc.l for if IT- oUrll CMHI,- H|, j|, || |V |,-;| V ,.|. ;||,,,||, ,)„. ,|;, r ,. r- ntleii ciillii ilcci.led (|ii,-sii,,i, ;,- to ili&lt;- dun- .»f tli«. -taic- in tlii&gt; I. fili " ii i- il'iH iii ivganl ro plaii.len- ulouc the gti miii it is thai It rid of the A'mw until animals arc paid for. ill, thev are often wtld. tr»,M off ,, r hi, Mm anil -.. thev arc often a- |m,ssiI,|,-. or |MMHtil ,.n from one owner to ano W ti.-w areas of int.-.i i,.i, a* t h.\ l,,t'.uv dying or \ II tin- notice .it' tbf State Veterinarian. It Notnc &lt;-,.iii|M-n~aii..ii were all..\v,-.| iluv w In .1 \v v \v. -ciici-allv mi. i |ironi|rtlv i-c|..,n,..|. Ii is M ,,i ,- „ -ciK-rallv an. I pmni|Xl.v i-i-|-. .rl« -. I . Ii is ,„,, ,- nm.-n.lr.l. |,, IU rvrr. tliat siicli iliseanetl animals be appraised a- * 1 1 n n It na hut at an actual caso ralm- inmn-.liai.-lv prior to k Init at an actual rash value imine.liatelv prior to killinc a- me animals arc practical h worthier. Km for the ben animals arc practically wort hi liui fo ih 11. ing to the general pnblie in their ilestrnriion it S( , ( - ing to the general pnblic in their destruction ii s,h-,,,&gt; the own — li*ntl*l be i i|Niisated to -• &gt;nn - degree. I be f«il«&gt;wing order was itwnwl in i-.uhh-.-i I lifi work of irlamlir- ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">1 H i tin i, 1 1 us Exist i &gt;l. ) is r \i wirl, whew with oilier tall tbev ream nnitted |\ ■■■HIM Ml which -hall have died fro mil ot il inn r Imricil (where possible on the pn Wli.-, with quick linn X in in- removed l»v ;inv animal which lias Um \ll ha\ in manp-r- r&lt; teethe r with be&lt;ldiiur, litter ami ma stall, must be careful! inieil. and when possible tht he partitions of stalls are such an mil be properly cleaned they must liken moved, wooden floors mii^i betaken out and burned, then tour ti iirhes of the dirt under it, or it' a ground Hi»&gt;r the same amount i-ti X.l.r.. M i&lt;l or highway. her shall thi illll iiiimI liv another il il- ti&gt;ll&lt;l\V» i\vi&gt;t down; the tWd I </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 if they :uc allowed to remain inuai be thoroughly wrabbed with a solution of boiling hot water, containing on* n of carMic ac-id to five parts of water, after which it si be whitewashed. m as to completely cover every par) of the ranaee, corners ami eracka The following is a good recipe for a durable whitewash Slack one-half bnahel of fresh lime with boiling water and cove. to prevent evaporation. Strain so as to lake mil all lumps of fh. lime (a piece of window netting fasten dl l.ott.,,,, •ox answers nicely), ;( . I.I .me peck of mil that lias been aiasolred in warm water, three pounds of rice Hour (if i| eaii Ik; obtained i or else wheat Hour naili* into a sun eight ounces of Spanish while, one pound of dine dissolved, im d five gallon of hot water. Mix well, pnt over the tire and stir until it reaches the boiling point. If too thick ipplv, add sufficient hot water or skim milk. Apply hot, if il cools whil, applying, reheat. Add one mince of rraboli? acid to each backet of whitewash. To prevent yellow mlor of old whitewash v an add a little bluing. •■■nip telv coverei with lime finely powdered, and r with dirt Ihe stall shonld remain \aeani where possible, for at leasi tour month All wagon poles, shaft •ckvokes Mini harness naad on »d animals must be washed with above carbolic acid nln lion, ami lmnicss I*, oiled : all lion, and harness 1k&gt; oiled : all able iitemila a- enrry nomhs, able Hleiisils a ~ currv AHnbs, brashes or cloths, aim bits imisi brashes or eloths, also hits miiRl e burned. lmrnei IIovh- thai have been expwed al all to dander* or faiw must Ik- kept in the possession of the same owner tor at least six months, or until released by the Stare Veterinarian, and if any suspicions symptoms s h a l| develop al an.v time, they must Ik.- reported at once to the State Veterinarian: or they mav be I'lie ground floor ,&gt;t' ihc xtall mi </seg>
            <seg id="p016">\ 15 M who shall rciM.n -ncli t( State Veterinariai The above rules are hereby set forth under authority grant- I to trie by Chapter 1. Article •_'. Sections 5 and 6, Compiled I AKI.F.S A. M.- KIM . but there hav* m&lt;! sheep of th« a contagious, parasetic, skin disease, imisr frequently caused by the mite known aa Paoroptes, or mav in other cases Ik- due in the Symbiotes mite, which produces what w called lail-iiiaiiirc. P These mite-. 1 i \«- &lt;&gt;u the surface i&gt;f the skiu ami by hitiug c rise in great irritation and itching. Most frequently the riles, iiitiiij; hing. Most frequentl frequently th* nve ns« sides of tin- neck and shoulders, base of the horns and at root sides of the neck and sh nil at root -if tail are the parta affected, gradually spreading over the body of tail are tin the Ivxly it irnuhtallv id from these parts, and a- ii d&lt;*&gt;s -&gt;&gt; the animal loses flesh. There will ben formation nf pimple~. exudation ami aliiuid- from tin 1'hen a 11 1 sralinji (iff of the skin, tailing! mil of hair and the formation iiiitiim &lt;if dry gray, brownish crnsta. It had become very extensively scattered over the s,iate, hi drv sjrav It ha lie slate. especially through the ranpe section, but in the eastern part of specially tin part of the state or feeding district, native cattle were not irenorallv the stale affected. Must every ease "t infection reported was in w(;steni affected. Mcist everv ca~c ..t infection n-i&gt;nrted \va- in western cattle . shipped in to feed, ur I iv native cattle placed in in tV-ed IdIs dIs, following western eattlc which had been previously the nativt herds which had been hroturhi from South Omaha or elsewhere. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 I I ti.l ii-r r\ . the federal inapt -iic certificates for cattle morn ■■tended for inhi— tale shipnieni Es erf the Bureau of Animal [■ permitted t" inspt-ct and i ■-state as well as for those i Tin-, federal inspector! also held state commissioner! i I, under which the; eould and did make inspections o ■ in feed lota, pasture, ami ,„, the range, and ordered tn. ■ nil state veterinarian- (without compensation from tin treatment of mA a- they found diseased. On account of these i-otKliriou during the Iiofthe iegialature of l!M)7-19O8 it was impossible to ■ ■ppropriatioo by whirl, this office eoold appoim state in tors to a »ist the federal inspectors in this work. (Early in tli&lt;. spring of led States rendered a dec i "f the Bureau of Anim emplate the regnlation n &lt;. and were therefore hel&lt;| •&lt;i7 'lit- snprame court of rh, "ii that the Rake and Regal* I lnhi-l rv were so drawn a- ■ i» .1 t mstaie movementa of Ii Ih- iiivali Regulations were revised with the intention of covering only the ////, liH-iii of live stoek. and them were eff I Therefore, it devolved u| heretofore been done by ie wav of preventing ..i - within our borders. m the -talc to do for itself wliai lie Bureau of Animal hid lating il tin-in oi On account of no funds being available for each «r&lt; ere onabte to appoint any state inspectors whatever, and the work Stale \ operate with the state, and permit iin to agi \eeorclingly, the Rules am v/&lt;j/&lt; control and nn O and after Apr 15. 1&lt;M&gt;7 nariari alone to attempt to do anv effective worl Honorable Secretary of Agriculture, thruugh the .1, ■ Bureau of Animal fmlnstry, Dr. A. l&gt;. M.-lvin, offer Airaill issue &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 fl tllt^ I cl I * '■ M • &lt;H i *1 i «t M ''1 I'H ell -laic would amid by appointing tors, provided, thai th liow niiicli assistance we would ...me st r(-in lor. The Honorable Secretary of Aeri&lt;'ultnre. "promising then c-ni nf -iicli a&gt;~i*tam-o by the t«p help in proportion to the ax They also insiHtod, howe lie! f &gt; in proportion to the ex Thev also insisicil. howl i r. that the Rules ami RegHla- hat the Uulcs and Regula tiona of ihc Bureau of Animal Ii he Bureau &gt;&lt;\ Animal Ii ilu-ti-y he accepted a- applying to the movemeni of &lt;t&lt;&gt;&lt;-k from | mint To |Miint within tin- state, tail- shipment. the same as if intended for inter- But, ;is we were nnwilling i n . ai-i-('|it tin- Iliii-faii re^ulatiotis we were nnwi in their entirity, it took Bevorml - between the statr ami fed* ion men whii-li were held in ,h 1 1&lt; &gt;i trli-i* time and many confer- 11*1 manv confer v •hill ral authorities, rattle ami eom- uthorities, cattle ami &lt;'oin- t^ between the i ion men whiel hinirton at lasi n l.incdln. Smith Omaha ami n Lincoln. South Omaha ami ii the followinc prooiamation he- imatioii 1m Waahington at la~i resiiltiup in has (i1 forth : NOTICE TO CATTLE OWNERS AM&gt; TRA.XSPORTA- TIOS COMPANIES ■ Hiuiin,,, of Itch. Atangt Kegi I'n I in NCI.r.. April 13th, I'.Mt iska lias been under iinarantine X,. M i 1 1 be Depntv State Veterinarian Ik- ( of the Siate of Nebraska, the Honorable Secretary of Agricnlture s Chief of the Bureau of Animal Industry, have decided I federal quarantine from tin M ii ii I'.uffal. ( I 1 ! « inc. Antelope, Knox. and all Sliei li.-S vernment, and \vluivu&gt; ii|xin f ij.-.i w Vallt-v. ( li .4' tlicv. and have omsented t. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I i KTATK VKT» UNA WAX the State of Sebraaka in th. in cattle within the state. •i »i the state lying west and nortl I the above named oounti&lt; lies in cattle ami that the rv of Agriculture, known stive in the iiiln-xht/f mm ontrol the inspection an. I iin the quarantined arm regulation of the Honorable S, m B. A. I. Order So. 143 the movement of cattle from an t' the State ,,( Nebraska Ellil I'miiilrl/. Tliat IIO cat! i markets or feeding-in-1 raska in ikm'iiIh in t h&lt; ■ ~T;u rmitted to l&gt;e ren a ransit yards within il i- for feeding or stocking pur) exeepl on certifiratex i*»ued I Animal hulnntn or of tin- I &gt;i iy the employes of the Iin ■pntv Stnti' Veterinarian : I /(// Provided Furfht 1 liai do cattle which are affente* to 1«- moved except on sjH^'ial per E scabies will be |&gt;ennifted ion to the ni.»! availabk ing, an. I in no inMaiice- dipping \at. for the pur hall they lx.' permitted r from quarantine to non-quarantine area of the state Second. \\ hen informal im •n\- p.. in named, such herds of infected or exposed cattle and premie will be at on.c iiuarantined until thev hav&lt;&gt; hom nmi»l« Ai.:. |iiaranrine.l until thev have been properly disil • supervision of the Deputy State Veterinariai ! 1111. I or an A — i-tain State N'eteriiiarian i or an inspector of rlio I! ■ I Animal Industry i. Se.-ti,,ii .".. Cliapl.r 1. Article 3, Compiled Stain l.ra-ka. I'.m»7. provide-: X. The Deputy State Veterinary Bun t Iterate with i In- utticials ..( and eradication , ( f scabic LX'.w. therefore, pamuuil to authority -.Mantel by Ohaptei Vni.-I,- 2, &lt;\, m ,,j|,-,l Statutes of Nebraska, ii is hereby red : First. Tluii ;ili nf i be ar hall lx- under qnarantin ment of cattle arc hereby adopt) </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 ATK VETKKISARIAS iicli rnlex and reenlations as to separating, modes of handling. renting, feediiur ami cart- of snch diseases ami excised animals t sn Third. All railroads, live stock transportation and stock companies and-their employees, and all other persona are hereby forbi«Wen to transport, drive, or in any way hand - tie in the State ot' Nebraska except in compliance with the fore sromg rule the Bnrean of Animal Indnstrj ii are hereby designated a- ' irve without compensation from insi&gt;eet cattle and to control the Fourth. All inspect ore of located in the State of Nebrask tant State Veterinarians, to M •he state, and are authorized to tlolis. Fifth. All previous regulations issued liv this ill partWWt f itch, manse, »eab and lice he extermination (HAS. A. M( KIM. Deputy State Veterinarian. Governor and Stat Veterinarian approval, T have hereunto sub - k- affixed the Great Seal of the X TESTIMONY of mv ■M-rilx tame and eatisei Ktf and do hereby proclaim that the above order of the Deputy te Veterinarian shall Ik- in force and effect from and after Mav 1, 1008 )()XE at Lincoln, this 1 GEO. ( '. JUNKIN Euliiig for the extern] tt It- :nv herebv revok ii. this 13th .lay of April. A. 1&gt;.. 1908. KORGE LAWSON SHELDON, Ckwtrnor. 1 ' ' It.ltll &gt; ''I » J( UlC n In- shall deem neeesaarv to prevail two elaam ol animals from eoming in contact wirh each other and perfectly isolate from other &lt;l cstic animals which have not bean exposed then- to, and which are Bnsceptible of becoming infected with the Be, and the veterinarian or hi* agents, are hereby authorized and empowered to enter npon any groondfl or prem- i-M-- (o carrv our the nn&gt;vision8 of this act. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 ( 1'cilcral Ins III *fl\ li'-Mini: ill I list nictioi mi: willi lixl .if :i | .1 ,t-4 .\ ,., | ,|ii,,. ,.,,-., W( ■i\VI Hi\V t-n In- \v i -li. 1c IllKlMftll In- Si.Mii- In Iv Ail Kim hInivi i In- i-;iiii;r wren- ili|i| III V« llli-IV Wl-l-r (HI funds U r work ih \ Wl 'II IlllWl'l-ll ill 111- "Wl bill thi-v win- urn i-.iiii|)i-I1i-i| &lt;-aiili' null-— the •■wm-r was w (iHII|M&gt;lls;ltlnll I am glatl to , a .v thai as a rule the rattle ovnen are takiiie 1 1- 'o the plan an. I arc KHopemtin* ni.-.-ly in the work. Onh few ao far have reftwed to Mde bv it, bat 1 am tryin*, bv n t- State, a|i|Mtin lllolll CollllDMISlI ;i~ A"i-i;nn State \«i&lt;i in;i i lie Stat««. ill ;lll .'lL.nl 98 n-,., Sl;|Ic Ill-lii s _ lia\ &lt;• Ut'ii ;ii :"t "lie. llli- Iii~|m-i-I \vlit&lt;-&lt; • lerritorv r In \nim;rf 4. Ill i'&lt;'i|i&gt;r;il I ll-|H'Chir. PV llll-V Wl'l ivwith iIk-c Stat*' Ins 'In owner of ili&lt;- ,-u amounts ;i- i !,| !»■ :ILll ■■ uniww in,- owner ru willing ... pav f..i- it. In some i stances men took their oumtiiioiiui* an ,\ worked without ai rin* rhp v **t\&lt; m f.iriv ,„ ,!„.,„ all ,| «i, liwill ,|,,, m </seg>
            <seg id="p022">I A V \ &gt; liirh have been owupied cleaned in tin- following love nil litttr Mini manure ruefully ;in&lt;l burn Mine, iv or saturate interior uurfaces, woodwork, tlixiring ami woodwork, flooring ami f |icu&gt;. ~lu-il&gt; ami c-liuics. fences, etc., with ■ 5 |x&gt;r cent wind i'f liens, abeds ami chutes, fences, etc., with ■ 5 |kt cent of pure carbolic a&lt;-i*l in bol water, ;i!-i.&gt; whitewash all ill in ln&gt;t water, also whitewash all rk and -c;iiici- 1 i 1 1 1&lt; - i.vit ground of yard* mnl ~ln •• 1~. van I •lic\i- with "in- nr two inure yean of careful and - wii inure vear- of earetul and aysti irk. this disease r«i he totally eradicated in the state. Itch or Mange in Horses.. li-ea-e can l&gt;c totallv eradicated in the -tatt c in Horses Itch or Main i Iwcii iv|&gt;'&gt;rtc(l fnMii ( nsitr. Knox, Dawaun, Phuretou, li.ivil an&lt;l Howard Counties, in ilu- latter County it lieeii reiiiirtcil from (nsicr. Knox, l)aw-un. I hnisi'Hi 1). \il ami Hi ssnrv i«&gt; enforce ;i quarantine and have ih&lt;- boraea, barns iii-ts thorough I \ 1 1-&lt; -«i i « -&lt; 1 and disinfected under super- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE VETKKINAKIAN Scabies in Sheep I rim ■li-.Ji^- 1 is* — |.i-aciicall.v been eliminated from the. state an. I all quarantine recnlation have heen inded. \ few liaiiril up. TnbereuJosiK in cattle has been re| H wteH from a l&gt;out SO n'U's hi tld- otfirr and j n su j )1( . f,.,, m , , e , Hint i f - | )M| ,, , |M rucdlv exintn in a great manv morp .-oiuities than thew. The raeordii which have been kepi by the Department of Animal Pathology, State Caiveraitr, will »how a ranch graater extent "t tin- infection in the statr. Aa the [^ialatiire of 1907 nude a «,wciaJ appropriation to led by the aboie .lepartment in the expwiBaaUa] investi Ration of this trouble in the state, the work has been left mostly ro them m thai 1 liave done nothini; along tliis line except to refer parties inakinjr retpiesi- n above department. examination and tests to the However, through the effort went of Animal PatholofFj of tin of flii- ..ffic- and the Depart Stale Kxjteriinent Statioa, all at the State Institution- have l^.-n tested ami in some it wta found to be rery neees-arv. Epon requeat, the Federal Government is now (-.^.[Kiratiug work of the State Experiment Station, having placed their Veterinarians at the dJapoaal of the Station, who Mting Dr. Peters the Veterinarian of the Station in the Such work being done free of Tuberculosis in animals i - ng even in advanced stage lymptoma by wJn'eh itaexjatenec an insidious diaearn, frequently i without any marked or visible in the animal « l&gt;e detected or |-'1»'i-i.'.| liiiv,- In-.ii -|MM-iiiM\ qnarantiMd ami Tuberculosis ;&lt;•-.( mg of herds in rhe -tat. ■ •liarge to flie owner. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">23 I chroo tumor* in udder or around the hoea, n r&lt;&gt; have his herd ex- ipon being slaughtered, he should at cattle, and take steps to have them in- ing all cows from which milk is sold a herd, is of vital importance in pre ind fr m the liar ervmg tin ■eaned yen K general real White Plagoe. How 1* »iii»: are Wi •.nine tlie meat and milk from 1 1. heron in ;ii' aunt iV K'ina: offered for sale by kwal butchers, many other times it occurs or how many &lt;■ furnishing us milk. and no one know- how affected da Local insiK th. : of all dairy herds, furnishing mill aniestlv and urgently recommended with my cattle entering the st with a certificate of h the taberculine test, from whence fhev con ih. showing they had been subjected t&gt; he State Veterinarian or hi&lt; agent hcmld Ix- issu Infectious Anaemia Fericious Anaemia Swamp Fever Typhoid or Malarial Fever Is a disease known l&gt;v all these name* and has Ix-en callei the unknown disease, etc., hut the canst' is now definitely dt termined to lie andnltra innt uyh hair, labored tVsh on good feed, etc hat hi&gt; li"ii&gt; have been mi &gt;&gt;t uttiiv have 1 awidently re&lt;l tuix'ivul til private slaughter lmu-t tor public conBumpi \ quarantim Met] for breeding or dairy purposes without beina; accompanied •"pic organism, and i-&lt; transmit </seg>
            <seg id="p025">.'4 I I ililc n&gt; horm, Mini.— and sages bv i nhentanooiislv. illation of blood low .&gt;r poorly drain. ind during wet [iiuvs. but has been found on higher I i~ cliiiracicri/cl l, v dullness, genera i. often the owner complains of tbe mi r tiring easily, later on the limbs or al Mne dropsical, remittent fever is preseii wnen mav swell or l« uiaeiiiia of all tUUCOli Ftbraaes, gradual emaciation in spi less over tbe loins an. I rapid pulse. •t ippetite. Te tPetechu or red qmta are Bometii ies of nose and eye, these often run : purple sjM.t to appear. t'l'reatnient of this diaeaae ha- I antiseptic*) baring given hmim ■ symptoms as they arise by the V.tei proves benefieial and most reliable relial I lie disease has existed in the Si;,t( • l'"»g '!»&lt;' Klkhorn am \ alleys, and also worn 'up Valleys, and ha ■e sections. §An appropriation was made for exp trinaent Station with this diaeaae tw., have not been rery satiafactory. •iimental work by th yean ago, but the r. ANTHRAX. I his i- ;,|s,, a gen,, disease bin I am glad to say that a I-. I'h, re were three &gt;e has been free from it for some v reports received dnrine the v or from I eoiiniy, but upon Anthrax. (ration the trouble was ii' '&lt; found to I p rev a i met line Counties. South Da which prevented any into | &gt;i\on or Cedai i quarantine order was at nee issued Hie &lt;lisc;is&lt;- ig niosrlv pivvul weakness, sf;, imal weming to Ik- \*i noticed ob the mem .vllier. panning a );,,„ ii satisfactory, intoa nic results, treatment of differ- he \ eterinariaa on the groun.l Fm » alleys, and also some in the f •&lt;l afrnat low to the nridente of (h. However Anthrax did break oal and l""ng the |&gt; : .s! fall i n Yankton and Clav «*&lt;»u H f i( -s. NVI&gt; rusks *iii&lt;l we li-i I i i . i </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Later ..n iIk di-ca-&lt; was prevalent in Fall* Iliver ("ountv, valeni in Kail- River Comity, I" Smith Dakota and Converse county, Wyoming, before notice ( intv, Wyoming, before notice w;is received &lt;•( tin- outbreak it lui.l *pn»ad into the northwest w;is received of this outbreak it had spread intn the northwest .[part of Sioux county. Prolnpi ;n 1 1 ] pnergi'tic measure* were taken however, and quarantine onler* i.-wue»l, which hail the effect of stampiiifr the disease out at once and with only the loss ..f seven head of cat - tle in thi- -title, all carcase* wire burned ami apparently the trouble is at an end. S Prompt ;i 1 1 &gt; 1 energetic measure* were taken however, and ha. I the effect of .stamping the Mid with seven head of cat tie in thi troiiMe is rued and apparently tin HI. M K-|.K&lt;;. m Hhick let; i- more or le&gt;- prevalent at all times among Bla&lt;4 revalent at all times among young cattle, hul most owners now vaccinate their -t.x-k sn voting cattle, hi M-cin.ite tin tnlly themselves. Many requests are received at this office for &gt;ts are received at this office for Slate Experiment Station. The rh the station, tree of eharjj*-. bv vaccine, but are referred to tin- State Experiment Station. The vaccine being furnished through the station, free of ckarge, bv the Bureau of Animal Indu-try at Washington, I). ( '. HAXMOKKHAOir 3EPTICBMIA. This is an acute bacterium disease. It is often mistaken Washineton, I). ( \ SF.PTICEMIA. This is an 1 1 is often mistaken for Anthrax, black-leg and malignant oedema. Outbreaks have oecured in Cedar, Cham, Dnra and Rojd for Anthrax, black-leg and malignant oedema War, Chase, Dawea and lioyd in ( counties. In the latter county there was a loss of :&gt;o hea I of latter coiinfv here was a loss of 20 hea I of cattle. i nhol&lt;lill£ a |MMt-niortem on one of the dead animal-. I can ne i»f the dead animals, I was infected in my left ton-arm and liecanie quite dangenxiitlv \ sick for several days. Horses, cattle and -wine are equally susceptible to the dis- sick for severs vs Horses, cattle and -wine art nallv susceptible to the dis- ease, which run- a rapid and fatal coarse, with sudden onset, ease, which nil high fever, rap ipid and fatal course, with sudden onset, ne and breathing, rtringy salivation, stoj&gt;- high fever, rapid pitta and breathing, stringy salivation. stoj&gt;- page of milk in cow-, visible nine. us membranes turn dark red. ,v largv, hard, painful and hoi swellings mav appear at different iml hoi swellings mav appear at different partx of the animal. Catuee seem to be due to the overflowing or Hooding of Matures or meadows, causing deposits ,,f decomposing organic alter from rich </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 Killing &lt;&gt;t affected animals ami burning •■! ihi sarcaa Ill' placing other animals -on new and higher ground and thorough eleaning np of all manure, litter, etc., and burning the same i- required L'he ground and grass where a dead animal lias laid shou 1m- burned over, affected pastures would !«■ plowed up, as the :itiii will live s» i i*l multiply in the soil. Treatment is not satis factory. N'liiiierniis reixiris of rattl iiuj suddenly in tCi ■ and fielils, have been receive been in feeding mouldv c &gt; 1 and in several cases the cans&lt; n. or over feeding young ani tin one or two eases ■ diagnosis of malignant oedema l« - made. ORN8TALK DISEASE. ISotue few pe|K&gt;rta of thi owners have learned th« trouble have been sent in, hut remove (lie can l'iils(i.\(iis PLANT I Reports «.t' hogx dying suddenly have beea reeeived fron &lt;&gt;ln and Lancaster counties, which, npon investigation \va - d to Ik- due to their eating cockel burrs. Some horses died in Perkins connty that doubtkss wen •ued by eating siiir ( . after it had become frozen tErgo( a parasitic fungua attacks the heads of rye, wild rve. s, and many other tpeeiea of grass and grain. It produces t i^ called ergotism. The ergot a- a rule is eaten in small itities at a time with the hay. producing a dry jrangrene of extremities so that one or more feet beeotac lifeless and xh off, often part of the tail or ears also tkmch off. If the ergot i^ ingested in large amounts it often product beat treatment in such eas, KKGOT hi: ERGOTIHM. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">STATK VKTKK1NAKIAN 27 1 rule reported to me. Occa - •e often through the UMfW These diseases are noi a ally a report may come in at the packing house centers than otherwise. It has been 0,1111. prevalent in certain part- at the state. In most ra&gt;es i find Swine Plague or Infectious Pneo monia to be the trouble, and not lion; Cholera. Much can tby proper care and feeding to prevent these troubles. In a few eases 1 have found it necessary to enforce tin state regulations as to burning or burying the hop dead of thi disease. I Report! have come in from Adams. Boyd, Buffalo, venue, (Mister. Cuming, Dawson. Douglas. Franklin. I 1, Ilarlan. Hooker, Ke.va Pftha, Lincoln, Maxwell, Mel rick, Nance. Pierce, Saline. Tbayer, Valley and Webster riii-.' w would not have proven to be either of these diseases The lliiivau of Animal Industry has now an anti-to tiuatol. doubtless many of abortion, thereby reducing greatly the natural increase of the M Report! of thi- trovbie have Ut-n received from Gredejr Change of bay or pasture generally stops the trouble, als.. cutting ha.v earlier in the fall. If the hay is so mfeetfld, &lt;-&lt;&gt;rn should be fed with it. Mil) PETES "K POOt ROT. This trouble \a sometime* mistaken for ergotism, but i&gt; tbv cattle having to stand in muddy places or c . One report waa received from Merriek eounty. Re- iiuning the eiiuse sto]&gt;s the trouble. BOG CHOLERA SWI.NK WLJiBV*. ■i'h.-s.- &lt;li&gt;ease&gt; are n.&gt;i as a rule reported to me. Ooc </seg>
            <seg id="p029">... ii i I eral wwrs and Ii..--. and a« ihr milk fv ne of the .-"ws h U-cn nsr.l and the mini bad liiin.llcl rnw ,,f the dead enwa ari lead i-ows u l'iiiv hands, he «a« advised togci with lii&gt; fiimilv to Chicago a take the Pasteur treatment, which he .lid and was inform them, thai the advioe piven him wa II I 'll.ll.M I \ o|; im.\ K i- \ ATT1.I 11 "-• Tliiirstuii and Wehtter. Adriee h;i- Im-.-h n- turned ;n loster, Greeley, Holt, Keith aii ion for disinfection of anima t iliHeased animals from nthe •nd premises and separation i hii&lt; ban rendered, ;il-.. n oojiy Animal Iiulustrv aeat. f cireular N'». K7, Bureau Mans ..tiler troubles ..f animals snefa i- ietino liveoni Vnmeraua mportu ni this disease have arrived from il., M-nof Brown. Bnone. 0a«, l»..,| u ,.. (; ;li ,,.. [jmcMtw, I{.K-k i-iiviiLir \",,. c,:,. Bnn-i f Animal h OXTAGIOl'S ABOKTK) Abortion affecting man* baa Ik-cm retorted in tine or iv cast* and in cows from (as,. Cuater, Greeley, Holt, Keith ai K.ya Paha oountien. fiMtrnetion for .lisinfeetion .,f ..Im. .li-riissr.l qtiwtion &lt;if ;i ,-ure aii.l |»rev&lt;titative for tin- ilise ll at |.rc&gt;ciit licwcvcr. tbeeosl of producing the toxin, mak,-^ it |&gt;rH&lt;-tical for general nae PAKALYKIfl (H ||. i,.s. Several reports .,t' hogg lo&gt;h,o ,]„. , ls ,. ,,,- ,[„.;,. | lini ] r ters havf been ivcciw,! and a.l\ i&lt;v a- m c-.-nv ami frc-atmwil li L r iM'ii. in iiii,&gt;i i-;i~,- with m, m ,,| rvmills. UAHI l&gt; ■ Hi II Ii|;ii|-||ii|;i \. Phi* tliaesMf bus Urn rc^Mtrteri fn&gt;in llamiUon, f^nu-as Paw-nce and Gap- nrHinties, bnl tlic lows of stork were sin In tin- ra-v iii Hamilton n.imtv. the &lt;«wii«i lo-r two mtilos ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p030">• Nii-i.iir StotiiHtitix nr -• ■ i"« - iiioiitli. a s Warts "ii calves ainl XLycotic Sto S. f cattle. Nnwl-ill «&gt;r l'vaemir Arthritis, ha Distemner, Irregular Distemper, Influenza. Chronic ( rinir.i Heniorrlweim, Kiviiii-ina M Ma IK'tiUIllCffll. have Ix-cn -iiit in. in "in- liistam iii Perkins ooiiBty, 50 head &lt;&gt;t' cattle &lt;li«-&lt;l. sample* of m11 found in ilic feed lots were sent to the office ;m&lt;l -trvclmine was foim i ots wen- sent to the f»ffi«' and strvchniue waa foun i freelv mixed witli it. In other reports from Caas, Plata an.l freelv mixed with it. In other iworta from Cms, Platte an-1 Sheridan counties positive pr&gt;«&gt;t' nt' j«&lt; &gt;i-;&lt;&gt;ii being present could Sheridan counties noeitivr proof nf |&gt;&lt; &gt;i~&lt;m being present could in. i he found. FINANCIAL REP0R1 Balance of Appropriation 1905 Unexpended !)*'&lt;•. I. Hmm'&gt;. FINANCIAL REP0R1 Balance of Appropriation 190.5 Sahiry of Deputy &gt;-1 ' Bxpennes JJJJ sr.it vox Amount Bzpended Dec. 1. l«m to April 1. li»7. 'HH'. to April 1. LH07 Siil;ir.v Deputy s:,(hi. ( hi K.xpeiiscs Ija])St'(l JJ^ Dellciency Claims Bill H. R. N.&gt;. :»»4, l»07. April 12, I'.toT. Dr. .). .1. Drasky s 1- ■-•'' C. A. McK'im '■•- ■•"''■' ('. A. McKiin C. A. McKiin I"' * C. A. McKim 1" " : • .]. .1. Urasky "-""• April \-l, HH»7. Dr. .). .1. Drasky s 1- c. A. McKim '■•- ■•"'''' C. A. McKim C. A. McKim ' : ' *' C. A. McKim 1T ~ :; c A MrKim </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 STATK VKTKRINAHIAX Office Stiite Veterinarian April 17. L907, Gillespie &amp; Phillips $23.00 15.00 Dr M. T. Bernard Dr. .1. E. Severn Dr. J. E. Severn Dr. E. F. Stewart Dr. K. F. Stewart Dr. J. E. Severn 5.00 H.90 4.00 5.00 5.00 Dr W. H. Cole 15.00 45.27 H).(K) Dr. C. A. McKim Dairyman Pub. Co. Dr. .las. ('. If yen 3.78 Dr .las. C. Myers 10.00 Dr. W. H. Cole 4.5:i Dr. J. E. Severn 4.00 El 24, 1*17, Dr. E. K. Stewart 6, 1907, Dr. C. A. McKim o. 1907. Smith Premier Typo Co. io.oo 33. 18 95. (XI $294.«1 Balance lapsed May :»0. 1907 5.39 $300.00 Saoo.on Claims Bill H. K No. 53H. April 12, 1907. Dr. W. D. Hammond Dr. G. R. Young Amount Appropriation, 1907. Salary Deputy sW.OOU.OO Assistants 400.1K. Stenographer Expenses 840.00 3,120.00 |7,8fi0.&lt;10 Total Amount Expended April T Salary for Deputy 1907 to Nov 80, 190K $•2,500.1X1 Assistants {(!.-).( hi Stenographer Expenst Total Expened 880.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">31 Salary Deputy s :.oo.ou Assistants :ir&gt;.&lt;M&gt; Stenographer K.xpenses •J10.(M) 449.06 Total </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>