<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00014">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00014</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA</title>
			            <date value="1903">1903</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p002">
LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, 


AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

OF 

NEBRASKA 

THE GOVERNING BOARD 

(tMI KQEHTfl O9 TW UMIVKNSITt) 

¦ F. KBNOWEB, President, "Wianer 
FORELL, Kearney 

EDSON C. RICH. Omaha 
JOHN L. TEETERS, Lincoln 
E. C. CALKINS, Kearney 
C. J. ERNST, Lincoln 

THE STATION OFFICERS 

E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director and Animal Husbandman 
T. L. LYON, B. 8. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist 
J. 8. DALES, H. PH., Financial Secretary 

WX. W. MARSHtT.T. Executive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

¦Peters, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist 
s&amp; E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist 

S. Avert, Ph. D., Chemist 

A. L. Haecker. B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman 
Lawrence Bruner. B. Sc., Entomologist 
Erwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geologist 
R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist 
O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer 
G. D. Swezey, M. A., Meteorologist 

K Smith, B. Sc., Associate Animal Husbandman 
Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist 
Pejun Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
BT B. A. EMERSON. 

INTRODUCTION. 

RIARD CULTIVATION OFTEN NEGLECTED. While it WOUld 
cult to suggest a method of orchard culture not on 
Nebraska, yet in many cases little or no cultivation 
of any sort is practiced. In some instances the orchards 
stand in a close sod of blue grass, pastured by young stock, 
or in a sod of timothy and clover regularly mowed for hay. 
Comparatively few orchards in the state are maintained 
under clean cultivation. It certainly seems reasonable to 
expect our deep, rich prairie, soil to be able not only to sapport 
an orchard almost indefinitely, but also to furnish, at 
the same time, such additional plant food as may be required 
by whatever grass or grain can find room to grow 
between the trees. 

Clean cultivation, a question of moisture. — The leading 
fruit growers of Nebraska, however, learned long ago 
that the conservation of moisture is our main orchard problem, 
and that in our rich prairie soils the question of plant 
food is of secondary importance. In eastern Nebraska, 
where abundant rains usually fall in early summer, fair 
results have been secured by maintaining old orchards in 
sod. Farther west in the state this method is out of the 
question. Even in eastern Nebraska the best orchards wer*given 
thorough cultivation while young, and are by no 
means neglected after having come into bearing. The one 
idea that has been most clearly and forcibly brought out 
at almost every session of the Nebraska State Horticultural 
Society is that careful cultivation for the conservation of 
soil moisture is an essential part of orchard treatment. A 
few dry summers are enough to convince most fruit growers 
that trees need more moisture than they are likely to </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 

Exptrhmtntt in Orchard Culture. 

IIVATION VKHSIS NEGLECT INJUN WRING WIXTKU. — 
Tlic unusually severe winter of 1898-99, which resulted in 
the destruction of so many orchard and nursery trees 
throughout the northwest, led many western fruit growers 
to question whether the accepted ideas of orchard culture 
did not need revising. From many parts of Nebraska and 
adjoining states, accounts came of neglected orchards that 
had almost entirely escaped injury, while neighboring orchards 
that were carefully cultivated were badly damaged 
by the severe cold. In some cases the freedom of neglected 
orchards from winter injury was ascribed to the protection 
afforded the tree roots by the mulch of grass and weeds. 
In other cases it was attributed to the early maturity of 
trees in the dry soils of uncultivated orchards. The fact 
that winter injury was more pronounced in cultivated orchards 
than in neglected ones led some orchardists to question 
the advisability of cultivating their trees at all. 

Tests at the Nebraska experiment station. — To help 
in the solution of questions of this sort, a number of experiments 
have been undertaken by the Agricultural Experiment 
Station. These tests have been in progress for the 
past three years, and it is believed that enough information 
of real value has been obtained from them to warrant publication 
at this time, although of course the experiments 
Konly fairly under way and should be continued for some 
b to come. 1 

A&lt; knowledgments. — In carrying out the experiments 
here described, the writer has been materially assisted by 
Mr. 0. G. Marshall, who has made many of the records and 
aided in computing the results. The Departments of Chemistry 
and Agriculture have kindly made most of the determinations 
of the soil moisture of the various orchard plats. 
The writer also wishes to acknowledge his indebtedness to 
the officers and members of the Nebraska State Horticultural 
Society, who have added much to the value of the 
experiments here reported by their friendly suggestions and 
criticisms. 

ducted at this Experiment Station during 1894-95, and reported in Bulletin 39, </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

5 

Experiment I 

EFFECT OF VARIOUS METHODS OF CULTURE ON MOISTURE 
CONTENT OF ORCHARD SOILS AND ON THE GROWTH 
OF YOUNG ORCHARD TREES. 

PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT. 

The orchard site and plats. — This experiment was 
gun in 1901. In the spring of that year an orchard of about 
six acres was set at the Experiment Station. It conof 
eight plats, each twenty-one rods long east and west liy 
six rods wide north and south. These lie side by side, making 
the orchard forty-eight rods long north and south by 
twenty-one rods wide east and west. The soil of all the 
plats is a fairly uniform upland loam. The land slopes 
gently to the northeast, except in the case of the south plat. 
one end of which slopes slightly to the southwest. The 
north plats are, therefore, on slightly lower land than the 
south ones, and appear to have a slight natural advantage 
over the latter in regard to the rapidity of tree growth. On 
the whole, the site is sufficiently uniform throughout for 
purposes of the test. The orchard is protected on the west 
Kd north by an osage hedge about twelve feet high and 
out three rods from the nearest orchard trees. 

R Varieties of trees planted. — All plats contain the same 
imber and kinds of trees, arranged in the same order. 
The varieties of trees planted and the number of each variety 
in each plat are : 

Apples — 12 Ben Davis, 6 Oldenburg, 6 Jonathan, 6 Wagner. 


Cherries — 1 Early Richmond, 4 Montmorency, 4 Windsor. 

Peaches — i Russell, 3 Wright, 3 Wager. 

Pears — 4 Keiffer, 3 Bartlett, 3 Flemish Beauty. 

Plums — 4 Wild Goose, 4 Forest Garden, 3 Abundance, 3 
Lombard. 

tOf the 608 trees in the orchard, there are, therefore. 240 
?pies, 96 cherries, 80 peaches, 80 pears, and 112 plums. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 

Experiments in Orchard Culture 

each plat containing 76 trees. A number of trees died the 
first year and were replaced in the spring of 1902. 

Treatment of the various plats. — During the two 
ywirs that the experiment has been in progress the various 
plats have been treated as. follows, the plats being numbered 
from north to south : 

Rat 1. This plat was cropped with watermelons in 1901 
with bush beans and turnips in 1902. These crops were 
a very thorough cultivation and occasionally hoed, no 
weeds being allowed to grow during the growing season of 
the secondary crops. The ground was not plowed in the 
spring of 1902, being merely stirred deeply with a disk as 
soon as thawed. 

Plat 2. This plat was treated exactly like Plat 1, except 
that pole beans were grown instead of bush beans in 1902. 

Pat 3. A crop of corn was grown in this plat both sea- 
The distance between the corn and tree rows was 
same as between the corn rows. The corn was given 
clean cultivation during the usual season. The stalks were 
left standing during winter to catch the snow. Soon after 
the frost ,was out of the ground in the spring of 1901, the 
stalks were broken down and cut up by a disk, followed 
by a common harrow, which also stirred the surface soil and 
helped conserve soil moisture. After the second cultivation, 
the ground was plowed six to eight inches deep, most 
of the stalks being turned under. The plat was then disked 
and harrowed frequently until corn-planting time. 

Plat 4. The trees here were given thorough, clean cultivation 
with disk and harrow throughout the summers of 1901 
and 1902. During the very dry season of 1901, the ground 
was disked at least once every two weeks from the time the 
trees were planted until well into October. The surface soil 
was stirred as soon as possible after every rain, to break the 
crust. Scarcely a weed was allowed to show above the surface 
at any time during the season. In 1902 the disk and 
harrow were started about the middle of March and run 
over the ground at frequent intervals until about the middle 
of October. Cultivation was not so regular as in 1901, owing 
to the very wet weather. Weeds occasionally became quite 
Mr J </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
7 

with disk and harrow. During fall scarcely a weed could 
be found in the whole plat. 

Plat 5. The plat was cropped "with oats both seasons. The 
seed was sown at the usual time in spring with a press drill, 
run as close as possible to the tree rows, leaving unseeded 
strips only a few feet wide in tree rows. In 1901, the ground 
about each tree was hoed once or twice. In 1902, the unsown 
strips were cultivated a few times with a Me-hone 
cultivator. The oats were mowed and removed from the 
field when ripe. In the fall of 1902 rains prevented harvesting 
and caused a heavy second growth. The stubble was left 
standing during fall and winter of both seasons and the 
ground plowed in the spring of 1902, like the corn ground in 
Plat 3, and worked down with disk and harrow before resowing. 


Plat 6. The plat was cultivated exactly like Plat 4 during 
the early part of both, summers. Cultivation was discontinued 
about the middle of July and a cover-crop 1 of millet 
sown. No further treatment was given during either fall. 
The cover-crop was left standing during winter to hold the 
snow. In the spring of 1902, cultivation was begun at the 
same time as in other plats. The cover-crop was worked 
into the soil with a disk, the ground not being plowed. 

Plat 7. The treatment given this plat was the same as 
that given Plat 6, except that oats were grown for a covercrop 
and that the cover was plowed under in the spring of 
1902, being found too heavy to be worked into the soil with 
a disk. 

I Plat 8. The treatment of this plat was identical with 
it given Plats 6 and 7 during the early part of both seans. 
Cultivation was discontinued a couple of weeks earlier 
than in the latter plats, and a cover-crop of weeds allowed 
to grow. The wet weather of 1902 caused such vigorous 
weed growth that the cover-crop was mowed early in 
August, making little further growth. In the spring of 
1902 the cover-crop was disked into the soil, as in Plat 6. 

'The term "cover-crop" is often misunderstood. A"crop" is usually something 
that yields a return on being harvested. An orchard "cover-crop," however, 
is grown solely for the benefit of the trees. Some of the ways in which 
orchard trees derive benefit from cover-crops are brought out later in this bul- </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 

Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

1'lai !i. I'.. -sides the eight orchard plats already described, 
a ninth plat, consist ing of only a few square rods of ground 
and containing no trees, adjoined the orchard on the south- 
This was sown to rye early in the fall of 1900. The 
rye m allowed to grow to maturity in 1901 in order to 
allow i lie effect on soil moisture to be noted. 

MUMS. — The percentages of soil moisture at the depth 
&lt;pf six to nine inches in the different plats were determined 
i.ii times each season. All the liBU were measured 
I after setting, and also after the close of each season's 
growth. The measurements included, in all cases, the diameters 
of the trunks, and in some cases the height of trees 
and spread of branches. Records have also been kept of 
the depth of snow in the various plats, the depth of freezing 
of the ground, the relative amount of washing from 
rains or melted snow, and, in short, of everything that it 
was deemed Might be of use in determining the relative 
merits of the different methods of culture. 

RESULTS OF THK EXPERIMENT. 

BOO. moisture. — To avoid confusion, the results from the 
tw&lt;0 vegetable plats. No* 1 and 2, have been averaged, which 
will in no way detract from the value of the results, since 
the two plats have received practically the same treatment 
and have given almost identical results. Of the three cover 
crop plats. Mo. 7, millet, has been chosen as representing the 
l*est type of cover-crop. The differences observed between 
this and the other two cover-crop plats will be presented in 
a later bulletin on cover crops. 

E percentages of moisture found in these five plats at 
i times during the two years are shown graphically 
accompanying chart (fig. 1), which also shows the 
1 when it equaled or exceeded one fourth inch. 

E A he vegetables dried the soil but little more than clean 
tivation. In neither case did the per cent of moisture bele 
dangerously tow, even during the protracted drought of 
1901, when only a little over seven inches of rain fell during 
the four months from May to August inclusive. The crop of 
rve dried the ground much more than anv other method, of </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
Pig. 1. — Per cents of soil moisture in orchard plats and inches of rainfall during 
summers of 1901 and 1902. The dots show dates of making moisture determinations 
and exact per cents of moisture found, the curved lines indicating 
probable fluctuations in moisture between these dates. The vertical bars show 
dates and amounts of rainfall 

flPUt 1 May june ; July ! ausu*t ; icPTtMMA; ocroac* I 
Fir-fl r li i i. 1 lih r 

I APRIL 
IS* 

MAY 

- J- - 

"77n1 ! 3jTTy ; *u«u&gt;t ; scprimca. ictihi 
•¦ "!: :---—- -----mi 

r- 

hi 

L... 

• A 

£Ss 

. 

r 

• I </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 

Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

culture tried. Not only was the rye ground somewhat drier, 
but it became dry earlier, and moreover, since no rains occurred 
to thoroughly moisten the ground after it had once 
become dry, the rye plat remained dry nearly a month 
loager than any of the other plats. Next to rye, the oat 
crop dried the soil most seriously during the dry season of 
1901, though it did not make the soil much drier than corn 
or cover-crops. Its effect, however, was noticeable much 
earlier in summer and lasted much longer. By the middle 
of July, when the corn plat was becoming dry, many trees 
have completed their greatest length growth and do not need 
so large a supply of moisture as they do earlier in the season. 
Furthermore, the ground of all plats was thoroughly 
moistened by the unusually heavy rains of late September 
and early October. The corn plat was very dry, therefore 
only about half as long as the oats plat The important 
difference between the cover-crop and the corn, just as between 
the corn and the oats, is that the soil in the cover-crop 
plat did not become dry for a week or two after the com 
ground had become dry. 

The great difference, as regards soil moisture, between 
the clean cultivation on the one hand and the rye and oats 
on the other is fully appreciated only when it is remembered 
that many plants established in common loam soil often 
wilt, or even die, when the soil still contains 8 per cent or 
10 per cent of moisture; or, in other words, that only the 
moisture in excess of 8 per cent or 10 per cent is available 
to plants. In June, 1901, the clean cultivation plat contained 
only a little over one half more absolute moisture 
than the oats plat Of the moisture available to tender 
plants, however, there was from two to three times as much 
in the clean cultivation plat as in the oats plat. 

In 1902, the plats did not vary greatly as regards soil 
moisture. Naturally, no method of culture dried the ground 
seriously at any time during this very wet season, when over 
twenty-eight inches of rain fell during the four months from 
May to August inclusive, or about four times as much as 
fell during the same months of the preceding year. 

During midsummer all the plats contained from 22 per </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
11 

after about three weeks of dry weather, the corn plat had 
about 18 per cent of moisture, and the oats, vegetables, and 
cover-crop plats somewhat less than 19 per cent. The clean 
cultivation plat at no time after April had much less than 
21 per cent of soil moisture. 

An important difference between the plats with respect 
to the absorption of water in heavy rains is shown in the 
chart for 1902. Just after periods of heavy rainfall the 
cover-crop and oats plats were almost invariably wetter than 
the others. The vegetation of these plats apparently held 
the water until it had time to soak into the soil, while there 
was little to prevent rapid surface drainage in the wellcultivated 
vegetables, corn, and clean cultivation plats. So 
far as average conditions are concerned, however, the 
greater ability of the oats and cover-crop plats to absorb 
water during heavy rains was counterbalanced by their more 
rapid loss of water during periods of little or no rain. The 
chief value of these crops, in rainy seasons, lies in their preventing 
too rapid surface drainage with the erosion which 
usually accompanies it in all but level sites. The ground 
of the clean cultivation plat was eroded considerably the 
past summer, in spite of the fact that it was rarely cultivated 
in the direction of the greatest slope. In the corn 
and vegetable plats, erosion, though less troublesome than 
in the cultivated plat, was still quite noticeable. In the oata 
and cover-crop plate almost no washing away of soil was 
seen during the time that they were covered with vegetation. 

Trees killed by dhought. — The great differences in soil 
moisture just described were not without corresponding effects 
on the young trees growing in the various plate. The 
following table shows the number of trees of each kind set 
in each plat, the number that died during the summer of 
1901, and the per cent of dead trees: </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 


Table I. — Effect of various methods of culture on drought-killing of 

young in 

Apple Cherry Peach Pear Plum Total 
trets trees trees trees trees trees 

rl number killed by drought are shown iu Ike accompanychart. 
(Fiji. 2.)' 

O PLATS land 2. 

VEGETABLES 

Fig. 2. — The shaded parts of the horizontal bars indicate the number of live 
trees ami the unshaded parts the number of dead trees in the different orchard 
plats at the end of the first year. 

The dean record of the cultivation plat certainly shows 
the value of thorough cultivation in keeping newly set trees 
alive daring very drv seasons. The excellent results obtained 
are to be ascribed to nothing but the effect of repeated 
thorough cultivation in keeping the soil moist 

j^ 

I Method of .'SS-S^MJ'S'JM «' ! « 
culture. S5-S^S = 'S?-S?^ Uk\ « 
E = = H ¦ = E » E B = 5 » 
zzti.zz:«zzs«zZ:a.zza,zzs 
rmelon crop 30 2 12 1 9 10 0 0 10 0 l'u 1 7 76 4 C d 
nnelon crop W 2 12 2 17&gt;O 0 0 10 2 20 H 0 0 76 6 70 
crop 30 2 13 1 j in -J 20 '" - 02 U 0 0 70 7 q'q 
i cultivation 30 1 12 (I g 10 0 (j 10 1 10 11 0 0 76 'J 3 G 
crop :*.) 14 4 12 t; 50 in 8 80 io «; 60 14 5 36 ?•&gt; «»5i'3 
¦-crop— millet ... 30 41312 21710 110"' -20'* 0 $16 9118 
--crop— oats 30 4 1312 4 3310 (I 01° 1101' 1 7|7« l«t j"l 
¦-crop— weeds ... '«l 7 9312 OHIO 0 0 1" n fi 12 2 14 76151]) 

_i i i i i i i i i i i i i ' i| t i i i 

The total Bomber of trees planted on each plat ami the </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

13 

what less favored than the clean cultivation plat, as might 
have been predicted from the moisture chart. (Pig. L) 
That the records of the cover-crop and corn plats are not 
quite so good as the clean cultivation plat is not strange. 
remembering how greatly these crops dried the soil. The 
extremely high percentage of dead trees in the oats plat 
is to be accounted for by the early and long-continued dryness 
of the soil of that plat rather than by the degree of 
dryness. It is very probable that no such disastrous results 
would have followed if the season of 1901 had been 
dry or if the trees had ben set the year before and bad 
become better established before the very dry season rame. 

Had rye been used instead of oats in the orchard plat. 
the chances are that all the trees instead of half of them 
would have been replaced the next spring. Even old, fairlyvigorous 
trees are sometimes killed by betas; cropped with 
rye. In Lincoln near the Experiment Station are many old 
apple trees. Since the land was divided into building lots. 
the individual owners or renters have given a gnat, diversity 
of treatment to the remaining trees. In one case the 
trees on a few lots were fairly uniform in health and vigor 
up to the spring of 1901. That summer a crop of rye was 
allowed to mature on about half of this ground, while oa 
the remainder a crop of cane was grown. The early and 
long-continued dryuess of the soil where the rye grew lmrt 
the trees badly, but none, or at least only a few of them. 
died that summer. The cane, of course, also dried the 
ground upon which it grew, but the drought was felt later 
and was of shorter duration. The early spring of 1902 was 
very dry. This, combined with the early drying effect of 
the rye crop, was more than the trees could stand. The 
abundant rains of June came too late to save the trees, which 
consequently presented the peculiar spectacle of dying from 
drought during one of the wettest seasons on record. ( See 
fig. 3.) The adjoining trees on the cane ground, while damaged 
more or less by droughty are still alive. 

Disasters as great as those just described may not occur 
again for several years as the result of growing oats or rye 
in orchards in eastern Nebraska. On the other hand, the </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 


year. No one can tell at planting time whether the summer 
will be wet or dry, and yet almost every spring orchard 
trees, and other kinds of trees as well, are set by hopeful 
but uninformed men, who later wonder why their trees die 
while the small grain is growing so well on the same ground. 
They usually come to the conclusion that this state is not 
adapted to fruit growing or that the nurseryman sold them 
poor trees. It would be quite as reasonable to blame the 
seedsman for selling them the seed oats or rye that killed the 
trees! 

Fig. 3. — Old apple trees dying from drought during one of the wettest sea 
sons on record — the result of continuous cropping with rye. 

Tree growth in the various plats. — After the completion 
of growth in both 1901 and 1902, the trunk diameters 
of all the trees were measured. The average sizes of the iree 
trunks in all plats for each kind of tree after the first and 
again after the second year's growth are given in the table 
below. In a few cases where a relatively large proportion 
of the rapidly growing kinds survived the drought of 1901, 
the 3.v£1*c1iigs obt*ii ncd from the supvivinfr j-rppti „« 1ot»ctot» </seg>


            <seg id="p015">
15 

than they would have been had all varieties lived. In other 
cases, where the slowest growing varieties alone survived, 
the averages were likewise lower than they would otherwise 
have been. The averages in these cases have, therefore, been 
corrected to make them comparable with the plats in which 
few or no trees died, the correction factor being obtained by 
finding the relative rapidity of growth of the various sorts 
of trees in the plats where few died. 

Table II.— Diameters of tree trunks in sixteenths of an inch for various 
orchard plats. 

i 

Method 
of 

Apple. 

Cherry. Peach. 

P&lt; 

:ar. 

Plum. 

Average. 

culture. 1901 1902 igol lg02 1901 1902 1901 
1 Vegetable crop 9.8 15.8 9.520.8 11.129.9 9.9 
2 Vegetable crop 9 8 16.1 9.4 20.4 1-2.231.1 9.1 
3 Corn crop ».O 15.U 9.117.5 9.6 22.1 9.1 
4 Clean cultiva- 
tion 9.6 16.2 9.520.6 10.8 29.9 9.7 
5Oatscrop 9.0 13.7 8.015.3 8.321.2 8.7 
6 Cove r-crop — 
millet 9.3 15.6 9.219.2 10.325.7 9.3 
7 Cover -crop — 
oats 9.5 15.4 8.618.5 10.9 26.9 9.0 
8 Cover-crop — 
I weeds. 9.6 15.3 8.819.110.125.8 9.6 

1902 

16.8 
16.1 
14.4 

1901 

11.2 
11.0 
9.5 

1902 

19.9 
20.2 
16.0 

10.2 19 5 
9.5 17.8 

[16.6 
14.3 

io. el 
9.21 

Il9.5 
114.4 

17.2 

9.8 

16.1 

13.7 

10.8 

17.5 

9.7 17.S 
9 7 17.9 

Il5.3 

10. 3I 

¦18.4 

rt the end of the second year in the orchard the height of 
trees and the breadths of their tops were determined, 
se records, corrected as in case of the diameter records, 
summarized in the following table: 

Table III.— Height and breadth 0/ trees 0/ orchard plats, in feet. 

Apple. 

Cherry. 

Pe 

ich. 

Pear. 

Plum. 

Method of culture. 

I Vegetables 
Vegetables 
Corn 
4 Clean cultivation 
5 O»ts 
6 CoTer-crop— millet 
7 Corer-crop— oats 
8 Corer-crop— weeds 

— -3 
•2f a 
« S 
s « 
5.52.8 
5.62.6 
5.52.5 
5. 7^.7 
4.51.8 
5. IS. 4 
5.02.3 
5.SS.3 

.a 
= 

5.1 
5.7 
4.6 
5.2 
3.8 
4.7 
3.9 
4.7 

1 

I— 

2.9 
2.7 
2.5 
2.3 
1.7 
2.6 
2.3 
S.6 

I 
a 

6.5 
6.7 
6.4 
6.3 

1 

5.2 
5.5 
3.8 
5.0 

i 1 II 
¦5 g C g 
B « 3 « 
6.12.37.13.7 
5.72.17.23.5I 
5.92.25.82.8 
6.11.96.83.0 
5. 11. 35. OS. 3 
5.72.16.02.7 
4.91.68.03.0; 
5. SI. 68. 52.0 

.1*1 
5 

H 

I 

I 

¦1 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 

Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

The average diameters of all trees in each plat are shown 
in fig. 4, and the heights and breadths of the trees in fig. 5. 

Kt is worthy of note that the oats plat makes the poorest 
\vin&lt;; in regard to height, spread of branches, and diamof 
trunks. The effect of the oats in retarding growth. 

O PLWTS I ond 2. 

10.2 VEGETABLES i|4 

Fig. 4. — Diameters of tree trunks, in sixteenths of an inch, at the end of the 
first year, indicated by shaded parts of horizontal bars, and at end of second 
year by full length of bars. 

Fig. 5. — Height of trees, in feet, indicated by full length of bars, and spread 
of branches by shaded parts of bars. 

though very noticeable, is not so great as its effect on the 
life of the trees the first year after planting (see fig. S). 
The corn plat is next poorest as regards size of tree trunks 
at the end of both the first and second years, the cover-crop 
trees having noticeably larger trunks. In breadth of top, </seg>


            <seg id="p017">
17 

however, the trees of the cover-crop plat exceed only slightly 
those in corn, and in height the trees of the corn plat are 
slightly ahead of the cover-crop trees. The shade of the 
cornstalks may cause the trees to grow in height at the expense 
of breadth of top and trunk diaawter. This tendency, 
so far as it goes, is certainly bad, since low. stocky trees are 
best suited to our climatic conditions. If the corn rows 
had been kept farther away from the tree rows, so that the 
tall stalks would not have shaded the tree tops, the observed 
effect on tree growth would probably not have been noticed. 
The vegetable and clean cultivation plats are ahead of all 
others in regard to size of trees. In size of trunks at the 
end of the first year the vegetable plat was slightly ahead 
of the clean cultivation plat, but at the end of the second 
year there was no difference between the plats. The trees 
in vegetable plats are slightly taller than those given clean 
cultivation and have noticeably broader tops. This slight 
difference may be due to the fact of the land^ sloping slightly 
to the north, the vegetable plats being, therefore, lower than 
the clean cultivation plat. 

Considering all these things — drought killing, height, 
breadth of top, and diameter of trunk — the vegetable and 
clean cultivation plats rank tirst, the former being slightly 
ahead of the latter. The next in rank are the cover crop 
and corn plats, the former being very slightly ahead of the 
latter. The oats plat naturally ranks lowest, much lower 
than the corn and cover crop plats. 

2 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 

Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

Experiment II. 

rCT OF COVER-CROPS ON FALL DEVELOPMENT AND WINTER 
INJURY OF YOUNG PEACH TREES. 

PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT. 

t Situation op the trees. — In the spring of 1901, 48 peach 
*s, all of the Wager variety, were set to test the effect of 
cover-crops on winterkilling of the trees. One half the 
trees were set on moderately rich upland loam, sloping 
slightly toward the north, protected by a windbreak on the 
south and east — on the whole a good site for a peach orchard. 
The other half of the trees was set on rich, welldrained 
bottom land, protected on all sides by windbreaks. 
This situation would certainly never be chosen by well-informed 
peach growers as a proper site for a peach orchard, 
since peach trees in this region often winterkill on low 
ground. The two sites were selected with the idea that if 
the following winters should prove mild, the different methods 
of treatment to be used might give results on the low 
land, and if the winters should prove extremely severe, killing 
all the trees on the bottom land, those on the upland 
might still show differences in winter injury due to differences 
in treatment. 

Treatment of the plats in 1901. — Both blocks of trees 
were given clean cultivation from the time the trees were 
set until midsummer. Notwithstanding the fact that the 
season was unusually dry, the thorough cultivation kept the 
soil moist and the trees in good condition. Those on the 
high land made fair growth, though of course not so good a 
growth as would have been expected in a more favorable 
season. The trees on the low land grew vigorously, no more 
vigorously, however, than trees on upland situations usually 
grow during seasons of abundant moisture. All the trees in 
each block were quite uniform in size and vigor. 

On July 13, both the lowland and upland blocks of trees </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

19 

of each block oats was sown as a cover-crop and in a second 
plat millet was similarly sown. At the time of sowing these 
cover-crops, the surface soil was very dry, but being sown 
with a press drill, which penetrated the dust blanket to the 
moist ground below, they began growth with fair promptness. 
Their growth throughout the fall was good, considering 
the unusual drought prevailing at the time. In the remaining 
plat of each block of trees, cultivation was continued 
throughout the summer, the last cultivation being 
given in October. 

RESULTS OF THE TEST OF 1901. 

Ripening of the summer's growth. — The trees in the 
upland block stopped growing early in fall, and their wood 
matured well before cold weather. No great difference was 
noticed between the trees that were cultivated and those in 
the cover-crop plats. In the block of trees on the bottom 
land, however, striking differences were seen between the 
different plats. The trees in the cover-crop plats practically 
stopped growing by the middle of August, only a month 
after the cover-crops were sown, and began to mature their 
wood. The trees in the plat given late cultivation continued 
growth much later. The cultivated trees had matured their 
wood and formed their terminal buds no more perfectly by 
the middle of October than the cover-crop trees had by the 
middle of August. Unfortunately, no photographs were secured 
showing this difference. Similar differences were seen 
in the fall of 1902, however, and are illustrated in fig. 8. 
By the first or middle of November, 1901, little difference 
could be seen between the trees of the cultivated plat and 
those in the cover-crops, so far as maturity of the season's 
growth of wood was concerned. The wood of all trees 
seemed well ripened and ready for winter. The trees of the 
cultivated plat were considerably larger, as a whole, than 
those of the oats and millet plats. 

Winterkilling. — At the time growth started in the spring 
of 1902 the differences between the trees of the various plats 
on the low ground were even more striking than they were 
in late August and through September of the previous fall. </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 


of many of the trees of the bottom land block was winter 
EL The inner bark and wood of the twigs were badly 
red, being quite brown, even where there was little 
(1 sign of injury. The discoloration seemed at that 

Fifj. 6 — Winter-injured peach trees. No. 1, best tree, and No. 2, poorest tree, 
on millet cover-crop plat; No. 3, best tree, and No. I, poorest tree, on clean. </seg>


            <seg id="p021">
21 

time somewhat greater in case of the trees that had been 
cultivated late in fall than in case of those in the cover-crop 
plats. Considerable discoloration, however, was found in 
twigs of all tm&gt;s. On April 21, when the trees were coining 
into leaf, it was found that one half of the trees on the late 
cultivation plat were apparently dead and the remaining 
half badly injured, while in the cover-crop plats about half 
the trees were badly injured and the other half were practically 
unhurt, not a single tree being dead. On Maj 17. 
after the trees had made considerable growth, two reave- 
Pe trees of the late cultivation plat and two from the 
lat were photographed, the least and worst injured 
ing selected in both cases. These photographs are 
ced in fig. 6. The number of uninjured, badly 
and dead trees in the different plats is shown in 

B 

Eg. 7. — Relation of cover-crops to winterkilling of young peach trees, 
iber of dead trees (like No. 4. fig. 6) indicated by unshaded Darts of horiil 
bars, badly injured trees ( like Nos. 2 and 3) by lightly shaded parts, and 
jured trees (like No. 1 ) by heavily shaded parts. 

The injured trees in all plats were pruned back to live 
wood and given clean cultivation until midsummer. All the 
trees in the cover-crop plats recovered, made good growth, 
and are now (February, 1903) alive with the exception of a 
few trees that were killed accidentally late in summer after 
having made a vigorous growth. Of the live trees in the late 
cultivation plat that came through the winter alive only 
three are now living, the other two having died in the summer, 
apparently from winter injuries. These three trees 
made a fair growth, but are not so large now as the trees 
of the cover-crop plats. So much for the trees on the bottom 
land </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 

Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

None of the trees of either plat on the poorer upland soil 
were seriously injured by the winter's cold. Some twigs 
were killed back a few inches from the tips, but the great 
majority of them were not hurt enough to kill even the tender 
tips. The winter was a comparatively mild one and 
practically no peach trees on upland soil in this part of the 
state were injured. An examination of the trees in the upland 
block made early in spring, however, showed that the 
different plats might have presented as great differences as 
did the plats on the bottom land had the winter been more 
severe. On March 14 the trees of the three plats of the upland 
block were carefully examined. In the cover-crop plats 
there was almost no indication of discoloration beneath the 
bark, the twigs presenting a fresh, bright appearance when 
cut across. In the plat that received late cultivation, however, 
nearly all the twigs showed considerable brown coloration 
beneath the bark. They were plainly injured, though 
not seriously enough to prevent normal growth the follow 
ing summer. Had the winter been as severe as many winters 
in this section, the superiority of the cover-crop over 
late cultivation would doubtless have been as pronounced 
on the upland as it was on the low land. 

REPETITION OF THE TEST IN 1902. 

(During the early summer of 1902, all plats of the peach 
&lt;m were again given careful cultivation. On Julv 16, 
llet was again sown in the plats where it was grown as a 
rer-crop the year before. All other plats, both those that 
«re in oats and those that were cultivated late the preceding 
year, were given clean cultivation until late in fall. The 
season of 1902 was as excessively wet as the preceding one 
was dry. The cover-crop did not, therefore, show as pronounced 
an effect in inducing early ripening of the new wood 
as it did in 1901. . Considerable difference was seen between 
the plats, however, especially in the upland block. About 
the middle of September, 1902, two twigs were taken from 
each tree in the millet plat and two from each tree that had 
received late cultivation both years. These twigs were selected 
to represent the average condition of the trees as to </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

23 

maturity. In case most of the young growth of the tree 
was immature, two immature twigs were chosen, and, similarly, 
when nearly all the wood was well matured, two mature 
twigs were taken. Where a tree presented a condition 
about midway between the two extremes just noted, one mature 
and one immature twig were selected. These twigB, 16 

Fig. 8. — Peach twigs. Nos. 1-14 froraiate cultivation, and Nos. 15-30 from 
cover-crop plat. Note maturity of latter and immaturity of former. 

from the cover-crop and 14 from the late cultivation plat, 
were photographed after having most of their leaves removed 
to better show their maturity or immaturity when crowded 
together. The photographs are reproduced in fig. 8. The 
twigs shown in the lower row, Nos. 15 to 30, were taken from 
the millet cover-crop plat, and those shown in the upper </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 


row, Nos. 1 to 14, from the late cultivation plat. It will be 
seen that of the 16 twigs from the cover-crop plat, eleven. 
No*. 16 to 36, are fairly mature, and five, Nos. 26 to 30, are 
immature, while of the 14 twigs from the late cultivation 
plat only three, Nos. 1 to 3, are mature, ami eleven. Nos. 4 
to 14, are immature. The difference between mature and 
immature twigs is perhaps better seen in fig. 9, where a 
Eture twig and an immature one are shown with leave* 
let. 

Fig. 9. — Mature peach twig on left, immature one on right. 

APPLICATION OF RESULTS. 

P)ung peach trees are especially inclined to grow too late 
ill, and, as the result, to be winter injured. The same 
ency is often noticed in Japan plums. Some of the 
American plums, like the Chickasaws and some varieties of 
apples, like Jonathan, Winesap, and even Ben Davis, would 
be hardier if they ripened their wood earlier. In any locality, 
then, where these trees are not entirely hardy, growing 
a cover-crop to hasten their maturity in fall would certainly </seg>


            <seg id="p025">
25 

En the other hand, our common native plums stop growlong 
before the Japan plums and peaches. The common 
eties of sour cherries ripen their wood very early and do 
not usually start growth again until the next spring, even 
though the fall may be wet Such varieties of apple as Oldenburg 
and Wealthy and the Whitney crab also get ready 
for winter early in fall. It is noteworthy that these varieties 
are hardy, probably on account of their habit of early 
ripening. With such fruits it would seem useless to grow 
rover crops to hasten maturity. </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 


Experiment III. 

rT-KILLING OF APPLE AND CHERRY STOCKS IN RELATION 
TO SOIL MOISTURE AND SOIL COVERS. 

PLAN OF THE TEST. 

RA preliminary test of the effect of a soil cover and of 
rious amounts of soil moisture on winterkilling of tender 
roots was made the past winter. Seven boxes, two feet 
square and eighteen inches deep, were filled with common 
loam soil of varied water content, the soil in every case being 
thoroughly mixed, to insure uniform distribution of the soil 
moisture. In each of these seven boxes of soil, 25 one-year 
apple seedlings and 10 two-year Mahaleb cherry seedlings 
were planted. About the middle of December, 1902, six of 
the boxes of seedlings were placed on the ground out doors 
in an unprotected situation. The spaces between the boxes 
were filled with hay, packed down and covered with soil, 
and hay and soil were also banked up around the outside of 
the group of boxes. A little later, the seventh box was put 
in a cool, dry cave. One box of soil was covered with a 
mulch of straw four inches deep. A second box was protected 
by about four inches of snow whenever snow fell, the 
protection remaining until the snow melted. The other 
boxes were left without covering of any sort, the snow even 
being swept off from them after each storm. The boxes were 
left in place until about the middle of February, when they 
were taken into a moderately warm room to allow the soil 
to thaw. The weather was so mild during the two months 
of the test that very serious injury to the roots was not to 
be expected. The severe weather of February occurred just 
after the boxes were taken in doors. The moisture content 
of the soil of the various boxes was determined before the 
test was begun. The box of soil covered with snow increased 
considerably in moisture during the test from the melting 
of the snow. The mulched soil also became somewhat </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

27 

RESULTS OF THE TEST. 

Pter the boxes had been taken indoors and when the soil 
entirely thawed, the seedlings were taken out and exed. 
It was then noted that some of the apple seedlings 
been injured more than others, some of the roots being 
discolored, while others were bright and apparently uninjured. 
In general, the roots from the drier soils showed 
more discoloration than those from the moister soils. The 
roots protected by the straw mulch were least injured of all 
excepting those kept in the cave, which showed no injury. 

Somewhat similar differences were noticed in case of the 
cherry roots, but they were not so pronounced. In fact, 
none of these roots were very severely hurt, the poorest ones 
showing nothing worse than a brown discoloration when cut 

After the preliminary examination, all the seedlings were 
heeled-in in moist sand in a greenhouse where they remained 
for about a week before being reexamined. It was then found 
that none of the cherry roots had been injured enough to 
prevent their growing, and practically no difference could 
be detected between the roots from the different boxes. 
With the apple seedlings, on the other hand, the injury was 
much more apparent than when the roots were first examined. 
In the warm, moist sand the uninjured seedlings were 
beginning to grow, the white tips of new roots could be seen 
plainly and the old roots presented a bright appearance. 
The leaf buds also were beginning to expand. On the other 
hand, where roots had been badly injured they were now 
quite brown and beginning to decay. None of the roots were 
entirely dead, the tips of all being bright and for the most 
part unhurt, apparently capable of growth independently 
of the top. The line of demarcation between the dead and 
the live parts of a root was usually well defined, the brown 
decaying part giving place abruptly to the bright, live part. 
In a few cases the dead part of the roots extended no more 
than an inch below the soil surface, but in most cases it 
ran down from two to four inches, and some roots were dead 
for as much as seven inches. In some cases, where seedlings 
were injured, bat not seriously enough to kill them, the </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
28 


Ems weiv starting feebly into growth. In external appearce 
such roots were like uninjured ones, except that they 
were a little less bright When cat into, very considerable 
discoloration was still seen. It was thought that these roots 
would proliably live and that they might in time recover 
from the injury. They were classed as merely "injured." 
the others being either "uninjured," when no injury could 
be detected, or "dead." when any considerable part of the 
root was dead, though the root tips were alive. In but very 


Fig. 10— Apple seedlings. Nos. 1 and 2, root-killed from surface of ground 
to a depth of (i inches, tops barely alive, root tips unhurt, sprouting; No. 3, 

uninjured. 

few cases were the tops of the seedlings dead. Even where 
six or seven inches of the root immediately below the soil 
surface was brown and decaying, the top was usually green 
and apparently uninjured. In most respects the injury to 
these apple seedlings was much like that which occurred the </seg>


            <seg id="p029">
29 

w inter before to apple seedlings standing in the Experiment 
Station nursery. A photograph of the latter is reproduced 
in fig. 10. 

Fig. 11. — Relation of soil moisture and soil cover to root-killing of apple 
seedlings. Number of dead roots indicated by unshaded parts of horizontal 
bars, injured roots by lightly shaded parts, and uninjured roots by heavily 
shaded parts. 

The number of dead, injured, and uninjured apple roots 
from the various boxes is given in the table below, which 
also indicates the treatment that each box of seedlings received 
and shows the per cent of water in the soil at the beginning 
of the test. The results are perhaps more clearly 
indicated in the chart (fig. 11). 

Table IV. — Root-killing of apple seedlings. 

I 

Number of roots. 

Where kept. 

Soil cover. 

Per cent 
of soil 
moisture. 

In 
test. 

Unin- 
jured. 

In- 
jured. 

Dead. 

1 Out doors None 
2 Out doors None 
3 Out doors None 
4 Out doors None 
5j Out doors Straw mulch 
6 Out doors Snow occasionally 
7 Cool, dry cave. . . None 

10.4 
15.2 
19.8 
25.6 
16.0 
15.8 
10.0 

B 
K 
28 
% 

I 

j 
• 

ll </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 

Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

That the great injury to the seedling roots in the drier 
snils is not due directly to the dryness alone, but to dryness 
and cold combined, is evident from the fact that the roots 
were absolutely unhurt in equally dry soil kept in a cool, 
dry cave. The same conclusion is indicated by the fact that 
the lower ends of the roots were never injured, even 
when several inches of the upper part of the same roots were 
dead, though the soil in the bottom of the boxes was as dry 
as at the top. That dryness alone was not responsible for 
the injury is further shown by the comparatively slight injury 
to roots in rather dry soil which was protected by a 
four-inch mulch of straw, while roots in bare soil of almost 
the same moisture content were very badly hurt. 

Kwhy severe freezing should injure roots worse in 
dry than in moist soil is not shown by the test reabove. 
On further investigation it may be found that 
ire simply unable to withstand severe freezing or to 
• from it unless surrounded by an abundance of moisture. 
Be this as it may, it is quite probable that one cause 
of the great injury in rather dry soil is alternate freezing 
and thawing. That freezing and thawing alternately is 
much more pronounced in rather drj' than in moist soil is 
well known. A test carried out in the winter of 1900-01 
showed that this is true, and further indicated that the more 
water a soil contains the less subject it is to frequent alternate 
freezing and thawing. 

The fact that the apple seedlings were much less seriously 
injured where protected by a mulch of straw than they were 
in bare ground is to be explained by the effect of mulches 
on freezing and thawing of the ground. The latter was 
tested during the winter of 1901-02. The mulch protected 
the soil not only against severe freezing during cold nights, 
but also against alternate freezing and thawing. The temperature 
changes observed on February 2, 3, and 4, 1902 — a 
very cold period — are especially interesting. The surface of 
the bare ground thawed during the middle of the day and 
froze severely each night. Two inches lower, however, the 
soil did not thaw out during this very cold weather, though 
the temperature changes between day and night were great. 
The temperature of the mulched ground both at the surface 
</seg>
            <seg id="p031">
Experiments in Orchard Culture 

31 

Etwo inches beneath it, remained constantly below the 
zing point and, moreover, varied but little during the 
od. 

A cover-crop that mats down on the arrival of cold weather 
protects the soil in just the same way that a mulch of straw 
does, both of them tending to prevent deep freezing and alternate 
freezing and thawing. Cover-crops that stand erect 

Fig. 12. — Depths of frost in bare ground represented by full length of horizontal 
bars, and depths under cover-crop by shaded part of bars. 

I ing winter naturally do not directly protect the ground 
inst severe freezing as thoroughly as those that mat down, 
ugh they check alternate freezing and thawing by shadthe 
ground, thus keeping it frozen during bright, cold 
ither. Erect cover-crops, however, have one advantage 
r mulch-forming ones. They hold the snow better against 
'ting winds. A blanket of snow is one of the very best of 
tections against severe freezing and alternate freezing 
. thawing. Moreover, the increase in soil moisture from </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
32 

Experiments in Orchard Culture. 

Ill* I I * 11^ \\ 1 V II \ 1 o I 1 ' | I | J (| I i I | | | 4 1 ( X I I I * /. 1 ¦ 1 f I I M I I I I 4 t '* 
ing. Some of the records of the depth of frost in bare grand 
and iu ground protected by a millet cover-crop are show n 
diagrammatically in fin;. 12. 
O 'iff o* 

APPLICATION OF RESULTS. 

Many trees with hardy tops are budded on rather tender 
roots. The cherry is worked on Mahaleb and the plum on 
Marianna or Myrobalan stocks. Neither of these roots is u 
hardy as the hardiest varieties of plums and cherries that 
are worked upon them and are sometimes killed by winters 
not severe enough to seriously injure the tops of the trees. 
The seedlings upon which apples are worked vary greatly 
in hardiness, the tenderer ones being even less hardy than 
the stocks upon which plums and cherries are budded. When 
propagated by piece-root grafting, hardy apples are less liable 
to root killing, since roots form from the scjons, making 
what is known as own-rooted trees, the seedling root if it 
IK-i-sists at all being so far below the ground that it is not 
likely to be injured. Deep planting may accomplish for 
budded apples in the orchard what is accomplished in the 
nursery by piece-root grafting. Unfortunately, it is often 
impractical to protect the tender roots of plums and cherries 
by deep planting, since the roots which start from the 
scion sprout very badly. 

Any method of culture that leaves the ground perfectly 
bare in fall, thus favoring deep freezing and alternate freezing 
and thawing, is not to be recommended where root killing 
is at all common. A cover-crop is one of the best means 
of protecting the roots of 'trees. Likewise, any method of 
culture that leaves the ground moist in fall has an advantage 
over methods that leave the ground very dry. In this 
regard, clean cultivation might be expected to be ahead of 
cover-crops. As a matter of fact, however, during the three 
years that cover-crop experiments have been carried on at 
the Experiment Station, the soil under cover-crops that are 
killed by the early frosts has been as moist on the approach 
of cold weather as ground given clean cultivation throughout 
the fall. </seg>


            <seg id="p033">
33 

GENERAL CONCLUSIONS. 

We may fairly say that the tests reported in this bulletin 
indicate the best all-around method of culture for young 
orchards to be thorough cultivation in early summer, followed 
by a cover-crop in fall, so far as tests covering only 
a few years can prove any method best. A mulch of straw 
is known to keep the soil moist during summer and it also 
protects tender roots in winter, but its use will surely in 
crease winter injury to tender tops of trees by prokMtgiBg 
fall growth. Besides, a mulch induces shallow root development, 
which may result disastrously in later years, and 
its use is out of the question in large orchards. Thorough 
cultivation protects trees against drought as well as mulching, 
and keeps the roots from forming near the surface of 
the ground. When cultivation is given in early summer, all 
that is necessary in order to furnish winter protection is to 
stop cultivating in midsummer, grow a cover-crop (weeds 
being better than nothing) which will dry the ground in 
fall, causing the new wood growth to ripen early in preparation 
for winter and which will, by holding the snow or by 
matting down to form a mulch, protect tender roots during 
winter. Good cultivation in early summer can often be given 
young trees by growing some cultivated crop in the orchard. 
Tender crops are best since they can not be sown so early 
as to dry the ground seriously in spring and are killed by 
fall frosts, thus preventing very late drying. Cropping with 
corn, for instance, insures fairly thorough early cultivation, 
and corn is a fair substitute for a cover-crop in fall and 
winter. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>