<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Some Factors Affecting the Cooking Quality of the Pea and Great Northern Types of Dry Beans</title>
               <date value="18??">October 1936</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Some Factors Affecting the Cooking Quality of the Pea and Great Northern Types of Dry Beans \ .;¦ ) I COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA I { AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION ; [ RESEARCH BULLETIN 85 f -v_;¦ : . ¦;• ¦-r .¦¦¦'¦.'¦..: ¦¦•¦ ¦ -.1 ¦ .. ' I ¦ ¦¦¦¦ . ¦ : ¦, ¦ .. . ...... ...¦.¦¦ -. ...-.-. -i ¦•'---• ..'¦¦¦": . ¦ ' ¦ ¦ ¦ -,¦-... t ¦ ¦ . i- •¦¦:'.-. ¦ ¦ ,- . ¦¦¦'. i i Edna B. Snyder [ ¦) Department of Home Economics . ¦ : .7 /¦'¦¦: ¦-'"¦ ¦...¦ ¦; -¦¦ "¦ ' :-¦...-:,: ¦¦¦ ...' - ¦¦..'".'¦. l I "... ¦-.-¦¦¦ :i ¦ ¦..' .....;.-.:_¦..¦¦¦. ' ¦ I i ¦ ¦¦¦¦•.¦¦ : &gt;v -¦¦:.' -. :¦¦'¦' ¦¦'¦'¦¦'¦¦¦'¦'¦¦'¦¦.::"'-':'-'''":¦ ¦' -V - ¦¦ ¦. ¦ ¦-. . ¦; :¦" . ¦¦' ¦ ' ¦'¦ ¦ V : -"' ¦¦.'¦.-¦" :¦¦':' .' ¦ ' ¦ ¦':¦¦'¦. ¦¦."•''.'¦¦ i' ¦-J ¦ ¦ i -. ¦ . ¦•. &#132;.-.. ¦ . -s f;.v- :.¦;: X ¦¦¦¦•;;/¦ '^y&lt;^^l^^''--\M' I ! LINCOLN, NEBRASKA ' ¦:{ if OCTOBER, 1936 | </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">,: :;';: : ;-Y..| ¦ ¦'¦ '.;:- ¦ .¦¦•¦'¦ •.¦¦¦ ¦¦/.¦¦' '•'"•'.:- :¦¦¦¦¦¦. i '¦¦ ¦-.¦•:. ¦¦¦¦:¦¦¦ '¦::¦¦¦¦-!- '¦¦"- -'.-}^: , ' ¦¦ '.¦¦•¦ ¦'/.: ':'¦''¦ . ¦ ¦¦¦'": ¦¦¦ - ¦¦¦¦' ",•'' ¦. ¦¦¦. -,: ¦ ¦ /¦ .' ¦-: '¦. ¦ I ¦ "¦ ¦_¦ ¦¦'']{ ..'¦¦¦. '-.-¦'.;'¦: '.-¦¦' I •: :^v¦.:/¦- f-;\ {-;;;¦¦¦¦ ¦ i ; . -AU ¦ ¦'¦-:'.'¦ ¦¦¦¦• ¦ : ' ' - i ¦.-¦.¦'.¦ :'. ¦¦'.:' ,¦ I/..; CONTENTS; ¦ &#132;'. ¦' . " .¦:. ¦•;¦:-¦;• ¦:¦•¦/¦ ¦:. ¦'". ¦¦ : '¦:• " ' ¦ Pace [ ¦ . Summary .....; :..:....... 4 Introduction ••...:...;.........,... 5 Economic Importance and Geographical Distribution of Beans 5 Purpose of the Study .....:........ 5 I Preliminary Studies g Soaking ......;.... ...........;...,..., g ' Methods of cooking.:. ;,........;...'..,,;.,;,,., '7 Experimental Methods and Re5u1t5.................... 7 Effects of 5carificati0n......;................,;. ;........ 10 Effects of size .:...................:J. ¦ H Effects of age and 5t0rage.................. 17 Effects of deterioration....;.... ........;............ &#132; 13 '• Effects of chemical solutions...... ..;........ 13 • Acid 501uti0n5............:........;....... 14 . Neutral salts ...:..,...... ................ 17 \ Sodium bicarbonate •...................:.... "."¦.¦ 21 ' . Sugar solutions ..-;.,,. [ ....... 1......... [ t \ ;..", ja ¦; Pectic solvents; ¦¦.:......:.,.....,,, j, 7j Practical Studies.... V;..! ............ 07 '¦ Discussion of Results... 29 [ . - -. . . ¦ - : ¦ ' ¦ . • '- -. ¦ . ' I :' :. ;¦ :.¦ ¦ ¦•¦: ¦:¦' ' ' " ¦ \ ' ',¦¦" ¦ . ' ¦ J ' ¦ - ''¦':' - ' : . '¦ ' ; ¦¦ • ¦ -' ¦'"'¦¦¦ ¦¦'¦¦Wv^--"V-^4-%^?;'':-;:T!;-YV^¦¦¦''.¦ ' ) 1 '..' ' ;--:. '¦' : ¦•¦-•.¦. ¦ :: -:¦¦/¦¦¦ ", '¦-¦:&gt; ¦¦:- ¦&gt;¦¦.¦ \ . i r.:-.::;:';,-r-/-¦::&gt;¦¦, :-;.;¦.-.;. i: : '¦¦¦/¦-¦:¦¦:. I </seg>
         <seg id="p004">SUMMARY Dry beans of (he Great Northern and pea-bean type from Nebraska and several other bean-producing states were studied to determine the factors affecting the cooking quality. A standard cooking procedure with distilled water was used to disclose differ - ences in cooking quality, and the percentage of beans too hard for table use was determined for each cooked portion. The factors studied were: soaking, including time and temperatures; storage, including time and storage conditions; age; size; place of origin; effect of chemical solutions; and the composition of the seed coat. The chemical solutions used were hydrochloric and acetic acids in different concentrations; sulphates and chlorides ot calcium, magnesium, and sodium; sodium bicarbonate; and ammonium salts of oxalic, citric, and tartaric acids. A quantitative analysis of the bean seed coats was made for the following constituents: protein, fats, calcium, magnesium, and pectic material. Results of the study are as follows: J. The cooking quality of the pea and Great Northern beans appears to be deter - mined almost wholly by: (1) the structure and composition of the seed coat, which may be inherently hard, may have become hard as a result of environmental con - ditions, or may have been hardened by chemical solutions; and (2) by the hygroscopic quality of the micropyle and germinal area. 2. Conclusions regarding the factors which modify or have a negative effect, on cooking quality arc as follows: 1I) Beans cook more rapidly if soaked previous to cooking. The optimum soaking temperature appears to be around 120° F., and the beans imbibe their own weight of water in five or six hours. A longer time is requited if soaking is done at a lower temperature. (2) The cotyledons of all beans giving no evidence of sclcrcma become soft when the seed coats arc scarified previous to soaking. (3) An optimum storage condition appears to consist of storage in tightly dosed containers held at a temperature in the neighborhood of 45° F. Age alone apparently does not produce a hard-shelled condition. (4) Size is apparently a negligible factor in cooking quality. (51 Difference in place of origin did not contribute marked differences in cooking quality of the beans studied. (6) Solutions of hydrochloric and acetic acid in concentrations of 0.33 normal, 0.1 normal, 0.03 normal, and 0.01 normal depress water absorption and harden the seed coats of beans. (7) Solutions of sulphates and chlorides of calcium and magnesium in concen - trations of 100 ppm depress water absorption and harden the seed coals of beans, and the hardness increases with increase of concentration of solutions. Solutions of sulphates and chlorides of sodium and potassium have no deleterious effect. (8) Solutions of sodium bicarbonate tend to soften the seed coats of beans and can be used effectively in amounts which are not deleterious to appearance or flavor. (9) Solutions of ammonium salts of oxalic, citric, and tartaric acid soften the seed coats of beans, that of oxalic being most efficient (10) The seed coats of the beans studied contained relatively large amounts of pectic materials (which appeared in the form of pectic acid or pectates), and calcium, and slight amounts of protein, magnesium, and fatty materials. The Great Northern type analyzed in this study contained about twice the amount of calcium found in the pea bean. Results from cooking and from chemical analysis indicate that the pectic material may be effective in preventing entrance of water into the bean. (11) Practical baking studies show little justification for the excessively long baking time recommended by conventional recipes. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">,-„— —¦ —P) ¦ -¦¦ ¦'¦¦.-¦ • ¦'. ; ¦ ¦'¦• ¦ . ."¦ ¦¦ •"¦ ¦ ¦'¦¦ ¦'¦¦¦'" - ¦ • ' I ¦:: '•¦¦¦.:::, v X-r- X\. . ¦'... ¦:":'";&lt;¦¦.' i. i Some Factors Affecting the Cooking Quality of the Pea and Great Northern Types ; of Dry Beans "-.. l | EDNA B. SNYDERI •; \ Beans have occupied an important place as a world food, dating back \ to the ancients. Their use has been more general in southern European \ and Asiatic countries than on this continent and they still serve as the i . chid? source ot protein in many old-world countries, especially among the &gt; | peasant classes. Because of their lack* of cystine they are considered made- ] quate when used alone to supply protein; however, they do serve to sup- I plement other more expensive nitrogenous foods and to add pleasing i • variety to the diet. Aside from their protein content, beans contain a high j percentage of carbohydrate, are relatively rich in calcium, phosphorus, and iron, and contain magnesium as well as vitamins A and B. :; ECONOMIC IMPORTANCE AND GEOGRAPHICAL j DISTRIBUTION OF BEANS J ; ; Beans constitute a leading crop in a number of states and are constantly ) increasing in economic importance. Reports of the Federal Bureau of Agricultural Economics in recent years show marked yearly increases in bean consumption in the United States. States leading in dry-bean pro- j duction are Michigan, New Yorki Colorado, New Mexico, California, and i j Idaho. Michigan leads in total yield and Idaho and California in acre yield. They are becoming an important crop in Nebraska. | ¦ The types of white dry beans most generally grown for marketing I purposes are the small, round pea bean and the large kidney-shaped bean known as the Great Northern. Both types probably originated in Chile . and belong botanically to the species Phaseolus vulgaris. The pea-bean \ ..type is grown in Michigan and localities farther east, while the Great X Northern seems to be generally better adapted to the states west of Mich- ] . • igan. Several of the larger commercial canners specify the smaller bean j for their products and in certain localities there appears to be a definite preference among consumers for this type. On the other hand, in certain \ other localities canners and consumers;alike express a definite preference i for the larger bean. Reasons for preferences appear rather vague. One '\ canner states that his choice of the pea bean is due to the fact that the '\ shape is retained during processing. It is probable that habitual use of one | type due to local production and prevalence in local markets has been the | chief factor in developing preference. -.'. j I PURPOSE OF THE STUDY | • .;¦.; It has been generally observed that the cooking o£ dry beans has v presented difficulty because of the variation in their capacity to become $ I soft. This variation was observed by the Greeks as far back as 300 B. C. 1 'The writer wiiha id acknowledge nijscnioni and criticiirai from Frafeuon J. C. Ruud md ¦ ':i M. D. Weldon of the neoanmenr of Acronomv. and M. |. Bli.h of ihe DeDartment of Awlcultural j Chemistry. -..-..,: .-'¦¦"-¦ ... ¦ ¦ ¦ • "1 ..." " - ¦ .¦;"-'.¦¦ ¦." ' . ¦&lt;"' '¦¦-¦¦ :'-".'.¦¦' '¦'- - ..- '¦ '¦'¦¦' . ¦'." - ¦ '¦¦:' ¦¦':¦'.¦¦ . ¦ li </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 As a result, wide variation in cooking quality occurs even in the same lot of beans. There are frequently beans with seed coats which remain hard and prevent the entrance of water to the inside even after being cooked in boiling water. Such protection of the embryo tends to insure the germination of a portion of the seeds from any one plant. The purpose of this study was to investigate: (1) various factors either inherent or a result of environment which conceivably might affect the cooking quality of the pea and Great Northern types of beans; and (2) procedures to modify these factors. Factors which were considered were: (1) place of origin, (2) size, (3) age and storage conditions, (4) structure and composition of the seed coat, and (5) deterioration. Modifying pro - cedures were: (1) soaking, including duration and temperature of water, (2) method of cooking, that is, boiling over direct heat, double boiler, pressure, and baking, and (3) effect of chemical solutions. The beans used for the study, together with their cultural histories, were secured from several important bean-producing states and from western Nebraska. 2 PRELIMINARY STUDIES It is at once evident that a procedure for cooking dry beans must pro - vide for the imbibition of a relatively large amount of water both by the seed coat and the cotyledons. Any treatment tending to lqssen the im - bibition of water would obviously be detrimental to the cooking process and to the quality of the resulting product. As a preliminary step to the study it was necessary to study some of the factors listed above as probably affecting cooking quality in order that a cooking procedure, satisfactory for use in disclosing differences in quality of beans from different lots, could be developed for use in the laboratory. The preliminary study consisted of experimentation with various lots of beans, methods of soaking, kinds of water (such as tap and distilled water), and methods of cooking (such as boiling directly over heat, double boiler, and pressure). Soaking.—To eliminate any effect from mineral present in the water, distilled water was used for both soaking and cooking the beans which were to be compared. Preliminary study, shown in Figure 1, showed that in general the beans absorbed their own weight in water in from five to six hours, provided the temperature of the water was considerably above room temperature. There was little increase in weight by longer soaking, and cooking time was not reduced. A lower soaking temperature required a longer time for the same result. The five-hour soaking period was well adapted to a laboratory schedule and should be practical in household use. The cooked beans which had been soaked were more pleasing in ap - pearance^ appeared lighter in color, and were more evenly cooked than </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Cookino Quality op Beans those which had not been soaked.: The cooking time was reduced con - siderably by soaking, but the.iweight of the cooked beans was the same whether soaked or not soaked-.;:/;;;. . ¦• ;': : .'¦..'•-"¦• : ; -. • &#132;-¦¦' Methods of cooking.—lt was found that when the beans were cooked in rapidly boiling water they tended to lose shape and become mushy; similar results were obtained when they were cooked in a double boiler slightly below boiling temperature. Considerable experimental work was done with the pressure cooker to determine if this method would produce .';¦ ;¦ ¦¦• '; '8-i —: — —: ——— ———:—¦—— —* •:•-'¦¦¦ 6' ' y£^^~~ : _1-_l' _"" ' o- I /^*^&gt;'ff'^' "^ —great northern (montana) ' I ///''"' --—-pea bean (Michigan) ¦• j 8"^ — r\ 1 -i — '—) rr- ——r —-i 1 ¦ p— ? 0 1/2345 67 8 OVER NIGHT 15 I .-• ¦ ,': ¦:-::¦'¦ '[ ¦'"¦':.' -:: f HOURS Fie. I.—Rates of imbibition of water by Michigan pea beans and Montana Great Northern beans. . . : a more tender product in a shorter time than by ordinary boiling. Cooking for 30 minutes at 15 pounds pressure produced beans which were'soft ; with tender seed coats, but were mushy and dark in color, with a flavor ;'¦ generally considered as undesirable. Cooking for 40 minutes with 10 pounds pressure produced a somewhat more desirable product, but still not meeting acceptable standards in: appearance and flavor.' Baking was j eliminated as a method for comparing the quality of different lots of beans, j because it isa more complicated procedure and difficult to standardize. 1 "¦: However, attention, was given to this ;method later in the study. j EXPERIMENTAL METHODS AND RESULTS I The soaking, cooking, and sorting procedures finally adopted were as j ;.,!'. follows: The, beans from the different places of origin were selected so ' that all appeared edible. One hundred grams were soaked for five hours ; in 450 cubic centimeters of distilled water at approximately 120° Fi The I ..; same water was used for both soaking and cooking, as the resulting flavor M was considered less variable when the soaking water was retained for j cooking. At the end of the soaking period the beans were drained and [ '. ' ¦ ' '¦¦•¦ ¦¦ ; ¦ . ¦''".'¦,-¦- . ( ¦¦'¦'•¦ ¦ "'. '.¦•¦¦' ': .]v : ' ¦¦¦¦'¦ ¦" '. . ¦ '.¦¦ [ ¦ '.¦'¦¦¦ ¦ . .;.¦ ¦.'.'. . I''-.- j..; '"'¦'¦ .-.¦''..: ¦ ' . : ¦'¦ I '.-. :/-': . ¦'-' '¦''. '..¦¦'.¦¦¦¦.¦¦' ¦¦'"(.'¦¦¦. '-¦''¦¦ :¦'¦¦¦'¦'". ¦' i.} ¦ ¦'¦..-¦¦' ' ¦.'¦¦¦• ¦.¦¦V- ¦¦¦' i..'¦ '. - ¦¦¦¦ ¦¦'¦'¦¦ ;¦¦ "•¦'¦¦ ¦'¦¦'¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Aorl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 weighed. Tht water was heated to the boiling point and the beans added and allowed to cook one and one-fourth hours, or the minimum time found necessary to produce a tender, uniformly cooked product with the beans used in the study. The utensils used were pans of pressed aluminum so shaped that they could be used in triplicate on a single burner. They were two quarts in capacity with tightly fitting lids held by clamps. The type of pan described was selected so that a greater number of portions could be cooked at the same time. The beans were cooked on a 1,000-watt electric unit, kept on "low" throughout the cooking period to prevent rapid boiling. The beans were cooked without salt, as the presence of salt appeared to mask or change the flavor. After cooking, the beans were again drained and weighed, and compared while still warm. Since tenderness of both seed coat and cotyledons is an important criterion for comparison of cooked beans, that characteristic was used as a basis of comparison and was supplemented with subjective ratings for flavor. Several mechanical methods were tried for measuring tender - ness but were abandoned because of difficulty in obtaining comparable measurements. The methods tried consisted of puncturing, cutting, and crushing the beans and measuring the amount of pressure necessary to do the work. It is not possible to standardize a bean as to size and shape as may be done with a cut vegetable. As a result of the swelling of the bean, the cotyledons when cooked tend to separate, leaving a space be - tween. Measurements are complicated because the resistance of the seed coat may be greater than that of the cotyledon, making it uncertain which resistance is being measured. When considering the cooking quality of the beans, slight variations in hardness are not important factors, but whether or not they are suitable for table use is important. Because of the above difficulties, a hand method was used for comparing the tenderness of cooked beans. It is conceded at the outset that the method chosen will be open to criticism, because it is not entirely objective. However, it pro - vided a more satisfactory basis for comparing different lots of beans than the mechanical methods tried. Frequently when a mechanical method is used for measuring tenderness of food products, it is justified on the grounds that it agrees with hand sorting. The procedure used in this study was as follows: Each quantity of cooked beans was sorted by hand into two portions—one portion made up of those beans which were sufficiently soft for table use and another portion of those too hard for table use. Testing was done by puncturing each bean by hand with a No. 5 sewing needle. By this method the entire quantity of beans was checked and the percentage, by number, of hard beans was computed. The wide variation in the characteristics of beans, even from the same lot, has been mentioned; no two samples of equal weight are identical in characteristics. Because of this lack of uniformity, results from cooking different quantities are quite likely to show wide differences, and it is impossible to duplicate results. Therefore in experimental work of this </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Cookivc Quality of Beans character a high degree of precision is impossible, and conclusions must necessarily be drawn from a large number of trials. In Table 1 is shown a comparison of the different lots of beans from the various places of origin when cooked by the standard procedure. All but one lot, which was received later during the study, were from the 1933 crop. The table includes the percentage gain in weight after soaking and after cooking and gives the percentage of hard beans, or those not sufficiently soft for table use, at the end of the cooking period. The Table I.— Percentage gain in weight of 100 grams of beans from soaking and cooking and percentage of beans unsuitable for table use. 1 Type I Source 1 I Moiirure I Gain in wt. I Gain in wt. I Unsuitable _ | source | cmnm , | fmm m)[ing | tmm mklllg | f OfoMeMK ;': ¦ . ¦ «*.«. p. a. '/&gt;.«.• f.tt. Michigan (1) Pej bean 15.00 86.00 151X10 ¦ 28.00 Idaho Great Northern 10.00 90.00 154.00 2J.00 Montana , Great Northern 10.00 88.00 ¦ 151,00 25.00 Colorado Pea bean ; 9.00 98.00 162.00 27.00 ComoierciaiFancy ; ¦¦:.•:¦' "Fernald" Idaho Great Northern ;.'. 96.00 16600 1500 Commercial Mich. ! BeanGrowerj Pea bean ... 106.00 15600 15JJ0' Michigan (2) Pea bean ... 93.00 Kl.qq bm Nehr.&amp;p. (¦ 7.60 111.00 174.00 22.00 Sta. plot I .Great Northern 7.«0 99.00 162.00 23.00 Nebr.No.l Grot Northern 9.01 85.00 165.00 UM Nebr. No. 2 Great Northern 9.13 90.00 177.00 11.00 Nebr. No. 3 i Great Northern 9.05 95.00 165.00 13.00 Nebr. No. 4 Great Northern 9.61 89.00 168.00 Io!oO Nebr. No. 5 Great Northern : 9.02 107.00 176.00 5.00 Nebr. No. 6" Great Northern 939 98.00 WM 9.00 Nebr.No.7 Great Northern ¦'' 9.39 97.00 179.00 0.00 -Nebr. No. (- • C'eat Northern 930 ¦ 109JX) 162.00 2!(»' Nebr.No.9 Pea bean . 8.00 105.00 155.00 17.00 numbe""f bani ""'^ WhC° *'" received-'Thc Percentage of hard bom vm calcuhted from the •All of the beanj itudied were from the 1933 crop except thole from Michigan (2) The momurc coment trai determined by drying to constant. weight in a vacuum oven. place of origin did not appear to be a significant factor in cooking quality, with the beans studied. Differences in the percentages of hard beans were small among lots of out-of-state beans. There were somewhat greater differences among the different lots of Nebraska beans. However, in several lots of the latter there were :a large number of broken seed coats, so that differences in weights or tenderness have little significance. In genera], the beans grown in Nebraska compared favorably with those from other states. !."¦ ' ' ; / : ; These results do not show a significant relation between cooking quality and moisture content. In the different lots grown in Nebraska there is generally a slightly lower percentage of hard beans with the higher moisture content, but again other factors such as breaks in the seed coat may account for this. The beans of the pea type in all cases maintained </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 their form during cooking somewhat better than did the Great Northern, because the seed coat of the former tends to remain intact. It is realized that a study of food flavor is subjective in nature and that it is difficult or impossible to set standards. Opinions of food quality vary widely and are conditioned by previous customs and habits. A com - mittee made up of members of the Home Economics faculty served as judges of the characteristics of the beans listed in Table 1. Very little preference was expressed for any particular lot of beans. They were all rated as desirable. The pea-type bean was characterized in some cases as being more pronounced or "nutty" in flavor, while the Great Northern was considered as slightly bland or neutral. In only a few cases were the seed coats designated as tough or hard, and such designations were about equally divided for the two types. Those of both types rated as most pleasing in flavor were grown in the sand hills of Nebraska under the same cultural conditions. Most of the beans were desirable in texture. Those which were poorest in texture were grown in a Nebraska Experi - ment Station plot in both fertilized and unfertilized soil. The beans were tender but mushy in appearance. Generally, beans which did not become sufficiently soft for table use after cooking one and one-fourth hours, responded to longer cooking. A small percentage passed through both soaking and cooking processes with - out imbibing water but invariably became soft after the seed coat was scarified, making it possible for water to enter. The above results are of interest in view of the fact that A. de Dominicis 3 states that the capacity of legumes to soften is not dependent upon the outer integuments, but upon the imbibition of water by the colloidal forms which make up the beans, the amount depending upon their previous history or their degree of reversibility. EFFECTS OF SCARIFfCATION Because of the apparent importance of the nature of the seed coat as it affected the entrance of water, some study was made of the effects of skin scarification. Beans were selected from the same lot, one portion containing only those with coverings which appeared visually to be intact, and the other containing beans with scarified seed coats. Samples from various lots were used. It was found that when cooked by the standard method, both the soaked and cooked weights of the scarified beans were somewhat higher than those with the covering intact. With beans which cooked relatively well the cooking time was reduced 40 per cent by this treatment, but of course the appearance was less desirable. Scarification has been used considerably as an aid to* germination of legume seeds, but has probably not been considered as an aid to cooking. Since scarification proved an effectual method as an aid to cooking beans, the importance of the imbibition of water by the seed coat appeared to warrant further study. It should not be assumed that the entrance of water into seeds is uniform over the entire surface. Studies have been •A. dc Dominicil, Ann. Scuolj A B r. Ponici 16:31 (1920), Chcm. Abs. 17:3388 (1923). </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Cooking Quality of Beans made which show that at least in some seeds, the entrance of water at ordinary temperatures is largely through the micrppyle and germinal area, which are hygroscopic. The seed coat of beans appears to be rather loosely attached to the cotyledons with a cement-like substance holding it to them., Observations of beans during soaking show that the germinal area swells first, indicating the entrance of water by this ¦ route. The water passes, around the periphery of the bean, causing .{he seed coat to become wrinkled. Gradually the inside of the bean swells and the wrinkles dis-j appear. The swelling of the embryo tends to loosen the seed coat from the hilar groove, thus providing an opening for water. Water enters freely, through breaks occurring in the covering. The.path of a liquid into. the bean can be traced by soaking in. iodine and observing the. blue color. • To verify the localized entry of water into the beans, the following process was used: The micropyle and area near it (Great Northern type) were blocked with melted beeswax. Each bean was weighed be - fore and after blocking. An equal number of control beans were likewise weighed. Both lots were soaked in distilled water at room temperature for 24 hours. At the end of the soaking period they were again weighed. From the lot with germinal areas blocked, the average gain was only 0.28 per cent, while for the controls it was 79. The experiment was repeated with bicycle-tire cement as a seal, as the latter formed a thin coating less likely than beeswax to break loose from the bean. Results were similar to those with beeswax. The percentage gain in weight for the beans blocked with cement was 3.8, while forlthe controls it was 52 per cent. A larger, percentage of beans of the pea type swelled with the germinal areas blocked, a result which might possibly indicate a more general permea - bility of seed-coat surface. j , It is admitted that these results can not be considered as precise. Among the controls with no seal to present entrance of water were several beans which remained hard and it is probable that a number of the beans with the germinal area blocked would have remained hard without the seal. Apparently the micropyle is not always hygroscopic, and results from cooking show that occasionally even cooking at boiling temperature is without effect.. Results do, however, point to the generally localized entry of water into the beans, and suggests the importance of further informa - tion regarding the structure and. composition of the seed coat. EFFECTS OF SIZE ¦' :.. To determine if size is a factor in cooking quality, beans .from the same lot were sorted into two portions according to size; samples were selected from various lots, and cooked by the standard method. Results from the different lots were not consistent. From some lots the small and large beans cooked equally well, while in others there was a decided ad - vantage in favor of the large beans. In general the beans which appeared well matured cooked most readily. A comparison of the two types shows that the Great Northern cooks as quickly as the pea type, even though the beans are considerably larger in size. </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 effects of age and storage Even though beans cook well when first matured, certain successive environmental conditions appear to affect their cooking quality. There appears to be a popular idea that all old beans are difficult to cook. Instances are well known in which beans which originally cooked well have become very difficult to cook after storage. Such an instance occurred in the De - partment of Home Economics. Beans stored under laboratory conditions of temperature and moisture became so hard that they could not be cooked satisfactorily. Beans stored in tin containers in the research laboratory near the steam pipes, likewise became hard. Similar results were obtained by drying beans in an oven at a temperature of 100° F. Laboratory temperatures range from 70° to 80° F. and the humidity is generally low. To determine the effects of storage at fairly constant temperatures, samples from various lots were stored in tightly closed glass jars with rubbers, a part of them at 72° to 80° F. and a part at approximately 45° F. Results are shown in Table 2. Table 2.—Effects of 15 to 17 months storage at temperatures of 45° and 76° F. on 100 grams of beans. Gain in Gain in Glin in Gain in . wt. from wt. from wt. from wt. from ' Mean Source soaking cooking Hard soaking cooking Hard Itorage without without beans liter after beam temp. itoragc storage storage storage ?¦«¦ P ¦«¦ ?¦'&lt;¦ P. «. P. en P. a. Dcz.F. ¦°ah» 98 164 5 76 Great Northern 90 154 28 99 176 2 45 Montana 100 155 5 76 Great Northern 88 151 25 102 IS3 10 45 Michigan pea beam 86 151 2! 92 142 2 45 Nebr. Ejp, Sta. Great Northern 99 162 23 104 167 3 76 Nebraska No. 1 . 85 165 14 105 179 2 45 94 177 5 76 Nebraska No. 2 90 177 11 75 179 15 45 98 167 13 76 Nebraska No. 3.. 95 165 13 100 170 4 45 106 164 2 76 Nebraska No. 4 . . 89 168 10 98 180 2 45 107 175 2 76 Nebraska No. 5. . 107 176 5 110 179 1 45 Nebraska No. 6 98 167 9 108 179 2 45 102 175 2 76 Nebraska No. 7 . 97 179 0 104 190 0 45 Nebraska No. 9 103 153 17 98 167 2 45 The table shows that under the conditions stated the cooking quality of the beans was not impaired and was even superior to that before storage. The imbibition of water after storage was somewhat greater than before. Those stored at 45° F. were most desirable. These results show that age alone is not a factor in producing hardness but where hardness results, the condition is probably related to temperature and humidity. A relatively </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Cooking Quality of Beans low temperature (not above 50° F.) with conditions that prevent or reduce loss of moisture probably otters the optimum storage condition. EFFECTS OF DETERIORATION : Several lots of beans of the navy variety were received from a local cannery with the report that they could not be softened satisfactorily for canning. The reaction of the beans suggested to the canners the possibility of their having been treated with lime previous to shipment. It was found that a large percentage of the beans became soft, but out of each lot there was a sufficient number of hard beans to give the effect of underprocessing. Chemical examination failed to disclose any presence of lime. The hard - ness was not confined to the seed coats; the entire bean resisted cooking. The hard beans were noticeably darker in color than those which became .tender. Various treatments were used in'an effort to soften the hard beans but none was entirely satisfactory. . From another source beans were obtained which were known to be fourteen years old. These beans were likewise dark in color and remained hard throughout various treatments. They gained weight in soaking and cooking but did not become soft. Their moisture content was as high as that of some other beans which softened readily. It is probable that this type of hardness is a result of adverse temperature and moisture conditions in the field during harvesting or during storage, and is undoubtedly that known as "sclerema", which is produced from enzymatic changes resulting from storage in damp atmosphere at high temperature with no ventilation. Gloyer states that sclerema is not a matter of age alone, as it can be pro - duced artificially in ten days.' •'.¦''/. EFFECTS OF CHEMICAL SOLUTIONS The results of the experimental work described above show that the long cooking period commonly used for beans is necessary largely for the purpose of softening the seed coat.; Beans with seed coats removed and without evidence of sclerema became tender when cooked from 30 to 45 minutes. Since the softening of the cotyledons appeared to depend upon the imbibition of water, the limiting factor being the seed coat, the prob - lem resolved itself into one of treatment which could be used safely to increase permeability and to hasten the softening of the latter. Such treat - ment would be advantageous from the standpoint of both economy and palatability. On the other hand, it was possible that certain treatments might result in actual hardening of the seed. coat, thereby preventing the imbibition of water and causing the product to be less palatable. Little detailed information seems available concerning the composition of the seed coats of beans. Reported chemical analyses of beans consist of the composition of the entire bean. Considerable microchemical study has been made of the structure of seed coats of legumes and other seeds but such:study has been from the standpoint of germination. Statements are &lt;W. O. Gtoyer. Sclerenu and furd «hell, two type* of turdooj of the bean. Proe. Anoc Offie. Seed Aralyiti of North America, pp. 11-21, 1921. . </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 numerous relative 10 the digestibility of beans—the low coefficient of digestibility being ittributed to the "insoluble" materials found in the seed coats. The constituents of seed coats have generally been believed to include complex carbohydrates in the form of celluloses and hemicd/uloscs in combination with pectic substances, with possibly some cutin, lignins tannins, and various fatty and waxy substances. There appears to be still a question as to whether or not some of these combinations are chemical or merely physical. Because of the complexity of seed-coat structure and composition and the lack of definite information, a theoretical selection of solvents was difficult. An empirical procedure was therefore followed in this study to determine the effect of various solutions on the beans The solutions used were: (1) acids, (2) neutral salts, (3) sodium bicarbonate, and (4) solvents for pectic substances. Acid solutions.—Because of the effect on imbibition of water from breaks in the seed coats of the beans, a portion of those used for the acid studies were selected so that they were free from visible breaks. For the first acid studies, twenty grams of beans, which were weighed on a Chainomatic balance, were used. The beans were soaked for five hours at a temperature of 120° F. Two variations in procedure followed the soaking. In one the beans were washed with, and cooked in, distilled water. In the other the solu - :ion was neutralized with Table i. — Effect of acids on imbibition oj sodium bicarbonate and the ~® Srams of Great Northern beans— beans cooked in the neutral- average oj three trials with soaking at ized solution. The acids chosen 120 ° F - were hydrochloric, represent- , Gain in Gain in . I . v"' Normality m. when »t. when ing an inorganic acid and one . . »rted coofced having a high degree of ioni- '.«. r.tt zarion, and acetic, represent- I'y'"' H|"" r"' »•¦» 'i.oo w .oo I 1 "-'" Hydrochloric 0.03 71.00 120 00 ing an organic acid and one Hruwnioric o.m 7CM &#132;0 00 having a low degree of ioni- MyoWhioricl &lt;U3 7UK) 67m~. zation. The acids were used "vd"*hl""c &lt;&gt;¦&lt;» 75.n0 123.00 in the following concentra- -" y'"'K''""' &lt; »m »7M _ lion,: 033 normal, 0.10 no, £ ££ J^J mal, 0.03 normal, 0.01 M""' w&gt;i -om kjo.oo normal. Acetic' dm , woo Controls with distilled Ace"c ow 70M '«•«&gt; water were used for compari- ~ '»M__ son. Typical results are shown , ™ 12fL_ in T-&gt;UI» 7 TL Li 1 CooVed in iliiiilleil waicr. m Table 3. The table shows -Cooked in ,oakin e .olu.ion neu, r a/ iz ed with .odium that the acids tended to de- "'""""""¦ press ,he imbibition of water and the depression generally increased with increased strength of acid. The effect on the beans of the 0.01 normal acid was slight, but the seed coats were very tough with the 0.33 normaJ </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Table 4.— Effect. of acids on 100 grams of beans selected without visual breads in the seed coats— . ..',' ; ¦ average of three trials. '. ¦¦ . ¦ : Pea beans '¦¦¦¦. . . Great Northern ¦ Acid Normality Cain in Cain in Gain in Gain in . ¦ . . weight weight ' . Results, weight weight . Results ' ¦ '„': -. , soaked cooked .. ¦¦ soaked cooked • . ¦ P. ct. /'. ct. P. a. . ..¦•¦. p. a. !P. cl. "r * ~~. ~ T" r ~ . -¦¦ Hydrochloric 1 0.33 ' 83.00 . 87.00 Very hard, coats intact ¦ '¦ 65.00 119.00 Coatj very hard, many loose Hydrochloric 0.03 87.00 113.00 Hard, coals intact 80.00 137.00 Coals hard, beans soft Hydrochloric 0.01 90,00 H2.00 Mure like control 83.00 163.00 Similar 10 control Hydrochloric' 0.33 ,82.00 107.00 Coats loose, cotyledons very soft 58.00 . 116.00 Coats loose, flavor and appearance undesirable Hydrochloric 0.03 86.00 93.00 Hard 67.00 141.00 Coats loose, flavor and appearance undesirable Hydrochloric 0.01 ' 88.00 12G.00 More like control 75.00 ' 173.00 Similar to control O Acetic 1 • ¦ 033 80.00 119.00 Very hard, coals intact ¦ 78.00 130.00 Very hard '~~~ ' ' ' r 9 Acetic 0.03 85.00 102.00 Hard coals, intact 80.00 KH.OO Hard ' . ¦ Acetic 0.01 92.00 140.00 Similar to control 83.00 175.00 Similar to conirol 3 Acetic* OJ3 — 78.00 99.00 Very hard, disagreeable flavor 78.00 . 132.00 Mushy, coats loose, tough, undesirable O Acetic 0.03 87.00 " Softer than above 84.00 170.00 Softer than above _ Acetic . 0,01 91.00 164.00 Similar to control 88.00 167.00 Similar to control &lt;O Distilled water ... 93.00 144.00 Soft 87.00 , 174.00 Soft ¦ . § 1 Cooked in distilled water.. ' ¦¦, ¦ ..¦, H 3Cookcd in soaking solution neutralized with sodium bicarbonate. ¦''.'.., '. .'. - . X .¦¦•'¦¦ Table s. — Effect of adds on 100 grams of beans selected without regard to breads in the seed coats — ° -¦"¦ • . ¦ average of three trials. 1 .bo ¦ . Pea beans ~~- ' [ ~~- ' Great Northern -.' " ' 2 ' . Gain in Gain in &#132; • Gain in Gain in ' ¦ .. \ ¦ ¦vt . Acid . Normality weight , weight . Results . weight ' . Results . ' soaked cooked Soaked ' cooked ¦__•¦ r. a. p. a. P. a. r. ct. p. a. ' ~ ~~\- : " Hydrochloric 0.33 ..:. Coats very tough . 52.00 113.00 Coats tough, loosened, beans soft Hydrochloric 0.10 79.00 117.00 Coatt very tough 54.00 124.00 Coats tough . Hydrochloric 0.03 ' 79.00 168.00 Coiu tough 57.00 139.00 Can tough ¦ . ¦ Hydrochloric 0.01 100.00 150.00 Similar to control 87.00 141.00 Similar to control Acetic OJ3 .... 7TOO 116.00 Coats very tough '. ~ ~: ~ Acetic 0.10 85.00 141.00 Coau lough 64.00 154.00 Coals very touch ¦ Acetic 0.03 87.00 134.C10 72.00 152.00 Coau tough Acetic 0.01 106.00 177.00 Similar to control 67.00 154.00 Similar to control Distilled water ... 99.00 162.00 Soft 105.00 167.00 Soft ~ 1 Before cooking, the acid soaking solutions were neutralized with NaHCO 3 , and the beans were drained and cooked in distilled water. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 acid. The interiors of the beans were soft but they gave the appearance of being hard because of the hard coverings. Acetic acid appeared to pro - duce a tougher seed coat than did hydrochloric. The beans cooked in the neutralized solutions were more broken and less desirable in appearance than those which had been washed and cooked in distilled water. Following the study with 20-gram weights of beans, 100 grams were used, as a greater weight of beans should be more representative of any one lot. The same procedure as described above was used. Results are shown in Table 4. The results in Table 4 are similar to those in Table 3. There is shown the same general trend of depressed imbibition of water with the acids and the same toughness of the seed coat. Further studies were made of the effects of acids on beans selected without regard to breaks in the seed coats. The soaking procedure was the same as that reported in the previous acid studies, but differed in that the soaking solution and beans were neutralized with sodium bicarbonate, the beans washed with distilled water, and cooked in distilled water Typical results are shown in Table 5. While the variations are less con - sistent than with the more carefully selected beans, there are similar general tendencies, and in no case were results as desirable as with the control. Tests were made with beans of both types—from various sources and various Jots. While there were wide variations in soaked and cooked weights of beans from different lots, the same general relative trends were shown from results with the acids as compared with the controls. Since the preceding studies indicated that for the procedures used the hardening effect of the acid treatment was on the seed coats only, further verification appeared advisable. To determine the effect of the acid solu - tions on the cotyledons of the beans, the seed coats were removed. Twenty grams of bean cotyledons were soaked and cooked in the acid solutions. The beans were cooked in earthen containers in the oven to prevent com - plications from the action of acid on aluminum. Controls were soaked and cooked in distilled water. Results are shown in Table 6. The beans which were soaked and cooked in the hydrochloric acid solutions were very soft, becoming gelatinous on standing. Those in acetic acid solutions were less soft than in hydrochloric, and the form of the bean was retained. Longer cooking increased the tenderness of the beans cooked in acetic acid. The controls were cooked to pulp. Table 6 shows that for both the controls and the acid-treated bean cotyledons, the percentage gain in weight was higher at room temperature than at 120° F. Reference to Figure 1 shows that beans with seed coats intact absorbed water more rapidly at a temperature of 120° F. than at lower temperatures. The percentage gain in weight from soaking of the controls as compared with the acid treated bean cotyledons was less than that shown in Table 3 where the entire bean was used. A few checks with 033 normal oxalic acid as the soaking solution showed that the effects of this acid were dissimilar to those of acetic and hydrochloric acids. Water imbibition was not depressed and the seed coats. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">CooKiNc Quality of Beans Table 6.—Effects of acids on 20 grams of cotyledons of Great Northern beans—average of three trials. 7m ~ I w«™,.r« (Temperature I Gain In wt~( Result Add | Normality I torKaking | whcatoaked I whencooied j P.ct. Dct.F. P. a. Hydrochloric | 0.33 120 ,72.00 Could not weigh : 75 to 80 85.00 . Very toft Hydrochloric; .....0.03 120 74.00 Very wfr ' . . . , 75 to 80 87.00 Very loft Hydrochloric 0.01 120 ; 71.00 Very loft 75 to 80 98.00 Vctj lolt Acclte •• 0.33 120 64.00 Leu toft than In HCI ' Wto 80 75.00 Lot wft than in HCI Acenc • 0-03 120 69.00 Lett wft than In HCI '5 to 80: 85.00 Leu toft than in HCI *««.... :.. 0.01 120 75.00 Leu toft than in HCI i 75 to 80 90.00 Leu toft than In HCI Control, diitlllcd mlcr 120 76.00 Pulp ¦ " -¦ ' ' - ... ¦ 75 to 80 92.00 Pulp . did not appear as hard in the latter. Obviously the use of this acid would be impossible in the preparation of an edible product, but the results sug - gest further investigation because of the possibility that calcium salts are present. Oxalic acid renders calcium insoluble, while hydrochloric would be expected to attack it. Table 7.— Analyses of'natural hard waters. Nature of hardness Western Manhattan, Edgemont, Blair, Marshall Co., , Sprints, 111. Kant. S.Dak. Nebr. Kant. Temporary hardness (alkalinity)...... 161.0 179.0 180.0 295.0 281.0 Permanent nardncjt........;.. 650.0 63.0 388.0 0.0 450.0 Total hardnejs—f ' : ; . . :. ai calcium carboiuic per million.. 811.0 242.0 568.0 295.0 731,0 Total hardness— '.-':. : . . as milli-equivalcntt per 1iter...... 162 ¦¦ 4.8 A 11.4 5$ Calcium, milli-equivalents per liter... 5.8 2.6 62 3.1 Magnesium (by difference) 10.4 12 52 2J&gt; Ch10ride....................... Trace Medium Large Trace Sulphate Urge Trace Medium None Neutral salts.—lt has been observed that in certain localities the cooking of beans is attended by difficulties which appear to be related to the water. Waters vary in the kind and amount of mineral salts which they contain. Some waters contain only temporary hardness in the form of calcium ot magnesium bicarbonate, which can be removed by boiling (precipitated as carbonate), while some contain sulphates and chlorides of magnesium and calcium which cannot be removed by boiling. ,The latter are known as permanently hard waters. There appears to be \ considerable disagree - ment as to the nature of the action of hard water on beans. Statements have been made to the effect that calcium and magnesium sulphates unite with the protein legumin to form insoluble compounds. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85n To obtain information as to the effects of water containing mineral salts, the following studies were made. Excessively hard waters were ob - tained from different localities, and were analyzed chemically. Beans were soaked in the different hard waters and then cooked in the same water by the standard procedure. Beans which had cooked well in dis - tilled water were used for the hard-water studies and were from the same lots. Tap water (Agricultural College Campus), which contains temporary hardness, was also used. Results are shown in Table 8. The table shows that for each water used, there resulted a depression in imbibition and a high percentage of hard beans, in one case as high as 100 per cent. The percentage of hard beans increased as the soaked weights decreased. The seed coats in all cases were less tender than those of the controls. Those cooked in the tap water were similar to the con - trols. A comparison of Tables 7 and 8 shows that Table %¦—Effects of natural hard waters on as the permanent hardness imbibition of 100 grams of beans—aver - of the water increased, the age °f three trials - percentage of hard Ivans Wjlcr(l(cd \v,.«i, en \v,.»hc n.rj tended to increase. nuked cooked beam To determine the kind p ra beans and amount of mineral &lt;"¦"••&gt; a"»" ?¦&lt;•¦ ... , | . , I .ip «-.ncr. Nrl»r. which may lie detrimental .^,l. c,&gt;iic X c ws 2-n 22 to cooking, standard solu- Mjniuiun. Kj/h. i"6 mo A 6 tions of calcium and mag- " lj" sa" 176 B" 59 . . 11, hliic-mom, 5. Dak. 161 231 67 nesmm sulphates and chlo- UVilrrii Spn|)iw 1M IM 2UI M rides in concentrations ujniuii r™my. Kans. \~i 213 100 equivalent to 2,001), 1,000, ih,nii«»i ».,«, »a 253 17 500, 2=50, and 100 parts per «"»' Nonkcrn be»ai million ot calcium carbon- ''\ c !V'"&lt; r.,iWr' is* 25» 12 ate were used for cookiny d.,.i u iu. kam i 6: w 46 beans, and results compared '""r- s''lir- U2 234 7} with those when distilled f'. 1""1""1' s Djk 165 "5 « ttVilrrn Sprmci. 111. 151 2N W water was used. In these Mjr.i»iu-jm«i». k»i». i« :m 100 studies, beans were selected n..r.iir.i wa.er 200 262 2 first without regard to breaks in the seed coat, and were from the same lots. Both varieties were grown under the same cultural conditions. The standard soaking and cooking procedure was used, except that the beans were soaked and cooked in the salt solutions. Typical results are shown in Table 9. In all cases the depression of water absorption increased as the concentration of the solution increased. Solutions of calcium salts produced a somewhat more pro - nounced hardness than did those of magnesium, and there was little dif - ference between concentrations of 2,000 and 1,000 ppm. There was also less tendency for the seed coats to loosen in the calcium solutions. Solu - tions of either salt in concentrations of 2,000 ppm produced beans almost as hard as uncooked beans. Solutions of the same salts seemed equally </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Cooking Quality of Beans Table 9.—Effect of standard hard waters on imbibition of 100 grams of beans selected without regard to breaks in seed coats. - '*' Pea beans Great Northern beans Solution Cain in ' din in Gain in I Gain in weight. weight Hard weight weight Hard . " foaked ' cooked beans soaked cooked beans P.». P. &lt;¦/. P. a. p. a. P. a. P. a. Calcium chloride. ¦'.¦'¦ - : 2,000 ppm -81 107 100 |79 . 107 100 1,000 ppra. ¦ . V .M 109 100 75 105 100 500 ppm 83 111 . Seed coats tough, i7O 115 .Seed coats tough. -Iniitlcs soft. ( Iniidcs fairly 150 ppm 99 174 Less tough. soli. 100 ppm SlighlijT tougher 99 : 164 Less lough. than controls. 107 160 Slightly tougher - ': , ¦ than controls. Calcium sulphate . ¦ . ' 2.000 pprri .81 106 100 79 111 100 1,000 ppm . 81 106 100 -I 81 109 100 500 ppm 103 119 Seed coals tough. '85 133 Seed coals lough. Irutdes soft.' . - ¦ lnsides soft. 100 ppm . . .". i 108 167 Slightly tougher . _...-. \ ¦ than eontroli. Magnesium chloride 2,000 ppm 87 113 100 89 122 100 : 1,000 ppm 87 115 Slightly less 98 161 ' Slightly leu hard than above. tough than above. : . . More broken ' . i ' ' ' " than in calcium. : . I 500 ppm ¦ 87 . .115 . ..... ¦«¦¦'.' '59 Lel« tough than ,- -. - ¦ ..-¦¦-¦'. above. 250 ppm 97 1M .;. 97 162 Less tough than ,„' ¦ : ¦ . ¦ ¦¦'¦¦¦ above. - -10" PPm ¦,¦" 103 171 More like ' ¦ ¦. . '¦¦..-.' ' ¦, controls. Magnesium sulphate ¦ ' ¦ : -..-.' ¦ ' - ¦ ' ' ?i ¦ '* 2.000 ppm 87 119 100 i.M !. ¦ ; "9: 100 1,000 ppm 85 . 131 Slightly lest ¦ 80 1 128' Slightly less hard than above. •¦';.. ' tough than above. 500 ppm ¦ 86 135 .... .88: 1« . ... 250 ppm .... ". 98 j .164 ' ... 100 ppm » 156 .'¦-•-¦.... M.J 163 ... Dillilled water 102 153 17 . 109 162 2 effective whether as chlorides or sulphates. In the magnesium solutions in concentrations of 1,000 ppm the hardness, was less perceptible than for 2,000 ppm. Longer cooking failed to sohen the seed coats cooked in either solution. With concentrations of 500 ppm the hardness was less evident than in more concentrated solutions but was noticeably greater than for the controls. Following the above, further study was made using beans selected without visible breaks in the seed coat so that water uptake through breaks was reduced to the minimum. Typical results are shown in Table 10. The table shows the same, tendencies but with greater consistency than those reported in Table 9, i.e., depressed imbibition arid hardness of the seed coat. Again the effects from calcium appeared somewhat more pronounced - than those from magnesium. To determine if the hardening effect from solutions of calcium and magnesium salts was on the seed coats alone, studies were made on the cotyledons of the beans as was done with the acid solutions. Twenty .-¦*¦..- ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 grams were used. They were soaked and cooked in the various natural hard waters and in the standard solutions in concentrations of 2,000 ppm. For comparison, equal weights of whole beans were treated in the same way. The cotyledons were cooked into pulp with one exception, those cooked in water from Marshall county, Kansas. In the latter, the form was retained and the beans were relatively hard. Results from the standard solutions are shown in Table 11. The table shows that for the cotyledons alone the percentage gain in soaked weights is as high as that of the control. The controls were cooked into pulp and those in the magnesium solutions were very soft, while in the calcium solutions the beans were soft but Table 10.— Effect of standard hard water solutions on imbibition of 100 grams of beans selected without visual breads in the seed coat — average of three trials. Pea Iwram Great Northern beans Solution Gain in weight Gain in weight Soaked | Cooked Soaked | Cooked pc:. P. a. P. a. P- "¦ Calcium chloride, 2.000 ppm .... 85 91 88 110 1.000 ppm 90 107 86 115 Calcium sulphate, 2,000 ppm . 87 101 8! 116 1,000 ppm M U3 82 118 Magnesium chloride, 2,0O) ppm 86 % 83 118 1,000 ppm »9 IH SS 133 Magnesium nilplule, 2,000 ppm . H6 101 81 122 1,000 ppm 89 129 89 133 Di.ulled »ater 89 I 2» 89 133 retained their form. They were similar in appearance to the beans cooked in acetic acid solutions. Comparison of percentage of gain in the soaked weights of the bean cotyledons with those of the whole beans shows the former to be considerably higher, indicating that the effect of the hard water is on the seed coat alone. Following the studies with calcium and magnesium salts, both salts of bivalent metals, studies were made to determine if the effects of solutions of sodium and potassium chloride, salts of monovalent metals, were sim - ilar. Results are shown in Table 12. There appeared to be no deleterious effects from either of the sodium or the potassium salts used; the imbibi - tion of water was somewhat improved and the seed coats were tender. Solutions of these salts at concentrations of 4,000 ppm, or double the maximum used for calcium and magnesium, were used with no observable ¦ effects. Since the effects upon the bean seed coats of the use of solutions of salts of bivalent and monovalent metals were dissimilar, information on the effects of a solution of a salt of a trivalent metal was obtained. A </seg>
         <seg id="p021">i . Cooking Quality of Beans .'. Table 11.— Effect of standard hard waters on imbibition of 20 grams of % Great Northern beans with and without seed coats. V Gain in weight Gain in weight ~~ :/ ... . Solution with teed coati without iced CMU ;}'¦ Soaked ) Cooked Soaked | Cooked ¦ ¦•¦¦«. —- ¦•¦ s solution of aluminum chloride with a concentration of 2,000 ppm was used in soaking and cooking the beans. The hardening effect upon the seed coats was very pronounced and similar to that of calcium and mag - nesium. The results may possibly be related to the effects of hydrochloric cht'arid Chl°"de itt solution hydrol yz«» forming hydro- Table \2.—Effect of solutions of salts of alkali metals on imbibition of 100 grams of beans. ¦ _¦.•;'.:¦¦¦. r* boni Great Northern beuu Solution. Gain in weight G, in in wtl^t | Soaked | Cooked Soaked | Cooked *¦"• P.«. P.rt. p a Pouniutn chloride ¦- .. - 84 Pouiiium nilphate " M ,'J Sodium chloride....:.. " " 83 : • Sodium sulphate...;; '.......',. . : ¦ 5 «i ' " iftOOppm " ~ ~ ~~ ! ' ' ' ; —~ Potanium chloride ::.................. M H8 85 m Polawium .ulphaie.. „... 93 H7 90 --'- 173 .....-¦ Sodium chloride 95 j 57 0 , )60 Sodhmmlphale..,.....-. 94 ,; 8 w m Diitilled water .......; 03 ISI 82 I^~~ Sodium bicarbonate.—The practice of adding sodium bicarbonate, a salt mildly alkaline in reaction, to the cooking water of dry beans is an old one. Reasons for its use appear to vary. In some cases it appears to ; be added for the purpose of softening the water and in others for the ¦-¦- purpose of softening the beans and reducing the time of cooking. In general, writers on nutrition regard its use with disfavor. Objections given are that it decomposes the proteins in the beans and renders them less nutritious and that it attacks vitamin B. While this study is outside the field of nutrition, that phase should not be ignored. Solutions of sodium bicarbonate were used in concentrations of 0.1 normal, 0.02 normal, 0.03 normal, and 0.0.1 normal for soaking beans, after which they were washed and cooked in distilled water. Results are shown in Table 13. </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 In concentrations greater than 0.01 normal there resulted many broken beans, but there was no perceptible odor or taste of soda in concentrations less than 0.10 normal. Water absorption was not decreased by the addition of soda, and the seed coats were tender. Results were undesirable when soda solutions were used for cooking, as the beans became mushy and dark in color. Therefore, an attempt was made to determine the minimum amount of soda which might be used effectively, both in soaking and cook - ing, using units of measure- _ , . , &#132; ment which were practicable T\ BLE of solntwns o sodmm for household use. Various &gt;&gt;,carbo n at e on imbibmon of 100 grams trials showed that soda to the "' beans - amount of one-eighth tea- Gain in weight spoon to one pint of water Soaked | cooked was sufficient to give benc- p a JT^ ficial results when distilled o.jo 91 173 water was used. «n&lt; " ¦ 15! c - £ ¦ (1112 IOH 168 Smce soft water .s not (m ,„, m always available for cooking m.ullc.l waici 15 16! purposes and the use of hard water is the only alternative, studies were made to determine the minimum amount of soda which could be used effectively with various natural hard waters. Both soda and water were carefully measured. The solution was allowed to reach the boiling point, after which it was filtered and used for cooking. It was found that one-eighth teaspoon of soda per pint of water was sufficient with all except one (Marshall county, Kansas) of the natural hard waters used, and for this water one-fourth teaspoon of soda per pint of water was sufficient. The beans cooked in the soda-treated water were desirable in flavor and appearance and comp - arable to those cooked in distilled water. The amount of soda necessary can easily be determined by trial for any water and the common practice of adding it in excessive amounts avoided. For the commercial canner chemical water-softeners would be indicated where available water is so hard that effects are deleterious. The practice of adding molasses and tomato juice or pulp to beans as seasoning is common, both commercially and in the household. Results from the studies of the effects of solutions of calcium and magnesium salts and of acids suggested that the hardness which is sometimes found in cooked beans might be a result of the calcium and magnesium present in molasses or of the acid present in tomato juice when these are added as seasoning. To verify the above, beans were cooked in solutions of distilled water and molasses of a common commercial brand, and in tomato juice and pulp in amount comparable to that used as seasoning. In both cases effects on the seed coats were similar to those from the addition of acetic acid and calcium and magnesium salts—-a very definite hardness. However, if the beans are cooked before adding the seasonings the result is not objectionable. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Cooking Quality of Beans Sugar solutions.—Concentrated sugar solutions were also found to have a hardening effect on the beans, but when used in small amounts such as are used for seasoning beans, the effects were not preceptible. Pectic solvents.—The results obtained from the use of the various solu - tions as described above, indicated that the presence of pectic constituents, which are considered to be the cementing substances holding the cells of plant tissues together, might account for the difficulty encountered in the softening of the seed coats of beans and might be related to the variable permeability of the seed coat. 5 A list of the pectic substances which are now recognized by workers in this field, together with some of their Table 14.— Effect of pectic solvents on the seed coats and imbibition of 100 grams of beans — average of two trials. - c i • " Gain in wt. Gain in wt. . „ , ' ¦ - Solvent . . .oakcd cooled """'•• ¦ /'. Cl, TTI. '.. : : ': ~" ; .... . Pea bean, Michigan ¦'"..'."' -: Ammonium online, 1% 99 165 Very soft iced coals. Seed coat! diiimcgrated. . . No discoloration. ¦ ¦ Ammonium citrate, 1% 92 162 Soft. Less effective than oxalatc. No discoloration. Ammonium tanrate, 1% 91 155 Soft, Ceil effective than nxalate or citrate. No discoloration. Distilled water 93 151 Soft. Seed coats not disintegrated. ...' ¦ . Greal Northern bean Ammonium onalatc, 1% 119 184. Very soft. No discoloration. Seed coatl disintegrated. Ammonium citrate, 1% 98 185 Soft. No discoloration. Less disintegration than with :' . . - . oxaklc. - - j ¦ Ammonium tartrate, 1% M 163 Soft. No discoloration. Leis disintegration than will ¦. - oxalalc. Distilled water......... 99 158 Soft. Seed (oats not disintegrated. properties, are as follows: (1) Pectose—the "parent" substance of pectin, insoluble in water, insoluble in alkaline solution,, hydrolyzed by acids; (2) pectin—the methyl ester o£ pectic acid, soluble in water, hydrolyzed by alkaline solution; (3) pectic acid—very slightly soluble in water, soluble in alkaline solution, precipitated by acid, soluble in solutions of ammonium salts of organic acids; (4) salts of pectic acid—those of Ca and Mg being insoluble in water, soluble in ammonium salts of organic acids." The solutions commonly used for extraction of insoluble pectic materials are ammonium oxa/ate, citrate, and tartrate. While there are valid objections to these solutions for use in food preparation, it was believed that for ex - perimental purposes a study of their effects upon the seed coats of beans should be valuable as an indication of the composition of the seed coats. Accordingly 1 per cent solutions of the above solvents were used for soak - ing and cooking beans. Results are shown in Table 14. •All analytical work on the seed coali of beam was done under the direction of Dr. M. l. Blish, Chairman of the Department of Agricultural Chemistry, University of Nebraska. . by the committee on the nomenclature of pectins of. the Agricultural Food Division ot the American Chemical Society, Sept. 6-11, 1926. </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 The table shows that in general both the soaked and cooked weights of the beans are greater when cooked in the extracting solutions. The most pronounced disintegration of the seed coats occurred from the oxalate, although the citrate is considered by Conrad to be just as effective as a pectic solvent. 7 It will be recalled that the effect of oxalic acid on the seed coats was less deleterious than that of hydrochloric and acetic acid. As a whole these results showed clearly that some constituent which was soluble in these solutions had been removed from the seed coats of the beans, resulting in greater softening and intake of water. Alcohol has long been used to precipitate pectic substances, but recent investigators prefer a procedure which consists of converting all pectic constituents to calcium pectate, which is insoluble. The objection to the use of alcohol is based on its property of precipitating other than pectic substances and that it fails to completely precipitate pectic substances in very dilute solution. Alcohol, however, was used as a rough qualitative test with the liquid from the cooked beans. Bulky precipitates of a jelly-like nature were obtained. While these precipitates appeared to be pectic jells, it seemed probable that other constituents were also present. Hydrochloric acid, which is a recognized test for pectic acid, giving a clear, gelatinous pre - cipitate, was used with positive result. The addition of calcium chloride also gave a gelatinous precipitate, which was, of course, contaminated with calcium oxalate. The qualitative results were so strongly indicative of the presence of pectic constituents in the seed coats of the beans that a quantitative analysis appeared justified. Beans were accordingly soaked in distilled water at room temperature until the seed coats could be removed. The seed coats were dropped into 95 per cent alcohol to prevent any action from enzymes. After drying with alcohol for 24 hours they were air dried until it was possible to grind them. They were ground to pass a one-half millimeter sieve. The procedure used for analysis was based upon the method now generally used by investigators for quantitative determination of pectic substances, that of convening all pectic constituents into calcium pectate. The method as adapted for use in this study was found to give comparable results and was as follows: Five grams of the finely ground bean seed coats were extracted with 0.03 normal hydrochloric acid for one-half to one hour in a 100-cc. flask over a water bath. The treatment with hydrochloric acid is generally used for the purpose of hydrolyzing pectose which may be present. Conrad found that the preliminary treat - ment with hydrochloric acid also facilitated the extraction of pectic acid from vegetable materials by ammonium salts. In developing the method used here, it was likewise found that a greater amount of pectic material was extracted by the ammonium salts following the hydrochloric acid treatment than when the latter was used alone. IC. M. Conrad. A biochemical study of the insoluble pectic substances in vegetables, Maryland Experiment Station. Am. lour. o( Botany VI:SJMB. </seg>
         <seg id="p025">¦ Cooking Quality of Beans j : The solution was neutralized with sodium hydroxide and ammonium ; ¦¦ oxalatc added to make a 0.5 per cent solution, after which the material : ; was extracted for one-half hour over the water bath. One extraction with - ¦ ammonium oxalatc appeared sufficient to remove all pectic constituents. The solution was made to the 100-cc. mark and filtered through filter ; paper pulp in a Buchner funnel by means of a vacuum pump. The filtrate was tested for protein to determine if any had been extracted by the ara - . : monium oxalate, but only a slight trace was found to be present. Aliquots of 25 cc. were used for making determinations of pectic material. Each aliquot was acidified with acetic acid and 75 cc of methyl alcohol was added, which precipitated bulky jells. After standing over night the jells were filtered in an ordinary filter and washed with methyl alcohol. The filter paper had been previously vacuum dried and weighed ; in weighing bottles. The jell was dried in a vacuum oven and weighed, this weight being pectic material plus other substances precipitated with . alcohol—probably gums. The dried residue and filter paper were placed in beakers with 50 cc. of distilled water, made alkaline with ammonium hydroxide, and boiled until all material was dissolved. The solution was again filtered, acidified with acetic acid, and the pectic acid precipitated with 20 cc. of molar calcium chloride. After standing several hours, the calcium jells were boiled tor five minutes, washed with at least 400 cc. of boiling water, filtered through dried and weighed filter paper, and finally vacuum dried in weighing botdes. Results are shown in Table 15. The final weights give the pectic constituents in terms of calcium pectate. The difference in weight between the alcohol precipitates and the: calcium pectate probably represents gums. jj Tablels.— Pecticcontent of seed'coats of beans, expressed as Ji' calcium pectate} II ' ~~ ~ ~~ Wl. of dry Wt. of dry I Difference H Source Type Extracting agtnt alcohol calcium (probably Calcium jl . ... precipitate pectate gumi) pectttc U ...:..: ' Cram Gram . Gram P. et. j Nebraika Great 0.03 hydrochloric acid, followed b)r V Northern 05 per cent ammonium oxalate 03231 0.2333 . 0.0898 18.6 1 ¦ Ammonium oxalate alone ';.. 0.2246 0.1490 . ..... 115 , ' Idaho Great 1 0.03 hydrochloric acid, followed bjr , Northern 0.5 per cent ammonium oxalate 0J293 0.2214 O.IOW 17.7 Ammonium oxalate a10ne.... 0.2635 0.1940 . 15 j . Michigan Pea bean 0.03 hydrochloric acid, followed by 0-5 per cent ammonium oxalate 0.36(9 0.2354 0.1295 18.8 ;..'.-: Ammonium oxalate a10ne.:...... 0.2477 0.1895 - 15.1 'One and one-fourth grami of Ked-coat material to each aliquot. 1 Further verification of the pectic-acid content of the seed coats was . made by comparing the optical activity of pectic acid made by converting purified pectin to pectic acid, with that of the pectic material extracted </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 from the bean seed coats. The agreement was close, that from the bean material giving a rotation of [aJ D + 232 c, from one purified pectin "T~225°, and from another +230°, all of which are in fair agreement with ' that given for pectic acid by other investigators. The remainder of the material, which was precipitated by alcohol and was assumed to be gum, gave a rotation of [i)d~ 100°, which is fairly close to a value of —110° found on a sample of gum isolated from wheat flour. The results from the analysis for pectic material suggested a possible difference in pectic content between the seed coats of beans which readily imbibed water and those which resisted water. Beans of both types were allowed to soak in water at room temperature. After a period of five to six hours the beans which had swelled were selected and the seed coats removed as described previously. Those which had failed to imbibe water after 24 hours of soaking were scarified and soaked again so that the seed coats could be removed. The seed coats were dried and ground and analy7.ed for pectic content by the method already described. In order that other differences in the two selected portions of bean seed coats might be noted, the amounts of the following constituents were also determined: protein, calcium, magnesium, fats, and lecithins. Standard procedures were used for all of the determinations made. In addition to the seed coats from beans selected on the basis of water imbibition, the determina - tions were made also on seed coats from Montana and Colorado beans. ( Results are shown in Table 16. ! Table 16.— Percentages calculated on the basis of dry weights of calcium, magnesium, fats, lecithins, calcium pectate, and gums in seed coats of beans. Sourer ITipc Mmsiim fl'iMcm I V.ili l.rothins| (a Me JTolal Jlh )Ci pctuicjcums' I" "¦ '' ¦¦¦ '' ¦ I" " I 1 .(. I' a. r. Cl. P.a. P.ct. ¦ Acbr ' 1.rv.11 N'.ntKrn lul ii v 22 &lt;i ]&lt;( &gt;t 0.44 18 6 8.0 Ncbr." &lt;.rr.,, Virlllrrn I 1.6 "1 n.22 11.19 2.1 0.4/ 21.6 4.0 Mich. 1 I'r.i Xii 5(, (1.44 0.2S 15 050 24.5 4.0 Mi&lt;h." IVa -i.l h.h 11.31 0 is ].» 0.4 X 24.3 2.4 Colo- IV.i ".« "(1 11.46 0.77 I.H 0.16 Mont, (.rrjl Siirlhern 7.S I.Y. (14? (i.hT 2.6 0.40 .. = Uaho l,ir.u '.'¦ s""'"rn l.« 0.16 6.2 Mich. IV., 17 04 j 51 Schr. 1.rr.11 ; N""1"''" 2.5 0.45 6.0 .. i 1 Sclcticil on b.iin i.l wjrer upukc "iofi" '! 'Srlecml on K,m, &#132;( «.,it, upu k. ¦¦• lucj". '! 1 By ihlfrrciu-r. j Results as shown in Table 16 do not show consistent differences in I pectic content of the selected seed coats. However, the part taken in water absorption by the micropyle is a variable factor which could not be measured. Therefore, this method could scarcely be relied upon as pro - t { / j </seg>
         <seg id="p027">,_¦'¦¦: Cooking Quality of Beans viding an accurate basis for selecting hard- from soft-shelled beans. A more precise method would be necessary before differences in pectic con - tent could be determined, and further study is suggested. The results showing protein content are also suggestive, because the "hard" shells appear to contain a greater amount of protein. Most significant of all dif - ferences is the greater calcium content of the Great Northern as compared to the pea bean. _ In Table 17 is shown Table and total ash content of a comparison of calcium whole beans, seed coats, and beans minus content of the bean seed ™c seed coats, calculated on the basis of dry coat as compared to the w^ght. cotyledons alone and the -¦ _¦ • ! ' ~~~~— whole bean. The rela- ?"'*"""""" ; Calci"m; S%t , lively higher percentage ~~ ~~~~-. c.a. 7^i. ~7^. ' of calcium'in the seed WWc-ta» ••••¦ O.llio 4.67 100.00 coats as compared to the f^.T""- """ 2Am m U7 1 1 J*^., . whole bra" minus seed cmi 0.0373' 4,18 92 83 cotyledons is striking. : " ' PRACTICAL STUDIES I Tr(e studies reported above were all confined to surface-burner cookery Any study of bean cookery would be incomplete without attention to the oven method. The conventional procedure for baking beans consists of soaking and parboilmg, followed by a relatively long period of baking at a low temperature-often as long as eight or twelve hours. The lone cookmg period has been considered necessary to produce the desired con - sistency and baked bean" flavor. Various seasonings are added to eive variety and flavor. A procedure which would give the desired flavor and consistency without the excessive consumption of time and fuel would be advantageous from a practical and economic standpoint. With the aim of developing such a method, the following oven studies were made All baking was done in an insulated electric oven with thermostatic control. Ihe oven contained upper and; lower units of 1,500 watts each. To deter - mine the effect of the various soaking and cooking combinations on time required, the aluminum pans were used for boiling, and baking was done in earthenware dishes. . The reader will recall that the "best cooking" beans used in the study were well done in one and one-fourth hours, when cooked on a surface burner, alter soaking five hours at approximately 120° R Such beans are however, quite different in flavor from baked beans. In amounts of 100 grams the beans were cooked by the procedures listed in Table 18 s The results in Table 18 are of significance only in showing that for any procedure used, a tender product resulted in a reasonably short time, ' and that beans which cook tender by top-burner methods will also cook tender '" the oven- h was not necessary that such beans be parboiled, or v^'lJ^/X^jl^'! bc"" could be * " "uick*- "°«M "¦' »&gt;'-'» I </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 Table 18.— Time of soaring, parboiling, and baling required for beans to coo\ tender at 500° and 300° F. Variety Time Time Time Thermostat soaked parboiled id oven setting ""¦ Hn. Hn. Dtg. F. Great Northern 5 i^ p.; cqa P" b°" 5 X 2-2% 500 Great Northern 5 0 ii/.! 300 p" ¦*" 5 0 2-4-3 300 Great Northern 0 0 2'A 500 "" ¦*"¦ 0 0 3-W 500 Great Northern 0 0 3-3 Un P° ¦*»¦¦ 0 0 MX 300 even soaked, and either or both procedures may be eliminated if it is more convenient to do so. With the use of a coal or wood range that is in operation throughout the day, it might be advisable to eliminate both soaking and parboiling. Beans which have not been soaked tend to be darker but for baked beans this is not objectionable. Following the above studies, beans were baked in earthenware baking dishes and with seasonings. The amounts used were: 200 grams dry beans (approximately 1 cup) ' 1 tablespoon molasses or V\ tablespoon brown sugar l/i teaspoon mustard salt *50 prams salt pork or bacon Water to vary with method (approximately -i cups for both soak - ing and cooking) Seasoning added to boiling water 2nd poured over beans Table ]9.— Comparison of different jawing procedures. Procedure | So^jn. | p afh .i, ins | Bjking [ n«™«*&lt; \ ~~~ „„„,„ iatWor "" ""• Conventional overnight at ]i. sor lonnr OTI 2""'" '" .' cndcrne" "d room temp. S 5 """ c°n«&lt;l=«d optimum. Variation No. 1 o«rnipht°a't IV. 7.-3,/ „„ Well done, desirable at 2^ room temp. A 2"3 ' ™ 5»"»- "ver removed. At 3'S hours very similar to , conventional method. ViriallonN°-2 SS? None j 350 s:^sr iDI Variation No. 3 None N one „ J5O 1 ventional method. Higher oven temperatures (400° and 450° F.) produced a very satis - factory product in a shorter time, but it was necessary to use a greater amount of water and the beans were more crusty on the surface? The product, however, was palatable and attractive and fairly comparable to that resulting from longer cooking at lower temperatures </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Cooking Quality of Beans The consistency of. baked beans that appears to be generally preferred is one which is moist, with the moisture inside the beans rather than around or between them. The amount of water added is an important factor in attaining the desired consistency. The material of the baking dish, the tightness of the cover, and the temperature of the oven are all factors affecting the amount of water required. It was found that beans would absorb approximately their own weight when soaked for five hours at 120° F. or over night at room temperature. Additional water is ab - sorbed in cooking, making a total gain in weight around 150 to 160 per cent. If beans are soaked and parboiled previous to baking, they will have absorbed practically all the water possible. Additional water is added to provide for evaporation or to attain the "just moist" consistency of baked beans. The time required for baking can be reduced by avoiding excess water or by completing the baking with the cover off. The addi - tion of water during the baking may be required, especially if the oven temperature is high. If, however, the beans are not soaked or parboiled previous to baking, sufficient water must be added to provide for the total uptake. The method used should be determined by cost of fuel and atten - tion required during baking. The results of variations from the conven - tional method would seem to give little justification for the excessively long baking period, either for flavor or tenderness, when economy of time, labor, or fuel must be considered. ; The addition of molasses in amounts of 2 to 3 tablespoons per 200 grams of beans resulted in a perceptible toughness of seed coats, but because of.tVie flavor contributed, the eflect was less obvious than from calcium and magnesium alone. The addition of brown sugar resulted in no deleterious effect. "•:':¦'.'."¦]¦ The baking studies were repeated with calcium and magnesium sul - phates and chlorides in concentrations of 2,000 ppm in place of distilled water. The toughness seemed less objectionable than from surface-burner methods alone, possibly because of longer cooking with oven conditions, or possibly .because the flavor of the baked bean obviated or masked the undesirable effects. The effects on the beans baked in the magnesium solutions were less obvious than those in the calcium solutions. .'"?: DISCUSSION OF RESULTS The result of the experimental work in this study show quite definitely that properties of the seed coat of the bean and of the germinal area are the important factors determining the cooking quality. Under ordinary storage conditions the percentage of bean cotyledons failing to become "tender with the admission of water would be small. Such beans would be largely eliminated by sorting, and are probably not important from the standpoint of practical cookery. The initial natural entrance of water into the bean is through the micropyle and germinal regions. The passage of water through the general surface is limited by the permeability of the seed coat, a'property varying widely in different beans. The tenderness of </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 85 the cooked seed is related to its capacity to imbibe water, and this capacity appears to be determined by its structure and composition. A certain amount of imbibition by the seed coat itself is necessary before water can be transmitted through it to the bean. Where water passes through the micropyle and germinal area alone, that imbibed by the seed coat must come from between this area and the cotyledon or pass between layers of. the seed coat directly from the micropyle. ', Most of the studies on permeability of seed coats have been done from the standpoint of germination, but are closely related to the problems in - volved in the cookery of seeds used for food. From the standpoint of both bean cookery and germination of the bean seed, differences in permea - bility may be grouped under three heads: (1) those due to structural or chemical variations initially present in the seed coats; (2) those resulting from environmental conditions during harvesting and storage; and (3) those due to the effect of chemical solutions or solutions other than pure water. Recent opinions appear to support the conclusion that delayed germination in legumes is due to the seed-coat structure and composition rather than to the conditions of the embryo. Pammcl as early as 1899 re - potted the finding of what he termed a "cuticle" containing a fatty or waxy material repellent to water and covering the legume seeds. He con - cluded that the greater part of the water was taken up by the micropyle and hilar groove." Denny worked with various seed coats, including the peanut, and concluded that semi-permeability was due to fatty substances, pectic substances, and tannins.'" Coe and Martin found that differences in permeable and impermeable sweet-clover seeds were due to physical rather than chemical structure and that the absorption of water in the latter was prevented by the "light line". 11 They were unable to determine the chemical nature of the light line (except the upper portion, where they identified callose), as the greater part of it failed to react to microchemical tests. In their opinion the negative results were due to the greater density of the light line.' 2 Lute studied impermeable seeds of alfalfa and found the impermeable layers to be in the outer end of the palisade cells, their reactions being such as to indicate pectin-like structure. Along the tips of the palisade cells she identified the light line. She found that the water intake was not governed by the cuticle. 13 The second type of variation in permeability, that due to environ - mental conditions in harvesting or storage, appears to be closely related to temperature and moisture. Gloyer found that beans which had developed hard shells regained moisture readily when placed in a moist atmosphere. He explains greater persistence of hardness of shells when immersed in ¦ 1.. H. Pammcl. Transactions of St. Louis Academy of Sciences, 1H99. 111 F. F. Denny. Permeability of certain plant membranes to water, Itolanical Gazette, (J3H6B-85, 1917. v H. S. Coe ami |. N\ Martin. Structure anil chemical nature of the seedcoat and Its relation to impermeable seed* of su-eel clover. U. S. I). A. Hill. H4-), I'art 11. 1920. v The "light line** it composed of a compact region of Maipighian layer running transversely across the lone dumtlcr of the edit, differing possibly in molecular structure or it possibly is a result of physical or chemical variations from other portions. It is conspicuous because of its ability to refract light more than regions above or below it. h is apparently not well understood. 11 Anna l.uic. Impermeable seeds of alfalfa, Colo. F.ip. Sla. Bui. 3?6, 1928. </seg>
         <seg id="p031">:.' ¦:.' ¦¦¦ Cooking Quality of Beans water as compared to moist air to be due to the greater size of the water molecule, which cannot penetrate the colloidal seed coat as readily as water in the gaseous state. ' The third type of variation in permeability, that due to the action of chemicals, is closely related to the first type because results from the use of different chemical solutions are determined'by the composition of the seed coats. All of the practical cooking tests and the chemical analysis of the seed coats of the beans indicate that the pectic constituents which appear to be in the form of pectic acid or pectates are important factors in affecting the permeability of die seed coat and its capacity to soften readily. It was found that sodiuni bicarbonate, which is alkaline and therefore should be expected to act as a solvent for pectic acid, softened the seed coats. Hydrochloric and acetic acids, which precipitate pectic acid, hardened the seed coats. Calcium and magnesium salts, which form insoluble, salts iwith pectic acid, also hardened them. Sodium and potas - sium salts did not harden the seed coats; these form soluble salts with pectic acid. The pronounced effect of known pectic solvents on the bean seed coats is supported by the results of the chemical analysis, which shows the presence of relatively large amounts of pectic acid or pectates in the bean seed coats. It would appear that the pectic materials bind the cellulose so densely that water is prevented from passing through the seed coats and from dispersing the cellulose sufficiently for tenderness. The use of limited amounts of sodium bicarbonate in practical bean cookery may be justified because of its effect upon the pectic constituents of the seed coats. It is open to question if its use in the amounts found to be effective in this study are detrimental to the nutritive value of the beans. Some destruction of vitamins in beans is probably not of vital im - portance since so many other sources are available. However, the nutritive value of the bean aside from its vitamin content is important, and its consumption is directly influenced by its payability. The addition of ex - cessive amounts of soda obviously should be avoided. Possibly the problem of developing a tender seed coat within a variety of beans is one for plant breeders. The ultimate aim should be to produce a type of bean having a seed coat the surface of. which is immediately permeable to water and which wjill itself be of such a nature that it will imbibe water with a result that the processed product is tender and palat - able. Careful selection of seeds with permeable seed coats carried over a period of years might produce the desired type. Even though such a pro - cedure proved to be long and tedious it should be profitable. Gloyer's breeding experiments carried on at Geneva, New York, gave encouraging results in the elimination of hard-shell beans.' 4 14 W. O. Glaycr, Two new varieties of red kidney beam, New York (Geneva) Slate Agr. Exp. Su. Tech. Bui. 145, 1928. . . .¦¦:,-...¦¦ . :¦¦¦'¦¦ '¦- .; ¦ ¦ : ' ¦ .:¦ ..:¦¦ ¦ ¦'¦¦¦ 13M1 </seg>
         <seg id="p032"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>