<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00001.00011">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00001.00011</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. FOR THE YEARS 1881 AND 1882.  LINCOLN, NEB.: JOURNAL COMPANY, STATE PRINTERS. 1883.</title>
               <date value="1883">1883</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-23</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2007-02-22</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>Thomas J. Wattenbarger</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item> 
         </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
THIRD BIENNIAL RKPOKT 


NKBRAJSKX INSTITUTE 

DEAF AND DUMB 

For the Years 1881 and 1882, 

LINCOLN, NEB. 

KNAL COMPANY, STATE PRINTERS. 

1888 


• </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
OFFICERS OF TIIK INSTITUTE. 

BOARI 

Lands and Buildings 

Secretary of State 

Hon. G. M. Bautlktt Treasurer"! State 

Hon. C. J. Dilworth Attorney General 

/ 

INTELLECTUAL DEPARTMENT. 

'ncipal, 

I'r 

73 


John A. McClcre, 
Frederick L. Reid, 
Fannie If. Henderson 
Margaret Pollock, 

Mary McCowen, (of Oral and Audiphone &lt; 
Lucy Butrick. Assistant. 

Hon. A. G. Kkndali Com'r of I* 
Hon. S. J. Alexander 

FOHN A. GlLLESPIE. 

Mary I. Farraxt, (of Articulation) </seg>


            <seg id="p004">
Steward, 

John A. (in.: 

Matron, 

IIki.kn '/.. QiLLB8Pli 

Physician 

I.C. Dkmsk. 


Carkik B. Dirkii 

[N8TRDCTOR8 IN INDUSTRIES. 

Btiphh F. Bucklit Printing Office 

Frkiikkh b K. Mavnakd 

Carpenter Shop 

M^RI"\ V ( '¦••¦ 

wine »rid 1 Iremmaking </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
'/'&lt;. /At Board of Public Lands and Building* 

Gentlemen: — Once more it is my duty and privilege to Mbinit 
to you i statement of the affairs of the Institute tor the 
Deaf and Dumb for the biennial period ending Nov. 30th, 1882. 

It gives me pleasure to report continued prosperity and progress 
in the work for which the institution was established and 
is maintained by the State — the education of its deaf. 

Much praise is due the faithful corps of instructors and officers 
for the fidelity with which they diacharge the manifold 
duties of their respective departments. 

Thr general conduct of the pupils has been good and their 
progress steady. 

THB ATTENDANCE 

for the period covered by this 
twenty, (120); males, (80) eig 
will be .seen that the ratio of 

report has been one hundred and 
ty; females, (40) forty. Thus it 
increase is about the same as re- 

HEALTH 

The health of the household has been good, no serious nick- 

ness having prevailed. We have had a few cases, all of which 

have, however, yielded readily to treatment and care. This con 

dition of health speaks for itself as to the sanitary condition of 

the Institute 

Under this head, however, it is my painful duty to mention 

the death by drowning of one of our brightest and best pupil 

Attie G. Page, of Omaha. lie was drowned in Cut Ott' Lake 

while skating, Dec. 18th, 1880. It is sad to record the death of 

ing and gifted as he. His education was far advanced 

o 

though but fourteen yean of ace. Be was a model youth in tin. 

ported two years agi </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 

REPORT OF THE 

school-room, in the workshop and on the play ground; hut he 
has left us and gone to that realm where his deaf ears are unstopped 
and where his dumb tongue shall ever voice the praises 
of Him who died that we might live. 

CHAN .r- 

Iew chaagei have occurred in our corps of instructors. Three 
itions have been made, Miss Effie Johnston was appointed to 
icancv caused by the withdrawal of Miss Eddy at the close of 
term 1881. Ivi i ss Johnston retired at the close of the year 
2 and was succeeded by Miss Margaret Pollock, late of the 
a Institution, who now has charge of the second class, and is 
ng good satisfaction. Miss Fannie Henderson, of Jacksoni, 
111., and Miss M. I. Farrant, of Salem, Mass., have been 
ointed additional teachers as provided tor bj the last Legisla- 

These ladies are valued additions to our corps of teachers. 

THK METHODS 

panned are the same as reported heretofore. The manual 
alphabet and the sign language being the principal means employed. 
Articulation, by means of Bell's system of visible 
h symbols, is taught by Miss Farrant. All who can learn 
to talk now have the opportunity to do so. Forty-seven pupils 
have daily drill in speech. Many of these are learning fast and 
in rime will make fair talkers ; others, because of a lack of capacity 
in this direction, do not do well and are dropped from the 
- from time to time. Drawing and painting have been practiced 
to a limited extent, sufficient, however to demonstrate the 
practibility of such instruction. Miss Henderson gives painting 
lessons to a few, out of school hours, and they do some very 
creditable work. Tt is my wish to make more extended facilities 
in this direction, and I recommend it for your consideration. 
Anything which appeals directly to the eye of a deaf mute is 
valuable as an auxiliarv in his education. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
T 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

This term, for the first time in the history of the Institute an 

oral class has been organized. It consists of thirteen members 

and is in charge of Miss McCowen. Part of these children hear 

somewhat, and are taught speech by means of the hearing with 

the audiphone as an aid. This method is an experiment. So 

far the progress has been marked, particularly with the hearing 

portion of the class. Though the labor of teaching by tin-* 

method is wearing in the extreme, we feel encouraged to perse- 

vere in the course marked out. 

The appropriation for machinery for the workshop has been 

expended in the purchase of an eight horse-power engine, and 

the necessary machinery for the shop. This is a valuable 

improvement ; manufacturing is carried more extensively, more 

boys are employed, and better results secured. This shop is 

now on a good working basi 

The printing office is in successful operation. Its advantages 

should be largely increased. At this time we have room for but 

ten boys; we should have accommodations for at least twenty. 

At present we can teach only plain composition. We should be 

able to teach all branches of the trade. With the proper facili- 

ties much of the State printing could be done in this institution. 

This plan is adopted by some of the states, and is found to work 

successfully. I recommend that an appropriation be made for 

this branch 

Phe Nebraska Mute Journal, a semi-monthly, four page, five 

column paper, is still published. The subscription list and adver 

tisements have been sufficient to defray the expenses incurred. 
The girls are taught general house work, plain sewing, fancy 

work, etc. Increased facilities are needed that they may be 

taught cooking and additional trades by which they may be en- 

abled to support themselves on leaving school. 

IMPROVEMENTS. 

The last session of the Legislature made provision for the 
erection of an additional building, heating apparatus, gas, hose, 

TRADES </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
V 

REP0K1 OF THB 

iohinery lor telephone, etc. These improvements have 
m made. A brick building three stories and basement, has 
in erected in front of the two wings, connecting them by 
ans of a corridor on each floor except the third story. This 
lding, though not completely furnished, is in use, and affords 
the room necessary at present. 

E. low presMiiv -team beating apparatus has been put in. The 
ers are located ahout one hundred feet in the rear of the 
din?. So far it has given good satisfaction. 

The appropriation for gas was expended in the purchase of a 
150 light combination gas machine, and the necessary piping, 
fixtures, etc., for the wings. This furnishes good and sufficient 
light. 

The appropriation for fire protection was expended in placing 
a hose on each floor, connected with tanks and with the steampump. 
This arrangement in connection with the Babcock extinguishers, 
aftords good protection against fire. 

¦Phe telephone we tind a great convenience in the transaction 
business in the city. 

OTHER IMPROVEMENTS REQUIRED. 

One of the pressing necessities of the present is more land. 
This institution should have at least 160 acres. It does not possess 
one-sixth of that amount. Laud contiguous to the Institute 
grounds can bo bought for less now than ever again in the future. 
It will be economy to make the purchase now. I earnestly recommend 
that sufficient money be appropriated to make this 
purchase at once. 

Eiiiw barn, a boiler and coal house with additional shop 
¦ over the same, an ice house, etc., are necessities, and I remend 
that appropriations be made to provide these build- 

I Another improvement which has been needed for years is an 
tlet to the City of Omaha. There is no laid out road direct 
the Citv from the Institute. The one usually tsaveled is sub- </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THB DEAF AND DUMB. 

9 

ject to change, as parties owning property over which it pusses, 

desire to improve the same, I recommend that the Legislature 

be requested to authorize the Board of Commissioner- of !&gt; i_r- 

las county to locate a road through the Institute ground*, where 

the proper authorities may select — see Chapter 78, Section M. 

Compiled Statutes of Nebraska. 

STATEMENT, 

Showinq Fiunniml Coiidt 

' tfn fndustr 

Farm, live stock, etc 

¦&gt; 

Balance on hand Nov. 30, 1880 139.00 

Received during year, including 

reived during year, including receipts per journal, 

Nov. 30, 1881 KMI 

ived during the year, Nov. 30, 1882 295.91 

;ceived during the year. Not. 80, 1882 896.91 

Total | L068.M 

Total $ MS8.54 

Expended during year, includi 

mended durin? year, including disbursements, per 

journal, Nov. 30, 1881 : 600.48 

Expended during year, Nov. 80, 1*81 473.61 

Total * H»74.09 

Balance on hand Nov. 30, 1882 14.45 

CAKPEXTKR BHOI 

Balance on hand Nov. 30, 1881 24.10 

Received from sale ol washing r 

iciiincs, wagons, etc 

Nov. 30, 1882 542.74 

Total 9 '»66.84 

Expended during year Nov. 30, 1MK2 588.94 

Balance on hand Nov. 30, 1882 -S 42.90 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
Ruurice on hand Not. 30, 1881 $ 198.68 

ived daring year Nov. 30, 1882 367.09 

Total 

$ 560.67 

Expended during year Vow 30, 1882 408.95 

nice on hand Nov. 30, 1882 8 151.72 

I \TES 

K estimates 
t expenses of the next 

ubmitted tor 

Living expenses, 1883 

$6,000 

1884 

813,000.00 

Employes' wages, per year, 12,000 4.O00.00 

Clothing lor poor, " 0 400.00 

. for poor, per year, $500.. 1,000.00 

Furniture. beds, beddinir, etc., per veur, $500 1,000.00 

Fuel, per year, $1,500. 

Paints, oil, etc., §300 600.00 

Repairs on buildings, p.-r year, $500 1,000.00 

Improvements on grounds, per year, $500 1,000.00 

Library, school books, apparatus; stationery, pel 

vear, $500 1,000.00 

3ALAK1E&gt;. 

Principal and Steward, per year, $1,500 

B,000.00 

Matron, physician, teachers, foreman, pr. yr., $6,500 13,000.00 

10 </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
U 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB. 

Hired and 

wenty pupils are from tht 

following 

The 

counties 

viz: 

COUNTY. COUNTY. 

Antelope 1 Hitchcock 1 

Adams...". 2 Jeftersor 

9. 

Buffalo 1 Johnson : 3 

Boone 1 Lancaster 9 

Burt 2 Lincoln 1 

Butler 6 Merrick 3 

Case '. - Nemaha 5 

Cheyenne 2 Xuekolls 1 

Cedar 1 Otoe 4 

Clay 1 Pawnee 1 

Colfax 1 Polk 4 

Cumin? 4 Richardson 5 

Dawson 2 Saline 5 

Dakota 8 Barpy 3 

Dodge 3 Siiunders 5 

Douglas 20 Seward 2 

¦&gt; 

Filmore 1 Sherman 1 

Furna8 4 Tliayer 1 

Gage 1 Washington 4 

Hamilton 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 

REPORT OF THE 

COUNTIES NOT REPRESENTED 

Coster, Dixon, Franklin. Frontier, Greeley, Goaper, Hall 

Hurlan, Holt, Howard. Keith, Kearney, Knox, Madison, Xanc 

Phelps, Pierce, Platte, Red Willow, Stanton, Valley, Wayn 

gter, Wheeler, York. 

HUSH OF DKAFXE 

JF THOSE PRK 

trenitai 42 

Spinal Meningitis 19 

Scarlet Fever 15 

Brain Fever 12 

Typhoid Fever 4 

Whooping Cough 

tula 1 


Cholera Infantum 


Measles 1 

r (kind not reported.) 4 

Fall in Infancy 

&gt; 

Bronchitis 1 

Unknown 

reported 5 

Total 

121 

\&lt; KNOWLKDGMENTS. 

Our thanks are hereby tendered (the different managers of rail 

wuvs in this State, for their kindness in furnishing the j 

transportation to and from school at reduced rates, am 

employe* who cared for them while in transit. Also 

itors and publishers of papers (a list of which is appended) set 

to the Institute free, or in exchange for the Mute Journal: and 

to the State Agricultural Society for free admission to 

t 

Fair. </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
18 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOK TH1 DBA! AM' I'IMB. 

CONCLUSION 

In takintr a retrospect of the past two years, I look upon the 
irk accomplished as successful and quite satisfactory. 

w&lt; 

Trusting that the Institute may always be worthy the gener- 

upport of the State, and thanking you each and all tor 

c 

&gt;ur many acts of kindness, and relying upon you for further 

v 

and upon my associates for efficient co-operation, ami 

usting the future to Him who doeth all things well, I tin 

ir 

another year with the hope of 

still better bucc&lt; 

Respectfully 

submitted 

T. A. GILLE8PIE, 


PHYSICIANS KKPORT. 

Omaha, Nebraska, December 16th, 1882. 

Gentlemen : I have the honor to report favorably of every 

ng in my department. The sanitary condition of the Institu 

r supply, drainage, heating, ventila 


1. 

m, food, lights, exerci.se of pupils, cleanliness and general ii 

or and out-door management, — is all that could be &lt;i 

With good hospital accommodations and efficient nurses, tl 

are well cared for. The superintendent, matron, nun 

nd teachers all seem to take a deep interest in their welfare 

i 

We have had a few cases of pneumonia "German m. 

phtheritic tonsilitis and typhoid fever, besides numerous lighter 

I 

ailments and casualties incident to so large :i collection of chil 

n 

Xo deaths have occurred except the one !&gt;y accident, im&gt;ii 

ntend&lt; </seg>


            <seg id="p014">
REPORT OF THE 

|\.ll the children were subjected to either primary vaccination, 
revaccination when required. 

I desire to call your attention to one thing only, by way of 
g^estion. There are a few feeble-minded inmates that are not fit 
jects for instruction in an institution of this character, and 
:ral of the same class have been refused admittance hereto. 
I nggaat whether the time has not arrived for the State 
nake some provision for this class of unfortunates. Tempoarrangements 
might be made for their care in one of the 
lie institutions now existing, till such time as the increased 
iber would demand more enlarged and better accommodas. 


Very respectfully yours, 

J. C. DENISI 

» 

Physician to the Deaf and Dumb Institute of Nebraska 

To the Commissioner. </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTE F"R THE DBA) AND IMMB. 

LIST OF PUPILS 

MALE 

NAM 

Aikins. Ja 

Allen, Edwar 

¦ptembt 

Arenson, Frank 
Bailey. Burt 

: epteinber 

Beahm. As; 
Beeman, G 

7 October 12 

B«-&lt;'k 


Belcke, Alexand&gt; 

Boa 

Brown, Char 

Brown 

Brunner, Fr 

Boat 

Bowmar 

ptember 

Burt 

Cain, James 10 September 

Septenibe 

Chambers, W 

hiiinock, Ne 

lark 

Cody, Edwan 

1 avis 

Dav 

Delanoy, Fn 

Dickinson, Artr 

t: 

Bveru. Mi 

r&lt; 

Flood. John 

Freeman, &gt;am 

A 

Hashberger, Dan 

Hawver. 

Hileman. William 

Humpal 

Huser. Get 

Jacobs, Juhn D 

Johr 

Kelly 

Kelly. Daniel.. 
Klein. Williar 

King. William 

King. I 

Kh 

Livingstone, W 

La 

Kdwar 

Louck 

Marsh. \V; 

Masters, I 


McKi 

Morria, Fn 

Merrill. Her 

My 

Ne 

fm 

Pa 

Pan 

Picker 

I'm 

Rot 

Staff 
Staff&lt; 
Steyt 

IDMimOM 

ptember 20, 1SS 

mbt-r -ii 

ber 22. 1881 

ptember 

10 -!¦[.' 

ptember 10 1871 



epteniber - 


Septemt- 


IS November 27, 1879, 

January 20. 1874 

8 September 15, 1879. 

October 16. 1879 

September I ¦ 

September - 

H Octobers. 1870 
8 Cictober : 

June 1 

Apri 

J December 18, 18' 

April . 

ictober 15. 18HJ 

September 20. 18N 
October 12. 1881... 

10 April 11, 1872 

V&gt; May 20. 1878 
9 septembi-! 

ptember 

September 20. 


September 20. 1882 
October 12, 1881 .... 

ptember 

¦ptembt 

mber 

February 13, 18? 

Marel 

February 1 

plemb€ 

jary 10. 18»: 

December 

March 1 

xi be 

¦nil 

item! 

( )ctober 

10 OCtOl 

oln 

¦pieiuutri 13 
¦ptember 17 

*pt€ 
Jctol 

COUNTY 

POST OFFICE 

Osceola Polk 

Overton Dawson 

: Lancaster 

()mah:i Douglas 

David City Butler 

Buckeye Hamilton 

•ratur Burt 

Peoria Ill inoi&gt; 

Nemaha 


NVniaha Citv Nemaha 

Nemaha City Nemaha. 

Oakdak- .'. Mitelnpe. 

Blair Washingtt 

~waburuh Dodge 

Plaitsmuiuli 

saw Adam-* 

Klkton Nuekolls 

Omaha Douglas 

Point Cuming 

De W1M -aline 

Beaver City Furnaa 

&lt; heeney Lancaster 

- '.under* 

(.'ereaco Saundern 

I'lica Seward 

Hie L man I4MMM 

Loup city -hermun 

Jmaha Douglas 

Saline 

Seward Bewaid. 

Sidney Cheyenne 
n Nemalm. 

Omaha houglas 

Schuyler ' olta-v 

Omaha Douglas 

I ukom City... I 

Pilzen Sauudura. 

i Furnas 

(iranoii Flllmor 

Lincoln Uncaster. 

loreno 

hlorenoe Douglas 
Omaha Douglaa 

Bvllevue Sarpy. 

BelleTue 

saltillo Lancaster 

Bennet 1 ancaster 

Dublin Boom 

Scribner Dodge 

Falls city kkhantoon. 

Tekamali Burt. 

- CMoa 

North Hlatte Lincoln 

Syracuse 

r Cumii 

(iage 

Calhoun Washington 

Witt ~alme 

Omaha Douglas 

Pawnee city 1 

steele City ¦ 

Plum Creek 1 

St. James Oedar 

Fairbury Jefferson 

Culbertson Hitchc ck 

Cedar Bluffs Saunders 

Kisine &lt; Ity Butler 

Rising city 
Omaha 

Butler 

lM.Utf'.n- 

Nemahn </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 


LIST OF PUPILS— Continued. 

MALES 

Loamsios 

SlHt 

pojt office 

COUNTY 

Stunt, Rudolf I 9 October 1ft. IK 

Omaha 

uglas 

Sullivan, William | 8 September 25. 18 1 


Snow. Martin 9 Octo.er U. 1881 

Ni-maha City 

Ncmaha 

Swenson. A. F 18 October 

Attahila 

Buffalo. 

I rny-r. Arthur _ 14 September 20. lit 
Toner, John 7 October 

I rny.-r. Arthur _ 14 -epteruber 20, 1882, Crete Snline 

Toner, John 7 October 12, 1881 |Omaha I'ouglas 

Turner. Robert 15 January 12. 1*80 Blair Washing 

Turner. Robert 15 January 

Blair Washing 


rher. Wencel 9 September 22 

Pilzen 

launders 

Vher. Wencel 9 September 22. 1880 Pilzen &gt;aunder 
..William 9 September 19, 1877 Central City Merrick 
'iraham 15 November 28, 1880 Unadilla otoe. 

: William 9 September 19, 1877... 

Central City 

Merrick 

Graham 15 November 2t 

Unadilla 

Young, George 10 September 22. 1880 CedarCreek I 

Young. George 10 September 22. 1880 

Cedar Creek 

as- 

FEMALES. 

FKMAI.E- 

Allen, Victoria 8 September 9, 1*74 Calhoun Wa-him 

Allen. Victoria 8 September 9 

'alhoun Wa-hiiiR 

¦ n 

Anderson, Johannes 19 December 18, IHT'.i Wayland I'olk. 

Anderson, Johannes 19 December 18, 187 

Uayland I'olk 

Aueuist, EmmH 8 Septenr Omaha Douglas 

Auguist, Emma 8 September 80. 

' 'malia 

Bishop, Lily 10 September 15, 1879 (iilmore Barpy. 

Bishop, Lily 10 Septen; 
Black, Linda 8 October 17, IS 

Gilmore 

Black. Linda 8 October 17, 187k Central City Merrick 

Idol 

ntral Citv Merrick 

Boyer, Lily 9 April 20. 1879 Omaha .' Douglas 

Boyer, Lily 9 April 

Omaha Douglas 

B Margaret '.'.'.." 12 October 3. 1880 
ard. Marj- 13 September 18. 

Bray. Margaret 12 October 3. 1880 Omaha Douglas 

Omaha Douglas 

Brouhard, Mary 13 September 18. 1879 Heaver City .'... Funias. 

September 

City :... Fun 

Druuuuru, ?mij xo 10 
Brouhard, Rose A 10 .-¦ ptember 18, 

Brouhard, Rose A 10 September 18, 1879 'Heaver City Kurnas. 

Beaver Citv Kurnas 

Buirv'k. Lucy 10 September y. 1874 Falls City _ Kichard 

Butrick, Lucy 10 Septembe 

Fail- City Kichards 

Cody, Margaret „ 14 December 7. 1878 Cheney Laniast 

Chenu y Lanrasti 

Cody, Katharim- 9 Decent Cheney I-aneas!&lt; 

y Lancast 

Cody, Bridget 8 September 22, 1880 Cheney Lancast 

ney Lancast 

\A^1T, UllU^Cl O OCpitTUlLT 
Collins, Eliza 12 -¦ 

Collins, Eliza 12 -eptember 9. 1874 Falls City Richard 

Falls Citv Richait 

Cornish. Ella 9 October 12, 1881 Omaha ." Douglas 

Cornish. Ella 9 Octob. 

imaha ." Douglas 

Coyle, Katharin. IS Septem Nebraska City.... 0 

KKatharin.- IS Septemb. 
rd. Otic 8 .Septemb. 

raska 

Crawford, Olio 8 Septem .... Tecumseh JobtnOE 

ptembor 2f) 

Forbes. Estella X September ¦_"&gt; - &lt;maha Douglas 

Hastings 

Gallaeher. Ellen 12 Septem total Cuming 
'irace 7 September 20, 1880 Hastings Adams. 

Adams. 
Dodge. 
Cheyenne 

Green, Ida 16 September 9. 1S74 Fremont Dodge. 

Green. Ida 16 September 9. IS 1 

Fremont 

Hedrick, Mary II Septembers ilncy cheyeni 

Hedrick, Mary II S&lt; i 
W.,t,t...* Vunnio Q QAntomlwir Q 1U7 

Hoppes. Xamm 

Hoppes. Nannie 9 September 9. 1873 Salem Richard 
Ma M 8 September 20, 1878 Inland 'lav. 

IE 

In 

Krause. Martha 16 October 12. 1881 Shelby I'olk. 

Krause. Martha 16 Octob 

I'olk 

Lotz. Katharine 13 October 12. Ih81 Dakota city Dakota. 

Lou. Katharine 13 October 

Dakot 
Johns 

Mavity. Martha 18 October 12, 1881 &gt;pring &lt; reck Johnsoi 

Mavity. Martha 18 October 12, 188 
MrBride. Laura 19 December 2, 18 

MrBride. Laura 19 December 2, 187m Ilysses Butler. 

Decembi 

Bull 
Butl 

Mclntosh. Linnora 18 Deeem' Ulysses Butler. 

Mclntosh. Linnora 18 Deeeni 1 

Atlant 

Mead, Isabella 11 September 22, 1880 Atlanta Saline. 

Isabella 

Saline 
Dougl 

Miller. Minnie 8 September 9. 1S71 Omaha Douglas 

Miller, Minnie 8 September 9 

Mohr, Agnes 8 Septen. 


Mohr, Agnes 8 September 22, 1880 West Point Cuming 
Klizabeth 21 October 12. 1881 i Ivsms Butler. 

Klizabeth -12,1881 


Butk 

Needham, Lenora 9 October 28. 1879 Central City Merrick 

Needham, Lenora 9 October 28. 1879 

Merrick 
Saline. 

Central city 

Ream, Kllen 17 \ovember22 

Ream. Kllen 17 November 22, 1881 Wiltoer Saline. 
Klla 10 February 13. 18.-0 Hebron TlTayer. 

Ilia 10 February 13. 18K 

Hebr. 

Tlrayer 

smith. ElUai^'r.'.Zr.'.'."™.".".'.'™ 10 December 14 

Richardso: 
Douglas 

Smith. Elizabeth 10 December 14, 187") Salem Richard 
Die 15 Ni Omaha Douglas 

\ 

15 Novembi 

Oma 
Omn 

Toner. Mary rl 1877 Omaha Dougliu 

Dougl a* 
Douglas 

¦««— " 

Oinahn 


l!i: TE Fi&gt;R TUE DBA1 AND DUMB </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
17 

EBKASb 

T OF PAPERS 

Mute Juurn 

/ 

w 

N, ' nc-La 

1 

V 

.n 

\ 

M 

,Y 

/i 

M 

¦ 

Virgin!*. 
¦A ; -.'.i- -i 

K 

M </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
1- 

KEPORT OF THK 

LIST OF PAPERS.— Continued. 

monthly Peaf Mute Hawk, v 

U B 

M 

N 

do Our Dumb Animals f 
do u inurnal Lincoln 

M 

n Wot 

, i 

The Aiylum [ndei iin&gt;l Review 
Th. Printer 1 ! Journal 

I 

M 

Quarterly American Annals of the Deaf and 1 inn'-. Waahing 

¦do Hesperian Sti 
do L'eaf M ute Pi 
lly Rural Xebr»&gt; 
Nebraska Fa 
Our i </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FUR THE DIAI 'NO PV.MR. 1 I 

RULES AND REGULATIONS 

f 

Nebraska I 

Deaf and Duinli 

&gt;r 

livin&lt;; in the State are admitted 

ill 

II. The applicant for admiaaioQ must be of good moral habits 
1 iet ween the ages of seven and twentv-five, of sound mind and 

i 

free from contagious diseas. Persons either younger or older 
mav he admitted, at the discretion of the authorities. 

III. Each pupil should come with suitable clothing to last 

one year. The clothing should be marked. A few dollars 

should be left with the Principal for repair of shoes, etc 

IV. No pupil will be allowed to leave the Institute before the 

close of the term, without permission of the Principal. 
V. Pupils will be required to conform alike to the rules and 

regulation 

VI. Applications for admission or information should 
made to the principal of the Institute for Deaf and Dumb, Omaha, 
Nebraska. 

VII. Information is required before entering, on the follow 
ing points: 

QUESTION 

1. What is the full name of the applicant 

2. In what place, year, month and day was the applicant born ? 

3. What are the full names of the father and mother? Please 
state if either is deceased, and the cause of death, and if a second 
marriage has taken place? 

4. What were the diseases from which the grand parent.* 
uncles or aunts have died? 

5. What is the occupation or profession of the father, and to 
what nation do the parents belong? </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
NEBRASKA [H8TITUU KuR TH-E DEAF AND DUMB. 

What irr the post office ftddrtiM an&lt;l 
or guardian, giving BWi ' office, I 
they ii 

nee of the pai 

i 

tWTial it the nearest railrc 
What an- rh&lt;- name- of tl: 

\v 

\r. 

i 

10. Hi 

.v)] at 

11. Wa 


12. W 

rn 

. II 

i 

17. la 

\ , 

i 

\\ 

i 

liort 

i </seg>

         </p>

		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>