<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  EVILS OF PREMATURE CREAMERIES</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A. PRESS BULLETIN NO. 41 Distributed May 19, 1913 EVILS OF PREMATURE CREAMERIES By J. H. Frandsen DEPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY NEBRASKA CONDITIONS FAVOR DAIRYING. Conditions in Nebraska are remarkably favorable for dairying and we may expect to see this one of the leading dairy states in the Union; but the industry here is as yet in its infancy and many years will elapse before it reaches its full "safe and sane" development. The operation of a creamery may be profitable to a community, but it is not a venture to be rushed into blindly without a thoro knowledge of the subject and local conditions. There are many districts in the state which are thinly settled and other sections where the people are more or less indifferent to dairying. In these districts the small cooperative creamery can scarcely hope to be successful. It is under these conditions that the centralized creamery with its cream station and cream routes fills a niche and opens up a market that could not, for a time at least, be had in any other way. Under these conditions, the farmers living in thinly </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ating in the territory than to go to the expense of building and operat - ing a new one. Ilowever, when a locality has an assurance that it will secure the ict of at least 600 dairy cows and where the farmers will give it heartiest support, there is no good reason why a cooperative nery should not be highly successful and satisfactory to its patrons, inly a well-managed creamery adds much to the prosperity of the mnity. Thru it the farmer members should secure a ready cash et for their dairy products. If the creamery is a cooperative one, and honestly managed, they have at least the satisfaction of know - hey are getting all that the business warrants. PROMOTER NOT NEEDED. I\8 a result of efforts put forth by farm organizations for cooperation S various lines, there is now in Nebraska much agitation in favor of building of small creameries, both private and cooperative. The mery promoter, with a keen eye for business, has been quick to take ntage of the situation and he has made an effort to capitalize for his benefit the sentiment already developed towards cooperation among rarmers. I All creamery promoters are not swindlers, nor are all creameries I by them failures. Frequently much good results from their efforts, many of them are entirely too careless regarding where they build merles. They have frequently placed creameries in localities and &gt;r conditions that could result in nothing but failure. Seemingly r interest in the creamery ceases very shortly after the last note has i collected. If the cooperative movement is at all worth while, it t start from within the heart of the dairy community instead of in fertile brain of a creamery promoter. I There are promoters who are so ready and willing to help the farm - that they frequently offer to organize a creamery company in any hborhood, solicit the stock, get out articles of incorporation, build equip the plant and turn it over to an association of farmers for a tin lump sum. This, of course, seems a very satisfactory way, as it &gt;ves the members of the creamery association of all the preliminary t. One can, however, rest assured that no one is doing this work for ling and that no outside party can do it as cheaply and effectively as farmers of the community. These promoters are not working for r health; they usually get a good profit, which the farmers pay. tTh« organization is not as strong as if it had been created entirely ind tot the community; therefore, again I emphasize — DO YOUR N ORGANIZING, AND ORDER EVERYTHING NEEDED DIRECT IM A RELIABLE CREAMERY SUPPLY HOUSE. The creamery nized by the farmers' own initiative not only is better and cheaper is on a more substantial foundation from the very first and better </seg>
            <seg id="p003">make possible the organization of a creamery by their own effort* assisted by disinterested outside help, such as that from the Experiment Station officials and others vitally interested in the permanent develop - ment and properity of the dairy industry, the chances are that the cream - ery promoter cannot develop enough interest and mutual confidence among the farmers to make the cooperative creamery a success after the promoter's influence is withdrawn. FIRST THING IN STARTING A NEW CREAMERY. When a sufficient amount of interest in a cooperative creamery has manifested itself, the first thing to be done is to carefully ascertain how many dairy cows within a radius of seven or eight miles can be counted on regularly for the support of the creamery. In taking this cow census, special emphasis should be laid on the necessity of getting the actual number of cows that can be counted on to furnish cream for the new creamery. If fewer than about 600 available cows are found in this terri - tory, the project had better be indefinitely postponed. ORGANIZATION. If it be found that there is a sufficient number of cows to give reasonable assurance of success, then the organization should be given most careful consideration, and again I would advise that the farmers do their own organizing, and that not too many city people without cows be admitted. I would qualify this by saying that frequently on account of superior training it may be desirable to select a well-trained business man as financial manager. HOW TO RAISE THE MONEY. The most satisfactory way of raising the money is for each member to sign an agreement and to be jointly responsible for the amount bor - rowed. When such an agreement is signed by a goodly number of responsible farmers, the money can generally be secured at a reasonable rate of interest, and with this money a creamery can be erected and equipped. As soon as the creamery begins operation, arrangements can be made for a deduction of one or two cents per pound of butter to go into a "sinking fund" out of which the debt is paid. The payment is so gradual that the farmer hardly notices it. This plan has the advantage of requiring each patron to pay exactly in proportion to the amount of butter manufactured for him. COST OF CREAMERY PLANT. The cost of a creamery building will be from $1,000.00 to $2,500.00, depending on the locality, kind of construction, and cost of material and labor. Such a building usually consists of a main work room, engine </seg>
            <seg id="p004">■boiler room (including space for refrigerating machine), coal room, gerator, storeroom and office. Machinery for a gathered cream plant will cost approximately $1,200.00. If refrigerating machinery is included, the cost will be from $800.00 to $1,000.00 more. The total cost of a creamery with complete equipment would therefore vary from $2,200.00 to $4,700.00 for a gath - ered cream creamery. This estimate, of course, does not provide for a large commission for a promoter, but, rather, is made on the assumption that the building is constructed by the responsible local contractor sub - mitting the lowest bid, and that the needed creamery machinery is ordered from a reliable creamery supply house willing to furnish the same for the lowest cash price. From facts and figures at hand it is estimated that the plan suggested would save the community from $1,200.00 to $2,000.00. The most serious objections to the "promoted" creamery is not the long list of wrecked creameries, nor the loss by the community of so much hard-earned cash, but it is the setback which the dairy interest suffers whenever one of these creameries fails, resulting in prejudice against the dairy business as a whole. To state it conservatively, it can be said, that for every one of these failures the dairy industry of that community has been set back at least ten years. The Dairy Husbandry Department of the University of Nebraska at Lincoln, upon request, will gladly furnish information regarding the number of cows needed in any locality, the proper organization for a </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>