<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Institute for Feeble Minded Youth BEATRICE, NEBRASKA To the Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings For the Period Ending November 30, 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Institute for Feeble Minded Youth BEATRICE, NEBRASKA To the Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings For the Period Ending November 30, 1912 Hon. Chester H. Aldrich, Governor For Term End ng January 1, 1913 Board of Public Lands and Buildings For Term Ending January 1, 1913 Hon. E. B. Cowles President Hon. Addison [Wait Secretary Hon. Walter A. George State Treasurer Hon. Gr/ NT Martin Attorney General Attorney General </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Amos Quein Steward Mrs. W. M. Thomas Matron C. P. Underwood Bookkeeper Cora Austin Stenographer SCHOOL DEPARTMENT Miss Katherine Rigg, Principal Miss Lillian Lawson Miss Irene Yale Miss Daisy Wardlaw Miss Josephine Brandon Jack O'Donnell, Band Instructor William Pollock Supervisor Boys' Department Mrs. William Pollock Supervisor Girls' Department Sara Brandon Supervisor Girls' Department W. C. ALVORD Supervisor Boys' Department Hospital Mrs. Nellie Alvord. Supervisor Girls' Department Hospital Mrs. M. Dillon In charge of Sewing Room L. B. Norris In charge of Laundry E. B. Storey In charge of Bakery T. G. Carlton In charge of Farm Department Lon Waite Chief Engineer D. B. Gillespie . In charge of Carpenter and Brush Department </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            
            <seg id="p004">NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH W. M. Thomas, Superintendent To Chester H. Aldrich, Governor of the State of Nebraska, and Honorable E. B. Cowles, Walter A. George, Addison [Wait and Grant Martin, Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Gentlemen: As provided by law I submit the following report of the condition of this Institution for the term ending November 30, 1912. December 1, 1910 to June 1, 1911 No. enrolled 394 No. admitted 48 442 No. discharged 3 No. remaining at end of period 432 Per Capita Cost $79.75 June 1, 1911 to December 1, 1911 No. enrolled at beginning of period 432 No. admitted 19 451 1 No. discharged No. died 42 43 No. remaining at end of period 408 Per Capita Cost $75.66 December 1, 1911 to June 1, 1912 No. enrolled at beginning of period 408 No. admitted 50 458 No. discharged 9 No. released on parole 1 No. died 18 28 No. remaining at end of period 430 Per Capita Cost $100.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">356 June 1, 1912 to December 1, 1912 No. enrolled at beginning of period 430 No. admitted 28 458 liUi UlCvl LtU £tU No. remaining at end of period 429 Per Capita Cost $73.59 The above population of institution by counties as follows: County Male Female Total Adams 2 5 7 Antelope 5 1 6 Arthur 0 0 0 Banner 0 0 0 Blaine 0 0 0 Boone 4 0 4 Brown 1 0 1 Burt 1 2 3 Butler 3 3 6 Buffalo 4 1 5 Box Butte 1 2 3 Boyd 0 0 0 Cass 6 6 12 Cedar 3 5 8 Chase 0 0 0 Cherry 1 0 1 Cheyenne 1 0 1 Clay 3 2 5 Colfax 4 0 4 Cumming 2 1 3 Custer 4 3 7 Dakota 2 0 2 Dawes 1 1 2 Dawson 3 4 7 Dixon 3 3 6 Dodge 5 2 7 Douglas 35 27 62 Dundy 0 0 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">357 Male Female Total Fillmore 4 9 5 Franklin 1 1 •&gt; Frontier 1 6 o Furnas o 1 3 Gage 13 18 Garfield 1 9. 3 Gosper 0 0 0 Greeley 9. 0 2 Grant 0 0 0 Hall 1 6 o Hamilton 1 9 3 Harlan 1 0 1 Hayes 0 1 1 Hitchcock 1 0 1 Holt 1 6 ,j Howard 3 3 6 Jefferson 2 4 6 Johnson ■2 1 3 Kearney 0 1 1 Keith 2 2 4 Keya Paha 1 0 1 Knox 2 1 3 Lancaster 10 14 24 Lincoln 0 7 7 Logan 0 0 0 Loup 0 0 0 Laurel 0 0 0 Madison 3 3 6 Merrick ■ 2 3 5 McPherson 0 0 0 Nance 0 0 0 Nemaha 1 4 5 Nuckolls 6 3 9 Otoe 6 5 11 Pawnee 5 3 8 Phelps ' 2 0 2 Pierce 0 2 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">358 County Perkins . Male Female Total 4 0 I Red Willow Richardson . Rock 1 4 0 5 i 0 0 Saline Sarpy 4 8 2 1 Saunders Seward. . 2 4 1 1 I Sherman Sheridan Sioux . . . 1 1 1 0 : 1 0 Stan ton 2 3 ! Scotts Bluffs Thayer o 1 - 4 1 Thomas . Thurston Valley... 0 0 1 0 4 1 • Washington Wayne 4 2 2 0 Webster Wheeler York 3 3 • 0 0 3 8 Total 224 205 Morality E umber of deaths during this period was 96, of which 71 lale and 25 female, and cause of death as follows : Epilepsy 23 Tuberculosis 26 Typhoid fever 20 Dropsy 4 Pneumonia 7 Brights disease 2 Hereditary syphillis 6 General debility 2 Acute peritonitis 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">359 Hemmorrhage Heart failure Apoplexy 1 1 1 Gastritis 1 Total 96 Epilepsy We wish to call your attention to the large number of deaths caused by epilepsy, tuberculosis and typhoid fever. At the be - g nning of our term December 1, 1910 there were about 100 applications on file. A large percentage of these were epileptics, who had been refused admission by former superintendents on account of their physical condition and of lack of room to care for them. When the two new cottages were completed and ready for occupancy April 1, 1911, we notified all who had applications on file in this off ce, that we were prepared to receive them as charges. A large percentage of those received were epileptics of a very low type. These together with those already charges of this Kitution constituted a very large percentage of the population, :e mortality from this cause has been heavy. Tuberculosis Of those whose death was caused by tuberculosis, almost all of them were males, and occupied what is known as Boys' Cottage No. 1, the first cottage south of the Administration Building. We attribute the unsanitary and filthy condition of this building at the time we took charge as the principle cause of so many contracting this disease. I wish to state most em - phatically, that the conditions in this building at that time were such that it was unfit to be occupied. The sanitary conditions were deplorable, the odor sickening, and as a result a very large percentage of those occupying these quarters became infected. Not only those who died from this cause but many of those who died of epilepsy and other diseases, their vitality being weakened by this dread disease, they could not withstand attacks of epi - lepsy and other diseases to which they were subject. We wish to state however that the interior of this building </seg>
            <seg id="p009">360 titions have been removed, a new entrance of the south added, cement floors laid, ventilation much mproved, is kept as clean and sanitary as possible, and we believe in the future, danger of infection is materially reduced. Typhoid Epidemic, Causes Thereof Ee records of this institution will show that since it was ach year there have been cases of typhoid fever. Four t times it became an epidemic. During the summer months of 1911, 123 cases developed, the first early in May and the last in October. Early in July the writer was stricken with the disease, but not until efforts had been made to discover its cause, and stop its spread as soon as possible. Samples of water were sent to Lincoln and analysis showed that water taken from well used for drinking was infected with feces caused by sewer seepage. Further investigation and ex - amination of the sewer system developed the fact of there being not less than 100 openings where sewer gas escaped. Many of these were under the cottages in the basements A large per - centage of these openings were caused by where the pipes were stopped, holes had been drilled for the purpose of inserting wire to clear them of obstruction, and these holes had not been prop - erly plugged. All the plumbing of the entire institution was found to be in horrible condition. Religious Exercises rfe have Sunday-school and preaching every Sunday after - which services are purely non-sectarian. Farm and Garden The following product was raised on the farm consisting of 222 acres, during the past two years. 1911 1912 Total Corn 1,000 bu. 1,100 2100 Oats 600 359 950 Alfalfa 75 tn. 100 tn. 175 Oat straw 12 tn. 12 Potatoes 600 bu. 600 bu. 1,200 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">361 Play Grounds and Amusements The play grounds are in excellent condition and afford for the inmates plenty of recreation in various ways. The lawns upon which they enjoy themselves are grassy and clean and adorned by excellent shade trees. Amusements consist of basket ball, football, baseball, etc. As often as twice a week dances are given, and in addition, various games. Improvements EFhe following improvements have been made. New plumb - throughout administration building and three cottages, g room addition to boys' cottage No. 1 reconstruction of interior, new porch on south side. Large soapstone sinks have been placed in both kitchens, large sink in each of the dining rooms. Interior of all buildings repainted and decorated, re - plastered where needed. New system of water mains, two new wells tested capacity 225 gallons per minute with proper pump- Sweet potatoes 75 Sweet corn 300 bu. 200 bu. Tomatoes 300 400 Onions 75 200 Turnips 75 100 175 Carrots 50 50 Beets 100 150 String beans . . . 50 75 125 Peas 10 15 25 Radishes 75 150 Cucumbers. . . . 50 25 Cabbage 5,000 hds. 5,000 hds. ,0.0.x. Rhubard 50 50 Lettuce 100 100 200 Spinach Green onions 60 150 50 200 a Apples Cherries 100 25 100 30 ■5 Cauliflower. . . . 100 hds. 200 hds. 300 Milk 18,250 gal. 14,600 gal. 32,850 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">362 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ' reconstruction of electric lighting system including new wiring and lighting fixtures in three buildings. 1000 feet of new cement walk laid, repainting of barns, carpenter shop and all worn out buildings. Laundry has also been equipped with two new washers and eight electric irons. I would estimate the necessary amount of money to be re- quired for this institution during the next biennial period as follows : Maintenance $ 90,000.00 General repairs 25,000.00 There are at the present time deficiency claims amounting to $14,582.32. These are without exception for repair work and material including cost of new water mains, one well and pump - ing machinery. Prior to August 1, 1911 the main supply of water had been obtained from Bear Creek. To have this stream furnish sufficient amount, it was necessary to build a dam, from which the water was pumped. Analysis of this water proved it was infected with typhoid to such an extent, that Professor Wait of the State University, who made the analysis stated that it was the worst water he had ever analyzed. LAt different times efforts had been made to obtain a suffi - t supply of water from wells, and in each instance it was given up, those having the matter in charge claiming the supply found was insufficient. When analysis of the water proved the well infected the Board ordered a small one put down, from which we could obtain drinking water. For this purpose, one was made south of the stand pipe. When completed it was tested and al- employees wages 35,000.00 toiler house 5,000.00 )airy 1,000.00 Chaplain salary 200.00 "eachers' salary 6,000.00 luperintendent salary 5,000.00 *hysicians and steward 2,400.00 Total $169,600.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">363 INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH though but four inches in diameter, was found to furnish fifteen gallons per minute. This was reported to the Board with the recommendation that a large one be made, believing that it would furnish an ample supply for the entire institution. This resulted in the making of two wells, which we are pleased to state furnish an abundance of pure water for all purposes. This together with new plumbing and many other improved sanitary conditions will lessen the danger of typhoid epidemics in the future. As a further precaution, I have during the past year had all innoculated with typhoid-bacteria, and the result has been very satisfactory. Per Capita Cost Your attention is called to the per capita cost at this insti - tution being higher than for the preceding biennium. This may be attributed to different causes, first : most articles of food are much higher, some costing double that of the preceding two years, second; $10,000.00 would be a very conservative estimate of extra expense incurred because of typhoid epidemic, during this period, third; items were charged and paid for from maintenance appropriation, which were properly chargeable to repair fund, or from a special appropriation to be made by the legislature for this purpose, for instance, the Board purchased stokers and charged them to maintenance, the original cost of the same being $3,800.00. Encluding the cost of labor, board - ing of men, etc., we would estimate this item alone has cost our maintenance fund not less than $5000.00. Regardless of our advice to the contrary they began installing them during the month of November 1911. This necessitated the rebuilding of the boiler house, tearing out of the old boilers, etc., resulting in a crippled condition of our heating plant during the entire winter, which was responsible for the consumption of an unusual amount of fuel, we think at least $2000.00 more than would have or - dinarily been consumed. Said stokers installed have thus far consumed a largely increased amount of fuel to obtain same results as were obtained from hand firins?. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">364 STOCK AT FARM E There is at present as follows: twenty-two (22) cows, one bull, forty-seven (47) hogs, eight (8) horses and two (2) School Department During the past two years there has been an average at - tendance of one hundred and twenty-five (125) between the ages of five and eighteen. Our school work consists |of (kindergarten, music, grade work, band practice, sloyd and drill. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>