<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00011">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00011</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>TWELFTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR BOYS AT KEARNEY, NEBRASKA.  FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1904.</title>
			            <date value="1904">1904</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-28</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
SUPERINTENDENT 

OP THE 

STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR 
BOYS 

AT 

KEAENEY, NEBRASKA. 

FOE THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBEE 30, 1904. </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
OFFICERS. 

B. D. Hay ward Superintendent 

H. I). Schaff Assistant Superintendent 

f. Partridge (Nov. '03-Nov. '04), E. F. Leavenworth 
(Dec. '02-Aug. '03) Stenographer and Bookkee]* r 

H. E. Dillon Manager "A" Grade 

Jas. A. Dallas Manager "B" Grade 

J. T. O. Stewart Manager "C" Grade 

Geo. T. Day Manager "D" Grade 

C. O. Brown Manager "E" Grade 

¦ C. V. D. Basten (Mar. '04-Nov. '04), Dr. H. S. 
Bell (Dec. '02-Mar. '04) Physician 

Ministers of Kearney Chaplains </seg>



            <seg id="p004">
State Board of Public Lands and Buildings: 

Gentlemen — It is with great pleasure that I present for 
your consideration the Twelfth Biennial Report of the State 
Industrial School for Boys, for the bienniuni ending No- 

I wish to express my thanks to the Board, individually 
and collectively, for the courteous treatment and hearty cooperation 
they have given in the work we have tried to do 
during this period. 

Very truly yours, 
B. D. Haywabd, Superintendent. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
REPORT. 

ithe beginning of this report I wish to say a few words 
rding our work, which seem appropriate at this time. 
¦e seems to be a wrong idea throughout the state a&gt; 
work that is being done here and the results ;u com 
led. People seem to think that boys are sent hen 
unished and to do service for the state for some wrong 
have done; and after they have paid the penalty for 
• wrongdoing, they are turned loose and told to go and 
10 more. I wish to correct that erroneous impression. 

Our work here is purely educational. We endeavor to 
educate the mind, the hand, and the heart, and so equip our 
boys that they may go out into the world able to do for 
themselves and become honorable members of society if they 
so desire. 

Everything penal is eliminated from our institution, and 
it is conducted on an educational basis in all departments. 
The only thing penal we have to deal with is the fact that 
before a boy can be placed in our school he must be charged 
with an offense, committed by a court, and brought here hjjr 
an officer. In this procedure a boy gets the impression that 
he is being sent here for punishment, and it requires a long 
time to get that idea out of his mind. He comes keyed up 
to the highest tension, thinking we are his enemies and he is 
to undergo some severe punishment or discipline. When our 
work is explained to him he can hardly understand it, it is 
so different from what he expected. 

We do not inquire into the causes for his being sent here, 
for we would rather not know about them so we will have 
no prejudices to overcome, and we ask him to forget whatever 
wrong he may have done, and start anew. We try to 
show him that we are here to help him, guide and protect </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
228 


I, and teach him to become a man. Of course you are 
re that this is a very difficult task, in many cases. After 
&gt;nts, guardians, and teachers have failed to give the boy 
proper training, he is turned over to the state, and by 
pulsory education, in a sense, he is sent to us to be sup-1 
with what the home and public school have failed to 
or him. This, of course, makes our work more difficult, 
we are glad to report that in nearly all the cases we are 
to do some lasting good for the boy. 

When a boy is received he is assigned to one of the fami, 
is welcomed by the family manager, given a good kith 
and furnished with new, clean clothes; his stomach is filled 
with good, wholesome food, and at night he is put into bed 
between clean sheets or blankets. He then begins to realize 
that it is not the kind of a place he expected. The next day 
he starts to school, spends five hours in school work, and five 
hours at some trade, or other work; and so the work continues 
until the boy is equipped, in a measure, educationally, 
industriously, and morally, to go out into the world and become 
a useful member of society, if he so desires. 

I do not want to be understood that boys dote on being at 
the State Industrial School; the boys we get are those who 
do not have a liking for any school where they can not do as 
they please. If they were sent to any military school, or to 
the State University, and compelled to do what they should 
do, stay there and conduct themselves in a proper manner, 
they would have the same desire and longing to leave that 
they have here. 

There is a certain period in the life of every boy when he 
knows more than he ever will again. No one can tell him 
anything; he looks with pity on his parents and friends for 
knowing so little ; and his only wonder is that one head could 
contain all he knows. This is the danger period of his life. 
It comes to all boys just as surely as the shedding of their 
teeth, and it is during this foolish period that they do things 
—contract habits — that stay with them through life. They 
are least able to care for themselves during this time, and </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
229 

STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

they should have the close, intimate companionship of 
nts, or friends, who will keep them in proper paths. 
They ue more helpless than at any other stage in life, and 
if they ciin be properly guided during this period, or restrained 
from going wrong until reason and judgment come 
to them, then the danger will be passed. In far too many 
cases this is neglected. A too-busy father, an over-induL 
¦other, a caivless step-father or mother, and sometimes 
tan, fail to do their duty at the proper time, and the 
boy wanders away from them and becomes a delinquent. 

It is this class of boys with which the state industrial 
si -hools have to deal, and we are glad to say that out of these 
"misfits," we are able, in the great majority of cases, to make 
men who become useful members of society. 

It is, indeed, gratifying to us to have men who have been 
students at this institution, and who are now holding important 
positions or are successful in other lines, visit our 
school and tell us how glad they are that they were sent here 
and how much good the training received here has done for 
them. Hardly a month passes that we don't have a visit of 
this kind from some of our former students. 

If these introductory remarks shall be the means of giving 
some one a clearer idea of the work being done by the State 
Industrial School, for delinquent boys of the state, or shall 
cause them to investigate for themselves, I shall feel amply 
repaid for the effort. 

SCHOOLS. 

In our educational work here we maintain a system of 
schools and do work up to and inclusive of the ninth grade 
in public school work. Heretofore our schools were 
ducted on the country school plan, but this fall they were 
graded and each boy placed in the classes where he could do 
the best work, and then, as soon as he is ready for promotion 
he can be placed in the next grade. </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
230 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

We have classes in each of the following grades: Second 
and third, fourth and fifth, sixth and seventh, and eighth and 
ninth ; then two grades are assigned to each teacher. In the 
fourth and fifth grade, there are so many boys that it is necesaary 
to have a duplicate grade; so we have the second and 
third in one school, the fourth and fifth in two schools, the 
sixth and seventh in one, and the eighth and ninth in one, 
making five schools in all. In the afternoon, we maintain 
an extra school for the small boys who are not large enough 
to be detailed to some trade. 

Our school begins at 7 :30 o'clock in the morning, and at 
1 :©0 o'clock in the .afternoon. It continues until 11:30 and 
5 ."00 o'clock, making four hours of school each half day, and 
after supper an hour is spent in some educational work, so 
lhat, in addition to the industrial training, a boy gets as 
much schooling each day as he does in the public schools. 

Our schools are equipped to do very efficient work. We 
employ the very best teachers we can find ; those who understand 
boy nature and are capable of doing the most possible 
good for him in the shortest time. Under this arrangement, 
no boy need go out from our school without being able to 
read, write, and understand ordinary business methods, and 
from that to having a good ninth grade education. 

LOCATION AND BUILDINGS. 

Je State Industrial School for Boys is located two and 
alf miles west of the city of Kearney, Neb. It conof 
320 acres of land, mostly rolling. On this land are 
ructed seven large brick buildings, consisting of five 
,y or grade buildings, an administration building and an 
strial building. Besides these there are horse barns, 
barns, hog houses, chicken house, boiler house, engine 
, greenhouse, paint shop, and pump house. The elevaon 
which these buildings are situated is the highest 
ad and is said to afford one of the finest views in the </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
231 

BEPAIBS. 

Administration Bdilding. — This building has been completely 
overhauled. Every window in the building bail 
be taken out and new sills and bases put in, and the ¦tone 
uiuler each window had to be recut, so as to give the proper 
slaiit in order to keep out the rain. In the second story, new 
hardwood floors have been laid in the hall and dining room. 
The living rooms have all been repapered, repainted, and refurnished; 
and the chapel has been repainted, floors paraffined, 
and everything thoroughly cleaned. In the tirst 
story new hardwood floors have been laid in the library, in 
the halls, and in the officers' dining room; and the living 
rooms and offices have been repapered, repainted, and refurnished 
throughout. This building has been painted, outside, 
two coats. 

tDusTBiAL Building. — The industrial building has been 
jfed and painted two coats. In the boys' kitchen, the 
3 have been cemented and caleimined and the ceilings 
ted; also a new cement floor put in the vegetable room. 
!W twelve-foot John Van range, with hot water tank, has 
installed. The laundry lias new floors and the walls 
been cemented, painted, and caleimined, and everything 
oughly cleaned. All of the employes' rooms in this buildtiave 
been thoroughly cleaned and repaired, and painted 
or three coats, all of the paper having been removed. 

Grade Buildings. — All of the grade buildings, consisting 
of buildings E, B, C, and D, have been reroofed, repaired, 
plastered or caleimined, and partially refurnished. The 
floors have al] been paraffined and the plumbing repaired. 
On the outside, the bricks have all been pointed with 
ment, and every one of the buildings painted two coats. The 
old F building, which has been renamed A, has been idle 
and vacant for a number of years. This building has beea 
thoroughly overhauled ; new floors have been put in the first 
story and the walls have been replastered and rooms repapered 
and painted. The plumbing has been overhauled and </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
232 


¦ in first-class condition, and the outside of the building 
been pointed up with cement and painted two coats. 

Boiler House and Heating Plant. — We have installed a 
100 horse-power marine boiler in our heating plant, have 
reset and repaired three of the old ones, and have completely 
overhauled the heating system so as to put high pressure 
steam into the mains. A new water tank, 16 by 60, has 
been installed, and our engines have been thoroughly 
hauled and repaired, so that we will be able to do 
all our work by steam. The exhaust from the engines is 
conducted into the heating system so that no heat will be lost. 
Two partitions, twelve feet high, have been put in the coal 
bin, making three bins instead of one large one, and a cement 
floor has been put in each bin. This has been done to prevent 
heating of the coal as must as possible. 

KERK HOUSE. — We have put a twelve-inch hollow vail 
id our greenhouse and installed an independent hot 
1 plant for heating purposes. 

IJT-Bt'iiDiNGS. — Our horse barn, cow barn, ice house, and 
sheds have been thoroughly overhauled, repaired, and 
ted, each two coats. A new chicken house, 100 feet by 
jet, is under construction at this time. Our standpij&gt;e, 
h is 112 feet high and 12 feet in diameter, has been 
led and painted two coats. Our old smokestack, which 
abandoned some years ago, has been torn down ; and the 
nstern, formerly used as a reservoir, has been torn out 
the brick used in making -other repairs. 

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING. 

We are accomplishing good work in this line, but we hope 
to be able to further equip our departments with machinery 
so as to give a regular course of instruction in these lines of 
manual training. 

In our carpenter department we are only able to have 
about four boys on a detail, and the work done there is mostly 
in keeping up the general repairs of the institution. The 
{It 1 ! mi*t ii li'ii t is (Hi hiddihI f n ii*l v wt*! 1 *is *i &lt;**i 1*1 m*o t&lt;*i* si ion *iti &lt;1 
</seg>
            <seg id="p011">
233 


Ioys are taught to do general work of this nature. We 
to have the department supplied with lathes, kind &gt; 
«, and other equipments, so we can handle a larger class 
ys in this departineut and give them a systematic traina 
wood work. 

Iichinery Department. — This department is in need &lt;&gt;f 
r equipment, so .that more boys can he taught this trade. 
a very useful trade, and many boys would like to learn 
we only had the facilities to teach them. 

Pointing Department. — We have a well-equipped printing 
department, and it is one of the most DOfWllar ief 
nit'uts of the institution. We teach boys to become practical 
printers, and it is a source of education to them in other 
lines, such as spelling, punctuation, composition, etc. We 
have a large number of boys who work in this department 
and a number of applications constantly on file for places as 
soon as a vacancy occurs. We publish a monthly magazine, 
called "The Courier," which has, during the last year. 
admitted by the post-office department a.s second-class sutler. 
It is printed and edited mostly by the boys, and has 
quitw a circulation. All the printing for our institution is 
done by this department. 

Laundry Department. — Our laundry is not only a useful, 
but a very practical department. It is well equipped and 
managed, and we are able to teach a number of boys to Impractical 
laundrymen, which is an excellent trade and i 
n uinds good wages. 

Tailoring Department. — In our tailoring department, all 
the boys' clothing, caps, underwear, sheets, pillow able 
cloths, towels, and everything in this line used by the insti 
tution, are made. All the repairing of boys" clothes is d 
in the tailor shop; and, besides this, all the citizen suit^ 
boys who are paroled are made here, thus giving boys an 
experience in making citizens' clothes, in addition to the uniform 
work. 

Shoe Shop. — In this department all the shoes used by the 
institution are made, besides all the repair work of shoes, </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
234 


harness, balls, belts, and other work in this line. It is a 
very valuable department and well conducted. 

Kitchens and Dining Rooms. — In our kitchens, boys are 
taught to become practical cooks and bakers, and in the dining 
rooms they learn to do the work mostly done there in a 
satisfactory manner. 

Korticulture. — We have a well-equipped greenhouse, and 
\ are given a thorough and practical training in the uianueut 
and care of plants. 

AGRICULTURE AND FARM WORK. 

'In this line we endeavor to teach the boys to be practical 
farmers, to learn to handle and operate all farm implements 
and machinery, and to do the work in all lines as it should 
be done. The following is a detailed statement of the farm 
and its workings: 

The school farm consists of the original 320 acres. The 
buildings, campus, drives, and canal (with ponds) occupy 
about 30 acres; 90 acres are planted in alfalfa, G5 acres in 
pasture land, 5 acres are planted to berries and fruit trees, 
and the remainder, or 130 acres, are cultivated. 

The state does not own sufficient farming land for the 
best interests of the school, consequently the custom of past 
years was followed and land was rented. In 1903, 172£ acres 
were rented at fo per acre, and 1-t acres were cropped on 
shares. This year, 102 acres of farming land, at $ 5 per acre, 
&gt;• rented, and also 120 acres of pasture for flOO. The 
state should own, at least, 160 acres more of land. 

Owing to the favorable weather conditions, close attention. 
and thorough cultivation, the harvests for this biennial 
period have been most bountiful. Sufficient fresh vegetables 
of all kinds, and of the best varieties, have furnished the 
tables to a degree of overflowing, an abundance has been 
stored in the cellars, with a surplus of many kinds for the 

During this biennium over 400 loads of manure were put </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
235 

The farm is free from cockleburs and sunflowers, and v 
have been kept down over the entire farm and roadsides. 

Iock. — During the first year of this period a small per 
of the fresh meat used was killed at the school, and it 
satisfaction to the extent that about all used during the 
just closed was killed on the school farm. The herd of 
1 cows has been substantially improved. Old cows i 
ned and replaced by young and better ones, and the herd 
ased until it numbers twenty-five. A thoroughbred t 
old bull has been purchased, and we have the following 
¦ cattle on hand: 13 beef cattle, 11 calves, 1 young bull. 

Hogs. — In addition to our own raising of pigs, we have 
purchased young shoats, at different times, to keep up the 
herd, as a surplus of the heavy, fat hogs were marketed, and 
two or three each week are necessary to furnish meat for the 
school. We are now changing the breed, from Poland China 
to Jersey Durocs. We have 121 hogs on hand at the present 
time, including 14 pigs. 

Kobses. — There are fifteen head of horses owned by the 
ol, most of them ranging from sixteen to twenty years 
Two young driving horses were purchased during the 

Eultry. — No poultry has been raised here for a number 
ars. In view of starting the enterprise, however, a new 
ry house is now being completed. 

Our farm implements are kept in good repair, though the 
plows and disks are well worn. A new carriage was purchased 
this year. Our carriages, buggies, and farm implements 
are all kept under a roof. 

The following is the crop raised during the year 1903 : 

Potatoes bu. 

1,640 

Cauliflower hds. 1,400 

Sweet potatoes. . . ., . bu. 

90 

Kraut bbl. 14 

Onions bu. 

300 

Peppers bu. 10 

Table beets bu. 

650 

Strawberries qta. 

tiips bu. 
ify bu. 

400 
20 

Alfalfa hay tons 165 
Corn bu. 1,400 

!sw0Gl oorn bu i o0 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
236 


f beans bu. 75 

f beans bu. 75 

Sugar beets. .. .tons 240.88 

Sugar beets. . . .tons 240.88 

Squash doz. 100 

String beans. .. .bu. 1- 

String beans. . . .bu. 1- 
Mangel wurzel. .bu. 1,0(10 

Carrots bu. 220 

Carrots bu. 220 

Mangel wurzel. .bu. 1,01 10 

Lettuce bu. 50 

Lettuce bu. 50 

Parsnips bu. 50 

Parsnips bu. 50 

iragus bu. 11 

i vagus bu. 11 

Cucumbers bu. S66 

Cucumbers bu. 

Rhubarb bu. 50 

Rhubarb bu. 50 

Radishes bu. 40 

Radishes bu. 40 

Melons loads 6 

Melons loads 6 

Tomatoes bu. 30 

Tomatoes bu. 30 

Spinach bu. 12 

Spinach bu. 12 

Cabbage lids. 14,001) 

Cabbage lids. 14,&lt;mm 

Celery plants 4,000 

&lt; Vlery plants 4,000 
s. bu. 2,451 

Peas (shelled) . .bu. 

Peas (shelled) . .bu. io_\ 

Wheat bu. 820 

Parsley bu. •"• 

Parsley bu. 5 

Oats. bu. 2,451 

Pop corn bu. 2&lt;» 

Pop corn bu. 2&lt;» 

I lie following list shows the farm and garden products for 
year 1904, together with the amounts consumed and sold 
the amounts now on hand : 

Amount Amount Amount Amount 

Product Raised Consumed Sold on Hand 

Potatoes 4000 bu. 280 bu. 75# bu. 3924Ji bu. 

Sweet potatoes. . . 220 bu. 220 bu. 

Corn (estimated). 300 Jbu. 150 bu. 2850 bu. 

Sweet corn 540 bu. 80 bu. (ears) (Seed) 500 bu. 

Oats 1020 bu (old and new) 1320 bu. 

Alfalfa hay 195 tons GO tons 13 tons 122 tons 

Wild hay 26 tons 8 tons 18 to) 
Onions 530 bu. 93 bu. 91 bu. 346 bu. 

H tal 

Navy beans 195 bu. 12 bu. 183 bu. 

String beans 40 bu. 30 bu. (seed) 3 bu. 

Table beets 550 bu. 480 bu. 70 bu. 

Mangel wurael bts 1000 bu. 700 bu. 300 bu. 

Squash 6 loads 3 loads 3 loads 

Turnip* 400 bu. 320 bu. 80 bu. 

CarroU 200 bu. 150 bu. 50 bu. 

Parsnips 40 bu. 15 bu. 25 bo. 

Salsify 32 bu. 16 bu. 16 bu. 

Lettuce 90 bu. 90 bu. 

Asparagus 21 bu. 21 bu. 

Radishes 40 bu. 34 bu. 6 bu. 

Rhubarb 70 bu. 70 bu. 

Tomatoes 570 bu. 570 bu. (used fresh and canned) 

Melons 12 loads 12 loads 

Kraut 20barrels 2 barrels 18barrels 

Peppers 20 bu. 5 bu. 2 bu. 
1_ /SI 0 1 

Spinach 6 bu. 6 bu. 

Peas 30bu. 20 bu. (seed) 2 bu. 

Celery 4200 plants 3700 plants 

Celery 4200 plants 3700 plants 500 plants 
Cherries 75bu. 75 bu. ( used fresh and canned) 

Plums 24 bu. 24 bu. (used fresh and canned) 
Strawberries 400 quarts 400 quarts 
Gooseberries # bu % bu. 


Cumnts 8bu. 8 bu. 

Sugar beets 265.389 tons 265.389 tons </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

237 

Amount Amount Amount Amount 

Product Raised Consumed Sold on i 

OTHEB DEPARTMENTS AND THADE WORK. 

Ii addition to the regular department work, in which 1 
regularly detailed, we have opportunity during the y»-ar 
each boys the following trades: Painting, plastering, 
brick-laying, cement work of all kinds, and 
oub other lines that may have to be dona 

PHYSICAL TRAINING. 

fe have no regular prescribed course in physical culture. 
boys have their athletics — baseball, football, basketball, 
-kating, and various other sports known only to a 
They also quite often have an opportunity to exer 
selves in doing the various "chores" on a farm, and the 
r work incident to keeping up such an institution. W« 
work of this kind a very satisfactory substitute for reguihysical 
training, and it can not be excelled as a muscle 
loper. 

In addition to this, our boys are organized into five military 
companies, officered by boys, and they receive systematic 
training in military tactics. Each company is drilled twice 
each week. We are hampered in this work by not hi 
guns for drilling, but we hope to be equipped with guns and 
other accoutrements before long. 

Once each year, usually on the 4th of July, we observe Field 
hay. On this day a fierce contest is waged in all the tit-Id 
sports and in military drills. Prizes are given to the winners 
of each class, an institution record is kept of the winners, 
and the records made each year, and it is the ambition of the 
contestants to break the previous records. Field Day has 
become a part of the institution, and it is looked upon as the 

Ebers 400 bu. 100 bu. (and pickles) 
berpickles. 14 barrels 2 barrels 
mer 1800 heads 1800 heads 
;e 15000 heads 120 dz. &amp; kraut 150 heads 

(ieed) Ub^rel 
"SOO head </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
238 


DISCIPLINE. 

The one great object of all training is discipline, whether 
it be of the mind, the body, or the soul. 

11 our work we endeavor to cultivate the good and restrain 
evil. We encourage a boy to do right in every way we 
and we make it as difficult as possible for him to do 
Qg. We prefer to reward him for doing well, rather than 
unish him for misbehavior. We keep on the lookout for 
good he does rather than for the bad. We never lose 
&gt;pportunity to suppress the wrong, however; yet we !•«¦-i 
in the old maxim, "The way to get rid of a vice 
a virtue in its place." 

To bring about the required discipline, we must resort to 
all the ways and means known. All cases can not be treated 
alike, and we must apply the remedy that seems best for the 
particular case, doses to be repeated as often as necessary. 

MORAL AND RELIGIOUS INSTRUCTION. 

We have no resident chaplain at the institution, but religious 
services are held every Sabbath afternoon at 2 :30 o'clock 
and conducted by the ministers of the different churches of 
the city of Kearney. There are seven of these ministers, and 
alternate in coming out for our church services. They 
take great interest in our work, and assist very much in carrying 
on the religious work of the institution. 

Our Sabbath school is held every Sunday morning, from 
10 ."00 o'clock to 11 :00. We have the schools divided into five 
classes, and thirty minutes are spent in the study of the lesson 
in the class rooms ; then they assemble in the chapel for a review 
and general talks on the lesson. Our Sunday school is 
conducted by the superintendent, assistant superintendent, 
and grade managers, and is made a regular part of the work 
of the institution. 

SANITARY CONDITIONS. 

¦e are profoundly thankful for the great degree of health 
we have enjoyed during this biennium. It has been </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
239 


t remarkable. There have been no deaths and no COBus 
or infectious diseases; in fact, we have had no 
except the minor troubles incident to childhood and 
i and a few cuts, strains, and bruises, resulting from 
tic sports. 

I'e believe that cleanliness is necessary for healthy cosins, 
and we wage war against dirt and filth, unceasingly, 
have thoroughly cleansed and disinfected every portion 
le institution, and keep up this work regularly. Wherever 
ar and wainscoting could be dispensed with, it h;is been 
», and paint and calcimine substituted, so that we are 
nnably free from vermin of all kinds. 

PAROLE SYSTEM. 

Een boys are sent to our school they are committed 
they are twenty-one years of age, or until they are ilisld 
according to law. 

This does not mean that boys are to remain here until 
they become of age. We have a system of parole by which 
a boy is allowed to go out from here, after he has complied 
with the rules of the institution and attained a reasonable 
proficiency in the work assigned him. After he is turned 
over to the state for training and preparation for citizenship. 
it is necessary that the state do this work as thoroughly 
can in the time given, so we require a boy to have a &lt;: 
fair education, and, in order to do this, it is necessary that 
he apply himself diligently to his school work. We also 
require that he learn, reasonably well, the trade that he undertakes, 
so that he will be able to follow it when he goe^ 
from the school. He must also maintain a good deportment, 
and satisfy us that his conduct will be what it should 
1 f ter he is paroled. 

I he time it requires to do this work depends entirely 
effort the boy puts forth and the interest he takes in it. 
throw the whole responsibility on him, and he can make 
time long or short. </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
240 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

After a boy is ready for parole, we make another requirement 
of the parents or guardian. We require that they make 
a showing that they are capable and willing to look after 
and care for the boy, furnish him a home, and have some 
thing for him to do. If we are satisfied with the showing 
made, after examination, we parole the boy for four months. 
We require a report from the boy and parent or guardian 
y two weeks. If the boy continues to do what he should, 
parole is extended, on and on, until he becomes of 
ase he violates this parole, and fails to do as he should, 
he is returned to the institution. If the showing made by 
the parent or guardian does not warrant our paroling the 
bov to them, we find a place for him ourselves. 

Our greatest trouble in paroling a boy to his parents is in 
putting him back in the same place and under the same influences 
that he had before being sent here. If the parent 
could not manage him when he was twelve or fifteen years 
old, he surely can not do it when the boy is eighteen and 
nineteen years of age. We meet with more success when 
boys are placed in new communities and under new influences. 
It is a very difficult thing for a boy to go back among 
his old associates and friends and not take up the old habits ; 
he may do it for awhile, but in time, if the associations are 
continued, he is very liable to be affected by them. No one 
knows this better than the boy, and quite often we have requests 
from boys to be allowed to change their locations on 
that account. 

The first three months after a boy is paroled usually determine 
which way he is going. During that time he begins to 
and think independently, and it is then that he needs 
counsel, close attention, and the assistance of those 
who are interested in his welfare. It is necessary that he 
have something to do to be kept busy, that he observe the 
proper rules of conduct, and that his associations be such 
that may lead him in the right way. 

Pie try to have people in each community take an interin 
our boys and assist them along these lines; to report </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
241 


the progress the boys are making, together with any wrong 
things they may be doing. This is separate from the parents' 
or guardian's report. If we find a boy is trying to do right, 
assist him in every way we can, even if he fails many 

| r e do not expect our boys to be perfect. The communijudge 
them by a much higher standard than they do the 
r boys of the community. This, of course, is unfair; 
they do, and we can not change the judgment. What 
lo expect of our boys, however, is that they do the best 
can, and form habits that will be useful to them an«l tn 
community in which they live. After having given them 
ir trial, and they persist in going wrong, we return them 
ur school for further instruction. After a boy is paroled, 
only as a last resort that we. return him to the school. 

Iur experience with the boys we have paroled during the 
s we have had charge of the institution is indeed very 
mraging and satisfactory. Out of the whole numlx-r 
&gt;led only a very few have been returned. Some are u&lt;»t 
lg as well as they should, and we are working with them, 
the great majority of them are conducting themselves in 
exemplary manner, are industrious, and are trying to do 
best they can. 

Ie are soliciting the aid of all good people in the state in 
work, which we think is the greatest work in the st. 
that of making good citizens. All that our boys want is 
s one to care for them and an opportunity to work, and 
will do the rest. 

POPULATION. 

Ece the organization of this school there have been 1,547 
enrolled. At the beginning of this biennium the atnce 
was 145 ; and during the two years we have received 
oys. The average age of the boys received during the 
ium was 14.3 years. 

There have been S3 boys paroled and 17 returned from 
parole. Of the total boys paroled during this biennium only 

!6 </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
242 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Is have been returned from parole, one because he had 
ne to care for him, and the other two for violation of 
le. The other fourteen who were returned were boys 
had been paroled several years and had not been looked 
• properly. 

The boys received during the period were from the follow- 

ing counties : 

Antelope 1 

Box Butte 2 

Cheyenne 1 

Cherry 4 

Dawson 4 

Dakota 2 


Jefferson 3 

Madison 3 

Lancaster 11 


Scotts Bluff 1 

Platte 2 


Adams 2 

Buffalo 11 

Cass. 4 

Custer 3 


Furnas 1 

_ 

Hall 1 

Howard 1 

Km »x 1 

Lincoln 4 

Nemaha 4 

Phelps 1 

Valley 1 

Seward 3 

Boone 1 

Colfax 1 

Cedar 2 

Douglas 4 

Fillmore 2 

&lt;e 1 

_ 

1 l*'lt ¦•¦••¦¦••¦•¦•••••¦• J. 

Johnson 1 


Merrick 2 

- 

Otoe 3 

Pawnee 1 

Saline. 1 

York 3 

The offenses 

with 

which 

they were charged 


are as 

Incorrigibility 

33, larceny 

32, mendicancy 15, burglary 11, 

Kiult and battery 5, horse stealing 3, robbery 2, obstructrailroad 
track 2, forgery 4. </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

243 

•l*SIS OF SOME OF THE IMPROVEMENTS MADE AND OF THE 
GENERAL WORK DONE DURING THE BIENNIUM. 

General repairing of all the buildings, inside and outside, 
-hown in the report of "repairs." 

I i'-building greenhouse and installing hot water plant for 
same. 

Overhauling and remodeling heating plant, installing a 
new marine boiler and resetting the others. 

Kking a large water tank out of one of the old boile 
institution has an abundant supply of hot water at 
mes. 

Installing a new twelve-foot John Van range in our boys' 
kitchen. 

Repairing the old, discarded steam engine and putting it 
in use, dropping out the large gasoline engine, except as a 
ive. 

Dividing the large coal bin into three smaller bins, by 
brick partitions, and putting cement floors in each to prevent 
coal from heating. 

B pairing and refurnishing the old D building, and, on 
int of the increased attendance, installing a new grade 
me, named A grade. 

K pointing all the brick and stone work of all buildings, 
; about ten tons of cement. 

Ee have built and equipped a chicken house capable of 
ing 500 hens, and have installed a regular chicken dement. 


Eir dairy herd has been increased and improved till we 
have twenty-five cows ; and we are also raising the calves 
same. 

We have changed the stock of hogs from Poland China to 
Puroc. 

Ke buy and raise our own beef cattle and hogs, and 
jhter them ourselves. 

Ke have added a new carriage, driving team, wagon, 
er, and other equipments to our farm department. </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
244 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

We have moved and repaired our corn cribs, and have 
built new wagon and implement sheds, so that our implements 
can be under shelter. 

We have graded our schools and have a regular course up 
to and including the ninth grade. 

Be have improved our monthly magazine, "The Courier." 
increased the subscription so it is admitted as secondmatter 
by the post-office department. 

We have organized a band, purchasing new instruments, 
and practice regularly, making excellent progress. 

Ie have abandoned the bread and water table and also 
general clipping of the hair. We allow a boy to let his 
grow as he wishes, so long as he cares for it properly 
maintains a good deportment. 

In fact, we have done everything we could to raise the 
standard of the school in all lines, and, from the results 
obtained, we are satisfied that our labors have not been in 

rIS OF SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE STITX NEEDED AND 
WHICH SHOULD BE DONE AS SOON AS POSSIBLE. 

All of the old board walks which are worn out should be 
iced by cement walks. 

Er machine and blacksmith shop should be moved down 
; boiler house and installed there, so the engineer's work 
all be together. 

Bother new boiler should be purchased and installed and 
Id ones taken out. 

We need a new, directly-connected engine and dynamo of 
the latest type to do our work. 

We need motors to do the laundry, printing office, and carjKMiter 
shop work. 

We need a new root and vegetable house, about forty feet 
square, with a deep basement. 

We need a small, well-equipped hospital. </seg>


            <seg id="p023">
245 

K r e need a manual training department to our school, so 
o give regular instruction along this line, and b* 
pments for other trade departments. 

I'e need one-half section more of land ; 160 acres of farm 
and 160 acres of pasture. The institution has been 
ng from $600 to f 1,200 rent for extra land each year for 
last ten or fifteen years, and it would pay the stat. 
the land rather than to do this. 

Ke need new floors in the school rooms, dormitories, and 
i of all grade buildings. 

Our buildings, for safety, should be rewired. 

Our military companies should be equipped with guns of 
some sort, for drilling purposes. 

FINANCIAL STATEMENT. 

E order to make clear the statement of "appropriations 
expenditures/' which follows, it will be necessary to give 
ntroductory explanation of the manner in which the 
tints designated as appropriations are derived. 

As this biennial period began December 1, 1902, and the 
new appropriations were not available until April, 1903, 
there were several months thaf we were using funds of the 
1901 appropriation. On August 31, 1904, however, this appropriation 
lapsed, and the balances then remaining in all 
the funds reverted to the state. 

Below is a table showing the balances in the various funds 
at the beginning of this biennial period, to which are adtlnl 
the appropriations for 1903; and from these totals are deducted 
the amounts which lapsed on August 31, 1904. The 
remainders, then, are the amounts which have been actually 
at our disposal during this period, and are used in the statement 
as appropriations: </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
FUND 

bal. irov. '02 

APPR. OS 

TOTAL 

LAPSED 

MET APPR. 

Officers' Salaries 
Employe*' Wage* . . 

$ 3,756.18 
3,451.31 

117,200.00 
17,000.00 
4,424.95* 
15,000.00 
24,000.00 
4,000 00 
8,000.00 
800.00 
8,000.00 

$ 20,956.18 
20,451.31 

$ 826.12 
871.50 

$ 20,130.06 
19,579.81 

Fuel, Electric Lights 
Board, Din. Room. . 
Library Books, etc. . 
Clothing, Bed'g, etc. 
Equip'g Trade Depts 
Perm. &amp; Gen. Rep. . 
New Armature 

10.37 
2,585.63 
512.57 
1,596.03 
440 79 
316.70 
200.00 

19.4S5.32 
26,585.63 
4,512.57 
9,596.05 
1,240.79 
8,316.70 
200.00 

3.74 
.03 
5.14 
34.15 
415.07 
15 65 
7.14 

26i585!6O 
9I56L90 
825.72 
8,30105 
192.86 

$2,178.54 

I 109,116.01 

$12,869.60 

I 98,424.95 

$111,294.55 

•Deficiency Decemt 

er, 1902, to A 

pril, 1908. 

As stated abo 1 

e, this t 

able is merely to explain the more 

complete statem 

»nt whic 

h follows: 

APPROPRIATIONS 

LND EXP1 

ENDITURES FROM DECEMBER 1, 1902 

TO N(N 

MEMBER 30, 1904. 

Officers' salaries — 

Appropriation f 20,130 06 

Expended 15,780 28 

Balance. 

|4,349 78 

Employes' wages — 

Appropriation $19,579 81 

Expended 15,055 46 

Balance 

$4,524 35 

Fuel, electric lights, etc. — 

Appropriation f 19,431 58 

Expended. 17,291 32 

Balance 

|2,140 26 

rrd, dining room expenses, etc. — 
Appropriation f 26,585 60 

Expended. 18,599 32 

Balance 

|7,986 28 </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
247 

SIXTH INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

Clothing, bedding, and furniture — 

Appropriation $ 9,561 90 

Expended 8,710 91 

Balance f 850 99 

Permanent and general repairs — 

Appropriation f 8,301 05 

Expended 8,127 13 

Balance $ 173 H 

Library books, periodicals, etc. — 

Appropriation f 4,507 43 

Expended 2,803 95 

Balance |l,703 48 

Equipping trade departments — 

Appropriation f 825 72 

Expended 112 67 

Balance $ 713 05 

New armature — 

Appropriation f 192 86 

Expended 192 86 

CASH ACCOUNT. 

Balance on hand November 30, 1902 ? 469 51 

Receipts from December 1, 1902, to 
May 31, 1903 f 2,378 17 

Receipts from June 1, 1903, to November 
30, 1903 1,444 93 

Receipts from December 1, 1903, to 
May 31, 1904 1,302 81 

Receipts from June 1, 1904, to No- 

vember 30, 1904 1,986 93 7,112 84 

Total </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
248 


Disbursements from December 1, 
1902, to May 31, 1903 $ 1,185 94 

turaements from June'l, 1903, 
to November 30, 1903 966 11 

Disbursements from December 1, 
1903, to May 31, 1904 1,585 90 

rursements from June 1, 1904, 
to November 30, 1904 2,075 12 

Total 

5,813 07 

Balance on hand November 30, 

1904 fl,769 28 

rATE OF AMOUNT OF FUNDS REQUIRED FOR THE BIENNIAL 
PERIOD BEGINNING APRIL 1, 1905. 

Salary of superintendent f 3,600 00 

Salary of assistant superintendent 2,200 00 

Salary of bookkeeper and stenographer 1,600 00 

Salary of chaplain 600 00 

Salary of physician 1,200 00 

Salary of five grade managers 8,000 00 

Employes' wages 17,000 00 

Fuel, electric lights, water supplies, and boiler 
house expenses 15,000 00 

Board, dining room expenses, and kitchen supplies 
24,000 00 

Clothing, bedding, and furniture 8,000 00 

Permanent and general repairs 8,000 00 

Equipping trade departments 1,600 00 

Iary books, periodicals and papers, school 
books and stationery, medicines, oils and druggists' 
supplies, telephone, telegraph, postage 
and office supplies, fugitives, freight and express, 
incidental and traveling expenses, music 
and amusements 4,000 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p027">
249 


CONCLUSION. 

t making the foregoing report, we have been as concise as 
)uld and yet make it intelligible. During the time I 
had charge of the institution (since April 1, 190 
given the management my personal attention in all delents. 
I have tried to conduct the business in a strict h 
ess-like manner and on business principles, and I am 
to say that we have received fair treatment from all 
whom we have dealt. We always try to know what W9 
to purchase, and we have always received what we did 
lase. 

Ie have been as economical as consistency with good manlent 
would allow. Since our appropriations were made 
ie legislature, the prices of nearly all supplies have ;ul 
ed materially, in many cases from 25 per cent to 50 pef 
during the biennium. Our attendance has increased 
ich an extent that, on September 15, 1904, it became 
ssary to start a new grade. Yet, with the increased cost 
upplies and the increased attendance, we have kept 
in our appropriations; and, unless something hapi 
we do not anticipate, we will have no deficiency in any 

We have combined work wherever and whenever we could. 
in order to reduce the number of employes to the actual 
needs of the institution; so that our present force is as small 
as good and safe management will warrant. 

Wherever it was possible to make a change or improvement 
in any department, that would be more economic;il 
without lowering the standard, we have done it as far as we 

Ee one sole object we have had in mind has been to do all 
&gt;uld,"in all the ways possible, for the betterment of the 
under our care; and to manage the affairs and business 
? institution in a careful and business-like manner. </seg>


            <seg id="p028">

We submit our acts for your consideration, feeling that 
we have done what we could. 

Respectfully submitted, 

B. D. Hayward, Superintendent </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>