<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  SOME INSECTS INJURIOUS TO WHEAT DURING 1905-1906</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">HUM.ETIN NO University &lt;&gt;k Nebraska. BULLETIN THK AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION NKHRASKA MB XIX, Article III SOME INSECTS INJURIOUS TO WHEAT DURING J905-1906 BKl'NKR ANIi MVRON II. SWKNK M \K^II U, 19lT LINCOLN. NEBRASKA V S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATION AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD IC Kf.lNTI Or TMr UP! VIM S. ALLEN. Lincoln Bi. WHITMO ERICK II ABBO1 . »R G. I.YHiRl THE STATION OFFICERS ■ BURNETT, B.S )ALES, M Pii . / \V. MARSHALl THE WORKING STAFF H. R. Smith, B.S F. E. Denny, A.B., Assistant in I foil I CARL I. KRNST. Pi A. I PETEKS, D.V.M., . \mmal /" ■f.rick I&gt;. Hf.ai.d, Ph.D., Botany u.way. Pii.I).. Cketm Haeokkk. ll.Sc.A., Dairy II IBMCI IIkinkk, B.Sc . ICntom Monk, i 'Mi kv. I' .Si . / : Mn. i kk. M.I .. Forestry s- H. Babbook, run C. R. Chatbikn. A.M., Higkwty l-'.n. . Ili'lll. IU o. \'. P. Stoct, C.E., Irrigation Eitgimet i ILovi i and, IVSi .. Mrteorv ; Kf.ysf.r. A.M .. Smts Snvdi r, M.S., &gt;np&lt; i • inlrnJtiit Experimental iAIN, M.D.C., Associate in Animal Ptthol Magdanz, Jh., A.B.. Assistant in . iuimal ///&lt; bauJry Sturdf.vant. A.M.. . Usistmmt in . tnimsJ l\itkology in Nelshn. M.S.. . I /&gt;s. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SOME INSECTS INJURIOUS TO WHEAT DURING 1&lt;X)5-I9O6 IKl NER AM) MYRON II. SWKNK. hie exception of the Chinch-bug there is no w l» more destruction to the wheat crop, or one ii islns more iu that direction than the Hessian »lete destruction of au entire crop in badly in- ■ in no uncommon thing, while the averau the whole country infested by it is annually ii tor ■out one tenth of the crop, an approximate amount of forty r more. Hence, when this insect appeared ish ance over the winter wheat growing section of in fall of 1!M)4, its presence excited great anxiety tli Iligent wheat growers and grain dealers of our n \ others directly interested in the wheat crop. i Stale Entomologist was besieged with let - parties calling for information and advice, ti t was one which had never before been pi imVient numbers to cause apprehension, our i h it was correspondingly limited, and the in- re able to then give was of a very general The \er&gt; obvious necessity for detailed knowledge v •ruing the local characteristics of the pest was pi before the State Legislature then in session, backed by the recommendations of several state societies and farmers" in ms a part of the biennial report of the State En- 11 t and is lia^i &lt;l on studies conducted during the past two years in. This particular part of the work was done and re- ported u]hiii by Mr Sweiik Other results of the work done are incor - i».nite&lt;l in the State Horticultural Society report for 1906, and still others will l&gt;e printed in the report of the State Board of Agriculture for the ame year. — Lawrence Brunt Hessian Fly (Mayetiola destructor Say). </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Some Inaecta Injurious to Wheat. stitutes, with the final result that a sum of three thou - dollars was appropriated for the purpose of inratigating and publishing upon this and other insert pests during the fol lowing biennium. Under the able direct ion of Prof Bruner the writer was placed in the tield April 1, 1 !•(»."». to investigate the Hessian th and other injurious insecis. and continued this work without interruption for the following six months. The notes gathered daring this period, together with the information secured through the discussions at im - nieroiis fanners" institutes addressed by him during the pre - ceding winter, form the basis for the statements made in the following report. At the same time all reliable published inents &lt;&gt;n the subject have been freely utilized, especially the papen referred to in the footnotes from time to time. ORIGIN A I. HOMK OF THE HESSIAN FLY The original habitat of this insert is still a matter of s doubt and probably always will be, but as it is found only on Wheat, rye. and barley and on no other liost plant it i - sonable to infer that its original home was the laud where these plants were tirst grown, which is. supposedly, wes Asia. It has been known as an inhabitant of Europe for a long time, and has a wide range over the wheat belt of that continent. Of recent years it has penetrated even to Zealand. Its introduction into America is thought by man\ to have been coincident with the landing of the Hea troops on Long Island in 177t&gt;, probably having been brought over in the straw used as bedding by these soldiers. 1 Two Hi - three years later it appeared to an injurious extent in the wheat near the locality of disembarkation, and since then has spread westward at an average rate of about twenty miles per year until it now covers the vast wheat growing area from Ontario to South Carolina and northern Georgia, and from 'For a discussion of "The Early History of th&lt; in An ica," see Webster, Annual Meeting fur thi m of Agricultu Science, Philadelphia. 1905. i </seg>
            <seg id="p005">/ 5 iota In Oklalioniii. In 1TS»&gt; it had coveted 844 Indiana and Illinois, and in 1860 Iowa N M u 1 s«i7 the fly crossed the .Missouri Hirer \ Iowa and gained a footing in Mattered wheat nVlds of md Otoe counties, and the next year it increased Ma- ilily in numben and spread out over these connt li year 1S»&gt;!) brought it into Sarpy and Douglas counties. extending westward, during the next three years the fly nto Lancaster, Saunders, Seward, and even into York where specimens were obtained in 1872. Two years appeared in Richardson, I'awnee. and Gage counties ie southern border of the state. In 1870 slight dam- lone to wheat in these counties, and the par;: nmdis hicmdlii was bred by Dr. Riley from material i ted at Blair on August 1(&gt; of that year. 1 In 1880 flies ■ fairly common. The next year it became very Bcarce, found slightly infesting wheat near Lincoln.- In was noted in wheat near Pawnee City and in 1886 i near Lincoln, luit in 1887 the Hies became very scarce owing to drv weather, and continued so for a dozen or i years.' The next evidence of increase and damage was n 19M when it was taken from stubble in the "flaxs. in July at Wakefield in Dixon county and Florence in Doaglafl county. 4 In 1M1 it became common enough to &lt;x -nine little comment, and Professor Hruner published in Kl'ir&lt; n titth Century Farmer" under date of March 27, an article of some length dealing with the appearance ife history of the insect, as well as advocating some ird remedies for it, at the same time requesting n regarding its prevalence and injuries in the state. Portions Osborn. Bull. 16, Div. Ent. U. S. Dept. Agric. p. 36 (1898). Brunei-. 3d Rept. U. S. Ent. Comm., pp. 243-44 (1883). McMillan. Bull. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta., Vol. I. No. 2, pp. 20-21 (1888). 'Specimens in collection of Univ. of Nebraska. IIISTOKY IN NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 of this article were published in certain other newspaper also. With the succession of extremely favorable mi during the next three years, characterised ;is they were b; unusually warm ami wet springs and summers, there rewrite* a rapid and increasing multiplication in numbers of the th all of which rapidly led up to its unprecedented ahundauc in 1!K)4. I'.y this time, too. the insert had extended its rang Eil it included all the wheat growing territory of the eaa one-third of the North Platte country, and tin- Sout He country west to Red Willow county, ;is is shown i the accompanying map Tin: iii:ssian v in I'.mii Knowing that the By had fall of 1903, and convinced i 19CH crop was due to the ra\ in order to fortify the wheat sen quite prevalent during hat urn short spring ro WSIR1BUT10N OF HESSIAN FLY.1905-06 Fig. 1. (Original.) by the fall brood, the Entomologist compiled, as IMvss l',i Eon, a leaflet letting forth in condensed form the methods &lt;&gt;f tack of and remedies for tin' Hessian tly. This bulletin was distributed September 1U. 1904, but the number of new but d ot,e moderate t letin No. 19, of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Sta </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 was vciv few indeed, sn tliat tin- rem il li received very little publicity. In itionary measures were taken by the Ybout the middle of October reports of da— gr lie Entomologist's office from all over Nebraska, and an attempt was made to ascertain the full extent of these injuries. A i[iies- nqairing into the presence or tirst appearan&lt; he nalure and extent of the injuries inflicted, and nations employed, was sent to the various den station agentl along the several railroads traversing using sections of the state, and to these questions x hundred replies were received. These replies ible the preparation of a tentative report and a h were published in the "State Journal'' for De - 1004. showing the infested areas and the various )f injury. The damage was found to be greatest in a tnbracing the counties of York. Reward, flay. Fill Saline where from 30 per cent to "&gt;0 per cent, and nstances as high ;is 7.~&gt; per cent of the plants were lading out into about 20 per cent damage in Lan - northern Cage, Jefferson, and Thayer counties. nder of the infested area was damaged 10 per Easing the estimate on the exported wheat in raa shown that, according to the reported percent ;s in this area would aggregate nearly five million trheat. The writer thoroughly l&gt;elieves that this not in the least overestimated, and a personal in - fields in nearly every county of the infested region •erred only to strengthen this opinion. The fact that the sur - viving plants formed the basis of an excellent erop in 100." not alter the situation, but goes to show how much was really lost through the destruction of from one-tenth to one - half of the pints and the lowered vitality of all by the KfCTC 'k of the Hessian flv in the fall of 1904 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 i r i With so great ;m abundance &lt;&gt;f Hessian fly in the f;i question lias repeatedly been raised as to why the win not suffer more severely under the attack of the spring This very question has given the writer no little concen while it can in a measure be answered, si ill a completely quate and satisfactory explanation has not been demon ble. That it was not due entirely to the work of par quite evident from the unusual scarcity of these valual sects in Nebraska, so we must look elsewhere for tl In the vicinity of Lincoln the Hies appeared on April st period of warm damp weather, and continued a r gence for four days, when there occurred a severe dr&lt;&gt; temperature which was sustain i v with snow. On the 14th and 15tB of A perature for the forty-eight houi \ twice dropping to 24 and n of 34°. That these conditions proved fat ready emerged is shown by the fact that following the cold wave no flies could be f&lt; furthermore, the unemerged individuals wei a whole day spent examining fields on the single female Hessian fly was picked op, a on they came rapidly, BO that by the 27th more county were swarming with Hies o young larvae had finished their migration I?y this time the plants were six inches h and thrifty, and uninterruptedly enjoying 1 weather conceivable for strong growth; h tack came they were prepared to meet it. attack these plants in force is evidenced same region on May 23d when the stems with mature larvae and "flaxsceds." in tin per cent and 40 per cent respectively. som&lt; ing as many as a dozen to fourteen of then IK That tl by a visit t were found i&lt; r Of course th badly infested stems were dead, but there remained plenty of proportion &lt;&gt;r '•' sinirlo stems hav </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 h i ti i subsequently formed an excellent crop. plains that the presence of two or three eroal modification of the stem or head, rinkle before harvest. The latter may be v tlie lack of high winds at this time. The tlicn, is briefly this: liecause of &lt; mi her the early emerging individuals were ■ females could become fertilized or de- his also retarding the emergence so that not recover its abundance until the last week hich time the wlu-at, under the influence of very \ weather, had reached so strong and ad- owim h that it was able to withstand a severe in- OB and still produce a good crop. It is very probable, her factors, not demonstrable, also played an writer at many fanners' institutes and on which traveled through the infested area dur - r and spring, all gave the standard methods of fating the fly most widespread publicity. As a result, lrly every intelligent farmer burned his wheat stubble in ■ summer and later destroyed his volunteer grain, while uiy additionally practiced late planting, and the care and rmity with which these measures were carried out suf - to all but exterminate the insect. In fact, the worst an flv damage in the crap &lt;&gt;f 19O."&gt; G comes from roll' in this matter. roll' in t sequent almost complete illwppf ranrf o( tkfl in- s failure to prove harmful to the winter wheat in :plainahle with ease and certainty. The sending Uganda of bulletins bj the Experiment Station, the imong grata men, millers, and railroad officials as ■ farmers themselves, resulting in several prh reprints &lt;&gt;f articles on the subject from this office, at ion of numerous articles in our leading news- id the verbal instructions given by both Professor </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Ce couuty, and is estimated at about a half of 01 We arc thus apparently in a fair way to be rid « Ear several years at least. I" TUT. AIHI.T II! Y The cause of all this trouble is, in th quito-like, two-winged, dark-colored ami long tare, measuring in the female about one-eighth of an ii length, while the male is still smaller ami more slender &lt; erally the abdomen of the female is swollen and of a n less decided red color, due to tin* eees enclosed in terminates in an extensible cylindrical ovipositor, \vh male abdomen terminab \\ per also differ in details uf head and antennae. A siin-e 1 7 1 S under the common name Hessian tlv i proba i cently it has been placed in an ITS LIFE \-\ V Considering the Hessian th two brooded insect, and in normal yea following round of life occurs: The ; brood begin to issue daring the last da, ptember, and shortly after emerj fertilization, the females fly to the yoi deposit their eggs in regular rows of along the depressions of the veins on th wheat blade, somewhere between the with the stem. These eggs are very sn of an inch in length, cylindrical, with l glossy reddish color. A single female i hundred or even two hundred or more are vcrv short lived and after the dutii \ i;- r iM-r Hi fiftieth n inded en llhl of ;l ay la\ lull flies allusion to its supposed Lntrodtii wheat plant, it wiis not until 1 S] mally described. In thai yeai /(•/or by the entomologi </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 v die within ;i few hours, three or le usual lease of lift according to conditions, these eggs \a. scarcely larger than the egg from (1, migrates down the blade and between em until it reaches a point near the root, the outside soil. Here it remains sta- \ rition by absorption of the plant jii weak for gnawing, and causing a gall •gement or swelling at the point of attack. Growth rapidly, and in about three weeks the larva is full- iv be described as a thirtecn-segmented, semi- t. flattened ovate maggot, measuring about one by meters. ring this growing larval period that the harm is lain stem being the most developed, it is gener- upon which the majority of the eggs are depos- linglv is usuallv the first to show attack. The is often to produce an abnormally dark uives the plants temporarily a very thrifty This, however. cjives way to a brownish, then a nd finally the blade shrivels and dies. When re is present and the plant is not too badly s out lateral tillers abundantly, and t 1 o strong stalks, thus making possible a par - spring brood is successfully overcome. In - v be recognized by their darker color, more nice, lack of stem, shorter, broader, and more id the lack of the tubular young central o develop. These differences are more ap- l y a comparison of the two wheat plants on figure 2 par which represent a healthy and an infested plant respectively. Once full grown, the larva contracts, leaving its outer skin Kn n bard brown shell or puparinm which is commonly as the "flaxseed." and this stace is called the "flax- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 seed" stage. It is in this stage that the insect passes the win Bifely imbedded among the roots of tion which would be severe enough &gt;y the plant as well. While enclose or larval skin, the insect turns fron on, which has been maintained sine the wheat, and ;iny to destroy it would ■•I within this "flax- its head downward tirst iiijjri \\ y to f h i * Fig. 2. Effect of Hessian fly atta healthy young wheat plant, and to sian fly (reduced from Webster). Kn which the head is directed upwan turning movement the "breastbone 1 all, forked process on the ventral and second segments, is used to adv en completes the transformation int&lt; i the pup; (IS. Till: SPRING BBO During the winter the main stems pal either matted to or in part covered 1&gt;\ e (*ohc*oji l(Mi \i\ i Ik* Ti*( *s li *i Till iitiinf(*^t'i*»i * tiallv decay and are irtll. Or else cut ire] v rrocD tillers, so that </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 i r 1 m tin v ai •aled an abundance of "flaxseeds" in be spring show them only after careful en supposed that the Hies have been in Needless to say, this condition is only lirst week in April the Hies begin to \ tern Nebraska and continue to do so _ ml and westward until the whole of their They do not all emerge at once but | iierease iii numbers, reaching therr maximum about r the date of first emergence, and the last ones until the tirst week of -May or possibly i les always emerge tirst and greatly predominate ii rs for the first day or two, after which the females pear in foret rging, tin- pupa simply forces off the upper end of laxseed" and makes its way out, poshing along under it h or biting through it with its hardened Ini.ii zposed. At first its color is pure white, but a pinkish. Having found a point of i pupal skin splits and the adult fly laboriously As a rule the fly does not travel far in the uds to reattack (he plants in the samt has emerged. However, they are very isiderable distances by the wind, and it fre it through this agency clean fields are at lown from an infested field a half mile to one Phis fact makes imperative the coopera pplying the various preventive measures. he spring brood differs from that of the fall mporfant respect: If the plant (in spring t coming through the ground the eggs are laid .1" upon the first leaf as usual, but if other leaves have appeared ipt to be laid upon these, and the larvae in their lownward migration often lodge in the second or third joint is well as the first, rarely even as high as the fourth. Here </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Some Insects Injurious to IVheat. they develop as in the fall, and so weaken the stalk in eral, and the point of attack iu particular, that the heads fail to fill properly, and just before harvest the stalk crinkl breaks at the point of attack, as if it had Ix-en beaten d&lt;&gt;uu by a storm. After harvest the puparia I for in the meanwhile the "llaxseed" stage lias again been assumed I remain in the Kl for the most part although a few of the higher ones lallj carried away in the straw, and in this stage the I the hot, dry summer as it did the cold winter, lag again in the fall they attack the young wheat, and •eh' of life is repeated. VARIATION IN NUMUKR 01 The exact iiuhiImt of broods of the Hessian th various parts of its range is a question that has long I ■ed by entomologists and still not decidedly as This phenomenon is intricately correlated not onh itude and altitude, hut as much with the n able conditions of temperature and humidity, ai of the th we have an insect unusual h fluences and one which very readilv quiescent stages, to the surrounding conditions mast really be expected of an insert infest in crop over so extensive an area. However, under n&lt; ditions over most of the wheat (Trowing belt of the I States, the ly is most apt to be primarily double br&lt; all additional hroods only partial or supplement; supplemental broods either follow the principal sprin »1 or precede the principal fall brood. Even in the northern part of the state, where comparatively little winter wheat is grown, there is apt to he a fall brood in the volunteer grain Alonfi the southern border of the state during wet summers the spring brood is likely to have some of its individuals emerge about the third week in .May and attack the spring wheat, developing pnparia therein before harvest, and aj&gt;- ROiriii'* *is 'i dults in tin* f'lll finis f'&gt;i'min &lt;r *i 1 1 1 &gt;i &gt;l ..* i </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 bird brood. This condition obtained during 1904, and was severe attack on the winter wheat u\ In dry summers this supplemental bird brood is omitted, and the pnparia of the principal pring brood remain intact in the stubble until fall, as has wen described. In .Missouri and southward another supple- s appears, working in the volunteer naking four in all. Under artificial conditions ,vl n demonstrated that as many as six generations ared, but of course the conditions necessary for this tain in nature. 1 mportant factor in this acceleration or retard* m levelopinent and consequently in the numl&gt;er of a given locality is the relative conditions of huniid- Ml r very unfavorable conditions the emergence of the ii. y lie retarded for a year without causing its death. .Moist weather ads very favorably upon this insect and under pplicable. for during dry weather the development i&gt;\\. In I he case of severe drought the larvae and puparia are killed outright in" large numbers. It assume that a single season of drought follow- which the tly was destructive would reduce it to its again. Temperature also lias a considerable ther being favorable and cold weather un- favorable lo the insect's development. A combination of it these favorable conditions, such as a warm moist year, would ■ ly bring the tly from scarcity to plentitude, and several years following in immediate succession, as was true in Nebraska from \W2 1904, even to a scourge. THE EFFECT OF I.ATITl UK AND ALTITI'DE. Iiilo, as has been shown, the actual time of emergence of brood depends upon the weather, the comparative d. an area approximating similar weather conditions vary Marcbal, Ann. Soc. Ent. France, pp. 1-105 (1897). omlitioMs development is rapid; and the &lt;■&lt; inverse is </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 according to latitude and altitude. This variation is about one day for each fifteen miles northward and for each (MM hundred feet of elevation. 1 To illustrate: The Hies em at Lincoln, April 8, 1905, and at Fairmont, April 1U, as was determined by our field breeding cages at then points; mom Fairmont is five hundred feet higher than Lincoln, which would make it five days later, but it is also nearly fifteen miles farther south, which would make it one day earlier. Thus the real ditl'erence when both factors are considered a four days, the exact time between the two actual dab emergence. It lms been shown that in localities of greatly varied altitudes the time of •■mergence depends very orach upon elevation, but in a comparatively fiat state ]ik&gt; braska the factor of latitude would be more Important. The practical application of this rule is this: The rate of by&lt; difference between localities being known, a normal may be determined for any point, and from these figures the n&lt; for all other points may be made out ; and by correct in £1 to the exact condition time for applying tin accurately established. of any particular various prevei NATURAL ENEMIES OF THE HESSIAN About a half dozen minute Hymenoptera beloi asitize the Hessian By during its larval stages, an&lt; stated that where these parasites are common fully nine tenths of the tlies are destroyed by them. The egff of I'ht of tlie Hessian fly, is deposited within the fly egg, the female employing her ovipositor for the purpose, and, after hatching, the parasite subsists upon the body of the grub unt il it reaches full development, when it makes its way out by boring a sin;ill circular hole through the enveloping sheath of the wheat. Then parasites are often double-brooded, and are affected in Hopkins, Agr. Exp. Sta. Bull. West Virginia &lt; li;ilci(li(l;ic and Proctotrypidae are known i«&lt; habitually ijosti r kerricktt, Packard, oar commonest Nebraska parasito </seg>
            <seg id="p017">/ Injurious 10 U'ltnit. 17 be Hessian fly itself by tin: conditiOM same in. tli mentioned above. In Nebraska we nd very few of these parasitic Hymenoptna, ation goea to show that they are few in this ics and individuals. Our two commonest n figure ;&gt;. Hissiau fly which occur in Nebraska; ■left uml Platygastrr lurmkii to the right, much er and from Riley). During our studies of the fly there came to light a hitherto recorded natural enemy in the form of a predaceous bug, \ m*, one of the damsel-bugs. While this bug was n all the fields where the fly abounded, it was found tartictilarly commoa in the area about and between the of Lincoln, Friend, Fairmont, Geneva, and Fairbury, &gt;n nearly coinciding with the area of greatest infesta- Dnring cloudy weather the bug remained hidden among the roots of the wheat, but on bright days when it was more active it was very much in evidence, and there were many inquiries regarding its identity, some even mistaking it for tin- fly itself. The first indication of its fondness for a fly diet was observed in the numbers which would congn upon our field breeding cages to devour the flies caught in the imslics; later the same habit was observed in the field where the bugs caught their prey independently. Their method was siiniklv to sit in sniiir ] i k&lt; *1 v i A *H'&lt; * * i in 1 *is the fl v cim(* nl on ** </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 I Injurious in W ize it with a quick motion of the powerful grasping fore and puctoring its hack with the long beak to suck mit the body juices. On the loraing of April 14th we pot three of these lilies into a jar with twenty-seven live Hessian ilics. and when next examined forty-eighi hours later all of the Hies had been killed while one of the bugs was dead and tin other two were very weak. After feeding tin E'al flies they seemed to revive, and were so rapacious that seized three or four of the Hies in rapid succession, and ■d to feed only when their holding capacity nt ted. At this time ■even] "flaxseeds" were placed in the and on the next day these still remained untouched and Mifjs were both dead. This would seem to indicate that bug will not feed upon the inanimate "flaxseed," but is Explanation of Plate — Male Hessian fly in characteristic flying p above; female fly ovipositing upon wheat plant; fullgrown larva pupt and puparium or "flaxseed" below; all eight limes natural size. </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
          
            <seg id="p020">19 . Furthermore, there vtm frequwrt i in latter .March, before the flies had and while there may be n«&gt; connection »int is at least suggestive. crop producer are the means which may ii in check. Accordingly, the various piv - vliich have from time to time been Mg| hi By will now be considered each in ■eferenee to our own state. As the first of llv consider on* or Repellmnt*. The use of salt, liine, been recommended as helpful in destroying r. not only do such appliances fail in being it they are so expensive and laborious that ) fields of even average size is highly un - recent reports the writer has met with of ml results from such methods are cribing how applications of limo, Paris xture. and kerosene emulsion were given md the amount of infestation then 1 plats. 1 All but the last named mate- v decided beneficial results, but in the In- results showed that substance to act during the infestation to 9 per cent, as n the untreated plats. The use of such s ever, in our great fields is not to be thought of. for our relief to some other preventive or fill- W mu il remedy, and as the best of the former class we have I.nt, Bowing. Beyond doubt the most important s' which can be used to protect the winter wheat from mea sur fall brood is late sowing of the grain, so that the plants Hi ENTIVB MEASURES. nji any injurious insect, the pmi or usclcssncss of each will be commented in. Bull Kentucky Agr. I '240 (1902) </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 dead, having found no f 1 plants for their larvae. T appearance of the tlies is probably not due u&gt; Bevere fn as is ofu-u supposed, for a few Hies are ki Wll tit Itaml severe temperature ;i to hatch and the larre U d in Ncinaliu county in 1*. Iniosi invariable rule durii he earlier the fields ;i i. Wheat sown during the n l!»l»J all verv badly infes up to the -Oth was tot the ,\ ::r, to hatch and the larva- to .mow. Indeed, Hi w abroad in Nemaha county in I'.mu as late as October !!• is la The almost invariable rule during years of tlv infesta (hat the earlier the fields are sown the greater is their in tat ion. Wheat sown during tin s in 1!&gt;OI all very liadlv infested, some fields ruii that sown the last few dav \ damage, while the October slightly infested. Bowevi escape, and a few fields examine BOWn in October were could have been sown in liiut and yet have been safe fro ever, desirable to risk such extn proper time to sow is when gone and the aeason still earl planting. That season for tin lu-aska is approximately the lirs this is advised only for years of 11 times early planting is desirable foi also depending for its success upo the fall brood is that of planting 3. Decoy Strip*. These need n should be sown at such a time that ■I start when the bulk of the tli attack these plants in large uiiin rs destroy them, when they should be plowed ui as possible. The proper time for sowing this ti &gt; cl few days in August or in early Se| s n </seg>
            <seg id="p022">21 / Winter Wheat. This method in extreme cases. Wheat that has trad should be deeply plowed under ■ the Hies Infill to emcrgr, and rop, rach as oats or corn. Tins must be finished by the tii-st lew of avail in destroying the ly. The • necessary to advise tliis procedure ion to determine, and should be iiusclf after careful consideration. Fields till stand in the spring to produce a pay mil v be left to run the risk of avoiding or spring brood, and in most cases a fair It is a point of common observation to infested region that when wheat follows iid crop is severely attacked; hence as a preventive the \s the only crops attacked hy the and ltailev, and to a very slight extent that a suitable rotation, bringing in uts or COTB, which are immune, will &lt;&gt;r it will find itself upon emergeaee ligrating to new Melds, and the mor - he destructive elements is very great, winds. To make this method most mong neighboring farmers i&gt; a greal ild lie arranged that the new wheat the old ones. In extreme cases the of wheat growing for a number of v to reduce the pest. The most efti \it suggested for making away with l&gt;. ubble. After harvest the majority in the stuldde in the "tlaxseed" Stage, al - irrieil away in the straw. Cosjseovently </seg>
            <seg id="p023">■:,&gt; i ■beat should be ait as high as j behind urns! of the "flaxseed* inent destruction. Two wetho I is purpose : burning and |&gt;li d is used ihc stubble slioul of iii least half a foot, in ord even further advocate the n Ilics i in Nebraska for sevei soil is light, burning exact t i ii i &lt; - uf iloini* tli ii R lift lion wit ll I lie lie - weather after ban . hut ii is w.ll in i I they occur ic chance be done at Spivadin • will help "llaxseeds" Ea lUM-i-ssii \ . I stack. llu\\i\ ll. Of rolirse well as the flies state that the farmer lias bul lilt A combination of plowing after l&gt; more certain, as a few &lt;&gt;f the "flas disti-iict ion by the burning alone. is, in all ordinary years, alone qui in check. Another cultural ooroll is in the 7. Destruction of \~&lt;&gt;linth&lt;r Wheat. ini-asiiiv is to gel rid of the volunteer had an opportunity to harbor developin roiimis individuals of the fall brood, an insect over the wiutrr that it may atta&lt; tlic wheat n tl </seg>
            <seg id="p024">23 DO winter wheat grown ci j liost plant for the fall I' heat should Ik- plowed uudi-r. ve already found lodgment, mn\ Im - re stage. Another sometimes de- It of ii is somei inies possible to WSIV gs by the feeding animals. I.ut con - in which the larva* are accessible and race the wheat affords it seems that iod is a matter of mere chance. Tin in the fall and sheep are the preferred requently l&gt;een noted that coarse, strong- wheat are somewhat less susceptible to ng brood than those with weaker stems. isahle to select the more of these several have l&gt;een rec he Underbill, (law son. Red Cap, et&lt; iable to attack. In Nebraska tin niversallv planted, and seems alioiit As none of them are proof to tin rative extent, the value of (his recom Much more important it is that r profusely following the fall attack lency that we owe practically our entiri \s a last measure should be urged the the effect of creating and preserving such ieat plant that it is enabled bj tillering to Iv withstand the attacks of the tl.v. Webster 1 ui h. a rich fertile soil, the creation of a pill- ntenan s' .;&gt;. Sta.. p. 2S4 (1899) and Circular &gt;v&lt;-&lt;l, si) thai i In- Hies may not timl lid to he quite unattractive to tin Soil nml Secdinq. This. msiilcivil us a preventive against tlv </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 Some Insects Injurious to Wheat 1&gt;\ early plowing and thorough working, ami ir idvantage of such treatment is perfectly olivi THi: W 1 1 EAT-STK M-MAGGOI / Numerous reports of d i\ received at llie Entomologist's office during the pa years, when carefully looked into, showed the real depi n to he the whea si the injuries lai an fly, howev md in of the latter insect is osuallv the 8y and probably extend v&lt; that insect, hut the region of urea test promim with Madison, Buffalo, and Thayer The wheat stem-maggot is a nai advent of cultivated crops found its h&lt; {Elymut), and wheat-grasses (Agropyron). ltesid wheat it attacks rye, barley, and oats. The ad greenish fly, marked on the thorax and abdomen with tin verixed, compact, moisture conserrin tiun df only the largest and in insert \v;is in |.;ill rlllp insect, li is by no mem slate it is present througltoi the p;ist liicniihim lms bt*»n in tin grasses, principally certain species of blue-grass i Po </seg>
            <seg id="p026">25 roods a year, passing tin- win- i r wheat, transforming into the pupa ml immediately thereafter, in latter ling adults of the first brood, which or spread to other fields or nt iposit upon the young growing steins h the sheath-like upper leaves. The (e. elongated, with pointed ends, ami e. The larva- which soon hatch from nd slender, about a quarter of an inch A V \ 1 3 / fc M &gt;\ \ V I fullgrown Wlnat Stem n n. with the head end pointed and the r greenish white. They work their way e the upper joint, where they enter the earing the tissues with a pair of black hooks situated lcking mouth, and f ceding upon the plant jmieea. nggot cause the unfilled head to die and turn white, while f the growing in nt of the wheat \ ■esi of the plant continues alive and green. These larva mature by the middle of June, pupate, and the adults of the uid brood appear in July. This brood is reared on volun larva working in wheat stem, nat- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 tembcr and October. This third brood tt lacks IIk wlicat and remains therein until spring Tlic larva- upon the winter wheat is to caus&lt; the central tuln lie, turning yell 11st above the r leaf of the infested plant to shrivel and the larva being located within th (Compare with this the usual non-api n It is thus apparent that t and spring both, and the t w i abot As a Vi destructive in Nebras fall attack is the mon \ insect are not entirely tion of volunteer w because of the abilit themselves are cleared thev tion from nearbv eras lands should lie burned ov&lt; that wheat planted in (&gt;t that sown earlier, in sp injury hv the stem-maggot. Tl so of this insect is the wo k its eggs on the maggots, and on consume the body of the host. Tin: KBIT FLIES I O.si-inis til i There seem to be a number of Hit? the larva- of which work in the stems the two species mentioned above an common and injurious. Here in Nebr little trouble with these two insects, i parent I hey were funn in llv ill tacks is rotation &lt;&gt;f &lt;r&lt; t&lt;&gt; various common nativ nyza arc abroad duri iii avoiding the Hessian fly w Macquari have had vi-r\ </seg>
            <seg id="p028">27 Saliu and Phelps counties, and riicrallv over the state The II Mies ir as yet not fully eluci ki show that thej probably in I hat of the wheat stem-ui Hies arc close relatives of the llielllltel-s of the same family. c Frit -Hi it 1 1 t- Hy of 1111 &lt;•{ head all ma;; pai it ' i.s ailed, in addition to all the cult! irious nat ive grasses belonging to th. / I'oa, etc, although aoror seems range of fiMMl plants than carbonari*. Thev three-brooded, the first brood appearing i he wheat, its larva; giving rise to the Fune and early July, the adult •viposil iijm.1i volunteer grain and u r i"ass, and from hird IuihmI which appears in September e winter wheat and gi a— s, overwintering probably as a papa. Jn attacking winter wheat the lv larva kills the central tubular leaf as does the wheat stem- •re harm is done to the spring wheat, when hut irva worl in the stem above the upper or second joint. preventing the filling out of the heads and causing the stem t(t \\ lit (liscojoi* - * fill l»i*i"ik o\i'i* 'it I lu* t &gt;i it t ■ ■ 1 1 •» -L • 1 1* tl </seg>
            <seg id="p029">28 the eggs and larva? of these frit-tiies resemble closely tliost the item-maggot, but are much smaller, the larvs be he larva scarcely more tlian one-half as large. Tli pupa is shortei than the larva and is enclosed in a hard \vn pupariuii Hot It species are in the adult, small 1 k Hies with S kings on the legs, but the two extent of the shining spot &lt;&gt;n i almost reaches the antennae bu preventives mentioned under I equally well here listininii li. nav d which in In n in Horor is mucli short Kirb THE WHEAT Mil" §ng with the several othei d, this one appeared dm and did its share towan ttinately it was not abundant en harm it is really capable &lt; where it has been a pest of long s crop sometimea result* from complaints have been received fron wheat midge is a close relative »&gt;1 i probably an importation fron in the wheat tields of that eontim &lt;'anada, it appeared in the Unite spread SOOthward and westward it is now present over most of oni N </seg>
            <seg id="p030">In 29 During June the adult mi&lt;L &gt;\i|.usi( upon the wheat head, usually near 1 he top. and in such •Mtiun that the larvae on hatching can tin«l their waj to the embryo kernels. The e| i»f the midge arc shaped and col- ored like those of the Hessian ■ at are very much smaller. .Minute colorless larva- hatch therefrom after several days ami migrate to the young ker- locating between them ami their enveloping chaff, where they suck up the juices which ntended to form the grain. Through this sapping of the ker- the latter become so shriv- eled and liiilit that the wheat is not worth the harvesting. Soon after locating on the kernels the larvae turn red. and after about three weeks of growth become full grown, being then oval- shaped maggots a little less than one-tenth of an inch long. Many now leave the plant through the agency of rains and make their way to the irronnd, which they enter, and then con- struct about themselves inhlllte ■ us. Within these they pass the winter as bum, pupate in the following spring, and emerge as adult midges in Jnno. Fig. 8. The Wheat Midge nlmrimit tritici); a, male in- fi-male insect, o 1 . natural wteg irreatly enlar if, antennal joints of mill same of female; f, ovipositor; I, greatly magnified; h, larva- on wheat kernel; i, larva in repose; /, larva crawling; /', natural size of larva; *. /. ante- rior and posterior end of moving larva (after Fitch). </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 U7, m The larva 1 which do not leave th&lt; arc carried away in tlic stru lire nr in stable use, siiccessl'ull \ emerge us do the &lt;&gt;i hers By plowing (lie ground which have entered the ground will lie buried s&lt; they can not emerge in the spring, and by burnii chaff and such of the straw in ir. those which remain in the head will he destroyed. 1 precautions will prevenl a recurrence of injury the Till] WilKAl During 1 1n* lasi received reporting da of a serious nature. The pi so obvious as in the ease &lt; frit-flics, for the si&lt; hut the kernels fail to develop and cle&lt;l. or arc perhaps not produced a nearly every sialk is thus affected. determine the cause of his trouble when he will discover each one so a grab or larva about one-fifth of an n in color, with a curiously \ In-own jaws. The presence of the j; by means of which this insect m;i\ of the Hessian fly, wheat stem-map ■hut arc of (-0111 (•&lt;], nor dot's 1 1 i mh 'li i it *&lt; **f win "i t \\ I ii I lti&gt;liiit&lt;&gt; t fit ■ i'l •!• Ik </seg>
            <seg id="p032">/ 31 &gt; \^M Y si raw- \ -i &lt; iiit.-ii X subsist V lllllllll \ «r of (lie two '■''- ;i Larva of ., Straw - worm, greatly in appear- (origiMi) us they were considered tlwtind spe- wm] iis ;i pupa in the stubble ;in«l gtrmw ied iis a pupa in the stubble and straw ml when spring has developed sulli cai-ly April, the atluli issues bv naw- March or early April, tbeaduli issues bv ran i the siniw. The ;i&lt;lults «»f this spring black, and usually quite wiu_ the straw. The adults of this spring ►lack, and usually quite wins! young wheat plants, l.v the 1 1 -^&lt; - of young wheat plants, by the dm of be females deposit an egg in the eni- males deposit an egg in the em i-eiiter of the stem, where the larva few days can olitain an alniii&lt;lan enter of the stem, where the larva lavs can obtain an abundance of r. The presence &lt;&gt;f the larva arrests he presence of the larva an item ami kills the young head. Orow- in. ami kills the young head. Orow- transfonuations are soon completed, (ind or Rummer generation commence and continue doing so throng] st it about the middle of the latter i is larger, stonier, and more brightly : brood, and all are fully winged, so apahle of migration from one field to i placed as before, singly in the center g wheat. Inn instead of being always tear the ground they may occur immediately ■bore any of tie stem, lmt usually in the highest one ae.es- h is for the mo&gt;t part the second or v ■low the head. Thus, while some of the lar\;e 1 awav in the straw at ll'irvest the nninritv ti'ill Yu\ ■ " iii«lj''lll^ Will LH^ </seg>
            <seg id="p033">32 I«'ft in. the stubble. They niatun loo tough iiinl dry for food, and after loilgii joint, pupate in October and remain ii remain throughout tin- winter. * y W If- v BIO. Tlic \\ t, adult female at sti-ni showii (after Rib smaller than the straw -wen all alike and all fnllv wing confined to wheat, lnit at tad that species, lint the larvae do n n tin- following spring, although tin of attack above the joints The most effective measure against is the one so strongly urged in combating the II 1 namely the burning of the stubble. As the insect is present in either the Ian t I \ t ' fl'ibfll I * i t I * 111 f 1 i * 1 1 I \ t I till* fi will \\ lit*'' \ 1 ' i I *( ■ \ \ ■ i I I Bklerably, in that it is Inn iis well. The adults are abroad summer generation of the straw \\ early June i. and the eggi are d before harvest This species &lt;&gt;ft&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p034">33 during the interim would haw pretty thoroughly. The lar- out iw are for the must part innocuous. y few indeed of the win_ VC1 be able to reach a wheat Held, and if ndividuals on the outside of the - scattered straw near a Held planted prolific source of injury. In the ohm v i re the spring generation is win. h 1 Joint worm i/ &gt;wing injury, nat (■male insect, enlarged (alter t lie migratory rammer gen- nance of le joint worm whose adults are always capable of subsisting on common na - &lt;&gt;d would be of less avail. It would clearing of all place* growing up to md borders of fields iai.k i:oui:i; {Papaipcma nitrln Qaesee). &gt;r the fust time in the history of wheat growing ihis insect proved a serious pest Anting the &gt;&lt;».). lii earlj .June uf that year it was one of Proliabh N rsing over the neigh bur ing fields, it is of crops would sliirvc out the ■pecfai </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 the chief causes of the "whitened abundantly in the fields all over east els to the acre, and alone the marc i more whitened unfilled hea&lt; extreme infestation, h N •wevel only was wheat at tact and blackberry ii.i injurious. It maj ta«ks various era stems to support it I! stiilk liol-el full sized. In I which the middle &lt; being pale yellow. I generally boring into from thence works t ion of the stem an ejl excrement. Tlii above the joint of enti while the remainder of i&gt;i the external appearnu elite of the Stalk ImiIVV is, ll w When the top of the plant is Bay out and attacks another ]&gt;] ined one of some kind, and &lt;■ a, when it pupates within the Ii July and early August In ; ir, moderately sized, brownish • to fly until late &lt; k-tober, d«'p» •at ion in grass lands. in icads" which ap rn Nebraska, apj \\ tiding as much damage along iliat 1 -&lt;&gt;i itself. Many liHils were dama large entrance bole in the joi </seg>
            <seg id="p036">35 Fig. 13. The larva of alkborer working in wheat, natural &lt;l prove a matter of great dim •dies. •!&lt;• fall of 1904-6 we had a prodigious «'. so that for a time the outlook was However, although the plants were courid- I in some Ictcalities. not many were aetuallv I. and tlie «pring attack was too short to he to the wheat. Lik&lt;- other memben of its i family, this plant-louse injures its host plant by rockiag the s lap, large numbers of them attacking the plant simulta nnm_ miii oi the Head iii the npnng. In the Ncctarophora cereali* Kali). intl perhaps tome related sp. ii.unsiy. tlms pnviMitiiii: the proper formation of growiac </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 II / i ,\ / N ■&gt; fall tin- lice work around the roots and l&lt;&gt; i result many of the lat in- i urn \ nn ii works in ill tin- heads, tin- I lire. After I In- win i / .^r~i r&lt;W)~\ \7 (ini Mar brood wliidi spread lit H. \ wheat and rye, young tin B subsist until the adven \ii the vear the lice Bes being usually viviparous. II. These plant lice are gen&lt; y several species of small pai II VI abundance of these par recent attack served to effeci u There is no efficient and pra N K during £cpt*&gt;uil ss adult or in tin the earh Ki»rin • &lt;&gt;ni inuiue in f«tl i !u </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>