<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00058.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00058.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Nebraska For 1925-1926</title>
               <date value="1926-12-01">1926-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT of the Adjutant General of the State of Nebraska For 1925-1926 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 1, 192G. From: The Adjutant General of Nebraska To: His Excellency, Adam McMullen, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. Subject: Biennial Report of 1925 and 1926. 1. In compliance with the requirements of Section No. 3305, Chapter 34, Article 1, Revised Statutes of Nebraska, 1922, the fol - lowing biennial report for the calendar years 1925 and 1926 is respect - fully submitted. ANNUAL ENCAMPMENTS The annual encampments of the Nebraska National Guard for the last biennium have been held at Ashland, Nebraska where further and more extensive improvements have been made, principally by the Federal Government, and where troops can now be trained without fear of high water or inclement weather. Since my last report there have been constructed permanent bath houses and latrines, being built as a combination, of hollow tile and stucco with heating plants for each that makes the baths more liberally patronized by the men than when only cold 'water from a deep well was available. The water supply has been moved to the north end of the camp where a well has been sunk to bedrock giving an abundant supply of clear, cold and pure water which is piped to. the kitchens as well as the bath houses. Combination kitchens and mess halls of a permanent nature are now very essential to take the place of temporary kitchens constructed at state expense and which, owing to the cheapness of the material used and the length of time they have served, are now of no practical value. The Federal Government has promised to replace these kitchens with permanent structures, but I doubt if we will be able to get them for camp this year. The swimming pool constructed by the State has not proven a decided success as the water is generally very low in August, the </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3 time of our state encampment, and is then only filled out of seepage water which is not considered fit for bathing purposes and it 18 therefore going to be necessary to tap the river and run a stream of water through this pool to insure a continuous change of water in the pool. The last two encampments have each shown an improvement over those held before and it is particularly gratifying to this office to note that the type of enlisted men has gradually been brought to a much higher standard and the morale is all that could be hoped for. A large per cent of our enlisted men are now University and High school students, and among many of our athletic activities will be found men who are members of the University of Nebraska football team and other University athletic activities. This condition not only prevails in and around Lincoln, but is now general all over the State, while most of our officers are veterans of the World War and are capable of imparting instructions of the utmost value. In addition to our own well trained officers, we have our Officer Instructors and Sergeant Instructors that are permanently detailed to the State and during camp time we have detailed to us in addition thereto, an able Corps of Regular Army instructors which gives us the maximum of instruction in the minimum of time, and as all transportation, subsistence and pay for these camps are taken care of by the Federal Government, it is also with minimum expense to the State. RIFLE RANGES The Rifle Range at Ashland, Nebraska, has become known as one of the best rifle ranges in the United States. It can be used for firing from two hundred yards to one thousand yards, the Chamber of Commerce at Ashland having purchased three acres and presented same to the State to round out the one thousand yard point. All men armed with the rifle have been required to fire on this range annually. UNITED STATES ARMY OFFICERS AND SERGEANT INSTRUCTORS DETAILED TO THE STATE The following is a list of United States Army Officers and Sergeant Instructors who are detailed by the War Department to the State of Nebraska for instructional purposes. Major Thomas F. McNeill, Inf. D. O. L., Lincoln, Nebraska. Capt. Leo. J. Farrell, Inf. D. O. L. Omaha, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4 Major James F. Presnell, M. C. D. O. L., Lincoln, Nebraska. Capt. McGregor Snodgrass, Q. M. C, D. O. L., Lincoln, Nebraska. Master Sgt. Lee R. G. Ward, Inf., D. E. M. L., Omaha, Nebraska. Sgt. Emet G. Roach, Inf. D. E. M. L., Lincoln, Nebraska. Sgt. Harvey L. Edwards, M. D. D. E. M. L., Lincoln, Nebraska. Sgt. Hjalmer R. Strom, Q. M. C, D. E. M. L., Lincoln, Nebraska. The above named Officer instructors and Sergeant instructors are rendering a valuable service and have done much to assist in placing the Nebraska National Guard at its present high standing among the other States of the Union. ARMORIES As reported before the most discouraging proposition with which the units of the Nebraska National Guard have to contend at the present time is the rental of armories. It is almost impossible to rent suitable buildings at reasonable rentals for armories for the National Guard units which give adequate protection to the government property that the State is required to protect and at the same time have ample Rfor training purposes, to say nothing of the desirability of g armories that can be made attractive for the enlisted personnel in which their athletics can be carried on and in which recreation rooms and rest rooms should be provided. Many of the states in the union have made appropriations for the building of armories for the Ntaional Guard units and when the present high rentals are taken into consideration in connection with the desirability of having armories with the facilities above described, it is the opinion of the reporting officer that it would be much cheaper in the long run for the State to construct its own armories, and the only reason a bill has not been presented to the Legislature for con - structional purposes is that it has been taken into consideration by this officer the other public activities that are requiring so much from the tax payers at the present time, but it is my intention to present a constructional program as soon as the new Capitol has neared completion. RIFLE TEAMS The following named Rifle Team was sent to Camp Perry, Ohio, in 1925 and made a very good record considering the limited amount of preliminary practice they had and that they were competing with the best rifle shots and rifle teams from all over the world. No team was sent to Camp Perry in 1926, owing to a lack of Federal funds to defray expenses of same. Major H. C. Stein, Q. M. C. S. S. C. &amp; D., Team Captain Major E. D. Fisher, 134th Infantry, Team Coach. Capt. Victor M. Hovis, Q. M. C. 35th Division Train, Range Officer. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5 Principals Pvt. lcl. Dewey Kimbrell, Co. E, 134th Inf., Scottsbluff, Nebraska. 1st Sgt. O. H. Burnett, Wag. Co. No. 119, 35th Dlv. Tn., Lexington, Nebraska. Cpl. John H. Pierce, M. T. Co. No. 137, 35th Division Train, Holdrege, Nebraska. Pvt. John P. Carmody, M. T. Co. No. 138, 35th Div. Tn., Fremont, Nebraska. 2nd Lt. B. C. Neff, Wag. Co. No. 119, 35th Div. Tn. Lexington, Nebraska. 1st Lt. J. Ned Allison, 2nd Bn. Hq. Co., 134th Inf., Gering, Nebraska. 1st Lt. Alexander Rieber, Co. G, 134th Inf., Hastings, Nebraska. Sgt. C. T. Smith, Wag. Co. No. 119, 35th Div. Tn., Lexington, Nebraska. Pvt. Don Woods, 2nd Bn. Hq. Co., 134th Inf., Gering, Nebraska. Cpl. Ray Clifton, 2nd Bn. Hq. Co., 134th Inf., Gering, Nebraska. Alternates Cpl. Jack Raue, Wag. Co. No. 120, 35th Div. Tn. Kearney, Neb. Tech. Sgt. Manford L. Gorman, Hq. Det. 35th Div. Tn., Lincoln, Nebraska. WORLD WAR RECORDS This office is now in possession of a record of service for every person who served in the army, navy or marine corps at any time daring the period April 6, 1917 to November 11, 1918, and who gave Nebraska as their residence at the time they entered the service. The records are in card form and show the name, serial number, color and race, residence, dates of service, date and place of birth, organizations served in with grades, dates of overseas service and date and kind of discharge. The number whose records have been credited to the State of Nebraska is 57,463. Nebraska Certificates of Service have been furnished to those whose records are on file in this office, in, conformity with House Roll No. 537, 1919-1920, out of which approximately seven thousand certificates have been returned on account of inability to obtain correct present </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL address of ones entitled to them. These certificates are the source of continual correspondence in this office and probably will be for years to come. We are also called almost daily to furnish certificates of service of those who served from Nebraska which are used in obtaining United States Compensation, pensions, longevity pay, membership in the American Legion, etc. CONCLUSION I wish to express my appreciation to the Officers and enlisted men of the Nebraska National Guard who, through their hearty cooperation in recruiting the National Guard to a higher standard and in training their units, have assisted so ably in bringing the Nebraska National Guard to the present high state of efficiency it enjoys. I also desire to express my gratitude to the officers and non-commissioned officers of the Regular Army on duty with this State for the assistance they have given in the training of the Nebraska National Guard. In conclusion I wish to express to your Excellency, my appreciation for the moral support and uniform courtesy always extended by you to this Department. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. FINANCIAL STATEMENT, NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD AS OF DECEMBER 1, 1926. Total Appropriations Warrants Drawn Balance Support — $150,000.00 $92,727.62 $57,272.38 H. R. 537, Soldiers' and Sailors' Certificates — $1,000.00 None 1,000.00 Code 239, Emergency — $15,000.00 None 15,000.00 STRENGTH BY COMPANY AND DETACHMENT OF THE NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD AS OF DECEMBER 31, 1926. 134th Infantry Enl. War. Officers Men Officers Regtl. Hq. &amp; Regtl. Hq. Co 7 75 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. 1st Bn 3 40 ? Company "A" 3 63 Company "B" _ 3 57 Company "C" 2 57 Company "D" 3 74 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. 2nd Bn 2 34 Company "E" 3 65 Company "F" 3 62 Company "G" 3 79 Company "H" 3 76 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co. 3rd Bn 3 30 Company "I" 2 67 Company "K" 3 85 Company "L" 3 70 Company "M" 2 68 Service Company 4 132 1 Howitzer Company 3 64 Attached Medical Detachment 5 35 60 1233 1 35th Division Train, Q M. C. Hq. Detachment 3 15 Motor Transport Co. No. 137 2 51 Motor Transport Co. No. 138 2 47 Motor Repair Section No. 119 1 24 Wagon Co. No. 119 3 52 Wagon Co. No. 120 3 50 Attached Medical Detachment 1 8 15 247 110th Medical Regiment Hq. Staff 7 Hospital Co. No. 130 5 62 Ambulance Co. No. 130 2 45 Service Section, Service Co 4 40 Band Section, Service Co 22 1 Veterinary Co. No. 110 1 37 Collecting Co. No. 130 „ 2 64 21 270 1 Grand Total 96 officers 1750 enlisted men 2 Warrant officers. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ROSTER OF OFFICERS OF THE NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Staff Officers Brig. Gen. H. J. Paul, A. G. D., State Capitol, Lincoln. Major H. C. Stein, Q. M. C, State Capitol, Lincoln. Capt. W. E. McConnaughey, Q. M. C, State Capitol, Lincoln. Capt. Frank B. O'Connell, A. G. D., State Capitol, Lincoln. Capt. Herbert M. Potter, Ord., 910 No. 11th St., Beatrice, Nebr. 2nd Lt. Byron E. Toder, Q. M. C, 2544 Sumner St., Lincoln. 85th DIVISION TRAIN, Q. M. C. Major Marcus L. Poteet, 807 Terminal Bldg., Lincoln. 1st Lt. Claude J. Williams, 3325 South St., Lincoln. 2nd Lt. M. A. Blodgett, 831 So. 30th St., Omaha. M. T. Co. No. 187 1st Lt. Gold Sonneborn, 810 Grant St., Holdrege. 2nd Lt. Orn H. Davidson, Holdrege. M. T. Co. No. 188 1st Lt. Nels Arthur Olson, 512 No. Main St., Fremont. 2nd Lt. Wesley H. Yakish, 240 East 1st St., Fremont. M. R. Sec. No. 110 1st Lt. L. E. Chadderdon, 501 West Ave., Holdrege. Wag. Co. No. 119 Capt. Victor M. Hovis, 515 Washington St., Lexington. 1st Lt. Edward A. Cook, 615 Washington St., Lexington. 2nd Lt. Clarence B. Nefi, Lexington. Wag. Co. No. ISO Capt. Ira D. Beynon, Box 622, Kearney. 1st Lt. Guy N. Henninger, Court House, Kearney. 2nd Lt. William J. Atkinson, 1925 5th Ave., Kearney. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 9 Att. Med. Dot. Capt. Henry Farrell, 2121 Central Ave., Kearney 184th INFANTRY N. N. G. Col. Amos Thomas, 454 Omaha Nat. Bank. Bldg., Omaha. Lt. Col. Robert G. Douglas, 315 Richards Blk., Lincoln. Major Clyde E. McCormick, 808 So. 59th St., Omaha. Major Earl M. Cline, 3rd Bn., 703 1st Nat. Bank Bldg., Lincoln Major R. L. Crosson, 2nd Bn., 321 Saunders Ave., Hastings. Major Edwin D. Fisher, 1st Bn., Box 193, Falls City. Capt. Allen A. Tukey, Adj., 613 Peters Trust Bldg., Omaha. Capt. Harold C. Capsey, Chaplain, Syracuse. Capt. Wm. G. Utterback, Regtl. Sup. Off., Nebraska City. Capt. Thomas Q. Thornton, 634 Mer. Bank Bldg., Omaha. Headquarters Co. Capt. John H. McAlpin, 706 Telephone Bldg., Omaha, Nebr. 2nd Lt. Howard Wilson, 2442 Mary St., Omaha. Service Co. Capt. Charles J. Ayers, 626 Lincoln Aye., York. 1st Lt. Albert P. Guidinger, York. 1st Lt. Harry A. Beckley, York. War. Off. Joy O. Payne, York. 2nd Lt. Raymond D. Haggard, York. 1st Bn. Hq. Co. 1st Lt. Ray A. Thurman, 5th and 6th Ave., Nebraska City. 2nd Lt. Leslie Yager, Jr., Nebraska City. 2nd Bn. Hq. Co. 1st Lt. F. R. Underwood, Sidney. 3rd Bn. Hq. Co. 1st Lt. Trev Gillaspie, City Hall, Lincoln. 2nd Lt. James F. Miller, 1562 So. 20th St., Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL City Howitzer Co. Capt. J. Ned Allison, Box 618, Gering. 1st Lt. John Fred Nelson, 1865 12th St., Gering. 2nd Lt. Alfred F. Hinze, Gering. Co. "A" Capt. Varro E. Tyler, 529 No. 9th St., Nebraska City. 1st Lt. Fred L. Holmberg, 907 6th St. Corso, Nebraska 2nd Lt. Henry Flau, Nebraska City. Co. "B" Capt. Robert L. Runyan, Falls City. 1st Lt. Mervin F. Myers, Falls City. 2nd Lt. Clarence S. Peck, Falls City. Co. "C" Capt. Fred H. Stoll, 522 No. 8th St., Beatrice. 1st Lt. Dean A. Coonley, Beatrice. Co. "D" Capt. Butler B. Miltonberger, North Platte. 1st Lt. Fred C. Petersen, North Platte. 2nd Lt. Claire Leslie Boyer, North Platte. Co. "E" Capt. Fred W. Stone, Post Office Bldg., Scottsblufl. 1st Lt. Ora Albert Eatwell, 2120 D Ave., Scottsblufl. Co. "F" Capt. Louis R. Eby, Hartington. 1st Lt. Carl M. Lange, Hartington. 2nd Lt. Wayne A. Larue, Hartington. Co. "G" Capt. Alexander Rieber, Hastings. 1st Lt. Ivan C. Riley, Hastings. 2nd Lt. Robert J. Vanfleet, Hastings. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 11 Co. "H" Capt. Aca F. Miller, 118 W. 14th St., Grand Island. 1st Lt. Orval C. Auhl, 504 W. 7th St., Grand Island. 2nd Lt. Percy Floyd James, 104 W. Blake, Grand Island. Co. "I Capt. Edwin F. Hoke, P. O. Bldg. &amp; Y. M. C. A., Lincoln 1st Lt. Emory O'Connell, 1821 F. St., Lincoln. Capt. Bert C. Grasborg, 205 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha. 1st Lt. Claude T. Frimann, 205 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha 2nd Lt. Emil B. Peterson, 205 U. P. Hq. Bldg., Omaha Capt. H. F. Elsasser, 3708 No. 21st St., Omaha. 1st Lt. Guy T. Davis, 6310 No. 34th St., Omaha. 2nd Lt. Alfred Thomsen, 834 So. 24th St., Omaha. Co. "M" Capt. Edward J. Geesen, Seward. 1st Lt. Chas. H. Campbell, Seward. 2nd Lt. Abraham Morton, Seward. At t. Med. Dot. Major Rolland R. Ensor, M. C. Box 33, South Omaha. Capt. Wm. H. Achenbach, D. C, 1000 Central Ave., Nebraska City. Capt. Norman H. Atwood, M. C, 430 World Herald Bldg., Omaha. Capt. Glenn D. Whitcomb, M. C, 826 Brandeis Theatre Bldg. Omaha Capt. Wallace A. Gerri, M. C, 505 Omaha Loan Bldg., Omaha. 110th MEDICAL REGIMENT Headquarters Col. David C. Hilton, M. C, 305 Richards Blk., Lincoln. Lt. Col. Philip H. Bartholomew, M. C, 1244 So. 25th St., Lincoln. Major Earl B. Brooks, 705 1st Nat. Bank Bldg., Lincoln. Capt. Earl N. Deppen, 911 Sec. Mut. Bldg., Lincoln. Co. "K" Co. "L" </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Service Co. Capt. Harry R. Ball, 1120 N. St., Lincoln. Capt. Harry A. Stearns, % Post Office, Lincoln. Capt. Ernest W. Hancock, Sec. Mut. Bldg., Lincoln. War. Off. Lumir C. Havlicek, Crete. 1st Lt. Henry H. Strickland, 709 So. 29th St., Lincoln. Amb. Co. No. ISO 110th M. R. Capt. Leonard A. Swanson, Hastings. 1st Lt. H. R. Turner, Hastings. Hosp. Co. No. ISO Capt. Jay Henry Matthai, Orthopedic Hosp., Lincoln. 1st Lt. Wm. C. Hoffman, 2112 Smith St., Lincoln. 1st Lt. George E. Lewis, Liberty Theatre Bldg., Lincoln. Vet. Co. No. 110 Capt. S. W. Alford, 1325 No. 37th St., Lincoln. Collecting Co. No. ISO Capt. James North Evans, Pollock Bldg., Columbus. Capt. Carroll D. Evans, Jr., Evans Clinic, Columbus. Division Surgeon's Office, 85th Div. Major Geo. W. Covey, M. C, 322 First Nat. Bank Bldg., L Major Carl J. Norden, V. C, 227 N. 9th St., Lincoln. Major John R. Bennett, D. C, 214 Sec. Mut. Bldg., Lincoln. Lincoln, (General Orders No. 7, Last of Series of 1924) </seg>
            <seg id="p013">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 13 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 2, 1925. General Orders, No. 1. 1. The current season of Range Practice is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1925, to December 31, 1925. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 1, 1925. General Orders, No. 2. 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Saturday, May 30, 1925, consecrated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, the National flag will, in accordance with Para - graph 449 of the Regulations for the United States Army, be displayed on all Armories and, all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist in the ob - servance of the day by Veteran organizations, Commanding Officers of organizations not in the Federal service will place their respective commands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic on that day. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 30, 1925. General Orders, No. 4. 1. Pursuant to authority contained in letter MB-354.1 Nebraska-9, dated April 22, 1925, the State Staff Corps &amp; Departments, 134th In - fantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, and the 110th Medical Regiment will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 3 to 17, 1925, inclusive, under command of Colonel Herbert J. Paul, Adjutant General's Department, State Staff Corps &amp; Departments, and upon completion of this tour of duty, the above named organizations will be returned to their home stations. 2. The State Staff Corps &amp; Departments, the Service Detachment of the Service Company of the 134th Infantry, consisting of Regimental Supply Officer, one 1st Lieutenant, 1 Master Sgt., 2 Sergeants, 1 Corp - oral and 15 Pvts. 1st Class or Privates, two of which will be Cooks; Service Detachment, 35th Division Train, consisting of the Train Supply Officer, 2 Technical Sgts., Staff Sgt., 1 Sgt., and 1 Corporal, 7 Privates 1st Class or Privates; Service Detachment of the Service Com - pany, 110th Medical Regiment, consisting of Regimental Supply Of - ficer, 2 Sergeants and 10 Privates 1st Class or Privates, will form an advance detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and estab - lishing camp for the reception of troops and will report to the Com - manding Officer, Ashland, Nebraska, August 1, 1925. The above named organization and detachments will report at the earliest possible moment on August 1, 1925, taking the first trains available for that purpose. 3. Upon arrival in camp August 1, 1925, the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 134th Infantry, will immediately establish mess </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 15 for all advance troops. Commanding officers of the above organization and detachments will forward with same sufficient tentage to establish camp in their respective areas for advance detachments as enumerated in Par. 7, Circular Letter No. 21, Nebraska, dated July 1, 1925. Com - manding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train, and 110th Medical Regiment, will see that tentage and equipment necessary for establishing commissaries are forwarded with advance detachments. 4. A rear detachment, consisting of the State Staff Corps &amp; De - partments will remain in camp August 18 and 19, 1925, both dates inclusive, for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 5. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equip - ment, etc., will be handled by letters from this office. 6. In compliance with Compilation Changes No. 1, Par. 206, Na - tional Guard Regulations, 1922, all officers who have not had physical examination made within the year will appear before a board, which will be convened during the annual encampment, August 3 to 17, 1925, inclusive, for that purpose, and will see that physical examination papers are turned in to the Adjutant, Camp Headquarters, before the close of the encampment. 7. Outside of advance detachments above enumerated, no troops, details or detachments will be permitted to go into camp in advance of first day of camp, i. e., August 3, 1925. 8. The travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. BY ORDER OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 13, 1925. General Orders, No. 5. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Upon the recommendation of the Regimental Commander and under authority of the War Department, Company A, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, stationed at Auburn, Nebraska, is hereby disbanded and will be at once mustered out of the State and Federal service. Captain W. E. McConnaughey, QMC, Nebraska National Guard, will muster out said company and promptly forward to this office the muster-out rolls and all books and records of the company together with the discharges of enlisted men which were not delivered at the time of muster-out. Pursuant to Par. 169, sub-par, (b), National Guard Regulations, 1922, the officers rendered surplus by this order, are hereby transferred in the respective grades in which they are com - missioned, to the National Guard Reserve of Nebraska. 2. The Regimental Commander, 134th Infantry, Nebraska Na - tional Guard, is authorized to organize a Rifle company, 134th Infantry, at Nebraska City, Nebraska, to be known and designated as Company A, 134th Infantry, Nebraska National Guard. BY ORDER OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. (General Orders No. 5, last of series of 1925.) STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1926. General Orders, No. 1. Section Range Practice Season _ „ I Circular Letters, Rescinding thereof II Company Funds III I — Range Practice Season. — The current season of Range Practice Is hereby designated to extend from January 1, 1926, to December 41, 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 17 II — Circular Letters, Rescinding thereof. — All Nebraska Circular Letters issued in the years 1921, 1922, 1923 and 1924, are hereby rescinded and may be destroyed, the subject matter being covered in National Guard Regulations, Army Regulations, Training Regulations, Orders and Circulars. Ill — Company Funds. — Company Funds will be accounted for in Company Council Book (Q. M. C. Form 452), in accordance with in - structions therein except that the two pages intended for one month will be used for any desired period to suit the number of entries, and the voucher numbers to be continuous between audits of the account. Organization commanders will be held responsible that the inspection of the funds will be made at least once each year, preferably at camp. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 15, 1926. General Orders, No. 2. 1. Upon the recommendation of the Regimental Commander and under authority of the Secretary of War dated February 27, 1926, Howitzer Co., 134 Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, stationed at Mitchell, Nebraska, is hereby disbanded and will at once be mustered out of State and Federal service. Captain W. E. McConnaughey, Q. M. C, Nebraska National Guard, will muster out said company and promptly forward to this office the muster-out roll and all books and records of the company together with the discharges of enlisted men which were not delivered at the time of muster-out. Pursuant to Par. 169, sub-par, (b), National Guard Regulations, 1922, the officers rendered surplus by this order, i. e., Captain Archie B. Jones, 1st Lt. Edward P. Grant and 2nd Lt. James A. Lane, are hereby transferred in the respective grades in which they are commissioned, to the National Guard Reserve of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. The Regimental Commander, 134th Infantry, Nebraska Na - tional Guard, is authorized to convert Headquarters Co., 2nd Bn., 134th Infantry, stationed at Gering, Nebraska, to Howitzer Co., 134th Infantry, with station at Gering, Nebraska. When this conversion is accomplished a complete roster of the unit, certified to by instructor, will be furnished the Militia Bureau, in compliance with Par. No. 2, of above named letter of authorization. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr, STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 17, 1926. General Orders, No. 3. 1. Pursuant to authority contained in letter MB-354.1 Ne - braska-13, dated March 17, 1926, a four (4) day Camp of Instruction for officers and selected enlisted men will be held on the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, June 14 to 17, 1926, inclusive, under command of Colonel Herbert J. Paul, Adjutant General's Department, State Staff Corps and Departments, at which the following detail will attend: State Staff Corps and Departments, Colonel Herbert J. Paul, A. G. D. Major Harry C. Stein, Q. M. C. Capt. Frank B. O'Connell, A. G. D. Capt. Walter E. McConnaughey, Q. M. C Capt. Herbert M. Potter, Ord. 1 Private 1st Class. 134th Infantry. (1) Field and Staff Officers: Colonel, Lt. Colonel, Major Clyde E. McCormick, Major Edwin D. Fisher, Major Raymond L. Crosson. (2) Howitzer Co: Captain, 1st Lieutenant. (3) Company "A": Captain, 1st Lieutenant. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 19 (4) Company "B": Captain. (5) Company "C": Captain. (6) Company "D": Captain (7) Company "E": Captain (8) Company "F": Captain (9) Company "G": Captain 1st Lieutenant. 1st Lieutenant. 2nd Lieutenant. (10) Company "H": 2nd Lieutenant. (11) Hq. Co. 3rd Bn. 1st Lieutenant, 2nd Lieutenant. (12) Company "I": 1st Lieutenant. (13) Company "K": Captain, 1st Lieutenant, 2nd Lieutenant. (14) Company "L": Captain, 1st Lieutenant. (15) Company "M": 2nd Lieutenant. (16) Att. Med. Det: Captain W. H. Achenbach, Captain Norman H. Atwood 35th Division Train, QMC. (1) Train Hq: Major, 1st Lieutenant, 2nd Lieutenant. (2) M. T. Co. No. 138: 1st Lieutenant, 2nd Lieutenant. (3) Mot. Rep. Sec. No. 119: 1st Lieutenant. (4) Wag. Co. No. 119: Captain. (5) Wag. Co. No. 120: Captain, 1st Lieutenant. 110th Medical Regiment. (1) Field and Staff Officers: Colonel, Lt. Colonel, Major Carl J. Norden, Major George W. Covey, Captain Henry Farrell. (2) Service Co: Captain Harry A. Ste.ams. (3) Amb. Co. No. 130: Captain. (4) Hosp. Co. No. 130: Major. (5) Vet. Co. No. 110: Captain. (6) Coll. Co. No. 130: Captain J. North Evans. 2. Twelve enlisted men for attendance at Officers four day school will be enumerated in Special Orders at a later date. 3. Owing to the fact that this four day school will be held ex - clusive of travel time to and from encampment, all officers and en - listed men are directed to report at the Ashland Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, on June 13, 1926 or at the earliest possible hour on June 14, 1926 ,in order that camp, messes, etc., may be established and in working order so as not to interfere in any way with the regular school routine which will commence the first thing on the morning of June 14, 1926. After reporting at camp, no officers or enlisted men will be permitted to leave same without permission from the Commanding Officer. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4. The Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, will establish an Officers' Mess for the officers of his command and such officers as - signed as Instructors and from State Staff Corps and Departments together with such enlisted men as may be assigned therto for mess. 6. The Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train, will establish an Officers' Mess for the officers of his command and such officers from the 110th Medical Regiment, Instructors and State Staff Corps and Departments together with such enlisted men as may be assigned thereto for mess. 6. The above messes will be established so as to serve breakfast, June 14, 1926, and will continue throughout the period of camp of instruction; i. e., June 14 to 17, 1926, inclusive. 7. Dishes for officers' mess will be furnished by the Adjutant General's Department. 8. All officers upon arrival in camp will immediately report to the Camp Commander in person and will furnish the Adjutant data giving time of arrival, etc. 9. The Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, will furnish five tents, officers' wall, for the field officers of his command; the Com - manding Officer, 35th Division Train, will furnish one tent, Officers' wall; the Commanding Officer 110th Medical Regiment, will furnish five tents, officers' wall, for the field officers of his command; Capt. W. E. McConnaughey will furnish tentage for the State Staff Corps and Departments, Instructors and Sergeant Instructors, and the en - listed men attending this encampment. Capt. Edwin F. Hoke, Com - pany I, 134th Infantry, will establish camp at such place as will be designated by the camp commander for all officers below field grade allowing four officers per pyramidal tent. All officers and enlisted men will bring their own bedding and tent equipment, Including cot and mosquito bar. 10. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewed on, Issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. 11. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry individual equipment Including extra blankets, clothing, shoes, etc. and the bed sack will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. It will not be necessary for enlisted men armed with rifle to bring same to this school. Company Commanders from whose Company </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 21 enlisted men are selected for this school should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing, i. e., cotton blouse, breeches and O. D. shirt. 12. Instructions as to transportation, bills of lading, etc., will be furnished direct by the United States Property and Disbursing Officer. 13. Company commanders from whose companies enlisted men are selected for this school, will see that the service record of each enlisted man attending this camp of instruction is up to date and that same be brought to camp in possession of the senior officer attend - ing from that organization, and that same are turned over to the U. S. P. &amp; D. O., upon arrival in camp. 14. All officers are directed to bring the following equipment to camp, for training purposes: Rifle. (Company officers of units armed with the rifle and other officers scheduled to take the course in drill and command only). Brush and thong. Oiler and thong case. Cartridge belt. Bayonet and scabbard. Canteen and cover. Cup and cover. First aid pouch and packet. Haversack and pack carrier. Shelter tent, half. Shelter tent, pole. Shelter tent, pins (5). Shelter tent, rope. Blanket. Rain coat, (foot). Meat can. Knife. Fork. Spoon. The following toilet articles are for use in display of equipment and packing haversack, and will be required of all company officers. Razor. Shaving brush, (or cream). Tooth brush. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Tooth paste, (or powder). Mirror, (small, trench). Comb. Soap, hand, (bath). Underwear, (suit, L. W.) Socks, (woolen, pr.) Towel, hand. Handkerchief, O. D. Shoe laces, pr. Breeches laces, pr. The following additional equipment will be needed by each officer: Prismatic compass. Note book and pencil. Field message book. Pertinent Training Regulations as per references in schedule. 15. The camp calls for the follows : School of Instruction will be as 16. The travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. First call 6 : 00 Calisthentics 6:30 Mess 7:20 Assembly 7:55 School 7:55 Recall 12 : 00 Mess 12:15 School 1 : 00 Recall 4:30 Mess 6:00 Taps 11 : 00 last day, June 17th: Recall 12:30 P. M. Mess 12:45 School 1 : 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 23 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 19, 1926. General Orders, No. 3%. 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Sunday May 30, 1926, con - secrated to the brave soldiers who sacrified their lives for the Ameri - can. Republic, the National flag will, in accordance with paragraph 449 of the Regulations for the United States Army, be displayed on all Armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist in the observance of the day by Veteran organizations, Commanding Officers of or - ganizations not in the Federal service will place their respective commands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic on that day. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. BY ORDER OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 3, 1926. General Orders, No. 4. 1. Upon the recommendation of the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train and under authority of the Secretary of War dated May 29, 1926 Attached Veterinary Detachment, 35th Division Train, Nebraska National Guard, stationed at Fremont, Nebr. is hereby </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL disbanded and will at once be mustered out of State and Federal service. Captain W. E. McConnaughey Q. M. C, Nebraska National Guard, will muster out said company and promptly forward to this office the muster-out roll and all books and records of the company together with the discharges of enlisted men which were not de - livered at the time of muster-out. Pursuant to Par. 169, sub-par, (b) National Guard Regulations, 1922, the officer rendered surplus by this order, i. e., Captain Charles H. Chambers is hereby trans - ferred to the National Guard Reserve of Nebraska. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr, STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 10, 1926 General Orders, No. 5. 1. General Orders No. 3, A. G. O., Nebraska, dated May 17, 1926, are amended by omitting the following named officers: Capt. Frank B. O'Connell, A. G. D., SSC &amp; D. Capt. Norman H. Atwood, Att. Med. Det. 134th Inf, Capt. Bert C. Grasborg, Co. K, 134th Inf. 1st. Lt. Lester E. Chadderdon, Mot, Rep. Sec. No. 119, 35th Division Train. 1st. Lt. Claude J. Williams, Hq. 35th Div. Tn. 2nd. Lt. Emil B. Peterson, Co. K, 134th Inf. 2. General Orders No. 3, A. G. O., Nebraska, dated May 17, 1926, are amended by including the following named Officers: Capt. Thomas Q. Thornton, Hq. 134th Inf. Capt. Allen A. Tukey, Hq. 134th Inf. 1st. Lt. Alexander Reiber, Co. G, 134th Inf. 2nd. Lt. Alfred Thomson, Co. L, 134th Inf. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 25 2nd. Lt. Clarence B. Neff, Wag. Co. No. 119, 35th Dlv. Tn. 3. Par. No. 8, General Orders No. 3, A. G. O. Nebraska, dated May 17, 1926, is amended to read as follows: "All officers upon arrival in camp will immediately report to the Camp Commander in person and will furnish the United States Property &amp; Disbursing Officer data giving time of arrival, etc." BY ORDER OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 1, 1926. General Orders, No. 6 1. Pursuant to authority contained in letter MB-354.1 Ne - braska-12 dated June 17, 1926, the State Staff Corps and Departments, 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train, QMC, and the 110th Medical Regiment will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 2 to 16, 1926, inclusive, under command of Colonel Herbert J. Paul, Adjutant General's Department, State Staff Corps and Departments, and upon completion of this tour of duty, the above named organizations will be returned to their home stations. 2. The following named organizations and Detachments will report at the earliest possible moment on July 31st, 1926, taking the first train available for that purpose: State Staff Corps and De - partments consisting of Colonel Herbert J. Paul, A. G. D., Major H. C Stein, QMC, Captain W. E. McConnaughey, QMC, and eighteen en - listed men. Service Detachment of the Service Co., 134th Infantry, consisting of one 1st lieutenant and nineteen enlisted men. Head - quarters Detachment, 35th Division Train consisting of one 2nd Lieutenant and twelve enlisted men; and the Service Detachment, Service Co., 110th Medical Regiment, consisting of one Captain and twelve enlisted men. They will form an advance Detachment for the purpose of preparing camp site and establishing camp for the </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL reception of troops and will report to the Commanding Officer, Ash - land, Nebraska, July 31, 1926. 3. Upon arrival in camp July 31, 1926, the Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 134th Infantry, will immediately establish mess for all advance troops. Commanding officers of the above organiza - tions and detachments will forward with same sufficient tentage to establish camp in their respective areas for advance detachments as enumerated in Par. 7, Circular Letter No. 26, Nebraska, dated July 1, 1926. Commanding Officers of the 134th Infantry, 35th Division Train, and 110th Medical Regiment, will see that tentage and equip - ment necessary for establishing commissaries are forwarded with advance detachments. 4. A rear detachment consisting of the State Staff Corps and De - partments will remain in camp August 17, 1926 for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 5. Details as to transportation, train schedules, supplies, equip - ment, etc., will be handled by letters from this office. 6. In compliance with Par. 4, National Guard Regulations 27, July 15, 1925, all officers who have not had physical examination made within the year will report to a medical officer for same during the annual encampment August 2 to 16, 1926 inclusive for that pur - pose, and will see that physical examination papers are turned in to the Adjutant, Camp Headquarters, before the close of the encamp - ment. The Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment will designate such medical officers as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this paragraph and will cause to be published the names of same at the beginning of the encampment, in order that those requiring ex - amination may know to whom they are to report. 7. Outside of advance detachments above enumerated, no troops, details or detachments will be permitted to go into camp in advance of first day of camp, i. e., August 2, 1926. 8. The travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Asst. Adjutant General, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 27 Circular Letter No. 33, last of series of 1924 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 14, 1925. Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Processes in Trials by Court Martial. To: All Officers, Nebraska National Guan All Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Numerous inquiries received by this office and the United States Marshal for this district having raised the question as to whether or not certain officers of the State have the right to serve processes, etc., in trials by court martial, decision was asked of the Attorney General, State of Nebraska, and letter received from his office is herewith reproduced for your information. "State of Nebraska, Department of Justice Lincoln December 19, 1924. "General H. J. Paul, Adjutant General, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear General: "We have received and considered the letter which you enclosed with your letter of December 18th pertaining to the right of certain officers of the State to serve processes in trials by court martial. We return herewith the carbon copy of the letter which you received from D. H. Cronin, United States Marshal. "Under the provisions of our statutes, it is our opinion that officers of the State, authorized to serve processes, would be authorized to serve processes in court martial hearings pertaining to members of the National Guard. "Very truly yours, O. S. SPILLMAN, Attorney General. By Lloyd Dort, Assistant Attorney General." </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. CORRECTED COPY STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 22, 1925. Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Armory Drill Pay for Fiscal Year 1925. To: All Unit Commanders, Nebraska Nation All Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. A part of Special Delivery letter, W. D., M. B., January 13, 1925, is herewith published for the information of all concerned. "1. Due to the increase in strength of the National Guard, the $10,200,000.00 appropriated for armory drill for the fiscal year 1925 will be insufficient if the percentage of attendance maintained during the preceding fiscal year is continued. It has been decided, there - fore, to apportion the 1925 appropriation for armory drill to the various States, this apportionment to be in direct ratio to the strength Of the National Guard in each State on July 1, 1924. On this basis it has been determined that the apportionment of your State amounts to $98,270.16, the strength of its National Guard on the date men - tioned and as reported by you having been 1699. "2. The apportionment stated above represents the total sum of money which will be available for the payment of armory drill pay. including administrative function pay, for all officers, warrant officers and enlisted men of the National Guard of your State during the en - tire fiscal year of 1925. You are requested to so arrange the at - tendance at armory drills, or the number of such drills, or to take other administrative action within your State as will insure that the amount represented by the apportionment mentioned in Paragraph 1 above will not be exceeded. "By direction of the Secretary of War (Signed) Geo. C. Rickards, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau," </seg>
            <seg id="p029">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 29 2. Owing to the fact that at the 'present rate we have run over our allotment approximately $12,000.00, and in order to keep within the above named allotment of $98,270.16 for the fiscal year 1925, armory drills cannot be authorized to exceed twelve (12) for each quarter commencing January 1, 1925, and drills in excess thereof can - not be paid for out of federal funds and will not be approved by this office, as there are no state funds out of which armory drill pay can be met. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 30, 1925. Circular Letter No. 3 Subject : Legislation. To: All Field and Staff Officers and Company Commanders, N. N. G. 1. The United States Senate Appropriations Committee has, with - out notice, inserted a provision in their report on the appropriations bill which provides, if enacted into law, to take from the National Guard and Reserve Officers rental allowance for all periods of service of less than thirty-one days' duration. This means that the above named officers will not receive rental allowance in the future only in case of a national emergency, which is perhaps the only thing that would cause them to spend thirty-one days or more in the field at any one time. 2. Brigadier General Milton A. Reckord, President of the Na - tional Guard Association, informs me that they have been unable to get them to eliminate this provision but that Senator Wadsworth, the author of the amendment, promised him a full and complete hearing before the joint conference committee of the Senate and House. 3. In my judgment we should contest this provision with all our power and I request that you communicate at once with both our </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL senators and members of the House, to the end that if we are unable to eliminate the provision before the conference committee, we may defeat it upon the floor of the Senate and House. 4. The provision which provides for the payment of rental allowance to National Guard officers was made a part of the original pay act and only a few months ago we succeded in having rental allowance paid to all officers, and it is at present satisfactory to the Regular Army, the National Guard, and the Reserve. There is no good and sufficient reason for a change at this time and I urge you to explain the situation fully and ask our representatives in Wash - ington to fight the provision. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 6, 1925. Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Efficiency Reports To: All Reporting Offlc All Reporting Officers, Nebraska National Guard 1. There are enclosed herewith blank efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 31, 1924, and which should have your immediate attention. 2. Before attempting to make this report, you are directed to make a thorough study of the instructions contained thereon, which are full and explicit and, if followed explicitly, will bring the proper report to this office before the expiration of the month. 3. Owing to the fact that some officers did not make a study of the instructions on these efficiency reports, some of the reports made last year should have been sent back as a discredit to the reporting officer. Some officers procrastinated in making out these reports to the extent that they did not arrive in this office until late in the sum - mer of 1924, thereby causing all reports to be held until they could be forwarded together, which made a very poor showing for the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 31 State of Nebraska and caused us to lose several marks in the effi - ciency class. 4. After having given a thorough study to the instructions on both sides of the efficiency reports, then make out your reports and forward same without further procrastination to the officer to whom the instructions direct you. This is a small matter if given your immediate attention. Let us all get them in in proper form and AT ONCE. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 9, 1925. Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Telegraphic Returns. To: All Unit and Sub-uni All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, N. N. G. 1. Attention is invited to the following letter received this date from the Militia Bureau with reference to telegraphic strength returns. "War Department Militia Bureau Washington February 5, 1925. "Subject: Telegraphic Returns. To: The Adjutant General The Adjutant General of Nebraska. "1. The rendering of monthly telegraphic strength returns to the Militia Bureau will not be required hereafter except for the months ending June 30th and December 31st. "2. The two returns required in the future should give the total number of active members of the National Guard of your State, on the dates specified, and should state the figures for officers, warrant officers, and enlisted men separately. "3. These two returns should be submitted not later than the fifth of the month following the date of the return. If it is not </seg>
            <seg id="p032">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 32 possible to have accurate figures by that time, the most accurate esti - mate obtainable should be submitted. It is very important to have this information in the Militia Bureau by the 6th day of July and of January of each year. For the Chief of Bureau P. L. Miles, Colonel, Infantry, M. B. Assistant." 2. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 28, October 29, 1924, is there - fore rescinded and telegraphic strength returns to this office will only be made for the months ending June 30 and December 31 until farther notice. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 25, 1925. Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: The Beatrice Military Essay. To: All Unit Commanders, Nebr All Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. There is published herewith full information in regard to the Beatrice Military Essay, and it is the desire of this office that the conditions be read to all units and everything done by each unit commander to make this a success. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska, FULL CONDITIONS THE BEATRICE MILITARY ESSAY The Beatrice prize of $100.00 is awarded to the writer of the best essay, upon a military subject, chosen each year by the donor. Subject for 1925: "The Citizen Soldier." </seg>
            <seg id="p033">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 33 Conditions. The writer must be an officer or an enlisted man in one of the component parts of the citizen army of the United States of the 7 th Corps Area. (a) (b) (c) (d) (e) (f) The National Guard of the several states. The Officers' Reserve Corps. The Enlisted Reserve. Men who have attended the C. M. T. C. R. O. T. C. Accredited Military Schools. I. The article must contain not less than 2000 words. II. III. IV. Article shall be of a practical constructive nature Article shall be typewritten, or written legibly. Article shall be in the hands of The President, Reserve Officers Association, Beatrice, Nebraska, by April 15th, 1925. V. Manuscript is not to be signed with the name of the writer, but with a nom de plume. VI. The manuscript shall be accompanied by a second envelope containing: (a) The nom de plume. (b) The name and address of the writer. (c) His grade or rank, and unit. This envelope shall be marked on the outside with nom de plume only. VII In searching for the best essay, the judges will look for the intent of the writer, and will give credit for basic thoughts, rather than for grammatical correctness. Neatness, however, will be a factor. VIII The Judges: Judges shall be appointed by the President of the Beatrice Reserve Officers Association. IX No judges shall compete. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 34 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 5, 1925. Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Inventory of Property. To: All Officers, Nebraska National Guard, responsible for Public Property. 1. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 33, November 14, 1922, is rescinded and the following substituted therefor. (a) Complete, detailed and accurate inventory of property and supplies will be made semi-annually to the United States Property and Disbursing Officer, Nebraska, on forms furnished by that officer. (b) The inventory may be made at any time during the semi - annual period, but must be submitted by June 1 and December 1 of each year. (c) The United States Property and Disbursing Officer, Ne - braska, will make quarterly reports on the progress made on Section (a). BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 20, 1925. Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Instructions for Annual Armory Inspection, 1925 All Company Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35 1. It is important that you have the following data ready for the Inspecting Officer on his arrival: Officers Enl. Men ( 1) Active strength of organization ( 7) Personnel with less than one year's service ( 8) Personnel in the U. S. Army dur - ing the World War ( 9) Average strength of organization during 12 months prior to this in - spection (10) Average attendance at Armory Drill during 12 months prior to this Inspection. (Compute from recapitulation back of payrolls since last Armory Inspection. Add the officers and men present for all drills separate and divide the sum by number of drills held in each case; i. e., officers and men.) (12) Personnel, based on present strength who are protected by (a) Anti-typhoid inoculation (b) Successful vaccination (13) Percentage of enlisted attendance, computed from items 9 and 10 above % Number qualified with pistol since last inspection Number unqualified (who are armed with pistol) Number qualified with rifle since last inspection Number unqualified 2. Attention is called to the fact that 1925 report differs from the 1924 report in the following particulars: Page 2, Par. 10, is changed to read "Drills or assemblies held dur - ing 12 months prior to this Inspection." </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Off. Men (a) Single formation drills (b) Split drills Page 2, the following questions are added, "Drills at which officers qualified for pay." (a) Single formation drills (b) Split drills Page 4, Par. 2, add "Has organization a unit mobilization plan approved by next higher Commander?" "Has organization copies of A. R. 120-10 and A. R. 130-10?" Par. 3, The identification record (Form 260, A. G. O.) is omitted from the blank forms the Recruiting Officer is required to have on hand. Page 5, Par. 1, add "Score card for rifle practice (83, A. G. O.) or Individual Record of Known Distance Firing (304, A. G. O.) "Score card for pistol practice (88, A. G. O.) or Individual Record of Pistol Firing (305, A. G. O.) Record of Pistol Firing (305, A. G. O.) "Monthly Roster (9, A. G. O., or 703, A. G. O., or 4, N. N. G.) "Requisition (Form 160, Q. M. C.) "Property Loan Record (263c, Q. M. C.) "Unit Mobilization Plan." Par. 1, OMIT "Individual Clothing slip" (165, Q. M. C.) "Stock Record (Form 258, Q. M. C.) "Requisition Record (Form 259, Q. M. C.) Page 11, Par. 3, add "A copy of A. R. 130-10 should always be kept in field desk." Is this done? If not, note general exceptions and reasons therefor. Par. 4, add "Are Training Regulations properly bound and kept posted up to date?" Extra Information. — "What is the consensus of opinion among Instructors and N. G. Officers regarding Training Regulations as at present distributed to the N. G. as to the following: (a) Are they entirely satisfactory for the N. G. purpose? If not, give defects. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 37 (b) Remarks on durability. (c) Specific recommendation, if any. 3. GENERAL SUGGESTIONS. Special attention should be given Page 12, Pars. 4 and 5; also Page 14, Pars. 1 to 8, inclusive, in re - gard to Armory Drill and Instruction. By careful questioning of the men, Par. 12 (b), Page 2, may be answered satisfactorily. Note that Par. 2, Page 10, specifically asks "If the following Blank Forms are on hand in the field desk and available for use when called into Federal service?" (Council Book, etc.) The STATE FUND BOOK and VOUCHERS pertaining thereto now in use should also be ready for inspection and audit by the Inspector. Blank forms that should be on hand are those listed in charts, "List, Accomplishment and Disposition of Records involved when a man is enlisted, transferred, discharged, or in case of death. Ed. 2-2-25." In order to comply fully with Par. 3, Page 3, and Par. 3, Page 11, a Company Order should be made to verify the assignment of a Recruiting, Administration, Training and Supply Officer. The Inspecting Officer usually desires to spend the afternoon of the date of the scheduled inspection in checking the records of the organization and in the inspection of the property. You are requested to make necessary arrangements to have your Supply Sergeant, First Sergeant, Company Clerk and one Commissioned Officer available at this time. Unless further instructions are issued from this office, the uniform for the inspection will be as follows: Campaign Hat (hat cord sewed on.) Flannel O. D. shirt (cravats will not be worn. Collar orna- ments will be worn.) Woolen Breeches (issue waist belts.) Issue leggins (wrapped from calf of leg down.) Issue shoes (well polished.) Equipment will be full field. The carrying in the pack of one (1) blanket only is authorized. Attention is called to the fact that full field equipment for N. C. O. and Officers includes such articles as </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL whistles, message books, field glasses, etc., as are prescribed in tables of equipment. Company commanders will issue Company Orders announcing the uniform for the inspection. 4. In addition to instructions contained herein, if called upon by the Inspector, all units of the 35 th Division Train will be required to conform strictly to directions given in the Display of Equipment chart, which has been sent to all Train organizations, during full pack Inspection. Certain Individual members of Train units will be questioned by the Inspector in connection with the following: (1) Nomenclature, care and use of (a) Pistol. (b) Rifle. (2) Preparatory training for target practice, as to extent and thoroughness and instruction. (3) Training of Train Headquarters. (4) Special attention will be given the following: Proficiency of Drivers, Mechanics, Wagoners and Specialists. (5) Conveys — rules and road discipline. 5. The same instructions as for other units will apply to Medical units, except those pertaining to records for Rifle and Pistol practice. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 39 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 28, 1925. Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Observation of Mother's Day. To: All Unit Commanders. Nebra All Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for the information of all concerned, and it is requested that all unit commanders cause this to be brought to the attention of the enlisted personnel of their units at the first assembly after receipt of same. "War Department Militia Bureau Washington March 19, 1925. "Subject: Observation of Mother's Day. "To: The Adjutant General of Nebrt The Adjutant General of Nebraska. "It is requested that you bring to the attention of every officer and enlisted man of the National Guard of your state, the desire of the Secretary of War that each officer and enlisted man write a letter to his home, if absent therefrom, on Mother's Day, the second Sun - day in May, May 10th, 1925, as an expression of the love and reverence we owe to the mothers of our country. "For the Chief, Militia Bureau: L. W. Prunty, Lt. Col., Cav., M. B., Assistant BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 40 &gt; STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 3, 1925. Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Armory Drills during Fiscal Tear of 1925. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following telegram, just received from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all con - cerned. A careful check must be made by each unit and sub-unit commander of the drills held during the present fiscal year, which ends June 30, 1925, in order that they do not run over the forty - eight (48) drills allowed for this fiscal year, as that number is all that can be paid for under the President's last order. "Adlut. General of State, Lincoln, Nebr. "The following for your information and guidance colon The President has comma by order of March thirty-one comma authorized expenditures from the one million three hundred thirty-two thousand dollars heretofore held in non-apportioned status comma of such sum as will comma together with moneys already appropriated comma permit each National Guard unit which has been under status Federal recognition during whole of current fiscal year to hold a total of forty-eight armory drills during that fiscal year. National Guard unit recognised during current fiscal year will be allowed their proportionate share of forty-eight drills period. Until further orders no units will be paid for more than forty-eight drills or its proportionate share thereof during fiscal year of nineteen twenty-five period. This order supersedes all previous instructions period. Detailed instruction by mail period By order of the Secretary of War. RICKARDS." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 41 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 11, 1925. Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Armory Drills. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Upon going over the report submitted on armory drills held for the quarter ending March 31, 1925, it is discovered that a general average of approximately 43.5 drills have been held, which leaves less than five to be held between now and July 1, 1925, for which pay can be received under the President's last ruling that only forty - eight drills can be held with pay for this fiscal year. 2. Notwithstanding the fact that the respective units can only be paid up to forty-eight drills, all unit commanders are urged to hold at least the four drills per month, or twelve for the quarter ending June 30, 1925, as a failure to do so will lower the morale of the organizations even more than being compelled to drill with - out pray. In addition to this, camp will follow within approximately thirty days after the ending of this quarter, and if the men are to be taken into camp at all prepared for the work there, the drills are absolutely essential. 3. Under the President's ruling pay cannot be promised for more than the forty-eight drills for the fiscal year, but every effort is being made at this time to get him to rescind that order and it is possible he may do so. In that event all units will be paid the same as usual, but in case a unit commander elects not to hold more than sufficient drills to bring his number up to the forty-eight allowed at this time, he will of course not qualify his organization and in that case will lose out if the present orders of the President are rescinded. There - fore, while you are not directed to hold more drills than the President has indicated will be paid for, you are requested to do so for the reasons set out above and for the good of the respective units and the organization as a whole. 4. In case the unit commander elects to hold drills as suggested above, he should then show the actual number of drills on the pay - roll for the quarter ending June 30, 1925, and an endeavour will be </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL made to get pay as there is some question about the legality of the President's decision. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 13, 1925. Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Circular Letter No. 7, 1925. To: All Officers, Nebraska National Guard, responsible for Public Property. 1. Pending the publication of the revised National Guard Regula - tions, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 7, March 5, 1925, is hereby rescinded. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 17, 1925. Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Armory Drills. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following telegram just received from the Chief, Militia Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned : </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 43 "Adjt. General, State of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebr "The Secretary of War has apportioned to Nebraska one hundred nine thousand one eighty-nine dollars four cents armory drill pay for fiscal year nineteen twenty-five comma under following conditions colon No committment for armory drill will be made by Nebraska of any sum which together with payment or other committment al - ready made will exceed this apportionment semicolon no rolls will be presented for payments of drills in excess of one per week in any unit during the remainder of current fiscal year semicolon no unit will be paid for more than sixty drills during current fiscal year. This super - sedes all previous instructions regarding apportionments of this fund and limitation as to numbers of armory drills semicolon Detailed instructions by letter. RICKARDS.' BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 9, 1925. Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Method of attaching supporting papers to Pay Rolls. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, N. N. G. 1. The following letter from Headquarters Seventh Corps Area, dated April 21, 1925, on above subject, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "Regulations of the Finance Department, U. S. Army, require that all supporting papers be secured to the back of the voucher and not to the face, and pursuant to such regulations it is requested that instructions be issued to all officers concerned with the preparation of pay rolls that all supporting papers, such as certificates, affidavits, etc., of unit commanders, instructors, etc., be attached to the inside of </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL last cover page of pay roll and not on outside of first page of cover. "For the Commanding General: (Signed) ABBOTT BOONE, Major, Field Artillery, Acting National Guard Officer. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 9, 1925. Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Programs and Schedules for Field Training Camps To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, N. N. G. All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, N. N. G 1. The following letter from Headquarters Seventh Corps Area, dated April 28, 1925, on above subject, is published for the informa - tion and guidance of all concerned: "1. It is requested that the attention of all unit commanders be called to the requirements of part IL paragraph 20, Page 33, Train - ing Memorandum No. 1, Headquarters 7th Corps Area, February 25, 1925, which require that programs for field training camps be for - warded through proper channels to arrive at these headquarters not later than two months prior to opening date of camp. "2. It is also requested that commanders preparing programs request instructors to endorse programs with such comments as the Instructor may care to make in order that these headquarters may know in advance that the instructor has seen the program and that it meets with bis approval, or that he recommends whatever changes may in his opinion be advisable. "For the Commanding General: (Signed) ABBOTT BOONE, Major, Field Artillery, Acting National! Guard Officer." </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 45 BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 13, 1925. Circular Letter No. 16 Subject: Payment of Rolls covering Armory Drill Pay for Fourth. Quarters, Fiscal Tear, 1925. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter MB 240.91 Nebraska-6, War Department, Militia Bureau, dated May: 4, 1925, on above subject, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. "1. The Militia Bureau is very desirous of closing the settle - ment of all outstanding payrolls for Armory Drill pay, fiscal year 1925, by August 15, 1925, to the end that the total cost of this im - portant phase of National Guard training can be accurately determined for use in preparation of estimates for adequate funds to provide for the payment of Armory Drills for the fiscal year 1927. "2. This matter is of such vital importance to the National Guard that it is deemed advisable to bring it to your attention with the request that you inform all officers charged with the preparation and certification of payrolls of the necessity for prompt action on their part in submitting all outstanding armory drill payrolls for the fiscal year 1925 to the Finance Officer for payment on or as soon after June 30, 1926, as practicable. "3. In this connection instructions have been issued to Corps Area Commanders to the effect that the payment of all rolls covering Armory Drills held by the National Guard of any State during the fourth quarter of the current fiscal year will be deferred until the payrolls of all units belonging 1 to that State have been figured and the total of all such rolls compared with the balance remaining to the </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL credit of that State. If it should then transpire that the available balance of the State's apportionment for Armory Drill Pay is Sufficient to pay for all armory drills allowed by instructions contained in Militia Bureau letter MB 240.91, dated April 17, 1925, rolls will be paid; otherwise, immediate report to the Chief, Militia Bureau, is to be made by the Corps Area Commander concerned. "By order of the Secretary of War: (Signed) GEO. C. RICKARDS, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 26, 1925. Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Participation in Decoration Day Exercises. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. There seems to be some misunderstanding as to whether or not a drill can be claimed for Decoration Day Exercises in addition to the weekly drill now allowed. Attention is invited to the fact that under a recent order issued by the President, only one drill can be claimed per week. Decoration Day, for those organizations partici - pating, will therefore take the place of the weekly drill for which pay can be claimed for that week. Attention is invited to Nebraska Cir - cular Letter No. 13, April 17, 1925, in connection with General Orders No. 2, May 1, 1925, A. G. O., Nebraska. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 47 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 29, 1925. Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Armory Drill Pay Rolls. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following memorandum from Headquarters Seventh Corps Area is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "HQ. SEVENTH CORPS AREA Office of the Corps Area Commander Omaha, Nebraska, May 22, 1925. "NATIONAL GUARD MEMORANDUM) NO. 4 ) "1. The following communication from the Finance Officer, U. 8. Army, is published for the information and guidance of all con - cerned : '1. An examination of armory drill pay rolls paid for the 1st quarter, 1925, disclosed that fifteen per cent of the rolls which have been paid to date were required to be returned for correction or com - pletion. This does not include a number which have been returned but have not again been forwarded to this office for payment. In addition to the erroneous rolls mentioned above, quite a number have been paid except as to one or more individuals whose remarks or pay data was not correctly shown. '2. Pay rolls for the 1st quarter, 1925, for approximately forty - five organizations are yet unpaid. (This number includes rolls which have been returned for correction.) '3. In view of the procedure to be followed in effecting payment for the quarter ending June 30, 1925, it appears that unless a greater degree of care is exercised in the preparation, checking and correction of rolls before submission for payment, than has been heretofore ex - ercised, this office will be unable to begin issuing checks prior to the </seg>
            <seg id="p048">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 48 time the Militia Bureau has indicated it desires settlement to be completed for the quarter in question. In this connection attention is invited to the errors and omissions most commonly noted on rolls for the quarter period ending March 31, 1925, as listed below: (a) Instructions printed on face of roll not complied with. (b) Cir. 46-A-24 not complied with in detail. (c) Minimum maintenance strength stated erroneously by deducting a variation of 10%, which variation is no longer authorized. (d) Inclusive dates of period for which administrative pay accrued not stated in remarks. (e) Date of orders changing status of payee omitted. (f) Grade in which discharged not stated in remarks in cases of "Discharge and Re-enlistment" within the period involved. (g) Reason for discharge omitted. (The authority under which effected is not a reason.) (h) Date of prior enlistment and qualification omitted in cases where "discharge and re-enlistment" occur within the period, or where an enlisted man is appointed to a commissioned grade. (i) Model remarks (see Model Pay Roll and instructions thereon) not followed. Uniformity in the preparation of rolls, especially in the form of remarks greatly facilitates examination and payment." For the Commanding General: (Signed) ABBOTT BOONE, Major, Field Artillery, Acting National Guard Officer." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR STATE OF NEBRASKA H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 49 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 13, 1925. Circular Letter No. 19 Subject: Defense Test Day, To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. It is the desire of the Governor that all units and sub-units report in uniform at the armory at some time 1 during the day of July 4th, 1925, which has been designated by the President as Defense Test Day. The time and work done the Governor desires to be left largely to the discretion of the commanding officers, although in localities where they are celebrating, it is his desire that the units participate in the parade. 2. It is requested that immediately upon receipt of this communi - cation, all unit and sub-unit commanders report to this office what, in their opinion, will be the turn-out for July Fourth and what they can do to make this day a success. 3. It must be understood that there are no Federal or State funds to defray any expenses connected with the above assembly, but it is suggested that this assembly take the place of the weekly armory drill for the week of July Fourth, and for which credit can be given for an armory drill. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Jane 25, 1925. Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Return of Strength as of June 30, 1925 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. In accordance with existing regulations, State authorities are required to submit to the Chief, Militia Bureau, a telegraphic return of strength as of midnight, June 30th, ol[ each year. Attention ot all unit and sub-unit commanders is again invited to the necessity of their reporting direct to this office by telegraph the strength of their organizations, giving officers and enlisted men separately in the fol - lowing form, i. e., "Company A three officers fifty-six enlisted men (Signed) Jones, Captain." 2. From this form it will easily be seen that it is not necessary to write a letter by telegraph in sending in this strength report. This telegram should be forwarded so as to arrive at this office not later than 3:00 p. m., June 30th, in order that we may have time to con - solidate the reports and forward to the Militia Bureau the same evening. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 1, 1925. Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1925. To: All Unit Commanders and all Field and Staff Officers, N. N. G. 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1925, having been set, t August 3 to 17, 1925, inclusive, no organization will be ex - from attending except when they do not comply with the pro - s of Pars. 110 and 932, as amended by Changes No. 3, 19 and 22 and Changes No. 4, National Guard Regulations, 1922, respectively. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making </seg>
            <seg id="p051">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 51 yourselves conversant with the above quoted paragraphs and changes, as non-compliance therewith will be expensive for company com - manders. There will be no separate officers' school of instruction or rifle competition this fiscal year. Team for Camp Perry will be sel - ected from the shooting members of the National Guard during record practice at the encampment as above designated. 2. All units will be notified direct by the United States Property and Disbursing Officer as to the exact hour of departure from home station, rations, handling of baggage, train schedules, transportation requests, bills of lading, making of vouchers, etc. 3. Company commanders are authorized to purchase one day's travel ration for enlisted men at seventy cents per ration, and will follow instructions received from the U. S. P. &amp; D. O. pertaining thereto. 4. Travel discipline. The senior line officer will assume com - mand of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained; 1. e., no men on top of cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders, and men's personal appearance and conduct must be correct. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movements by Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The commanding officer will make a thorough inspection of the train be - fore troops enter train at home station, and after they detrain at camp. 5. Travel uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Chapter IV, Volume I, Waldron's Platoon Training. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack, cots and mosquito nets will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. Company Commanders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing; i. e., cotton blouse, breeches and O. D. shirt. 7. Additional equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment consisting of axes, water bags, G. I. cans, colors, field desk, lanterns, marking outfits, rakes ranges, typewriters, shovels, tools, and all cleaning materials; sufficient pyramidal tents to provide for six men to a tent, and two additional (one for orderly and one for supply tent), and all other tentage except latrine screens. Information pertaining to saddles, saddle equipment </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL, and harnesses will be furnished in a separate circular letter. 8. Ordnance. All ammunition, all empty cartridges (brass) in packing boxes, Belgian aiming device, all extra rifles and pistols that need repairing, that ordnance with which the individual and com - pany are equipped, and fire control instruments, will be brought to camp. Ammunition carts and machine gun carts will not be brought to camp as same will be furnished there for demonstration purposes. Ordnance carried in baggage cars will be considered excess baggage. The commanding officer of Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will bring only such necessary gun carriers, carts, etc., as will enable him to fire on the field. 9. Special equipment. All signal, medical and engineer prop - erty Is to be carried; also the glass tubes of calcium hypochlorite and lister bags. 10. You are advised that all equipment referred to in this letter is based upon Equipment Tables, National Guard, with which all con - cerned have been furnished copies. 11. Records... All records and office supplies will be taken; i. e., Property Records, Individual Records, stationery, Service Records, Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in duplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in dupli - cate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to cause of such absence, will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. 12. Messes. All company officers will mess with their organisa - tion and should provide themselves with tables and chairs. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organisation. The Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, together with the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train, Q. M. C, will establish officers' messes for the field and staff officers of their own organizations and such officers of the State Staff Corps and Departments, and instructors, as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 3, 1925. BT DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 53 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 7, 1925. Circular Letter No. 22 Subject: Pay of C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. employes. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Copy of letter from Mr. L. B. Lyman, General Superintendent, Chicago, Burlington &amp; Quincy Railroad Company, is herewith furnished for the information and guidance of all concerned. "Lincoln, Nebr., July 5, 1925. "Mr. H. J. Paul, Adjutant General, Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebr. My dear Mr. Paul: Referring to your letter of July 2nd: We plan on paying members attending the National Guard en - campment; that is, we compensate them, less the amount they receive from the State or Federal Government. In other words, we make up the difference so that they will receive the equivalent of their salary. Yours truly, (Signed) L. B. LYMAN, General Superintendent, C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. Co." BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 54 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 15, 1925. Circular Letter No. 23 Subject: Transportation To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. MOUNTS: Mounts will be furnished to respective organiza - tions for the following: S. S. C. &amp; D. — 1 Col. AGD, 1 Capt. AGD, 1 Major QMC, 2 orderlies. 134th Inf. — 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 3 Majors (Bn. Commanders), 3 Battalion Adjutants, 1 Supply Officer, 1 Adjutant, 4 orderlies. (1 for each Battalion and one for Hq.) 35th Dim. Tn. — 1 Major, 1 Adjutant, 1 Supply Officer, I orderly. 110th Med. Rest. — 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 3 Majors, 1 Adjutant, 1 Supply Officer, 2 orderlies. The officers designated below will furnish riding equipment complete: S. S. C. &amp; D.— Q. M. C. Captain 5 134th Inf.— C. O. Regt. Hq. Co „ 7 C. O. each Bn. Hq. Co 3 35th Divn. Tn. — C. O. Hq. Det „ 4 110th M. R. — C. O. Service Co 9 2. MULES, DRAFT: Mules will be asigned for demonstrative purposes as follows: Machine Gun Officer, 134th Inf 2 Howitzer Co., 134th Inf 2 35th Division Train 4 Camp Quartermaster 4 Equipment for the above will be furnished as follows C. O. Co. H, 134th Inf.— 2 sets M. G. harness; 1 cart, M. G. Am - munition; 1 cart, machine gun. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 55 C. O. Howitzer Co., 134th Inf. will bring in the necessary harness and carts. TJSP&amp;DO will furnish the necessary wheel and lead harness and escort wagons. 3. MOTOR: USP&amp;DO will transport all available tracks (heavy and light) and ambulances stored at the State Arsenal to camp. Commanding Officer, Co. K, 134th Inf. will see that his truck with two drivers will leave Omaha August 3, 1925 at 7:00 AM, reporting upon arrival to Capt. McConnaughey, QMC-NNG. This truck will load company equipment of the Omaha units in baggage car on August 2nd. The Commanding Officers of the organization will furnish truck drivers immediately upon arrival of their first units to Capt. Mc- The Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 21, 1925. Circular Letter No. 24 Subject: Restriction on Armory Drills for National Guard for fiscal year 1926. All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. To: 1. Copy of letter received from the Chief, Militia Bureau on the above mentioned subject is furnished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "MB 240.91 Gen. — 54 War Department Militia Bureau Washington onnaughey, Transportation Officer, as follows: 134th Inf 8 35th Division Train 2 110th Medical Regiment 2 H. J. PAUL, </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL July 9, 1925. Subject: Restriction on Armory Drills for National Guard for fiscal year 1926. The Adjutant General of Nebraska (Thru: C. Gen. 7th C. A.) 1. The Secretary of War directs me to inform you that no Federal payments will be made for the fiscal year 1926 for any armory drills in excess of 24 per unit in the first half year and 12 per unit in each of the third and fourth quarters, a total of 48 drills per unit during the fiscal year. The drills here authorized are inclusive of the "Annual Armory Inspection". 2. Detailed instructions, together with statement of amount of armory drill funds apportioned to your State for the fiscal year 1926, will be communicated to you at a later date. 3. Until revoked or otherwise changed, instructions contained in letter (M. B. 325. 44 — Gen. 13), dated April 14, 1925, will govern as to maximum strength allowed to the National Guard of your State during the fiscal year 1926. CREED C. HAMMOND, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 15, 1925. Circular Letter No. 25 Subject: Examination of candidates for West Point. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Adjutant General of the Army, dated August 20, 1925, addressed to the Governor of Nebraska, is </seg>
            <seg id="p057">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 57 published in part for the information and guidance of all concerned. Applications for this examination should reach this office not later than October 15, 1925, to enable us to prepare for the competitive examinations which will be held between November 1st and 15th, 1925, the exact date to be announced later. "The regulations for the selection of enlisted men of the National Guard for appointment to the United States Military Academy provide that the candidates shall be apportioned among the States, Territories, and the District of Columbia according to the enlisted strength of their respective National Guard organizations. Candidates from the States and Territories will be selected by the respective Governors thereof from successful competitors in a preliminary examination of a scope and nature similar to the regular examination for entrance to the Military Academy, to be instituted and conducted by the Governors, and to be held between November 1 and November 15 of each year. Under the statute authorizing these appointments, the Governors are restricted in their choice of candidates to enlisted men of the National Guard who conform to the requirements mentioned. "To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an ap - plicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal Government. He must, on the date of admission, July 1, 1926, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of nineteen and twenty-two years and must be not less than five feet four inches in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. Similarly, service with a National Guard organization prior to its recognition by the Federal Government may be considered, the date of enlistment of the soldier governing, and not that of the recognition of the unit. The requirements for admission to the Military Academy are fully set forth in the enclosed pamphlet, a supply of which is being sent to you under separate cover for distribution to those interested. "The candidates so selected will be authorized by the War Depart - ment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is scheduled to be held beginning on March 2, 1926, and the appoint - ments available on July 1, 1926, will be awarded to the qualified candidates in the order of merit established at that examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. You are, there - fore, requested to select, in accordance with the foregoing, one can - didate from among the enlisted men of the National Guard of your State, and to designate him for the entrance examination mentioned, using therefor the enclosed blank form. These cadetships being award - ed solely as a result of competition, alternates cannot be considered. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL There is no limitation to the number who gjay compete in the pre - liminary examination and it is suggested that this matter be widely advertised throughout the National Guard organizations of your State so that every enlisted man who is eligible as to age and length of service may be afforded this great opportunity." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 18, 1925. Circular Letter No. 26 Subject: Forms for Pay Rolls. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from Headquarters Seventh Corps Area, dated September 17, 1925, on above subject, is published for the in - formation and guidance of all concerned, and one mimeographed sheet to be used for the pay rolls for the quarter ending September 30, 1925, is enclosed herewith. "1. Under date of September 1, 1925, instructions were re - ceived from the Militia Bureau that due to the limitation of funds for pay of the National Guard, the item under the heading "Appropria - tions" on Form No. 367, W. D., March 9, 1922, should show ap - propriations divided up in four separate classifications: 1 for armory drill pay of officers, 1 for administrative pay of officers, 1 for pay of warrant officers, 1 for pay of enlisted men. Consequently it will be necessary for all pay roll forms now in use to be amended by pasting over, under heading of "appropriations" and just above the certificate of the instructor, a copy of the appropria - tion brief as inclosed herewith. There are enough sheets inclosed bo as to provide one copy of brief for each of the three rolls prepared by all organizations in your State for the quarter ending September </seg>
            <seg id="p059">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 59 30, 1925. It should be noted that the mimeographed sheets inclosed herewith should be cut Into four parts, each part being pasted on a separate roll. 2. It is requested that mimeographed forms, with the necessary instructions be forwarded to organization commanders. "For the Commanding General: "ABBOTT BOONE, Major, Field Artillery, Acting National Guard Officer." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 2, 1925. Circular Letter No. 27 Subject: Annual Inventory. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The annual inventory of federal property in the possession of organizations of the Nebraska National Guard will be made by in - structors on duty with the respective organizations during the month of December, 1925. 2. Organization commanders will be notified of the date of in - spection by the instructor designated to take the inventory. 3. All federal property will be arranged for an actual physical check. This includes all articles issued to individuals on Form No. 637, as well as articles of organization equipment. To this end, energetic co-operation and assistance of unit commanders are re - quired. All portable items of property will be arranged in piles on the armory floor to facilitate counting. This includes articles ordi - narily kept in wall lockers or barrack bags. Arms will be verified in arm racks, and bulky articles of organization equipment may be </seg>
            <seg id="p060">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 60 verified in stock rooms if items are separated and property grouped for verification. 4. The responsible officer, with Supply Sergeant and two assist - ants, will be prepared to assist the Instructor in the inventory. S. Attention is invited to Par. 6, S. O. No. 18, A. G. O. Nebraska, dated October 24, 1921, and to Par. 905, National Guard Regulations, 1922, to the fact that equipment will not be removed from the armory. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 9, 1925. Circular Letter No. 28 Subject: Shortage of Pyramidal Tent. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders and instructors on duty with the Nebraska National Guard. 1. Attention is invited to the following copy of letter from 1st Lt. Trev. Gillaspie, Hq. Co. 3rd Bn., 134th Infantry, Lincoln, Nebraska, which will be self-explanatory: "At the annual inventory of this organization on December 3, f!6, by Major T. F. McNeill, Inf. DOL-Instructor, it was found that i organization was short one pyramidal tent and it is the belief this officer that this tent has been misplaced and is in the supply room of some other organization. It is requested that during the annual armory inspection, the Instructors be advised to make a special effort to locate this pyramidal tent. Also wish to report that I have one large wall fly over." 2. It is requested that all Instructors endeavor to locate the pyramidal tent spoken of and that any unit or sub-unit commander finding himself over a pyramidal tent, immediately notify this office of same; also any unit or sub-unit commander being short a large wall tent fly, advise this office of that fact. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 61 BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 25, 1926. Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Form No. 4, N. N. G. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Form No. 4, N. N. G., Monthly Company Roster, Strength Return and Drill Program has been made unnecessary by Form No. 100, M. B., and its discontinuance as a strength return has been ordered by Par. 2, General Orders No. 1, A. G. O. Nebraska, dated January 1&gt; 1926. 2. Form No. 4 has been revised and modified to take the form of an Armory Training Schedule, and as modified will be submitted by all companies and similar units in accordance with instructions on the back of the form. 3. A sample of the revised Form No. 4 is attached hereto and a twelve months supply is being mailed under separate cover to all company commanders. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 26, 1926. Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Form No. 100, M. B. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. In lieu of instructions contained in Paragraph 13 on the back of Form 100, M. B., and for reasons set out below, all three copies of this new form will be sent direct to the Adjutant General's Office where distribution will be made. 2. Owing to the fact that this new form will effect pay, any error permitted to go by might cause a suspension against a unit commander and it is obvious that it is necessary to have these copies all checked for error by the personnel clerk in this office before distribution is made as it would entail considerable loss of time if it became necessary to recall a copy from the War Department even if it was possible so to do. 3. Unit commanders must exercise great care in submitting these reports as one little clerical error such as a misspelled name or error in grade or failure to show promotion or reduction will necessitate all three copies being returned to the unit commander which would have to be made all over again. 4. It is also necessary in case of gains to forward copy of en - listment papers to this office and in case of losses to close service records and forward them; the above papers to accompany Form No. 100, M. B. together with copies of company orders effecting changes. 5. In conjunction with forms abolished by Circular No. 53-A33, Militia Bureau, dated December 1, 1925, it will also be unnecessary to submit strength return (Form No. 73, W. D., A. G. O.) to the Regi - mental Commander as formerly required, however, it is believed that Form 367b should be kept as it will make it much easier for unit commanders in making up the quarterly payroll. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 63 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 23, 1926. Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Requisition for Equipment. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, N. N. G. 1. Requisition for all equipment required by your unit for its peace, enlisted strength based on the new Organization Tables — Na - tional Guard must be submitted by March 20, 1926. 2. Requisitions are now required to be submitted quarterly by this office. Requisitions submitted in second quarter would not arrive in time for annual encampment. 3. ALL REQUISITIONS FOR CLOTHING MUST STATE SIZES. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska, STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 29,1926. Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: The Beatrice Military Essay. To: All Officers, Nebraska Nation AH Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following conditions of "The Beatrice Military Essay," which is put on by the Gage County Reserve Officer's Association, is published for the information of all concerned. Unit and Sub-unit Commanders are directed to read these conditions to their respective organizations at the first Assembly after receipt of saame, and it is hoped by this office that an interest will be manifested by the Mem - bers of the National Guard, and that we may later receive information </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL that the prize of $100.00 has been received by some member of that organization. FULL CONDITIONS THE BEATRICE MILITARY ESSAY The Beatrice prize of $100.00 is awarded to the writer of the best essay upon a military subject, chosen each year by the doner. Subject for 1926: "Preparedness — The Guarantee of Peace." Conditions: The writer must be an officer or an enlisted man in tof the component parts of the Army of the United States of the Corps Area. (a) The regular Army. (b) The National Guard of the several states. (c) The Officers Reserve Corps. (d) The enlisted Reserve. (e) Men who have attended the C. M. T. C. (f) R. O. T. C. (g) Accredited Military Schools. I. Article shall contain about 2000 words. II. Article shall be of a practical constructive nature. HI. Article shall be typewritten or written legibly. IV. Article shall be in the hands of Lt. C. A. Anderson, President, Reserve Officers Association, Beatrice, Nebraska, by March 30, 1926. V. Manuscript is not to be signed with the name of the writer but with a pen name. VI. The manuscript shall be accompanied by a second envelope containing: (a) The pen name, (b) The name and address of the writer (c) His grade or rank and unit. This envelope shall be marked on the outside with pen name only. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 65 VII. In searching for the best essay, the judges will look for the intent of the writer, and will give credit for basic thoughts, rather than for grammatical correctness. Neat - ness, however, will be a factor. VIII. The Judges: Judges shall be appointed by the President of the Gage County Reserve Officers Association, Beatrice, Nebr. IX. No judges shall compete. JUDGES FOR 1926 Brigadier General, Edward L. King, Commandant, General Service schools, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas. Lt. Col. F. P. Amos, (Cavalry) Acting Chief of Staff, 89th Division Omaha, Nebraska. Captain Clyde B. Dempster, Ord-Res., Beatrice, Nebraska H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 1, 1926. Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Form No. 100, M. B. To: All Field and Staff Officers and all Unit and Sub-unit Com- manders. 1. Supplementing Circular Letter No. 2, January 26, 1926, this office on the above named subject: All Staff and Field Officers re - quired to make Form 100 M. B., will forward the three copies to this office through the officer in charge of making pay-roll, who in turn i </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL will make the necessary record entitling the respective officers to pay, and then immediately forward the three copies to this office. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 8, 1926. Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Excuses for failure to hold 48 drills during a calendar year. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Chief Militia Bureau, is pub - lished for the information of all concerned. "War Department Militia Bureau Washington January 27, 1926. Subject: Excuses for failure to hold 48 drills during a calendar year. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska (Through the Command- ing General, Seventh Corps Area.) 1. In paragraph 3c of letter of this Bureau to you, dated July 31, 1925, subject: "Limitation of Federal Aid, Strength and Re - striction on Armory Drills for Fiscal Year 1926," appeared the fol - lowing statement: "c No Federal payments will be made for the fiscal year 1926 for any armory drills in excess of 24 per unit in the first half year and 12 per unit in each of the 3rd and 4th quarters, a total of 48 drills per unit during the fiscal year, except that in the event of funds remaining available at the end of the third quarter, fiscal year, 1926. justifies such action, the Acting Secretary of War will authorize Fed - eral payment for additional drills within the limit of available funds, during the fourth quarter. The 48 drills authorized during the fiscal year are inclusive of the 'Annual Armory Inspection.' </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 67 In order to avoid any possibility of exceeding the funds avail - able for armory drill pay, the Acting Secretary of War will and does excuse, where necessary, any unit from attendance at any drill authorized in this paragraph." 2. Section 92, National Defense Act, provides: "Under such regulations as the Secretary of War shall prescribe, each company, troop, battery, and detachment in the National Guard shall assemble for drill and instruction, including indoor traget prac - tice, not less than forty-eight times each year, * • » • unless such company, troop, battery, or detachment shall have been excused from participation in any part thereof by the Secretary of War." 3. When a company, troop, battery or detachment, has failed to hold 48 drills during a calendar year, the General Accounting Office will not allow payments of armory drill pay for the final quarter of the year unless it appears that the Secretary of War has excused the failure to hold such part of the prescribed 48 drills as was not actually held. 4. To avoid the possibility of suspensions by the General Ac - counting Office when an organization has failed to hold the prescribed 48 drills during the calendar year 1925, the following action will be taken: a. The State Adjutant General concerned will forward through channels to the Chief, Militia Bureau, a request to be excused for the failure to hold such part of the prescribed 48 drills as was not actually held. This request should show the reason for the failure and the number of drills held during each calendar month of the year. b. If an excuse is granted by authority of the Secretary of War, a certified copy thereof will be attached to the pay roll for the quarter October 1 to December 31, 1925; or, if the pay roll has been filed with the Finance Officer, U. S. Army, authorized to pay it, the certified copy will be forwarded to him to be attached to the pay roll. 5. This Bureau cannot now state what the situation will be dur - ing the period July to December, 1926, as to availability of funds for armory drill pay, but it may be that the amount available will be sufficient to authorize only 24 drills. If this is so, each organization must have held the full 12 drills authorized for pay during each of the first two quarters for the calendar year 1926, if 48 drills are to be held during that year. Accordingly, each organization should hole! the 12 drills authorized for pay during each of the first two quarters of the calendar year 1926. Failure of an organization to hold 48 drills </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL during the calendar year 1926 will be excused only for lack of funds or other good and sufficient reason. Colonel, Infantry, M. B., Executive, For and in the absence of the Chief, Militia Bureau." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 10, 1926. Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: M. B. Form No. 21-24, Combination Enlistment Record and Service Record. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, N. N. G. 1. We are sending under separate cover a supply of the new M. B. Form No. 21-24, being Combination Enlistment Record and Service trd. You are directed to destroy all blank enlistment records i M. B. No. 21, all blank service records, A. G. O. Form No. 29, all extracts of service records, A. G. O. Form No. 29a. 2. In making out enlistment papers, attention is invited to the fact that the full name must be given and that this name must be the same throughout the record. The middle initial is permissable in giving the full name. Any abbreviation used will make it necessary to return the enlistment paper which will have to be made all over again, i. e., Jos. for Joseph, Chas. for Charles and Jas. for James is not permissible and will not be accepted. Care must be taken that both copies will be signed by the Recruiting Officer and the applicant. 3. Reference Par. 6, The Enlistment Record, sub-par, f (5) of instructions, you are advised that on discharge of a soldier, his original enlistment record will be filed in the inactive records of the company E. J. WILLIAMS, </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 69 from which discharged and only the closed service record will be forwarded to this office to be filed with the duplicate enlistment record sent to this office at the time of the enlistment of the soldier. 4. This new form is only made applicable to new enlistments and re-enlistments made after date of receipt thereof. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 17, 1926. Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Appointment of non-commissioned officers and continuing warrants therefor. To: All Unit Commanders. 1. There being some little confusion as to the appointment of non - commissioned officers and especially to continuing warrants therefor in case of re-enlistment, attention is invited to Par. 303, N. G. R., 1922, and to A. R. 615-5 for line troops, and to A. R. 615-15 for troops of Medical Corps. BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. *~ </seg>
            <seg id="p070">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 70 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 17, 1926. Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Pyramidal Tent. To: All Unit Comma All Unit Commanders 1. Upon checking property in the covered that there is one pyramidal Lincoln Armory it has been dis - tent over. Any Unit or Sub-unit Commander being short a pyramidal tent will immediately notify this office. 1. Owing to the fact that funds available for Schools of Instruc - tion prior to July 1, 192G, are very limited and that it is our desire to hold our school prior to July 1st, the following information is re - quested by endorsement hereon by return mail. (a) Will it be possible for you to attend a School of Instruction, to be held at Ashland, Nebraska, June 13 to 17 inclusive (b) In case you will be able to attend as above outlined, are you willing to come to Ashland, June 13th without pay? This will give BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN • February 19, 1926 Circular Letter No. 10 , Subject: School of Instruction. Co: All Officers, N. N. G. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 71 June 14, 15 and 16, and until noon of June 17 for nearly all officers as actual school time, and those officers who will be able to reach their homes in the afternoon of the 17th, will be excused, but officers who are not able to reach their homes by remaining until noon, may be excused the evening of the 16th, or the morning of the 17th. Our allotment of funds will not permit more than four days' pay for officers attending this school, and it may be necessary to eliminate all field and staff officers and confine the school to the first and second in command of all units. (c) Unless you have indicated by endorsement hereon, that yon will be able to attend this school under the conditions above set out, by March 1st, you will not be included in our estimate, and it will therefore be impossible to add your name at a later date. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 24, 1926. Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Efficiency Reports To: All Reporting Offi All Reporting Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. There are enclosed herewith blank efficiency reports to be made out for the year ending December 31, 1925, and which should have your immediate attention. 2. Before attempting to make this report, you are directed to make a thorough study of the instructions contained thereon, which are full and explicit and, if followed explicitly, will bring the proper report to this office before the expiration of the month. 3. Owing to the fact that some officers did not make a study of the instructions on these efficiency reports, some of the reports made last year should have been sent back as a discredit to the reporting officer. Some officers procrastinated in making out these reports to the extent that they did not arrive in this office until late, thereby causing all reports to be held until they could be forwarded together, which made a very poor showing for the State of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4. After having given a thorough study to the instructions on both sides of the efficiency reports, make out your reports and for - ward same without further delay to the officer to whom the instruc- K direct you. This is a small matter if given your immediate tion. Let us all get them in in proper form and AT ONCE. 5. Owing to the fact that the&gt; efficiency reports for the 134th Infantry are practically all in, this letter is only applicable to the 110th Medical Regiment and the 35th Division Train. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 4, 1926. Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Enrollment of National Guard Proteges in C. M. T. Camps. To: All Unit Commanders Nebraska National Guard. All Unit Commanders Nebraska National Guard. 1. At the home stations of every company unit of the National Guard there are a certain number of young men over 17 years of age, not now members of the National Guard, whose character, education, physique and standing in the community, render them especially desirable for enlistment at the proper time in the local National Guard unit. Many of them are known to the local National Guard com - mander or to his officers. Normally only a very small number of these especially eligible and desirable young men are likely to affiliate with the National Guard. If, however, their minds are directed along military lines during this formative period of their lives, it is prob - able that a much larger percentage eventually will become National Guardsmen. And those who for business or other good reasons do not enter the Guard, are likely to have greater sympathy and interest therefor and a better understanding of, and consequently a more friendly attitude toward the National Defense. Probably the most convenient, economical and quickest way to bring these young men into contact with things military is to induce them to enroll for the Basic Course in a 1926 C. M. T. Camp where they would receive one </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 73 month's military training and instruction in citizenship under almost ideal conditions and without expense to themselves. 2. It is the desire of this office to have the unit commanders make an earnest effort in interesting the class of young men above enumerated in the C. M. T. Camps for this year, and to notify us not later than March 15, how many, if any, basic courses C. M. T. C. 1926, vacancies he desires reserved for his unit, it being understood that each unit commander will use his utmost endeavor to secure that number of applicants from the eligible young men of his community. 3. Upon receipt of the number of vacancies desired as set out in Par. 2, this office will inform Headquarters, Seventh Corps Area of the total number of such vacancies desired, and the C. M. T. C. Officer, Seventh Corps Area will make reservations as requested, which will stand until June 1, 1926, and will transmit to the Adjutant General for distribution to unit commanders, the number of application blanks for requested vacancies, and other necessary data. 4. All applications secured by unit commanders will be marked on the bottom "National Guard Protege" will be forwarded to the C. M. T. C. Officer, Headquarters, Seventh Corps Area, Omaha, Nebraska, through the Adjutant General, in time to reach the above named Headquarters by June 1, 1926. 5. It is understood that all National Guard Proteges will be carried as such during the C. M. T. Camps, and at their conclusion the National Guard Commanders concerned to be informed, through the Adjutant General, as to how each of the Proteges has met the conditions of the camp and his rating upon discharge therefrom. 6. It is further understood that National Guard Proteges will not be encouraged during C. M. T. Camp to return thereto during subsequent years, except at the request of the National Guard au - thorities of the States concerned. Instead these proteges are to be encouraged in every proper way to enlist in the National Guard. 7. This scheme has been worked out by Headquarters, Seventh Corps Area and is suggested by them solely for the benefit of the National Guard and it is a desire of this office that every effort be made by the respective unit commanders to make this a decided success this year in order that we may determine definitely and for all time whether or not the National Guard will receive a real benefit from such a policy. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 74 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March S, 1926. Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Notification of Inspection and Repair of Ordnance Material. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from Headquarters Seventh Corps Area is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "HQ. SEVENTH CORPS AREA Office of the Corps Area Commander Omaha, Nebraska Mar. 3, 1926. 7CA0 No. 333.4-Nebr. N. G. "1. You are advised that Technical Sergeant Godtfred Larsen, Ordnance Department, these headquarters, will visit the following organizations of the National Guard, State of Nebraska, on the dates indicated for the purpose of inspecting all items of ordnance material on hand, and of making as many repairs as possible during his visit. For the purpose of making repairs, Technical Sergeant Larsen will carry with him certain tools which are necessary in the repair of small arms and their pertaining equipment. He will also take with him a small amount of spare parts, especially for rifles and pistols. ORGANIZATION STATION Date Co. L. 134th Inf Omaha Mar. 8-9, 1926 Hq. Co., 134th Inf Omaha Mar. 10, 1926 Co. K, 134th Inf Omaha Mar. 11-12, 1926 Co. F, 134th Inf Hartington Mar. 13-14, 1926 Hq. Co. 1st Bn., 134th Inf Nebraska City ....Mar. 15, 1926 Co. A, 134th Inf Nebraska City ....Mar. 16-17, 1926 Co. B, 134th Inf Falls City Mar. 18-19, 1926 Co. C, 134th Inf Beatrice Mar. 20-21, 1926 Hq. Co. 3rd Bn. 134th Inf -Lincoln Mar. 22, 1926 Co. I, 134th Inf Lincoln Mar. 23-24, 1926 Train Hq., 35th Div Lincoln Mar. 25, 1926 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 75 Co. M, 134th Inf., Seward Mar. 26-27, 1926 Serv. Co., 194th Inf York Mar. 28-29, 1926 Co. G. 134th Inf Hastings Mar. 30-31, 1926 Motor Transport Co. No. 137 and Motor Repair Section No. 119-Holdrege Apr. 1, 1926 Co. H, 134th Inf Grand Island Apr. 2-3, 1926 Wagon Co. No. 120 Kearney Apr. 4, 1926 Wagon Co. No. 119 Lexington Apr. 5, 1926 Co. D, 134th Inf North Platte Apr. 6-7, 1926 Hq. Co., 2nd Bn., 134th Inf Gering Apr. 8, 1926 Co. E, 134th Inf Scottsbluff Apr. 9-10, 1926 How. Co., 134th Inf Mitchell Apr. 11-12, 1926 Motor Transport Co. No. 138 Fremont Apr. 13, 1926 2. In order to expedite the inspection and repair of all items of ordnance material in the above mentioned organizations, the follow- ing is requested: That the commanding officer of each unit be present, if possible. for at least a portion of the time during the period of inspection and repair. If it be impossible for the commanding officer to be present, then it is suggested that one of the remaining officers of the unit be present. b. That the supply sergeants and organization mechanics, or those performing similar duties, be present in order to receive from Technical Sergeant Larsen instructions in regard to the repair of small arms and, at the same time, assist him. c. That all spare parts for rifles, pistols, machine guns etc., be carefully collected and sorted in the storeroom of the organization in order that Technical Sergeant Larsen may know, upon arrival, the amounts of spare parts on hand. In this connection, wherever or- ganizations have a small arms repair chest, M1910, such chest should be available as it contains a number of spare parts which may be of great use in making the necessary repairs. d. That all rifles, automatic rifles, automatic pistols, revolvers, holsters for automatic pistols and revolvers, field glasses, and other items of ordnance equipment that may be in the hands of members of the organizations, be returned to the storeroom of the organization for the period of inspection and repair. In this connection, it is highly desirable that Technical Sergeant Larsen sees every item of ordnance equipment for which the organization is responsible. e. In view of the fact that it is particularly desired to go over all rifles and pistols in each units, regardless of their condition in </seg>
            <seg id="p076">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 76 order to properly gage them, it is desired that if any rifles, pistols or machine guns be in cosmoline, they be cleaned and made ready for inspection. f. It is also desirable to have Technical Sergeant Larsen check over the condition not only of the items of ordnance equipment re - cently covered by inventory as made by instructors, but also to check over the condition of all accessories and spare parts pertaining to the major items. In this connection, it is desired that the loan and record cards of each organization be balanced up to date and made available for reference during the period of inspection. It will be entirely agreeable to these headquarters to have any other personnel present you may desire, but such a procedure is not necessary for the purpose of the inspection. 3. This schedule has been prepared for the dates indicated there - on but it is quite possible that due to experience gained from day to day, as regards the length of time required to finish an organization, it may be changed by such unforseen conditions. If the schedule as indicated be not satisfactory to all concerned, it is requested that you inform these headquarters, as soon as practicable, to that effect. For the Commanding General: (Signed) John W. Crissy, Captain, Infantry, D. O. !■., Acting National Guard Officer." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 9, 1926. Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Limitation of Federal Aid, Strength and Restriction on Armory Drills for fiscal year 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 77 All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. To: 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau is published for the information and Guidance of all concerned: 'WAR DEPARTMENT MILITIA BUREAU Washington February 27, 1926. MB-240.91-Nebraska-9 "1. Paragraph 3c of letter dated July 31, 1925, on the above subject, limiting the number of armory drills to be held during each quarter of the fiscal year 1926, is by authority of the Secretary of War, modified as follows: 'Organizations of the National Guard that have held less than 24 drills during the first half of the fiscal year 1926, may, in addition to the 12 drills authorized in the third quarter, hold such extra drills as will bring the total of drills held during the first three quarters to 36; and in like manner, organizations that will have held less than 36 drills during the first three quarters of the fiscal year, may, in addition to the 12 drills authorized in the fourth quarter, hold such extra drills as will bring the total number of drills held during the current fiscal year to 48; provided, that in no event will any organization exceed 48 drills during the fiscal year 1926, or exceed the maximum of eight drills per month authorized by law." 2. Organizations that, pursuant to the above, hold more than twelve (12) drills in the third and fourth quarters, should show on the pay rolls for these quarters the number of drills held in preceding quarters so that it may be determined whether or not the maximum number of thirty-six (36) drills to the end of the third quarter, and forty-eight (48) drills to the end of the fourth quarter, have been exceeded. 3. In this connection, attention is invited to paragraph 5 of letter dated January 27, 1926, on the subject: "Excuses for failure to hold forty-eight (48) drills during a calendar year," and it is urged that each organization hold the full number of drills authorized herein so that the necessity for requests to be excused for failure to hold forty-eight (48) drills during the calendar year 1926 will be re - duced to a minimum. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4. You are advised that it has not yet been determined whether or not the available funds justify authorization for additional drills in excess of the maximum of forty-eight (48) now authorized for the fiscal year 1926. C. C. Hammond, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." BY DIRECTION OP THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 11, 1926. Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Uniforms. To: All Office All Officers, Nebraska National Guard 1. Owing to the fact that a recent change has been made in the uniform, and that a number of officers may desire to get new uniforms, it is deemed advisable to invite your attention to the fact that the pink and light breeches and the olive green blouses are not prescribed in Regulations as being any part of the American uniform, and it is the desire of this offfice that every officer in the Nebraska National Guard possess at least one serge uniform, in order that on occasions of ceremony, we may present a really uniform body. 2. It is realized that the pink breeches and olive green coats tworn by many of the field and staff officers; that they look very and tidy, but at the same time they are not uniform and are too picuous when on duty with troops or an assembly of officers. 3. This office has samples of cloth from the General Sales Store t Philadelphia, and if any of the officers desire to purchase cloth work over the collar of their old blouses and make it conform to new regulations, samples will be sent to make these selections m. However, they are not much cheaper than some of the Uni - form Houses, and little can be saved in this way. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 79 4. Some of the officers of Lincoln are having their blouses made to conform to the new regulations by a Lincoln tailor for which they are paying seven dollars and furnishing the cloth. This change is for the collar only, and an additional charge would be made for changing the pockets. This is not given you with any desire to solicit business for a Lincoln tailor, but simply to give you an idea of what it should cost you to have your collar changed. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Circular Letter No. 16 April 2, 1926. Subject: Leases and Allowances for Target Ranges. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders. All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders. 1. The following Circular Letter No. 5, M. B. W. D., reproduced for the information and guidance of all concerned. 2. For any Unit and sub-unit commanders who desire to take advantage of this opportunity of securing a target range for their local organization, it will be necessary to make a very careful study of this letter as the instructions therein contained must be followed explicitly. "WAR DEPARTMENT Militia Bureau CIRCULAR NO. 5 (Cir. No. 5 B) B Washington, D. C. February 12, 1926. LEASES AND ALLOWANCES FOR TARGET RANGES 1. The Secretary of War directs the announcement of a policy governing National Guard target range leases, construction, and all allowances therefor, as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p080">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 80 2. a, Leases for National Guard target ranges at home stations will not be authorized for a period of less than three years, and they will not be subject to termination at the option of the lessor except with the consent of the lessee. b. Exceptions to the foregoing provision may be authorized by the Chief, Militia Bureau, at those localities where no other suitable site is procurable than land held for sale and procurable only with the reservation of the lessor that the lease shall terminate at the option of the lessor in the event of a bona fide sale. In such cases the term of the lease should be for not less than three years, with the provision that, after the expiration of one year, the lessor may, after thirty days notice, and only in the event of a bona fide sale, terminate the lease. c. The Militia Bureau will approve leases and authorize in the name of the Secretary of War the expenditure of funds for the rental, construction and maintenance of target ranges, including 600 yards ranges, as prescribed below; the leases to run for not less than three years and not to exceed the costs authorized herein. Not to exceed 70% of the above amounts may be expended during the first year of the lease for rental and construction. The lease to cost approximately not in excess of $200 annually. The above figures indicate the maximum, rather than the average payable. d. It is the policy of the War Department to encourage the establishment of simple and economical ranges adjacent to the home Eons of all National Guard troops. For troops armed with the a range of 200 yards is acceptable where one of 300 yards can - be obtained at a reasonable cost. Due to the limited time avail for home training, the various subjects to be covered and tho e of basic training in marksmanship at the shorter ranges the War Department no longer favors the establishment of ranges in excess of 300 yards at one or two company stations: e. Machine gun and howitzer (37-mm) units are authorized a 20% increase over the amounts in c above for standard ranges, where a larger area is required (see F below). Machine gun units are au - thorized one (1) sliding 1000 inch target per company. Number of units Total amount armed with authorized for Number of double Approximate minimum widt: rifle. 3 years. (1 $1000.00 (2 1100.00 lowance (3 1500.00 (4 — 5 1200.00 targets. 2 4 5 6 in feet. 40 60 80 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 81 f. For machine gun 1000 inch ranges where standard ranges are not available or required, and for all pistol ranges, leases will be executed as provided in a and c above, and the allowances for rentals and construction will not exceed 50% of the amounts authorized in c above. g. Upon the expiration of the three year leases, they may be renewed and an amount not to exceed 30% of the three-year totals provided in b, c, and d above will be authorized for rental and repairs for each subsequent year of the lease thereafter. h. Leases will be authorized for periods preferably in excess of three years, and an allowance of not to exceed 30% of the three-year totals provided in b and c above will be authorized for each subsequent year therafter for rental and repairs. It is desired that leases be made for the longest time possible, under the most favorable terms, and with option for extension and purchase if possible. i. (1) All projects having more units and calling for a greater number of targets than listed in c above, desired for installation on land leased for three or more years will be submitted separately. (2) All projects and plans for the development of target ranges on land owned or controlled through long leases, by the Fed - eral Government, the States or organizations, will be submitted separately, and their individual needs considered with a due regard for the number of troops to be served and the cost and permanency thereof. 3. All projects and their estimates with a total annual cost of not exceeding $500.00, including rentals, may be submitted to the Militia Bureau at the convenience of the States. 4. All projects and estimates which include construction costs in excess of 1500.00, will be submitted to the Militia Bureau at such time as will permit them to be returned to the States for additional information if desired, before being submitted each year for the action of the Secretary of War, on July 10 and December 15th. 5. States should include in all estimates a brief history of the range: Stating the area, whether Federal or State-owned, or leased; for how long, length of option for renewal, if any, amount previously expended by Government or State for acquisition, and cost of all improvements; number of troops to be accomodated, and all informa - tion that will assist in the consideration of the projects. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 6. In the larger centers of population, where suitable target range sites within reasonable distances are unavailable or prohibitive in cost, and where sufficent units of the National Guard are stationed to justify the cost, the Militia Bureau will consider applications for lease of suitable sites at greater distances, where week-end camps may be held for target range instruction. Estimates for facilities for not to exceed one company at a time, and one wooden building for office, officers' mess and bath house may be included in applications for lease. 7. Leases will be executed in quadruplicate, on M. B. Form No. 17 (Authorized January 29, 1920,) and approved by the Governor with his own signature. The leases will be submitted with the de - tailed estimates, accompanied by a map or ink sketch in triplicate showing location of range with reference to troops or towns using it. 8. Instructors, preferably during visits of instruction, will investi - gate proposed ranges and make a report to corps area commanders, same to be forwarded to the Chief, Militia Bureau, on the following: (a) Necessity for range at the particular place. (b) Convenience of location for the troops who will use it. (c) Number and designation of units — and troops — to be accomodated. (d) Comparison of rental asked with rentals in same locality. (e) Purchase price asked by owner, probable purchase price in case of condemnation, and advisability of purchase. (f) Suitability of land for use as a target range. (g) Approximate estimate of cost of preparing range for use. (h) Liability of injunctions against the use of the range. (i ) Any other pertinent information. 9. The target ranges at training camps should be provided for in the estimates for preparation of camp sites for field training when - ever they are used exclusively for that purpose, as the provisions and allowances herein are intended primarily to provide ranges for troops at or near their home stations when practicable and funds are avail - able. 10. The above allowances are not intended to prohibit the States in anyway from adding additional facilities or expending greater sums, providing they are met from funds other than Federal. The amount of funds herein are all that can be allowed under existing appropria - tions. The use of concrete and other expensive construction, and the construction of mess-halls and other facilities on short term leased ranges is not approved by the War Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 83 11. All estimates and requests will be submitted in itemized detail through the Corps Area Commander for his recommendation. 12. Circular No. 3-B, Militia Bureau, February 28, 1924, is hereby rescinded. (M. B. 684-1 Gen.-IT.J BY ORDER OF THE SECRETARY OF WAR: CREED C. HAMMOND Major General Chief, Militia Bureau. Assistant." OFFICIAL: IRA A. CARROLL, Captain, Cavalry, M. B. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 2, 1926. Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Limitation of Federal Aid, Strength and Restriction on Armory Drills for Fiscal Year 1926. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders. 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau is publish - ed for the information and guidance of all concerned. "MB — 240.91 Nebraska — 9 Militia Bureau Washington April 10, 1926. Subject: Limitation of Federal Aid, Strength and Restriction on Armory Drills for Fiscal Year 1926. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska, (Through the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area) </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Paragraph 8c of letter dated July 31, 1925, on the above sub - ject, limiting the number of armory drills to be held during each quarter of the Fiscal Tear 1926, as modified by letter dated February 27, 1926, is, by authority of the Secretary of War, further modified aa follows: Organizations are authorized to hold 13 drills in the fourth quarter, and in addition to the 13 drills herein authorized they may hold such extra drills as will bring the total number of drills held during the Fiscal Year 1926, to 49; provided, that in no event will any organ - isation exceed 49 drills during the Fiscal Tear 1926, or exceed the maximum of 8 drills per month authorized by law. JOHN W. GULICK, Colonel, C. A. C, Executive For and in the Absence of The Chief, Militia Bureau." H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 19, 1926. Circular Letter No. 18 rect: Mothers Day. All Unit and All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders. 1. The Second Sunday in May having been dedicated to the Mothers of our country, as the day on which we should express the love and reverence which we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of the members of your organization, who may be separ - ated from their mothers on May 9th, the duty which they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mothers' Day. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 85 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 3, 1926. Circular Letter No. 19 Subject: Incorrect or incomplete Form 100 M. B. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders. All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders. 1. The Chief, Militia Bureau has just called to our attention that in making out Form 100 M. B., it is necessary to show the Divis - ion and the Brigade, therefore all officers of the 134th Infantry, re - quired to make Form 100 M. B., in the future will show both, i. e., 35th Division, 69th Brigade; officers of the 110th Medical Regiment and 35th Division Trains will simply show 35th Division. 2. We are also informed that a separate report must be rendered for Battalion Headquarters, so Battalion Commanders will govern themselves accordingly. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 11, 1926. Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Fishing License. To: All Officers, Net All Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. During the last annual encampment a check was made of members of National Guard found fishing and it was discovered that many of the enlisted men and some of the officers were of the opinion that it was not necessary to have a fishing license to fish on the Gov - ernment Rifle Range. This is an error as the law makes no exceptions and it is therefore necessary for all persons desiring to fish during </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL the School of Instruction or Annual Encampment to have in their possession a fishing license. Therefore all Unit and Sub-Unit com - manders are directed to bring this to the attention of the members of their respective commands and to see that they procure licenses before doing any fishing at the Rifle Range in the future. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 14, 1926. Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Armory Rentals. To: All Unit and Su : All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders. 1. Armory rentals have been mounting over the State to such an extent that it now becomes necessary to caution all Company Com - manders of the necessity of having these rentals reduced on the ex - piration of the present lease. Armory rentals should be figured not to exceed one dollar per enlisted man per month and in most instances rentals should be obtained cheaper than this, and these rentals should also include water, heat and light. 2. Armory rentals have increased to such an alarming extent that there are very few funds left for improvement purposes and all who are conversant with the situation at our permanent camp know there are many improvements to be made yet and that in order to get the Federal government to do its share, the State must make reasonable expenditures showing good faith on its part. 3. Unless Armory rentals are reduced by the Company Com - mander as outlined in the first paragraph of this letter, it will be necessary for this office to arbitrarily whack them down, and it is thought that it is much better for the Company Commander to do this. 4. Company Commanders in their zeal and desire to see their home town improve and get as much money from outside sources as possible, must not forget that they are members of the National Guard </seg>
            <seg id="p087">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 87 and as such are one of a big family that can only exist by our working together and pulling together, and as money is an absolute essential in keeping up our organization, they must help this office to save as much on rentals as possible. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 22, 1926. Circular Letter No. 22 Subject: Arrest of William C. Cassidy. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders and all Field Officers, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Pvt. 1st Class William C. Cassidy, Company "I" 134th Infantry, NNG.. is charged with criminal assault on a six year old child. He was last seen in Lincoln on May 26 in the evening. Cassidy is 22 years old, weight 125 pounds, height 5 feet and 2 inches. He has an American flag tatooed on his left forearm. He is accustomed to wear his sleeves rolled up and is fond of swimming. It is directed that this letter be read at the next meeting of your organization. It is also directed that any member of the Nebraska National Guard who should happen to meet Private Cassidy, immediately place him under arrest, hold him in the city jail and notify this office and the Chief of Police of Lincoln who holds a warrant for this man and will immediately come after him. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 88 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 7, 1926. Circular Letter No. 23 Subject: Limitation on Number of Armory Drills, during the fiscal year 1927. All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. To: 1. The following letter from the Chief, Militia Bureau is pub - lished for information and guidance of all concerned: "WAR DEPARTMENT OFFICE OF THE CHIEF OF THE MILITIA BUREAU Washington May 28, 1926. MB-240.91 Neb.-lO Subject: Limitation on Number of Armory Drills, during Fiscal Year 1927. To: The Adjutant General of Nebraska, Through the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area. 1. The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of drills for the first half of the F. Y. 1927 will be limited to twenty-four (24); and that you will be authorized to hold twelve (12) drills in the 3rd Quarters, F. Y. 1927, and in addition to the twelve (12) drills authorized in the 3rd Quarter, you are authorized to hold such extra drills as will bring the total number of drills held during the first three quarters to thirty-six (36). 2. The number of drills to be authorized for the 4th Quarter F. Y. 1927, will be determined at a later date. C. C. Hammond, Major General, Chief, Militia Bureau." H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 89 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 10, 1926. Circular Letter No. 24 Subject: Armory Inspection. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. It is with considerable gratification and pleasure that the following letter from the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area is published for the information of all concerned, and I wish to com - mend all Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, who obtained a rating of "Satisfactory" or better, for the cooperation given this office and for their individual efforts in bringing up the reports in a way that would cause this letter to be written. "HEADQUARTERS SEVENTH CORPS AREA Office of the Corps Area Commander Omaha, Nebraska. May 24, 1926. Subject: Improvement in the Nebraska National Guard. To: The Adjutant Gerenal of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. The Annual Armory Inspection Reports, 1926, of National Guard units in the State of Nebraska show that there is only one unit in the entire State which did not attain a rating of at least "Satisfactory". In 1925 there were three "Unsatisfactory" units. The decrease in number of "Unsatisfactory" units from three to one in one year 1b evidence of the increasing efficiency of the Nebraska National Guard. It is therefore desired to commend the State authorities and the Na - tional Guard personnel concerned for the considerable improvement made. B. A. POORE, Major General, Commanding." H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska, </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 24, 1926. Circular Letter No. 25 Subject: Return of Strength as of June 30, 1926 To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. In accordance with existing regulations, State authorities are required to submit to the Chief, Militia Bureau, a telegraphic return of strength as of midnight, June 30th of each year. Attention of all unit and sub-unit commanders is again invited to the necessity of their reporting direct to this office by telegraph the strength of their organizations, giving officers and enlisted men separately in the fol - lowing form, i. e., "Company A three officers fifty-six enlisted men. (Signed) Jones, Captain.' 2. From this form it will easily be seen that it is not necessary to write a letter by telegraph in sending in this strength report. This telegram should be forwarded so as to arrive at this office not later than 3:00 P. M., June 30th, in order that we may have time to con - solidate the reports and forward to the Militia Bureau the same evening. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 1, 1926. Circular Letter No. 26 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1926. To: All Unit Commanders and all Field and Staff Officers, N. N. G. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 91 1. The dates of the annual encampment, 1926, having been set, i. e., August 2 to 16, 1926, inclusive, no organization will be excused from attending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Pars. 110 and 932, as amended by Changes No. 3, 4, 19 and 22, National Guard Regulations, 1922, respectively, and tables of organ - ization for National Guard effective January 1, 1926. At this point you are cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted paragraphs and changes, as non compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of pay of company officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the United States Property and Disbursing Officer as to the exact hour of departure from home station, rations, handling of baggage, train schedules, transportation requests, bills of lading, making of vouchers, etc. 3. Company commanders are authorized to purchase one day's travel ration for enlisted men at one dollar and twenty cents per ration, and will follow instructions received from the U. S. P. &amp; D. O. pertaining thereto. 4. Travel discipline. The senior line officer will assume com - mand of the train and see that travel discipline is maintained; i. e., no men on top of cars or on platform, men not permitted to get off trains at stations without orders, and men's personal appearance and conduct must be correct. All officers will familiarize themselves with Chapter IX, Movement by Rail, Field Service Regulations, 1923. The commanding officer will make a thorough inspection of the train be - fore troops 'entrain at home station, and after they detrain at camp. 5. Travel uniform. Enlisted men will wear wuolen O. D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewn on, issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Com - pany commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp this year as they will not be permitted to wear them on leaves or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. 6. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Train - ing Regulations 50-80 and 50-90. Extra blankets, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack, cots and mosquito nets will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. Company Commanders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear: socks, towels, tooth brush, paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing, i. e., cotton blouse, breeches and O. D. shirt. 7. Additional equipment. Organizations should carry as excess baggage (freight) organization equipment consisting of axes, water </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL bags, 6. I. cans, colors, field desk, lanterns, marking outfits, rakes, ranges, typewriters, shovels, tools, and all cleaning materials; suffici - ent pyramidal tents to provide for six men to a tent, and two additional (one for orderly and one for supply tent), and all other tentage except latrine screens. Information pertaining to saddles, saddle equip - ment and harness will be furnished in a separate circular letter. No tent stakes and target material will be brought to camp as they will be furnished there. 8. Ordnance... All ammunition, all empty cartridges (brass) in packing boxes, Belgian aiming device, all extra rifles and pistols that need repairing, that ordnance with which the individual and company are equipped, and fire control instruments, will be brought to camp. Ammunition carts and machine gun carts will not be brought to camp as same will be furnished there for demonstration purposes. The commanding officer of Howitzer Company, 134th Infantry, will bring only such necessary gun carriers, cart, etc., as will enable him to fire on the field. 9. Special equipment. All signal, medical and engineer property is to be carried; also the glass tubes of calcium hypochlorite and lister bags. The company officers of 134th Infantry, 110th Medical Regi - ment and 35th Division Train will bring their guard tents to camp, there having been three guard tents issued to 134th Infantry, one to 110th Medical Regiment and one to 35th Division Train for this purpose. 10. Tou are advised that all equipment referred to in this letter is based upon Equipment Tables, National Guard, with which all con - cerned have been furnished copies. 11. Records. All records and office supplies will be taken; i. e., Property Records, Individual Records, stationery, Service Records, Morning Reports, all text books, all blank forms on hand, and Score Books. A list in duplicate of all officers and men attending camp will be turned in immediately upon arrival in camp. A list in dupli - cate of all officers and men absent from camp, with a statement as to tof such absence, will be turned in immediately upon arrival in Telegraphic reports of strength when in training are not re - this year. 12. Messes. All company officers will mess with their organiza - tion and should provide themselves with tables and chairs. Every ef - fort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and Mess Sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organization. The Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Commanding Officer, 110th Medical </seg>
            <seg id="p093">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 93 Regiment, together with the Commanding Officer, 35th Division Train, Q. M. C, wiil establish officers' messes for the field and staff officers of their own organizations and such officers of the State Staff Corps and Departments, and instructors, as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 2, 1926. BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 9, 1926. Circular Letter No. 27 Subject: Welfare Work. To: All Unit and Si All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG 1. The following letter from the Chaplains, 134th Infantry and 110th Medical Regiment is published for the information and guidance of all concerned, and it is requested that all aid be given to these Chaplains in their work. "It is desired to make the work of the Chaplains in the annual encampment as helpful to all ranks as possible. For this purpose all officers are requested to cooperate with the Chaplains to the fullest possible extent and to inform their organizations of the provisions made. Chaplain Harold C. Capsey of the 134th Infantry and Chaplain Jack Leonard of the 110th Medical Regiment will be in camp available for any service in their line of duty and for consultation. Religious services will be conducted, entertainments planned, writing tables with stationery provided and the Recreation Hut open at all times. The Chaplain's Office may be used by visitors as their headquarters and information center. Officers commanding organizations are requested immediately on arrival in camp to furnish to the Chaplain's office, through the Camp </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Adjutant, one copy of roster of all men in camp for use in the informa - tion and post offices. Attention is called to the necessity for instruction in the form of addressing mail coming to camp. This form should be called to the attention of relatives and friends by all ranks. Rank and Organization must be given, as Private Paul Jones Company "B", 134th Infantry National Guard Camp Ashland, Nebraska. All ranks are urged to feel at liberty to call on the Chaplains for any service they can render or for personal consultation. HAROLD C. CAPSEY, Capt., Chaplain, NNG." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 19, 1926. Circular Letter No. 28 Subject: State Primaries. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. Owing to the fact that the Nebraska National Guard will be in camp at Ashland, Nebraska, this year during the State Primaries, August 10, 1926, and that all good citizens should exercise their right to vote, unit and sub-unit commanders are directed to inform their men that by making application to the county clerk, city clerk or elec - tion clerk as the case may be, they will be permitted to cast their ballot before leaving for camp or by mail. Detailed information and instruc - tions will be given the voter by the respective clerks and the men </seg>
            <seg id="p095">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 9 5 should be urged to exercise their right of franchise and cast their ballot before leaving for camp. S. S. C. &amp; D. — 1 Col. AGD., 1 Capt. AGD., 1 Major, QMC, 1 Capt., QMC, 1 2nd Lt., QMC, 1 Capt. Ord. Dept., 2 orderlies. 134th Inf. — 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 3 Majors, (Bn. Commanders), 3 Battalion Adjutants, 1 Supply Officer, 1 Adjutant, 4 orderlies, (1 for each Battalion and one for Hq.) 35th Div. Tn. — 1 Major, 1 Adjutant, 1 Supply Officer, 1 orderly. 110th Med. Regt. — 1 Col., 1 Lt. Col., 3 Majors, 1 Adjutant, 1 Supply Officer, 2 orderlies. a. The officers designated below will furnish riding equipment complete : S. S. C. &amp; D. — Q. M. C. Captain 8 134th Inf. — C. O. Regt. Hq. Co 5 C. O. 1st &amp; 3rd Bn. Hq. Co. each.. ..3 C. O. Company H, 134th Inf 3 (these will be used for 2nd Bn. Hq.) 35th Div. Tn. — C. O. Hq. Det 4 110th Med. Regt. — C. O. Service Co 9 BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 20, 1926. Circular Letter No. 29 Subject: Transportation. Co: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. MOUNTS: Mounts will be furnished to respective organiza- ions for the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. MULES, DRAFT: Mules will be assigned for demonstrative purposes as follows: Service Co., 134th Inf 4 3 5th Division Train 4 Camp Quartermaster 4 Equipment for the above will be furnished by the USP&amp;DO, and will consist of the following: 2 escort wagons 1 combat wagon 1 ration cart 1 water wagon with the necessary wheel and lead harness. 3. MOTOR: USP&amp;DO will transport all available trucks heavy and light and ambulances stored at the State Arsenal to camp. Commanding Officer, Co. K, 134th Inf., will see that his truck with two drivers will leave Omaha, August 2, 1926 at 7:00 AM, report- ing upon arrival to Capt. W. E. McConnaughey, QMC-NNG. This truck will load comany equipment of the Omaha units in baggage car prior to August 2, 1926. The Commanding Officers of the following organizations will furnish truck drivers immediately upon arrival of their first units to Capt. W. E. McConnaughey, QMC-NNG., Transportation Officer, as follows: 134th Inf „ 8 35th Division Train 2 110th Medical Regiment 2 H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 1, 1926. Circular Letter No. 30 Subject: Army and Navy Football Game. To: All Officers Nebraska National C All Officers Nebraska National Guard. 1. The officers of Seventh Corps Area are endeavoring to get enough people for a special train to go and see the Army and Navy </seg>
            <seg id="p097">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 97 football game at Chicago on November 27th, leaving Omaha the night of the 26th and leaving Chicago after midnight the night of the 27th. They hope to get a round trip rate of one fare plus fifty-cents. 2. Any officer of the Nebraska National Guard desiring to take this trip will notify the National Guard Officer, 7th Corps Area, Army Bldg., Omaha, Nebraska, giving the number in each officer's party and the prullman accomodations he will require, at the earliest possible date. It is proposed that all eat and sleep on the train from start to finish. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 10, 1926. Circular Letter No. 31 Subject: Unit Mobilization Plans. All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, N. N. G. To: 1. The following letter from the Adjutant General of the Army is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "AG 381 (7-6-26) (Misc.) M-C July 10, 1926. Unit Mobilization Plans. Commanding Generals of all Corps Areas and Departments, Chiefs of all War Department Branches, and the Chief of the Militia Bureau: 1. Each unit of the National Guard add Organized Reserves will prepare but one mobilization plan, this mobilization plan to be the unit plan under the War Department General Mobilization Plan. These units will not prepare supplemental plans to meet the require - ments of specific war plans. 2. Corps area and department commanders and chiefs of branches concerned will upon receipt of mobilization orders notify units of such modifications of their units plans as are necessary in order to comply with the requirements for the war plan for which mobilized. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. The War Department will, upon the issue of the next periodic Changes to A. R. 120-10, A. R. 130-10, and A. R. 135-10, correct these regulations to conform to the instructions contained in Para - graphs 1 and 2, foregoing. By order of the Secretary of War: Robert C. Davis, Major General, The Adjutant General, H. J. PAUL The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 16, 1926 Circular Letter No. 32 Subject: Examination of candidates for West Point. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, Nebraska National Guard. 1. The following letter from the Adjutant General of the Army, dated August 27, 1926, addressed to the Governor of Nebraska, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. Ap - plications for this examination should reach this office not later than October 15, 1926, to enable us to prepare for the competitive exam - inations which will be held between November 1st and 15th, 1926, the exact date to be announced later. "The regulations for the selection of enlisted men of the Na - tional Guard for appointment to the United States Military Academy provide that the candidates shall be apportioned among the States, Territories, and the District of Columbia according to the enlisted strength of their respective National Guard organizations. Candidates from the States and Territories will be selected by the respective Governors thereof from successful competitors in a preliminary examination of a scope and nature similar to the regular examination for entrance to the Military Academy to be instituted and conducted by the Governors, and to be held between November 1st and November 15 of each year. Under the statute authorizing these appointments, the Governors are restricted in their choice of candidates to enlisted men of the National Guard who conform to the requirements mentioned. "To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an ap - plicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal </seg>
            <seg id="p099">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 99 Government. He must, on the date of admission, July 1, 1927, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of nineteen and twenty-two years and must be not less than five feet four inches in height. The age and service requirements are statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. Similarly, service with a National Guard organization prior to its recognition by the Federal Government may be considered, the date of enlistment of the soldier governing, and not that of the recognition of the unit. The requirements for admission to the Military Academy are fully set forth in the inclosed pamphlet, a supply of which is being sent to you under separate cover for distribution to those interested. "The candidates so selected will be authorized by the War De - partment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is scheduled to be held beginning on March 1, 1927, and the appoint - ments available on July 1, 1927, will be awarded to the qualified can - didates in the order of merit established at that examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. You are, there - fore, requested to select, in accordance with the foregoing, one candi - date from among the enlisted men of the National Guard of your State, and to designate him for the entrance examination mentioned, using therefor the inclosed blank form. These cadetships being awarded solely as a result of competition, alternates cannot be considered. There is no limitation to the number who may compete in the pre - liminary examination and it is suggested that this matter be widely advertised throughout the National Guard organizations of your State so that every enlisted man who is eligible as to age and length of service may be afforded this great opportunity. In the past some States have failed to take advantage of the opportunity to designate candidates, while other States have designated their full quotas and are constantly asking for the privilege of making more appointments. As a result it has been decided to require that designations shall be made promptly following the November pre - liminary examination, and in no case later than December 15, 1926. When sending in your designations, it is requested that you inform the Department as to the number of other desirable candidates, if any, you may have available. The allotments of those States which allow </seg>
            <seg id="p100">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 100 the opportunity to lapse through failure to fill their quotas by De - cember 15, 1926 will be given to other States. Very respectfully, Lutz Wahl, Brigadier General, Acting The Adjutant General." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 16, 1926. Circular Letter No. 33 Subject: Army and Navy Football Game. All Officers, Nebraska National Guard. To 1. Supplementing Circular Letter No. 30 pertaining to the Army and Navy Football Game, this letter is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. With reference to the Army and Navy Football game to be held at Chicago November 27th, the following additional infor - mation is furnished: a. Special train will leave Omaha some time after 6:30 P. M. Nov. 26th (exact hour and route not yet decided upon.) b. Train will arrive at Chicago sometime on the morning of November 27th and sleepers may be used as hotel accommodations by all on board. c. Game will commence at 2:00 P. M. at Soldiers Field. d. Train will leave on return trip shortly after midnight the 27th thus affording opportunity to attend the Army dinner and dance at Drake Hotel following the game. Tickets for the game, other than for Regular Army per- </seg>
            <seg id="p101">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 101 sonnel or members of the Army Athletic Association, may be ob - tained from the "South Park Board, 57th and Cottage Grove Avenue, Chicago, 111." In view of the great demand for tickets it is suggested that those desiring same act promptly. f. Those wishing to go on the special train please notify the National Guard Officer, 7th Corps Area, indicating probable number in party and Pullman accommodations required. HARVEY W. MILLER Adjutant General." BY DIRECTION OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 25, 1926. Circular Letter No. 34 Subject: Change of Property Accounting System To: All Officers Responsible for Property. All Officers Responsible for Property. 1. Pursuant to instructions contained in M. B. Circular No. 18, dated April 16, 1926, the Property Accounting System now in force in the National Guard will be changed as follows: a. All property to be signed for by responsible officer on Mem - orandum Receipt. b. In the future all Shipping Tickets will be signed by the Property and Disbursing Officer after signed copies of Mem - orandum Receipts are received from the responsible officer. 2. The enclosed Memorandum Receipts have been prepared from the records in this office and it is directed that same be checked against your records, signing the original and three copies returning same to this office with the least possible delay. 3. Upon receipt of these signed memorandum receipts. Shipping Tickets will be prepared and signed by the Property &amp; Disbursing Colonel, A. G. D., </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Officer, furnishing you with one copy which will be a credit voucher to your Property Loan Record cards. 4. Q. M. C. Form No. 75 will be furnished each organization so that an abstract of the Memorandum Receipts will be kept, in lieu of the Property Loan Record cards. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 30, 1926. Circular Letter No. 35 Subject: Undelivered Checks. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, N. N. G. 1. The Finance Officer has just called our attention to the fact that the records of his office show a large number of checks, covering National Guard drill pay in this State, are outstanding and unpaid for more than ninety days. You are therefore directed to immediately return all undelivered checks in your possession which have been held for ninety days or more. 2. In the future, undelivered checks for National Guard drill pay will not be held in excess of ninety days. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. SPANISH WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers who parti - cipated in the service of the Spanish-American War in the First, Second, and Third Nebraska Volunteer Regiments and Troop K, Third Volunteer Cavalry: COMPANY A — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Arat. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dae : Bye, Joseph G $3.20 Allen, Roller C 3.20 Burl, George J 3.20 'vt. 'vt. Kelly, Charles R 3.20 Morgenstern, Henry A. 3.20 "vt. Shlvely, Bion 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 103 Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Freeman, Charlie 0 3.20 Gelvin, Robert N 3.20 Hensley, Minor N 3.20 Kremer, Cochron A 4.00 Pvt. Sommers. Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Turner, Robert W 3.20 Pvt. Wompler, Elmer B 3.20 COMPANY B — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Garinger, Albert $0.80 Pvt. Grainger, Louis I : 1.60 Pvt. Andrews, Clias. J 4.00 Pvt. Killhom. Perry A 4.00 Pvt. Black, John 4.00 Pvt. Ressekuie, Herbert L. 4.00 COMPANY O— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Johnson, Hans $3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F 3.20 Pvt. Campbell, Roy G 3.20 COMPANY D — FIRST REGIMENT Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Pvt. Alley, John S $4.00 Pvt. Hawes, Fred M 4.00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A 4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie, Samuel B 4.00 Pvt. Bloom, John J 4.00 COMPANY E — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land, Noah B $1.60 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F 3.20 Pvt. Amerman, Arba B 1.60 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Blackburn, Win.' C 3.20 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H 1.60 Pvt. Pvt. Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt. Moffett, Jesse C 3.20 Pvt. Lisk, Jack G 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G 3.20 Pvt. Pecinovsky, Joseph W. 3.20 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H 3.20 Pvt. Bays, Wm 80 COMPANY F — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 3gt. Gallagher, Joseph P. -$3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvin W 3.20 Cpl. Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E 3.20 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua .... 3.20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E 3.20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Davidson, Houston .... 3.20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D 3.20 Pvt. Olson, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY G — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burlington, John $3.20 Pvt. Anderson, Hugh S 80 Pvt. Deaver, Harvey W 3.20 Pvt. Dowte, Jonathan E 3.20 Pvt. Merryman, John R 3.20 Rank Name Amt . Dae Pvt. Mohler, Chas. E 3.20 Prt. Underwood, Henry C. 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P 3.20 COMPANY H — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H $3.20 Pvt. Brlsbine, Lewis H 2.40 Pvt. Dawson, Eugene M 4.00 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L 3.20 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W 1.60 Pvt. Smith, George J 4.00 Pvt. Downing, Edward S... 4.00 Pvt. Mansker, James F 3.20 Pvt. Sutton, Roy 0 1.60 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Mengler, FTank 80 Pvt. Winagel, Anthony J... 2.40 Pvt. Peterson, Hanc C 4.00 COMPANY I — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due tHotsell, Leon V $4.00 Berndtson, John E 4.00 Bordwell, Frank J 4.00 Fricke, Albert W 4.00 Gregg, Edwin F 4.00 Pvt. Jeon, John M 4.00 Pvt. Jones, Oliver J 4.00 Pvt. McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 COMPANY K — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Delong, Herbert B $3.20 Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt. Crittenden, David L... 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F 3.20 Prt. Fingado, Harry, Jr 4.00 Pvt. Witsch, Max N 3.20 Pvt. Schmeider, Wm. G 3.20 COMPANY L — FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Downs, James W $3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin 0 3.20 Pvt. Green, Fred L 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Humphrey, Mortimer B. 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H... 3.20 COMPANY M— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Spence, Monroe W $3.20 Pvt. Coons, Chas. J 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 105 Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Rucker, Winifred L... 3.20 Pvt. Jack, Cecil B 3.20 Pvt. Coxson, Alvin A 3.20 Pvt. Kennedy, Phillip S 3.20 FIELD AND STAFF — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt, Due P. M. Brown, Robert S $4.00 Mus. Murnhouse, F. Edd.... 4.00 COMPANY A — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Cupernell, Ernest H...$3.20 Art. Devinney, Harry M 3.20 Cpl. Paine, Lewis A 3.20 Pvt. Miller, Ned K 3.20 Pvt. Blough, Clay C 3.20 Pvt. Mott, Mathew 3.20 Pvt. Carman, Chas. S 3.20 Pvt. Charles, Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T... 3.20 Pvt. Tuffs, Frank 3.20 Pvt. White, Wm. A 3.20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Forman, David A 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry 3.20 Pvt. Woodruff, Charles .... 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William 3.20 COMPANY B — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Frink, Alberto D $3.20 Cpl. Whitmer, James K..~. 3.20 Pvt. Jackson, Wm 3.20 Pvt. Minnich, Herbert J 3.20 Wag. Crow, Wallace H 3.20 Art. Grossett, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Beebe, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Eli A 3.20 Pvt. Briggs, Ernest G. (Died in service) 3.20 COMPANY C! — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Miles, George $3.20 Pvt. Church, John H 1.60 Cpl. Spencer, Hiram C 1.60 Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C 3.20 Pvt. Clark, Wm. B 3.20 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B 1.60 Pvt. Kime, David 1.60 Pvt. Lee, Ira E 3.20 Pvt. McLain, Clarence E 1.60 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. Roddy, John H 3.20 Pvt. Cristianson, Edw. R... 3.20 Pvt. Shanklin, Sylvester .... 1.60 COMPANY D— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A $4.00 Pvt. French, John C 3.20 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larsh A 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae Pvt. Anderson, Albert R 4.00 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E 4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R 4.00 Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M. 4.00 Prt. Lloyd, Wm. T 4.00 COMPANY E — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Andrews, Nick $3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J 3.20 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicek, John 3.20 Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W 3.20 Pvt. Cooper, Clarence 3.20 Pvt. Dahlem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Frame, George W 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Edward J... 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout, John H 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E 3.20 Pvt. Vandervort, Sam'l M. 3.20 COMPANY F — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Grofton, George $3.20 Pvt. Hall, James H 3.20 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M 3.20 Pvt. Mitchell, Harry D 4.80 COMPANY G — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 2nd Lt. Hodgins, Eli $3.20 Pvt. Hugh, Harry 80 Cpl. Hays, Robert A 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T 80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S 80 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 3.20 Pvt. McFarland, Sm'l F. .. .80 Pvt. Blenkiron, Harry V 80 Pvt. Deverall, Ralph H 80 Pvt. Neucomb, Frank S 3.20 Pvt. Newton, William 3.20 Pvt. Drake, Henry L 80 Pvt. Packard, Hugh M 3.20 Prt. Fisher, Leo 80 Pvt. Quimby, Lucien E 80 Pvt. Gainey, John H 80 Pvt. Ritter, David 80 Pvt. Horn, George L., Jr. ..3.20 Pvt. Thompson, Eddie D 80 COMPANY H — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Borland, John A $4.00 Pvt. Johnston, George H 4.00 Art. Neill, John W 4.00 Pvt. Logan, Alvah 4.00 Mus. Ray, Stanley T 4.00 Pvt. Meitner, Joseph 4.00 Pvt. Bowers, Henry H 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, John 4.00 Pvt. Boyd, Wm. J 4.00 Pvt. Perry, Herbert N 4.00 Pvt. Davis, Harry E 4.00 Pvt. Serensen, Ole C 4.00 Pvt. ' Ditzler, Al 4.00 Pvt. Tucker, Harry 0 4.00 Pvt. Gillespie, David E 4.00 Pvt. Hershey, Will L 4.00 Pvt. Whitney, John A 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 107 COMPANY I — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name A nit. Dae Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Rainey, Jacob A $4.00 Pvt. Schooler, John H 4.00 Cpl. Giblin, John S 4.00 Pvt. Schuelke, Herman A... 4.00 Pvt. Evans, Fletcher 4.00 Pvt. Thompson, Theodore.. 4.00 Pvt. Hammill, Oscar 4.00 Pvt. Walker, Joseph H 4.00 Pvt. Humpal, John J 4.00 Pvt. Way, Rueben D 4.00 Pvt. Penland, John W 80 COMPANY K — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Erickson, Francis T...$3.20 Pvt. West, Charles 3.20 Cpl. Hill, John T 3.20 COMPANY Ii — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Jack, Charles H $2.40 Cpl. Kohout, Frank W 4.00 Pvt. Clarenden, Alvin T 4.00 Pvt. Evans, John 3.20 Cpl. Sage, John M 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, John 3.20 Cpl. Wellman, Frank P..... 3.20 Wag. Bauman, John P 4.00 Art. Carter, Charles J 3.20 Pvt. Leonard, Wm. C 80 Pvt. Powell, Joseph A 3.20 Pvt. Rainey, Wm. N 3.20 Pvt. Abel, Louis 3.20 Pvt. Sloan, John H 2.40 Pvt. Anderson, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Collins, James R 3.20 Pvt. Cottrell, Eugene W 3.20 Pvt. Smith, George W 1.60 Pvt. Wilson, Thomas B 1.60 COMPANY M — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Alfreds, Frank H $5.60 Pvt. Payne, Wesley R 6.40 Pvt. Londlodge, Henry W. 5.60 Pvt. Schwart, Wm 5.60 Pvt. Steele, Duncon C 5.60 FIELD STAFF AND BAND — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae RB Mus. Henderson, Roy D. $ 9.60 RB Mus. Lyon, Harry C 1.60 Rank Name Amt. Dae RB Mus. Parkhurst, Harry.. 3.20 RB Mus. Wells, Richard L... 12.00 COMPANY A — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae QM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W. $32.55 Pvt. McDonald, Geo. A 4.00 Cpl. Ford, John J 5.60 Pvt. Marksbury, Thomas N. 1.60 Cpl. Steinbach, George 12.72 Pvt. Michael, Wm 14.61 Cpl. Ross, Matthew 1.60 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Mus. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. O'Leary, John J 2.40 Mus. Lenker, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Pace, Perle R 2.40 Art. Ball, Wm. A 18.39 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Pvt. Allen, Thomas 4.80 Pvt. Pierce, Frank W 10.84 Pvt. Avery, John S 1.60 Pvt. Reynolds, John A 1.60 Pvt. Bliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt. Schneider, Wm 2.40 Pvt. Collins, John H 1.60 Pvt. Smith, John J 1.60 Pvt. Gallenbuck, Frank J. 1.60 Pvt. Strough, George W... 4.00 Prt. Gray, Burton E 2.40 Pvt. Taylor, James J 2.40 Pvt. Horahan, Chas 5.60 Pvt. Trombly, Warden, Pvt. Hinckley, John S 1.60 A. F 18.39 Pvt. Hurst, Arthur J 1.60 Pvt. Wolf, Chas. T 2.40 Prt. Koontz, Edmund J... 2.40 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr. 2.40 Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 COMPANY B — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae QM Sgt. Covell, Herbert E. $33.64 Sgt. Spencer, Chas. L 33.64 Pvt. Metts, Edmond M 80 Pvt. Mungoran, Peter 3.20 Sgt. Hawkins, Harry 15.70 Pvt. McGrew, Frank 80 Wag. Palmer, James H 32.69 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt. Bradford, George H. .80 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W. 33.64 Pvt. O'Shea, Howard 18.53 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H 33.64 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas 80 Pvt. Place, John F 21.36 Pvt. Custer, Elisha 80 Pvt. Ray, Evert P 20.42 Pvt. Francisco, John H... .80 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust .... 33.64 Pvt. Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Roop, Scott D 80 Pvt. Greenlee, William .... 3.20 Pvt. Sawyer, Ernest E 33.64 Prt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Schwartz, Wm 80 Pvt. Habbick, George W... 1.60 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N... .80 Pvt. Jarvis, Chas. T 80 Pvt. Torrence, LeRoy E. 33.64 Pvt. Keanes, James N 80 Pvt. Ward, William R 80 Prt. Line, Jno. M 17.59 Pvt. Whalen, Edwin F 3.20 COMPANY C— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dae iSgt. White, Thomas R. $27.46 Bailey, Frank C 22.74 Dillion, Samuel H 27.46 Pvt. Hileman, Robert E... 27.46 Pvt. Howell, Harry H...:. 22.74 Pvt. Keliher, John F 4.80 Cpl. Sydow, Emil 2.7.46 Pvt. Long, Wilber W 5.75 Cpl. Miller, Wm. E 27.46 Pvt. McCall, William J 2.40 Pvt. Mitchell, Edward F. 2.40 Wag. Clayberg, Elmer 27.46 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Art. Freeman, Nathan W. 27.46 Pvt. Norton, Ernest H 11.41 Pvt. Paul, Henry C 2.40 Pvt. Sheil, Daniel J 7.64 Cpl. Burkett, Harry B 2.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p109">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 109 Pvt. Breechwald, Philip.... 2.40 Pvt. Seek, John A 2.40 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F 2.40 Pvt. Costello, Michael F. 13.30 Pvt. Collins, Bernard P.- 8.58 Pvt. DeRivieres, Francis L. 4.80 Pvt. Swanson, Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Taylor, Edward 4.80 Pvt. Dobbins, Albert 2.40 Pvt. Vernon, George A 12.36 Pvt. Henske, Fred 80 Pvt. Wahlstrom, Albin F. 2.40 Pvt. Hawkins, Elgin C 8.5 S Pvt. Zurubsky, James .... 7.64 Pvt. Henry, William 2.40 COMPANY D — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Reynolds, Walter D...$ 4.80 Sgt. Dennett, Albert G 29.57 Cpl. Abernathy, Fred B... 26.74 Pvt. Jansen, Nels P 23.91 Pvt. Juul, John M 30.52 Pvt. Jones, Lewis C 80 Cpl. Christensen, Chris- Pvt. Kregersen, Henry .... 22.96 tian A 36.18 Pvt. Landsbury, Harry .... 1.60 Cpl. McDowell, Wm. G 29.57 Pvt. Lundell, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Nelson, Chas. M 8.00 Mus. Howel, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Ivan G 8.00 Pvt. Allwein, John C 1.60 Pvt. Pool, John E 4.80 Pvt. Anderson, Edward .. 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Andrew .. 3.20 Pvt. Bandy, John W 1.60 Pvt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 Pvt. Rief, Ralph S 4.80 Pvt. Robie, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Carlson, Albert 29.57 Pvt. Sutton, Frank E 6.40 Pvt. Flor, Sigurd 8.80 Pvt. Warren, Walter H... 6.40 Pvt. Hamilton, James 3.20 Pvt. Wiederholz, John J... 28.63 Pvt. Hope, Daniel 4.00 COMPANY E — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt, Due Sgt. Siddell, Bert E |13.01 Pvt. Anderson, Claude .... 4.00 Pvt. Flenniken, Robert B. 13.96 Pvt. Pardew, Avery A 20.56 Pvt. Reinbolt, Fred 80 Pvt. Smith, Fred S 22.45 Pvt. Hays, John S 28.12 Pvt. Van Epps, Bert L 80 Pvt. Lewin, Samuel C 80 COMPANY F — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Wilburn, Claude A. 136.69 Pvt. Kment, Joe 1.60 Art. Becker, Otto 36.69 Pvt. Knott, Fred 80 Pvt. Baughman, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Loss, Isaac 36.69 Pvt. Brunker, Frank 1.60 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J 1.60 Pvt. Esplin, Lucius 36.69 Pvt. Nicholson, James T... 1.60 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Olson, Chris 80 Pvt. Hayes, John C 8.80 Pvt. Olsen, Lars P 36.69 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Doe Rank Name Amt. Dae Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Owens, Victor L 80 Pvt. Hon. Anton 1.60 Pvt. Phillips, George W... 1.60 Pvt. Houdek, Charles .... 1.60 Pvt. Saare, Alfred H 80 Pvt. Hudec, Wm 3.20 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Johns, Olvey 0 80 Pvt. Underhill, Charles .... 36.69 Pvt. Johnson, Wm. L. 36.69 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M 80 Pvt. Karges, John 36.69 Pvt. Woods, Thomas J 3.20 COMPANY G — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Due t Burnett, Hamilton H. $29.72 Larson, Felix G 29.72 Collins, Wilke S 29.72 Arnold, Isaac C 21.72 Pvt. Forsman, Oscar 29.72 Pvt. Fuller, Guy W 1.60 Pvt. Howard, Edward .... 29.72 Pvt. Jones, Frank 29.72 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Prt. Knapp, Willie R 29.72 Pvt. Larson, Axel W 29.72 Pvt. Burke, Frank J 29.72 Pvt. Burnett, Marcus V... 3.20 Pvt. Bowerman, Wm. F... 4.80 Pvt. Carter, Wm. H 29.72 Pvt. Lehman, Paul 29.72 Pvt. Meade, Frank 29.72 Pvt. Morton, Frank H 29.72 Pvt. O"Connor, William.... 4.00 Pvt. Conner, Clement T... 29.72 Pvt. Durham, Miller L..... 29.72 Pvt. Pickard, Harry M 29.72 Pvt. Reap, Warren A 29.72 Pvt. Ferguson, Isaac 80 Pvt. Ryan, William 29.72 COMPANY H— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dae Pvt. Headwell, Axel $31.09 Pvt. Jackman, Wm. N 6.55 Pvt. Keever, Oscar W 13.16 Pvt. Robinson, Andrew M. 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Edson J 31.09 Pvt. Thomas, James T 3.20 Pvt. Leichty, John 6.66 Pvt. Williams, Edgar T 31.09 Pvt. Moyer, George E 5.60 Pvt. Matson, Albert 5.60 Pvt. Robinson, Edward .... 3.20 COMPANY I— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dae KDerienger, George ....$36.61 Lewis, Charles E 4.80 Pvt. Houghs, Chas. I*. 4.00 Pvt. Hutchinson, Albert L. 1.60 Sgt. Waterman, Harry Pvt. Jones, Lloyd 0 4.00 D. S 37.56 Pvt. Marqwadt, Fred W... 1.60 Cpl. Dickenson, John W... 12.07 Pvt. Miller, Fred S 9.24 Cpl. Felts, William B..... 6.40 Pvt. Morris, Benjamin F. 9.24 Cpl. Jensen, Chris M 4.00 Pvt. Padol, Adam 80 Cpl. Meyer, Otto 4.00 Pvt. Perry, Chas. E 11.12 Wag. Brott, Zina H 22.45 Pvt. Phillips, Ellis J 3.20 Pvt. Brower, Bertie M 29.72 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 111 Art. Shepardson, Benj. W. 23.40 Pvt. Aitken, George F 37.56 Pvt. Baird, Francis H 4.80 Pvt. Bersley, Wm. G 31.89 Pvt. Brown, Frank H 4.00 Pvt. Potter, Forrest A 9.24 Pvt. Palmer, Archibald G. 5.60 Pvt. Ray, Warren Hopkins 2.40 Pvt. Roberts, James W 9.24 Pvt. Selby, Arthur L 9.24 Pvt. Carroll, John W 4.00 Pvt. Starky, Cyrus 37.56 Pvt. Center, Albert 4.80 Pvt. Stone, John G 4.00 Pvt. Dinsmore, Claude R. 9.24 Pvt. Swan, Richard B 89 Pvt. Unger, Edward W... 4.00 Pvt. Fairchild, Homer .... 1.60 Pvt. Guthercole, Fred A. 4.00 Pvt. Hackler, David D 1.60 Pvt. Hanks, Harry E 1.60 Pvt. Vandyke, John T 6.40 Pvt. Vandyke, Sherman .. 6.40 Pvt. Warrington, Albert J. 2.40 COMPANY K — THIRD REGIMENT Bank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae 1st Sgt. Jacobson, Carl L. $34.29 Cpl. Fountain, Francis N. 34.29 Pvt. Meade, Wm. B 3.20 Pvt. Mines, James S 1.60 Pvt. Arnold, Otto H 80 Pvt. Painter, Wm. C 2.40 Pvt. Cofield, Chester A 11.64 Pvt. Porterfleld, James R. 34.29 Pvt. Gray, Lyman 3.20 Pvt. Reardon, Patrick J... 2.40 Pvt. Gress, Henry C 14.47 Pvt. Roll, John L 29.57 Pvt. Hightower, Harry A. 2.40 Pvt. Kennedy, George H. 7.20 Pvt. Smith, Albert L 34.29 Pvt. Snider, Charles 3.20 Pvt. Kankright, Pvt. Stamp, Samuel 1.60 Clinton D 27.68 Pvt. Thompson, James B. 3.20 Pvt. Kruger, Wm 80 Pvt. VanSickle, Cyrus .... !.•• Pvt. Matthews, Stanley .. 30.52 Pvt. McCaulley, Wm. G... 1.60 Pvt. Williams, Wm. M 1.60 COMPANY L — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dae Cpl. Brown, Cleveland W.$ 7.20 Cpl. Nicholson, Chas. J... 4.00 Pvt. Fox, Ernest S 24.79 Pvt. Grove, George W 5.60 Cpl. Lowe, Walter 8.00 Pvt. Jensen, Hans 27.62 Cpl. Taft, Charles C 21.01 Wag. Stockton, Andrew .... 32.34 Pvt. Kritsch, Herman .... 6.40 Pvt. Laflin, Gilbert B 8.80 Pvt. Jockens, George H... 25.73 Pvt. Jones, Joseph B 4.80 Pvt. Kelley, Robert S 6.40 Pvt. McColl, John 14.40 Pvt. Lee, Jestivin E l.«0 Pvt. McCormick, Benj. D. 8.00 Pvt. Lehmus, Lewis A 21.01 Pvt. Mardock, John E 1.60 Mus. Woerhide, Charles E. 6.40 Pvt. Miller, August 4.80 Pvt. Murphy, Simon 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Joseph M 32.34 Art. Watson, Grant 24.79 Pvt. Nystrom, Charles A... 10.40 Pvt. Athos, Andrew G 27.62 Pvt. Nystrom, Gus E 4.80 Pvt. Black, Wm 2.40 Pvt. Pendarvis, George H. 5.60 Pvt. Dubee, Alexander .... 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Pvt. Bradshaw. Pvt. Redfleld, Cyrus R 4.80 Thomas H 5.60 Pvt. Rundus, Frank 32.34 Pvt. Burns, James E 3.20 Pvt. Croop, Marian E 23.84 Pvt. Chisolm, Ralph 0 5.60 Pvt. Foster, Louie C 32.34 Pvt. Simpson, Wm. R 4.80 Pvt. Sherry, John W 5.60 Pvt. Swanson, Nels 32.34 Pvt. Turner, Carlton B 6.60 Pvt. "Walker, Chas 27.62 COMPANY M — THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Foster, John E $ 4.00 Sgt. Lord, George E 35.38 Pvt. Heisler, Robert D 80 Pvt. Hensel, Wm. A 2.40 Cpl. Alsen, John C..~ 35.38 Pvt. Kleinsmith, Morris 35.38 Cpl. Williams, Richard .. 12.72 Mus. Porter, Lester E 16.50 Pvt. Leonard, Harry H... 17.44 Pvt. Maddan, Chas 35.38 Pvt. Bennett, Niles 21.22 Pvt. Maxwell, Joseph E... 11.78 Pvt. Biegler, George 34.44 Pvt. Brewick, Andrew T... 3.20 Pvt. Ratekin, Janson L 80 Pvt. Short, James S 27.83 Pvt. Cantello, John 10.84 Pvt. Timmons, Alfred D... 34.44 Pvt. Carigan, Robert J 35.38 Pvt. Custard, Marshall .... 1.60 Pvt. Wiesman, Jacob 2.40 Cpl. Forrester, Herbert A.$13.60 Pvt. Drustrup, Nels 3.20 Pvt. Alley, Franc 2.40 Pvt. Foster, Frederick W. 17.44 Pvt. Beardsley, Wm. S 80 Pvt. Graham, Alonzo 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, John D 13.60 Pvt. Griggs, Bert 2.40 TROOP K— THIRD CAVALRY Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae Pvt. McLaughlin, Walter.. 2.40 Pvt. Robinson, Fred 2.40 Pvt. Mossbarger Pvt. Schutz, Gottlieb 13.60 Claude G 2.40 It is recommended that this list be given a circulation in the news - papers of the State with a view to locating such of these men as possible. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>