<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  GROWING FEEDER STEERS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXIII, Article II. t ROWING FEEDER STEERS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. Report of Experimental Substation, North Pi.atte, Nebraska W. P. Snyder, Superintendent E. A. Bubnett, Director. DisTKiiUTEii February 1, 1911. SHEDS AND COHKALS FOB WINTERING CATTLE. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (the regents of the university.) HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D, LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc . Director. ■ DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. J. Aiwat, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, B. Sc. M. E., Agricultural Engineering. H. R. Smith, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. A. L. Haeckeb, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. E. G. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronovty. Frank J. Phillips, M. F., Forestry. Erwin H. Barrour, Ph. D., Oeology. G. R. Chatburn. A. M., Highway Engineering. R. A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulture. O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering. G. A. Lovelakd, A. M., Meteorology. C. W. Pugslet, B. Sc, Soil Agronomy. ■ P. Sntder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation. North Platte. Miss Vents W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. George K. K. Link, S. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. R. S. TiiiMnri.i., A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Barker, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). T. A. Kiessei.bach, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy (Crops). Erwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). L. B. Sti'rdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Assistant in Entomology. R. F. Howard, B. Sc in Agr., Assistant in Horticulture. RfV. Burr, B. Sc, Assistant in Soils and Crops. North Platte; Assistant Agriculturist. Of/Ice Dry Land Agriculture. U. 8. Department of Agri - culture. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fritz Knorh, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. S. W. Perin, Farm Superintendent * Mrs. Nelle S. Scott, A. B., Scientific Assistant. Seed Testing. • Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">I AKLK OF CON I KM- Prices used for feed and cattle t&gt; Kind of forage fed to each lot 7 Plan of bulletin 8 Continuous record of steers, Tables 1 to 8 9 (Jains during first winter, Table 9 18 Daily gains, winters and summers. Table 1« 19 Relation of summer and winter gains Relative gains of steers, Table 11 S3 Weights of steers at ends of periods, Table 12 24 Forage required for winter, Table 13 Forage eaten per steer daily, Table 14 Cost of gains Pounds feed required for 100 lbs. gain. Table 15 87 Cost of 100 lbs. gain during winter, Table 16 28 Cost of 100 lbs. gain during summer, Table 17 29 Cost of feed for wintering steer, Table 18 29 Cost of steer at end of periods, Table 19 31 Cost of steer per 100 lbs. at end of periods, Table 20 32 ■live standing of forage rations as indicated by winter gains, Table 21 ■itive standing of forage rations as indicated by summer gains, Table 22 34 ■ktive standing of forage rations as indicated by gains for the year. Table 23 34 Values of steers for different periods during experiments, Tables 24 to 31 inclusive 35 ■s in price per 1M lbs. necessary to cover cost of winter feed. Table 32 44 Decrease in price per 100 lbs. that may Iw permitted in fall below the spring price, Table 33 44 Cost of steers per 100 lbs. in spring, Table 34 45 Cost of steers per 100 lbs. in fall. Table 35 46 ■; of 100 lbs. gain in summer at various charges for pasture, Table 36 48 ■itive price received for ton of forage when cattle are sold in spring, Table 37 49 Summary of entire experiment 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">r OWING FEEDER STEERS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. BY W. P. SNYDER During 1906 and 1907, experiments, were conducted with steers to study the effect of alfalfa, prairie hay, cane hay, and mixtures of the latter two with alfalfa in wintering steers. The results of these tests were reported in Bulletin 105. In the fall of 1907 a similar experiment was begun. In this test there were 108 steer calves, divided into 6 lots of 18 calves each. These calves were bought out of herds adjacent to North Platte. They were a fairly good class of grades of the leading beef breeds. They were not, however, all of one breed, but were of mixed breeds and colors. The cost varied from $3.75 to 94.00 per 100 lbs., or about |17.00 per head. The average weight was 450 iChe plan contemplated putting each lot on a separate ration, :inuing the same forage ration for three winters, and selling steers off grass the fall after they were three years old. This l was adhered to, excepting that the steers were marketed rust 5, owing to a shortage of pasture due to dry weather. r'he various lots were quite uniform. There was a loss of b steers during the experiment. One steer dropped dead at feed rack and the other two were killed by lightning. Ehe quality of the forage was not always uniform. The ie hay was of good quality thruout, but the cane was some - i coarse, and some of the alfalfa during the third winter was ie and damaged by being stacked when too damp. Each lot ran in a corral of about an acre in extent with a constant supply of water and an open shed 22x24. The steers of each lot were branded on a different part of the body, so that </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska E would be no difficulty in determining the lot to which each belonged. During the summer all lots ran together in yon pasture of 1,500 acres which they shared with about id of horses and cattle. iV prairie fire on March 26, 1910, burned the cattle sheds and als. This caused all the steers to be thrown together with other cattle. Fortunately weights had been taken March 18. time from that date until the steers were turned on grass is &gt;unted for in Period 5B. Three weights were taken at the beginning and close of each period, excepting at one or two times when two weights gave fairly uniform results. The cattle were weighed when they had been away from water 12 hours or more, and had not been fed hay for the same length of time. The aim was to get a fair and uniform shrinkage on each lot. Tho care was taken to accom - plish this, it is probable that the spring weights of the lots carry - ing the most flesh do not represent the actual weights as nearly as the corresponding weights of the thinner lots. However this may be, the weights recorded would be the usual weights upon which the steers would sell if changing ownership at that time. PRICES USED FOR FEED AND CATTLE. In writing up the results of an experiment it is always diffi- cult to decide what prices should be assigned to the feed used and to the stock, owing to many factors, among which are the changes in prices during the progress of the experiment and the difference in prices in various localities. In this test we have assumed the following prices : Alfalfa, per ton $6.00 Prairie hay, per ton 5.00 Cane, per ton 4.00 Corn, per bushel 50 Oats, per bushel 35 Cattle per 100 lbs. in spring 4.25 Cattle ner 100 lbs in fall 7*5 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 It is obvious that cattle are worth more per pound in the spring than in the fall. During the winter the expense is ueav\ and the gain is light, while during the summer the opposite is true. We have assumed that this difference is oO cents per l'ni lbs. The results of the experiment show that in order to have gotten the value assumed for the feed, we should have made the spring price more than 50 cents per 100 lbs. above the fall price. We have assumed that the cost of the pasture during the summer was equal to 6 per cent interest on 8 acres of land valued at $8.00 jkt acre, plus a slight charge of 25 cents per head for water. This amounts to |4.09 per head for the summer. If the pasturing season were 6 months in duration, the cfcaigi would be at the rate of 68 cents per month. During the first winter all the calves were fed a light grain ration of 2 pounds daily per calf. The grain was two parts coin and one part oats. The forage was weighed in wagon-load lots as it was drawn to the steers. It was piled in front of fe»*»linfr racks, and given to the steers twice daily. The waste was not KIND OF FORAGE FED TO EACH LOT. The forage ration was as follows Lot 1. Alfalfa. Lot 2. Prairie hay. Lot 3. Cane. Lot 4. One-half alfalfa and one-half prairie hay. Lot 5. One-half alfalfa and one-half cane hay. Lot 6. One-half prairie hay and one-half cane hay JPhe experiment began December 3, 1907. and ended August M.0. The time covered has been divided into six periods, each including a summer or a winter. Period 5 has been sub - ded into Periods 5A and 5B. This is on account of the break he experiment caused by the fire of March 26, 1910. Period covers the winter up to March 18, while the steers were in irate lots on the different forage rations. Period 5B covers </seg>
            <seg id="p008">»time from March 18 to May 4, when the steers ran to - er and were fed alfalfa and prairie hay. As the pasture burned the grass was late in starting and the steers were later in the spring than usual. PLAN OF BULLETIN. In the following account of the performance of these steers, Tables 1 to 8 give the continuous record from December 3, 1907, to August 5, 1910, carrying the cost forward from one period to the next until the end of the experiment. The steers are charged at $3.75 per 100 lbs. at the beginning of the experiment in Table 1. The "cost" of the steer from that date is obtained by adding, to the original cost, 6 per cent interest on the money invested in the steer and the market price of the feed eaten. The interest is computed at the end of each period. This causes a charge for interest to be made in the case of each steer for the money invested in him up to the end of the preceding period. In this way there is interest charged on the feed or pasture after the end of the winter or of the summer period. Tables 25 to 31 inclusive give the record for each winter and summer period independently of the preceding or the succeeding period. The account treats the steer as if he were bought at the beginning of the period and sold at the end. The assumed market value of the steer is used for the basis of each period, rather than the amount the steer had actually cost at that time. These tables show the profit or the loss on each lot of steers for each winter and each summer. The value of the steer in the fall is assumed to be $3.75 per 100 lbs. and in the spring 14.25. To the price of the steer at the beginning of the period is added the cost of the feed and interest at 6 per cent on the money invested in the steer during the period. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Table 1. Period 1, Pibst Winter. December 3, 1907, to April 21, 1908. tparative valties of alfalfa, prairie hay, and cane, ami &lt;&lt;t&gt;n - binations of these, \oith a light grain ration for wint - calves. Each lot contained 18 steers. There were 19S iugt in the period. LotNo 12 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa Alfalfa Prairie rations Alfalfa P £™ Cane and JjJ P hay cane cane Average first weight, Dec. 3, lbs 446 460 452 451 «1 449 Average last weight, Apr. 21, lbs 578 489 512 568 ,576 511 Average gain, lbs 132 39 60 117 125 62 Average daily gain, lb 94 .28 .43 .84 .9 .28 .43 .84 .9 .44 Relative gain, per cent 100 30 45 \ 90 95 47 Forage for steer during winter, lbs 11741 1481 1860 11695 !l831 1578 Forage per steer per day, lbs..; 12.5 10.65: 13.3, 12.19 13.17 11.35 Forage for 100 lbs. gain, lbs. 1312 3798 3100 1448 1464 2545 Grain for 100 lbs. gain, lbs . . 212 717 i 467 239 224 451 Cost of feed for wintering steer $8.33 $6.81 $6 83; $7.77 $7.69 $6 66 Cost of forage for wintering Cost of forage for steer wintering 5.22 Kr 5.22 of grain for wintering r 3.11 3 70 3 72 4.66 4.58 3.55 3 70 3 72 4.66 4.68 3.55 Cost of grain for wintering steer 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 3.11 Cost of feed for 100 lbs. gain . . 6.01| Cost of feed for 100 lbs. gain . . 6.01 17.46 10.74 6.63 6.15 10 74 17.46 10.74 6.63 6 15 10 74 Cost of steer in fall at $3.75. . . 16 73' 16.88 16.95 16 91 16 91 16.84 16.88 16.95 16 91 16 91 16.84 Cost of steer in fall at $3.75 ... 16 73 Cost of wintering — feed and in - terest ; 8.71 Cost of wintering — feed and in - terest ; 8.71 7.20 7.22] 8 16 8.08 7 05 7.20 7.22 8 16 8.08 7 05 Cost of steer in spring 25.44 Cost of steer in spring 25 44 24.08 24 17 25 07 24 99 23 89 24.08 24 17 25 07 24 l&gt;9 23 89 Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in gpring 4.40 Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in spring 4.40 1 4.92| 4.72J 4 41 4.34 4.67 4.92| 4 72 4 41 4.34 4.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Table 2. Period 2, First Summer. April 21, 1907, to October 31, 1908. I 'ling steers on pasture after being wintered on rations indi - cated in Table 1. Each lot contained 18 steers. There toeie 198 days in the period. Lot No 12 3 4 5 6 E rations fed previous Alfalfa Alflf Prairie Alfalfa Alflf Prairie Forage rations fed previous winter e °- -£■• £ 5 Alfalfa Alfalfa Average first weight, lbs 578 first weight, lbs 578 489 512 568 576 511 489 512 568 576 511 Average last weight, lbs 785 last weight, lbs 785 726 742 748 758 745 726 742 748 758 748 Average gain, lbs 207 gain, lbs 207 237 230 180 182 234 237 230 180 182 234 1.22 1.19 93 .94 1.21 Average daily gain, lbs 1 .07 - daily gain, lbs 1 . 07 1.22 1.19 93 .94 1.21 Cost of summering - feed and interest 4.90 Cost of summering - feed and interest 4.90 4.86 4.87 4.90 4.89 4.85 4.86 4.87 4.90 4 89 4.85 Cost of steer in fall 30 34 Cost of steer in fall j 30 34 28 94 29.04 29 97 29 88 28.74 28 94 29.04 29 97 29 88 28.74 Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in fall 3.87 Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in fall 3.87 3.98 3.91 4.00 3 94 3 86 3.98 3.91 4.00 3.94 3.86 Itive gain, per cent 81 ; 100 97 76 76 99 of pasture $4.09 $4.09 $4 09 $4.09 $4.09 $4 09 of pasture per 100 lbs. n 1.97 1.72 1.76 2.26' 2.19 1.74 of steer in spring 25.44 24.08 24.17 25.071 24.99, 23.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Table 3. Period 3, Second Wintxr. October 31, 1908, to March 31, 1909 rparatiie values of alfalfa, prairie hay, and cane and ■ binations of these for wintering yearling steers. Lot I &lt;&lt;&gt;n tained 17 steers; the other lots 18 steers each. There were 150 days in this period. Lot No 1 3 4 5 6 a A l f _ a i fa Alfalfa P £™ Prairie Cane and. -£d ha J hay uane prairie ana Forage rations Alfalfa hay Average first weight, lbs . . 785 Average last weight, lbs. 900 726 742 748 758 745 787 880 905 792 088 Average gain, lbs 115 Average daily gain, lb 76 38 L* 45 132 147 47 25L» .30 .88 98 .31 Relative gain, per cent .78 26 L* 31 90 100 32 Forage per steer during winter, lbs 4085 2481 3536 3590 4504 3150 Forage per steer per day, Forage per steer per day, lbs 27 16.5 20.3 23 9 30 Jl Loss 7850 2710 3120 6700 16.5 20.3 23 9 30 2\ Forage per 100 lbs. gain, lbs 3552 Forage per 100 lbs. gain, lbs 3552 Loss 7850 2710 3120 6700 Cost of feed for wintering steer $12 26 Cost of feed for wintering steer $12 26 $6 20 $7.07 $9.87 $11.26 $7 09 Loss 15.75 7.45 7.66 15.07 $6 20 $7.07 $9.87 $11.26 $7 09 Cost of feed for 100 lbs. gain 10.66 Cost of feed for 100 lbs. gain 10.66 Loss 15.75 7.45 7.66 15.07 Cost of steer in fall 30.34 Cost of steer in fall 30.34 28.94 29.04 29 97 29.88| 28 74 28.94 29.04 29.97 29.88i 28 74 Cost of wintering — feed and interest 13.02 Cost of wintering — feed and interest 13.02 6.92 7.80 10.62 12.01 7.81 6 92 7.80 10.62 12.01 7.81 35.86 36.84 40.59 41.89 36 55 Cost of steer in spring 43.36 Cost of steer in spring 43.36 35.86 36.84 40 59 41.89 36 55 Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in spring I 4.81| Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in spring I 4.81 5 21 4.68 4 61 4 63, 4 M 5.21 4 68 4 61 4.63 4 Kl • L Indicates loss. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Table 4. Period 4, Second Summer. March 31, 1909, to November 2, 1909. f year-old steers on pasture after being wintered on ration* indicated in Table S. Lots 1 and 2 contained 17 steers each; the other lots 18 steers each. There were 216 days in the experiment. 12 3 4 5 6 Lot No . Alfalfa Ai falfa Prairie Forage rations fed previous winter hay cane hay Average first weight, lbs Average last weight, lbs 900 688 787 I 880 I 906 930 985 | 998 1010 242 198 118 106 1 1022 Average gain, lbs. 122 1.21 .92 .55 .49 100 82 49 43 $4.09 $4.09 $4.09, $4.09 *4 Average daily gain, lbs Relative gain, per cent. .57 50 75 $4.09 $4.09 Cost of pasture . Cost of pasture per 100 lbs 3.35 43 36 1.69 2.07 3.47 3.89 35.86 36.84 40.59 41.89 2 26 3S 55 Cost of steer in spring . Coat of summering—feed and interest 5.64 49 00 5.38 5.41 5.54 5.59 41.24 42 25 46.13 47 48 5.40 Cost of steer in fall . Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in 479 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Table 5. Pkriod 5, Thikd Wintkb. November 2, 1909, to May 4, 1910. rparative values of alfalfa, prairie hay, and cane and com - binations of these for wintering tico-year-old steers. Lots 1 and 2 contained 17 steers each; the other lots 18 steers each. There toere 18S days in this period. Lot No 1 2 3 4 5 6 Alf^ fa Alfalfa P™ 1 ™ Forage ration. Alfalfa P £™ Average first weight, 985 998 1010 973 1022 930 1039 899 Ayerage last weight, 965 1083 1074 962 20 L* 85 64 11 L» Average gain, lbs .. 17 31 L* Average daily gain, lb .09| 16L* 10L» .46 .34 05L» Relative gain, per cent 20 3L« .2L* 100 75 Loss Forage per steer dur- ing winter, lbs 4606 4279 4992 5739 5654 4748 27.5 31.3 30.8 26.9 Forage per steer per day, lbs 26.1 23 3 Forage per 100 lbs. gain, lbs 27090 Loss Loss 6760 8834 Loss Cost of feed for win- tering steer $13.71 $1109 $10 89 $16.92 $14 63 $11 33 Cost of feed for 1001 ». gain I 81.27 Loss of steer in fall 49.00 4124 Loss 18.73 22.70 Loss 42 25 46 13 47 48 41 96 Coat of wintering — feed and interest .. I 15.20 12.36 1218 1733 15 98 12 61 Cost of steer in spring 64.201 53.59 54 43 63.46 63.46 54.56 5.64 5.87 5 90 5 67 Cost of steer for 100 lbs. in spring 6.171 5.96 I • L Indicates loss In weight. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska Table 6. Sub-Pkbiod BA, Winter Experiment. November 2, 1909, to March 18, 1910 Jyarative values of alfalfa, prairie hay and cane and com - binations of these for wintering two-year-old-steers. Lots 1 and 2 contained 17 steers each; the other lots 18 steers each. There were 1S6 days in this sub-period. LotNo 12 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa Alfal j a Prairie Forage rations Alfalfa P»£* Cane and hay cane Average first weight, lbs 1022 930 985 998 1010 973 Average last weight, lbs ... 1054 901 984 1157 1118 970 Average gain, lbs . . 32 29 L» 1 L* 159 108 3 L* Average daily gain, lbs 23 21L» Loss 1.16 -79 Loss Relative gain, per cent 20 Loss Loss 100 68 Loss Forage per steer dur- ing period, lbs . . 3595 3268 3981 4728 4643 3737 Forage per steer per day.lbs 26 24 29 35 34 27 Forage per 100 lbs. gain, lbs 11234 Loss Loss 2973 4300 Loss Cost of feed for win- teringsteer $10.79 $8.17 $7 96 $13.00 $11.61 $8.41 Cost of feed for 100 lbs. gain 3370 Loss Loss 8.18 10.75 Loss Cost of steer in fall .. 49.00 41.24 42.25 46.13 47.48 41.95 Cost of wintering- feed and interest. .. 11.90 9.10 8 92 14.05 12.69 9.34 Costof steer in spring, March 18 60 90 50.34 51.17 60.18 60.17 51.29 Coat of steer per 100 lbs. March 18 5.77 5 58 5.40 5.201 5.41 5.28 * L Indicates loss. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska 15 Table 7. Sub-Pebiod 6B, Spring Experiment March 18, 1910, to May 4, 1910. rrd of steers fed alfalfa and prairie hay after being wintered on rations indicated in 5A. Lots 1 and 2 contained 17 steers each; the other lots 18 steers each. There were 47 days in this sub period. 901 984 1157 1118 970 899 965 1083 1074 962 Average first weight, lbs. . . . 1054 Average last weight, lbs 1039 Average loss (shrinkage), lbs. 15 Average daily loss, lbs 2 19 74 44 8 .04 4 1.5 .9 15 M Forage per steer during pe- $2.92 $2.92 $2 92 $2.92 $2.92 50.34 51.17 60.18 60.17 51 29 Cost of steer March 18, 1910 .. 60.90 Cost of spring keep — feed and interest 3.30 3 25 3.26 3 28 3.29 3.27 ■ of steer in spring, May 64.20 53 59 54 43 63 46 63.46 54.56 Cost of steer per 100 lbs. in spring 6. 17 5 96 5 64 5 87 5 90 5.67 ,otNo 'orage rations All lo ts ran t ogethe r, fed p rairie h ay and fl, lbs 1 ;« per steer per day, lbs. . of feed per steer, Period 1011 1 21.5 $2 92 1011 21.5 $2.9! I ■ 1011 1 21.5 $2.92 1011 21 5 $29: 1 &gt; 12 1011 1 21.5 $2.92 * </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska Table 8. Period 6, Third Sumkkk. Ma; 4, 1910, to August 5, 1910. tie-year-old steers on pasture after being wintered on rations indicated in Table 5. Lot 1 contained 16 steers, Lot 2, 17, and the other lots 18 steers each. There were 92 days Brable 1 gives the record from December 31, 1907, to April 1908. Table 2 gives the record from April 21, 1908, to October 31. Table 3 gives the record from October 31, 1908, to March 31. Table 4 gives the record from March 31. 1909, to November in 'iix pcnot. 1 1 2 3 4 5 • »;e rations fed previous Alfalfa Prairie hay Cane Prairie LTerage first weight, lbs iverage last weight, lbs Lverage gain, lbs Lverage daily gain, lbs telative gain, per cent lost of pasture !ost of pasture per 100 lbs. lost of steer in spring, May 4 . !ost of summering— feed and Sost of steer in fall, August 5 . !ost of steer per 100 lbs. in 1039 1215 176 1.91 84 $2 17 899 1092 193 2.09 92 $2.17 965 1175 210 2 28 100 $2.17 1063 1074 1232 1251 149 177 1.61 1.92 71 84 $2.17 $2.17 962 1164 202 2.20 96 $2.17 1.22 64.20 1.12 53.59 1.03 54.43 1.46 1.23 63 46 62.46 1.07 54.56 3.15 67.35 9 QQJ 56^58 3.00 57.43 3 14 3.13 66.60 65.59 3.01 57.57 6.541 I .IK 4 88 5.40 5.24 494 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 V fable K gives the record from November 2. 1JH»!&gt;. to March 1910. Table 7 gives the record from March 18, itlO, to May 4. IMM Table 8 gives the record from May 4. 1910. to August ."&gt; It should be noted thai Tables ti and 7 cover the same time Fable 5. There was a change in the conditions on March »f the third winter. Tables i\ and 7 show the difference in two parts of the period covered by Table ."&gt;. In Table .1 -periods 5A and 5B are combined. During Sub-period 5B steers all ran together and were fed alfalfa and prairie hay i favored the lots that previously had not been fed alfalfa hat it furnished them a new and letter kind of forage than were to have received. Irhe chief disturbfng factor, brought about by the unavnid change made at the end of Sub-period 5 A. was in the nkage on the fleshier lots during Sub-period SB. However this change was a disturbing factor it did not affect the 1 results sufficiently to cause any appreciable change in the it or loss on the steer and in the relative standing of the ons. It was decidedly unfavorable to the steers fed rations taining alfalfa, and therefore favorable to those fornierh fed alfalfa. I We have compiled several tables from the preceding tables order to bring together in a more accessible form the sub s of chief importance, such as the increase in weight during iter and summer, the feed required for winter, the feed for His. of gain, the cost of feed for winter and for summer and 10(1 lbs. gain, the relative value of the forage rations, and illy the relative profit or loss resulting from the various ions and the profit or loss on all the steers during the entire eriment. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska Table 9. — Gains made by calves fed a light grain ration and forage during winter from December S. 1907, to April 21, 1908. Average gain .— per calf during Average daily r^^ in period * ain P er calf Kind of forage Pound* 132 125 Pound 94 ! Alfalfa and cane 90 Alfalfa and prairie hay Prairie hay and cane . . . Cane 117 .84 62 44 60 .43 Prairie hay 39 2S The grain ration was the same for all lots (Table 9). The difference in the gains can be attributed only to the difference can ihe forage rations. The steers fed a full ration of alfalfa alf alfalfa gained from 2 to 3£ times as much during the :er as those that did not have any alfalfa in their ration, lowest gain per calf waa 39 lbs. during the winter, or .28 lb. day from priarie hay, and the highest gain 132 lbs. during winter, or .94 lb. per day from alfalfa. The forage rations ng the first winter ranked in value, as indicated by the eas3 in weight of calves, as follows: alfalfa, alfalfa and &gt;, alfalfa and prairie hay, prairie hay and cane, cane, and rie hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Table 10. — Average gain in /munilx per day, per steer. I, study of Table 10, in which the daily gains of the various ods are brought together, indicates that the results of the e winter periods were similar. The steers getting alfalfa or alfalfa made fair gains, while those fed on prairie hay or ! or both of these made slow gains or lost flesh. The steers in 2, fed prairie hay, lost an average of .4 lb. per head daily ng the three winter periods. The steers fed cane, Lot 3, ng the same time gained .22 lb. per head daily; those on rie hay and cane, Lot 6, gained .23 lb. per head daily, while steers fed alfalfa, Lot 1, gained .59 lb. ; those fed prairie and alfalfa, Lot 4, gained .72 lb. and those fed alfalfa and gained .74 lb. The relative gains for the six periods are q in Table 11. I The low gain of Lot 1 (alfalfa) during the third winter has been accounted for fully. The difference in the appearance the lots indicated the results given by these figures. Why : 1 did not do better we are unable to state, but we are of opinion that the quality of the alfalfa was less favorable Winter Summer Lot : -. 1st 2d 3d Ave 1st 2d 3d Ave. Lb. Lb. Lb. Lb. Lbs. Lba. Lbs. Lb* I lfa .94 .76 00 .59 1.07 57 1.91 1 18 rie hay 28 25L* 16L» 4L» 1.22 1.21 209 150 s 43 30 .I0L* .22 1.19 .92 2.28 146 lfa and iriehayj .84 88 .46 72 93 .55 161 1.02 .lfa and e- 90 .98 .34 .74 .94 .49 1.92 1 12 rie hay I cane.. 44 .31 06L* 23 1.21 .84 2 20 1 42 rage. 64 .50 .10 41 1.09 .76 2 00 1.28 Average for all lots three summers, 1.28 lbs.; average for all lots three winters, .41 lb. * L indicates loss in weight. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska ti lot than to Lots 4 and 5, and also that alfalfa alone does ive as beneficial effect on steers reaching maturity as on er steers. During each winter, cane gave greater gains i loss than prairie hay. A combination of cane and alfalfa larger gains during the first and second winters than t and prairie hay, but during the third winter the opposite roe. On the average a ration of prairie hay and cane i slightly greater gain than either fed alone, but the ad - je of the combination was very slight. The average daily gain per steer for all lots combined was, during the first winter .64 lb., the second winter .50 lb. and the third winter .10 lb. The grain fed during the first winter would account for the gain being greater than during the second winter. The low gain of the third winter is partially due to the running of the lots together during the latter part of the period and the consequent shrinkage on the fleshier lots. How - ever, the gains during period 5A in the winter was only .3 lb. per steer per day. When all factors are taken into account, the daily gains are less during the third winter than during the second or first. RELATION OF SUMMER AND WINTER GAINS. When we turn to a study of the gains made during the summer, we find that the lots which made the faster gains din - ing the winter made the slower gains during the summer fol - lowing. The steers that went to pasture in good condition did not gain as much during the summer as those which went to pasture thin in flesh. The lots wintered on alfalfa or part alfalfa were no doubt fleshier in the spring than the steers of the average herd, and those not fed alfalfa were not as thin in flesh as the thin cattle of the average herd. None of the steers were so thin as to be weak. It is probable that during the first few weeks on pasture the fleshier steers lost more in weight than the thinner steers. Period 5B indicates this. The </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 relative summer gains of the six lots (Table 11) show that during two summers Lot 2, wintered on prairie hay, gained more than any other lot and that during the other summer Lot 3, wintered on cane, made the greatest gain. The average rela - tive gains for the year place the lots much more closely t« » gether than the summer or winter gains alone. Tho there wan a tendency for the steers poorly wintered to catch up to the others in weight during the summer, yet they were much lighter than the better wintered steers when put on the market. If the steers had been kept till fall before being sold, the weights of all lots might have been more nearly the same, but it is probable that the increase in weight on steers during the sum mer is largely made before August 1. I "he average daily gains of all lots for the three summers strikingly lacking in uniformity. During the first summer average daily gain per steer from April 21 to October 31 1.09 lbs. These steers were yearlings. During the second mer the average daily gain per steer for all lots from March o November 2 was .76 lb. The steers were then two years During the next summer, when the steers were 3 years the average daily gain per steer for all lots was 2 lbs. from 4 to August 5. I 'here are several reasons for lack of uniformity in the gains i during the three summers. The climatic conditions of the &gt;ns were not similar, and, as the acreage of pasture was :e.d. this affected the pasture. There was about the same ber of stock in the pasture each season, but during the two seasons a herd of 50 cows ran with the steers. There a division fence and another water system put in in the ag of 1910, and during the season the cows were kept rate from the steers. Eis probable that the 8 weeks of fastest gains are from 15 to July 15, or possibly a week or two later, depending e season. Another period of rather rapid gains is believed </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 by some cattlemen to be during September and October, after the flies have gone and when the weather is cool and the gniss mature. This was no doubt true during the time of unlimited range, but in the large percentage of pastures now the gi-ns* is short before fall and fast gains are not possible. As evidence of the truth of this the fact may be cited that it was not ■■ uncommon practice to ship "beef cattle from western Nebraska ranges 20 years ago that sold on the market at the same price as grain-fed cattle, but shipping "beef steers off grass has gone out of date because fat steers are no longer produced on the western Nebraska range as in the years gone by. This bears directly on the relative gains of these summers. Steel's on pasture during May, June, and .July should show a larger gain per day than steers on pasture from April 1 to November 1. The two-year-old steers made slower gains than the yearlings. but they were on pasture as late in the fall and a month earlier in the spring than the yearlings. It is quite probable that the month of April considerably reduced the daily average. The condition during the third summer was even more unfavorable. Practically all the pasture land was burned over March i2&lt;i. The steel's were held on forage till May 4, so that the pasture might have an opportunity to recuperate. Tho the grass was thin and short it may have been in condition to make faster gains during the early summer months than if it had not been burned. The steers were on pasture from May 4 to August 5. ;i short period favoring fast gains without any period of shrinkage. Another factor worthy of consideration is *hat in 1910 the spring weights were taken after the cattle had all run together in a field of several acres in extent for 47 days and had shrunk greatly. The shrinkage per steer in Lot 4 amounted to 74 lbs. It is probable that the spring shrinkage, which usually comes after the cattle are on grass, came this time before they were put in the summer pasture. Also during the first two seasons </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 I steers remained on pasture till the first of November. It robable that there was a shrinkage daring October and •ably no gain after September 15 tho we have no data to Inn this or disprove it. The three-year-old steers were ;hed August 5, and the experiment closed. Their summer od ended before the beginning of the fall shrinkage or the i of slow gain. On the other hand, the summer of 1910 was of the driest of any during the past 35 years and did not r growth of pasture. From these facts it is evident that gains of the three summers should not be considered as in tive of the relative gains that may be expected from steers hese different ages. Table 11. — Relative gains of steer for six periods, in cent. per using 100 per cent for the highest gains as a basis Lot No , 1 2 3 4 5 6 A" 8 "* Alfalfa Cane „_?!_:„ and Prairie hay and Forage rations... Alfalfa I^ ie P™ rie cane cane hay First winter 100 30 4o 90 &lt;Ju 47 Second winter 78 26L» M 90 100 ■ Third winter 20 3L» 2L»| 100 75 Lom Average 3 winters. 78 Loss 38 99 100 43 :&lt;s 99 100 43 First summer 81 , 100 97 78 7K 99 43 Second summer 50 100 82 49 75 Third summer 84 92 100 71 *4 *&gt; 69 91) Average3summers 75 100 95 91 A verage6 periods. 96 1 80 «&lt;9 98 100 H * L Indicates loss in weight. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 'tTO%O%HQ 1 6GQGT riteCTS %n Westertl PiGOra&amp;ICQ Table 12. — Weights of steers at beginning of experiment and end of each period. Lot No 1 1 * I 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa Alf)f Prairie Forage rations Alf^fi? Cane -ft. £* hay PF airie cane »» tendency of the thin steers to even up the weights by the end ; hay cane , Period 1 average Pound* Pound* founds Pound* , Poundt Pound* first weight. Dec. 3,1907 446 450 452 451 451 449 Period 1, average last weight. . Apr.21,1907 578 489 512 568 576 511 Period 2, average last weight Oct. 31,1908 785 726 742 748 758 745 Period 3, average last weight. ... Mar. 31. 1909 900 688 787 880 905 792 Period 4, average last weight. . Nov 2, 1909 1022 930 985 998 1010 973 Period 5, average last weight May 4,1910 1039 899 965 1083 1074 962 Period 5A, aver- age last weight. Mar. 18, 1910 1054 901 984 1157 1118 970 Period 5B, aver- age last weight. May 4,1910 1039 899 965 1083 1074 962 Period 6, average laat weight. Aug. 5, 1910 1215 1092 1175 [ 1232 1251 1164 The weights of the steers at the end of the period as giveu in Table 12 indicate the effect of the winter rations and the </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska 25 Table 13. — Forage eaten by steers during winter, in pounds per $teer. 12 3*56 Alfalfa Prairie Alfalfa*^ Cane Forage rations hay °* ne c*ne Pound* I Pound* Pound* Pound*] Pound* Pound* 139 days.. 1741 1480 1860 1690 1831 1578 150 days.. 4085 2481 3536 3690 4604 3150 Calves* Yearlings Two-year-olds 183 days.. 4606 ' 4279 4992 5739 5654 4748 . Total for 3 winters, in tons 5.21 I 4.12 5.19 5.62 5.98 i 4.73 ■ The calves were fed 280 lbs. of grain each during the winter or 2 of grain each daily. The amount of forage required by the different lota (Table 13) varied considerably. The steers that were fed cane usually required more pounds of forage than those on any other single kind of forage. The steers fed prairie hay ate less pounds of feed than those fed any other ration. There was a rather large percentage of waste in feeding the cane and almost no waste in feeding the prairie hay. The largest quantity of forage used by any lot was usually alfalfa and cane, but during the third winter the lot fed alfalfa and prairie hay ate more than the lot upon alfalfa and cane. Table 13, showing the amount of forage fed to the steers, varies in inexplainable ways. The waste when the feed was not of good quality may account for these variations in part, and it is probable that this waste at timer was greater than necessary. The waste was especially noticeabh with Lot 1 during the third winter, due to coarse and damaged alfalfa. At any rate this table shows the forage consumed with good feed racks and with care taken to feed all that the cattle would eat, and not to waste any feed unless it was coarse stems or stalks </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Growing Feeder flteers in Western Nebraska Table 14. — Forage eaten by steers during winter — pounds per steer daily. Lot No 1 2 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa.,. ,. Prairie Aver «*« Alf-fc^ Cane and ««• hay C8ne cane found* Pound* Pound* Pound* Pound* Pound* Pound* Average | 21.5 | 16.8 20.4 22 4 24.6 19 4 21.9 ■The calTea were fed 280 lbs. of grain each during the winter or i. of grain each daily. Ible 14 gives the forage eaten per steer daily. This shows the calves with a light grain ration were fed from 10.6 to lbs. of forage daily. Daring the second winter, with no l being fed, the forage eaten amounted to about twice as i as during the first winter. The forage eaten per day ag the third winter was not very much more than during second winter. The forage eaten per steer daily for the ; winters, taking the average of all the lots was, the first er 12.2 lbs., the second winter 23.1 lbs., and the third winter lbs., and the average for all lots during the three winters 21.9 lbs. per steer daily. COST OF GAINS. The amount of feed required for 100 lbs. gain or the cost of 100 lbs. gain when wintering stock cattle may be misleading. The carrying of the cattle thru the winter from one summer period of cheap gains to another summer period of cheap gains is of much more importance than the gain made during the winter, tho during a fattening period the gains are the all - important part. However, the gain made during the winter is of value in itself, especially when the owner markets the cattle wo-year-olds 12 5 27.0 25.1 10.6 16.5 23 3 13 3 20.3 27 5 12.2 23.9 31.3 13 2 30.0 30.8 11.4 21.0 25 9 12.2 23.1 27.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">XrTQXCXflQ rQGCLQT HtCCTS IH ft G9i€Vtt A €bt'(lSiCO 27 in the spring, and may indicate the condition and vigor of the animal due to the forage upon which it has been wintered. Th« - forage required for 100 lbs. of increase in weight varies greatly when only roughage is fed, as much the larger part of the feed is used in maintaining the body of the animal. One noticeable feature with the lots of steers was that the increased weight of the heavier lots over the lighter in the spring was largely flesh rather than frame. While the lighter lots often lost weight during the winter, the loss was in flesh and they continued to develop frame tho losing in total weight. The loss of flesh and of weight during the winter is. on the whole, not economical, and methods of wintering should he worked out which not only will be cheap but will permit the animal to gain in weight. rl5. — Feed required for 100 lbs. increase in weight with steer 8 during the winter. I fable 16 gives the cost of feed for 100 lbs. of gain on each during each winter. Where there was a loss in weight, no mpt has been made to estimate the cost of the loss. The res indicate that gains made during the winter on stock le are very expensive. This is due to the increase in weight ig made, slowly on expensive feed. This table indicates rly that the selling price in the spring must be much above t in the fall if the steers pay for the feed eaten during the ter with the rations used. .ot No 3 5 = Alfalfa Prairie hay Cane Alfalfa and prairie hay Alfalfa and cane Prairie hay and - Pound* Pound* Pound* Pound* Pound* Pound. lahre8 l forage... 'earlings, forage, •wo-year-olds, 212 1312 3852 27090 I 717 3797 Loss Loss 467 3100 7850 Loss 239 1448 2710 6750 224 1464 3120 8834 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska Table 16. — Cost of feed for 100 lbs. gain on steers during each winter. Lot No 1 2 I 4 5 6 Alfalfa and cane Alfalfa and cane Prairie and prairie Forage rations Alfalfa Cane hay hay First winter . . Second winter Third winter . $6 01 $17.46 Loss Loss $10.74 15 75 $6 63 7 45 $6.15 18:8 10 66 7 66 81.27 Loss 18.73 22 70 I^hese figures have very little relation to the cost of the steers hundred in the spring, since the entire cost of wintering a r may be charged againet a very small gain. The increase in weight during the summer was made three times faster (Table 10) than during the winter. These gains are also much cheaper as shown by Tables 16 and 17. The cost of the summer gain depends largely upon the conditions under which the steers are pastured. Renting pasture on the usual terms prevailing is cheaper than owning the land. In the Sand Hills area, and in other parts of western Nebraska where it is not deemed advisable to crop more than a small proportion of the land, pasture is still cheap, but in the farming sections pasture for growing cattle can not be considered cheap, when the cattle are charged with interest on the money invested in the land; at least it can not be considered "cheap" in the sense that this word has been applied to pasture in western Nebraska. Under the conditions on the Substation farm and in the country adjacent to North Platte and probably thruout a large part of the hard land areas of western Nebraska, the cost of summer pasture for a steer will not be far from the charge we have made, where the owner has title to the land. This charge is fi per cent inter eat on 8 acres of land valued at $8.00 per acre plus 25 cents for </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 years. In many places this charge may be reduced because of a lower valuation on the land, but even in the Sand Hills area there is but little land valued at less than $4.00 per acre, and here the acreage per steer required is much more than that used in the estimate above. If there is much winter pasture it will probably be outBide of the acreage pastured during the sum mer. Table 17 gives the cost of 100 lbs. gain of the six lots. when each steer is charged $4.09 per summer for pasture and water. Table 35 gives the cost of 100 lbs. gain if these steers were charged for pasture at prices ranging from 25 cents to 75 cents per month. (Page 46.) tE 17.— Cost of 100 lbs. gain on steers on pasture during each summer — pasture at $4-09 per steer. 1 2 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa A , f . f Prairie °- .as* 1ST » 5 A £ r " hay cane cane Alfalfa*™™ Winter rations hay Yearlings $1.97 $1.72 3.35 1.69 1.22 1 12 $176 $2.26 $2.19 $174 $190 2 07 3.47 3.89 2 26 2.70 Two-ye*r-olds . . Three-year-olds 1.03 146 1.23 1.07 1.19 Average i $2.18 $151 $1.62 $2.40 $2.44 $1 69 $1 93 Table 18. — Cost of feed per head for wintering steers in this experiment. Lot No 1 * S 4 5 6 -^•J** Alfalfa Pj* 1 " 6 hay cane Forage rations .... Alfalfa P ££ ie Calves $8.38 $6.81 $6.83 $777 $7.68 $6.66 UUTOB fO.OO #U.O1 fU.Od #|.ffl fl.W fW.W Yearlings 12.26 6.20 7.07 9.87 11.26 7.09 X TCU11UKB 16. uki \j . au 1 ,ui v . \jt *■ * .am 1 • w Two-year-olds. 13.71 1108 10.89 15.92 14.53 1133 Total $34.90 1 $24.10 $1479 $3354 "$38.48 $15.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Table 18 shows the cost of feed for wintering steers at the prices charged for forage and grain in this bulletin. The farmer or stockman often has the forage and the grain so far from market that the market value has little or nothing to do with his operations. Under such conditions he should consider the value of the feed at the price it costs him to produce it. He will not be counting any profit on the selling price of the forage but all his profit will come from the steers. But the man who is within reach of market points should count his feed at the price it will net him on the market. He may then find that the steer does not give a return above the market value of the feed, but if the steer pays the market value for the feed he is not causing the owner any loss. The farmer may think he can winter his cattle at much less expense than the figures in Table 17 indicate, but after he has used the products that he could not otherwise convert into money he will find that the cost will be approximately as indicated if he charges the values used in making up these figures. The above table gives the cost of feed eaten by the steers each winter. The total cost of wintering lV« |,Xaa|m. O Vl fill 1 /I O 1 O/\ 1 Y1 / * 1 1 1 /I O 1 Tl f'OPOQ^ #~\T1 v TIYTIID^TTIDTI t </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 Table 19. — Cost* of steers at the beginning of the experiment, and at the close of each period. Lot No 12 3 4 5 6 Prairie Alfalfa *£?* Forage rations Alfalfa P ™ ne Cane «* and bay I The "cost" as used In this table is arrived at as follows: The first at the beginning of the experiment values the steer at $3.75 per lbs. To this first cost there is added at the end of the lirst period r cent interest on the money invested and the cost of the feed eaten he prices quoted on page 6. The amount thus secured is considered cost at the beginning of the second period. The cost at the end of second period plus 6 per cent interest on that cost during the period, ; the cost of the feed during the period, gives the cost at the end of period. The cost at the end of the other periods is arrived at in the e manner. Table 19 shows that the lots fed alfalfa or part alfalfa had a greater expense account to settle than those not fed alfalfa, but they also had more weight than the other lots with which to offset this account. They would also have commanded a higher price per 100 lbs. on the market, due to the better con - dition of flesh. K Table 20. showing the price per 100 lbs. at which the steers Id have to sell in order to pay the account against them, I nearly shows the true condition. tst = si , . , . \ beginning $16 73 $16 88 enod * j close 25.44 ; 24.08 'eriod 2, close 30.34 28.94 'eriod 3, close 43.36 35.86 ■eriod 4, close 49.00 4124 •eriod 5, close 64.20 53.59 'eriod 6, close 67.36 56.58 $16.95 24.17 29.04 36.84 42.25 54 43 57 43 $16 91 $16 91 25.07 24.99 29 97 29 88 40.59 41.89 46.13 47.48 63.46 63.46 66 60 , 65.59 28.74 36.55 41.95 54.56 6757 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Table 20. — Cost of steer per 100 lbs., including purchase price, interest and feed from date of original purchase, December 1907, to marginal date. Fall. Lot No 1 2 3 4 5 6 Spring. Lot No 1 2 3 4 5 6 SsT Forage rations. Alfalfa P^* e Cane hay 9 -a April 21, 1908 $4.40 ' $4.92 $4.72 $4.41 $4.34 $4.67 4.61 4.63 4.61 5.87 5.90 5.67 March 31, 1909. ... 4.81 5.21 4.68 4,1910 6.17 6.96 , 5 64 Bhe prices given in this table are ate that the steers pat on the above market values and &gt;t would not have market id their account in full. The cost per 100 lbs. rose each g higher than each preceding spring and higher each fall the preceding fall. This rise is magnified because the i were being charged more for feed than their market value inted. However, Tables 24 to 31, inclusive, which give each 1 without any relation to the other periods, indicate the in the main. The gains of the second summer cost more those of the third summer because of reasons already noted ding the pasturing season. The low cost of summer gains p to fast gains on cheap feed. 'orage rations. . . . Alfalfa Prairie hay Cane s i . j _ I Eber3,19O7.. r 31, 1908 . . ber2,1900. t 5, 1810... $3.75 3.87 4.79 5.54 $3.76 3.98 4.43 5.18 $3.75 3.91 4.29 4.88 $3.75 4.00 4 62 5 40 $3.75 3.94 4.70 5 24 $3.75.2 W </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 Iv studv of the gains made by the six lots during the differ periods and years, and the rank that these give the various ge rations, is very interesting and instructive. During the :er the steers getting alfalfa or part alfalfa made larger s than those getting no alfalfa, while in the summer the )site was true, but at the end of each year the steers fed lfa had gained more than those not fed alfalfa. The follow tables give the data for this statement in detail : Table 21. — Relative standing of various forage ration* as shown in pounds of gain daily per steer during winter. Calves Yearlings Two- year-olds c c c 1906-06» -a 1908-10 a 6 c Lb*. Lb. Alfalfa andprai- N riehay. . . .46 Alfalfa 88 and cane. 34 and cane 1.20 Alfalfa rie hay . 1 . 14 .76 Alfalfa.. .08 Prairie hay and .31 cane 06+ .31 Cane 10t Prairie Prairie ■.... .66 .... .39 28t hay 16t * The data for these years are taken from Bulletin 105. 1907-08 •§ 1906-07* | 1908-09 L6. " Alfalfa Alfalfa \lfalfa . .94 and cane. .76 and cane Alfalfa Alfalfa andprai- andcane. .90 Alfalfa... .68 riehay . Alfalfa Alfalfa andprai- and prai- rie hay. .. .84 rie hay.. .51 Alfalfa.. Prairie Prairie hay and Prairie hay and cane 44 hay 15f cane Cane 43 Cane 53f Cane Prairie Prairie bay 28; i hay </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 e daily gains of steers during summer that on the different forage rations indicated. Table 22.—. — Relative wintered c were Yearlings Gains Two-year-olds Gains Three-year-olds Gains Lb*. Lbs. Lbs. Prairie hay 1.22 ; Prairiehay 1.21 Cane 2.28 Prairie bay and Prairie hay and 1.21 Cane .92 cane 2.20 and cane Prairie hay and 1.19 cane 84 Prairie hay 2.09 ask 1.07 Alfalfa 57 Alfalfa and cane . 1.92 Alfalfa and prai - .94 rie hay 66 Alfalfa 1.91 Alfalfa and cane . Alfalfa and prai- Alfalfa and prai- rie hay . When we consider the summer gains made by the six lots, we find that the steers wintered on prairie hay made the largest gains two times out of three and those wintered on cane made the largest gains once. Those wintered without alfalfa always made larger summer gains than those wintered on alfalfa or a ration one-half alfalfa. Table 23. — Relative standing of various forage rations as shown by the gains made by the steers during the year — winter and summer. 00 00 00 5 Second Year 3 Third Year | Total Gains First Year o o a Lb$ Lb* Lb* Lb* Alfalfa and Alfalfa and! Alfalfa and cane |241 cane 800 |339 cane 252 Alfalfa and Alfalfa and Alfalfa and Alfalfa and prairie hay. 234 prairie hay. 781 307 prairie hay. 250 Alfalfa and prairie hay 297 Prairie hay Cane 243 Prairie hay 296 Alfalfa 237 and cane and cane ... 191 Cane 723 Prairie hay Prairie hay Cane 290 and cane ... 228 Cane 190 and cane ... 715 Prairie hay . 276 Prairie hay ... 204 Prairie hay... 1 162 Prairie hay ... 643 .83 [I Alfalfa and cane, i .48 \ rie hay 1.61 Alfalfa 193 Alfalfa 769 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 Table 23 shows that the total gain for each year was more for those fed alfalfa or a ration one-half alfalfa than for those not fed any alfalfa. From this it is evident that alfalfa gave better results than no alfalfa during each year, with the ex - ception of one lot in the second year, and that, tho the financial statement shows a greater financial loss with the lots fed alfalfa than with those not fed alfalfa, that only means that for this experiment the relative assumed price for alfalfa was too high. i fables 24 to 31 inclusive give the results of each winter and mer period without any relation to any other period. The r is charged at the beginning of a winter with his weight ed at $3.75 per 100 lbs. and at the beginning of summer od at $4.25. To this is added 6 per cent interest for the od on his valuation at the beginning of period and the cost he feed or pasture. These tables show the profit or loss ing each summer and each winter, with the values assumed feed and cattle. Table 24. — First winter account — market values — cohrs. December 3, 1907, to April 21. 1908. .otNo 1 2 3 4 5 forage rations . . . Alfalfa i P j£ rie Cane Alfalfa and prairie hay Alfalfa and cane I lvalue of steer in fall at $3.75.... $16.73 $16.88 Dost of feed 8.33 6.81 interest on invest- Dost of steer in spring 25.44 24.08 Value of steer in spring at $4.25.. 24.57 20.78 Loss per steer dur- ing winter 87 3.30 Value of steer in fall per 100 lbs.. 3.75 3.75 Dost of steer in spring per 100 $16.95 6.83 .39 24.17 21.76 2.41 3.75 $16.91 7.77 .39 ; 25.07 24.14 .93 3.75 $16.91 7.69 .39 24 99 24.94 M 4.34 I </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska 36 Table 24 shows a loss during the first winter on each lot. This loss is greater as the steer becomes older and as the winter gain is less. The greatest loss during the first winter was with the steers fed prairie hay and the least loss with those fed al falfa and cane. In order to have balanced their account the steers fed prairie hay would have been obliged to sell for 58 cents more per 100 lbs. than those fed alfalfa and cane, tho the former were so much thinner than the latter that they would have sold on the market for probably from 25 to 50 cents less per 100 lbs. The lots costing the most for wintering would have settled their account more easily in the spring than the lots costing the least during winter. The 50 cents more allowed as the selling price in the spring above the selling price in the fall was not enough to pay for the feed eaten and interest on the money invested in the steer. When the price in the fall was 50 cents less than in the spring the steers often failed to pay the summer expense. In Period 1, the price would have been |1.17 with Lot 2, and 59 cents per 100 lbs. more with Lot 5 in the spring than in the preceding fall if the steers paid for only the feed and interest. The difference in price would have been miifh irrpfltpr dnrincr the third winter. uiuv.ia g»i^«»i.^.» ***** u^ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 Table 25. — First summer account — market value* — yearlings. April 21, 1907, to October 31, 1908. Lot No 1 Winter rations . Alfalfa Prairie hay Value of steer in spring at $4.25. . $24.57 Cost of pasturing steer | . 4.09 Interest on value of steer at 6 per cent .79 Cost of steer in the fall 29.45 Value in the fall at $3.75 29.44 Profit during sum- mer per steer . . . Loss during sum- mer per steer ... .01 Value of ste«r in spring per 100 lb... .. 4.25 Cost of steer in fall per 100 lbs . ...| 3.76 $20.78 4.09 83 25.70 27.23 1.53 4 25 3.54 3 4 5 Cane Alfalfa and prairie hay Alfalfa and cane Prairie,, hay and; cane } 31.76 $24.14 $24 48 $21.72 4.09 4.09 4.09 4. OS .70 .78 79 7G 26.55 29.01 29 36 26.51 27.83 28 05 28 43 2794 1 28 1.43 96 93 4.25 4.25 4.25 4 25 3.58 3.87 3.87 3.69 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">.75 $29.44 $27.23 $27.83 $28.06 $28.43 A 12 26 I 6 20 7.07 9.87 11.26 Bstment 74 .68 .70 ! .70 71 .70 of steer in ig 42.44 34.11 36.60 38.62 40.40 35.73 I 4 n 1 3.75 3.75 3.75 3.75 4.38 4.41 a a Km steer uur- winter...... 4.19 r\f ctcor in Eoi steer in per 100 lbs.. 3.75 of* steer in no- npr 100 3.7£ </seg>
            <seg id="p039">rteer in .i. *J OK *oq OK *OQ O * *QQ 4R • Q'7 Jft «QQ 4ft steer.. 4.09 4.09 4.09 4.09 4.09 \ 4.09 r\c • r%s\ in I . I . 3. ) 1.80 5.42 6.04 2 46 398 i.ZU 4 3S ! *.iw l&amp;u ai* to. in ov.tjo «n-uu Profit during sum- mer per steer ... 50 Loss during sum- mer per steer. .. 5.38 Value of steer in 9U1II1K WVl 1W lbs. . 4.25 4.25 Cost of steer in fall per 100 lbs. 4.27 3.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">fall at $3.75. r* i _* * j .... « m fallat$3.75 $38.33 $34.88 $36.94 $37.43 $37.88 $36.49 Costoffeed 13.71 11.09 10.89 , 15.92 14 53 ! 11.33 Interest on invest- mentat6percent: 1.17 1.05 1.13 1.14 1.16 1.11 Cost of steer in spring | 53.21 47.02 48.96 54.49 ! 53 57 48 93 Value of steer in spring at $4.25 44.16 38.21 41.01 46 03 45.65 40 89 Loss during win- ter per steer ... 9.05 8.81 7.95 8.46 ! 7.92 8.04 Value of steer in fall per 100 lbs.. 3.75 3.75 3.75 3 75 3.75 3.75 Cost of steer ini spring per 100 1m 1 5.12 6.23 5.07 5.03 4.98 5.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">— fallat$3.75 $3833 $3488 $36.94 $37.43 $37.88 $36.49 Hn.t. nf f»»r! 1 fl 7Q Q 17 7 Oft 13 IW 1 1 fti B 11 ent tsi /» hz .oo in ■nrincat, ti 2fi U SO »A 9fl 41 85 10 17 17.52 11 ing winter ... 5.19 j 5.55 3.90 2.11 2.82 4 49 Value of steer in fall p«r 100 lbs*. 3.75 3.76 3.75 3.75 3 75 3.75 Cost of steer in two " . </seg>
            <seg id="p042">as Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska Table 30* — Spring account — market values — three-year-old steers. March 18, 1910, to May 4. 1910.T Lot No 1 2 3 4 « Alfalfa Alfalfa Prairie Perorations.... Alfalfa P £f Cane «£ Jj hay Value of steer in spring at $4.26. $44.80 $38.29 $41.82 $49.17 $47.52 $4123 Cost of feed 2.92 2.92 2.92 2.92 2.92 2.92 Interest on value of steerat 6 percent .35 .30 35 .39 .37 35 Cost at end of 5B . . 48.07 41.51 45 09 52 48 50.81 44.50 Value at end of 5B at$3.75 38.96 33.71 36.19 40 61 40.28 36.08 Lossduring Period 5B 9.11 7.80 8.90 11.87 10.53 8.42 Value of steer in spring per 100 4.25 4.25 4.25 4 25 4 25 4 25 Bof steer per lbs. at the end 'eriod 5B 4.62 4 61 4 67 4 84 I 4.73 4.62 ■ Tables 29 and 30 coyer the same time as Table 28, dividing the time the two Sub-periods before and after March 18. t After the prairie fire on March 26, all lots of steers ran together and were fed alfalfa and prairie hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Table 31. — Third summer account — market values — three-year - old steers. May 4, 1910, to August 5, 1910. fable 32 shows the amount that should be added to the fall » of the steer to secure a spring selling value that would for the feed eaten and interest on money invested in the during the winter. The average rise in value per 100 lbs. of all the lots during the winter, in order that the winter feed and interest on the steer would have been paid, would have been 82 cents for the first winter. 83 cents for the second winter, and fl.33 for the third winter, or, for all lots for the three winters, 99 cents. That is, taking the average selling price in the fall as $3.75 per 100 lbs., then the steers would have sold necessarily for 99 cents per 100 lbs. more, or $4.74, to have paid interest on the money invested in them during the winter and the value of the feed Lot No 1 2 Winter rations Alfalfa Prairit hay Value of steer in spring at $4.25.. $44.16 Cost of pasture per steer 2.17 I nterest on value of steer 68 Cost in the fall per steer 4701 Value in the fall at $3.75 45.59 Loss during sum- mer per steer ... 1.42 Value of steer in spring per 100 lbs 4 25 Cost of steer in fall per 100 lba 3 .87 $38.20 2.17 .59 40.96 40.95 .01 4 25 3 75 .i B Cane Alfalfa and prairie hay Alfalfa and cane 1 41.01 $46 03 $45.66 ■ M. 2.17 2.17 2.17 U 63 .71 69 M 43.81 48.91 48.51 ... 43.40 46 20 46.93 41 2 07 1.58 * 4 25 4 25 4 . ■ Ul 3.73 3.97 3.88 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Grouting Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska Table 32. — Price steer must sell at in spring per 100 lbs. above a fall cost of $8.75 per 100 lbs. to pay for winter feed and interest on fall valuation. 4 5 6 P™ lne cane and *** cane 97 JO. 66 $0.59 ! 10.92 $0 82 77 .63 .71 I .76 .83 132 1.28 1.23 1.33 1.33 1.02 .86 .84 1.00 .99 which steer may sell in the fall below a spring cost of $4.25 per 100 lbs. and pay for pasture at $4.09 per steer per summer and interest on spring valuation of steer. Lot No. 12 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa Alfalfa Prairie Alfalfa*™* Cane p^£ $ A^er- Winter rations . hay cane Yearlings. $0.50 (0.71 $0.67 $0.38 I $0.38 $0.56 $0.53 .32 .04* 10» 25 : .16 .52 .28 .37 .50 : 42 .50 .21 .22 .44 i .37 Two-year-olds . Three-year-olds Average 3 falls. 02* .56 38 .50 25 .59 BThe fall selling price of these three lots would have been the amount ated above $4.25 per 100 lbs. in order to have paid for summer ire and interest. Table 33 shows the drop that may be permitted from ;i spring valuation of 94.25 per 100 lbs. and have the selling prior cover the spring cost of steer, interest on investment, and cost of summer pasture. This table indicates that usually a drop ■ot No 12 3 4 'orage rations Alfali Alfalfa *»"• Cane p »J hay i spring lints- spring year-olds — spring age 3 springs $0.66 $117 I $0.97 $0.« .96 1 20 .77 .« 1.37 1 48 132 1.2f .99 1.28 102 .81 Tabus 33.— Price c 4 which steer may sell </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 and pasture bill settled when the spring value is set at $4.25 per 100 lbs. In the fall of the second season Lot 1 would have had to sell for 2 cents, Lot 4 for 4 cents, and Lot 5 for 10 cents per 100 lbs. above the spring price in order to have paid for the summer expense. Aside from these the decrease that might have been permitted in the fall selling price below the spring price of $4.25 varied from 25 cents with Lot 6 in the second fall to 71 cents with Lot 2 in the first fall. The average decline that might have been permitted on the value of all the steers in Period 2 was 53 cents per 100 lbs.; in Period 4, 16 cents per 100 lbs.; and in Period 6, 42 cents per 100 lbs., — or the average for all steers for the three periods 37 cents per 100 lbs. That is, taking the average of all the steers for the three summers, if the purchase price in the spring were $4.25 per 100 lbs. and they were sold for 37 cents less per 100 lbs., or $3.88 per 100 lbs., in the fall, they would have paid interest on the money invested in them and the pasture bill. Table 34. — Price per 100 lbs. steers must sell for in the spring to pay for winter feed and interest on investment with a fall Table 34 shows the price that the steers of each lot would necessarily have sold for each spring in order to have paid for the feed eaten during the previous winter, charging the prices indicated for forage on page 6 and considering the steers worth $3.75 per 100 lbs. in the fall with interest on the investment. If a steer in Lot 1 cost $3.75 per 100 lbs. in the fall and sold for vahtation of $3.7o. (Compiled from Tables 24 to 31.) ■otNo 12 3 4 5 • Alfalfa rations.... Alfalfa P ™f Cane hay Alfalfa and cane I 'irst spring $4.40 $4.92 $4 73 $4.41 iecond spring ... 4.71 4.96 452 4.38 turd spring j 512 5.23 : 5.07 5.08 $4 43 4.46 4.96 01 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 10 in the spring of the first year, he would have paid his pnal cost, interest on this, and the value of the feed eaten, have accomplished the same, in the second spring he would e sold for (4.71 per 100 lbs. and in the third spring for $5.12. cost of the steer per 100 lbs. was higher each successive r^K 35. — With pasture at the follouHng price per head per month, these steers, if purchased at $4.25 per 100 lbs. in the spring, would have paid for pasturage, if sold at the folloic - ing price in the fall: First Summer. Lot No 1 2 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa Alfalfa Prairie Winter rations Alfalfa P ™" e Cane m *. and !»"J Aver " winter rations Aiiaiia , hay v * ue prairie * n " and age hay oane cane Taf — ££ ** cane Pasture, per month Pasture, per month 25«mt8 $3.32 $3.06 25eente $3.32 $3.06 $3.13 $3.42 $3.42 $3.11 $3.42 $3.13 $3.42 $3.42 $3.11 $3 42 35cenU j 3.39 3.15 35cenU 3.39 3.15 3 21 3.50 3.50 3.19 3.32 3.21 3.60 3.50 3.19 3.32 50cents 3.51 3.27 JSOcents 3.51 3.27 3 b3 3 60 3.61 3.31 3.44 3 b3 3.60 , 3.61 3 31 3 44 75 cento 3.70 3.48 75cente | 3.70 3.48 3 54 I 3 81 3.81 3 .51 3.64 3 54 3 81 3.81 3.51 3.64 Second Second Summer. 3 4 5 6 A^f e r ~ Summer. 3 4 5 6 A .!5J" Lot No 1 2 Pasture, per month Pasture, per month 25cents $3&gt;9 $3.31 25cents $3&gt;9 $3.31 $3.56 $3.86 $3.96 $3.61 $3.70 $3.56 $3.86 $3.96 $3.61 $3.70 35cents 3.95 3.37 35cent8 3.95 3.37 3.61 3.96 4.02 3.69 3 76 3.61 3.96 4.02 3.69 3 76 50centa 4.04 3.49 50cents 4.04 3.49 3.70 4.06 4.11 3.77 3 86 3.70 4.06 4.11 3.77 3 86 I 3.86 4.20 4.25 3.93 4 00 75eents 4.18 3 63 75cents 4.18 3 63 3.85 4.20 4.25 3.93 4.00 Third Summer. Lot No. 1 2 3 4 Pasture, per month 25 cents $3.76 $3.64 3.80 3.70 3.88 3.77 400 3 91 $3 62 $3 86 3.67 3.91 3.75 3 .98 3.87 4.10 $3.77 $3.65 $3.72 3.82 3.69 3 76 3.89 3.77 3.84 4.00 3 90 3.96 35 cents • 5 6 A^- </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 Table 35 gives the price that the steers should have !»••* n sold at in the fall to have paid for the summer pasture, count ing the cost of the steers in the spring at $4.25 per 100 lbs. ami charging a fixed price per steer per month for pasture. The pasture season is considered as six months. If a steer in Lot 1 cost $4.25 per 100 lbs. in the spring and the pasture bill were 25 cents per month for six months, the steer if sold in the fall at $4.32 per 100 lbs. would have paid the original cost and the pasture bill. The interest on the investment and insniain •»■ against loss are not counted in this calculation. Lot 6, yearling steers. Ration, prairie and cane hay. Photo, spring, 1909. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Table 36. — With pasturage at the price per month indicated in the margin the summer gains of the steers would have cost per 100 lbs. as follows: Eable 36 has been compiled to show the cost of 100 lbs. of on the several lots during each summer, charging for the ire a fixed price per month per steer of 25 cents, 35 cents, ;nts, 75 cents, and fl.00. This should give the farmer and 'IK8T lUMMEE. 1 2 3 rations Alfalfa P ™" e Cane I I 4 5 6 P^ y " e — £ne "■■ Pasture, per month 25cente $0.77 $0.68 $0.70 36centi 1.00 .96 .99 50eents 1 56 1.36 1.41 75cents 2.36 2.06 2.11 $1 .00 3.12 2.72 2.80 $0.90 $0.89 $0 69 $0.77 1 26 1.25 97 1.08 1.80 1.80 1.39 155 2.70 2.70 2.08 2 33 3.58 3.55 2 76 3 09 Second Summer L I I i i r~ LotNo 1 2 3 &lt; » • A jr Pasture, oer month - — — — raaiure, per iiiuuui 26cents $1.33 $0 70 $0 82 36cenU 1.85 .93 1.14 60cenU 2.68 1.29 1.58 75cente 4.00 2.00 2.45 $1.00 .... 6.30 27U 3 26 Pasture, per month $1.37 $1.55 $0.90 $1.11 1.91 2 15 1.24 1.53 2.64 2.97 1.73 2.13 4.11 4 62 2 70 3.31 5.47 614 1 3.60 4.64 Sllil Third Summer. -*&gt;tNo | 1 2 3 4 5 .ot No . 6 r Pasture, per month Scent* $0 92 $0.84 $0.77 $1.09 $0.92 »cent« 1.28 1.16 1.07 1.51 1.27 iOcenU 1.77 1.62 1.47 2.10 1.76 r 5cenU 2.76 2.51 2.31 3.26 2.80 SI. 00 3.70 3.34 3.07 4.33 I 3.64 $0.80 1.11 1.54 2.40 3.19 1.23 1.71 2.67 3.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska 49 stockman a more or less definite idea of the cost of summer gains under his conditions. The pasture season is considered as six months. The interest on the investment and insurance against loss are not counted in this calculation. Table 37. — Record of six lots of steers fed different forage rations during the winter and run together in a canyon pas - ture during the summer. There were 976 days in the esperi- December 3, 1907. to August 5, 1910. Lot No 1 2 3 4 5 6 Alfalfa Alfa]fa Prai. ie rations Alfalfa P £™ Cane and Average first weight, lbs 446 450 452 451 451 449 Average last weight, lbs 1215 1092 1175 1232 1251 1164 Average gain, lbs ! 769 642 723 781 800 715 Average daily gain, lb .78 Relative gain, per cent 96 (55 .74 80 .82 .73 80 90 97 100 ■ Feed eaten per steer during experiment, tons 5.21 (grain $3.11 Cost of feed forage 31.19 I pasture 10.35 5.21 4 12 5.19 5.59 5 99 4.73 $3.11 $3.11 $3.11 $3.11 $3.11 31.19 20.99 21.63 30.43 30.37 21 97 10.35 10 35 10 35 10.35 10.35 10.35 First value of steer at $3 . 75 ... I 16 . 73 16.88 16.95 16.91 16.91 16 81 Interest at 6 per cent on total investment (computed at end of each period) 5.13 4.59 4.75 5.08 5 11 4 72 Total cost at North Platte 66.51 55.92 56.79 65.88 65.85 56 90 Selling price per 100 lbs. at North Platte to balance ac - count 5.49 5 12 4.83 5.34 5.26 489 Omaha weight (North Platte weight less 3.1 per cent shrinkage) 1177 1068 1139 1212 1128 Bof shipping and selling, »1 per 100 lbs. Omaha $2.97 $3 20 $3.35 $3.41 $3.17 weight $3.31 Total cost of steer when sold . . 69 . 82 58.89 59.99 69.23 69 26 60.16 Kper 100 lbs. Omaha es - te 4.55 4 25 4.50 4.70 4.70 4.5q Value in Omaha at above price 53.45 44.97 51.26 56 12 56.96 50 7g Lobs Der steer 16 ¥7' 13 32 8 73 13 11 12 30 9.4 - *^*^^ r^ •**■"-'• - - I *w . «j 1 1 *** • **■■ * v " * -^0 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Grouting Fmdmr Steers in Western Xebraaka Table 37 gives the results of the entire experiment with six lots of 18 steers each, fed different forage rations during the winter and run together during the summer in a native grass pasture. The time covered is from December 3. 1907. to August The lots began with an almost uniform weight, but ended the experiment with a difference of 159 lbs. per head in favor of Lot 5, fed alfalfa and cane, over Lot 2, fed prairie hay. The increase in weight during the three years ranged from Ml Ib6. per steer in Lot 2 to 800 lbs. per steer in Lot 5. and averaged lbs. per steer for all lots. On the average, the yearly in - crease in weight per steer was 246 lbs. The increase in weight daily per steer ranged from .Go lb. in Lot 2 to .80 lb. in Lot ."&gt;. The rank of the forage rations as indicated by the total fail l&gt;er steer was as follows: alfalfa and cane, alfalfa and prairie Way. alfalfa, prairie hay and cane, cane, and prairie hay. The tons of forage eaten per steer varied from 4.12 of prairie hay to 5.99 of alfalfa and cane. There was more alfalfa required than prairie hay to winter a steer, but there was much more increase in the weight of steer from the alfalfa. IFhe total average cost of the feed per head for the three rs was f39.56. The lowest cost was 134.45 for the steers in 2. The interest on the investment is ordinarily not given consideration by the owner. In this table the interest is iputed at the end of each period on the cost of the steer at beginning of that period and these several amounts brought ?ther as the total interest on the investment. The interest the average steer during the entire experiment was $4.87. If we add together the first cost of the steer, the value of all feed eaten, and the interest on the investment, the total will give the entire cost of the steer. By this method, on August 5. 1910, the cost per steer ranged from $ 55.92 for those in Lot 2 to $66.51 for those in Lot 1. The average cost of each three-year-old steer on August 5 of the third summer was $61.32. This was at </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska 51 the time when the average weight was 1188 lbs. per steer. To have paid their cost at that date, they would have sold neces - sarily at $5.16 per 100 lbs. The net selling price at Omaha amounted to |4.29 per 100 lbs. on the North Platte weights. The exact profit or loss on the entire operation is rather difficult to determine. But we can arrive at it fairly accurately. The difference between home weights and Omaha weights was 3.1 per cent. That is, a steer of Lot 1, weighing 1215 lbs. at home after being in a corral over night without water, shrunk 38 lbs. before he was sold in Omaha. We therefore consider the weights of the steers of each lot to be the home weight less 3.1 per cent. The cost of shipping and selling was equal to 28.1 cents per 100 lbs., Omaha weights. This makes the cost of shipping and selling $3.23 per steer besides the shrinkage. The total cost of the steer when sold in Omaha includes the original cost of the calf in the fall of 1907, the cost of all feed, interest on cost of steer at end of each period, and the cost of marketing him. Calculating in this way, the average steer of Lot 1 when sold in Omaha had cost $69.92, and of Lot 2 $58.59. The price of the steers of the other lots ranged between these. The steers of each lot were put into a separate pen at the Stock Yards at Valley where a cattle salesman from Omaha placed an estimated selling value on each lot. Taking his valua - tion, which is given in Table 38, as the selling price, tho it was slightly below the actual selling price, we find that the steers of no lot paid all that they had cost. The heaviest loss was with the steers fed alfalfa. For reasons already mentioned we do not think that the loss on this lot should have been as much as the results of this experiment indicate, but we have no explana - tion to offer for the loss on the other lots. We believe these figures represent approximately the average result of keeping cattle under conditions similar to those under which these cattle were kept. The conditions were similar to those prevailing on the better </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 class of western Nebraska farms and ranches, except that these steers consumed no cheap or unmarketable forage to reduce their cost. The steers were not of uniform breeding or color, but were a good class of grades. The protection from storms, the water facilities, the pasture and the forage were certainly as favorable to profitable results as on the better managed farms. The forage is charged at a rather low figure, considering the value of land and the acreage necessary for a steer. We believe that the man keeping steers where he feeds hay worth the price charged in this experiment and pastures them in the summer time on grass that costs the price charged here will have approximately the same financial loss, unless he buys at a lower price or sells at a higher price. We are accustomed to think that it does not cost as much to raise a steer as is charged in this test, but if we will observe closely the wintering of cattle on many of the ranches we shall find that it is not un - usual to feed two tons of hay per head of cattle. The farmer will reduce this cost by feeding forage that, be - cause of its quality or of the distance from market, does not command the price charged in this bulletin. In so far as he does this he reduces the cost. The ranchman living a consider - able distance from market feeds hay that can not be put on the market because of the distance, and often pastures on land that he neither owns nor rents. However, there are not many cattle pastured in this manner now. But the man who feeds hay that he could sell at the price per ton in the stack charged in this bulletin is not making a profit from the steers. It would seem evident that under existing market prices the feeder cat - tle must be wintered on forage worth less than the ordinary market values. Where the owner of the cattle raises his forage, he may obtain a profit on the entire operation of growing forage and feeding it to steers, but the profit will come from the price charged for the forage. If the steers pay more than the cost of </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 the production of the forage, they give a profit. On the farm where there is more forage than would otherwise be used ami where it cannot readily be marketed, if the steer will consume it and give a fair return for it he is giving a profit. In the matter of net profit or loss there are many factors entering in to obscure the final result. These steers are charged market value for all they consumed. They required some at tention, but they left on the farm a large quantity of manure. If the value of this were known, we might find that the rteeri gave a profit in the end. It is difficult to determine which ration gave the most profit able results. The final result would indicate that cane gave the least loss and alfalfa the most. Even taking the final profit or loss as the determining factor, this would indicate only that the relative values assigned to the three kinds of forage were not correct. Alfalfa or combinations of alfalfa and other forage gave more pounds gain during the winter and during the entire time than a ration containing no alfalfa. This shows that alfalfa is a better forage for growing steers than prairie hay or cane. But for wintering steers that are to be marketed off grass in the fall, alfalfa is not worth as much more than prairie hay and cane as is charged in this bulletin when fed under these con- However, there arises the question of the relative amount of jwisture eaten by the various lots during the summer. The steer wintered on alfalfa did not gain nearly so much during the summer as the steer wintered without alfalfa. It may be that lie did not eat as much grass. In this case we have charged him with more than his purl (if the cost of pasture. SUMMARY. E^he steers that went on grass in the spring thin in flesh in - sed in weight faster during the summer than the steers that t on grass in good tlesli. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Steers wintered on alfalfa or a ration one-half alfalfa make iiuith faster gains during the winter than those wintered tm prairie hay or cane alone, but do not make as fast gains the fol lowing summer. Eteers wintered on a ration of alfalfa or one-half alfalfa make •ater gain during the winter and the summer following com I than steers wintered on prairie hay or cane alone. Kioth yearling and two year old steers lost weight when led ■ or a ration one-half cane and one half prairie hay. Steers alfalfa or a ration one-half alfalfa gained in weight during i winter. fhe value of cattle should be approximately |1.00 per IM more in the spring than in the preceding fall in order tli.it may pay for their winter feed. The value of cattle in the fall may be considerably lower than in the spring and the cattle still give a profit on the sum iner operation. The value of alfalfa in comparison with prairie hay or cam - is higher when fed to cattle that are to l&gt;e sold in the spring than when fed to cattle that arc to l&gt;e sold the fall following. fVith the prices used for feed and cattle in this bulletin it is profitable to produce steers for the feed lot. The price of cattle is too low in comparison with the market value of forage. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>