<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Studies on the Vitamin A Content of Cheese</title>
               <date value="18??">July 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 103 Studies on the Vitamin A Content of Cheese I. L. Hathaway and H. P. Davis Department of Dairy Husbandry LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JULY, 1938 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">SUMMARY The vitainin-A contents of twenty-two kinds of cheeses were studied by feeding these cheeses to rats whose body stores ol vitamin A had been exhausted by being fed a vitamin-A-deficient diet. Twelve experiments were made in which approximately 1100 rats were used. There was considerable variation in the vitamin-A content of the samples studied. The samples of cottage, Neufchatel, and Limburjjer cheeses had the lowest vitamin-A potency. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Studies on the Vitamin A Content of Cheese I. L. HATHAWAY "AND H. P. DAVIS Comparatively few studies have been made of the vitamin-A content i of cheese. According to some writers (3) there are probably eighteen distinct varieties of cheese although the names of more than four hundred kinds may be found in the literature. Since there are so many kinds, variations may occur in the vitamin-A content of this product. A lumber of factors might affect the«vitamin-A content of cheese. The vitamin-A potency of the milk from which the cheese was made, the amour it of fat in the cheese, the method of processing, the method of packaging, the method of storage, and the organisms used in the manu - facturing process may result in products of unequal vitamin-A potency. Since so many factors are involved, the correct vitamin-A value of a given kind if. cheese can probably be stated only after a large number of assays have been made. These studies were made, therefore, in order to con - tribute data which might be: used to arrive at the average vitamin-A values of this product. ''¦'..'¦ i : REVIEW OF LITERATURE Coik and Axtmayer (1) studied the vitamin-A content of pasteurized milk ;tnd whole-milk cheese which were produced in Puerto Rico. The milk was found to contain two units per cubic centimeter and the cheese 20 units per gram (approximately 9,080 units per pound). 1 Coivard and Morgan (2) reported that English Cheddar cheese con - tained 5,500 International units of vitamin A per 100 grams (approximately 24,970 I. U. per pound).; Mtrgah (5) studied the vitamin-A content of California cream cheese j (Cheddar type), Limburger cheese (from New York), and Swiss cheese (from Switzerland). From this study it was concluded that the California (¦ cream cheese and the Limburger cheese retained the vitamin-A content of ' milk in an unusually concentrated form, since rats fed daily one-half gram j portions of these cheeses recovered rapidly from vitamin-A deficiency. .(-. Under similar conditions one-gram doses resulted in normal growth but &#132; ophthalmia persisted to some extent. . j Rice and Munsell (6) reported studies which were made at Columbia I University. In these experiments ; it was found that American cheese,/ cream cheese, Parmesan cheese, and cottage cheese contained approximately 11,20Cy 22,400, 11,200, and -480 vitamin-A units per pound respectively. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURES Trie breeding stock were pied rats reared in our laboratory. The management of the colony .was the same as that outlined in a previousi study (4) except where otherwise indicated. The breeding stock was maint lined on the Steenbock Stock Ration composed as follows: lln his report no attempt has been.made to convert (he units reported by various authors to any one paricular unit. The,approximate relationship, as given by the board of trustees of the U. S. Pharmac ipoeia, is as follows: One Sherman unit ofvitamin A equals approximately 1.4 International units or 1.4 V. S. P. XI units, j , j . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">N'hBKASKA AcKL. EXP. STA. RESEARCH BULLETIN 103 Stock Ration 1 Villnw ccrn 76.0% Cirnuml alfalfa 2.0% l.msnil ml nn-al . . 16.0% Sodium chloride 0.5% Oiiclc cisrin 5.0% Gilcium carbonate 0.5% The materials were finely ground and then five per cent by weight of butter was added. In addition to this ration, the rats received fresh whole milk daily and head lettuce several times each week. The method used for the determination of the vitamin A was essentially the same as the U. S. Pharmacopoeia method for the vitamin-A assay of cod-liver oil (7). Male and female rats, 22 to 25 days old and weighing between 35 and 45 grams, were placed in individual cages which were equipped with false bottoms of 13 millimeter screen. These rats were ted a vitannn-A-free basal ration composed as follows: Basal Ration 1 CaM-in - 18% Corn starch 65% Salt mixture :1 4% Vegetable oil"' 5% Vc,t 8% All of the rats received distilled water to which iodine was added once each week. The rats were weighed weekly except near the end of the depletion period, at which time they were weighed daily. When the rats were depleted (7), after approximately five weeks, they were allotted into groups. As far as possible the litter mates were distributed throughout all of the groups. These groups were fed the \itamin-A-frec ration (negative control groups), the cheeses (experimental jiroups), or U.S. P. reference cod-liver oil (positive control groups) as the cource of vitamin A for eight weeks. The reference oil contained '.000 U. S. P. XI vitamin-A units per gram and 4.5 milligrams of this oil was fed weekly by means of a pipette to each rat in the positive-control group. The weekly allowance was fed in three doses. The cheese samples used in the first six experiments, those used in Experiment Vlll, and the sample of Edam used in Experiment IX were made in the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station creamery. The other samples were purchased locally. The samples were ground in a lood chopper, thoroughly mixed, and stored in fruit jars at 0° F. until led. Once each week a rat's weekly allowance of cheese was weighed into a bottle. This allowance was stored in an electric refrigerator at 38° F. and was fed in three doses during the following week. Twelve experiments were made in which approximately 1,100 rats were used. The results obtained are shown in Table 1 and the chemical analyses arc shown in Table 2. U. S. P. grade oil was used as a supple - ment to the basal ration in Experiment 1. Since the exact vitamin A potency of this oil was not known the vitamin A potency of the cheese ' I'urificil ciscin (So. 453) was obtained from (lie Casein Co. of America, New York City. It w.is extracted continuously for fnc days with 95 per cent ethyl alcohol and then heated for five il.u* in .in electric o\cn at 90° C. ' S.ih mixture No. 2 (7) was used. 1 \on-irr.idutc&lt;l yeast nnd 30 I) yeast (Fleischmann Yeast Co.) were mixed so that each pram of ihe dirt ciiniained H I. S. P. XI units of vitamin D. • The vesctaMe nil was "I'rimex" manufactured by Proctor and Gamble. : </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Vitamin A Content of Cheese fed in this experiment cannot be estimated. In the other experiments U. S. P reference cod-liver oil, containing 3,000 units of vitamin A. per gram, was used as a supplement to the basal ration. Since the gains made 1 y the groups of rats which were fed the cheeses' were not identical with those made by the reference oil groups, the vitamin A potency of the cheeses cannot be stated definitely. The estimated unitage is shown however. : Table 1. — Summary of the average gains in. weight of rats fed varioui ¦ cheeses as a source of vitamin A. Ay. wt. Approximate Rats whenfeeding Av.wt.at ; iTcpvi Sour :c of vitamin A in the source of end of "• v. s. I.AI group vitamin A experiment gain omtsot began vltamlnA ¦ ¦ • . - per pound Grtms No. Grams Grams Grams Experiment I 0.3 Ncifchatel ........ 20 103.6 167.1 63.5 0.3 Ch:ddar (Wis. type) 20 107.7 164.3 56.6 0.3 Criam ...:...:... 19 107.0 162.2 57.2 .... Positive control 1....,. 8 94.0 180.1 86.1 Ncjjat ye control -..... 5. | 87.0 66.23 Died .... Experiment II 0.2 Chrddar (Wis. type) 16 110.1 197.0 86.9 10,896 0.3 Ch:ddar (Wis. type) 16 105.1 196.1 91.0 0.4 Ch:ddar (Wis. type) 17 116.2 213.1 96.9 .... 0.2 Cr^arn ........... 16 J 107.2 191.0 83.8 10,510 0.3 Criam .-.¦.'.: 18! 112.2 202.7 90.5 .... 0.4 Criam ..:. 18 | 115.8 209.5 93.7 PositWc control-*.....: 10 j 111.2 151.9 40.7 .... Neyat ye control 2 16 I 98.7 69.5 3 ' Died I Experiment 111 . .-•'¦ 0.2 Pirjcnto cream..... 15 j 98.0 179.0 81.0 7,400 0.4 Pimento cream. 15 ! 110.7 . 213.6 102.9 0.2 Ncifchatel 12 i 103.6 160.0 56.4 5,153 0.4 Neifchatcl ........ 12 '¦ 105.1. 197.5 92.4 0.8 Cotage .;......... 9 106.3 145.2 38.9 885 1.0 Cbtage ........... 12 104.4 147.6 43.2 ... . Pbsitiie c0ntr01*...... 13 95.3 151.1 55.8 Negatve control 2..... .8 86.0 ' "0.7 3 Died . : . .' . i Experiment IV . ¦ 0.15 Olile nut.....'..... 14 117.1 185.2 68.1 10,472 0.3 Olive nut.......... 12 119.2 207.0 87.8 ¦ .... 0.15 Reiish cream.. 16 123.5 203.0 79.5 12,227 0.3 Reish cream....... 14 112.7 212.1 99.4 .... 0.1 Ch:ddar (N.Y.type) 10 109.5 152.5 43.0 9,897 0.2 Ch &lt;Idar (N. Y. type) 13 113.8 188.9 75.1 Positiie control-*...... 12 . 112.9 '! 157.1 44.2 . Negative control 2..... 13 105.3 79.7 B Died .... 1 U. SJ P." grade cod-liver oil was llic source of.vitamin A. 3 The' uicgativc controls received only the vitamin-A-frcc diet. " 3 Average weight of the rats at death. . . ¦ '. . 4 U. S. I*, reference cod-liver oil (2.25 units) was the source of vitamin A. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 103 Table I.— Summary oj the average gains in weight of rats fed various cheeses as a source of vitamin A. — (Continued) Ay. wt. Approximate Rats when feeding Ay. wt at nT P "v Source of vitamin A in the source of end of . U.S. I.AI ijroup vitamin A experiment Kain units of besan vitamin A per pound Crams No. Oramt Grams Crams Experiment V n.fi Cottage 15 123.1 201.8 78.7 3,306 O.K Cottage 15 116.6 216.6 100.0 Hi Cheddar (Wis. typo 8 130.1 162.7 32.6 8,217 0.15 Cheddar (Wis. type) 14 113.3 176.2 62.9 0.1 Pimento cream H II 1.0 187.6 76.6 19,295 v.l 5 Pimento cream 15 113.4 205.6 92.2 Positive control 4 9 113.1 153.6 40.5 Ncjiarivc control-'. . 9 107.1 79.5 :1 Died Experiment VI I' 4 Cottage 6 116.1 144.X 28.7 7,156 0.1 Neufchatcl 8 112.1 H5.2 33.1 9,942 "¦1 Cream (&gt; 117.1 149.0 31.9 9,579 0.09 Olive nut 7 126.8 155.5 28.7 9,584 0.075 Pimento cream 7 129.8 172.1 42.3 16,949 0.075 R c h s h cream . 10 121.5 163.2 41.7 16,707 Positive control 4 6 115.1 149.0 33.9 Ni-lUtivc control 2 7 106.8 78.X;! Died Experiment Vll li.Od Roquefort II 92.8 142.8 50.0 18,216 0.1 Roquefort . 7 97.5 161.8 64.3 0.15 Roquefort 10 93.0 168.5 75.5 (1.(18 Camemhert 10 100.5 145.6 45.1 16,400 (i.l GimcmbiTt « 98.0 153.5 55.5 0.15 Caincmbcrt 11 101.2 180.0 78.8 O.IIK Licdcrkran/. 9 101.4 144.3 42.9 15,606 0.1 I.iedcrkranz H 94.3 149.6 55.3 0.15 l.icderkranz 11 98.4 171.6 73.2 .... Positive control 4 4 93.5 128.5 35.0 Negative conrtol 2 S 937 71 (fl D j c( ] [ Experiment VIII 0.4 Oitta^c 5 121.6 135.0 13 4 j n" Outage II) 116.4 151.7 35.3 856 \ 1.0 Cotta R e 'J 109.4 169.8 60.4 i 1 n 08 Canned Cheddar 10 119.7 152.8 33.1 7,037 ! 0.10 Canned Cheddar 7 110.0 157.7 47.7 \ 0.15 Canned Cheddar 12 113.1 180.0 66 9 f 0.08 Neufchatcl . 9 (13.8 133.7 19.8 h 0.1 Neufchatcl 11 111.5 142.4 30.9 5,266 i 0.15 Neufchatcl II 112.8 164.4 51.6 . :¦.. f Positive control * 10 116.7 176.5 59.8 £, Ncsative control 2 6 97.3 73.63 Died I i:' I. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Vitamin A Content of Cheese Tabie I.— Summary of the average gains in weight of rats fed various cheese as a source of vitamin A.—(Concluded) Ay wt "''¦;¦¦¦•• Approximate Rats whenfeeding Av.wt.at . AT^v! S( urcc of vitamin A in the source of end of . U.S. r.AI group vitamin A experiment gam "mtsof . began vitaminA I - per pound Grants No. Grams Grams Grains Experiment IX 0.1 iimburgcr ........ 15 112.0 149.7 37.6 5,811 0.15 limburgcr ........ 16 114.6 177.4 62.7 0.1 Danish brick...,.,. 15 113.8 184.2 70.4 10,896 0.15 Danish brick. 14 111.7 195.3 83.5 i 0.1 Edam ............ 8 113.6 140.8 27.2 0.15 Edam ....,,.,... 11 U6.0 164.8 48.7 5,024 Postive control* 10 114.6 180.6 66.0 Negative c0ntr015...... g 1Q2.6 73.23 Died. ,-.'.¦' Experiment X 0.1 Edam /......... ..11 128.5 177.4 48.9 11,213 0.15 Edam 11 123.9 184.5 606 0.1 Danish 81ue....... 11 127.0 196.8 69.7 15980 0.15 Danish 81ue....... 12 127.0 217.0 90.0 0.1 Ghantelle ; llj 120.0 157.8 37.8 8,67 i |; 0.15 (fhantelle . 12 126.5 196.9 70.3 Positive control* 12 128.3 172.8 44.5 Ncgjative control 2..... 7 136.5 91.53 Died .... i Experiment XI 0.1 ¦ Kraft pimento ..... 13, 125.6 179.0 53.3 10,714 ; 0.15 Kraft pimento ..... 14 ( 132.2 203.0 70.8 I 0.1 Kraft American ...: 13; 123.6 172.4 48.7 9806 • 0.15 Kraft American .... 12| 130.6 177.9 47.2 I, 0.1 Kraft brick .&gt;:.... 13 129.9 152.0 22.0 ;' 0.15 Kraft brick ....... 12 121.7 169.5 47.7. 6,386 Posiive c0ntr014...... 13 129.0 179.7 50.7 ; Negbtive control 2..,;. 7 144.0 103.4 3 Died .... |: Experiment XII ; 0.1 Kraft Limburgcr .... .13 ' 121.4 153.6 32.2 6,628 j. 0.15 Kraft limburger .. 15 125.8 175.9 50.1 !; 0.1 J raft Creamed j: Old English ..... 15 .126.4 194.2 67.8 13,937 ]1 0.15 kraft Creamed j, Old English ..... 15; 123.9 204.7 80.8 ji 0.1 Kraft Swiss ,-. I 4; 125.6 169.2: 43.6 8,943 .; 0.15 Kraft Swiss ....... 15' 129.5 185.6 56.1 .'; Positive controM!. 11 126.0 175.6 49.6 i.i Ncgjitive control 2 14 135.0 80.83 Died ij ; __ _ _ !l ¦¦'¦.-"¦ ¦.&lt;•¦¦''" ¦' : ' - •'¦•¦¦•' •': : •¦¦¦¦'. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 103 ; Table 2. — Chemical analyses in percentage of the cheeses used in the various experiments. Kind of cheese Acid' Protein ,' Fat J Moisture | Ash | Sugar 2 Experiment I X,ulchatel . . 20.02 62.82 Cheddar (Wis. type) . 31.09 38.04 Cream . . 30.70 53.72 Experiment II Cheddar (Wis. t\pc) .. 0.3S 28.23 31.1') 24.25 4.28 2.05 Cream ' . . 1.6? 'i.H iW) 52.12 1.67 2A\ Experiment 111 Pimento cream (1.32 13.8 V 17.60 65.04 1.61 1.85 Xcutchatcl 0.33 11.19 19.&lt;H 66.10 0.66 2.99 G.tta.ne lI.IS 14.44 2.14 79.99 1.07 1.55 Experiment IV ()l,\c nut 35.37 53.2-f ... ... Relish cream . ... 18.12 67.39 Cheddar (N. V. type) . . . 31.47 56.43 Experiment V (-...tune (1.20 13.07 5.44 78.29 1.12 2.08 Cheddar (Wis. type) . . 0.69 26.95 29.88 35.65 4.06 3.46 Pimento cream till) 13.86 10.42 62.51 1.54 3.66 Experiment VI , Cntujje ... 0.14 13.33 4.49 79.39 1.01 1.76 ' Neulchatel 11.2S 10.3(1 19.05 63.08 1.91 4.85 Cream . 0.31) 6.37 24.15 60.58 1.71 6.18 Olnc nut 0.25 6.28 25.5J 58.06 2.02 8.11 I'im.-m.. cream 0.31 13.51 15.94 63.15 1.61 5.77 R.lvh cream 0.4S 8.97 IH.IO 61.54 1.63 10.26 Experiment VII Roquefort 1.6" 2 r. 51 29.38 36.37 5.59 1.15 Camemlx-n 1.10 17.78 22.18 55.44 3.44 1.14 l.iederkranz 0.985 18.24 25.12 55.06 2.91 Experiment VIII Cciiiauc . 0.15 12.53 4.29 78.32 1.30 3.56 Cheddar (canned) 1.08 25.62 27.29 39.14 3.40 4.55 Vufchatel 0.32 12.07 17.60 63.29 1.65 5.31 Experiment IX j I.imburner ().8h 23.116 28.85 44.77 3.63 Danish hnck 0.61 24.08 31.06 38.31 3.22 3.32 ; Edam 0.90 28.23 32.23 32.00 5.35 2.18 j Ex|Kriment X :J GuiHiiercul Warn . (1.H4 30.06 25.57 36.24 6.20 1.11 ; Danish Blue 1.37 23.44 32.77 35.78 6.52 1.44 I Chantellc 0.61 24.86 29.05 39.65 3.89 2.54 i Exix-riment XI &gt;' Kraft pimento 0.82 23.34 28.71 39.76 4.98 3.21 ;, Kraft American 0.71 23.38 29.46 39.48 4.85 2.82 f Kraft brick . .. . 0.70 21.38 27.58 41.01 5.54 3.68 \ Experiment XII f Kraii Umburncr 0.61 15.97 21.34 56.58 4.19 1.91 I Kraft ("reamed £ Old English 1.01) 19.08 32.09 41.45 3.31 4.06 1 Kraft Swiss . 1.06 26.25 25.81 39.84 5.24 2.85 r 1 Calculated as lactic acid. I f </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Vitamin A Content of Cheese I rom these data it was estimated that a pound of each of these cheeses contained the following number of units of vitamin A: Units . 1i.,:., Chcddar(N.Y.typc)........... 9,897 Chanteltc .. 8 671 Roqicfort ... 18,216 Limbur S cr ......... i%\\ Cammbcrt .. 16,400 Kraft pimento ........ 10*714 Licddrkranz ; 15,606 Kraft American ... .......... [', 9806 Cheddar (canned) 7,037 Kraft brick :'.-...'... 6386 Dam h brick.......... v....... 10.896 Kraft Creamed Old English. .'.'.'.'. 13,937 Edan (made in Station creamery). 5,024 Kraft Swiss 8 943 EdanV (purchased)... 11,213 Kraft Umburgcr ...'.'.'.'.'.'.'.['.'.'.'. 6,62* Damn 81ue....... ..15,900 In several instances different samples of a given kind of cheese were fed n different experiments and the following vitamin A values were obtained: . ..-";'. Cheddar (Wis. type)..:........ , 10,896 and ' 8,217 Cream .......... 10,510 and 9,579 Ohyc nut ...;...... 10,472 and 9,584 Relish cream........ ..;.. 12,227 and 16,707 Sf'jsc : 885, 3,306, 2,156 and 856 Neufchatel ..............;..,.. 5,153, 9,942 and 5,266 ; Pimento cream...... .......... 7,400, 19,295 and 16,949 Tifiese data probably are not extensive enough to establish definitely we average vitamin-A content of a given kind of cheese. A jarge number .'¦ of samples would have to be assayed in order to establish the exact vitamin- A po :ency. It seems evident, however, that there is considerable variability in tlie vitamm-A content of this product; Furthermore, the vitamin-A poter cy of a given kind of; cheese may vary with different samples. From • the ciemical analysis which was made of these samples,it is evident that the vitamin-A potency doe^ not strictly parallel the fat content. In general i the simples of cottage, Neufchatel, and Limburger cheeses had the lowest vitarr in-A potency. 1:' ' -¦ ;¦¦ : ¦¦¦ •'.' ¦' •• - ' ¦'=¦ '•' . ¦'' ¦¦¦" -V ¦¦'.'. . ' : -'.';¦¦ .. i ¦;-•¦- ¦¦'.¦".'¦¦ '-¦ •¦ ¦¦'¦'¦ ¦'..... ;¦ - ¦¦•,•• " . . ¦¦ :. - .-¦•. •'.- ; .. - I ¦ :': -: :...-¦¦ !| .':•¦.-¦¦ '..-¦¦: • ' '' \ ' - ¦' -.- ¦¦ ¦ ¦¦'..¦¦ '¦ ' ¦ • ¦' ¦ ¦ "¦ . ¦ r l"'-' . ¦ ¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p010">I Nebraska Ac;rl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin' 103 LITERATURE CITED I Cook. 1). H.. anil Axtmaier. |. H. |l|ij. Nl-TRITHIN STTDIIS 01 FIXHKITFI S UsED IN THE PUERTO RICAN DIETRY VI. Tmh Vitamin A Content of Pasteurized Milk and Native Cheese. Put-no Rico ]our. Pub. Health ami Trop. Mcd., 9:90-92. J IWaril. K. 11.. ami Morgan. B. G. K. , ' l'Ml OIANTITATIYF KsTIMATION- Ol VITAMINS A AND I) IX VARIOUS I'OOD Si bsta.m ts Cooked and Fresh. Brit. M«l. Jour. 3908:1041-4-). v Doant. C. F.. Lawson. H. W., and Matlu-son. K. J. I \'iU. Varieties eh Ciiefsf: I)fs&lt; rictions and Analyses. U. S. IX A. Bui. 60S. 4. Hathaway. 1. L.. and Davis. H. P. ' I'tJS. The Vitamin A Content ov Sour Cream Butter, Sweet Cream Bi-ttfr and Maikjarinks. Ncbr. Aur. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 79:1-8. i. Morgan. Agnes F. 1926. Hiiii.(k;icai. F(kid Tests—lX. Vitamin Am Three Varieties of Chefse. Amt-r. Jour. Physiol.. 7S:ll-li. h Rice. Pt-ncloix: H.. anil Munscll. Hazel F.. I'lU. Tiiv Approximate Units of Vitamin A and Vitamin C in Foods. N't-w York As«n. fur linprininj; the (jindirion of the Poor. 1-6. ". L. S. Pharmacopoeia. I'ij4. A 1 1J34 Rfmsion oi mi Text and Assays for Cod Liver Oil of the Phahmacopoeia of the United States. Tenth Decennial Revision- U S P. X. Interim Revision Announcement No. 2:1-11. f &gt; | S I 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 104 Influence of Age of Dairy Cattle and Season of the Year on the Sex Ratio of Calves and Services Required for Conception .•¦'¦'.¦ . ¦ ¦ [ . y ¦. ¦'..-.•'¦ : R. F. Morgan and H. P. Davis Department of Dairy Husbandry 1!.. - -if -,"¦¦..¦'•.• !!"¦¦.-¦ ; ¦' -. ¦'¦¦-. '•..';¦- ¦¦•-.:¦¦ -. j| LINCOLN, NEBRASKA !!¦¦'-' AUGUST, 1938 j - v.:. ¦¦¦¦^¦z.:;-¦'':-Vz'-' '..v'^z; , </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Summary The present study was based on records of the dairy herd of the Uni - versity of Nebraska for the period 1896 to 1934, and covers five breeds, Holstcins. lerseys. Guernseys, Ayrshires, and milking Shorthorns. In all, ' 2,090 cows have been included. The purpose was to determine the in - fluence of the age of the bull, the age of the cow, and the season of the year upon the number of services required for conception, and to determine also the influence of these factors upon the sex ratio of calves born, number of twins born, and the percentage of abortion. Young bulls under two years showed the smallest number of services for conception. From two years of age through eight years of age, the number of services required varied very little. There were not enough data for older bulls to permit conclusions. Cows under two years of age (virgin heifers) required more services for conception than any age group of cows up to ten years of age. Be - tween the ages of two and thirteen years, with the exception of the ten - year-old group, cows showed little variation in the number of services required for conception. Among bulls of varying ages mated with cows of varying ages, the iwoyear-old bulls mated to two-year-old cows showed the smallest number ot services for conception. Between the ages of two and eight, cows and bulls show little influence of age upon the number of services required. Bulls three years of age and older were not efficient when mated with females under two years of age. The average number of services required tor conception for 2,090 cows was 3,041 for 1,375 conceptions, or 2.21 services for each conception. Among the calves there were 730 males and 62X females, together with 30 sets of twins and 47 of unknown sex. The sex ratio was 53.75 per cent males and 46.25 per cent females. The average percentage of abortion was 12.58. During the season from May to October 2.28 services were required lor conception, while from November to April 2.14 services were required for bulls of all ages mated to cows of all ages. The monthly variation in number of services for conception varied from 1.94 in December to 2.86 in September. As fas as the sex ratio was concerned, all months showed more males than females except November. i i 1 I f </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Influence of Age of Dairy Cattle and Season of the Year on the Sex Ratio of Calves and Services Required for Conception R. F. MORGAN and H. P. DAVIS In the breeding of dairy cattle the use of proved sires is advocated as the surest method of improving the herd. While there are many definitions, the proved sire is most commonly defined as one that has first of all sired five or more unselected daughters, each of which has completed at least one production record, and that these cows have been out of different dams that have had comparable production records. The second step is a coimarison of the records, which may or may riot "prove" the bull. The proved bull will never be less than four years of age and more often he will be six or seven years of age, and perhaps much older. The use of a mature bull, and especially a bull of seven years or older, entails certain difficulties and hazards, such as proper housing for safety, fertility cf the bull, and disease control. Many breeders frankly state that their troubles with older bulls have been so nany that they prefer to use and do use young bulls. ¦ In.an effort to determine the influence of age of bulls and cows in a dairy herd upon the number of services required for conception, the breeding records of the dairy herd at the University of Nebraska have been s:udied for a period of more than a third of a century^ During the period the herd has suffered from Bang's disease (infectious abortion) up to about 1930, when this disease was eradicated from the herd. Definite evidences of trichomoniasis were discovered in 1936, and there is likelihood that tr is disease existed earlier. In other words, the dairy herd is a large herd tiat has been handled; as far as disease, feeding, and management are concerned, in accordance with the best practice. The four principal dairy breeds are represented—Holstein-Eriesian, Jersey, Guernsey, and Ayrshire, and in the earlier years milking Shorthorns. Th: general plan has been to use such pastures as were available and to use alfalfa hay and corn silage as the principal roughages. The grain mixtures fed have usually contained approximately 14 per cent digestible proteir composed of ground corn, ground oats, wheat bran, and one or more of the following high-protein concentrates—cottonseed meal, lin - seed rreal, fish meal, gluten meal, gluten feed, soybean meal. During the past ten years, one per cent of iodized salt,-one percent of steamed bone meal, md one per cent of lime flour have been added to the grain mix - ture. Molasses and dried beet pulp also have been used in the ration. For several years beginning! in September, 1926, and ending May, 1931, oats sprouted for eight hours were.fed to both cows and bulls. REVIEW OF LITERATURE Write and associates (11) in studying the influence of infectious abortion (Bang's disease) upon the reproduction of a dairy herd, found that 1.82 services were required for conception with negative cows, 155 service: for cows of doubtful reactions, and 2.09 services for reacting cows, ,-. ',''¦• ;¦ '• "'¦¦"¦'¦ '-¦ i ¦'¦¦¦' ¦ ¦'';¦¦.' -' - ¦-.•¦'¦' ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 104 thus indicating the effect of that disease upon breeding. Some data were presented regarding the age of heifers at first breeding upon the number of services required for conception as follows: Age of Heifer Services per Heifer for Conception Less than 15 months 2.40 IS to 17 months 1-91 18 to 20 months 1-60 21 to 23 months 2.54 24 months and over 2.89 In their study of 40 bulls the number of services for conception varied from 1.00 to 3.18. indicating that the individual bull is a prominent factor in this problem. Cows appeared to conceive more promptly within the first 60 days after calving. During the season from November to April 2.02 services were required for conception, while for the other six months, May to October, only 1.8 1) services were required. Kckles (1) in a study of the dairy herd at the University of Minnesota lor a period of 29 years, reported the number of services for conception to average 2.52. He says, "The data assembled bear out the usual opinion that abortion is a factor in sterility, although the effects of abortion in this respect are often over-emphasized. Of all aborting animals 21 per cent were sterile following abortion." Fitch and associates (2) studied a clean herd of 33 animals and found that 1.7 services were necessary for each conception. In a herd of. 16 infected with Bang's disease, 2.4 services were required for conception. Moseley and associates (8) report that pasture for four months had no significant effect upon the percentage of cows conceiving at first service. Pasture appeared to have a slightly favorable effect in reducing the number of services for conception in cows bred more than three times. For all cows in the herd, 1.7 services were required for conception. Gowen and Dove (3) in an analysis of records of 7,696 cows found that 60 per cent conceived at the first service, and that 95 per cent had conceived by the fifth service. There was a variation in the percentage of services that resulted in conception from a low of 55 in September to 64 in August, with no distinct effect of season. The effect of the age oMhe cow upon the services required for conception indicated a progressive in - crease from 70 per cent (1.428 services) for females under one year, to 45 per cent (2.222 services) for females 16 years of age. He indicates a steady decline in fertility with advancing age for both males and females. Miller and Graves (6) in reporting on the health of a herd that had Bang's disease, state that before the infected animals were eliminated, 2.88 services were required for conception. After separation the negative cows required 2.92 services for each conception. If the services to sterile animals were included, the respective figures were 3.94 before separation, and 3.48 services for conception after separation. There is some reason to believe that this herd might have suffered from trichomoniasis. In figures presented to show the effect of season of the year upon fertility covering four years and 22 bulls, the lowest number of services, 2.44, were required </seg>
         <seg id="p015">. . Services Required for Conception in December and May, while September showed 4.36 and July 4.28. Young bulls required 3.06 services for conception as compared with 3.83 for ma ure bulls. I Miller and associates (7) report that the number of services required for con:eptton in positive cows when bred after normal calving was 2.63, while when bred after abortion the number was 3.20. They present a table to show the percentage! of conception at each of a varying number of services. . ¦ I . : ¦ Peajl (10) in reporting the effects upon sex of breeding early, in the middleJ or late in oestrum found a total of 657 males and 656 females, or approximately an even sex ratio. Nebraska data (9) based upon five breeds, Holstein-Friesian, Jersey, Guerns:y, Ayrshire, and milking Shorthorn, with a total of 1,235 calvings, show-5.1.48 per cent males, 46.52 per cent females, and 1.54 per cent twins. This is a ratio of 114.94 males to 100 females. ' Johsnsson (4) in a study of. 124,000 births of Swedish Red and White, Swedish Friesian, Swedish Landrace, Finnish Ayrshire, and East and West linnish Landrace breeds, found that the sex ratio was 106 males to 100 females. The age of the cow appeared to have no influence upon the sex ratio. . . . ¦']¦¦ Knctt (5) in a study of (the gestation time of Holstein-Friesian cows shows hat of 2,824 gestations of single births, 1,441 calves were males and 1,3:83 were females—a ratio of 51.02 percent males to 48.98 percent females' or 104.2 to 100. Of the 86 sets of twins, the sex ratio was 109.7 males to 100 femalesv Miller and associates (7) reported a sex ratio of 113.6 males to 100 females, with five sets of mixed twins. INFLUENCE OF AGE ON SERVICES REQUIRED AND ON SEX RATIO OF CALVES In compiling the data, the first study was made on the effect of the age of the bull, with cows of varying ages. The ages of the cows and bulls w:re those on the date of service which resulted in conception. The bulls wi:re sorted according to age by years. Only fertile cows, as determined by subsequent calving, were included. Table 1 shows the data for bulls between the ages of 12 to 23 months inclusive, with cows varying in age from under two years to 18! years of age. The table shows the number of bulls used oh the cows of different ages, the number of cows served, the number of services per cow, the number of'conceptions, the number of services required for. conception, the sex ratio in percentage for males and females, and other data. ¦ A bull may appear more j than once, if the same bull served cows of different ages. In successive tables the same cow may appear more than once, her appearance depending upon the age at which she was bred. To obtain the figures under , the: heading "services per cow, average number," the total number of services was divided by the number of cows served for a particular age of cow. To obtain the "services for conception, average number,' 1 the total number of services was divided ¦ ¦ '¦¦.'" /¦.¦' '¦; •.•¦¦¦¦¦. '¦ . .«' ¦ '. "¦¦'¦¦¦ ¦ ¦¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 104 by the number of conceptions. In some cases, the sex of calves aborted was unknown, which accounts for the number of calves of unknown sex appearing in the table. The column showing the percentage of abortions is included in order to throw some light upon the effect of abortion upon the number of services required for conception. Table 1 shows that the average number of services required in the case of bulls 12 to 23 months of age when breeding cows of varying ages was 1.94 and that there was a general trend toward more services for con - ception when bulls of this age were used to breed older cows. Tables 2 to 13 represent data for bulls of different ages. In general the trends are much the same as in Table I. It is interesting to note that the male calves always exceeded the females in each table except Table 4, for bulls 48 to 59 months of age. and Table 12, for bulls 144 to 155 months of age. No reason is apparent. Tables 1 to 13 are largely self-explanatory. Table 14 is a summary table. In that table the data for bulls of all ages when breeding cows of varying ages are presented. A total of 2,090 cows (not individuals) were served 3,041 times for 1,375 conceptions, or an average of 2.21 services per conception. In a total of 1,358 calves there were 730 males and 628 females, or 53.75 per cent males and 46.25 per cent females, or 116.24 males to 100 females. This is a slight increase in the proportion of males to females since the previous Nebraska data (9) were presented. This rate appears higher than others have obtained with no apparent reason. There does not appear to be a very definite trend in any direction as far as the number of services required for conception is concerned. Females under two years of age require more services for conception (2.52) than those of any other ages except those ten years of age (3.15). That is not considering the older ages, for which few data are available. It would appear therefore that between the ages of two and ten years there is little difference, as far as age of cow is concerned, in the number of services required for conception. Table 15 presents data showing the effect of age of bull upon cows of all ages. For bulls under two years of age, 1.94 services were needed for conception, the lowest number of services for conception for bulls of any age. With the exceptions of bulls eight years or older, where the data are somewhat limited, there was a distinct trend toward more services with the increased age of the bull. This is illustrated in the column headed "Yearling bulls as a standard, variations in percentage." It appears that there is a tendency for older bulls to be less sure as breeders. There is little indication that abortion had any measurable effect upon the number of services required for conception. Complete data on the prey- | alence of abortion in the herd are given in reference 9. I Table 16 is an analysis of data presented in Tables 1 to 15. By read- i ing across and down the table, the number of services required for con- , ception for bulls of any age in breeding cows of any age can readily be determined. The summary at the bottom of the table is taken from the J data in Table 15. The summary at the right is taken from Table 14. J, I </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Services Required for Conception It i! evident from Table 14, or the last column of Table 16, that heifers inder two years of age required more services for conception than females of older ages up to 10 years of age, when bred to bulls of all ages, \yhen young bulls, yearlings and two-year-olds, served such females, the numbers, of services required for conception were respectively 1.80 and I 1.67 as compared with 2.52 for bulls of all ages. It would appear, there - fore, that the use of young bulls on virgin heifers might be of considerable advantage. The number of services required for conception for four-year - old coys using five-year-old (bulls was 1.36, the lowest figure for any ! group vhere there was a considerable number of cases. This is apparently , due to he influence of the cow, since in Table 14 when bulls of all ages ;. served four-year-old cows, the number of services required for con - ception, 1.97, was the lowest for any age where there was a considerable number of cases: In Table 15, five-year-old bulls showed an average number of services for conception of 2.26, which is not the lowest but about : what rright be expected from the trend from young to old bulls. The average number of services for conception for 2,090 cows was 2.21. The difference between the figures,for the older ages of cows in the various column: and the figures in the last column may be explained as follows: A cow nay be bred to a bull of a certain age but may not conceive, and ; later m: ybe bred to another bull and conceive to the service of the second ; bull. ¦-¦'..'• ;'¦.'. ..-¦¦¦¦ '.. ' ' . EFFECT OF SEASON OF YEAR ON NUMBER OF SERVICES AND ON SEX RATIO OF CALVES | It rh ght be expected that season of the year would have some influence i uP°n^the number of services required for conception, especially in a I; climatic environment where pasture is ordinarily not available more than i) three or at the most four months. The influence of green growing crops , on reproduction has been thought to be quite material. It seemed as if ,: ¦ the division of the year into two seasons—summer represented by the I months May to October, and winter represented by the months November |j to April—might reveal the effect of season. ] Tabks 17 to 20 present the effect of season upon the number of services ,¦¦ required for conception and the sex ratio when bulls of varying ages were ! mated brcows of varying ages. Tables 17 and 18 contain data classified I according to the ages of the bulls, for the two seasons. The average number of services required for bulls of different ages in breeding cows of all , ages wai 2.28 for the summer season, compared with 2.14 for the winter ; season. The proportions oi male calves were 55.13 per cent in summer | and 52/4 per cent in winter. The abortion rate in summer was slightly . lower, 11.88 per cent, as compared with 13.24 per cent for the winter |. season.* '. .'. ¦ :•" - - ¦"•. ..: ¦-" ' ¦••¦..'.... : ¦:• Tabl:s 19 and 20 present data classified according to ages of cows, and the! c data agree in averages with Tables 17 and 18. Here again is ' . emphasised the fact that females under two years of age require distinctly | more services than the average for cows of all ages or for any but extreme </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 104 ages. Table 19 shows that for the summer season 2.73 services were iequired tor conception, as compared with 2.33 services during the winter season. Tables 17 and 18 show that bulls under two years and two-year - olds required fewer services in both summer and winter than older bulls at either season. Table 21 presents the influence of season by months for cows of all ages served by bulls of all ages. Here there was a fairly even distribution of the 3,041 services. In the low month, March, there were 211 services and in the high month, December, there were 279. The conceptions \aried by months from 84 in September to 144 in December, with a total of 1,3"x The services required for conception varied from 1.94 in December to 2.85 in September; these were 51.61 and 35.14 per cent respectively. A possible explanation of the large number of services required i'or conception in August and September, namely 2.78 and 2.85 respect - ively, is that on the average these months are hot, and while September is not so hot as July there may be a cumulative effect upon the bulls or upon the cows. The reasons for the variations in February and March are not apparent. A possible explanation may be that domesticated dairy cattle still retain some of the characteristics of their remote ancestors as to periods ot fertility. The influence of month of birth upon sex is illustrated in Table 21. Here November was the only month that the females born exceeded the males, the percentages being respectively 47.36 and 52.64. The animals dropped during November were conceived between January 23 and February 21. The largest proportion of males dropped was in the month of September, when the relation of males to females was 60.98 to 39.02 per cent. These calves were conceived between November 23 and December 22. There does not appear to be any evidence that the season of the year influenced the sex. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">' Table I.— Data on bulls 12 to 23 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years — all seasons. . Age of . Bulls Cows Ser- Services . Con- , for con- Male. Female .Ratio Ratio Living Abor- . Abor- cow ¦ __ servcil vices per cow editions __cc-ption— calves calves males ¦ females calves lions .inn. No. No. No. . Ay.no. . No. .iv.no. No.. No. . P.ct. . P.ci. No. No. P.ct. 2 yrs. .......... 47 121 164 1.36 91 1.80 48 4P 53.93 -16.06 78 . 14» 8.53 2 yrs. .......... 23 19 63 1.29 34 1.85 . 16' 18 -17.05 52.94 31 4s . 6.34 3 yrs 23 41 53 1.29 25 2.12 15' II 57.69 42.30 25 1 4.00 4 yrs. .......... 18, 21 . 29 1.38 16 1.81 12' 5 70.58 29.41 15 2 12.50 5 yrs. .......... 13 22 28 1.27 16 1.75 7.9' 43.75 56.25 15 2» 12.50 6 yrs 15 18 24 1.33 13 1.85 8 5 61.53 38.46 12 1 7.69 r - -7 yrs. 12 16 22 1.38 11 2.00 9 2 81.81 18.18 9 2 18.18 "ft 8 yrs. ..10 12 17 1.42 9 1.89 4 5 44.44 55.55 8 1 11.11 2 9 yrs 6 7 8 1.14 5 1.60 4 1 80.00 20.00 5 0 . 00.00 £ 10 yrs. .;........ 9 12 21 1.75 : 6 3.50 3' 4 42.85 57.14 5 2 33.33 2 11 yrs. 1 1 1 I.oo' 1 1.00 0 I .... 100.00 1 0 00.00 S&gt; -12 -yrs.-:...-.-.-.:;-.--- 3 '—3 ~3 I.CHI- 2—: 1.50 :—J— 1 50.00 — 2 0 00;0O-^~ ~S 13 yrs. .......... 2 2 3 1.5(1 1 3.00 1 0 100.00 .... 1 0 00.00 (? 14 yrs. 23 12 4.00 2 6.00 2 0 ItKMHI ¦ " ..... I 1 ... 50.00 a 18 yrs. .......... 1 1 . 2 2.1K1 0 0.110 0... I] ..... .... .... .(... C Av.orluial ;. ¦." 329 450 1.38 232 1.94 130 103 55.79 44.20 208 30 12.93 5 ¦ .— —.— ——. — ¦ ; . — _ ¦ —,—. __ — _— — ... _ . : _— —. m .'One set of twins. = 'I'hrcc calves of unkntitvii j ex. 3 One calf of unknown sex. ' . ° Table 2.— Data on hulls 24 to 35 months of age and cows 2to 18 years— all seasons. ''' ' ' . § ; Ai-eof ¦ ' Bulls Cows Ser- Services Con. . for con- Male Female Ratio ; Ratio : Living Abor- AlKir- O cow •' . served vices- pcrcow ccpliohs ccplioit calves calves males females calves lions tions Z : No. No.. No. Ay. no. No.. .lr.no. No. ' No. . P.ct. P.ct. No. No. P.ct. : S_ Under ..''.¦¦¦ - . H 2 yrs. .......... 30 78 105 1.35 63 1..-.7 36' 27i 57.14 42.85 61 4&gt; 6.34 5 2 yrs. .......... 27 63 89 1.41 52 1.71 ' 20 30' 40.00 60.00 47 6" 11.53 Z 3 yrs. .......... 23 67" 103 1.54 47 2.19 26 20 56.52 43.47 45 2' 4.25 4 yrs. 21 40 60 1.50 23 2.61 . II II 50.00 50.00 19 4* 17.39 5 yrs. 15 24 37 1.54 19 1.95 10 9 52.63 47.36 19 0 6 yrs. 15 24 33 1.38 14 2.36 8 4 66.66 33.33 11 3 1 21.42 7 yrs. .......... 12 20 30 1.50 13 2.31 9 4 69.23 30.76 12 1 7.69 8 yrs.' 8 12 14 1.17 9 1.56 5 4 55.55 44.44 8 1 11.11 9 yrs. 9 12 17 1.42 7 2.43 6 1 2 75.00 25.00 7 1 14.28 10 yrs. .......... 5 -7 11 1.57 5 2.20 4 1 80.00 20.00 4 1 20.00 11 yrs. .......... 4 S 10 2.00 4 . 2.50 3 1 75.00 25.00 4 12 &gt;ts. 1 1 1 1.00 1 1.00 0 1 100.00 1 . 13 yrs 1 I 2 2.00 1 2.00 0 1 .... 100.00 1 Ay. or total 354 512 1.45 258 1.98 138 115 54.54 45.45 239 23 8.91 . s One set of twinl * Two calves of unknown sex. ' Three calves of unknown sex. * One calf of unknown .ex. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 104 I --! ' I il! - ?,-.Z'.v?.?.z i • _ _1 i 53^-_.s.Ssg : -.g : -. : -.2 . ,| I s- __Z"-,^_."-. = : '¦ ± &lt;- =• i^'-'^-'s'S'-'S' •' :K' :•' •' ;_; 5 j: 1 S '¦i " I J^---- "&gt; &lt;_¦-'- *" — — — • —i _ -ii _&lt;;.___ = t a. . . J O -_ : ;^l,i^l£-^-- Tr— ¦ _. -_ O t&gt; j: ;r ~i~ —« — ac ——i .-r- .__ .oc 3 Vi .. ~' I - . - * ~" "I ¦- i i ' _ ¦- ' - = _ j . I* '• — -- ! r " * _V = !C. =. = ='- P I* -- ~ M-u-l^C—.l^ — «r..cC—. -••--, • - _ - ' —--•~&gt;^—=c _ ~ ; s c ¦ ¦ — - _ v .xNc..i.qcmcc. . . .. - ;-. _ r jtff^-'.TTff jj ; ;~ x z c. !7-i7- * _SRS_?;SS—; ¦- ¦ 'l/v 'i 5 . ~ ~ 3 ~ ' X v, 1 S 14 * ?.--.-.iV_ = -___ : '.- . S? •§¦§ _ _zKg-^gS,_ :=_ ;gg -.fe = - -= ¦_ ;?f?i,xt!r's?ff ••? _ g *= - ????g'?;SR!_ :KS :g|l •'? _ °' ii I r.| \ ZZ;i. .... 1 5 |5 , .. J C-3^-'''' — *= O _ &lt; —— — -- en '«- - J " -i - "*' I ¦* '. § v : , ... ; § _as _ t.„ ,_, | "MH" " { , -r - = '. ', "7 "x .^ --.9f; S = '~" -0 E a « .-iElrvi^ .^ i- ec ,«(_ o a •Q o •o. ' ... \ -Z Z :&gt;**.— 'i.r__u-^^__ &gt;" - ,-.—. e:.-.1-;Oi/.uy.,c=00-SS-~&gt; j -5 I 1 wf- . rt p.r!_ . rt ri_ — T ri __ _t_¦ — l-irir-IM —rlr-ifif^rC^.i ".--^ '-j ¦ _¦ _ - — -y. — - - - B B ' R 2 ! r% !- '.TTi'--- - '¦"' ? q^ = = £ i?SS!-?i-_;!_' r""",-r _&gt; - &gt;| -- o-i ._ c ! 1 . o i .5 ** S i -^ -; ~ i..i.._-^._— . __ &gt; - - n?';:' i;^ plTl ci^?-,0 _-_ jH - " _. *- '• " " . C _.-- ; :.;,--iLi = 7, r, "'-''"r ~ — = is _, i_u _: -«r*_-_;-«-ffih.N«i&gt;---r n ( _; ¦„- _ —*i - -. **¦ f -*¦ r•»¦ i "i S; (,(_ __ -cif&gt;",fnWlNfn —t *T c j- - &lt; — "- © «« &gt; ¦&lt; — **¦ « 5 "a ; » i G --- Q -- i | » i &gt; r:;i?" 1 !-'-,r,-:L: ¦'"•*•'"¦'-? T »&gt; o ,^^SS_:_;_;^ I"0""", S! " '. • ¦' t " I c z &lt; _ zz 3 ~z~ _- ,~ - '-£';_" «r it -r _• ——-r — ¦ *_J _ O cOwl'-NNrr,OUiT-TN«-"-i ¦ H 5 "- {_j = &lt; "~*' j: — M 1 — i;iii!!!!!!Mi;;; f U tiiiiinuiiiiiii I -i 1. _: -&gt;¦-*¦--&gt;.-¦&gt;- &gt;. &gt;-&gt;.&gt;.&gt;•&gt;,&gt;... « v -_!&gt;,&gt;.&gt;.&gt;._n&gt;^&gt;^&gt;,&gt;,&gt;,&gt;,^s-,&gt;,&gt;,&gt;._. r; "^i'i-tu-ci-xcc— 'i*.i. • _ j^MNrn, Tiris_:i&gt;.eoO\o*-&gt;fSfn-rr&gt;.eoc ?&lt; </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Table s.—Dataonbulls 60 to 71 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years— all seasons. *__?¦ Bulls Cow. Ser- I. Services Con- I ? 0^„! . Male: Female Ratio Ratio Living I Abor- I Abor - -- I l—mmL- 1 virrs_|_.per^oi_^-ccptioni^-_ e eps, |sn -l^-c a |,e,_._ ca |v. i males — \~ females— |—cilvef-|— tionr— | tions — Under '' '.""'¦ N°- N °' . Jv.iio. No. Ay.no. No. No. P.ct. P.ct. No. No. ' P.ct. ll'r\' '¦••"¦.••'•."¦ '}?..¦. 4| ..-/« ' '¦'}¦»'..¦ 24 3.00 14 10 58.33 41.66 22 2 8.33 ¦¦3m •¦•'¦" 13 to %X" ' S 2.04 —: 10 — 12. ." 45.45 54.54 20 3' 13 04- A y'\- •¦ ]l ?2 J5 -?5 13 1.92 9' 5 64.28 35.71 14 . ... ¦¦_„_ ." f H '» "J 2 " '-36 "&gt;' 5 66.66 33.33 4 7.4 5 &gt;rs. ......... II 21 27 -29.. H, 2.45 ¦: 9« ¦ .. 3. 75.00 25.00, ;12 . ... 7^- ¦•¦-,_¦¦ JIiHI,? H 0 2 2 .50.00 50.00 4' l&gt; 20 66 g 5 8 ml •••¦lO ,'» 27 -f» » J-08 .4 9 30.76 69.23 12 1 7.69 " oyrs. .......... Jf 2 H 3 6 1-50 3 3 50.00 50.00 6 . . 1 9,n............. 45 5 . -00 2 2.50 0 2 .... 100.00 1' 50 66 O &#132;¦£_• ¦ f , 2? J-S,.- ° 3"67 ¦ 1 ¦ 5 16.66 83.33 6 . .... H 1 yrs. .......... 11 1 .00 l 1.00 l« .¦ I 50.00 50.00 2 . ... ' __ 2 yrs. .......... j r 1- 1.00 1 1.00 1 o 100.00 .... 1 ... S - . 18 ""¦ ; 1 1 2 2.00 1 2.00 0 1 100 00 I W Av.0r.0,a1....,:.. . 195 271 .1.39 120 2.26 6? 58 52.45 VM 115 97^ .'..§ ' One set of twins. • 'One calf of unknown sex. g Table 6.—Para on bulls 72 to 83 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years— all seasons. '•_ A'Sw* B"!'» ,£"?_ Z^Z J CT C! C°- n- fo Cr"o„? - Male Female Ratio Ralio I Living Abor- Abor- n '"&gt;ed vices pcrcow ccplton. ccp , io - calve. calves males female. | calves lions lion. _? Under No: N°- -Vo- Ay. no. No. Ay.no. No. No. , P.ct. P.ct. No. No. P.ct. O 2 yrs. .......... 13 42 59 1.40 20 2.95 9 8 52.94 4^05 17 3' 15 on 3 2 yrs. 4 32 49 1.53 12 4.08 7 5 58.33 4166 1 1 83? S \ »"•-¦ :••:*¦ ¦ _? '••« !-p' 2? 2-H » 10' 56.52 41.SV 2_ § .J"' ••••¦¦•¦¦„ ?. '¦'?. ¦¦''•§5 Z 2-I 8 5' 12 29.41 70.58 16 2' 11.76 Z. 6m""' 69fM? '5 '•?» 3 5 37.50 82.50 82' 20.00 ?'"•••• • £ ,» J3 •_} &lt;! 2.17 4 2 66.66 33.33 5 1 16.66 II"' ¦•¦ I_ " •-£ 9 : . 2.78 5 3 62.50 37.50 81&gt;1 II 8 yrs. .......... 8 ,M 25 L/ 9 8 3.13 6 1 85.71 14.28 7 1&gt; 2 50 ,„?"•••¦ | | ¦¦¦¦¦* '•_„ * l-°0 1 2 33.33 66.66 2 2 J 50.00 |oyrs 5 5 9 1.80 4 2.25 4 0 .... 100.00 4 0 _£'• •--.-¦¦ «-¦¦ ? -¦¦¦'?¦ iS 7 2°° S 2 71.42 2857 7 0 WV ."yrs.. 1 Jl 1 1.00 I 1.00 0 0 .. n 1» lnOnn Av-ort °'al 197 301 1.53 120 2.51 62 50 55.J5 44.64 106 16 13-3 ' '¦ ¦'. *°"&lt;: «t of twins, - ' Three calves of unknown .ex. &gt; One calf of unknown sex. . «Two calves of unknown sex. </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Table 7.— Data on bulls 84 to 95 months oj age and cows 2 to IS years — all seasons. AH.' &lt;&gt;l Pull, t&lt;&gt;». S.r S.rvi... I on lotion Nl-' 11' l.m.ili Kuio X..no l.i.inn Al.or Al&gt;or - ."" &gt;..,..-.l I .ii.-s I p.-, ...» .r i&lt; I &#132;.!„„,„ I ...1.,-. I &#132;.K., I „...!,, I 1.m.i1., I ..i1.,-. lion. 110 m 2 ii.. h si. 1 sii :i 1111 12 h i,n.ini .in mi pi ¦&gt;* 9 S' S 2 it.. H 17 IS 1.27 .'I ill 11 111 52. IB 17 1.1 21 £ 1 yrs » 211 II lIS H 2.111 1 ll' 21-12 7n.57 12 2 IS.IH T. 1 vis 1. M 21 1,1.2 H 2.1.1 S 1 1,2 Sii 17 Sii 7 I |, so &gt; S yrs. I. M l&lt;l 1.29 'I 2.(111 S 1 &#132;2,51 l 17 Sll 7 " "" -, (. in. 4 l» 14 1.411 S 2.811 4 1 Wl.im 211 III! S •*" 7 yrs. I I 4 1.11 2 2.00 I I Sllllll SII.IHI 2 § X yrs 5 I. 7 1.17 4 1.7S 2 2 SII.IHI SIHHI 1 | ?S IHI r lyi. 5 ', 14 I.SI. (, 2.3.1 1 1 Sunn Sllllll &#132; 11l vr. 2 I S 1.1.7 I S nil I II Inn nil I PI 11 yrs .1 4 4 1.11(1 1 1.31 I I Sllllll Sllllll I « «,(,(, SS 12 vrs. 2 1 S 1.1.7 1 5.111 l II 1 11111.111 l | s.orloial I7H 252 1.42 94 2.1.X 48 -H S2 17 47. 82 US 111 1111,1 OO ' One set of twins. -One .all of unknown sex. _J Table B.— Data on bulls 96 to 107 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years — all seasons. z Age of | Ul || s Cows Sci- Services Con- for con- M" ,c Female K.ilio Kaliii Living Abor- Abor- W cow served vices per cow ccplinns ceplion calves c.ilves utiles females calves lions lions W jVo. A'o. A'o. Ay. no. So. Ay. no. So. So. I', it. I. CI. Xo. So V ct S Under ' 2 2 yrs 5 10 If. 1.60 3 5.33 0 3 .... 100.00 2 1 3113 2 yts 5 18 27 1.5(1 14 1.93 10 4 71.42 28.57 13 1 714 03 3 yr 5 12 14 1.17 7 2.(1(1 4 3 57.14 42.85 7 &lt;3 4 yrs 5 111 14 1.40 8 1.75 7 1 87.51] 12.50 8 C 5 yrs 4 7 12 1.71 5 2.4(1 4 I 80.00 20.00 5 hi 6 yrs 2 8 9 1.13 6 1.50 6' 1 85.71 14.28 6 I' 16.66 3 7 yrs 2 5 5 1.00 4 1.25 1 3 25.00 75.00 4 . Z 8 yrs 2 2 2 1.00 1 2.00 0 1 .... 100.00 1 __ 9 yrs 12 3 1.50 1 3.00 1 0 100.00 1 ' O 10 yrs . ... . ... ... ' " -«. 11 yrs 1 11 1.00 1 1.00 0 1 .... 100.00 1 12 yrs 1 1 1 1.00 1 1.00 II 1 .... 100.00 I v. or total 76 I_4 U7 51 _04 ii 19 63.46 36.53 49 3 5.88 1 One set of twins. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">13 : ¦' Table 9,—Dato on bulls 108 to 119 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years — all seasons. Agcof Bulls Cows Ser- Services Con- for con- Male Female Ratio Ratio Living Abor- Abor- j-? row served vices per cow ecplions ccp ,i, m calves calves males females calves tions lions so No. .' . . ATo. - ": No. Ay.no. No. Ay. no. So. . ¦ So. P.ct. P.ct. No. Xo. P.ct. O ¦ Under .-..'.•¦.''.¦•''..' tfl —2-yrsr-TTTT^^ __-. : -5- 11 -— - —2.-20 —2 -5.50^—. 2. 0 -100.00 - -'---rrrr— 2&gt;-~ : :—; ¦' M '2 yrs. '.. , 1, 2 : 3 1.50 1 .. 3.00 1.0 . 100.00 ".... .1 . . ' &gt;S 3 yrs. .......... 1 3 6 2.00 1 6.00 0 1 100.00 .. 1 100.00 S 9 yrs. 1 .1 1 1.00 1 1.00 1 0 100.00 1. .. 2 tv. or total . 11 21 . 1.91. ,5 4.20 4 1 80.00 20.00 4 1 20.00 S 1 . -. — . — . '¦ : . , : : 50 Table 10.— -Data on bulls 120 to 131 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years— all seasons. &gt;« ... . Sendees '" ¦ - ¦= O Agcof Bulls : Cows Scrr Services Con- forcon- Male Female ' Ratio Ratio Living Alior- Abor- ¦ ¦"¦• cow served vices pcrcow ecplions ccpiion calves calves males females calves . tion. lions O No. . No. No. Ay.no. No. Ay.no. So. No.: P.ct. P.ct. No. No -P.ct. _¦ Under .. 2 2 yrs. ..: 1 13-29 2.23 4 7.25 I 3 25.00 75.00 4 ¦. : . ... . .2 yrs. ......'.;.. .1 7 14. 2.00 '.• .5 . . 2.80 4.1. .. ¦ 80.00 ¦ 20.00 3 2 40.00 _j 3 yrs .1¦ 6 12 2.00 ,4.,. : 3.00 2 2 50.00 50.00 3. 1 25.00 O 4 yrs ... .. 1 .!'¦•' 1 1.00 1 1.00 1 0 100.00 1 . .. Z 10 yrs. 1 1 3, 3.00 1 3.00 ¦ 1 0 100.00 .... 1 tv. or total 28 59 2.11 15 3.93 9 6 60.00 40.00 12 3 20.00 </seg>
         <seg id="p024">14 m Table 11. — Data on bulls 132 to 143 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years — all seasons. 2 Age ol n„i|! Cows Ser- Services Con- f.'rYon- Male Female X.mo R.llin Liiing Alx.r- Abor- ?_ cow served vices per cow cepnons .rplion calves calve, ni.ilcs fc-males ciilvcs lions lions So. So. So. Ay. no. No. Ay. no. So. So. I. CI. V. cl. So. So. P. cl. O ."m 3 9 17 1.89 7 2.43 3 4 42.85 57.14 6 1 14.28 P 2 „. 1 4 6 1.67 4 ISO 3 1 75.00 25.(111 2 2 50.00 _- 3 ..„ I 7 9 1.29 6 1.50 4 2 66.66 33.11 4 2 33.31 U •1 ..,, 1 I 3 1.00 3 1.00 3 0 100.00 .... 3 .... - 5 &#132;r s 1 I 1 1.00 1 100 0 1 100.00 1 .... ' 10 vrs 1 1 &gt; l-"0 ¦•¦ •¦•• ¦•¦¦ if «... or total 25 37 1.48 21 1.76 13 8 61.90 38.09 16 5 23.80 5 Table 12. — Data on bulls 144 to 155 months of age and cows 2 to 18 years — all seasons. z Services Age of Bul l, Cows Ser- Services Con- f or con . Male Female Ratio Ratio Living Abor- Abor- m cow served vices per cow ecplions ceplion calves calves males females calves lions lions m No. So. So. Ay. no. No. Ay. 00. So. So. I', cl. I', ct. So. So. P. CI. ""v" 211 18 1.64 6 3.00 2 4 33.33 66.66 5 1 16.66 __ 2 i-rs. '". " 312 15 1.25 8 1.88 5 3 67.50 37.50 8 . .... BJ t™ 14 8 2.00 2 4.00 1 1 50.00 50.00 2 .... G 4 yr, 2 5 7 1.40 3 2.33 1 2 33.33 66.66 2 1 33.33 f. 5 „. 1 3 8 2.67 2 4.00 1 1 50.00 50.00 1 1 50.00 m i 01,,' ..".::.':' 1 1 1 1.00 1 1.00 o 1 .... 100.00 1 .... d Ay. or total , 36 57 1.58 22 2.59 10 12 45.45 54.54 19 3 13.63 Z 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p025">15 -^— TABi_Eul3v^J-i-^^ff--.tf«Vj-JJf5-f-L^^ — all-seasons^- — — Agcof Bu |j $ Cows Ser- Services. Con- for con- Male Female Ratio Ratio. Living: Abor- Abor-.: cow . . -. .erved vice. per cow ¦ ccption. ccption calves. calves males female., calve. lions tions No. No. No. Ay. no. . No. . Ay. no. No. No. /'. ct. /'. ct. No. No. P.ct. -Under 2 yrs. I 4 7 1.75 1 7.60 1 0 100.00 0 1 . 2 yrs. 2 3 3 1.00 2 1.50 1. 1 50.00 50.00 1 1 50.00 4 yrs. 1 1 1 1.00 1 1.00 1 0 100.00 .... 1 . .... m 5 yr. 1 1 1 1.00 1 1.00 0 1 .... 100.00 1 . ..... w 6 yrs. 1 1 2 2.00 1 2.00 1 0 100.00 .... 1 . .... 3 Av.ortotal 10 14 1.40 6 2.33 4 2 66.66 33.33 5 -.'¦' 1 16.66 5 -'¦ -— ¦ :: _ ; :—; : _—; .. ' .: ¦ o ...¦.-..___: - - :.-. ¦ ' .: .j __. ... j .j-'_. . -.. .'¦¦.-¦¦ '• w Table 14. — Data on bulls of all ages and cows of varying ages- — all seasons. » .Agcof- Bull. Cow. Ser- . Service. Con-. f or con- Male Female I .Ratio- Ratio Living Abor- Abor- Unknown "2 - cow r .erved vice. pcrcow ccption. cc ptiori calves' : calves | males females calves lion. lions sex .5 No. No. No. Ay.no. No. Ay.no. No. No. P.ct. p. .7. No. No. P.ct. No. S Under 2 yrs; ....... 114 537 . 803 1.50 319 2.52 162' 149' 52.25 47.47 282 41 12.85 13 a 2 yrs. ....... 104 368 512 1.39 250 2.05 123" 124" 49.79 50.20 221 33 13.20 7 50 3yr 88 305 442 1.45 210 2.10 I 12» 100' 52.83 47.16 197 20 9.52 5 ' *. 4 yrs. 76 205 292 1.42 148 1.97 82' 69' 54.30 45.69 133 15 10.13' 2 V 5 yr. 56 158 226 1.43 113 2.00 65 J 46' 58.55 41.44 101 15 13.27 5 § 6 yrs 47 125 180 1.44 83 2.17 49 s 30 62.02 37.97 68 16 19.27 5 O 7 yrs. ....... 47 ¦ 121 171 ; 1.41 82 2.09 45" 35 56.25. 43.75 71 12 14.63 3 H 8 yrs 40 85 129 1.52 57 2.26 28 27 50.90 49.09 50 7 12.28 2 3 . 9 yrs. 34 63 84 1.33 41 2.05 24' 17 58.53 41.46 38 5 12.19 2 S 10 yrs. ....... 27 51 85 1.67 27 3.15 15 J 13 53.57 46.42 24 4 14.81 0 S 11 yrs 21 35 49 1.40 24 2.01 . 15» 10 5 60.00 40.00 24 2 8.33 1 12 yrs 13 18 23 1.28 13 1.77 5 fi 45.45 54.54 11 : 2 15.38 2 13 yrs. 6 • .. 816 2.00 3 5.33 1 2 33.33 66.66 30 0. 14 yr 3 4 13 3.25 3 4.33 3 0 100.00 ..... 2 1 33.33 . 16 yr 1 2 9 4.50 0 0 0 0 . .... 0 0 0 . 17 yrs. ....... 12 2 1.00 1 2.00 1 0 100.00 . .... 1 0 0 . 18 yrs. ....... 2 3 5 1.67 1 5.00 0 1 .... 100.00 10 0 Total . 2090 3041 ... 1375 ... 730 628 .... .... 1232 173 .... 47 Average.. ¦ ... ¦¦¦¦ 1.46 ... 2.21 ... ... 53.75 46.25 ... ... 12.58 1 Two sets of twins. 'Three sets of twins. ; set of twins. ; * Four. sets of twins. </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Table IS.--.SYiT/et" records of bulls oj rarying ages, with coin of all ages. =-' " ~ w.ii'lnoi I A[ .,. „, ,¦„„, -&#132;, 5,,, &#132; ¦-....... l,„|l. &#132;, .. Mil. I . "... I. R.in.. I'""- L c Al-r M".r \7T AY AoT u~~^- ':','';¦ l-..i~ A". A... /•..;. ''..'¦ A" S" ''¦•&lt;• l,'"'" j,, &#132;., 45,1 117 .'l' 194 H ll' SS79 4-1 211 2HB III" 12 91 &#132; ' i-| IS4 Sl&gt; 114 258 198 212 Uu' US" 54 54 4S IS 219 JI- H,, 1 , ,71 IS9 52n 14S 24i, 2 11 897 128' II"' 5182 48 17 211. 36 14 20 a ' SI 292 441 IS2 185 219 2140 87' 91' 48 87 S| 12 ISB 31« 1.2. Z 5. 118 I9S 2TI 119 |2n 2 2i. 1645 64= 58= 52.45 47 54 lis 9- ,25 m '„,, i„ 7 &#132;,, |51 |2n 2 SI 29 14 1..™ Sir' 55.15 44 64 HI6 16- 1111 g -"" ,- 17N 25' 142 94 2681821 48 44-' 52.17 47 82 BS 111 111.52 &gt; 8 &#132;,. 11 76 1114 I 17 SI 2.1H 5.1S H' 19 1,1.46 16.51 49 3 5.76 _. &#132; ;' 511 'I I'll 5 4.211 111. Ml 4 1 80.111! 211.111, 4 1 20.011 &gt; H, ' sB 59 'II IS I'll 1112.81 9 6 1.11.(111 411.1111 12 1 211.1111 II ' 111 25 17 1.48 21 1.76 111. 11l II 861 '111 18,119 16 S 21.811 j_» p" ' 111 16 57 1.58 22 2.59 11. 57 111 12 45. 45 54.54 19 3 13.63 g i"l ..,.' 6 111 14 1.411 i. 2.H 211.16 4 2 66.66 33.33 ¦&gt; 1 0 r To I , . 2,191. lIHI H75 71,1 (.28 1212 171"' .U t „„. . 1.46 2JI . 51.75 462-, 12.58 pi 'Three sets of twins. 'One set &lt;&gt;( twins. "Thirteen calves of unknown sex. " ITuec calves &lt;.( unknown sex. 7 'Two scls of Iwins. ' Five elites of unknown sex. '¦ Two calves of unknown sex. "' F.my seven calves of unknown sex. ,_ - - r' Nine salves of unknown six. "Ten calves of unknown -sex. H Table 16. — Services per cow required for conception — cows and bulls of varying ages. g Alic of bull at lime of service in nmnlhs All 5g Age of ¦ . 1 1 1 j j j j j j a ß cs -, row , 223 24 _, 5 | „•„.,- | 4 8 .,„ | m . 7l | 72 . 8i | H4-95 | 96-107 | 108-11') | 120-131 | 132-143 | 144-155 | 156-167 hulls £ No. No. So. So. So. So. So. So. So. So. So. So. So. No. 5= U 2n'.. r . 1 81) 167 2.97 2.78 3.1.(1 2.95 4.(10 5.33 5.50 7.25 2.43 3.00 7.00 2.52 X 2?" 1,15 j7l is; 212 2.1.4 4.08 2.14 1.93 .3.00 2.80 1.50 1.88 1.50 2.03 CO . ;.„ 2'l' 219 18| 207 1.92 2.14 2.38 2.00 6.1.0 3.1.0 1.5(1 4.00 ... 2.11 r_ 4 • : ": fiai i:6i vi 2.27 i.*. 2.1s 2.1.3 1.75 ... 1.00 1.00 2.3.1 1.00 1.97 p '&#132;.... 1.75 1-95 2.18 1.77 2.45 1.80 2.181 2.411 1.00 4.00 1.00 2.00 g 6 Its 1.85 2.36 2.22 2.07 2.80 2.17 2.80 1.50 ... ... ... •¦• 2.00 2.17 _J 7 rs 2.00 2.31 1.58 2.55 2.08 2.78 2.0(1 1.25 ... ... ... ... •¦¦ 2.09 z I „ 1.89 1.56 3.00 2.58 1.50 3.13 1.75 2.00 ... ... ... ... -¦¦ 2.26 9 yr 1.60 2.43 2.09 2.25 2.50 1.(10 2.33 3.0(1 1.00 .„ ... ... ... 2.05 0 10 ,s 3.50 2.20 2.50 7.00 3.67 2.25 5.00 ... ... .3.00 ... 1.00 ... 3.15 _&amp;. 11 yrs 1.00 2.50 1.50 4.00 1.00 2.00 1.33 1.00 ... ... ... ... •-• 2.01 12 yrs 1.50 1.00 1.50 2.00 1.00 1.00 5.00 1.00 ... ... ... ••• ••• 1-77 13 yrs 3.00 2.00 4.00 ... ... ... ... ¦•- ••• ••• ••• ••¦ ¦•• _| 3 14 yrs 6.00 1-00 «•» |7&gt;- '-00 _•*, : :;: ::: ::: ::: I:SS TolVh-ll..:. 185 17. 171 153 108 '99 '60 33 5 5 10 10 6 2090 ¦¦"al cow. 329 354 359 292 195 197 178 76 11 28 25 36 10 cows A." I-I "-cl'" 194 1.98 2.11 2139 2.26 2.51 2.68 2.04 4.20 3.93 1.76 2.59 2.33 2.21 </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Table 17. — Data on influence of season — bulls of different ages, cows of all ages — Summer, May to October. —— —- ' ' Age of— I Bulls —' —Cow—— —Ser- Services — j—Gon— : —fortßlF —Malc-7— l-Fcmalc Ratio -Ratio —-— Livings -^A l»or — —r-Abor_— —Unknown — '¦ ¦ cow J served vices percow | ccption. ccption calves | calves | males females' calves lions lions ¦ sex No. . No. No. Ay.no.. No. Ay.no. ' No. No. P.ct. P.ct. No. . No. P.ct. No. - Under 2 yrs ...48 171 249 1.46 114 2.18 69' 44 . . 61.06 38.93 . 103 13 11.40 3 2 yrs. 39 203 289 1.42 150 1.93 78' .70 52.70 47.29 143 9 6.00 4 3 yrs. 34 182 261 1.43 116 2.25 56 58' 49.12 50.87 101 17 14.65 4 4 yrs. 29 131 209 1.60 ' 83 2.52 48' 36» 57.14 42.85 '74 14 16.86 4 . 5 yrs 19 80 116 1.45 46 2.52 29a 18' 61.70 38.29 45 3 6.52 I Cn 6 yrs 20 88 141 1.60 55 2.56 27 21 56.25 43.75 47 8 14.54 7 tn 7 yrs. . 12 78 124 .1.43 .46 2.70 19 26' 42.22 57.77 42 5 10.86 2 2 » yrs. 7 38 51 1.34 24 2.13 16 8 66.66 33.33 23 1 4.16 . g 9 yrs 2 2 . 3 1.50 1 .3.00 0 1 . .... 100.00 0 . I 100.00 . '. ; 2 '¦_:.'¦ lOyrs. '..„...¦• I ' •14. . 31 2.21 6-' 5.17 3 3 .50.00 50.00- 4 2 33.33 . S 11 yrs."-...... 3" — 19" 30 "1.58 "16 KBB : " 12~ 4 75.00 25.00 11- 5 31.25 """ . ,__ .'¦'.¦ 12 yr 3 19 .24 1.26 12 2.00 5 7 41.66 58.33 10 2 16.16 ... fn 13 yrs. ..'., 2. 5 8 . L6O 4 „ 2.00 3. .1. '• 75.00 . 25.00 . 4 .0 0.. . . b \v. or total ....; 219 1039 .1536 1.48 673 2.28 365 297 .55.13 44.86 607 80 11.88 25 g — ¦ - : ' ! : ! : — —— '¦ — ; • — _ '¦ — ¦ : : —I 1 Two sets of twins. 2 Three sets of twins. 'One set of twins. E_ . Table .18.—^ Data on influence of season— bulls of different ages, cows of all ages—Winter, November to April. 1 g &#132; I .... &#132; ... 1 A 0 Agcof Bulls Cows Ser- Services Con- for con- '-'Mile- Female Ratio Ratio Living Abor- Abor- Unknown ("J cow ' served vice. percow ecplions gep,;,,,, calves calves males females calves tions tions. sex O ; No. No. ; No. Ay. 110. No. - Ay. no. , No. ¦ No. P. cl. P. ct. No. No. P.ct. No. O . 'Under ¦¦•'.'¦'•¦. H 2 yrs. ..;.... 52 . 158 201 1.27 118 1.70 61' 59 1 50.83 49.16 105 17 14.40 2 3 2 yrs. ..38 151 223 1.48. . 108. 2.06 60: - 45' 57.14 . 42.85 . 96 14 . 19.96 5 S ¦'¦3 yrs. 40 177 . 259 1.46 130 ; 1.99 72' , 61&gt; 54.13 45.86 115 19 14.61 1_; * y«- • 29 161 234 1.45 102 2.29 39' 55 41.48 58.51 84 19 18.62 9 5 yrs. ....... 25 115 155 1.35 74 2.09 35' 40" 46.66 53.33 70 6 8.10 1 6 yrs. ....... 19 109 160 1.47 65 2.46 35' 29' 54.68 45.31 59 8 12.30 3 7 yrs. ....... 12 87 124 1.43 . 46 2.70 29 18 61.70 38.29 43 5 10.41 1 8 yrs. 5 38 53 . 1.39 27 1.96 17' 11 60.71 39.28 26 2 7.40 0 9 yn 2 9 18 2.00 4 4.50 4 0 100.00 .... 4 0 0 0 10 yrs. 1 14 28 2.00 9 3.11 6 3 66.66 33.33 8 1 11.11 0 11 yrs 3 6 7 1.17 5 1.40 1 4 20.00 80.00 5 0 0 0 12 yrs. ....... 3 17 33 1.94 10 3.33 5 5 50.00 50.00 9 1 10.00 0 13 yrs. 2 5 6 1.20 2 3.00 1 1 50.00 50.00 1 I 50.00 0 Ay. or total 231 1051 1505 1.43 702 2.14 365 331 52.44 47.55 625 93 13.24 22 1 One set of twins, ' Three sets of twins. ' Two sets of Iwins. </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Table 19.— Data on influence ol_jeason—cou^^f_different ages, bulls of allyg^Jum^.Ma^J^ctobe^ v of Cow, Ser Service, lon- (T'T M-' 1" |:'"&gt;' lc X"'" X'"" ll""( A 1"- A" r Uk"" U" AZf "Ul" scrvco VKC. per..." .ep.ion. « ___¦ ___¦ le.nales .- ¦ — — ~ ~7TIZ So~. 1.-, no. ivol Nol fT&lt;7 1' rr. No. No. P. cl. No. U'" lc' .- „- a„, ISO 14- 271 Hl' 59 58.45 41.54 128 21 14.28 7 2 I'"' «,', f-k "r '5 PI 111, 02' 58' 51.66 48.11 110 11 111.74 3 _ "*¦ S ,_ ,« 41 7 2 14 42 Hl' 58.11 41.1* 67 6 8.45 £ J&gt;" .'. "„",' ,1 " ,i 2(1 14 22' 60.71 39.28 50 9 15.51 3 £ ' 1" V -?, &#132; 44 41 _„ 24 17 58.51 41.46 &lt;5 8 18.(0 2 g s&gt;" !',• ,'! „, -^ Jf 23, IV 16 54.28 45.71 3 1 4 11.11 2 * •r- 23 37 50 ,15 2, 2.3- I* jl-jl ft* » | J;» J 0 &gt;" 5 ,4 17 121 II 17 5 4 55.55 44.44 8 2 20.00 1 &gt; _'" ', " .22 I.W 2 3 40.00 (41.00 511616 1 g £g^E ', _j _j L4B g 2.2, g g *.. _j g;ii !_ F ¦ Two sets of twin,. » One «¦ of .«»&gt; ' Three S« S ° f '"in!- J Table 20.— Data on influence of season— cows of different ages, bulls of all ages—Winter. November to April. g A.eof „ &#132; Cow. Ser- Service, Con- ?"„,„' Male Female Ra.io Kali.. Living Abor- Abor- Unknown _ ASw """' Slaved vice. Per Co" ccption, __j__ calves calve, males female. calves lion. g» Mo. No. No. .4... "o. .Vo. .4,.. no. No. .Vo. /'. ,-,. P. a. So. So. P. ct. \o. jj U, n''cr m ,80 401 143 172 213 79 89' 47.02 52.97 154 20 11.62 6 Of 9 _£_ f 9 Jo? .75 42 29 213 61 66' 48.03 51.96 111 20 15.50 4 X 1»" _? ul 208 41 90 231 60' 32' 65.21 34.78 84 9 10.00 __ J vr " S ,§ HO 4 77 182 40- 39' 50.63 49.36 71 9 11.68 1 g 3 5 v " 3? 76 08 42 55 1.96 31' 24' 56.36 43.63 51 6 10.90 2 r _ &gt;" ii .2 ,S 44 4u 108 25» 13 65 78 34.21 33 8 20.00 3 £ «»"•.. if 5? Ii {39 a. 85 26 19 57.77 42.22 38 8 17.39 1 5 1 I" U 5. || -.42 34 2.50 14 19 42.42 57.57 29 5 14.70 1 § _*"£ 52 „ {iT __ 170 8' 11 42.10 57.89 17 4 20.00 2 z 10 yr' ••::•: 3 IS II ii. 8 J-S . J &lt;lw ww » » 2307 0 s ll vr s {7 21 32 1.52 14 2.29 10" 6' 62.50 37.50 16 0 0 0 = 2Jm " " I 9 12 1.33 7 1.71 3 3 50.00 50.00 6114 28 1 !t _¦ ? % 7 2 33 2 3 50 0 2 .... 100.00 2 0 0 0 M Jt.:::::::: II s I-, i i:oS " . 100.00 .... 1000 16 y». ...... 1 1 _ &#132;00 i 2.66 i 6 100.66 i 00" 6 8 Jr.' •".'.•". 2 3 I I_S 1 5.00 0 I 100.00 I 0 0 0 </seg>
         <seg id="p029">¦ . ¦ ¦:. . . -.. \ ¦ ¦ :¦¦-.¦ - Services Required for Conception Tabu 21.— Influence of season—cows of all ages bred to bulls of all ages. Total I _ I Services ¦ ¦ . Calves horn Calm born : " M°"'f :,¦&amp; ¦f^.iteA ml|^ k ~m,.cs I j;,;, No. No. No. p.ci. flo. &lt;Vo. P. a. &gt;.&lt;•/. So. Pel. January ... 252 123 2.08 48.80 63' . CO" 51.22 43.78 18&lt; 14.63 February .. 218 97 2.25 44.49 52' 43&gt; 54.74 45.26 17» 752 March ... 211 110 2.46 40.59 58' 51» 53.21 4679 13= 1181 April ..... 251 116 ,2.16 46.21 64&gt; 51- 55.65 44.35 1« 9.48 &gt;fa&gt;- ¦:¦»» .¦•••'«¦ I 2-2" «•¦(/ ¦¦•«!•¦¦ 55' 52.54 47.41 9' 789 ™c •}£". ¦ JM 2.10 4-.G9 M 57&gt; 52.89 47.11 13* 1048 (ul)- ..... 277 134 2.07 48.37 76» 59' 56.30 43.70 14' 10 44 Aujua .... 270 97 2.78 35.92 53" 39 57.61 42.39 14« 1443 Sf"l mT "• 'S? M 2.85 35.14 50 32 60.98 39 02 1' 3.09 October ... 237 120 1.99 50.20 6P 55« 52.59 47.41 9« 583 NovcmbJr .234 112 2.09 47.86 54' . «0&gt; 47.36 52.64 8« 714 ,&amp; ¦.!» SUI 6?« "J 86 "H ,7?. lB°s ¦ivcrage ¦-....;....... 2.21 -45.21 ...... 53J5 46.25 ... 1158 'One set of twins. • SU calves unknown sex. 'Tw ids of twins. T Two calves unknown sex. •• Thru sets of twins. 'One calf unknown sci. •Thnt calves unknown sex. . . • Seven calves unknown sex. Fou: calves unknown sex. 10 Forty-seven calves unknown sex. LITERATURE CITED 1. Ecklcs, C. H. 1929. A Study of Breeding Records of Dairy Herds. Minn. Acr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 258. 2. Fitch, C. P., Boyd, W. L., Dclcz, A, L. 1929. Report of Experimental Work in the Control of Bovine Infect - ious Abortion. Jour. Amcr. Vet. Mcd. Assn., Vol. LXXV pp. 215-229. 3. Gowcn, J. W., and Dove, W. F. 1931. -.Fertility in Dairy Cattle.' Maine Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 360. i ¦i. [ohansson, Ivar 1932. Conclusions o.v Sex Inheritance. Jersey Bulletin, March 9, 1932. 5. Knott. J. C. ..¦'.' . 1932. Study of Gestation Period of Holstein-Friesian Cows. Jour. Dairy Sci. Vol. XV, No. 2. ¦ .. . r ¦ -.. 6. Miller. F. W., and Graves, R. R. ..-.¦'-. 1932. Reproduction and Health Records of the Beltsville Herd of the Bureau of Dairy Industry. U. S.Dept. of Agr. Tech. Bui. 321. 7. Miller, F.W., Graves, R. R., and Fohrman, M.H. ¦ 1937. Management and Breeding Data on a Dairy Herd in Which Bang's Disease (Infectious Abortion) was Eradicated by Segregation. Jour. Dairy Sci. Vol. XX, No. 8, pp. 537-550. ,¦ ¦ 8. Uoseley, T. W., Stuart,. Duncan, and Graves, R. R. . ' .1929. Dairy Work at the Huntley Field Station, Huntley, Montana, 1918-1927. U. S. Dcpt. of Agr. Tech. Bui. 116. 9. Nebraska University,. Department of Dairy Husbandry. ' 1930. Economic Aspects of Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station Res. Bui. 46. j 10. I'carl, Raymond ¦'.".:. j 1917. Report of Progress o.v Animal Husbandry Investigations in 1916. j Thirty-third Annual Report, Maine Agn Exp. Sta., pp. 121-31. I 11. White, Gco. C, Johnson, Robert E., Rettgcr, Leo F.; and McAlpine, Jas. G. j 1925. Some Economic Phases of Bacterium Abortus Infections and I Other Observations in Dairy Herds. Storrs (Connecticut) Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 135. ; ¦:.'' ; :: " ¦'¦'::'¦•.- ¦'¦¦. • ' '¦' ¦' ¦''¦' ¦¦¦ • wsi-m '. ¦ i </seg>
         <seg id="p030"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>