<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Field Experiments and Seed Corn Treatments and Crop Stimulants</title>
               <date value="1927-05">1927-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 218 May, 1927 Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments and Crop Stimulants T. A. KIESSELBACH Department of Agronomy i ' - m II II nl XXIV I % J R . EATED ' UNTREATED^ A typical germinator test of seedling stimulation by seed treatment with orßantc mercury compounds THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY Except m the case of small grains infected with covered smuts, seed treatment of Nebraska grown crops was not beneficial m tests made at the Nebraska Experiment Station during the three-year period from 1924 to 1926. The seed used was representative of varieties of corn, winter wheat, oats, and barley adapted to this locality and was selected for planting m accordance with usual farm practice. The organic mercury disinfectants, including Uspulun, Semesan, and Bayer Dust, applied to ordinary seed corn had no significant effect upon the germination, field stand, rate of seedling growth, crop vigor, percentage of smut, barrenness, lodging, yield per acre, or quality of product. The securing of equal field stands is indirect evidence that the damage from worms was not reduced. Results by other investigators suggest that favorable response from these treatments may be expected primarily with Diplodia-infected and Gibberella-infected seed. Evidence indicates that these are not serious factors as seed-borne diseases m the corn production of this state. There was no sign of damage caused by seed-borne diseases to corn grown from either treated or untreated seed under the conditions of these experiments. Uspulun and the standard treatments, copper carbonate and formalin, have proved effective m the control of stinking smut of wheat. Used as crop stimulants, these organic mercury compounds have no material effect upon the growth or yield of healthy wheat, oats, barley, or corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">... ■ ;.■ . '-; Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments and Crop Stimulants T. A. KIESSELBACH The use of certain organic mercury compounds as seed corn treatments and crop stimulants is so universally advertised and recommended by their manufacturers and dealers that the farmers' interest has become aroused. Many inquiries concerning them are being received by the Agricultural College and it is the purpose of this bulletin to supply the desired information, based on results obtained from com - parative tests by the Nebraska Experiment Station. OBJECT OF SEED TREATMENT The reasons that have been advanced for seed treatment are (1) disinfection against seed-borne diseases, (2) protec - tion of seed against soil-borne diseases, and (3) growth stimulation. Disinfection of corn with these mercuric com - pounds appears to be proposed primarily to destroy certain " root, stalk, and ear rot diseases" and to bring about stim- •• ulated seedling growth. Corn smut is not included m this class of diseases and, as is well known, could not be affected by any form of seed treatment. On the other hand, it appears that certain smuts are the only serious diseases of small grains m Nebraska which may be controlled by recognized seed treatments. THE NEBRASKA TESTS CJiaracter of Seed Treatments Used. — The object of these tests has been to determine the need for seed disinfection under Nebraska conditions and to study the possible growth stimulation, exclusive of disease control, m the cereal crops. It has been the desire to establish the general principles con - cerning the use of such seed treatments m this state rather than to secure comparative results from specific brands. It was necessary, however, to use commercial products and those selected as fully typical have been Uspulun, Bayer Dust, and Semesan Jr. The active ingredient of these seed treat - ments is either hydroxymercurinitrophenol sulphate or hydro - xymercurichlorophenol sulphate. The Uspulun treatment con - sists of soaking the seed for a period of 1 to 2 hours m a one-fourth per cent water solution. The seed may be sown wet or first dried after treatment. It was dried m these tests. Acknowledgment is made for assistance by \V. E. Lynesi and T. H. Goodding m erowinc the crop and making plant counts m the field. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 218 Both Bayer Dust and Semesan are used as a dust and are applied to the grain at the rate of 2 ounces per bushel of seed. In these experiments the application was made by use of a revolving box, such as is used in the copper carbonate treat - ment of wheat for stinking smut. CROPS TESTED WITH TREATMENTS The first tests in Nebraska with any of these products were made in 1924, and 3 years' data are available. Two of these years, 1925 and 1926, were relatively unfavorable for crop production, except during its early growth, due to severe moisture shortage. The yields are therefore abnormally low. but the results in general should be suggestive of what may be commonly expected from these seed treatments under Nebraska conditions. There is no reason to suspect that con - ditions in other regions of the state would result in a different type of response. In all, 4 kinds of crops have been treated for their response to one or more of these preparations. The chief grain crops in this state were included, — corn, wheat, oats, and barley. FIELD EXPERIMENTS WITH SEED CORN TREATMENTS Farmers' Varieties. — During the 2 years, 1925 and 1926, seed corn was obtained from 30 different farmers living within a radius of 10 miles of the Experiment Station. No direct effort was made to compare diseased and healthy corn in these tests. In most cases the seed was taken from corn that had been shelled by the growers for planting their own fields. A composite sample was prepared from equal quantities of each farmer's seed. This was divided for comparative plant - ing into 4 lots, one of which was untreated, and the other 3 treated respectively with Uspulun, Semesan Jr. '^nd Bayer Dust according to methods recommended by their manufac - turers. This series of 4 lots of corn was planted in one-eighteenth - acre field plats consisting of 3 rows each. Six systematically distributed plats of each treatment were grown and- conclus - ions are based on the averages for the duplicate plats. Equal numbers of seed were planted in all cases in hills 3.5 feet apart. Detailed notes concerning the comparative stands, plant de - velopment, and yield were taken. These are summarized in Tables 1 and 2. Smut counts are included in these corn data merely to correct a mistaken impression gained by many growers that these treatments might be expected to control this disease. It is apparent that none of these treatments materially affected the field germination, the vigor of seedling and mature growth, or the yield per acre. There was no significant in-- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments fluence upon the percentage of barren plants, lodged plants, smutty plants, suckers, shrinkage of ear corn after husking, or shelling percentages. There was no indication whatever that plant growth was stimulated, or that disinfection with any of these products was helpful. In 1926 individual comparisons were made of both Uspulun treated and untreated seed from 20 of the farmers who sup - plied the seed for the tests just described. The results are summarized in Table 3. No benefits are apparent from the seed treatment. Dates of .Planting. — In order to determine whether the time of planting might be a factor in the response of corn to seed treatment, comparative tests were made in 1926 with 3 lots of seed planted at 7 different dates of about 10-day intervals, starting 2 weeks earlier than the customary beginning of the corn planting season. Two lots of this seed were Nebraska White Prize arid Hogue Yellow Dent corn respectively, both standard eastern Ne - braska varieties which have undergone no special selection during the last 20 to 30 years for type or disease resistance, aside from picking sound appearing ears at the regular time of corn husking just as most farmers pick them. The third lot of seed was picked in the spring from a pile of 200 bushels of field-run corn that had been placed in a poorly ventilated granary at the time of husking. Many of the ears were moldy and would commonly be regarded as poor seed. Half of each of the 3 lots of seed was treated with Uspulun and half was left untreated. This made a series of 6 samples planted in duplicate in 2-row field plats of one - twenty-seventh acre area, on each planting date. The treated and untreated seed of the same variety were planted side by side in the field. The stand counts taken 3 weeks after planting are shown for each date in Table 4. There seemed to be no significant advantage in favor of treated seed at any date, and the poorest grade of seed as well as the better grades gave no appreciable response to treatment. The yields and other ob - servations concerning plant development from each lot are averaged for all 7 planting dates in Table 5. There was no significant departure in the results of any planting date from this average. The average increase or decrease in yield per acre from treated seed at each successive planting date was (1) 0.0 bu., (2) —0.8 bu., (3) —2.00 bus., (4) +0.7 bu., (5) +0.7" bu., (6) +1.6 bus., (7) 0.0 bu. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Table 1. — Effect of seed treatment upon the growth and yield of dent corn secured from 30 dif- ferent farmers and planted in composite. 1925. ===== - -^_, _ ===== ■ ■ — g; ,, I Tit 100 plants Ear-corn i Yield K No. fivhl Miiluri' - - ... ; shcll'-d BB Treatment ,,lam stand hi-iirht i Shrink- Shellinu corn P&gt; "■ ; "ecimil Smutty Barren IxxIkm-cI Suckers HKe percent ! por acre *J t , , ''• ct - '"• '"■ I', el. V. rt. I', rt. I', rt. /'. rt flu Uspulun 6 79.2 98 17 15 25 6 5.7 82 6 39 2 &gt; Semesan. Jr 6 78.7 !)!) 16 lfi 20 5 9.1 83 0 39 5 w Bayer Dust 6 78.5 98 15 15 21 7 8.3 82.4 38.7 X Average all treatments 18 78.8 98 lfi 15 22 6 77 82 7 39 1 S Untreated _ jj^ 79.0 98 lfi 15 . 22 . 7 : 6.8 ■ 82^9 ' 39^4 » Plats consisted of 3 rows, 64 hills in length. Yields were based on center rows. H Table 2. — £7fec£ 0/ seerf treatments upon the growth and yield of dent corn secured from 30 dif- w _ === ferent farmers and planted in composite. 1926. g M s" ii on, ,. Per 100 plants - Ear-corn " ; Ykld S No. rnOil , Scnlline Mature _ «h,.l]r&gt;l H Treatment plats hUh.1 \ heicht h..i K ht , . , shrink- Shellin K "nrn Z _ av - Becured | June 7 Smutty i Damn : LckIkiiI . Sucki-ra am- per cent | per acre Uspulun 6 74.0 8.4 74 40 68 18 5 ! 10 5 79 3 I 7 4 P Semesan, Jr._. \ 6 74.8 8.0 74 41 ; 68 ) 19 5 10.6 79 5 69 £ Bayer Dust _j q 72.1 8.5 73 35 ; 60 19 7 11.1 80.0 7.3 H Average all SJ treatments... 18 73.6 8.5 74 39 fi5 19 6 10.7 79 6 7 2 M Untreated _.... 6 73.2 8.5 73 37 63 20 5 8.3 79.9 7.'2 oo Plats consisted of 3 rows, 64 hills in length. Yields were based on center rows. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">TABLE 3. — Average effect of seed treatment upon the growth and yield of dent corn secured from 20 Nebraska farmers, and tested individually at the Experiment Station in 1926. nj Per 100 plants ] Ear-corn Yield M No. Field Scedlinu Mature — : — 1 shelled O Treatment plats stand helsht height : Shrink- . Shelling corn av. secured June 7 Smutty Barren | Lodged Suckers I ago per cent per acre (Tj p.et. Tn. . lit. P.ct. P.et. P.ct. P.et. P. ct. P.ct. Bu. * Untreated _ 20 74.7 8.6 . 74-42 71 17 6 . 11.5 80.0 . . 7.7 g . Uspulun __ 20 77.3 8.3 74 -41 77 15 4 12.2 80.2 7.6 H Single row plats, 64 hills in length. • . . . . TABLE 4. — Comparative field stands secured from treated and untreated seed of dent corn, planted !jj ' at 7 different dates in the spring. 1926. ! w Average §3 . Field stand obtained at various dates of planting 2 lab. Q a^'d U?atac1it V20 ~T~*4726~ I S/5 [ B/1S I S/25 6/S | 6/16 ,| Av. . * "tSts"' O " P.ct. r. el. P.et. P.et. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.et. P.et. W W U8Dufun Ze 87 86 87 83 76 88 72 83 98 _, Untreated _____ 87 87 86 83 77 85 72 82 97 S H( UsDUlun 79 82 81 81 80 75 69 78 93 S Untreated 80 80 83 82 80 74 68 78 94 g P °U8Dufifn _ . „ 78 75 78 72 69 75 66 73 89 § Untreated. T-I—I 74 77 76 72 69 78 71 j 74 86 g Duplicate two row plats, 64 hills in length. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 CO TABLE 5. — Effect of seed treatment* upon the growth and yield of com, as an average for 7 plant- m ____ ing dates. 19J(&gt;. j* .... , , .. ... , , . IVr li»l pliinls Enr-corn Yidil rrl Kind ,,f No. l-,.l,l L.,,,,. Elll sialk _ , MM gl «f.-&lt;l un,| pints sumil in h.-ivrhl h.-iuhl Shrink- Shi-llinn corn « tn-ntmi-nt nv. ».-curnl (n»«,-l SnHilly Harm IxmIsiiI Surk.n. aw per c.nt per acre frj White Prl«e " "'• '" '" '" ''"' '' " " '' " '' " '"^ 7 &gt;T * ""' g Uspulun 14 82.7 S/:i Xfi 71 2fi 30 (ifi 1 :{ 10.fi i 78.0 10.7 H Untreated 14 82. H 8/3 H7 72 25 29 B7 12 12 0 77 5 10 6 Zk Hogue Uspulun ... 14 7S.2 7/31 :)2 In 21 2!) «S :12 11 7 80 3 12 2 2 1 Untreuted 14 77. S 7/.I1 .! 1 li!l 2f&gt; I!0 «8 34 10 6 78 3 12 2 &gt; Poor seed H Uspulun 14 73.4 7/:51 2!t Ii7 IX 2!l 8fi 2fi 12 6 80 9 10 8 S Untreated 14 74.0 7/31 2il (iS 1 &lt;i 30 87 24 14.3 81.7 11.2 ?&gt; Average , W Uspulun .. 42 78.1 32 711 23 2!l 73 24 11.6 79 8 11.2 S Untreated 42 77.9 32 70 23 30 74 23 12.3 79.2 11.3 C* Two row plats, 64 hills in length. J3 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments When the results from all varieties and planting dates are averaged it is found that the field germination, tasseling date, stalk and ear height and percentage of smut were identical for both treated and untreated seed. The number of barren and lodged stalks was one less per hundred for the treated corn, and the yield was one-tenth bushel per acre higher. These slight differences probably should not be regarded as significant. No differences were noted in the quality of crop harvested and none of these data suggest that such seed treat - ments reduced the damage from worms or rodents. LABORATORY TESTS WITH SEED CORN TREATMENTS Repeated germination tests of treated and untreated seed in soil filled boxes that were similarly watered and exposed in the laboratory have failed to show increased germination or vigor of growth in response to treatment None of the growth stimulation effect which is sometimes pictured for some of these preparations has been observed with any of the corn used. A typical test of this kind made in the spring of 1926 is shown in Figure 1. It may be mentioned in this connection that germination tests may be very subject to systematic errors and are apt to be misleading unless precautions are taken to have all con - ditions uniform. STIMULATION TESTS WITH HEALTHY SEED OF THE SMALL GRAINS Oats.— Kherson oats known to be free from smut were tested in field plats for their response to treatment with Fig. 1. — Typical results from Rermlnation tests of treated seed corn. All treatments were made according to recommended practices. The seed used was just ordinary corn prepared in the usual manner. The variety name, treatments, germination per - centages, and seedling heights after the twelfth day in this test were as follows: (1) HoKue, Uspulun, 87 p.ct, 8.5 inches; (3) Hogue. Bayer Dust, 84 p.ct. 8 0 inches; (6) Hogue, not treated, 84 p.ct, 8.5 inches; (8) Hogue, water soaked 85 p:ct, 8.5 inches: (2) Reid, water soaked, 98 p.ct., 8.0 Inches; (7) Reid. Uspulun 96 p.ct, 8.5 inches; (4) White Prize, Uspulun, 93 p.ct, 8.6 inches; (5) White Prize water soaked, 94 p.ct., 8.5 inches. ' ' </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 218 Uspulun in 1924 and 1925. From the results reported in Table 6 it is seen that the plant height and dates of heading and ripening were the same for both treated and untreated seed. The untreated seed yielded 2.7 bushels more per acre in 1924 and 0.3 bushels more in 1925. Due to the low number of replications, these differences may probably be regarded as within the limits of experimental error. Table 6. — Effect of Uspulun used, as a stimulant upon the growth and yield of smut-free Kherson oats. 192U and 1925. . No. of Date j Yield Treatment field plats ' Plant in Date I grain Test averaged height : head ripe per acre weight I lnche* Bushels Pounds YEAR 1925 Untreated 3 26 6/17 7/11 51.0 ' 29.5 I L'spulun 3 26 6/17 7/11 | 48.3 29.0 YEAR 1026 Untreated 2 22 6/4 6/29 12.3 30 0 I ■ 1 Uspulun 2 21 6/4 \ 6/29 12.0 [ 2! &gt;-° Tests were made in thirtieth-acre field plats. Barley. — Comfort barley, which is a high yielding smooth bearded variety, was tested for its response to Uspulun treat - ment in 1926. Ten alternating thirtieth-acre field plats each of treated and untreated seed were grown. The results reported in Table 7 show no significant effects. Table 7. — Effect of Uspulun used as a stimulant upon the growth and yield of Comfort barley. 1924 and 1925. No. of Yield Treatment field plats Plant Date Brain Test averaged height ripe per acre weight Inches Bushels Pounds Untreated _ _ 10 24 6/28 29.5 46.5 Uspulun 10 24 6/28 29.9 46.6 Tests were made in thirtieth-acre field plats. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments Winter Wheat. — Uspuliin had no measurable effect upon the growth or yield of smut-free Kanred winter wheat grown in alternating field plats of treated and untreated seed, replicated 7 times. (Table 8.) Table 8. — Effect of Uspulun and Bayer Dust used as stimu - lants upon the growth and yield of smut-free Kanred winter wheat. 1925 and 1926, 1 No. ol • Date Grain Treatment , plats Plant in Date yield Test \ averaged height head ripe per acre weight Inches Bushels \ l'ounds YEAR 1925 ■■■■-■• Untreated _ 7 19 5/28 6/24 6.8 60.5 Uspulun ! 7 19 5/28 6/24 6.8 60.0 YEAR 1926 Untreated ! 10. 6/26 10.4 ' 59.0 Water soaked j 10 j 6/26 10.9 59.2 Uspulun -I 10 i 6/26 11.2 59.0 Bayer Dust 10 j : 6/26 10.8 59.0 Thirtieth-acre field plats in 1925 and 5-row nursery blocks in 1926. In 1926 this same variety was tested in well replicated nursery blocks for its reactions to Uspulun, Bayer Dust, soaking in warm water, and no treatment. The slight dif - ferences of a fraction of a bushel in yield would not seem significant. TREATMENT OF SMALL GRAINS FOR SMUT Tests at the. Nebraska ' Experiment Station with Uspulun and the standard treatments, copper carbonate and formalde - hyde, indicate that these disinfectants will control the stink - ing smut of wheat and smut of oats. Uspulun and formalde - hyde are suitable for both of these cereals, whereas copper carbonate is less satisfactory for oats due to the hull of the grain preventing direct contact of the dust with the kernel. The benefits from seed treatment of smut-infected winter wheat for stinking smut may be illustrated by 3 years' re - sults as presented in Table 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 218 TABLE 9.— Effect of treating Kanred winter wheat which was heavily infected with stinking smut. Three-year aver - ages, 1924-1926. I Yield of Per cent TriRtmcnt (train Test smutty heads per acre weight in crop jrrown Bushels ' Poumln Vntreated _... I 10.8 56.9 42.0 Formalin 17.2 59.3 1.0 Copper carbonate 17.3 58.5 4 0 Uspuhin 1 6.5 58.8 1.6 Teats made in duplicate thirtieth-acre field plats. RESULTS ELSEWHERE IN THE UNITED STATES Concerning the growth stimulation induced in corn by seed treatment, Lantz * has concluded that " In general, it can be said that soaking in Uspulun had no stimulating effect upon the growth or catalase activity above what is secured by soak - ing for the same period in water. As a fungicide it effectively prevented the growth of molds without injury to the corn." From an extensive test with sweet corn, conducted in 1925 in Illinois and Iowa, comparing the effects of 7 different treat - ments upon nearly disease-free seed, Diplodia-infected seed, and Gibberella-infected seed, Reddy, Holbert and Erwin f conclude that : " No practical control of bacterial blight of sweet corn was obtained by treating the seed. When nearly disease-free seed was used, the field stands and yields were affected but little by seed treatments with organic mercury compounds. When seed diseased with Diplodia zeae or Gib - berella saubinetii was used, the field stands and yields nearly always were materially increased by seed treatments with organic mercury compounds. The yields from nearly disease - free seed were slightly higher than those from treated Dip - lodia-infected seed, and considerably higher than those from treated Gibberella-infected seed. When only diseased seed is available for planting certain seed treatments will have dis - tinct value. Such seed treatments do not injure the seed." Investigations with seed treatment of dent corn conducted in Illinois by Holbert, Reddy, and Koehler $ were briefly re - • Lantz. C. w.. Respiration in corn with special reference to catalase. American Journal of Botany, vol. 14. no. 2. pp. 85-105, 1926. "•«■■&gt;&lt;;. «mencan t Reddy. C. S.. J. R. Holbert and A. T. Erwin. Seed Treatments for sweet corn diseases. Jour. Agr. Research, vol. 3. no. H. 1926. tHolbert, J. R., C. S. Reddy and Benjamin Koehler. Seed treatments for the con - trol of certain diseases of dent corn. Phytopathology, vol. 16, no. 1 1926 Cooperative invesications by the Office of Cereal Investinations Burea'u of Plant Industry U. S. Department of Agriculture, the Funk Brothers' Seed Company, and the Illinois Agricultural Experiment Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments ported in Phytopathology in 1926. The increases or decreases in the yield per acre of dent corn resulting from treatments with 15 different preparations are given. Three lots of seed were used with each treatment, namely " Nearly disease-free seed, Diplodia-ihfected seed," and . " Gibberella-inf ected seed. The technique of these tests is not described. The conclusions are reproduced as follows : " Extensive experiments conducted at various places in Illinois during the past five years have shown that dent corn grown from seed infected with Diplodia zeae and Gibberella saubinehi is greatly improved in both yield and quality by seed treatment, while corn from Fusarium moniliforme in - fected and scutellum-rotted seed has not been improved. Only under certain soil conditions not fully understood, have seed treatments increased the yield of corn grown from seed in - fected with Cephalosporium acremonium. Treated, infected seed has not yielded as well as untreated, nearly disease-free seed. Seed treatment may prove important when it is impos - sible to secure sufficient nearly disease-free seed." Discussion. — Since these investigators obtained striking benefits with their Diplodia and Gibberella infected seed and no improvement or negative results in 11 cases out of 15 with " nearly disease-free seed," it seems probable that the failure to secure benefits from treatment in the Nebraska tests indi - cates that these particular disease organisms do little damage thru seed infection under Nebraska conditions. It should be borne in mind that the diseased seed used by Holbert, Reddy, and Koehler, represented extreme cases of infection, whereas the corn used in the Nebraska treatment tests, except one sample, was typical farm seed selected without respect to the diseases in question. A broad interpretation of the data pre - sented in connection with the United States Department of Agriculture experiments here cited and often partially quoted in advertisements would not seem to warrant the conclusion that good farm seed would be greatly benefited by any of the treatments tested. . * The comparative absence of injury to Nebraska corn from seed-borne diseases has been further demonstrated in several field tests, comparing seed which had been selected by the germinator method as the two extremes of infection. Such a test made in 1921 was reported by the writer in 1922 * comparing the field performance of " diseased " and " disease - free" ears with the original unselected seed. During the following 4 years both " diseased " and " disease-free " Hogue Yellow Dent and Nebraska White Prize corn were • Klessclbach, T. A.. Corn Investigations, Nebraska A?r. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 20, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 218 Table ; 1O.— Comparative yields of "diseased" and "disease - free" seed corn selected by the individual ear germinator test.* Average for Nebraska White Prize and Hogue Yel - low Dent Corn. Five years, 1921-1925. „ .... . i Field Yield per acre Description of stand : corn planted obtained 1921 ! 1922 . 1923 ! 1924 | 1925 | Average P.et. Bu. Bu. Ba. Bu. Bu. | Bu! Ordinary 82 51.2 37.1 66.6 33.8 31.7 ' 44.1 Disease-free 84 51.2 35.1 66.6 31.9 29.8 42.9 Diseased 85 52.0 35.5 64.4 31.4 30.7 ' 42.8 No. of plats averaged 4 7+ 18 18 18 18 18 •The Kerminator test used In detecting the diseased ears in this test has been described by Holbert and Hotter in Farmers Bulletin No. 1176 of the U. S. Department of -Agriculture. tin 1921. 47 plats of ordinary seed and 218 and 194 diseased and disease-free ear-to-row plats, respectively, were averaged. Composite seed was planted In the other years. further compared and 18 plats of each were averaged an - nually. The 5 years' results shown in Table 10 fail to indi - cate a material difference in results from the two classes of seed. While some Diplodia-infected ears, which are characterized by more or less mold or rotting, may occur in Nebraska corn fields and in severe cases may cause death to the infected kernels, such ears are quite readily distinguished by the grower as unsound and are largely discarded in the selection of seed ears. Durrell * shows that Diplodia infection is local, not systemic. It occurs in midseason or later at the nodes, leaf sheaths, ear shanks, and ear tips from wind-borne spores of the organism which have over-wintered in infected parts of plants grown in previous years. Thus the occurrence of diplodia-rotted ears cannot be credited to the planting of diplodia-infected seed. If corn selected for seed should con - tain some diplodia-infected kernels the damage under Ne - braska conditions is not likely to extend beyond that caused by some reduction in germination and stand. Slight reduc - tions in germination do not materially affect acre yields. Gibberella is recognized as a disease of no importance in Ne - braska. • Durrell. L. W., Dry Rot of Corn, Iowa Airr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bulletin 77, 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Field Experiments with Seed Corn Treatments The almost universal cause of low germination of corn seed m this state is freezing injury, during the fall and winter while it still contains a high percentage of water. No treat - ment can be expected to overcome the effects of low vitality due to freezing. If any farmer should plan to test the effect of seed treatment, it is suggested that (Treat care be taken to have all conditions alike in both treated and untreated plate In order to eliminate. the effects of soil variations which occur in every field it is recom - mended that the plantings be repeated in several places in the field, and the result* from the duplicate plats can then be averaged. Misleading results and erroneous con - clusions may easily, be reached from poorly conducted tests. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>