<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SEVENTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF Public Lands and Buildings TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">OF THE BOARD OF Public Lands and Buildings TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1910 Compiled By EDWARD B. COWLES Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings The Claflin Printing Cc. ■*^S?"' University Place, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">that part of the Constitution of the i reports from state officers, I have the reports of the Hoard of l'ul&gt;li&lt;- Sir: — In compliance with State of Nebraska, relating ti the honor to submit hen- with Lands and HuildiiiL's for th&lt; seventeenth Biennium, beginning November W. 1910, together with December 1. 1908 and ending nts of the various state institutions pectfully, reports from the Superintend* Respectfully, h I Ml .\ l\ I) I &gt;. I &lt; ( \\ I &gt; r&gt; r&gt; . ( iilllllllNKliUK'l . </seg>
            <seg id="p004">ROSTER OF STATE OFFICERS 1909-1910 ASHTON ('. SHALLENBERC M. R. HOPEWELL ■AM T. THOMPSON RD B. COWL* RD C. BISHO1' ...State Superintendent Railway Commissioner Railway Commissioner Railwav Commissioner ■ WINNETT. CLARK JR. W H. COWGIL (decea OBOBOI C. JUNKIN LAWBON O. BRIAN. SILAS R. BARTON </seg>
            <seg id="p005">ROSTER OF STATE OFFICERS 1911-1912 » CHESTER H. ALDRICH H. R. HOPEWELI ADDISOX WAIT Lieutenant Go\ Secretary of State E 'ALTER A. GEORGE [LAS R. BARTON" RANT O. MARTIN DWARD B. COWLKS \.\IKS W. CRAHTRKK J. WINNETT State Treasur Railway Com: Railway Commissioner Railway Commis* Railway CommUsl II. T. CLARK, M W. J. FURSE (appointed) COMMISSIONERS OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS OF F. M. DAVIS A. G. KBNDALU JOSEPH SCOTT.. JOHN STEEN A R. HUMPHREY H. C. RUSSELL ■ liter Attorney G&gt; i I^and Coinniis- ■tau- Supprint. J'KTER MORTKXSKN (elected) J. V. WOLFE. QEODRGE 1). FOI,UMER H. M. EATON </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NAME AND LOCATION OF STATE INSTITUTIONS AND SUPERINTENDENTE IN CHARGE I)K. J. T. HAY DR. W. K. KKKX INSANE ASVLI'M NORFOLK 1&gt;K. A. JOHNSON. NERKAHKA BOI.DIKKH' .\M&gt; SAII.DltS' HOME (iKANIt ISLAM. I). W. I1OYT. IIKXKY HOVARI) home rnii the ! - i:ii:.\]ii.i:ss Lincoln i No appointment madi STATE IXItl'KTUIAL SCHOOL KEAKNEV C. H. MANUEL CIRLS' l.MilS'llMAI. Ilitnl. OKNEVA .MISS LYDA .1. MC.MAIIOX N'KKUASKA INIM'MTKIAL HOME MII.KOItl MISS LENA WARD IATI-: I'KNITEX JAMES I)F TIAltV LINCOLN iLAIIUNTY. N'RRRAHKA INHTITI'TE KOU 1KI BLE MINDKIl VOI'TII REATRK'l THOMAS hospital rou citirri. :i&gt; CIIILUUEN LINCOLN \i' appointment mad 1NSTIT1 T1-: Fill; THE DEAF AXIl MWIIi 11MAIIA No appointment mad IN8TIXITXK KOU Till 1 ' It F I N I ► N I ' 1 ■ 1 1 \ S K \ &lt; ' I T V NKBKASK.X HOSPITAL KOII THE INSANK I.IMiil.v m:p.i:\sk\ state iiohimtal 1"&lt;&gt;u rni: insani: iiasiinc II.IHKKS AMI SAII.oKS" HciMi: MII.I'n!:i&gt; DR. \V. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">&lt; OFFICIAL ROSTER 1909-1910 Commissioner Chief Clerk EORGE E. BMERY, Beatrice NKST B. FAIRFIKU), Lincoln BKRT HARVEY, St. Paul Hookk Sur\' KPHILX.IPPI, Hebron I. BKATNKV. Hastings I SWAIN. Dunba. r" WARD B. COWLES, Fairbury C. BOSLAW, York H. D.-linquent cl^rk </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BIENNIUM BEGINNING APRIL 1, 1911 AND ENDING MARCH 31, 1913. Salary of ( 'omiiiissiun.-r Salary of Deputy Salary of Chief Clerk Salary of Bookkeeper Salary of Surveyor Salary of Recording &lt; !lerk Salary of Deliquent Clerk Salary of Stenographer Furniture liture, repairs, telephone, U-l&lt; tionery ami other expem iph. postage ta l- r i ••S ::: Traveling exponw; </seg>
            <seg id="p009">BOARD MEETING DATES Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Sleet first .Monday in each month EDWARD B. ( "OWL.ES, Commissioner KN WAIT, Secretary of State R A. GEORGE Secretary State Treasurer Attorni Board of Educational Lands and Funds. i IIKSTER H. ALDRICH, Governor EDWARD B. COWLDS, (omission WALTER A. GEORGE Chairman GRANT G. MARTIN Board of Purchase and Supplies. lleeta first working day in January, April, July and October. i HKSTERH ALDRICH, Governor Chainn Chairman KDWARD B. COWLES. C( mmissioner orCt' Secretary of State WALTER A. GEORGE State Treasurer Attorney General GRANT G. MARTIN Board of Pharmacy M.-, -t&gt; second Wednesday in February, May. August November SILAS R. BARTON, Auditor Chairman Secretary EDWARD B. COWLKS, Commissioner Attorney General CRAXT G. MARTIN Mefts second Tuesday in each month. ft State Treasurer Secretary of I rnej Q«i CRANT G. MARTIN </seg>
            <seg id="p010">N lleeta third Tuesday in .January. April, July and November (HESTER H. ALDRICH, Governor t'hairn hairman JAMBS \V. CRABTREE, State Superintendent KHWARD B. COWLES retarv Commissions JOEL A. PIPER Chief Clerk Board of Irrigation. lleeta tirst Wednesday in April and September CHESTER H. ALDRICH, Governor Chairmai Commissioner Attorney General eretai v Board of Assessment and Equilization. Meets for assessment tirst .Monday in May Meets for equilization third Monday in July CHESTER H. ALDRICH, Governor Chairmai ADD I SOX WAIT Secretary of StaU WALTER A. GEORGE State Treasure SILAS R. BARTON Auditor EDWARD B. COWLES Conimissione EDWARD B. COWLES GRANT O. MARTIN E C. SIMMONS </seg>
            <seg id="p011">RATA REGARDING NEBRASKA STATE CAPITOL AT LIN- COLN, NEBRASKA ne laid ( Jorner st&lt; Ana of ( round ipit uildin Cost ml drive ast and west it and wei &gt;rth and south irth and south st corridor Length of Width of Width st and we I s Width mtta eorridoi )f north an la first floor Aci in ove the fir Height of Height of ldin II of 1 ■&gt;th :ind K rt.,204 ft. and 38 ft., high , and 38 ft., high uilts and el' Height &gt;\ ve lilt rseetK ft. Size of S ■nate ( mi )(•!' Hall ♦;r,xsi ft Size of \ellisi\e of V Average size of ex 1244 It Est of paving walk Dfth of building &lt; idth of building e* milling in uildiii'' n r&gt;ox8i Represent] </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 APPROPRIATIONS AND EXPENDITURES Board of Educational Lands and Funds Furniture, stationery, telephone and postage Aniouiil appropriated $ 1,70 * 1.7(K) lid Amount expended 1.226 !M Balance on and November W, 1910 Eaveling expenses : t appropriated t expended 241 55 Balance on liand November •'!&lt;•. 1'JIO rving notices, reviewing lands. Co. Trs. snpi&gt;l i Amount appropriated f 2,000 (Ml s •».()(i(i (»o Amount expended 1,307 27 Balance on hand November :*0, l!)10 692 7 Be-apprauing school lands: Amount appropriated 000 00 Aniount expended 396 (mi Balance on hand November 30, 1910 2,604.00 E Traveling expense Educational Lands and Fund ount appropriated $ 1,000 00 ounted expended Balance on hand November :&gt;o. 1 1(1 &lt; &gt; ."&gt;(&gt;( I (Ml 258 4:» </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 1 f 1 lijMx (JK AK. Y oCHOOLi r UWJJ The temporary hool fund is derived from the following permanent school funds, rentals on hinds Int. i balance due on lands sold, bonuf mder 1 nent rental and interest and money received for licena t ni»l fund is apportioned twice ■ year to i the state for the support of the publie he ,Hff PERMANENT SCHOOL FUND The permanent school funds are derived from the sale of dueational lands, escheated estates and five per cent of the pur- chase price of public lands sold within the state, and are inv&gt; ■s bonds, registered county bonds in inter riniir United Stat ind Nebri warrant everal amounts invested in these funds are as follows ( 'omnion I'niversitv Agricultural Coll N(trmal Endowmen Total EDUCATIONAL LANDS Total number of acres acquired Total number of acres deeded Acres remaining Eber of acres under sale contracts her of acres under lease contracts her of acres unclassified, Nos. 1 I Number of acres in model farm wived as pi are lease contracts, interest on delin- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">UNII fOM.MISSIONKRS RKFORT 14 Number af acres in city lotH Number of acres Lincoln Hospital : ! 2 ti!t!l (14 Total acres now held by the stat 1,977.979 4:; rLLECTION AS SHOWN BY RECEIPTS RECEIVED DUR ING THE BIENNIUM Total rental on lease contract* W.") 211 Total interest on sale contracts 2HA.ru Total bonus and added interest 8,257 0! Total principal on sale contract 610,108 13 Total fees .")..").") 1 1 i!t Total collections for the biennium r -ANNUAL APPORTIONMENTS OF TEMPORARY SCHOOL FUND Total $1,242,881 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Staff sell!) Total 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 LAM) COMMISSIONERS REPORT M &gt;() i 1909-1910 hool tax 5,629 Interest on sale eoatraeta Rental on lease contracts. 28:5.:.: J35.38! Interest on bonds and warrants Discount on bonds 556,080 1,159 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NOHh OK TMK BIKNMI M I Otal Ac Count use UnclauMad Vr&lt;|Mlro&lt;t Dec ritract Adams Antelo Maniici Htitt 220.00 (MM I HI 1 I I L414 I &lt;¥) r.oo.oo it ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p018">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 18 WORK OF THE BIKNMIM— (( 'ontiiiuedt Total Acres Total Ac I COUN'TY &gt;tal Acres Total Acres Under Sale Under Lease I .cqulreil Deeded contract Contract ( 13,44O.(M) 12,236.67 840.00 .40 11,704.44 3,535.56 Johnson Kearney Keith .. — 3,341.40. 45,663.90 1.4M1.77 4,551.91 :S'.Uil1.41 72.81 r 45,662.&lt;K) U\'i;.TT 4,551.91 :!'.Mill.41 7M.S1M Keya Paha Kimball .... 2fi.:.!:2:2.4r&gt; 413.30 20.70 25,76 2fi.:.!:2:2.4r&gt; 413.30 20.70 25,788.46 3(1,618 29,34 300.00 36,377.54 12.00 &gt;1 20,070.62 .V&gt;i4.0t&gt; 16339.13 Knox Lancaster Lincoln .. 31.236.84 28,017.87 2,454.52 7*4, 85.55 14,295.94 74,923.60 S5.55 14,295.94 74,923.60 Logan Loup 30,48030 800.00 19,68000 1 '.U&gt;: 20,480.00 SlMI.OO 20,39 T(l."&gt;. »■&gt;.". :.\:.!4:t.:so 17.44 1.;:: 05.6 243 17.444. Madison 34.639.43 19,359.43 :!.(MHI.(M) 2,280.00 24,639.43 19,359.43 :s.(MMMM&gt; 2,280.1 McPherson Merrick _.. 56,330.00 56,320.00 ,.:5miMi 14.!i7(&gt;.:M 9,619.64 2,586.98 2,769.59 1.02 1,566.78 7,066.13 53,692.61 407.50 Morrill . Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe 11302.34 1l.0d3.4'.i 44(UM) 145.63 123.20 11,802.34 11.0(13.4'.! 44O.IM) 1 4.').f.." ( l-':!.^) 1 ! 31,049.10 1S.42O.Ki 2,109.00 526.00 520.00 21.992.44 30^02.44 1,530.00 3*0.00 260.00 Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte . 30.034.85 19^74.85 r.sO.IMl 10 MM Ml 31,523.75 IO.00 31,513.75 1,51 20,228.60 14,469.00 4,119.60 1,640.00 4.11'MMI 2O.ASOJO0 11.U4O.IHI 2308.00 6,032.00 20.480.00 ll.ii40.0O .'.Mis. (Ml 23,655.48 20,771.03 1,795.35 1,089.10 23,655.48 20,771.03 1,795.35 1,089.10 16,787.68 14,547.48 1,278.20 942JW.. Polk Red Willow Richardson Rock 25,485.30 4368.10 5,897.90 14,719^0 10,400.00 8,950.00 B80.00 570.00 SMI.Of) 40^32.40 160.00 1,720.00 38,352.40 40^32.40 KMMMI 1,720.00 38,352.40 20,480.00 19,56030 800.00 I2O00 ",.(,■1 867.70 28438 1.99 25.227.04 1,123.95 40.00... 20,480.00 19,560.00 SI 10.00 1:20.00 Saline Sarpy 40.00 Saunders J90.1H) 25,467.65 1,316.32 7.14.-).f&gt;.-) 16,909. - Scott's Bluff Sewarrl 25,467.65 1,316^2 7,145.65 16,999.68 20,560.00 lii.44r,.:;(i 1,033.64 90M . 20,560.00 lii.44ii. 1,033.64 so.00 94,627.74 567.87 245.00 93,814.87 Sheridan Sherman Sioux ... 7.74 24.VO0 814.8 20,477.20 8,654.38 5,949.71 11 2^2 ir.Ci.fH) 880.00 79,932^2 15,360.00 1 1,436.09 3,48 440.00.. Stanton Thayer Thomas Valley . 30,472.35 17,09635 2,958.00 41&amp;00 25.600.00 25,600.00 20.474.SS 9,93823 6,189.91 !5.48 21 I3.851.8A 1 1.STT.01 533.40 1,364.5.') : Washington Wayne 1 5.360.00 14.fiS0.00 680.00 20,480.00 13,828.41 6,194.89 440.00 17.70 '1 Webster Wheeler York 20,480.00 4:i.(MI 1.1 :.'(&gt;.( X) 1!Vil7.00 R73 .1 20,480.00 18,326.61 l.:»SO.0O R73.3'.) ,797. 135.05 - 177.03 1,702,128 Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 WORK OK TIE lUK.NNUM ■- 1 Continued i UNIVERSITY Total Acres Total Acres Total Acres Total Acres OOO3T1 Total Air,' Total \ -lctaaalltod A.-.n lircil Contraet Contract [,000.00 40.00 A i i-,,uir.Ml i Uract r 1,930.00 l,52( BQlW ' Dakot '"" '" ■ ■I 640.00 440.00 SOO.00 ' , 12.10 H Holt 100410 4 V"! X 160.(1" .Madison , -., in ,. :;:.-,.(», 15SJ0 Nuckolli es 4* 1 ,0'. w 15,4 r,M9.17 l(l.0t)4.00 7,494.71 12.05 AGRICULTURAL COLLEGE Total Arm 1 Total Ai tsl Aires NTV Total iai*ta* .irc.l DsmM &lt;"on' itr»ct A&lt; ,, f 1,40.00 IHI1.00 7. I!. r 35.405.47 2 ),:,94.08 1,087.91 . MX) ( umlng M „, *kot !' alcotl1 2,147.77 80.00 J! 1XOn 191 10 »43.73 8.1OW.47 1,4.19.00 p. nO \ 10.114.56 S.708.92 7 640.00 E KlerCe I 400.00 10. 400.00 1 Wayrn- MJHtM l» SALIN1 slAcTf* Total Acres A IXE ,talArrm Total Aires OOmtTY ''' r Sal&lt; " "**" Il&gt;ils '' li»'l»» rtl ' wl Arauirad D.v.1.,.1 Contrart Contract 164.49 1.1S1.16 1.-..160.00 12 Ijincast NORMAL Total Acres Total Aires otal Acre* Total Arm rnHaiulBed COCN ntrart •M0 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 KEY TO UNCLASSIFIED LANDS il. Supposed right-of-way Us Railway. of Omaha, Niobrara and ]?lacl&lt; 2. Supposed right-of-waj of IT. P. Railroad ■\. In Missouri Rivei 4. In .Missouri Rivers Supposed right-of-way !l. In river. 10. In Platte Rivei 11. Supposed right-of-way oi I'. 1'. Railroad 1i'. Hi A. Supposed right-of-way of U. I*. Railroad. 71 80-100 A., in Platte River. 13. 160 A. Paid out on hut not deeded. 47 50-100 A. Supposed right-of-way oi' Wyoming and Western Railroad. 14. In Missouri Riv 15. Supposed right-of-way It;. Iii Loup River. of l'&gt;. &amp; M. Railroad 17. In river. In river. of Chicago, St. Paul. Minneapolis 22. 2 16-100 A. Supposed right-of-way of Chicago and Northwestern Railroad. 15,103.84 acres of saline land wei aside by tin- legislature as follows: State LIniersity and City 320 acres; Ldneoln Hospital for Insane H!i!&gt;.o4 acres: Model Farm. 1.2&gt;&gt;o acres: Normal School. 12,804.80 aer R Supposed right of way &lt;&gt;f I'. 1'. Railroad. Supposed right-of-way of I'. 1'. Railroad. ] i*.-'i 1 acres. Supposed righi of way of Chicago, St. Paul .ipolis and Omaha Railroad. ~&gt;4 acreg in .Missouri River. Supposed right-of-way of I". 1'. Railroad. 119. Supposed right-of-way of ('. ]'». k Q. Railroad. -iK Supposed right-of-way of Chicago, St. Paul, Minneapi (1 Omaha Railroad. L21. Supposed right-of-way (1 Omaha Railroad. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 ■r. EC 7 x a / EC /_ r r r ' ■r ■ A / /: </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 /■- r 7- ac U U •:• r-wowo^xj©^ 1 *" - -f C ~. — ?t -f *~ I - - fc* — i* *» I- *— — X X r- r — •■ — ?- — P. i- -rj — '- m r. — x - •-. i- t i- — i- r 30 — i- -y: -4 r- ~: r- c- -r ?t t- /: — i - i r. a - * x X t- I- r- rt f- 7 e* *• g g 2 J: - - X X £ X x X X x X X k. " i i : :::::ocoo:: — ;S i 5 i i? 5 7- x. £ ! )- X X 5 X ) - X t- &lt; 1 S5 l- t- M tfi 2 n " K y; C XI 7 x r = — : « Sou !C O M 3 M X i- 3= = </seg>
            <seg id="p023">3 X t- X /: x : © x x l&gt; - •/: -; t- x - — r _ 7 ' / — 7 h = r *■ ! &lt;r. t ' ■'. I *!*.*'■.**.*'/ / </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 x r- I oc &lt;£ O X O C-3 r- Ci 00 «C ■ I- r- r- ci co r- M t- X t- GO ■ &gt;.- c ; c c c t- 5D(-C -C C o rn o rc O © r- — — -* - — 00 X x X M &lt;fr 01 -J Ml* «D 00 ri 00 ■ ■/.- t- X ?- X J" ■f f . ~ . o © r- f. I /: X °° &gt;- •/. a •» ! I i il i 3 « 5 i oo X x a: " : CO CO ■T 00 X X t- x - V. £.:sfc M-3 ■J-. M tfi ■I. A ' •"•"" </seg>
            <seg id="p025">-■ — r i - — — i /. ■/. =/. •r. r r I f. / -f. x J ■j. r V </seg>
            <seg id="p026">ESTIMATES AND WORK OF THE BIENNIUM E&gt;n the preceding pages appear the estimate* for the coming liutii. for salaries, office equipment, telephone, telegraph, ge and other expenditures incidental to the office of Com - oner of Public Lands and Buildings. These estimates as out - . are calculated with a view of meeting the actual needs of Bee; and will he found on comparison with the statement of pended balances for the hiennium past, to leave a very oar - margin to cover the fiscal period. With the change in the administration of the office of Com - oner of Public Lands and Buildings, on January 7, 1909, i anie also a material change in the personnel of the appointees thereto. A new set of employes was installed; and by the elimi - nation of one bookkeeper, at a salary of $1,350.00 per year, two junient clerks and one contract clerk at salaries of $1,000.00 cadi, a saving to the state lias been made for the bieiinium.- of $5,400.00 in salaries alone, while the estimate for office and in - cidental expenses w,is scaled down to the lowest possible limit at which the department could b maintained. Khc entire appointive force nr with the mass of routine for the office was wholly un - ind detail work incident therc- tit in demanding efficiency and energy, as a prerequiaito appointments, the commissioner with this diminished corps sistants has earned forward the work with the usual dis - . and without the imposition of extra hours or hardship to a ■ employee. In the School Land Department, the standard of regularity and promptness, so necessary to the sucessful handling of this important factor for public school revenues, has been thoroughly maintained. The interests of the stale have been properly sub - d. and the rights of the lease holder protected. 54,897.35 - have been sold at an afrK' M 'J- r i'te of $807,469.64, which sum will in due time be added to the permanent school fund of the </seg>
            <seg id="p027">ESTIMATES AND WORKS OF RIEXMTM During the hiennium, two new counties have been organ M or rill county, erected from n the western northern and major part of Cheyenne county, with Bridgeport ind Garden, erected from all of that par r Deuel county Iving north of townships 14 in raises 42 4:5-44 4"&gt; nl 4fi. with its county seat at Oshkosh. The school lands of i1«-«t troii Ise comities n&lt; ind spread upon the ahxtrad Auctio &gt;f leasing lands that pur ited lists for non-paymen v tro in the r i Intals. new leases issued in accordance therewith, deeds executed, signmenta and miscellaneous transfers promptly recorded, ap - ieations to purchase reviewed, and all lands eligible to purehaae idrr such applications, have been placed under sale eontraeta deeded outright at the option of the applicant. Re-appraisement of counties for rental purposes haa ken up by the Hoard of Educational Lands and Funds with the suit that. Hooker. Banner, Loup and ('lav counties have Illce therewith, deeds executed. re i Us. new leas reviewed, and all lands eligible to pur' ms. ha placed under sale eonti n he applicant )|itloll t' rental purj ie-ai il Lands and Funds with the Banner, Lou| ■mil ('lav counties have praised, ('uster and Cherry idded to the abstract act of land •ounties have been ordered for appraisement, and no doubt will &gt;rt before the close of the fiscal year re, In the matter of re-appraisement of ('uster county, the ap- tee from the County Hoard has refused to struction of the Board of Educational Lands llselllent I iplv wi Funds, basing its right to refusal to perform the work, on the ii compensation. The case lias been ret nt of the state for advice as to the i, md proper proceeding* to be had in toe matter. Appraisement of ther counties will follow as the exigencies of the case lemand. and the appropriation therefor will warrant. Those provisions of the school land law. permitting holders lucational lands within the /. • segregated for governi purchase their holdings irrespective of the in late of leasing, has resulted in much speculation and discus the rights of any and all lease owners to purch date on which the lease was issued Under the laws existing, provision is made for three class purchasers. The first includes the owners of tl ises that re hissed prior to July 9, 1897; the second provided v </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 hANI) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT i in lands that arc irrigable from private or corporate di while the third class embraces the holders of leased lands tli within any government irrigation project. The average lease hold er cannot comprehend why these conditions should obtain naturally contends that he should have all the rights and | leges that inure to his more fortunate neighbor who may chane to !«e across the line that marks the irrigable, from tl The coming legislature will no doubt be called upon this unfortunate condition of affairs by placing all lan&lt; state within the eligible list for pure! The controversy lid ween this office and the General Land office at Washington, dealing with the resurveys made in 1894 t( 1900, whereby settlers' claims were surveyed from school lands belonging to the state, has thus far resulted in little satisfaction This is a case wherein the Federal Government presun erect homesteads fur alleged settlers, by surveying out tin- gam from lands of which the state has been seized since its adm ■ into the Union. In many cases these lands wen' under leas contracts, and the state is still receiving rents therefrom methods employed in surveying out these claims, is wholly at variance withany known rules or established precedents foi veying. Little attention was given to government corners, and tlie claims themselves conform to no laws regulatin divisions of government lands; hut on the contrary w wherever the fancy of the claimants seemed to lead. It is true that lands have been offered in lieu of those taken and lands contiguous to these school sections affected have withdrawn from homestead entry; hut the contention of 1 hi is predicated on the belief that the state cannot be divested of its lands by any such arbitrary methods. The state was not advised that such surveys were contemplated, nor had any knowledge of the matter until long after the claims were established, ami onlv then when the plats and field notes were placed on tile. Tin acceptance of lieu lands, is bound to entail a loss upon the stat&lt; from the fact that there are no lands left that compare in valu. to those taken. The very nature of the confiscation, for that i what it amounts to. is proof that they were ehoicelands of th sections from which taken. E. P.. COWLES Commissioner Public Lands and Huildin </seg>
            <seg id="p029">&gt; legislature of 1907 made an appropriation of $1,500 for ighting the ('apitol square. Thin was half of the sum a~ us which the Board had made could l&gt;&lt; 1 nut only in part. Twenty posts were erected ami there ich post ami the lighi which these gives the darkness which prevailed in former he work of pi icing electric lights in the corridors, the dome, where they had not formerly been used icen continued so that at this time gas is used only in the lab ussioncr been pla 1 on some of the corn. Si t purpose being $500. pur quired repair ■pairs from time t&lt;&gt; time at from time to time at a ei 4.12 f. ropriation of two yean ago was sufficient to enable n yean ago wns sufficient to enable oard to make some changes in the walks. Cement walks iiiitrcs in the walks. Cement walks utheasi corner of tbe square to the south side of tbe Capitol from st corner of the square to the •rner, and on th &gt;uth side of the Capitol from icb runs along the south side of tin- ins along the south side of the the ( which which the old walk was made ins of which the old walk was n tjstones iry and to the Hospital for the Fn- were traded to the Penitentiary and to the Hospital for the Insane for cinders. Some of the stones were sold, the receipt! from this iiirs wire told, the receipta from this amount was applied in payment of iree being $~M0 and this amount was applied in payment of he new w men! walks so far laid is about * lent walks so far laid is about $3 and sod to till in some spacea which of soil and sod to till in some spaces which were formerly covered by the unsightly flag stones. Alton 1 le unsightly Bag stonea. About liird of the walks on the grounds have been changed from - ounds have been changed from si ipreme Court room, in the third w to ceinen Capitol, and formerly used for committee rooms and story of tl by the legislative reference library, i divided into smaller The </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 rooms or offices for the members of the Supreme Court. Tin appropriation for this purpose was $1,000 The room in the basement, under the rooms occupied by tin Railroad Commission, w;is fitted up for an office and is now occupied by the Commission. The cost was aboul $1,500, and \\;is paid out of funds controlled by the Commission. Numerous improvements have been made in the eleven insti tutions which arc under the control and management of tli Hoard of Public Lauds and Buildings during the last t\v Some of the mure important are noted below Hospital for Insane, Lincoln. An appropriation was made Latare to the amount of $3,000 ted. The size is li'xlou fee the boiler room. A cold storag n house lias been repaired house, costing a thousand dollars at the last xession of tin- I for a standpipe. This lias 1 i Stokers have been placed in plant has been installed. The and made larger. A lai . has been built. Hospital for Insane, Hastings The legislature of 1909 made an appropriation of $50, for the erection of an additional building. The contract for its erection was let last spring to the Trenton Construction I pany and the building is completed. It is a three story, fire- Ef. brick building. The Jones underfeed stokers have been cd in the boiler room with the expectation that their use result in a savin}.' of fuel. The top of the smokestack had ral cracks, probably caused by lightning. Fourteen f&lt; top w-is taken down and a new top built. The cold s1 t was overhauled and put in Hrst-class shape. Girls' Industrial School, Geneva II contract has been entered into with the electric light plant ■neva by the terms of which the state buys the electricity i is used in tlie slate's buildings. This plan does away with ervices of an engineer. The plant in the boiler room is at present only for heating. Bhe main building lias been painted on the outside, roof 11 as sides. New and up-to-date electric wiring has been ed. Storm windows have been purchased. The heating has been improved by making changes in pipes and by </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 Mddition of radiators which will result in a saving of the i'l. The state buys water for this institution from the eneva. A very noticable improvement is the new which post $2,200. The old barn was sold and moved away. Industrial Home, Milford The old boiler room was situated about ten feet from MM f the dormitories. A new brick building 4(»xtili feet in has been built about 300 feet from the site of the old plant. Some of the briek in the old building were used in the new boiler iom. A tiO II. 1'. engine has been purchased and installed. The il wooden tower and water tank has been torn down and an svated steel tank of 25,000 gallon capacity stands near tfe the old tank. New floors were laid in the kitchen and sewing om. A year ag &gt; the heating system was overhauled and addi - mal radiators were placed where needed and the buildings ere more comfortable last winter than ever before. Hospital for Insane, Norfolk. The store room and the cottage for men that were provided for by the legislature of 1!'&lt;&gt;7 were completed during the summer of 1910. The building for women, provided for in the - bill, will be ready for occupancy in a few weeks. The eontri who was awarded the contract proved to be so incompetent that was compelled to take eharge of carry the work to completion. for erecting these buildings the Hoard of Public Buildings them in September. 1909 LA barn of concrete blocks ilt during last summer. The hingle roof. 32x80 feet, was st was about A water tube boiler. 2.~&gt;0 II I'., an engine T."&gt; II. 1\. and an electric generator have been installed. Feeble Minded Institute, Beatrice The roof of the cattle barn was raised some 8 feet, th doubling the storage capacity of the loft. A granary was built as an addition to the horse barn. The smokestack was damaged a few years ago by lightning. It was repaired to some extent by placing bands of iron around it. Last year it bulged out near the base and as there w; </seg>
            <seg id="p032">LAND COMMISSIONERS RKI'OK'I ■falling ;it any time, it was torn down and ■ new stack was 1 mi the same foundation at a cost of M.OOO. B'lic legislature of 1909 in wo fire-proof buildings, iwarded to Geo. A. Shaul in tile new year. ide an appropriation of $70,000 Tin' contract for building these and they will be ready for u^. ■ boiler of 125 II. I', was after taking out an old 7 For use. New and 1 inter |(invliased and set in the boiler "&gt; II. I", boiler which had become steam pipes were purchased and Bin the tunnel which connects the boiler room with th» uildings. About •"&gt;&lt;"&gt; feet of new tunnel were built. G\n S-inch sewer lias been laid from the new building I •eek on the east side of the hinds belonging to th&gt; tance of aboul 1,100 feet. Penitentiary A new i f of shingles has been laid on the west half of th" broom factory. Since the Lee Broom Company did not em - ploy all of the convicts the Hoard entered into a contract with Kohn &amp; ('o.. to use loo men. &lt;&gt;r as many as the broom company did not need, in making shirts. The ground floor of the factory was extended to 40 feet to the east to make more room for the shirt factory. One of the old boilers was taken out of the boiler roon lad a new boiler of 12."&gt; II. I\ was set in its plae B contract has been entered into by which the state may e about 20 acres of land which adjoins the state land on est provided the legislature thinks the bargain is a good id will make the necessary appropriation . Boys' Industrial School, Kearney Fire destroyed the ban and burned the horses that were in it about two years ago. Sheds were put up for temporary use. A new brick barn has been built at a cost of .+4.20(1. Daring the dry season last summer it became necessary to put down two additional wells at the pumping plant. The brick oven which hid been in use for many years has been taken out and a new steel oven put in its place. The change his resulted in a saving of fuel. An irrigation plant which will water a few ac the buildings has been commenced. Water will be pumped from </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Til*' Id K''. 1 11 (* J)1|M*S 1 1 1 &lt; I from scnni' old boilers so the 1 are th which are taken if the plant will lie aln Soldiers' Home, Milford. The administration building was completed in the early part Bl liieiniiuni ami since its i miiiaridunt and his family A new Phoenix engine 50 II. This furnishes power fur the elei I*, whs purchased and installed. rie plant and for pumping. Soldiers' Home Grand Island. Emsiderable painting ha* been done both outside and inside at work is still going on. New concrete conduits were laid w and larger pipes have been plaeed in these eondfl t the boiler room with the different buildings in the Home. Kveral new wells were sunk list summer to increase the of water. AVERAGE POPULATION AND PER CAPITA COST FOR TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910. Av. D| A 627 $185,281.61 $:"■ 1061 _ 77 291 i:r 74 !47 160,816.24 "14 M K Industrial School i Industrial Home ntiary 46" 44O.."i 1. L'77 .38 Feeble Minded Institute Orthopedic Hospital 416 102,' 24.V64 ■ K. B. COWLES, Commissioner. mpletion has been oeeupia B Hospital, Lincoln Hospital, Hastings Hospital. Norfolk s" Home, Burkett •s' Home, Milford Industrial School </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 x •/.-- (A U (ft * O tH * i i 7. i. W /: K X u M a e *■ x L m r'. C -r ■ M ■ / X M 7 ■ -Z / r - ■s. X C« CJ V u U U U OJ I^55 M .5 W g *J _ — 5*3 3 «C * *• * &gt;- C &lt;-&gt; .5 = X ~* ! i - /. m 2 S " ■y. g Js--S.2g.SE </seg>
            <seg id="p035">X X m X ' * * X n 2 7 ■*■ r- I 8 * if.~*^. &gt;■ x K * C J-. &lt; 8SS onn«oeO"SS X o h x m n &lt;o « « - &gt; CJ fr K r~ t- SS I ;S8 f! ■&lt; * ic Jncos :So«ei « 1-1 * « NON 00 «h : M t- C3 — l i t: » ,° o o — « « \£ ! cc ci n -" m i M --r m -c 35 o c^ — n in C! cj Nco»t-o«eo o ei c c is ; be 'S. -Z ■*-* w J^ O I &lt;=&gt;2 I«l»z1»z </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 LAXI) COMMISSIONERS REPORT Iy virtue of his office, the Commissioner controls the ap - iiciits in the Department of Surveying, and is custodian of ais. field notes and records of surveying pertaining to the of Nebraska; but the general management of the depart - is in the hands of the State Surveyor. Indvr him are three By State Surveyors appointed by the Land Commissioner, in lance with legislative enactment of l!t(i!t. Khe report of State Surveyor Harvey is appended, showing illected for the biennium : DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING Robert Harvey, State Surveyor and Draughtsman The regular routine office work of the Stale Surveyor and Draughtsman, consists of the care of the floTrmiTnl reeon Surveys of the State, supplying tlie office force with such data as may he required from siicli records, making computations and maps for office use. copying field notes and plats of Goverment surveys for the use of the county and local surveyors, and in - dividuals who may apply for the same, answering correspondence relating to surveys, and the such other duties as may }&gt;■ quired by the Commissioner. 1,11 correspondence pertaining to surveys are referred to this tmeiit for answer. Durinjr the hiennium !):{&lt;• letters have written and information given in a large Dumber of tele - ■ and telegraph messages and personal, calls from county and private surveyors and landowners. During the hiennium the following have been received ■neral Land Office. Washington, 1). ('. : Bhe field notes of the retracement and re-estaMishment of &gt;wndary line between Nebraska and Wyoming handsomely in one volume with accompanying map. Bie field notes and maps of resurvey of T. 8 V. R. 30 \V. and st tier of sections in T. S X.. R. 2!&gt; \Y. The field notes and maps of resurvey of T. 23 X. R. 13 The field notes and maps of resurvey of T. ."54 X. R. :52 \Y The field notes and maps of resurvey of T. :!2 X. R. 47 W The field notes and maps of resurvey of T. 2!t X. R. 35 W Ee map of sections 10 and IS T. 22 X. R. 41 \Y.. eliminating the plat of ivstirv' 'ii&gt;. appt i( i h </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Upon examination of the invoici eminent Records ol I find that at the time of the trans laid records I r General of the District of Kansas and s Nebraska Territories, to the Surveyor Genera] of the Distri Nebraska and Iowa in 1867, nor at the time of transfer of tin property to successive Surveyor Generals and finally to the - if Nebraska in 1889, there was not taken a complete item nvoice of the field notes, maps, and other records, that w the purpose of a eheck or memordanda in case of mispl incut or loss of any record. To supply this greatly needed » meiit or loss of any record. To supply this greatly n led there is in progn tematie classification and imlexinir of all classification and indexing of all a Reid notes, maps and records pertaining to government mm mips and records pertaining to government sin of the state up to the present tine. At the beginning of the present biennitum the binding of the nt tun At the beginning of the present biennium the binding of th three volumes of correspondence of I . 8. Deputy Surveyors with Surveyor General was completed and placed on the shelves as pondence of I'. 8. Deputy Surveyors with Surveyor General was completed and placed on the shelves as a part of the records of Government surveys. There is yel if Government surveys. Thei sufficient miscellaneous correspondence pertaining to the early fficient miscellaneous correspondence pertaining to tin - to make a volume of very interesting matter. The surreys to make a volume of very interesting matter. The i of binding the reports of inspections of government survey inding the reports of inspections of government surve. yearly increasing, as it is often necessary to consult thea yearly increasing, as it is often necessary to consult the* making up tin- data for use of the office in making sur making up tin- data for use of the office in making sur in answer to inquiries from County Sur\ The Held notes of surveys west of the 6th Principal .Meridian mostly hound in a very poor thin quality of leather which -&lt;i deteriorated that it is almost impossible to copy the - of the hooks without their falling to pieces; consequently n answer to inquiries from County Survey* 1'he field notes of surveys west of the 6th Principal .Meridian mostly bound in ■ very poor thin quality of leather which -&lt;i deteriorated that it is almost impossible to copy the - of the hooks without their falling to pieces; consequently during the hiennium 125 volumes of field notes have been rel. luring the biennium 125 volumes of field notes have been relx in khaki in nearly tin- same color, it being considered more las ■aki in nearly tin- same color, it being considered more I leather. An equal number &lt;&gt;r more will probably hav. than leather. An equal number or more will probably ha rebound during the eoming hiennian. In the rebinding of these volumes the subject matter of n ■ en rearranged to the prevailing uniform system. A nui •11 found where surveys of fractional town- he rebinding of these volumes the subject matter of rearranged to the prevailing uniform system. A nui •n found where surveys of fractional town- have been accidentally hound wholly out of their num&gt; have been accidentally bound wholly out of their aumei order and proper volume and without an index as to their j order and proper volume and without an index as to their j of existei The legislature of 1909 passed an act giving the Commis- of existent The legislature of 1909 passed an act giving the &lt;&lt;&gt;n sioner of Public Land andBuildings authority i deputy state suveyora who should i sinner of Public Land andBuildings authority i </seg>
            <seg id="p038">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 38 each day's service and their necessary expenses to be paid by the parties interested in any dispute over lands or boundaries. This approved April 3d, 1910, and the following July, when the 1 iw took effeet. so many applications were on Hie that it was considered advisable to appoint at least three deputies, who were County Surveyors, in order to expedite surveys; especially since it was impossible to procure the services of experienced and com - petent surveyors who would devote their entire time to the work during the surveying season at the per diem allowed by law. rdingly Jas. L. Paul. St. Paul. Xebr., II. D. Patterson, Papil - lion. Xebr., and Geo. ( '. Reed, Alma. Xebr.. were appointed Deputy State Surveyors. Iefore setting this force at work it was necessary to form - and issue general instructions to govern the deputies in the id of executing surveys and in the preparation of their Held and maps before submitting them to the office for approval. Before assigning a survey to any deputy it is the rule of the office to require the applicants to deposit with the commissioner an estimated sum. as an evidence of good faith, to be applied in payment of the surveyor's per diem and expenses when the work mpleted. The applicants are also required to furnish in - formation as to the cause of dispute, the location of all known Go\ eminent corners in the vicinity and the notes of priwr surveys by County Surveyors. The necessary data from the Government Held notes and maps on Hie in this office is copied, so that the deputy may have full information to assist him in the execution of the examination anil survey. I'usually there is also issued in - structions to the deputy to guide him in general or specific mat - but a great deal must be left to his good judgement, skill and fidelity. When the field notes and maps of surveys are submitted to the office they are carefully examined before being recom - mended for approval. b All. this requires considerable time and labor and as a partial tnpense for the same, a reasonable minimum fee is required, h is paid into the General Fund. Assignments of applications for surveys have been made as rapidly as the deputies could spare the time from their regular official duties in their respective counties. Some of these assign - ments covered so much territory or were of so complicated a </seg>
            <seg id="p039">iture as to require considerable time in their execution urinp the liiennium thirty surveys wen completed and tl artially completed. There arc now on file 1(&gt; applications for surveys awaiting Ijustincnt. and at the rate which tilings are being made, it m robable that,- if the present force is unable to devote their entire me to the work during the next surveying season, it will be necessary to appoint more deputies Field Work Below are tabulated the number of the survey, name ion of applicants. Jo. of Survey '■ No. MS W. A. Bower, Hampton, Hamilton county, continued from last biennium and completed. * No. 50 Huston [nvestmeni Co.. Lincoln. Lancaster county. No. •")! .John Lainpshcrc. I lord. Hamilton county. *■ No. '-&gt;'! Peter Hardens. (Jr.md Island, Hall county. •■■■ No. ."&gt;:{ A. &lt;). Huff, Arcadia. Valley county. «■ No. ")4 .John Wall et al. Arc tdia. Valley county. '• No. •")•") Geo. Fischhach. Orleans. Ilarlan county. - No. •*&gt;(&gt; .Michael MeLaughlin, Crooksti.n. Cherry county. »■ No. ")7 -John Kredricksen. Maxwell. Lineolo county. ,0. No. 58 Charles Gregaton, Hamlet, Hayes county. £ No. •"»!) ('. A. Lapham, Dendley, Furnas county. No. 60 W. S. Fitch. MeCook, Red Willow eounty. ,7. No. ii"&gt; A. Henry. Lexington, Dawaon county. ,,. No. til Geo. l&gt;everid&lt;re. Paxton, Keith county, and Kilpatrick Bros. Beatrice, jointly. ,4. No. 62 -J. F. Hough, MeCook, Red Willow county. ,5. No. t;."5 H. Hudson et al. Superior. Xuckolls county. .6. No. M •]. F. Wheatcraft, .North Loup, Valley county. £ No. titi Herman Klumpe. White. Hayes county. No. tiT Board of Normal Schools, Luther 1'. Ludden, 8 tary. for resiirvey of campus State Normal School at Peru. 20. No. ti.S W. K. Baliman. St. Lihory. Howard county. a. No. ti!( .J .P. Staska. Weston. Saunders county. .. _ ,, ., . .. , . .. ..,(•.. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT . No. 72 I). A. VauSant. Ansley, Caster county. 2.".. Xo. 73 I. R. Barton et al, Brule. Keith county. Guide Meridian through Dundy county. Continued. Frontier county I No. 7ti 1). A. Hancock. Wood Lake, Cherry county. No. 77 John Hoffman. Ashland. Saunders county. Xo. 78 Haas, lloi-d Cattle Co.. Lakeside. Sheridan county Xo. 7!) Gteo. K. Bacon. Overtoil, Dawson county. Qeo. K. Brown, Trenton. Hiteheoek county. 1 W. A. Mi-ssersmith. Spalding, Greeley county. Xo. 82 W. M. (iray. Ord, Valley county. Fees E3, 50, 51, -V2. 53, ;&gt;4. :&gt;."). til. (i7. tih and 74 were ,1'veyed by Robert Harvey. State Surveyor. tea required 114 days: 22 days of which were for \iy of Peru Normal School at Peru, no per diem RFCAPITULATION OF FEES COLLECTED \ ed for copying field notes and plats ived for sur cyirjr by the state Surveyor per diem 92 days .&gt;. 71 II. P. Peterson et al. Denmark. Lincoln county \'o. i4 Stale of Nebraska, appropriation for resurvey of 5th 27. No. To Mrs. R. \V. McAllister, oee, Lavierie, Maywood, charged. !»2 days service at $6.00 per day Nos.57, tia. 71, 7l\ 77. Bl Mild 82 were surveyed s 552 00 by J. L. Paul, from whieh were received us ot'l $31 00 56, ti4. (ill. 7."). 76 and 79 were surveyed by II. 1). Patterson, from which were received as office fees :!2 27&gt; Hi- also assisted in surveying No. til. ."&gt;!&gt;. tilt. (12. ti:S. liti. 7::. 7S and BO were surveyed by Geo. C. Heed, from which were ived as office fees :.:&gt; i id 11&gt; 25 Total $ 670 2:. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 liirin^ data for Deputy their returns ived fees charged for prej yon and examination of 1379 7:&gt; Total To this should he added for bienhun a balance due for Sheridan County arned durin&lt;r the opyin&lt;r held no!' .;;,- 86 Reclamation 4:! («) - Total -1 61 abulation of Held work and the lays in survey of the eampv ru. on application of the I; no per diem was charged, the In addition per diem collected, I spent 22 the State Normal School at !'■ of Normal Schools, for which i. however, paying my n&lt; sary expenses amotintiii - tkinjr examination of rarveyi ; and Funds at the request of the days for which no per diem tcr eas.- is one where the - 1. 1 also spent 14 days in the Board of Educational I, and harged by the office. Th feme Court, seeks to quiet title etion :sii T. 30 X. R. 32 W.. by an original suit in the Sii( ire than lt)(l acres of Ian - grant to the - claimed by a parly adversely &gt;rs by the parties interested in Per diem paid Deputy Su v - 5.00 per day ►5.00 per day -).(M) per day IV -i II. I). Patterson )| IV Keel l.V)' , day rota Some History of Surveys Rwo of the above surveys are of sufficient general ini uire more than the brief mention in the above tabulation of survey The tirst is No. tJT of the Campus of the State Normal B at Peru. In 1863 the Methodist Seminary and College at founded, and by an enactment of the Legislature of •Since received and paid into the General Fund. And six townships for the U. S ice Attorney General, a total of '■'&gt;&lt;&lt; -urvey J. L. Paul 253' t day </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 LAND i OMMISSIONER'S RKl'OKT . l&gt;y the trustee*, duly trail: conveyance August 10th, 1867. sist of not less than sixty m ferred to the State by deed of rihe two tnu-ts in their dt&gt;i^\ "t The trustees intended to d conveyance; the first 52 l /« acres upon which the buildings were situated, and Hie second 8 aci first named trad and idjaceiii in the description of the |»la&lt; of beginning caused the Locus be a quarter of a mile north Phis error was discovered by this by the Legislature then in session. The campus is a timbered tr t situated on the summit of tin- Muffs overlooking the \illajn Peru and the Missouri River. Valuable improvements w •re beiiifr made by the own&gt; of lots along the south tier of Mo ks of \eal"s addition to Peru, and it w.is feared by the authorities that they were trespas&gt;iiiL r on tlie campus, therefore, the application for a survey to de - termine and establish the boundaries of the normal grounds. 1 was engaged «&gt;n the survey 22 days. After considerable in - vestigation I was forced to the conclusion that an actual author - ized survey of the Campus hid never been made and thai there ■eat dearth of corners of lots and blocks in the addition to the village adjacent to the north line of the campus. Fortu - nately I discovered under the debris of many years the monument from which the description in the deed was initiated and with ttie aid of two Government corners was able to establish the boundaries of the campus and signalize the corners with monu - ments of 1 ' -j_ inch iron pipe ."&gt; ft. long tilled with concrete and D a concrete base 12 in. square and 2 ft. deep, and witn by marked bearing trees, li was found that not only was there no trespassing but that a little excess existed between the su| Kand established line. Then ork but the Hoard refunded was no per diem charged foi my personal expenses. Khe second was No. 74. wher ipropriation of $525.00 for Meridian through townships 1. 2. :!. and 4 \. in Dundy county by this Department. It was claimed by the settlers and so represented to tlw ■s lyin^r immediately west of the thereto, hut an omission of a eall Department in 1 !K &gt;7. in time fora corrective measure to l&gt; the Legislature of l ( .»(i!» mil. a resurvey of the 5th (Juiili </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 lettlers am I h nl been bo imperfectly done that a and local surveyors to find it ; it was imp that the opposii suits and that li waged numerous expensive law - cat ly feared by the citizens 11 I \va ( 'mint v offieia Act, the Department immediately l&gt;. •ollectill from the Held notes, maps, and ieiice not milv other record nected with t information from those who hid been con- Surveyor General's office at the time of the &lt; &gt;ll the eve of heirinriirur the vviirW tin. fUsaniAP original sur\ received a li f beginning the work the Governoi 11 Hon. George \V. Norris, Representative in District, requesting a postponement of the ( loner Ervey by th the (Jelle had secured the promise of a resur\ey e at Washington, I). &lt; '. veys for Xebras examination following M ys and report his findings, Th ler sill of lion. \V. Z. 'I hill authorizing tl \ td others ii the Comm latter, it was considered ad\ that the State Surveyor represent th imeiit in said resurvev. and assist the (i temlier. 186! lines of township Colorado line in&lt; subdivided towns! of Ranges 41 am isive, and the same year Geo. \V. Fairtield [&gt;s 1 to 4 X. Range 40 W. and townships 1 X. 42 YY. Mr. Keyes reported in his notes that if the Guide Meridian north of the Kansas rods too short, and that it swunyr to the the first ti mil line was 4 about roi ded north: he accounted for this &lt;l&lt; Maying that he remeasured the Kansas I in t'ction in the lin oiijr the south ile was only ab indary of section :il R. 4d W. and that the 7d chs. long, or was 40 rods too short. Mr. ling T. 1 X. R, 40 \V. said that he remeasnred found it :&gt;S rods too short and as he fi Fairfield, in sululh the same line and his chainman had These deputies rei red the Kansas line from the SE. co ( &gt;I1 ftp Mr. N. l&gt;. Sweitser, I'. S. Examiner of Sur- by the Government to mak animation. At the request of Culbertson, who had charge of the irvey by the state, the County Sarv&lt; The ori« was run by John W. Daugherty in 8. 1&gt;. Keyes established the boundary &gt;. and 4 N. from Kan^"' -M W. to the made a mistake, again remeuured the line. i 1 T \ I » _i I \V W i * v t Tib till' \ i\\t\t**ii\i\ I 1 1 1 a * * i II if ?**'Iii»T*ti L 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 44 te short, excepting one, and the aggregate shortage to b« 21.92 ins or nearly 88 rods. I went to Haigler, Dundy County, May 8th, and daring the mvestigation that followed, we remeasured the nine and one - half miles of the Kansas line, reported short, finding all the stone monuments, excepting three, and thai all the miles were approxi - ly 80.00 eh lins in Length and the total distance only eighi len than the original survey by Todd and Withrow in Mmth boundary of section 31 B. 40 \V. was a few inches a mile in length instead of 4d rods too short. This glaring mis - representation created a strong suspicion in our minds that seri - ulls defects existed ill the surveys made by Keyes and Kairtield. Cfter lo diys investigation Mr. Sweitser recommended to eneral Land Office an immediate resurvey of not only the Meridian but of several townships adjacent thereto. On September 22d. two Government surveying parties started from Lewellen for Dundy County, where I joined them on the 29th. Diligent search was made for more than four weeks by both parties for evidences of original corners not only on the Quids but on adjacent lines as well. It was found that the 20 miles of the north boundary of the County had been veyed in L888 without finding an original cornel', &lt;■• qnently the northern terminus of the Guide on this line was lost. About IT.") miles of lines were retraced. The original NW. eor - ti the County was finally found whereby it was possible locate that part of the north line of the County and re - northern terminus of the Guide. We found it i to retrace the Colorado line for the 24 miles along the boundary of the county. The Nebraska-Colorado line run by o. N. Chaffee in 1869 was regarded lost and in dispute. K and Fail-field, the deputies heretofore mentioned, reported in their notes of survey of T. 1 N. B. 42 \V. that the total lengtl each of the tj miles renieasuivd by them was 7.:W chains and 750 chains, respectively, too short. A remeasurement of the same distance by us from the Chaffee monument at the 8W. corner of the slate, north to the 6th mile post, was found to be nine in excess of Chaffee '■ measurement and the 24 miles about et in e\ Although no extended search wns made half of the original mil'' posts wen' found. The falsification of tiist Hurt's 'ibove nottHl on t 1k ; t wo st ut &lt;• 1 Ktiiii* iiirit-*s by t lie two </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SURVEYING 45 rious complications and caused mock • to discover the &lt;• rase for tin - ill solve the difficulty. The principal hard labor and point in tin- controversy was tin- proper location of the ei if townships 1 and 2 V. on the Guide Meridian. The finding &gt;f the Colorado line led to important discoveries of orig hat we were able to restore said township cornel •orn by proportionate measurements so that the excess of land both north and south, east and w tionaielv according to the ori ■st. could be distributed propor - rinal survey. On the niornii: the above corner, which is m_ diameter, -i feet long, Bel in a -ding to the ori November 2. we re-established ixed by an iron post :{ inches ii aches in crete base -'- feel in the ground. A brass cap surmounts the post in which is stamped the description of the corner. Hv mutual agreemeni and under instructions from Mr Sweitzer, one of the parties was withdrawn to another pai Slate while the other was instructed to restore all the eoi the Quide on the north IS miles with iron posts, hut the six miles or through T. 1 X. would be left blank, as lie had no re that portion of the line. That part of tin instrui .Meridian I will restore early in the spring. My traveling ntal expenses, hoard and necessary material fur necessary Dished to assist in the work amounted to $84.35. The per diem for 40 working days of the two trips 24O.IK). which has been turned into the Fund. The total expenditure was $324.35, leaving an unexpended balance of $200.65, which is amply sufficient to complete the work for which the appropriation was made. 1 returned to Lin- coln November 3rd In the three preceding biennial reports I called attention to the fact that the experience of this Department in Held work hid been, that in nearly all the cases of disputes where applications for surveys had been made, they were owing to loss of original corners and the carelessness or inability of County and privatt them. As the landowner finds his hold survey v increasing in value he is more anxious to have the bound tries of his land permanently established from original eon It has been the steady and earnest effort of this Department in the prosecution of tin- field work to make thorough, vigorous leputiea was &gt;f time to tatements in the records, anil MTiil "s\ T **tt'in'iti&lt;* m*'ipi*}i for tii(* opi"ihh1 i*(tpnt*rs iis &lt; ► trit.* i&lt;ill\' t* *■ </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 lislu-il by the (io\ eminent. Tin' percentage i»f success along this line iif procedure testifies to tin- thoroughness of the inves tioiis and is an encouragement to imprest! not only mi the deputk ■ted with tlie settlement I as well, the greal neci nents if they expeel to urveys thai will stand t of disputes liui the county siir - isity of recovering these original &gt;e successful in making satisfac- test of tile courts In November, 1903, this Department prepared and issueil to ('(•unty Surveyors i pamphlet of fifty pages of original m treating on the subject of searching for obliterated corners in the prairie country, retraeement of lines, restoration of lost ami obliterated corners by proata measurements, the survey of frac - tional sections into their lejral subdivisions with fuU instruc - tions of procedure, and examples of how to calculate the legal inn of corners, which are not found in any other publication on surveying. This publication met with a widespread demand opies not only in Nebraska, but in the two Dakotas, Colorado, Wyoming, New Mexico, Oklahoma. Iowa. Illinois. Wisconsin, .Minnesota, and the Department of the Interior at Washington. Sipply being limited, only ut of the State. Each ( ed with a copy, hut it i ; do not turn over their ;i few complimentary copies were •unty Surveyor in the State was found that retiring County Sur - opies as p i it of the aivhiv I lice to their successors: l&gt;em&lt;r in paper binding thej out. so there is a constant demand from County Survi ent requests are also received from landowners and at - s. The supply, however, has long since I n entirely ex - ■d. ■ the past it was the practice of County and private siir - and many locators, when corners were not readily found, struct new corners in imitation of the original or Govern- B corners, and this custom is mnties at the present time e regarded as the original ■ or condition arises that ( t in our investigations two generally followed in the west Very many of these in time monuments until some eireum - all for a resurvey. The or more corners are frequently found, each claimed by interested parties to be the legal or original monument. To determine this interesting and very important question, calls for knowledge gained by experience in the in vest i« r at ion of such conditions \nd while it is tr ener*illv </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 t t I in easy matter For the experienced surveytwr who has made ■ tudy of the changing condition* i»f nature's o{&gt;erations in the in reatmeni of materials used to perpetuate corner in mumentx I 1 he inexperienced surveyor, the laity, or the adversely inter sihle tank, lla.l the State loi&gt;.«: tarty it is a difficult or imp v enactment, prohibited the construction of corner monu units in imitation of those extahlished by the Government, E'Ht cause of dispute ;\!):1 uiiieh costly litigation would to ■n prevented. In all the surveys executed i ■ State Surveyor the monuments have been constructed ol lestruetible material, and in a differeni manner than that fol- real cause of dispute and much costly litigation would I urveys executed in ; •n he State Surveyor the monuments have been constructed ol ii tilile material, and in a different manner than that fol lowed by the Government so they may he easily identified by owed by the Government so they may be easily identified l&gt;y i the record. All of the deputies are instructed to pursue the aame record. All of the deputies are instructed to pursue the same method in perpetuating the corner monuments established by it monuments established by them. Early in the history of the Government, our present s\ Early in the history of the Government, our present s\ - of rectangular surveys was adopted and 1 iws passed governing of rectangular surveys was adopted and 1 iws passed governing V the method of subdividing sections into their smallest legal tethod of subdividing sections into their smallest legal suh in divisions, which have remained unchanged for more than a hun- •hanged for more than a him divisions, which have remained in dred years. The National Congress passed i law approved February 11th. dred \M e National Congress passed a law approved February 11th. \ ISO."), which provided that sections sh:dl lie subdivided into ions shall be subdivided into w quarter sections by running right lines between the opp lit lines between the op UHrter sections hv running n quarter section corners and the point of intersection of • point of intersection of the* lines is to lie the common corner of the four quarter sections, &gt;f the four quarter sections lii or the center of the section. That quarter sections shall be sub- nter of the section. That quarter sections shall he sul»- divided into quarter-quarter sections by placing intense o quarter-quarter sections by placing interim il-lti corners on each of me four sides of the quarter section &gt;ur sides of the quarter section llti corm and running right lines between these corners and at the point trnera and at the point and rimnin \\ of intersection of these lines is the common corner of the an lines is the common corner of the qu of intersect quarter sections, or the center of the quarter section. It will thus the quarter section. It will thus liter ,1 ii be s. en that there is only one way to subdivide a section legally iv to subdivide a section legally mlv out and that is to proceed according to the above law. which succeeding ( 'impresses, have never seen tit to change. V-' tate. some of the siir\ '■ in perhaps every county in the state iw. follow the practice of sub f them d have, and in my !! tions by measuring lt&gt;" dividing calling it a subdivision of the wo sides IIll owns the southeast quarter ler Jones lh( </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 section and employs the County Surveyor to establish the north - eorner. The surveyor proceeds to measure 160 rods north from the '4 section eorner on the south side of the section ;md ltin t-ixU west from the 'i section eorner &lt;&gt;n the east side, and where these two lines meet establishes a eorner and records it subdivision of the section, and the corner as the eenter of the section regardless of the fact that it is not in alignment with the ■tioii corners, and is on the land legally belonging to the other quarter sections: in like manner, he proceeds to survey out a quarter quarter section or 4&lt;&gt; acres by Measuring 80 rods froin tion. or lection corner, without ascertaining the real h of the half mile and dividing the distance equally and placing the eorner on a true line between the opposite corners: very often he measures so rods into the quarter section from one side only and establishes a corner for the center of the quarter • &gt;n. regardless of area, alignment, or distance between the opposite corners. En either ease farmer .loties jrets by such illegal survey a full ltiit acres while his neighbors gel what is left of the section. her too much or too little. I he surveyor expects or hopes that his survey will never be oiled or the error discovered at least until the law of limita - as run and the party for whom he surveyed has acquired ible and adverse possession of all the land included by the o run. Bhis illegal method of making surveys is the cause of end - tigation in many count i BSvery owner of land is entitled to a legal survey or his land to correct the above method this Department has m id&lt; - nous efforts by lending to County Surveyors instructions •ninjr the method of restoring extincl corners and the proper od of subdividing sections and by furnishing all applicants nformation as to how surveys should be made, with full ■ xplicit details of how to proceed and by lending such printed mation as may be at our eommand. The Legislature could greatly assist in correcting suel called surveys by declaring them void. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>