<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00034">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00034</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  NEBRASKA BOYS' AND GIRLS' CLUBS COURSE I TWELVE LESSONS ON FOODS AND THEIR PREPARATION</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">! ! I I r % .! ii r I 5 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebraska, U. S. A. NEBRASKA BOYS' AND GIRLS' CLUBS COURSE I TWELVE LESSONS ON FOODS AND THEIR PREPARATION By Orpha E. Nesbit Ie Boys' and Girls' Club Work in Nebraska is conducted by the University ebraska tn cooperation with the United States Department of Ajrlcul- Bureau of Plant Industry, office of Farm Management. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C. W. Pugsley. Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p003">* 1. Alfalfa Management. 2. Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska. 3 Testing Seed Corn. 4. Cooking and Sewing (Boys' and Girls' Clubs). 5. Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle (Boys' and Girls' Clubs t. Part II.— Corn. Part III.— The Home Garden. 6. Spraying Apple Trees. 7. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. 8. Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm. 9. The Selection and Care of Seed Corn. 10. Organization of Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs. 11. Cooperative County Farm Demonstrators. 12. Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs. (Growing Potatoes.) 13. Agricultural Extension Short Courses. 14. The Climate of Nebraska. 15. A CourSe of Study for Home Economics Clubs. 16. Twelve Lessons in Sewing — Course I. 17. Twelve Lessons on Foods and Their Preparation — Course I. The above bulletins will be sent free to residents of Nebraska upon request to College of Agriculture or NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION. Lincoln, Nebraska. &lt;2&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p004">INTRODUCTION I his bullentin has been prepared especially tor the Nebraska Girls' Club. Eight hundred and fifty girls are enrolled in this club. The courses outlined for study are in Gardening, Cooking and Sew - ing. Each member may enroll in one or more of these courses. Ee lessons as outlined in this bulletin are taken up one each h. Most of the work is done by the girls at home, especially ig the months when school is not in session. In many towns and rural communities the girls, who are especially interested in the study of domestic science, form a local club that meets once or twice every month. At these meetings they compare their work, study and discuss some particular topic suggested by the lesson, or a topic of interest to all members, and also take up the problems to be developed in the next lesson. A teacher, or other person interested in the work, acts as local leader and advisor of the K'hen a club member has completed the work given in the lesson, makes out a report from questions given at the close of the les- Slie sul mits this report to the local leader or sends it to the t leader. Kirls who complete satisfactorily Course No. I in Cooking as n in this bulletin may enroll for Course No. II in Cooking the wing year. Keachers will find these courses well adapted for use in the gram - grades of both rural and village schools and also for use in i school. Much of the work must necessarily be done by the girls at home, especially where the school has no domestic science equipment. toods and their preparation is a science that every girl should ly. The lessons in this bulletin should be correlated with other ects taught in the school. Very practical and interesting lessons inguage, drawing, physiology, geography, arithmetic, physics and nistry may be taught and illustrated from these lessons. Teach - of this kind will not only bring real life into the work of the K)l but will also bring the school life into the home. t : oods such as suggested in this bulletin, will be exhibited at te and County contests conducted in the interest of the Boys' and Is' Clubs. (3) </seg>
            <seg id="p005">A Busy Club Member. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">USES OF FOODS AND THEIR PREPARTIOX The Purpose of the Course in Foods E)d, clothing and shelter are the three necessities for mankind. :y are the first essentials to health, and health is necessary to ost complete happiness and highest usefulness. fuch time and thought has been devoted to feeding on the stock is. and much attention has been given to the right nutriment for ts in order to obtain the most use from them, so time and ght should certainly be given to the proper diet for human frong men and women cannot be raised on insufficient food or so poorly prepared that it is irritating to the digestive organs unsatisfying to the appetite. The girl is doing useful work who can intelligently choose foods and properly prepare and combine them for meals that will meet the needs of the family. In order to be able to do this she must know something of the different kinds of foods, their value and use in the Essentials in Cooking K Neatness in personal appearance : Be careful that the hands fingernails are clean and hair well brushed back from the face, that the dress is well protected by a clean apron. //. Cleanliness of utensils: These should be carefully washed, no particles of food adhering, and the bottom of kettles well scoured. If utensils have been handing in the open be sure they are well wip - ed before using. III. Economy in the use of materials and fuel: Watch the food from the meal and make use of it the following day in some ,• If you are using the top of the stove for ironing purposes, use oven for baking and preparing the dinner. Or, if a gas or oil (5) </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 stove is used, plan to prepare the entire dinner in the oven if oven is to be used in any way for the meal ; in this way economize fuel. IV. Exactness of measurements : Exact measurements are ne - cessary in order to get the best results. All materials are measured level, that is, by filling the cup or spoon as full as it will hold and leveling with a case knife. Flour, meal and fine sugars are sifted before measuring, and not packed when measuring. Standard measuring cups holding y 2 pint should always be used. A half spoonful is measured by dividing the level spoonful length - wise. A fourth spoonful is measured by dividing the half crosswise. Table of Measurements and Weights Suggestions for Order of Washing Dishes K Scrape all portions of food from dishes, empty and rinse , wipe all greasy dishes with a soft paper. Fill greasy pots pans with hot water to which a teaspoon of sal-soda has been d, and let stand. K. Soak all dishes used for milk, eggs, batter, dough or any ■hy material in cold water. Soak all dishes used for sugary substances and for sticky, gummy substances like gelatin in hot water. III. Pile all dishes of a kind together. Order: Cooking utensils, glassware, silver, china. I'easons: The cooking utensils are emptied first as food hardens them, because it is better to do the hardest thing first and be - se the dirty water is not likely to be used for china or glass. Work is often lightened if saucepans and other cooking dishes are washed as soon as used. E'eneral Instructions: Wash all dishes, including kettles inside outside in soapy water; rinse in clear water, drain and wipe . Use sapolio to remove food that sticks or is burnt on. Use K;aspoons (t) = l tablespoon 2 pts.=rl quart (qt.). (T). 4 c flourr=l pound (lb.). = 1 cup (c). 2 c butter=l lb. = 1 pint (pt.)- 2 c sugar=l lb. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 wire strainers. Clean seams of tinware and enameled ware with a wooden skewer. Uses of Food Iood is any substance that can perform at least one of these :tions: (1) that of building up the body, (2) furnishing heat energy which are necessary for the body to do its work. In growing of the child certain food materials are made into bone, icle, blood and nerve tissue ; also are used by the adult, who i though he has ceased growing, is constantly wearing out :s of the body and these must be replaced or the- body will en - ly wear out. There must be some food then that has in its er the building and repairing of the body. Heat is required to maintain the body temperature. No matter what the. temperature of the air is outside the body, the body warmth is almost always the same. A few degrees variation causes death. Work goes on internally, as in the beating of the heart, breathing, digestion and absorption of food, as well as ex - ternally, so there must be food. that will give heat and produce jy or power to work. Classes of Foods e foods necessary to supply all these body needs are divided :•.;'■ five groups or classes, each class having its functions in the &lt;&gt;dy. Some portion of each class of food is required at t-ach meal. Classes Examples in Each Functions in the of Foods Case Body Classes Body Protein Lean meat. eggs, Builds and repairs milk. fish, cheese, worn out tissue, also beans, peas, gluten in gives some heat and flour, macaroni, nuts, energy to the body. Unbalanced meals: Meat, baked beans, mince pie, cheese, or beef, macaroni and cheese, peas, custard. These meals contain too much protein, therefore, there is a waste of money as well as a waste of nutriment. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 Balanced meals: Baked beans, tomato sauce, sliced onions in vinegar, brown bread, apple pie, or beef, sweet potato, string beans, custard. 2. Fat Butter, cream.che ese, Give energy and heat milk, fat meat, olive to the body, also pro - oil, nuts. duce fat in the body. Unbalanced meals: Pork, vegetable with butter sauce, salad with oil dressing, cheese and whipped cream dessert or, pork, fried potatoes, rich pudding with butter sauce. These meals would contain too much fat and might cause sickness. Balanced meals: Pork, escalloped potato, apple sauce, rice pud - ding, or pork, sweet potato, tomatoes, fruit pudding with lemon sauce. 3. Carbohydrates. Sugar. Give heat and energy and are stored as Cane body fat. Fats and Beet carbohydrates are Maple called fuel foods be- 2. Noncommercial cause they give heat Honey Fruits to the body. Vegetables Carrots Beets Sweet Corn Starch Flour Bread Cereals ( Breakfast foods) Vegetables Corn Potatoes Peas Beans 1. Commercial </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 Meat, potatoes, sweet potatoes, rice, tapioca pudding, or combination rice and meat, pota - toes, beets, eornstarch pudding. These meals would contain too much starch or sugar Balanced meals: Cottage pie, apple salad, eornstarch pudding or meat, rice, tomatoes. Brown Betty. Conclusion: Some of each of the five food nutrients must be combined in our diet, for a food which fulfills only one of the functions required will not support life. It is necessary, therefore, to have different kinds of foods, and to proportion them rightly, so that one kind will supply what another lacks. It is best to have contrast and variety, that is, have some heavy and some light food, some strong flavored and some mild flavored, some moist and some dry, some sweet and some sour. Some foods contain two or more food nutrients and when combined with another class make a bal - anced dish. Example : Baked beans contain protein and carbohy - drates, and combined with fat added in cooking make a complete 4 Mineral M latter Common Salt Builds bone and Other minerals in makes red blood. fruits. Strengthens nerves Vegetables ( especial- ly green). and cells. Helps in digestion. Eggs, meat, cereals. Water All foods and bev- erages. Of necessity to the body. About 3 pints should be taken daily as pure water. It ♦ makes up two-thirds of the body weight, being found in all the tissues and fluids of the body. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Lessons in Cooking 10 Preparation of Meals Breakfast Coffee Oatmeal with sugar and cream Stewed Prunes Ruttered Toast Browned Hash Stewed Prunes t'ash prunes well, cover with cold water, soak over night. In the ning put them on to cook in this same water. Cook slowly until adding a little sugar near the end of cooking. The long slow ing retains all the sugar the fruit originally possessed and makes tional sweetening unnecessary. How does the body use prunes? Oatmeal Place 2 c of hot water in the upper part of a double boiler with salt. Boil and add slowly to this boiling water Y± c of rolled oats, not stirring tut lifting with a fork so as to keep the grains distinct and not make a pasty mush of the oatmeal. Boil for 5 minutes, set over hot water in the lower part of double boiler ; cook at least 1 hour, preferably 2 hours to develop flavor. Bnder what class does oatmeal belong? Df what use are cereals lebody? Browned Hash Put meat and potatoes left from dinner through a meat grinder, moisten with gravy, season well. Put in a hot buttered iron frying pan until well browned, turn one-half over the other like an omelet, garnish with parsley and serve at once. Coffee Add 2 T level or 1 T rounding of coffee to each cup of water. Boil 3 minutes. Order of Work &gt;.'ight before : Soak prunes, grind meat and potatoes, start cereal. Morning: Put prunes on to cook, put cereal on to cook, heat frying pan, prepare coffee, lay table, cook hash, place toast in oven. Order of Serving : Prunes, cereal, hash, toast, coffee. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 Lessons in Cooking Dinner Chicken Fricassee Mashed Potatoes Peas (English Fashion) Cinnamon Rolls Green Tomato Pickles Chocolate Bread Pudding Hard Sauce Chicken Fricassee Cut up chicken as usual, roll in flour, salt and -pepper mixed to - gether. Brown in small amount of fat in an iron frying pan. When brown remove chicken and make a thin gravy. Put chicken and gravy in a roaster, put in oven and cook very slowly for two MM!*. Serve hot. Peas (English Fashion) Wash 1 can of peas. Add % c water and heat. Add 1 sprig of mint, season with salt, pepper, 1 t sugar, and 2 T butter. Serve hot. Chocolate Bread Pudding 2 c stale bread crumbs 2/3 c sugar 4 c scalded milk 2 eggs 2 sq. chocolate Y A t salt 1 t vanilla fiak bread in the milk 30 minutes, melt chocolate in saucepan ?d over hot water, add y 2 c sugar and enough milk taken from d and milk to make the chocolate mixture of consistency to •; add to bread and milk mixture with remaining sugar, salt, lla and eggs slightly beaten ; turn into a buttered pudding dish bake 1 hour in a moderate oven. Serve with Hard Sauce. Hard Sauce ]/ 2 t lemon juice 2/3 t vanilla 1 c powdered sugar 1/3 c butter Cream butter, add sugar gradually, add flavoring. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 Potato Chowder Egg Rolls Jelly Ginger Snaps Cocoa Potato Chowder Juice from 1 onion 3 c milk rib. ham (cooked or raw) 2 T butter few sprigs parsley 2 T flour 1 c water 4 medium sized potatoes Crackers (whole) tire and cut potatoes in dice. Cut ham into small pieces, put in ig pan, fry until light brown. Put a layer of potatoes in sauce sprinkle with ham, parsley, onion juice, pepper, salt, then layer otatoes and so on until all are used. Add water, cover closely, ner 20 minutes, melt butter, add flour, stir until well mixed, milk and cook until thickened. Add this to the chowder, stir fully until boiling hot. Add one large cracker or two or three II crackers to each plate of soup and serve hot. Egg Rolls 2 c flour y 2 c milk Yi t salt 4 T butter 4 t baking powder 1 egg beaten until very light ift flour, then measure and sift again with dry ingredients, cut ub the butter into the flour. Combine milk and eggs, and mix :ly with flour. On floured board roll to }£ inch thickness. Cut Wong pieces about 2 inches in width and 4 inches in length, and i a floured knife crease through center of each roll. Brush over top with white of egg or milk and sprinkle lightly with granu - i sugar. Bake 15 minutes in hot oven. Cocoa 3 T cocoa 2 c boiling water 3 T sugar 2 c hot milk Few grains of salt </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 Mix cocoa, sugar and salt, dilute with one-half cup boiling water to smooth paste, add remaining water and boil 3 minutes, add milk and bring to boiling point. Beat with Dover egg beater two minutes. Individual Work for the Month f:pare some time during the month these three meals (or other balanced meals) according to recipes and directions, having each recipe until it has become familiar. QUESTIONS I. Give the menus used. 2. Number served at each meal? 3. Length of time it took to prepare each meal? 4. Approximate cost of each meal? I Approximate cost of meal per individual? What dishes in each meal contained protein? What dishes in each meal contained carbohydrates? What dishes in each meal contained fats? Write out a menu for one breakfast, dinner and supper, which you would consider well balanced. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Lessons in Cooking Lesson II STARCH AND ITS USE IK THE DIET. Ippcarancc: Starch as we know it is made up of very minute of various shapes and sizes depending upon the plant from :h they come. These cells are so small they seem like powder. h cell is composed of an outside layer protecting the real starch ns. This outside layer of cellulose, if examined under the micro - «, shows distinct markings depending upon the plant from :h it comes. In order to free the starch from the cellulose var - processes are used. iiurce: Starch is found largely in the vegetable kingdom; in :s, stems, bark of trees, but in greater abundance in seeds, is, roots and tubers where it has been stored up as food for the ig plants. This provision which nature makes for the young t furnishes the greater part of man's food supply. The ccittll rains contain from 50 to 75 per cent starch ; peas, beans and toes contain from 10 to 25 per cent starch. Nearly all of our ufactured starch comes from rice, wheat, corn and potatoes, nvroot, tapioca and sago are forms of purest starch. Food value: Starch is one of the most important heat giving and energy giving foods. During the process of digestion starch is changed to sugar. Since starch and sugar are fuel foods, they should form three-fifths of our daily food supply. They are econ - omical because cereals, vegetables and fruits which contain them are cheap, abundant and easily obtained. Starch alone cannot sus - tain life but must be taken with building and repair foods. Xature has provided that it be taken with one or more of the three nutri - ents, protein, fat and mineral matter, as in cereals and vegetables. These nutrients if not already present can be supplied when pre - paring the food for the meal by adding other ingredients that con - tain the lacking nutrients. Example: Rice in itself is composed mostly of starch and in order to make it a well balanced dish, cheese may be grated and added to the rice, thus supplying the needed pro - tein and fat, or White Sauce may be added introducing a small a - mount of protein and fat. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Lessons in Cooking 15 Things to be Remembered about Starch 1. Starch mixes with cold water but is not effected by it, that is, starch grains do not dissolve in cold water. Kin order to prevent lumping, starch should be mixed with water or with butter or sugar before adding boiling water. The in each case is to separate the starch cells. 3. Boiling water swells and bursts the starch cells 4. Moisture and heat are necessary to soften the starch grains. 5. Long cooking of starch develops flavor. 6. Starch is used as a thickening agent. The most common ag - ents used for thickening are flour, cornstarch, arrowroot, rice, po - tato, tapioca, sago. Starch thickens more than flour, therefore, only half as much starch as flour is needed to be used to thicken the same quantity of liquid. Method No. I. Mix flour with 2 T of liquid. Heat remainder of liquid to boiling point. Add flour mixture and stir until thick - ened. Add butter bit by bit stirring constantly. Iv ES Sauces No. of Sauce. Liquid Used. Butter Flour Co. I. 2 cups of either milk 1 T 1 T water tomatoes meat stock . vegetable water fruit juices 2 T 2 T , Km. IV. it it 3 T 4 T 3 T 4 T s: \ethods of Mixin Sauce </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 Lessons in Cooking Bethod No. II. Melt butter until it bubbles, add flour and mix sughly, cool, add cold liquid and heat to boiling point, stirring tantly. Boil until it thickens. fote : When milk is used as the liquild the result is called White :e and is used in the preparing of cream soups, escalloped dish - jravies and croquettes. When water is used as the liquid the It is called Drawn Butter Sauce, to be used as a substitute for y or White Sauce. When tomatoes are used for the liquid the It is called Tcmatoe Sauce. When fruit juice is used as the d the result is called Fruit Sauce, to be used for puddings. Application of Sauces Cheese Toast Boast slices of bread. Butter and sprinkle with grated cheese. :e Sauce No. II (using milk as the liquid) and pour over the t. Serve hot as a breakfast or supper dish. Tomato Toast Koast thin slices of bread and butter. Make Sauce No.II (using atoes strained as the liquid). Pour over the toast. Serve as a kfast or supper dish. Cream Soups: The basis for all cream soups is Sauce I, II or III, using milk as the liquid, except in clear tomatoe soup where tomatoes are used as the liquid. The No. of White Sauce to be used depends upon the thickness and strength of the vegetable pulp. Suggestions or soups ind of Soup Seasonings Garnishes lear Tomato Pepper corns, parsley, bay Croutons leaf, cloves, onion ,a Onion or mint cooked with Mint ~. peas Onion, parsley, celery salt Chopped Parsley £. Sugar and cayenne Pop-corn Onion and bay leaf scald- ed with milk Serve all soups boilin: hot. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Lessons in Cooking 17 A spoonful of whipped cream may be served on all cream soups except those containing acid. Croutons Cut stale bread in one-third inch slices and remove crusts. Spread thinly with butter. Cut slices in one-third inch cubes. Put in oven and bake until delicately brown. Crouton sticks are prepared in the same way, but cut in strips one-third inch thick and two inches Cream of Tomato Soup 2 c tomatoes t white pepper 4 c milk 1 t salt 4 T butter y A t soda 3 T flour (tew tomatoes until soft enough to strain easily, before straining soda. Make a White Sauce of the milk, butter and flour. When is thickened, season, add tomato pulp, beat with Dover egg beat - nd serve at once. Do not combine mixtures until just ready to e for fear of curdling. Clear Tomato Soup 2 c tomatoes 1 T butter 1 c hot water 1 slice onion 2 t sugar 1 sprig parsley 1 t salt IT flour 2 cloves 1 bayleaf 3 peppercorns croutons Cook first six ingredients and bayleaf together for 15 minutes. Melt the butter in a sauce pan, add onion and parsley finely chopped, fry a golden brown ; add flour and stir until smooth. Add this to tomato and let boil one minute. Strain and serve boiling hot with croutons. Cream of Cabbage Soup E small head cabbage 3 T flour c milk (hot) Salt T butter White pepper Chop cabbage fine, cook in boiling water until tender. Make thin </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 Lessons in Cooking W lute Sauce of butter, flour and milk. Partly drain cabbage, add to milk and season. Serve hot with crisp crackers. Starch Desserts Cornstarch Pudding No. I 2 c milk whites of 2 eggs well beaten 4 T cornstarch V 2 t vanilla 2 T sugar */g t salt Icald \y 2 c milk, mix together y 2 the cornstarch, sugar, salt and cold milk. When the mixture is smooth, add hot milk and cook mixture over the fire five minutes, stirring constantly. Cook the ture over boiling water for thirty minutes. Remove from the er and add vanilla. Fold in the whites of the eggs beaten stiff, r into a cold wet cup or mold. Serve with cream and sugar or i crushed strawberries or sliced peaches. Cornstarch Pudding No. II. Add 1 square of unsweetened chocolate and 4 T sugar to the proportions in No. I. Melt chocolate over hot water, add cornstarch custard to it a little at a time, then fold in the whites of the eggs beaten stiff, add flavoring. Serve with whipped cream. Cornstarch Pudding No. III. Kake as in No. I, but use water instead of milk and add 4 T le - juice and 4 T sugar. Tapioca Cream 2 T Minute tapioca 1/6 t salt 2 c milk ft t vanilla 4 T sugar 2 eggs Idd tapioca to milk and cook in double boiler until tapioca is r. (A pan set in another pan of hot water with the inner pan ected from the bottom of the outer pan by a piece of folded :r or cloth may be used instead of double boiler.) Add half the ir and as soon as dissolved pour hot mixture on remaining su - mixed with salt and egg yolks slightly beaten. Return to double </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 boiler and cook until mixture thickens. Add white of egg beaten stiff. Flavor and cool. Amber Pudding Yi c Pearl tapioca 4 c water 2 c brown sugar Soak Pearl tapioca twelve hours in the water, add sugar and cook in a slow moderate oven until clear, stirring occasionally. Serve with plain or whipped cream. QUESTIONS 1. What is the chief source of all starch? 2. What is the use of starch in the daily meals? 3. What foods do we commonly use that contain the most starch? 4. In what order do you mix the ingredients together in the making of cornstarch pudding? Why this order? KMake a sauce where milk is used as liquid, where tomato is I as liquid, where meat stock is used as liquid. How did you e each sauce and with what other food did you serve it? 6. Each week use some of your left-over vegetables in the mak - ing of a cream soup. What kinds of vegetables did you use, what seasonings and garnishes? Was your soup smooth of a good flavor and hot? 7. Use tapioca or sago in making a dessert. What thickens these puddings? </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 Lesson III. VARIETY IN THE USE OF CEREAL GRAINS Importance: Cereal grains are one of the most important food substances because they furnish the bread stuff for the human race, they are easily cultivated in almost every part of the world, are hardy of growth, give an abundant yield, are easily digested and very nutritive. The most important cereal grains are wheat, corn, oats, barley and rice. These grains are used in various forms al - though we often speak of cereals as synonymous with breakfast foods. They are used in the form of flour or meal for bread. The whole grain is sometimes used as a vegetable such as rice. Hard wheat is used in the manufacturing of macaroni, vermicelli and spaghetti. The grains used as breakfast foods are prepared in var - ious ways. Eareals are extensively used because they are rich in nutriment contain so little refuse. They are comparatively inexpensive, well, are easily prepared for the table and are palatable and tible. Classification of cereal breakfast foods according to method of preparation : — 1 Whole grain Example: Whole Wheat 2 Ground Examples: Cream of Wheat, Cracked Wheat, Oatmeal, Hominy, Samp, Corn Meal, Rice. 3. Partially cooked then ground, rolled, flaked or shredded. Examples: Rolled Oats, Rolled Wheat, Corn Flakes, Shredded Wheat. 4. Predigested or Malted Example: Grape Nuts. Care of cereals: Keep in a cool, dry place, unexposed to air and insects. With warmth and moisture insects will flourish. Cereals containing fat become rancid with age, therefore, should be pur - chased in small quantities. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">21 I ow position: In general, grain foods are called carbohydrate tarchy foods, although some cereals contain a large amount of :ein, more or less fat and some mineral matter. All are deficient .-ater due to the drying process in ripening, hence, a large amount »-ater must be supplied in cooking them. The following outline shows the composition, value and rank of each cereal : You can see from the outline that some cereals contain all food but some rank higher in one substance than in others. For example, rice ranks highest in carbohydrate but lowest in pro- Food Functions in Body Rank as to Rank as to Nutrient Amount o f Nutritive Value each Food Nutrient C Build fatty tissue. Rice Gives heat and en- Rye ergy. Wheat Barley 1. Oats Corn Oats Protein Builds and repairs Oats tissue. Wheat Rye 2. Wheat Barley R?cT I Gives heat and en- Oats 3. Rye ergy. Corn Builds fatty tissue. Rye Wheat Barley 4. Bar ey Rice r Builds bone. Keeps Barley body fluids and blood Oats in good order. Rye Wheat 5. Corn Corn Rice 6. Rice </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 tein, fat and mineral matter. Oats rank high in both protein and fat and comparatively high in carbohydrate and is, therefore, one of the most nutritive of all cereal grains. Value to the body: If properly prepared, cereals are of great value to the body. They give to the body a large amount of heat and energy or power to do work. They help build fatty tissue and some help build and repair tissue. Cookery of Breakfast Foods Purpose of cooking: (1) to sterilize, (2) to improve flavor and appearance, (3) to soften and break down the cellulose walls so that the starch will be set free and then can be acted upon by the digestive juices. Ieneral method of cooking: (1) Have the outside of the double :r a little more than one-third full of boiling water and put the inside as much salt and water as is needed for the amount kind of cereal to be cooked. (2) Place the inside of the double :r directly on the stove and as soon as the water boils hard, in the cereal slowly so as not to stop the boiling of the water. flaky cereal lift with a fork instead of stirring. (3) Boil this minutes lifting occasionally with a fork so that it does not burn tick. (4) When it has boiled 5 minutes put the inside of the ble boiler into the outside of the double boiler and let cook the th of time given in the table. Table for Cooking Cereals &gt;real Amount of Water Salt Time Cereal Rolled Oats Cream of Wheat Fine Hominy Coarse Oatmeal Cracked Wheat 1 c 1 c 1 c 1 c 1 c 1 c 1 c 2 to 3 c 2 c 5 c 4 c 4 c 4 c 3 c 4 c V/2 t 1# t iyi t \y* t iyi t I </seg>
            <seg id="p024">23 tWith cream and sugar (avoid too much sugar) With butter or cream. 3. With fruit, fresh or canned. 4. Dates, figs or raisins cooked with cereal and served with cream and sugar. 5. Moulded with fruit and served cold Left-over Cereals iour left-over cereals into a we tmould, cover and set away to . Slice in thin slices and fry or saute in 2 or 3 T of butter or bacon fat. Serve with maple or sugar syrup. Left-over cereal also be used in place of some of the flour in the making of Fins, griddle cakes or waffles. Rice as a Vegetable iave a large kettle of boiling salted water. Pour in slowly the led rice, cook rapidly until the grains stand apart and are ten- Drain, set on the cooler part of the stove to dry. Never stir. ater has boiled down to a sticky paste, drain rice in a colander allow cold water to run through it. Place rice in a steamer iven to reheat. Serve as Rice and Cheese by mixing lightly grated cheese and sprinkle with cayenne pepper. Pile lightly serving dish and serve while hot. Rice as a Dessert Swelled Rice Pudding % c rice % c sugar 4 c milk y A c salt Cinnamon, nutmeg or grated rind of l /i lemon sprinkled on top. I 'ash rice, mix ingredients, pour into buttered baking dish and : in a slow oven 2 l /i or 3 hrs. Stir with a fork once in 15 min. ng the first hour. J/£ c seeded raisins may be added at the last ing if desired. A fireless cooker may be used in the making he puddine by heating all ingredients to boiling point and plac - in the cooker, according to the usual method, for six hours. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 3 T rice ]/ 2 c cold water 1 c sugar 1 pt. hot milk l / 2 box gelatine or 1 t vanilla 2 T of granulated gelatine whipped cream Wash the rice and add to the hot milk in double boiler. Cook 2 hours or until rice is soft, then add the sugar. Dissolve the gelatine in cold water and while rice is still warm add the dis - solved gelatine and vanilla. When cold fold in the whipped cream. Cereal breakfast foods are sometimes used in breads, cakes, rookies, etc. Cream butter and sugar ; gradually add well beaten eggs and milk. Mix and sift the soda, flour, salt, cinnamon and cloves, then add the raisins and uncooked oatmeal. Drop by spoonfuls into a but - tered tin, two inches apart and bake in a moderate oven. QUESTIONS use do you make of cereal grains each day? In what rent forms do you use them ? 2 Why are they valuable as food? fWhat cereal breakfast foods are best for cold weather and those who work hard out of doors? 4. What breakfast foods have you prepared this month? 5. What did you do with the breakfast food you had left over? fi. Serve rice as a vegetable for one of your meals. Are your grains separate and distinct? What food would you omit if you used rice as the main vegetable ? Why ? 7. Make Swelled Rice Pudding. What thickens this pudding? Oatmeal Cook kies 'A c sugar 1 c butter 1 t salt 1 small t soda 2 eggs 4 T sweet milk 2 c raisins 2 c uncooked oatmeal 1 t cinnamon 2 c flour / 2 t cloves </seg>
            <seg id="p026">25 Lesson IV. BREAD AND OTHER USES FOR FLOUR Importance I read has been an important part of man's diet from the earliest i. Many savage peoples ground their own grain by crushing Jtween stones, mixed it with water and baked it on hot stones n hot ashes, thus making a simple form of bread. Early records of the Israelites eating leavened bread; of the Ancient Greeks ivating yeast and of the Pom]&gt;eian oven in which was found t loaves of bread not unlike our own. The materials used in id making are easily found, the process of making is not difficult the result is a highly nutritive and economical product. Bread ing should be one of the most important and interesting duties he housekeeper. Value in Diet Bread is called the "Staff of Life." It combines easily with other foods and thus forms one of the most valuable articles in our diet. It is economical giving a large amount of nutriment for a small amount of money, and being so completely digested there is practically no waste. Bread that furnishes the greatest amount of digestible matter is the most nutritious; therefore, since bread made of White flour is the most completely digested (because of the fineness cf its flour) it is considered the most nutritious. Gra - ham flour and Whole Wheat flour contain more protein and mineral matter, but the particles are large and resist the action of the di - gestive juices, therefore, the body loses some of the nourishment contained in these flours. In cases of constipation where a laxative is desired. Graham bread should be indispensable. A certain amount should be used daily bv every one. Composition The composition of bread depends upon the ccmposition of the ingredients. In general, bread contains a large amount of carbo- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 hydrate food in the form of starch, sugar and dextrine; small amount of protein in the form of gluten, casein (if milk is used) and albumin; small amount of fat (depending on the amount of short - ening used) ; water and some mineral matter. Compared with butter, meat and eggs it lacks in protein, fats and mineral matter. therefore, we use it in connection with those foods in our diet. Flour: Flour is powdered wheat, rye, oats, barley or corn. It is comi&gt;osed chiefly of starch but must contain a certain amount of -ul 'stance called gluten which is necessary in bread making, since it retains the gas and thus gives the porous character of the loaf. Because Wheat flour contains more gluten than any other flour it is considered the best for bread making. thite flour is made of the wheat grain with bran coats removed inner portion of grain finely ground. Other flours made of wheat are the Graham, a coarsely ground flour with bran coats retained ; Whole Wheat, a flour with less of the bran removed, hence contains more of the wheat grain than white flour; Pastry flour, made from winter wheat contains a Infer portion of starch than the bread flours and may be used for breads, doughs and batters not requiring yeast. Pye flour, corn meal, oatmeal and barley are generally used with ite flour in bread making because of their lack in gluten. Liquid: Water, sweet milk, whey, potato water, butter milk or water in combination with any of other liquids, are used. Milk increases the protein and fat, reduces the need of shortening and makes a more tender moist loaf. Whey and potato water furnish food for the yeast plant and also give a loaf that will keep moist. I east: Yeast is used to make the bread light and hence more stible. It is a very tiny little one-celled plant which has no is. leaves, flowers or seeds but grows by one cell budding or nng from another cell. These plants are found growing every - re; in the air, in the skins of fruit, etc. They are also culti - d for use in distillery work and in bread making. There are e kinds of yeast on the market. The dry yeast which is made lixing fresh yeast with enough meal to make a stiff dough. The ?h is then pressed into shape and dried at a low heat. Most 1C yeast plants are at resting stage and warm water and a little </seg>
            <seg id="p028">27 sugar are added to make them grow and be ready to mix with the other ingredients for bread making. Liquid yeast or Bakers' yeast m very common at one time. It is made from sugar, potatoes, water and sometimes a small amount of hops or malt with a small amount of yeast to start the yeast plants growing. If fresh it makes a good sweet bread. If old there is danger of acid fermentation making the bread taste sour. Compressed yeast is made by skim - ming the yeast from the top of fermented liquor, washing it sev - eral times, straining and pressing it, and mixing it with just enough starch to press into cakes. These cakes are wrapped in tin foil to keep the yeast from drying. Compressed yeast gives a quick action as one cake alone will contain millions of yeast plants, but it does po» have the keeping qualities of the other forms of yeast. When fresh it should be firm, slightly moist and of a light creamy color throughcut. It will keep a week if kept in a cool, dry place. Be - cause of its quick action it is perhaps the best yeast to use in the summer. Elt: Salt adds flavor, inhibits the growth of bacteria and retards entaticn, consequently should be added toward the end of the Kugar; Sugar hastens the process of fermentation or rising of id as it furnishes direct food for the yea9t plant until the starch he flour can be changed to sugar. Eortening: Shortening in the form of lard, butter, chicken fat. ippings, is used to decrease the natural toughness of the wheat ire. Too much shortening clogs the gluten cells and retards '. If milk is used shortening can be omitted. General Rules for Bread Making I. Temperature: The temperature of the mixture should be carefully regulated. Yeast develops best at about 37° C or when materials are about lukewarm. Mixing and raising must be done in a warm place away from drafts. B Sterilization : Water should be boiled before it is used, and should be scalded in order to kill any bacteria present, then d to lukewarm temperature before adding the yeast. Why? ///. Mixing. The ingredients should be mixed thoroughly and </seg>
            <seg id="p029">28 j * )\\ i \ ill order nidi 1 1 it n' hi r i )v in cii y\ orivtrti n ■ smj i i i&lt;i i c * 1 1. 1 1 sidiv 11 grain will come in contact with moisture and thus give a good, even (. Kneading ; The s])onge must be thoroughly kneaded. ( 1 ) istribute the yeast throughout the entire mass so that the pores be of uniform size; (2) to thoroughly mix all ingredients so e will be no streaks and the texture will be the same through - (3) to introduce more air, the oxygen of which serves as food the yeast plant. Much kneading will cause the bread to rise more slowly, but so ereatlv improves the texture that it makes up for the loss in time. In shaping the loaves never add flour as it gives a starchy flavor to the bread and leaves uneven streaks. K. Riamg: Let the dough rise until double its bulk. If it ri&gt;e - long the dough becomes sour. To prevent souring cut or knead let it rise again before shaping it. If. Baking: Bread is baked. ( 1) to cook the starch and make it e digestible, (2) to develop flavor. (3) to kill the yeast plants s to check further fermentation. (4) to stiffen the gluten so the pores formed by the gas will retain their shape. (?) to e off gas and alcohol. (6) to form a brown crust which protects crumb of the bread. VII. Care after baking: Take the loaf from the pan and set in a dry, airy place to become cool and to allow the steam to escape. Do not wrap in a cloth while hot as this shuts the steam up in the loaf and makes the bread damp and encourages the growth of mold. When cool, place in sterile jars or tin boxes which are air tight, or better still wrap in paraffin paper (this can be obtained at any drug store for a small sum). Characteristic of a Good Loaf Ek'hen bread is done it should be an even golden brown color all r the outside, should be light, not soggy or heavy. Crust should thin, of a nutty flavor and should crack when broken. The mb should be of a sweet flavor and not taste of the yeast, should e fine and uniform pores throughout, should spring back to </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Lessons in Cooking 29 level surface when pressed easily, should have a moist, glossy ap - pearance, should not be streaked or have heavy s|&gt;ots and should have a good creamy white color. The loaf should be evenly raised and of uniform height in all parts. Imperfections in Bread tSogywcss: Soggy bread is due to flour whose gluten lacks th, or to yeast lacking in vitality, or to defective kneading, ; and baking. If. Cnimblitiess : This is due to use of harsh, dry flour not suf - ficiently fermented or over-raised dough, making the loaf larger than the gluten of the flour will stand. E'. Large pores in bread: These are due to over-raised dough, of kneading, to dough that is too moist, or to too hot an oven {'. Sour bread: This is due to over-rising or to the introduc - of bacteria which cause lactic or acetic fermentation. Bacteria be introduced by means of the yeast, water, utensils or from air. When the yeast is active and vigorous the bacteria are in check, but when the activity of the yeast subsides bacteria me active. During the summer months, salt may be added le sponge when it is first mixed because salt inhibits the growth acteria. Bread Judging — Score Card Flavor ) Taste } 40 ( )dor \ Texture of Crumb Lightness 10 \ Doughiness 10 / " * - in V Doughiness Moisture 10 &gt; 4? .tiumuiv ivy / </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 Lessons in Cooking Crust Color 5 f Hardiness 5 t lu Size and Shape 5 RECIPES Plain Wh\te Bread (Slow Process) 1 c milk y 2 T sugar 1 c water (boiled) \y 2 t salt y 2 cake dry yeast dissolved in 2 T lukewarm water 6 to 7 cups wheat flour Scald the milk, add the water and sugar, cool until lukewarm, add dissolved yeast. Add 3 c flour gradually and beat thoroughly. Why? Let rise over night (be sure this sponge is kept away from drafts). In the morning add the salt and remaining flour until the dough can be worked into a lump without sticking to the hands or to the board. If too much flour is added the bread will be too hard and dry. Knead lightly and with a quick motion of the hands. Continue kneading until the dough is elastic when pressed with the finger and you hear a snapping sound. Long kneading makes a fine grained bread. Place in a buttered bowl, cover with a towel and let rise again until double its bulk. Be sure you do not keep the bread too hot as heat kills the yeast plants, or too cold as cold re - tards their growth. When doubled in bulk, shape into loaves by taking the dough from the bowl, kneading it a little without adding flour and dividing it into equal parts. Knead each portion to fit the shape of the pan in which it is to be baked. Set the loaves in a warm place to double in size. When double in size bake in a hot oven from 45 to 60 minutes, depending upon the size of the loaf. During the first half hour the bread should continue to rise and brown. To insure thorough baking on the inside of the loaf and prevent the formation of too thick a crust, the temperature should be lowered for the next fifteen minutes. Then the heat should be increased for the last fifteen minutes to dextrinize or caramel - ize the crust, (length of time must be according to the size of the </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Lessons in Cooking 31 loaf — this is for a pound loaf about 4x5x10 inches in size). Xote: — If the oven is too hot at first the crust will crack, be - come dark and the gas trying to escape may leave large boles under the crust. If the oven is too slow the bread will rise too much in Boven and become too porous he loaf will not burn when sides will shrink away from n thumped. When bread is done the bottom placed on the palm of the hand, the pan and it will sound hollow Graham Bread 3 to 4 c Graham flour 2 c water cake dry yeast dissolved in 2 »'i c molasses y 2 t salt T lukewarm water 3 c White flour I feat water until lukewarm, add molasses, yeast (dissolved) and ite flour, beat thoroughly and let stand over night. In the morn - add salt and (iraham flour to make a soft dough. Knead lightly, rise until double in bulk. Shape into loaves, let rise again until hie in bulk. Bake. Plain Rolls 1 c milk 1 t salt l /$ cake dry yeast dissolved in 3 1 c water T lukewarm water 1 T butter 6 to 7 c flour 1 T sugar Scald milk, dissolve sugar in it. Cool until lukewarm, add water d dissolved yeast, and enough flour to make a thin drop batter. \ nd over night. In the morning add salt, melted butter and flour 5 to knead. Knead thoroughly, let rise to double size, shape into rolls, let rise until double in size and brush with milk or melte.l butter. Bake 25 to 30 minutes in a hot oven. Quick Breads tne leavening in quick breads is not yeast as you used in bread chemical compounds which act more quickly and under con - ns different from those necessary for yeast. The chemicals l we use most commonly are soda and baking powder. Soda </seg>
            <seg id="p033">32 is used to neutralize the acidity of sour milk, molasses and brown sugar. Baking powder is used with sweet milk and water. Baking powder is made of an acid (usually cream of tartar), an alkali h ) and cornstarch which acts as a filler and absorbs moisture, thus keeping the other two ingredients from acting and forming gss. Proportions for Making 1 lb. of Baking Powder Alkali=soda y A lb. Acid cream of tartar j j lb. Filler= .- cornstarch "4 1°. Mix by sifting twelve times. Place in a glass jar, seal. 1 t of soda is allowed for 2 c brown sugar 2 t of baking powder are allowed for 1 c flour ( with 2 eggs used i 1 ' .. t of baking powder are allowed for 1 c flour ( with 4 eggs use! i The acid found in molasses, sour milk, lemon juice, etc.. combined with soda will liberate gas. In baking powder the gas is set free by the acid in cream of tartar. In these processes heat and moisture are both required. As soon as the moisture is added to the mix - ture the gas begins to escape. Therefore, mixtures containing baking powder or soda should Le combined quickly and baked im - mediately. If it is necessary to let the mixture stand, set in a cool place and do not stir. Why ? RECIPES Plain Muffins 2 c flour 1 to \Vi c milk 4 t baking powder 2 T melted butter Yi t salt 1 egg Have in readiness the materials and utensils. Grease tin pans, heat iron gem pans while mixing muffins, then grease. Sift flour before measuring. Measure flour, and other dry ingredients into sifter, sift all together into mixing bowl. Separate the egg. beat yolk until light and lemon colored and white until stiff and dry. Rules as to the Use of Baking Powder and So&lt; la 1 t of soda is allowed for 1 c mnhiiri 2 t of soda is allowed for 1 c sour milk </seg>
            <seg id="p034">33 Add milk to yolk and pour gradually into flour stirring it in wider and wider circles until all the flour is moistened. Pour melted shortening into the batter, beat vigorously until all lumps are re - moved. Cut and fold in white of egg. Half fill pans and bake in a hot oven 20 to 30 minutes. Plain Muffins (Sour Milk) 2 c flour 1 c sour milk y 2 t salt 2 T melted butter 1 t baking powder 2 eggs l / 2 t soda Mix according to directions in Plain Muffins. Baking Powder Biscuits 2 c flour y 2 t salt 2 T lard or butter Yi c sweet milk 4 t baking powder Sift dry ingredients, cut or rub gradually and cut with knife to a board, roll out to l /z inch thickness, butter into flour, add the milk soft dough. Toss on a floured cut in rounds, place in a floured pan and bake in a hot oven 20 minutes. All ingredients should be cold Handle as little as possible. Soda Biscuits 2 c flour }i t soda 2 T lard % t salt 1 t baking powder y A c buttermilk or sour milk tft flour, baking powder and salt together. Cut or rub butter flour. Add soda to milk. Stir milk gradually into flour and tto a soft dough. Roll, cut and Egg Rolls bake as baking powder biscuits. 2 c flour y 2 t salt y 2 c milk 4 T butter 4 t baking powder 1 egg beaten until light Sift the flour, then measure and sift again with dry ingredients, cut or rub butter into flour. Mix the milk and egg and add to </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 the flour ; mix lightly. Roll to inch thickness on a floured board, tut in oblong pieces and with a floured knife crease through the center of each roll. Brush over the top with white of egg and sprinkle with granulated sugar. Bake 15 min. in a hot oven. This i - an excellent dough for shortcake. Ginger Bread '/ 2 T ginger 1 c molasses 1 egg well beaten 2 c flour % c brown sugar 2 T lard, melted 1 1 c boiling water 1 t soda yi t salt tix molasses, sugar and lard, add sifted dry ingredients, then water and egg. Bake 25 minutes in a moderate oven. QUESTIONS 1. What kind of flour is best for bread making' Why? 2. What is yeast? 3. How does yeast make the bread light? rWhy is it necessary to thoroughly mix and knead bread What is the purpose of baking? »Bake bread once each of the four weeks of this month — each grading it according to the Score Card. 7. Why can soda and sour milk be substituted for baking powder? 8. Why can soda and cream of tartar be substituted for baking powder? ' 9. Why should the soda be sifted with dry ingredients? 10. Prepare at least three quick breads during the month. State which you prepared End the results. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">35 Lesson V. SPRING VEGETABLES Importance: Vegetables should form a large part of our daily food — first, because they furnish small amounts of all the nutri - ents required by the body; second, because they have a beneficial effect upon the whole system in that they help furnish th« bulk in the diet so necessary to keep the digestive tract in perfect order ; third, because they give variety to our diet at a small cost and can be prepared in such pleasing and palatable ways that they stimulate tflow of digestive juices. jses of Vegetables 1. Heat giving vegetables or starch and sugar vegetables, beans, lentils, potatoes, carrots, Examples : — Corn, peas turnips. 2. Muscle building vegetables or protein vegetables (meat sub- stitutes). Examples :— Peas, beans, lentils. [. Mineral giving vegetables or bone building, blood building and nerve building vegetables. Examples: — Asparagus, lettuce, onions, radishes, greens, spinach, tomatoes, green peas, string beans, celery, carrots. Note: Most of our spring vegetables come under the third class and are ready for use at the time of the year when the body is most in need of their help. rral Directions lor Preparing and Cooking Prepare and cook as soon after gathering as possible. Wash thoroughly in cold water and rinse. Cook until tender in a small amount of fresh, boiling, salted water (1 T salt to 1 pint water). </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 Lessons in Cooking 4. Cook with cover off to preserve the color. »Do not drain as some of the nutriment would be lost in the r; rather boil until almost dry. Asparagus with Butter Sauce teak off tough lower end, wash stalks, tie in bunch, place with up in boiling salted water. Cook 20-30 minutes or until ten- Drain, serve with melted butter, or on toast with melted Asparagus Creamed Kit asparagus in inch pieces, cook tough portions first and add during last 15 minutes. Drain, mix with White Sauce No. 3. e on toast. Green Onions Gean and cut off part of green tops; tie in bundles; cook until tender in boiling salted water; serve on toast with melted butter. Spinach or Greens Wash thoroughly in 5 or more waters to remove grit. Cut off roots and faded leaves, drain and put into a large stew pan without water or a very small amount. Place on back of range and cook slowly 15 minutes. Move to hotter part of stove and boil until tender. Add salt, pepper and butter to taste. Chop fine, heat again, and serve on toast, and garnish with hard cooked eggs. Buttered Peas Remove peas from pods, wash, drain, cook with a small amount of boiling water. Add salt during last 15 minutes of cooking. Cook from 50-60 minutes. Season with butter, salt, pepper, and if they have lost their natural sweetness add 1 t sugar to 2 c of peas. String Beans Remove strings and cut in one-inch pieces, wash and cook in boiling water from one to three hours, adding salt the last half hour of cooking. Drain, season with butter, salt, pepper. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">37 [Why should vegetables form a portion of our daily food? Why are spring vegetables of value to the body? Xame some vegetables that can be eaten raw. Some that are better cooked. I. What is the aim in the cooking of spring vegetables? (Why a small amount of water) ? 5. What vegetables have you prepared and cooked as directed in this lesson? QUESTIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p039">38 Lesson VI. FRUIT:— CANNING AND PRESERVING Value of Fruit in Diet Ilthough fruits have very little food value aside from the starch sugar they contain, yet they have an important use. They ain a large amount of sterile water, necessary to the system; ■ acids and flavors stimulate the appetite, therefore, improve stion ; their acids, skins, bulk and water make them act as a tive, therefore, often relieve or prevent constipation. They )ly the body with iron and other minerals, (that help purify blood, and act on secretions) therefore, help to keep the body ood condition. traits then, as well as vegetables should form a large part of diet, in winter as well as summer. As fresh fruits are not lys available the year round they must be prepared in some when in season to preserve them for the winter use. Preservation of Fruit Decomposition of fruit: The decomposition or spoiling of fruit is due to a very low order of plant life. They are very tiny plants and reproduce with amazing rapidity when the conditions such as temperature, light, moisture, and food are favorable. These plants are called bacteria, yeast and mold. Yeast is easily killed by heat. Mold can be seen with naked eye, and is not so commonly the cause of spoiling of cooked fruit. Bacteria are the most troublesome plants the housekeeper has to deal with. We have them always; in the air, in the water, in the ground, in the can, in the cover. If allowed to grow, they form substances which make fruits unfit rethods of preservation (inhibiting the growth of these plants): I. Temperature (a) Low Temperature: — These plants flourish in warm </seg>
            <seg id="p040">39 temperature, therefore, cold retards or checks their growth — this is only a temporary method. Meth- ods : — Cellars, caves, refrigerators, cold storage. (b) High Temperature: — Canning — a process for killing plant life (bacteria and yeast) present in the fruits and sealing to prevent the entrance of new plant life. This process of heating is known as steriliz- ation. When canned fruits or vegetables spoil it is due to one or more of the following causes : — ■ 1. Using utensils for cooking that can be affected by acid of fruit. »2. Presence of some invisible form of plant life which has escaped destruction by heat. 3. Failing t othoroughly sterilize cans, rubbers, spoons or any other utensil used in the pro - cess of canning. 4. Leaving in the can air which is not sterile. 5. Imperfect sealing, allowing the entrance of bacteria. Note: — Cans one-half full will keep if fruit, cans, rubbers, covers and space above the fruit is sterile and if properly sealed. II. Removal of Moisture (desiccation). Drying of fruit (taking out the supply of water necessary for growth of plant life). III. Use of Allowable Preservatives. (a) Sugar: — Used in large amounts in canned fruits, preserves, marmalades, jams, jellies, etc. (b) Spices and condiments used in pickling. Selection of Fruit: I a) Select sound, perfect fruit. (If skins are broken bacteria enter more easily). (b) Ripe fruit — neither over nor under ripe. (c) Fresh fruit. Do not pick directly after a rain as skins are much softer and break more easily, and the flavor is impaired when the fruit is water soaked. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">40 Lessons hi Cooking Selection of Utensils: Eessels of earthen or granite ware. Wooden spoon for stirring. Feet jars. Plain smooth covers that fit jars tightly. New rub - that fit jars. Application of Principles .\fcthod cf sterilizing jars: Wash jars and fill with cold water; place on ■ cloth to prevent the jars from touching the bottom of the kettle. Surround the jars with cold water, heat gradually un - til water 1 oils. Keep jars in boiling water until ready to fill, then empty and fill. Put covers in hot water and let stand 5 minutes. Dip rubber bands in hot water but do not boil them as boiling in - jures the rubber. Itethod of Ming jars: Place the rubbers on the jars and stand m on a towel in a pan of hot water. Put in fruit scalding hot, to overtoiling. Use the blade of a sterile silver knife to push it from sides of jar in order .that the air bubbles may rise to the face. Put on covers and fasten firmly. Let stand until cold, in screw cover, wash jars and label. Proportions for syrup: Canned Sweet Fruits : — To 3 quarts fruit use 2 c sugar, 2 l / 2 ter. Boil sugar and water 10 minutes. It. Preserved Fruits: — To 1 quart fruit use I 1 /? to 2 c sugar, water. Boil sugar and water 10 minutes. The amount of sugar ends upon the taste and condition of fruit. In warm, sunny ;ons the flavor and sweetness is better than in cold, wet seasons fruit will not require as much sugar. Usually Sweet fruits, l as peaches and pears require 2 c sugar, 4 c water. Sour fruits l as gooseberries and cherries require 2 c sugar, 2J4 c water. Methods of canning: I. Fruit cooked in jars (a) In water or steamer: Pack fruit in jars and cover with a syrup made by boiling 2 cups sugar with 3y 2 cups water ten minutes. Adjust covers loosely. Steam until tender, filling with more syrup if necessary. Seal and label. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Lessons in Cooking 41 Fruit in Steamer. Wash-boiler may be used. (b) In fireless cocker: Place filled jars in fireless cooker can. Fill can to neck of jars with water. Bring to boil. Place can in cooker and cover. Leave 1 hour. Seal and label. (c) In the oven: Prepare fruit according to directions, fill sterilized jars with it and pour in enough hot syrup to fill jar. Run blade of sterile silver knife around inside of jar. Set cover on lightly. Place jars on asbestos or in pan of hot water in moderate oven. Cook 15 to 30 minutes depending on size and kind of fruit. Remove from oven, fill jar with boiling syrup. Seal and label. II. Fruit cooked before it is placed in jars: Place prepared fruit in boiling syrup. Cook until clear. Place fruit in jar, add syrup and seal. Ke: — If fruit is hard, steam it or cook in boiling water until tender. Then put it into the syrup to finish cooking. Fill jars and seal. The water in which fruit was cooked may be used in making the syrup. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 RECIPES Canned Strawberries I. Eash strawberries by placing them in a colander and pouring water over them. Pick out caps and stems. Can according ethod I. Earn by placing in a vessel in which a cloth or folds of i»per «e of wood is placed in the bottom and fill to neck of jars lukewarm water. Cover vessel and bring to boil; boil half ur. Remove jars and seal. Canned Strawberries II. I'repare as for Canned Strawberries I. Can according to Method using 1 c sugar to 1 c water to 1 quart of fruit. Canned Blackberries or Raspberries Iollow either method used in the canning of strawberries. These •ies contain less acid, hence '/&gt; c less sugar is needed. Canned Cherries Remove pits. To each quart of cherries use 2 c sugar and 2 c cold water. Can according to methods I or II. Canned Rhubarb or Gooseberries Erause of large amount of acid these fruits may be canned Wash, pare, and cut rhubarb into inch pieces ; stem and wash berries. Seal in fresh water. All air must be excluded and no s left. These may be canned according to Method II using t sugar to 1 pint water for syrup. QUESTIONS tFrom the information concerning the causes for the sailing ruit state six things that are necessary to remember in canning t. Divide as follows: — ( 1) Two for the fruit. (2) Two for the utensils. (3) Two for the process of canning. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">43 2. Which method of canning do you find makes the most at tractive jar of fruit? Why? 3. What canned fruits will you exhibit at your local, county and state contest? Note: — In labeling your fruit use the following form Xame Kind of fruit Year of canning Method used </seg>
            <seg id="p045">44 Lesson VII. VEGETABLES:— SUMMER AXD WINTER Kegetables, from the housekeeper's standpoint include all plants [ for food except fruits and grains. They are universally used are derived from every part of the plant ; roots, tubers, bulbs, is, blossoms, fruits, seeds and pods. rts: — beets, radishes, turnips, parsnips, carrots, sweet pota - toes, oyster plant. Tubers : — Potatoes. Bulbs : — Onions, garlic. Es : — Celery, rhubarb, asparagus, chives. es: — Spinach, lettuce, cabbage, brussel-sprouts oms : — Cauliflower. Fruits: — Cucumbers, squash, egg plant, tomatoes. Seeds and Pods: — Peas, beans, lentils, corn. Structure and Composition Cellulose is that which gives the vegetable shape and constitutes the walls of the vegetable cells. Enclosed within these walls are minute grains of starch, sugar, protein, fat, water, mineral matter and vegetable acids. Most vegetables are rich in one or more of these food substances and very deficient in others ; therefore, we classify them according to the functions they perform when taken into the body — as in Lesson V. Eote : — It is because of the large amount of cellulose and the that with age the cellulose or framework becomes woody and I, that some vegetables are harder to cook than others. Food Value Vegetables when in season are a very economical item of food and are a necessary part of our diet. Dried beans and peas are the most nutritious and may be used in place of meats since they fur - nish the necessary protein in a cheap form. Potatoes, turnips, car- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Lessons in C ooktHQ 45 I and beets rank next because of the starch and sugar they con- Cabbage, lettuce, celery, greens, and other green vegetables valuable because of the mineral matter and acids they furnish. General Directions I oiling vegetables : Wash vegetables thoroughly. Pare, scrape eel thin. If old vegetables, allow them to stand in cold water mr before cooking. Cook until tender in fresh, boiling, salted ;r, allowing 1 T of salt to 1 qt of water. Strong flavored ve - bles such as cabbage, onions, turnips should be cooked uncov - in a large amount of boiling, salted water; and if vegetables very strong in flavor the water should be changed at least once ng the process, boiling water being used to replace that which irown away. Iegetables such as carrots, turnips, parsnips and celery should ut in small pieces and cooked in as small amount of boiling, :d water as possible. Do not drain, rather let the water boil DSt away. In draining much of the nutriment of the vegetables •st. If the water is not all evaporated save it as it can be used orm part of the liquid for soups. fimc of cooking: The time of cooking the same vegetable varies rding to the freshness and age, therefore, timetables for cook - serve only as rough guides. In general : Young peas, beans, green corn, asparagus, spinach and tomatoes should be cooked from 15 to 20 minutes. Potatoes, summer squash, celery, cauliflower and young cabbage should be cooked from 15 to 30 minutes. Summer turnips, beets, carrots, parsnips, onions and cabbage should be cooked from 30 to 45 min - utes. Winter vegetables should be cooked from 1 to 4 hours de - pending upon the woodiness of the frame work. Care of vegetables : Summer vegetables should be cooked as soon after gathering as possible. In case they must be kept, place in a cool, dry, well ventilated place, or in the ice box, or place in cold water, especially if they are wilted. Lettuce, mint and parsley may be kept by sprinkling with cold water and placing in a glass jar tightly covered, or in a tin pail closely covered, or may be wrapped in a damp cloth and placed on ice. Vegetables containing sugar </seg>
            <seg id="p047">46 Lessons in Cooking lose some of their sweetness upon standing, especially corn and Winter vegetables should be kept in a cold, dry, well ventilated place, away from the air if possible, therefare, put in barrels or pile in bins. Sweet potatoes should be wrapped in paper, packed in a box and kept in a warm place. Squash should be spread and care - fully watched for dark spots. Parsley and mint, may be trans - planted to a box or pail and kept growing in the house all winter, or the leaves of celery, parsley and mint may 1)e dried, packed in cans and kept for winter use. I'anned vegetables : If glass jars are used keep them in a dark ■e to retain color. When opened, never let vegetables stand in can as a chemical change takes place when the canned material les in contact with the air. Canned peas, beans and asparagus uld be emptied into a strainer, drained and cold water poured r them and allowed to run through. There is only a small a - lnt of nutriment lost and the flavor is much improved, also ger from the tin being dissolved by the vegetables is lessened. Dried vegetables: Keep in a dry place. They should be soaked in cold water several hours before cooking in order that they may take up the water they lost in drying. Eid of vegetables served at one meal: Generally one starchy able, such as potatoe, and one green vegetable is quite suffi - for one meal. If a third vegetable is used it should be entirely ent from the other two vegetables. Example: — String beans and peas should not be served at the same meal. Dried peas and beans should not be served at the same meal. Dried peas and beans should not be served with a heavy meat unless in the form of soup as they themselves give to the body enough protein necessary for that meal. If two or at the most three vegetables well chosen can give both the variety and the food value necessary, why prepare more? Seasoning: For 1 qt. of cooked vegetables use 4 T butter, y 2 t salt, % t pepper. Milk, cream, white sauce or bacon may be used for variation. Use of left-over vegetables: Vegetables that are left from one or more meals may be used either alone or combined in the making </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Lessons in Cooking 47 i i cream soup, salads, left-over meat dishes and escalloped dishes i Future Lesson) RECIPES Starch and Sugar Vegetables Boiled Potatoes I'hoose potatoes of about uniform size. Wash, pare thinly and [&gt; at once into cold water to prevent discoloration. Cook in ih, boiling, salted water (1 T salt to 2 qts. water) until they are throughout. Drain at once, uncover and shake gently over heat until the outside is dry and mealy, sprinkle with a little and serve in a hot uncovered dish. Potatoes will be water Iced and heavy if water is not boiling when potatoes are put in. k-ater is not kept boiling and if they are cooked too long. Po - es may be mashed with butter, hot milk and salt added, and the ture beaten until light and creamy, or to 2 cups of these mash - potatoes add the whites of two eggs beaten stiff, put mixture i a well greased baking dish and bake in a quick oven until well led and brown. Potatoes on Half-shell .5 baked potatoes 1 T butter 2 T milk or cream Salt to taste Hake potatoes of uniform size with smooth, fair skins ; when done cut in two lengthwise. Remove interior portion and mash. Add butter, salt, cream, beat until light, pile mixture in shells and put in oven to brown. Garnish with parsley. Left-over Potatoes Creamed Potatoes Et cold boiled or baked potatoes into cubes, heat thoroughly hite Sauce No. II. When potatoes are heated, season and tit diced potatoes with alternate layers of White Sauce No. II buttered baking dish, sprinkle with buttered crumbs and brown </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 in the oven. Crumbs are prepared by drying left-over bread, and grinding it. To 1 c of these crumbs add 2 T of melted butter. 1 little cheese may be added to creamed potatoes to give flavor increase nutriment. A little minced parsley, green pepper, or nto may be added for variation and flavor. Sweet potatoes may be prepared according to any of the above directions. Canned Peas with Fresh Carrots K crape or pare two carrots, cut lengthwise into quarters, and quarters into strips \% inches long and )/% inch wide and thick. mer until tender in a very small amount of water. When ced, water should be nearly evaporated. Eain peas, rinse in cold water, add y, c boiling water. Boil nutes, drain and add to carrots. Season with 1 t salt. 1 t ', J4 t white pepper and 3 T butter. Shake over fire to mix dients. Serve at once in a hot dish. Creamed Parsnips and Cheese Eash and scrape parsnips, cut in thin slices and cook in small int of boiling water until tender. Drain and put in buttered ig dish. Cover with White Sauce Xo. III. Add grated cheese. : in oven for 5 minutes. Serve hot. Beers Wash, but do not cut them as some nutriment will be lost and color impaired. Cook in boiling water until tender. When cooked put in cold water and rub off the skin. Cut in slices and serve hot with butter, salt, pepper or cut in dice and heated in the following sauce: J4 c sugar 2 T vinegar or more 2 T flour Salt 2 T butter Cayenne pepper % c boiling water Eelt butter, add flour and stir until smooth, add sugar and water, c until thickened. Add vinegar, season highly with salt and *r, pour on beets and heat. Serve at once. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">■w Protein Vegetables Dried Lima Beans tiak 1 c dried beans over night, drain and put into boiling, salted r, simmer about \y 2 hours or until soft with cover partially If beans are strong pour off water after 30 minutes and add 1 boiling water to finish cooking. When done drain, add butter, er. salt and J4 c milk or cream. Serve in hot dish. Corn, ned tomato, and a little onion may be added to beans making Dtash. Baked Beans Ick over 1 (|t. beans, wash, cover with cold water and soak over t. In the morning drain, cover with cold water and simmer when you take a bean from kettle and blow on it the skin will t. Drain. Take ]/ 2 lb. salt pork, part lean, part fat, and scrape until white. Cut off slices '/ 2 inch in width and place in bottom le bean pot. Cut through rind of remaining |&gt;ork every y&gt; inch ing cuts 1 inch dee]). Put beans in pot. bury pork in beans. 2 t salt, 3 T molasses, ■/&gt; T mustard, add 1 c boiling water, ■ over beans, add enough boiling water to cover, and keep ng more water as needed until the last hour. Cover pot and 1 8 to 12 hours in a slow oven. Uncover the last hour. Other Vegetables Broiled Tomatoes 3 large tomatoes Salt I circular slices of buttered toast utter Pepper Cut tomatoes crosswise in halves. Sprinkle surface with salt. ]&gt;epper and small bits of butter. Put in shallow baking pan. Place in oven 15 min. Place each half on a slice of toast and serve at Escalloped Tomatoes Cover bottom of baking dish with buttered crumbs. Put in layer of tomatoes, season with salt, pepper and a very little sugar and </seg>
            <seg id="p051">50 Ei juice ; another layer of crumbs, then tomatoes seasoned and bs on top. Bake J/&gt; hour in a moderate oven. Slices of bread red may be used in place of buttered crumbs. Corn may be loped in the same manner. Escalloped Cabbage iake off outside leaves, cut into sections, remove core, wash in waters and drain. Have large kettle 2/3 full of violently ing water. % t and 1 T salt to 2 qts. of water. Place leaves ,-ater one at a time and do not let water stop boiling. Boil un - 'red until tender. Drain, put in buttered baking dish. Add ite Sauce Xo. III. Cover with buttered crumbs and brown in oven. Onions may be prepared in the same manner. QUESTIONS r) Grate a small piece of a potato. Put grated potato in a cloth, wash in a bowl with a pint of cold water. Allow the water to stand. What happens? (b) Taste water in which potato is washed. The peculiar taste is due to mineral matter. (c) Mix contents of bowl together and boil. What did it maker (d) Put the part left in the cloth in a dry place for one day. What is lost? What is left? (e) What conclusions do you draw as to the substances which make up the composition of the potato? Prepare four different vegetables. Name them and their od of preparation. KName four things that you have learned about the prepara and cooking of vegetables. EWhat use have you made of two left-over vegetable Whv mav vou use baked beans in place of meat </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Lessons in Cooking 51 Lesson VIII. PRESERVATION' OF FRUIT (Continued from Lesson VI) By Means of Preservatives Ireservatives are substances used in food preservation to pre - or retard the growth of plant life. Primative peoples used such ervatives as salt, smoke and spices. In recent years there has i a rapid growth in the number of preservatives. You must ember that any substance sufficiently active to destroy or check growth of plant life should be questioned because it may have milar effect on the living tissues that line the digestive tact, only preservatives that are harmless and that give the most rable flavors. The following preservatives we know are absol - f harmless in moderate quantities : — Salt, sugar, vinegar and Bote: — In canning, just enough sugar is added to improve the &gt;r — not enough to act as a preservative. Sugar as a Preservative Sugar in large amounts is a very effective preservative. It gives a good flavored, wholesome food, but one that must be used spar - ingly in the diet. Preserves, jams, marmalades, conserves and jel - lies come under this class. Preserves are now less sweet, less thick, therefore, less easily kept than formally, so must be sealed. Ems and marmalades are an improvement over jelly in both lesomeness and taste. They are a rich, sweet product in - ing fruit pulp as well as fruit juice. Pulp left from jelly ing or imperfect fruit can be used. Conserves are made from a mixture of fruit with and without other materials such as nuts and raisins. Jellies are a beautifully colored, palatable result obtained by using fruit juices in such a manner that the resulting mass will quiver not flow, when removed from the mold, and will cut easily with a spoon and yet keep its shape. Since only juices of fruit are used </seg>
            <seg id="p053">52 Ely making, the food value depends largely upon the sugar used, nutritive value is not high in proportion to the amount of y and labor expended, consequently jelly would be counted g the luxuries in the diet. Cause of jellying: The jellying of fruit juices is due to the presence of a substance called pectin that has properties similar to that of gelatine. Different fruits contain different amounts of i&gt;ectin in their juices and this accounts for the differences in the jelly making quality of various fruits. This pectin will not act MleM M acid is also present, therefore, the two essential things necessary in jelly making are pectin and acid. Peaches, peas and sweet apples contain pectin but insufficient acid. Partly ripened grapes, green grapes, plums, raspberries, blackberries, crab apples, sour apples and currants are rich in both pectin and acid. Apple skins and carrots are also rich in pectin and can be boiled and their juice added to introduce this substance to other fruit juices. Jelly bag and table ready for jelly making. lixeraction of juice from fruits: For jelly making the juice should always be obtained by cooking the fruit, as this brings out </seg>
            <seg id="p054">53 the pectin better than grinding or pressing. Pectin is frequently not found in raw fruit juice l&gt;ut is found in abundance in the cooked juices of this same fruit. Sofe juicy fruits such as grapes and berries should be placed in a preserving kettle, little or no water added, cooked slowly, crushed and stirred occasionally with a wooden sjkjoii to prevent sticking. In less juicy fruits unsound parts should be discarded, sound parts cut up in pieces, covered with water and simmered and mashed when soft. To separate the juice from the pulp place the cooked fruit in a moistened jelly bag and drain. The bag can be made of double pieces of cheese cloth, cut s(|uare and folded over to make a funnel shape and sew edges together. The fruit should be allowed to drain without squeezing as this will cause some pulp to come through and make your jelly rlowdj. This is extraction No. I. If jelly is made from fruit rich in nectin. the pulp left in the bag may be put back in the preserving kettle, water added to cover and allowed to boil slowly one-half hour and the juice extracted as before. This we call extraction No. II and will make a very good quality of jelly. This last ex - traction contains less acid, is less rich in pectin and contains more water, therefore, either more sugar should be used, or better the juice should he rapidly boiled down until it approaches the rich- IW1I of extraction Xo. I. Effect of Sugar: While not essential to jelly making sugar is used first, because with the addition of sugar jellying takes place sooner, therefore, gives more jelly to the amount of juice; second. because it improves the flavor unless too much is used. In this case the jelly may be stringy. The proper amounts of sugar very ac - cording to the nature of the fruit. For fruits that are sweeter and for fruits cooked in considerable water use c sugar to 1 c of Kimc of adding sugar: Sugar should not be added until the e has been cooked one-half the time required for making the ■ and should be added warm so as not to cool the juice. Time of cooking jelly: Juices rich in pectin such as currants or partly ripened grapes, require about 10 minutes rapid boiling in all. ■uices containing less pectin require from 20 to 30 minutes rapid in K . </seg>
            <seg id="p055">54 Lessons in Cooking Boiling for a long time destroys pectin, therefore, juice will not If juice does not jelly in a reasonable length of time add a quantity of fresh juice and reboil or pour into glasses and set in the Kests for jellying: Drop the hot syrup from the tip end of the &gt;n. If it breaks off instead of stringing the jelly should be re - ed at once from the fire. This is the quickest test. iake out a small quantity of syrup with a spoon and pour on a plate. Set it in a cool place. If it is sufficiently cooked, the e will stiffen or jell in a few minutes. This is the best method a disadvantage because the whole mass must be removed from fire so that the boiling will not continue while the portion is ing. Filling jelly glasses: As soon as jelly gives "jelly test" remove at once and pour into sterile glasses placed in a pan of boiling water or wrapped with a cloth wrung out of hot water. When cool cover with hot paraffin. When paraffin is hard, cover with lids or paper and label. RECIPES Sugar as a Preservative Strawberry Preserves Kse equal weights of sugar and strawberries. Put alternate lay - of berries and sugar in preserving kettle. Heat slowly to boil - point and boil from 12 to 15 min. depending upon juiciness of t. Put into sterile jars. Cover with parrafin when cold. Explain why fruit containing a small amount of sugar must be sealed while hot, and jams and preserves are sealed after cooling. Rhubarb Preserves Kse equal amounts of sugar and rhubarb which has been peeled cut into short lengths. Use grated or sliced ginger root to :. Cook until signs of jellying appear. Cherry Preserves Kse equal amounts of sugar and cherries. Cook until signs of ing appear. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Lessons in Cooking 55 Marmalades rarmalades are made of the pulp and juice of fruit with sugar. Peach, Quince or Apple Marmalade Pare and core quinces, nearly cover with water and cook until tender. Rub through a sieve, return to the fire, add }i lb. of sugar to every pound of fruit. Cook slowly 20 minutes, stirring occasion - ally to prevent burning. Peach and apple marmalades are made in the same wav. Grape Conserve 5 lbs. grapes 1 lb. raisins 2 medium sized oranges 4 lbs. sugar 1 lb. English walnuts finely chopped. Separate pulp of grapes from skins. Cook skins of grapes until tender. Cook pulp and put through a sieve to remove seeds. Chop oranges and raisins. Mix fruit, add sugar and cook until mixture jellies. Remove from fire, add nuts. Put in jelly glasses and when cold cover with paraffin. Preserved Grapes Weigh the grapes and allow jkj lb. of sugar to one pound of fruit. Rinse the grapes in cold water, drain and squeeze the pulp from the skin of each grape. Heat the pulp gradually and cook until the seeds come out easily. Press through a sieve just enough to keep back the seeds. Cook the skins until tender adding a small amount of water if necessary, then add the pulp and cook 10 minutes. Add sugar and continue cooking until the liquid thickens when cooled. Can and seal. Rhubarb and Orange Marmalade (i oranges 2 lemons 2 lbs. rhubarb Sugar i/ash and wipe the oranges and lemons, cut in quarters length - i then into thin slices. Discard seeds. Weigh oranges and ons and to each pound add 3 pints cold water. Let stand 24 rs. Simmer until rind is tender, let stand 24 hours. If rhubarb rmng and tender retain skin, otherwise remove. Cut stalks into inch slices, add to the oranges and lemons, weigh all. Bring oilinp point, simmer 5 minutes, add one pound of sugar for each nd of fruit. Cook until it thickens slightly. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">56 Currant Jelly I:lect currants that are firm and not too ripe. Do not pick them after a rain. Pick from stems, cook and extract the juice rding to general directions. Measure the juice. Measure one of sugar for each cup of juice and place the sugar in the oven to . Boil the juice 5 minutes, add the sugar, then boil 5 utiimtu. :n it gives the jelly test pour into sterile glasses. Let it cool, cover with hot paraffin ; put on covers and label. Apple Jelly I 'ash and wipe perfect apples, cut them into pieces without par - or coring. Put the fruit into an enameled kettle, cook and ex - t the juice according to general directions. To each pint of f allow one pound of granulated sugar. Put the juice into a le and bring to boiling point, boil rapidly 20 minutes, t'len add ir. which has been warmed in the oven. Stir un'.il the sugar issolved. remove scum as it rises, boil 5 minuses, then turn into ses. When cool cover with paraffin, then pal on covers and 1- Crape Jelly Pick over, wasli and remove stems. Put in sauce pan, mash a few, cook, and when soft strain through a jelly bag. Measure, boil five minutes and to each pint of juice add an eoual quantity of su - gar. Roil rapidly 3 minutes more or until it jellies. Use pulp for the Grape Catsup. Preservation by Spices and Sugar Grape Catsup 2V 2 qts. grape pulp and y 2 qt. water. 2 T cloves (grcund ) 2 lbs. brown sugar 1 pt. vinegar 2 T cinnamon (ground) 2 T allspice (grrund) 1 T salt 1 t cavenne Add sugar, vinegar and spices. Boil until it thickens, then can and seal. Preserved Melon Rind temove the green outer layer of the melon rind and cut the re - ider into small pieces of uniform size. Cover with cold water, one T of salt for each quart of water. Let stand over night, i drain and rinse thoroughly. Cook in boiling water until trans - ■nt. Drain carefullv. For each pound of rind make a syrup I lb. sugar, 1 c water, y 2 oz. ginger root and 1 lemon cut in ;s. Cook the melon in this until it looks rich and clear. Can &gt;rding to directions. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">57 Spiced Currants 7 lbs. currants 3 T cinnamon 5 lbs. brown sugar 3 T cloves 1 pint vinegar Pick over currants, wash, drain and remove stems. Put in a preserving kettle, add sugar, vinegar and spices tied in a piece of muslin. Heat to boiling point and cook slowly 1 ' j hours. Store in a jar and keep in a cool place. Serve with meat. Sweet Pickled Peaches or Pears 1 qt. vinegar 2 oz. stick cinnamon 4 lbs. brown sugar J / 2 oz, cloves Prepare fruit as for canning. Make a syrup by boiling vinegar and sugar 5 minutes. Tie spices in a cheese cloth bag, and cook in svrup. Skim if necessary. Cook fruit a little at a time in syrup until soft. Can according to directions. These proportions are sufficient for 7 lbs. of fruit. Apple Ginger 4 lbs. apples chopped very fine 1 oz. ginger root 4 lbs. sugar 4 lemons, rind and juice 2 c water Make syrup of sugar and water by boiling together 3 minutes. Add lemon, apples and ginger root shaved fine. Cook until clear. can and seal. Apple Chutney Hsour apples mild onion 1 T ground ginger 1-2 c red currant jelly 2 c sugar 2 green and 1 red peppers 2 c cider vinegar Y- t cayenne 1 T salt 1 c seeded raisins Tuice of 4 lemons tiop the apples, onion and peppers very fine; add the vineear let simmer one hour, stirrine often ; add the other ineredients rook another hour, stir to prevent burning. Can and seal. OUESTIOXS 1. What arf the harmless preservatives used in canning and prpcervine of fruits? 2. What substances are necessary in fruit juices to make fruit jcftr? KMake currant, gooseberry, grape or apple iellv using Ex - ion N'o. II. as well as Extraction Xo. I. Compare the two ts as to clearness, transparency, softness and flavor. 4. PresfT' 1 at least two different fruits in at least two different methods. What fruits and what methods did vou use? </seg>
            <seg id="p059">58 Lessons in Cooking Lesson IX. CANNING VEGETABLES IN THE HOME Review the principles of successful canning given in Lesson VI, "Preservation of Fruit." The decomposition of vegetables is due to the presence of bac - teria rather than yeasts and molds. Bacteria are almost universally distributed in the earth, air, water and food material, making it difficult to protect food from their action. If the conditions, such as warmth, food and moisture are favorable these bacteria grow very rapidly, but if the conditions are unfavorable they pass into resting or seed state called spores in which they neither feed nor grow. In the active state bacteria are easily killed. Moderate heat for an hour or boiling for twenty or thirty minutes will de - stroy them. In the resting or inactive state (seed form) such a temperature has little value in destroying them as they can resist a very high temperature. Difficulties in the Canning of Vegetables Vegetables may contain two kinds of bacteria, active and rest - ing. If they contain only active bacteria or bacteria that are un - able to produce spores fas with most fruit) then the boiling pro - cess is enough ; but if they contain some of these resisting bacteria spores or bacteria that produces spores, the brief boiling process is not enough to kill them and vegetables undergo decomposition. Green corn and peas contain a certain kind of bacteria which de - velop spores capable of resisting a very high heat, therefore, suc - cessful canning has been considered difficult in the home methods of canning. Methods of Canning Vegetables The method to be applied in the canning of vegetables is the use of greater heat. Any one of the following processes may be used: </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Lessons in Cooking 59 /. Heating for a short time at high temperature: Increase the heat by boiling in a closed vessel under pressure. This method is used by commercial canners but small size outfits for home use can be purchased and used to an advantage where large quantities of vegetables are raised on the farm. See Farm - ers' Bulletin 521 "Canning Tomatoes at Home and in the Club Work." //. Prolonged heating: Cook in an open kettle from four to eight hours and when tender fill jars and seal, or place the vegeta - bles in tin cans or glass jars and fill them with cold water ; cover loosely with the lids, and cook them either in the oven, in the steamer or in the fireless cooker. a. — In the Oven. Place jars in a hot oven on two or three thicknesses of asbestos sheeting, (which may be purchased for ten or twelve cents per pound) or place in a pan containing five inches of water. b. — In the Steamer. Steamers range from three to eight dollars, those with side openings are most convenient. A wash boiler or large bucket may be substituted for a steamer by making a false bottom of slats or a board with holes bored through to allow the water to circulate in order to protect the jars from breaking by heating unevenly and knocking together. Fill the bucket or boiler with water to the neck of the jars. c. — Heating in Fireless Cooker. The filled jars are placed in the fireless cooker kettle and surrounded with warm water, the filled kettle is then placed on the stove and the water boiled for fifteen minutes so that the contents of the can will be thoroughly heated. When heated thoroughly, place the kettle with jars into the cooker and cover. Allow to remain six hours. This takes more time but requires no attention. The disadvantage of method II is that the flavor is some - what destroyed by the long process and more time and fuel is required. K Intermittent Sterilisation or heating on three successive Vegetables are put in jars and filled to the top with water, in a steamer, wash-boiler or bucket prepared as in Method </seg>
            <seg id="p061">60 Lessons in Cooking I and boiled or steamed for one hour. Seal and allow to stand twenty-four hours. The boiling this first day kills the mold, 5t and bacteria, but the spores remain uninjured and develop full living plants. Repeat the heating for one hour on the &gt;nd day leaving the cans sealed (there is no danger of expan - i at this time). Repeat the process the third day. tote : — 1 T vinegar to 1 qt. vegetables or 1 t salt to 1 qt. vegeta - may be added when vegetables are first placed in the jars. The Use of Chemical Preservatives: There are many preserva - tives or canning powders sold under various names at the present time, which are represented as being harmless and also guaranteed to keep fruits and vegetables. If sound fruit and vegetables are used, and the methods of preparation have been according to les - sons in "Canning of Fruits" and "Canning of Vegetables", there is no need of the aid of any chemical preservative, and by not using them you may feel sure that there will be no harmful effect resulting from the use of such chemical compounds. Other Methods of Using Vegetables Green Tomato Sweet Pickles Epk. tomatoes, sliced large onions, sliced c salt 2 T white mustard seed 1 c stick cinnamon 2 T cloves 4 qt. vinegar 2 lbs. sugar 2 T ginger root (shaved) Cavenne if needed. 3 red pepper pods cut in strips Sprinkle alternate layers of tomatoes, peppers, and onions with salt and let stand over night. In the morning drain and boil IS minutes in 2 quarts of water and 1 quart of vinegar; then drain again. Cook together remaining vinegar, sugar and spices (which should be tied in a cheese cloth bag) 10 minutes. Add tomatoes and simmer gentlv one hour, stirring occasionally to prevent burn - ing Can according to directions. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Lessons in Cooking 61 Bordeaux Sauce 1 gallon cabbage gallon cider vinegar ounce celery seed ounce black pepper i Yi gallon green tomatoes J Yi dozen large onions J i ounce cloves, ginger and tur- J4 c salt (scant) i 6 ounces sugar meric % lb. white mustard seed Chop the first three ingredients, then boil all together 20 minutes Chili Sauce 18 ripe tomatoes sliced (do not 3 t salt peel) 2 t cinnamon 6 onions 1 t allspice 3 green peppers 1 t nutmeg 1 c sugar 1 t cloves 2y 2 c vinegar rk tomatoes until tender, add other ingredients, — Seal. Corn Salad 1 doz. ears corn 2 T mustard seed 1 large or 2 small cabbages 2 qts. vinegar 2 onions chopped 2 c sugar 2 peppers (large) chopped Salt to taste Cook 20 minutes, can and seal. Cold Catsup Eop fine 1 pk. ripe tomatoes, and drain well through a cheese - ; then add to pulp 6 good sized onions and 5 green peppers )ed fine, y 2 c salt and 54 lb. mustard seeds. Boil 1 qt. vinegar [ c sugar together 5 minutes, pour while hot over mixture. Pickled Beets Wash beets, boil in an open vessel until skins come off, peel, slice and pack firmly in jar. Fill jar with equal parts of water and vinegar sweetened to taste. Cover jar and boil in vessel following directions given for canning strawberries. Boil 10 minutes, seal and boil for one hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">62 t«l small white onions, cover with brine consisting of c salt c boiling water, let stand 2 days, drain, cover with fresh brine let stand 2 days longer. Boil onions in fresh brine, put in jars, ng bits of mace, bay leaf, cloves, peppercorns and red pepper, jars with boiling mixture consisting of }/* c sugar to 2 qts. of jar. Seal while hot. Sweet Pickled Cucumber or Watermelon 4 c sugar 1 T whole cloves 2 T cinnamon 2 c vinegar Pire and cut in strips the rind of ripe melons. Soak in alum r to cover, allowing 2 t alum to 1 qt. water. Heat gradually )iling and cook 10 min. Drain, rinse in ice water, drain again cook in vinegar, sugar and spices until tender. Put it in jars. QUESTIONS 1. What causes vegetables to spoil? 2. Why is the process of canning vegetables more difficult than that of canning fruit? 3. What vegetables are easy to preserve by canning? What more difficult? 4. What harmful preservatives are sometimes used in preserva - tion of fruits and vegetables? 5. According to Method No. Ill, can one pint of peas and one of sweet corn. 6. How have you used vinegar and spices as a preservative? </seg>
            <seg id="p064">63 Lesson X. MEAT AND ITS USE IN THE DAILY DIET Eeat is the flesh or muscle of animals used for food. It includes veal, mutton, lamb, pork, chicken, turkey, geese, duck, quail' idge, wild duck, grouse, deer, squirrel, rabbit, etc. Structure of Meat t Muscular tissue: Muscular tissue or lean meat is made up of lies or tubes. These bundles can be divided into smaller and ler bundles until finally the cells or tubes are reached. These are so small you cannot see them with the naked eye. In these ■shaped cells is the juice of the meat. 2. Connective tissue: This tissue is the white tough part that holds these fibres of muscular tissue together and forms the bundles. This tissue is very tough and the greater the amount of it in a piece of meat the tougher the meat. The white fibres of the connective tissue unite to form the cords or tendons which attach the muscles to the bones. I Fat: Fat is stored in quantities which can be easily seen, is also distributed in such small quantities between and inside different fibres and the bundles of fibres that it cannot be seen l the naked eye. No part is so lean that it contains no fat. Eote: Cut a piece of meat across the grain. Each of the lies of muscle fibres can be seen but each of these bundles is e up of a number of muscle tubes. Composition The material found in each of these muscle cells or tubes belongs to the protein class. The protein in meat is in the form of myosin, which is the dead muscular tissue, albumin, gelatine and fibrin found in the blood. Meat also contains fat, water, in large quanti - ties, mineral matter and extractives which contain the flavoring matter of the meat and cause the flavor of meat to differ in the different animals. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">64 The value of meat as food depends upon the presence of two classes of untrients, protein and fat. Both of these yield energy and give heat, but protein is the only class that can build and repair the tissues of the body. It is therefore necessary that it be taken in some form in our daily diet. Protein is also found in eggs, milk, beans, nuts, dried peas, and protein from these sources can be used in place of meat to give the necessary protein needed by the body. Animal foods alone would support life with the aid of water and oxygen of the air, but would be very extravagant as an exclusive diet, because animal foods are more expensive than vege - table foods, and because in order to obtain enough of certain ele - ments to give the required energy and heat necessary to keep up the daily waste and loss, one would take nearly four times as much protein as is needed. To get rid of the extra protein would over - tax the various organs of the body, especially the kidneys. One protein dish at a meal is quite sufficient. Classes of Meat There are two classes of meat, the tough cuts and the tender cuts. The toughness is due to the amount and kind of connective tissue, or may be due to the lack of the proper care after slaughtering. The older the animal and the more its various muscles have been used the tougher the connective tissue. Therefore, veal is more tender than beef. Porterhouse and sirloin steak, which is taken from the back of the beef where the muscles are not used, is much more tender than the round where the muscles are constantly used. Although these portions are more tender, they are not the most nutritious. Those portions which are constantly being used and are constantly demanding a new supply of food brought to them by the blood are more nutritious. The best cuts of meat whether tender or tough are those that have the fat evenly distributed throughout the lean portions. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">65 Fbnk I Shin 1 Chuck Ribs ( Sirloin \ Porterhouse Tender Cuts , Tenderloin Tough Cuts / Neck J Prime Ribs / Rump V Upper Round J Navel / Brisket \ Lower Round r Heart Other parts H iver i Tongue ' Suet Cookery of Meats The cooking of meat is one of the most complicated problems the housekeeper has to meet. It differs from the cooking of starchy or carbohydrate foods in that high heat and long cooking toughens the protein and makes it very indigestible. The objects to be at - tained in the cooking of meat are to develop flavor, to improve the appearance, to soften the connective tissue, making the meat more digestible, to kill any living organism and in accomplishing all these things not to toughen or harden the protein. This necessi - tates great thought and care. The methods used in cooking meats depend upon the toughness of the meat, the forms of protein and fat it contains, the amount and kind of connective tissue it contains, and the use that is to be made of the cooked product. Tender cuts: For tender meats such as steaks, chops and roasts, where the meat alone is to be used, the aim is to retain all the juices in the meat. The method is to expose the meat to a very high heat until the outside is well browned (this keeps in the juice) then reduce the temperature for the remainder of the time in order not to form a thick crust on the outside. Tough cuts: In tough cuts such as parts of the round, shoulder, chuck, flank, etc., where meat and broth are both to be used the aim is to retain a part of the juice in the meat and have part of it in the broth, and to soften the tougher fibres by long, slow cook - ing at a low temperature, as in braized meats and stews. The method is to brown the surface of the meat in hot fat or in a hot oven, pour over it the amount of boiling water necessary and cover </seg>
            <seg id="p067">66 closely. Reduce the temperature and cook until tender. ( Be sure your temperature is reduced below boiling point.) The long slow cooking will extract much of the flavor from the meat so a few highly flavored vegetables such as onions, carrots, celery, turnips, are added to improve the flavor. The result is a tender, juicy. palatable, nutritious meat and a rich gravy. I hen the tougher cuts are finely divided by chopping or mincing, or Hamburg Steaks, Beef Loaf, etc., the meat is made more stible by separating it into smaller particles. Tougher cuts be used for soups, broths, beef tea, etc., by extracting the :s. mineral matter and flavor. This is done by soaking the t, cut in small pieces, in cold water for an hour. Bring grad - r to simmering point (just below boiling) and keep at this t for five or six hours. In this case the meat itself will be er tasteless and lacking in nutriment. ii all left-over meats whose nutritive value is almost equal to h meat, the aim is to make an attractive and palatable dish, gain this result more care and thought must be given than in cooking of fresh meats. The method is to reheat and supple - it its flavor by adding sauce, vegetables and seasonings. Cost of Meats The constant use of tender cuts of meat is extravagant because their price is higher, their waste is often greater and their nutri - tive value less than most of the tougher cuts. In considering the relative cost, the amount of waste must be taken into consideration. Chuck ribs sell from 10 to 15 cents per lb., round from 15 to 20 cents per lb., and porterhouse and sirloin from 20 to 35 cents per lb. The waste material is about y 2 in the chuck ribs, about 1/12 in the round and l /% in the porterhouse. This makes the real cost of the edible portion of one pound of chuck about 25c, of round about Uy^c, and porterhouse about 31c. The round, since it has the least waste, is the cheapest meat. Economy comes in using the cheaper meats containing the least waste portions, in making use of the left overs and in using in the soup kettle all odds and ends of meat, and bone whether cooked or uncooked. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">67 RECIPES Tender Meat Cookery Pan— Rolled Beefsteak Irepare steak as for broiling. Use a cast-iron, not a sheet-iron and let it become almost red-hot, rub it with a piece of fat l meat to keep meat from sticking. Put the meat in the pan let it lie on one side till seared, then turn it, using spoons or e and fork to avoid piercing it, and continue turning occasion - until done. If necessary, to keep meat from burning reduce slightly and cook more slowly after meat is well seared. If collects in pan, pour it off. Time for cooking steak 1 inch {, 5 to 10 minutes; \y 2 inch thick, 7 to 15 minutes; whether or well clone. Serve with salt and pepper. Roast Beef Iipe meat with damp cloth, dredge it with flour; place on a in a dripping pan, skin side down. Cover bottom of pan lv with flour, place in hot oven that surface may be quickly :d, thus preventing escape of juices. When flour in pan is m reduce heat, add salt and pepper and baste every 10 min - with drippings from bottom of pan. After a time turn roast rown skin side. If meat is very lean put a few bits of fat in. If there is any danger of burning the fat in the pan, add a little hot water. Bake 12 to 15 minutes to the pound. The ler the piece of meat, the shorter the timejeer pound. Gravy : Remove some of fat from pan, leaving 3 T. Place on front of range, add 3 T of flour and stir until well browned. The flour dredged and browned in pan should give additional color to gravy. Add gradually l/ 2 c boiling water, cook 5 minutes, season with salt and pepper and strain. If flour should burn in pan, gravy will be full of black particles. Salt Pork. Country Style Eut pork in J / 2 in. slices, put in frying pan, cover with cold water, g slowly to boiling point ; boil 2 minutes then drain. Dip each e in flour and brown quickly in frying pan. Remove to hot </seg>
            <seg id="p069">68 platter. Add flour to fat in pan (3 T flour to 3 T of fat) stir until well mixed, add 2 c cold milk, cook until thickened, stirring con - stantly. Serve with baked potatoes. Breakfast Bacon ""Keep bacon in a cold place that it may be hard and firm before slicing. Shave off the smoked edges and the rind as far back on strip as required for one meal. Then with a very sharp knife shave off very thin slices. Put on a tin plate or shallow dripping pan and cook in oven until clear and crisp, but do not brown too much. Serve alone or with egg omelet, veal cutlets, liver or oysters. Tough Meat Cookery Braized Beef Elb. beef (lower part of round ]/ 2 c onions may be used) y 2 t salt c salt pork 3 t cloves c carrots 6 t pepper c turnips 1 bay leaf Mix pork and vegetables together, spread them on a baking pan, reserving ]/ 2 c for top of meat. On the vegetables place the meat dredged with flour. Place in a hot oven 20-25 minutes to brown, then add 2 c water with the other seasonings. Cover closely, re - duce the heat and cook slowly 4 or 5 hours. Success depends on slow cooking. When done, strain sauce from pan, season if nec - essary, thicken, pour a little over meat and serve the rest in a sauce - boat. Vegetables are served with the meat. A pot roast is much like braized beef except that the meat is first browned in an iron pot on top of the stove, then hot water added with some seasoning, the vegetables being omitted. It is then closely covered and cooked slowly several hours. Swiss Steak Eund flour into both sides of a piece of round steak. Season and brown in hot suet drippings. Add sufficient water to y cover, and simmer slowly for one hour or more. Add more </seg>
            <seg id="p070">69 water if necessary. When ready enough liquid to moisten the meat be used instead of water. to serve there should be just thoroughly. Tomato juice may Beef Loaf 2 lbs. lean beef 1 T onion juice rib. fresh pork, ham or saus - age 1/3 c cracker crumbs 1 T salt 1 egg well beaten y A T pepper flit meat through grinder, add seasonings, egg, and cracker nbs. Mix shape into loaf, place in a dripping pan and bake hour in a moderate oven, basting to prevent roll from becom - dry. Left Over Meat Cottage Pie 1. \ l / 2 c cold meat 4 T butter or drippings 1 y 2 c hot mashed potato 2 T flour Salt and pepper 1 pt. meat stock or water Cut meat in small pieces. If meat is tough simmer for a while. Season with salt and pepper. Cook butter and flour together until quite brown. Add gradually 1 pt. meat stock or water and simmer 5 minutes. Add meat. Pour into a deep buttered dish. Cover with seasoned, mashed potato and and brown in oven. tCold Roast Beef and left over gravy may be used, adding a drops of onion juice to meat. QUESTIONS I. Cut a piece of meat across the grain. Read again that part the lesson under Structure of meat. Name the parts you can in this piece of meat. K Scrape a small piece of raw, lean meat with a spoon until fibre is left. Observe the fibre. What part of the meat is it? 3. Cut a piece of raw meat into pieces, cover it with cold water. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">70 wash meat in cold water? 4. Cut a piece of raw beef into pieces. Pour boiling water over. What happens? Boil for ten minutes and examine the meat. What effect has high temperature had on the meat? Would this meat be very- digestible? 5. What rule would you give regarding the cooking of all meats? KWhat different kinds of meats have been used in your home month? What ones have you cooked and how did you pre - them? 7. Give the prices of the different cuts of meat in your own home markets? 8. Give one recipe you like to use for left-over meats. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">71 Lesson XI. MEAT SUBSTITUTES Ergs, cheese, nuts, dried peas and beans are all classed as pro - foods, their value in the body being the same as that of meat, is — to build and repair the tissues of the body. For the sake ariety in the diet, the cost, and the danger of eating too much :, these foods are used as meat substitutes. Egg* Itructure and Composition : The shell is of a porous nature and *titutes about one-twelfth of the entire weight. The white is ansparent jelly-like substance which lies within the shell, being :ccted from it by a membrane. It is almost pure albumen (a n of protein food) and water, with a small amount of min - mattcr. The yolk is held in place by two cords attached to the te. It contains fat, protein (vetellin) and mineral matter, bein^ led especially for its fat and mineral matter. The white con - s more water than the yolk. The water is so combined with other parts of the white that it is in liquid form. The yolk tains more fat in emulsion and mineral matter and less water, •efore, it is not in as liquid a form as the white. I'ood Value: Eggs contain the correct proportion of all food istances necessary to the body, with the exception of carbohy - te. Because of the amount of protein they contain they make excellent substitute for meat. To make a well balanced meal, ;s must be combined with carbohydrate foods in some form, ei - r prepared or served with carbohydrate vegetables, bread and it. Unless sold at less than twenty cents a dozen they would considered an expensive food as it takes nearly a dozen eggs furnish the same amount of nutriment as a pound of beefsteak. t as they are easily prepared, are a good source of iron and oth - mineral matter and are easily digested, they have a very im - tant place in the diet. Method of keeping eggs; The shell being a porous structure the </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Lessons in Cooking /--■ 72 water on the inside evaporates. Air with bacteria passes through the shell and takes the place of evaporated water, and bacteria cause changes to occur within the shell which result in spoiled eggs. In order to preserve eggs perfectly, the shell must be protected so as to exclude all bacteria. This may be done by packing them in salt, bran, oats, saw dust, or by coating with paraffin, vaseline, melted fat, or by immersing them in boiling water for one second. A still better method is to cover them with a preparation called water glass, which is one part sodium silicate and ten parts water. Water glass solution can be obtained at any drug store for 10c per lb. or 20c per qt. Use \y 2 qts. of this solution to 18 qts. of cold, boiled water (boil the water to kill all bacteria present). Eggs pack - ed in water glass will keep from 3 months to 8 months perfectly. Cooking of eggs: Aim is to improve the flavor, to make more palatable, to improve the appearance and to make them more quick - ly digested, although raw eggs are more easily digested. Method; Eggs are a protein food and all protein is hardened and becomes tough if cooked at a ■Wpi temperature, or cooked for a long time. As eggs coagulate (harden) under a moderate degree of heat they should always be cooked below boiling point. See recipes. Cheese Cheese is a very concentrated protein food containing about equal amounts of protein and fat. It has a very high food value and a small amount of it will contain a large amount of nourish - ment. As it contains protein and fat in such a compact form it is somewhat indigestible unless properly prepared. If cheese is used in the meal it should be used in the place of meat, or if it is used at the end of a meal should be taken in very small amounts, as you have already had enough protein in some other form of food. For an active man it is one of the cheapest and most nutritious foods as it contains more protein to the pound than meat. To make a well balanced meal, combine cheese with a carbohydrate food, such as macaroni, rice, white sauce, potatoes, and serve with an acid vegetable or fruit. Source: Cheese is made from whole milk, skimmed milk, or milk and cream. The milk is curdled and the liquid, called whey, drain- </seg>
            <seg id="p074">73 ed off. The curd or solid part is heated, pressed, colored and al - lowed to stand to ripen. In the process of ripening, certain harm - less bacteria are allowed to grow, that bring about changes which give the cheese its characteristic flavor and texture. The variety of flavor is due to the kind of bacteria or mold developed in the Kookiny: Because of its large amount of protein the same rule Id be used here that we used in the cooking of meat and eggs. ; temperature for a short time. Komposition : Xuts also rank fairly high in protein and especial - ligh in fat and cellulose. Some nuts such as chestnuts rank i in carbohydrate. talue as food: Nuts can be used in the place of meat as they ain some protein, but must be combined with carbohydrate Is in order to make a well balanced meal. They must also be ind before using to make them easily digested. Because of r large amount of fat and cellulose, and their lack of mineral &gt; in their natural state, they are hard to digest. In using them ther in a prepared form or raw it is best that they be eaten with e bulky foods, such as vegetables, breads, fruits. They should . part of the meal rather than eaten between meals. RECIPES Boiled Eggs Place eggs in a deep vessel. Fill the vessel with boiling water, cover closely to retain the heat, but 4o not place on the fire. Leave in the water 7 minutes. This gives a very palatable, soft cooked Poached Eggs Eill a shallow pan two-thirds full of boiling, salted water. Break h eggs into a saucer and carefully slip them into the water, water should cover the eggs. Place the pan where the water keep hot but not boil. Let stand until a white film is formed • the top of the eggs (about 7 minutes). Remove carefully </seg>
            <seg id="p075">9 74 with a buttered skimmer or buttered flat spoon. S«M«I but - ter, salt and pepper. Scrambled Eggs % t pepper }£ t salt 1 T milk to each egg 6 eggs 2 T butter Break eggs into a bowL Add salt, pepper and milk. Stir just enough to break the yolks. Heat omelet pan, put in butter, and when it is melted turn in the mixture. Cover until of a creamy consistency, stirring and scraping from the bottom of the pan. The mixture when done sin uld he flecked with white. Chopped meat. bacon, cheese, or peas may be added. Eggs and Ham Cream or milk 8 T chopped ham 8 T bread crumbs t picked 4 eggs from loaf of bread) Salt -and pepper Mix bread and meat' with just enough cream or milk to make a Hatter, season. One a' baking dish with this, break the eggs into the*VfisTi: Cover with the remaining batter. Bake in a pan of wa - ter in the oven until the eggs are set. Onions and Eggs [ok four large onions until tender in boiling, salted water. Cut quarters. Cut four hard boiled eggs into halves and put esjgs onions alternately in a baking dish. Make white sauce Xo. Pour sauce over the eggs, and onions. Sprinkle with 2 T of red crumbs and brown in the oven. Macaroni with Cheese Break macaroni into one-inch lengths. Boil in a large amount of boiling salted water i2 T salt to 2 qts. water). Boil slowly one hour, drain and rinse in cold water. Put into a buttered baking dish. Cover with white sauce No. Ill, to which has been added y? c grated cheese. Sprinkle buttered crumbs over the top and brown th </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Lessons in Cooking 75 tc scalded milk y 2 t mustard c soft stale bread crumbs ]/ 2 t salt lb. grated cheese cayenne pepper T butter 3 eggs Bix first six ingredients together, add yolks of eggs beaten until and lemon colored. Cut and fold in the whites beaten stiff. ■ into a buttered baking dish and bake 20 minutes in a moderate . Serve at once. English Monkey Yi c grated cheese 1 T butter 24 c stale bread crumbs y 2 t salt H c milk cayenne pepper 1 egg. slightly beaten rat milk, add crumbs and butter; when crumbs are well soft - add cheese. Stir until cheese is melted. Add seasoning and Pour over crisp crackers. Escalloped Cheese 2 c milk y A lb. cheese Eeggs 6 slices buttered toast t salt or crackers ftter a baking dish. Beat eggs, add salt, pepper and milk to . Dip bread in mixture and place in dish in layers. Sprinkle layer with chopped cheese. Pour remaining liquid over and until brown. Nut Loaf 2 c soft, stale bread crumbs Pepper 1 c crushed nut meats 1 egg, slightly beaten T i t sage Cold water % t salt Soak bread in small amount of cold water ten minutes. Put in cheese cloth and wring dry. Mix all ingredients. Shape into a loaf and bake one hour in a moderate oven, frequently basting with hot water in which a little butter has been melted. Serve with a </seg>
            <seg id="p077">76 QUESTIONS 1 . What foods can be used as substitutes for meats ? 2. Why are they called meat substitutes 3. What rule can you make as to the cooking of all protein foods? How does it differ from the cooking of vegetables and bread? t Prepare either boiled eggs, poached eggs or scrambled eggs. e your boiled or poached eggs soft and creamy, not tough hard? Were your scrambled eggs as soft as thick cream and ed with white? t Prepare at least two of the cheese dishes. Which did you e ? Was your cheese in every case soft, not tough and hard to If it was tough and string)- it was cooked at too high a tern - re. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">77 Lesson XII. SUGAR AND ITS USE Source of sugar: Sugar is found largely in the same places as starch ; namely, in roots, grasses, stems of plants, trunks of trees, leaves, fruits, milk, vegetables, etc. Starch is the form in which plants store their food for future use, while sugar is the form into which this starch must be changed before the plant can make use of it as food. This is what happens in the spring time when the trees begin to bud and leaf, when the seeds begin to sprout and grow. A green apple or green banana tastes starchy, a ripe apple or a ripe banana tastes sweet. The riper they become the sweeter their taste. The starch has by a chemical change become a form of sugar. tinds of sugar; Commercial or manufactured sugar is the r we buy on the market. The two kinds of manufactured r we are most familiar with are the cane sugar and the beet r. The cane sugar is manufactured from the sugar cane, the sugar from the sugar beet. Xon-Commercial sugar or sugars id in foods such as milk sugar found in milk called lactose; sugar found in grains called maltose; fruit sugar found in : called levulose. I'alue of sugar; In whatever form starch or sugar is taken into the body, it must be changed into a still simpler form called dextrose, before the body can make use of it as food ; just as the starch in the plant must be changed to a form of sugar before the plant can us eit as food. This change can be made in the body because there is a ferment in the saliva of the mouth, gastric juice of the stomach and intestinal juice for this purpose ; or this change can be made outside of the body by adding an acid to the sugar and boiling. Therefore, jams and butters are easily digested forms of sugar. If sugar is eaten in small amounts it will take the place of starch and will be more quickly made use of by the body because it is in a simpler form than starch and will not have to go through all the changes starch must go through to be made into that simplest form of sugar (dextrose). If the sugar is in excess of the amount needed for the daily use of the body it is changed to fat and is stored as fat. That is the reason that in some cases of fleshiness Doctors will omit sugar entirely from the diet. Effect of sugar: Sugar is a quick form of fuel food .because it mu«t go through fewer changes for body use than other foods; </seg>
            <seg id="p079">78 Lessons in Cooking therefore, can be used to an advantage in small amounts when one is very tired, to relieve fatigue when one is on long tramps or is doing hard labor. I mount of sugar; The average amount for people living in a aerate climate is J4 lb- daily, including the sugar used in cook - and taken in fruits and vegetables. Danger from the use of sugar; The chief danger from the use of sugar is that it so satisfies the body that it takes away the appe - tite for other foods. Therefore, it should be taken as flavoring in other foods such as fruits and vegetables, or in the form of candy. If used in the form of candy it should be taken at the end of meals as part of the dessert and not between meals. Iookery of sugar; To prevent waste in cooking, sugar should be added to the food, until the cooking is nearly completed, lecessary to cook sugar any length of time, or if the food con - s an acid, the amount of sugar must be increased ; thus to eten a glass of lemonade, one tablespoon is enough ; if used i lemon pie where heat and acid are combined, one-half cup squired. The same is true in the use of fruits. If eaten raw. sugar is required than if prepared in some form by using heat. RECIPES Puffed Rice Candy 4 cups puffed rice % t salt 1 c sugar l / 2 T vinegar •^4 c molasses 1/3 c cold water 2 T butter Kt rice in shallow pan and place in oven until srisp. Cook r. molasses, sugar, salt, water and vinegar until it will form a hall when dropped in cold water. Pour over rice. Mix thor- rly. then pour into buttered pan. Chocolate Fudge 2 c sugar 1 c milk or water 2 T butter 2 squares of unsweetened chocolate 1 t vanilla 1 c chopped nuts 2 T corn syrup Eiil together all ingredients except vanilla and nuts, until when ped in cold water it forms a soft ball that just keeps its shape, ove from fire ; add vanilla and nuts and beat until creamy then into a buttered pan, and when cool cut in squares. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">79 2 c granulated sugar l /^ c butter 1 c milk 1 t vanilla ]/i c candied fruits and nuts Combine sugar, milk and butter. Cook to a soft ball stage. Fin - ish as for chocolate fudge, adding fruits with nuts. Peanut Nougat Kc finely chopped peanuts 1 c granulated sugar t salt Put sugar in omelet pan (frying pan). Stir over a slow fire. It will lump then gradually melt. When all melted add peanuts; mix thoroughly. Butter knives and the under side of a pan. Turn candy on this and with the two knives shape into a square Yt inch thick. When partly cool cut in small squares or strips. Parisian Sweets 1 lb. figs 1 lb. dates 1 lb. English walnuts Powdered sugar Lemon juice iick over, wash and remove stems from figs and stones from ■s. Mix fruits and nuts and put through a meat chopper. Work 1 well blended, using the hands, then add lemon juice. Dredge rd with sugar, roll until 1/3 inch thick and cut in J4 inch ares, roll each piece in sugar. A good confectionery for Christ - ; dinner. Cranberry Sauce 2 c sugar 4 c cranberries 1 c water Pick over and wash cranberries. Put in a sauce pan, sprinkle sugar on top. add water, cover and heat very slowly. Do not stir. Roil slowly 10 minutes or until skins are tender. Remove from the fire skim and pour into a mold. Serve with chicken or turkey. Cranberry Frappe 1 qt. cranberries 2 c water 2 c sugar Juice of 2 lemons Kook cranberries and water 8 minutes ; then force through a i'. Add sugar and lemon juice, freeze to a mush, using equal s of ice and salt. Serve with cold turkey. Christmas Steamed Pudding 11 c raisins 2 T '. t soda y 2 c molasses 2 eggs 1 c warm water T i c nut meats or more 2 t cinnamon 2' &gt; c flour Add cinnamon and soda to raisins and flour : mix yolks of eggs </seg>
            <seg id="p081">80 Eies, and water together, and add chopped nuts and fold three or four hours. add to flour and other ingredi - in whites of eggs, beaten stiff. Sauce for Pudding 1 i c butter % t grated nutmeg 1/3 c of any fruit juice 1 c light brown sugar 2 egg yolks Kream butter; add sugar; place over boiling water; stir until er melts; add yolks, nutmeg and fruit juice. Stir until mix - thickens and serve at once. 1. Why do green fruits not taste sweet 2. Name the different kinds of sugars you use daily 3. Prepare 6 apples for the making of apple sauce. Cook three without sugar until just as you take them from the stove. Sweeten to taste, keeping account of the amount that was used. How much sugar did it take to sweeten the sauce? Use the same amount of sugar in the cooking of the other three apples and add the sugar at beginning of cooking. Compare the results. Is this sauce sweet enough? What conclusions would you make as to the time of adding sugar to fruits or other foods to reduce the amount of sugar needed? 4. What did you prepare for the Christmas dinner? QUESTIONS </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>