<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Annual Report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture for the Years 1920-21</title>
               <date value="1921">1921</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska State Board of Agriculture FOR THE YEARS 1920-21 PREPARED BY E. R. DANIELSON. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002">1W1 Jacob North ft Co Printers and Hinder* Lincoln. Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Office of Secretary Lincoln, Neb. His Excellency, S. R. McKelvie Governor of Nebraska, Sir: In compliance with Chapter One, Section Three, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913, I have the honor to submit this, the Annual Report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture for the years 1920 and 1921. Very respectfully, E. R. DANIELSON, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">ANNUAL REPORT of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture 1920 </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">7 PROCEEDINGS OF ANNUAL MEETING JANUARY 20. 1920 The Nebraska State Board of Agriculture convened at the Lindell Hotel, at 2 o'clock p. m., on Tuesday the 20th day of January, 1920, R. M. Wolcott of Central City, President, presiding. Notice of the annual meeting was read by Secretary Danielson. NOTICK OK ANNUAL. MEETING Lincoln, Neb., Dec. 17, 1919. The Annual meeting of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture will be held at the Lindell Hotel, Lincoln, on Tuesday, January 20, 1920, at two o'clock. At this meeting will be considered the revision of the premium list, rules and regulations, the election of officers. membership, and such other business as may legally come before said meeting. Presidents of regularly organized, live County Agricultural So- cieties, which have filed their reports prior to this meeting, are ex- offlcio members of the Board. If the President cannot attend, the So- ciety must elect a delegate, and file authenticated credentials. No proxies are admitted. The following Committees have been appointed by the President: Revision of Premium List, Rules and Regulations E. R. Purcell Broken Bow William James. Dorchester A. W. Lamb Albion Z. T. Leftwich St. Paul G. E. Hall Waterloo This Committee to report Monday, January 19, 1920, 9 A. M. Credentials and Returns Charles Graff , - Bancroft T. B. Keedle _ Minden Perry Reed _ Henderson This Committee to report Monday, January 19, 1920, 7 P. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 PRCK'KKDIXr.S NKBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGMICULTUBE Auditing T. H. Wake Seward W. B. Banning Union C. S. Hawk Chadron This Committee to report Monday, January 19, 1920, 9 A. M. Members Whose Terms Expire January, A 020 V. Arnold Richardson County R. M. Wolcott Joseph Roberts William James W. B. Banning. Jacob Sass E. R. Purcell T. B. Keedle Kearney County O. G. Smith Buffalo County G. E. Hall Douglas County C. W. Pugsley Lancaster Comity Perry Reed Hamilton County B. T. Moore Furnas County J. C. Cox : Keith County W. T. Parkinson Pawnee County Members Whose Terms Expire January, 1921 W. C. Caley Knox County J. A. Ollls Valley County J. P. McArdle _ Douglas County Charles Graff Cuming County George Jackson „ Nuckolls County E. R. Danielson Z. T. Leftwich C. G. Crews J. H. Harms Charles Strader T. H. Wake Seward County C. S. Hawk Dawes County A. W. Lamb Boone County C. H. Gustafson Saunders County Suggestions for improvement of Premium List, Rules or Regula- tions requested. Send to Secretary prior to meeting of Committee. R. M. WOLCOTT, President. J. F. McARDLE, Vice President. E. R. DANIELSON, Secretary. Roll-call by the secretary showed a quorum of members present. &gt;tt Merrick Count; rts Dodge Count; 168 Saline Count; Ing Cass Count; Sarpy Count; U Custer Count; son Polk Count; en Howard Count; Hitchcock Count; t Franklin Count; ider Lancaster Count; </seg>
            <seg id="p009">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA NTATE BOARD OF AGRK'll.TI RK 9 Communications were read by the Secretary from the following: G. E. Hall of Waterloo, B. P. Moore of Bayard, and J. C^Cox of Pax ton, all expressing regret at their inability to be present at this meeting. Secretary Danielson moved that the three members be excused, which motion was duly seconded and carried. The Credential Committee submitted the following report: Lincoln, Neb., Jan. 20, 1920 We, your Committee on Credentials and Returns, recommend seating the following delegates County Delegate Alternate Boone C. B. McCorkle Buffalo E. D. Gould Butler _ J. D. Hasik Chase Fred Hoffmeister Cheyenne H. G. Gould Clay J*. M. Buchtel Custer E. R. Purcell Dawes J. F. Lawrence Dodge H. S. Spath Dodge M. A. Uehling Douglas E. P. Noyes Fillmore Jacob Weis Franklin J. H. Harms Frontier X. H. Cheney Furnas T. E. Deaver Hall .H. J. McLaughlin Hamilton E. J. Eggert Hitchcock C. G. Crews Holt Arthur Ryan Howard. _ _ R. A. Calvin Jefferson John P. Thiessen Kearney William Johnson Madison .Henry Sunderman Morrill H. A. McComb Nemaha Thomas Reed Nuckolls C. H. Malsbury Pawnee W. T. Parkinson Pierce William Prahl Red Willow William Plourd Seward Shelby Ramsey Sherman H. J. Johansen Stanton Charles McLeod Thayer E. J. Mitchell Wayne V. L. Dayton </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Or AGRICULTURE The committee finds several county fair associations that have delegated another representative than the president of the said as - sociation, who is also a member of the State Board of Agriculture. Under the state law this is not permissible. We therefore recommend that the State Board member who is also the president of the county; fair in his district shall be the only delegate participating in this annual meeting, and that only in his absence can another be delegated to represent the said county. Respectfully submitted, CHARLES GRAFF, Chairman PERRY REED THOMAS KEEDLE Credential Committee. Mr. Cheney moved that the report of the Credential Committee be adopted and the Committee continued for its final report. Motion was seconded and carried. The President: Last year the following resolution was adopted by this Board in regard to attendance at the sessions: "Believing that the meetings of the State and County Fair officials Are highly beneficial and, in turn, educational, and that subjects under discussion at these meetings are very beneficial to the whole people of the state, if they are taken back to the people by the accredited del - egates to these meetings, and especially are they beneficial to our Coun - ty Fairs and the building up of agriculture through these Fairs, taking a broad viewpoint it is essential that all information to be obtained at these meetings should be in the hands of the various Fair Boards, given to them by their accredited delegates. "RESOLVED, That at future meetings of the State Board of Agri - culture and the State County Fair- organizations, a roll be made of the membership of said Board and all duly accredited delegates from the various agricultural societies, that said roll be called at each session of the State Board of Agriculture and State County Fair Association and that any members or delegates failing to answer the roll call and re - maining, unless excused by the President, shall not be entitled to the regular mileage and per diem for attendance at said meetings." I call your attention to this resolution at this time so that if you have any other matters to attend to while in Lincoln it can be done outside of the time occupied by the Board meetings, and the banquet at the Commercial Club which will take place tonight at 6 o'clock. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AOBICl'LTl'EE 11 PRESIDENTS ADDRESS Gentlemen of the State Board of Agriculture: Another mile-stone in the journey of progress for the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture has gone, and with the Victory State Fair, the greatest Fair in point of attendance, finance and exhibits that was ever held upon our grounds. But with all this, it is not a path of sun - shine for the State Board of Agriculture, when we meet with such losses as we had on December 17th — the loss of our large cattle barn. But with the aid of the public spirited citizens of Lincoln, we are go - ing to meet this loss and try to be ready for the coming State Fair. In view of the stress of business, the unusual unrest and relaxa - tion due to the war aftermath, we are more than gratified to meet with such success; but our efforts must not cease with self-congratula - tions, for our Fair can be made to accomplish much more — to be a larger and more complete organization if it will receive the support and material assistance it justly merits from future legislatures. This State Fair is but yet in its infancy, so to speak, for do we not see it develop and grow from year to year, each succeeding Fair being larger and better than the one preceding? To prove this, the year books show that the actual increase each year has been from ten to twelve thousand until this year when the attendance exceeded that of the previous year by 48,400 or a sum total of 262,447 for the week. Looking back over the annual reports of 1889 we find the total re - ceipts from all sources for the five years '85, 86, 87, 88 and 89 were but $204,789.24 which was less than the entire receipts for the past year, 1919. Is not that a cause for self-congratulation? With such progress an established fact, may we not justly ask ourselves what will be the outcome in the next ten or twenty years with our limited grounds, which are already too small for present needs? Equipped as we are with fairly commodious buildings, we are still in need of more buildings and larger buildings; we need more ground space as our present acreage is inadequate for our needs. And with this great need In mind I confidently hope to see our facilities eclipsed as the years bring added changes and improvements. Gentlemen, it is not my intention to take your time and attention in giving a tiresome resume of facts and statistics, but I trust I may be pardoned for here saying a few words of a personal nature. There are doubtless present a few men who are older than I in point of years, but I think I can safely say there are few — if any — who have attended the State Fair as many consecutive years, thirty-one to be exact. My first year of attendance was as an exhibitor in the fall of 1888 and I am proud of an unbroken record of attendance to the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE present. As a matter of interest, it may not be amiss to state that there are but few of the members of the "Old Guard" present, and none on the present Board. To the best of my knowledge, Eli A. Barnes of Hall County, R. B. Windham of Cass County, and S. H. Web - ster of Valley County are the only members who have not passed to the Great Beyond, and in another thirty years most of us will have followed our brother members gone before. At the time I mention, the State Fair was a mere infant, giving little promise of its present day growth and development. There were then a few small wooden buildings scattered over the grounds. and of these there remain today the old poultry building, the old agricultural hall and the Secretary's office. There were a few sheep and swine pens located where the machinery exhibit now stands. The horses and cattle were housed in temporary stalls along the outside fence from the 17th street entrance to the east side of the agricultural hall. All these have been replaced with modern and convenient buildings. Many are the changes since that day. In the last two years there have been more improvements than can be credited to the past ten years, namely, the building of the new swine barn, the terminal sta - tion and street car tracks, the women's comfort building, the sheep and the poultry buildings, and in addition there has been done much grading and parking of streets, the laying of cement curbing, gutters and sidewalks, and various other necessary work. Looking back over the thirty odd years, I can see a great contrast — the natural improvement which time, in its swift onward march, is bound to bring to a progressive organization like this. And thirty years hence our younger members will see a like development, a won - derful improvement over our methods of administration. Let the good work go on. Not one of us would wish to see the work stop here with these few attainments. There are yet needed a horse barn, more grandstand room, a new administration building, more dining halls and better sanitation. And this, gentlemen, is but a small part of our present day needs. We need room for expansion, our building space is limited, automobile parking space is inadequate, there is great need of room, and more room. Where can it be obtained? It could be made by filling the old creek bed as we have been gradually doing, but that is too great an expense to compass at one time. I would recommend the opening of an entrance at the southeast corner of the grounds in order to relieve the congestion of automo - biles at the 17th street entrance and, if possible, arrange an exhibit at the 16th street point, thus relieving congestion in that quarter. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE The time has come when for the second time I return to you the of - fice with which I have been honored, and as I surrender the chair to my successor, allow me to thank your Board of Managers and Secre - tary for their hearty support and co-operation. I know of no organi - zation that has worked together with such harmony and good will. I trust the pleasant associations heretofore existing among you may con - tinue, and that the best interests of this association may be conserved for future benefit. Whatever changes may be made in the control and administration of the State Fair, I feel I am but voicing the sentiment of each member in saying that our interest and support are unfailing and to it we give our heartiest and best wishes for its future success. The following nominations were made for members of the Board to fill places of those whose terms expired this year: First District — W. T. Parkinson, V. Arnold, C. W. Pugsley, W. B. Banning. Second District — G. E. Hall, Jacob Sass. Third District — Joseph Roberts, R. M. Wolcott. Fourth District — R. A. Burns, William James, Perry Reed. Fifth District— T. B. Keedle, W. H. Arnold, H. J. McLaughlin. Sixth District — E. R. Purcell, O. G. Smith, J. C. Cox. On motion of Mr. Keedle, duly seconded and carried, the nomi - nations were closed. It being announced by the Secretary that Mr. Parkinson had been appointed to fill an unexpired term the question arose as to who would be elected to fill the three year term and who to fill the one year term. Mr. Purcell moved that the party receiving the lowest vote be elected for the short term. The motion was seconded and carried. SECRETARY'S REPORT In placing before you my report for 1919, I desire to digress from the usual custom somewhat and impress upon you the wonderful re - sources and opportunities of the state which we are proud to call "home." It is sometimes a question whether or not those who are privileged to live within the boundaries of Nebraska appreciate their advantages and make the best use of the same. Our state is richly endowed with resources and conditions favoring agricultural, social and economic de - velopment and occupies such a position in civilization that it is not necessary to seek — through any specific channel — to further immigra - tion or to increase the population at the expense of the best interests of our commonwealth. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRIfVLTl BK Nebraska covers an area of 77,510 square miles, of which better than sixteen million acres are under dry farming and more than a quarter million acres under irrigation. Our state has an altitude of from 840 feet in the southeastern part to 5,240 feet in the northwest, and this fact of itself would indicate that there are many diversified fields of industry. Our surface features vary from smooth plains to mountainous areas and some mighty different types of soil are found within our borders. In going over the weather bureau records we find that the aver - age temperature of the state decreases from east to west and south to north. The mean temperature is 51 degrees in the southeast, 50 de - grees in the southwest, 48 degrees in the northeast and about 45 de - grees in the northwest. We also find that the highest temperature on record is 115 degrees recorded in 1918, and the lowest 47 degrees below zero in 1899. During the period from 1876 to 1919 the average temperature of the state was 48.6 degrees. January has generally been our coldest month, with December and February slightly warmer. July is the warmest month, although individual "hot" days may occur in either June, July, August or September, with August slightly be - low July and thereafter the decline in temperature is gradual. Our summer evenings are usually cool, compared with mid-day tempera - ture. Our growing season — free from frost — is approximately 160 days in the southeastern counties and about 130 days in the northwest. The shorter season in the northwest is accounted for by the fact that frosts sometimes occur throughout May and early June. Our humidity generally averages about 70 per cent and is usually highest in the mornings and lowest in the early afternoons. It is greater i-n the win - ter than in the summer and the western part of the state has a lower humidity than the eastern. The average rainfall between 1876 and the present time has been 23.64 inches, the eastern part of the state receiving more than the western. The state, as a whole, has a com - paratively large amount of sunshine; the cloudiness is greatest in the eastern and southeastern counties and comes from association with rain and snow. The average wind velocity, while not exactly known, is approximately nine miles an hour for the state. It averages higher in the western part than in the eastern, and the prevailing direction is from the north and northwest from October to Ma;, from the south and southeast in May, June and July and nearly straight from the south during August and September. Nebraska is comparatively free from destructive storms and com - pares favorably with other states in this respect. Hall storms are of record but the effect is generally over a small area. The climate of our state is regarded as more healthful than the average, and, taking </seg>
            <seg id="p015">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 15 the above conditions as a whole, we feel that Nebraska is a state of which all may well feel proud. Nebraska ranks higher in the mineral production than is generally supposed. We have more than 20 large sand producing centers along the Platte River from Kearney on the west to Louisville on the east, and from these sand pits are produced sand for engine use, plaster, and the coarser grades which are prepared by screens are used for con - crete and other purposes. With the extensive good roads program as outlined, calling for a large quantity of sand for surfacing and for use in concrete as well as a place to use the screened gravel from the sand, fortunately the state has adequate resources to meet this demand. There can be found a number of deposits of clay and silt, some suitable for the manufacture of brick and tile but unfortunately a great deal of our best clay is thickly covered with mantle rock, making its working comparatively expensive. Even under these conditions there are several brick plants in operation in Nebraska and it seems that the clay resources and the strong demand for clay products of! various grades would warrant the extension of brick making and tile manufacture. During the early history of the state a lime was made at several places but the manufacture of Portland cement was delayed until some few years ago, when a plant was established at Superior which was operated for a while, abandoned for a temporary period, then re-built and re-opened and is now producing some 750 barrels of Portland cement a day. This plant, we understand, is to be in - creased to a capacity of 2,500 barrels a day and in this "cement age" such a plant will be of untold value to the state. And just here per - mit me to suggest that the growing demand for permanent buildings justifies a much greater increase in this industry. One of the important factors in increasing agricultural produc - tion, not so much in Nebraska as in other portions of the United States, la potash. This is a new industry that had its inception during the war. It advanced in three or four years to a point where Nebraska was producing about sixty per cent of the potash output in the United States. A large amount of money was invested in the plants and pipe lines for the manufacture of this commodity but due to the fact that the price, to the manufacturer, was greatly decreased after the close of the war these plants are closed. It is to be regretted that this in - dustry cannot be given some protection to insure the sale of the home product rather than a foreign made article. A low tariff or a subsidy would assist the domestic industry in starting and would insure a per - manent potash industry for the nation. Nebraska is exceptionally well supplied with good well water, both in quality and quantity, which can be obtained in most parts of the state at a comparatively shallow depth. Some of our water power </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE has been developed but this is still in its infancy and I trust the time is not far distant when the state will avail itself of nature's endowment and improve the same. This will mean more mechanical power, with a conservation of the nation's supply of coal. Nebraska, as an agricultural and live stock state, needs no intro - duction to this body of men. When we pause for a moment to consider the vast possibilities contained in the rich rolling acres that cover the state, rich for the returns from the farm lands and the production of the highest and best types of live stock, we feel that enough cannot be said of our state's future. No greater heritage has been bestowed upon the state than the deep, fertile soil that covers it, and while there is enough variety to interest several kinds of industry, in no por - tion of the state do we find barren land that is of no value to the own - ers. We have passed the experimental state, in agriculture in Ne - braska, and know positively that success will attend the efforts of those who engage in this occupation. We have a progressive class of citizens who are proud of the fact that we are a step in advance of many other states, in the buildings and equipment found on our farm homes giving more than an average of efficiency per unit of labor; therefore the per capita production is very high. CORN Our principal grain crop, which is grown on about one-third of the cultivated area of the state, is "King Corn," with an acreage of 7,030,000 acres and a cash value of $230,452,000.00. The favorable climate and good soil make this state particularly adapted to such pro - duction. The cash value and acreage of corn is more than the total of wheat, oats, rye and barley. Only one corn crop — that of 1917 — had a greater value than that just harvested, and I doubt if it realized as much in cash as will the corn crop of 1919. Taking it as a whole, I do not think Nebraska has ever experienced a more prosperous year in its history, or a year which could be more adequately described than by the one word "VICTORY." WHEAT Next to corn, wheat is Nebraska's most important grain crop. The natural development of the western sections of the state and an increased demand in recent years have been an incentive to larger acreages, the last twenty years showing an increase of approximately a million and a half acres more being sown to this crop. As Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p017">PROCEED! NGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OK AI.KIl I I II KK 17 increases the number of her head of live stock, it becomes necessary to increase proportionately the number of acres of oats as this grain has a definite place in the development of bone and muscle in the young growing animal. The crying need of food during the period of the war has taught the American people that there is a growing demand for corn and wheat for human consumption, and as these products are being used more every day for this purpose we find that the acreages of barley and rye must be increased accordingly, to take their place. The soil, the climate and the farmers of Nebraska are all adapted to realize the necessity of this increased production along emergency lines of substi - tution, and have done their best to meet the demand that has arisen. If the price for corn and wheat as a human food continues to warrant such a procedure, no doubt we will continue to find many acres of our state given over to the production of these substitutes. The year 1919 was a more normal year than we have had the pleasure of experiencing for the past two years, yet the wet spring hung on so late that a great deal of red rust started in the wheat and this, combined with the weather turning from cool to excessive heat, caused a serious shortage in our wheat production. Yet we had close to an average crop of this commodity — the value of which is more than one-third that of the value of any previous year's crop. ALFAUFA The last ten years have witnessed the greatest development in the production of alfalfa. In 1908 there were devoted to this crop a half million acres while in 1919 we find this wonderful producing plant covering almost a million and a quarter acres. It is easily grown and the fact that it comes up year after year makes it a crop to be handled with the minimum of care. While playing a large part in balancing the grain rations of our live stock, its usefulness as a soil builder must be given due consideration. Another important source of income to the grower of alfalfa is the milling industry, which furnishes a channel through which the producer can dispose of his crop direct. SUGAR BEETS We were one of the pioneer states in the sugar beet industry, with some sixty thousand acres devoted to this crop in 1919. The climate and soil of the western counties are especially adapted for the pro - duction of the sugar beet containing the greatest per cent of sugar con - tent. An Interesting fact in connection with this industry is that the </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AOKICULTUBE second sugar beet factory to be established in the world was erected at Grand Island, followed by those at Norfolk, Ames, Scottsbluff. Gering and Bayard. POTATOES The importance of the potato crop in Nebraska cannot be over - estimated. The production is steadily increasing and I attribute this largely to the establishment of a potato growers' association, through which we may expect to see the best varieties and strains of seed po - tatoes grown and disseminated. HORTICULTURE Early in the history of Nebraska it was demonstrated that we could grow fruits of many kinds. Through the efforts of the State Board of Agriculture and the State Horticultural Society, as well as the growers' organizations, our fruit products can compete favorably with those of 'nearly any state in the Union. CATTLE In the raising, breeding, feeding and slaughtering of beef cattle, Nebraska is recognized as among the foremost. Much of the west central and western part of Nebraska is a native prairie which supports successful grazing. Nearly all of the ranches have well bred cattle, as pure bred sires have been used for many generations and most of the animals are now of good quality. A great many of the range cattle of the west are shipped to the eastern part of the state where they are either sold as feeders or finished for the market. We are becoming an important factor in the production of pure bred cattle, and this is due in no small way to the fact that our best breeders have not hesi - tated in founding their herds by obtaining the best animals possible even though it was necessary to import them. DAIRYING We have importance as a dairy state and, with the proper incen - tive from all sources, we will ultimately become one of the leading dairy states of the Union. This will be made possible by the fact that a balanced ration for the dairy cow can be produced as cheaply in Ne - braska as elsewhere. This will mean a greater production of human food, will build up the soil fertility faster than any other method and </seg>
            <seg id="p019">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 19 will mean larger yields per acre of our grain crops, thereby paying a better investment on our high priced land. SWINE Owing to the fact that corn and hogs are closely related, Nebraska now ranks as the second greatest swine producing state, in propor - tion to her population, being outclassed by the state of Iowa alone. Although the swine business is primarily a market venture, practically every community has its breeders of pure bred hogs. This industry might be called a universal activity throughout the state, and while both cattle and hogs conserve the fertility of the soil, the producer se - cures quicker returns on the swine. nHKKI" The production of sheep is steadily increasing. Climate and feeds here make it possible for Nebraska to be one of the finest sheep raising states to be found but there is a great deal of room for educa - tional propoganda along this line. We have not as yet realized how great this industry can be made, but as Nebraska becomes more thickly populated I predict the sheep industry will assume its rightful place among the foremost activities of our state. HORSES Horse raising in Nebraska is not a leading industry at the present time. While there are numerous breeders of pure bred stock and a large number of farmers who make a practice of raising a few horses as a side issue, the auto, truck and tractor have reduced considerably the demand for horses in most places. Yet few farms in the state have been able — by the substitution of motor power — to entirely dispense with the horse. While much of the plowing, harvesting and hauling Is done by motive power there remain a number of places where horses are more dependable, and for this reason it will be many, many years before the horse disappears from our farms. POULTRY The poultry population of Nebraska is about twelve million birds. There are approximately twenty thousand incubators and brooders in the state and it is estimated that 170,000 people raise chickens on the farm, ranch or in the backyards of our towns and cities. While much </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE of the poultry and eggs are consumed by the producers, still large quantities of these commodities go into commercial channels. Few people realize that the combined value of the eggs and poultry con - tribute some fifty millions of dollars to the wealth of our state eacb year, nor is this industry given the serious consideration it merits in comparison with other activities that mean much to the importance of Nebraska. MANUFACTORIES We all agree that Nebraska is one of the leading agricultural states of the&gt; Union, but how few of us ever realize that we have an - other branch of activity that means a well balanced state. The an - nual output of the state's manufacturing plants is something over half a billion dollars. There are some four thousand factories scattered within our borders, and to a great extent they utilize much of the raw material produced. It would be impossible to make mention of any number of these plants but much of our big wheat crop is turned into mill products right here in the state and then dispensed to other points. The packing plants have an output yearly of over 288,000,000 dollars, not to mention the farm implements and machinery. We do not main - tain that Nebraska is as yet equal to some of her sister states but we are only beginning. Our wealth of raw material and our transporta - tion facilities will combine to bring us greater advancement in manu - facturing as the years go by. I do not claim to have included in this brief survey all of the ad - vantages to be found in Nebraska. I have only touched lightly on some of the high points and I have done so to bring before you the fact that we are admirably situated, from all angles, to put on one of the best if not the very best state fair in the United States and Canada. And right here I maintain that Nebraska's 1919 "Victory" State Fair was the greatest ever held and compared more than favorably with that of any other section, taking into consideration the superior ad - vantages some of them enjoy in the way of better grounds or greater territory from which to draw the crowds. However, we entered a new class in which only the better fairs attempt to compete — that of the quarter million crowd. Our week's attendance was something over 50,000 better than any previous fair, with a record crowd of 71,000 «n Wednesday. It is with a feeling of pardonable pride that I can report to you the improvements that were made last year. The legislatures of Ne - braska are beginning to realize the importance of the state fair and are gradually becoming educated to the necessity of making adequate appropriations toward permanent improvements on the grounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRK'II.TIRK 21 We were privileged to receive the sum of $25,000.00 for the woman's and children's building; $15,000.00 for a sheep barn; $12,000.00 for a poultry building; $5,000.00 for cement walks and curbs and $2,500.00 for general improvements. To the above ap - propriations — due to the increased cost of labor and materials — we were compelled to add some $15,000.00 in order that we might com - plete the three new buildings in time for the "Victory" Fair. In ad - dition to this amount we spent some $16,000.00 on the grounds, mak - ing a total expenditure from state fair receipts of over $31,000.00 for these permanent improvements in 1919, and when our gates were thrown open the first day, we felt well pleased with what had been ac - complished. Our new street — Ollis Avenue — was curbed and guttered, a park - ing space laid out in the center, and a heavy bed of cinders placed in the driveways and finished with a top dressing of good gravel. Since the last fair these parking spaces have been filled with trees and shrubs, with the idea of giving to the fair visitor a favorable impres - sion as he enters the grounds. It is the purpose of the Board to make Morton Avenue from the street car entrance east up the hill a dupli - cate of the plans laid out for Ollis Avenue. The first building as you enter the grounds and turn to your right is the new sheep pavilion. The sheep breeders showed their ap - preciation of this building by bringing in a much better exhibit than at any previous fair. Like all other buildings of recent construction on the fair grounds, this is of stucco and built along broad, low lines. ■ It has been said by those who have examined it to be one of the best in the country. It is similar to the new swine barn of a year ago and has 110 steel pens. It offers those interested a good opportunity to look over the animals and I believe that the sheep breeders of the country appreciated the building, as our show this year was muoh superior to that of any previous time. If this building proves as great an incentive to better exhibits as the swine barn, we will feel our ef - forts were well spent. J From the new sheep barn we can step next into the poultry house. This is also of stucco and provides a fine home for one of our leading smaller industries. With the establishment of uniform coops and the new home provided, our chicken show was as well housed as any de - partment on the grounds. I have reserved the best for the last and feel I can truthfully state our new woman's and children's building was one of the most popular on the grounds. It was designed with forethought for the needs of the tired mothers and children who visit the fair. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE The east half of the upstairs was fitted up as a rest room for the ladies and it needed only a look at the rooms to see how they appealed to the tired pleasure seekers. On the ground floor one wing was devoted to a nursery with at - tendants in charge. It certainly was wonderful to step into this room and see the wheeled cribs with their weary little occupants resting so comfortably, the assistants watching over them. Another new in - novation was a supply of clean milk and sterilized bottles at the dis - posal of those who wished to take advantage of them. On all sides were found big, clean, comfortable porches with plenty of chairs and the proof of their popularity was shown by the fact that they were oc - cupied from early morning to late at night. The management of the Nebraska State Fair has educated their patrons to expect big things. We are more than willing to continue to furnish big attractions, and we know that "Yankee" ingenuity will continue to furnish us with something new to place before the Ne - braska Fair, for the best is none too good for our visitors. • We have gone a step ahead of any other fair — to the best of my knowledge — in the line of amusements we offer to our patrons. No other fair has had the temerity to hire outright a three ring circus as a free attraction, but we found that this pays. After having secured the automobile races, the big three ring circus, the horse race program and the fireworks spectacle for each night, your management decided that they had well balanced attrac - tions. But the last needed touch to complete one of the greatest amusement programs ever assembled was Lieutenant Ornier Locklear, who each day treated the fair visitors to a genuine "thriller." Lock - lear and his pilots, Lieutenants Short and Elliott, are in a class by themselves and gave a wonderful exhibition that was of educational value to the people as well as amusing, and demonstrated what has been accomplished with these heavier than air machines while this art is in its infancy. I will make brief mention of the several departments of our Fair, beginning with the first class — Horses. We must admit that the horse show was not large. One possible reason is that our horse barns are not of the best and some breeders feel when they go to the expense and trouble of bringing their animals before the public they should have proper facilities for exhibiting. For the future welfare of an agricultural state like Nebraska, the encouragement of draft horse breeding is not only desirable but essential and I trust that we will soon be able to make such improvements in our quarters on the grounds that we will draw to our fair one of the biggest and best ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICII.TI RK hibits of horses to be found in the country. Our exhibit of Shetland ponies was especially good. Our cattle show is always good and was especially so this year. The splendid show of beef breeds was one of the features of the Fair and while some classes were not as large as others the exhibit was equally good from the standpoint of quality. One of the growing phases of the cattle department is the dairy exhibit and Nebraska breeders should begin to realize the vast importance this industry can assume, with our natural facilities for such growth. We must report that on the morning of Dec. 17 th there was the first disastrous fire on the fair grounds, resulting in the total destruction of our cattle barn. But we are glad to be able to also state that we expect this barn to be replaced before the 1920 fair with a reinforced concrete and steel building. This will occupy the same ground space as the one destroyed. We have long felt the need of adequate quarters and facilities for placing before our patrons a real exhibit of dairy cattle and owning to the con - gested condition of the grounds, we have conceived the idea of placing an additional story on the barn with a reinforced concrete floor, the upstairs to be entirely devoted to dairy cattle equipped with stanchions, feed troughs, gutters, calf pens and litter carriers. With this arrange - ment we hope to present to the man who is contemplating the found - ing of a dairy herd the model and sanitary way of equipping his barn for such an industry. The lower floor, which has heretofore had to accommodate both the beef and dairy exhibit, will now be devoted entirely to the beef breeds and in this arrangement we find that on the same ground space we can practically double the capacity of this barn. The first question that will arise in your minds is the source of the funds for this building. It gives me great pleasure to state that the citizens of Lincoln, through the organization known as the Lincoln Commercial Club, immediately saw the necessity of replacing this building. Knowing we did not have these funds at our command and realizing the importance of the cattle exhibit at our state fair, they have agreed to advance this money until the next legislature con - venes at which time we trust that body will appropriate funds to re - imburse those who aided us in this emergency. When we asked for an appropriation of $80,000.00 to erect a new swine barn, we heard what we considered many idle remarks that it would never be filled. You are all more or less familiar with condi - tions confronting the past two swine shows in this new building, and we have already found our new quarters inadequate to take care of this fast developing industry. I predict that the same will hold true with our new cattle barn, as it has been demonstrated that when </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE suitable and adequate quarters are furnished, our exhibits will be in proportion. A deep realization of the vast possibilities in this state should awaken our citizens in the very near future to the fact that we need immediate and continuous financial assistance, in the future de - velopment and expansion of the grounds and buildings. The day of the old, wooden, dangerous structures is past — they have served their purpose and have no place on any public grounds where over 71,000 people congregate in a single day. In 1918 our exhibitors and patrons were introduced to the new swine pavilion, a reinforced concrete and steel constructed building conceded to be the largest and best in the United States. Our exhibit in this department has passed our fondest expectations both years, and we were compelled to erect a hundred and twenty temporary pens under canvas last fall. The quality of the animals here shown bear out the assurance that Nebraska produces hogs that are not only qualified to win at our own state fair but have upheld her reputation in other state fair swine shows as well, and can carry off creditable honors at the national swine show. A new proposition that is confronting us is the matter of furnish - ing adequate exhibit space for the members of the boys and girls pig clubs of Nebraska, who desire to show their animals at our state fair. The first show of this kind was held last fall, quartered in the two old swine barns north of the new building. One member of the club per - sonally prepared and exhibited one litter of pigs for which he later re - ceived the sum of $5,000.00, This is the clearest illustration that the work of these boys and girls is not to be passed by lightly. In contrast to the quarters we have heretofore had to offer to the sheep breeders, the new barn was a revelation. It was and will con - tinue to be an incentive toward more sheep and better exhibits in Ne - braska. It is needless to say that the sheep exhibit of last year was the best ever held, as was evidenced by the throngs of visitors who filled this barn from early morning until late at night. The exhibit was made still more attractive and educational by a fine display of the different kinds and grades of wool, as furnished by the agricultural college. Here many received their first real impres - sion of this Industry. The new poultry building — like the others — may not prove large enough to hold the exhibit if it continues to grow as it has in the past. This building was designed to hold not only the poultry but the rabbit exhibit, which is assuming rather large proportions in the calcula - tions of Nebraskans. We had the same full to overflowing and had to remove the rabbits to another building, to make room for the birds. The quality of the show was as good as the quantity and we are glad </seg>
            <seg id="p025">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 25 to know that the importance of the poultry industry i-n Nebraska is being recognized and demonstrated more every year. Agricultural Hall presented a beautiful appearance and is always one of the most attractive buildings on the grounds, being thronged constantly with visitors. There were very fine displays from a num - ber of counties, being especially complete this year. In some instances the county agents were present to explain the work of their particular county. The horticultural display was large and beautiful, and always adds much to the appearance of the building as well as being evidence of the ability of Nebraska to compete with other states in the raising of fruits and flowers. / The agricultural extension service of the University of Nebraska occupied their customary place in the northeast corner of the balcony of agricultural hall. They had a much larger exhibit than heretofore, which consisted of an information booth, rest room, a mod«l farm bureau office, home demonstration agents, help of the farm family, model farm kitchen, public health, hot school lunch, a room showing the arrangement of clothing most convenient to the housewife, one de - voted entirely to sewing and new innovations showing the equipment whereby the farmers could study the methods of testing and grading grain. In one corner of this room were found exhibits of the common barberry and the Japanese barberry, with signs instructing farmers to destroy all the common barberry bushes for the reason that they har - bor the black stem wheat rust during one of its stages. The Japanese barberry is not a host plant for this rust. There were also maps show - ing where the barberry had been found in the state and a chart ex - plaining how to eradicate this shrub. In the southwest corner of the balcony was to be found the ex - hibit of the boys and girls canning teams, in conjunction with the demonstration work. More than twice as many exhibits of club products were to be seen than were ever shown before. There were thirty-two individual teams in the contest, among them being ten bread making teams, nine canning teams, three poultry teams, three pig raising teams, one rabbit and one sewing team. Competition for prizes called for a demonstration of the work in hand, together with an explanation of exactly how the same was to be accomplished. The securing of an education is made much more in - teresting to the boys and girls of today through club work, and the Nebraska State Fair should lend every encouragement to these citi - zens of tomorrow. Class H, Domestic Products, is one of the departments of th« fair particularly interesting to the ladies. This year we had a large and </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE attractive exhibit of baked goods and preserves. A great many of the exhibitors are Lincoln people, but there is always a good display by out of town patrons. Class I, Bees and Honey, while not a very large department, is constantly growing. Many people do not realize the importance of this industry and do not appreciate that it is a good investment of time and money and will yield rich returns. Class J, the Woman's Department, is always a big busy place and is the mecca for all the women who visit the fair. There are always new articles to be exhibited showing what the deft fingers of the ladies can accomplish and I might add that the men often drop in to look the department over and show considerable interest in the fine display of work. Class K, Fine Arts, made a creditable showing so far as the ex - hibits went, but I am frank to say that I feel there is much room for improvement. I trust those having in charge this department will en - deavor to bring out the productions by the best talent not only in the city but also in the state. Too much cannot be said of the educational department at the State Fair. The boys and girls who bring or send their work to the fair of today are the men and women of tomorrow who will prove the most efficient exhibitors. The rural school exhibits were extremely good and demonstrated the good work that can be accomplished by the children. There were several schools which displayed tables, book-cases, chairs and other forms of carpenter and forge work in addition to the regular school work exhibits. Our display this year was the largest and best ever brought together. In Class O, our Better Babies' department, there was a change made this year which we hope to see continued. This is without doubt one of the finest departments of the fair and no fairer or better speci - mens of humanity could be found than in Nebraska's Better Baby show. It was held in the new woman's comfort building, where we have a balcony arranged for the spectators, overlooking the big glass covered room in which the examinations are made. In former years we have awarded Beveral prizes in each class but this has been omitted and we give a silver trophy to the champion boy and the champion girl. The "improvement class" admits children who were entered last year and their score at that time is compared with the newer examination and their final score based on the result. This is an incentive for the mothers to attempt to bring their children up to a better physical and </seg>
            <seg id="p027">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OP AGRICULTURE 27 mental standard. Two cash prizes of $10.00 each are given to the two making the greatest improvement during the year. The seventh annual Boys' Camp proved as popular as ever, with nearly 150 boys in attendance. The Camp is run in a semi-military fashion, beginning with setting up exercises and a flag raising. After breakfast comes the tent inspection and from eight to eleven o'clock in the morning there are classes held in various educational branches. Dinner time comes at eleven o'clock and at eleven-thirty a certain re - quired number of the boys report for duty as ushers in the grand - stand while the remainder are taken on excursions to the various de - partments of the fair and to other points of interest in the capital city. This Camp is becoming a permanent fixture and the grounds and equipment are being improved each year. After the boys are through serving as ushers in the evening, a camp fire is held where singing and speaking are indulged in before the boys retire to rest after a strenu - ous day, to have visions of what the following day will bring forth. It is in this Camp that lessons in co-operation are taught, which all boys need at this time of life if they would have future success. We can point with pride to the machinery exhibit at our 1919 Victory Fair. This was the largest on record, with the greatest variety of machinery ever assembled in the state. It took about 30 acres of ground to hold the exhibit and if there were any labor saving devices or farm equipment omitted, we fail to know what it was. Electric lighting plants for farm use, with all the attachments, such as power, washing machines, electric irons, churns and vacuum cleaners were more numerous than ever before, and many farm women took ad - vantage of their opportunity to impress upon their husbands the need for some of these modern labor savers inside as well as out. Our immediate need for more space has been brought forcibly and vividly to our attention by the fact that the heavier classes of ma - chinery, viz., the trucks, tractors and threshing machines practically occupied as much space across the street east from the automobile hall as our entire machinery exhibit consumed some ten or twelve years ago. The automobile men also came to the front with a fine exhibit, en - tirely filling our big auto hall. The only drawback to their enjoy - ment was that they were not all able to get all the machines they wanted for exhibition, due to the fact that the manufacturers are a little late in getting out orders. The manufacturers' exhibit was again very pleasing but, like the horse show, we cannot expect the best along this line until a suitable building is provided for the exhibition of manufactured products. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 PBOCEEDINOS NEBRASKA STATIC BOARD Or AGRICULTIRE We have bad considerable complaint in the past regarding the way our feed department and electrical connections were handled. It was decided by the Board that they would supervise these two propo - sitions this year, to ascertain if service and charges could be bettered. It is with a great deal of satisfaction that I am able to report that both of these departments were handled with much greater satisfac - tion to the exhibitors than in the past, in proportion to the increased prices. Only the best feed products were purchased and the cost of sam«, plus handling, was the price to the consumer. Our electrical department will show about an even break, and the many assurances of satisfaction from our patrons in both departments should induce us to continue the control of them. In looking back over the year 1919, there is little to criticise and much to commend, due no doubt to the fact that Nebraska entered a new state fair era. The 1919 attendance was only 50,000 short of equalling the combined attendance of 1914 and 1915. It behooves us to continue the spirit of co-operation that has been of assistance in bringing us such great success, and to lay well our plans for immediate relief in many directions. I have, in the capacity of your secretary, labored hard during the past three years to bring about a closer relation between the city of Lincoln and the state fair and am very much pleased to say that re - sults along this line are being obtained. This is as it should be, for so long as your state fair continues in this city, Lincoln, in the capacity of host, should bend every energy to meet us half way. The ac - complishment of this means the blue sky is the only limit and the state fair of Nebraska will continue to expand when given the proper incentive, from all sources. There is under consideration at this time one and possibly two additional paved streets to the fair grounds, one by the county and city combined and one by the city alone. When these materialize, it will mean an added improvement on our grounds in the way of streets to connect with these new entrances. For the first time, we have realized the inadequacy of our water system to combat such a con - flagration as occurred last month. The city fire department has ever been ready to answer our calls and minister to our needs but when they are handicapped by having to place three streams of fire hose from a four inch water main you can well realize how powerless they are. New and larger water mains are a necessity, and this should be among the first improvements on the grounds. Plans are now under consideration for the enlarging of our sewerage system and while we have erected toilet facilities as fast as </seg>
            <seg id="p029">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Or AGRICI I.Tl RE 29 our funds would permit the existing condition must be remedied be- fore we open our gates for the 1920 fair. I have just mentioned a few of the most important improvements that need immediate attention, and feel that the men who have com- posed your Board of Managers in the past as well as those who will make up your Board in the future are intimately acquainted with the needs and necessities so a further detail of these conditions is not necessary at that this time. During the recent past, but more especially in 1919, the fairs of this country have been riding upon a high tide of prosperity and many conditions indicate that still further immediate advancement will be made. Let us hope that those charged with the management of these institutions may be alert to seize the opportunities so con- stantly offered to broaden the scope of their activities. Then may the historian of the future truthfully say the great agricultural fair has been a powerful force in the education of our people in a stronger Americanism, and in the art of that mode of living which promotes peace, contentment, and a realization of the blessings de- rived from a residence in a country which grants to its citizens the fullest measure of personal liberty ever enjoyed by the people of any nation in the history of the world. Receipt* Advertising _ % 165.00 Boys' Camp _ 685.00 Cattle Stalls 711.75 Concessions _ _ 37,200.02 Exhibitor's Tickets 790.10 Feed Department 4,996.59 Horse Stalls 253.00 Interest 448.50 Machinery Grounds 115.00 Machinery Hall 3,175.00 Miscellaneous 31,775.71 Miscellaneous Rentals 652.53 Percheron Futurity 49.00 Sheep Pens 109.00 Speed 2,406.00 State Appropriation 2,000.00 Swine Pens 1,170.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Ticket Account Bleac her s $14,296.00 Exhibitor's Tickets 1,780.00 General Admissions 30,515.50 Grandstand 14,266.85 Grandstand, Standing 4,056.50 Grandstand, Night 7,285.00 Sunday and Evening 3,098.75 Turnstiles 42,367.00 Turnstiles, Over 698.95 Vehicle Permits 435.00 118,799.55 $205,501.85 Expenditures Advertising Bill Posting $ 494.70 7,506.03 Fireworks 3,500.00 25,275.04 Board Expenses Board 570.38 Delegates 781.00 Expense Annual Meeting „__ 1,137.63 Hotel _ 579.80 Miscellaneous 141.42 Officers' Salaries 2,550.00 Railroad Fare 715.82 6,476.05 Bulletins 221.22 City Papers, Lincoln Farm Papers 281.04 250.15 M iscellaneous 626.50 "Nebraska" 831.40 Other Dailies 690.84 Plates and Cuts 1,011.53 Posters and Lithographing 988.30 Speed Weekly Newspapers 116.85 1,993.50 ttrnctions Aeroplane 4,000.00 Automobile Races Bands 4,053.40 5,221.64 Circus 8,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 31 Boys' Camp 2,505.66 Certificates of Deposit 35,080.00 Electricity, Express. Freight and Drayage Electricity 617.51 Express 19.34 Freight and Drayage 448.52 1,085.37 Fair and Office Supplies 3.261.82 Feed 4,961.99 Guards 3,068.90 Insurance and Bonds 478.16 Maintenance of Grounds Caretaker 890.33 Electrical Supplies 2.210.86 Garbage Contract 112.50 Labor 12,679.42 Maintenance 7,357.47 Material for Repairs 486.20 23,736.78 Miscel laneous 3,751.81 Permanent Improvements _ 32,014.42 Postage 346.50 Premiums Class "A", Horses 1,423.50 Class "B", Cattle 6,246.50 Class "C". Swine 4,645.00 Class "D", Sheep 1,422.00 Class "E", Poultry 1,370.50 Class "F", Farm Products 5,132.23 Class "G", Dairy Products 98.00 Class "H", Domestic Proaucts 415.75 Class "I", Bees and Honey 344. 0&lt; Class "J", Woman's Department 588.50 Class "K", Fine Arts 465.65 Class "L", Educational 718.76 Class "O", Better Babies 20.00 Horticultural Society 1,197.75 Pig Club 155.00 Re-issues , 115.25 24,358.39 Printing 668.37 Salaries Secretary 3,000.00 Employees 2,800.15 5,800.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Or AGRICULTURE Speed 10,676.01 Subscriptions 500.00 Superintendent* Clerks 1,040.34 Concession Pay Roll 1,298.89 Helpers 465.93 Judges 1,161.61 Physicians, Class O 402.72 Superintendents 2,484.89 Assistant Superintendents 735.76 7,590.14 Ticket Sellers and Taken Treasurer's Pay Roll 1,393.73 Supt. of Gates Pay Roll 961.33 2,355.06 Telephone and Telegraph Telephone 414.62 Telegraph 70.34 484.96 Water 768.90 Total $202,670.51 Mr. O. G. Smith moved that the secretary's report be accepted and made a matter of record. The motion was seconded and carried. TREASURER'S REPORT Mr. President and members of the State Board of Agriculture, your Treasurer begs leave to submit the following report: Receipts Advertising $ 165.00 Auto Hall 3,175.00 Boys' Camp 685.00 Cattle Stalls 711.75 Concessions 37,200.02 Peed Department 4,996.59 Horse Stalls 253.00 Interest 448.50 Machinery Grounds 115.00 Miscellaneous 31,775.71 Percheron Futurity 49.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 33 Rent 652.53 Sheep Pens 109.00 Speed 2,406.00 State Appropriation 2,000.00 Swine Pens 1,170.10 Ticket Account Bl eac h ers $14,296.00 Exhibitor's Tickets 2.570.10 General Admissions 30,515.50 Grandstand 25,608.35 Sunday and Evening 3,098.75 Turnstiles 42,367.00 Turnstiles, Over 698.95 Vehicle Permits 435.00 119,589.65 Total $205,501.85 Balance on hand Jan. 1919 $ 1,132.84 Receipts for 1919 Fair 205,501.85 Total $ 206,634.69 By expenditures, 1919 1918 warrants 240.47 1919 warrants 202,388.17 Exchange 1.48 202,630.12 Balance $ 4,004.57 Of this amount $282.34 is unpaid warrants, which leaves the bal- ance on hand $3,722.23. We also have $35,000.00 in Nebraska banks, certificates of deposit, and we have $2,950.00 in Liberty Bonds. The total amount on hand is as follows: Balance in bank $ 4,004.57 Certificates of deposit 35,000.00 Liberty Bonds 2,950.00 Total «. $41,954.57 Respectfully submitted JACOB SASS, Treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE On motion duly seconded and carried the Treasurer's report was adopted and made a part of the records. TO THE HONORABLE PRESIDENT AND THE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE: Gentlemen: We, your Auditing Committee, respectfully submit the following report. We find the receipts and expenditures in the various funds for the year 1919 to be as follows: Receipts, 1919. Advertising $ 165.00 Boys' Camp 685.00 Cattle Stalls 711.75 Concessions 37,200.02 Feed Department 4,996.59 Horse Stalls 253.00 Interest 448.50 Machinery Grounds 115.00 Machinery Hall 3,175.00 Miscellaneous 31.775.71 Percheron Futurity 49.00 Rent 652.53 Sheep Pens . 109.00 Speed 2,406.00 State Appropriation 2,000.00 Swine Pens '. 1,170.10 Ticket Account Bleachers $ 14,296.00 Exhibitor's Tickets 2,570.10 General Admissions 30,515.50 Grandstand 25,608.35 Sunday and Evening 3,098.75 Turnstiles 42,367.00 Turnstiles, Over 698.95 Vehicle Permits 435.00 119,589.65 Total $205,501.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">PROCEEDINGS NEBBA8KA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTUBE 35 Expenditures Balance on hand Jan. 1919 $ 1,132.84 Receipts for 1919 Fair 205,501.85 Total . 206,634.69 By expenditures, 1919 1918 warrants $ 240.47 1919 warrants 202,388.17 Exchange 1.47 202,630.12 Balance $ 4,004.57 Of this amount $282.34 is unpaid warrants, and we would recom - mend that when these are presented for payment, they be cancelled and re-issued. Included in the expenditures we find $35,000.00 issued for certifi - cates of deposit, placed in Nebraska banks. We also find we have $2,950.00 in Liberty Bonds. We have checked all the above amounts with the receipts from the Treasurer, and find that the totals correspond. We have also checked the concession books and find the receipts as follows: This agrees with the records of the Secretary and the receipts issued by the Treasurer. All of which is respectfully submitted T. H. WAKE, C. S. HAWK W. B. BANNING, Auditing Committee. Total contracts _! .$29,320.58 Circus . 1,639.72 Carnival . 4,427.21 Swing Check stand 100.92 324.70 Electric Lights . . 1,386.89 Total .$37,200.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD Or AGRICULTURE This report was adopted and made a part of the record by motion duly made, seconded and carried. THE REPORT OF THE PREMIUM REVISION COMMITTEE WAS READ We, your Committee on Revision of the premium list, beg leave to submit the following report. All dates in the 1919 premium list to be changed to conform to the dates of the fair for 1920. The following page revisions refer to the 1919 premium list Page 14, pay roll schedule: change the salary of the superin tcndent of amphitheatre from $30.00 to $40.00. Change the salary of the superintendent of automobile parking from $40.00 to $50.00. Strike out the words and figures "Guards, $50.00." Change the salary of the superintendent of sanitation from $40.00 to $50.00. Change the salary of the superintendent of tickets from $45.00 to $50.00. Strike out the following: "Assistant treasurer per day $6.00." Also strike out "All other assistant superintendents per day $4.00." Change the salary of the gate keepers per day from $4.00 to $5.00. Change the salary of the ticket sellers per day from $4.00 to $5.00. Change the salary of the judges of speed from $3.00 to $5.00. Strike out the following: "Messengers per day $1.00." At the bottom of page 14 add the following paragraph: "The salaries of all others not mentioned above to be fixed by the Board of Managers." Page 20, section 10, change the salary of the secretary from $250.00 per month to $350.00 per month. Page 23, section 27, strike out "Amphitheatre, except boxes $.50, and also "Boxes in amphitheatre $1.00." Add to section 27 the following. "The Board of Managers is em - powered to fix the price for amphitheatre, quarter stretch and infield tickets and to make any changes deemed necessary in the ticket system, said changes to be made prior to the publishing of the premium list. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE We herewith submit and recommend for adoption, complete re- visions of certain classes, and added to and made a part of this re- port is a detailed revision of each of the classes so changed. Hotsee 1919 1920 Percherons $ 809.00 $1,070.00 Clydes and Shires 372.00 698.00 Belgians 372.00 698.00 Poniea 420.00 583.00 Saddle horses 75.00 75.00 Mules 315.00 738.00 Jacks and Jennets 172.00 172.00 $2,535.00 $4,034.00 2,535.00 Increase $1,499.00 Cattle 1919 1920 Shorthorns (H Shorthorn Ass'n) $1,585.00 $2,142.00 Herefords 801.00 1,264.00 Herefords, Neb. class ( V4 Neb. Breed Ass'n) 250.00 396.00 Aberdeen Angus (Breed Ass'n $400.00). 1,049.00 1,494.00 Galloways 753.00 943.00 Red Polled (Breed Ass'n $400.00) 965.00 1,446.00 Polled Durham (Breed Ass'n $200.00) 857.00 1,290.00 Fat Cattle, same (Stockyards $350.00) 740.00 740.00 jerseys 605.00' 914.00 Guernseys 500.00 669.90 Ayrshires : 500.00 669.00 Holsteins 606.00 914.00 Holstein Priesian (Neb. Ass'n $150.00) 300.00 300.00 $9,510.00 $13,181. 00 9,510.00 IncrewM $3,671.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Page 47, strike out all of paragraph 3 and substitute the follow - ing: "More than one application from any one herd will be rejected. Parties misrepresenting the ownership of any portion of their herd, for the purpose of securing additional pens, will be subject to a forfeit of all premiums and barred from showing 'for such time as the Board of Managers may designate." "The superintendent is authorized to demand pedigrees or certifi - cates of registration from exhibitors, at any time he deems it neces - sary." Change paragraph 5 to read as follows: "Applications for all pens and entries will close Saturday, August 21st, at six P. M." Change paragraph 6 to read as follows: "When orders for pens are cancelled after August 21st, money will not be refunded." Change paragraph 8 to read as follows: "Not to exceed eight pens will be assigned to any one exhibitor for any one breed, or but one pen for boars farrowed after January 1, 1920, and one pen for gilts farrowed after January 1, 1920. All boars over six months shall have their tusks removed before shown. All animals must be re - corded or out of recorded sires and dams. Swine $2,643.00 $3,274.00 2,643.00 Increase 631.00 'oland China $ 526.00 $ 694.00 lat'l Spotted Poland China (% by Ass'n) (erkshires 358.00 346.00 100.00 694.00 &gt;uroc Jerseys ihester Whites 563.00 506.00 748.00 694.00 Iamp8hireB lule Foot 344.00 344.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 39 Sheep 1919 1920 Cots wolds _ $ 148.00 $ 218.00 Leicesters and Lincoln 148.00 218.00 Hampshires 148.00 218.00 Oxfords 148.00 218.00 Shropshires 148.00 218.00 Southdowns 148.00 218.00 Rainbouillets 148.00 218.00 Merino _. __ 148.00 218.00 Amateur classes ( % Paid). 200.00 200.00 $1,384.00 $1,944.00 1,384.00 Increase 560.00 We recommend the following premiums fqr goats: Mil. ( II &lt;JOATS Rucks Buck 2 years old or over _ __ _ _ $5 $3 Buck 1 year old and under 2 _ _ _ 5 3 Buck under 1 year _ 5 3 Does Doe 2 years old or over $5 $3 Doe 1 year old and under 2 5 3 Doe under 1 year 5 3 In the rabbit portion of Class E, we have accepted and recom- mend for adoption the classification as submitted by those interested. and who are qualified to make the changes involved. In 1919 the premiums offered amounted to $138.00 and in 1920 they total $318.50, a total increase of $180.50 Page 75, Class F, the following rules are to be added at the be- ginning: "The Board does not feel justified in paying liberal cash premiums unless there is fair competition and therefore adopt the following </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOAKD OF AGRICULTURE rules: Provided, two or more counties in each district must exhibit to make competition in individual classes. In any and all classes where there is no competition, as above specified, then only one-half money will be paid." Page 75, Lot 1: Strike out No. 1510 — winter oats. Strike out No. 1514 — winter barley Change No. 1519 — white speltz to "spring einmer." Change No. 1520 — black speltz to "winter einmer." Add the following: "white pearl barley." Page 76, Lot 3, Eastern Division: To No. 1568 — white flint corn — add the words "8 rows." To No. 1569 — yellow flint corn — add "8 rows." Add two new numbers, white flint corn, 12 rows — and yellow flint corn, 12 rows'. Page 77, Lot 4, Western Division To No. 1586 — white flint corn — and No. 1587 — yellow flint corn — add the words "8 rows." Add 2 new classes showing white flint corn and yellow flint corn, showing in each "12 rows." Page 77, Lot 5, To No. 1604 — white flint corn — and No. 1605 — yellow flint corn — add the words "8 rows." . Add 2 new classes showing white flint corn and yellow flint corn, showing in each "12 rows." Page 78, Lot 6, To No. 1623, white flint corn and No. 1624, yellow flint corn add the words "8 rows." Add 2 new classes, white flint corn and yellow flint corn, with the words "12 rows" in each. Page 78 Cut out No. 1637, winter oats, and 1641 winter barley Add the following: "white pearl barley." </seg>
            <seg id="p041">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 41 Change No. 1644 — white speltz — to "spring eninier Change No. 1645 — black speltz — to "winter emmer Page 79, Lot 8 In No. 1695 and No. 1696 take out the words "with stalks Page 80, Lot 10. Change No. 1751 to read "timothy" instead of "tame Page 81, change the money purses from $3,000.00 to $4,000.00. In line 25, change the word "sixty" to "forty" and change $2,680.00 to $3,530.00. In the same paragraph, last line, change $300.00 to $350.00. In the next paragraph change the first amount to $50.00, the second amount to $40.00 and the third amount to $30.00. Cut out entirely the next paragraph, starting "Provided that Ijhe highest scored ." *A^ * Corrected score card also submitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 PROCEEDINGS 'NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE I i i « ©moo e c coo cia c c c s : i : i i ! ! sanaj.ni A jo ou pjjituri etc— — a aaaa ooo o oooo fc £ I a. C I t ( 1 I 1 I 1 i • ! t fe~ I 2 I ! 1 i u n • i \\\\i ll ij | iidJj fj \hU liilifflsfflB ! o o£ s tsS j t. cd at o c a c— 3 ait. o UU?OfflOcnOfcHft 1 Oaie:SZh«: h s — H 0 I I rJlNmiftn'xVoCCJC^NwVirt^l-X s-injHir 9JODS 928J3AV saapnf I : I ; I i j j i t I I I j I : i I I | I I I I j | j I I i ! i I j | | | ! 1 I I I j I j I j i I i j j I { I j j I I ; I I i ! I I ! ; I I I I I I : I i I i i ! I i I i ! i i I I I i 1 I i I 1 i i i I i i I t i ! I ! i • I ; I I ; I • I I • I I I ■ I I ; ; I £ ! aaoDs I j L : I'D I C : s. : -^ : C : !■ : i : - : 9 I : : : pooo pajoos &amp;s m s o&gt;£ jooj S|3' |S«! uinipaw 2*0 1 pooo p5 x w &lt;u S3idui«s to on TTTTTTTTTTTTTTTm : i i i i i i i : i i • i i i i i i i ! :;;;;:; •!■!;!•!••• ■ i I i i i i i !: i i !:!!!: i i I I I j I j I j j j I I I I I j I : I I I I I I i I i ! i I I i I I i i ! I I t t I f t i 1 i i t ! i i i ! I I i i ! 1 1 1 i i ! i ! I i I i ! ■ aooj 1 1| i i 1 1 1 ! i i| 1! 1 1 1 i i "TTTTTTTTTTTTTTTTT"! : j j ! j { j j j j i j 1 1 i i| j j \ ! 1 j j i j i ! 1 1 i |i M ! j | |_ MMmMMMMMM I I I [ I i I i I ! I ! j I I 1 1 I ; ill i llllllll 11111111 11 1 ! oooooooooooooooooo o OlOOOOOOOOOOOOOiOOlOU) O HHrtrtHHiHfHHiHHiH rH tO • : 5 L. uinipan s t i | pooo I ■»«|O&lt;J JO •ON aiqissod 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 43 Page 89, Class H, Domestic Products, we have accepted the recom - mendations of the superintendent. In 1919 the premiums offered were $590.00 and this year they amount to $695.75 — an increase of $105.75. Page 95, Class I, Bees and Honey, we recommend the following addition. Professional Class — Sweepstakes Fi rst premium _ _ _ _ $50.00 Second premium ._ 30.00 Th i rd premium __ 20.00 RULES FOR PROFESSIONAL EXHIBITORS IN CLASS I Exhibitors in Professional class will not be permitted to compete in other classes except with such entries as are the product of their own apiaries, subject to the foregoing rules. Full score in profes - sional class shall be 500 pounds each of comb and extracted honey and 100 pounds minimum of marketable beeswax, either in bulk or in de - signs. For each 100 pounds of either comb or extracted honey less than the full score of 500 pounds deduction shall be made from prem - ium award at the rate of ten per cent for each 100 pounds or fraction thereof which is short; provided, that the minimum for comb and ex - tracted honey shall be 300 pounds of each and that for each 100 pounds of either comb or extracted honey or fraction thereof in excess of the full score of 500 pounds corresponding credit shall be given for any shortage in either comb or extracted honey above the minimum quantity. Page 97, Class J, Woman's Department, we also accepted the recommendations of the superintendent. This involves a very small increase in the premiums. Page 105, Class K, Fine Arts, we have accepted the revision of the premiums as submitted, which include an addition to the prem - iums offered of $153.75. Page 111, Class L, Educational, we have an entire new revision including the regular educational department and the different boys' and girls' clubs throughout the state. Last year we offered $1,595.00 in this department and this year we offer $1,674.25, an increase of $79.25. Respectfully submitted. E. R. PURCELL A. W. LAMB Z. T. LEFTWICH Revision Committee. WM. JAMES </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Mr. Jackson: I want to refer to page 14, superintendent of speed $40.00 — clerk of speed $40.00. Now the superintendent of speed is the first on the ground and the last off and I want to move that he be allowed $50.00. The motion was seconded and carried On motion duly seconded and carried the report of the Com mittee on Revision of Premium list, as thus amended, was adopted. At this time the Board adjourned to visit the poultry show at the Auditorium and to resume business at 9 o'clock on Wednesday morning. SECOND SESSION Lincoln, Nebraska, January 21, 1920. The second session of the State Board of Agriculture meeting was called to order by President Wolcott at 9:30 a. m. on Wednesday, January 21, 1920, at the Lindell Hotel. Roll call by the Secretary showed a quorum present Mr. O. G. Smith moved that the members present at this meeting be paid $5.00 a day for the three day session and their railroad fare. The motion was seconded and carried. The president appointed as tellers Messrs. Lawrence, Banning and N. Dwlght Ford. Mr. Hawk then moved that the Credential Committee having made its final report, and completed its work, be discharged and their re - port be adopted. The motion was seconded and carried. Mr. McLeod moved that the President, Vice-president and Secre - tary of this Board be elected as delegates to the association meeting to be held soon in Chicago, and stated that he thought these men, who were vitally interested in the success of the State Fair, should be the ones to attend that meeting and bring back all the good that could be secured from it. The motion was seconded. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">PROCEEDINGS NEHBASKA .STATE BOARD OF AGRIC'll.Tl RE 45 Mr. Roberts: I fully indorse this resolution; I believe if we send delegates to Chicago they should bring back all the information they can from Chicago to carry on our State Fair and I think they are men who are right up to the head to put things in operation, and I believe this is a movement that should have been adopted years ago. Since we have not done that I believe this motion should be adopted now. The motion being put was unanimously carried. Mr. O. G. Smith moved that the Board of Managers be empowered to fill any vacancies in the delegation. The motion was seconded and carried. Mr. Smith: I am not here to criticise the management but I am here to boost for the management of the State Fair,, every one of us who has attended the State Fair for several yearn has been disap - pointed with our speed program. We have felt that the grand stand for which we paid $29,000.00 and the receipts from which are a good proposition, with the circus given in front of the grand stand and which fills it to overflowing, it seems to me we could get a better speed program. I know personally that these men have blue-penciled Nebraska and have not been fair to our Nebraska people, while our local and state men have done everything possible to make this part of the Fair a success. I believe we should all assist the management in getting a better speed program. Mr. Smith moved that it be the sense of this meeting that a com - mittee of three consisting of the Superintendent of Speed, Mr. Gould of Kearney and Mr. Ronin of Fremont be asked to come before the Board and consult with them in regard to a speed program. The motion was seconded and carried. Mr. Lawrence: I believe there might be minor changes in the program which the Board would like to make and I move that the Board be empowered to make any minor changes necessary in the pro - gram. The motion was seconded and carried. Election of president being in order nominations were invited for that office. Mr. Ollis: I desire to nominate a man you are all acquainted with and a man who has been a member of this Board for a good many years. He comes from Douglas County which has the largest popula - tion of any county in the state, and I want to say this in regard to Douglas County; you all know the State Board of Ag-iculture has had more or less trouble getting as large appropriations from the legisla - ture as the Board felt the legislature ought to make, although they have done pretty well for the State Fair and the Board of Agricul- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE ture in the last few years, and I think in every instance this man from Douglas County has supported every appropriation suggested for the Board of Agriculture, and is in full sympathy with all agricultural activities. I nominate for the office of president Mr. J. F. McArdle. There being no further nominations Mr. Ollis moved that the nominations be closed and that the secretary be instructed to cast the unanimous ballot of the association for Mr. McArdle as president for the coming year. The motion was seconded and carried, the secretary cast the ballot, and Mr. McArdle was declared duly elected. Mr. McArdle: I am not going to burden you with any extended remarks. I want to say that on the Board of Managers it is prac - tically understood that we .have two men who do all the talking. You probably know who they are, it has kind of grown on the members of the Board that these men shall do the talking and the others shall keep still and work along, and of course these men you will hear from again, and they are not selfish and are not at all times blowing their own horn, they are generous at times in spreading some of the praise over Borne of those who associate with them. Of course I am not la - boring under any delusion. I think you could lay your hand on men better qualified than I am to fill this position; but I appreciate in my heart the action you have taken. There is just one thought that comes to me and that is that Nebraska is growing. I have the dis - tinction probably of being the first native-born Nebraskan to fill this position and of course I appreciate all the honor conferred upon me and I always appreciate it as a native Nebraskan. I thank you. FIRST VICE-PRESIDENT Mr. Cheney: You all know the man I am about to nominate, he has made good at every turn of the road and it is a pleasure to me to present his name at this time, Mr. Charles Graff. There being no further nominations on motion duly made, sec - onded and carried the nominations were closed, the rules were sus - pended, the secretary cast the unanimous ballot of the State Board of Agriculture for Charles Graff as its- First Vice-president for the coming year and he was declared duly elected. Mr. Graff: I am glad of course that you have honored me by electing me First Vice-president of this, the greatest organisation in the State of Nebraska. I am also glad to be able to say to you this morning that you have elected me to a position where I stand very </seg>
            <seg id="p047">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOA ED OF AGKICULTUKK 47 close to the man you have Just elected president of this organization, a man who, even though an Irishman, was one of the first men con - nected with the State Board of Agriculture whom I learned to know and I have always felt that he played the game fair. He has earned that distinction. Of course I rather except to some of his statements in saying that he was the first President elected on the State Board of Agriculture who was born in this state. You gentlemen know that that is a matter that President McArdle never had anything to say about nor any control of. It is not my fault because I was not born in Ne - braska. I came here just as soon as the law allowed me to come and that was when I was 21 years of age. I have labored in one capacity or another upon this Board for quite a number of years and I cannot recall any organization, society or whatever you may call it that I have ever been connected with where I have enjoyed the work as much as I have with this Board. Now when Mr. McArdle said that you would perhaps know the other members on this Board who usually did the talking, and for fear that you might think that I was one of those two, I want to cut my talk short. Gentlemen, I can only thank you for this honor. ' I am glad to be able to assist and stand close to the President of the State Board of Agriculture for the coming year. SECOND VICE-PRESIDENT Mr. Leftwich: It gives me great pleasure to nominate our dis - tinguished citizen, George Jackson, for this office. Mr. Purcell — I want to second this nomination, Mr. Jackson has been very close to the State Board of Agriculture for a great many years and has been a county fair man and been. closely connected with the county fair organization, and I don't know of a member of the State Board of Agriculture who is better qualified and probably more entitled to this office than George Jackson. There being no further nominations Mr. Smith moved that the rules be suspended and the secretary cast the entire ballot of this Board for Mr. George Jackson for this office. The motion was seconded and carried, the secretary cast the ballot, and Mr. Jackson was de - clared elected as Second Vice-president. Secretary Danielson: In announcing the election of Mr. Jackson to this position I think I am safe in saying that he is one of the most thorough fair men that I have found in the State of Nebraska. He understands the game from all angles and I have never yet been able to catch him when he did not come back with an answer on any proposition connected with this business. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 PROCEEDINGS .NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGBICULTURE Mr. Jackson: Anybody who could not talk after such an intro - duction as that, better go home. I was sitting there feeling a little like Jonah when he was about to be swallowed by the whale. Presi - dent Hughes and a young lady were walking through an art gallery in New York and saw a picture of Jonah about to be swallowed by the whale, and the young lady said "I don't see how Jonah can have such a contented look on his face when he is about to be swallowed by the whale," and he says "Oh, that is nothing, he knows he won't be asked to make a speech at the banquet." But gentlemen, I have felt it a dis - tinct honor to be a member of this State Board of Agriculture. I have been a member of different organizations of the state, political and otherwise, but when I want to get among my friends I come to the State Board of Agriculture and the allies that go with it, who are doing things in this state, and I don't know of any organization where we get closer together, where we greet each other with that spirit of friendship, that we do in this organization, and when we meet at the State Fair it just seems to me every member of this Board that I meet is a brother. I don't know whether the president meant me or not, but I am not much of a talker. I want you to know that I appreciate this honor, and that is all I have got to say. I believe you under - stand. TREASURER Mr. Leftwich nominated Jacob Sass and moved that the nomina - tions be closed and that the secretary be instructed to cast the vote of the organization for Mr. Sass. The motion was seconded, carried, the secretary cast the unani - mous ballot, and Mr. Sass was declared elected as treasurer for the coming year. Mr. Sass: I certainly appreciate the honor done me and I surely •hall do the best I possibly can. I want to tell you that whenever you get out of money for the State Fair, just come to the treasurer and he will take care of it. I thank you. SECRETARY Mr. Smith: I rise to place in nomination a man who needs no introduction to this body, a man who was made secretary a few years ago and some of us were satisfied at that time that he would make good; a man who has been on the job all the time, every day and Sun - day, who lives Fair and dreams Fair and who ranks with the best Fair secretaries in this western country, our present encumbent, Ed Danielson. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AliRKTI-TlRK 49 Mr. Purcell: I had the pleasure of placing in nomination Ed Danielson when he was first elected secretary of the Board of Agri - culture and I said at that time that he was a man who I believed would make good and I have not changed my mind, and I want to second his nomination. Mr. McLeod: I think we are all unanimous in this and I move that the rules be suspended and the president be authorized to cast the unanimous vote of this body for Ed Danielson for secretary. The motion was seconded, carried, the president cast the unani - mous ballot, and Mr. Danielson was declared elected as secretary for the coming year. Mr. Danielson: Gentlemen, there are times for wit and there are times for seriousness; I see why I am feeling in such a good mood this morning, but there is only one thing I do regret and that is that there are not offices enough to go around in this organization so that you could keep me on my feet for the next hour declaring each one of you elected to office. I feel that each of you are officers in this or - ganization. I have felt ever since I became secretary that you have stood by me with the most hearty co-operation or my work would not have been the success it has been from the standpoint of the office, and it means the success of the State Board of Agriculture and the success of the State Fair. I do not want to take all the credit upon myself and do not want you to put it on me, but I want to give it back to you, where I feel a great part of it rightfully belongs. I am simply you clerk in a way, acting for you while you are at home. I am put - ting across the things that you want put across and along with that sometimes I see some things on the side that I think ought to be put across and I get a little obnoxious to some of the members and some of the members will say "Hold on, not quite so fast," but I find that spirit must be dominant somewhere; somebody must have the life and have some initiative and while maybe I think up crazy things once in awhile, I want to say I have gotten many a good idea from you men out over the state as you have drifted in and dropped a remark which you probably did not think amounted to much, but after you had gone I have thought it over and it perhaps has grown into quite a large proposition. As you know, we have had a run of successful years and I men - tioned in my report yesterday that we have expected to have a good run this year, and the year following this, but this will be a hard year and there will be many trials and troubles which will confront us and there is only one way to come back next year the same as we have this, and that is by all sticking together, to stay together as an or- </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE ganization and whatever we start out to do we will put across and I will be there to help you do it. I thank you. Mr. Pureell: I want to say just a word before we close in re - gard to the State Fair work as regards the legislature. We are as - sembled here representatives from practically every county in Ne - braska. The State Fair must have aid from the State, every county fair should have aid from the county, to do the things that are neces - sary- This probably is a little closer to me than it would be if I had not been mixed up in the work as I was last winter with the appropri - ations for the State Fair through the legislature. We should have legislative help. If the members of the County Agricultural Societies will speak to their representatives in the next legislature relative to reasonable and liberal appropriations for the State Fair buildings it is going to make it much easier to get those things which the State Fair grounds need. Along that same line I want to say to the county fair men that I believe the county boards of Nebraska should help the county fairs. I think they should help to put good buildings on the county fair grounds, and along that line if you will remember and have that in mind I believe it will help us to put through the next legislature a law making it possible to make a levy either to start an appropriation or a fraction of a mill or more for the purpose of mak - ing the county fairs of Nebraska a success, and agriculture and stock - raising are the main things in Nebraska and I think the people of the state should help them by the general taxes that they pay. It is the best way to do it and I believe those things can be accomplished if we will speak to our representatives in regard to it. Mr. Pureell moved that the incoming president appoint a legis - lative committee of one member from each county in Nebraska hav - ing a county* fair, and that they carry out a suggested plan of opera - tion and that the president make this appointment during the next 30 days. The motion was seconded and carried Mr. McArdle was introduced as the newly elected president and nominated the following members on the Board of Managers, who will serve with the President and Vice-presidents: Messrs. Pureell, Caley, Leftwich and Wake. On motion the nominations so made by the president were con firmed by the Board. Mr. Graff moved that this Board extend to Mr. Wolcott, the re - tiring president, a vote of thanks by a rising vote for his capable and efficient administration. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 51 The motion was seconded by various members and was carried by a unanimous rising vote. On motion duly seconded and carried the Board then adjourned sine die at 12 o'clock noon. </seg>
            <seg id="p052"/>
            <seg id="p053">ANNUAL MEETING of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture 1921 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">PROCEEDINGS OF ANNUAL MEETING JANUARY 18-19, 1921 First Day — Afternoon Session The first session of the January 1921 meeting of the State Board of Agriculture was called to order at 2:00 o'clock P. M. on the 18th day of January 1921 by President J. F. McArdle. Mr. C. H. Rudge, a former president of the Board, was invited to seat at the President's right. The call for the meeting was read by the Secretary. NOTICE OF ANNUAL MEETING Lincoln, Neb., Dec. 10, 1920. The Annual meeting of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture will be held at the Lindell Hotel, Lincoln, on Tuesday, January 18, 1921, at two o'clock. At this meeting will be considered the revision of the premium list, rules and regulations, the election of officers, membership, and such other business as may legally come before said meeting. Presidents of regularly organized, live County Agricultural So - cieties, which have filed their reports prior to this meeting, are ex - offlcio members of the Board. If the President cannot attend, the So - ciety must elect a delegate, and file authenticated credentials. No proxies are admitted. The following Committees have been appointed by the President Revision of Premium List, Rules and Regulations This Committee to report Monday, January 17, 1921, 9 A. M. 3. R. Purcell Broken Bow oseph Roberts L. W. Lamb Fremont Albion \ H. Wake Seward . A. Ollis Ord </seg>
            <seg id="p055">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 55 Credentials and Returns Z. T. Leftwich __ St. Paul T. B. Keedle Minden Perry Reed Henderson This Committee to report Monday, January 17, 1921, 7 P. M. Auditing H. J. McLaughlin ...Doniphan W. B. Banning Union Charles Strader Lincoln This Committee to report Monday, January 17, 1921, 9 A. M. Resolutions Committee Charles Graff Bancroft O. G. Smith _ __ Kearney George Jackson _ —Nelson C. H. Gustafson. ___— ; Mead C. W. Pugsley _^ _ Lincoln This Committee to report Monday, January 17, 1921, at 7 P. M. Members Whose Terms Kvpire January, 1921 V. Arnold Richardson County J. A. Ollis Valley County J. j*. McArdle _ _ Douglas County Charles Graff Cuming County George Jackson Nuckolls County E. R. Danielson Polk County Z. T. Leftwich Howard County C. G. Crews _ Hitchcock County J. H. Harms Franklin County Charles Strader _ Lancaster County T. H. Wake _ Seward County C. S. Hawk _ _ _ Dawes County A. W. Lamb Boone County C. H. Gustafson _ Saunders County </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOABD OF AGRICULTURE Members Whose Terms Expire January, 1922 R. M. Wolcott Merrick County Joseph Roberts Dodge County William James Saline County W. B. Banning Case County Jacob Sass Sarpy County E. R. Purcell Custer County T. B. Keedle Kearney County O. G. Smith Buffalo County G. E. Hall Douglas County C. W. Pugsley Lancaster County Perry Reed Hamilton County H. J. McLaughlin Hall County J. C. Cox Keith County W. T. Parkinson Pawnee County Suggestions for improvement of Premium List, Rules, Regula - tions or Resolutions requested. Send to Secretary prior to meeting of Committee. J. F. McARDLE, President CHARLES GRAFF, Vice President E. R. DANIELSON, Secretary Roll call showed a quorum present. Communications were read by the secretary from Messrs G. E. Hall, R. M. Wolcott, C. G. Crews, and Charles Strader, and the sec - retary moved that these members of the Board be excused from at - tendance at this meeting. The motion was seconded and carried Report of Credentials Committee. Jan. 18, 1921. We, your Committee on Credentials, beg to report the following presidents and delegates of County Fair Associations entitled to vote and otherwise participate in the deliberations of the annual meeting of the State Board of Agriculture. County Town President Delegate Antelope Neligh Boone Albion Boyd Butte D. L. Shanefelt C. B. McCorkle J. M Sieler Buffalo. Kearney E. D. Gould E. T. Winter Ray C. Pollard Butler David City Cass Weep'g Water Chase Imperial Dr. Geo. Hoffmeister </seg>
            <seg id="p057">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATK BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 57 Custer Broken Bow E. R Purcell Clay Clay Center N. M. Buchtel Dawes _ Chadron J. F. Lawrence Dawson Lexington R. E. Falkinburg Dodge Sc r i b n er H. S Spath Dodge Hooper M. A. Uehling Douglas _ Valley E. P. Noyes Fillmore Geneva Jacob Weis Franklin... Franklin J. H. Harms Frontier Stockville L. H. Cheney J. E. Bonser G. W. Spiegel Furnas Beaver City Gage Beatrice Halt Wood River D. O. Dodge Hamilton Aurora E. J. Eggert Hitchcock CulbertBon John A. Kirk Holt O'Neill Peter W. Duffy Howard St. Paul R. E. Calvin Jefferson Fairbury O. R. Jones Johnson Tecumseh L. Lyell Kearney _ Minden Wm. Johnson Keith Ogalalla B. W. Sheldon Lancaster -..Lincoln L. B. Schoenleber Madison _ Madison Henry Sunderman Merrick Clarks H. M. Kokjer Nemaha \ uburn Homer J. Pohltnan Nuckolls Nelson Chas. Malsbury Pawnee _ Pawnee City D. W. Osborne Pierce _ _..Pierce Wm. Prahl Polk Osceola Chas. Newcomber Red Willow Ban ley W. H. Arnold Seward _. Seward Shelby Ramsey Sherman Loup City Will Hancock Stanton Stanton John A. Ehrhardt Thayer Deshler E. J. Mitchell Valley Ord John C. Meese Washington Arlington P. L. Cady Webster niaden W. E. France York. York Con McCarthy Respectfully submitted, Z. T. LEFTWICH T. B. KEEDLE PERRY REED Committee </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Moved, seconded and carried that Con McCarthy be seated as dele - gate representing York County. On motion report of the Credentials Committee was adopted and the Committee continued. PRESIDENT'S ADDRESS To the Members of the State Board of Agriculture. Gentlemen: The By-laws require that I render to you in writing a detailed account of my official acts covering the year just closed, but as a simi - lar requirement is placed upon the Secretary, I take it that his com - prehensive statement that will follow, covering in detail the trans - actions of the Society the past year, should relieve me from entering into this phase of the subject. The President acts at all times as a member of the Board of Managers, and the minor things that come within his prerogatives, that are independent of the Board, would be of little interest to you. It does seem that the State Fair, in the last few years, has ad - vanced out. of all proportion to other activities of our State. While this should be very gratifying to all of us, it carries with it the danger of growing top-heavy, unless ways and means are provided to secure the necessary props to sustain it. The Board has labored strenuously to meet the fast increasing wants and needs of the Exhibitor and Pub - lic, but unless material aid comes soon from the people, through their Legislature, the limit of accommodations will retard a further growth. One of the disagreeable tilings that confronted your Board in the beginning of their term was the loss of the Cattle-barn by flre. We had no money to rebuild, and no opportunity at that time to receive state aid. We could not afford to lose the work of years in building up a great cattle exhibit — which would follow, should we fail to pro - vide housing for them at the coming fair. The prospects were indeed gloomy, but the business men of Lincoln arose to the occasion, and we had the best cattle exhibit of our history, housed in one of the finest cattle barns in the Country. While the furnishing of this $150,000, by the men of Lincoln was indeed great, the intense interest and loyalty shown by these men toward the State Fair is of a value that will be better Been as the years go on. I feel assured that I may speak for this body of men in tendering to those who came to our assistance when in need, our grateful thanks, and renew to them the promise of your Board, that we will use all honorable means with the Legislature </seg>
            <seg id="p059">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 59 to secure an appropriation covering the money advanced to erect our Cattle-barn. Your Board expended about $40,000 out of our funds in general improvements, such as streets, sidewalks, curbing, sewerage, toilets, addition to Grand-stand, electric light system, and many other things that are of a permanent nature. Added to this there was an outlay of $14,000 for general up-keep of the grounds, and repairing of the old buildings that they might be servicable a little longer. The work of street fixing, and beautifying the grounds has just begun, and there must be many repetitions of the above outlay before our grounds will in any manner compare with our Sister-States. An institution like the State Fair should be in a position to ac - commodate every meritorious exhibit that asks to enter, and, until this is made possible, we are not functioning as we should. The Hog-barn, that we were all so pleased with, is now wholly adequate to meet the demands made upon it, and the conditions now are a source of greater discomfort to all concerned, than were the conditions before the erec - tion of the building. Then the exhibitors realized our position, and faced the condition with good natured patience;- now that we have the new barn, they resent our inability to provide them a place to exhibit. At the late Fair we cut the space for sale pigs to the minimum, but with that, we failed to meet the requirements of exhibitors by some four hundred pens. There should be at least two sections added, or better still, if possible, add another story to the present building. The present Horse-barn, and the other old buildings have long ago passed their time as a source of satisfaction to the management, but until they can be replaced with permanent ones, it is imperative that we repair, and brace them up to meet actual wants. While the horse exhibit was not what it should be in the later years, it showed a marked improvement last year. With the pendulum swinging back in the horse's favor, and a real building to house them, I feel confident that he will take his old place among the great live-stock exhibits. The one thing that seems to be uppermost in the minds of the Board, and men and women interested in State and County Fair-work, is the encouragement of Exhibits by our boys and girls. While this is more or less a new innovation, it is coming to the front so fast that it calls for the first consideration of Fair Managers. You should visualize the wonderful prospects that this field will open up, and begin now to lay the proper foundation. Paraphrasing an old truism — the boys of today will be the Fair-men of tomorrow. How much better qualified will they be to take up the work when you are through. This ad - vantage, in itself, would be sufficient to justify your best efforts in ad - vancing this kind of work, but it is a small part of the benefits that </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE will accrue to the boys and girls, and through them the State at large. You men can vision a commodious building, filled to capacity with ex - hibits that are the fruits of minds in the embryonic stage — education in all its ramification to guide the boys and girls; a pleasure for the Fathers and Mothers to view. Begin now and have your Legislators vision with you. While a pleasure, I also deem it a duty, to call to your attention at this time the necessity of closer co-operation with the organization of the State Association of County Fairs. Many of us have failed to realise the benefits to the State Fair that a strong organization of this character will develop. The benefits received are mutual to all concerned, but you will find that the majority of them come from the bottom, up. Let us open a field here where the higher ideals, so gal - lantly pleaded for by Brother Lawrence, will find an outlet. As the National Association of Fairs has recognized the importance of this organization by allowing them membership, I suggest membership for them in the national body. As it now stands, the manner of raising funds to properly finance this organization is wholly inadequate, therefore I recommend that membership fee, and the expenses of at least two deleagtea to the annual meeting at Chicago, Illinois, be covered by the State Board of Agriculture. Wholesome criticism is one of the things that urge us to better efforts. It usually reaches us through two sources, one, emanating from the sour-visaged and cadaverous reformer who spends his time on the grounds hunting for the one dark spot, while the ninety and nine bright ones never come within his melancholy view, this class usually over-shoot the mark, but do leave a bad taste in the mouth. The other kind comes from men and women whose only aim is to see the Fair prosper and grow along the higher line, who looking for all the bright spots on the grounds find here and there things that are, to them, objectionable. In drawing the management's attention to these features, their criticism becomes a suggestion, and should receive the earnest consideration of the men in charge. We receive letters from parties whose criticisms are general, and they usually admit that they could do far better than those at the helm. To fortify ourselves against these truths, we revert to that King of Spain who stated that had he been around at th- time of creation he could have improved on God's work. While I feel the time has come when we should diligently use the pruning-knife when issuing permits for concessions, I would draw your attention to the fact that we court comparisons with out Sister-fairs in the kind and tone of these exhibits. A talk with the show people would convince you that Nebraska is the tightest on their circuit. Many so called attractions are closed while on our grounds, to be </seg>
            <seg id="p061">PROCEEDINGS .NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 61 opened again when they pass on. We have striven to remove the things suggestive or of an immoral Tiature, but there are many other things that hunt a place on the grounds, that, while not objectionable in themselves, fill no want of our patrons whatever, of no educational value, unless to educate the people that the other fellow's game is best let alone. My immediate predecessors were constrained to call to your at - tention in their annual statement, the abnormal conditions the Coun - try was passing through, owing to the World's War, and its aftermath. Fortunately the first has passed over, but the year just ended found us in the aftermath — the tail end of it, let us hope. We were con - fronted with a tidal wave of exorbitant prices for material and labor. They were out of proportion with other years in all of our activities. With these conditions confronting the Board, they deemed it imperative that some action should be taken to increase the revenue necessary to meet this increased cost of conducting the Fair. The main channel of revenue comes from the sale of tickets, and concession privileges. A decrease of concession receipts was to be expected, as the Board had decided to eliminate many concessions that were heretofore on the grounds; this left an increase in ticket rates the only avenue by which they could cover the increase in cost. After learning that all other Fairs had raised the entrance fee, your Board did likewise, and fixed the fare for gate and grandstand at seventy-five cents respectively. Had the Board failed to take this action, we would have been on the wrong side of the Ledger for an amount that would be painful to con - sider. An old member of this Board when asked why devote so much time and energy to Fair work with such small emoluments, answered — "It is in the Blood." Through the long years that I have been as - sociated with you I have often searched for a reason for your activity, your faithful service, your intense loyalty to this great institution, and for a compensation not sufficient to cover your expenses; search as 1 would, the mind reverted to the above — "It is in the Blood." Not being able to see very far in the future, I would not deny that a better and more efficient way might be devised to manage the State Fair, but this I do know, that unless it gets into the blood of every person con - nected with it, the end will be a failure. The results of your labor for the year have been fruitful, and a wonderfully successful Fair has crowned your efforts. There is more to be done in one week of the Fair than is done in the same time in any other business. All men connected with it are at high tension, and working under a nervous strain. Under these conditions men say and do things that are not from the heart, and should be forgotten when we are back to our normal state. May I hope that you are gathered </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Or AGRICULTURE here at this time with eyes on the past only that you may gather from it the experience that will guide you, with a broader vision, to higher efforts in the future. Nominations for members to fill vacancies on the Board were then made as follows, First District — W. Arnold, A. J. Weaver, C J. Warner Second District — J. F. McArdle, Jacob Sass Third District— W. W. Cole, A. W. Lamb, Charles Graff, William Prahl. Fourth District — E. R. Danielson, O. R. Jones, secretary of the Jef - ferson county Fair Association, Thomas H. Wake, and C. H. Gustafson. Fifth District — George Jackson, J. H. Harms, Fred Hoffmeister, C. G. Crews. Sixth District — C. S. Hawk, Z. T. Leftwich, J. A. Ollis, W. L. Me Nutt, Winfleld Evans. SECRETARY'S REPORT The year 1920 again justified the faith of the nation in the farmers of Nebraska in their ability to meet their proportionate requirements in the production of food for humanity, feed for livestock and the pro - duction of the raw materials to be made into clothing. In the face of enormous difficulties, Nebraska farmers this year produced — with a single exception — the largest harvest in the history of the state; a feat of which they have a right to be justly proud. These remarkable results were achieved under conditions which were decidedly disheartening, in the beginning of the spring work. The farmers were confronted with an unusual number of obstacles and many of them were formidable; the spring being late, cold and wet, threatening to restrict the crop acreage and making it uncertain whether the seed planted would rot in the ground or whether that which germinated would reach maturity. In only four years of the last thirty-seven was the progress of plowing, up to Hay 1st, bo back - ward as in 1920. With this initial handicap and with prevailing un - certainty regarding weather conditions during the grcwing season, Ne - braska farmers were much discouraged. They saw no hope of a price reduction in machinery, supplies and labor, all of which had greatly increased since the year 1914. To make matters much worse, the labor supply was approximately forty per cent short and wages had risen to such a point in 1919 that the farmers were appalled at the thought of having to pay a still higher wage in 1920. Many of the </seg>
            <seg id="p063">PROCEEDINGS NEBRA8KA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 63 men who entered the military and naval services and other war indus - tries did not return to farm work. Wages in all industries as well as trade and transportation increased so rapidly that their lure became irresistable to many laborers who had thus far remained on the farm, and they too were carried with the current to urban centers. Thus, summing up the conditions, the farmers were confronted with the most difficult situation they had ever experienced. After they had mastered the difficulties of their planting and har - vesting operations, after they had solved the problems of production, they were brought face to face with "a more serious condition con - fronting them in the rapid decline of market values. As a result of this, a situation was brought about which made immediate conse - quences serious, not only to the agricultural activities but to the na - tion as well. During all the months when the farmers were cultivat - ing their crops, paying for labor and supplies at unusually high rates, the price of agricultural commodities generally remained high but by midsummer when their outlay was nearly at an end and their income period about to begin, a sharp decline occurred in the prices of prac - tically all farm products. While covering nearly everything the farmer had to sell it did not materially affect the articles he had to buy. For labor and materials used in harvesting, they were compelled to pay prices substantially as high as those prevailing during planting and cul - tivation. This means the farmers of Nebraska, and the United States as well, are not receiving adequate returns for their efforts. It means also that the very foundation of our nation — stabilized agriculture — is threatened, and that everything possible must be done to prevent or at least to lessen the effect of a recurrence of the conditions under which large numbers of farmers have conducted their operations at a loss. The farmer must have and, under ordinary conditions, is entitled to a reasonable prospect of a fair return for his labor and the use of his capital. The operation of a farm today has become a scientific business proposition, and this business cannot thrive unless the pro - prietor is suitably and profitably paid for the products of his farm, or unless he receives compensation sufficient to enable him to continue to produce and to maintain for himself and family satisfactory standards of living. In moments of sober thought, you and I realize that the abso - lute necessity of a sustained agriculture in this state and nation is im - perative. There is perhaps no single solution for the situation which the farmers are now facing, but there are many steps which can and should be taken to place agriculture on a more satisfactory basis and to stabilize the business of farming. Not in the interest of the farmers alone, but in the interest of the nation as a whole, the matter is of such tremendous importance to our entire population that it should be recognized not only as a state but as a national problem as well, and </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE dealt with as such. We must adopt every feasible means to enable the farmer to adjust himself to changes in economic conditions, such as have recently occurred. It should be a fact that when the farms of the country produce abundantly the consuming public will be liberally supplied with food at reasonable prices, the farmer taking his profit because of large production and the consumer receiving his fair, pro - portionate share from having available an adequate supply at a reason - able cost. In general, we should expect it to be true that the farmers' condition is improving in direct proportion to the number of bushels of wheat or corn he produces. However, it frequently happens that when all farmers have extraordinary good crops during the same year, low prices leave him worse off than he has been in other years, with shorter crops and higher prices. One thing which I feel would help to remedy this is some means of carrying over the surplus from years of high production to periods of lower production, whenever feasible. Thus should more attention be given to marketing and the develop - ment of the latent consumption demand in years of large supply. It would, to my mind, be a happy solution of present day conditions. With the fortieth session of Nebraska's legislature just convened, the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture can lend their moral support to the passage of laws regarding better marketing conditions. A feel - ing seems to exist that there are plenty of laws upon our statute books today covering our basic industry of agriculture and lifestock, some of them better laws than most states can boast. There are other laws passed by former legislatures which no doubt need some amendment, viz., our pure seed law, our present dairy law, our good roads bureau program, with perhaps a larger appropriation to meet the federal ap - propriation of indemnifying owners of live stock that have been con - demned on account of tuberculosis. There is no question but what this is a very important matter and reaches far beyond the live stock in - dustry alone. Our bottle fed babies should be protected in every man - ner possible from the contraction of any transiniitable disease through contagious milk. Again let me state that I have no hesitancy in recalling that the work of the State Board of Agriculture has for years been effective and of value to agricultural Nebraska. A worthy work has been car - ried on extending into many phases of farming, yet I do not .feel that the work of this organization, while of great value, is all that it might be or all that it should be. Through a long period of years this Board has been handicapped by a lack of funds for extending the scope of our activities. In relying on our own resources and building up better than a million dollar institution in the name of the state at the Fair grounds, we have been limited along other lines of activities which are just as necessary and just as essential as the one which has been practically our sole means of support. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 65 In the past this Board has fostered and helped to create numerous individual branches along agricultural and livestock lines, and I sin - cerely trust that some means may be created whereby the allied agri - cultural organizations and the State Board of Agriculture can be brought closer together in their educational work and that financial aid will be given whereby the scope of this work can be broadened instead of being handicapped. Along the lines of education, or perhaps better still, propoganda, I feel there is no larger problem of more importance than that of sell - ing "Rural Nebraska" to the city man. At the present time there are about forty-one per cent of our people residing upon the farms of America, while but a few short years back there were more than fifty per cent of our population upon the farms of the nation. It is a well known fact that the average farmer has not had sufficient finances with which to manage his business. I can imagine some of you think - ing of the perfectly splendid homes in your community with which you are familiar. The home of the farmer who owns his own farm, and equipment, who doesn't owe anybody a dollar, you have in mind that man and that man's family, but remember that the majority of mw tilling the soil of the nation do not own the land upon which they re - side. They do not happen to have the land all paid for, owing perhaps a large sum of money on it and the equipment which which they till the soil. The day of producing food cheaply is no more. In times passed we could raise hundreds of thousands of cattle on the broad plains of the west with only the expense of the cow puncher and the delivery to market. That day is gone. It now costs real money to produce the meat and food products on the farm. Again let me repeat that the big problem of today, from the food producers' standpoint, is selling the "rural problems" to the other fellow. It means the organization of the leaders of the farm game, men engaged in Agricultural Fairs, men engaged in the breeding of pure bred livestock, men engaged in maintaining a live rural spirit. Through some centralized agency we must tell the American peo - ple the honest and truthful story of agriculture in this country, with its lights and its shadows. We must not hesitate to call to their at - tention the farm wives — the women of the farm — who have worked steadily, and whose hours of labor have been set only by their power of endurance. The mother of the rural family has striven to raise her family in the path she hoped they would follow, done all she could toward the development and guidance of the womanhood and manhood that comes up from rural America, comes up into the councils of the state and nation and into the management of our big business enter - prises. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE The story of the farm boy and girl must be told; they realize that they can leave their rural homes — go into the city — where hours of labor are shorter and remuneration greater. In some other way, prove to the American people that at the end of the year of burden carrying the farmer has less in his pocket as remuneration and reward for his year's effort, his family has less in hand than any class of people on the American continent. This is the problem of the leaders in agri - culture. The farmer is not asking sympathy, he doesn't ask for any - thing peculiar for himself, he merely asks that in the new adjustment, in the new era that lies ahead of us, his business shall take its proper place with other industries of the country. All he asks is that he shall receive a fair return for his labor and investment, and that is a funda - mental principle of economics. All the farmers are asking is a proper balance between agriculture and the other industries of this country. At present we are somewhat overindustrialized, we have — for the mo - ment — lost sight of the fact that America must never cease to be an agricultural nation. That nation only is great and strong in which its agriculture flourishes. That nation only is great and strong which brings up from its plains and hillsides strong, virile men and women. How many years would it be before the great cities of the country would fall into decay if it were not for the fresh young womanhood and manhood that is continually poured into the great centers of population. We cannot fill our great cities at the expense of the rural districts. The right hand of man or woman will find its place in the world. We cannot ask that all people remain on the farm; that is no part of the divine plan. We do want to have life in the open country so regulated and orderly with all the business of the country that it shall be a good place to live, and that the future American people can say with pride: "I had the privilege of being born on the farm." We want it so they can count it as one of the greatest privileges of their lives when they can also say they had the opportunity of growing up on the farm; th»s they had faced the adversities of farming, of laboring, against the ele - ments, of playing — as the farmers play every year — the greatest game of chance of any of our people. It toughens the fibre and it diciplines the body and mind and, above all, it grows a great soul. Then let us, as an organization and as individuals, lend every effort possible to assist in placing agriculture upon the high plane which it so rightly deserves. The one great activity of this organization is the holding an - nually of the State Fair. The records show — and the records are what we are guided by — that Nebraska's 1920 "Prosperity" State Fair was a record breaker, with a total attendance for the week of 270,664 against a total of 262,458 for 1919. This shows a substantial in - crease, in spite of the fact that the weather man predicted rain and </seg>
            <seg id="p067">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 67 unsettled weather conditions from Monday night until Thursday morn - ing. However, his predictions never materialized but they had the de - sired effect of keeping people with automobiles at home, and we must concede that the automobile is a tremendous factor in the attendance record of any fair of the present time, and will no doubt attain more importance as the good roads program of the state is further advanced. The most successful fair cannot be entirely measured by attendance, as a large attendance with a decrease in exhibits does not make a well balanced fair. However, we can boast of the fact that many of the departments were overloaded with exhibits and, in places, some were turned away. With the record which the Nebraska State Fair maintained dur - ing the period of the war, and the two fairs held since the closing of this world conflict, it has been demonstrated clearly that the state fair has become a real institution of the state, and is so judged by its peo - ple, especially from the fact that an attendance equal to one-fifth of the entire population passed through the gates of this institution in six days. We hear much criticism in regard to the buildings and the grounds being available for use during such a short period of the year. If the same results are obtained within these few days as are obtained by other educational institutions during a period of months, I feel that the criticism is unjust, and is advanced by a party or parties who have not as yet gained the fullest conception of the educational value of the state fair. I am pleased to say that today the fairs are upon a much higher plane than they have been during any period of their history. They will continue to receive greater consideration than ever at the hands of the people who furnish the patronage. The men who are elected to the legislatures in Nebraska heartily approve of an agricultural fair such as Nebraska can boast. Because of this, it is expected they wi'l continue to furnish substantial appropriations, in comparison with those made to other lines of the state's activities, in order that the grounds and buildings may keep apace with the state's growth. With the small acreage contained within our fair grounds, and the numerous old wooden buildings which have long ago served their purpose, we can now see clearer than ever the need of financial as - sistance whereby we can start a well laid building and expansion pro - gram. It is a regrettable fact that in the past our building program has been too much of a hit-and-miss proposition; this from the fact that we have asked for a certain amount to be appropriated for a cer - tain building and when we have been fortunate enough to get the appropriation asked for, it has usually been cut from one-fifth to one - half of the original amount asked for. One of the best instances of </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE this kind is our present swine barn. The appropriation of $100,000.00 was requested for the grading and the erection of this building and when it was finally made, the amount was cut to $80,000.00. There - fore, our plans had to be altered to comply with our purse and, as most of you are aware, we have been short of space to exhibit all of Nebraska's swine which the breeders desired to bring to the State Fair. I trust such conditions as these will be remedied in the future by ade - quate appropriations for the erection of buildings in keeping with the future growth of the several activities which constitute Nebraska's in - dustries, and to the men who are charged with the responsibility of handling the state fair in the future, I wish for them a much easier task in obtaining adequate appropriations to erect buildings and the justifiable expansion of the grounds. A year ago I reported to you the erection of three new buildings and much improvement in the streets and sidewalks. This was made possible by an appropriation from the legislature of 1919. From a successful financial year of 1919 we were also able to maintain an average pace of improvements; for instance, the placing of a combi - nation 15 and 21 inch sewer from the automobile hall straight west on Morton Avenue, connecting with the city sewer west of the present street car entrance. This was a dire necessity and furnishes adequate outlet for our sewerage proposition through the center of the grounds for many years to come. The cost of the same was $8,158.75. The erection of a large toilet building on Dunham Avenue south of the dining hall building was at a cost of $6,500.00. The building of an - other entrance just west of the state arsenal and Butlington railroad tracks cost approximately $700.00. We laid a new cement sidewalk on both sides of Morton Avenue from the street car entrance up the hill to Dunham Avenue, and the placing of curbs and gutters and the installation of the parking spaces at an approximate cost of $6,468.47. The addition of two rows of boxes on the front of the amphitheatre at an approximate cost of $3,300.00 added 996 more seats to our grandstand. The sum of $11,044.00 was paid to the bank and the outstanding notes against the Board were taken up, as final payment of the street car facilities now on the Nebraska State Fair grounds, all of which is owned by the state of Nebraska. The rest of the money listed in the financial report under permanent improvements includes the reconstruction of our electric light system, additions to sidewalks, water system, sewerage system and permanent work done on the build - ings and grounds, making a sum total expended for permanent im - provements from our funds of $46,327.00. In addition to this amount of money, expended from our treasury, there was erected on the grounds this year a new concrete and steel cattle barn, the same tak - ing the place of the one destroyed by fire on the morning of Dec. 17, 1919. The erection of this building was made possible by the busl- </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 PROCEEDINGS NEBBASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICUI.TIBE ness interests of the city of Lincoln, they underwriting an amount of fl50,000.00 for the same. The contract was let and the building erected and ready for occupancy at the opening of the 1920 state fair, a task of no small dimensions. This Board feels very grateful to the individuals who advanced this money and the request has been made of the present legislature to appropriate an adequate amount to reim - burse those who advanced the same, with a fair rate of interest. This building — as perhaps some of you know — covers a ground space of 174x242 feet and is of the double deck type, the ground floor being devoted to the beef cattle, the upper floor to the dairy interests. It drew words of commendation from all who saw it, and ranks favor - ably with the cattle barns built by the Iowa and Minnesota state fairs the past year. Our financial report will show the money advanced for the erection of the building was placed to our credit by the business men of Lincoln and the contractor's estimates as paid by us are on file in the office the same as all other bills. It is a pleasure to note that the buildings and improvements which have been made during the past few years are assuming a perma - nent and uniform architectural design. I would recommend that this program be closely adhered to in the future erection of buildings and the necessary changes in the grounds, to meet the natural growth of the institution. There is a plan under way whereby the athletic authorities of the University of Nebraska are trying out the advisability of using the live stock coliseum for a basket ball gymnasium and they are seriously con - sidering the staging of their 1921 football schedule in the quarter stretch in front of the grandstand. If satisfactory arrangements can be made whereby the University athletic program can be staged on the State Fair grounds, it will mean a large saving to the tax payers of Nebraska in the construction of a new down town athletic field and equipment, which must of necessity come sooner or later. To my mind, it is simply a matter of educating the people in attending these athletic contests at the State Fair grounds instead of the University campus. I desire at this time, after careful consideration, to recommend that the old wooden building originally known as Agricultural Hall be wrecked this year, and that what lumber is available be used in the erection of small, uniform concession and exhibit buildings, finishing the same with a coat of stucco. This change is to fit in with the plan of making the approach to the grandstand more accessible, than at the present time. Right here I might say that we have requested of the legislature an appropriation large enough to pave Humphrey Avenue between the sheep and poultry buildings, the block south of the swine barn, Morton Avenue between the parking space from the street car </seg>
            <seg id="p070">1 70 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE entrance east to the top of the hill, Dunham Avenue from the intersec - tion of Morton and Dunham streets north down the hill to the grand - stand and past the west bleachers. This paving is very necessary to protect curbs and gutters and storm sewers and in expediting the flow of water into the sewers in case of rain, at the same time stopping the dreadful wash from the side hills. I would further recommend, if funds permit, to centralize all live - stock departments, the removal of the old draft horse barns from their present location to the ground north of the swine barn. This to eliminate the danger that has existed of the horsemen being com - pelled to lead their animals through the most congested part of the grounds in order to get them into the show ring. We have been very fortunate in the past, in not having any accidents occur. I make this recommendation with the thought in mind that it may be some time before funds are available for the erection of the type of horse barns which we desire to see located on the space reserved for same at the time the other livestock buildings were erected. The space now occupied by the old draft horse barns should be held in reserve for a building to be known as a strictly educational building, wherein the State University, Agricultural College and Ex - tension Service, Boys' and Girls' Clubs, Public School exhibit and the state institutions would have the proper facilities for placing their work before the people of the state in the most attractive manner. No greater work is being encouraged today than that of the Boys' and Girls' Clubs. It would indeed be distinctly wrong for an institu - tion the size of our State Fair to do anything that would place a handi - cap in the way of the progress of these clubs. There is no greater in - centive to this constructive program for tomorrow than the impetus given through the keen competition furnished by exhibiting at the Fair. Every consideration should be given these youngsters in this, their earnest effort to accomplish the work which they have started to do. No effort should be spared in keeping their interest in farm life their greatest ambition. The basic industry of Nebraska — agriculture — is handicapped every time one of these boys or girls is lost to our rural communities. Let us be liberal in our thoughts and acts toward these American citizens of tomorrow. The 1920 State Fair was the most costly, from the standpoint of dollars and cents, ever staged. This was due to the universal existence of high prices in every activity, which had to do with the putting of this fair together, and, in part, due to our liberal increase in prem - iums. I cannot help but feel that the high point has been passed in inflated prices and that conditions will assume their more natural level during the present year. I do not advocate any decrease in </seg>
            <seg id="p071">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 71 premium money offered for exhibits, as we are closely on a par along this line with other state fairs of the middle west. No other fair in the country presented to its patrons a program of the magnitude of ours. No fair has commanded greater attention from the man interested in fairs and expositions the continent over than has our own State Fair. This was best exemplified last fall when we had as our guests fair managers from the Gulf of Mexico to the Dominion of Canada, and the greater part of the middle west. They had read for three years of the Nebraska State Fair and its feature attraction — the circus — supplemented by automobile racing, horse rac - ing, daring aviators, fireworks spectacles, and the world famous bands and in order that they might see this, the most wondw*ul program of all, secretaries, managers and members of Boards ofvDirectors came personally to see how we did it. I While your Board found it necessary to increase tfte outside gate admission from the time immemorial "half dollar" to seventy-five cents, they took recognition of the fact that they must furnish the peo - ple with a seventy-five cent show. The verdict rendered by the in - creased attendance justified the action taken by your Board of Man - agers. The year 1921 is dawning with its many new problems and I hesi - tate to make any recommendations for the coming year's program re - garding admission charges, attractions, etc. I feel that the men who will constitute the Board of Managers for this year should be in a po - sition to take advantage of any price reduction which may develop as the season wears on. It might be of great interest to you to have some data on what constitutes the official family to properly handle and conduct the pres - ent day State Fair. This official family, brought together once a year for the short period of the Fair consists of the following number, in their respective assignments: superintendents 26; assistant superin - tendents 19; clerks 44; helpers 43; judges 55; ticket takers 63; ticket sellers 43; sanitation 36; concession department 32; automobile park - ing force 22; guards 188; boys camp 126. This makes a total of 697, to which we can add some 40 or 50 for the ground labor force. Thus it will readily be seen that the working force of the state fair consti - tutes the population of an average Nebraska town. In addition to this are the members of the bands, circus, carnival company, all the exhibi - tors and their helpers, and the concessionaries with their assistants, making the total of the people actually engaged on the fair grounds during the week run into the thousands. Allow me to suggest at this time, that I feel the fair has outgrown the system under which our official family is handled and would </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE HOARD OF AGRICULTURE recommend that a more efficient system be installed in handling our several pay rolls, that they may be brought under one head where they can be checked, audited and warrants drawn with less confusion than we have experienced in the past. As this institution will naturally grow larger with each succeeding year, it behooves us to change our methods to meet the added growth and facilitate the vast amount of business which is transacted in the short period of a week or ten days. I have nothing but words of praise and commendation for those charged with the responsibility of the several departments of this or - ganization, for the time and effort which they put forth each year in making our institution a continued success. Realizing that each year finds some changes in the personnel of the working force, and to impart to them the proper working knowledge and information necessary for the correct transaction of the business, both from the standpoint of this organization and the exhibitors, I would recommend that a school of instruction be arranged whereby all detailed information can be given to those charged with the responsibility of the several depart - ments previous to their assuming the obligations placed upon them at the opening of the fair. I would further suggest that the president spend the two weeks previous to the opening of the fair here in assisting to work out the many details involved in the last molding together of the fair. This suggestion is prompted by the fact that many little details accompany - ing the preparation days could be handled by him, leaving the Board members free to immediately take up the supervision of the several parts of the grounds to which they are assigned, upon their arrival. These are some of the most important changes which I deem neces - sary, from past experience. After a careful study of conditions I feel these changes are vital and have to deal with the systematic carrying out of the working program. I feel the time is ripe for an innovation in our carnival and concession business and should I be privileged, I shall urge this strongly to the incoming Board of Managers. I have in mind many minor, detailed changes, for the betterment of the State Fair, but do not desire to consume your time with them as they are matters for your Board of Managers to work out. I have refrained from consuming your time by the presentation of a detailed departmental report. However, I shall make a separate report covering a resume of the 1920 fair and same will be printed in the annual year book. In conclusion, allow me to extend the appreciation of the officers to the other members, to those who so willingly assisted in the handling of this gigantic task, to all the exhibitors who gave unhesitatingly of </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 FBOt'EEDINGH NKIIRASKA STATE BOABD OF AGRICULTURE their time and effort in presenting the wonderful products of the soil and manufacturing plants, to the women and children for their work of handcraft, to those who furnished the recreation as well as the more serious side of the fair, and to the better than a quarter of a mil- lion people who placed their stamp of approval on our efforts by an unstinted patronage of Nebraska's greatest outdoor educational and amusement enterprise — the State Fair. Receipts Advertising _ _ $ 415.00 Boys' Camp _. _ 945.00 Cattle Barn Salvage _ _ 139.00 Cattle Stalls _... _ _ _ 898.50 Concessions _ _ _ 37,859.92 Exhibitor's Tickets _ 1,056.45 Feed Department _ _ _. 5,413.58 Horse Stalls _ _ _ _ 275.00 Interest _ _ 1,431.78 Li ght Department _ _ 1,284.06 Machinery Grounds _ 78.00 Machinery Hall _ _ - 2,654.00 Miscellaneous 183,261.28 r en t _ __ 1,189.71 Percheron Futurity ._ _ _ _ 49.00 Sheep Pens 127.10 Speed _ _ _" 3,285.00 State Appropriation _ 2,000.00 Swine Pens _ _ _ _ 995.10 Ticket Account Bleach ers _ _ _ $11,946.50 General Admissions _ 94,047.00 Grandstand __ _. 23,639.00 Grandstand Night 3,863.50 Grandstand Standing 3,599.50 Season 2,543.00 Sunday and Evening 4,594.50 Vehicle Permits 525. 00 144,758.00 Total $388,115.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 PBOCEKDING.S NKBRAMKA STATE BOARD OK AGRICULTURE Expenditures Advertising Bill Posting $ 609.64 City Papers, Lincoln _ _ 515.10 Farm Papers 56.25 Miscellaneous 619.43 "Nebraska" 1,196.20 Other Dailies _ _ 1,135.55 Plates and Cuts 1,067.17 Posters and Lithographing _ _ _ 1,362.50 9,018.94 Fireworks __ _ 4,362.99 46,911.55 Board Expenses Board 518.90 Delegates _ 363.83 Expense Annual Meeting 1,105.45 Hotel 624.35 Miscellaneous _ 187.05 Officers' Salaries 2,550.00 Railroad Fare _. _ _. 581.14 5,930.72 Boys' Camp 2,514.48 Certificates of Deposit _ _ 9,000.00 Electricity, Express, Freight and Drayage Electricity 1,107.82 Express 198.21 Freight and Drayage 746.10 2,052.13 Fair and Office Supplies 7,587.77 Feed _ — 4,910.12 Guards 5,667.42 Insurance and Bonds 288.40 Speed _ 246.50 Weekly Newspapers 2,210.60 ttractions Aeroplane ..._ 4,000.00 Automobile Races 5,015.56 Bands 9,533.00 Circus 24,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOABD OF AGRICULTURE 75 .Maintenance of Grounds Caretaker _ _ 1,225.50 Electrical Department Labor _ 4,628.23 Electrical Department, Supplies _... 2,755.97 Garbage Contract _ _ 2,296.08 Labor _ _ _ _ _ 10,082.81 Material for Repairs __ 1,811.19 Supplies Fair Grounds _ 1,613.03 24,412.81 Miscellaneous _ _ _ _ 3,015.93 1 Vrmanent Improvements _ _ 19 fi, 327. 76 Postage _ __ _ _ _ 5 2 C . 9 1 lVemiums Class "A", Horses _ _. _ 2,491.00 Class "B", Cattle _ 11,783.00 Class "C", Swine _ _ 6,180.00 Class "D" Sheep _ 2,095.00 Class "E", Poultry 1,194.25 Class "F", Farm Products _ 5,875.75 Class "G", Dairy Products _ 92.00 Class "H", Domestic Products 450.50 Class "I", Bees and Honey _ __ 447.00 Class "J", Woman's Department 591.25 Class "K", Fine Arts J 582.25 Cla?p "L", Educational 1,327.14 Class "O", Better Babies _ __ _ 20.00 Boys' Camp _ 11.00 Horticultural Society _ 1,068.50 Re-issues _ _ __ 232.00 34, 440. 64 Salaries Secretary _ _ __ 4,200.00 Employees 4,245.05 8,445.05 Speed 13,302.13 Stationery __ _ _ 342.37 Superintendents Clerks 1,395.68 Concession Pay Roll _ 1,585.20 Helpers 1,390.59 Ju d ges _ _ 1,638.05 Physicians, Class O _ _ 378.00 Superintendents _ 1,939.99 Assistant Superintendents 1,027.63 9,355.14 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Ticket Sellers and Takers Treasurer's Pay Roll 1,665.49 Superintendent of Gates Pay Roll. _ 2,227.01 3,892.50 Telephone &amp; Telegraph Telephone 448.17 Telegraph 59. 3St 507.49 Water 678.65 Total $389,128.91 TltKASlltKICS RKPORT Mr. President and members of the State Board of Agriculture, your Treasurer begs leave to submit the following report: Receipts Advertising $ 415.00 Auto Hall 2,654.00 Boys' Camp y45.u0 Cattle Barn Salvage 139.00 Cattle Stalls 898.50 Concessions 37,859.92 Feed Department 5/413.58 Horse Stalls : 275.00 Interest 1,431.78 Light Department 1,284.06 Mac'ninerey Grounds 78.00 Miscellaneous : 183. 261. 2S Percheron Futurity 4 U . 0 0 Rent 1,189.71 Sheep Pens 127.10 Speed 3,285.00 State Appropriation 2,000.00 Swine Pens 995.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGBICLLTl RE 77 Ticket Account Bleachers $ 1 1,946.50 Exhibitor's Tickets _ _ 1,056.45 General Admissions 94,047.00 Grandstand _ _. 23,639.00 Grandstand Night 3,863.50 Grandstand Standing 3.599.50 Season _ _.. 2,543.00 Sunday and Evening 4,594.50 Vehicle Permits 525.00 145,814.45 Total _ $388,115.48 Balance on hand Jan. 1920 $ 4,004.57 Receipts for 1920 Fair 388,115.48 Total _ _ $392,120.05 By expenditures, 1920 1919 warrants 144.10 1920 warrants _ __ 388,848.98 388,993.08 Balance $ 3,126.97 Of this amount $279.93 is unpaid warrants, which leaves the bal- ance on hand $2,847.04. We also have $24,000.00 in Nebraska banks, certificates of de- posit, and we have $2,950.00 in Liberty Bonds. The total amount on hand is as follows: Balance in bank $ 3,126.97 Certificates of deposit _... 24,000.00 Liberty Bonds 2,950.00 Total $ 30,076.97 Respectfully submitted, JACOB SASS, Treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Neb., Jan. 17, 1921. TO THE HONORABLE PRESipENT AND THE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE: Gentlemen : We, your Auditing Committee, respectfully submit the following report. We find the receipts and expenditures in the various funds for the year 1920 to be as follows Receipts, 1920 Advertising $ 415.00 Boys' Camp 945.00 Cattle Barn Salvage 139.00 Cattle Stalls 898.50 Concessions 37,859.92 Feed Department 5,413.58 Horse Stalls 275.00 Interest 1,431.78 Light Department 1,284.06 Machinery Grounds _ — 78.00 Machinery Hall 2,654.00 Miscellaneous 183,261.28 Percheron Futurity 49.00 Rent 1,189.71 Sheep Pens 127.10 Speed 3,285.00 State Appropriation 2,000.00 Swine Pens 995.10 Ticket Account Bleachers $11,946.50 Exhibitor's Tickets 1,056.45 General Admissions 94,047.00 Grandstand 23,639.00 Grandstand Night 3,863.50 Grandstand Standing 3,599.50 Season 2,543.00 Sunday and Evening 4,594.50 Vehicle Permits 525.00 145,814.45 Total $388,115.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 79 Expenditures Balance on hand Jan. 1920 $ 4,004.57 Receipts for 1920 Fair _ _ _ 388,115.48 Total _ _ $ 392,120.05 By expenditures, 1920 1919 warrants _ 144.10 1920 warrants _ 388,848.98 388,993.08 Bal ance _. _ _ _ $ 3,126.97 Of this amount $279.93 is unpaid warrants, and we would recom- mend that when these are presented for payment, they be cancelled and re-issued. Included in the expenditures we find $24,000.00 issued for certifi- cates of deposit, placed in Nebraska banks. We have $2,950.00 in Liberty Bonds and your Committee has checked these items in the bank. We have checked the above amounts with the receipts from the treasurer, and find that the totals correspond. We have also checked the concession books and find the receipts as follows: Collected on contracts _ _ $31,166.85 Circus _ 1,860.39 Carnival _ _ 4,593.48 Checkstand _ _. 239.20 Light Department _ _ _. 1,284.06 $39,143.98 This agrees with the records of sued by the Treasurer. the Secretary and the receipts is- We desire to recommend that the heads of all departments shall hand in to the treasurer an itemized list of the amount collected, and the source, and that the Board of Managers work out a plan whereby this can be carried out. All of which is respectfully submitted h. j. Mclaughlin w. b. banning Auditing Committee. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE On motion duly seconded and carried the reports of the Secre - tary, Treasurer, and Auditing Committee were adopted as read. Lincoln, Neb., Jan. 18, 1921. To the President and members of the State Board of Agriculture Gentlemen: We, your Committee appointed on the revision of the 1921 prem - ium list, beg leave to submit the following report, to-wit: That all dates of the 1920 premium list be changed to conform to the year 1921, in this year's premium list. That the incoming Board be empowered to accept or reject spe - cial premiums as received from the several breed associations. That the ticket system when published provide for a return check to be used at the grandstand in place of the reserved seat coupon. PAGE 16: salary of the Superintendent of Camping grounds be raised from |30.00 to $40.00. Eliminate the superintendent of sani - tation, and the superintendent of Class "Q", Feed and Forage, the same to be handled by the Board of Managers. Eliminate all items in the pay roll schedule after "Assistant Class F", same to be turned over to the Board of Managers. PAGE 27: Revision of sections 27 to 30 inclusive, ticket system, be left to the Board of Managers. Make the price of exhibitor's tickets and stalls throughout the premium list conform to the new prices adopted. PAGE 27; section 31, price of pens to be changed as follows: Cattle stalls, double, from $2.00 to $3.00. Dairy stanchions, from $1.00 to $2.00 Swine pens, from $1.00 to $3.00 Sheep pens, from $1.00 to $2.00 PAGE 33: Lot 1, premium number 5, put in ribbon premiums. Change No. 7 to read "Brood mares five years old and over." In No. 11, put in ribbon premiums. PAGE 35: Cut out first paragraph at the top of the page. In No. 23 and No. 24, cut out the amount of the prizes offered, leaving the same blank. In the first line of the next paragraph, after the word "prizes" add the words "and amount of premiums." </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Change the closing date to Aug. 17th for stalls, pens and entries, in Horses, Cattle, Swine and Sheep departments. PAGE 52: In the swine department, make the following pro - vision: "No money will be accepted for pens unless accompanied by the entries, properly filled out." In the swine department, add an additional $4.00 premium all the way through on herds and groups. PAGE 65: Eliminate Lot No. 6. PAGE 75: Class "E", Poultry, make entries close Aug. 31st at six P. M. Add to the poultry department the breeds as recommended by the superintendent of poultry. Refer suggestions for the revision of Class "F", Agricultural Pro - ducts; "H," Domestic Products; "I", Bees and Honey; "J", Textiles; "K", Fine Arts and "O", Better Babies, as submitted by the various superintendents, to the incoming Board of Managers for action. We further recommend that the superintendent of concessions be requested to furnish a surety bond in such sum as the Board of Managers may deem necessary. Respectfully submitted, E. R. PURCELL JOSEPH ROBERTS T. H. WAKE J. A. OLLIS A. W. LAMB Revision Committee. QUESTION — What is the idea of raising the price of swine pens? Mr. Purcell: That was discussed from practically every angle and the superintendent of swine stated that he had talked with a very great per cent of the swine exhibitors and that was apparently very satisfactory to them. I will say further that the cost of cleaning out of the swine pens has been much greater than we had any idea of, and the price of $3.00 is really what it will take to maintain the building. In addition, in Iowa and other adjoining states, where they have closed swine barns, they have adopted the same price of $3.00 per pen. Mr. Purcell moved that the report of the Committee on Revision of the Premium List be adopted, and the motion was seconded and duly carried. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON RESOLUTIONS We, your Committee on Resolutions, beg leave to submit the following: First. These are strenuous days for agriculture. During the war and the years immediately following the armistice the farmers rallied to the call of their government and produced abundant food at high cost. The sudden drop in prices of farm products has caused all livestock and grain farmers serious financial embarrassment — so serious that many find themselves completely bankrupt. They are compelled to pay notes given for labor and equipment to raise corn at a time when corn is worth only one-fourth the former price. We therefore recommend the extension of existing loans at reasonable rates of interest where needed, and urge both the state and national governments to extend all possible legitimate aid in tiding agriculture over this unusual and trying period. We believe the Blue Sky law in its present form has made it possible for stock salesmen to represent that their projects have been approved, or even guaranteed, by the state and because of this mis - representation they have sold Nebraskans millions of dollars of worth - less stock. We also call attention to the fact that our Blue Sky laws give the state no power to investigate or supervise the companies after permits have been issued, thus leaving the promoters free to conduct their companies as they desire, subject only to the general laws. We further call attention to the fact that our present laws do not require any guarantee of performance, as do our insurance and banking laws with their bonds and guaranty funds, thus leaving the stockholders without protection. Therefore, we recommend that the Blue Sky laws be so amended that these defects be remedied. We regret that the Supreme Court of the United States has not handed down a decision on the constitutionality of the Federal Farm Loan Act. The delay of the Supreme Court cost the farmers of Amer - ica millions of dollars in 1920. If a decision is not gfven before March 1, the mortgage bankers will be able to make loans at higher rates for still another year. We respectfully urge an early decision. If the law is declared unconstitutional, we urge the speedy passage of new laws by congress. We believe that our motor vehicle license laws should be so amended that all of the money raised in each county should be held and spent on the roads within said county, except a small amount for the purchase of licenses and the administration of the law. We be- </seg>
            <seg id="p083">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 83 lieve also that the state highways within the county should first be maintained from this fund, and that the remaining portion should be used on other roads. We urge the National Congress and the state legislature to pass laws prohibiting Boards of Trade, bucket shops and other gambling in futures. Regardless of the fact that the prices of farm products have rapidly declined, we find no indication of a general decline in prices of farm implements. Since all other lines of manufactured goods seem to have declined, we believe the implement manufacturer should take his medicine along with the rest. We believe the farmer is war - ranted in using every legitimate means to reduce implement prices. We are in entire sympathy with farmers' economic organizations. We believe that a great opportunity is presented to these organiza - tions as well as all unorganized farmers at the present time. The Farm Bureau is the one farmers' organization with the immediate pos - sibility of becoming a national voice for agriculture. We urge all farmers and farm organizations to give it their support. By so doing farm organizations will materially strengthen their own organizations, for the Farm Bureau plan is to supplement the work of existing or - ganizations. WHEREAS: It is with sincere regret that the State Board of Agriculture, in annual meeting assembled, records the death of our friend and co-worker, W. C. Caley, of Creighton, Nebraska, who de - parted this life on October 29, 1920, and WHEREAS: Mr. Caley was one of the oldest members in point of service, being a member of our Board for seventeen consecutive years; in 1903 and 1904 he served as its second vice-president and the past four years has been a member of the Board of Managers, and WHEREAS: The long continued and faithful service of Mr. Caley in the positions he occupied on the Board are highly appreciated by us, therefore BE IT RESOLVED: That in the death of Mr. Caley we feel the state of Nebraska has been deprived of the services of a very useful and able citizen, those who knew him best of a tried and trusted friend, and the State Board of Agriculture of one of its faithful, efficient and esteemed members, and that we tender to his bereaved wife and fam - ily in this — their hour of sorrow — our most sincere sympathy and con - dolence, and </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE BE IT FURTHER RESOLVED: That a copy of these resolutions be spread on the permanent records of this Board and also that a copy of the same, signed by the officers, be forwarded to the family. CHAS. GRAFF CHAS. PUGSLEY C. H. GUSTAFSON O. G. SMITH GEORGE JACKSON Mr. Roberts: If the automobile money is not spent in the coun - ty where it is raised, where is it spent? Mr. Jackson: If a car license cost $10.00, seventy-five per cent of it comes to Lincoln and five per cent is held here and is spent on fed - eral aid roads; what we are trying to get at is that the license money should be held in the county treasury instead of coming up here. We have in Nuckolls county an average of $25,000 laying up here all the time. We want it left in the county banks, that much in the banks of our county would mean a good deal, then we want the federal roads taken care of first, kept up and maintained, and the rest of it to be under the supervision of the commission. Mr. Roberts: A good many people have an idea that this money is spent outside of the county, but that is a mistake, the money is spent in the county where it is raised; five per cent is spent for overhead in the state engineer's office and seventy per cent is spent for perma - nent roads; but the idea of keeping the money in the county is abso - lutely right. Mr. Graff: The committee have in mind, and discussed this ques - tion a great deal. We are of the opinion that it is a poor law, espe - cially at a time like this, that there should be $100,000 piled up here in Lincoln, taken out of our counties, money that has been needed in the counties, and if it is to be spent there eventually why send it down to some center instead of leaving it where it is to be used? I believe that the legislature will fail to do their duty unless this law is amended to take care of that very matter. Mr. Hoffmeister: A law has already been introduced to amend this law and I move that a certified copy of the first resolution of this committee be sent to each member of congress and to our senators and also to the members of the House of Representatives. Mr. Cheney: I am heartily in favor of the motion. The matter which has been suggested is an important one, as to the money coming down here, and I can speak for our own county in this particular, that during the summer we had several thousand dollars held up after the work was completed and certified and sent to Lincoln because they </seg>
            <seg id="p085">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 85 claimed there was a technical clerical error in some report, and I know that in this one instance our people had to advance the money and pay the help $3,000 and they lost the interest on it for two months. We should have had the money there; we had earned the money and had sent in our report and paid the help and we did not get the money back for more than sixty days, and you know that did not set very well with the boys advancing the money and losing the Interest, and this will simply clarify the law and make it better. I second that motion. It was moved to amend the motion by providing that all resolu - tions except the memorial resolution be printed and copies sent to the members of Congress from this state and to the legislators, the senators and the members of the house of the state legislature. Mr. Jackson offered the following resolution, and moved the adoption of the resolution and that the president and secretary be in - structed to sign the same. WHEREAS: H. M. Kokjer of Clarks, Merrick County, Nebraska, is contemplating making a trip to Denmark and other European coun - tries, and having for forty-two years been active in the work of agri - cultural betterment in the state of Nebraska, therefore BE IT RESOLVED: That the State Board of Agriculture request him — while traveling and visiting at different points — to gather such information as might be of interest and benefit to the State Board of Agriculture and its several activities, and report at the annual meeting to be held in Lincoln in January, 1922. E. R. DANIELSON, ATTEST: Secretary. J. F. McARDLE, President The motion was seconded and carried. Mr. Purcell: In listening to the reading of the reports of the president and secretary it impressed me that those should go to the people of the state and should be in the hands of the various county fair boards of the state and in the hands of all the newspapers of the state. They carry with them a digest of the state fair work that I be - lieve will be of value to the people and the resolutions, I think, touch on vital points at this time, and I move you that the address of the president and the report of the secretary, and that part of the resolu - tions not including the memorial resolution be printed in pamphlet form and distributed as stated. The motion was seconded and carried Mr. Sonderman: In the matter of county fair aid last year, we had under consideration raising the five cents to eight cents. We </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE found that counties with twelve to sixteen thousand inhabitants were under this head and that eight cents revenue for commissioners instead of five cents would be advisable, and I would just like to bring the question up for debate as to whether it will be advisable to adjust this to counties with more than sixteen thousand people, to eight cents in - stead of five cents. Mr. Engles: For the benefit of the gentlemen who were not here yesterday afternoon I would say that we held an informal meeting of all the representatives here yesterday afternoon and have appointed a legislative committee of five who are to report at the banquet this evening, and they are hard at work on this subject and it will be thoroughly discussed at the banquet this evening. Mr. Hoffmeister: I would like to bring another matter to the at - tention of this meeting and that is that our meeting be held at the same time that the agricultural meetings are held, and that the law be changed so that this meeting be held the first week in January. I don't make that as a motion but I think we should talk it over. The President: We have had that under discussion in the Board for some time and we are compelled under the law to meet at this time. I think your suggestion is well made and I would be rather of the opinion that it would be better to leave the date open if possible, say subject to the call of the president, than to limit it to a certain date. Some other conditions may arise in the future which would make it unfavorable to meet at that time. Mr. Mitchell: I remember our experience and that was the ar - rangement before and when we would come in here we found the town so full that it was hard to get any place to stay and it did not prove satisfactory. I believe that our present dates are better even if it does lap over the date of the Denver Live Stock Show, and I believe it is better to leave it as it 1b. Mr. Graff: After a man has been connected with this board for several years he realizes how difficult it is for us to work out these things. If the legislature worked it out so that we could meet at a certain time then they would have to pass a bill which requires "Or - ganized Agriculture" to meet that same week. We have agreed to draw away from that week of organized agriculture for the reason that Mr. Mitchell has mentioned. There is a great difference of opin - ion among the people in Nebraska connected with the agricultural activities and one of the reasons many give is that there are so many meetings that they are not able to attend those they are interested in if they are all bunched up in one week, and the Board of Agriculture has seen fit to make this change. There is no schedule to compel them to meet any certain time and with me it is a debatable question </seg>
            <seg id="p087">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 87 whether it is better the way it is now than the way it was before. I think a few of us have an opportunity to attend those meetings during the week of "Organized Agriculture" and the Board of Agriculture meetings. The Denver Stock Show, we made an effort years ago to have them change their date and one year we prevailed upon them to do so and it happened that they got into a bad week and they have always charged us up with it since and they have gone right on with their show regardless of when we carried on our activities here. Many people in western Nebraska are greatly interested in the Den - ver Stock Show and I believe that it is going to be more popular to carry on this meeting and the winter activities of the agricultural societies in the way we have done this winter than the way we had done it in the past. It is a debatable question. The Secretary: I think perhaps you did not all catch in the message of the president, as I did in reading it, this fact, that he recommended in that message that the Association of County Fairs of Nebraska as an association join the American Association of Fairs and Expositions. Up to a year ago it was impossible for the County Fair Organizations of the several states to belong to that National Organization, but the by-laws were amended a year ago and the state associations were allowed membership in the organization. The fees are 150.00 a year and our president has suggested in his message that the State Board of Agriculture pay the fee for Nebraska and that we pay the expenses of two delegates to attend that convention which will meet in Chicago the first week in December of this year. . I don't think there will be any serious objection from the county fair men to joining that association if the State Board pays your fee and your ex - penses to Chicago. Under that organization you get the protection that the state fairs get. If you have anybody that goes wrong on you, you have protection through that association. I move that the State Board of Agriculture pay the fee for 1921 in the International American Association of Fairs and Expositions for the County Fair Organization in this state and pay the expenses of two delegates to attend the meeting in Chicago next December. The motion was seconded and carried. On motion the Board adjourned to meet in banquet at 6:30 P. M. and for a business session at 10:00 o'clock Thursday morning. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE BANQUET H. J. McLaughlin, Toast master: Twelve months have gone by since our last meeting here and we come together to consider ques - tions that come before the agriculturists of the state. And I will say that this bunch of men has more pep, more determination, than any other bunch of men I ever saw in my life. We come to talk over things in order that we may be more successful and make our fairs more successful, as well as our personal affairs. We are going back as producers to the farm, and in spite of the fact that this year's big crops have been produced at a loss we are going home from this farm meeting to try to produce these crops a little cheaper, but produce them we must. We will make them pay a little better if we can. And I find a determination on the part of the county fair men here attend - ing these meetings to accomplish more, to get more ideas, to carry on our work in a more economical way, and I think before the evening is over we will get into a discussion that will perhaps keep us until morning. If anybody gets sleepy he can sleep but I don't want any - body to leave. Mr. Mitchell read a paper on preparation for county fairs APPROPRIATIONS FOR COUNTY FAIRS After looking over the method of making appropriations for county fairs in Ohio, Iowa, Wisconsin and Illinois I am better astisfied with the Nebraska plan. Ohio allows 2 cents for each inhabitant, based on the last Government census, with an $800 limit; Iowa will appropriate 70 per cent on the first thousand spent for premiums and 60 per cent on the second thousand with a $1,500 limit; Wisconsin offers 80 per cent with certain restrictions; while Illinois pays 60 per cent on the first thousand spent for premiums, 50 per cent on the second thousand, 40 per cent on the next two thousand and 30 per cent on all in excess of four thousand. In Nebraska we are allowed 5 cents for each inhabitant, based on the last congressional vote, multiplied by five. To illustrate: In Thayer county the congressional vote in 1918 was 2,794, multiplied by five gives 13,970, the number of inhabitants which multiplied by five amounts to $698.50, the appropriation we drew in 1919 and last year. Our premiums amounted to about $1,300 each year. We also draw five cents for each child of school age which gives us about $200 additional to be used for school exhibit work. For judges and the extension exhibit we pay out about $300. These figures clearly show that the Thayer County Fair pays out far more for premiums and the </seg>
            <seg id="p089">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE educational exhibit than it secures from appropriations, not including the eight thousand children's free admission tickets issued to children and teachers of Thayer and neighboring counties, good on Children's Day. Our congressional vote last year was increased to 4,355 on ac - count of the women voters, multiplied by five gives 21,775, which at 5 cents each will give us an appropriation of $1,088.75 for the 1921 fair. I believe that every fair should be self-supporting so far as pos - sible, but where liberal premiums are paid and the educational de - partment taken care of an appropriation is absolutely necessary and it seems to me it should be sufficient to cover premiums paid and ex - penses of the educational exhibit and the judges. This expense will approximate $2,000 annually at our fair, about double the amount of our appropriation. It seems to me that the proper thing to do would be to make ten cents for each inhabitant the law instead of five as at present. Instead of the Government appropriating immense sums for Na - tional Expositions, of a temporary nature, I am in favor of making a permanent National Exposition at each state fair, with the Govern - ment appropriating sums sufficient to erect permanent buildings and make exhibits. The state fair ground should be utilized by the state university throughout the year as far as practical and its buildings should be erected with this end in view. The state fair ground should be a park open to the public at all times. At every county fair there should be a state exhibit which should include a Government exhibit. The county 'fair ground should be a public park, open throughout the year, where picnics, Chautauquas or any large gathering could be held. The Thayer County Fair Ground comprises 40 acres (.not half large enough). It is located inside the corporate limits of Deshler, has city water and electric lights. The society has a deed to 20 acres and the city of Deshler a deed to 20 acres. The society has leased its 20 acres to the city for a park ex - cept when wanted for fair purposes and the city has leased its 20 acres to the society for fair purposes. Mr. Shirley Nelson: The subject assigned me is "Boys and Girls Clubs at Fairs." I assure you that this topic is not secondary to any topic that might be selected for this kind of an audience, for one of the real problems today, as has always been, is the problem not to cul - tivate the soil, not to develop the fair, but of producing men and women. Our chairman spoke of the crop that is just in and what big crops there were this year and that you produced it at a loss, but I assure you there is one crop Nebraska has produced steadily year by year upon which she never lost a penny, and that is her crop of </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE men. I am proud ot Nebraska. From the time as a little kid I rode in the tall blue-stem on the banks of one of our best rivers, all the years since then I have been proud of our broad streams, broad prairies, rich soil, but best of all our splendid people in Nebraska. At no time am I more proud of our state than year by year when I stand on the streets of our State Fair and see the multitude of men go by. The men and women that throng those streets, after all, is Nebraska. All she has produced in any direction has been shaped by their brain and nourished in their heart; finding it a desert island they have made it blossom as the rose. The poet and philosopher spoke of that man who could make two blades of grass grow where only one blade grew before, but the men and women of Nebraska have made a harvest of grass grow where God never made any grass. And Nebraska is today what it is because of the kind of people she has had. I often-timeu have coveted the place of Cruick-shank in history when I see the broad back, and the well filled beef quarter at the market place; I often wish I could have been the man in whose heart that thing was born, but I crave still more the place of the man who put it into Cruick - shank's heart and started him on the road, and after all when you put a thing like that into a man's heart you have done the big thing in life, and when you put it in his heart early enough you have done the biggest thing that can be done. I am for the Boys Club work be - cause I believe it is one of the biggest things that we can do, and I am for the Girls Club work because the boys work depends on the girls and money put into the boys and girls club work is in my judg - ment, the best spent money the men and women of Nebraska have ever invested, first of all because it is a matter of conservation. I believe in conservation; in the great timber conservation and in soil conserva - tion; I believe in conserving the water powers of our country; but I am still more in favor of man conservation; that we store up and save the man-power of our state and nation, and I am not half as fond of reclamation as I am conservation, and I don't take any stock in this long-drawn-out cry "back to the farm." With a few exceptions like Ned Brown, I would not give a whoop for the man who has moved to town and come back, nor for the city man on the farm. It is a pro - fession and needs a lifetime of endeavor to develop it and if you have lost the high tide of that young life you have failed in the most im - portant part of his career; and I believe in fostering the boys and girls club work because it is the conserving of power; it is the power of all powers in my judgment to hold the boy and girl back in the old home community where they belong. A lot of them ought not to stay there, and all I am thinking of is to give them a chance at home, and if they are not interested after that, then let them go some place else. In our county we had a Pig Club, about sixty boys, and all of them had fine porkers. They were very proud of them. I had the privilege of visiting moat of the boys while the pigs were in the development </seg>
            <seg id="p091">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 91 stage and was at place after place where the boys were reading the larm paper and man after man told me that his boy watched the mail box and got the paper and he could not get any chance at it until the boy was through with it. The boy had not only invested money in that pig, but life, and he wanted to know all the things in that paper to help him in raising that pig, and he had begun to dream about making a world of success not only in tilling the soil but in that which is much more attractive to the boy, actually handling life, and in controling things that make him feel a responsibility, and when he got through he was captured for life. We had forty of these boys at our county fair and it was a pleasure to me as I noticed every night a bunch of fellows lay there in bed, they were there both day and night, and they were talking about their pigs and they had the different premiums all placed before the judges could get to it. They didn't agree with the judges always, but the fact is that they had sized up those pigs that were there and formed their own judgment on who should have the prizes. I only know of three sore spots in four years, and those boys are learning self-reliance and learning to meet things as they come, and when the hard things come to them and misfortunes come to them and low prices hit them hard they will take it like men, for after all it is the ups and downs of life that has made a lot of you fellows. You would not be all that you are or what you are if the ups and downs of life had not given you the courage to go on with life. And so all these boys and girls clubs are doing just what their pig club has done for them, and if they will do that I am for them, for we want to reach these boys and girls in early life. And the boys are figuring that if they bring their cow-hides and sand-hill corn to town in sacks they will make a better success of Nebraska than we have made, and when they do that they will be going some. Mr. McLaughlin: The rest of the program will be Succotash. Organization seems to be the need and the demand of the hour in this organization of county fair managers, and they are thinking seriously. We have been meeting here year after year and we have this little banquet and one or two set speeches and then some random talks that are good and we come here and go back again to our thinking and wondering why this organization cannot be made stronger and why we cannot do some real work for ourselves. Some think we need legisla - tion; perhaps we do need a little legislation, but if we are going to succeed as men the best help we can get is to help ourselves. If we organize and work together and one fair association stops fighting the other fair association we will get further and do more. So there is this demand for a bigger and stronger organization of fair managers in Nebraska, and that is coming. Yesterday and today we have been in small groups talking perhaps of organization and putting into the field a man or a paid secretary or what ever you like to call him to </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOABD OF AGRICULTURE help us do our work, to help us work more in harmony and one fair work with another to get more good out of the state fair and do more for the state fair, and the hope is that we will thus become enthused to make more of our farms and our livestock, and make better homes and keep our children interested in better things on the farm. We will let this discussion run for a while, and I think Mr. Engles, of Nemaha perhaps wants to open this discussion and I will ask him to speak first and we will then let the different persons speak as they will. Mr. Engles: When my friend McLaughlin named me as chair - man of the legislative committee I did not understand that he was ex - pecting to call upon either of us for a talk tonight and my associates, Mr. Jackson, Mr. Smith, Mr. Mitchell and myself have worked almost continuously for nearly 24 hours in trying to gather the various ideas of the different delegates and what their financial conditions were and what their wishes were for further legislation. During the evening we have prepared a bill and Mr. Smith has that in his pocket to read and I hope it will meet with the approval of this gathering. However that is up to the wishes of you all this evening and open for discus - sion and I would like to have Mr. Smith read that bill and explain it. Mr. Smith then read and explained the bill presented by the legislative committee. Mr. Hoffmeister. I don't know why they have mentioned my name for a speech except to place on exhibition a very rare specimen, I might say an exception in Nebraska, a democrat. There are only four of us located in the big state of Nebraska. There might be some more democrats that are flunking on us just now; a good many claimed that we quit the party but we can't see it so, we are bound to stay by the ship and we have to bear the brunt of it. I am glad to be here this evening. I always enjoy these meetings. I am three hundred miles away from home, I come from Chase County, and that is one of the best counties in the state of Nebraska. You might not agree with me but you would come to it after awhile. And I want to state further that Chase County has had thirty-five fairs and we have never missed one, never missed paying our premiums in full. This is a great agri - cultural state, in fact that is our principal industry and I see by the morning paper that Nebraska now ranks first in the raising of alfalfa, and I am further pleased that I carry a little crop right along with me. So far as this bill is concerned I am not going to discuss it be - cause it does not matter what I might say, we will not be listened to anyway, but now I think it has my approval. There might have to be a little amending to it. Mr. Ehrhardt: I want to say that I have been drafted into this proposition; they have been drafting me for some thirty-four years in </seg>
            <seg id="p093">PROCEEDINGS NEBBAMKA KTATE UOAKU OF AGBICl I.TtRE 93 our county by getting into some little trouble and then shifting it onto my shoulders. I worked quite hard for a number of years as secre - tary and a year ago the president moved to California, he got rich in office as president of the Stanton County Agricultural Society, and 1 was drafted again and I have had considerable grief; I have been so indignant and so mad a number of times that I didn't know what to do when one of the minions of this tax law required a big penalty be - cause we had not paid an income tax, we were thirty or sixty days behind time in paying the tax, and I got about $25 worth of satisfac - tion in writing to the collector and sending a lot of affidavits showing him that we were not subject to an income tax. So far as the raising of alfalfa is concerned I don't know anything about it, and I don't know anything about these Plymouth-rock cattle, I don't know any - thing about Duroc Chickens or Percheron Cows. While I was raised on a farm until I was fifteen years old and then was in the army until I was twenty-two, by that time I had got so lazy I wasn't any good on the farm and I have made my living in town ever since. I have en - joyed this meeting today and am glad to be here, and hope I can be perhaps of some little benefit to the Stanton County Agricultural So - ciety when I get home, from the fund of information I am gathering while I am here. Mr. Jackson: I have felt nervous ever since this banquet started and hardly know what to do. I have lost my reputation as a ticket seller, I know, because we sold so many tickets that we didn't have places enough for the people. For a number of years they have relied upon me to sell tickets and just see what has happened. I just imagine I look like the old negro lady I read about once. An artist went from Washington into North Carolina to sketch some pictures, and in looking around for a suitable back-ground he came to a thicket of timber with a little raised place in the center and there was an old negro lady picking up sticks and he invited her to sit on this raised place and let him sketch the picture. Finally she said, after sitting there for some time, "Say boss, how long this gwine to take?" He said it was going to take about twenty minutes I should judge. He went on with his work and she finally got awful nervous and she said: "Boss hain't that picture about done?" and he said it was nearly done. He said, "are you in a hurry to go?" She said, "No, I hain't in no hurry to go but I am sitting on an ant hill." So I have been sitting on an ant hill. I was glad to hear from Mr. Hoffmeister, to know he was one of the four democrats that was lucky enough to get under the wire. Mr. McLellan: This fair association is something new to me but I enjoy every minute of it. This is the first one I ever attended. I have the honor however to be a member of our Board for Hall County and </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE I have taken quite an interest in it and have been in several meetings you people have had and I have gained a good deal of information about a lot of things but I still have a lot to learn. Mr. Ronin: I have been in the race-horse business about thirty years and during that time I have accomplished a little good and a whole lot of bad. However I believe a good many here are familiar with one of the horses that I have put on the track. I am very fond of horses and am mighty glad of the fact that I have been in the horse business. In Baltimore, Maryland, where I was a few years ago, I said to a young man, "You have an abundance of building material here, we have to manufacture ours where I live, Nebraska." And he said, "You have lots of tornadoes don't you out there, don't most of the people live in the ground?" And he said, "We have lots of corn here in Maryland," and I said "In Dodge county, Nebraska, we raise more corn than the whole state of Maryland," and I invited him sometime to come west and see the country. I said, "you are one hundred years behind the times here." But it took me quite awhile to convince him I was telling him the truth. He thought I was the worst liar he ever saw, but I am proud of Nebraska. Mr. Gould: A great many years ago I was engaged quite heavily in the breeding of horses. About 1902 I had the distinction of hav - ing produced more champion and record breaking horses than any other breeder in the United States. The stock I have raised has gone to New York and Chicago and has sold in competition with those raised in Kentucky, but they were all raised in Nebraska. On the farm now we have something over 125 brood mares and about 83 colts and about 35 or 40 preparing for market in New York. It seems like each crop is a little better than the other and 1 take pleasure in that, more particularly for the entertainment it gives to ourselves and the benefit to the association. I think the bigger part of the life of the county fairs is the racing. Mr. Engles: There is no one here who enjoys these talks more than I do nor enjoys the stories that are told more than I do. How - ever I think it is time that we get down to business as we have some real business propositions to dispose of this evening, one of them is the bill proposed by Mr. Smith. I move that it is the sense of this meeting that we approve and recommend to the legislature for passage the bill as read here tonight by Mr. Smith. Th motion was seconded. QUESTION: About how much would that make the proportion for the average eastern Nebraska county? </seg>
            <seg id="p095">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AQBICULTUBE 95 Mr. Engles: The amount that might be raised in your county would be absolutely impossible for us to determine without knowing the valuation. In Nemaha about $8,000 would be raised by the one mill levy. Mr. Banning: I don't believe that our fellows would stand for that in the eastern end of the state, it would raise an enormous sum ol money here in the east. Mr. Mitchell: This says that it shall not exceed the money actually paid for premiums. The balance would revert to the county general fund. Mr. Engles' motion being put was carried by unanimous vote Mr. Cheney: Moved that the committee which has prepared the bill be requested to see that it is properly introduced in the legisla - ture and to look after its passage. The motion was seconded and carried Mr. McLaughlin: The question we are now about to bring up is where the county fair associations are going to try to help themselves and if we are going to be worth anything it must be through our own efforts, and I will ask Mr. Jackson to tell something of the thingR that have been talked of in this re-organization. Mr. Jackson has been in this county fair work a great many years and I think he is more fitted tor that than any one else here to present this matter. Mr. Jackson: This is a question I have been interested in all my life and if you are interested in the growth and prosperity of our country you too are interested in fairs. This matter of fairs is one I am heartily in favor of, because go back as far as you want to and you will find out that all big things have been built up by organization and co-operation. Every big thing is built that way, both railroads and cities, and we can build up one of the biggest fair organizations in the state, and I know other states will follow in building up the state fair organizations. I don't know what can be done in hiring concessions and reporting on the grafting which travels around to these fairs which we want to cut out and things of that sort which we ought to handle, but there are things that enter into it that will be objection - able and which must be worked out. Conditions are so different in different parts of the state that a secretary for one or two years will not think he is getting anywhere, but it is a matter of education, and 1 am satisfied that a valuable secretary will build up these state and county fair organizations and by so doing will build up the state fair, because if by one stroke of the pen you should knock out all the county fairs in the state, we know you would have no state fair. The state fair is made up of the best people from all over the state from </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE the congressional districts, and the county fairs are made up of the best citizens of the counties, the stock breeders and corn and potato growers and everything along that line that is making the state of Nebraska what she is, and it all comes right down to the home of the breeder of fine stock and all those things. They are holding an ex - periment station at their homes where they talk plants and rations and all those things, and it runs in an endless chain from the state fair to the breeders on the farm and there is no end to the work a field secretary could do. I don't know just the best way to get at this and have no authority to speak for the State Board of Agriculture but I feel that if the county fairs would join this organization and we would have a field secretary and assess the other associations twenty-five to fifty dollars I am satisfied the State Board of Agriculture will meet us half way. They will probably put up as much money for that pur - pose as the county fair associations put up. Mr. Ehrhardt: I am personally in favor of an organization that can function and can do things but would rather hesitate to take it into my own hands to say that the Board of Managers or directors of the Stanton County Fair Association would warrant me in pledging our association to make this subscription. There is no question in my mind that when I make a report to our association they will gladly appro - priate whatever sum may be necessary. If you will fix it at $25 I would rather pay it myself than have the matter not function, but I don't feel at this time that I ought to pledge our association to a mat - ter they absolutely know nothing about. Mr. Cheney: I am sure our western county fairs are heartily in favor of this movement. They have at all times been enthusiastic supporters of this little association we have had for eleven years, or - ganized at the suggestion of Mr. G. W. Harvey of Omaha. It has been suggested, however, that perhaps it would be fair to scale this thing just a little and for the fairs from the west, while we are not asking for any particular favors, that you make a scale so that it would not be uniform. Fifty dollars for some of the large fairs where their attendance will run from 25,000 to 30,000 would be far less than $25 would be for fairs whose attendance is under 10,000, and possibly it ought not -to be charged to all alike. While I am sure our fair association will gladly come to the front I feel like by friend from Stanton county that we are not authorized to pledge our as - sociations to something which they know nothing about at this time. I am in favor of this thing and for the purpose of getting the matter before the house I move that the matter of perfecting an or - ganization and securing a field secretary be referred to the president and secretary of this organization with power to act. The motion was seconded. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Mr. Smith: I want to say I think you are starting on the right road but think you are putting a good deal of a burden on the chair - man and secretary. I am in favor of a movement that will bring about a better organization. We have been organized eleven years and we come here and meet and have done well but not as well as we should have done. I believe the committee ought to be larger. I be - lieve there should be a representation from every congressional dis - trict in this state to help the chairman and secretary. I think they ought to be empowered when they can get a sufficient number pledged to go on and do business. I move to amend this motion that the committee to take care of this matter consist of one from each congressional district and the president and secretary also act as members. The amendment was accepted by the mover of the motion, Mr Cheney. Mr. Lawrence: I think this motion is a move for the best that could be done, the best thing that could happen to the county fairs, but I am somewhat struck with something we used to study in school, which was arithmetic. We have sixty county fairs and at $25 if you get them all in that would be $1500, and at $50 a piece it would be $3,000. It will cost $1,000 a year for that man to travel and visit as often as needed all the county fairs of the state. The chances are you will not get more than 50 per cent of the fairs in to start with. If you are going to get any cheap John man as secretary you better not start it. I just offer that as a suggestion. A Member: I was wondering just a little bit, I have always dis - covered that when you load a gun wfth fine shot or more than one bullet it is likely to scatter considerably, and while I think it may be wise to have an assistant to the committee I would rather make it one or two. I think some one should feel the responsibility is on their shoulders and then you have action. I suggest that the secretary for the first year act as field man, and one from each congressional dis - trict act as an advisory board. But if you were to get seven or eight together every time there was anything to consider you will never get anything considered. This association has a president, a vice president, a secretary-treasurer, and it seems to me this matter could be turned over to them with power to act and to call to their assist - ance any member of this association living in any congressional dis - trict of the state, and then you have the three principal officers of the association responsible for the business and responsible to get just as much work out of the balance of us as they possibly can. It was moved and seconded that this matter be referred to the executive committee, the president, vice president and treasurer-secre- </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE tary of this association with power to call to their assistance any mem - bers of the association and to go ahead and perfect this work. The motion was seconded by Mr. Lawrence. Mr. Lawrence: The county fairs are going to make money out of this organization and will be having a secretary to help them and if they put in $25 or $50 they will get that back in benefit to the county fair. It will perhaps be more than that but it will bring back the money in the long run. Mr. Graff: I believe that we are all agreed upon this one propo - sition, that we need a closer organization, that we need more co - operation with the state fair board, and in fact you men that are con - nected with the county fairs know that you are a part of the state fair. I am not able to guarantee to you that the state board will do this or that but I will take the responsibility upon myself to say to you men that all of you who are representing county fairs, if you are willing to put up a certain sum of money to carry out this great project, which I believe is the one thing to do, that the State Board of Agriculture will match every dollar you put up. They realize that in order to build up a great state fair they must continue to look to the county fairs in this state. I believe that the project is Easily worked out. J don't believe there is a county fair association in the State of Ne braska that would be so small as to hang back and refuse to come in and support this great movement and thereby lose the great opportun - ity that it would have. I hope that you will get together and put this thing on the map. And I will say about the secretary'* office, you know what it is, you know that you are welcome there and that you will receive all the aid the State Board can give you and we will take upon ourselves a great part of the work that must be done without it costing the county fairp one cent. Another proposition, it has been mentioned and the State Board of Agriculture has decided that it will be well for you men to get a closer organization and select two men annually at your meetings to represent you at the association of fairs and expositions held at Chi - cago, and the State Board stands ready to pay the expenses of those two delegates that you select, and you will get in touch with the men that you must find in order to put on amusement features and such things at your county fairs, and you will be able thereby to get this information for less money than where you all go by yourselves. I don't wish to dictate about how you will go about it but I say to you fellows that this is a day of co-operation. In every agricultural move - ment it was always one of my missions to call attention to the fact that we must get all of these agricultural organizations heading to one great center. You must do this through the State Fair to get any- </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Or AGRICULTURE where, and I hope you will decide this evening to do something, some - thing that will start you along the lines which will mean much to your county fairs all over this great state of Nebraska. As Mr. Law - rence says, it is doubtful if half of the county fairs will come in at first, but I don't know of a county fair that if it is explained to them in a proper light but would be more than willing to give $25 or $50 because it would be the greatest investment they can make toward their county fair. Mr. Lamb: I believe a man is guilty if he comes to one of these meetings and has something he feels he ought to say and don't say it. You can't get any force out of any organization unless you get three - fourths of them. I belong at Tecumseh and I have spent lots of time for the county fair and I am willing to put more into it. I don't know just exactly what I think about this, but since Mr. Graff talked I feel somewhat as he does when he says the state fair is really the head of all our shows. If that is true, without any of our county shows lining up to start this wouldn't it be like a child telling the parent what to do, and my thought would be wouldn't it be a good idea for the State Fair Board to have an assistant secretary and they could send him out and attend to a lot of this business and help line up the best we have in every county fair for the state fair. These things have come up to me hurriedly and I might change my mind about them. -" Mr. Graff: We have a place for such a man in our office and would be glad to assist him in every way possible and I believe the State Board would go 50-50 with the county fairs on expense. A Member: That comes right along the line I have been think - ing of. In regard to the amount for each association to pay it is pretty hard to determine, there is such a difference in the strength of the organizations. While $50 is not very much it is considerable for a county that has an attendance of maybe 1,500 or 2,500 people. Could not a deal be arranged so that a certain proportion of each county fair fund could be turned to the State Board of Agriculture for their part of the expense of the secretary; say our county turned over 5 per cent, that would be about thirty or thirty-five dollars. Mr. Mitchell: I believe that we are all interested in this mat - ter but the way it comes before us we hardly know how to work It out. Since I have been secretary of the Thayer county fair I have been trying to find out what Is good in the amusement line. The people want good amusements. I have tried to find out about the at - tractions and whether they are satisfactory and how often they have got let down. I tried to get a good clean carnival company, realizing If we could get a good amusement line, that is necessary to make any </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE county fair a success and we would all be glad to get them under one bead. I have been working along that line and the matter of cost seems to me is a secondary consideration and I believe that every or - ganization will pay their share if the executive committee is authorized to go ahead and formulate some plan and act and a little later they may be able to say about what it is going to cost. Mr. Danielson: I am sorry that I have not heard all the remarks that have been made here this evening. I am placed in rather a peculiar position in this matter. I admit I stirred up perhaps What you might call a hornet's nest this year. I have spent four years as secretary of the state fair board and have put everything I have into that work. I am saturated with it and no truer words have been said than that it is "in the blood" and you can't get it out. I have car - ried the responsibility of the state fair in my mind and I have carried the responsibility of the county fairs in Nebraska. I haven't got out among you as I should have done and there is a reason for that; four years ago I left the farm, I tried to run it one year after I left and found that labor conditions were such that I could not do it and I had to rent it and you know what has transpired in those four years and you know what living expenses have been especially in a city of this size. I have a family of five which I am trying to educate and I think my wife and myself and family are entitled to a fair living. We have been getting it to a certain extent; but I have spent my money to make the state fair the biggest thing in Nebraska and you know everybody liked it and it has cost me money every year I have been in Lincoln to run the state fair. So far as the work is concerned there is no work too long and no job too hard for me to undertake to make a success of the fair. You have discussed the proposition of organization. I don't like the idea of assessment because you will not get them all in and I want an organization that is 100 per cent. I want to see the county fairs in Nebraska subdivided into districts with a vice president placed over each of those districts. I want to stop all the overhead expense we possibly can, and those are the problems you have to fight and you have been fighting them individually; I think .you have done more business yesterday and today and in the five years gone by. I am not reflecting on the past officers, but you did get together and get to thinking about these things. This is a day when men, to prove a suc - cess in any activity must pull together. You must organize, there was never a time in the history of man when it was as essential to or - ganize as it is today, or when one man was as small as he is at the present time. I don't want to beat anybody out of a job. If you want me to go into this thing I will do it and will do the best 1 can for you and if you do like me and fire up the steam engine away we'll go. I want to be in a game where we can get somewhere. We can have power but we can be clean with it and we are not asking for any- </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 PROCEEDINGS NKKKASKA STATK BOARD OF ACiRHTI.TI RK thing only what we are entitled to. I have been harping on this or - ganization to get together for a long, long time. My heart has been in it and my soul is in it and my life is in it. I saw how you were working and it seems to me up to the present time you have been missing a good deal, that you have been hitting occasionally on two or three cylinders. Let us hit all six cylinders together and if you think I can handle this thing I will do it and if not I will forget everything I have done in the past and we will go ahead on something else. I think you should handle this through the State Board of Agriculture where it will cost the county associations almost nothing. The State Board should head this organization and everybody drop in line and have a 100 per cent parade. The substitute motion made on this matter was hereupon stated to the assembly and carried. It was moved that the offer of the State Board of Agriculture to pay the expenses of two delegates to the Chicago meeting be accepted by this organization. The motion was seconded and carried It was moved that the president and vice president of this asso - ciation be elected as delegates to the Chicago meeting. The motion was seconded and carried. Mr. Cheney moved that the present officers of this association be declared the officers for the coming year and that the rules be sus - pended and the secretary cast the unanimous vote of this association for these officers. The motion was seconded, as stated by Mr. Cheney and unan - imously carried, the ballot was cast and the officers declared elected, as follows: President — H. J. McLaughlin, Doniphan Vice President — E. J. Mitchell, Deshler Secretary-Treasurer — W. H. Smith, Lincoln. Mr. Mitchell moved that a vote of thanks be returned to the Com - mercial Club of Lincoln for the courtesy of the banquet furnished the association tonight. The motion was seconded and carried Adjourned. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 PROCEEDINGS NEBBA8KA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE SECXJ.ND DAY — MORNING SESSION The State Board of Agriculture was called to order at 9:00 o'clock A. M. on Wednesday, January 19, by President McArdle. The Committee on Credentials presented its final report which on. motion duly seconded was adopted. Roll-call showed a quorum present and the Board proceeded to the regular order of business. Mr. Smith: I move that the treasurer of the State Board be di - rected to pay all delegates and members of the board $5.00 per day for three days and the railroad fare for attending this meeting. The motion was seconded and carried. The next order of business being the election of officers the presi - dent appointed as tellers Messrs. Cheney, Hawk, and Smith. Ballot being taken resulted in the casting of fifty-seven votes and the election of the following members of the board. First District — C. J. Warner and A. J. Weaver. Second District — J. F. McArdle, Omaha Third District — Charles Graff, Bancroft; A. W. Lamb, Albion William Prahl, Pierce. Fourth District — E. R. Danielson, Osceola; T. H. Wake, Seward; C. H. Gustafson, Mead. Fifth District — George Jackson, Nelson; J. H. Harms, Wilcox; C. J. Crews, Culbertson. .Sixth District — C. S. Hawk, Chadron; Z. T. Leftwich, St. Paul; W. L. McNutt, Ord. These members having received the majority of all votes cast were declared duly elected as members of the board for the coming term. Election of Officers — For the position of president for the coming term Mr. J. F. Mc- Ardle was nominated. Mr. Purcell moved that the rules be suspended and the secretary be authorized to cast the unanimous vote of this board for Mr. McArdle as president for the ensuing year. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 103 The motion was seconded and carried, the secretary cast the vote and Mr. McArdle was declared elected as president. Mr. McArdle: I am not going to take any of your time, later in the game when I retire permanently I want to be in position to thank you gentlemen for your kindly consideration. I am glad to be with you another year and all I ask is the loyal support that you boys have given me in the past and that my predecessors have received from you in the last fourteen or fifteen years in the association. First vice president. Charles Graff was nominated and on mo - tion duly seconded and carried the rules were suspended and the sec - retary cast the unanimous ballot of the organization and Mr. Graff was declared elected as first vice president. Mr. Graff: It is a question whether you men have chosen wisely and perhaps before the year is out you will feel differently. If a fellow can do anything now days he is likely to draw fire. A. man in order to stand for what he believes is right is sure to meet with more or less opposition and of course in my labors in connection with the State Board I want to do it along the lines that will permit me to feel that I can be satisfied with myself in doing those things. If I cannot satisfy you I at least want to try and satisfy myself in the action that I take. I don't want to make any speech but I want to thank you for this honor. Second vice president. George Jackson was nominated, on mo - tion duly seconded and carried the rules were suspended and the sec - retary cast the unanimous vote of the board and Mr. Jackson was de - clared elected as second vice president. Mr. Jackson: I am not going to even attempt to make a speech but I just simply want to thank you for this continued confidence. Treasurer. W. B. Banning was nominated. Mr. Sass moved that the rules be suspended and the secretary cast the entire vote of the board for Mr. Banning as treasurer. The motion was seconded and carried. Mr. Banning: I want to thank you for the honor, because I do consider it an honor; but at the same, time gentlemen I appreciate far more the friendship and the good fellowship of the Board of Agricul - ture than I do the office. It is always a pleasure to me to come to these meetings and meet the progressive fellows of Nebraska and I as - sure you in this office I will do my best and if we don't get money enough to carry this thing along I shall come out and take it away from some of you. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE Mr. Lawrence moved that the Board extend to Mr. Sass, the re - tiring treasurer, a vote of appreciation for the excellent work and faithful service that he has given to the Board as treasurer during the past year. The motion was unanimously carried Secretary. Mr. Purcell nominated E. R. Danielson and on mo - tion duly seconded the rules were suspended and the president cast the unanimous ballot for Mr. Danielson and he was declared duly elected as secretary for the coming year. Mr. Danielson: Men, I think I realize your appreciation of my work here. I have not spent four happier years in my life than the last four years in doing the work that we have been doing here. I can see no reason why this work cannot continue art grow and be en - larged from what it is at the present time. I feel satisfied that the Board of Agriculture and the county fair organizations of the state of Nebraska, in getting together, are going to do something worth while and I stand in the same position that I have all the way through. I am here to do all I possibly can to further your interests and in do - ing that I am doing what I consider best for one of the greatest, fastest growing states in the union. I thank you men and I trust that I will continue to deserve your confidence and to retain it in the future. As additional members of the Board the president appointed Messrs. Leftwich, Purcell, Wake and Sass and on motion duly seconded and carried the appointments were confirmed by the Board. The following motion was offered. I move that the Board of Managers arrange to give cordial recognition to the past presidents of this Board and that they be given a suitable badge of recognition for their past services, such past presidents to have no special power other than in an advisory capacity. The motion was seconded and unanimously carried Mr. Smith moved that in appreciation of the splendid work done by the secretary for this association during the past four years the Board recommend that the secretary's salary be raised to $5,000 per year. The motion was seconded and unanimously carried by the Board. Mr. Lawrence: I would like to make a little report to you rela - tive to the county fair exhibits whicn the University has been sending out to the county fairs. There have been some questions put to me, not criticisms exactly but feeling that I ought to be able to tell them today whether the counties can have that University exhibit. It is im- </seg>
            <seg id="p105">PROCEEDINGS MCHRAKKA STATE BOARD OF AORICULTl'RE 105 possible to do that because you have not all sent your dates in and have not told me whether you want the exhibit or not. Last year it was way in July before I was able to find out the dates of some of the fairs and whether they wanted the exhibit or not. Of course you should let us know as soon as possible. We feel that this exhibit is a very valuable one and we got requests from seven thousand people for literature from those fairs last year so we believe that the educa - tional part of it from that standpoint has been worth while. Second, in getting your program lists they have not run along right in accord with the state fair catalogues and I have felt that there might be some assistance offered to you, if you want it, in getting out a helpful pro - gram and we are getting out a suggestive one and will send it out to you if you desire it. This is simply an advisory program list to keep you posted and to keep you from getting entangled in your own pro - grams. Third, there has been considerable stress laid in this meet - ing on the entertainment side of the county fair. Three years ago I told you how the county fairs are made up of two sides, one is the en - tertainment side and the other the exhibition side and I wonder how many of you find difficulty in getting people to exhibit each year Btronger and better? That is the basis of the county fair. The en - tertainment is necessary but I think the stress has not been laid on the exhibit side as strongly as it ought to be. I have brought to my attention a few weeks ago a plan worked out by a man in this state relative to getting the school districts working in a competitive way on school exhibits in these county fairs; that combines many things that I have talked to you about previously in getting more children to working on the county fair exhibits. If you people are interested in seeing what that proposition is I will prepare it and have it sent out to you. This is a scheme for working out advancement of the county fairs and if you will notify me I will try and send it out to you. Mr. Mitchell: The committee appointed last night finds this work is in a very experimental stage. Briefly this is the plan that we are going to take. We will prepare a circular letter as soon as we can get it in the hands of the printer and that letter will suggest the object of this committee and there will be questions and we will want to know your fair dates and how much money you will want to pay out for attractions and whether you have a night fair, whether you have fireworks and whether you have a carnival, and we will want you to send that back so we can have them all in here within three weeks. At that time the concession men will be in here and we can take that data and arrange the program to be sent for your approval. We have to have your co-operation if we arrange this and fix it so you can get (he attractions of merit. If you ' have already contracted you can make that notation in there. It is not likely that we will get a field man in charge this year; we will have to work up to that. Meantime </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE if you need the service of a, man we will try and have a man come to you who knows what you want and what you need and is able to help you. We believe that this will amount to a whole lot, but it is up to you whether it does or not. Mr. Smith moved that the Board be directed to make any changes in the premium list that may be necessary. The motion was seconded and duly carried. Mr. Purcell moved that we extend our best wishes through the secretary to Mr. C. G. Crews in the hospital at Omaha and hope thai he will have a speedy recovery and that we instruct the secretary to send flowers to Mr. Crews on behalf of this Board. The motion was seconded and unanimously carried Mr. Keefer: There is a new recommendation by the governor that all these societies come under the Board of Agriculture and I think all of the societies ought to get behind that thing and not work at cross purposes. Mr. Cheney moved that the Board of Agriculture endorse the recommendation of the governor in section 12 of the agricultural pro - gram of the governor's message, and that the secretary forward a copy of this resolution to the governor, and that the recommendation also be made to the governor that the associations put under the man - agement of this body be allowed a representative in the meetings of the State Board of Agriculture. The motion was seconded and duly carried On motion the State Board of Agriculture adjourned </seg>
            <seg id="p107">PREMIUMS AND ENTRIES IN CLASSES 1920 STATE FAIR </seg>
            <seg id="p108"/>
            <seg id="p109">PKOCEEDIN'GS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 109 CLASS "A" — HORSES — 192O Percent paid of premiums offered, 57.9. LOT Number of Entries Amount of Premiums Offered Amount of Premiums Paid 1 2 3 4 5 Percherons Clydes, Shires Belgians Ponies, not to exceed 12 hands high _ Show or herd of recorded horses any age Saddle Horses _ Mules Jacks and Jennets 97 10 15 77 | 9 15 $1,610.00 698.00 648.00 585.00 Diploma 75.00 391.00 347.00 $1,279.00 170.00 200.00 545.00 6 7 8 14S.W 184.00 Totals 225 $4,354.00 I $2,523.0&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE GLASS "B"— CATTLE— 1 920 LOT Number of Entries Amount of Premiums Offered Amount of Premiums Paid 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 .0 .1 Breeding Shorthorns „ Breeding Heref ords Breeding Aberdeen Angus Breeding Galloways Breeding Red Polled Breeding Polled Durham Pat Cattle Breeding Jerseys Guernseys Breeding Ayrshires Breeding Holsteins 176 129 58 30 132 71 34 60 53 54 187 $ 2,292.00 2,060.00 1,614.00 943.00 1,446.00 1,290.00 740.00 914.00 669.00 669.00 1,244.00 $ l,888.0i l,993.0i 1,123.01 872.01 l,435.0i 1.006.01 585.0i 787.01 607.01 617.0i 1,174.01 Totals 964 $13,881.00 $12,087.01 Percent paid of premiums offe: ed, 87. </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE CLASS "C" — SWINE — 1920 Percent paid of premiums offered, 80. LOT Number of Entries : Amount of Premiums Offered Amount of Premiums Paid 1 2 3 4 5 6 Poland China. Spotted Poland China.... Berkshires Duroc Jersey. Chester Whites Hampshires Mule Foot I I 549 162 109 666 257 292 $1,711.00 474.00 694.00 2,040.50 1,094.00 1,539.00 146.00 I $1,528.00 333.00 641.00 1,286.00 1,052.00 1,481.00 Totals _ ... 2,035 2,035 $7,898.50 16,321.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 PROCEEDINGS MCKRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE CLASS "D" — SHEEP — 1920 LOT Number Amount of of Premiums Entries Offered Amount of Premiums Paid 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 Cotswolds | Leicestors and Lincoln Shropshires Hampshires Oxfords I South downs Ramboullets Merino For Amateur Sheep Growers....! Milch Goats I 50 46 170 57 114 37 49 31 68 31 $ 257.00 242.00 314.00 284.00 302.00 242.00 242.00 242.00 200.00 48.00 $ 257.00 235.00 314.00 284.00 302.00 239.00 207.00 233.00 178.00 37.00 Totals . 653 $2,373.00 $2,286.0&lt; Percent •aid of iremiums offe ed, 96. </seg>
            <seg id="p113">PROCEEDINGS. NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AQJUCL'LTURE 113 CLASS "E" — POULTRY — 1920 Number j Amount of Amount of LOT of Premiums Premiums Entries Offered Paid 456 1 American $ 600.00 $ 281.00 Asiatic J 73 320.00 640.00 360.00 200.00 80.00 2 3 Mediterraneans _...! 367 213.50 105.00 4 English _ I 115 Polish 75 67.50 5 6 Hamburgs 16 80.00 20.00 7 French 40.00 I Continental 6 80.00 5.50 9 Games and Game Bantams. I 6 200.00 6.00 10 Ornamental Bantams 43 80.00 39.50 11 Ducks I 138 160.00 120.00 160.00 Geese _ _ 86 100.00 12 13 Turkeys I 1 60.00 .50 14 Capons I 3 3.50 3.50 15 Rabbita 232 363.50 122.50 $3,307.00 $1,204.50 Totals 1,616 Percent paid of premiums offered, 36.4. </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTUKB CLASS "F-— FARM PRODUCTS— 1920 LOT Number of Entries Amount of Premiums Offered Amount of Premiums Paid 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 L0 LI L2 13 Threshed grains, legumes and other large seed Seeds of millet, forage grasses and legumes Mitture corn — Eastern Mature corn — Western _ Corn growth of 1920 — Eastern.. Corn growth of 1920 — Western Sheaf display Stalk display Vegetables _ ~ Baled Hay Vine Products Sweepstakes County Collective Exhibits 514 166 115 268 177 219 970 412 772 38 333 23 19 $ 281.00 166.00 135.00 270.00 215.00 430.00 410.00 138.00 451.00 88.00 263.00 44.00 4,000.00 $ 187.00 84.50 135.00 214.50 186.00 202.50 324.50 97.00 296.00 38.00 150.00 22.00 3,932.16 Totals 4,026 $6,891.00 $5,869.1 Percent paid of premiums offei ed. 85. </seg>
            <seg id="p115">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 115 CLASS "O" — DAIRY PRODUCTS— 1920 LOT Number of Entries Amount of Premiums Offered Amount of | Premiums Paid 1 2 3 4 5 Farm Butter ." Ornamental Butter.... Grand Sweepstakes.... Cheese Milch Cows i 6 7 $ 36.00 28.00 5.00 18.00 74.00 $ 161.00 $ 18.00 37.00 $ 55.00 Totals 13 Percent •aid of iremiums offei ed, 34. </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE CLASS "H"— DOMESTIC PRODUCTS— 1020 LOT Number of Entries Amount of Amount of Premiums Premiums Offered Paid i 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Bread and Cake _ Canned Fruits and Vegetables.. Preserved Fruits Conserve —...-. _ Jellies, Jams and Marmalades.. Fruit Juices Pickles Salted and Dried Miscellaneous Collective 216 256 92 13 218 27 127 25 61 9 | 159.00 f 107.50 119.25 92.50 45.00 34.00 6.75 6.25 103.50 86.75 22.50 13.00 81.00 61.25 15.75 12.00 33.75 23.50 10.00 10.00 Totals 1,044 $ 597.50 $ 446.7 Percent paid of premiums offe: ed, 75. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 117 CLASS "I" — BEES AND HONEY — 1920 Number ! Amount of I Amount or LOT of Premiums Premiums Offered Paid Entries 1 Bees and Honey — Open to the world I 123 $ 324.00 $ 324.00 2 Professional Class — Sweep- stakes 3 3 4 Honey Vinegar | 6 Totals 136 $ 447.00 | 447.00 Percent paid of premiums offered, 100. 100.00 13.00 10.00 Honey Producing Plants 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE CLASS "J" — TEXTILES — 1920 LOT Number of Entries Amount of I Amount of Premiums , Premiums Offered Paid 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Household Fabrics and Quilts. Antiques Old Ladies' Department Crocheting . Knitting Tatting Cross Stitch Hand Sewing French and English Eyelet Embroidery Needle work — not otherwise specified or entered in other classes Professional List Sofa Pillows Baby Department 35 46 166 476 32 1S3 54 106 $ 38.25 24.00 138.50 120.75 40.50 45.75 27.50 41.25 * 27.00 13.00 81.00 107.25 21.00 44.25 27.50 41.25 lO 87 48.00 34.00 1 .2 3 252 3 37 155 123.75 6.00 33.75 ' 93.00 89.25 6.00 14.25 66.75 Totals 1,632 * 781.00 $ 572.50 Percent lid of iremiums offe: ed, 76. </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE CLASS "K" — FINE ARTS — 1920 Number LOT of Entries Amount of Amount of ; Premiums Premiums Offered Paid 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 I 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 Professional — Oil Paintings 62 Water Color 97 Pastel 62 Pen and Ink. _ 61 Pencil or Charcoal 90 Textile Design 20 Miscellaneous Design 40 Amateur Oil Paintings 28 Water Color 30 Pastel _ 5 Charcoal 3 Pencil 22 Pen and Ink 13 Juvenile List _ 16 Pencil 2 Pastel 8 China Painting or Ceramics 84 China Painting or Ceramics (Conventional) 73 China Painting or Ceramics (Amateur List) 134 Wood Carving, Not Burned. 6 Basket Craft _ _ 18 Bead Work 3 Leather Work 3 Arts and Crafts _ 18 Antiques 2 - $ 45.00 % 44.00 50.00 50.00 50.00 50.00 50.00 41.50 50.00 50.00 15.00 11.50 40.00 34.50 33.00 21.00 29.25 22.75 25.50 " 5.25 14.20 2.00 14.00 9.50 10.50 6.00 12.00 4.75 4.50 .50 9,00 3.00 127.00 77.00 99.50 55.00 68.50 59.00 18.75 4.50 12.00 12.00 7.00 2.00 16.25 2.25 17.50 13.50 LOO 1.00 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 ! I I Totals 900 Totals $ 819.45 $ 582.50 I J ! Percent paid of premiums offered, 71. Percent paid of premiums offei </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE CLASS "L"— EDUCATIONAL— 1920 Percent paid of premiums offered, 75. LOT Number of Entries Amount of Amount of Premiums Premiums Offered Paid 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 IS 19 20 21 Boys' and Girls' Club Work by any Standard Club Boys and Girls' Club Work by County Demonstrations Pigs Poultry Garden Products _ Potatoes _ Canned Products Preserves Pickles and Relishes Course 1 Canning Club Course 2 Canning Club Cooking and Baking Sewing Crocheting Knitting Tatting Cross Stitch _ Sofa Pillows „ Illustrated Booklets Penmanship : A — Rural Schools B — Town and Village Schools C— City Schools Maps Woodwork Free Hand Cutting: A — Rural Schools B — Town Schools C— City Schools Original Water Color: A — Rural Schools B — Town Schools C — City Schools Drawing: A — Rural Schools B — Town Schools C — City Schools Buildings and Grounds Collective Display of School Work 14 7 33 747 21 96 1 365 26 48 7 2 86 203 59 3 3 | 70 $ 40.00 40.00 154.00 972.00 136.50 108.75 15.00 180.00 48.75 90.00 30.00 30.00 60.00 112.50 48.75 26.25 15.00 15.00 18.75 15.75 12.50 12.50 12.50 22.50 108.75 22.50 22.50 22.50 18.75 18.75 18.75 18.75 18.75 18.75 25.00 60.00 I I 40.00 40.00 154.00 972.00 33.25 64.00 152.75 20.25 39.00 30.00 18.00 52.75 69.00 34.00 3.50 3.25 " 5.90 15.25 10.75 9.75 12.00 22.50 53.50 18.50 15.15 15.50 12.50 12.25 13.30 15.00 18.25 14.75 10.00 60.00 44 25 29 82 48 22 23 24 41 22 21 25 37 28 25 26 64 39 32 9 27 28 52 Totals .. 2,394 $2,590.75 $2,060.60 I </seg>
            <seg id="p121">PROCEEDINGS NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE 121 CLASS "O" — BETTER BABIES Number Amount of Amount of LOT of Premiums Premiums Entries Offered Paid Neb. Spoons Spoons and 1 Rural ; 74 and Ribbons Ribbons Neb. Spoons Spoons and 2 Town .' 63 I and Ribbons Ribbons Neb. Spoons Spoons and 3 I City, 78 ! and Ribbons Ribbons Improvement Class 10 $20.00 $20.00 4 225 $20.00 $20.00 Percent paid of premiums offered, 100. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>