<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE GAME AND FISH COMMISSION OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1912 TO THE GOVERNOR</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">Eame and Fish Commission * &gt;i i } ii STATE OF NEBRASKA I OR THE TWO YEARS ENDING DECEMBER II TO THE GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">To His Excellency. Chester H. Aldrich. Governor of the State of Xebratka: Deaii Sir — I have the honor to submit herewith a report of the finan - cial conditions of the Game and Fish Commission for the biennium be iinuing December 1, 1910, and ending December 1, 1912. Also a report of the number of arrests and convictions caused for unlawful hunting and fishing : the amount of fines imposed; the number of illegal fishing devices confiscated and destroyed; the amount of game and fish con - fiscated and disposed of; the amount of money realized for the sale of fish for stocking private ponds and from the sale of licenses during the years of 1911 and 1912. Also recommendations pertaining to a few changes desired in our present game and fish laws; supplemented with a detailed report of the State Pish Hatchery by W. J. O'Brien, Superintendent. Respectfully submitted, HENRY N. MILLER, </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">BIENNIAL REPORT OF III! GAME AND FISH COMMISSION AFPKOPK1AT1OXS A X D K X P K X S K S . Sai aki (II Clll» Dkim rv WABDEN. Amount on hand December 1, 1910. 1500.00 500.00 Bunt expended to April 1, Hi 11 unt appropriated April 1, 1911 *•&gt;•' -ov Amount expended to December 1, 1912 Balance on hand December 1. 1912 $500.00 SaIAKY OF Si I'KKINTKMIKV 1 lif 1 I \ I ( 1 1 MSIKS, Sol Til BK.1U, XKIIK. Amount on hand December 1. 1910 $600.0(1 Amount expended to April 1. 1911 M0.M Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $3,20».00 Amount expended Jo December 1. 1912 2,400.60 Balance December I, 1912 Bunt on hand December 1. 1910 unt expended to April 1, 1911 unt appropriated April 1, 1911 Amount on hand December 1. 1910. $7.".. "ii 7.".. mi Amount expanded to April 1, 1911. Amount appropriated April 1, 1911. ■ Amount expended to December 1. 1 Amount expended to December 1. 1 912 Illl ■! I \i:i . |W.W 2HII.IMI 912 S \i \i:v oh S \l tIT Oh Skckkt \i:i Amount on hand December 1. ltlO. 1380.00 2xii. mi Amount on hand l)ei ember 1. 1910. Amount expended to April 1. 1911. Amount expended to April 1. 1911. Amount appropriated April 1. 1911. Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 |1.« MS 1.47 Hi 1.47 Amount expended to December 1, 1 Amount expended to December 1. 1 Balance on hand December 1. Nkw Aituiati Balance on hand December 1 1912 $210.00 1912 $210.00 New Ari'Aic.vn s AMP Rk.I'AMSS. HM.OT 1M.M 10.79 AMP RCFAIH) Amount on hand December 1. 1910. Amount on hand December I. 1910. ISO. OS Amount expended to April 1. 1911. Amount reverted Amount expended to April 1. 1911 Amount reverted $0.79 Amount appropriated April 1. 1911 Amount appropriated April 1. 1911 *1,8««.»» *1. Sim IMi Amount expended to Dnemfir 1, 1912 1.7 SA1 \i:&gt; i)f TllHEE DKI'l"! IKS. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Ballard's Marsh. Famous Cherry County ducking ground. Shooting Prairie Chii kens at Valentin. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">9 Necessary Labor. Amount on hand December 1, 1910 $406.00 Amount expended to April 1. 1911 406.00 Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $2,500.00 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 1,918.50 Balance on hand December 1, 1912 $581 . 50 Procuring and Transplanting Fish. Amount on hand December 1, 1910 $427.75 Amount expended to April 1, 1911 426.95 Amount reverted $0. 80 Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $4,000.00 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 3,954.71 Balance on hand December 1, 1912 $43.28 Stationery, Postage, Telephone and Otficx Expense. Amount on hand December 1, 1910 $138 . 15 Amount expended to April 1, 1911 137.84 Amount reverted $0 . 31 Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $1,300.00 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 1,299 . 63 Balance on hand December 1, 1912 $0.37 Traveling Expense. Amount on hand December 1, 1910 $810.67 Amount expended to April 1, 1911 810.51 Amount reverted $0 . 16 Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $5,000.00 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 4,973.64 Balance on hand December 1, 1912 $26 . 36 Cement Work and General Improvements. Amount on hand December 1, 1910 $1.28 Amount reverted December 1, 1911 1.28 Amount appropriated April 1. 1911 $1,500.00 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 1,391.96 Amount on hand December 1, 1912 $108.04 Procuring Breeding Stock and Conducting Experiments. Amount on hand December 1, 1910 $159.29 Amount expended to April 1, 1911 159.00 Amount reverted $0.29 Amount appropriated April 1, 1912 $600.00 Amount on hand December 1, 1912 500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">One of Nebraska's pretty mill-ponds near Valentine, Cherry County. Long Mne Creek, Brown County. A fine Trout stream. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 11 Main u \\\c t i\i&gt; Imi-i«&gt;\kmen rs Sni-FisH Hatcheiiy, ("mushy OM.ITI. Amount on hand December ■!, 1910 $332.68 Amount expended to April 1, 1911 Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 4,493.(3 Amount on hand December 1, 1912 $.".nfi :!T Propagation of Game. Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $5,000.00 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 4,9' Amount on hand December 1, 1912 Co.xsTBfcTiKo Barn, Storeroom, Etc Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $3,&gt; Amount expended to December 1, 1912 3,499.97 Amount on hand December 1, 1912 0.0:; Tiunskekicing Fish, and Conservation ok Nathl Fism Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 $3,000.00 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 '. 2,899.45 Amount on hand December 1, 1912 * Cash Find. Amount deposited from December 1, 1910, to December 1, 1912. . $600.80 Amount expended to December 1, 1912 450 . 45 Amount on hand December 1, 1912 $150.35 Si si mart. Total amount on hand December 1, 1910 $3,91 1 . 69 Amount appropriated April 1, 1911 44,580.00 Total receipts $48,491.69 Expenditures during biennium $44,981.56 Reverted to State Treasurer 2 . 35 44.9 V,. 91 Total liRliiiii'*- on bait' • r 1. 1918 $3,507.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Black Bass from Shallenberger Lake, Chase County Pour Valentine sports with string of Brook Trout from a Cherry County </seg>
            <seg id="p012">vsA.Yic* Artis r ion ilON 1 Moneys Paid to State Treasurer fob Sale or Li&lt; tob thi Ybabs or 1911 aito 1 cnruts and Sals or Fisi .912. ! Non-resident Licenses Counties — =33 — ; Fishing Hunting and only Fishing Ho\ liutte 20.00 Brown $8.00 " .'.'..'.'.'.".'.'.'. HiitTul* • Bun 2.00 30.00 '.'.'.'.'..'..'.'.'.'.'. 3600 120.00 Cu.ninn '.' 4.00 ............ Curter 20.00 Dakota 166.00 250.00 D»we« 6.00 20.00 Dawaon 10.00 DourIm ...y.'.'.'.'.'.'." 6.00 620.66 Fillmore 10.00 Franklin 30.00 Bm^am . ./ ............. 6 00 '.'.'..'.'."..'.'.'. Jefferson 12.00 Johnson 20.00 Kearney 10.00 licenses - 30.00 120.00 20.00 250.00 20.00 10.00 $746.00 1,305.00 1.00 208.00 806.1)0 1.00 168.(10 S09.00 1 ."&gt;2o.00 too M1.00 1,369.00 -&gt;o.oo 192.00 1.277.00 1. 55.00 !)23.00 ■&gt;7().00 1,132.00 822.1X) 573.00 610.00 648.00 244.00 253.00 2,222.00 7,932.00 113.00 1,161.00 636.00 406.00 4&lt;»2.OO 1,178.00 291.00 -.'75.00 164.00 213.00 142.00 1,616.00 1.00 495.00 68.00 139.00 1,163.00 135.00 494.00 1,591.00 760.00 I 806.00 168.00 SI 7.00 1.525.00 924.00 651.00 l,M».O0 50.00 1.1M.O0 8!558!00 113.00 1,171.00 1,178.00 291.00 275.00 164.00 213.00 142.00 1,616.00 1,165.00 1,608.00 620.66 10.00 20.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Canada Geese State Pair exhibit of game birds. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">(1A.MK AND FISH COMMISSION 15 fob Sale of Licenses un Sue ot Fish of 1911 axd 1912— Concluded. Non-i-esident licenses D Counties Total Fishing Hunting and Hem— (inlv Fishing 10.00 iMli.OO LMii INI Keya Paha 24(K) 52.00 nm KimlKill 29.00 titO.IIO -,111'Ni Laaeaatci 260.00 4!I.')S.(XI 5,218 ini I .me c. In HUH) 707.00 115.00 115.00 I.I IMI Mr!Mier&gt;on •J.voo 25 mi Ma.l.MHi 1,373.00 1 ..." Merriek I'wil (10 374.00 N.'inal.a r, un 71S.IM) NuckclU 4IM) 1,006.00 l,o*i 2 00 | 1.060.(10 UN f&gt;i:«.oo lo.oo i mm :ii ini PMpa | 1.00 s:u.oo itos.oo I'"lk 10.00 (KM (HI 614.00 Kill Willow ;i7.'&gt;IN( 1 _»_' I li I iHl.oo 1,532.00 1.711 IN) ."•JO.OO -1KM) 1,771.00 1.771 ini lillilMI Siiiinclcrs i.7\::.(N) UlulT S74(K) rfrwmrd 1,784.00 I.7K4.OO Sheridan JIN) 30.00 441 (Nl SlirriH;ilL :c&gt;4.oo 69.00 1O.(N) 532.00 .I s - ! II I 1 3S2.0e - 17:!IN) ritur&gt;t(iii :iiis.()&lt;) H17.INI 627.00 Hi.iHi ington 812.00 R12.00 :;ii:;ihi It on 754.00 U.INl 1 ,918.00 t Total K42.00 *l.(&gt;;«t.(K&gt; | 171,666.00 \ $7 , ig Kre— m, 393, at *2.(X) Ufie penniu, 13, at tljOO .... 12.00 Total S.VJ2.00 Seining licenses. 393, at *2.00 Grand total $74,41(4 (Nl Receipt* for the' sale of fisli for stocking private ponds. Hill and ''"- IHNI.INI $75.(1- 2 I K I </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Foreman's Cottage, Cherry County Branch Fish Hatchery. Hatching-house, Cherry County Branch Fish Hatchery. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">17 ARRESTS, SEIZURES AND CONVICTIONS. Eurlng the last bicnnum the Commission has caused the arrest of persons, charged with the violations of the Game and Fish laws; if these were convicted and paid fines; 32 were acquitted, and cases ist 3 are still pending. The total fines imposed and paid to the &gt;us county treasurers amounted to $1,839. Eie number of unlawful fish nets and fishing traps confiscated and &gt;yed during the last biennium was 462. A great many lines, having than the legal number of hooks thereon, have also been destroyed. ery case where fish were found in these traps they were released. Two hundred and eleven prairie chickens, ducks and quail were con - fiscated and disposed of to charitable institutions; 133 of these birds were turned over to the Child's Saving Institute and House of Hope at Omaha, and in most cases where the offenders had just a few birds the judges before whom the cases were heard disposed of them, and in several cases the judges found the persons guilty, imposed a fine and allowed them to retain the game. In addition to the above, about 30 pounds of Catfish, confiscated, and 600 pounds of Carp and Buffalo were given to the House of Hope, and about 700 pounds of Carp and Buffalo were given the Child's Saving Institute. Four thousand pounds of Carp and Buffalo confiscated at Ashland, Nebraska, were unfit for use by the time that a conviction was secured. Approximately, 100,000 pounds of Carp and Buffalo and Gars were taken from the waters of Carter's Lake, Douglas county, Swift's Lake, Saunders county, and Crystal Lake, Dakota county. These fish were dis - posed of in such a manner to reimburse those engaged in the work so that the state would be put to no additional expense. Iudges before whom nearly all prosecutions were brought seemed lenient in imposing penalties, in every instance the minimum fine given. The officials of this department have at all times endeavored o their duty, and have at no time insisted on heavy fines for first ises, but in several instances where parties have been arrested the id time we have tried to have a greater penalty imposed. In many i where the offense was trivial, as in case of parties hunting without ense, the offender has been permitted to go with a warning. RECOMMENDATIONS. In certain sections of the state the law has been enforced with sat - isfaction; this is due to sportsmen and citizens who desire to see the game and fish protected and assist this department in securing the con - viction of offenders. In other localities the sentiment of the public is contrary to the game and fish laws, and in these localities it Is almost i in possible to enforce the laws and protect the game and fish as we had desired. The Game and Fish Commission employ three deputy wardens on a salary not to exceed eight months of the year, leaving four months for each deputy without employment, and giving the department the actual service of two men for twelve months. This is insufficient assist - ance, and I would recommend that a bill be passed allowing at least the three deputies pay for twelve months of the year. This department also appoints a great many sp cial deputies, who receive no compensation, excepting one-half of the fine actually . imposed and collected from vio - lators, and In this case the special deputy must act as complaining wit - ness. These special deputies do not feel disposed to spend their time pro - tecting the game and fish, with only a prospect of receiving a portion of </seg>
            <seg id="p017">hunting on Platte River near Grand Ishmd, Mekr. » Duck Hunting on the Platte River at Grand Island. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 19 a fine imposed on some friend or neighbor; thus very little assistai secured from this source. I would recommend that the appointment of special deputies be limited, not to exceed six; those to be appointed and serve at such times as extra help is actually required, and they to be paid a small salary for the time actually employed. i'he universal license law as passed by the legislature of 1911 has en to be a very satisfactory law with the sportsmen and the public leneral throughout the state, and a very substantial revenue pro - r. The hunters and anglers express themselves as being willing to the dollar for the license, but in return they feel as though the money collected should be put at the disposal of the Game and Fish Cora - ion for the improvement of its interest, so that more protection ■ an liven the birds and fish we now have and more of the same propa - i, and I most heartily recommend that the coming legislature apprn - tes in amount equivalent to the amount of revenue collected for the of hunting and fishing licenses. I would also recommend that the present seining law be repealed, and that the use of seines and nets be prohibited entirely by the general pub - lic. This method of fishing is only beneficial to the party holding a seining license and is very destructive to fish spawn and small fish, and in waters where seines are frequently \ised. fishing for the angler is ab - solutely destroyed. i would also mommend that the coming legislature pass a bill regu - ig the manner of fishing in the Missouri river from the Nebraska Under our present laws the Missouri river is entirely exempt from regulaticn of our game and fish laws, excepting within one nun feet from the mouth of tributary streams, and the fact is hundreds of and seines are constantly used, and a great many times dynamite been used land will be used in the future, if some regulations are made) to secure large quantities of fish for the market. Under our ing laws the department is absolutely helpless in preventing this inter. I lie open season on fishing and the various game bird shooting mm p very satisfactory to the sportsmen and anglers, and I would recom - d that the coming legislature leave them as they are. The bag limit ;ame birds has some little opposition by the sportsmen. Persons in eastern section of the state are compelled to travel some distance for rie chicken and grouse shooting, and are allowed to kill but ten kens or grouse in any one calendar day, and allowed to have but chickens or grouse in their possession at any time. This makes . bird killed quite expensive to the person traveling two or three ired miles to shoot them. I would recommend that the legislature ige this law slightly, leaving the limit of chickens or grouse shot in one calendar day ten. and the number for a person to have in their esslon twenty. GAME BIRDS. The general condition of the game in this state is quite satisfactory, showing an increase in prairie chicken and grouse, and also in quail, during the years of 1910 and 1911, but owing to the severe winter of 1911 and 1912 the quail have decreased; the heavy snows and cold weather for weeks at a time prevented them from finding shelter and food. In several instances bird-lovers among the farmers have shown great interest and helped care for the birds. If funds were provided this </seg>
            <seg id="p019">20 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION ixterminate the game bird, if not fed and cared for, than all of the ers In the state. Hunting, up to date, is not conducted as in former s. Hunters would then go into the fields with their dogs and guns tramp all day for game birds. It was sport with them and is what moat of them went for. Nowadays a few go hunting this old way, but majority of huntere take an auto, rush out to where the birds are Led, kill the limit or more, and are back home in a short time. Hunt- In an auto will get more birds in a short time than a sportsman will in several days, and with the large number of autos now in use it readily be seen that a large number of birds are killed in a short . A sportsman picks a few birds out of each covey, leaving the bal - to multiply. Those who go out for birds only take every one in t. regardless of consequences to the next breeding season. The result ventually, the loss of all game birds. The propagation of game birds in captivity has not been reduced to a practical basis except, perhaps, in the case of the Ring-neck pheasant In mm states. The result may be successful if experiments being made can find some method to raise the birds after they are successfully hatched. We find from last year's experience in game propagation that in order to raise the young birds, conditions must be made as nearly as possible as they would have them In the wild state, with plenty of room to roam, otherwise they cannot be kept in a healthy condition. The appropriation made by the 1911 legislature was too small to purchase land, secure ex - perienced help, and properly conduct the propagation of game. If the state expects to continue this work I would recommend a large enougn appropriation so that a tract of land can be purchased, not less than 160 acres. This would give enough space to keep the ground in a sanitary condition and free from disease germ's and give the birds more liberty. Through the kindness of the park board we were able to secure space in Antelope Park gratis. Suitable buildings, cages, coops, hatching nests, and netting inclosures were erected and purchased. Five hundred birds, consisting of several varieties of pheasants, were purchased from various game preserves at Oak Park, Illinois, Yardley, Pennsylvania, and Jeffer - son City, Missouri, but we had the same experience as other states have had in the beginning — losing a great many of the birds in transporta - tion and in change of quarters, and also on account of inexperience and knowledge of the habits and requirements of these birds; therefore, the results are not all that we could have hoped for. In the neighborhood of 200 birds have been distributed and liberated over the state, and 432 birds are still on hand. The distribution is as follows. 80 birds — Cherry County — Nine miles west of Valentine, Nebr. 10 birds — Cedar County — Near Hartington, Nebr. 20 birds — Dodge County — On island in Platte river, south of Fremont, Nebr. 8 birds — Dodge— County — West of Hooper, Nebr. 7 birds — Dodge County — North of Fremont, along Elkhorn river. 10 birds — Cass County — South of Louisville, Nebr. Eds — York County — Near York, Nebr. ds — York County — Near Bradshaw, Nebr. ds — Hall County — Near Grand Island, Nebr. ds — Custer County — Near Broken Bow, Nebr. 10 birds — Franklin County — Franklin, along the Republican river. 10 birds — Saunders County — Island in Platte river, east of Yutan, Nebr. 4 birds— Saunders County — West of Wahoo, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 2. 10 birds — Lancaster County — South of College View, Nebr. 2 birds — Lancaster County — Near Raymond, Nebr. 10 birds — Chase County — Twenty-eight miles west of Wauneta, Nebr. 4 birds — Butler County — Near Ulysses, Nebr. 6 birds — Lancaster County — Near Rokeby, Nebr. 2 birds — Thayer County — Near Hebron, Nebr. 4 birds— Saline County— Near Wilber, Nebr. 4 birds — Nrmaha County- — Near Brock, Nebr. 2 birds — Adams County — Near Hastings, Nebr. Amount Expended for Material, Labor, Feed, Wire Netting, and Biros. CONCLUSION. In conclusion, I wish to express my sincere thanks to the sportsmen of the state, also to the various Rod and Gun Clubs that have interested themselves in this department; to the special deputies of the depart - ment, through whose efforts a number of prosecutions have been ac - loinplishccl: and also I wish to express my thanks to the press of the state for different courtesies extended. Very respectfully, HENRY N. MILLER, ,umber, wire netting, and supplies 11,601 . II 'ood and grain 378 . 0! •rayage, express, and freight 99.9: tlrds 2,029 . 61 *bor 855. 0( Total M.964.5: </seg>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022">And his laugh was a gurgling croak. While the grandson told of a monstrous fish He had hooked on a line — which broke. Then the eld man gravely smiled and said. My dear boy, it was large, I know. For I hooked that same old fish myself Some fifty -odd years ago. I PORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE STATE FISH HATCHERIES. '"h&lt; xtrr H. Aidriek, (!m I have the honor to submit a report of the number and kinds of fish led and planted from the fish hatcheries, seined from overflow wad iplanted from one body of water to another, or purchased for dis - tion. There has net only been a gratifying increase in the number h and fry planted, but for the first time in the history of this Com - lon we have been able to meet every demand made on this depart - for fish, both for public and private waters, have handled a larger nt:ige of fish from six to eighteen months old than ever before dur - a like period, and have a surplus of several thousand Bass and pie on hand for spring distribution. SIMMARY OF D1STRIBITIOX. 1911-12. Wall-eyed Pike ( fry, estimated ) 18,625,««e Brook Trout ( fry, estimated ) 812.750 Rainbow Trout ( fry, estimated ) 703,600 Large-mouth Black Bass 22' Crappies 17 &lt; "hannel Catfish 50.JJ5 Yellow Bullheads 52,765 Striped Perch 48,250 Rock Baaa «.2i» Small-mouth Black Bass 1,800 Pickerel 1.000 Buffalo-fish 13,690 lerman Carp T.xcin loldflsn 1,180 lull-frogs 22.500 Total 20.771.120 </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">■&gt;:, IVll the Hike were planted in the fry stage practically as soon as hed. The bulk of the Brook and Rainbow Trout were from four to weeks old when liberated. About one-half the large-mouth Bass were ited in the fry stage, the balance were from six to eighteen months when planted, as were also all other kinds of fish enumerated. IMPROVEMENTS Frame barn and storeroom, 22 by 44 feet, 16-foot steading, with hip i oof, cement foundation and floors throughout, drop siding, interior ceiled with yellow pine flooring; grain and feed bins, lined with sheet-iron, rat proof; steel feed racks and stall fixtures, modern in every respect; driv - ing sheds, 12 by 30 feet; cement foundation and floor, lined with ship - lap. Three thousand five hundred lineal feet of cement retaining walls around fish-ponds. These walls range from 18 inches to 4 feet deep, and average about 10 inches in width at top to 18 inches at bottom, con - structed of sandstone and cement, re-enforced. Five hundred feet of ce - ment walk laid around hatching-house. Four hundred feet of cement i inp ten inches thick put on two lower stone dams and two-inch iron pipe handrails and posts put on same. Cement tank put in at new barn and cement brick tank along roadway in front of hatching-house. Cement floor in tool and feed-house, and waterway below large dam cemented. Two cement nursery ponds at rear of hatchery rebuilt, and 100 feet of ten - inch tile relaid In cement from hatching-house to river. Nine by twelve cement re-enforced engine-room built adjoining spring-house. Brick and nt reservoir, 12 feet wide and It feet deep, constructed on hill op - posite main spring, and 1,700 lineal feet of one- and two-inch iron pipe laid below frost from spring-house to reservoir, from reservoir to super - intendent's residence, barn, lawns and hatching-house. This gives a good supply of water for all purposes and a fine pressure in case of fire. Here - tofore we had no protection whatever. Frame engine house, 9 by 12 feet, built below supply pond, and 6-horse power Fairbanks-Morse gasoline engine, and 4-inch suction centrifugal pump, with necessary pipe and connections, installed in same to pump water direct from Platte river, if needed; 2-horse power Fairbanks-Morse gasoline engine and typhoon pump installed in engine house at spring for filling reservoir. One hun - dred rods of 50-inch Elwood woven wire fence, with steel posts and gates erected around ponds from east to west entrance to grounds. New white cedar posts, and fence rebuilt around entire fifty-three acres of property. New floor put in dining-room at residence and 30 feet of porch screened off. Interior of tool and feed-house celled with ship - lap. All seats, tables and hitching racks in grove thoroughly repaired and painted and new toilet-room built. Stairs rebuilt in hatching - house and galvanized gutters and down-snouting placed on hatching-house. New supply troughs for Pike. Hatching and wooden supports replaced by two-rnch iron piping. Elevated general supply wooden tank in hatch ing-house replaced with large iron pipe, giving direct pressure from main spring. Hatching-house, superintendent's residence, assistants' cottage. barn and storeroom, driving sheds and workshop, ice and tool-house. In - cluding all outbuildings, painted. Fish car "Antelope" repaired at Platts - mouth shops, car tanks rebuilt, large locker for carrying nets and seines put in, new drop platform, flcor racks, new linoleum on floors, standard coach curtains, new air hose, roof repaired, and car painted and varnished interior and exterior. Fifty shipping cans. 50 hatching trays, one 700 - foot and three smaller seines purchased. New spring wagon and double </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026">27 harness, cement brick machine, two lawn mowers and one hundred feet of hose, and much other needed equipment added. Ponds graded and sodded around cement retaining walls, and may other minor Improve - ments made. SUB-FISH HATCHERY. After looking over all sites accessible 10 the railroad, and taking into consideration the superior shipping facilities afforded at Valentine, I finally accepted the offer of the town council of a free site for the perma - nent location of the Cherry eoftnty hatchery. The land lies along the picturesque Minnechaduza Creek, the water supply being drawn from a flne little spring stream known as Government Canyon Creek. During the summer of 1911 we began the construction of a diversion dam and Bass and Crappie ponds, and now have four ponds constructed with a surface area of about eight acres; also trout hatchery, 20 by 30, with cement floor and foundation and necessary tanks, troughs and hatchery equip - ment; a neat foreman's cottage. 24 by 24, with screened porch; a small barn and other outbuildings, and eighty-eight acres of land enclosed with a two-wire fence. Three of the ponds were stocked with adult Bass, brought from Dewey and Willow lakes thirty miles by wagon last May, about 400 Bass in all being placed in the ponds. Owing to the close proximity of the breeding season and the long haul over rough sandy roads they were not in the best condition, and 25 per cent perished after being placed in the ponds; the remainder spawned and produced a healthy lot of fry. and when the ponds were drawn off in November, over 30,000 young Bass were removed, and there is anywhere from two to live thou - sand still in the ponds for spring delivery. The young fish made an excellent growth, considering that the ponds were new and partially barren of vegetation, which is so essential for successful Bass culture. About 500 of the Valentine stork was shown as a part of the state exhibit at the state fair, and were pronounced by all who seen them, who were familiar with Bass culture, as having made a wonderful growth for three months old fish, and I have no hesitancy in saying that if the Baas hatchery at this point is properly developed it will become one of the most successful in the 1'nited States. The stream feeding these ponds runs through a deep canyon for over two miles before being diverted and daily pours thousands of insects and larv* into the ponds as food for the young fish, while the exposure to the air warms the water to about the proper temperature for pond or lake fish. For the past two years about 75 per cent of all trout hatched were handled at the Valentine hatchery, it being in charge during the winter months of Scott Alexander. He followed instructions to the letter, and I cannot speak in too high commendation of his work. I only regret that he is not a younger man. so that he could stand the rough work incident to fish culture and become a permanent employee of this department, as no finer trout fry were ever turned out of any hatchery than those produced at Valentine the past two MM As I have mentioned in the last report, there is no occasion for large or expensive buildings being erected at this station, but the pond are* should be gradually enlarged until we have at least twenty acres of water and the culture of small-mouth Bass. Ring Perch, broad-eared Sunfish, Catfish, and possibly other varieties of pond or lake fish added. We can never carry a brood stock of Trout at this station as the tem - perature of the water will be too high during the summer months, but if necessary and funds become available we can likely make arrange- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">y. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 29 ments with the I". S. Biological Survey. Bureau to use the spring-fed lionds at old Fort Xiobrara, on the newly established bird reserve, tor Trout rearing purposes. til improvements made at Valentine are of a permanent and endur - chararter, all supply and drain pipes being 8-inch cast-iron. The ■nt diversion dam will need to be supplemented with a heavier dam permanent cement spillway further down the creek and necessar&gt; drain pipes. WALL-EYED PIKE. A comparison with the report made two years ago will show that we have almost doubled the output the past two years, eggs being col - lected as usual at Bay City. Lake Huron. Pike fishing has been better than common the past summer and some good catches were reported on the Niobrara, at Milford and Wilber on the Blue, and Columbus on the Platte. The fishermen seining coarse fish at Carter Lake, near Omaha, and Crystal Lake, in Dakota county, report specimens weighing as high as twelve pounds, but they were not numerous. Hen with is shown a string of seven very nice Pike taken from the Platte river near Ashland, only a few miles from the hatchery, the past summer by George Cornell, an expert angler of Wahoo, Saunders county. To the uninitiated who read this report it would appear that we pay more attention to pike hatching than other kinds, but this is not a fact. Pike eggs are col - lected at a small expense, the incubation period being only fifteen days, the fry being liberated practically as soon as hatched, it not being feasible to rear them to a more mature size; for this reason we turn them out in large numbers. As I mentioned in a former report, while the slight expense in Pike hatching may be justified, the number of Pike taken from our streams or lakes has never been commensurate with the number planted and from some waters we have had no re - sults whatever. BROOK TROIT. An increased number of Brook Trout was planted, the major portion of them being placed in streams that have shown by years of experience to be adapted to their culture. Whether we are gaining any ground In the increase of Brook Trout I am unable to say. Trout fishermen whom I nave interviewed claim there are thousands of small flngerling Trout in most of the streams, but the more mature fish were scarce. The high price of meat and the consequent close pasturing of most of the land along the Trout streams, the tramping in of the banks and roiling the water doubtless had a bad effect. At best the number of streams adapted to their culture in our state is limited and I think we are hatching all the Brook Trout we are justified in planting and this branch of our work should not be enlarged. The Brook Trout disease which made its ap - pearance here among our brood stock in 1895, as it did in most of the hatcheries, still periodically recurs and it looks like a needless expense to endeavor to keep up a brood stock of Brook Trout here, so we now carry mainly Rainbows in the ponds. However, with the present high price of fish food, we can purchase Brook Trout eggs fully as cheap as we can carry an adult stock in the ponds, and this should be done in the RAINBOW TROUT. Considerable increase in the number of Rainbow Trout planted dur - ing the past two seasons, as compared with former years, and more Rain- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">30 GAME AND PISH COMMISSION Pare being taken than Brook. Long Pine Creek, in Brown headwaters of White river, in Dawes county, still continue to e best fishing points in the state for this fish. We have an ck of Rainbows in the hatchery ponds and should collect a ainbow eggs during January and February. LARGE-MOUTH BLACK BASS. More Baas from six to eighteen months old than ever before in a like ,erlod have been planted during the past two years. This is accounted for by the 30,000 fingerlings grown at the Valentine station, as well as a considerable number seined from overflow waters. Bass fishing has been very good in some of our waters, but there is complaint from prac - tically all the Bass stocked lakes in the sandhills that the adult stock is gradually getting smaller in size, while there appears no diminution In numbers. Whether this is caused by a lack of food or continual inbreed - ing I am unable to determine, but those living on the lakes who have noticed the disappearance of the three- to five-pound Bass lean to the latter theory, and an exchange of the adult stock between the different lakes and the introduction of new blood will be made the coming year. Owing to the severity of the winter of 1911-12 we suffered a consider - able lots of brood stock which had to be replenished at considerable cost and trouble. CRAPPIES. Iis a result of the fund for seining overflow waters we have been en d to more than treble the plant of Crappies the past two years aa pared with 1909-10, about sixty thousand of these being secured from flows along the Missouri river, ranging from six months old to ure fish. As will be noted by referring to the tables of distribution, have been pretty well scattered In all sections of the state. Every •t should be made to increase the number of Crappie planted. With exception of the German Carp, they have made a better showing In increase in numbers than any fish we are propagating. They are migratory and flourish in both murky and clear water. STRIPED PERCH. Ear some unaccountable reason the Perch do not seem to make the ing in our waters that they should. They are an exceedingly hardy and prolific in egg production, but their increase has been very and I am inclined to attribute this condition to the spawn-eating . Owing to the glutinous character of their eggs, the spawn all ring together in, a mass, they fall an easy prey to the Carp or other sr-mouth fish. CHANNEL CATFISH. Owing to the fact that the Channel Catfish is our best native fish and the demand for them to stock streams and mill-ponds has always been large. It is to be regretted that we have been unable to successfully propagate them In ponds as we do the Yellow Bullheads, but experi - ments are still being carried on by the U. S. Bureau of Fisheries and many of the states and their artificial culture may yet be solved. YELLOW BULLHEADS No fish will give better returns for the money spent in their cultiva - tion or transplanting in a state like Nebraska than the Bullhead. There </seg>
            <seg id="p030">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 31 seems to be a natural aversion to the name Bullhead, and some states and the U. S. Bureau have dignified a species of Bullhead by calling them Marble Catfish. However, they are well worthy of the money and time spent in their propagation and distribution under any name, and if every mill-pond in the state were stocked with them they would give abundant returns for the money expended. Last spring about two car - loads were collected and put in the retaining pond at Dewey Lake and later transferred to waters in the central and eastern part of the state, and a large number were seined out of Clarks, Blyburg, and other overflow waters in the past two years and transplanted. This work should be continued. SUNFISH. iost of the Sunfish planted during the period covered by this report seined from overflow waters or transplanted from lakes that were stocked. While the Sunfish do not attain a large size, they live thrive in small ponds or lakes where the Bass would prove a failure. ■ also exist in lakes that are strongly Impregnated with alkali and ish a prime article of food in the place of high-priced meat on many Die. An effort should be made to secure a stock of the broad-eared ish from some of the northern lakes the coming spring as we have s available for that purpose. SMALL-MOUTH BLACK BASS. Our experience so far with this fish has been rather disappointing. While we have been able to hatch out a fine lot of fry from the limited number of brood stock we have on hand, we have not succeeded in rear - ing them up to the six-months-old stage as successfully as the large - mouth Bass, and have only been able to distribute 1,800 during the past two years, where we ought to have had that many thousand. An effort will be made to secure additional brood stock the coming spring, and some of these will be placed in the ponds at Valentine, as the conditions at this station are better adapted to their culture than in the black soil bottom ponds here. There is an insistent demand from the anglers for the introduction of these fish In our best lakes and every effort should be made to introduce and make a success of them in our waters, if possible. ROCK BASS. t small number of Rock Bass spawners have been carried In stock e hatcheries for several years, and from these we have planted a over six thousand Rock Bass the past two years. They do not well adapted to our waters, but an occasional specimen has been from Carter and other lakes. BULL-FROGS. Eie attempt to acclimate the bull-frog, has not up to date been a de - success. Plants made at Long Pine, in Brown county, Beatrice, in county, and Benkelman and Imperial, In Chase county, hare Ised some results, but the efforts to introduce them into the swampy till lakes has thus far been marked with failure. FISH CONSERVATION. While we hear much of conservation, and meetings have been held </seg>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032">33 mpliahed in a practical way. The last legislature save this com - mission an allowance of $:'&gt;.n«ni for the purpose of conservation and trans - ferring fish from overflow waters. Out of this fund men have been paid 10 keep air-holes open during the winter in our best lakes in the sandhills. A temixirary sen en was put in at the outlets of Dewey and Willow Lakes the past spring, and the annual slaughter and waste of Bass prevented. Overllow ponds along the Missouri and Platte rivers I'xaniined. and when found to contain fish enough to justify the ;ime have been seinnl and the fish distributed to living water. live seining being don" at Blyburg. Nebraska City, and Iji Platte. At the latter point nvir liip.iiuii Crapplc were removed, besides a large numl' i of Mass, Bullheads, riunhsh. :md Carp. This lake or si' known as Clark's Lake, went entirely dry during the summer of 1911. .•inly and holding ponds were built at this point and a crew main laimii for over tvo months seining the past fill, and this work will ntinii'd ihe coming sprint, as it is the intention of the landowners to entirely drain this slough to benefit the adjoining binds. 1 in keeping the balance of the fish in this body of water alive through int' r, fully as many fish as have already been removed can be 'ak&gt;-n out in the spring, which will give some idea of the enormous annual loss of fish in these shallow pondl .ind slouehs when they are nol cither removed Of airholes kept open to admit air duri 1 and continued cold weather. In addition to the game fish removed from these- shallow ponds over tO,64M Carp and Buffalo fish were also i. a large proportion of these betas iish that would weigh one pound or over. Some of our anglers will likely criticise me for saving these - fish, but this branch of the fish and game department should not ndin ted altogether for the benefit of the angler, but in the inte of the greatest good to the greatest numlwr. and while up to the pres t-ni this department has recalTBd little ren nue from the seining of coarse in my opinion the time is ripe for a change. Several of the state commissions now let the permits to rWCTi coarse tish out by competi - tive- I ids and the state of Mlanesota now receives thousands of dollars annually from such permits. An unsuccessful bidder for the privilege of seining Lake Shetek. for e-oars" fish, in a controversy with the warden's uneiit. c laims that the coarse fish privilege on this me inland lake is worth *4".iHM&gt; annually. While we have* no lakes in Nebraska to ire with this one. we should either let these permits by competi ids or exact a percentage of the precredi of all coarse fish sold. tish are' state property, ancj a favored few should no longer be allowed to profit at the expens ■■ of 'he many. AQl ARIAL KXHIBIT. iie annual live Iish display was made at the st:ite fair, in 1911 and In addition to the adult specimens of 'noth the native and intro- I species, fish from the (iretna and Valentine state hatcheries and elman private fisheries, from three to six months old. were also n. The fish building should be enlarged so as to permit of flsh of us ages being shown. It has been the constant aim of this de - lent to make this exhibit not as good as those shown at other state but the best made at any state fair, and this standard should be tained. CASH FIND. This fund is derived from the sale of fish for stoc king strictly private </seg>
            <seg id="p033">34 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION ponds and for ornamental fish, as provided in section 13 of article 1 of the present laws; $630.80, was received from this source and paid over to the state treasurer. RECOMMENDATIONS. I would recommend that the present law permitting the use of nets and seines by the payment of a license of $2, and the depositing of a tined check for $100 with the Chief Warden, be repealed. Under the guise of this law. and the excuse of removing the coarse fish in some instances at least, not only the coarse fish but all others have either been removed or destroyed. A good example of the vicious features of this law wa* turnished by the permit granted to parties to seine Swift's Lake near Ashland, in the fall of 1911. They began work about the first of Sep - tember and continued to seine until after ice formed on this lake tinually handling over the thousands of Crappies which this body of water contained. In the spring the shore was lined with dead Cra) and fishing was ruined. As a recompense for this slaughter th&gt; treasury was enriched the magnificent sum of $2, and this is on of many similar occurrences. I would recommend that the laws be so amended that it shall be ur lawful to take in any manner from the public waters of the state, oi ■ell or offer to sell, any of the following named fishes less than th&lt; length specified: I would recommend that ■ license fee be imposed for fishing in tht- Mtaaouri river according to the kind and size of net used ; this license to be modeled after the Iowa law. APPROPRIATIONS Th&lt; last legislature gave the fish and game department for all pur poaes about $40,000. Of this amount about $8,000 was expended for permanent improvements at the Gretna and Valentine fish hatch' and $5,000 was allowed for the purchase of game birds and starting . propagation, leaving a balance of about $27,000 for salaries, of game wardens, office expenses, and maintenance of fish hatcherii s. From fie ures just received, what we have had for the expense of this depai ' looks like thirty cents as compared with what even our neighbors are ■pending. Colorado spent $118,179.85; of this amount $ti4.4".ii was a alive appropriation, and the balance collected from game and fish licenses and fines. Iowa si&gt;ent $137,91 2. S7, all of which was received -• f and fines. I have not the complete figures from Kansas, but this state has spent in the past twelve months owr $73,000 in constructing a ■cries of eighty ponds at their fish hatchery, and are now Invi $80,000 more in buildings — all of this money being derived from their sp fund. The amount produced from our license system in thi&gt; ■tate is not yet available, but it will likely total over $60,000, and hay all been paid into the state school fund. The coming legislature should be asked to appropriate an amount equal to whatever the sportsmen and anglers have paid into this fund in the past two years, and no appropriation should be asked for or received by this department. In my opinion this money should not only be used for fish and game prop Blue or Channel Catfish 10 Inches. SVall-Eyed Pike 10 inches. Pickerel 10 inches. Grapples 6 inches. Rinp Perch 6 inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">35 agation and protection, but a portion should be set aside yearly for the purchase of the abutting lands around such lakes as Dewey, Willow, Haekberry and Trout, in Cherry county, so that the general public will for all time have access to such lakes. There are many other lakes that will In a few years afford fine fishing, and the state should own or con - trol frontage on all of them. To the sordid minded, or those who wish to place the dollar mark on all things, this will appear a visionary proposition, but Wisconsin, one of the best governed states in the Union, Inaugurated this policy in 1904, by withdrawing from sale 40,000 acres of •tate lands, and have acquired by purchase or government grants about 400,000 acres more In her lake region, which has been set aside for all time as a camping, hunting, fishing, and recreation grounds for her citizens. Few hunters or anglers would object to paying a dollar towards acquiring fish and game lands in this way, but they do strenuously ob - ject to paying money that, under the guise of a fish and game license, is turned into the school fund, and if this method of handling this money cannot be changed the law should be repealed. With the Improvements that have been made at the Gretna hatcheries during the past two years no costly Improvements will be required dur - ing the coming biennium. The balance of the ponds should be cement walled, some additional cement walks should be constructed, some of the stone dams will need to be repaired, and the remaining dams not cov - ered with cement walks should be finished and iron pipe railings put on in place of the present wooden ones. A portion of the ten-inch tiling used in flushing out mud and leaves from trout ponds should be relaid in cement. Another road should be graded Into the grove so that room can be afforded for the many automobiles that now wish to stop here during the summer months. The present wooden hatching troughs should be replaced with cement troughs and supports; also some additional hatching jars and aquariums purchased. A small auto truck is needed, and the fish car "Antelope" should be thoroughly overhauled and re - paired and a new lighting system installed on same. More help will be required to keep the grounds in shape during the summer months and to look after the stream of visitors who daily visit this institution. If the Cherry county hatchery is to be properly developed, a permanent diversion dam with large cement spillway to carry off possible freshets, and large iron drain pipes and at least ten acres more ponds should be added, and a storeroom for nets, hatching apparatus, shipping ca.au Miilt. Considerable grading and rip-rapping and other work will be re - quired and a permanent fence constructed to enclose the property In place of the present temporary one. I T p to this time the foreman at the s-.ub-hatchi'iy has received only $60 per month; this should be advanced to at least fit, and the wages of all employees at both Gretna and Valentine should be increased to compare with wages paid other state employees. Some of the funds are nearly exhausted now, with three months more expenses to be paid out of the present appropriation, but there will be no deficiencies in this branch of the game and fish depart - ment. All state property at both fish hatcheries is in good condition, and I trust that many members of the legislature will make it a point to visit this Institution and learn what this branch of the fish and game department is doing with the money appropriated. In closing I wish to acknowledge th« assistance and many courtesies shown me by the press, the co-operation of the Chief Game Warden, and my assistants at CONCLUSION. </seg>
            <seg id="p035"/>
            <seg id="p036">37 the hatcheries. These agencies have all contributed to whati cms I have attained in this branch of the game and fish department. Respectfully submitted, W. J. OBkien lhjmiii Finli Commilt STATK I'lllil'KRTY AT FISH HATCHERIES. '&gt;f 5:1 acres, all fenced ivuuO.VU Hatching-house 2.5OO.OO Hatching apparatus furniture, and shipping cans 1.000.00 Superintendent's residence Assistants' cottage Barn, storeroom, and driving sheds Ice house, tool house and work shop 1 .11OO.OO Two engine rooms, gasoline engines. leoefTOlr. He 1,000.80 Steel windmill pump and flume 400.00 Spring-house and 1,000 feet supply pipe 000.00 Fish distributiting car "Antelope" and car-house 4,000.00 Twenty-flve ponds with dams and supply pipe 4,000.00 Estimated value of fish held in ponds One team of horses, three wagons, two sets harness 000.00 Row boats, nets, seines, etc 300 . 00 Miscellaneous tools Hatching house at sub-station 1,000.00 Foreman's cottage at sub-station 1,200.00 Four ponds, including dams and supply pi|&gt;e 1,000.00 Fenc ing and other improvements Estimated value of fish in ponds WALL-EYED PIKE DISTRIBI'TIOX. 1911. Fingerlings. Disposition Yearlings. Counties. Fry. and Adults. Dunning, Middle I.oup River 600,000 Angus, Little Blue River 25.000 Hooper, Elkhorn River 500,000 Omaha, Carter Lake 500,000 Waterloo, Elkhorn River 500,000 Laketon, Crystal I&gt;ake 1,000,000 Howard — St. Paul, Middle Loup River 50,000 Grand Island, Wood River 500,000 St. Michaels. St. Michael's Slough 500.000 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">■ GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Flngerlings, Yearlings, Disposition Counties. Pry. and Adults Niobrara, Niobrara River 1,000,000 Norfolk, Elkhorn River 500,000 Genoa, Middle Loup River 1,000,000 Pulton, Middle Loup River 1,000,000 Fisheries, Platte River 1,000,000 Gretna, Elkhorn River 1,000,000 Seward, Blue River 600,000 Crete, Blue River $00,000 Saundera — Ashland. Salt Creek 500,000 Ord, Park Lake 50,000 York, Beaver Creek 50,000 York, Lincoln Creek 50,000 York, Blue River 50,000 WALL-EYED PIKE DISTRIBUTION, Itl2. Oakdale, Mill-pond 50,000 Petersburg, Mill-pond 25,000 Atnsworth, Mill-pond 25,000 Cuming- Wert Potat, Mill-pond 600,000 Angus, Little Blue River 50,000 Button, Little Bine River 200,000 Omaha, Carter Lake 600,000 Waterloo, Elkhorn River 200,000 Bine Springs, Blue River 600,000 Niobrara, Niobrara River 600,000 Columbus, Loup River 1,000,000 Crete, Blue River 800,000 Seward, Blue River 100,000 Ulysses, Blue River 50,000 Gretna, Elkhorn River 500,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 39 Disposition, Yearlings, Counties. Fry- and Adults. Halsey, Middle Loup River 1,000,000 Estimated total 18,625,000 BROOK TROUT DISTRIBUTION, 1»11. Royal, Verdigree Creek 20,000 20,000 Anoka, Spring Creeks Long Pine, Pine Creek. Johnston, Plum Creek . . 20,000 15,000 Cheyenne — Redington, Lawrence Creek 30,000 Valentine, Spring Creek Valentine, Sears Creek Valentine, Seven Creeks Valentine, Gordon Creek Valentine, Schlegel Creek Chesterfield, Boardman Creek Pullman, Head Middle Loup River. Wood Lake, Fairfleld Creek 5,000 5,000 10,000 10,000 20,000 30,000 10,000 10,000 1 )undy — Benkelman, Buffalo Creek Benkelman, Indian Creek Parks, Rock Creek 5,000 5,000 5,000 Dawes — Chadron, Little Bordeaux Creek. Chadron, Indian Creek 5,000 15,000 10,000 10,000 10,000 Chadron, Big Bordeaux Creek. Whitney, Ash Creek Crawford, Spring Creeks. Dorsey, Steele Creek O'Neill, Eagle Creek O'Neill, Red Bird Creek Middle Branch, Spring Creek. Cella, Brush Creek 30,000 30,000 5,000 15,000 15,000 Stuart, Big Sandy Creek Kimball— 10,000 Kimball, Lodge Pole Creek 15,000 10,000 10,000 10,000 Bazlle Mills, Bazile CreeK. Morrill— K Angora, Willow Creek t's Bluff— tScottsbluff, Spring Creek, tdan— Rushville, White Clay Creek. Rushville, Larrabee Creek Rushville, Spring Creek . . . 10,000 10,000 6,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Trout ponds and Assistants Pottage, State Fisheries. Gretna. Nrt&gt; Summer Scene, SUte Fisheries </seg>
            <seg id="p040">(1AMK AND FI8H COMMISSION 41 and Adults. K Disposition ties. Glen, Soldier Creek Harrison, Monroe Creek . Harrison, Hat Creek Harrison, Sow Belly Creek Thomas- Seneca, Big Creek. Seneca, Calnius Creek HROOK TROIT DISTRIBUTION, Antelope — Orchard, South Verdigree Creek Orchard, Middle Verdtgree Creek. Orchard, Spring Creek 25,000 5,000 Brown Ix&gt;ng Pine, Pine Creek, .lohnstown, Plum C 10,000 10, I I'nion, l.arsh Pond 10.01MI 10,000 Chadron. Big Bordeaux Creek Crawford, Spring Creeks Iienkelman, Indian Creek Benkelman, Buffalo Creek Parks, Rock Creek 5,000 5,000 5,000 1912. BROOK TROIT DISTRIBUTION Cheyenne — 10,000 25,000 Redington, Pumpkin-seed Creek. Redington, Lawrence Creek . . . Cherry- Pullman. Head Middle Loup River Kilgore. Spring Creek 1(1.000 10,000 10,000 10,000 10,000 Valentine, Schlagel Creek Crookston, Minnechaduza Creek Wood Lake, Fairfield Creek . 5,000 O'Neill, Apple Creek 10,000 Middle Branch, South Verdigree Creek. Dorsey, Steele Creek 15,000 Horsey. Apple Creek Atkinson, Eagle Creek . Atkinson, Sandy Creek . Atkinson, Willow Creek Atkinson, Baker Creek Celia, Brush Creeks 5.000 4ii.il(iO 15.00(1 5,000 10,000 15,000 10.000 Kimball, Lodge Pole Creek Bloomfleld, Devils Nest Creek </seg>
            <seg id="p041">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Disposition. Yearlings. Counties. Fry. and Adults Sheridan— Rushvllle, White Clay Creek 10,000 Ruahville, Larrabee Creek 10,000 10,000 Estimated Total 812,750 RAINBOW TROUT DISTRIBUTION, 1911. Royal, Verdlgree Creeks 20,000 Anoka, Spring Creeks 15,000 Long Pine, Pine Creek 50,000 Johnstown, Plum Creek 15,000 Valentine, Schlagel Creek 16,000 Valentine, Gordon Creek 5,000 Crookston, Minnechaduza Creek 40,000 Kilgore, Minnechaduza Creek 15,000 Wood Lake, Fairfleld Creek 10,000 Pullman, Middle Loup River 10,000 Benkelman, Buffalo Creek 10,000 Benkelman, Indian Creek 10,000 Parks, Rock Creek 10,000 Parks, Rock Creek Ponds 2,000 Chadron, Chadron Creek 10,000 500 Crawford, White River 50,000 Kimball— Kimball, Lodge Pole Creek 15,000 Grayson, Pine Creek 20,000 Beott's Bluff— ScotUbluff, Spring Creeks 10,000 Glen, White River 35,000 Glen, Spring Creek 5,000 Glen, Soldier Creek 5,000 Seneca, Big Creek 10,000 Seneca, Calamus Creek 10,000 RAINBOW TROUT DISTRIBUTION, 1912. Orchard, South Verdigree Creek 10,000 Royal, Middle Verdlgree Creek 10,000 Long Pine, Pine Creek 35,000 Johnstown, Plum Creek 10,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">43 Disposition. Yearlings. Counties. Fry. and Adults Petersburg, Head Beaver Creek 10,000 Valentine, Schlagel Creek 10,000 Valentine, Minnechaduza Creek 10,000 Wood Lake, Fairneld Creek 10,000 Valentine, Canyon Creek 5,000 Pullman, Head Middle Loup River 10,000 Chadron, Big Bordeaux Creek 11,000 Chadron, Chadron Creek 10,000 Chadron, Indian Creek 5,000 Chadron, Dead Horse Creek 5,000 Benkelman, Buffalo Creek 5,000 Benkelman, Indian Creek 5,000 Parks, Rock Creek 5,000 Middle Branch, North Verdigree Creek 20,000 Dorsey, Steele Creek 10,000 O'Neill, Louse Creek 5,000 Atkinson, Eagle Creek 26,000 Kimball, Lodge Pole Creek 10,000 Sheridan— Rushville, Spring Creek 10,000 Orayson, Pine Creek 10,000 Thurston — Pender, Spring Creek Pond Estimated Total 703,600 LARGE-MOUTH BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION. 1911. Nellgh. Mill-Pond Oakdale Mill-pond a Buffalo — Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake Long Pine, Hagan's Lake I Lynch, Ponca Creek Anoka, Niobrara Sloughs Spencer, Hocak's Pond . . . Box Butte — Alliance, Irrigation Lake Albion, Beaver Creek Dunning, Field's Pond Schuyler, McAllister Lake 10,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044">45 Disposition. Yearlings, Counties. Fry. and Adults. Imperial, Champion Lake Imperial, Moranville Lake 600 Cuming— West Point. McKirrahan Lake 500 West Point. Wort man Lake 300 Dakota— Laketon, Crystal Lakf ... I&gt;aw.s Crawford, Spring Lakes 1.000 Crawford. White Clay Lake IN Chadron, Spring Lake '■&lt;•" Douglas— 50,000 ( (inaha. Carter Lake (MM Pries I^ake Hi Pries I^ake Fremont, Fried's l.akt Howells. Spring Lake • ; &gt; n " Scribner, Elkhorn Slouph : '00 Scribner, Dirkschneider's I 'end I** 1 Frontier— Maywood. May wood Lake "&gt;| |IP Curtis. Curtis Lake 1 " |W1 Franklin- Franklin, Spring Lake HI (.iHrdpn Mumiier, Blue Lake HI Oarfield— Taylor, Williams' Pond M Grant — Whitman, Center Lake 300 Whitman, Foley's Lake 500 Howard— St. Paul. Spring Creek HI St. Paul, Spring Lakes IMN Hi St. Paul, Spring Lakes. Harlan— Republican City, Mill Cm k HI Alma, Methodist Creek 4"" Orleans, Mill-pond HI Hitchcock — Culbertson. Frenchman River Hi OXeill. Elkhorn River -"" Grand Island. Schimmer Lake Hi St. Michael, St. Michael's Slough HI Jefferson — KFairbury, Little Blue River ison — Holsehuh's Pond !-&gt;n Creighton, Creighton Lake Bazile Mills. Mill-pond </seg>
            <seg id="p045">NVw barn and Rtore-room at Fisheries. Gretna. Xebr. A Sunday afternoon scene at the State Fisheries. Feeding Rainbow Trout </seg>
            <seg id="p046">47 Disposition. Fry. and Adult8 Counties. Yearllngi. Lincoln- North Platte, Bird wood Ponds. Maxwell, Mylander'g Pond . . . B Madison — Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn. Tilden, Stanton'a Lake soo Morrill. Irrigation I^ake Angora. Willow Creek Ponds 600 N'iKkoIls— Superior, Mill Pond Onoa, Spring Lakes Genoa. Kirby I^ake B Red Willow— McCook, Plummer's Lake Newport, Wolf's Lake E Richardson — Falls City, Maust Lake Saunders — Prague, Wagner's Pond Sufrni&amp;n — Rookville, Rock Creek. ;:: Sheridnn — Hay Springs, Hay Creek Ponds. Thurston — Winnebago, Whitcomb's Lake. Valley— Ord, Park Ponds. WVI'St.T Blue Hill, Little Blue River 10,000 Hlue Hill. Meyer's Pond York, Beaver Creek . . York, Lincoln Creek. 400 LARGE-MOI'TH BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1912. Antelope — Nelieh, Mill-pond IS ■Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs ms— Hastings, Park I^kes Dunning, Middle Loup River Brown— Ainsworth, Mill-i&gt;ond Buffalo- Kearney, Kearney Lake 200 Kearney, State Hospital Pond. Miller, Harse's Lake Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Orapples taken from mill-pond near Pierre. Pierce Count v String of Black Bass taken from Dewey and Marsh Lakes. Cherry County, by three Ainsworth anglers. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 49 Disposition. Yearlings. Counties. Fry. and Adults. Loretto, Beaver Creek 1,000 Petersburg, Beaver Creek 1,000 Albion, Mill Pond 1,000 Imperial, Champion Lake 500 Imperial, Moranville Lake 600 Cherry- Cody, Raccoon Lake 1,000 Schuyler, McAllister Lake MM Sutton, Little Blue River 500 Cumins — West Point, Wortman Lake 400 West Point, Brick Yard Pond 400 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 2.'i'iO Valley, Sullivan's Lake 500 Florence. Buller Lake 160 Deuel— Chappell, Lodge Pole Creek 500 Dakota — Dakota City, Crystal Lake 1,000 Dawson — Summer, Wood's Lake 600 Crawford. White Clay Lake 1,000 Crawford. Spring Lakes 800 Chadron. Irrigation Lake 1,000 500 Ponca, Hurley's Pond 200 Frontier- Curtis, Curtis Lake 1,000 Grant- Whitman, Center Lake 450 Whitman, Foley Lake 450 Whitman, Stump Lake 500 Hyannis, Moran's Pond 150 Wymore, Blue River 3,500 Beatrice, Mill-pond 1.600 Harlan— Orleans, Mill-pond 1,000 Alma, Spring Creek 600 Ewlng, Elkhorn Sloughs 1.300 Page, Antelope Lake 2.500 O'Neill, Elkhorn River .*. . . 2.000 Grand Island, Spring Lake 5.000 300 Grand Island, Schimmer Lake 600 Grand Island. Wood River 500 St. Michael. St. Michael's Slough 1.000 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">50 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Counties. Fry. and Adults. Mullen, Twin Lakes 500 Hitchcock— Culbertson, Frenchman River 600 Trenton, Mud Creek 100 Trenton, McConnel's Lake 100 Trenton, Macklin Creek 800 Kesterson, Snyder'g fond 100 Cook, Holschuh Pond 200 Kim ball Klmball, Irrigation Lake 1,100 KnoxvlUe, Schreier'i Pond 100 Lincoln, Syford's Pond 250 Lincoln, 8tate University 100 Martell. Gumbo Lakes 200 Morrlll, Grewell Pond 200 Merrlck Central City, Sand-pit Lakes 2,000 BatUe Creek, Wendt's Lake 2,000 500 Tilden, Howl's Lake 1,000 Superior, Mill-pond 500 Auburn, Spring Lake 10,000 800 Brock, Nemaha Cut-off 260 Peru, Spring Lake 150 Genoa, Spring Lakes 10,000 700 Syracuse, Mohr's Lake 100 Columbus, Ice-house Lake 600 Columbus, Shell Creek 200 Columbus, Kyle's Slough 400 Duncan, Blauser'e Slough 200 Humphrey, Spring Lake 5,000 1,600 200 Humphrey, Spring Lake Rising City, Albers' Pond 1.000 Pierce, Mill-pond 2,000 Richardson — Verdon, Spring Lakes 600 Newport, Pony Lake 2.500 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 51 Disposition. Yearlings, Counties. Fry. and Adults. Wilber, Mill-pond 500 Saunders — Yutan. Peters' Lake 400 Cedar Bluffs, Peterson's Lake 2,000 260 Scott's Bluff— ScotUbluff, Wood's Lake 500 Sheridan — Gordon, Clear Lake 800 Seneca, Seneca Lakes 1,000 Inavale, Spring Creek 500 Blue Hill, Little Blue River 5,000 Washington — Ft. Calhoun, Horseshoe Lake 500 York, Lincoln Creek 500 Bradshaw, Spring Pond 400 Estimated Total Fry 124,000 9«.200 CRAPPIE DISTRIBUTION, 1911. Antelope — S Neligh, Mill-pond Oakdale, Mill-pond Long Pine, Hagan's Lake Ainsworth, Mill-pond . . . 300 500 Bellwood, Loomls Pond 2,000 300 Lynch, Ponca Creek Buffalo — Pleasanton. Pleasanton Lake . Wood Lake, Dewey Lake Angus, Little Blue River Cuming — West Point, McKlrrahan's Lake. West Point, Wortman's Lake . . . Champion, Moranvllle Lake f Crawford, Spring Lakes Chadron, Spring Ponds. Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake Omaha, Pries Lake a Fremont, Frled's Lake... Scribner. Elkhorn Slough </seg>
            
            <seg id="p051"/>
            <seg id="p052">53 Fingerlings, Disposition. Counties. Yearlings, Fry. and Adults. l.aketon, Crystal Lake Frontier— I ■Curtis Lake lklin— Franklin, Spring Lake O'Xelll, Elkhorn River St. Michael, St. Michael's Slough Hitchcock— ■Culbertson, Frenchman River ■rson — ■Fairbury, Little Blue River oln— North Platte, Birdwood Pond. Maxwell, My lander's Pond . . . . X Ijincaster— Hallam, Busch Pond Denton, Spring Pond s Madison — Tilden, Stanton's Ijike Madison, Union Creek Madison, Taylor Creek 1 Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn. Morrill- Morrlll, Irrigation Lake Oconee, Hitchcock's Pond ■Newport, Keller's Lake lardson — Falls City, Farrington's Lake. Red Willow— ■McCook, Plummer Pond ■idan— ■Gordon, Clear Lake ird- ■Milford, Blue River man — Rockvllle, Rock Creek ■Dorchester, Little Blue River iders — s Wahoo, Wahoo Creek Prague, Wagner's Pond Thurston — Winnebago, Whitcomb's Lake Ord, Park Ponds Washington — Herman, Kramer Lake = </seg>
            <seg id="p053">54 GAME AND PI8H COMMISSION CRAPPIE DISTRIBUTION, 1912 Fingerlings Disposition. Yearlings and Adults Counties. Fry Antelope — Neligh, Mill-pond 50C Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs LOO,, Adams — Hastings, Park Lakes urn Lyons, Mill-pond Loretto, Beaver Creek Petersburg, Beaver Creek S Albion, Mill-pond Buffalo- Kearney, Kearney Lake Kearney, State Hospital Pond Ravenna, Mill-pond 1.000 l,00f&gt; Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake Sehuyler, McAllister Lake MM Imperial, Spring Lakes Louisville, Park Lakes .. Louisville, Jochim's Pond 2,000 100 Cheyenne — Redington, Pumpkin Creek Ponds 500 Angus, Little Blue River Button, Little Blue River as Ansley, Mill-pond Cody, Raccoon Lake Omaha, Carter Lake Florence, Buller's Lake Dakota City. Crystal Lake Homer, Omaha Creek •a Scribner, Mud Creek . . Scribner, Elkhorn River Sumner, Wood's Lake S ouuiucr, nuuu B LJO.KV Chappell. Lodge Pole Creek Chadron, Irrigation I4ike . . Whitney, Cut-off Lake Crawford, White Clay Lake S Cambridge, Mill-pond ;: Curtis, Curtis Lake </seg>
            <seg id="p054">55 FingerlingB, Yearlings. Disposition Counties. Fry. and Adulu Garden — Mumper, Blue Lake 500 Wymore, Blue River Beatrice, Mill-pond . 1,000 Grant— ■Hyannis, Moran's Lake hcock— Culbertson, Frenchman River Trenton, McConnel's Lake . . . Trenton, Macklin Creek 500 500 1.100 Oxford, Republican River Orleans, Mill-pond Ewing, Elkhorn Sloughs O'Neill, Elkhorn River . as 600 S Grand Island, Schimmer Lake . . . Grand Island, Wood River St. Michaels, St. Michael's Slough Jefferson — Kesterson, Snyder's Pond Johnson — : 500 ; Tecumseh, Mill-pond Kimball— Klmball, Irrigation Lake KKnoxville, Schreler's Pond master- Lincoln, Syford's Pond Martell, Gumbo Lakes Madison — ■ Tllden, Clear Lake Oakdale, Elkhorn River . . Norfolk, North Fork River ,.000 Nemaha— Brock, Nemaha Cut-off Peru, Spring Lake . . Humphrey, Spring Lake . Duncan, Blauser's Slough Columbus, Shell Creek . . Columbus, Kyle's Slough Richardson — Falls City, Maust Lake. ■Wllber, Blue River, ■idan— Gordon, Clear Lake Scotts Bluffs — Soottsbluff, Woods Lake </seg>
            <seg id="p055">i I e - ,11111 ! X v&gt; i </seg>
            <seg id="p056">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 57 Yearlings, K Disposition ties. Fry. and Adulu Saunders — Ceresco, Shultz Lake Cedar Bluffs, Spring Lake Wahoo, Wahoo Creek . . . 1.000 Seward — Seward, Blue River Milford, Blue River 500 500 Springfield; Nebles Pond Meadow, Sand Pit Lakes. i. ILa Platte, Trestle Lake hington — Ft. Calhoun, Horseshoe Lake Webster— Inavale, Spring Creek York, Lincoln Creek York, Beaver Creek York, Spring Lake 500 500 500 Total 2,000 177,360 CHANNEL CATFISH DISTRIBUTION. 1911. Neligh. Mill-pond 500 Oakdale, Elkhorn River 500 Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 500 Kearney, Watson's Lake. .000 Lynch, Ponca Creek Bellwood, Pond Bruno, Pond . s KDeweese, Little Blue River, ins- West Point, Mill-pond West Point, Wortman Lake 500 Wisner, Elkhorn River 500 Omaha, Carter Lake Omaha, Spring Lake ■a Howells, Spring Lake I Scribner, Elkhorn River DmkoL- Laketon, Crystal Lake O'Neill, Elkhorn River Grand Island, Wood River </seg>
            <seg id="p057">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 58 and Adults K Disposition ties. Fry Howard — KSt. Libory, Spring Pond hcock— : »Culbertaon, Frenchman River •rson — ■Fairbury, Little Blue River ison— Tecumseh, Mill-pond Tecumseh, Nemaha River Lincoln— ■North Platte, Birdwood Pond, aster— Roca, Mill-pond 400 Denton, Spring Lake Madison— 300 ■Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn tolls— ■Superior, Mill-pond nee- Table Rock, Nemaha River MM ■Table Rock, Wood's Pond lardson — ■ Humboldt, Nemaha River Willow— McCook, Driftwood Creek ::: Mi-Cook, Plummer Lake Newport, Spring Lake Dorchester, Turkey Creek . Tobias, Pond s Saunders — Wahoo, Wahoo Creek Prague, Spring Pond S ■Ord, Park Lakes hington— : Herman, Kramer's Lake York, Lincoln Creek York, Blue River ... Z CHANNEL CATFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1912 Antelope — Nellgh, Mill-pond s Oakdale. Elkhorn River Hastings. Park Lakes UlywM, Pond Bruno, Pond . . JS Lyons, Mill-pond </seg>
            <seg id="p058">59 Yearlings. Disposition Counties. Fry and Adults. Buffalo- Ravenna, Mill-pond :,oo Kearney, State Hospital Pond 200 Kearney, Kearney Lake 500 Kiinning, Middle Loup River. l-ouisville, Joachim's Pond Sutton, Little Blue River m Deweese, Little Blue River Douglas 500 Omaha, Carter Lake ,: Soribner, Elkhorn River Beatrice, Mill-pond . Wymore, Blue River a Harlan — Oxford, Republican River Orleans, Mill-pond a Hitchcock — Culbertson, Frenchman River Jefferson — E Falrbury, Snyder's Pond Johnson — Tecumseh, Mill-pond ■Keystone, Spring Creek •aster— Martell, Gumbo Lakes Martell, Freye's Pond a Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn I ■Auburn, Spring Pond kolls— Superior, Mill-pond Syracuse, Mohr's Pond B Columbus, Ice-house Lake lardson — Falls City, Maust Lake Saunders — Ceresco, Schultz's Lake Weston, Krumlacek Pon S 100 Cedar Bluffs, Eggers' Pond Dewitt, Blue River Crete, Blue River 500 Wilber, Mill-pond </seg>
            <seg id="p059"/>
            <seg id="p060">GAME AND PISH COMMISSION 61 E Disposition, ties. Fry Seward — Seward, Blue River Milford, Blue River Springfield, Neble's Lake .Papillion, Horn's Lake . Alexandria, Averill's Lake Alexandria, Baruth'a Lake Halsey, Middle Ixrap River Total YELLOW BULLHEAD DISTRIBUTION, 1911 Antelope— ■Neligh, Mill-pond :- z Lyons, Mill-pond Bruno, Pond KMurdock, Schewe Pond ing- I West Point, Mill-pond Deweese, Little Blue River Chadron, Spring Ponds Scribner, Elkhorn River Howells, Mud Creek Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake Omaha, Spring Pond 800 200 Laketon, Crystal Lake Grand Island, Wood River » Grand Island, Schimmer Lake St. Michael, St. Michael Sloughs B O'Neill, Elkhorn River lan- E ■ Orleans, Hill-pond hcock— BCulbertaon, Frenchman River srson — Falrbury. Little Blue River s </seg>
            <seg id="p061">62 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION and Adults Counties. Pry Johnson — 1,600 Tecumseh, Mill-pond . . Tecumseh. Spring Pond 100 M-taon- Kearney— Holsteln, Pond Lancaster— Rma, Mill-pond S Hallam, Busch Pond Firth. Pappe's Pond Lincoln, Wyuka Cemetery Pond 1,000 Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn 500 Angora, Willow Creek Ponds. Morrill, Irrigation Lake a Nuckolls— Superior, Mill-pond Syracuse. Little Nemaha Creek ■ Table Rock, Nemaha River Willow— McCook. Driftwood Creek Seward- Milford, Mill-pond Seward, Blue River iS Saunders — Wahoo, Wahoo Creek Ashland, Platte River Thurston — Winnebago, Whitcomb's Lake York, Lincoln Creek York, Blue River . . s YELLOW BILLHEAD DISTRIBUTION, 1912 Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs : Hastings, Park Lakes Butler — Ulysses. Blue River . Ulysses, Spring Pond S Lyons. Mill-pond BOO B Albion, Mill-pond Loetto, Bearer River . . . Petersburg, Beaver River Buffalo — Ravenna, Mill-pond ■S Kearney, Kearney Lake </seg>
            <seg id="p062">63 Yearlings, ' K Disposition, ties. FVy. and Adults. Louisville, Park Lakes Sutton, Little Blue River s Deweese, Little Blue River Dakota— ■Homer, Omaha Creek son- : Lexington, Fagot's Pond Soribner, Elkhorn River Dodge, Mud Creek ■Whitney, Cut-olt lakes Has- South Omaha, Root's Poad Furnas— Cambridge. Mill-pond Beatrice. .Mill-pond . Wymore, Blue River Oxford, Republican River Alma. Spring Creek a s Grand Island, Schimmer Lake Grand Island, Wood River Hitchcock- s Trenton, Mud Creek. Trenton, McConnel's Lake Trenton, Macklin Creek . Johnson — Teeumseh, Mill-pond s ■Tecumseh, Spring Creek ■rson — Fairbury, Snyder's Pond \ Knoxvllle, Schreier Pond Battle Creek, Wendt's I^ke Peru, Spring Lake Pawnee City, Kohn's Pond Columbus, Shell Creek Duncan, Blauser's Slough Humphrey, Spring Lake Dewltt, Blue River Crete, Blue Rlv«r Wllber, Mill-pond !:i = </seg>
            <seg id="p063"/>
            <seg id="p064">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 65 K Disposition. ties. Yearling*, Fry. and Adulu. Saunders — K Ceresco, Schultz Lake Wahoo, Wahoo Creek Seward— 1 Milford, Mill-pond Seward, Blue River Springfield, Neble's Lake La Platte, Trestle Lake Paplllion, Horn Pond Thayer— Alexandria, Sinn's Pond = Ord, Murscbel Pond Webster— Inavale, Spring Creek York, Blue River. Total STRIPED PERCH DISTRIBUTION, 1911. Dunning, Pond 1M Ainsworth, Mill-pond 30* Buffalo — Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake 206 Valentine, Mill-pond «oe Wood Lake, Dewey Lake 200 Sehuyler, McAllister Lake 1,000 Laketon, Crystal Lake 1,1* Red Willow— McCook, Plummer Pond IT* Saunders — Prague, Wagner's Pond , 1 ,000 159 York, Lincoln Creek &gt;&gt;00 York, Blue River 500 STRIPED PERCH DISTRIBUTION, 1912. Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Slougbs j 50* ■Bralnard, Horacek's Pond »lo— K Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake le— Loretto, Beaver Creek Petersburg, Beaver Creek </seg>
            <seg id="p065">rof Pike taken from Platte River near Ashland by a Saunders County angler. A few Pickerel from Whipple'g Lake, near O'Neill, Holt County </seg>
            <seg id="p066">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 67 Counties. Colfax— Fry. and Adults Scnuyler, McAllister Lake Valentine. Mill-pond ■Imperial, Spring Lakes er— ■Ansley, Mill-pond 3ta— Dakota City, Crystal Lake Douglas- ■Omaha, Carter Lake »1- Chappell, Lodge Pole Creek ier — Curtis, Curtis Ijike Wyniore, Blue River 1,000 Heatriee, Mill-pond 1,000 Kwing, Klkhorn Sloughs 15,000 Hitchcock — Trenton. Macklin Creek |M Jefferson — Falrbury, Snyder Pond 100 Kimball, Irrigation Lake IN Lancaster— Martell, Gumbo I^ake 2-&lt;» Central City, Sand-pit Lukes .Madison- Battle Crec-k, Wendt'a Lake aha— Rrock, Xemaha Cut-off Ml Duncan, Blauser's Slough Columbus, Kyle's Siough Columbus. Shell Creek 200 Itluff— Spring l-nkes "no - G«rdon. Horseshoe 1-ake .'.no Saunders — ■ 1'rague, Wagner's Pond 1 .utto Wilber. Mill-pond TOO York, Blue River 5no York, Lincoln Creek f.00 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p067">M GAME AND PISH COMMISSION SUNFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1911. Fingerllngs. DispoBition. Yearlings and Adults Counties. Fry. Antelope — Neligh, Mill-pond Brown — Enderslake, EnderB' Lake Long Pine, Hagan's Lake 2,00(' 400 Box Butte— Alliance, Irrigation Lake 1.000 Anoka, Niobrara Sloughs Lynch, Ponca Creek 800 30f' Laketon, Crystal Lake 50v Douglaa— Omaha, Carter Lake Omaha, Pries' Lake l.OOti 400 Howella, Mud Creek Howells, Spring Lake 1.000 Frontier— Maywood, Maywood Lake St. Michaels, St. Michael's Slough Alma, Republican River Orleans, Mill-pond Hitchcock — Frenchman River Johnson— Tecumseh, Mill-pond Jefferson — Fairbury, Little Blue River Lancaster — ■Firth, Pape Pond oln— North Platte, Birdwood Pond mfm W liO^"' Table Rock, Nemaha River Red Willow— McCook, Driftwood Creek Saunders — Prague, Wagner's Pond Thurston — Winnebago, Whitcomb's Lake SUNFISH DISTRIBUTION, 1912 Ravenna, Mill-pond ■Ainsworth, Mill-pond er— M </seg>
            <seg id="p068">69 Fingerlings, Dispoeltion. Counties. Yearlings, and Adults. Pry. Sutton, Little Blue River Douglas- Omaha. Carter Lake Furnas— 300 Cambridge, Mill-pond 500 Beatrice, Mill-pond Wymore, Blue River Hitchcock- 500 Trenton. Mud Creek 150 Trenton, McConnel's Lake 650 Trenton, Macklin Creek 500 Orleans, Mill-pond Spring Creek ison — Tecumseh, Mill-pond 500 Tecumseh, Spring Creek Jefferson — 200 Snyder pond aster — Lincoln, State University Nuckolls— Superior, Mill-pond Nemaha— 500 Brock, Nemaha Cut-off Peru, Spring Lake . . . 500 100 Richardson — Stella, Mullen's Pond Papillion, Horn's Pond 50 Wilber, Mill-pond Saundere — K Prague, Spring Pond rston — KPender, Spring Lake "7— . KOrd, Murschell's Pond •ter— Inavale, Spring Creek Total ROCK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1911. Buffalo— = Pleasanton, Pleasanton Lake Cherry- Valentine, Mill-pond Laketon, Crystal Lake </seg>
            <seg id="p069">Four Brown County anplers with catch of Rainbow Trout from Long Pine Creek. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">71 Disposition. Counties. Year lines. Fry. and Adults. Jefferson — Fairbury, Little Him- River ROCK BASS DISTRIBUTION, 1912. Brown — Ainsworth. Mill ]«ond Do,. K la S - E B Omaha. Carter I^ake »ta— Dakota City, Crystal Lake Srhuyler, McAllister Lake 500 Beatrice, Mill-pond Wymore, Blue River 200 Kwing. Elkhorn Sloughs K Grand Island, Schimmer's Lake aha— Auburn, Xemaha River Syracuse, Mohr's Pond B Columbus, Guder's olough hington — Fort Calhoun, Horseshoe I&gt;ake. Total SMALL-MOITH BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION. 1911. Cherry — s Wood I^ake, Dewey Lake. Valentine, Mill-pond Dakota— :: BLnketon. Crystal I^ke idan— Gordon, Clear I.ake SMALL-MOUTH BLACK BASS DISTRIBUTION. 1913. Cherry — ■ValPntine, Mill-pond ota— ■Dakota City, Crystal Lake dy- : Benkelman, Adkinson I-ake Total PICKEREL DISTRIBUTION. 1911. 300 Wood I-ake. Marsh Lake Dewey Lake, Dewey T^ake </seg>
            <seg id="p071"/>
            <seg id="p072">73 Fingerlings, Disposition. Yearlings. Counties. Pry. and Adults. GOLDFISH DISTRIBUTION. 1911, 1912 1,180 GERMAN CARP DISTRIBUTION, 1911. Dakota — Homer, Missouri River 2,OUO Lancaster— Hallam, Geistlinger's Fond 100 Firth, Pape Pond 100 Nuckolls— Lawrence, Bueseher's Pond 100 Saunders — Ashland, Platte River M Saline — Tobias, Kuieras' Pond 100 GERMAN" CARP DISTRIBITION Brainard, Horacek's Pond Brainard, Kobza's Pond . s Edholm, Mashek's Pond Hitchcock— Culbertson, Hanke's Pond Nebraska City, Missouri River. La Platte, Platte River Hampton, Austin's Pond Total 2U0 BUFFALO-FISH DISTRIBUTION. 1911. Homer, Missouri River BUFFALO-FISH DISTRIBUTION. 1»12. S Nebraska City, Missouri River Iji Platte, Platte River Totai FRESH WATER CLAM DISTRIBUTION". 1 Lincoln, State Uni\. </seg>
            <seg id="p073"/>
            <seg id="p074">75 HIM. -FROG DISTRIBl TION, 1911. Fingerlings. disposition. Yearlings. Couni Fry. and Adults. Brown— Long Pine, Mill-pond - 2.000 Long Pine, Hagan's Lake 1,000 (""berry — Wood Lake, Dewey Lake MM Valentine. Mill-pond l.OOtt Imperial. Spring Lakes MM l.akcton. Crystal Lake MM Grand Island. Schimmer's I.ake MM Fisheries, Platte River 1,000 Dorchester, Little Blue River 1 .&lt;&gt;«&gt;•"' BULL-FROG DISTRIBl TION, 1912. B Cedar Creek, Metzger's Swamp TV— s Valentine. Mill-pond Col fax— Sehuyler, McAllister Lake Dakota City. Crystal Lake Frontier- Curtis, Medicinp Crook Total </seg>
            <seg id="p075">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION THE CATFISH. When de nights is warm an de moon is full You kin tech mo' cats dan you cares to pull. No trouble 'bout de bait; A grub '11 do or a li'l fat meat, Fer all he wants is supp'n' to eat. En be ain t no ban' to wait. Ner dar ain't no trouble 'bout luck wid him You kin tie yo' line to a swingin' limb. En when you goes to look You'll fin' dat limb a-dodgin' roun En bubbles risin' en floatin' on down, En a catfish on you hook. But I choose to take a pole in mine En git a splotch er bright moonshine En fish dar wid my nan'; I knows, den, when 'e hits his lick (He gwallers de hook; you needn't be qui&lt; k &gt; Een I lets him show his man. When I slings him out on de good dry grac: He don't complain, but he's full er Mas. He kicks a little while. Den lays dar, wid a pleasing look. En while I's rippin' out de hook He takes it wid a smile </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Hatching-house and ponds, Benkelman private fish hatcheries. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>