<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Division of Fire Prevention Seventeenth Annual Report 1925</title>
               <date value="1925">1925</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION SKVKNTKENTH ANNUAL REPORT 19 2 5 John C. Trouton L. J. Butcher State Fire Marshal Assistant State Fire Marshal M. Margaret Morrow E. E. Hayduk Secretary Deputy State Fire Marshal Deputy State Fire Marshal Deputy State Fire Marshal Deputy State Fire Marshal Thomas L. Wilson Ray E. Eaton A. F. "Jack" Rhanney </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ADAM McMULLEN Governor of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003">JOHN C. TROUTON State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OP THE STATE FIRE MARSHAL Office of State Fire Marshal State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska To His Excellency, Adam McMullen, Governor of the State of Nebraska: Dear Sir: The law governing this department provides that a report of the business transacted and the acts performed by the fire marshal and others constituting the department be made to you annually, and I have the honor to herewith submit suck report covering the work we have accomplished during the past year. We have endeavored to carry out and enforce every pro - vision of the law insofar as it lay in our power, and to bring about the greatest amount of good to the greatest number. In our educational work we have endeavored to call the attention of the public to the enormous waste of property, low of life and injury resulting from fire. We have warned against care - less practices and dangerous conditions. We have resorted to every means at our command to get these facts before the public in such a manner as to be effective and bring about the desired results. The Fire Departments. We have viewed with pleasure the increasing interest mani - fested by cities and towns over the state in their fire fighting organizations and equipment, and have tried to aid by sug - gestions and advice to a great number of those adopting new </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 4 methods of discipline and equipment. While the men are the heart and spirit of the department, suitable equipment must be provided or their efforts are retarded and limited. A group of husky firemen with a syringe do not constitute a fire depart - ment. You must have good equipment to work with. And yet, 'with the departments so limited, some municipalities wonder why some of their fires are not more speedily extinguished. The boys can't fight fire with their bare hands. Give them equipment and they reduce fire losses. Fire Prevention Work In all the towns that we have visited officially in the interests of fire prevention, the people have seemed to appreciate our efforts and have assisted us in carrying out the provisions of the law. We have received several invitations to deliver addresses on the subject of fire prevention before town councils and com - mercial clubs, but the duties of our office have been such that we have not been able to respond except in a few instances. We hope during the coming year to visit a number of towns and address them along fire prevention lines. The people over the state have awakened to the fact that keeping their property clean and in good condition means the preservation of life and property by the prevention of fires caused by the accumulation of rubbish, trash and inflammable material, defective electric wiring and defective flues. At the request of the mayors, chairmen of town boards and village boards, city councils and chiefs of fire departments, we have appointed and commissioned Special Deputy Inspectors in nearly every town in the state. The work of these inspectors has been of much benefit to the towns and a great assistance to this office. I hope that in the coming year every city and village will avail themselves of this opportunity to have perpetual care exercised over their buildings by a competent commissioned deputy fire inspector from this office. Fifteen years experience with the State Fire Commission law disclosed the fact that in order to obtain the best results, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION 5 the law should be amended to clothe these Special Deputies with authority so that if the occasion required they could make all inspections in their city or village in regard to fire prevention. The law was amended in this manner at the last session of our state legislature, giving all Special Deputies the authority to make such inspections of their city or village. The Nebraska State Fire Prevention Association has worked in conjunction with us in fire prevention and has rendered us much valuable assistance. Buildings Condemned. There has not been an appeal taken in any of the cases we have had on condemned buildings, and we have issued over one hundred and seventy-five orders on which we have had compliance for the removal and repairing of buildings during the past year. There are as many more on which we have issued orders which are now in the process of removal and repair. Fires Investigated. We have been called upon during the past year to make investigations of what were reported as suspicious circumstances in connection with one hundred and eleven fires. In addition to the arrests made in several of these cases there are a number still in the hands of the various county attorneys for considera - tion as a result of the investigations made by this department. In the matter of gathering evidence, we have exercised the greatest care that no innocent person suffer, but when satisfied a crime had been committed we have done everything in our power to bring the guilty ones to justice, without fear or favor. We have also made it a practice to not burden the county at - torneys with evidence gathered unless this evidence tends to show that a crime has been committed. School Buildings. The Boards of Education and school faculties in the various towns and cities throughout the state with whom we have had </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION occasion to correspond in regard to some item of fire prevention or fire protection in connection with their school houses, have responded willingly to the efforts made by this department to safeguard our school children. In nearly every instance they have met our requirements with no pressure whatever from this office. As Fire Marshal of the State of Nebraska, I have re - garded the above stated fact with a great deal of satisfaction. The installation of proper methods of fire prevention and fire protection in our school buildings is something I desire very much to see accomplished. This can be done only with the cooperation of the Boards of Education and the school faculties, and this we have received to a very large degree during the past year. Words of Appreciation. To you. Governor McMullen, I wish to extend thanks for the interest you have always taken in the work in this office and for the help you have given me personally in promoting; effective service. For the splendid aid and cooperation the Division of Fire Prevention has received from the (ire chiefs and members of the fire departments in the various cities, towns and villages over the state, from the county attorneys, sheriffs and all fire prevention organizations in the interest of the elimination of fire hazards and the investigation of incendiary fires, I wish to ex - press my sincere appreciation. We have endeavored to operate the department in an economical and business-like manner. The success of the work is due to the loyal efforts of everyone connected with the department. The appointment of Mrs. Margaret Morrow as secretary has meant much in carrying on the work started by my predecessors, as her duties have been performed in a most satisfactory manner. Assistant Fire Marshal Lynn J. Butcher and Deputy E. E. Hayduk have rendered valuable service, have always been ready to respond to every call of duty, and are entitled to a </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 large degree of credit for the work that has been accomplished during the year. Our new deputies, Thomas L. Wilson, Ray E. Eaton and A. F. "Jack" Rhanney are manifesting a real interest in the department and are energetic workers. With their added assistance we hope to accomplish much more in 1 926 than dur - ing the past year. In conclusion, I desire to thank you, Governor, for the con - fidence you reposed in me, and I hope that my efforts have met your expectations. I shall endeavor to merit your con - tinued confidence by faithful and honest performance of my duties. Very respectfully. JOHN C. TROUTON. State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 8 FINANCIAL REPORT The law provides a tax to be collected from the fire insur- ance companies doing business in the State of Nebraska "for the purpose of maintaining the department of state fire marshal and paying all the expenses incident thereto." This tax is de- fined in the statutes as follows: "A sum equal to three-eighths of one per cent of the gross premiums and assessments received for fire insurance, less re- insurance and return premiums." The law states further that "the state shall not be liable in any manner for the salary of the fire marshal, deputies, inspec- tors, clerks and other employees or for the maintenance of the office of fire marshal or any expenses incident thereto, and the same shall be payable only from the special fund provided for in this section," this "special fund" being the money collected from the fire insurance companies on business done in the state as explained above. The taxes received by the state fire marshal in 1925 are as follows: Abeille Fire Insurance Company $ 9.36 Aetna Fire Insurance Company 657.47 Agricultural Insurance Company..- . . ... 137.85 Allemania Fire Insurance Company 2.32 Alliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia 89.52 American Alliance Insurance Company 52.99 American Central Fire Insurance Company 1 1 8. 72 American Druggists Fire Insurance Company 5.92 American Eagle Fire Insurance Company 104.72 American Fire Insurance Company 355.51 Atlas Assurance Company, Limited, of London 36.82 Automobile Insurance Company 158.41 Bankers &amp; Shippers Fire Insurance Company 50.88 Boston Insurance Company 86.46 British American Assurance Company 24.59 Buffalo Fire Insurance Company 38.41 Caledonian Insurance Company 67.33 California Fire Insurance Company 13.78 Camden Fire Insurance Company 65.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Capital Fire Insurance Company 276.72 Central Manufacturers Mutual Insurance Company- 24.57 Chicago Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 7.86 Citizens Insurance Company of Missouri 27.23 City of New York Insurance Company 29.40 Columbia Insurance Company * 2.23 Columbian National Fire Insurance Company 7.09 Commerce Insurance Company 18.63 Commercial Union Assurance Company 1 74. 70 Commercial Union Fire Insurance Company 12.13 Commonwealth Insurance Company 133.55 Concordia Fire Insurance Company 31.12 Connecticut Fire Insurance Company 556.08 Continental Insurance Company 522.70 County Fire Insurance Company 12.06 Detroit Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 5.81 Dubuque Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 77.18 Eagle Fire Insurance Company 5.65 Eagle Star &amp; British Dominions Insurance Company 74.58 East &amp; West Insurance Company 22.03 Employers Insurance Company 51.54 Equitable Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 74.68 Eureka Security &amp; Marine Fire Insurance Company 9.92 Federal Insurance Company— 23.68 Federated Merchants Mutual Fire Insurance Co 99.09 Fidelity Phenix Fire Insurance Company 418.20 Fire Association of Philadelphia 143.13 Firemen's Fund Insurance Company 129.21 Firemen's Insurance Company 181.92 Fitchburg Mutual Fire Insurance Company 23.57 Franklin Insurance Company 122.85 General Fire Assurance Company 2 1 .44 Girard Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 63.63 Glens Falls Insurance Company 279.32 Globe &amp; Rutgers Fire Insurance Company 703.60 Grain Dealers National Fire Insurance Company 1 31.33 Granite State Fire Insurance Company 31.06 Great American Insurance Company 504.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Great Lakes Insurance Company 1 3.28 Hanover Fire Insurance Company 144.88 Hardware Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 83.32 Hartford Fire Insurance Company 1,007.1ft Home Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 12.34 Home Insurance Company..* 1,056.50 Hudson Insurance Company 38.94 Imperial Assurance Company 13.38 Importers or Exporters Insurance Company 15.16 Inter-Ocean Re-Insurance Company 1 1.62 Insurance Company of North America .— 627.00 Insurance Company of State of Pennsylvania 43. 1 5 Law Union &amp; Rock Insurance Company 23.63 Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe Insurance Company 41 1.13 London Assurance Corporation 25.72 London &amp; Lancashire Insurance Company 109.39 London &amp; Scottish Assurance Company 5.27 Lumbermen's Mutual Insurance Company 11.38 Maryland Motor Car Insurance Company 1 3.08 Massachussetts Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 9.54 Mechanics Insurance Company of Philadelphia 69.56 Mechanics &amp; Traders Insurance Company 24.32 Mercantile Insurance Company of America 561.09 Merchants Fire Assurance Corporation 62. 1 6 Merchants Fire Insurance Company 6.45 Merchants Insurance Company 10.89 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Illinois 29.29 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 2.54 Millers National Fire Insurance Company 58.72 Mill Owners Mutual Fire Insurance Company 69.61 Minnesota Implement Fire Insurance Company 93.70 Milwaukee Mechanics Fire Insurance Company 1 75.96 National American Fire Insurance Company 415.29 National Ben Franklin Fire Insurance Company 74.55 National Fire Insurance Company of Hartford 1 ,89 1.16 National Liberty Fire Insurance Company 129.57 National Reserve Insurance Company 27. 35 National Retailers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 4.27 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 11 National Security Fire Insurance Company 280.97 National Union Fire Insurance Company 1 32.80 Nebraska Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Co 225. 75 Netherlands Insurance Company . — 56.92 Newark Fire Insurance Company 38.21 New Brunswick Fire Insurance Company 21.64 New Jersey Fire Insurance Company 35.56 Niagara Fire Insurance Company 103.39 North British &amp; Mercantile Insurance Company Ltd. 244.21 Northern Assurance Company, Ltd 70.94 North River Insurance Company 100.62 Northwestern Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company — 78. 1 5 Northwestern Mutual Fire Insurance Company 92.85 Northwestern National Fire Insurance Company — 1 42. 1 1 Norwich Union Fire Insurance Society 72.03 Ohio Farmers Insurance Company 1.34 Ohio Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company 43.06 Ohio Millers Mutual Insurance Company 40.90 Old Colony Fire Insurance Company 25.10 Orient Insurance Company 104.57 Pacific Fire Insurance Company 53.33 Palatine Insurance Company 42.68 Patriotic Insurance Company of America 1.94 Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company 156.47 Philadelphia Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 22.59 Phoenix Assurance Company, Ltd. of London 60.69 Phoenix Insurance Company of Hartford 506. 1 6 Potomac Fire Insurance Company .20 Providence Washington Fire Insurance Company- 32.81 Prudential Insurance Company 23.97 Queen Insurance Company 292.05 Reinsurance Company "Salamandra" 128.64 Reliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia 24.89 Republic Fire Insurance Company 21.41 Retailers Fire Insurance Company 12.63 Retail Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company— 107.65 Rock Island Fire Insurance Company 79.60 Rocky Mountain Fire Insurance Company 2.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 Royal Exchange Assurance Company 2 1 .08 Royal Insurance Company, Limited 375.27 Safeguard Insurance Company 25.91 Scottish Union &amp; National 109.57 Security Insurance Company 249.61 Springfield Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 649.63 Standard Fire Insurance Company 3.72 Star Insurance Company of America 44.09 State Assurance Company of Liverpool 19.22 Sterling Fire Insurance Company 7.84 St. Paul Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 599.23 Sun Insurance Office of London 60.04 Superior Fire Insurance Company 5.92 Svea Fire Insurance Company , 37.77 Tokio Marine &amp; Fire Insurance Company 20.86 Twin City Fire Insurance Company 1 32. 1 1 Union Assurance Society 16.08 Union Fire Insurance Company of Lincoln 71 7.23 Union Fire Insurance Company of Providence 20.53 Union Insurance Society of Canton 19.98 United Firemens Insurance Company of Philadelphia 7.43 United States Fire Insurance Company 218.82 U. S. Merchants &amp; Shippers Insurance Company .85 Utah Home Fire Insurance Company 4.02 Victory Insurance Company 21.54 Westchester Fire Insurance Company 109.70 Western Assurance Company 18.06 Western Grain Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Co... 98.10 World Auxiliary Insurance Corporation 1 4. 1 5 Total Tax Collected $ 21,734.22 Balance on hand January 1st, 1925 in treasury- 8,697.77 Total Fund January Ut, 1925 $ 30.431.99 The above figures show the amount of tax money on hand to cover the expenditures for the year 1925. These expendi- tures were as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p014">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 13 $ 7,779.67 7,779.67 Salaries Office Expense Express . 1.64 Printing _ 172.05 Stamps 120.00 Supplies and Equipment 190.87 Telegraph 6.84 Telephone 124.25 Miscellaneous 9.70 Total $ 625.35 625.35 Inspectors' Expenses (Traveling) Railroad Transportation $ 891.86 Hotel Expenses 2,023.95 Telephone and Postage 26.49 Auto Expense, Taxi and Carfare 1.071.00 Miscellaneous 36.20 Total $ 4,049.50 4,049.50 Expenses Incurred in Investiga - tions of Fires Temporary Services $ 70.50 Photographs 11.75 Total $ 82.25 82.25 Fire Report Fees Paid to Fire Chiefs for Reporting 1924 Fires _$ 690.00 690.00 Total Expenditures for 1925 $ 13,226.77 Total Fund January 1st. 1925 $ 30.431.99 Total Expenditures Jan. 1 to Dec 31. 1925 13.226.77 Balance on hand Jan. 1 , 1 926 $ 17.205.22 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 On January 1st, 1926, the balance is $17,205.22, which with the tax collected in 1926 for the business done in 1925 will make the total fund to cover the expenditures of the depart- ment for 1926. SUMMARY OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Inspections made— 8100 Orders issued by inspectors 8454 Buildings demolished by order of this department 105 Buildings repaired by order of this department 70 School buildings equipped with fire escapes, repaired, and otherwise altered, to meet the requirements of the state laws, by order of this department 46 Theaters extensively repaired and altered, to meet the requirements of the state laws, by order of this de - partment 1 7 Fire escapes installed on apartment houses by order of this department 3 Fire escapes installed on buildings other than school houses and apartment houses by order of this de - partment . 1 0 Fires investigated 1 1 1 Persons arrested for arson 1 4 Persons convicted of arson . 5 CAUSES OF FIRES AS REPORTED DURING 1925 Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Sparks from chimney on roof 247 75 146 468 Defective chimney 16 6 54 76 Gasoline and kerosene stoves 1 7 51 68 Overheated stoves and furnaces 20 7 37 64 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 15 Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Communicated 19 6 34 59 Defective electric wires and motors 16 7 33 56 Spontaneous combustion 25 10 26 6 1 Children and matches 29 3 21 53 Cigarettes, cigars and pipes 33 3 18 54 Inflammables too near stoves and pipes 8 4 17 29 Bonhres and burning grass 27 1 15 43 Incendiary 15 3 15 33 Gasoline explosion 1 5 1 4 29 Hot ashes against wood and in wooden containers 23 2 14 39 Oil burners in stoves and furnaces 7 11 18 Short in auto wires 3 11 14 Sparks from engine 1 2 10 13 Lightning 1 8 9 Overheated and defective stove and furnace pipes 2 2 8 12 Gas heaters 1 7 8 Chicken brooders and incubators 7 8 Heating oils and greases on stove 6 , 7 1 3 Defective stoves and furnaces 2 6 8 Miscellaneous 6 6 Starting fires with gasoline and kerosene 5 5 Motor backfired 5 6 Mice and matches 6 4 Careless use of matches 1 2 4 16 Electric flatirons and curling irons, etc.— 1 7 3 20 Popcorn machines 3 3 Motor overheated 2 2 Motion picture films 112 4 Fireworks 5 2 7 Hot air registers "Z. 2 2 Curtains, etc set on fire by lamp 2 2 4 Light cord on bed post 1 I Defective incinerator __^____ 2 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Tar kettle exploded I 1 Fire place 3 115 Meat on stove 1 1 Rubbish against building 2 1 3 Hot air and steam pipes .. 1 1 2 Candles on Christmas trees ... 1 1 Coffee urn exploding 1 I Acetylene tank exploding 1 1 Toy films I 1 Thawing out pipes with torch and blow pot 3 1 4 Washing clothes with gasoline 3 1 4 Washing woodwork with gasoline 1 1 Unknown 76 16 167 259 Paper over flue hole, 5 5 Sparks from stoves and furnaces 7 7 Sparks from belt 1 1 Friction sparks 1 1 Blow torch .... 5 .. _ 5 Overheated smoke stack and furnace pipe 2 2 Leaky gas pipes 2 2 Fumigating __ 2 2 Filling lamps, lanterns and oil stoves. 2 2 Lamp upsetting 1 1 Total number of fires 691 159 786 1636 1925 FIRE LOSS, VALUE OF PROPERTY INVOLVED, AND AMOUNT SAVED BY FIRE DEPARTMENTS Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Value of Buildings $23,876,127.00 $999,050.00 $4,058,005.00 $28,933,182.00 Loss on Buildings 284,063.67 121,000.00 717,488.50 l!l22|552.17 Saved en Buildings 23,592,063.33 878,050.00 3,340,516.50 27i8ioi629.83 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 17 Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total A BRIEF HISTORY OF THE OUTSTANDING ARSON CASES INVESTIGATED DURING 1925 Ewing, Nebr. — January 1 3th, the Ewing Mills burned at 1! : 30 a. m. Valued at $ 1 5,000.00, insurance $9,000.00. Charles E. Peterson arrested February 7th. Tried in District Court March 1 7th and jury instructed to bring in a verdict of not guilty. Columbus, Nebr. — April 4th. Residence of Mollie I. Porter set on fire at 1 :45 a. m. House saturated all over with kerosene. Charles D. Prickett, a roomer, only person at home, Mrs. Porter having gone to Omaha in the evening. Both were arrested and bound over to District Court. Prickett was tried on September 23d and the jury disagreed. Both will be tried next term of court. Thedford, Nebr. — May 2nd. 1925, Earl Myers and Claude E. Thurmond were arrested for the burning of a farm property, belonging to Myers' father and two uncles, on April 10th, 1923. In 1924 young Thurmond was converted at a revival meeting and decided to live a straight clean life. So he went to the proper officials of the Burlington Railroad Company, as this railroad company had paid the loss on the buildings believing a prairie fire set by one of their trains had set fire to the build - ings, and confessed to them the whole story. The case was turned over to the State Fire Marshal to investigate and prose - cute, which was done. Myers was cashier of a bank at Thedford. Preliminary hearing was held on June 1 8th and the two men were bound over to District Court November 12th, 1925. At this trial Myers pleaded guilty and the judge paroled them both from the bench with the understanding that each was to pay back to the railroad company the money obtained. Myers paid of Contents x&gt;ss on Contents laved on Contents 145,011, 224.00 229,091.17 44,782.132.83 185.000.00 897,000.00 694.071.98 1,731.407.39 1,108.163. 47,410,540.: </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 $775.00 and half the costs of the case and Thurmond $475.00 and half the costs. Creighton, Nebr. — On February 28th at 3:00 a. m. the farm home of Dr. Jay Foreman, I 3 miles west of Creighton, was burned to the ground. Seymore R. Leisure, a young man resid - ing in the neighborhood, was arrested on June 5 th and held for preliminary trial on June 1 7th. The evidence was insufficient in the opinion of the prosecution to bind him over to District Court and he was dismissed. Omaha, Nebr. — May 1 2th at 1 :00 a. m. a small shack owned and occupied by Caronio Distefano at 1212 South Thirteenth Street was burned. Distefano was arrested May 25th but the two main witnesses disappeared and the case was dis - missed June 6th. Omaha, Nebr. — June 1st at 2:45 a. m. the hotel at 2323 N Street, South Side, owned and occupied by Nick Salistean, was burned. Building and contents over-insured. Salistean was arrested and bound over to District Court to be tried in Jan - uary, 1926. Leigh, Nebr. — July 26th the farm home of Mrs. Gerhard H. Buesing, 2 miles south of Leigh, occupied by Emil Molle, was set on fire about 3:30 p. m. in the absence of the occupants. A can of coal oil was used. The fire department answered promptly and small damage was done. The husband, Gerhard H. Buesing, is suspected of setting the fire in revenge, as he is not living with bis wife and threatened her on several occasions. He was seen the day of the fire but disappeared and is still missing. Alliance, Nebr. — July 3 1 st at 1 1 :30 p. m. the dwelling of Mrs. Florence G. Timmins occupied by Vernon L. Thompson and wife, Helen Thompson, was burned to the ground. On the evidence obtained, Thompson and wife were arrested on September 1st down in Missouri and returned to Alliance where they were bound over to District Court. When the case went to trial it was dismissed for lack of evidence to prove the corpus delecti. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 19 Cumro, Nebr. — On July 25th, about midnight, Clifford A. Watts, living on a rented place 2'/2 miles northwest of Cumro in Custer County, set fire to the house and barn to collect in - surance on the contents. He confessed and was paroled from the bench for a period of two years. York, Nebr. — September 1 6th. Charles W. Harter at about 11:30 p. m. set fire to his house and contents to collect the insurance. He confessed to the insurance adjuster and then dis - appeared before the law could take him into custody. He baa not been captured as yet. Oakdale, Nebr. — On November 14th at 1:20 a. m. fire destroyed the barn and damaged the house of Wm. Wagner, one and one-half mile south of Oakdale. Virgil Wagner, a son, was arrested and bound over to District Court in $1000 bond. DEATHS FROM FIRE Alliance — Mrs. F. H. Buelow was fatally burned when her clothing caught fire in her attempt to kindle a fire with kerosene. Arapahoe — Earl A. Stamfield was fatally burned when a five gallon can of louse killer which he was heating on the stove exploded, covering him from head to foot with the flaming contents. Arapahoe — The four-year-old son of Mr. and Mrs. William Blazier was burned to death when he set fire to their barn while playing with matches. Axtell — Mrs. Anton J. Sievers died from burns received when she used kerosene to start the kitchen fire. Beatrice — Mrs. Lillith Obdink died from barns received when gasoline which she was using for dry cleaning exploded. Bloomfield — Fred Heavrin, a volunteer fireman, was killed by the explosion of their chemical tank while attempting to extinguish a burning popcorn machine. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 Broken Bow — Elizabeth Donahue, fifteen years of age, died from burns received when sparks from the cook stove ignited her dress. Butte — Harold Henkle, five years old, received fatal burn* when a gasoline lamp exploded. Chappe'l — Dee Mick died from burns received when a blow torch which he was using exploded. Chester — Jack Ray was fatally burned when he poured coal oil on a dead fire in an effort to start it. Columbus — The three small children of Neal Drum, Leland 4, Maurice 2, and Neal Jr. five months, were burned to death when the house caught fire from an overheated stove. The children were alone at the time. Columbus — Paul Carstenson, four years old, was burned to death in a hay barn containing 40 tons of hay in the mow. It is thought he was playing with matches and set the barn on fire. Cornlea — Mrs. Samuel Payne and her 2 1 months old son were fatally burned when she attempted to start a fire with kerosene. Falls City — Frank Fortner, 68 years old, and his two grand - children, Orville and Marie Elders, 1 5 and 1 2 years of age, perished when his farm house caught fire, supposedly from an overheated stove. Hooper — Mrs. William Boldt, Sr. and her little grand - daughter, Obera Martin, were burned to death when their home caught fire from an overheated kitchen stove. Humphrey — Two-year-old Esther Streblow was burned to death when her dress caught fire from the kitchen stove while her parents were absent from the house. Kearney — Orville T. Shreve was fatally burned when he lit a cigarette after his clothing had become saturated with gasoline while repairing an auto. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 21 Kearney — Julia George, two years old, waa fatally burned while playing on the floor with matches. Fumes from a nearby gasoline can ignited and caused an explosion which engulfed the child in liquid fire. Lincoln — Mrs. H. F. Ludwig died from burns received when she attempted to hurry the kitchen fire by pouring gasoline in it. Lincoln — Miss {Catherine Kotch died from burns received while filling a lamp. Her clothing became oil-soaked in some way and were ignited. Lodge Pole — Little Charlie Robinson, 1 3 years old, was fatally burned while playing with gasoline and a lighted blow torch. He and several other small boys were dipping sticks in an open can of gasoline, then lighting them at the blow torch and chasing each other around. Charlie stumbled over the can of gasoline, spilling it on his clothing which immediately took fire from his blazing stick. McCook — William S. Parsons, a teamster, was fatally burned when he used kerosene to hasten the fire in the kitchen stove. Milligan — Harry Wilson died from burns received when his car caught on fire, supposedly from a cigar or pipe. Nebraska City — Mrs. Fred Markel died from burns received while filling a gasoline lamp with gasoline from a pitcher. A static spark caused the vapor to explode, throwing the blazing liquid over her. Nebraska City — Violet Kreider, five years old, died from burns received when her clothing caught fire while she was play - ing near a stove. Oconto — Mr. Claire Bissell, Miss Eva Moore and another young lady were fatally burned when they were trapped beneath their car which had turned over and caught on fire. Omaha — Francis Hildebrand, four, was burned to death when his parents' home was destroyed by fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 Omaha — Mrs. Rose McDonald died from injuries received when her auto collided Math a fire truck that was making a run to a fire. Omaha — Anthony McGinty, aged recluse, burned to death in his home. Cause unknown. Omaha — Mrs. Sarah H. Reagen was burned to death when she went to sleep smoking a cigarette which set fire to the bed clothing. Omaha — Mrs. Edith H. Shinrock, 69 years old, died from burns received when her night gown caught fire from an electric heater by which she was warming herself. Omaha — Mrs. Paul Fickenscher died from burns received at her home, from an explosion of gasoline which had been used in the dumb waiter to kill ants. Mrs. Fickenscher went to place something on the dumb waiter and struck a match and the fumes of the gasoline exploded instantly, enveloping her in flames. Plainview — Mrs. Perry Kingsbury Smith, 82 years old, died of burns received when her dress caught on fire. Royal — W. S. Borden died from burns received when he started a fire with kerosene. Sargent — Mrs. Frank A. Gustafson, 50 years old, died from burns received when she used kerosene to hurry a slow fire. Superior — H. C. Smith, 68 years old, found burned to death in his yard. It is thought that his pipe set his clothes on fire and that he ran out into the yard. Sutherland — Little Lena Marie Jensen, 3 years old, was burned to death when her home was struck by lightning. The child's mother was knocked unconscious by the bolt of lightning and on regaining consciousness found the house destroyed. Table Rock — Herman Brauer, 32 years old, committed suicide by pouring gasoline over his clothing and setting fire to them. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION 23 Talmage — Mrs. Henry Kramer was burned to death when she used kerosene or gasoline to hurry the fire in the stove at the wash house. Tobias — Mrs. Sarah Wilson died from burns received while rendering lard which caught on fire, igniting her clothing. Weeping Water — Mrs. Mabel Robbins died from burns re - ceived when the oil tank on an incubator exploded, setting her clothing on fire. INJURIES FROM FIRE Albion — James Barta was severely burned by the explosion of a gasoline tank. Alliance — W. R. Harper, a fireman, run over by a truck and leg broken and foot smashed on a run to a fire. Arlington — Herman Jungbluth, a farmer, was badly burned about the hands and face when a can of gasoline exploded just before he started to pour it on the fire in the kitchen stove. Arapahoe — Mrs. Earl Stanfield was badly burned about the head and shoulders when a five gallon can of louse killer her husband was heating on the stove exploded. Mr. Stanfield died from the burns he received. Battle Creek — H. F. Hans was severely burned when the linseed oil which he was heating on the stove exploded. Beatrice — Mrs. Ada Barrett was badly burned while trying to save her daughter, Mrs. Lillith Obdink, who was fatally burned when the gasoline she was using for dry cleaning ex - ploded. Brainard — Joe Zikmund had one arm badly burned when the gasoline-soaked rag he was using to wipe the grease off his tractor exploded. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 Bridgeport — Keith Galfort, eight years old, was severely burned, being totally blinded, when a gasoline tractor tank, around which he was playing, exploded. Butte — The small son of William Henkle was severely burned 'when a gasoline lamp exploded. The other son, Harold, was fatally burned at the same time. Bridgeport — Roy Reed was badly burned from a gasoline explosion when he slipped and spilled gasoline against a hot stove in a garage. Bridgeport — Floy Butler, I 2 years old, was seriously burned about the face, neck and arms when starting a fire in the cook stove with kerosene. Chappell — Ed Jones was badly burned on hands and arms when he picked up a lighted lantern immediately after washing grease off his hands with gasoline. Columbus — Henry Moschenross was severely burned on face, neck and hands when he threw a gasoline-soaked brush into the stove, the flames leaping out and burning him. Columbus — Otto B. Johannes, Assistant Fire Chief, was badly burned by the explosion of a gasoline blow torch. Cornlea — Mable Payne was badly burned on the hands and arms in trying to save the lives of her mother and baby brother who were fatally burned when the mother attempted to start a fire with kerosene. Crete — John Kvech and his son August, 12 years old, were both severely burned by contact with a live electric wire. David City — Two firemen were slightly injured while fight ing fire. De Witt — One fireman slightly hurt on a run to a fire. Fairbury — Jess Bradshaw, who operates a dry cleaning </seg>
            <seg id="p026">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION 25 establishment, was badly burned when a fire started in his gaso - line cleaning machine. Fremont — Mrs. Chris Kielstnip was badly burned when gasoline stove exploded. Fremont — Ralph Herman was severely burned on face and hands when a kerosene tank whcih he was cleaning out ex - ploded from a candle falling into it. Fremont — Mrs. Thomas Jens was slightly burned on the arms when she rushed into a burning garage and saved the life of little Melvin Young. Fremont — Mrs. A. C. Gerken and son Jack, 3 years old, were painfully burned when she tried to save personal effects from their farm home after it caught fire from a defective chimney. Gering — Vaughn Carpenter and Albert Smith were seriously burned while blasting rock near there. Grand Island — Robert Bean, 6 years old, was severely burned by the explosion of gasoline. Grand Island — Arthur Wilson, a U. P. R. R. employee, was severely burned about the hands and upper portion of his body when paint which he was carrying past a stove ignited. Hastings — A fireman was dangerously hurt from falling glass while fighting the American Hotel fire. Kearney — Mrs. George and her 1 1 year old son were badly burned trying to extinguish the flames from a gasoline explosion which burned her little daughter, Julia, to death. Kearney — Carl Jones, a prisoner, was burned when he at - tempted suicide by setting the bed clothes in his cell on fire. Lincoln — Mrs. J. P. Ford received severe burns to her right foot when making her escape through the burning hall of an apartment house. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Lincoln — Dr. George E. Condra of the State University suf - fered painful burns to the right hand and his face when a motion picture film in the photographic room of Nebraska Hall took fire. Lincoln — Arthur Sinamark, a mechanic, was painfully burned on his hands and face when the gasoline with which he was washing a motor caught fire from a short in the wiring. Lincoln — Mrs. Ella Kotch was severely burned about the hands in trying to save the life of her daughter, Katherine, who was fatally burned while filling a lamp. Merna — Charles Lutes, a mechanic, was severely burned by ■n explosion which occurred while he was beneath a car clean - ing some of the parts with gasoline which was ignited by a spark. Monroe — Ted Brockman was severely burned while filling die tank of his car with gasoline at a filling station. A lighted lantern in the rear seat of his sedan set fire to the fumes from the gasoline. Nebraska City — Fred Markel was severely burned on the hands in trying to save the life of Mrs. Markel who was fatally burned while filling a gasoline lamp with gasoline from a pitcher which was exploded by a static spark. Nebraska City — C. I. Livingston, a farmer, was seriously burned when the gasoline engine he was attempting to start exploded. Norfolk — Leo Sedlacek, ten years old, was very seriously burned and injured when he touched a match to a dynamite cap which he found in the basement of the school house. Omaha — Paul Fickenscher was severely burned trying to save Mrs. Fickenscher' s life. Mrs. Fickenscher was fatally burned by a gasoline explosion. Omaha — George Blubaugh, about the face and hands when fur cleaner, was badly burned gasoline stove exploded. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION 27 Omaha — Marvin R. Bishop, driver for Assistant Fire Chief, ■was overcome by smoke and was in the hospital for some time. Omaha — Mrs. Sophie Waskyevic and her five year old son, Thomas, were very severely burned when she attempted to start a fire with kerosene. The house burned to the ground. Omaha — Roy Nelson, an employee in a dry cleaning estab - lishment, was severely burned when 90 gallons of gasoline took fire from a spark of static electricity. Omaha — Cecil Hildebrand was seriously burned when her parents' home was destroyed by fire. Her small brother was fatally burned. Ord — Devona Bilderbae, fourteen months old, was seriously burned when her dress caught fire from an exploding heating •tove. Pawnee City — Leslie Percival, 1 6 years old, suffered severe burns to his hands when he attempted to start a fire in a stove with gasoline. Pawnee City — Mrs. Ed Shinn, living 9 miles northeast of Pawnee City, was perhaps fatally burned when her clothing caught fire while she was attempting to start the gasoline engine to a washing machine. Pierce — H. J. McMillan was painfully burned with an elec trie wire while working on a pole. Scottsbluff — Ward Elliott, a prominent attorney, was severe - ly burned about the face and hands when he threw coal oil in the furnace to hasten the fire. Springview — Mrs. Abe Titus was perhaps fatally burned when she attempted to start a fire with kerosene. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">28 TOTAL DEATHS FROM FIRES Men 1 3 Women 19 Children 1 7 Total 49 TOTAL INJURIES FROM FIRES Men 32 Women Children 11 13 Total 56 JUST A FEW WORDS IN REGARD TO FIRE PREVENTION How few of our buildings like hospitals, sanitariums and hotels are planned for safety to life and how often are even percautions taken nullified by careless use and handling. Theaters are too often built with little thought of safety to patrons in case of fire, have inadequate exits and are allowed to be crowded beyond safety. With scores of lives we neglect even the most common precautions. We pass laws compelling our children to attend school and then put them in dormitories and school buildings that are a menace to their lives and prac - tically shuts them off in case of fire from all but a bare chance of escape. The God of War no longer destroys our young manhood. Why should the fire demon be allowed to destroy our women and children? Our brave soldiers laid down their lives to save civilization and Christianity on earth, to make the world safe for democracy, and from our crushed hearts we say "It is well," </seg>
            <seg id="p030">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION 29 but there is no excuse for our people, through ignorance and carelessness, to sacrifice the lives of our women and helpless little children in the smoke and flames of the fire fiend. The state laws of Nebraska provide that the teachers of public and private schools and educational institutions shall hold two fire drills each month, and also that 30 minutes of each school month be given to the teaching of fire prevention. If our teachers obey this law it will do much to lessen the fire danger in our schools. The responsibility of keeping all doors and exits unlocked during school hours is also laid upon the teachers. There is an average of six school house fires a day in the United States. It behooves us to give our school house careful attention if it is not going to be one of these six that are destroyed by fire every day. 1 wish to call attention to some electrical hazards found nearly every day by our inspectors both in school houses and business places. The misuse of fuses of all kinds is the big question of today because of the process of easy substitution. The purpose of a fuse is to protect the line or circuit from being over-loaded and to protect the building from a dangerous fire. Some people are of the opinion that if the fuses blow, almost anything will be good enough if it will keep the lights burning or the motor running. This seems to be one of the worst troubles. These substitutes are used without figuring on the weakness of some other part of the line. The weak points are switch and socket contacts and wire joints. A fire started by one of these defects does not start immediately, but will smolder away for periods varying from one to forty-eight hours before breaking out. There are many hazards created by defective wiring. Inas - much as the wires are the carriers of the current, they should be perfect in design and be properly installed in order to avoid all unnecessary trouble. Rubber covered wire is the type most commonly used and the one with which we have the most trouble, not because it is rubber covered but because of its </seg>
            <seg id="p031">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION 30 misuse. It is used for all interior work, with the exception of moving picture machines. The greatest trouble so far resulting from wires is the failure of drop cords and the way they are installed, repaired and misused. Drop cord should never be used for wiring purposes and where it ia used for that purpose, it should be taken out and replaced with rubber covered wire no smaller than No. 1 4 B. &amp; S. gauge. This No. 1 4 rubber covered wire must not carry over 660 watts on one circuit and must not be fused to carry over 1 0 Amp. As an example of what fire prevention can accomplish, we are quoting below the 1925 yearly report of the Kearney Fire Department, as reported by Mr. Rhoades, Fire Chief: "Kearney, Jan. 15, 1926. Dear Sir: I herewith take pleasure in submitting fire report for the year, 1925. We responded to 47 alarms segregated as follows Chimney burning out 1 Tar exploded while heating • I Overheated gas mangle I Oil stoves Gasoline cleaning . 2 Matches 1 Sparks from chimney on roof 4 Grass fire 3 Heating linseed oil on gas stove Sparks from train I 2 Gasoline stove 1 Defective flue Automobiles 4 6 Spontaneous combustion 2 Smoking 1 Coal gas in furnace 2 False alarm Unknown 5 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 31 Hours spent at fires for year 1925 19 hours, 43 min. Water used 5 times 40 gal. chemical used 10 times 2J/2 gal- chemical used 5 times Pumper worked 3 hours, 10 minutes Largest attendance of members at fires 36 Smallest attendance of members at fires 4 Average attendance of members at fires 23 Total estimated loss for year 1925 $5,000.00 "Possibly the latter part of this report is not of any vital interest to you, but as we had same compiled, are passing same on for your disposal. I wish to say at this time we feel very proud of this report, and think we have just cause. As an active member of the Kearney Volunteer Fire Department for about 30 years and its chief for the last 8 years, I wish to state that to the best of my knowledge and belief this is the lowest per capita loss ever experienced in any one year. "Another item of great interest to us and no doubt will in- terest you, is the fact that we only used water 5 times for 47 alarms and one of these was on a grass fire. This will clearly demonstrate the value of chemical and one of the principal reasons for our low loss. "Another feature that we most heartily endorse and will cooperate with you to the limit, is the state inspection that has been put on in Kearney in the past year. We feel that this has been very beneficial in bringing to minds of the people of Karney the great importance of fire prevention, and we think we are now reaping the results. "Last but not least by any means, we wish to inform you of the splendid cooperation of the Boy Scouts of Kearney, which was in a measure responsible, in our judgment, in hold- ing down our loss. "Summing it all up, we as the Volunteer Fire Department of Kearney feel we have closed a very successful year and with </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 32 the continued close friendship and cooperation of parties here - tofore mentioned, will continue to do our part to the utmost. Yours for cooperation, KEARNEY VOLUNTEER FIRE DEPARTMENT By Elmer L. Rhoades, Fire Chief." (Signed) This is a marvelous record for a town the size of Kearney and the citizens of the town may well be proud of their fire department. I believe Kearney boasts the lowest fire loss for 1925 of any town of its size in the State of Nebraska, perhaps in the United States. There are always a great many condi - tions in a town the size of Kearney which, if not eradicated, will cause fires. The surprisingly low fire loss shown on this report is a silent tribute to the work done by the boys of the Volunteer Fire Department of Kearney in the eradication of these dangers. Inspection of a town by its fire department is always of great benefit to the town, both in the eradication of conditions which result in fires and the education given its citizens in fire prevention by such an inspection. I sincerely hope that 1926 will be even more successful for this energetic fire department of Kearney, and that many more towns will profit by Kearney's experience and be equally succesful in keep - ing their fire loss down in 1 926. In closing, I will quote for the information of the fire de - partments, city councils and town and village boards, the law covering the levying of a tax to raise money for equipping a fire department. We have had several inquiries regarding this law and believe this information will be of interest to a great many: "Section 4469. Compiled Statutes for 1922. FIRE DE - PARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX. All cities of the metro - politan, first or second class or villages, organized under the laws of the State of Nebraska, shall have power and authority to levy a special tax of not more than one and one-half (1%) mills each year upon all taxable property in said city. Such special levy shall be made by the same officers or board and shall be levied in the same manner as in the case of general city taxes. Revenue raised by such special levy may be used only for the purpose of purchasing equipment for a fire department </seg>
            <seg id="p034">DIVISION OP" FIRE PREVENTION 33 of such city or for installing and equipping a fire alarm system, or in payment of bonds as hereinafter authorised. "Section 4470. BONDS — AUTHORIZED. Any city or Tillage having levied a tax as herein authorized may anticipate the col - lection of such tax so levied, and for that purpose may issue bonds with interest coupons attached, in a sum amounting to 90 per cent of the tax so levied. Such bonds may run for a period of not more than five years, and may bear interest at a rate not to exceed 5 per cent per annum. Bonds so issued shall be secured by such tax so assessed and levied, and shall be payable only out of the funds derived from such tax. In any case in which bonds are issued as herein authorized, it shall be the duty of such city, on receipt of such tax when paid, to hold the same as a separate fund to the amount of the bonds so issued, and the interest thereon, for the purpose of paying or redeeming such bonds." DON'TS DON'T use make-shifts instead of proper fuses in ' your elec - trical circuits; the fuse is the safety valve of the system. DON'T leave electric flatirons or other heating devices turned on while attending to something else. DON'T look for gas leaks with an open flame light; you will be sure to find them. DON'T use gasoline or other volatile liquids to remove spots from clothing or for other purposes. It is cheaper to pay for dry cleaning than for a funeral. DON'T throw your matches or lighted smoking material where they can possibly start a fire. DON'T smoke in bed; even if those guilty of this practice are too green to burn, the beds are not. DON'T let the children play with matches or bonfires. DON'T fail to have your defective chimneys avid flues mended; they cause numerous fires in our state. DON'T forget to have your smokepipe cleaned of soot; if clogged it may overheat and start a fire when you operate the furnace. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION DON T neglect to protect walls, ceilings and partitions from the overheating of stoves, furnaces and pipes. DON DON T T put hot ashes into wooden boxes or barrels fill oil lamps or stoves by open flame lights; many lives have been lost by this form of carelessness. DON T let rubbish accumulate; uncleanliness and fire go hand in hand. DON T fail to keep a bucket of water and a bucket of sand in a convenient place for use in case of fire; they may save the lives of your family. DON T fail to purchase a good fire extinguishing chemical (one or more) for your home. DON T fail to look after chemical extinguishers; see that they are immediately charged after being used. A 2 '/2 or 3 gallon turnover chemical can be used by man. woman or child and one or more should be installed in every home. REMEMBER, IN CONCLUSION, FIRE IS A DANGER THAT NEVER SLEEPS," SO BE CONTINUOUSLY ON YOUR GUARD. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">York Blank Book Co., York, Nebraska</seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>