<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1912 TO THE GOVERNOR</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1912 TO THE GOVERNOR Gillespie A Phillips, Printers, Lincoln, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Office of Secretary of State, Lincoln. Nebraska. November 30, 1912. To His Excellency, C. H. Aldrich. Governor of the State of Nebraska: KDear Sir: — I have the honor to present herewith my biennial report Secretary of State, for the biennium ending November 30, 1912, rh contains a statement of all fees received by this office. This report contains appropriations for, and the expenditures of this office, also list of corporations filing articles during the last biennium. The report of municipal and school bonds approved by me is omitted, as the same appears in the report of the Auditor of Public Accounts. I have also omitted certificates of approved banks, as this list appears in the report of the Banking Board. List of notary commissions issued has also been omitted. The contracts made and entered into by the Board of Public Lands and Buildings for repairs and improvements at the several State Institutions I have also omitted, together with the contracts for fuel and supplies, as the same will appear in the report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. In this report I have endeavored to include only such matters as pertain to this office. • Respectfully submitted ADDISOX WAIT, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">SECRETARIES OF STATE TERRITORIAL 1. Thomas B. Cuming. Aug. 23, 1854, to Mar. 12, 1868. 2. J. Sterling Morton, July 12, 1858, to May 6, 1861. Algernon S. Paddock, May 6, 1861, to Feb. 21, 1867 STATE. 4. Thomas P. Kennard, from Feb. 21, 1867, to Jan. 10, 1871 5. Wm. H. James, from Jan. 10, 1871, to Jan. 13, 1873. Acting Governor, from June 2, 1871, to Jan. 13, 187 6. John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. 7. Bruno Tzschuck, from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879. 8. S. J. Alexander, from Jan. 9, 1879, to Jan. 4, 1883. 9. Edward P. Roggen, from Jan. 4, 1883, to Jan. 6, 1887. 10. Gilbert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1887, to Nov. 20, 1889. Resigned to fill unexpired term in Congress caused by the death of James Laird. 11. Benjamin R. Cowdry, from Nov. 20, 1889, to Jan. 8, 1891. Appointed by Governor Thayer to fill vacancy caused by resigna- tion of Gilbert L. Laws. 12. John C. Allen, from Jan. 8, 1891, to Jan. 3, 1895. 13. Joel A. Piper, from Jan. 3, 1895, to Jan. 7, 1897. 14. William F. Porter, from Jan. 7, 1897, to Jan. 3, 1901. 15. George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. 6, 1905. 16. A. Galusha, from Jan. 6, 1905, to Jan. 3, 1907. 17. Geo. C. Junkin, from Jan. 3, 1907, to Jan. 5, 1911. 1% Addison Wait, from Jan. 5. 1911, to Jan. 9, 1'.' </seg>
            <seg id="p006">FACTS AND EVENTS IN NEBRASKA HISTORY THE TERRITORY. Territory of Nebraska was organized May 30th, 1854. The Territory was a part of the Louisiana Purchase ceded by France to the United States in 1803. First Territorial Legislature held at Omaha commencing January 16th, 1855, consisting of 13 Councilmen and 25 Rep - resentatives and the 12th and last session convened at Omaha January 19th, 1867. The seat of Government was permanently located at Lancaster, the present site of Lincoln, July 29th, 1867. The Territory sent 3,157 men to the Union army during the Civil War. Lincoln statue and memorial erected on State House grounds — unveiled Sept. 2nd, 1912. THE STATE. Nebraska was admitted to the Union as a State March 1st, 1867, by act of Congress passed February 9th, 1867, and by Proclamation issued by President Andrew Johnson and attested by Hon. William H. Seward, Secretary of State, and* dated March 1st of that year. The first State Legislature was held in Lincoln January 7th, 1869. The present Constitution was adopted November 1st, 1875. The extreme length of the State east and west is 412 miles. Its greatest breadth north and south is 208 miles. Its area is 76,895 square miles, or 49,212,000 acres Number of votes cast in 1868 — 15,291. Number of votes cast in 1907—271,491. Population in 1900 was 1,066,300. Nebraska's population in 1910, 1,192,214 Gain in last decade, 125,914. Gain percentage, 11.8. Counties showing net loss, 21. Counties showing net gain, 71. Counties losing in First district, 6 of 7. Counties losing in Second district, 1 of 3. Counties losing in Third district, 3 of 15. Counties losing in Fourth district, 5 of 12 Counties losing in Fifth district, 6 of 18. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">FROM 1868-1912 1868 15,291 1889 167,268 1M1 Ju 1872 15,250 1890 214.07:: 1902 198,574 1876 49,387 1891 145,131 .06,587 1887 145,708 1900 251,000 1012 259,124 1888 202,291 « HON. ADDISON WAIT, SECRETARY OF STATE At the Lincoln Monument, which was unveiled and dedicated on the State House Grounds Labor Day, September 2nd, 1912. 1879 61,682 1892 195,290 lHOt 1880 87,452 1893 181,606 1905 102.152 1881 75,527 1894 213,6:&gt;2 1906 194.W2 1882 86,259 1895 141,412 1907.. :'03,934 1883 99,409 1896 224,174 1908 271,491 1884 134,193 1897 194! _t)7,576 1885 126,840 1898 190,657 1910 243,390 1886 138,209 1899 22rt.^4!&gt; 1911 225,380 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 LINCOLN MONUMENT Brief history of the Lincoln Monument, erected on the State House Grounds, Lincoln, Nebraska. Address delivered by Hon. Addison Wait at the unveiling September 2nd, 1912: The difficulty in promoting an enterprise of this kind is in creating a public sentiment for it. All art is based on sentiment, and it is only occasionally a subject is conceived which creates general public interest, and the more valuable as an educational factor the more it appeals to public sentiment. The life and character of Abraham Lincoln is one of the most inter - esting biographies of our time and every man, woman and child of the age of reason, in our country, knows much of that life and receives inspirations for better things from knowing it. This sentiment is strong Pthe survivors of the Civil war in the North, and especially with the rans that participated in the conflict. Abraham Lincoln as president their commander-in-chief ; not only that, he was their comrade, and honor and love they cherished for him in those dark days remains enshrined in their hearts more lustrous than ever before. It is not strange, therefore, that they, above all others of our citizens, should take the initiative in an enterprise of this kind. There have been efforts put forth at five different times to raise funds for the erection of a memorial to Abraham Lincoln, and each time but one, started by a veteran of the Civil war. Effort No. 1. The first of which I find any information, was made by Comrade Sargent (since deceased), a member of Abraham Lincoln Post No. 10, G. A. R., of David City, who, about 1880 introduced a resolu - tion in the Post providing for the payment of ten cents by all members Ke G. A. R., in the department of Nebraska, to create a fund for the ion of a memorial to Abraham Lincoln on the University campus at Lincoln. This proposition was taken up by the state department, but was not promoted to a successful issue. Effort No. 2. Another comrade, John Currie, of Lincoln, who as a Kble cutter, had developed considerable skill as a local sculptor, made lodel life size statue of Lincoln, which created considerable public interest, so much so, that the state of Tennessee contributed to Nebraska two blocks of marble to be used by Comrade Curry for further develop - ment of his artistic skill. These blocks of marble still repose on the state house grounds, and the ambition of the local sculptor was never realized. Effort No. 3. During the twenty-eighth session of the Nebraska K filature, Comrade J. H. McClay, representing Lancaster county in the we of Representatives, introduced House Roll No. 78, which provided an appropriation of ten thousand dollars for the erection of a monu - lt on the campus of the state capitol in the city of Lincoln, Nebraska, in memory of the life and public services of Abraham Lincoln. This bill </seg>
            <seg id="p009">passed the House almost unanimously, but in the Senate an amendment was attached, providing that the city of Lincoln should add an equal amount to the proposed appropriation, and the bill as amended failed to pass. Effort No. i. During the incumbency of F. W. Brown, as Mayor of the City of Lincoln, he started a subscription list among the citizens of Lincoln to obtain the means for the erection of a statue of Abraham Lin - coln on the campus of the City Hall in Lincoln. This, however, was a purely local enterprise, and for some unknown reason was abandoned. Notwithstanding the apparent failure Of these efforts, they have in an indirect way borne fruit in creating that essential factor for this enter - prise, "public sentiment." Effort No. 5. On the evening of the 12th day of February. 1908, being the 99th anniversary of the birth of Abraham Lincoln, which was cele - brated by a banquet at the Lincoln hotel by the Young Men's Republican Club, a veteran of the Civil war introduced a plan for providing means and promoting an enterprise for the erection of a statue and memorial to Abraham Lincoln on the state house grounds. This plan was later put into force and effect, and the following prospectus was issued for the information of the public: "Lincoln, Nebr., March 28, 1908. To everybody living in Nebraska young or old. We extend a patriotic greeting. February 12, 1909, will be the one hundredth anniversary of the birth of Abraham Lincoln. Ne - braska has long neglected her duty to her citizens and their posterity in her failure to recognize the wise and patriotic lessons to be derived from a suitable monument and statue on the state house grounds, in com - memoration of this great American citizen. What undertaking can be more patriotic and fitting for us who have appropriated his name for our capital city, an enterprise in which all may participate, than to com - memorate this anniversary with our contributions much or little and thereby insure that this monument will be a reality without further delay. At a meeting of the Young Men's Republican Club held in Lincoln. Neb., on February 12, 1908, in commemoration of the- birth of Abraham Lincoln, the following plan for providing means for the erection of a monument to his memory on the state house grounds was adopted by a rising vote of all present, and this was the birth of the movement. So profiting by the experience of others in the past who made efforts along this line, born of a loyal and patriotic motive, but at an unpropitious time, and failed, we have organized this association on the basis of a state-wide interest in the movement, and with the state officers as of - ficers and trustees of the association, believing there should be a head and systematic method in conducting such affairs. A meeting of the elective state officers wasjield at the office of Governor Sheldon on Feb - ruary 17, 1908, and a plan proposed, which was adopted and the follow - ing officers named: Oov. 0. L. Sheldon, president; Geo. C. Junkin, secretary of state. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 fttary; L. G. Brian, state treasurer, for treasurer; Addison Wait, ty secretary of state, corresponding secretary. The following were ?d as trustees: H. M. Eaton, commissioner of public lands and lings; W. T. Thompson, attorney general; E. M. Searle, Jr., state tor, and J. L. McBrien, superintendent of public instruction. The wing is the plan for the government of the association and for the •mat ion of the public: I First. — This monument to be erected on the state house grounds in city of Lincoln, the site to be designated by the officers of the elation. Second. — The funds for the erection of the same shall be raised jointly by individual contributions and appropriations by the legislature. 1 Third. — The state treasurer is hereby made the custodian of all funds cribed and paid for this purpose, and said funds are to be transmitted is successor in office if not used during his term of office. I Fourth. — The secretary and the corresponding secretary are author - to use such methods as they may deem expedient for raising the s and promoting the success of the association. t Fifth. — The officers of the association are hereby authorized to ■nd a sum not to exceed ten per cent of the amount of the comribu - i for the promotion of this enterprise. No salaries are to be paid to officers and no money expended except for plans and specifications, age, stationery, printing, stenographic work, necessary clerk hire and missions for raising funds when necessary. I Sixth. — The raising of this fund is in no sense to be considered a tisan or local undertaking, but shall be state-wide in its soliciting, and are asked to contribute regardless of political or religious affiliation, , color or sex. The officers of this association are to be succeeded as ir successors to the various state offices are elected. I Seventh. — Pledges may be made to this fund payable on the call of treasurer. Blanks will be provided for this purpose. It is desired all contributions be made before the 31st session of the legislature, h convenes on the first Tuesday in January, 1909. Eighth. — If for any reason the money subscribed and paid cannot be used for the above purpose on or before July 4, 1910, the same shall be refunded (unless otherwise agreed), less ten per cent of the amount, which may be used for necessary expenses as provided for in section five. t Patriots will be needed in every community to canvass for funds, the secretary will furnish such printed matter as may be needed i application. We will appreciate the aid of the newspapers of the :, as the success of the undertaking largely depends on its publicity, lly send the secretary marked copies and the clipping will be used in prospectus. The corresponding secretary is a veteran of the Civil and will depend on the comrades of the g~eat war president in every munity to assist according to their ability jn raising the $25,000 nec - ry for the completion of this memorial. We, more than any other ration of men living, know the worth and character of Abraham </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Lincoln. He was one of us in the dark days of the sixties, ever giving us courage when experiencing doubts and fears as to the outcome of that awful strife, now while the light holds out to burn, let us pay this last tribute to his blessed memory. This we owe to posterity and the present generation. tThe president of the association is a veteran of the Spanish-American and will appreciate any effort in behalf of this enterprise by his rades of that army. If each one of us shall make this a personal :er success is sure and a grateful commonwealth will say — "well Soon after issuing this prospectus subscription blanks were dis - tributed throughout the state and subscriptions were being generously made. The officers were now satisfied that sufficient funds would be available, so they extended an invitation to Mr. F. M. Hall of Lincoln to assume the responsibility of selecting a committee to assign the commis - sion of making the 3tatue to a sculptor of their choosing. Mr. Hall ac - cepted the invitation, and named as such committee. Chancellor E.. Ben - jamin Andrews, General ("has. F. Manderson. Guerdon \V. Wattles. Prof. Wm. F. Dann, Dr. H. B. Lowry, and Addison Wait. On June 24th, 1909. this committee held a meeting in the office of the secretary of state, and after due deliberation, unanimously awarded the commission of making the Lincoln statue to Daniel Chester French, sculptor, of New York City. Mr. French accepted the proposal of the committee, and in Janu - ary. 1911, submitted a model of the statue and plans of the accessories. On January 31st, the committee held a meeting at the Capitol and adopted the following resolution: t 'Resolved, that the model of Mr. Daniel Chester French for the le of Lincoln, together with the plans thereof, be hereby approved adopted, and that Mr. French be authorized to proceed with the ution of the central feature of the monument, consisting of a bronze statue of about eight and- one-half feet in height, with pedestal and back - ground in granite, to be decided upon later, the cost thereof not to ex - ceed $30,000, payment to be made as the work progressed." On December 12. 1911, a proposition from Kimball Bros, of Lincoln, to build the granite facade for the sum of $7 000 was accepted, and con - tract and bond ordered drawn accordingly. These contracts have been fulfilled, and the committee presents to the state the finished product. I desire to read an article written for the press on the anniversary of Lincoln's birth, 1911: "The signing of the contract with the famous New York sculptor, Daniel Chester French, for the work on the Lincoln statue, marks the beginning of the end of an idea which for years has been uppermost in the minds of the most patriotic citizens of Nebraska. The present movement, the one which after three years of effort, now indicates its success, had its inception at the banquet of the Young Men's Republican Club, held at the Lincoln Hotel on the evening of February 12, 1908. Much impetus was given to the movement on that </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 evening, and among all those present there was not one but that en - thusiastically promised his aid in carrying the idea to successful termina - tion. That very week another meeting was held to further the cause, and the matter assumed more definite shape. ' The Abraham Lincoln Centen - nial Memorial Association of Nebraska was organized, with Geo. L. Shel - don as president, Secretary of State Geo. ('. Junkin as secretary, and Addi son Wait, the present secretary of state, as corresponding secretary. L. C. Brian, the state treasurer, was made the treasurer of the associa - tion, and the attorney general, the state superintendent of public instruc - tion, and the commissioner of public lands and buildings were named as trustees. It was stipulated at that time that the successors of these men should constitute the active officers of the organization. The campaign for funds was then begun in earnest. The first money to be subscribed and paid into the fund was from the Union Veteraus' Republican Club, and the General Custer Circle of the Ladies of the 0. A.*R., each society contributing the sum of $25.00. Other offerings came in from the city and over the state from all manner of sources, until the amount today totals nearly $10,000. The last ron of the legislature made an appropriation of twice that amount so the fund now at the disposal of the association is $30,000. This all be spent for the statue proper with its background and pedestal. I An additional amount, estimated at between $8,000 and $10,000, will needed to complete the work and provide for the base and other accessories as planned originally. This will include an elaborate facade, a platform laid in cement, and tiled, with an eighteen inch balustrade of polished granite surrounding it. Much granite will enter into the make - tof the statue setting, and there will be two bronze lamp posts of sually elaborate design mounted on the base. These alone, it is mated, will cost between $500 and $1,000 apiece. When completed the Lincoln monument and statue, it is expected, will be the finest in the Vnited States, even excelling the one located in Lincoln park, Chicago. The sculptor. Daniel Chester French, has given assurance that he will have the product of his handiwork completed by May 31st, of next year. A model of the statue is now on exhibition at the city library." Ground was broken for the concrete foundation December 22, 1911. Suitable recognition of the event was observed by the presence of Gov - ernor Aldrich and the state officers, Mr. F. M. Hall, Rev. J. H. Presson and many others, nearly all of whom gave expression of approval and commendation of the enterprise. The granite used in the monument is from the celebrated quarries near -Quincy, Massachusetts. The first car load arrived on -May 6th, 1912, and the first large block in the base was placed in position on May 16th. The statue arrived over the Northwest - ern railroad on June 22nd, and was erected in position on June 29h. The entire monument, including the facade, cement walk, parking, etc., was completed on Saturday. August 24th, 1912, and this day marks the closing of a period of over four years since the movement began. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">KKPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE The architectural features of the memorial were designed by Henry Bacon, of New York, who is the architect for "the San Francisco exhibi - tion to be held in 1915, and who has been recently honored by the Gov - ernment Commission by the adoption of bis plans for the Lincoln •memorial to be erected in Washington, D. C, at a cost of over one million dollars. t. Daniel Chester French, of New York, who made the statue, has won rid-wide fame for his statuary and art productions and has added ter and renown to his name by the production of our Lincoln. It would be unfair to conclude this sketch without mentioning the name of Mr. F. M. Hall, of Lincoln, whose efforts for the enterprise made it possible for success. I shall always remember with gratitude the en - thusiasm and earnestness which characterized his motives until the last block of granite was in place in the monument. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">A GOOD VIEW OF THE STATUE </seg>
            <seg id="p015">KEl'OUT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATK 15 DESCRIPTION OF STATUE AND MEMORIAL The statue is of heroic size, being eight feet six inches high and pro - portionately large; weighing 1,300 pounds. It represents Mr. Lincoln in an attitude of deep meditation, the head bowed looking toward the ground, the hands tightly clasped, left foot slightly forward and weight of body resting on the other, seemingly about to deliver those immortal words embodied in the Gettysburg speech. On the whole, it impresses one with the serious aspect of Lincoln's life, and to behold it arouses new interest in the wonderful character and experiences of the martyred president. tThe pedestal of polished granite on which the statue stands is six high and four feet wide and two feet thick. The background of the tie of polished granite, on which is engraved the Gettysburg address, ds sixteen feet high and fourteen feet wide and two feet thick, arfd six blocks of which it is composed weigh about forty-five tons. At er end of the background are carved thirteen grooves representing the thirteen original colonies. A band encircles them, representing the force of the adage "In union there is strength." At the base of these emblems is an American eagle carved from and a part of one of the blocks of granite, with extended wings assuming an aggressive attitude charac - teristic of the bird when annoyed. Placed on a granite base at either end of tha plaza are two bronze lamp posts six inches in diameter and ten feet high, representing stalks of corn, with leaves projecting near the bottom, and surmounted with tungsten electric lamps and glass globes eighteen inches in diameter, giving a beautiful soft lighting effect to the whole monument at night. The facade in front of the statue facing the west is twenty-one by seventy feet. On the east side and at the ends is a granite wall four feet high and two feet thick. The several blocks composing this wall and the slabs in the floor weigh about fifty tons, giving a plain but massive effect to the entire structure, particularly indicative of the character of the man it commemorates. In front of this to the west three steps descend to a concrete plat - form twelve by eighty feet and from this steps are provided to reach the walks to the front and sides of the platform. tThe committee desires to express their appreciation of the help ac - ed by the newspaper reporters of this city, and the editors generally ughout the state, who at all times have been boosters of the enter - prise, appreciating to the full extent the value of this memorial and statue as an inspiration to the citizens of today and for those in all future generations. This monument is built to endure, and the lessons it imparts will grow in the esteem of the people more and more as tkrc </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE House Roll No. 36, of the 31st session of the Legislature, introduced by Mr. H. P. Henry, representing Holt county, now a resident of Iowa. An act to provide for the erection of a statue and memorial to Abraham Lincoln on the state house grounds in Lincoln, Nebraska, and to appropriate money therefor. Le it Enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska: Section 1. "That there is hereby appropriated out of any funds in the state treasury not otherwise appropriated the sum of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000) for the erection of a statue and memorial to Abraham Lincoln on the state house grounds in Lincoln, Nebraska. Section 2. Said statue and memorial shall be erected under the supervision of the Governor and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings acting jointly with the Abraham Lincoln Centennial Memorial Associa - tion. The Governor, the Board of Public Lands and Buildings and the trustees of said association shall have power, acting jointly, to prepare specifications, employ a sculptor and architect, and to make all other arrangements necessary for the erection of said statue and the memorial. Provided, that the Abraham Lincoln Memorial Association shall place in bank, subject to the order of the joint commission provided for in this act not less than $10,000 before the above appropriation or any part thereof shall become available for the purposes of this act. The statue and memorial shall be the property of the State of Ne - braska, under the care of the Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Section 3. The Auditor of the State of Nebraska is hereby author - ized to draw warrants upon the State Treasurer of the State of Nebraska for the amount of tHis appropriation upon vouchers approved by the Governor and Secretary of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Approved March 12, 1909. A. C. SHALLENBERGER. Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Itemized Cost of Statue and Accessories. Statue $20,01' Architect's fees 2.000 00 Two bronze lamp post 1,400.00 Background and accessories and eng aving Gettysburg speech eagles, etc 8,890.00 7,000.00 Kacade and granite wall. Front, platform, walks, parking, etc 940.00 Total $40,230.00 Resources. Appropriation by State Legislature l*M $20,000.00 Appropriation by City of Lincoln r&gt;,000.00 Sale to sculptor for privilege of copying in miniature or statu - ettes 2,890.00 General subscriptions 10,950.00 By Board of Public Lands and Buildings for platform, parking, etc Unpaid pledges 450 . 00 Total $40 230.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 RKPORT OF THE SECRETARY OK STATE • OFFICE FORCE OF DEPARTMENT OF STATE Addison Wait. Syracuse. Nt-br Deputy Secretary of State Ceo W. Marsh. I'niversity Place. Nebr Bookkeeper T. W. Smith. I'niversity Place. Nebr Corporation Clerk Walker Smith, Normal. Nebr Clerk. Beula Wait, Lincoln, Xebr Nellie M. l.each. Lincoln Nebr M. E. Holland, Lincoln. Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p019">NEBRASKA STATE GOVERNMENT F FOLLOWING ARE THE OFFICERS OF THE STATE AS SHOWN THE RECORDS OF THIS OFFICE. THE TERMS OF THE EXECUTIVE OFFICERS EXPIRES ON JANUARY 9, 1913. ter II. Alilruh ( iovernor Lieutenant Governc tlao of State. urer M. K. Hop. Addisuu Wait Walttr A Auditor of Public Account Silas K. Itarton Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildin KM ward H Attorney General Grant ('.. Martin Superintendent of Public Instruction James B. Delzell Winnett. H. J., Lincoln. 1H12 Hailway Commissioner Ilfe, Jr., H. T., Omaha. 1914 I. T. I... Lincoln, 191o DMoaaai OFFICERS-ELECT WHOSE Railway Commissioner Railway Commissioner TERM OF OFFICE EXPIRES •i&gt;, OFFICERS-ELECT WHCSE TERM OF OFFICE EXPIRES JANUARY, 1915. JANUARY, 1915. Governor John H. Mor. ernor John H. Mor Lieutenant Governor 8. R. McKeh it- itenant Governor B. R. MiKel retary of State Addison V Treasurer Walter A Auditor of Public Accounts \V. B. Howard Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings Fred Beckmann Attorney General Grant G. Martin Superintendent of Public Instruction • lames K. Delzell Clarke, Jr., H. T., Omaha. 1914 Railway Commissioner Hall, T. U, Lincoln, 1116 Railway Commissioner Taylor, H. C... Central City, 1918 Railway Commissioner FEDERAL DEPARTMENT I'nited States Senator Xorris Brown. 1913 United States Senator Gilbert M. Hitchcock, l :♦ 1 7 Inited States Senator-elect George W. \orri&gt; CONGRESSMEN WHOSE TERMS EXPIRE MARCH 4 1913. First District John A. Maguire Second District C. O. Lobeck Third District Dan V. Stephens Fourth District Charles H. Sloan Fifth District George \V. Xorris </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 CONGRESSMEN-ELECT WHOSE TERM OF OFFICE EXPIRES MARCH 4, 1915. First District John A. Maguire Second District CO. Lobeck Third District Dan V. Stephens Fourth District Charles H. Sloan Fifth District Silas R. Barton Sixth District Moses P. Kinkaid CONGRESSIONAL. DISTRICTS BY COUNTIES. rt District — Cass, Otoe, Xemaha, Richardson, Pawnee, Johnson, and Lancaster. Second District — Sarpy. Douglas, and Washington rd District— Burt, Thurston, Dakota, Dixon, Cuming, Dodge. Colfax, Stanton, Wayne, Cedar, Knox, Pierce, Madison, Platte, Nance, Boone. Antelope, and Merrick. r-th District — Saunders, Butler, Seward, Saline, Gage. Jefferson. Thayer, Fillmore, York, Polk, and Hamilton. ri District— Hall, Adams. Webster, Franklin, Kearney, Phelps, Harlan, Gosper. Furnas, Red Willow, Frontier, Hitchcock, Hayes. Perkins, Chase, Dundy, Nuckolls, and Clay. ri District— Sioux, Scotts Bluff. Banner, Kimball, Dawes. Box Butte, Cheyenne. Sheridan, Deuel, Cherry, Grant, Morrill, Garden. Keith, Lincoln, McPherson. Hooker, Thomas, Ix&gt;gan, Dawson, Custer. Blaine. Brown. Keya Paha, Rock, I.oup. Holt, Garfield, Valley. Sherman, Buffalo, Howard, Greeley. Wheeler, and Boyd. JUDICIARY SUPREME COURT. Chief Justice — Manoah B. Reese. Lincoln, 1914 Justices — John B. Barnes, Norfolk, 1916 Jacob Fawcett, Omaha, 1916 Samuel H. Sedgwick, Lincoln, 1916 Charles B. Letton, Fairbury, 1918 William B. Rose, Lincoln. 1918 Francis G. Hamer, Kearney, 1918 DISTRICT JUDGES. Term expires 1914. tt District — John B. Raper, Pawnee City, •nd District — Harvey D. Travis, Plattsmouth. Third District— Albert J. Cornish. Lincoln; P. James Cosgrave, Lincoln; Willard E. Stewart, Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Fourth District — George A. Day, Omaha; Lee S. Estelle, Omaha; Howard Kennedy, Omaha; Charles Leslie, Omaha; Willis G. Sears. Tekamah; Abraham L. Sutton. South Omaha; Alexander G. Troup, Omaha. Fifth District— George F. Corcoran, York; Edward E. Good, Wahoo. Sixth District — Conrad Hollenbeck, Fremont ; George H. Thomas, Sehuyler. Seventh District — Leslie ('. Hurd, Harvard. Eighth District — Guy T. Graves. Pender. Ninth District — Anson A. Welch, Wayne. Tenth District — Harry S. Dungan. Hastings. Eleventh District — James R. Hanna, Greeley; James X. Paul, St. Paul. Twelfth District — Bruno O. Hostetler. Kearney. Thirteenth District — Hanson M. Grimes, Xorth Platte. Fourteenth District — Edward B. Perry, Cambridge. Fifteenth District— R. R. Dixon, O'Neill. Sixteenth District— Wm. H. Westover, Rushville. Seventeenth District— Ralph W. Hobart, Mitchell. Eighteenth District — Leander M. Pemberton, Beatrice. STENOGRAPHERS. Supreme Court Stenographer*. Nettie M. Dortch Norfolk C. L. Hobbs Lincoln O. E. Johnson Lincoln J. E. Ferris Lincoln Winifred Kaup Western Florence Wilson Lincoln Evelyn Hanna Lincoln District Judges' Stenographers. First District Ernest J. Brown, Beatrice J. A. O'Keefe, Beatrico Second District Farl R. Travis, Plattsmouth Third District Myron E. Wheeler, Lincoln Arthur R. Richardson, Lincoln C. A. Emery, Lincoln W. S. Heller. Omaha Fourth District Thos. P. Wilson, Omaha W. J. Fawcett. Omaha Geo. W. Meecham. Omaha W. I. Speice, Columbus Seventh District Daisy Williams, Geneva Eighth District J. B. Rossister, Walthill Ninth District W. H. Powers, Norfolk Tenth District G. M. Baird, Wilcox Eleventh District O. A. Abbott. Grand Island . j T D 1 "* t D 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Twelfth District _.T. Hermanson. Kearney Eeenth District teenth District enth District. . E. A. (ary. North Platte V. R. Schober. Cambridge C. B. Scott. O'Neill J. D. Scott. Rushville SUBORDINATE STATE OFFICERS Adjutant General, N. N. 0 E. H. Phelps Banking Board E. Royse, Secretary Board of Irrigation D. D. Price, Secretary Board of Charities and Corrections Joel A. Piper Deputy Labor Commissioner L. V. Guye Deputy Game and Fish Warden Henry N. Miller Deputy State Food Commissioner Nels Hansen Deputy State Veterinarian A. Bostrom Chief Oil Inspector \Vm. Husenetter Printing Board Harry Thomas Dep. Comr. Agricultural Society. Horticultural Society W. R. Mellor, Secretary C. G. Marshall. Secretary Board of Equalization Henry Seymour, Secretary Dairymen's Association S. C. Bassett, Secretary Poultry Association A. H. Smith, Secretary UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BOARD OF REGENTS. George Coupland. Elgin : January, 1914 C. B. Anderson. Lincoln January, 1914 Charles S. Allen, Lincoln January. 1916 \V. O. Whitmore, Valley January, 1916 Frank L. Haller, Omaha January. 1918 V. G. Lyford, Falls City January, 1918 .1. Stuart Dales, Lincoln Secretary Samuel A very, Lincoln Chancellor STATE NORMAL SCHOOLS. Peru Daniel \V. Hayes. President Kearney A. O. Thomas. President Wayne it. s. Conn, President Chadron Joseph Sparks, President </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE INSTITUTIONS Industrial Home. Milford Lena K. Ward. Superintendent School for the Deaf, Omaha Dr. P. W. Booth. Supt School for the Blind. Nebraska City R. C. King, Superintendent BOARDS The Secretary of State, by virtue of his oil member of the following boards: Board of Equalization and Assessment. Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Board of Educational Lands and Funds Board of Purchase and Supplies. Board of Pharmacy. Board of Canvassers. Board to Approve Depository Bonds. Board of Prison Inspectors. Voting Machine Commission. Board of Veterinary Medicine. Following is a list of the various State Boards, and the members thereof: BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. Meetr first Monday of each month. Edward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands and BalMlngl. President Addison Wait. Secretary of State s. retary Walter A. George. State Treasurer The following otHeers are appointed their terms expiring to pleasure of the appointive power, the officers being as foil" Nebraska Hospital for Insane. Lincoln. .. Dr. B F. Williams. Supt. Hastings Insane Asylum. Ingleside Dr. W. S. Kern. Superintendent Norfolk Asylum for Insane. Norfolk Ilr. A. Johnson. Superintendent Soldiers" &amp; Sailors' Home, Grand Island. T). \V. Hoyt. Commandant Soldiers' &amp; Sailors' Home. Milford Toseph Teeters. ( oiim State Penitentiary, Lancaster S. M. Meliek. 'Warden Orthopedic Hospital. Lincoln Dr. H. YVinnett Orr. Supt. Tuberculosis Hospital. Kearney Mr*. I'earl Barker. Head x am! Superintendent Institute for Feeble Minded Youths. Beatrice Dr. W. M. Thomas. Supt. Boys' Industrial School. Kearney C. B. Manuel. Superintend- Girls' Industrial School, Geneva I.ydia 3. McMahon Snpt. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS Meets second Tuesday of each month. Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman Edward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public I^ands and Buildings Secretary Walter A. George, State Treasurer. Addison Wait, Secretary of State. Grant G. Martin, Attorney General. BOARD OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES. Meets first working day of January, April, July and October. Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman Edward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings. . . . Secretary Addison Wait, Secretary of State. Walter A. George, State Treasurer. Grant G. Martin, Attorney General BOARD OF PHARMACY. Meets second Wednesday of February, May, August and November. Silas R. Barton, State Auditor Chairman Edward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings. . . .Secretary Addison Wait, Secretary of State. Grant G. Martin, Attorney General. Walter A. George, State Treasurer DEPOSITORY BOND BOARD Called Meetings. Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman Addifon Wait. Secretary of State. Grant G. Martin, Attorney General BOARD OF ASSESSMENT AND EQUALIZATION Meets for assessment first Monday in May. Meets for Equalization third Monday in July Chester H. Aldrich, Governor chairman Addison Wait, Secretary of State. Walter A. George, State Treasurer. Silas R. Barton, State Auditor. Edward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings Henry Seymour Secretary PRINTING COMMISSION Chester H. Aldrich. Governor Commissioner Harrie G Thomas Deputy Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BOARD OF CANVASSERS. Meet* second Tuesday in September and fourth Monday in November. Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman Walter A. George, State Treasurer Silas R. Barton, State Auditor. Addison Wait, Secretary of State. Grant G. Martin, Attorney General BOARD OF EDUCATION. I. F. Koach. President, term expires 1915 Lincoln A. H. Viele. Vice-President, term expires 1916 Norfolk J. J. Tooley. Secretary, term expires 1914 Anselmo *. P. McDonald, term expires 1913 Kearney A. L. Caviness, term expires 1917 Fairbury James E. Delzell, Superintendent of Public Instruction Lincoln Walter A. George. State Treasurer Lincoln PRISON INSPECTORS. Board of Public Lands and Buildings VOTING MACHINE COMMISSION. Called Meetings, Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman Addison Wait. Secretary of State Silas R. Barton, State Auditor. BOARD OF VETERINARY MEDICINE. Called Meetings, Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman Addison Wait, Secretary of State. Silas R. Barton. State Auditor. A. Host roni State Veterinarian BOARD OF HEALTH. Called Meetings. Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman James E. Delzell, State Superintendent Grant G. Martin, Attorney General BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. Meets third Tuesday of January, April, July and October Chester H. Aldrich, Governor Chairman James E. Delzell. State Superintendent Secretary Edward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">:■ REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE TRANSACTIONS OF BOARDS The report of the Board of Educational I ands and Funds will be found in the report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, which will also contain the transactions of the Board of Purchase and Supplies. The action of the Board of Equalization and Assessment will be found in the report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, which will also contain the transactions of the Board to Approve Depository Bonds. The Board of Canvassers has canvassed the vote on the several Con - stitutional Amendments, and declared the same adopted by a majority vote; also the vote on Presidential Electors, and issued certificates of Election to the same. The Board of Prison Inspectors will be included in the report of the Warden of the State Penitentiary. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">r MATED EXPENSES FOR THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE FOR THE BIENNIUM COMMENCING APRIL 1, 1913. OFFICF EXPENSES For preparing session laws for printer, copying comparing, and indexing same, stationery, books, blanks, printing, binding, lithographing, express, freight, telegraph, telephone, ship ment of laws and journals, furniture, repairs, postage, such clerical and stenographical help as may be necessary for the recording and licensing of corporations and other office penses $4 •&gt; f registering letters, blank applications, blank records and issuing licenses for automobiles Total appropriation for the- biennium $6.60 SALARIES Secretary of State, salary, two thousand dollars $2,(H Four thousand dollars for the biennium $4," Salary for Deputy, eighteen hundred dollars $l,v Three thousand six hundred dollars for the biennium $3,K Salary of Bookkeeper, sixteen hundred dollars $ 1,600. 00 Thirty-two hundred dollars for the biennium $3,200.00 Salary of Corporation Clerk, fifteen hundred dollars $1,500.00 Three thousand dollars for the biennium $o.000.00 Salary of Recorder, one thousand dollars $1,000.00 Two thousand dollars for the biennium $2,000.00 Salary of one clerk, one thousand dollars $1,001). 00 Two thousand dollars for the biennium $2,00 Salary of Motor Vehicle Clerk, one thousand dollars $1,00 Two thousand dollars for the biennium $2.000. M Salary of Stenographer and Copyist $1,000.00 Two thousand dollars for the biennium </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 FEES The fees revived by this office for services performed during the past two years, from December 1st, 1910, to November 30th, 1912, inclu- sive, are as follows: » tiling and recording Articles of Incorporation and Cer - tificates of Agents $ 45,224.29 t affixing Great Seal of State and forwarding Notarial Com - missions 1,982 . 00 For filing and allowing Live Stock Bramds 1.884 . 46 For Motor Vehicle Licenses 11,708.20 For Certificates, Transcripts, Trade Marks and Labels 1,426.51 For Corporation Permits -. 121,041 .30 For Corporation Penalties 5,200.00 Total $188,466.76 APPROPRIATIONS AND EXPENDITURES The Legislature of 1911 made the following appropriations for this office for the purposes named below: Secretary of State. Salary (per annum $2,000) $4,000.00 Expended 3,000 . 00 Balance November 30, 1912 $1,000.00 Deputy. Salary (per annum $1,800) $3,600.00 Expended : 2,850 . 00 Balance November 30, 1912 $ 750.00 Bookkeeper. Salary (per annum $1,500) $3,000.00 Expended 2,375 . 00 Balance November 30, 1912 $ 625.00 Corporation Clerk. Salary (per annum $1,500) $3,000.00 Expended 2,375.00 Balance November 30, 1912 $ 625.00 Recorder. Salary (per annum $1,200) $2,400.00 Expended 2.000 . 00 Balance November 30, 1912 $ 400.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 Clerk. Salary (per annum $l,OO'i) $2,000. Expended „ 1,666 . 6«"» Balance November M, 1911 $ Stenographer Salary ( per annum $840.00) $ Expended 1 Balance November HO. 1912 For preparing Session Uws for comparing, and indexing printer, copying, ame, stationery, books, blanks, printing, binding, lithographing, express, freight, telegraph, telephone, shipment of laws and journals, furniture, repairs, postage, such clerical and stenographical help as may be necessary for the recording and licensing of corporations and other office expense $4 Expended ::,:',4M . 76 Balance November 30, 1912 $1.! For registering letters, blank applications, blank record books, seals, issuing licenses for auto - mobile, and one clerk not to exceed twelve months during the biennium 12.100.0 Expended Balance November M, 1!»12 $ For fireproof fixtures in vault of Secretary of State. .$3,506.90 Expended .' Balance November 30, 1912 •. $ 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 NEBRASKA MOTOR VEHICLE LAW EFFECTIVE JULY 7TH, 1911. For an Act defining motor vehicles, requiring and regulating the registration of motor vehicles, providing a fee for such registration, regulating their use and operation upon the highways and streets, provid - ing that registration fees be placed in a road fund, and providing a penalty for the violation of thit act, and to repeal sections numbers KTS.i, i'.2.'!0. I, ltS7, 6238, 623!t, 6240. t,241, 6242, 6Ui. 1246, 6247, tS48, 6249. !. fi2."i2, K&gt;:,3, Cobbey's Annotated Statutes of Nebraska :'or 1M§. Be it Enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska K Section 1. The word^ and phrases used in this act shall, for the ost of this act only, be construed as follows: K "Motor vehicles shall include all vehicles propelled by any power r than muscular power, excepting, however, traction engines, road - rs and any vehicle which run only on rails or tracks. K Highways shall include public streets, roads, turnpikes, parks, park - , drives, alleys and other public ways used for the passage of road les. Fees. Section 2. Every person, firm or corporation, owning, or who may hereafter own a motor vehicle, shall file in the office of the Secretary of 3tate, on a suitable blank furnished by such Secretary, a brief description of every such vehicle, owned by such person, firm or corporation, except as otherwise provided in this act, and shall at the same time, and annually thereafter so long as such motor vehicle is owned by such person, firm or corporation, pay a registration fee of One Dollar ($1.00) for each motor cycle, and Two Dollars ( |2.00 1 per year for each motor vehicle other than motor cycle. Provided that no registration fee shall be charged for any motor vehicle owned by any city or village in this state for the use of the police, fire or other departments. The Secretary of State shall file the statements herein provided for in his office and register each such motor vehicle in a book to be kept for that purpose, and shall assign each a number, numbering them consecutively. Every owner of a motor vehicle registered as herein provided shall be considered and treated as the owner thereof until there shall be filed in the office of the Secretary of State an original bill of Hale, or certified copy of same, showing a change of ownership and accompanied by an application, on a blank fur - nished by said Secretary of State, requesting registration of such change of ownership, also accompanied by a fee of One Dollar ($1.0-0) for register - ing such change of ownership. No change of ownership of any motor vehicle shall be registered unless the annual registration fees for such vehicle are fully paid up. Motor vehicles owned in this state at the time this act takes effect and on which the state license or registration fee </seg>
            <seg id="p031">has been paid, need not again be registered until the expiration of the year for which such license has been paid. Fee:, to Be Paid to County Treasurer. -■•ction :;. All registration fees provided for in this act shall be paid to the treasurer of the county in which the applicant for registration resides and shall bo credited to the County Road Fund for the construc - tion and maintenance of permaneut roads. The county treasurer shall issue a receipt in duplicate and one copy of such receipt shall be filed with the Secretary of State. No motor vehicle shall be registered and no change of ownership shall be recorded unless the application for same shall be accompanied by such county treasurer's receipt showing that the proper fees have l:een paid. Manufacturers and Dealers. Section t. Each rrauufacturer of. or Sealer in. motor vehicles, doing business in this sfate may register one motor vehicle of each class manu - factured by or dealt in by him. and if a number corresponding to the registration number issued to such manufacturer or dealer is displayed as pro\ided in this act, on every vehicle of the class for which it is issued, while such vehicle is being operated on the highways by such manufac - turer or dealer or his agent or representative, it shall be deemed sufficient compliance with this act. Provided, however, that nothing in this act shall be construed to apply to a motor vehicle operated by a manufacturer or dealer for his private use or for hire. In construing this section, electrically driven motor vehicles shall constitute a class, those pro pelled by steam a class, and those propelled by gasoline explosive enuines a class. Must D. splay Nurr.ber on Front and Rear of Automobile Section 5. The owner of each motor vehicle shall have a number corresponding to the registration number assigned by the Secretary of Stace conspicuously displayed upon the front and back of each motor vehicle owned by him, except as in this act otherwise pro\ided. when - ever such motor vehicle is used on the highways, such numbers to be separate Arabic numerals not less than four inches high and each stroke to be at least one-half inch wide and such numbers shall be followed by the letters NEB. not less than three inches high, and said numbers and letters shall be in white on a black ground, and from one hour after sunset till one hour before sunrise shall be so lighted as to be plainly visible at a distance of one hundred feet. No other marks of identity shall be required on said motor vehicles. Must Be 16 Years of Age and Over to Operate Motor Vehicle. Section 6. It shall be unlawful for any person under sixteen years of age or for any intoxicated person to operate a motor vehicle, and any ovner. dealer or manufacturer of motor vehicles who permits a person </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 E;r sixteen years of age or an intoxicated person to operate a motor cle shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be punished ereinafter provided for violation of the provisions of this act. Rate of Speed. ' Section 7. No person shall operate a motor vehicle on any highway outside of a city or village at a rate of speed greater than is reasonable and proper, having regard for the traffic and use of the road and the con - dition of the road, nor at a rate of speed such as to endanger the life or limb of any person nor in any case at a rate of speed exceeding twenty - five miles per hour; and within any city or village no motor vehicle shall be operated at a speed greater than twelve miles an hour or at a rate of speed greater than is reasonable and proper, having regard for the traffic and use of the road, and the condition of the road, nor at a rate of speed cuch as to endanger the life or limb of any person. T'pon approaching an intersection of highways, or a bridge or a sharp curve or a steep descent, or another vehicle or an animal or person outside of any village or city, the person operating a motor vehicle shall reduce the speed of such vehicle to a rate not exceeding eight miles an hour and shall not exceed such speed until entirely past such intersection, bridge, curve, descent, vehicle, animal or person. When crossing an intersection of streets within any city or village, motor vehicles shall not be driven at a speed exceeding six miles per hour. Upon approaching any place where passen - gers are getting on or off street cars every person operating a motor vehicle shall bring snch vehicle to a full stop and shall not again start until said street cars have started. Provided, that the speed limits in this section shall not apply to physicians or surgeons or police or fire vehicles or ambulances when answering emergency calls demanding isive speed. Caution Signals. Section 8. Any person operating a motor vehicle shall at request or on signal by putting up the hand, from a person riding or driving a restive horse or other draught or domestic animal, bring such motor vehicle im - mediately to a stop, and if traveling in the opposite direction remain stationary so long as may be reasonable to allow such horse cr animal to pass, and if traveling in the same direction, use reasonable caution in passing such horse or animals, and the operator or occupant of any motor vehicle shall render necessary assistance to the party having in charge such a horse or other draught animal in so passing. Whenever any person traveling with any vehicle or conveyance on any road in this state shall overtake another vehicle or conveyance traveling in the same direction and shall by sound or call indicate to the driver thereof his or her desire to pass, U shall be the duty of the driver of the vehicle or conveyance in front, if the nature of the ground or the condition of his load will permit it, to promptly turn to the right of the center of the road and the driver of the vehicle or conveyance behind shall then turn to the left of the center of the road and pass by without interfering or inter - rupting, and the driver of said vehicle or conveyance passing, shall not </seg>
            <seg id="p033">KKl'OKT OK THK 8ECRETAR r ATI return to the center of the i"oad until at least Tl ahead of the vehicle or conveyance passed. Brakes, Bells, Horns. Etc Section 0. Every motor vehicle while in use on public highways shall be provided with good and sufficient brakes, and also with a suit - able bell, horn or other signal, and shall have exhibited during the period from one hour after sunset to one hour before sunrise, one or more lamps showing white lights visible within a reasonable diEtance from the direc - tion toward which such vehicle is proceeding and a red light visible from the reverse direction. Penalties. Section It. The violation of any of the provisions of this Act shall be deemed a misdemeanor, punishable by a tine not c ■() for the first offense, and punishable by a fine or not less than $50.00 or more than $100.00 or imprisonment not exceeding sixty days in the county jail for each subsequent offense, or both fine and imprisonment in the discre-' tion of the court, provided, however, if any person operating a motor vehicle in violation of the provisions of this act shall by so doing seri - ously maim or disf gure any person or cause the death of any person or persons, he shall upon conviction thereof, be fined not less than $i nor more than $500.00, or be imprisoned in the penitentiary for not less than one year or more than ten years. Local Authorities. Section 11. Nothing in this Act shall be construed in limiting the power of local authorities to make, enforce and maintain any ordinance rule or regulation, in addition to the provisions of this Act affecting motor vehicles. Non-Residents. Section 12. The provisions of this Act so far as they relate to regis - tration and fees shall not apply to motor vehicles owned and operated, for a period not exceeding thirty days at a time, by non-residents of tbis state, provided the owners thereof have complied with any law requiring the registration of owners of motor vehicles in the state, territory or fed - eral district 'of their residence, and providing the registration number and initials of such state, territory or federal district shall be displayed on such vehicle substantially as provided by this Act. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS Kind of Author - ized Capital" Stock Instru- Place of Business When Filed irate NAME ment Albion Milling Co Amendt Albion ' $250,000 Dec. 9 1910 Akron-Loretto Telephone Company Articles jLoretto ... Z.oOii Dec. 22 1910 American Development Co.. Articles Omaha ....I 25.0OC Jan. 16 mil American Car &amp; Foundry Co. Agree- M. C. Peters Mill Co ; ment jOmaha Feb. Feb. 7 1 !) 1 1 S Itll Atlanta State Bank Amendt Atlanta 10,000 Alliance Creamery &amp; Pro- duce Co Amendt Alliance ... 50,000 Feb. Mar. Mar. Mar. Apr. it 1911 American Sugar Cone Co... ; Articles I Omaha . ... 10,000 19U American Collection Co Articles Omaha .... 10,000 22 1911 Anti-Tobacco Habit Co Articles Omaha .... 1,000 3 1911 Angus (The) Cattle Co Articles ■ Kennedy .... 25,000 11 1911 Aurora (The) Mencantile Company Articles Aurora . 25,000 Apr. 20 lit 11 Ashland Platte River Bridge Company Articles Ashland . . . 20,000 May May May June 9 1911 12 1911 Auto Delivery Company.... Articles Lincoln ... : 24,000 American Brotherhood Articles Malcolm 1911 Allen, \V. P. Company Articles Valparaiso 20,000 8 1911 American Automobile Equip- ment Company j Articles Omaha 100,000 July Aug. 1911 Aarons Articles Omaha .... 20,000 3 1911 Aurora Artificial Ice Co Dissolu- tion Aurora Aug. 25 1911 Alfalfa Co-operative Cream- ery Association ! Articles Mason City 25,000 Sep. 18 1911 American Metallic Packing Company Articles Omaha I 100,000 Sep. 14 1911 Erican Security Company irmerly Shimer &amp; Chase mpany) Amend't Omaha 100,000 Sep. Sep. Oct. 26 1911 27 1911 Adams Mercantile Co Articles Adams . 10,000 Albright. Edwin, Company.. Articles 25,000 Beemer 1911 American Assurers Aid Asso- ciation Articles lOmaha 1,000 Oct. Oct. Nov. Nov. Nov. 26 1911 301911 E»tt A Linn Lumber Co . . Articles ra Elevator Company. . Amend't in- Peterson Shoe Co ... Articles Anchor Fence Company Articles rican Investment Co. . . ' Articles Genoa .. 25,000 Aurora 25,000 1 1911 15 1911 22 1911 Omaha .... 100,000 Omaha 5,000 Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS — (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Authcr- Place of Business ized When Capital Filed CORPORATE NAMI Stock Krican Automatic Mail tcher Mfg. Co Articles Lincoln 5 1911 American Investment &amp; Loan Company Amend't Articles Articles Amend't Articles Articles Amend't Amend't No. Platte Aurora . . Dec. 7 1911 K Aurora Construction Co b Gas Construction Co. . lope County Bank - I 1911 •&lt;-. 27 1911 Hastings Jakdale Omaha . Jan. 4 1912 American Silica Co Alliance Fruit Company. A. O. Albrecht Company Anchor Bank 20,000 Jan. 18 1912 10,000 Feb. 29 1912 Alliance Omaha 100,000 Mar. 4 1 ill 2 15,000 Mar. 161912 Merriman Erican Safe Deposit ults (formerly Ameri - l Safe Deposit &amp; Trust mpany) Amend't Articles Lincoln Ashland Apr. 5 1912 Ashland Club Apr. 9 1912 B cultural &amp; Amusement sociation Articles Articles Stuart Avoca 10.000 Apr. 26 1912 ■ Apr. 2&lt;» 1912 Avoca Town Hall Co Allen Filter Service Com - pany of Nebraska Articles Articles Omaha Omaha 13.000! May 11912 100,000 ! May 28 1912 Atkinson Realty Company. . Acme White Lead &amp; Color Works Articles Dissolu - tion Lincoln Alhambra Real Estate Co... Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha June 7 1912 Alfalfa Feed Co. Articles Articles Articles 10,000 June 1 1912 100,000 July 13 1912 25,000 I July 19 1912 Ematic Valve Seating Ma inery Co. (formerly Ol a Mfg. Co Amend't Lincoln Amend't Lincoln Amend't Omaha Articles ! Axtell Articles iAyr . . Sep. 11 1912 100,000 Sep. 12 1S12 100,000 Sep. H 1912 Armstrong Clothing Co Allen Brothers Company Axtell Electric Company... Ayr Grain &amp; Supply Co A lam i to Sanitary Dairy Co.. Baer, W. C. ft Company Burt County State Bank 10.0OC Oct. 15 1912 8,000 Nov. 12 1912 Amend't Omaha . Amend't York . . . Amend't Tekamah 300,000 Nov. 15 1912 Dec. 6 1910 Dec. 7 1910 Bryne &amp; Hammer Drq Goods Company. Amend't Omaha 500 June 6 1912 Auto Vacuum Freezer Co Abbott, J. A. Co </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Place of ment Business ized When Capital Filed Stock CORPORATE NAME Burrougs Adding Machine Company Articles St.Louis.Mo. 10,000 Jan. !&gt;1!U1 Buffalo Bill Gun Club Articles No. Platte. . I Jan. 17 l'.Ul Brandeis, J. L. &amp; Sons \ Amend t Omaha Jan. I Butler Electric Co Amende David City . 25,000 Jan. 24 1911 (The) Bank of Cortland. ... Amend't Cortland . . 20,000 Feb. 11 1911 Bloom (J. F.) &amp; Co Articles Omaha .... K) | Feb. 13 1911 Bostwick Hardware Co Articles Bostwick . . 00 Feb. 1 ■ Bruno Farmers Grain &amp; Live Stock Co Articles Bruno &gt;0 Feb. I Bank of Dixon County : Articles Ponca m) Feb. ! Britt Lyceum Bureau Articles Lincoln .... 25,000 Mar. - Bank of Hickman i Amend't Hickman Apr. i ! Bank of Belgrade Amend't Belgrade . . 50,000 Apr. 18 1911 Bear (The) River Lumber Company Articles Lincoln 60,000 Apr. 21 11*11 Burns (The) Jay Baking Co. Amend't Omaha 150,04)0 Apr. 20 l'.Ul Bramblett (The) Engraving Company j Articles Omaha 10,000 | May 12 1911 Boyd County Agricultural Society Amend'tfButte j May 17 1911 Burgess-Granden (The) Co.. Amend'tiOmaha .... 100,000 May 18 1911 Bradbrook-Saunders Lumber Company Articles Pruning . . . 20,000 | May 27 l'.'ll Burket, H. K. Undertaking Company Articles Omaha .... 15,000 j May 29 1911 Bank of Dorchester Articles Dorchester . j 25,000 May 31 1911 Beebe &amp; Runyan Furniture Company Amend'tOmaha .... I June 6 1911 Bailey Dental Co. Articles Omaha .... 5,000 June 26 1911 Brunswick-Balke-Collender Company of Nebraska Articles Omaha .... 10,000 June 28 1911 Bright-Shine Metal Polish Company Articles Lincoln 15,000 July 4 1911 A -«| A 1 nn r\ i__ -t a A./vn t..i r i ni 1 Brandeis, C. Coal Co. Articles Omaha . 10,000 July 5 1911 Big 4 Transfer Company formerly Carter Transfer Company Amend't .Omaha .... July 21 1911 Bank of Rosemont ! Amend't Rosemont .. 10,000 I Aug. 3 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Instru- Place of ment Business ized When Capital Filed Stock CORFORATE NAME ECochrane Construe- Company (formerly dner Cochrane Con - ction Company Amend't Lincoln Articles Bee . . Aug. 17 1,11 25 1911 19 1911 Bee Elevator Company 25,000 km* Ele &amp; Van Rrsdale Co. . . jewater Mercantile Co. of Tarnov Amend't Beatrice . . Articles Bridgeport Articles Tarnov . . Articles Norfolk .. Sep. 25,000 I Sep. 15,000 Oct. 25,000 Oet 30,000 Oct. 13 1911 23 1911 Ballah Land Company Bank of Eagle Amend'ti Eagle 1911 Kel Missionary Baptist urch Articles Amend't Articles So. Omaha Rulo 24 1911 28 1911 31 1911 Bank of Rulo Bone, D. E. &amp; Company Beatrice Steel Tank Manu- Fairbury Articles facturing Company Beatrice 2 1911 Bassett-Horsefoot Telephone Company Articles iBassett 14 1911 Ek Automobile Company, lers Investment Co rn Produce Company. . . ?mian American Publish- Articles Lincoln 23 1911 Articles Omaha 271911 Articles Omaha 25,000 Dec. 5 1911 Articles ing Company So. Omaha. 20,000 Dec. 25.000 Dec. 25,000"* Dec. 8 1911 13 1911 21 1)11 22 19U Bennington tSate Bank Boyd Nursery Company Articles Bennington Articles Ainsworth Boston Investment Company Buchanan County Amend't Lincoln Dissolu- tion No. Platte 27 1.U1 Key &amp; Woodward Lum - r Company Dissolu tion 27 1M1 Ashland Eamin nvestment Corn - ay (formerly City Trusl mpany &gt; Amend't, Omaha 29 mi Eof Home Missions of Presbyterian Church in U. S. of America Articles 16 1912 22 1912 2^; 1912 Burket &amp; Leslie Company. . Amend't Omaha Articles Neligh Articles I Lincoln Berry Company. Butter-Nut Bread Co. vnt Brodegaard. Fred Jewelry Company Articles Omaha. 25,00" 30 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Autnor- Instru Place of Business ized When Capital Filed CORPORATE NAME ment Stock Bank of Polk. Amend't Polk Feb. z 1S»12 ■Elevator Company m &amp; Company. . . . Amendti Bee Feb. 3 1912 Articles Lincoln 10,000 Feb. 3 1912 Brown Consolidated Milling Company Articles Fremont . . . 100,000 Feb. 8 1!&gt;12 Brinn (The) &amp; Jensen Co.. Bank of Oxford Ajnend't Omaha | 50,000 . Feb. 13 1 Ji Amend't Oxford .... Feb. 14 1912 Bet (The) Stores. ; Auto Company Articles [Lincoln .... I 100,000 Feb. 19 1912 Articles Butte 15,000 I Feb. 23 191 Eell Electric Company., ice Metal Culvert Wks ice Iron Works Articles IBurwell ... 75,000 I Feb. 23 1912 Articles Beatrice . 50,000 I Mar. 12 1912 Amend't Beatrice ... 150,000 Mar. 13 1912 Beacon Press Articles 'Omaha 100.000 Mar. 14 1912 Be Creek Electric Light mpany Articles Battle Creek I 25,000 ' Mar. 21 1912 Benway, A. D. Co. Amend't Lincoln 100,000 Mar. 23 1912 Backstrom-Higby Company. . Board of Church Extension Articles Lincoln 2,000 i Mar. 27 1912 Kthe Evangelical Assn. . . ner, R. H. Company. . . . ers" Realty Investment Articles jFremont ... Apr. 18 1912 Articles lomaha 25,000 | Apr. 23 1912 Company Articles Omaha 300,000 | May 1 1912 Brabec Lumber Company... Bank of Doniphan Articles Yutan 15,000 i May 6 1912 Amend'tiDoniphan . . 7,500 i May 8 1912 Eany Realty Company . . . leo Clothing Company. . Bordeaux Telephone Co er Valley Land Co Articles j Bethany ... 5,000 I May 8 1912 Articles Omaha 20.000 May 16 1912. Articles Ichadron ... 630 i May 20 1912 Dissolu- tion Minden May 22 1912 Benevolent and Protective Order of Camels. Articles Lincoln \ May 22 1912 Eany Traction Company, deis, J. L. £ Sons on Lumber &amp; Grain Co is Drug Co Articles Bethany . . . 25,000 '• May 23 1912 Amend't Omaha I May 24 1912 Articles Rurton 10,000 May 28 1912 Dissolu- tion Peru i Tune 7 1912 Borchman, A. Construction Company I Articles Omaha 2 25,000 June 12 1912 Bohanan-Aitken Livery Co.. Articles Lincoln .... 10,000 ; June 1 Bohemian Mutual Telephone Dissolu- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author Instru Place of Business ized When Capital Stock 'ORPORATE NA.MK ment Belgrade Telephone &amp; Im- ; I tissolu tion Belgrade Iunelll!M2 provement Company Dissolu- Belvidere Grain &amp; Coal Co tion Belvidere . . '■■ June l'T l!il Eley Grain Company. . . . waiter-Smith Company, of Scotia Articles Milford . Articles Winnebago Amendt Scotia July 11912 Bankers Security Company. Bank of Glenville Articles Omaha uly •"&gt; 1912 Amend't Glenville Bankers Mortgage Loan Co. Bank of Julian Articles Omaha 2.1 Amendt Julian July 2O1»13 Articles Lincoln .... •" \uk. 5 1»11 Black Hills Military Institute Beatrice Cold Storage Com- pany (formerly Beatrice Poultry &amp; Cold Storage Company Amendt Beatrice .. 250,000 Aug. 12 1 HI K Valley State Bank of College View . . of Stapleton Articles Sprig Ranch 1MN Aug. 21 1912 Amendt Col. View (0 Sep. I Amend tstapleton dep 23 1912 Articles Bloomington ct 2 1912 tington Telephone Co. man Cattle Company, of Braiaerd Articles Valentine .. lM.OUt) Oct 7 1912 Amend t Brainard Oct. 16 1912 Bihler, Albert E., Inc. Brownlee State Bank Amendt Omaha . 10,00o net 21 1912 Articles i Brownlee .. 2.'&gt;.000 Nov. 7 1912 Blue Hill (The) Cigar Co... t'ozad Shipping Assn Articles !Blue Hill . . 1,0)0 Nov. 2T) 1912 Articles | Co/.ad .. ) Dec. 17 1910 (The) Church of Christ Curtis State Bank Articles Orchard Dec. 22 1910 Articles Curtis 25.000 Dec. 26 1910 Conant Hotel Company Articles Omaha . . 10.000 Ian. 111911 Capital Carriage Company. . \rticles Des Moines. la I 25,000 Ian I E Telephone Company., lac Co. of Omaha ey-Hunter-Royer Co. . . Ion. P. .T. Sons AmendTCraig . . 12,000 Ian. 19 1911 Articles Omaha 50.000 Ian. 27 1911 Articles Omaha &gt;0 Feb. 211911 Amendt Omaha .... vlar. 4 1911 Etlidated Sales Co. Clothing Company Mills (The) Amendt Omaha 100.000 Mar. 6 1911 Amendt Lincoln ... 8 1911 Amendt Crete 300.000 Mar. 8 1911 Coit Automobile Co., now Btchell Motor Company . ens Telephone Company Amendt Omaha Mar. - Amendt Atkinson </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru ment Author- Place of ized When Business 1 Capital Filed H1ATK NAME Stock Citizens State Bank. Amend'! Dorchester Mar. 30 1911 Curtis Telephone Co. (The) Can (The) County Farmers Articles \ Curtis .lar. 31 1911 Articles Mutual Telephone Co. Louisville 20,000 ; Apr. 11 1911 Citizens Lumber &amp; Grain Company Articles Wahoo 40,000 Apr. 11 1911 50,000 Apr. 14 1911 Citizens State Bank. Cox Realty Company Articles St. Paul Dissolu tion 3o. Omaha Apr. 18 1911 Eber of Commerce rt Lumber Company. . a &amp; Jeffrey Co Articles Hastings Apr. 18 1911 Amend't Brunswick Apr. 19 1911 Articles i Dmaha 100. 00C Apr. 25 1911 40,000 Apr. 28 1911 100,000 May 4 1911 150,000 ; May 101911 2r&gt;,OO0 : May 201911 Amend! Commercial State Bank Crystal Lake Distillery Co. . Campbell Soil Culture Co... C. &amp; R. (The) Electric Co.. Christian Volunteer Workers Citizens State Bank Coleridge Amend! S. Sioux Cy Articles Lincoln Articles Scotts Bluff Articles Lincoln June 2 1911 Amend'! Wood River June 13 1911 Central Mercantile Company Dissolu- tion Omaha June 19 1911 Christiansen Company Dissolu- tion St. Edward June 21 1911 Rter Clad Malleable Range mpany Amend' Omaha 250,000 June 26 1911 200,000 June 28 1911 50,000 June 29 1911 25,000 June 30 1911 Crowell Elevator Company. Articles Omaha Fuel Company Articles Lincoln Conservative Investment Co Amend' Crete Bmbia Land, Loan &amp; lilding Association Amend't Columbus 700,000 July 1 1911 Kch of Sts. Peter and ul Articles St. Paul July 3 1911 Clark Land &amp; Development Company Articles Omaha 50.000 July 8 1911 15,000 July 101911 8.000 July 101911 12.500 July 14 1911 Citizens State Bank. Articles Palmyra Chalco Elevator Company.. Articles I Chalco Cortland Telephone Co. Amend'tlCortland Ktral Nebraska Land &amp; &gt;an Company Articles Ord 50,000 July 14 1911 Cortland Farmers' Grain &amp; Amend't Cortland </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author Place of ized When Business | Capital Filed COIU'oRATK NAME Stock Central Nebraska Millwork Company Articles Hastings Stratton July Aug. 24 I9U Crescent -Mfg. Company.... City Trust &amp; Safe Deposit Articles 1911 Amend't Amend't Omaha Company 300,000 Aug 9 1911 Johnstown Citizens Bank Aug 12 1911 En Coal &amp; Supply Co. . r Construction Co erfield Drug Company Articles Articles Dissolu - tion Omaha 50,000 Aug. 10,000 Aug IN 1911 lit 1911 F'airbury Diller Aug 24 1911 Central Nebraska Bridge &amp; Culvert Company Articles Central City \ug. 26 1911 Central City Omaha .... 0 Aug. 21,000 Aug ■i Aug 20,000 Aug Articles Omaha 21,000 \ug. t Ego (The) Laundry Co. (The) Land Company, al City Ice Company., ns Bank Articles Plattsmouth IM.MI Aug Plattstnouth Central City Bancroft . . Articles Central City 20,000 Aug. 31 1911 Araendt Bancroft Sep. 4 1911 Columbus Light, Heat &amp; Power Company Amend't Columbus Sep. 5 1911 13 1911 20 1911 30 1911 ttal Beach Company.... Linotyping Company... ral Land Company ral Wyoming Mining Co. perative Stores Co mercial Exchange Bank ens Telephone Co Articles Lincoln 150.000 Sep. 10,00 25,000 Sep. 25.000 Oct. 2."),000 Oct. 25,00" Articles Omaha Articles Lincoln Articles Crawford 5 1911 7 1911 31 1911 Articles Omaha Articles Douiphan Dissolu- tion Atkinson Nov Eford Fruit &amp; Produce mpany (formerly J. L. orp Company Amend't Crawford Nov 13 1911 Carter Transfer &amp; Storage Company Amend't Lincoln 50.000 Nov 20 1911 Central Station Engineering Company Articles Omaha 10 000 Nov 22 1911 Cody Lumber, Coal &amp; Grain Company Articles Cody ■ Nov 24 1911 Ehton, John A. Real Es - ; Company (formerly n A. Creighton Real Es - ) &amp; Trust Company. . . Amend't Nov 21 1911 Omaha Cole, Pavid. Investment Co. \ A *» ' f\ u </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock CORPORATE NAME ment Caldwell and Haigler Tele phone Company Articles j 1,000 Dec. 14 1911 City Savings Bank (formerly City Trust &amp; Savings Bank Amendt David City Dec. 16 1911 Cochrane. Thos. Grain Co.. Dissolu- tion .Lincoln Dec. 201911 Continental Realty Company Amend't Dundee Dec. 21 1911 Cole (The) Corporation.... Articles Cody 100,000 Dec. 23 1911 Clay &amp; Silica Products Co.. Articles Omaha 150,000 Dec. 30 1911 Cushman Power Sprayer Co. Dissolu- tion Lincoln Jan. Jan. Jan. Jan. 19 1912 Culp Horton Clothes Shop.. Articles Omaha 10,000 Citizens Savings Bank Amendt Blair Citizens State dank Aniend'tiArapahoe Carlson. G. L., Horse Breed- Dissolu- ing Company j tion Arapahoe Jan. Jan. Jan. 20 1912 22 1912 23 1912 Cummings, M. T., Grain Co. Amend't Lincoln 49,999 25,000 Citizens State Bank Amend't Comstock Commonwealth Life nsur- ance Company Amendt Tan 24 1912 Capital Garage &amp; Motor Car Company I Articles Lincoln 26 1912 20,000 Jan Central Loan &amp; Investment Company ; Amend't Lincoln Feb Feb Feb Feb Central Drug Company Articles Omaha 10,000 15,000 25,000 9 1912 10 1912 12 1912 Citizen Publishing Company Articles Holdrege Citizens Gas Company Articles McCook C. B. S. Pole &amp; Neck Yoke Dissolu- Manufacturing Company., tion Brady Feb. Feb. 28 1912 29 1912 Custer Land &amp; Cattle Co. ... Articles Omaha 25,000 Conway, George M., Inc.... Articles Sioux City. la. 100,000 Mar 4 1*12 Chapman Co-operative Dissolu- Creamery Company tion Chapman Mar Mar 16 1912 191912 Capital Cajtercar Company . Articles Lincoln 10.O00 Citizens Hotel Company.... Articles Hastings Mth 125,000 Cheney Telephone Company Articles Cheney 2. OHO Mar Callahan, \V. E. Construe tion Company Articles ; Omaha 100,000 25,000 Mar Mar :s Commercial Bank of Grant. . I Amend't rGant </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued Kind of Instru - merit Author- Place of ized Business Capital Place of Business When Filed CORPORATE NAJfl Stock Chain Reference Bible Co Dissolu- Dissolu- tion Lincoln tion Lincoln ... .Mar. . &gt; Callaway Milling &amp; Electric Light Company Articles Callaway .. 75,000 1 Apr. 11912 Articles ("alia way . . Articles Colon Colon Hardware Company. . Cleveland &amp; Son Department Articles Apr. 1 1911 Articles Nebr. City.. 100,000 Articles Articles Apr. l' Hi 12 Apr. J1»1J Store Crosby iThe) Company.. Cornell- Wigman-Searl Co. Articles Lincoln . . . (formerly Cooper &amp; Colt; Bros.) Amend't Amend'tiLincoln ... 1 Apr. I 1911 Apr. 16 1912 Apr. IT 1912 May 2 1912 May Commercial Club Articles Omaha .... 150,000 Articles Omaha . . . . clay County State Bank Conservative Trust Company Clay County Grain Co Amend't Edgar Amend'tEdgar Articles Lincoln . . . Articles Lincoln Amend't Fairtield . . . Amend't Fairtield California Fig Orchard Co. . Dissolu Dissolu- tion Omaha May Capital Publishing (ompaio Dissolu- tion Lincoln May 11 l'.»12 Colorado Farm &amp; Fruit Land Company Articles Omaha .... May 24 l'H 2 May M Chicago Club Articles So. Omaha Central Station Engineering Company Articles Omaha 50,000 June 4 1!U2 June 7 1912 June S 1912 June 10 1912 June 11 1912 June 13 1912 June I Cummings Motor Car Co. . . . Commonwealth Power Co. . . Crete Commercial Club Commercial Publishing Co.. Crosby-Kopietz-Casey Co. . . . Citizens State Bank Articles Gr'nd Island 10,000 Articles Lincoln . . . 7,500,000 Articles Lincoln Articles Crete 1,000 Articles ,Crete Articles Omaha 5.000 Articles Omaha Amend't Omaha .... 100.000 Amend't Omaha Amend't Creston 100.000 50.000 Amend't Creston . . . 50.000 Dissolu- Circle Investment Company. Dissolu- tion Falls City tion Falls City. July July 18 1912 July ' July 1 Eerdale Realty Company, mbus Fire Insurance Co. man Aviation Assn ral Nebraska Elevator Articles Omaha .... 100,000 Amend't Omaha 100,000 Articles Omaha .... MM Co. ( formerly Conrad Articles Conrad 15.000 Grain &amp; Elevator Co. Articles Conrad July 27 1912 Kkson Milling &amp; Grain impany Articles Clarkson . . _ Cortland Creamery Company </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock ' IRATE NAME Articles Imperial . . . 10,000 Sep. 3 1912 Chase County Shippers Assn. Cuming County Independent Telephone Company Amend't Wisner .... 25,000 Sep. 4 1912 Ei Reference Bible Co. . . al Furniture Company, ones Commission Co Articles Lincoln . .. 25,000 Sep. 4 1912 Articles Central City ; 20,000 Sep. 12 1912 t\v ( ox-Jones- Van Al - e Company Amend't So. Omaha. 50,000 Sep. 14 1912 Kn Lumber &amp; Silo Co. . . im Garment Makers of Articles Omaha 100,000 Sep. 19 1912 Nebraska Articles Omaha 10,000 Sep. 28 1912 Cole &amp; Fry Company Articles Omaha J00.00O Oct. 11912 Bmbus Electric &amp; En - leering Company Articles Lincoln . . . 25,000 Oct. 3 1912 Chopie Gasoline Engine Co. Cleveland, W. G. Company rrmerly W. G. Cleveland lg Company) Amend't Omaha Oct. 9 1912 Eon Realty Company pell State Bank try Club of Lincoln. . . . rete Silo Company Articles iOmaha 250,000 Oct. 18 1912 Articles jChappell . . 25,000 Oct. 21 1912 Amend't Lincoln ... 75.000 Nov. 7 1912 Articles Lincoln ... 25,000 Nov. 16 1912 Derby Woolen Mills. Dissolu- tion iOmaha . ... Jan. 4 1911 Double Draft Collar Co Articles IOmaha 15,000 Feb. .. Eity Esterbrook Co. (for e r 1 y Deputy-Spangler it Company) Amend't Lincoln Mar. 15 191 ! El Cole Investment Co.. w Disc Sharpener Co. . hue &amp; Randell Co Articles Loup Cttj 20,000 Mar. 17 191 Articles Omaha .... 10,000 Apr. 11911 Articles Crete 1,000 Apr. 3 191 i Doane Owl Pub. Co. (The) Dawson Milling Assn. Dissolu- tion Dawson ... Apr. 4 1911 Bdy County Irrigation Co. bar State Bank Amend't Benkleman j Apr. 4 1911 Amend't Dunbar May 16 191 1 Double-Draft Collar Co Diehl Chemical Company.. Dwight Farmers' Grain Co.. Dale, John &amp; Son Dissolu- Omaha .... June 30 1911 Articles Dwight 25,000 Aug. 26 1911 Dowling &amp; Purcell Company Amend't North Bend Sep. 26 1911 Articles Plattsmouth 200,000 Oct. 7 1912 Articles Omaha 200,000 Mar. 14 1311 Amend't Omaha 25,000 May 27 191! Articles Omaha 20,000 Sep. 14 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued &gt; Kind of I Author- Kind of Instru - ment Instru- Place of ized When Place of Business Ri'c (RATE NAME • :rcp}{ atk name ment Business Capital Fited Stock Davis, Fredk. H. Realty Co. Articles Omaha . . . Donald (The I Company (for - merly Donald &amp; Porter Co. j Amend t Gr'nd Islan. •■ t. IT 1S1J Donald (The I Company (for- merly Donald &amp; Porter Co. Amend t Gr'nd Island ! - Oct. 17 191 Darlow Advertising Co ' Amend't Omaha .... Darlow Advertising Co ' Amendt Omaha .... Drummond Motor Company. Articles Omaha .... Drummond Motor Company. Articles Omaha .... David City Hospital Articles ravid City. David City Hospital Articles ra\ id City. Dietz, C. N. Lumber Co Amend't Omaha I &gt;• Dietz, C. N. Lumber Co Amendt Omaha .... D&lt; Depew DIM Sharpener Co.. Dissolu- . Him- Sharpener Co.. Dissoli tion Loup City.. Jan. !■ tion Loup City... Jan Durland Trust Company.... Amend't Norfolk .. Defiance Starch Company. . . Dissolu- Defiance Starch Company. . . Dissolu- tion Omaha Feb. i tion Omaha .... Feb. : Druid Camp Real Estate Co. Articles Omaha .... Druid Camp Real Estate Co. Articles Omaha .... Diet7. Club Articles Omaha Diet7. Club Articles Omaha I Dreshers Brothers Articles Omaha Dreshers Brothers Articles Omaha Mar DeWitt Light &amp; Power Co.. Articles I&gt;e\Vitt j DeWitt Light &amp; Power Co.. Articles I&gt;e\Vitt i Drayton Bros Articles Orchard . . . Drayton Bros ; Articles Orchard . . . ! 50,000 Apr Dundee Realty Company... Amend t Omaha .... 500.000 May I Dundee Realty Company... Amend t Omaha . ... 500.000 May! Derryberry &amp; Forbes Articles No. Platte.. lay 11 191 5 Derryberry &amp; Forbes Articles No. Platte.. !ay 11 1912 Douglas Auditorium Assn... Articles Omaha .... Douglas Security Company. Amend t Omaha .... I 1 1*1J Douglas Security Company. Amendt Omaha . ... 150,0 4 191 Duncan Mercantile Co Articles Duncan ... 25,000 Nov. Duncan Mercantile Co Articles Duncan ... 25,000 Nov. Doty &amp; Hathaway Articles Omaha .... Doty &amp; Hathaway Articles Omaha .... Lug. 22 1!H2 Diller Farmers Grain Co. ... Amend't Diller Nov. I Diller Farmers Grain Co Amend't Diller Nov. 25 1912 Exchange Bank Building... Articles Gibbon 15,000 Dec. - Exchange Bank Building. . . Articles Gibbon 15,000 Dec. 22 1910 East Garfield Telephone Co. Articles Red Cloud.. 10,000 Jan. 9 1911 East Garfield Telephone Co. Articles Red Cloud.. 10,000 Jan. 9 1911 Enola Hall Company Articles Enola .in. 18 1911 Enola Hall Company Articles Enola 500 Jan. 18 1911 Etting Candy Company Amend't Gr'nd Island Jan. 311911 Etting Candy Company Amendt Gr'nd Island Jan. 311911 Eddyville State Bank Amendt Eddyville .. 25,000 ' Feb. 7 1911 Eddyville State Bank : Amend't Eddyville 25,000 Feb. 7 1911 Elm wood Mill &amp; Elev. Co.. . Articles Elmwood .. 6,000 | Feb. 8 1911 Elm wood Mill &amp; Elev. Co. . . ', Articles Elm wood 6,000 Feb. 8 1911 Klkhorn Valley Condensing Klkhorn Valley Condensing Company Articles Waterloo . . 50,000 Mar. 13 1911 Company Articles Waterloo 50,000 Mar. 13 1911 Edholm, Albert Amendt Omaha .... 100,000 | Mar. 27 1911 Edholm. Albert Amend't Omaha 100,000 Mar 27 1911 Ea«t, H. A. Company Articles Lincoln . . . 25,000 i Apr. 20 1911 East, H. A. Company Articles Lincoln 25,000 Apr. 201911 200,000 Apr. Elkhorn Land &amp; Cattle Co. . Articles Bassett 200,000 Apr. 24 1911 Elkhorn Land &amp; Cattle Co. . Articles Bassett 24 1911 Exeter Elevator Company... Articles lExeter .... Exeter Elevator Company. .. Articles Exeter .... 25,000 June 13 1911 25,000 June 13 1911 El Cana Land &amp; Plantation Company Articles Gr'nd Island 25,000 July 17 1911 El Cana Land &amp; Plantation Company Articles Gr'nd Island 25,000! July 17 1911 Eckles Stoneware Co Dissolu- Eckles Stoneware Co Dissolu- tion Omaha Aug. 7 1911 Aug. 7 1911 Edgar (The( Canning Co.. . . Articles Edgar </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru - ment Place of ized When Business i Capital Filed C&lt; &gt;K1'&lt; &gt;RATE NAME Stock Equitable Loant Co. (former - ly Equitable Trust Co.)... Amend't Omaha . . Amend't Omaha . Articles Ellsworth Oct. 10 1911 Eggress &amp; O'Flyng Co. 200,000 Oct. 2 1911 Korth Supply Company. B-Brown Lumber Co. 30,000 Nov. 61911 ( formerly Bingenheimer- Evans Company Amend't Norfolk 250,000 Jan. 15 1912 25,000 Feb. 12 1912 Articles Elkhorn Monument Co. Xeligh Klsior Remedy &amp; Manu - turing Company Articles Omaha 10,0ft Feb Mar Eagle Hall Company Amend't Xebr. City Evangelical Lutheran Church V. A. C Articles Tilden Mar. Apr. June Aug. Sep. Oct. Eschange Bank . Amend't Wilcox Omaha Omaha 15,000 16 1912 Evans Model Laundry Co. . . Eastern Plating &amp; Mfg. Co. . Evans Hotel Company Elmcreek Shipping Assn... Electrical Specialties Mfg. Articles Articles Articles Articles KiO.OOO I 5,000 75,000 Columbus Elm Creek. 2,500 Company Articles Omaha 25,000 Oct. 10 1912 El well &amp;. Sons Co. (formerly Elwell-Peters Co.) Amend't Springfield Nov. Dec. Dec. Dec. Jan. Jan. Jan. Jan. » E) Farmers State Bank. ) Farmers State Bank. iers Telephone Co ) Farmers State Bank. . ) Farmers State Bank. . iers Co-operative Assn. . iers' Grain &amp; Supply Co. land Bros. Co Amend't Callaway 40,000 Amend't Callaway Articles Chappell 50,000 Chappell 8,000 | 17 1911 Articles Mason City 25,000 25,000 50,000 12,000 Articles Wabash Articles Hemingford Articles Ulysses Dissolu - tion Omaha Jan. Jan. Feb. Feb. 201911 25 1911 E) Farmers' Tel. Co a. H. E. &amp; Company . . . klin Ice Cream Co iers' Ondependent Ship ! Articles Maywood ."i.OOO Articles 50,000 125,000 ?S Genoa Amend't Lincoln ping Association. I Amend't Wilsonville Jan. 101911 Ft. McPherson Pure Bred j Live Stock Assn I Articles Maxwell Fremont 3,000 Feb. Feb. 201911 23 1911 Fremont Mfg Co Articles 50.000 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock ORFORATE NAME ment Falconer (Thos. ) Co. (for - merly Rich &amp; Falconer Company t Amend't Omaha Mar. 1 1911 Ferry Screen Company Article*. Omaha lar. 2 1911 Farmers &amp; Hallam Tel. Co.. Article* Hallam ... 10 Mar. 11 1911 Farmers' .Mutual Tel. Co Articles Weyerts Mar. 14 l'.Hl (The! Farmer's Elevvatoi Company Articles Bradish Mar. 14 1911 Farnam Bank Amend't Farnam Mar. 23 1911 Farmers' Land Company. ... I Articles Omaha .... 25,000 Apr. 1 l«i 1 1 Frenchman Valley Tel. Co.. Fairmont Creamery Co. (the) Articles Amend't Beverly Omaha Apr. K 1911 \: Fullerton Mill Company.... Amend't Fullerton .. 12,500 Apr. 7 1!»ll Eers' Telephone Co ers State Bank., era State Bank., ers State Bank.. Articles Taylor 10.000 Apr. 111911 Articles Inland Ipr. 131911 Amend't; Central City Apr. In 1911 Articles Elba tpr. 27 1911 Farmers &amp; Merchants Ele - vator Company Articles IFiUey .lay 11911 Farmers' (The) Grain &amp; Supply Company Articles Dannebrog 20,000 May 16 1911 Eers State Bank ers' Creek Tel.' Co .... ers' I'nion Tel. Co ers Grain &amp; Lumber Articles Springfield 25.000 May :.'."&gt; 1911 Articles Inavale .... MM May 29 1911 Articles Edison 1 030 May 2H 1911 Company Articles Sprague 15.000 May 31 1911 Farmers' Grain &amp; Live Stock Shipping Association Articles Mason City 5,000 June 19 1911 First (The) Trust Company of Lincoln, Nebraska Articles Lincoln 100,000 ' June 20 1911 Francis Lumber Company.. First Trust Company Articles Lincoln 100.000 'July 6 1911 Articles Omaha .... 500,000 ' July 8 1911 Amend't Shelton July 10 1911 Eiers' Elevator Company iers' &amp; Merchants' Club klin Taxicab Service July 10 1911 Articles Rising City. •uly 13 1911 Company Articles Omaha .... 20.000 July 211911 E Savings Bank (former- First Trust &amp; Savings ik) Amend't Lincoln July I Farmers" Trust Company . . . Amend't Beatrice Vue 1 lftll </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock CORPORATE NAME El Real Estate Company rmerly Folda Real Es - i &amp; Trust Company) . . . Amend't Schuyler Aug. 2 1911 Farmers' Grain &amp; Live Stock Company Amend't Norfolk Aug 9 inn Fairbury Light &amp; Water Co. Dissolu- tion Fairbury . . : Aug. 12 1911 Eiew Mutual Telephone (formerly Farmers' tual Telephone Co.) . . . Amend't Articles Articles Eustis Aug 21 mil Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank First State Savings Bank. . Ceresco Superior uui 15,000 Aug 2&gt;; inn First Trust Company of York Articles York ,000 ! Aug mn Farmers' Grain &amp; Live Stock Stock Association Articles Coleridge 25,000 Sep. 4 mn Kers' Co-operative Grain ociation Amend't Articles Articles Edison Cordova Beatrice Sep ii mil Ultll 14 1911 Fraternity Hall Company. . . Farmers' Grain Company . . . 20,000 Sep. 40,00f Farmers' Grain, Stock &amp; Im - plement Company Articles Articles Dissolu - tion Eagle 10,000 Sep. 200,00&lt; 15 1911 20 1911 Fidelity Trust Company- Fremont Fowler Publishing Company Lincoln :Sep. 211911 Biers' Grain &amp; Lumber mpany Articles Dodge 25,000 | Oct. 4 1911 Farmers' (The) Shipping Association Articles Broken Bow 25,000 Oct. 10 1911 E Savings Bank of Friend »rmerly First Trust ft vings Bank) Amend't Friend Oct. 14 1911 Fairbury Mill &amp; Elevator Company Articles Articles Articles FairBury Kramer Lincoln 55,000 Oct. 25,000 Oct. 26,000 Nov 18 1911 26 1911 14 1911 Farmers State Bank. Folsom (The) Bakery. First State Savings Bank of Beatrice (formerly First Trust ft Savings Bank) . . . Amend't Beatrice Dissolu- Nov. 20 1911 Farmers' Lumber Company 16 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Instru ment Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock CORPORATE NAMI Farmers (lay Froducts Co.. Articles Tekamah .. 100,000 Dec. 181*11 Frick, A. N. Company Articles Omaha &lt;ec. 22 1911 First Trust Company Amend't Omaha .... 500.00C Deo. 2:; 191 1 Farmers' Produce and Com mission Company Articles Omaha *c. 30 1911 Federal Security Compan&gt; i formerly Federal Trust Company) Amend't Omaha .... Ian. :: 1911 Fremont Savings Bank (for - merly Fremont Trust &amp; Savings Bank* Amend't Fremont ... Ian. S 1912 Florida Lake Region Land Company Vrticles Omaha .... 12 n. 111912 Farmers Lumber. Coal &amp; Im plement Company Articles llreenwood Francis Self-Lighter Co.... Articles Omaha .... I.2M Jan. 191911 The Farmers State Bank... Articles Hampton .. 15,000 Ian. 2." 1912 Farmers Creamery Company l formerly Crab Orchard Creamery Company I Amend't. Crab Orch'd in. 2»&gt; 1912 Fralick Furniture Company. Articles CJr'nd Island | .in. 29 1912 First Savings Bank Amend't Crete Feb. 11912 Farmers' Cooperative Store Articles Marsland .. 25,000 Feb 2 1912 First State Bank Amend't Kenesaw . : Feb. 2 1912 Farmers State Bank Articles Bradshaw Vb. 5 1912 Franklin Ice Cream Co Araend't! Lincoln ...I lSo.oon Feb. 14 1912 Francis Self-Lighter .Amend't Omaha XI Feb. 14 1912 Farmers' Co-operative Grain Association Amend't j South Bend .Mar. •"&gt; 1912 Fawn Lake Ranch Company Amend'tiRushville . . Mar. 13 1912 Farmers Elevator Company. Amend) Farmers Elevator Company. Amend't Wilber Exeter Wilber .... 25,000 Mar. 27 1912 Mar. 0 Apr. 27 1912 4 1912 Fanners tt Merchants Bank . Articles Exeter xpr. 4 1912 Farmers tt Merchants Bank. Articles Firth Grain &amp; Lumber Co. . Dissolu- Firth Grain &amp; Lumber Co. . Dissolu- Firth "' Apr. 9 1912 tion tion Firth T Apr. 9 1912 Pickrell ... \pr. 13 1912 Farmers State Bank Amend 't Farmers State Bank Amend't Pickrell Apr 13 1912 Farmers Grain Company... Articles Farmers Grain Company. .. i Articles Osceolg ... 2"., Dim Apr. 15 1912 Osceola ... 15.0M Apr. 15 1912 Farmers Lumber Company. Articles Farmers Lumber Company. .Articles Osmond ... 25.0DO Apr. 22 1912 Osmond Apr. 22 1912 Foresters Hall Rssociation. Articles Foresters Hall Rssociation. ' Articles rrofton ... l.niK) Apr. 2fi 1912 rYofton Apr. 26 1912 Farmers Co-operative Creamery Company Articles Farmers Co-operative Creamery Company Articles Sargent ... »1 May 3 1912 Sargent ... 2:.,oO)' May 3 1912 25.000 May Pririe Hme lay 4 1912 Farmers Grain Company. . . . Articles Farmers Grain Company. . . . Articles Pr'irie tt'me </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru Place of Business ized When Capital Filed CORPORATE SAME ment Stock Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank I Articles Davenport . 15,000 May IS 1*11 POntanelle Building Co Articles Florence . . 15,000 May 1 1 L913 Farmers State Bank | Articles ! Benedict . . 15,000 May I First State Bank : Articles ; Pawnee ... 30,000 May I Fairbury Alfalfa Mills j Articles -"airbury . . 10,000 May 1 First State Bank Amend't Hemingford 86,000 -May I Farmers State Bank (Articles Fullerton .. 25,000 May 2i 1912 Farmers State Bank Articles Verona 10,000 June 10 l»12 M LM1 11 l»12 Farmers State Bank Articles Greenwood 25,000 June Farmers Supply Company. . Articles Trenton 15,000 June Farmers Hall Association... Articles Pender iit.000 June 191 Flitton Optical Co. (former- Omaha ly Huteson Optical Co.) . . . Amend't June Franklin Brokerage Co j Articles Omaha 25,000 July 10,000 July 50,000 July St. Mary. Farmers Elevator Company. Articles Farmers State Bank Amend't Rosalie Foster-Baker Company (for - merly H. E. Palmer, Son Amend't Omaha July &amp; Co. I Farmers Elevator Company. Articles jBennet 25,000 July 22 1911 The Farmers Union Co-oper- ative Association. Articles Creighton 25,000 I Aug. 101912 Fairview Realty Company.. Articles Fremont 30,00 Aug. 13 Ift12 Farmers Grain Company... Articles Morse Bluff 12 000 Aug. 14 1912 Farmers State Bank . Articles Ayr 25,000 Aug. 26 1912 First Evangelical Church... Articles Allen Aug. 27VJ12 Farmers State Bank. Articles Plymouth 50,000 Aug. 30 1912 Farmers State Bank. Amend't Glenville Aug. 301912 Farmers Grain &amp; Stock Co. . Articles Creston 9,000 Sep. 2 1912 Farmers Bank. Amend't Stapleton ! Sep. 4 1912 Farmers State Bank. Articles Talmage 20,000 Sep. 18 1912 Farmers Union. Articles Crofton 10,000 Oct. 311912 Frontier County Bank. Articles Stockville 10,000 Nov 4 1912 First State Bank. Articles Whitman 25,000 Nov 9 1912 Faulkner Coal Company. . . . Articles Omaha 125,000 Nov 18 1912 Farmers Loan &amp; Investment Lancaster Company Articles County 50,000 Nov 10,000 Nov 221912 30 1912 Farmers Grain Company. . . . Articles Bancroft Gilmore- Armstrong Co. Dissolu- </seg>
            <seg id="p051">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Place of ized When ment Bus; Capital Filed CORP&lt; (RATE NAME Stock Great Western Hide &amp; Fur Company Articles Omaha Feb. (The) German American Safe Deposit &amp; Trust Co. . ; Articles Beatrice Grand Island Marble &amp; Granite Works Articles Grnd Island - Gaudreault Clothing Co. (for merly Rhea Clothing Co.) Articles Holdrege . . Feb. 14 1911 Grand Island Land Co Articles Grnd. Island' George Gifford Co | Articles Omaha Guggenheim Co. (The) Dissolu- tion Lincoln ... Mar. § Graceland Park Cemetery Company I Articles Omaha | 100,000 Mar. 27 Bwool Telephone Co.... Articles Blue Hill. .. linger, A. Company.... Articles Lincoln ... Gardner-Cochran Construe (n Company Articles Lincoln ... en West i and Co Araend't Omaha June t on Fire Proof Ware use &amp; Van Company &gt;rmerly Kxpressmen's livery Company) Amend I Omaha June"' id Island Contract Co... Articles Gr'nd Island 5,000 July 10 1911 enwood Club Articles Greenwood 1,000 Aug. 8 1911 d Roads Incorporated... Articles Helena, Golden West I and Co Amend't Omaha ' 'une 2: Em Fire Proof Ware ise &amp; Van Company rmerly Kxpressmen's Delivery Company) Amend I Omaha .... ; June 30 1911 Kd Island Contract Co. . . nwood Club 5,000 July 10 1911 1,000 Aug. 8 1911 Good Roads Incorporated... Mont. ... 5,000 Aug. 9 1911 Gustin. Edward E. &amp; Co tin, Edward E. &amp; Co Articles Lincoln ... 100,000 Aug. 25 1911 Glade, Henry (The) Milling Company de, Henry (The) Milling ompany Articles Gr'nd Island 90,000 Aug. 25 1911 Great Bras D'Or Gold Mining Company at Bras D'Or Gold Mining ompany Amend't Omaha Sep. 28 1911 Gyroscope Mfg. Co oscope Mfg. Co Articles Omaha .... 9,000 Nov. 8 1911 Grand Island Publishing Co nd Island Publishing Co Articles Gr'nd Island 25,000 Nov. 22 1911 Kd View Orchards and leyards nd View Orchards and ineyards Articles Lincoln . . . 50,000 Xov. 25 191 1 enslit Lumber Company. Articles Ravenna .. 25,000 Dec. 2 1911 Greenslit Lumber Company. Gordon-Lawless Co. (former ly Western Tinware Mfg rdon- Lawless Co. (former ly Western Tinware Mfg </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author - ized Capital Stock Instru- Place of ment ! Business When Filed CORPORATE NAME Geddes ft Co. (formerly Fra - lick-Geddes Co.) Amend't Gr'nd Island Articles Lincoln . . . Dec. Dec. LI inn Gulf Coast Development Co 10.00C Graduate Nurses Official Di - rectory Association Articles Lincoln Articles Omaha Amend't Burr . Dec. Jan. Feb. Feb. 28 1911 Galligher Real Estate Co.. German-American Bank. . G. E. F. Medical Co. Articles lLorton j Garden City Feeder Co. (for - merly Pella Stacker Co.). Amend't Pella, la.. 100,004 Mar German American Family Society Articles Articles Lincoln Lincoln 1.IMU Mar Apr. 28 19,= Gillen &amp; Boney Building Co. 13 1912 25,000 Garfield Mutual Telephone Association Articles Burwell . . . Apr. If ry 18 1912 17 1912 Gray Bonnet Taxi Line. Articles Omaha 50,00( K;e Brothers of Omaha rmerly Potter, Cobb ft ikle Co.) Amend't Omaha Articles iLincoln June June urn: IT, 11.12 German nvestment Co. 25,000 German-American Coffee Co of Nebraska Articles Omaha I 100,000 June 27 1912 Gooch Milling &amp; Elevator Company Amend't Lincoln Dissolu- 500,000 June 27 1912 Gem Laundry Company tion Crete July 5 1912 German Nurseries &amp; Seed House Articles Beatrice . . . 100,000 July July July Aug. Aug. Aug. 15 1912 16 1912 201912 BCity Mfg. Co. We Clevis Co. Articles Omaha 100,000 Articles Omaha 25,000 Eian Bank of Millard jn Multiprint Company, ey, J. F. Company , White &amp; Schatz Co... Amend't Millard 30 1912 Articles Omaha 20.000 Articles Lincoln ... 10,000 Dissolu- tion No. Platte Aug Sep. Sep. Oct. 29 1912 4 1912 Gray Bonnet Taxi Co Gate City Malt Company. . . . Geneva Mfg. ft Supply Co. Grand Island General Hos Articles Fremont . . I 20,000 Amend't Omaha 23 1912 4 1912 Articles Geneva 6,000 pital Articles Gr'nd Island Articles Columbus . 100,000 Oct. S3 Galley Dry Goods Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author - ized Capital Instru Place of Business When Filed CORPORATE NAME ment Stock B Mercantile Co. Id Telephone Co Amend't DeWitt 25,000 Oct. 30 1912 30 1912 Articles Garfield ... &gt;') I Nov. 1 1912 Grand Island Horse &amp; Mule Company Articles Gr'nd Island 25,000 1 Not. Hershey Land Company.... Certifi- cato shey...j 10.000 Dec. 5 1!) 5 1910 (The) Harrison State Bank. Howland, E. H. Lumber &amp; \rticles Harrison .. 20,000 IVc. - Coal Company So. Omaha. 100.000 Dec. 30 1910 (The) Hardy Company Dissolu- Twin Falls. tion Idaho Nov. ■ &amp; Daggett (now Col urn- Fixture. Motor &amp; Pow- Company Amend't Lincoln ... 50,000 Jan. 14 1911 Havelock Improvement Co.. Hampton Elevator Co Articles Lincoln ... 100,000 Jan. 21 mil Articles Hampton . . M.tOO Jan. 2 Halm I^and Investment Co. . Hanighen. J. J. Co Articles; Lincoln ... 150,000 Jan. . Articles Omaha 100.000 Feb. Amend't Omaha Vb. In I'.Ml Hospe I A.) Co B Candy Company Lumber Co Amend i Hastings Articles I Henry 25,000 Feb. 23 1911 Hildreth Mercantile Co Herald Pub. Co Articres Hildreth . .. Articles ! Alliance 4,000 Mar. 29 1911 Harkert Cigar Co. of Grand Island Articles Grnd Island 15,000 Mar. Amend'tlomaha 10.000 Apr. Hochstetler Realty Co Hunter Realty Co.... Amend't Omaha 10O.000 Apr. 10 1911 Hansen Brothers Articles Upland EDawson Remedy Co. &amp; Kern Clothing Co. North Star Club. . . Implement Co Articles Lincoln ... 60,000 Apr. - Articles Ravenna .. l."&gt;,i&gt;00 May Articles Haigler 1,000 May 9 1911 Articles Hay Springs j 15.0O0 | May Haller Music Company Dissolu tion Blair June 1" Amend't York I June 12 1911 Eon Nursery Company, an &amp; Seymour. Inc.. n Bros. &amp; Company. . . Articles Elgin 100,000 Tune Dissolu- tion Hildreth... June 24 1911 Homer State Bank . . Homer State Bank . . Articles homer une 26 1911 Amend't Homer June 26 1911 Articles Fremont lO.OOO.July 11911 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of ; Author Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed CORPORATE NAME Stock Hafer, C. Lumber Company. Articles So. Omaha. 10,000 July 5 1911 6 1911 Harvard Electric Company. Amend'tHarvard July Haux Hardware Company. . Dissolu- tion Gr'nd Island ; July 11 1911 Howe Coal Company : Amend't Omaha July 18 1911 Hallam Bank Amend't Hallam 10,000 July 23 1911 Hardy-Enslow Lumber Co. . . Articles Col. View.. 25,000 Aug 11911 Hord, T. B. Land &amp; Cattle Company Amend'tCentral City Aug. 1 1911 Hoeschen Manufacturing Co. Articles Omaha 100,000 Aug. 4 1911 Havelock Co-operative Assn. Articles Havelock Holdrege Creamery Co j Articles jHoldrege 10,000 Sep 20,000 Sep. 22 1911 Holdrege Ice Cream Co Articles Holdrege 7,500 Sep 20 1911 Hastings Ice Cream Co Articles j Hastings 10,000 : Sep. 28 1911 Hrabak &amp; Gorham Articles Walthill 49,000 I Sep 29 1911 Havelock Commercial Club. Articles Havelock 5,000 ' Oct. 3 1911 Home Builders I Articles Omaha 100,000 Oct Home Builders' Investment Company Articles Omaha 25,000 Nov. 25,000 Nov. 25,000 Dec. 20,000 : Dec. Heaton Investment Company i Articles Central City 25 1911 Hillcrest Land Company. . . . Articles lAvery 6 1911 Hamer, A. G. Notion Co Articles Lincoln 13 1911 Hamilton County Republican Association Articles Aurora 10,000 Dec. Hay ward Cattle Company. . . Dissolu- tion Chadron Dec. 30 1911 6 1912 Hehnke-Lohmann Company. Articles Gr'nd Island Hay Springs Lumber Co. ... Articles Hay Springs 75,000 Jan. 25,000 Jan. 50;000 Jan. 25,000 Jan. 10,000 Jan. 111912 19 1912 30 1912 301912 Higgins ft McDonnell Co... Articles Fairbury Hanson State Bank Articles Hanson Hope Investment Company. . Articles Omaha Hastings Foundry ft Iron Works Amend't Hastings 150,000 Feb. 10.000 Feb. 25,000 Mar 9 1912 29 1912 15 1912 Helvey Farmers Elevator Co. Articles Helvey Horn Auto Supply Co ; Articles Omaha Herman Brothers Company. Dissolu- tion ( Lincoln Mar I Held-Woodman Auto Co.... Articles | Omaha 25,000 Apr. 5,000 May Holdrege Smoke House Co. . Articles I Holdrege </seg>
            <seg id="p055">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru Place of Business (RPORATE NAME ment Home Telephone Company.. Dissolu - tion Papillion May Hemingford Loan Co. (for merly Hemingford Loan &amp; Trust Co.) Amend! Hemingford Amend! Howells . . . May : Howells State Bank 20,00i&gt; 25 1912 Haas &amp; Hord Cattle Co Amend' |('entral City 27 1912 Handcraft Furniture Co jncoln 1912 Howard County Telephone Company tion St. Paul July 2 1912 Honey Creek Coal Mining Dissolu- Company tion Repub'n Cjr Julv 2 Hasting3 Poultry Company. Articles Hastings 10,000 Aug. 16 1912 Herndon &amp; Kern Clothing Dissolu- Company tion Ravenna Aug. 29 1912 10 1912 24 1912 9 1912 12 1912 12 1912 28 1912 1 1912 18 1912 IS 1912 24 1910 Hay Springs Commercial Co. Articles Hay Springs 15.00 &gt; 0 Oct. 0 Oct. 100,000 Oct. 10,001' ■ Nov. Heyn, The Photographer Articles Omaha Harding, I,. &amp; Sons. Inc Articles Omaha Happy Hollow Club Amend 1 Dundee Harney Holding Company. . Articles lOmaha Articles Omaha Hippo Theater Company Herald Building Company. . Articles Omaha Harris Plumbing Company. . Articles Nov. I I&gt;ec. Lincoln Harvard Milling Company. . . Articles Harvard Indianola Land Company. Articles Lincoln International (The) Tool Manufacturing Company.. Articles Omaha 25,000 Apr. 11 1911 Ideal Manufacturing Com- pany of Nebraska City... Article? Xebr. City. International Institutes Co.. Articles Lincoln Imperial Land &amp; Cattle Co. . Articles Chadron Interstate Live Stock Com- mission Company Articles So. Omaha. ily 19 1911 500.000 Aug. 28 1911 Hen Biscuit Company Amend't Omaha .... Inter-Mountain Land Co Articles Omaha p. 16 1911 Iowa-Nebraska Public Ser- vice Company Articles «-t. 21 1911 '. t. 24 1911 Norfolk Independent Telephone Co.. Amend't Amherst Idlewild Club. Articles Omaha 2.0O0i Jan. 18 1912 Inter-Mountain Realty Co... Omaha \rtlplP" Ama Vi n Author- ized Who:i Capital Sto .June Articles I Dissolu- June 10.IXX) May 30 1911 2. r ).000 June 20 1911 100.000 July 6 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author Place of ized When Business j Capital Filed Stock Independent Publishing Co.. Industrial Garage Company. Iowa Farms Company Amend't iGr'nd Island 28,000 Apr. 3 1.H2 Articles ! On? aha 10,000 May 18 1912 Amend'tSOmaha Articles Omaha 50,000 May 22 1912 E Motion Picture Co ta Manufacturing Co. . . 3h Ladies' Aid Society . . e (The) Company 25,0Wi I Sep. 11 H» 12 Articles (Lincoln 10,0001 Oct. M 1912 Articles jSo. Omaha Feb. 15 191 1 Arucies so. umana tea. loiaii Articles Belfast 85,000 Oct. 24 1911 Jack Morrow Flats Tele phone Company Articles .No. Platte 10,000 Nov. 23 1911 Jefferson County Bank Amend't Day kin Feb. 28 1912 KIThe) H. Von Steen Co. on Farm Company. . . . tone Auto Lock Co. Amend t, Beatrice 200,000 Mar. 6 1912 Articles Fremont 25,000 I Apr. 27 1»12 trmerly Wilt- Johnstone npany i Amend t Amend't Articles Lincoln 200,000: Apr. 27 1912 Esaw Exchange Bank. .. Foundry Company,. . . . er-Smith Ranch &amp; Stock Kenesaw 50,000 1 Dec. 13 1910 Xebr. City. 20.000 1 Dec. 16 1910 Company Articles Omaha r.o.i'OO Dec. 17 1912 50.000 Dec. 17 in 12 (The) Kearney Alfalfa Meal Company Articles Kearney 10.000 Feb. 24 1911 Kearney Sa\ings &amp; Loan Association Articles Kearney 500.000 Mar. 2 1911 King Drill Mfg. Co. Amend't Xebr. City. 100,000 ! Mar. 9 1911 Eman &amp; Wernert Co.... ch, E. Company as &amp; Nebraska Inv. Co Articles 5,000' Mar. 23 1911 No. Platte. . Articles Omaha Ml | Mar. 2fi 191 1 f Nebraska (now Kansas Nebraska Inv. Co Amend't 1 incoln . . . Apr. ."&gt; 1911 B;hts (The) of Columbus ub Articles Omaha 24,000 May 2 1911 Eball, Thomas L. Co 5er, Frank Company.... :ka Glass &amp; Paint Co.; Amend't Omaha 10,000 June 12 191 1 Articles :S. Sioux Cy. 10.000 June 22 191 1 also Kostka Drug Co Killian. A. 1... ft Co Kramer Lumber Company. . Kenesaw Fraternity Assn.. King-Roln bough Company. Krotter &amp; Hall Lumber Co. . Amend t Lincoln ... June 27 1911 J Ullf Lt 19 11 50,000 July 13 1911 Articles Omaha 10.000 Aug. 15 1911 Dissolu- &lt;"&lt;)Kl'iiK.\TK NAMK Amend t Norfolk Articles Crete 10,000 Aug. 11911 Articles Kenesaw .. 10,000 Aug. 14 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued i Author CORPORATE NAME Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock ment Instru- Kind of Kean Hardware Company.. Dissolu- tion Ravenna Sep. 7 1911 Killian. A. ('., Clothing Co.. Kruger Brewing Company. . Kleins Mercantile Company. Kohl Land &amp; Investment Co. Kearney Land Company. . . . Articles Kearney 20.0IX, Nov. 27 1911 75.0M Dev. 14 1911 200,000 Jan. II 1912 10,000 Feb. 19 iyi2 Articles 3. Sioux Cy Amend't Beatrice Articles Wayne . . . . Amend't Kearney 100,000 Mar. 2.". 191 Kloke Investment Co. (for- merly Kloke-Headley In- vestment Co.) Keeley Institute Amend't Dissolu - tion )maha Apr :: 1912 Blair Apr tS 1912 25 1912 29 1912 8 1912 28 1912 Kennedy Building Company. Kelly Boiler &amp; Tank Co.... Kearney Canning Company. Kearney Opera House To. . . Kearney Ladies' Outfitting Amend't Articles Articles Articles Omaha Omaha loo.non Apr. 20,000 Apr. 100,000 May Kearney Kearney 4,500 June Com pan y Articles Kearney Auk 9 1912 Kearney County Chautauqua Auditorium Association... Articles ;Minden 5,000 Oct. 10,000 Oct. 1912 Kimball County Fair Assn. . Kimball Laundry Company. (The) Loup Valley Bank... (The) Lincoln Typewriter Articles Kimball 25 1912 12 1912 30 1910 Amend't Omaha Xov Amend't Palmer Dec. Exchange Company Articles Lincoln ■ Jan. 4 1911 Lincoln Lister &amp; Manufac - turing Company Articles Lincoln 100,000 Jan. 100,000 Feb. 9.000 Feb. 10,000 Feb. 1911 Lincoln Hospital Assosiation Lowell &amp; ?4inden Tel. Co... Lincoln Typesetting Co Lamoreaux-Feterson-Xoyes Articles Lincoln II 1911 27 1911 Articles iMinden Articles Lincoln I instruction Company.... oln Pure Butter Co Miller Hardware Co. Articles Articles Omaha Lincoln 25.000 Feb. 100.000 Mar. 28 1911 10 1911 (now Thomas &amp; Court - right Hardware Co. ) Amend't Fremont Amend't Palmer Articles Riverton Articles Lincoln Mar 11 1911 14 1911 17 1911 20 1911 E&gt; Valley State Bank. . . . f Creek Telephone Co.. an-Warner Company... ■I Lutheran Colonization Mar 1.500 Mar. 25,000 Mar. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru ment Author- Place of ized When Business ' Capital I • Filed CORPOUATE NAME Stock l.ynch Milling &amp; Power Co.. Dteaolu- tion nch | Apr. :i l'.M 1 (The) Laurel Stock Pavilion Association Articles Laurel 10,000 Apr. 4 Itll L. P. Larson Real Property Company ' Articles Fremont . . 100,000 I Apr. 14 1911 Limited Lyceum Bureau. ... Dissolu- tion Lincoln ...' Apr. 18 1911 Loup Valley Land Co Articles Omaha .... 25,000 &gt; May 81911 Leisure Hour Club Articles 'Bellwood . . 300 I May 9 1911 Logan Valley Land Co Articles Oakland ...I 25,000 July G 1911 Lincoln Trust Company Articles Lincoln ... 100,000 j July 7 1911 Long Wood Irrigating Canal Company Articles Comstock . 2.200 July 18 1911 Lincoln Accident Insurance Company Articles Lincoln ... July 29 1911 Lincoln Grain Company.... Dissolu- tion Lincoln ... j Aug. 2 191 1 Logan Valley Bank Amendt Uehling Aug. 10 1911 Lindsay State Bank i Amend't Lindsay Sep. 14 1911 Lemp. Win. J., Brewing Co.. Dissolu- tion Omaha Sep. 29 1911 Live Stock Loan Company (formerly Live Stock Loan &amp; Trust Company) Amend't So. Omaha. 'I Oct. 9 1911 Lehmer, Joseph R. Co Articles Omaha 150,000 Oct. 28 1911 Lancaster County Social &amp; Reading Club Articles Lincoln 500 Nov 7 1911 Lancaster Milk Producers Association Articles Lincoln 25,000 Nov 18 1M1 Lancaster Milk Producers Association Articles Nov. 18 1911 Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln Baseball Club Amend*. 30,000 Nov 211911 Long Pine Bottling &amp; Ma chine Company Articles Ix&gt;ng Pine 15,000 Dec 10,000 Dec 10.000 Dec 12 1911 19 1911 23 1911 Lincoln Rotary Club. Articles Lincoln Loree Abstract Company. . . . Articles Falls City. Lincoln Telephone &amp; Tele- graph Company ] Amend't Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed CORPOU.YTE NAME Stock E&gt;ln Safe Deposit Co. rraerly Lincoln Safe De - iit &amp; Trust Co. ) Amend! Amend't Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln Lakeside Jan. Ian. 500. Win Jan. 1912 E)ln Trust Company.... &gt;ln Paint &amp; Color Co. . . side Telephone Co )ln Fixture &amp; Supply 17 1912 Amend't 31 iyi2 Articles Mar 15 1!U2 Company Articles Lincoln Apr. May May May 27 1912 Eln Musical College.... In Packing Company.. State Bank Articles Lincoln 7 1912 i 1911 Articles Lincoln Articles I/eigh Eister Milk Producers' ociation Amend't Lincoln June 1912 Loma- State Bank Articles l.oma June 17 1912 Lincoln Land Company. Long Pine Mercantile Co Amend't Lincoln June Dissolu- tion Long Pine. July 13 1!U! Dissolu- Lawrence Milling &amp; Elevator Company tion Lawrence July ;: 1912 Lincoln County Land Co Amend't Davenport. la. Aug. 15 1912 Lowden. Isabel, School of Physical Education and Expression Articles Omaha 5,000 Aug. 17 1912 Eln Steam Paste Co. w Lincoln Feed &amp; Fuel lpany) Amend' Lincoln 50.00C ; Aug. 27 1912 LeBlanc Mercantile Co Dissolu- tion Oxford Oct. 23 1 !M 2 Liberal Publishing Co. Articles Creighton 15.000 Oct. 10,000 Deo, 25,000 Feb. 50,000 Feb. 10,000 Feb. Feb. 2,000 Mar (The) Murrey Dipper Co. . . Mid-West Cigar Company... Merchants Bank Articles Lincoln Articles Omaha 1 1911 10 1911 14 1911 18 1911 Articles Utica Elow Grove Tel. Co in (F. S.) &amp; Co dan Telephone Co hants Syndicate Catalog Articles Mead. Grove Articles Omaha Articles Randolph 6 1911 Company Amend't|Omaha 10O,00f. Mar 29 1911 Kkell Town Hall Assn cey Music Company Articles Maskell 5,000 Apr Articles Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p060">CORPORATIONS— (Continued) MISCELLANEOU i i ■:l'(iKATE NAME Kind of Instru- ment Author- Place of ized Business Capital Stock When Filed Missouri Valley Educational Association Articles Omaha . . . . | 25,000 Apr. 4 1911 Midwest Investment Co Articles Lincoln . . . lOO.OOii Apr. 27 191 1 Madison Hardware Co Articles '.Madison ... I 4 May 2 1911 Modern Homes Construction Company Articles Omaha 200,000 May 5 1911 Missouri Valley Trust Co. . . Articles Omaha .... 25,000 , May 11 1911 Mid-West Engineering Co. .. Articles Omaha I 10,000 . May 12 1911 Mithen-Drew Company Articles Omaha .... 100,000 May 15 191'. Missouri Valley Electric Co. Articles Odell 150.000 ] May M 1»11 Maxwell Lumber &amp; Coal Co. Articles Maxwell ... 10,000 May 27 1911 Morris (The) Transfer Co. (formerly Morris Trans- portation Company) Amend't Lincoln May 12 1911 Mercantile Incorporating Co. Dissolu- i tion Omaha June 10 1911 Mickel Investment Company Articles Omaha .... 25,000 i June 26 1911 Morton Grain Company Dissolu- tion Xetar. City . ! June 29 191 1 Maple Grove Land &amp; Live Stock Company Amend't Omaha July 8 1911 Marsh. W. \V., Company (for- merly Marsh, YV. W., Es- Bte &amp; Trust Co.) Amend't Omaha .... j '. July 18 1911 ird Auditorium Assn... Articles Millard .... 4.(HK) July 19 1911 erick Loan &amp; Trust Co. Amend t Hay Springs July 19 1911 Maupin-Shoop Publishing Co. Articles Lincoln ... 5,000 ! Aug. 7 1911 Merriam Commission Co. ... Articles Omaha .... 20,000 j Aug. 15 191' Milton Company Amend't Omaha Sep. l'B 191 1 Midland Investment Co J Amend't Lincoln ... : Nov. 8 1911 MaskeH Mercantile Co Articles Maskell ... 10,000 • Jan. 81912 Metcalf Coffin Company.... \rticles Lyons 2."&gt;,000 Jan. 8 1912 Maverick Investment Com- pany (formerly Maverick Loan &amp; Trust Co.) Amend't Hay Springs Jan. 12 1912 Merchants Grocery Syndi- cate Articles Omaha 50,000 Jan. 17 1912 Masonic Temple Assn Amend't Ixmg Pine Jan. 25 1912 Millard Hotel Company Uissolu- </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) ■ Miller Weigand Co Articles Bertha 10,000 Feb. Murphy Land &amp; Cattle Co.. Articles Banner .... '" Feb .'1 1 1* I tort's Clothes Shop Articles Omaha .... 10,000 Mar. 11 1^1 Miller. Burd F., Co Articles Omaha Mosby &amp; Young Co. (former- ly Frank Kruger Co.) Amend't Sioux City la Mar. Metal Shingle &amp; Machine Co. Articles Fremont . . Maple Grove Land &amp; Live Stock Company Amend t Omaha Mar. 27 1*1 ■&gt; Martin-Senour Co. (The) ... Articles Lincoln ... 100.00m Apr Ein Luther Academy and rmal School ( formerly rtin Luther College) . . . Amend't Articles Articles Amend't Sterling Omaha Lincoln Lincoln Apr. ■&gt; i Apr 2 ■ : I Merchants Drug Company. . Meriden Manufacturing Co. . Jlemmen, T. F.. Company... Krest Clay Manufacturing mpany Articles Wahoo . n May ■ End Title Guarantee &amp; tract Co. (formerly d 1 a n d Guarantee &amp; st Company) Amend't Omaha May ■-&gt; Merchants Syndicate Catalog Company Amend't Omaha .... 1 •&gt; Morris Transfer Company. . Malcolm State Bank Mulig Machine Company Manhattan ivestment Co. . . . Eest Electric Co. (for rly Johnston Electric npany) Amend't Omaha . . . . July - Munn-Reise Construction Co. (formerly Callahan Bros., Munn &amp; Reise) Amend't Omaha \ - •&gt; Kind of Author- Instru- Place of ized When imrporate XA.MK ment Business Capital Piled Stock Mills Real Estate Co Dissolu- tion Omaha Ian. t\ Miller Hotel Company Dissolu- tion Omaha Ian. 27 191 Myers-Dillon Drug Co Articles Omaha ... Merriam &amp; Millard Co Amend! Omaha Feb. Amendt Lincoln . June 11 1*12 Amend't Malcolm June 1 Articles York Articles Omaha .... </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 17 1S12 S3 Itll 111.11 if 1*11 4 1912 12 1I-11' 23 1912 30 1910 1719,1 3 1911 261911 101911 28 1912 23 1912 is:: 4 191 i 9 1911 111911 111911 13 1911 30 1911 311911 on :inue I Kind of Instru- Place of CORPORATE NAME ment Business Author- ized Capital Stock When Filed CORPORATE NAME Middle West Elevator Co... Dissolu- Aug. 17 1 tion Omaha .... Mool, Harry W.. Company.. Articles Omaha .... 25,000 Aug. 26 1 Masonic Temple Association Articles Kearney . . 15,000 Sep. 6 1 Mid- West Electric Co Amend't Omaha 125,000 Sep. 7 1 McLeay Drug Company Articles Shelton . . . 65,000 Sep. 23 1 Mutual Service Co. (formerly Oct. 11 1 Western Manufactures Co. Amend't Beatrice . . . Mutual Service Company. . . . Amend't Beatrice . . . 50,000 Oct. 22 1 Magee &amp; Deemer Articles Omaha .... Midwest Construction Co... Articles Lincoln ... 100,000 Oct. 29 1 000 Nov. 4 1 K;r Brothers Company . . . Articles Lincoln . . . il County Fair &amp; Stock owers' Association Articles Bridgeport inley Mercantile Co. ... Articles Harrison .. 75,000 Nov. 12 1 10,000 Nov. 23 1 20,000 Dec. 30 1 Mel lellan Stock Co | Articles Ericson . . . 1.000 Feb. 1 7 1 (The) McNish Land Co Articles Wisner 100,000 Mar. 3 1 McFherson County Fair As- 500 Apr. 12 1 sociation Articles Flats McCoy &amp; Finlayson Co Amend't Omaha McGrew State Bank Articles McGrew ... 15,000 25,000 Apr. 17 1 July 26 1 ook Telephone Company ! Dissolu- Nov. 10 1 tion McCook . . . McCook Co-operative Hos- pital Association: Articles McCook ... 25,000 Feb. 28 1 McCrory (J. C.) Company... Articles Omaha .... Nebraska Mercantile Land &amp; 50,000 Nov. 23 1 Etle Company Articles Broken Bow nal Supply Company.. Articles Omaha .... iska Mutual Life Insur- 25,000 Dec. 13 1 50,000 Jan. 3 1 ance Company Amend't Hastings .. Jan. 4 ) I The) Nebraska &amp; Kansas 10,000 Jan. 9: Telephone Company Articles Red Cloud. . Nebraska Suspender Manu- facturing Company Amend't Omaha Nebraska State Bank Articles 'Lincoln . . . Nebraska Material Company • Amend't' Lincoln ... Nebraska Engineering Co. . . Articles j Lincoln . . . Jan. 11 : 50,000 Jan. 11 : 100,000 10,000 25,000 Jan. 13 : Jan. 30 Jan. 31 Newport Loan £ Trust Co . . Articles Newport . . . Nebraska Silo Company | Amend't Lincoln . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Place of ized When COKPO&amp;ATE xa.mk ment Business ' Capital Stock i Nebraska Improved Live Articles Lincoln Articles Lincoln Feb. 2 Stock Hreeder^ Nebraska Printing Company Nebraska Implement &amp; Seed Company Articles Lincoln 10,000 Mar. i Nebraska Furniture &amp; Car- pet Company Amend't Omaha .... Mar. 1 1 Niemann, Carl J.. &amp; Bros. . . Amend t Omaha ... &gt;00 Mar. 1 National Automobile Train Articles Omaha ing Association Mar Nye &amp; Turner Co Amend't Omaha Mar. National Health League Nora State Bank Articles Lincoln t Apr. Amend't Nora In, 000 Apr. - -ehneider-Fowler Grain Company Amend't Omaha . Articles Randolph Dissolu- 500.000 May 4 19.1 31 1M1 K western Farm Line... Ik Laundry Company.. tion Norfolk Articles Omaha Articles Lincoln Amend't Milford Articles Naponee Articles Ellswort Dissolu- June June June June June June 13 1911 22 lit 11 281911 Eska Mausoleum Co. . . . ska School of Business ska State Bank 200.000 25,000 Naponee Milling Vompany.. Noe Cattle Company 25.000 50.000 Nebraska Central Land Co. . tion Lincoln July 6 1911 Nebmska (The) Apple Cul ture Company Articles Lincoln 5,000 July National O. I. C. Chester White Record Association (formerly Western O. I. C. Recording Company) Amend't Hastings July July 8 1911 31 1911 Nebraska Fire Apparatus Co. Amend't Omaha ; 50,000 Nebraska Macaroni Manu - facturing &amp; Selling Co... Dissolu- tion Omaha Aug 2 1911 Kska Advent Christian terence Amend't Lincoln Articles Lincoln Aug. \ug. ,;::;; Nebraska Typewriter Co. . . . 25,000 Nebraska State Savings Bank (formerly Nebraska Trust &amp; Savings Bank) . . . Amend'tjWahoo </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author - ized Capital Stock Instru- Place of ment Business When Filed CORPORATE NAME Nebraska State Bank (for- merly Fidelity Bank) Amend't O'Neill .• Aug. 17 1911 Nebraska Regal Sales Co. . . Articles Omaha 10,000 Aug. 29 mil Nielsen &amp; Mackprang Hard ware Company I Articles Oxford .... 10,000 Aug. 31 l»ll National (The) Pumice Co. . Articles Omaha 100,000 Sep. I ltll Nebraska Yearly Meeting of Friends Articles Central City ; i Sep. 11 1911 Nerraha Oil &amp; Gas Co Articles Shubert ... 10,000 ! Sep. 22 1! Hill National Live Stock Com- mission Company Amend t So. Omaha. :»n,ooo Oct. S 1911 National Fidelity &amp; Casualty Company Amend llomaha ... 250,000 Oct. 27 Ltll Novelty Company Amend't Omaha . . . . 50.000 Oct. _ Nebraska Sub-Irrigation &amp; Land Company Articles .Lincoln ... 100,000 Nov. S 191 1 Nebraska Pressed Brick Co. Articles Omaha . . . . ; 25,000 Nov. 11 1911 Nebraska State Bank Articles jVerdigre ■ . I 30.000 Nov. 11 liil l National Lumber Box &amp; Dissolu- Package Company i tion lOmaha Nov. 15 1911 Nebraska Seed Company... Amend'tlOmaha .... 12.".. 006 Nov. 20 1911 North Arkansas Lumber Co. Articles Hastings 25,000 Nov 2A 1911 National Automatic Vehicle Fender Company Articles Omaha 25,000 Dec. 6 1911 riska State Conference the Church of God in Christ Jesus Articles Hastings .. Dec. Nebraska Placer Company.. Articles Omaha 3.00G Dec. 8 1911 Nelson Sewer Company. Articles Nelson . 10,000 Dec. 9 1911 Nebraska State Swine Breed- era Association. Articles Lincoln ...I Dec. 16 1911 Newport Land &amp; Loan Co.. Amend't jNewport . . Dec. 27 1911 National Automatic Vehicle Fender Company Amend' tjLincoln Jan 25,000 3 1912 Niobrara Valley Bank. . . Jan. 10 1912 Amend't Niobrara Nebraska State Association of Graduate Nurses. Articles Omaha .... Jan. 10 1912 Nebraska Investment Co. formerly Dorsey Trust So.) Amend't Dorsey Jan. 10 1912 Nebraska Silo Company.... Amend't Lincoln 250.000 Jan. 16 1912 Nebraska Motor Company. Seward ... "0 | Jan. 18 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">• •► ■&gt; ■» MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued ) Author- Kind of Instru- Place of ized When CORPORATE NAME ment Business Capital Piled Stock Nebraska Investment Co. ... Amend 1 1 Lincoln North PUtte Lumber Co Articles No. Platte. 25,000 Feb. North Star, Sheridan &amp; Cur ; Cnrtim tia Telephone Company.. Article Nebraska Distillery ! Articles So. Omaha. Nebrio Construction Co I Articles iOmaha ....! 100,000 IVb. _ Nimrod Club ! Articles Red Deer National Cleanser Company : Amend t Omaha .... .'.lar. I Nebraska Live Stock Rem- Fremont . . Mar. I.'j 1!»1 edy Company Artiol Nebraska Mutual Life lnsur- 1 Hastings . , • Mar Amend'! ance Company Nebraska Atchison Steel! Lincoln ... 1G Post &amp; Pole Co ' Article N.-braska State Bank ; Amend't Lincoln ... 1 Nebraska Workman Acci Aurora .... \pr. ■ dent Association Article Nebraska Blaugas Company j Articles Omaha ... North l.oup State Bank | Articles North I.oup National Employees' Assn.. Articles Omaha .... Neligh Hotel Company 'Articles Neligh .... Norfolk Packing Company .. &lt; Articles Norfolk ... 35.000 Apr 2 Nuway Water Supply Co. . . . Articles Hastings . . May 1 1 191 l Norfolk Ice Cream &amp; Bak- ing Company Articles Norfolk ... Northwestern Mutual Tele phone Company i Articles Cozad MM May Nebrasga Chiropractic Col- lege Articles Lincoln ... lune 10 191 Nebraska Warehouse &amp; Stor- age Company Articles Norfolk ... »K&gt; June ■&gt; National Automobile Train- ing Association Amend'tOmaha 80,000 June 21 191 Nebraska Casket Company. . Articles Lincoln ... 50,000 June 2 Nicholas Senn Hospital Association Articles Omaha June 2."&gt; 191 Newman Telephone Co Articles Fullerton . . t.400 June I Northwestern Telephone Co. Amend't Neligh .... 25,000 Tuly Rh Platte Electric Co. &gt;rmerly North Platte Gas ft Electric Co.) Amend t x 0 . Platte. . | 100,000 Jun. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">ATIONS— ( ontinued) MISCELLANEOUS CORPO CORPORATK NAME Kind of Instru- ment Place of Business Author- ized Capital Stock When Filed Nebraska Suspender, Garter Aug. 9 1912 A Belt Company Articles Omaha .... 25,000 National Automatic Fender Co. (formerly National Au- tomatic Vehicle Fender Omaha .... Aug. 12 1912 Company) . . . . t Amend't I 100,000 Nemaha Valley Light &amp; Power Company Articles Pierre, S. D. 50,000 Aug. 14 1912 . 100,000 Aug. 26 1912 Nebraska State Bank Articles Ord New England Bakery Co ... Articles Omaha 50,000 Sep. 3 1912 Norris &amp; Norris ( formerly | Omaha .... 50,000 Sep. 3 1912 ...... Norris &amp; Martin) Amend 1 1 Nebraska Engineering Co.. Dissolu- tion Lincoln . . . Sep. 9 1912 Nebraska State Poultry As- Lincoln . . . 10,000 600,000 Sep. 111912 sociation Amend't Nebraska Corn Mills Articles Lincoln . . . Sep. 27 Mil Oct. 11 1912 Eska Blaugas Co | Amend't Bka State Building Co. Articles ska Atchison Steel Omaha .... 2,000,000 Lincoln . . . 100,000 Nov. 19 1912 Post &amp; Pole Co i Amend't Lincoln . . . Nov. 30 1912 Omaha Tractor Mfg. &amp; Foun- dry Co. (formerly Omaha 9,00C,000 Dec. 1 1910 (tor Car Company) Amend't ) Omaha Traction ft g. Co Amend't . Oil &amp; Burner Co Articles lala Land &amp; Cattle Co.. Amend't ha Traction &amp; Mfg. Co. Dissolu- tion ard &amp; Wilhelm Co Dissolu- tion ha Brick &amp; Tile Co Amend't Omaha .... Omaha .... 300.000 Dec. 1 1910 Gr'nd Island 5,000 Dec. 17 1910 Omaha .... 120,310 Dec. 21 1912 Omaha .... Dec. 23 1910 Omaha .... Dec. 26 1910 Omaha Dec. 27 1910 Omaha &amp; Western Iowa 250,000 Dec. 311912 Traction Co I Articles Pierre, S. D. Otoe Brewing Co Amend't Omaha Structural Steel Wks. Amend't (The) Omaha Country Club Amend't Octa via State Bank Amend't Oakridge Investment Co | Articles Nebr. City. : Omaha Omaha . . . . 200,000 50,000 Jan. 16 1911 I Jan. 17 1911 Jan. 18 1911 : Octavia 10,000 Jan. 20 1911 100.000 | Jan. 28 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Instru- Place of ized When CORPORATE NAME ment Business Capital Filed Stock (The) Omaha Robe &amp; Tan- ning Company Articles Omaha 25,000 Feb. 14 1911 Omaha Film Exchange Articles Omaha 9,000 Mar. 17 1911 Omaha Secret Service De- Dissolu - tective Agency tion Omaha Mar. 24 1911 Omaha Tapestry Paint Co . . Articles Omaha 10,000 Mar. lo 1911 Oskkosh Impt. Co Articles Oshkosh 25,000 Apr. 3 1911 Odd Fellows' Hall Assn .... Articles Gordon 15,000 Apr. 10 1911 Omaha Clay Works Articles 'Omaha 100,000 Apr. 17 1911 Omaha Secret Service De- tective Agency Articles Omaha May 3 1911 Omaha Concrete Stone Co. . Articles Omaha 25,000 May 111911 Omaha Taxicab &amp; Auto Liv ery Company Amend't Omaha 30,000 May 18 1911 Order of White Uniform. .. Articles Lincoln May 25 1911 Kto Telephone Co. (for - rlly Oconto Telephone Central Exchange) Articles Oconto 2,000 | May 30 1911 Omaha Mutual Realty Co. . • Dissolu- tion Omaha June 6 1911 Ord Commercial Club Articles ;Ord 10,000 June 19 1911 Omaha Paper &amp; Notion Co. . Articles Omaha 20,000 June 27 1911 Omaha Building Investment Company Articles Omaha 40,000 June 27 1911 Omaha (The) Peddlers Union Articles Omaha July 5 1911 Overland Life &amp; Accident Association Articles Omaha July 14 1911 Omaha (The) General Hos- pital Articles Omaha July IS 1911 Omaha Sanitary Supply Co. (formerly Johnson Rowe- Paige Company) Amend't Omaha Aug. 5 1911 10,000 Aug. 18 1911 Omaha Sales &amp; Supply Co. Articles Omaha Ord State Bank Amend't Ord Aug. 28 1911 Official Registry Association of Graduate Nurses Articles Omaha Sep. 16 1911 Omaha School of Music. ... Articles Omaha 10,000 Sep. 25 1911 5,000 Sep. 28 1911 Omaha Athletic Club Articles Omaha Omaha Messenger &amp; Express Company I Articles Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed CORPORATK NAME Stock Omaha Wrecking Company. Dissolu- tion Omaha Oct. 21 1911 Omaha Wholesale Grocery Company Amend'tOmaha 26,000 Nov. 3 1911 Orchard Investment Co ; Articles lOmaha 25,000 Nov. 10 1911 Omaha Safe Deposit Co Aniend't! Omaha . ... I Dec. 12 1911 Omaha Safe &amp; Iron Works. Articles ' Omaha .... ec. 16 1911 O. K. Tobacco Company.... Articles Hastings .. j 25,000 Dec. 211911 Omaha Rod &amp; Gun Club Amend't Omaha I Jan. S 1912 Omaha Fibre &amp; Corrugated Box Company I Articles Omaha 100,000 Jan. 16 1912 Omaha Real Estate Co ; Amend't' Omaha .... Ian. 13 1912 Omaha Society of Fine Arts. | Articles Omaha .... ] Ian. 30 1912 Oakland Grain Company , Articles Oakdale . . . 24.0U0 Feb. 16 1912 Olson Manufacturing Co Articles Lincoln ... 100,000 Feb. 19 1912 Order of Good Samaritans. . Articles Lincoln .. . Feb. IT 1912 Orchard Ranch Company. . . Dissolu- tion Ainsworth . i Feb. 29 1912 Omaha Wholesale Drug Co. . Articles Omaha 150,000 I Mar. 4 1912 Omaha Cooperage Company. Amend'tOmaha .... lOO.iKiO ', Mar. 4 1912 Omaha Sugar Cone Co Articles Omaha j 5,000 j Mar. 8 1912 Omaha Motor Car Co Articles Augusta, Me 500,000 Mar. 28 1912 Omaha Can Company Amend'tiOmaha .... 75,000 Apr. 8 1912 Omaha Merchants Express £ Transfer Co &gt; Articles JOmaha 100,000 : Apr. 19 1912 Omaha Rod &amp; Gun Club. ... Amend't Omaha 100,000 i May 3 1912 Omaha Fixture &amp; Supply Co. '. Articles JOmaha 25,000 May 50,000 June 24 1912 11912 11 1912 28 1912 13 1912 3 1912 121912 17 1912 20 1912 4 1912 9 1912 11 1912 Orr Motor Sales Co ; Articles I Omaha Orleans Athletic Association Articles Orleans 6&lt;M) June Omaha Furniture Mfg. Co. . Articles i Omaha 10.0,000 June 10,000 July 3,000 Aug. 10,000 Aug. Ord Drainage Company Articles Ord Obert mprovement Co Articles lObert Omaha Retail Grocers' Assn. Articles | Omaha 25.000 Aug. 150,000 Aug. 20,000 Sep. 100,000 Sep. Otto, M. C, &amp; Co Articles Aurora Omaha Oil Company Amend't ;0maha .... Omaha Hide &amp; Fur Co Articles Omaha Omaha News Company Articles Omaha Omaha Casket Company.... Amend'tOmaha Sep. Overland Real Estate &amp; In- Dissolu- vestment Company ' tion Xebr Citv I Sep. 20 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of I Author- Instru- Place of ized When inent Business Capital Filed CORPORATK NAME Stock Omaha Provisional Battalion Nebraska National Guard Articles Omaha 45,0(M) Sep. 23 1912 Orcutt, F. H.. &amp; Son Co Amend tlOmaha 200,000 Oct. It! 1 1» 1 2 Omaha Realty Owners' Cor poration Articles lOmaha ....10 ct. 261912 Otoe Packing Company Articles .N'ebr. Cit&gt; »0 Nov. 2 1912 Omaha Lodge Supply Co... Articles Omaha i 10,000 Nov. 13 1912 Petof Sick Benefit Society. . Articles Omaha .... 1,000 Dec. 3 1910 Princess Theater Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Jan. Physicians &amp; Surgeans Hos- pital I Articles No. Plat t- 10,000 Jan.: Peru Fruit Farms Articles Peru i 25,000 Jan. 28 1911 (The) Pierce Elevator Co. . Articles Pierce 50.000 Feb. 18 1911 Prague Farmers' Stock &amp; Grain Company Amend't Prague .... I Feb. 21 1»11 Positive Print Machine &amp; Paper Company Articles iOmaha 300,000 Feb. 24 lit 11 Philpot Ranch Company. ... Articles Weeping Water ... 100.000 Mar. 13 1911 People's Furniture &amp; Carpet pet Co. (now Union Out- fitting Company I I Amend't Omaha Apr. 1 1911 Palmer Opera House Co i Articles .Palmer 10,000 May 28 1911 Plattsmouth Auto &amp; Wagon Bridge Company Articles Plattsmouth 50,000 June 300.000 June 21911 13 1911 Peters, M. C. Mill Co i Amend't Omaha .... Pine Ridge Educational So ciety Articles Pine Ridge . June 26 1911 Peters Trust Company Amend't Omaha June 30 1911 Platte Valley State Bank. . . ! Articles No. Platte. . 50,000 July- 5 1911 Pythian Investment Co Articles E. Minatare 25 1911 25,000 July People's Ice &amp; Cold Storage Company Amend't Omaha 250,000 Aug. 16 1911 9 1911 7 1911 1 1911 3 1911 Parks, Lefler &amp; Company... Articles So. Omaha 6.000 Sep. 20,000 ' Oct. 10,000 Nov. 10,000 Sow Paxton Taxieab Livery Co. . Articles Omaha Prairie Park Club Articles Omaha Pleasant View Fruit Farm . . Articles Florence Prairie Park Company (for merly Prairie Trust Co.) . . I Amend't Omaha Nov. 9 1911 9 1911 Plattsmouth Water Co I Amend't plattsmouth 90.000 Nov. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) E's Loan ft nvestment pany (formerly Peo- Loan &amp; Trust So.) . . Nov. Amend't Lincoln 18 1911 Petersburg Co-operative Live Stock Shipping Assn Articles { Petersburg 1,000 Nov. 25 1911 Progressive Film Exchange Company j Articles Omaha 15,000 Dec 23 1911 Phenix Investment Company ( formerly Phenix Trust Company) Amend't Omaha Dec Jan. Jan. 29 1911 Payne Investment Co Amend't Omaha 500,000 25,000 Potter, H. W. (The) Co Articles (Elba People's Auto Package De livery Company Articles Omaha 10,000 Jan 23 1912 Peterson, Edward, Contract ing Company Articles Omaha 150,000 Feb. Feb. Feb. Feb. Feb. Feb. Mar i:s; Parks-, George, &amp; Company. Articles Omaha . . . . 5.000 Phelps-Gray Company ' Articles McCook 10,000 Peterson, Edward, Co Amend't Omaha 28 1912 21 1912 Pioneer Specialty Co | Articles Omaha 10,000 25,000 100,000 P. O. Pugsley Lumber Co ... | Articles Genoa Pioneer Irrigation Co ' Articles Haigler E Valley Cement Tile . Co. (formerly North d Cement Ttile Mfg. Co.) kmend'tiXorth Bend 50,000 Mar 23 1912 Parks, Robert Heating &amp; Plumbing Company Articles I So. Omaha 5,000 18 1*11 23 1912 3 1912 Apr. Apr. May tie's Co-operative Store ;er Insurance Company. ler-Schureman Mercan- Articles Fairbury Articles Lincoln 10.000 100,000 tile Company Articles ■ May wood 40,000 May 2 1912 Plattsmouth Loan &amp; Build ing Association Amend't Plattsmouth 1,000,000 May 2 1912 Palace Theater Company... Paxton Taxicab Livery Co.. Articles So. Omaha. 25.000 June 3 1912 Dissolu- tion Omaha lune 22 1912 Peters, M. C, Mill Co , Amend't Omaha 500,000 June 11 1912 Phi Delta Theat House Association | Articles Lincoln 25.000 30,000 July 12 1912 July 12 191? Palace Furniture Company.. Articles Lincoln CORPORATE NAME Kind of Instru- ment Place of Business Author- ized Capital Stock When Filed I </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed ct mi'oRATE name ment Stock Pleasanton State Bank Platte Valley Mercantile Co. People's Co-operative Store. Public Service Company of Amend't Pleasanton July It; 1912 Articles Denvel, Col Fremont . 25.000 ; July Aug. 17 1912 Articles 1912 Western Nebraska Articles Articles Articles Scotts Bluff Aug. 12 1912 Ele's City Mission Home iyra Hook &amp; ladder Co. bytery of Xiobrara of Lincoln Aug 29 1912 16 1912 Palmyra Niobrara ; Oct. :&gt; 1912 the Presbyterian Church in the United States of America Articles Amendt Peoples Bank of Red Cloud Platte Electric Light &amp; Red Cloud. Springfield . Nov. •', i«ji2 1912 Power Company Articles Articles Articles Amend't Kity Oil Company. . rside Bridge Co. . . irter Publishing Co Omaha 2 191] 1910 Willow Isld Bethany . . . Dec 1910 (The) Red Cloud Chautau - qua Association Articles Red Cloud. Jan Richardson Realty Co Richardson Drug Co Reliance Land Company.... Rock County State Bank... Rogers (F. B.. The) Co Roberts (R. E.) Elevator Co. Rich (Thos. C.) Company... Rogers Tent &amp; Awning Co. . Richland State Bank Articles Omaha _ 1911 Amend't Omaha Jan 1911 Articles Omaha i Feb. I Ft-b. ' Feb. 10,000 .Mar 10,090 Mar. Mar. 2 1911 17 1911 24 1911 24 1911 1 1911 1 1911 14 1911 Amend'l Newport Articles Omaha .... Articles Arlington Articles ;Omaha Articles Fremont Amend't Richland Road (The) Men's Co-op - tive Store Articles Articles Articles 10,000 Apr 25,000 Vpr 25.000 May 1 1911 _&gt;0 1911 1 1911 Alliance Lincoln Omaha Round Baler Company Riverview Investment Co. . . Rusland-Young-Henderson Company Articles Omaha lay 1 1911 Knson. J. ('., Real Estate mpany Articles Articles Waterloo Lincoln 100.000 slay Roberts' Sanitary Dairy Co. Reichenbach Land &amp; Loan Tune 23 1911 Company (formerly Reich- Amend't </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock CORPORATE HAMR ment Rock (reek Power &amp; Light Company ', Articles Benkelman . 26^K)0 Sep. i Rickard's Incorporated Articles Beatrice ... 7. ".00 Sep. 15 1911 Rupert (The) Ditch Co Articles Culbertson 10,000 Oct. 26 1911 Richards &amp; Comstock Articles Ellsworth . .'00.000 Nov. 6 1911 Rundschau Publishing Co. . . Root, A. L, Incorporated... Articles XorfoFk Huhmi Dec. 11 1911 Dissolu- tion Omaha .... Jan. 10 1912 Royal Hotel Company Articles ; Lincoln ... 10,000 Jan. 19 1912 Realty Investment Co. (for- merly Realty Trust Co. ).. Amend't Omaha Jan. 19 1912 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co Amend'i Lincoln Jan. 23 1912 Rondo Land Company Articles Omaha .... 10,000 -Jan. 29 1912 Red Deer Hunting Club i Articles Lincoln ... 10,000 Jan. 311912 Rivett Lumber &amp; Coal Co. . . Articles Benson 50,000 Feb. 2 i:&lt;12 Republican Printing Co.... Dissolu- tion Aurora ' Feb. 20 1918 Ringgold Mutual Telephone Company Articles Eustis 1,200 Mar. 1 1912 Rincker Book &amp; Drug Co. Articles No. Platte.. 10,000 Mar. 7 1912 Royal Order of Lions Articles Evansville Ind Apr. 12 1912 Reed Tire Company j Articles Omaha .... 5,000 Apr. 27 1912 Reeoe Shoe Company Articles Columbus . 25,000 May 2 1912 Republican Valley Bank.. Articles Naponee May 8 1912 Rosalie Mercantile Co. Articles Rosalie 25,000 June 10 Rainey Mail Exchange Co. . Articles Omaha I 1,000,000 Aug. 17 1912 Retail Creditmen's Assn Articles Omaha . 10.000 Sep. 6 1912 Root Investment Company.. Articles Sholes .... 10,000 Sep. 14 1912 Rambler Motor Company. . . Amend't Omaha 10,000 Oct. 11912 Red Front Mercantile Co Amend't Valentine . . Oct. 3 1912 Round Baler Company Dissolu- tion Lincoln Oct. 26 1912 Ralston Motor Company Articles Omaha 150,000 Oct. 29 1912 Roundup Coal Mining Co. . . Amend't Omaha .... Nov. 1 1912 Reeves Drug Co: (formerly Central Drug Co.) Amend't Omaha Nor. 11912 Rural Weekly Company. Articles Omaha . ... 100,000 Nov. 26 1912 (The) Springview Flour &amp; Certifi- Grain Company cate Springview 15.000 Dec. 3 1910 Saline Lumber Company </seg>
            <seg id="p073">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Place of Business ized When capital Filed CORPORATE NAME ment Stock Kior Corn Mill . M K.. &amp; Co Articles Superior Amendt Omaha . Iei Smith clothing Co. . . it (.1. A.I Mercantile Co ber. Bruce &amp; Bedford... Catherine's Hospital.... el Samuels Clothing Co Honiface Church Articles Omaha lan. 1 mil Articles (Superior .. (an. 12 1911 Articles ! Omaha .... Ian. 21 1911 Articles lOmaha Jan. _ Amend't Lincoln 1). 2 1911 Articles Stuart Feb. - Articles Kcr (.I.T.i aker. .1. 1.. Co. Schuyler Mar. 2 1911 Articles Omaha Strickland-Palisade Tele- phone Company Articles I Hayes Cent I Mar. 22 1911 e Bank of Liberty Amendt! Liberty Shedd-Miller Seed Co. (The) Dissolu- tion Ashland \pr. Snyder -Malone-CofTman Co.. Seumd C.rain &amp; Live Stock Amend't Omaha Apr. Company Articles Seward Apr. 19 1!H 1 Ercreek Telephone Co. . . hills Land &amp; Cattle Co. herdson Grain Co Articles Silver Creek Apr. 24 1911 Articles Omaha •&gt;l I Apr. 22 1911 Articles Omaha I Apr. 2.-&gt;1911 Kerged Land Company, t, J. K., Sewer Co Articles Beatrice \pr. 27 1911 Dissolu- tion Omaha May 4 1911 Articles Omaha .... 2"., 25,000 May 9 1911 Star Land &amp; Fruit Co. Skinned Manufacturing Co.. Saunders Suburban Homes Articles Omaha r&gt;0.000 May IT 1911 Company Articles Articles Omaha Omaha 50.000 May 18 1911 Biour Lake Country Club h Omaha Horse &amp; Mule 30.000 May 27 Company Articles So. Omaha. 50,000 May 27 1911 E'er. M. F., &amp; Company.. i. E. Building Assn Catherine's Hospital idard Land Company. . . srior Cattle Company... Amend't Omaha . ... 100,000 May 29 1911 Articles Lincoln ... 10,000 Jun« 2 1911 Amend't Omaha June 2 1911 Amend'tiUncoln ... June 6 1911 Dissolu- tion - Superior . . i June 10 1911 Smith Grocery Company... St. Patrick's Church Articles Omaha 2,000 June 20 1911 Articles ifhadron Tune 28 1911 Smith Bros. Loan &amp; Trust Co. (now Smith Bros. Co.) AmendtBeatrice </seg>
            <seg id="p074">CORPORATIONS— (Continued) MISCELLANEOU Kind of Author- Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed Stock i-iiKl'ORATE NAME Schaefer's Cut Price Drug Dissolu- tion Omaha | July 3 1911 Schietzel Electric Shot-Fir- ing Machine Company. . . . I Articles Omaha 100,000 July TliUl Shutt Drug Company Articles Diller 10,000 July 8 1911 Standard Furnace &amp; Supply Company Articles Omaha B.tM July 17 1911 Sheridan Coal Company Amend't Omaha . . . . ! July 18 1911 Security State Bank Amend t Osmond ... 50,000 July 18 1911 Superior Hydraulic Cement Brick' &amp; Tile Co Dissolu- tion Superior July 18 1911 Articles Alliance ... 10.000 July 19 1911 Telephone Company... ity Investment Co.... Dissolu tion So. Omaha | Agu. 17 1911 Sons of Nebraska Articles lomaha Aug. 20 1911 Kk, Tailor Bank Articles Omaha 10,000 Aug. 30 1911 Amend't Indianola Sep. 11911 Standard Grain Company... St. Edward Mercantile Co. . . _ ._ Articles Omaha 25,000 Sep. 11911 Articles St. Edward. 24,000 Sep. 7 1911 State Bank of Nebraska .... Amend't Seward ... 35,000 Sep. 181911 Security Savings &amp; Loan Association Amend't Lincoln Oct. 4 1911 Southwick Loan &amp; Trust Co. Amend't Friend 25,000 Oct. 5 1911 Kndard Land Company .... Nicholas Church Amend't Lincoln . . . 200,000 Oct. 7 1911 Articles Valentinue Oct. 13 1911 Sterling Realty Company... Stickel. W. L. Lumber Co. . . Sanitary Wet Wash Co Sheldahl Oil &amp; Gas Co Articles I Omaha 180,000 Oct. 211911 Amend'tKearney .. 100,000 Oct. 23 1911 Articles Omaha 20,000 Oct. 31 1911 Dissolu- State Bank of Bee tion Omaha '. . . . I Nov. 1 1911 Amend't Hee 10,000 Nov. 11911 St. Francis Church Articles So. Omaha. Dec. 12 1911 Ky Bros. Fruit Co ner Manufacturing Co. . ton Oil &amp; Gas Co Articles Lincoln ... 100,000 Dec. 13 1911 Amend't Omaha .... 100,000 Dec. 15 1911 Articles Shelton ... 20,000 Dec. 22 1911 Article^ Omaha .... 250,000 Dec. 25 1911 Dissolu- *■&gt;• Development Co uel Clothing Co Shafer. M. F.. &amp; Company.. tion Lincoln ... Dec. 29 1911 Amend't Omaha .... 100,000 Jan. 13 1912 Articles Hemingford I 'an. 131912 Spencer Lumber Company. . </seg>
            <seg id="p075">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author - ized Capital Instru- Place of Business When Filed CORPORATE NAME merit Stock Stitt-Dillon Motor Car Co... Dissolu- tion Hastings ; Jan. 17 1912 Sons of Poland Articles I So. Omaha Jan. 26 1912 Spear, \V. L., ft Company. . . Star Loan Co. of Nevada . . . Articles iGeneva 10,000 I Jan. 27 1912 Dissolu- tion Ian. 3 1 Security Land &amp; Improve ment Company Amendt Omaha i Feb. 11913 Star Mercantile Co. (former - ly Lindahl Merc. Co.) Amendt Oakland . . . Slater Drug Company Dissolu tion Virginia . . . i Feb. 8 1912 Sistek, Tailor Dissolu- tion Omaha ' : Feb. 14 1912 Stockmen's Bank Articles Seneca 'eh. 14 1912 Standard Loan Company... Storz (Arthur) Auto Supply- Articles Omaha .... HU&gt;imi Feb. Company Articles Omaha | 50.000 Feb. U 1912 Seager Engine Works Articles Lansing. Mich. ... , Mar. 4 1912 Eon Light &amp; Power Co. . i Clothing Company... i8h Evangelical Luther- Articles Shelton ... lar. 4 1911 Amend't Omaha Mar. an Betfage Congregation of Nebraska Articles Axtell Mar. I Luke's Hospital op &amp; Brundage Co er Creek State Bank e Throat Cure Company, them Florida Coloniza- Articles Kearney . . Mar 12 1912 Articles Lincoln ... lar. 19 1912 Amendt Silver Creek Apr. 1 1912 Amendt Lincoln ... Apr. 11912 tion Company Articles Sidney .... vpr. ::i912 St. Michaels Church Articles (Tarnov Apr. 4 1912 Sanitary Supply Company. . Sichl Hotel Company Articles (Madison ... 10,000 Apr. 111912 Dissolu- tion Xebr. City. Apr. 12 1912 Sichl Clothing Company Dissolu- tion Xebr. City. Apr. 12 1912 Saint Clair Mutual Tele- phone Company Articles Tilden 10.00c j Apr. 15 1912 Kis Timber Company &gt; Bank of Humboldt Articles Lincoln ... 150,000 Apr. 17 1912 Amendt Humboldt ...... M </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS i — (Continued) Kind of Author- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Instru CORPORATK NAME ment Stock St. Anthony's Church Articles West Point May 8 1912 Shultz Bros Articles Omaha 50,000 May IT 1912 Security Bank Amend't 5,000 May 23 191 Meadow (;r Sarvis Timber Company.... Amend't Jncoln 200,000 May 31 191 Sondermann Furniture &amp; Un taking Company Articles Jrnd Island 15,000 June 5 1912 Lincoln . . . 50,000 June 13 1912 Superior ... 3,000 July 8 1912 Shogo Lithia Springs Co. ... Amend't Superior Gravel &amp; Sand Co. Articles Security State Bank Articles Wakefield . 0 July 8 1912 State Bank of Odell Amend't Odell 100 July 20 1912 Snyder State Bank Amend t 3nyder July 24 1912 State Journal Company Amend't Lincoln ... ! Aug. 3 191 Storz (The) Arthur Auto Supply Company Articles Omaha 25,000 Aug. Shelton Alfalfa Milling Co.. Articles 3helton 25,000 Aug. 20 1912 Scott-Rawitzer Mfg. Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Sep. 3 1912 Scott-Parr Company Articles Omaha 25,000 Sep. I Sanderson's Tintine Co. . . . Articles State Building &amp; Loan Assn Amend't Lincoln 6,000 Sep. 17 1912 Omaha Sep. 17 191] St. Libory's Church Articles 3t. Libory. . Oct. 14 1912 Superior Corn Mille Dissolu- tion Superior . . I Oct. 16 1912 Superior Corn Products Co. Articles 20,000 Oct. 161912 Superior Superior Alfalfa Products Company Articles Superior 65,000 Oct. 18 1912 22 1012 23 1912 24 1912 Schatz, A. A.. Company Articles 10,000 Oct. No. Platte . . Shelton . . . Shelton State Bank Articles 50.000 Oct. State Bank of Omaha Articles Omaha Omaha Lincoln 00,000 Oct 3,000 Oct Standard Filler Machine Co. Articles Oct. Sigma Tau Articles Oct. St. Matthew's Evangelical Lutheran Church Articles Oct. Oct. Xov 29 1912 30 1912 Omaha Ralston Lincoln Seymour Lake Country Club Articles 50.000 10.000 Star Real Estate Co Articles 1 1912 Tilden Farmers' Elevator Company Articles Tilden Tryon 40.000 Dec. Dec. Dec. Feb. Mar. Mar. 12 1910 16 1910 19 1910 16 1911 (The) Tryon State Bank Articles K.MO Tanner Brothers Articles Arapahoe 25,000 Tribune Pub. Co Articles Falls City. . Lincoln . . . 7,500 Trenton Building Co ! Articles 10.000 ,;;:;; Tri-City Duplicating Co Articles Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p077">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued i Kind of Author- Instru- Place of ment Business ized When Capital Filed Stock RPORATE NAME (The) Typewriter Inspection Supply Company i Articles .Omaha ir i 1 Trimble Brothers. Amendt Omaha Apr mil Tagg Brothers Articles ! So. Omaha. I 25.000 May Taylor, A. W.. Company.... Articles C.rnd Island !■ !!»1 1 Tribune Publishing Co Articles Bloomington 1,250 lane 29 Tully-Mu£ser Cattle Co Articles Rushvillt Tilden Milling &amp; Grain Co Dissolu- tion Tilden Thayer Cattle Company Articles Ellsworth Trinity Lutheran Church... Articles Omaha .. Ti Tonner Pharmacy Dissolu- tion Lynch Tolinan Townsite &amp; Subdi vision Company Articles Omaha A Thurston County Fair and Speed Association Articles Walt hill i P Taylor. B. F., Company. Articles Omaha - Thompson-Davidson Co Articles Omahii '11 Thomas, J. S.. &amp; Son Articles Lexington . Tolerton &amp; Warfield Co Amendt Sioux Cy. '■■ Eale, E. A.. Grain Co ell Chemical Company. e Rock Clay Company . . Articles Hastings Ml Articles Bancroft Jan Dissolu- tion Table Rock I Jai 1 Torpin Land &amp; Live Stock Company I Articles Oakdale ... Twin City Coal Company. Dissolu- tion Omaha Feb Torpin Grain Company , Dissolu- tion Oakdale Feb. 2 Tuttle. Frank N . Co Articles iOmaha Mar. 4 IMS Taylor-Japs Company ; Articles Lincoln 101 Tate-Ehrhardt Company. . . . j Dissolu- tion Fremont Mar. . Tribune Publishing Co Dissolu- tion Bloomington Apr. Theatrical Society of Bone- Disaolu - mian Brothers tion Dodge June Thomas Curtain Fastener </seg>
            <seg id="p078">MISCELLANEOU CORP RATIONS— (Continue Kind of Instru- ment Place of Business Author- ized Capital Stock When Filed CORPORATE NAME Epson Creek Telephone lpany Articles Riverton . . 1,500 Ben Real Estate Co... Articles Omaha 10,000 Docekal Drug Co. (for ly C. A. Melcher Drug Aug. 18 1912 Nov. 19 1912 Feb. 4 1911 Company) Amend't Omaha Union Investment Co Articles Rushville .. 40,000 Mar. 27 1911 (The) United Brethren Hos Mar. 31 1911 fil Articles Beatrice i Stock Yards Company Omaha Amend't Omaha May 18 1911 University (The) Publish June 27 1911 ing Company Amend't Lincoln . . . 75,000 University Club Articles Omaha 20,000 United Alfalfa Company.... Articles Omaha .... 50,000 Ingles Hoggette Mfg. Co. . . Articles Lincoln . . . ! 25,000 United States Equipment Co. Dissolu June 22 1911 July 27 1911 Aug. 21 1911 J tion Jersey City Union Company of Omaha. . j Amend't Omaha .... 500,000 Union (The) Church j Articles Col. View Utah Colonization Company . Articles Omaha 200,000 Union Realty &amp; Investment Sep. 2 1911 Sep. 5 1911 Oct. 2 1911 Oct. 19 1911 Co. (formerly Union Re- alty &amp; Trust Co. ) j Vmend't \ o . Platte Union Real Estate Company (formerly Union Real Es- tate &amp; Trust Co.) Amend't Lincoln Union Stock Yards Co Amend'tj Lincoln Union Mercantile Company. Articles Col. View... 25,000 Oct. 25 1911 Oct. 26 1911 Dec. 16 1911 Jan. 101912 Ummo Round Baler Co Articles Lincoln . . . 100,000 Jan. 11 1912 I'mmo Round Baler Co j Amend't Lincoln . . . 100,000 Uehlin Townsite Company. Amend't Vehling Feb. 28 1912 May 13 1912 University of Nebraska School of Music Amend't Lincoln ... 150,000 Union State Bank Amend't Beatrice June 13 1912 Aug. 6 1912 En Development Co Articles iOmaha ....| 1,000 »d Clothes Shop Articles j Omaha 4,000 na Grain &amp; Lumber Co. Articles iProsser . . . 10,000 araiso Automobile Co.. Articles Valparaiso . 10,000 Camp. E. &amp; Co Articles Omaha I 30,000 s Theater Company. . . Articles Omaha I Sep. 261912 Oct. 16 1912 Apr. 13 1911 May 13 1911 June 14 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru- Pla£e of ized When Business Capital Filed CORPOKATE NAME ment Stock Van Gorden Company Articles Gresham .. 10,000 Feb. 27 1912 Von Seggern Auto Co Articles Wayne .... 25,000 Mar. 18 1912 Vollmer Clothing Company. Dissolu- tion Omaha Apr. 9 1912 May 4 1912 June 3 1912 Aug. ■&gt; 1912 Aug. - Dec. I Vogel Investment Company. Articles Omaha .... 120,000 V. T. Mills (The) Articles Humphrey . I4.M4 Veneer Barrel &amp; Machine Co. Articles Omaha 150,000 Veneer Pail &amp; Machine Co. Articles I Omaha 150,000 Wantland &amp; Shelton Co ', Article* Omaha 100,000 Witherspoon-Englar j Articles Chicago, 111. ' Dec. 6 1910 Wroth Amusement Co i Articles Omaha .... 10,000 Dec. 17 1910 Dec. 17 1910 Wagner Bros. Company Articles Omaha 20.00C (The) West India Mahogany Company Articles Lincoln 250,000 Dec. 24 1910 Winters Creek Coal Co Articles Scotts Bluff 100,000 Jan. 17 1911 Wentworth, Lew, Inc Articles Omaha I 10,000 Jan. 21 1911 Wolf Bros. Tent &amp; Awning Company Amend't Omaha Mar. 4 1911 Winter's Creek Canal Co Amend t Scotts Bluff Kill. (KM, Mar. 10 1911 Wauneta Farmers' Tele- phone Company Articles Mar. 29 1911 Apr. 211911 May 3 1911 Wauneta Lincoln 24,000 White-Mathews Land Co Articles 10,000 Wood River Auto Co Articles Wood River Council 5.000 Waterloo Creamery Co ! Amend't Bluffs, la. 100,000 50,000 10,000 May 23 1911 June 2 1911 June 12 1911 June 20 1912 June 10 1911 July 24 1!M1 Waters Tabulator Co Articles Omaha Western Mercantile Co Articles Western Western Duplicating Co.... Articles Omaha 5,000 Watson Hay Company Amend't Inman 3O.M6 Western Furniture Co ! Articles Omaha 12,000 Western Reference &amp; Bond Association Amend't,Omaha 10,000 30.000 10.000 Aug. 1 Aug. 16 1911 Sep. 9 1911 West Point Cadet Band Articles West Poin . Western Tobacco Company. Articles Hastings Wiggins-Babbock Accounting Company i Articles Omaha 25,000 Sep. 16 1911 Workmen's Co-operative Mercantile Association.. Articles Omaha. .... </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- Instru Place of ized Business Capital When Filed CORPORATE NAME - ment Stock Bans Home and Foreign Bsionary Society of the angelical Lutheran Sy- nod of Nebraska Articles Lincoln Oci 25 l •• 1 1 Webster County Light &amp; Power Company ! Articles Blue Hill... Plattsmouth Lincoln . . . Nov. Dec. Dec. ■5S Western Serum Company... Articles 50.000 \Vilt-John8tone &amp; Co Articles Ware Land &amp; Live Stock Co. Dissolu- tion David City Dec Wakefield Manufacturing Company Articles Wakefield i Dec Wareham Farmers' Tele- phone Company Articles Randolph Dec Wayne Live Stock Pavilion Company Articles Wayne 3,000 Dec. Dec. Jan. Jan. Jan. 22 liu l Western Glass &amp; Paint Co.. Amend! Lincoln 150,000 Wright &amp; Wilhelmy Co Amend't Omaha 500,000 ss Williams-Murphy Company. Amend't Omaha 50,000 Woodman Cafeteria Co Articles Omaha .... 10,000 Walrath &amp; Sherwood Lum- ber Company Amend't Omaha .... 600,000 Jan. Jan. Mar. Apr. Apr. May May July July Waterloo Elevator Co Amend't Waterloo . . 25,000 Wood, Ben B.. Realty Co. ... I Articles Omaha 100,000 IS 1*11 Wood worth. F. W., Co Amend't Lincoln I l»U E»ce Lumber Company.. Articles ern Manufactures Co.. Articles &gt;n Steam Boiler Co.... Articles Homer Telephone Co.. Articles Wallace ... 10,000 a i»u Beatrice ... 25,000 Omaha .... 50,000 Homer 3,000 Wyoming Alfalfa Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Whitton-Carlisle School Cor- poration Articles Lincoln Hastings 25,000 4,000 Aug Aug 1 1912 Western Bottling Works | Articles Western Auto Sales &amp; Mfg. Company Articles Omaha 50.000 15,000 25,000 16,000 Aug. Aug. Sep. Sep. 13,9,2 23 19,2 14 1912 26 1912 Wood River Roller Mills... Articles Wood River Wayne .... Wayne County Bank Articles Western lumber Company. : Articles Western Wymore Independent Tele phone Company Articles Wymore Omaha 25,000 Oct. 1 1912 Western Real Estate Co.... Articles </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author - instru- Place of ized ment Business Capital When Filed CORPORATE NAME Stock Ktern Academy of Sci - ce Articles Omaha 10,000 Oct. Oct. 7 1912 19 1912 Wahoo Lumber &amp; Grain Co.. Articles | Wahoo 50,000 Els Brothers Silo &amp; Man - during Company (for - rly Nebraska Silo Co.). Amend't Lincoln Articles Lincoln Articles Omaha 1,000,000 100,000 Oct. Nov Xov Xov 29 1912 7 1912 8 1912 12 1912 Ward Tractor Company Western Land &amp; Trust Co . . 25.O0O West Side Electric Co Articles Omaha . . . . ! 5,000 Western Land Securities Co. Articles Bowman, N. D 150,000 Nov. Jan. Mar 12 1912 24 1911 28 1911 Yost, J. H., Lumber Co.."... Amend't Harvard ... 40 York Milling Mompany Articles |York : York Ice Company Dissolu- tion | York Jan. Aug. Oct. 6 1912 2 1912 1 1912 York Printing Company Articles jYork 20,000 Young, Ed, Cigar Company. Young &amp; Henderson Co. (for- Articles Lincoln 20.000 merly Rusland-Young-Hen- derson Co I Amend't Omaha .... I </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 FOREIGN CORPORATIONS Appointing Resident Agents in the State of Nebraska Name of Corporation Place of Business When Filed American Naval Stores Co 'Savannah, Ga July Jan. Jan. Feb. iyi2 Bentley Clothing Company Kansas City, Mo. 19 1911 Bradley, Merriam &amp; Smith Council Bluffs, la •'7 19U Barber (The) Asphalt Paving Co Camden, X. J :&gt;. Hill Bemis Bros. Bag Co St. Louis, Mo Sep. Mar. 11 1911 Barnhart Brothers &amp; Spindler Jersey City, N. J 191? o Byers Bros. &amp; Co |C"hicago, 111 Sep. Feb. 21 n 1912 Diamond (The) Rubber Company... New York City, N Y 1911 Urake Marble &amp; Tile Company St. Paul, Minn Sep. Dec. 14 1911 Eckhart Carriage Co Auburn, ind •&gt;■'. 1910 Kdwards &amp; Bradford Lumber Co Sioux City, Iowa. Mar 20 1911 Fireetone (The) Tire &amp; Rubber Co. . . Akron. Ohio Apr. Jan. ■&gt;•&gt; 1911 Franklin Automobile Company 3yracuse, X. Y s 1912 Ford Paving Company Iowa June July July Feb. Dec. Jan. 4 1912 Fisk Rubber Company New York, X. Y 12 191 Good Roads, Incorporated I Helena, Mont 28 1911 Ceneral Electric Company iSchenectady, X. Y 10 1912 Hastings Gas Company Portland, Maine 10 1910 Hershey Land Company New York 17 1911 Hastings (The) Industrial Co (Chicago, 111 Jan. 16 1912 Hupp Automatic Mail Exchange Co. . Wilmington. Dela. '.Vilming:on. Dela. Muncie, Ind Nov. 13,1912 1912 lowa-Xebraska Public Service Co Interstate Automobile Company. . Oct. 21 1911 Feb. 19 1912 International Harvester Company of America 'hicago, 111 Nov. 15 1912 Johns-Manville (H. W.) Company New York City, X °eoria, 111 Y. Aug. 31 1911 Keystone &amp; Steel Wire Co. Nov. 4 1911 Kansas City Structural Steel Co. Kansas City. Mo. Kansas City, Mo. Bast Moline. 111. Indianapolis, Ind. St. Joseph. Mo. . Chicago, 111 Oct. 14 1912 Ee- Wiles Biscuit Company. le Automobile Company. . ke-Richards Iron Works.. June 21 1912 Dec. 26 1911 Jan. 9 1911 Xold (The C. H.) Lumber Company. Feb. 23 1911 Nelson Egg Case Filler Mfg. Co. Ovt. 26 1911 Pierce Milling Company. Davenport, Iowa. . Cincinnati. Ohio. La Porte. Ind. . . . Wilmington, Dela. 3t. Touis, Mo. . . . Apr :t 1911 Proctor &amp; Gamble Distributing Co. . May 24 1912 Rumley Products Company. Feb. 26 1912 Remington Typewriter Co. Apr. •&gt;_-. 1912 Royal Typewriter Company. Sep. 6 1912 Sturgis Milling Company. Sturgis, So. Dak. Simpson. Kansas. Mar. 6 1911 State Line Lumber Company. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 ■&gt; 1 FOREIGN CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Name of Corporation Place of Business When Filed Studebaker (The) Corporation of South Bend, Ind. Kansas City. Mo Osage. Iowa . . . America Oct. 11. l'.Ml Dec. 1 Ian. - June 7. 191:! Oct. 7. 1!M2 Nov. 2. 1!»12 Sep. fi, 1!'12 Dec. ■::',. 1»M Seavey &amp; Florsheim Brokerage Co. Smith Hovelson Lumber Company. . Smith, L. C, &amp; Bros. Typewriter Co... Jersey City, N. J. . Ef &amp; Hutchinson Co. ige &amp; Warner Co. . . . eim New York, N. Y St. Paul, Minn. Cedar Rapids. Iowa. Jersey City, N. J.. . Chicago. 111., Ked Motor Omaha Co . . ed Mercantile Agency Pierse, S. 1) Sep. Apr. 26. 191:; Oct. 1«. IM] !!ec. ■ \ur. : E:d States Investment Co. . ersal Stenotype Company erspoon-Engler Co Monte Vista. Colo. . Wilmington. Dela. . Chicago. Ill Wrought Iron Range Company St. Louis. Mo Indianapolis Ind </seg>
            <seg id="p084">RAILROAD INCORPOR TIONS AND EQUIPMENT AGREEMENTS Author- Kind of Place of ized When Instru- _ .. .! _.. . Corporate Name Business Capital Filed Stock ment Agreement between American Car Foundry Company and M. C. Peters Mill Co Agree- St. Louis Bethany Traction Co ment Articles Omaha Bethany $5,182.26 Feb. 6 1911 25,O0ff May 23 1912 Equipment agreement Chicago, Rock Island &amp; Pacific Railway and United States Express Chicago New York . . . Agree- Company Equipment trust agree- ment 100,000 May 2 1912 ment between Chicago, Rock Island &amp; Pacific Agree- Chicago Xew York . . . Company and nkers Trust Co 360,000 Oct. 19 1911 ment Kipment agreement be- ■een Chicago &amp; Xorth estern Railway Co. Chicago Xew York . . . and Farmers Loan &amp; Agree- Trust Company ment 10,000 Feb. 5 1912 Epment agreement icago &amp; North West l Railway Company d Farmers Loan &amp; Agree- Chicago New York . . . Trust Company ment 10,000,000 July 29 1912 Lease between Chicago * North Western Rail- way Co. and Farmers Loan &amp; Trust Co. (Ed win S. Marston, trus- Agree- Chicago Xew York . . . tee) ment 10,000,000 Oct. 25 1912 Hastings &amp; Northwestern Railroad Co Articles Omaha 100,000 July 21 1912 Eement conditional e, between Missouri ciflc Railway Com- Agree- pany and Central Trust Company Nebraska Central &amp; West- Xew York . . . ment 2,940,000 Dec. 26 1911 ern Railway Company. Articles Arnold, Xeb . . </seg>
            <seg id="p085">85 RAILROAD INCORPORATIONS — (Continued) Author- Kind of Place of ized When Corporate Name Instru- Business Capital Filed ment Stock Stock Kaska-Northwestern ilway Company . . Articles Spring'w, N'b 300,000 Apr Omaha &amp; Western Iowa Traction Company Articles Pierre. S. D Dec Omaha. Sioux City &amp; Northern Railroad Co.. Articles Tekamah, Nb Specifi- July sn.ooi Eia, Lincoln &amp; Bea :e Ry. Co. and West - house Electric Man - during Co cation Agree- Lincoln ment Pittsburg 6,650 Jan. Equipment trust agree - ment between Rock Island Improvement Co.. Chicago, Rock Island &amp; Pacific Railway Co. and Bankers Trust Co Agree - ment Chicago New York 360.000 Oct. Rock Island Improvement Company and Bankers Trust Company Assign - ment Chicago and New York Xov Trans'r Equip - ment Equipment trust inden ture between Rock Isl - and Improvement Co. and Bankers Trust Company Trust Inden - ture Chicago New York 1 500, Nov Equipment trust inden - ture between Rock Isl - and Improvement Co. and Bankers Trust Company Equip - ment Trust Inden - ture Chicago New York .605.000 Xov Assignment and transfet between Rock Island Improvement Company. Chicago, Rock Island &amp; Pacific Railway Com - pany and Bankers Trust Assign - ment j u l v and Chicago Trans'r Sew York ... j 5.100.000 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">S6 DRAINAGE DITCHES Name Drainage District Number One (1) of Scotts Bluff County, State of Ne- </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>