<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00032.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00032.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE STATE BANKING BOARD OCTOBER 1, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
         
            <seg id="p001">OF THE SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE STATE BANKING BOARD OCTOBER 1, 1914 By E. ROYSE, Secretary 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">DEPARTMENT OF RANKING OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA BOARD. Governor, President Auditor of Public Accounts Hon. William B. Howard Hon. Grant G. Martin Attorney General E. Royse Secretaiy Mary Muldoon Heffley Maude Hoge Clerk Assistant Clerk Henry C. Berge Anna Gass Assistant Clerk Stenographer EXAMINERS. E. H. MULLOWNEY Paul Jones M. C. Wilde S. A. Lapp E. N. Van Horne A. D. Touzalin T. R. Riley John Boatsman </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Lincoln, October 1, 1914 To his Excellency, John H. Morehead, Governor, Hon. William B. Howard and Hon. Grant G. Martin, The State Banking Board : Ientlemen : — I have the honor to submit herewith the twen - jcond annual report of the Department of Banking, for the od beginning July 1, 1913, and ending June 30, 1914, ving the condition of the building and loan associations of State of Nebraska at the close of business June 30, 1914, piled from annual reports of the several buiiding and associations submitted to the State Banking Board, in irdance with the provisions of the building and loan act, roved April 4, 1899. Tabulated statements, detailed re - s, comparisons and such information and comments touch - this report as are deemed beneficial will be found on the wing pages. I am pleased to inform you that the building and loan asso - ciations under your supervision continue to command the con - fidence of the people, as evidenced by the remarkable growth of the aggregate assets of these institutions, the increase dur - ing the past year being $4,391,686.97. I 'he Nebraska building and loan law has demonstrated the dom of its founders by the progress made by the associa - is operating under its provisions. It is becoming apparent, fever, that in some particulars the law will soon need ending". Such amendments as may be proposed should not made until after careful scrutiny and consideration, as a d law may be easily mutilated by amendments until it be - les a bad law. iwill refer you in particular to one provision of the law t, in my opinion, should receive attention. As the law now nds the amount of stock held by any one person is limited $5,000.00 par value. Inasmuch as the law provides that )an shall not exceed the par value of the stock held by the •rower the maximum loan that can be made is $5,000.00. is was a wise provision at the time the law was enacted, ; conditions have changed and what appeared to be an am - loan provision at the time the law was passed is now </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE found to be entirely inadequate and absurdly constrictive as applied to some of the larger institutions. I will not attempt to recommend a basis for enlarged privileges in the matter of loans, except to state that care should be taken in extending the limit to which a stockholder may invest, and to call atten - tion to the fact that in enlarging the loan limit it will be dan - gerous to consider full paid or matured stock as any part of the basis upon which the limit of loans might be predicated. Ehere are many minor amendments that might be made to law that would enable it to work more smoothly, but the ndment referred to above stands out clearly as an impor - one. E; is often suggested to this department by officers of build - and loan associations, that provision should be made in law for the investment of idle funds of the associations in e, county and municipal securities. Such suggestions are thy of consideration, provided the mutuality of building loan associations is fully protected ; and here again, as a s of investment, full paid and matured stock should be uded for apparent reasons. Pare should be taken in any and all amendments that are red to the law that mutuality, the basis of these associa - s, be fully protected, and that no errors be permitted to p in that would make these institutions a place of refuge the idle funds of the idle rich. Very respectfully, E. ROYSE Secretary State Banking Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">8 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SUMMARY of the condition of the BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS of the STATE OF NEBRASKA on the 30th day of June, 1914 (Number of Associations, 72) ASSETS First mortgage loans. First mortgage loans $ 33,628,785.73 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 212,791.70 212,791.70 Stock loans 609,447.93 Real estate 239,94o!85 Furniture and fixtures 32,145.43 Cash 1,709,787^83 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 97^840.85 Ksnses and taxes paid 20,534.92 r assets 172.845.28 172,845.28 Real estate sold on contract 414,292.74 Total $ 37,138,413.21 LIABILITIES Capital stock running $ 23,870,884.52 Full paid and matured stock 11,183,023.95 $ 23,870,884.52 Reserve fund 827,777.55 Undivided profits 33o!654.78 Due share holders on incomplete loans _ 674J60.20 Advance dues 4o!429!46 Advance interest and premiums 20,840.00 Other liabilities 190,042.75 Total ..._ | 37,138,413.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 9 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1, 1913 $ 1,^55,946.25 Dues 9,632,908.81 Full paid stock 3,245,482.73 Interest 2,271,660.64 Premiums _ 106,640.67 Fines _ 8,704.66 Membership and transfer fees 26,440.91 Loans repaid 6,138,805.27 Real estate sales 171,536.00 Rents _ 41,330.69 Bills payable _ 29,371.02 Other receipt 372,094.79 Certificates of deposit : 76,783.58 Total $ 23,877,706.02 EXPENDITURES Loans _ $ 10,885,815.04 Salaries 193,826.42 Commissions ••■■ 31,748.46 Other expenses 103,426.18 Withdrawals, dues 6,641,727.40 Withdrawals, earnings _ 359,429.83 Matured stock 597,128.20 Matured stock, interest 57,671.20 FuH paid stock 2,212,980.23 Full paid stock, interest _ 332,847.39 Cash on hand 1,709,787.83 Bills payable 35,171.54 Real estate 339,352.21 Certificates of deposit _ 78,988.10 Miscellaneous 297,805.99 Total $ 23,877,706.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of associations Permanent 50, serial 6, combined 6; total 72 Par value of each share of stock .50 of $100 each, 1 of $101, and 21 of $200 Number of series issued since organization (if serial) 645 Number of shares issued since organization 1,273,755.66 Number of shares in force at date of last report 740,580.09 Number of shares issued during year 207,652.81 Footing of two preceding items 948,232.9 Footing of two preceding items Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 72,065.79 Number of shares matured during year.. 21,925.59 Number of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn 37,809 Footing of three preceding items 131,800.38 Number of shares in force at this date 816,571.25 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date.... 733,070.28 Number of shares full paid and matured stock in force at this date 83,500.97 Number of shares loaned on _ 192,810.67 Number of shares . loaned on 6,929 Number of sharec subject to cancellation for nonpay - ment of dues 1,390.5 Number of borrowing stockholders 26,201 Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) 49,153 26,201 Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) Number of minors holding stock in the associations 1,670 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 2,175 Number of loans made for payment of homestead mort- gages during year 3,960 Average running time of stock matured during year 103 Months Total amount of dues delinquent at this date $ 33,261.53 3,960 33,261.53 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders 48,287.07 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid.... 117,142.06 48,287.07 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid. riber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same, No. 509. ._ 593,480.81 Number and amount of mortgages in process of fore- closure, No. 198 * 213,791.70 &gt;unt of loans on improved real estate 33,553,848.58 213,791.70 Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 63,239,797.25 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which 88,597.00 loans have been made 279,935.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the associations as collateral security 42,851,187.58 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to to the associations as collateral security 25,261,020.48 Amount of advance payment of loans during year 1,096,048.74 25,261,020.48 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 143,168.37 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 runt of dividends declared on running stock dur - ing year 2,136,982.60 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 610,683.77 rper cent, of dividends declared on running stock during year 8' ; Hate per cent, of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 6.2'i Hate per cent, of interest charged borrowers during year 8.2"&lt;- Rate per cent, of premiums charged borrowers during year : 2.7" </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT Showing the increases and decreases in the Assets and Liabilities of the BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS of the STATE OF NEBRASKA During the fiscal year ending June 30th, 1914 ASSETS Increases Decreases First mortgage loans $ 4,128,099.00 First mortgage loans under foreclosure 45,826.46 Stock loans 82,331.74 Furniture and fixtures 20,127.66 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 5,359.37 Expenses and taxes paid 1,592.89 ■ estate sold on contract 312,175.02 estate $ 147,768.66 Real estate Cash 46,158.42 Other assets v 9,898.09 Net increase of assets 4,391,686.97 :,OJ7J.,' </seg>
            <seg id="p013">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 13 LIABILITIES Capital stock running $ 2,847,743.90 Full paid and matured stock 1,412,296.07 1,412,296.07 Reserve fund 106,355.85 Premiums unearned 14,793.46 Advance dues 4,194.04 Other liabilities 182,316.51 Undivided profits $ 14,261.15 Pue shareholders on incomplete loans 147,500.90 Advance interest and premiums 2,046.33 Bills payable 12,205.48 Net increase of liabilities 4,391.686.97 Total $ 4,567,700.83 $ 4,567,700.83 Total assets, 1914 $ 37,138,413.21 Total assets, 1913 32,746,726.24 Net gain $ 4,391,686.97 1914 1913 Increase Decrease Number of loans made for building purposes in the year 2,175 2,183 8 riber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year 3,960 3,533 427 6,135 5,716 427 8 Borrowing stockholders : .26,200 24,029 Non-borrowing stockholders 49,153 46,967 2,171 2,186 75,353 70,996 4,357 Amount of improved real estate loans $ 33,553,848.58 Amount of unimproved real estate loans 88,597.00 Amount of stock loans 609,447.93 Appraised value of real estate and improvements 63,239,779.25 Appraised value of unimproved real estate 279,935.00 Amount of assigned fire insurance in force 42,851,187.58 Amount of assigned tornado insurance in force 25,261,020.48 Amount of business done during the year 23,877,706.02 At the cost of 1.37 per cent 329,001.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATEMENT BOf total number of associations, number of shares in force, and assets, from 1892, the first year that authentic reports were made, 1 to the present time. Number of i Associations Year II 71 84 M 81 1910. 73 68 64 6(1 60 59 58 59 60 59 61 66 68 70 70 69 68 70 72 Two associations were organized during the year as follows: Home Savings and Loan Association, Lincoln. I4** mgi u&gt;| m 1 0-1 1 *_ « q y\/4 T /\qm A ccApi Q^if\Ti T T n ivfircifv L^I ** t*c\ Number of lhares in Force Total Assets 45.012.5 61,964.1 71,231.5 70,615 64,891.75 67,597.5 79,973 89,492 105,625 119,985 130,083 153,424 174,022 196,030 220,648 315,372 372,826.77 438,054.19 512,344.71 602,159.94 668,122.85 740,925.29 816,571.25 $ 2,902,557.67 3i554i788.08 3,428,728.11 4|758.'293.97 5,343,429.38 6,217,350.40 7,269,297.48 8,961,788.11 11,422,890.86 13,415,822.89 17,094,771.57 21,327,766.83 24,885,285.15 28,946,108.63 32,746,726.24 37,138,413.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 STATEMENTS Showing the condition of each of the seventy-two Building ;-.nd Loan Associations in the State of Nebraska at the close of business June 30, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALBION, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President P. A. Krause Vice-President Wm. Weitzel Secretary F. A. Doten Treasurer F. S. Thompson Attorney O. M. Needham DIRECTORS. El. Krause L Doten B. Martin ». Bull W. S. Price Wm. Weitzel J. C. Mann G. K. Pittenger F. F. Willott F. S. Thompson T. F. Martin ASSKTS first mortgage lo&amp;us $ 12T.WJQ.00 Stock loans- 8,4410.00 Furniture and fixtures _ 11.57 Cash _ It.Mfl II Tax sale certificates HLM Total $ 143.761. 6a LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues aud dividends) $ 110,483.06 Full paid and matured stock 29.100.00 Full paid and matured stock 29.100.00 Reserve fund 3,750.00 Undivided profits — - 428.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS Balance on hand .July 1. I!tl3 S J.1«J lines I runiiiii).' stock i - -&gt;'■ 77_' U I uterest tax sales _ - - 'J*.*. 17 Interest - Ki.7Ui.nfl Premiums - l.iil? lei Fines jTi.rpii hfeabershia and transfer fees l.i 'Mil- repaid _ Bills payable ::..".m.iiti Insurance returned - - 41 4n Tux sale certificate* _ -'. 4 :&gt; Total $ 70.SO3.61 KXPENIllTTHES i - $ i" &gt;!«•.'«' Bills payable 3.3011.(10 other ex lienses _ 71 07 Withdrawals, dues — - 14 ' ' Withdrawals. earnings 7 7^1 '.»&gt; Matured Itock - 4.300.00 Matured stuck, interest .- 243.10 Kill! paid stock 13.20(1.1)0 Full paiil stock, interest 2.«4S on band. 6..W8.10 Interest paid on bills payable _ 11.10 Insurance advanced .... 41.40 -ale certificate! - 87U28 Total $ 7V ■ SIPPLEMENTAI. REPORT. Plan of association .Formerly Serial, now Pern Nuinlicr of shares issued since organisation 11 mrj Nuinlier of shares in force at date of last report 4._'47 Number of shares issued during year Its! Footing of two preceding items 9 -"-'- Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during vent- 581 Number of shares matured daring year \~~i Footing of two preceding items Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 4.1S1 Bber of shares of full paid and matured stock in force t this date - - -".'1 Number of shares in force at this date 4.47'J Number of shares loaned on. - 1 •■*'-' Number of harrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders I including minors) Number of minors holding stock in the association 4s Number of loans made for building purposes during year _ 3 NumlN'r of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages durin M rear Plan of premium Fixed. Payable Monthly Art i am running time of stock matured daring year _ 1L'."&gt; M l'iir viilm' «t f:\fh share at iterk - - $ lflnui Amount of interest, premiums anil lines due and unpaid 934.00 Kber of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, ami the ajitrrepate mount of same. No. 11 IMKIO.U) Amount of loans on improved real estate - 120,000.011 \ppraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made. 217.400.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate 1 .900.09 \ppraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have l,een made 4JW100 ■unit of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 128.375.00 ■ unit of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 11!' ' Amount of advance payment of loans daring year 33.300.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year B26.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year R.447.(S Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock dtrlng year Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ■! per cent of interest paid on matured nnd full paid stock during year Matured 7',. Full Paid Stock R»te per cent of interest charged borrowers daring year Rate ner cent of premiums charged borrowers during yenr Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during yenr </seg>
            <seg id="p018">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 18 STATEMENT of the condition of the ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President R. M. Hampton Vice-President A. D. Rogers Secretary B. F. Gilman Treasurer R. M. Hampton Attorney B. F. Gilman DIRECTORS. R. M. Hampton A. D. Rogers F. W. Harris Jerry Rowan George E. Davis John McDonald F. W. Irish James A. Hunter B. F. Gilman ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ $ 108.343.01' First mortgage loans iu process of foreclosure 7.400.00 Stock loans . 1 078 ir&gt; Furniture and fixtures . 325.00 Cash _ __ _ 1 13.0M!i') Expenses and taxes paid _ 44:146 Total $ BMB.T] LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (does and dividends) _..f 75.507.71 Full paid and matured stock _ _ 128|235.4O Reserve fund _ j.(Nio.u&gt; Due shareholders on incomplete loans _. ISvM&amp;AO 2.000.(10 18.8W.flO </seg>
            <seg id="p019">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 19 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. ItEC 1- IPTS. Balance on hand July 1. I'.'i: 1. Due* (running stock) _ 12.8R! Kull [mill stock - *i~ '■ Real estate loans Stock loans.. .. 1. v m; Interest paid _ 4-Yuti Total - * IK i EXPENDITURES Real estate hums t 3fi.illiU" Stork loans I 1. liiO.no Salaries - __ Other expenses _, _ 124.81] Withdrawals, dues Matured stock _ 4.;r&gt;.in Matured stock. Interest _ 4jii.7t Full paid stock _ 41.208.IW Full paid stock, interest _ _.. s.."&gt;4'.t I .". Cash on hand „ 15,006.1 ' Interest _ Z.4* Total * 110£7&amp;.« SUPPLEMENTAL REPOKT Plan of association _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization _ 4 .it;u.74 Number of shares in force at date of last report 1.833.51 Kier of shares issued during year.- T01.6 ng of two preceding items _ _ 7*11.6 Footing of two preceding items. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 57Jt Bber of shares matured during year ZT6iM Ins of two preceding items ::44..'t: ber of shares running stock in force nt this date 1.4UB.3 276.34 Number of shares of full paid and matured stuck in force at this date _ 701.2s Number of shares in force at this date _ 2.2&lt;ki.7S Number of shares loaned on _ 1.AM Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ _ 124 Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of does N Number of borrowing stockholders 170 Numlter of non-borrowing stockholders i including minors) 40 Number of minors holding stock in the association 9 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 0 ■her of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during ear _ _ _ It Average running time of stock matured during year 114 Monti's ■value of each share of stock _ _.! f 200.00 1 amount of dues delinquent at this date _ l.s'.n.iki Total amount of dues delinquent at this date— Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders - i.8U4.tN&gt; Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate B mount of same. No. 8 _ 10,500.00 ber and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. '• 7,400 U Amount of loans on improved real estate 1U6.343.OU Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _._ I .tl3.7lMi.iai Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate 4.17. iki Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 1 U»i cm Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _... 223.S0U.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ 3X300.00 •»™ i"i ■** it ■ ui ovv u • a i j ■«. . . ai^uuu.in' Amount of advance payment of loans during year _ 16.200.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 1R8.0U Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 4.331.63 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year IJj Kper cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during •nr _ M Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 9.96?t </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 STATEMENT of the condition of the SOUTH-EASTERN NEBRASKA BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AUBURN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Wm. B. Smith Vice-President R. M. Gillan Secretary J. M. Gillan Treasurer W. H. Hay DIRECTORS. ■H. Hay I. Gillan Wm. B. Smith J. M. Gillan E. M. Kerns R. E. Harrison ASSETS Kirst mortgage loans „ „ „..$ 164.545.00 First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure _ 3,753.45 Stork loans 765.00 Real estate „ _ ti.'JKt.iM Furniture and fixtures _ 2UK0U ('ash 1 193 4ii _ . . ... . . _ ■..«.— — • » . i ■.. j Delinquent Interest, premiums and tinea 3.741.S3 Taxes anil insurance paid _ 447 i;. 447.6.-. Real estate sold on contract - -,-7 ■_■:; Total $ 18!' LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) 4 47.206.80 Full paid and matured stock 130.000.00 130.aw.no Reserve fund [ &amp;788JM Cndirtded profits Z...~~'~.. L. oli03.93 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans "".. 377!5&lt;) Advance interest and premiums 1£M am </seg>
            <seg id="p021">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 21 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS Balance on liiinil July 1. 1913 - * U.114J3 I'ues i running stock I Full paid stock „ 38.800.(0 Interest and premiums [ 11.3 Meml&gt;ershi|i and transfer fees „ 174 rm Loan* repaid 1 26.100.WI I'm v ments on contracts _ M 4.1 at Iteiits ; _.._ &amp;4.5O other receipts s7 .m Totml $ 102.506.81 EXPENDITURES. I is $ 35.312.S0 Sa hi rie« _ ■!. \ i;l ::■ i i 'out missions _ 130.00 other ei|M-nses 1 7H3.XI Withdrawals, dues and earnings 7. ss.ii. iiTi Matured stock and earnings _ 7.mhj.ini Full piiiil stock _ 37.tWO.Oll Full paid stock, interest... _ 7,812.07 Cash on band.. 1.193. 40 Una! estate account _ 216.88 Foreclosure account _ 1.699.00 other expenditures 7li.ti:i Total KK.508.W I SUPPLEMENT AL KKl'iiHT Plan ns association L Permanent Xmnlier of shares issued since organization _ 17 Ml Number of shares in force at date of last report 4.099 Nunilier of shares issued iluriiiL' year 890 Footing of two preceding items _ -T'.is't Numlier of shares withdraw! before maturity, during year HV, .Number of shares matured daring year 7S ■ ng of two preceding items I l&gt;er of shares of running stock in force at this date l'.!&gt;2« Numlier of shares of running stock ill force at this date Numlier of shares of full paid ami matured stock in fore*' at this date 1.300 this dale Number of shares in force at this date 4 _'i'i'. Number of shares loaned on 1.7M1 Numlier of borrowing stockholders _ 171; Number of non borrowing stockholders {including miuorsi ll'.i Number of minors holding stock in the association « Number &lt;if loans made for building purposes during year 9 Numlier of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year L Plan of premium Average running time of stock matured during year Class A S4 months, (lass It 144 Months Par value of each share of stock % nai.oi Amount of Interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid :i.741.s:'. ■nber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 10 R.73O.IX1 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 'A Amount of loans on improved real estate 161.74.~i (K&gt; Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 327. Ill I. " *&gt; Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate ■ raised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have lieen made „ 7. sim.cn Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 20m00.ftl Burnt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 188.5SO.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year HMMVI Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year TtWT7 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 7JO&amp;9I Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during vear M Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year *',' v Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the AURORA BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AURORA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President B. A. Munson Vice-President W. E. Reber Secretary Jas. Schoonover Treasurer W. E. Lounsbury Attorney J. H. Grosvenor DIRECTORS. B. A. Munson W. E. Reber N. J. Ronin E. C. Rinehart H. E. Newton Jas. Schoonover Joseph Johnson J. A. Isaman W. E. Lounsbury ASSETS. Pint mortgage loans $ 108.4i»t'* Mock loans "j.lHt'.tii. Real estate _ 1.120.27 Furniture and fixtures _ 170.21 Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines 700.25 Certificates of deposit Total. $ 111 Ml M LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) .$ 87.632.10 Kpald stock 44.35001) ve fund LOMJW Iiulivided profits Tutnl f 11J ,im M </seg>
            <seg id="p023">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 23 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. ItF.CEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1. 1913 $ 55&amp;XI Duex I running stock i i:t.04::..~in Full paid stork . is.wm.nn * * """* "»■-"-•• -• - •■ ■--- • Membership, transfer and loan fees lt.:J". ■ repaid 10.673.43 Bent* . 47JBS Taxes repaid _ M.I Total * S2.42S.30 FXrHNKITinKS - ...» 16 Other expense: Withdrawal, dues _ j 024 00 Withdrawals, earnings I :::, i'l Matured stock 11.01 Matured stock, interest lv_\r,7 Full paid stock 1.1 Matured stock, interest : _ l^i'..~7 Full paid stock 13 Full paid stock, interest Cash nn hand OrtlflratM of deposit Cash paid on real estate I13.C7 Total * r,j.4jr&lt; SUPPLEMENTAL ItKl'ORT. Plan of association. Serial Number of series issued since organization ___ 23 Ninn'icr &lt;if &lt;birr&gt; issnil tiact oraranlmtlop .",.c»f, Nunitier of sliares in force at date of last report 2JMH Nunilier of shares issued daring year _ TM Footing (f two preceding items I Numlier of shares withdrawn liefore maturity, during year i Number of shares matured during year 21(i Footing of two preceding items _ .-.-I.'. 1 Number of sliares of running stock In force at this date 2.10" Numlier of shares of full paid and matured slock in force at this date 44:!'.. Nninlier of shares in force at this date - L'.rmiL, Nunil&gt;er of shares loaned on _ 1.106 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent ST1 Numlier of Rhares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dins Nninlver of borrowing stockholders 0 Number of nun borrowing stockholders {including minors* _ 141 Number of minors holding stock in the association _... 1-' Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during Average running time of stock matured during year 122 M Par Talue of each share of stock _ $ lmuii Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ rvni.nci Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders! 4413.011 A mount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 7UL2 Kber of mortgages subject to forciosure. and the aggregate mount of same. No. 10 _ 11. s Amount of loans on improved real estate _ Iff! ■ Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made l'.iT ■mitt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 12S i ■unit of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 128.700.00 Amount of advance payment of loans during year 10.1 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 305.82 Amount of reserve fund during year distributed to maturing stock 324.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year CMMB Amount of Interest paid on matured and fall paid stock during year Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... '.i r ', ■? per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year ,. _ Matured 77,. Full Paid Stock 8% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year lu#4 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President H. H. Norcross Vice- President D. G. McGaffey Secretary C. F. Gale Treasurer Louis Graff Attorneys Rinaker and Kidd DIRECTORS. H. H. Norcross T. J. Chidester A. H. Kidd A. H. Phelps A. E. Weber ASSETS. Klrxt mortgage loans 4 741.22S.0O First mortgage loans in proreM &gt; f foreclosure.. 16.550.00 Stock loans _ s.V».*H* Keal estate _ 18.231.07 building (i.iwo.oo Heal estate sold on contract _ Kuril it lire and fixtures 117 l»-liiniueiit interest, premiums :i ml tines i 44'.&gt; 13 f &gt;t her assets Total $ 9ir. LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) Jf (E.V Full paid and matured stock 241,779.011 241,775.00 Reserve fund _ Indlvided profit- _ 38.2U4.O2 Due sliareholders on inc.niplete I.., - 1.438.5(1 other llabilittc* 103.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 25 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914. RE( I- II 'TS. Balance M hand July 1. fM) Does iriiiiniiijr stock) ■ SSSi Kpaiil slock •st 222M Membership and transfer fif I. Huns repaid 41.Mfi.96 Ken I estate sales Other receipt! Total I EXI'EXDI TIRES. I KiRRlons . expense Withdrawals, dues ■drawals. earnings paid Itock 183.* Kiiii paid stock, interest Other expendini' 14.31O.W &lt;":is|i on hand Total I AL REPORT SUPPLEMENT Flan of association Permanent Numlier of shares issued since organization _ 77.093 Numlier of shares in force at date of last report _ 2&gt;&gt;.!i43'i| Number of shares issued daring year 7. 17:; Footing of two preceding items _ ::i; ii."'.._. Bher of sliares withdrawn before maturity, daring year :i.im«&gt; l&gt;er of shares matured daring yenr 334 Blier of shares canceled during year, hut not withdrawn 1.1(7(1 Inc of three preceding items 4.4"4 Number of sliares of running stock in fore-*- at this date '_1i.L H .i:!% Bher of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at his date -'.417*, Numlier of shares in force at this date "1 Tll'j Nuinlier of shares loaned on Numlier of borrowing stockholder* .... 71c Numlier of minors holding stock in the association Bl«er of loans made for building purposes diirini; year lier of loans made for payment of homestead mortgage" durii year Ill Average running time of stock matured daring year - ll.'t Month* Par value of each share of stock $ WO.tMi Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid 6,441.11 ■ulier of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, anil the aggregate amount of same. No :t4 37.O25.0U Numlier and amount of niorttfaues in process of fore&lt;l&lt;isure. No. 11 IfUi Amount of loans on improved real estate 740,iS75.flO Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loan* have Iieen made 1.658.213.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate 7(m.iio Appraised value nf unimproved real estate upon which loans have heen made 2.4WM ■unit of tire Insurance In force and assigned to tlie anaoclatloa as collateral sec-nrity Burnt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ OT&gt;1 Amount of advance payment of loans daring year 103.22S.OII Amount credited to reserve fund during year 3.116.41 .i"i"'ii» .ii.im.i !.. ■ *.-.!■ i *i iiiii. ■ .iiii in*. .. n i -i.ii". ii Amount of losses charged to reserve fund durinp year T*v* 1 1 Amount of dividends declared on running stock daring year 41'. Amount of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 14 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock du*ing year KjMT I'flll oi cue nit" nun mcNiic-ii oil l iiiiiiiii^ miicr iiiii cut; ( %tmi " . per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during ' t* "1 V 1 1 ' ' Rate per cent &gt;&gt;f arged borrower! during jrear </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President C. P. Fall Vice-President Ernst Schaekel Secretary E. F. Kimmerly Treasurer F. B. Sheldon Attorney F. B. Sheldon DIRECTORS. C. P. Fall C. A. Janssen H. E. Sackett ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 328.820.96 Plr«t mortgage loans In process of foreclosure 5. 784.8!* - loans... _ 7:&lt;o.i)u Real estate 12.473.4H Kuru it ure and fixtures „ 690.00 &lt;:i~h 58,000.28 Delinquent interest, premiums and flnea _ other assets „ _ _ Total | 4410. 3.(1. "7 LIABILITIES. Bal stock running (dues and dividends) $ 244.863.4K&gt; paid and matured stock ~ 145 14&lt;'i«&gt; ve fund LflMMW Kided proBts. 13, liabilities... </seg>
            <seg id="p027">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 27 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. I Mi on hand I running • paid stock HSt hiins &gt;ership and s repaid estate sales s repaid fees ■ racetpti Total RECEIPTS. .July 1, 11&gt;13. took I transfer fees ~ Balance on iMin.t July 1. T.n: i ruiniiliu' stuck I 31.768.10 Kpaid stuck. !8 t Premiums 1.4111.1" Membership and transfer fet Loans repaid MOW. Real estate sales Taxes repaid. Loan fees Other receipt 1 Total.. SNI.44M1 KXnCHDITCBU I "olll IlllRSlOIIS Other fxpi-n Rrawals. •lues.. . rawals. earalai mill Mock ■ paid stock. Interest mi hand Taxes paid. Other I'xpenilitnr Total. 290.448.11 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association. PenbaneBl Biter of shares Issued since organisation l&gt;er of shares in force at liate of last report her of shares issued during year IJ.l'.V.I.'.l 2.080 Footing of two preceding items. Bber of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year her of shares matured duriug year- 1.185 Footing of two preceding items Number of shares of running stock in force at this dali Numlier of shares of full paid and matured stock in for at this dale. 1.451.4 Bber of shares in force at this date her of shares loaned on Number of borrowing stockholders.... Number of eon- borrowing stockholders (Including minors) Ml Number of loans made for building purposes during year IB ■nber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year „ IT Average running time of stock matured during year. 113 Months Par \ a hie of each share of stock .....'. $ Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid L874.ll Bber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. !&gt; '.i. lcm. mi Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. So. 7 5.764.89 Amount of loans on improved real estate ■raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Biunt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 3ttT&gt;.i;.Vi.'m BHint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security Mint of advance payment of loans during year Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ _ 1.300.00 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 1.(100.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 16.W Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 7.754.67 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year v ; Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the GERMAN LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Philip Graff Vice-President J. E. Lang Secretary W. J. Mohlmann Treasurer Carl Sonderegger Attorney Jean A. Cobbey DIRECTORS. J. E. Lang Philip Graff H. Jurgens W. J. Mohlmann Carl Sonderegger ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 41,"i«uki Furniture and fixtures 4!i7 To C«sh _ ~ 17,61:134 wi.ro Delinquent Interest, premiums and flnex 2K2.44J Expenses and tuxes paid m.74 Total f •MMT.U LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) ....$ 14.n7u ..'4 Full paid and matured stuck 44. 440.00 Undivided profits 2,554 n Advance interest and premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 rCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECBII TS Balance on hand .Inly 1. 101 Dues rnnnlni; stock Full paid Itoek 13.lt Membership and transfer fee; «n m Total. , jfi ii , EXPEND1 T [•RES is Other expeaaei '.&gt;j:;.14 Wltliilr:i\v:ils. dues Knll paid stork ... 2.353 JO ll.itaum ■ paid stork, interest.. on liand Total * 6T..-..'-."l BUPPLEMEN I AL REPORT. l*l:i ii of association Permanent Number of share* issued sim-e organization Number of shares in force at date of las! report 1.113.6 Bier of shares issued during year l.."i!t."i nj: of two preceding items 1,586 Footing of two preceding items.. Number of shares withdraw! before maturity, during year. B...1 .'I .'IIIIK.1 ■III1IIIIIIKII .r,,..|. 111UI 11. llj , ...... II,* J.I.I tier of shares of running stock in force at this dale. I.'.in; Number of shares of full paiil ami matured stock in force lit this date tin Number of shares in force at this dale Number of shares loaned on.. Number of borrowing stock liolders _ 4'.i Number of non-borrowing stoikholders (Including minors association H Number of minors holding stock in th Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1 Bber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during ear ..: J4 I • in I'ar value of each share of stink Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _ lTT.mi Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Amount of loans on improved real estate „ _ 41,15(MJU Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ CK.Ofl Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 1,430 "" Ent of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as llateral security 57.030.00 lit of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association lateral security 4'.'. Amount of advance payment of loans during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 720. 83 Amount of interest paid on matured ami full paid stock daring year 154.08 72D.W Kate per cent of dividends on running stock during year I Hate per cent of interest paid on matured anil full paid stock during rear 11 ••■• Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dartag year. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 STATEMENT of the condition of the BLAIR BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BLAIR, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President E. R. Stewart Vice- President F. W. Arndt Secretary Jno. Schmaling Treasurer C. A. Schmidt DIRECTORS. Clark O'Hanlon J. E. Carver J. Mueller ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ *J7 Cash ._ 1,573.87 Total '. $ 6B.flB8.87 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends! $ 111.687.43 Reserve fund 2,44704 I'ndlviileil profits Bills payable </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE I 30, 1914. RECEIP TS Balance on hand July 1. 1913 Dues (running stock) _ I Interest Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid- .. 175.00 1O.775.9U _ $ 30.ru: a Total. EXPENDI TURES Salaries lltUKI B- expenses ilrawals. dues 4i.ru 3.&amp;.'O.50 Matured stock, interest. Full paid stock _ ltil.Oii 9,40000 1.573.S7 Bon band paid 3.000.00 Interest on notes.. 398.68 Total. s 30.T16.M Sl'PPLEMKN T AL REPORT. Plan of association - Permanent Number of shares in force at date of last report UN Bber of shares issued during year _ 310 ing of two preceding items _ LMS ber of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year \X&gt; 816 Bber of shares matured during year 79 Ing of two preceding items Jl s Footing of two preceding items... Number of shares of running stock in force at this date l i'.iT Number of shares in force at this date - 1.«'7 Number of shares loaned on_ CM Number of shares on which dues are delinquent '-".' Number &lt; f share* subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Number of borrowing stockholders K Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors 1 11- Nuinlier of minors holding stock in the association. 9 Average running time of stuck matnred ilnrimr year Ins Montbi Par value of each share of stock - $ liHUNi Total amount of dues at this date MM.NI Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders - litS.OO Amount of Interest, premiums aud fines due and unpaid 8&amp;81 Bber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. 1 _ _ 1.3M.7O Amount of loans on improved real estate 67.5ii.~&gt;.in&gt; Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ _ 148.800.00 Burnt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 83.8(1(1.00 lunt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 57.01k i.m Amount credited to reserve fund ddring year Amount of dividends declared on running stock durum' year Bper cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... S%* per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ENTERPRISE LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION CAMBRIDGE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President W. H. Faling Vice-President R. H. Rankin Secretary D. L. Tallmadge Treasurer James Kelly Attorneys Lamb and Butler DIRECTORS. J. M. Hollingsworth D. F. Neiswanger J. W. Hammond H. D. Bellamy W. H. Faling H. E. Day W. H. Faling H. E. Day C. M. Brown R. H. Rankin F. H. McCabe ASSETS First mortgage loam $ 11. S Stock loans . . . 2.ii7tUi V. vv ~" »vmu»... . — . Delinquent Interest, premiums and flues In 34 Expenses and taxes paid 188.10 Total $ 16.400.25 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running idues and dividends) 4 l-'.ltil 00 Reserve fund '-'•".-•7 f'nillvlded profits 4.MIW Advance does </seg>
            <seg id="p033">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 33 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1013 £ 746.67 Dues (running stock).- 6. 440.00 Interest mi „ , I ,, 1,365.62 Fines 53.30 Membership and transfer fees— _ 8.00 Loans repaid _ _ 5,400.00 6.00 Loans repaid.. Total $ 14,011.7» EXPENDITURES. Loans S l.Oi'i .00 Salaries 151.00 Wit hdrawals, dues _ 0,668.00 Withdrawals, earnings 1,046 67 Cash on hand - 2,121.12 Total — t 14,011.79 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial and Permanent Number of series Issued since organization ~. | 2 Number of shares issued since organization 1,068 Number of shares in force at date of last report __609 Number of shares issued during year ..._ . .„ 69 Footing of two preceding items _ 678 609 Footing of two preceding items... Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 209 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 461) Number of shares in force at this date 460 Number of shares loaned on _ 128 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 10 Number of borrowing stockholders _ 16 16 Boer of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) 41 ber of minors holding stock In the association 2 2 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 7 Par value of each share of stock .$ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ 30.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders.. 30.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 23^01 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 11,800.00 11,800.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ I 24,450.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 14,750.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security. 14.750.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 15.18 as collateral security Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durina* year 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CENTRAL CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CENTRAL CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President E. E. Ross Vice-President John Patterson, Jr. Secretary F. K. Sprague Treasurer J. W. Vieregg DIRECTORS. E. E. Ross R. Tooley F. K. Sprague John Patterson, Jr. J. W. Vieregg ASSETS. First mortgage loans * IS.; mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 3,01)0.00 Total _ _ $ 27 LIABILITIES Capital stock runniug (dues and dividends i $ 2»", Reserve fund... _ TM ..:'. Undivided profits H 1 .7 Total ..* 27.534.6. 1 . </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand .Inly 1. 1913. Hues iruuiiiiig stock) -? 5.575.(W 2,4S2.0i Interest Mije Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid MJO 9.350.00 Total ..._ 4 20.050.33 KXPEXDITIRES sas. 4 4.15O.0U ISM &lt; oniuiissious shoo Withdrawals, dv 7,514.45 2.474.25 Withdrawals, earning Cast &lt;&gt;ii band. -..7W.« Advance interest refunded 15.00 Total. _ _4 20.060.33 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association Permanent Nunil&gt;er of shares issued since organization _ 1,650 Number of shares In force at date of last report 675 Klier of shares issued during year 170 ing of two preceding items- 845 her of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 148 t&gt;er of- shares of running stock in force at this date _ W N.imber of shares In force at this date _ _ ffi'T Number of shares loaned on ~ -'-fi Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ !)0 Number of sliares subject to cancellation for non payment of du Number of borrowing stockholders _ jt; Number of Don -borrowing stockholders (Including minors) Number of minors holding stock in the association _ C Number of loans made for building purposes daring year ■tier of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during (■iir Par value (if each share of stock .$ 10tUK&gt; Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 1.624.01) Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _ 360.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 4M.T3 Kber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. 1 IS.OIIO.on Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 1... 3,000.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate ls.7."i(Miii Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 47.WMUPO Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ! M£00.00 Kint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association s collateral security _ _.... 24.200.00 Amount of advance payment of loans during year 96.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 129.78 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year I^MB_I Rate per cent of dividends declared mi running stock during vc.u </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CHAPPELL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CHAPPELL, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. (In Process of Liquidation) OFFICERS. President and Treasurer Isaac Woclf Secretary „ Guy C. Neumann DIRECTORS. Adam Stutzman A. J. Swanson Isaac C. Woolf ASSETS Real Estate _ _ $ 800.00 Cash _ 173.29 Xot*l_™~— — — . , . $ 973.29 LIABILITIES Full paid and matured stock ™$ '■65.00 Reserve fund 108.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 37 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1, 1P13 $ RLH Dues (running stock) _ - _ ■ -'" Interest - - 121JS9 Loans repaid 3.6O0.O0 Total - $ 4,329.02 EXPENDITURES. Ot h(*r t?x iM*iist*s.. — .....-_ ..._.....„....„..--........$ 1 II' ' 7"' W it In] rii wo Is duos .............. ■ ,..„.„—.....— _.. l,U»ttt.4H Matured stock - — — 2,670.&lt;m Matured interest.. „ , _ 115.50 Cash on hand - — -.— 173.2S* Total I— % 4.329.(12 SUPPLEMENT A I RE POET. Flan of association - Serial Number of series issued since organization.. 2 Number of shares issued since organization _ -"■'■• Number of shares in force at date of last report 38 Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, duurlng year 36 1 Plan of premium - Weekly nan ui (irruiiuiij — •••— — " tt»»j Average running time of stock matured during year • yt-nrs AvrraKC llliimii^ iiuik ui sh&gt;&gt; » uiaiuieu uuiiug j roi — \* j*;*»»o Tar value of each share of stock ~ $ 100.00 Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock ilur- ing year - ( &gt;'" r e per cent of interest ouart'.-'i borrowers during yen: Kate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CLAY CENTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CLAY CENTER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. r resident H*. W. Orr Vice- President John C. Ward Secretary J. L. Campbel; Treasurer J. L. Campbell DIRECTORS. George A. Allen J. W. Whitlam N. W. Johnson J. L. Campbell George S. Ward APSETS First mortgage loan* _ $ 60,070.00 (. a g h ~ ....;. 1,798.50 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines _ 3M.TJ Taxes paid on mortgaged property _ _ _ 18.70 Judgment - - 2,800.00 Total - — — •$ 64,881.92 I.IABILITIKS. Capital stock run nine nines :md dividends) _ $ 47,457.36 ..'..., ■ j_ i_ ii ■ m h i nA Kull paid and matured stock _ - 14 '25'!X indiTided pis1« ' *9,' '"' A (% T* fl W f^O /I 114^^ * «»#*■»*#»«■■■•■»•■••»■*•••——•——*——•• 1^ I »^JU Advance interest aud premiums 33.60 Total * w vsl : '- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 39 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand .Inly 1. 1913 _ $ v 1_'U4 iMies (running? stock 15.14.~i.ini Full paid stock 1,700.00 Intermit - 4.M0.M Premiums 1.224.W SI M Mrmlicrship and transfer fees - H "" Loans repaid lO.omui Sundries '-'• '• » ■■■ Total. EXPEND! IT RES L oang _ _ $ Commissions 1 14 &lt;n (ItlllT expense Wit hd raw a Is, dues „ ...— 1 .!'.'.&gt; i w i Withdrawal*, earning! I &lt; &gt;T 1 :'.'-&gt; Full paid stock. I5.800.M ■ paid stork. Interest 1.7«2.2» on hand 1.798.30 mt failed. l»t NMt'l Bank. smton _ 271 &gt;" Taxes mi iiinrt^;iL. r t'il property 18.18 Taxes on mortgaged propertj i s .7i" Tats] — • B3.7S1JB SII'I'LKMKNTAL RBPOBT. l rotal SUPPLEMENT Al. REPORT. Ptaa »! aaaoelatloii - Pmaaiiwri 1 rian &lt;&gt;f association rmanent Number of ikarea in farce at sate of lust report 1.847 Number of shares in force at date of la 1.647 4 i i-porl Number &lt;&gt;f ibare* lamed during year - 11 - nh: nf twu pit ding items IT"!' Somber of ibarei I—sis' daring jreat 112 Footing of two pn ding Itetni Nnmhef of ihare* wttMrawn before maturity, daring year S19 Number of (hare* withdrawn hefore maturity, daring year 19 Number of (bare* matured do ring year - 19 ■her "f sli.u-cs matured daring year - 19 inir of two nreredinir items Footing i&gt;f two preceding item* "■ "■*■ Number of ihare* of running stock In force at this date 1.-V 1 Number &lt;if sliarcs . f full paid and matured stuck in foree at this date - *^- Kher of iharea i r full paid and matured stork in force at his date - « this date. Nuinher of shares in force at this date 1 &lt;-' Kber of shares in force at this dat tier of shares loaned on Vmiiher of shares leaned on - aw Nninlier &lt;&gt;f shares on which dues are delinquent 1 Bl»er of sliares on which dues an ber of borrowing stockholders her of non-borrowlnj- »tockhoM&lt; llnquent M Number of borrowing stockholders J .-., Nnmher of non-borrowing utookboMem (Inrlndlng tuinors i ._ '-T {Including tninorsi \uinlier of minors holding stock in the association _ 1' ■lier of minors holding stork in the association - her of loans made (oi payment of homestead morfiriws during 1-. Number of loans Bade foi payment of homestead mortgages during year Ptaa of premium. 10 per cent of face of loan divided into .Ml equal payment* parable monthly - ge running time of stock matured during year _ il Month* B&lt;T premium, m per cent of fare of loan divided into r&gt;0 equal aynients payable monthly je running time of stork matured daring year _ 71 Month Par value of each share of slock $ .J°!i ■ value of each share of stork $ VJ"!^ 1 amount of dues delinquent at this date 464.00 KKI.I-P Total amount of dues delinquent at this dale 4 ?i 0( Amount of ilues owing by borrowing shareholders 4... '_" Amount of .lues owing by borrowing shareholders ST'2 Amount of interest, premium! and tines doe and unpaid Ut .: due and unpaid I'M Kber of mortgages subject to forecfc mount of same. No. I ure. ami the aggrejrate Amount of loans on improved rea' estati Appraised value of improved real MtBI npon which loans have 1&gt;.LT-.I». l)ceu made. Amount of loans upon unimproved real 300.00 est me. Appraised value of onimprored real tat upon which loans have been made. ■Mint of fire insurance in force and assi collateral security ned to the association as 82.950.00 assigned to the association \niounf of tornado insurance in force and TV.lV.i.i as collateral security Amount of advance payment of loans daring year 8.100.00 Kut of advance payment or loans nuriiiB year _ - ..,, , nt credited to reserve fund daring year.... — •;! »» •.•71 so Amount of losses charged to reserve fund daring year ■ SI'S Amount of dividends declared on running stock durinit year ;'-.',, Amount Of interest paid on matured and full paid stock daring year '',';: 1 7'''-' 'JV Rale per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest paid I a maturity and full paid Noes » &lt;1 M r i ii tz vi'iir </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the COLUMBUS LAND, LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President J. H. Galley Vice-President G. W. Viergutz Secretary Henry Hockenbcrger Treasurer E. H. Chambers DIRECTORS. L. F. Gottschalk E. P. Dussell T. C. Hogan C. C. Hardy Theo. Moersen ASSETS. Flr»t mortgage loans $ 398.700.00 Stock loans - - 32.000-00 C««n - 11.634.28 Delinquent Interest and fines _ 2,395.34 Total $ 444.779.te LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 855,760.29 Full paid and matured stock — 85,500.00 85,500.00 Reserve fund 3,233.86 Undivided ritft- 222.07 Vd ranee interest - 63.60 Total - % 444.779.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914 TS. It EC Eir Balance on hand July 1. 1013. Dues (running stock) * Kpaid stock - ist Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid _ Bills puyah'c Mortgage foreclosure Total. EXPEND1 TTUKS l!Mt.'.M»l.l»l (II tier expensi Bilrawals. dues ilrawals. earning: red stork 1II7.1I«MH&gt; 15.200.00 4.39S.70 Kull paid stork ■ paid stock, interest on lmii'l -age forecloaart Cills payable Interest refunded _ Insure expense Total. SUPPLEMENT AL REPORT. Permanent linn of association m Numlier of shares issued since organizati in.. Number of shares in force at date of last report. -•.'.•40 Nunber of shares issued daring year _ — 1MB j^ 1'iiiliiit' of Iwii lirececl ilii.' items .... _ .- 11 ■«.'_ footing of two preceding items Kber of shaves withdrawn before maturity, daring year T79 her of shares matured during year 1.OT1 i 11 ir of two prectdinc items — uajaj her of shares of running stock in force at this date — v • tier of shares of full paid stock In force at this date — 865 Iiap nf elinrt.a In l'prrt&gt; fll this riilte •' • *- Vi. miter of shares in icree at this date Number of shares loaned on .'. — Number of shares loanec 1 on. Number of shares oa which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of &lt;ln Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) 12 Numbers of minors holding slock in the association.. Number of onns made for building purposes during year. Kof premium, lamp sum deducted from Ician bj bidding er of loai s mad" for payment of homestead mortgages dnrii V( .;lr I tWItj* running time of stock matured during year _ sv Months Dai* rdlna t\t nnr&gt;h «(mrc e\f uti&gt;r*k ..._ f '' ■value of each share of stock - - 1 iiimimt r»f iliK's n.-liimiiei.t lit this date Total amount of dues delinquent at this dat Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders i', '.V- V! ■ut of Interest, premiums and BBC* due and unpaid er of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregat KM amount of same. No. M Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have V been made - ; Knt of loans upon m. improved real estate - _ - 8.flOO.flO ised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have __ iraiSeU VaiUf Ul UUlUllllUtru iroi Trmavt i.j-.-.i nusi . u -■■■ '- l&gt;een made : • •. ' ueeu niacie Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as 371.043.00 collateral security Knt of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association collateral security - - ,.■„,.'&gt; -lll.'.lVi.HI as coii.liciiii »c-&lt; ui ii.t ■ r 1 , ... Amount of advance payment of loans during year i ?L ■ KDI or acivanc-e |»;i^ ineiu oi i". iii^ Mining nt credited to reserve fund during year --,,, Km creuueu lo re»trr»e iciuu \iuime jra. — nt of losses charged to reserve fund during year _ .&gt;■&gt; v»- r Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year- Amount of interest paid on full paid st.ck daring rear- Bate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ■ per cent of Interest paid on full paid simk during year _ '"•'' t^oi. »ont nf interest charired borrowers during year • s i |K ' Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year.. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President : Daniel Schram Vice-President David Thomas Secretary _ J. C. Echols Treasurer G. B. Speice Attorney Louis Lightner DIRECTORS Daniel Schram David Thomas J. C. Echols G. B. Speice Louis Lightner ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 371.500.00 Stock loans.. _ _ 6.125.00 $ 371.500.00 E«&gt;al estate 5,386.70 Iflinquent interest, premiums and flues — {.CAOlM Fxpenses and taxes paid 171. 8S Total -$ 396,221.35 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) JJ 180,884.81 Full paid stock 206,S0O.(«J Reserve fund (&gt;.277.f'k&gt; Undivided profits _ - 558.00 Advance dues- - _ 1,980.40 Advance interest and premiums 12L80 Total $ 396,221.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance mi hand July 1. Ml _ $ I» ii«--*_ iruiinihLr itorkl. •"■" 1'ull paid stock .... H'T I merest - "-&gt; * I Merest Membership ninl traimfei fee*. 593.03 ■ repaiil :. ir&gt;f,. xki.i.m Voml&gt;ership and traimfei fees 5B8.fi Loans reiiald :. 159.400.tfl hoal estate mIm 1.S24J3 Rnal estate sales 1.524JS Ii.icrost on deposit* 118.13 Total &gt; :::')&gt;Tn.-ii BXPENDITUBBS. - s 174.!I2."&gt;.&lt;W «'t her expense Withdrawals, Ones 13.IH2.WI Withdrawals, earnings. I12..'t3 Matured stock ''• '■ Matured stock. Interest. 1 Full paid stock 01 Kull paid stock, interest - "'ash on li!i ml '. A jiaid IU8 .■state Pet ii rued interest 324.M Total * 3M.S75.2* SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. P!.in of association Permanent XunilMT of shares issued since organization _ •."J.'.hV Nnmlier of shares in force at date of last report _ 9.716 W Number of shares issued during year 4,"i.'i'.M._, Total of two preceding items I4.2M 4.639 « Total of two preceding items. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year '.'.'.174 Ntmiher of shares matured during year Number of shares canceled flaring year, but not withdrawn 168 ng of three preceding items Numlier of shares of running stock in force at this date 8,209 ■her of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at his date - 2.06S Number of shares in force at this date — MUS Number of shares loaned on Number of shares on which dues are delinquent. 44-' Numlver of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues— 31 Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowtag stockholders (including minorsi 713 Number of minors holding stock in the association 19 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 17 Number of loans maile for payment of homestead mortgages dur ing year ' l rage funning time of stork matured during year _ lllTi Months 01 Average funning time of stock matured during year I'ar value of each share of stock ♦ 100.00 1 otal amount of dues delinquent at this date 3.flfl0.B0 Amount of dues swtaf by borrowing shareholders _ 3.960.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 2.440.00 Kber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. 16 22.flflO.lin Amount of loans on improved real estate __ 366.. s 50.00 Appraised value of impioved real estate upon which loans have lieen made T91.025.0fI Amounts of loans upon unimproved real estate _ I.CMjH ■ raised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have J»een made 10.S75.1M Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ■Mint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 318 - as collateral security Amount of advance payment of loans during year 4.WHt.i«&gt; Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ _ LMB.M Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 15.082.11 /.mount of interest pa'd on matured and full paid stock during year 1- Itate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of Interest paid on matured and full paid stork dur- |*iiv vpflr - . -• - -— **' ' </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION CRETE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Geo. H. Hastings Vice- President F. J. Rademacher Secretary : W. S. Collett Treasurer W. S. Co'.lett Attorney Geo. H. Hastings DIRECTORS. I. H. Hastings K. Hopkins r. Shebl F. J. Rademacher Geo. W. Baldwin Ed. M. Parker F. Nedela, Jr. W. S. Collett L. H. Denison ASSETS. Ilmt morttagr loans $ 117 First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure LMMS Stock loans _ _ 6(fl80cOO ijJBM Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines _ i'-s.-to T»x sale certificates, insurance and delinquent dues 412.89 Total _ 4 127.820.13 LIABILITIES Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ $ 110.465.28 Full paid and matured stock (certificates of indebtedness) 13,700.00 I'.eaerve fund „ _ 1.616.54 'ndivided profits , 41.34 K shareholders on incomplete loans _ _ nee dues ". l.flMJV _ _ 1O6.(R&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 45 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1. 1913 Balauce on hand July 1. 1911 * 1,450.25 (running stock) 20.360.30 20.360.30 Interest _ 6.705.73 Tines _ _ _ 227.47 Membership and transfer fees 263.00 I oans repaid 1 24,975.00 ( ertifleates of indebtedness, matured stcx-k _ _ 16,450.00 Total _$ 70,431.9ft EXI'KMHTIItES. I _ _ $ 17,225.00 Salaries J 480.00 K expenses I 198.73 rawals. dues - - 36.158.00 198.73 Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings - 12.329.07 Matured stock (certificates of Indebtedness) 2,750.00 Matured stock, interest ._ 14.13 Cash on hand 1.248.99 Insurance and tax sale certificates 28.08 Total - $ 70,431.96 SIPPI.EMENTAI. REPORT Plan of association _ _... Serial Number of scries issued since organization 12 Number of shares issued since organization 6.811 Number of shares in force at date of last report 3,447 X umber of shares issued during year _ 551 Tooting of two preceding items _ MM 561 Footing of two precedin;; items. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 397 Bher of shnres matured during yenr 41S Ing of two preceding items 812 t&gt;er (if running stock in force at this date 3,186 Number of shares In force at this date _ 3.188 Number of shares loaned on _ __ 1.367 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 175 Number of borrowing stockholders 108 Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) 152 Number of minors holding stock in the association _ _ 26 Number of loans made for building purposes during year • Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during Krear — 1 use running time of stock during year _ 141 Months value of each share of stock _ — $ 100.00 1 amount of dues delinquent at this date — 249.50 1 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders 242.00 Bant of interest, premiums and fines due ami unpaid 288.40 her and amount of loans in process of foreclosure. No. 1 1,399.86 lint of loans on improved real estate _ llti.lS5.15 2S8.40 Amount of loans on improved real estate ■ raised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 220:500.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ 130,085.15 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa- tion as collateral security - 89.550.00 Amount of advance payment of loans during year _ 24.975.00 Knt credited to reserve fund during year _ 375.00 nt of dividends declared on running stock during year 6.S44.00 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 14.13 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... 5.85% Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year — t% </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the DAVID CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION DAVID CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President. Wm. Delaney Vice-President S. J. Hyatt Secretary G. A. Bryant Treasurer John Eberly Attorney R. C. Roper DIRECTORS. Wm. Delaney S. J. Hyatt G. A. Bryant John Eberly H. F. Anderson Chas. D. Ammon C. F. Clark J. B. Hookstra B. J. Sheldon ASSETS. Kirst mortcfliie loans % I (tlii tMt Furniture and fixtures- _ _ _ _ L'lvTtl Cash - — - - 18t.79 Fzpenses and taxes paid 105. SB Total.... _ _ _ $ SJBM4 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ $ 3.175.50 Kpald and matured stock „. 2.(100.00 rve fund Tided profits _ Total - $ 5,V,'.M4 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE :i(i 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand .July 1. 1913 1 $ 1.3OS.3: I»ues (running stock t _ Dividends (running ttork) 11.'..* I nterest _ _ 470.71 1 ull paid stock 1. ioo.no Loan fees, etc 106.71 Membership and transfer fees 101.31 Loans repaid _ 4.5SO.U0 Total _ $ 11 KXi'i:.vi&gt;rn i:i:s. Loans ..._ _ $ Commissions _ :.l SO Or her expenses _ _ 17TJI Withdrawals, dues S25.M Withdrawals, earnings ___ 7.M Interest on bills payable _ Full paid stock . _ _ 1 100.00 Full paid stock, interest _ 145.41 Cash on hand _ 184.710 Dividends, installment 8hares_ _ 114.75 Furniture and fixtures - - - 10.75 Total _ _ _ _ _ $ 11,022.31 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 4VJ 1 .. Number of shares in force at date of last report 3."&gt;"Mi Number of shares issued during year 117 FoiHIlg of two preceding items _ _ 474'-} Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 135"4 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 31'J B&gt;er of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this ate _ _ 20 Number of shares in force at this date SM Nunilier of shares loaned on MM Kher of borrowing stockholders _ her of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) 16 7 Number of minors holding stock iti association 10 ■her of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages dur- Dg year _ 8 Plan of premium OOc per mo. per share I'ar value of each share of stock...- _ _ $ 100.00 Amount (if loans on improved real estate _ 4,80046 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 18,000.00 ount of loans on unimproved real estate - — 200.00 18,000.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate.. ■ raised value of unimproved real estate upou which loans have been made _ _ - N&amp;M B&gt;unt of fire insurance In force and assigned to I lie association as collateral security MWjM •unt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa- tion aR collateral security i;.k»I(«i Amount of advance payment of loans during year __ 4.550.(10 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ — 100.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year S1.08 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during 61.15 ■year «i-i» ■ per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8% Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock dur - ing year — ■ - . ■ : v Z% Pate per* cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FAIRBURY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRBURY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President A. V. Pease Vice-President E. L. Simpkins Secretary E. A. Wunder Treasurer L. M. Nelson Attorney E. A. Wunder DIRECTORS. F. L. Rain A. V. Pease J. O. Evans S. H. Diller H. H. Todt E. L. Simpkins L. M. Nelson J. A. Axtell G. L. Pritchett ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ _ _ — $ 58,ll~(io Stock loans 1.215.0O Other assets _ U7.20 Total _ $ an.37i&gt;.74 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 48,120.76 Kt&gt;11 paid and matured stock 11.089.73 Reserve fund 1,200.00 Undivided profits ■ 10.2fl </seg>
            <seg id="p049">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 49 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Bit mi hand July 1, 1913 - $ ii.i'13 37 (running stock) 19 534.0! Kull p&amp;id stock _ - ~~.—.. 3,900.00 I merest „ .'. .-jrCM'.t 1 in*'-* and «1 ui's _ Membership mmI transfer fees Loans repaid _ Loan dues I Total s EXPENDITURES. Loans _ t lG.140.i«t Salaries :;i»' •»&lt; • 'mil missions _ 14T.i») Other expenses _ Withdrawals, dins ami famines _ !!&gt;."&gt; Matured stock and interest .. « 1 „ *&gt;**,** J7 Kull pa id stock : - 2,500.00 I'ull pa ill stink, interest _ 197.33 Cash on hand _ _ 8MJM Total - .$ S8.919.02 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organization Jlil Bber of shares In force at date of last report _ _ 1.3(*&gt; ber of shares issued during year _ Footing of two preceding items _ Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year 171 Number of shares of running stock in forci' at this date_ 1,322 Number of shares of fill 1 paid and matured stock at this date.... 101 Number of shares in force at this date - L4H Number of shares loaned on - _ N'uinlter of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders (Including minors i Number of minors holding stock in the association Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages dur ing year I ra«e running time of stock matured daring rear 74 Months Average running time of stni'k matured daring year Tar value of each share of stock _ $ 100.110 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ :S'.»4 .'.mi Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of ISBM. No. ."&gt; _ 5.700.00 Amount of loans mi improved real estate _ 56,112.01 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 56,112.00 .t mount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 58.760.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year .. Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid Slock during ■year ; per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock dur - ing year _ _ M Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year- ...._....... * t </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FAIRFIELD BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRFIELD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President _ C. L. Lewis Vice-President Walter Hogue Secretary F. Anawalt Treasurer T. P. Shively DIRECTORS. C. L. Lewis J. E. Saptz Walter Hogue William Hoevet William Ashby F.- Anawalt ASSETS. First mortgage loans y 51,625.00 rxpenses and taxes paid 71.48 Total 4 52.l'1." ■!-• LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 28,894.33 Full paid and matured stock 17,000.00 Reserve fund _ 1,200.00 B Tided profits " 2.236.66 payable _ i 2,840.00 •-\L'.w.«;t&gt; Other liabilities _ I 44.43 Total „ _ % 52,215.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 51 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE i 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. ce on liand July 1. 1SM3 _ _ _ $ l.iKtvW &lt; running stock) Full paid stock 5.500.00 Premiums 1 19.78 Kines 13 -1.J.7T .Membership and transfer (its _ Loans repaid _ !• (40.01 Bills payable - _ Miscellaneous _ lt&gt;7 Total I EXfENDITUBBS. Loans _ _ $ 11,450.00 ,s 332.00 Other expenses. W it lul rawals. dues ami earnings „ Matured stook '.Mno.iHi Matured stock, lntere-t... - , 171.47 Full paid stork Full paid stock, interest SA1.O5 CMk on hand _ ftlS.OU Pills payable _ _ Miscellaneous — _ Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association.... _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares in force at date of last report _ 007 Number of shares issued during year _ 209 Footing of two preceding Items 1.116 Footing of two preceding: Items Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, (hiring year 140 Number of shares matured during year _ J 36 Footing of two preceding items „ 176 ::?, Nunilier of shares of running stock in force at this date 766 ■ilier of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this date 174 Number of shares In force at this date ;&gt;4O Number of shares loaned on 530 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ 13!) Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 43 Number of borrowing stockholders _ _. 71 Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors}.. _ ~&lt;&lt;i Number of minors holding stock in the association 7 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 4 ■iiber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages dur - ing Year - _ IS ** ■ . ...... . . . * . ...... — —~- Average running time of stock matured during year _ 'JO Months Par value of each share of stock _..$ lOO.OW Total amount of dues delinquent at this date „ _ 848.60 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders S4&gt;.fi( Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ 642.73 ■iber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 7 _ 4.250.011 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 51.62.~i n" Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 10!) - BMint at fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association ■s collateral security _ ...«. 68.055.00 Mint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa- tlon »R eollalernl security _■. 6S.UV&gt;&lt;»&gt; Amount of advance payment of loans during year 9.64O.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 17540 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2.233.13 ■tunt of interest paid on matured and full paid' stock during year 1.153JU Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... if; Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock dur- ing year • I e per cent of interest charged borrowers during year '.)'', Ttate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FALLS CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President J. H. Hutching V ice-President R. R. Rule Secretary W. L. Redwood Treasurer W. A. Greenwald Attorney R. C. James DIRECTORS. P. B. Weaver J. H. Hutchings R. R. Rule W. L. Redwood W. A. Greenwald ASSETS. Pint mortgage loans _ $ 65,015.00 First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure _ 1.750.00 Stock loans _ I 2,529.00 {'ash „ lift?. 16 Delinquent Interest and fines 271.01 Total- . . S 59 8ftM7 ™ WiLU - 11 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ _..$ 49,523.26 Kpald stock B.9H U m ve fund _ 4.ss.6T. Undivided profits X 174 m K shareholders on Incomplete loans _ _ ifj!" J." nee dues ., „__„. "il.&lt;iO SI. 00 Advance Interest I 44.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 53 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914. RE( I II TS. Balance on hand July 1, 1913 Imes (running stock) -» mm 1O555.W Full paid stock.. 1.850.00 4.804.H 15.50 Membership and transfer ft 102.73 Loans repaid. Fronts on withdrawal Loan fees_ Total $ 2-Vl-J.M EXPEND! TURE8. set Loans - $ »,141.5O .&lt; CoaamlMlona &lt; Vinin issions 18.&amp;0 Other expenses .... Withdrawals, due! Other expenses Jl'i.l."&gt; Wit h'lnittiils, &lt;i lies 3.467.1M Withdrawals, earnings I'nll paid stock WithMniwals. earnings I "nil paid stock — Kull paid stock, interest Cash on hand „ 29T-M Total BUPPLEMEN T AL UKI'oltT. Plan of association _ Pern. Blier of shares issued since organization I ber of shares in force at date of last report 1,570% N'unil&gt;er of shares issued during year 426H ing of two preceding items „ l.'.Kti Kber of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year... 204 ber of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn 44 Footing of two preceding items 1M Numlier of shares of running stock in fore* at this date l.ifi.'t'j Klier of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at his date - Number of shares in torn at this date 1 743 Number of shares loaned on - rtM'._. Numlier nf shares on which dues are dellnqnenl _ JH'._. Number of iham rabjeel to cancellation fur non-payment of dues Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders (Including minorit 74 Numtier of minors holding stock In the association Number of loans made for building purposes daring year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages dnr lug year 1 - valne of each share of stock _ $ limcm 12 Par raise of each share of stork Total amount at dues delinquent at this date _ 47."'. TS Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _.. Amount of Interest and fines due and unpaid _.. Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 1 1.750.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate r&gt;4.(i5O.(f I Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 114.000.00 Amount of loans upon m. improved real estate _ Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made ■)unt of flre Insurance in, force and assigned to the association as collateral security 63,330.00 ■Hint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa - tion as collateral security _ _ 60,000.'|0 Amount of advance payment of loans during year _ 600.00 Amount credit to reserve fund during year 239.M Amount of dividends declared on running stock during jear ".M7 M Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during ■year - aw.1 e per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year .... !» :M.v Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock dnr e uer cent of interest charged borrowers during year — _ '.' tfi Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year- </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Frank Hammond Vice-President Frank Fowler Secretary Arthur Truesdell Treasurer Chas. B. Veazie Attorney Geo. L. Loomis DIRECTORS. Chas. B. Veazie Geo. L. Loomis Fred Bader Frank Hammond Frank Fowler Arthur Truesdell Jas. A. Donahue Frank Hanlon Fred H. Richards ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 168.000.0° Stock loans 1,675.00 Furniture ami fixtures ( i»h 9.900.S7 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines _ _ 844.30 other assets 1.662.5« Total $ 182.997.75 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 148.485.2? Kull paid and matured stock 29.475.00 It»»serve fund „ 3.000.00 Undivided profits I ue shareholders on incomplete loans iisn 7!i .'dvance interest and premiums A&lt;rrued interest on full paid stiwk RU </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 UFA K IPTS. l'alance on band July 1. ttll Hues (running stock) I 7.951 « Fall paid stock Interest iiffnm ;•...«;.-, Membership mid transfer ft' Loans repaid lll.l" Other receipt Total EXPENDl 1 i:i:s. fCL I Other expen Erawals. dins rawals. earnin ?d stock I Matured stock, interest :"ull paid stock ■ paid stock, interest on hand Other payment Total s SrPPLEMEXTAL KEPOUT, f'lan of association „ _ Serial and permanent S'timlMT of series issued since organization "'. Bl&gt;er of shares issued since organization _ DMT"-! her of shares In force at date of last report _ _ 1.672 Nnmlirr of shares issued since organization Blicr of shares issued during year 711% ing of two preceding items _ Footing of two preceding items Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year u."&gt;4 Ktier of shares matured during year 19 ing of two preceding items Footing of two preceding items. Number of shares of running stock in force at this date MBt Blier of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at his date _ 147% this date.. Number of shares in force at this date _ 2.000% Number of shares loaned on 861 *i Number of shares od which dues are delinquent l |f ~» Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dnei Number of borrowing stockholders IM Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) 1 Kt Number of minors holding stock in the association _ IS Numher of loans made for building purposes during year I s Number of loans made for payment on homestead mortgages dur- ing year * .11 Average running time of stock matured during year _ 119 Months Par value of each share of stock _ $ 2m».'*i n Par value of each share of stuck. Total amount of dues delinquent at this date SfiO.On Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _ Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid... .'Cumber of mortgages subect to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 1. 100.00 ount of loans on improved real estate _ - lOfc.ft » 1 1 * i Amount of loans on improved real estate.. Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 249.850.00 ■ount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 150.ono.on Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa- ■tion as collateral security &gt;unt credited to reserve fund during year 137.fiOO.no _ 500.00 .T Ill'-Ulll 1 ITIIIU II IW itOTTl It I llll'l I 1 11 1 I I 1 h- ,»C«lt •.. — • fl™-w Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 11.174 !fi Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... hate per cent interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year _■'■■■ Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7.1"'. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA STATE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President T. L. Mathews Vice-President Ross L. Hammond Secretary D. D. Rowe Treasurer J. T. May Attorney W. J. Courtrifrht DIRECTORS. T. L. Mathews J. T. May Paul Colson W. J. Courtright Wm. Fried E. R. Gurney BL. Hammond . Rowe ASSETS. Flr»t mortgage loans $ 1 .370.475.07 mortgage loans In process of foreclosure 4.961.98 Stock loans... _ 4J0O.OO Foal estate I'eltnquent Interest _ UMlSB Real estate sold on contract „ Total Ji 1.4l&lt;M..VS1.3n LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends). $ 1.023 I ull paid stock 41" 7 _. * _ ..... -- — ..— »«*... p.eaerve fund _ 22,000.10 T'ndivided profits „„ Dm shareholders on incomplete loans Interest (delinquent) Total $ 1,408.561.23 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 57 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. » RECEIPTS. I'alauce ou haud July 1, 11)13 $ 34,:t41 17 Dues ( running stock). - 245 Dues ( running stock). - -4"' I* ull paid stock 133,4&lt;IU.OU Interest 114.3Uo.^ Interest - 114.3O5.^S Incomplete loans „. - — ~— . C,873.«iO Incomplete loans ™ — — . t&gt;,873.«io lines " " «li.S5 liues til:;. S3 Memberablp Z 1,478.00 Membership 1.47S.OO Loaus repaid — liO4.U5ti.Sl Loans repaid — :.&gt;O4,u50.KJ l.eal estate sales, rents, etc — (i.OliXliS I.eal estate sales, rents, etc — (i.OliXliS foreclosure account - y,71'J.33 1-oreclosure account - 9.71U.33 Loans, fees and forfeited earnings - 3,730.37 Loans, fees and forfeited earnings - 3.73U.37 Other' receipts- - - 810.00 Other receipts- _ - Slti.OU Total - - * 8iU,Si»4.:)7 Total - * (_o,M&gt;4.:.7 EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURES. Loans _ _ * 4O1.S1XJ4 L,, a ,, 3 _ _ $ 401,818.24 Commissions - - 2.JHK.3B Commissions - - 2,y(tt.3O Otuer expenses - ~ — ,it4t&gt;.y»&gt; Withdrawals, dues and earnings - - — - MO,flH4.79 Incomplete loans — - _?'*4?-i' Matured stock and earnings — 73,0ou.7tt Foreclosure account - 13.lT1.47 Full paid stock - 7t&gt;,ouo.oo Full paid stock, interest — — •.'•-',oyo.4(&gt; Cash on hand...! .'. - 53,4:J0.(« Heal estate, repairs, etc - — — - - 1B.D34.30 Examination of abstracts _ 474.00 Kuildiug. reut, heat, light, etc - - UOLM Total - - $ 8HM*_SJ SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT I Ian of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organization..... _ __- ho.075 Number of shares in force at date of last report _ _...3o,S01 Number of shares issued during year _ — - S.tiW l'i&gt;iiTitiir of two nrecediuir items 44-oGo Footing of two preceding Items. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year V.: Number of shares matured during year - 7IS1 Footing of two preceding items 731 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 3:!.M4 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at 4.1L-7 this date.. Number of shares in force at this date '■ ?''?!! Number of shares loaned ou - 1 i 1 ii 1 , 5 Number of borrowing stockholders ■ 1..S00 Number of non-borrowing stockholders ( including minors) — 2,188 Number of loans made for building purposes during year- _ Ill Number of loans made for payment of bosmtead mortgages dur- ing year - — ~ rrnrp riiniiinir time of stock matured during year 1*0 Months Average running time of stock matured during year I'ar value of each share of stock ~ * Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _ 17,639.jiO A ui&lt; 'tint of interest due and unpaid B.286.M Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate .,. Q1^ nl amount of same. No. M ■ — «S?"12 Kber and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 6-_ 4,961.1* unt of loans on improved real estate - — 1.3t»«.4 ■..&lt;(. Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have ,__„ been made - -— — -'.8bO.M30.oO Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - -■■ iWMI*— i Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa- _-&gt;•_.— tion as collateral security - - 1 ' 4 'i &gt;- i_J'S Amount credited to reserve fund during year r.'.'JS't?. Eunt of losses charged to reserve fund during year...- J^S?S unt of dividends declared on running stock during year - HO.isl.ab unt of interest paid on matured and full stock during year 22.0BM8 Hate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year _ Rate per cent of interest paid ou matured and full paid stock dur- Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year •• </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION GRAND ISLAND, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Chas. G. Ryan Vice- President Richard Goehrinj? Secretary C. W. Brininger Treasurer S. N. Wolbach Attorney James H. Woolley DIRECTORS. R. J. Barr B. Miller . Sinke R. R. Horth C. B. Norris L. T. Geer August Kruse ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ Stock loans 7c i - neal estate 12,000.4)0 Cash _._ &lt;:.•-".&lt;■•&gt;. Delinquent Interest, premiums ami fines 1.019.33 Tax sale certificates -.'.Vt.lT --age loans settlement balances Total v LIARILITIKS Capital stock running (dues ami dlvidi-mlsi % 77" - "ve fund "JS.liKt.4Kt I ndlvided profits ■}-' l: £l Advance lateral anil premiums &lt; ertificates of indebtedness arnmnt matured shares 1"»'.&gt; Interest aicrned OB above cerrlflrati </seg>
            <seg id="p059">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 59 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914. REC1 II IS. l'alanre on hand July 1. 1U1 l»ues (running stock) &lt; IllttTfSt 4J4..~k» Membership and transfer fee: Loans repalfl r ,2«7.T0 Payments on settlement balance accounts • ■ of foreclosure Miseellaneoui .-,.."-» Total. I 417.152J* EXPENDITURES. I Salaries Other expense: Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, oertiB'eates of Indebebtedncas Matured stork. Interest, certificates of indebted nrss "ii hand K building account llaneous I.I Total 417.152.90 BSIITLEMENTAL of association l« of series issued sini-e MrganilMtlOB MFOBT. Serial and Permanent H Number of snares Issued ataee organisation Number of shares in force at dale of lasi report — 20,334 Number of shares issued dariag year - 8,881 Footing of two preceding items - Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during fear— l.iwo Number of shares matured daring year 1 IV--' Number of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn lit ■1 t&gt;f three preceding items. 4 74.". her of shares of running; stork in force at this dan' Number of shares ill force at this date 22.570 Number of shares loaned on during year -\74.t Number of shares o:i which dues arc delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of does ■her "f borrow lag stockholders ■ ; i her of non -borrowing stockholders (including minors) MM Number of minors holding stock in the association _ l-i&gt; Number of loans made for building purposes during year! -!-"&gt; Number of loans made fur payment of homestead mortgages dur ing year Average running time of stock matured during year „ 317 Weeks I'ar value of each Shan of stock _ $ 100.00 317 W Total amouiii of dues delinquent at this date - 4fl6J5 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders MC.9G Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid 1 OltJS ■nber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 amount of same. No. 1 Amount of loans on Improved real estate - "'I'" 11 " 1 ■.raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 1 71' Amount of loans upon unimproved renl estate l'.4i"&gt;.00 ■ raised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made — - ■■•■ i, 4ihm«i ■ mnt of tire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security •■•- 1.0+ 1 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa- Btion as collateral security nj}&gt; &gt;unt of advance payment of loans during year - "z^'lj &gt;unt credited to reserve fund during year SJrii 71O.82S.0V Amount of dividends declared on running stock durim; rear Bt21Ut Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during (raw </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HARTINGTON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President J. G. Beste Vice- President Geo. F. Scoville Secretary F. O. Robinson Treasurer W. S. Weston DIRECTORS. W. S. Weston Geo. I. Parker H. D. Spark J. G. Beste G. F. Scoville ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 60.y5O.UU Stock loans__ _ -'5— 5.UU Cash __ _ __ _ 523.13 l'xpenses and taxes paid „ 334.43 Total _ t 62,132.54 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 54.001.93 Reserve fund xiT.iiO Undivided profits _ 2.8WJ8 2.8M.M Advance dues 1.005.75 Pills payable _ _ 2,800.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 PCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1913 _ $ Dues (running stock) 13.4V...-&gt;ii Ralance on band July 1, 1913 I nterest -. — Membership and transfer fees lvi..v&gt; Loans repaid ~. ." 'J7-V 1 ■ i Money borrowed 7.000.01 Total. » £ EXPENDITURES. Loans _ _ _ _$ 22,100.00 Salaries _ 4m m • Other expenses _ 156 'Jt Withdrawals, dues ami earning* 564.17 Matured stock 4.6O0.O0 Cash on hand _ Bills payable and interest I dl' M Total _ $ 32,816.30 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ „ Serial Numt&gt;er of series issued since organization _ -.'I Number of shares issued since organization. Number of shares in force at date of last report 1,299 Number of shares issued during year. Bing of two preceding items .". _ ber of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year 3S Number of shares matured during year _ 4ti Footing of two preceding items _ iM Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 1..7.IJ Number of shares in force at this date _ _ 1 "&gt;'.'- Number of shares loaned on _ _ CM Number of borrowing stockholders „ Number of nonborrowing stockholders (including minors) 114 Number of minors holding stock in the association _ 18 Number of loans made for building purposes during year lit Average running time of stock matured during year Par value of each share of stock __._ $ 100.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate.- - ■raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ „ 130.000.(»t Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associa - tion as collateral security _ 10.06*0 Amount of advance payment of loans during year _ Amount credited to reserve fund during year 100.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year— 4.1XL21 Rate per cent of dividend.-, declared on running stock during year ... 10&gt;4Cr Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year V' </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HASTINGS BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HASTINGS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President H. C. Haverly Vice- President F. L. Pease Secretary J. O. Rohrer Treasurer J. O. Rohrer Attorney John Snider DIRECTORS. G. H. Pratt Ezra Langevin H. B. Cornelius Wm. M. Lowman H. C. Haverly F. L. Pease Henry Siekmann ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ $ 16S.ftfl0.0O Stock loans 1S.815.00 Furniture and fixtures 175.00 Cash itj .-»»; Expenses and taxes paid CM Total $ 180.158.U LIABILITIES Capital stock running (dues ami dividends) $ 171.14533 Reserve fund 4.884.W Undivided profits Overdraft .... ~T" 1JO£M Total * lS0.158.lft </seg>
            <seg id="p063">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 63 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on band July 1, 1913 - * Dues ( running stock) Membership and transfer fee Real estate loans repaid. - '-"-'■ 133.00 Stock loans repaid B.WJ.JiO Attorney's earnings , ! '-I r ' Total KXl'KXDITl'RKS. ,. s i.ira.«i Other expense* - — 398.81 Wit lid raw als. dues - 11,458.00 Withdrawals, earnings - - 2,068.36 Matured Stock — T.lf.'.MKl Matured stork." interest ::.r.o::. t- Cash on band! '.' .'. - 172.56 ti's. etc 150-OB DeHnqnenl tax Total BUPPLEMEXT AL REPOUT Permanent Plan nf organisation. Number of siiarrs Issued since organlsatl l.-....7rt Number of shares in force at date of last repo Number of (bare* issued during year - 1.&lt;H&gt;4 Footing &lt;&gt;f two preceding Itemi Bi ni_- of two preceding items l&gt;er of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year ."&gt;7 l&gt;er of shares matured duriiii: year.. .._ 11 Number &lt;&gt;r tbarea withdrawn before matnrlty, during year 570 Namber of iharea matured daring year.. Ill dk of two preceding items Namber of shares matured during year Footing of two preceding Items. Namber of shares of rannlng stock In force ai this date .... Number of shares of running stock In force at this dati Namber of shares in force at this dati Namber of shares in force at tliis date - !]!.''; Namber of shares loaned on ~ *_\.'.4.&gt; Number Of shares loaned on.. Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Namber of shares OB wbtch dues are ilelinqneiii "'! Number of shares subject to cancellation Namber of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues 44 or nonpayment f dm « Bin i • ■ i .-ii.ii'.-' .-uiijii i ■ • ■ ' i» '...it her of borrowing stockholders Namber of borrowing stockholders... ■l&gt;er «f non-borrowing stockholders t»er of minors holding stock In the Namber of non-borrowing atockbolden (Inolading minorsi -'■•'•' Deluding minors i -'■"•'•' Namber of minors holding (took in the association _ 1" wociatios _ ~ 12 Xumtier of loans made for building piiri Number of loans made for building purposes and payment of homo i.l mortgage* daring year and payment of home stead mortgage* during year Average running time of stock matured during year _ 1 — • Month" Average running time of stock matured Par value of each share of stock - $ JJS'21 Par value of eaefe share ni Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ litO.OO K amount of dues delinquent at tliis date _ 190.00 nt of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Anit'iint of dues owing by borrowing shareholders I-wF.fi) Ainonnt of dues owing by borrowing shar Amount of lntereat. premlnma and lines due and unpaid _ IM0.OT "4IM O Number of mortgage* labject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. N Amount of loans mi improved real estat Appraised value of improved real estate &gt;n which loans have 1 i ni made tied to the association as Amount of tire insurance in fon n si •ollateral security 1 assigned to the associaiioi Amount of tornado insurance in force at as collateral security Amount of advance payment of loans during year Knit credited to reserve fund during year..." - int of dividends declared on running stock during year li&gt;_ ltatc per cent of dividends declared on running stock durii Kate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year - for 7 ni'inth - </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HAVELOCK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HAVELOCK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Sam'l Hinkle Vice-President A. Adams Secretary V. F. Hofmann Treasurer F. B. Young Attorney F. B. Sidles DIRECTORS. C. F. Ballard Fred Kroehler Sam'l Hinkle W. F. Ackerman G. W. Anderson E. E. Anderson A. Adams V. F. Hofman F. B. Young F. B. Sidles ASSETS. First mortgage loans m , — — ( 179,400.00 Stock loans 2.1W.0O Cash _ 3S5&amp;21 I.562J1 Other assets.. 277 Mi Total.. _ „ „ .$ 1S5,37O.«J7 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) 4 117.544.40 Full paid and matured stock _ __ 64.700.00 Reserve fund- _ 1.400.00 Kided profits ~ .58 shareholders on Incomplete loans 1,722.3;; liabilities _ 2.37 Other liabilities. Total ..._» 185.370.(17 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 rCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1913- - I 1,167.30 Dues (running stock) _ 25.499.00 25.400.00 Full paid stock _ 34.2O0.flO Interest 15.414.52 Premiums _ - 2.684.11 Fines _ 59. SO Membership and transfer fees m 3$5l50 Loans repaid 14,232 44 Total _ 4 93.842.07 EXPENDITURES. Loans - $ 42.270.00 Salaries - 1,085.00 Commissions 310.00 Other expenses 612.71 Withdrawals, dues _ _ 8.010.00 Withdrawals, earnings ~ - 2,518.35 Matured stock- - 5.200.00 Full paid stock 25.500.00 Full paid stock, interest _ 3.908.00 Cash on hand - 3,552.21 Other expenditure - 676.40 Total _ _ X 93,642.07 SUPPLEMENTAL KEI'ORT. Plan of association „ _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 3.004 Number of shares in force at date of last report _ 2.460 Number of shares issued during year 350 Footing of two preceding items ISM 350 Bber of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring yenr 220 her of shares matured during year 26 Footing of two preceding items 246 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date _ .2,241 ■her of shares of full paid matured stock in force at this ate _ 323 Number of shares in force at this date _ Number of shares loaned on Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ 38 Number of borrowing stockholder* 104 Number of non borrowing stockholders {including minors) XnmlKT of minors holding stock in the association 32 Number of jonns made for building purposes during year Bber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during ear 14 Average running time of stock matured during year _ US month* Par value of each share of stock _ A 200.00 L-OO.no Total amount of dues delinquent sit tins date _ 2S5.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders.... _ 2S5.00 Amount of interest, premiums and rims due nnd unpaid _ IV" IS Amount of loans on improved ml estate _ 17!i. 4110.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which leans have been made 269.500.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 100.700.00 ■mat of tornado insurance in force and assigned to tiie association ns collateral security 100.700.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ."!'.&gt;. 4*&gt; Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year - 110.40 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during vear _ r,- r Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 10% </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HOOPER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President B. Monnich Vice- President Jno. F. Heine Secretary Geo. W. Heine Treasurer Jacob Sanders Attorney Wm. Meyer DIRECTORS. A. M. Tillman Joe Stipsky Jacoh Kusch H. J. Vlasak Henry Schemmel ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 12.50O.0O Blture and fixtures 4.~&gt;.tKi _ fHHM Other assets Total $ 13.596.u2 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends! $ 12.908.76 Reserve fund MMI Total 4 13.596.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1914. KKl EIF TS. Dues (running stock. - » ■bership and transfer fan is repaid 21.50 2.80O.O0 K payable, nts 800.00 Total * I' syi i h , i:xri:.\i)i rriiKs * ■ expense* 2CM Irawals. dues and earnings _ 2,324 98 2C.M mi hand _ 978.82 Kills payable Overdraft pay aide 2,15(1.00 raft . - '-'■ Total - » 0.W.0O 8UPPLEMEN T AL REI'HKT Plan or association Permanent Number of gbares issued since organiutl Number of shares in force at date of hist report _ I'M Bber of shares issued during year _ _ 43 Ing of two precedinp items _._ j:~f Bher of shares withdnr n before maturity during year 10 her of shares of running stock in force at this date. 1'»3 M Number of shares in force at this date. Number of shnres loaned on. Xumtier of borrowing stockholder 12 Nnmiier of noa- borrowing itockboldera 'hiding minors i in Number of mlnort holding stock in tin- iat ion Number of loans made for building purr luriiit? year 2 ! tz Z-i mm Par value of each share of stock Amount of loans on improved re:il estate 12.500.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have l&gt;een made _ ■_'■" AmiMint of fire insurance in force and assigned to the asaociation as collateral security 12.650.00 collateral security Am.. unt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 12.ft3O.0U Amount of advance payment of loans daring year. 2.000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund dnriag year Amount of dividends declared on running stock daring year Rate per cent of dividend declared on running stock iluriiiL r year . v Rate Der cent of interest charired borrowers durinir ve*tr </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HUMBOLDT BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION HUMBOLDT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President L. S. Hackett Vice-President Otto Kotouc Secretary H. E. Boyd Treasurer Irvin Shirley DIRECTORS. H. E. Boyd L. S. Hackett J. B. Davis B. Stramer E. S. Cope Otto Kotouc 0. L. Bantz Irvin Shirley N. C. Campbell ASSETS. First mortgage loans Stock loans _ S Real estate... 1.500.0U Total.. LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 43.08lt.TO ,41 Matured stock.. 13.250.00 Reserve fund. ""' \ "■ 4MAB Bills payable. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 69 BCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1. 1913 _ 4 Dues (running stock)... _ _ _ 18,109.78 Interest 4 r.l:;.»i*i Membership and t ransfer fees_ _ _ Loans reDaid~ 16 ! Rents _~~_ _ ;t;ini Forfeited earnings . 107 it" Bills payable ' 2.:«KU«&gt; Total - - - $ *&gt; EXPENDITURES Loans _ $ ]9.~ Other expenses. Withdrawals, dues '.'.si vj: Matured stock i Matured stock, interest. Cash on hand 223. 1 * Total _ $ 40.01H.SI SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of Association - Number of series issued since organization 10 Number of shares issued since urbanization Bber of shares in force at date of last report „ _ UBtS her of shares Issued during year _ 4.Y7 Footing of two preceding items... _ IM Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year Number of share smatnred during; year. Nanber of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn 17 Binn of three prewlinir items..' _ _ her of shares of running stock in force at this date 1.4a' 1 Kber of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this ate »i Number of shares in force at this date _ 1 v.iv.. Nuiut&gt;er of shares loaned on. Number of shares on wMeh ilues are delinquent 1.18 Number of borrowing stockholders _ si Number of non-borrowing stockholders (Including; minor* I -"• Number of minors holding stock in the association SI Number of loans made for building purposes (luring year.. ■aber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year in Average running time of stock matured during year 30f. ■ Par value of each share of stock $ Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders- _ 1.715.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid...- _ Amount of loans on improved real estate _ &gt;l.~&gt;.&lt;)0 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ i&lt;rs.t Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate 1.005.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ ■Hint of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 500.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the asso,i:i atlon as collateral security _ 41 ■■ Amount credited to reserve fund during year ioi.imi Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock taring year Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ■6 per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during J-ear Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durii _ </seg>
            <seg id="p070">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 70 STATEMENT of the condition of the KEARNEY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION KEARNEY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President S. A. D. Henline Vice-President John N. Dryden Secretary Willard F. Bailey Treasurer Willard F. Bailey Attorney John N. Dryden DIRECTORS. S. A. D. Henline John N. Dryden Willard F. Bailey John W. Patterson N. P. McDonald Gilbert E. Haase J. E. Plank ASSETS. Kirst mortgage loans $ 2S.33O.Ori Cash LSMJB Total. 4 Mi ill ( 'K&gt; LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends i f Kpaid stock ve fund iL'.t7r»..K) Indivlded profits MLM Due shareholders on incomplete loans Loan fee surplus </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS. ■ (running stork i paid stock Loans repaid Loan fee surplus Total EXPEND! TIUKS Withdrawals, dues. Withdrawals, earnings Full paid stork. ■ paid stock, interest on hand _ Overdraft July 1, 1913. Total li&gt;; BUPPLEMEN AL REI'OltT T I 'Ian of association _ Perm.ii t KIht of shares Issued since organization her of shares in {over at date of last report 77:'.';.. tier nf shares issued during year .. *J47 :l i inn of two preceding items I l.flBtU Footing of two preceding Items Nnmber of slums withdrawn before maturity during vear Number of shares of running stoek in force at this date....._ ■her of shares of full paid ami matured stock in force at this _ 124% ber of shares in font- at this ilate !i71' t Number of shares loatieil on. Biier cif shares em which lines are delinquent _ tier of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Number of borrowing stuck holders _ Nnmber of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors;. •..7 Number of minors holding stock in this association .'. 6 Number of loans made for balldlng purposes during year Number of loans made for payment of homestead niortgages during year ;T_ " 5 Par value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at this date .iMKi.im Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders. Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid. ■nber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1' 2.400.1") Amount of loans on improved real estate 25.3Do!uil .*&gt;■.•.. iih .'■ ■vhih ..11 iuijmimco real esiaie _.»..». Appraised value of improved real estate noon which loans have been made _ 4; Amount of fire Insurance in fonv and assigned to the association ■as collateral security H ,000.00 ■ nut of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount credited to reserve fund daring year Amount of dividends declared on running stock daring year Amount of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock luring year Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock faring year ll';_"; year .*' •" Rate pat cent of interest charged borrowers during year _ </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LAUREL, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President J. B. Felber Vice-President C. F. Furley Secretary Guy Wilson Treasurer Guy Wilson Attorney F. P. Voter DIRECTORS. W. T. Graham C. E. Nevin J. B. Felber C. F. Furley C. C. Sackttt F. P. Voter Guy Wilson ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ - 1 - l&gt;eiinquent interest, premiums and flues i::T "ii K\l&gt;enses and taxes paid - Interest paid f.4.J-". Total * HW.11 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running idues ami (livicleinlsi $ 23.407.53 Reserve fund fndivided profit* 051.71 Advance dues TtJtU </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages daring I By(ijl p _ i of premium — Semi annual Average running time of stock matured during year _ !'T u Par value of each share of slock _ I Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of ilues owing by borrowing shareholder! Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid IXtM Niiinlier of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security : Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount credited to reserve fund daring year _ Amount of dividends declared on running &lt;iock during year Hate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dnrinir year mi-annual) -— -••• ■■- ; Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during Kyoar - p percent of Interest charged borrowers during fear &lt;'&lt; ■ per cent of premiums charued charged borrowers during year *Vi% 1 UECEin *. Pe on liand July 1. MS (running stock &gt; •rsliip nnil transfer fees repaiil navable - 1 • Total 14&gt;. KXI'KNI'ITIIiKS. (^ ~ expenses _ rnwals. dues... _ rawala, earnings- »d st ock. 1 DB hand payable ■u on liills payable -1 Total s UJgtCM sriTI.KMKNTAI. REPORT. I'lan of association ! Number of series issued since organisation _ Number of slinros issued sin&lt; - c or^nuiziitiou Manber of slmres in force at date of last report Nnmber of ibarM issued daring year _ Footing of two preceding items NiunNer of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year Number of shares matured daring year Footing of two prradtag items Numlier of shares of raaaing Stock in force at this date Nuinl&gt;er of shares in (area at this date Number of shares loaned on Namber of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders linrludlng minor*) Number of minors holding stock in the association ;;;;;;■ ■£ aM m </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA CENTRAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Homer K. Burket Vice- President John Gibson Secretary M. W. Folsom Treasurer T. N. Burket Manager of Agencies E. P. Leonard Auditor J. A. Piper DIRECTORS. T. N. Burket M. W. Folsom John Gibson H. K. Burket E. P. Leonard ASSETS. First ■Wt«f Inn us $ 2,541.-7'' tZ First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure _ ill . f building, furiture and fixtures 17i"il s&lt;i Cash 153.07V .V. .... . 153.07^ 56 roeiviible KI0 00 estate 53.16ft&gt;&gt;r. •'state sold mirier contract „ _ 45.282.46 Total $ 2.888.7MI. LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ _ 4 1,813.043.07 Full paid and matured stock - _ _ 806^15.79 808.515.79 Ueserve fund _ T8JXH.01 Tndivided profits _ K.28H 7" Total 4 2.88S.79&amp;5' </seg>
            <seg id="p075">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 75 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance M hand July 1. l!&gt;i:s $ N;.M^:,! (running stock) iwi Kill I | ill id si ock _ ill 4.' I" I ntf»rpst ■' l c ' Membership and transfer fees _ reps i*l Real estate estate Bold under contract _ _ ve fund I" '■" ■' "I Total it EXPEND! rritE !&gt;i2.74f Commissions Other expen Withdrawals, due Withdrawals, ciiiiiiiiirs an*d dividends en Real estate litt'il ■estate sold.. paid stock— 4.736.10 10C.441.40 ■ l&gt;:i ifl stork. Interest i&gt;h ottice liuildiliL' nil llllllll Oflec furiiltnr Reserve fund.. Total BVPPLEMEXT AL KEPORT Plas of association - I 1 '-'" Number of shares issued since organisation Number of shares in force at date of last report BS.."W6 Nnmlier of shares issued daring year - 31.812 l.-.,..ti,,.r ,,r t.vn !,i line ii,.ins _ '-Ml footing of two preceding Item Niiniher of shares withdrawn before maturity during year 1 :•..'.&gt;:;•; Number of shares matured daring year _ 1.10(1 Number of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn 432 Footing of three preceding Item* pr of shares of running stock in force at this date 8B.1M." Ker of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this I,. _ 8.HS3 Number of shares in force at tins date 74.930 Number of shares Number of borrowing stockholder Number of non-borrowing stockholders (Including minors) 4..VH Numlier of minors holding stock in the association... "■" Nunilier of loans made for building purposes during year I'M Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages dnrin .\ ea i 1 Average running time of stock matured during year _ 114 months ralue of each share of stock - I Im.m Kyalue ot eacn snare or siock - - ,,...-_• unt of interest and tines due and unpaid _ lS.214.!n her of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate Amount of interest and tines due and unpaid Mire, and tlie aggregate amount of same. No. 11 Number and amount of mortgages In pri of foreclosure. No. 4."i 61 .•.'."V0&lt;*1 VJl.lTTME Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real PStal upon which loans ha\e lieen made force anil assigned to tin Amount of lire and tornado insurance in association as collateral security 4.612 Amount credited to reserve fund daring year - vnioiitit of losses charred to reserve fund during year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 114 - Amount »f interest paid on matured and full paid stock during vea r Rate p«'' eent of dividends declared -unning stock duriug year Hale ]!!■&lt;■ cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during ve:&gt; r </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the AMERICAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President E. W. Brown Secretary E. F. Snavely Treasurer E. F. Snavely Atorneys Burkett, Wilson &amp; Brown DIRECTORS. C. J. Olson L. C. Oberlies W. A. Selleck E. W. Brown E. F. Snavely K. C. Leonard John T. Dorgan J. H. McClay ASSETS. First mortgage louns _..$ 127. 47.".* " • Stock loans.. 179. a M) Heal estate _ _ liM.l'.t Furniture and fixtures.- ~ - fash - _ — 1N.&lt; Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines -.. 9MJ3 Total -..$ i4&lt;;.-".r. ."••; LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ Full paiil and matured stork luti 7 Reserve fund _ rmlivided profits _ _. 2,718.11 Dae shareholders on incomplete loans 7,276.52 (^■neral fund Iikmki Total $ 1M^«BlM </seg>
            <seg id="p077">77 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914. BECF II 1 TS. Itiiliim e on hand July 1. l'.iK Dues (running stock) Kpiiid itoek m Membership and transfer fei Loans repaid 9.401.« K estate sales llaneoas Hi.:'- 3H.7U Total nPENDITDSU Sa liirie Other ex pen PX 1 1**11 St'S Withdrawals, doai hiLwiils. dues Vlrawals. earning paid itock. lni wjils, t*u filings ji;i id sio«k 43.720.00 -•.4S0.2.-. ■paid stock. Interest on hand pftld stork, iiitcn-si _. (Hi htiiid t'Stilt t' InjltlS Furniture and fixture: Total I 192.397 JM SI PPLEMEN r AL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Numlier of shares Issued since organizati 3ii J 1 1 .T'.Ht Number of shares in force nt date of la it report — 906.50 Numlier of sliarcs issued daring year S.457.65 Footing of two preceding items Numlier of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 1.238.85 Bber of shares matured daring year 44 Ing of two preceding items — — Numlier of shares of running stock in force at Tills date 'JKH Bber of snares of full paid and matured stock in force t this date - li*V7 Number of shares in force at this date ::. 171.3 Number of shares loaned on 1,257 Numlier of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholder! (including minorsi 14". Number of minors holding stuck in the aaaociation— Numlier of loans made for bntldlng purpose* diiriiiL' year Klier of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during eat - -l rear ■value of each share of stock _ $ limim nut of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid _ MM ■her of mortgage! rabjeet to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. 1 - ,mi&lt;»i Am. Mint of loans OB improved real estate _ 121,175.00 Kised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been ade 299.490.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made L'l ' Knit of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association s collateral security 1 til. 750.00 Knt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association collateral security 100.250.00 Amount of advance payment of loans during year 9,401.49 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 288.M Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 493.46 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year. Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during M r _ _ 11.675 W Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dprlng year t\ n ' c ■i- per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year iV, Rnte per era! Of in'erest charged borrowers dnrin;.' fW. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SECURITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President L. C. Oberlies Vice-President J. T. Dorgan Secretary E. F. Snavely Treasurer E. F. Snavely Attorney E. W. Brown DIRECTORS. J. H. McClay B Oberlies Dorgan E. W. Brown W. A. Selleck ASSETS. ■ortgmfa loans Jt 423.!iNfl "•" mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 1.4&lt;io.iio siiH-k loam - - l'OB.oo , -si a if _ _. Delinquent interest, premiums and tines 12. v - Other assets Office lease 1.375m Ml Total _ _ _ $ 515.11 '■ 38 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _..$ 274.365.1S Kpaid and matured stock 224.380.00' •ve fund li ■-•iiii u.", 224.380.00 Ueneral fund I'ndivlded proflts._ </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914. RECEIPTS. Balauee on hand .Inly 1. 1!&gt;13 J! 7&gt;:i.nri.:u Dues (running stock] 82,498.97 Dues (running stock]' 82,498.87 Full paid stock 10.225*00 Full paid Htock 10 - Stock loans 705.66 Stock loans 705.66 Miscellaneous 771.37 Miscellaneous 773.:!7 Keal estate fiftl.Oti Keal estate fiOO.Oti Total - $ 254.54^.fil Total _ $ -54.54:!.fil KXI-ENDITrHES. EXl-EXDITfllKS &lt; »t her expenses _ 6.070.82 other expenses 1 6.070.82 Wit lnlniwals, d ues „ 63,'t7iK~&gt;J Withdrawals, earnings „ WJM Full paid stock T7.131.41 Knll paid stock, interest - 16.7M».40 Cash on hand _ 51,393.18 Total $ 254.542.&lt;il SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Permanent Namber of sliares issued since organlaatloa _ 33.222.47 Nuiulier of shares in force at date of last report 17.075.65 Xumlier of sliares issued daring year 47* Footing of two preceding item ■ Bg of two preceding; items 17.553.65 Imt of shares withdrawn jiefore maturity, during year 5.527.35 :&lt; ■tier of shares matured during year. 153 in*r of two preceding; items 153 Number of shares of running (took in force at this dnte 9,629. ■her of shares of full paid anil matured stock in force at his Sate_ 2.24:1.8 Number of shares in force at this dale U.873JI Namber of shares loaned on ~. 4,800.8 Namber of borrowing stockholder* 41 1 Namber of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) Namber of minor* holding stock in the association SI Namber of loans made for building purposes during year Average running time of stock matured during year 4 years Par value uf each share of stock _$ iiXMIO Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 12.827.00 Bber c.f mortgages subject to foreclosure, anil the aggregate mount of same. No. 101 112,475.00 Namber and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 1 1.4om»&gt; Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 4l'" ■ Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made „ „ „ S19.065.0li Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate ■ raised value of unimproved real eslate upon which loans have been made l.'MUm.oO ■Hint of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as col lateral security _ _ 52o.tHIO.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force anil assigned to the association as collateral security 248.675.00 I moil n I "f advance payment of loans during year i!7.(1nJ.(K&gt; Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1,646.93 Amount of losses charged to reserve fulid during year 61&amp;12 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 20.7S7.29 L-O.7S7.29 Amount of interest paid on matured anil full paid slock during year l.~i 7:'.4.27 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year s Bate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ _ 6% .' ' "• ~ — WTO Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year !&gt;% </seg>
            <seg id="p080">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 80 STATEMENT of the condition of the LINCOLN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President E. W. Brown Vice-President H. H. Wilson Secretary E. F. Snavely Treasurer Frank Parks Attorneys Burkett, Wilson &amp; Brown Manager of Agencies K. C. Leonard DIRECTORS. E. F. Snavely K. C. Leonard Frank Parks K. Wilson . Brown Charles Olson E. C. Hurd ASSETS. First mortgage loans _.$ 4!i.; First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 1.700.00 Stock loans T l.tnS.'M Real estate _ „ 17,740.66 Furniture and fixtures !M*.V Cash ~ "&gt;.16o!n6 Expenses and taxes paid „ _ 717!ob Real estate sold on contract 1 2 325 00 Certificates of deposit 3.00ftflO 3.ou&gt;.m Total $ 526.900.38 LIABILITIES. ■tal stock running (dues and dividends) „ $ 170.975.71 paid and matured stock 314.425.00 vlded profits ~ 30 OR'.' 37 rve fund 4 465^83 4.465.83 Due shareholders on incomplete loans L 7!(&gt;01.47 Total $ f&gt;2G,9O0.3S </seg>
            <seg id="p081">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 81 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS. Halance M bud July 1. tMI _ $ 17.801.02 I Hies i riinriiiii; stock I _ M.4!»:: .1 M.v.i::' .1 Full paid stork _ 145,740 Interest S7.47S..TII Fines _ 43.10 Membership Mini transfer fees „ „ I.(t^l..*i4i Loans repaid _ Heal estate sales •.*»&lt;.&lt;»• other siiurees Stock loans _ j.i nT on Furu It lire and fixtures _ ."•! .36 Total - t :s77.iK&gt;n.i4 KXI'KMim ItKS. I.oaiiK 1 $ 17n.173.flU Commissions „ 1 (27.81 Other expenses ?».i^:' It". Wit hil raw:) Is. dues 4'.t .^'."^ ~, i Withilrawals. rarnin;. _ 2.917 12 Matured stock _ Matnred stork, interest 4iinm Full paid stock _ SS.i Kull paid stork, interest „ !."» 7 on liainl _ Abstracts _ 1 irii; :i- Stock loans Furniture anil fixtures Certificates of deposit _ _ 3.000.00 Real estate 20.152.2i Total _ * 377.005.14 SUPPLEMENTAL KEI'olt Plan of associat ion _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation - 29.2V2.44 XuiiiIht of shares in force at date of lust report 15.17! Number of shares issued during year 5,18 Footing of two preceding items 20. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year Ixn; Number of shares matured during year. Footing of two peceding items L8H Number of shares of running stock in force at this date _.!.". :imi Kber of shares of full paid and matured stock in force t Iliia rtnto t Ml •&gt;-, nt this date _. 3.144. Number of shares in force at this date 18,524 Number of shares loaned on 4.!»7O Number of borrowing stockliolders 414 Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minorai. 1,073 Number of minors holding stock in the assn. i.ition 24 Par value of each share of stock... i t I00.0U Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, anil the tggngate B mount of same. No. 13 5.279 12 ber and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure. No. 1 amount of same. No. 13.. Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made n26.Kl.~i m Amount of loans upon unimproved real estati Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 27.iam.fW ■■nut of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ Amount of tornado insurance in force nnd assigned to the association ■as collateral security _ &gt;unt of advance payment of loans during year _ W.!H Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ Amount of losses charged to reserve fund dnrtag year 4vJ 7'. Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 11.355.99 Amount of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 15.7 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during V &amp; A I* ft '~* Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring &gt;• ■ 8an&lt;!!&gt;-. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 82 STATEMENT of the condition of the UNION LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President A. W. Miller Acting Vice-President L. J. Dunn Secretary Loyd A. Winship Treasurer L. J. Dunn Attorney Loyd A. Winship DIRECTORS. A. W. Miller J. M. Stewart L. J. Dunn L. A. Winship ■ mortgage loans ASSETS, $ 44:t.7"&gt;().iKi First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure „ 2.900.00 Stock loans * 3. 31*7. 50 Real estate _ Furniture and fixtures _ 1.506.ft6 Interest and flues due and unpaid 3,447.70 Expenses and taxes paid . &amp;.M4 7« Other assets _ _ 1.265.S5 1.265.SS Certificates of deposit 13.412.70 Real estate sold _ 2,flSO!0O Salaries .... 3.5GO.OO Total _.._ $ 497,803.95 LIABILITIES. Capital stock miming (dues and dividends) _ $ MB.tt9.M Full paid and matured stock _ 2ft6.225.&lt;«&gt; Reserve fund _ _ 1 4.470^00 !'nd hided profits _ [ 8.914.1)1 Dm shareholders on incomplete loans 8MM4.M Total $ 497.W3.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 Balance oa band .Inly 1. tM3 l&gt;ues irnnolng stock i ■paid stock K loans repaid repaid ■ stair suit I Vrt iticales of licpi sii l\i\ ■ iTtitir.iiis. iiisiirniKf and tiiM's ;nlv B receivable expenses. Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earning PaM ti|i stoik iiitrri's Insurance ami ta\rs ndTanced Certificate* * f deposit ■ on liaml ii I &gt; stock estate. Tax certificates. Furniture and fixture: Plan of association Iber of slmros issued since organizatioi bat of shares in force at date of last be! of shares issued during yrar ins: of two preceding Items ber of shares withdrawn before matin ber of sharrs of running sto&lt;*k in for 11.BR4. report IT it y. daring Tear. at tins date 10.S04.T Number of shares of full paid and matured stork in for Bt this date 2.962.25 her of shares in force at this date _ _ 13.7C7 M2 Number of shares loaned on Number of borrowing stockholder" Numtier of non-borrowing stockholders lincludinu niinorsi. 1.301 BbCf of minors hnldiiiK stock in the association _ „... 22 bat of loans made for building: purposes during year ■ Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages durin rear .1 **:i r Par value of each share of stock 100.(10 Amount of interest, premiums and tines dnt and unpaid.. Bbcr of mortgages subject to fored mount of same. No. 13 ure. and the SKKregatt iss .if foreclosure. So. 2 2.000.00 Number and ainount of mortgagca in pro. Amount of loans on improved real estate 430,223.00 Appraised value of improved real estate been made upon which loans have Amount of loans upon unimproved real I state '• 7J.".'» i Appraised value of unimproved real estat been made upon which loans have ■ ■nut of fire insurance in force and I as collateral security idied to the association ■Hint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 12.' Amount of advance pay nt of loans during year _ 163.300.011 Knt credited to reserve fund taring year _ 1.37O.1!t nt of dividends declared on running stock during year I,MH Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during vcji r IT ■"'^1 ." " ' — — - Rate per cent of dividend declared on running stock during year ■I per east of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during yea r ft' i Rate per eenr;VfTniere«rcharg^'horrowers during ZUZZ :&gt;", </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FIDELITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President W. A. Forsyth Vice-President W. E. Sharp Secretary W. J. Hill Treasurer H. B. Treat Attorney E. J. Hainer DIRECTORS. I A. Forsyth E. Sharp J. Hill H. B. Treat E. J. Hainer A. R. Talbot C. E. Spangler C. E. Bardwell A. O. Faulkner ASSETS. First mortgage loans - $ NIO.660.00 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 1,500.00 Real estate _ 3,060.80 Furniture and fixtures _ ffislfio Cash 1.J4O.T9 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines _ Expenses and taxes paid HLM Other assets - Total _ _ _ $ lou.iu &gt;..*•_• LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ OR Full paid and matured stock 41.800.00 4i.80o.un Reserve fund 4.".4.i!ii Tndivided profits 2,982.46 i&gt;ue shareholders on incomplete loans LMUI Total J 108,018.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 85 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. I M nil hand July 1. l'.illi RECEIPTS. $ 7,270.40 REC Balance on hand July 1. 101 i mining stock) ( running stock)" 22.15S.U3 Full paid stock Interest paid stock ] 3 800 00 13.800.00 «t 7,115.110 ,115.«8 Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid .crship and transfer fees 103.00 108.01 i repaid 9 178 '_".' ::s7..-,.i ;:s7 ..-,i&gt; Sundry ttOM ■y items _ 890.22 890.22 r«tml - * «o.;mi&gt;4^ Totml 60.908.42 kxpenditcuks EXPENDITURES. .. $ 23 ' 'oinuiissioiis „ 63.50 lissions „.„ 63.50 &lt; &gt;t her expenses .. tipCBMf - - Wit lit 1 rji wals. &lt;1 ins XZ,'*"*--' '~ 1 ril wills. d lies lli.'.'T-. 1 '7 Withdra wa Is. earnings -- 407.^8 lmwals famines . — 407.^8 Full paid stock 15.500.00 paid stork 15.500.00 Full paid stock, interest _ 2.K44.H paid stock, interest _ 2.K44.H ( 'ash ,.ii hand _ 1,340.79 Caah on hand _ 1,340.79 Fixtures .W&lt;'&gt;.*t Fixtures Sundry items - 352.!&gt;4 Sundry items - 8B&amp;M Total - $ CftMS.4Z 80.908.42 Total. SfPPI.EMKNTAL REPORT. BUPPLEMEN T AL REPORT. Plan of association _- - Permanent IMmii of association _ - Permanent Number of shares issued since srganlBBlkn _ 6.062 Number of •bare* issued itnce organisation _ 6,062 NuiiilXT if shares in force at date of last report 3.047 Somber of shares in force at date of last report _ 3.04' Nunilier of shares issued daring year 1.13H4 Number &lt;&gt;f shares issued daring year l.i::i'.j Footing of two preceding items „.. 4.178H Bin^r of two preceding items „.. 4.17SH lier nf shares withdrawn before maturity, during year.- Htfl Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, dnrlng year.- M(4| Nunilier of sliares of raaning slock in force at this date _ :i,251 Numlier of sharps of running stock in force at this date _ :i,2"&gt;l .XninlxT of sliares of full paid and matured stock in force at t his date _ 418 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at t his date _ 41S Number of shares in force at this date _ _ MM Number cif shares in force lit this date MM Numlier of shares loaned on _ 1 108 Number of sliares loaned on _ Number of shares on which dues arc delinquent 275 Blier of shares on which dues are delinquent 275 tier of borrowing stockholders Number of borrowing stockholders M Number of borrowing stockholders Number of noo-borrowlng stockholders (including minors i._ 173 Nnmlier of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors I... 173 Number of minors holding stock in the association ,.._ 17 Numlier of minors holding stock in the association , 17 Number of loans made for buildinj.' purposes daring year _ 12 Numlier of loans made for building purposes daring year _ 12 Numlier of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year - Par value of each share of stock _ 9 HHuU Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ 751.W Knt of dues owing I iy borrowing shareholders 1 731.00 nt of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid _ IT::: Kl&gt;er of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. "i _ &amp;3.000.(K) amount of same. No. Numlier and amount of mortgage* in process of foreclosure. No. 1 1,500.00 Amount of loans en improved real estate _ 1&lt;h ■ ■ Kiised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been 17'. Kint of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association s collateral security MB I Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association Es collateral security 4t; mt of advance Barmen I of loans daring year _ _ B.1UL29 int credited to reserve fund durine year lWi.llo •&amp;3UMM Knt of dividends declared on ruuning stock during year 3,277.13 nt of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 2,829.1(4 - B2S '4 Rate per eent of dividends declared on rnnnlng stock during year , Rate per cent of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the GERMAN BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Wm. Seelenfreund Vice-President Henry H. Barth Secretary ~I""...~~....'.'..~. " "~'"'""ZZ7!J F. B. Sidles Treasurer Fred Whittemore Attorney F. B. Sidles DIRECTORS. F. B. Sidles Fred Whitemore Wm. Seelenfreund Henry H. Barth Frank E. Gillen ASSKTS. l'ir-ii iMrtHil lonns. $ :'.i K .' Stock loans im.it&gt; Furniture and fixtures ■. 510.93 Cash „ 18,012.49 &lt; Hher assets - 274.153 Total 4 34* LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ $ r&gt; Full paid stock _ E •jiEi.flfio.uo Reserve fund 1,100 00 I minified profits _ _ 2,861.55 Total _ _ ~$ 348,543.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 87 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE i 80, 1914 HVA I- II TS Ilalanoe cm hand .Inly 1. 11)1 Does (running stockl * Kpatd stock, •st Membership niiil transfer fee: I. onus repaid 160.31 Insurance and taxe: Toti _ $ 247 - EXPRND1 Tl'HKS I 123.4HKl.iin 4.960.00 Commissions . Other expense Plrawals. dues lrawals. earning paid stuck is.mi'.l'.'. ■ paid stock, interest on hand Bailee and taxes [ture and fixture! t.v.i &lt;; t 16.73 Total I 247.260.87 SUPPLEMENT AI. KEPORT. Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares in force nt date of last report Number of shares issued daring year ....3.900 Footing of two prec-eding items Nuinl&gt;er of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year I:', 1 *? 1 Number of shares matured during year IB Niimlier of shares canceled doling year, lint not withdrawn King of three preceding items. . her of shares of running stock in force at this date tJSZl Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this date "059% Number of shares in force at this date Number of shares loaned on Bher of shares on which dues an her of borrowing stockholders her of non-borrowing stockholder! delinquent (including minors i Number of minors holding stock In the association Number of loans mnde for building purpose's during year Manner of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year i:i _i * hi I'nr value of each share of stock Total amount of clues delinquent at this dale I Ann unt of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premiums and hues due and unpaid _ Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 'i r.'.'mni Amount of loans upon improved real estate _ - jft.~i.0ll Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have Ixpen made _ Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate _ Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hav tieen made Amount of fire insurai in force and assigned to the association as collateral security I x&lt; ■ •nut of tornado insurance in fori-e and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount of advance payment of loans during year Amount credited to reserve fund during year Pnt of dividends declared on running slock during year 7 ».;i M nt of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 12.16S.40 per cent of dividends declared on running stock daring year Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during .. .»•■* v : 9* </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Byron J. Morey Vice-President Horace T. Wilson Secretary Frank Mills Treasurer Emery E. Butler Attorney James A. Brown DIRECTORS. Byron J. Morey Horace T. Wilson J. Y. M. Swigart Emery E. Butler James A. Brown Frank Mills Cecil L. Ward Cecil L. Ward ASSETS. Kirst mortgage loans _ „ $ "J.-iiio 'XI Cash I486 i(7 . . — . — — p • ■«■• • • Keliiinuent Interest, premiums and fines ____ 5.60 Mfinl&gt;ershlp fees due— _ Total _ _..$ t.if.i 4 7 LIABILITIES. t'npital stock running (dues and dividends) _ $ -tiNmi Full paid stock _ 1 1,367.00 fnillvided profits I ..." "' 1« 17 Advance dues 3UKI 3l'.m Advance Interest and premiums 4.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Dues (running stock I l'ull puiil stock 4,757.00 :«i.7l Membership »ml transfer fees _ 115.00 PlM f"f examining abstract 45.IW Total. BXPEND1 TVBE8 1-..--I (oiiiuiissiolis ex pen 186J* umb Full pniil stock l.-MW«» ■ paid Moek, imert on liiiinl 16.M 1.4.s.Yi&gt;7 612.H Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of associat inn _ Permanent Naaiber of ibarei iaaned since organization... M4JR Number of share* issued daring year Number of Iharea withdrawn before maturity, during year.... Ill 4IH..7 .■» ll lit i n-i «'l i i.i i i-^ nuiKiiniiii i,i i ..i i. luiiij, niiiiii^ .. ■ Number of shares canceled during year. Imt not withdraw ii 121 144 Biik of two pmtdlll items _ &gt;er of gliares of running stock in force at this date _ 29 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at .1.1.- .!_._ ■'" ~.7 this date. Number of shares in force at this dat (20. Namber of shares loaned on. 24 Number of shares on which dues are dt iiiquent - --" for uou payment of ibics i.'.' Number of shares subject ti&gt; cancellation her of borrowing (tockholden 4 Number of non-borrowiag rtookholdtr Niiuiiier of loans made for building purpc luring year. imeatead niortcap Number of loans made for payment of h during 1 year Par value of each share of Itork Total amount of dues delinquent at this [late ;i relic ihlers _ 4&gt;i Amount of dues owing by borrowing sh Amount of interest, premiums and tint ilue and unpaid— 5.60 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 4INUKI Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have l&gt;eeu made '&lt;■* made ■ NMt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ - 3.400.00 ■&gt;unt of tornado insurance in force aud assigned to the association us collateral security 3.400.00 as collateral security. Amount of advance payment of loans during gyear....Hues UUBO, interest W.20 7 ' Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year HU it *4 Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during ] cm r ■ • Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the THE McCOOK CO-OPERATIVE BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION MCCOOK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President John E. Kelley Vice-President J. A. Wilcox Secretary F. A. Pennell Treasurer ,. L. Thorgrimson DIRECTORS. John E. Kelley J. A. Wilcox H. P. Waite L. W. McConnell C. L. Fahnestock W. B. Mills M. Lauritson M. Lauritson F. M. Kimmell C. J. O'Brien ASSKTS. First mortgage loans * 17- J First mortgage loans in procriu of foreclosure 1 !'!&lt; Stink loans ... 2.573.011 Real estate™ _ I *t*l i mi iien t interest _ _ _ l ."► T. * • 4 rises and taxes paid MM6.I * Delinquent aaaeaaakwta. 117. Vi Total $ 1st LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) * 17 : ve fund ".n Undivided profits 5.244.42 Ad\ ance dues </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 rCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1013 _ - $ I'-'. 173.88 Dues (running stock) _ _ 34.- Interest _ 15 Premiums MO II Fines and membership and transfer fees Loans repaiil V. ■ Real estate sales _ _ Tax sale redemption! Received OB loans iu foreclosure _ 1. 540.20 Total $ 123,067.21 IKES EXPEND! Loans * 65.675.00 Salaries _ 540.00 ()rlu - r pxnt'iist's J 'fcii "0 Withdrawals, dues and earnings .''7.41 \Ia t ur€*d stock . - ,,.1, — 7.7"* u ** ' (''I^IiODIIIIIHI I ■ ■! ■ -,-■-■---- t MH»&gt;HMWMMM "T /l ] ! ' ' Tax sale certificates M8.CI Total $ 123 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT I'lan af association - Number of series issued since organisation ■tier of shares issued since organisation '.i.44.". 1 J ber of shares in force at date of last report 2.714V4 '.'.44.' Number of shares issued during year... VJIM Footing of two preceding items ■her of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year ."14' ber of shares matured daring year and withdrawn 138* I'mit in;.' of two preceding items 4."&gt;3 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date Number of ■hares in force at this dal Number of shares loaned on. Number of shares on which dues are delinquent - 11T 1 -.. Number of borrowing stockh ciders 1*kJ Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) Number of minors holding stock in the association Number of loans made for building pnrp iscs during year imcsteail mortgag Number of loans made for payment of h 1 u i 11 yea r Pof premium - Bid age running time of stock matured during year 121 months value of each share of stock _ _ $ UWMIO U0IUI0 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date ]17."&gt;&lt;&gt; Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders - 108 Ml Amount of interest due and unpaid ' '" ,i Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 3 1.918J6 Amount of loans on improved real estate 172 - ■ raised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - S48.8SO.00 Amount of fire and tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 396.550.00 Kunt of advance payment of loans during year _ 21,30000 nnt credited to reserve fund during year - MM| unt of dividends declared on running stock during year 13.866.35 21,300 00 Bper cent of dividends declared on running slock during year per cent of interest charged borrowers during year • </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MADISON COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION MADISON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President C. S. Snyder Vice- President Jacob Henderson Secretary A. E. Ward Treasurer J. L. Grant DIRECTORS. C. S. Snyder J. L. Grant D. Q. Nicholson F. M. Yaezel Jacob Henderson Fred H. Davis ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 54.900.1 « I Stock loans 200.00 Furniture and fixtures _ 100.00 Cash _ :«t.4O Delinquent interest, premiums and fines _ 108.62 &lt; &gt;t her assets... 1 73.07 Total _ I 55 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running nines and dividends! $ •*.' Full paid and matured stock... 18,200.00 Reserve fund l,O3O.i«) Undivided profits </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 REC F IPTS Balance on hand July 1, 1913 Dues (running stock) Full paid stock. Fines and membership fees. Loans repaid. Total.. EXPEND1 T i ui:s. Loans Salaries Other expenses.. Withdrawals, dues and dividends Full paid stock ■ luiid stock. Interest : BTOJt on band « S2Mt Total i 29.181.08 329.40 J Total SUPPLEMEN T \L REPORT. Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organization i' 44::', Nuiul&gt;er of shares in force at date of last report ti4."i', ■her of shares issued during year jr.i' ing of two preceding items _ Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 721 Number of shares niiilured during rear.. Footing of two preceding items Number of shares of running stock in force nt this date 7&lt;W*1 Number of shares of full paid and matured Mock in fori* at this date 71 Number of shares in force at this date Number of shares loaned on _ _ 292V Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of due Number of borrowing stockholders B Number of non- borrowing stockholders (including minors) Number of minors holding stock in the association Kber of loans made for building purposes during year _ II Hire running time of stock matured during year l'-H mouths 13 ge running time of stock matured daring year Par value of each share of stock. 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid Kber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. 1 1. 400.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate •") Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security f. 8&amp;325.Q0 Kmt of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association s collateral security B '-_ Amount of advance payment of loans during year - 5,700.06 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 74J8 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year Itate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Hate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MADISON BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION MADISON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President I. M. Dawson Vice-President A. G. Sterner Secretary W. L. Dowling Treasurer C. E. Plass DIRECTORS. Fred Funk J. M. Smith J. H. Katterman L. A. Wagner C. F. Baisch ASSET8 First mortgage Ion us f H.3fift till Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 196.01 Expenses iiud taxes pziid - Total $ 14,01*3.7:; LIABILITIES. ■tal stock running (dues and dividends i 6.980 90 paid and matured stock 4,800.00 rve fund 0,-,_i t&gt;54.1'4 Individed profits _ i 1.5SX.58 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 HECE IPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1913 _ _...$ Dues (running stock) 1 . 17v"'O I merest T.-.8.1O 1. 1&gt;» us repaid 1.100.00 Taxes redeemed 34.03 Total.. i:;n- EXPEND1 T URES. Loans * O«i.im Sa lories .......................... .... .._.. 1. h t 00 &lt; (I her ox i &gt;euses 47.'"* Withdrawals, dues _ _ (7&amp;M Withdrawals, earnings :!((•. (XI Matured stock l.SOO.fK) Ma I u red stock, interest :^!i;.."&gt;il Cash on hand - 4.3U7 Total.. SriM'LEMKXTAL REPORT I'l:in of association NuuilK'r of series issued since organization .".1 Number of shares in force at date of last report _ 3H&gt; Bber of slmres issued during year 30 iug of two preceding items _ _ Footing of two precediag items. Nuinlier of shares withdrawn l&gt;efore maturity, during year Namber of slmres matureil daring year Footing of two preceding items _ B Number of shares of running stock in force at this date _ 261 ■tier of shares of full paid and matured stock In forqe at his .late - 48 Nunilier of shares in force at this date — :;il Namber "f shares loaned on H.".'_. Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ 54 Namber of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues 10 Number of loans made for building purposes daring year 1 Average running time of stock matured daring year _ 11 years Par value of each share of stock $ iiHUXt Total amount of dues dclincpieiit at this date BH.50 Knt of dues owing by borrowing shareholder - T'l.-Vi nt of interest, premiums ami tines due and unpaid |&gt;unt of loans on improved real estate railed value of improved real estate upon which loans have been in ad i' - 23.700.01 been mnde. Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security IT I ■ unit of tornado Insurance in force and assigned t" the association :is collateral security 1.300.00 Amount of advanced payment of loans daring year 113.00 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year S34L9O Hate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dnriag year Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during </seg>
            <seg id="p096">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 96 STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Henry Fastenau Vice-President J. W. Butt Secretary W. H. Pitzer Treasurer , H. F. Meyer Attorney W. H. Pitzer DIRECTORS. ■tf. Cook W. Metz G. Mueller Henry Thiele H. F. Meyer John Petring E. H. Buhlman George Bader W. H. Pitzer ASSETS. First mortgage loans.... First mortgage loans „ _ $ Hti.-'LVi i."» Stock loans 3.175.3.1 17. Real estate 1.900.35 Furniture and fixtures 1(K).(K&gt; Cash | 10JMMH Delinquent interest 1.001.07 Expenses and taxes paid Foreclosure account 96.81 1. 07O.i» Total _ 4 1MJS8.73 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues anil dividends! $ llL'.rc'l .17 Full paid _ 45,flU'OO Reserve fund Undivided profits 3^358.61 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDIXC JUNE iO 1914. RECEII rs. Italaiiee on lianil July 1. 1913 $ I&gt;ues (roaning stock) _ Full paid stock J4.i««Mrf Membership uml transfer fees _ MC23 I. .'.i us repaid _ _ _ 24.y-T.lfl Rents _ „ _ 1 (fci.i » i Total _ $ 96 7 KXI'KXnn IRES - - * 33,788.90 I II her expenses » Iol.*l3 \V it In I raw a Is. dues „ 15*236.81 Withdrawals, earning* - 3,618.81 Matured stock 12.0iio.tci Mat u red stuck, interest _ 5.5HO.02 Full paid stock 5.550.(10 ■ paid stock, interest _ J.imi^.Im Cash on hand 10.MB.tt4 I in proved real estate — — 57.74 Insurance and taxes 262.41 Total SO BUPl'LEMEX 1 AI. REPORT Plan of association- _ _... Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation 7 ."ii:&gt; Nillnlier of shales in force at dale of last report _..J.4'.'T' Nmulper of shares issued daring year — 70T 1 , Footing of two preceding items 3.205 Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 4L".i :1 l Number of shares matured during year 00 Footing of two preceding items iv&gt; , Number of shares of running stock In force at this date 2.4S Numlier of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this dnte _.. - Number of shares in force at this date 2,715V| Xuinlier of shares loaned on _ - 1.0BS Nu in her of horrowing stockholders „ - Number of non- borrowing stockholders (Including minors i 2M Number (if minors holding stock in the association _ Bber of loans made for balldlag purposes duriiiir year l&gt;er of loans made for payment of Homestead mortfr»(fen during V-(ijii- _ r. ■ ate rannlng time of stock matured during year 1.14 months value of each share of stock _ _ .$ 2KMIO 1.661.07 Knt of interest 1.661.07 nt of loans on improved real estate 146,355.15 Amount of loans on improved real estate ■ raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have l.een made 237.656.00 Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association aa collateral security 217.435.00 K» LVIIBICini W »K H ,, • •■ ........... int of tornado insurance in force and assigned to t!ie association as collateral security _ 122,735.00 Amount credited to reserve fund dnriag year _ 5T&gt;7.7!» 122,735.00 Amount of dividends declared on ranning stock during year 7.444. AiiKinnt of Interest paid on matured stock dorlng year 7.983JI Kate per cent of dividends declared on rannlng stock during year Kate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock daring year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during yeai- </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NUCKOLLS COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NELSON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Geo. Lyon, Jr. Vice- President W. C. McHenry Secretary C. R. Imler Treasurer Henry Fox, Jr. Attorney E. D. Brown DIRECTORS. F. E. Bottenfield W. A. McHenry W. W. Hawley Thos. Graham Geo. Lyon, Jr. E. D. Brown H. E. Goodrich Thos. Graham H. G. Smith J. B. Goodrich ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ u. Stock loans 700.00 Cash _ _ _ Delinquent interest, premiums and Isea - _ - Expenses and taxes paid. _ Interest paid „ 122.48 Tax sale certiticates _ _ _ - 38.06 Total _ _ __$ 08,288.12 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ ....$ 01.3O4.S5 Full paid stock _ 13.900.00 Reserve fund 7_.'i 7J Undivided profits -.360 75 Total - -* 68,289.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. _ f MMJD Balance on hand July 1. IM3 Dues (running stock i Bpaid stock »st and fines "■it 10.250.00 5,194.97 62.32 Membership and transfer fi Loans repaid 113.75 11.1.-^1X1 Bsale certificates redeemed sst refunded- _ Total - $ 41 .'.'74. 71 EXI'EXDI r ritKs J 180.08 Salaries SS.10 n.:&gt;7-.--J other npeiMI Withdrawals, dues Tax sale certificate! Full paid stock 61. JO 6.250.00 ■ paid stuck, interest - on hand 64140 !75.H Total „ $ 41.274.71 SUPPLEMENTAL BEPOBT Plan of association - Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation _ _ 2,408 Numlier of shares in force at date of last report 1.3KO ■her of shares issued durins.' year _ _ 400 ing of two preceding items _ 1.780 ■her of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year her of shares running stork in force at this date 1.516 1.516 ■her of shares of paid and matured stock in force at this ;,,,. 139 date ■tier of shares in force at this dat&lt; her of shares loaned "ii 705 Ilier i&gt;f shares on which due* are 'I her of borrowing stockholders her of Bon-borrowlBg stockboldera tier of niinots holding stock in the her of loans maile for building p lier of loans made for |iaytnent of flinquent 28 7f, (Including mlnon)_l 7S association 15 association. orpoae* during year 0 homestead mortgages during 17 year Total amount of ilues delinquent at thi ilat. Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders — 2*59 Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid - _ 36.64 Amount of loans on improved real estate 87.O27.9fl Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have l.een made - 1 13.72S.00 Knit of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association s collateral security Si Ainoiint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ?,' i- IX Amount of advance payment of leans during year _ - ll.laO.00 as collateral security ll.l.-ill.OO Amount credited to reserve fund daring year _ '-'"■'• Jj Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3.862.34 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 541.10 Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dnriag year Kate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock! during mid ''•'; </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEWMAN GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Chas. Letheby Vice-President C. J. Peterson Secretary-Treasurer E. H. Gerhart DIRECTORS. Chas. Letheby C. J. Peterson E. H. Gerhart A. L. Doty O. O. Buck Edw. W. Lyon ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ $ 1 l'.'.« W.U0 Expenses and taxes paid 142.01) Sundries i M .t."i..Vi Total * 13.tK.-..so LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _.$ 11,828.90 Ui'st-rve fund 39fi BO Individed profits - 1,411.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE \ EAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 REC EIPTS Kalaiiif on hand July 1. 1!H3 $ I'lit's * riiiiniiiLT stock t Premiums 4.1V 41 Loans repaid 1.300.00 Ka mines _ 20.49 Sun dries 195.80 Total _ | 7.900.08 EXPEN HI 1 IRES Loans $ I Hlier expenses '_"J.ni Withdrawals, clues ~ Wit lidra wals. earnings J4 1 * '_'* &gt; Kull paid stock J 800.00 Sundries Lti.i.Vi Cash on hand - .. i".'v Total _ S '.'.» «'.'«&gt; SUPPLKMEXT AL RE I 'OUT Plan of association _ Serial N'uiiilier of series issued llnce organization 18 Nuinher of shares issued simc organisation _ 1,119 Number of shares in force at date of last report 173 Number of shares issued during year _ 114 Footing of (wo preceding items... _ Number of shares withdrawn I.efore maturity, during year !3 Number cif shares of running (took in force at this date -74 Nuiulter of shares in force :it this date I _ 'J74 Number of shares loaned on _. '►." Nuiutier of shares in force at this date. ii.1 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent - I s Number of borrowing stockholders 12 N'nmlier of non-borruH itiL r stockholders i in&lt;-luiliiig minors) S3 Nuinher of minors holding stock in the association Number of loans made for building purposes during year 4 plan of premiums '. _ Monthly Par value of each share of stock _ * IIHI.IKI Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ ]4- j' Amount of dues owlmg by borrowing shareholders _ 132X1 Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid 1M.79 Amount of loans on improved real estate 12,9 132.M) 14.', 7." ■ raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been ■lade _ 19.000.00 Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 12..TO0.flO Ann nut of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association ■as collateral security 12.r&gt;UMiO unit credited to reserve fund during year 64.90 as collateral security. «4.«0 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund daring year Amount of losses chanced to reserve fund daring year M.M Amount of dividends declared on rnnnlng stock during yetr L2tft.4A Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 10Jaj Hate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring year S 1 "- Rate per cent of premium* charged borrowers daring year _ 1.6^ </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President H. A. Pasewalk Secretary C. B. Durland Treasurer E. W. Zutz Attorneys Mapes and McFarland DIRECTORS H. A. Pasewalk S. G. Dean I. M. Macy A. Bear A. Bucholz G. B. Christoph John Welsh J. C. Stitt ASSETS First mortgage loans S 261.400.00 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 4,700.00 Stock loans 2,116.49 Real estate 2,523.01 Furniture and fixtures 300.00 C»gh _ 1,582.22 Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines 1.93S SO Expenses and taxes paid _ 1,645.37 Insurance 101.85 Personal accounts 246.60 Real estate sold on contract 1. 120.00 Profit and loss 560.12 Total _ _ $ 278.234.06 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ * 176.011.76 capital shock running uiues anu uiviuenusj - * n«.v" l « Full paid and matured stock 56.2O-.'io Reserve fund _ 4,700.00 Undivided orofits M00._ V .. .V**- |*1 UU ...J - Fines " i ;;.; ;■;.: : 44.00 Interest on loans 10,716.24 Dues 29,139.00 Personal account - 11.40 Disbursements 9.94 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 103 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RF.CEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1. 1913 $ 4.48K3 - I running stock ) .. - _ „ _ Full paid stock „ MfiS.UO _T m L65.Uf) Full paid stock Imprest and fines I jj im* s8 Insurance _ 108.70 Stock loans. _ _ _ 4.522.43 I.. &gt;u us repaid _ _ 07 . H."i.0U Real estate sales _ 572.49 Beati _ 135. 00 Total.. ..$ 22U. 4.77.79 EXPENDITTRB8 I.,. a us _ $ 127.745.fl0 Salaries and other expenses _ Personal account! _ 235.20 Slock loans _ 4.14AJ8 \V it hdra w:i]s. dues „ „ „ 1 4_'.&lt; *o Wit hil ni wills, car u in us .". . 41J Mat ured stock _ 17.-M '" ' Matured stock, interest lo.71C.iW Full paid stuck .. 17.- Full paid stuck, interest _ 1 BHU6 Cash on hand _ Dividend! on installment stuck. _ - 787.38 Furniture, fixtures and &gt;orplua _ 700,'JO Total _ $ 22!» 4.'i7.T» SUPPLEMENTAL REPOBT I'lan of association Permanent Number of shares in force at date at last report 4.260 Blier uf sliarcs issued during year 2,467 tag i'f two preceding items _ 6.7: .J.-Mu Bber of shares withdrawn iM'fore inaturity. during year 1.298 her of shares matured during year 14U Footing of two preceding items _ l M Numlier of shares of mnnlng stuck in force at this date 5,003 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this date _ - _ -M Numlier of shares in force at this date _ 5.334 Numlier of shares loaned on I'i4 Bber of shares on which dues are delinquent ".41 her of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues ■&lt; her of borrowing stockholders 2.V.1 841 Number of borrowing stockholders.. Numlier of non-borrowing stockholders (including minorsi. Number of minors holding stock In the association ■ Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1." Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgage* daring year _ _ 42 Average running time of stock matured during year 124 month! Par value of each share of stock .". - t Total amount of dues delinquent at this date - 1.472.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ 2,031».00 Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. .1 I L'.Ooo.on amount of same. No. Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 4 4.700.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ - 280.90000 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made ™ I 4T8 ' Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate „ Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 320,600.00 ■Hint of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 204.300.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 48O.0i! Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 17.341.63 4S-MH Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 1.900MB Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year — Mfj </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ELKHORN BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President H. J. Cole Vice- President F. E. Davenport Secretary T. E. Odiorne Treasurer H. J. Cole DIRECTORS. H. J. Cole W. P. Logan A. Degner H. C. Matrau T. E. Odiorne F. E. Davenport ASSKTS. First mortgage loans ~$ 35,120.(18 Delinquent interest, premiums and flues Expenses End t&amp;xes paid __~— ss .l. r j Total I 42.219.71 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running ulueg and dividends! $ 12.517.85 Full paid and matured stock _ 27 .7 Reserve fund 1.40O.UI ('■■divided profits , 601.66 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING 81PPLEMEX I AI. REPORT. Plan of aaaaetatton - Permanent Number of shares Issued sim- fanlsal in Number of iharei In force at date of last report rtxi .176' Kber df aharea Issued daring year 17W4 Inn n* * 1 »-.-i itT*f&gt;&lt;iiiil il&gt;irit..Tii. 1 '■ nc of two preceding items ■her of ■harei withdrawn before maturity, daring year. 100' her of shares matured daring year - 14 JUNE 30, 1914. lU'.rEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1. l'.n:; lines (rannlng stuck i Full paid stock le|i;i ill laneous - 2.470.73 1 1 Total &gt; :si ■ EXPENDITURES • ItluT expenses Withdrawals, does. Withdrawal*, earning* Matured si ink Matured stuck. Interest Full paid sinik Full paid stuck, interest _ mi hand $ i;.7V.'.T'.i r.l.tn Total s 31.3X2.71 Footing of two preceding items Number of share* of running stoek In force .-it tins date - 529 1 * Number of ihirn "f full paid ami matured stock at this tale — 138% Number of shares in force :it this date - Number of borrowing stockholder* - Number of non-borrowing »torkboldem I Including minor*)-! Number of minor* holding stock in tbe aaaoclatloa - Number of loan* made for building purpoae* during jrear_) Average running time of stcick matured during year Par value of each share of stoek — * \niniitit of interest. |iretuiuins and lines doe and unpaid — Number of mortgage* subject t" forecloaure, ami the aggregate am it of same. No. " - Wnoiint of loans mii Improved real estate App raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have Keen made ■■•••- Amount of fire Inaurance in fovea and aaatgaad to the association as collateral seeurity ■ - ■•. Amount of tornado Inaurance in foree ami assigned ro the aatoclation as collateral security Viiiiiiiiit of advance payment of loans during year Kmmiiit credited to reserve fund during year \monnt of dividends declared on running stock during year..... Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stoek during i;-itc' M per Vent of dividend- .1.-. -lared ,.n running stock durhig year Bate I'er 'ent of intere-- piiid on matured and full paid stock taring Uate'i-'r . ■•■i.t . f inter. ■ ciuriiig jmt- iooaoo '1 Sit HI - </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NORTH LOUP BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH LOUP, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Geo. E. Johnson Vice- President E. A. Hutchins Secretary E. J. Babcock Treasurer H. E. Davis Attorney E. J. Babcock DIRECTORS. E. J. Babcock S. L. Clement H. E. Davis E. A. Hutchins Geo. E. Johnson A. T. Jones Geo. S. Mayo ASSETS First mortgage loans _ f 23,047.70 Stock loans _________ rt4&lt;nxi Cash ~. 603.53 Delinquent interest, premiums and Hues 702.45 Total $ 24,993.«8 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends! $ 21,287.51 Full paid stock _ 1.500.00 1.500.00 Reserve fund , j ."Uti.a: fndivided profits D8H.W I&gt;ue shareholders mi laconplete loans 960.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 107 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS Balance on band July 1, 1913 &gt; Dae* {running itock)__ 1 Iiimti'&lt;i 1 1,515.(9 pine* 1 20lS Mi-inticrsli i|&gt; anil transfer fees Loans repaid OtM Total $ 4.114.67 EXI'EXDI TVRES i _$ 2M0M Salaries (V n i missions „ „ _ l.Y'Hi r expenses _ Wit hdrnwals. dues „ _ „ Wlthdra » a Is. earning* — _ ■ paid sto.k. Interest lCBJIO on linml - MJI * 4ii4 or Total BUPPLEMEN T AL REPORT rian of aaaoHatfoa - Perninnent ■her of share* issued since organization _ 1.344 V4 her of shares in force at date of last report - .535 Number of shares in force at date of last report B ■ber of shares issued daring year 56 inn of two preceding Items - - 591 Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 05 Number of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn 10 footing of two preceding items Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 501 ■tier of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at his dale - l- r &gt; Number of shares in force at this date - 516 Number of shares loaned on. tti Bber of shares on which dues are delinquent _ M berof shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues ■ lier of borrow i lit' stockholders _ Number of non-borrowing stockholders (Including minors )_I Number of minors bold In K stock in the association s Number of loans made fcr building purpose* during year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgage* durin 3 Par raise of each share of stock ■■$ I'*.". 1 " year K amount &lt;&gt;f dues delinquent at this date nt of dues swing by borrowinc shareholders _ 523.50 nt of Interest, premium* and Hues due and unpaid 702.49 ■her of mortgages subject to forecli mount of same. No. !i ure. and the aggregate Amount of loans on improved real estan Appraised value of improved real csiati been made upon which loans have Ami unt of loans upon unimproved real I tate...! J 200.00 Appraised value of unimproved real petal lieen made upon which loans have 300.00 Amount of tire insurance in force and a iirned to tlip association 24.615.00 a* collateral security Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 24.015.00 Amount of advance payment nf loans daring year 417.30 Amount credited to reserve fund daring year MM' Kill credited to reserve Minn iiiirini; year..- .-.&gt;.^ - nt of dividends declared on rannlng stock during year. 1.51 i.&lt;M Amount of interest paid on matured mid full paid stock during .year 105.0JJ Kper cent of dividends declared on running stock dnrlajg year, mi-annual ly ■■■ — - ■ ; •** Rate jier cent of 'interest pniil OBJ matured and full paid stock during year • — ■ • ;:: Tm - " Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year...- _ W% </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Thos. C. Patterson Vice-President Victor von Goetz Secretary Samuel Goozee Treasurer Frank E. Bullard Attorneys Wilcox and Halligan DIRECTORS. Ira L. Bare James M. Rannie Victor von Goetz Frank T. Redmond Lester Walker Thos. C. Patterson C. O. Weingund Wm. H. Blalock Geo. W. Finn ASSKTS. Flrtt mortgage loans $ HMHXOQ First mortgage loans in proi'ess of foreclosures o.OOO.'M Stock loans | 4.600.00 Real estate '. i 27.734.m Furniture and fixtures j 582.75 Cash 1 10.24O.1.1 Delin&lt;iuent interest, premium! and tines '.is:; .mi Expenses and taxes paid 1.373.66 other assets . _ 152 32 !IN.-!.IKI Total _ _ $ 633.885.92 LIABILITIES. Kal stock running (dues and dividends i $ 253.844.41 paid stock 334.500.00 11.850.00 Individed profits 28.426.71 Advance Juts _ _ 5.237.00 A.hau e interesi 7.80 Total._ - _» 633,885.»2 </seg>
            <seg id="p109">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 109 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS. Balmier on baad July 1. !»H _ * 12.487.01 Dues (running stock i _ _ 77.174.12 Full paid stock „_ 133.300.00 I f] t L.J-t.Cf *W1 *lff* 1ft Membership and transfer fees . 4tI'J.T5 Loans repaid 57.852.79 Real estate sales _ «„ .. 23.6PO.0Jj Ta xes and insu ra nee _ .. 104.67 Total $ 323.678.19 EXPENDITURES Loans $ 178.500.00 Salaries 1.500.00 &lt; *t her ex penses _ _ _ .. 515.03 Witlidniwals. dues _ _ 17.901.00 Withdrawn Is. earnings _ 3.21KMK) Full paid stock J 98,400.00 Real estate and office building 27.734.04 Other real estate 188.25 Full paid sto.-k. interest 16.490.18 Cash on hand _ 10.240.15 Furniture and fixtures 582.75 Taxes and insurance i'4.V- H .i Total * 323.07S.19 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial to 1905; Now Permanent Number of series issuer since organisation _ _ 17 Number of series issued since organisation - 17 Number of shares in force at date of last report 7.O92V4 ■her of shares issued daring year 2.676V4 Ing of two preceding items _ B.TM Footing of two preceding items Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 1.507 Bber of shares matured during year 57 ing of two preceding items L LSM Footing of two preceding items Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 6,532 Vi Number of shares of full paid and matured stock In force at this date _....1.672H Number of shares in force at this date _ 8.205 Number of shares loaned on _ 2.964 this date. Number of shares loaned on Number of shares on which duel are delinquent _ 269 ■her of shores subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues 12 her of borrowing stockholders _ 364 Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) .132 Number of minors holding stock in the association _ _ Number of loans made for building purposes daring year _ 53 Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during 21 Average running time of stock matured during year 123 months Par value of each share of stock - t 200.00 Par value of each share of stock.. Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ _ 807.30 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _ 752.50 Bint of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid _ 9P3.OO her of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 - 1.500.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process i&gt;f foreclosure. No. 3 5.000 00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 5R2.6OO.UI ■ raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 1.040.905.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate _ 600.00 ■raised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made • 1.500 00 ■Hint of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 665..":;.. .00 ■unit of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association ■as collateral security 624.92.1.OO &gt;unt of advance payment of loans during year 86.500.00 86.500.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1.750.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year lS.294.6fl Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 16.3ST).«3 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Hate per cent of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock during ft* yftgr .„... - ~-— '* i Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7.3% </seg>
            <seg id="p110">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 110 STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President. Thos. A. Fry Vice- President R. S. Wilcox Secretary J. R. Brandt Treasurer G. E. Haverstick Attorney John L. Kennedy DIRECTORS. Thos. A. Fry David Cole Thomas F. Godfrey R. S. Wilcox Bartholomew Julien Byron R. Hastings G. E. Haverstick W. B. T. Belt Thomas J. Fitzmorris ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 777.168.00 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure- 1.3M.80 Stock loans. _ _ 28.971. in Real estate 804.65 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 42O.S6 Real estate sold on contracts T.MMS Total _ _ $ 825.194.88 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends* _ $ 521.187.70 Full paid stock „ 256,527.45 Reserve fund _ _ 10,244.35 t'ndlvided profits _ 4,191 II Due shareholders on incomplete loans 30.037.90 Bills payable 4,000.00 Total 1 MB.194.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1913.. _ _ $ 36,285.35 I running stock).'. „ ____. 234,550.20 Full paid stock _ _ _ _ 33.510.00 33.510.00 Loans repaid _ „ 60.-6-.65 Real estate sales _ 15. T Received on loans in foreclosure— _ _ _... TM.1t i mi ii I it ii&lt; hi accounts _ _ 10 ..'.. Bills payable 4.000.00 Total _ t ~41.S-3.43 EXPENDITURES. Loans _ 1 .$ -23.2O7.M Salaries _ !__________ -.O47."0 Other expenses _ _ _ 1.N90.45 Witliilrnwals. dues, earnings and matured stock _ 155.953. 89 Full Daid stork I' 1 7-4 83 Real estate „ 19.049.67 Cash on hand _ _ _ _ 8.7N9.72 Accommodation accounts 1O.: Safe purchased _ ___ MCM Total . _ $ 541.S SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association „ Permanent Number of share issued since organization _ C". li:u 4 Number of shares in force at date of last report 17,539' Bber of share issued during year _ 6.904% Ing of two preceding items _. 24.443^4 Number of shares canceled during year _ 3.030&lt;£ Number of running stock in force at this date i's.wS'.i Number of shares of full paid and matured stock In force at this date.._ _ 2.4S4 Number of shares in force at this date 21,413^ Number of borrowing stockholders _ 47. Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors)— 804 Number of minors holding stock in the assication Number of loans made for building purposes during year 82 Kber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during ear _ 83 Par value of each share of stock _ _ t 100.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 420.86 Bber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. 7 11, 71*). 39 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure, No. 1 1.3Tifl.8O Amount of loans on improved real estate ___ 777,168.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 1.542,630.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 1.0?H&gt;' Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the associa - tion as collateral security _ 914.557.63 .Viiinnnt credited to reserve fund during year 2.076.30 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 26.156.11 ■unit of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ _ _ _ 14.3S7.72 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... iff Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock ilur- ing vear e per" cent of interest charged borrowers during year f.H'r Bate per" cent of interest charged borrowerg during year.. </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President G. A. Loomis Vice-President W. S. Wright Secretary W. R. Adair Treasurer W. R. Adair DIRECTORS. C. E. Black R. J. Dunning John H. Butler E. A. Parmelee Joseph Barker M. M. Robertson ASSETS. Fir«t mortgage loans _ t 6.480.731^0 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosing 6.622.18 Stuck loans...- 164,1168.01 Real estate 14,634.06 Furniture and fixtures * 325.33 i •:,«!, __ _ 23K.177.M Iiilinquent interest, premium* ami tines 4.1 :4 ._■&gt;; other assets. Md'ague Bntldinti 128.17*.** ('oatract sale Dunlins Block i'4..VtO.0O other assets Total * 7.(M0..-.liUfi LIABILITIES. Capital stock running nines and dividends) $ 4.3-V&gt;.fl83.fi6 Kpald and matured stock ve fund - 145,741. ••", I'udivided Droflts _ . . f» ""■•-'' " ■••- Due nhareholders on incomplete loans lW.S71.fJ Total - * 7.mo.r.lc; Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p113">XI)I\( * 1 4.U3J ' Permai 1 1 1 I I 1 ' ■&gt; RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR E JUNE 30, 1914. amount of saini&gt;. N Number ami amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure. N. Amount of loans on iinproveil real estate 6.496.731 Appraised value of Improved real estate apon which loai heen inaile -J. mj. I'.l Amount of loans apon onimproved real estat Appraiseil value of unimproved real estate upon which loans Ihmmi nia "le _ I 1 '1 .mm Amount of tire Insurance in force ami assigned to the association as collateral security _ 8,107.81 Aiiiouut of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 6.07K.M71 AtiHMint credited to reserve fund iluring year _ M.4 Am. unit of losses charged to itaKiia fund daring TearJ ant of dividends declared on runninx stock during year l Amount of interest paid on ma tared ami full paid stock during year 118,191 per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year t ■■ per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during &gt;&lt;■:"■ - : — : ■ « per cent uf interest charged borrowers during year in." i.ii i .-^. (t on linml .Tnly 1. ins i running stoek i - &gt;aid stock t illieoiis reps Id .. •tate dales _ I'axue building.. - U^llls l»l(M'k - ... &gt;niiren Total EXPENDITURES. Commissions other expense* _ Wit hdrawals, dues estate Improvements osures l'ull paid stock .hi band _iif building _ Tata! SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. I Ma 11 of MSOCiat it'll Number of shaies issued since organisation Nnmber &gt;&gt;( aharea in force at date of hist report xo.5:J5i Nnmber of shares Issued daring year 'Ji'.ttW' Footing of hvn preceding Items Naasber of shares canceled during year, liul not wlthdtan n Number of shares of running stuck in force :it this das SO.'.KiG 1 Nnmber of snares nf full paid and matured stock in force ;it this data 9.992' Nnmber of shares in force at this date _ Number of shares loaned on _ Nti nitter of borrowing stockholders Nnmber of non-borrowing stockholders Number of loans made for building purposes daring year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mort9a.£t?s durin Plan of premium Si&lt; Par value of each share of stock Amount of interest, premium* and tines due and unpaid Numlier of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregal n </seg>
            <seg id="p114">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 114 STATEMENT of the condition of the OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President John F. Flack Vice-President R. A. McEachron Secretary E. N. Bovell Assistant Secretary J. T. Brownlee Treasurer J. A. Sunderland Attorney T. F. Wiles DIRECTORS. John F. Flack E. N. Bovell Robert Dempster R. A. McEachron J. A. Sunderland ASSETS. First mortfcape loans $ 3.374.512.S0 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 32,155.3" Stock loans _ 21.3ft4.OO Real estate sold on contract 53.437.!»9 Cash _ - - 269.674.25 DelinQuent interest, premiums . —_.... 17.460.0G Total - $ 3.76S.613.47 LIABILITIES Capital stock running (dues and dividends i * 1.733.!t\!4.7»&lt; vajMim siuift luiiuiug uiurs aim uiviucuum j., i«&gt;o.-' -t. i j Full paid and matured stock _. _ „ 1,856,376.44 Reserve fund 1.-&gt;0.0(IO.OO Undivided profits 4.115.71 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans _ U4.1!»6.4i* </seg>
            <seg id="p115">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 115 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING Balance on haml .Inly 1. 1913 _ $ 325.0ft6.42 Balance &lt;m hand July 1. l!tl Dae* i running: stock) D«n i running stock) _ 450.197.9S Full paid stock 574.7Ofi.'.i7 Interest _ 20O.JM1.41 Premiums M.335.01 Fines 802.50 682.50 Membership ami transfer fe» Loans repaid , irsliip Mini transfer fees „ __ 3.363.80 J63.80 Loans repaid ! 529.029.28 9.929 28 Real estate - Real estate Rent estate ou contract - - 15 1 Real estate on contract Loan fees and expenses Foreclosure I.&lt;i:iii fees And expenses .. „.. Foreclosure 22 7 •7 Total * 2.217.IU4 im Total .'17.W4.im EXPENDITURES. .$ 1,O37.4.\1.'.C 21.305.S1 &lt; 'oiiimissions to agents 1 12.S59 .7 rommisslons to agent Other expenses 12.SS9 Other expense* Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earning Profit and loss Wit lidra wals. dues _ Withdrawals, earnings 78 Profit and loss _ 107.'*l 107.:-.l Contract of sale - 2.202.50 Contract of sale. Full paid stock.... 2.202.50 363.424.7:; lts.201.74 289.874.23 ld.nil.IM Full paid stock _ '....'....'. 363]4l'4.7^ ■ paid stock, interest - on hand Full paid stock, interest 9S.2O1.74 Cash on hand '. 2W1.O74 .'.". Blosure and real estate ft and expense Foreclosure and real estate „ 16.1M 1 Jt Milc;me and expense - 2.28fi.ll .2Sfi.ll Total * 2.217.1.1 1 •«&gt; Total. .* SJ17.044.00 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. RI'PPLEMEX T AL REI'oItT Plan of association Permanent Plan of association Permanent Nuniher of shares in force at date of last report 44.7"&gt;O 'J'J-120 Number of shares in force at liate of last report 44.7"&gt;&lt;l 22-120 Number of shares issued during year 12,485 15-40 Number of shares issued during year 12,485 15-40 Footing of two preceding items 57 21." 67-1X NhdiIht of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year....7.1W^ 4 Xiimlier of shares matured during year .'.._ HBft Footing of two preceding items _ Number of shares running stock in force at this date 40.11s 37-120 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in foree at this date 9.14S Numlier of shares in foree at this date _ 49,260 37-120 Number of shares loaned on 22.218 Number of borrowing stockholders _ _ 3. OSS Number of non-borrowing stockholders 4.111 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 184 Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during 7^1 year BCi! I - ■ • 1 of premium monthly with interest ige running time of stock matured daring year _ 1(VS month* 1(VS month* Par value of each share of stock $ 200.00 Amonnt of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ 17.488.06 Kher of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. Xo. 24 21.000.00 amount of same. Xo. 24 Xnmber and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 04 S2.15B Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 3,342.3.17. 4"! Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 7.wn.7"7.&lt;K&gt; Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association us collateral security 1 — S.90B.S Amount credited to reserve fund during year J0fi.3TiO.fln Amonnt of losses charred to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year It. :: l.~. Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 101 I Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year. Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stork during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dnring year 6&lt;~r " ' cent of premiums charged borrowers durln'ir ■ ~ ° 4 r r </seg>
            <seg id="p116">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 116 STATEMENT of the condition of the CONSERVATIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President George F. Gilmore Secretary P. W. Kuhns Treasurer P. W. Kuhns Counsel William Baird DIRECTORS. E. A. Benson A. W. Bowman Randall K. Brown Rob't Dempster John F. Flack J. A. Sunderland Chas. C. George H. A. Thompson Byron R. Hastings A. P. Tukey J. C. Robinson C. M. Wilhe C. M. Wilhelm ASSKTS. First MrtpfC loans $ 8.4.«-J First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure .'14.817.89 K loans.. _ ______________ 122.44n.-t. estate „ _ _ __ i 3l'.s2ti'.ll; 31.828.12 Certtficates of deposit „ „ 1 30.000.00 fash 4fl.064.81 Delinquent interest j 17.4(10.20 Ofllce building and lot 80,000.00 Total „ $ 9.380.44.' _".i LIABILITIES Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 6.730,588.28 Kpaid stork li.072.4-J8.08 \f fund 235.000.00 ■.'.((T'J.428.08 Undivided profits .. ...._Z '.... 11.12R.T2 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans „ _ 322. "-"•♦". 'Jl Total f 8,380.442.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 117 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1. 1!U3 _ * 334.4M.4t Hues (running stock) _ _ 3.&lt;B» Full jmiil stock _ „ K£! Interest _ t 516.359.17 Foreclosure account. 68.425.53 Real estate acquired through foreclosure 20.077.90 Membership and transfer fees 5,771.97 Loans repaid l,819.»&gt;r.s.4o Real estate sales _ 2.469.98 Rests •.'..Vii.s:! Certificate* of deposit - _ 1K.849.20 * IiKiiraiMt' commissions J 6.500.00 Bxpenaa and undivided profits _ 622.11 Total _ - * 6,525,025.40 KXI'KNIUTIHKS. Loans $ 1 ::."..^ 1 - Salaries _ 4r..(ljr..t M i &lt;Vrtitieates of deposit L 28,649.20 i rates of deposit .. 28,G49J£O expense* 18.500. .u Other expenses Is ~&gt;tr,&lt;. .u Withdrawals, dues and earnings _ 2,508.688.11 lrawals. dues mid earnings _ i50K.6K8.l1 Foreclosure account _ ho.i losnre account _ _ 80.OS3JI7 Real estate acquired through foreclosure 40.97&amp;94 estate acquired through foreclosure 4&lt;).!t76.94 Real estate sold on contract _ :(.7'.in ■atate mm m rum met _ 3.7K8..'£S Beserre fund .. ."'... "tT'j.itT ve fund .". .."tT'J.!'" paid stock. ei\ minus 1 57i».4tt4.23 Full paid stock, earnings J 57U.464J Cash on hand 4&gt;-: ■st on stock withdrawn _ _ building _ lii.js." ill Interest on stock withdrawn _ _ _ j ,m .".7 Otfice building _ li'.i's.*. 61 Total $ tjae&amp;JBB&amp;M si ITLKMKXTAl. KBPOBT. I 'la n of association Perinanent .Number of shares issued since organization 775.8B7 Nuuilier of shares in force at date of last report 233,606 Number of shares issued daring year 58.819 Footing of two preceding items 293,49 Number of shares canceled during year ami withdrawn Number of shares of running stock In force at this date 237, 5C1 Number of shares of full paid and malured stock in font ;ll this .late _ 2O.17: : Number of shares In force nt this date J" . 7 1 Number of borrowing stockholder! 4,9X1 Number of non-borrowing stockholders lincludiug minor* i 1: Ji;i Number of minors holding stock in tlie aaaociation Number of loans made for building purposes daring year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year -H v I'ar'value of each share of stock _ ....$ 100.01 Amount of interest _ - - IT ■ Number of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. W U5.900.00 regatt amount of same. No. W Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 2(1 34,817.90 fiunt of loans on improved real estate 8,482,862.86 raiseil value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 18,411,718.00 8.482.8e Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate 500.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon whicli loans have lwen made 8,000.00 t&gt;unt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security lOJSl'.OMS.dO »unt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association 7 .'^ a &gt; I h H 1 1 a i Kas collateral security 7.. r i&lt;li).(N_K( &gt;unt credited to reserve fund during year _ _ :&gt;vj7i'.' 38.572.97 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 3.572.'-&gt;7 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year .'!-".' Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 114 ■ Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent dividends paid N matured and full paid stock during year </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President W. D. Lincoln Vice- President N. A. Speisberger Secretary A. D. Touzalin Assistant Secretary A. A. Tenopir Treasurer L. D. Spalding Attorney Thomas D. Crane DIRECTORS. W. D. Lincoln L. D. Spalding J. J. McMahon Chas. T. Kunol J. P. Leary John C. Wharton ■A. Speirsberger Thomas D. Crane C. D. Hutchinson D. Touzalin ASSETS First mortgage Ion us _ _ $ MI.MM First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure 6.32O.(U Stork Iohiis _____ 4.44&lt;S.!H Real estate Furniture and fixtures Cash Delinquent Interest, premiums and flues 1 r«&lt; u Expenses and taxes paid _ „ m..*5O Total _ $ 273.087.59 LIABILITIES. Bal stock running (dues and dividends) _ _ J$ .14 paid and matured stock -I'.t.OBflLOO Ye fnnA 4^0. ~)\ Doe shareholders on Incomplete loan*-. 7,T4LH </seg>
            <seg id="p119">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 119 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1 1913 _ ... _ $ 2,519.28 Due* (running stock") '...'. 17O.8«8.»« Balance on hand July 1. 191.1 17O.888.M Full paid stock _ S29.4*"'."') Interest _ _ ie,.&lt; - ('•&gt; id mission account- — _ 18S.S8 Fines _ _ 88.22 Loans repaid _ 34 'Jitr, i:, 1 - -„_.... Rents _ „ 1.135.00 Expense _ 208.18 Stock loans _ 4.716.'M Miscellaneous accounts- _ _ Total _ S :ir.i i;7".&lt;o EXPENDITURES. Heal estate loans _ - _$ BB.218.M Stock loans _ 4.900.O* Salaries I S30.00 Ot her expenses _ 'J..~&gt;lti.Ml Wit hdra wals. dues , „ ~ J lir.i Full paid stock _ 14 _ Full paid stock. Interest _ tJHMI Cash on hand ..._ _ - 4.:;m ?:t Miscellaneous account! _ _ 10" Total _ — - ■? 3.11.670.09 SUPPLEMENTAL UEPOUT. Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organization _ M.0TOM Number of shares in force at date of last report .S.676 Number of shares issued during year _ 752% Footing of two preceding items '.&gt;.4'."- 1 « 752V4 Footing of twn preceding items.. Blier of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 880 her of shares of running stock in force at this date K.WlU .XCMI ■iiber of shares ,&gt;f full paid and matured stock in force at this date _ 44!t&gt; ■tins date _ -tw'h nher of shares in force at this date _ _ S.548J4 Number of shares loaned on _ _ 2.520 Number of shares on which dues arc delinquent _ H Number of borrowing stockholders - 2'-*'&gt; Number of non-borrowing stockholders i including minors) _ IM Number of minors holding stock in the association — '-'- Number of loans made for '..uildlng purposes during year 52 Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during ■year -... 2M value of each share of stock — $ 100.00 milt of interest, premiums and Hues due and unpaid l.WfcVO ..$ 100.00 Amount of interest, premiums and Hues due and unpaid Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 4 (5.320.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 249.163.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have I n made J 538.660.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security. - 299.380.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association 176.700.00 as collateral security - 176.700.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 400.00 Amount of li sses charged to reserve fund during year _ S91.85 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 7. 493. 11 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 3.399 81 Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 6% Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during 13 year </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the COMMERCIAL SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Patrick J. Sheehy Vice-President W. P. Adkins Secretary Jas. J. Fitzgerald Treasurer F. W. Thomas Attorney A. H. Murdock DIRECTORS. Patrick J. Sheehy D. J. O'Brien Frank Koutsky W. J. Coad L. T ". Et T. J. (~ri !-n W. P. Adkins C. Kohansky Jas. J. Fitzgereld ASSETS. First mortgage loans 5 938.KB.00 First mortfcatre loans in process of foreclosure 1.301.10 laaai l".(H».Oti e«tate_"."V.'r~".V.l_Z..............."......................_. - 17.036.70 Furniture ami fixtures 500.00 C,«h - TtMt* Delinquent interest - - 324.99 estate or contract &amp;3nl.Ml K LIABILITIES. ill stock running nines anil dividends* * 808.217.36 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues .uid diviilemls) * sl lii ';'!' •'' Full paid and matured stuck _ 1 '"»"_-_• "-"" ■'"' [mill and matured stuck — %nnn Iiidivided profits } t i\ I" iiplrlt* loans _ 11' -.i'- . 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 121 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPT8 Balance on hand July 1. 101.1 _ &gt;• 46.TW.0i I mos i running stock i :;&lt;n.747.-'4 Full paid stock _ ::■.. • Expense _ _ _ 1,415.10 ■ •state on contract - „ 41. '-WJ Mortgages In foreclosure 30.30 Loans repaid _._ _ _ 1 lj.1 mi.ihi Heal estate _ stork loam - - -~&gt;.\ Cash exchang s: expense - i.."tv Total f 855.118.ne EXPENDITURES Loans _ Salaries 2.(100.00 Real estate - - Expenses _ _ 8,651.3) Withdrawals, dues _ _ 286.574.40 Delinquent interest _ 34.04 expense _ 1,567.06 Mortgagees in foreclosure 1 1 lo.uo Full paid stock -''_'.7mu** Undivided profit! Cash on hand _ 27.85U Stock loans 32JMT.O0 •" W* - ■■.» »■*»«*■■«■** VfWW* W* Cash exeban Incomplete loans _ _ _ lit: . Reserve fund -. 3.110.M Total - - * &lt;i.V..llvi SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. plan of association _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation _ :;s.inh ■her of shares in force at date of last report 16,61 her of shares issued during year :!.»»: Footing of two preceding items.....'. _ 20.287 W Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year. _■ M'i'j Number of shares of running stock in force at tliis date 1&amp;93UV4 Number of shares of full paid and matured stuck in force &amp;t this date _ her of shares in force at this date _ 17.768 Number of shares in force at this date. Nomber of shares loaned on 6,423 Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors i 1.3ft" Number of minors holding stock in the association Number of loans made for building purposes daring year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgage* durin year - - 11- Plan of premium _ Monthly 11.' Par value of each share of stock -.$ 200.00 Amount of Interest due and unpaid KJ4.9H Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. 1 1.301. 10 Amount of loans on Improved real estate _ M6.863.'J0 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hnve been made - 1.876.025.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate 3.075.M Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans haw - been made 10,000.00 ■Mint of tire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association ■as collateral security _ si1i.77.-i.Kl nunt of advance payment of loans during year _ 118,3^2.20 829,775.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year..." 3,075.00 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year - 3.025.00 Amount of dividends declared on ruiniing stock during year 41.936.S3 3.025.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock taring year.. Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 9.774.11 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year... f.-; Rate per cent of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock dnrtng '■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PRUDENTIAL SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President W. C. Bullard Vice-President Chas. R. Sherman Secretary _ : D. H. Christie Treasurer D. D. Miller Attorneys Smyth, Smith &amp; Schall DIRECTORS. W. C. Bullard D. D. Miller T. E. Stevens E. A. Blum T. E. Wood KR. Sherman . Christie ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 224,200.23 Stock loans - _ 350.00 Real estate _ 1.035.10 Furniture and fixtures - - - 821.43 Cash 4JM.M Total - - - * 230.663.77 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ l'l'3.061 .2-.t Reserve fund 700.00 ..$ 223.0S1.9 Undivided proflts S26.J3 6.434.&lt;15 ■shareholders on incomplete loans 6.434. &lt;15 fees 1 1 OM Loan fees Total » 23O.W3.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1914. KKl Kir TS. Balance on hand July 1, 1913 Does (running stock) „$ 4.-...1 ftl.011.fil Interest _ 1-7 Membership and transfer fees 29B.70 Loans repaid, stock _ 190.00 Rents __ _ 286.00 Miscellaneous 14 i - Total - 4 1-'J.733.4S EXTENDIT IRES. Loans ...— ..— - - - - — •$ 51. Ss " "4 Salaries""...".—'. - 1,560.00 Rent, fees, etc ..... ..._._... — . — - — .. l.litl.15 Withdrawals 4H.O74.43 Cash on hand - 4,i"i6.»U Miscellaneous - 14. 770.17 Total— - - — - - * 1^.7:t3.43 BUPPLEMEN T AL REPUKT Plan of association — Permanent Number of shares issued since organization _ _ I 1&gt;' Number of shares in force at date of last report _ 8.8ft 1,330 Kier of shares issued during year — 1,320 ng of two preceding items- - 7.156 Footing of two preceding items. Number of shares matured and canceled during Tear, but nut with- nhcr of shores of rnnning stock in force at this date I Number of shares of running stock in force at this dat«" Number of shares in force at this date - Number of shares loaned on _ Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors). _... Number of minors holding stock in tlie association. Number of loans made for building purposes during year. _ 10 Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages daring K ear _- value of each share of stock _ * I" 1 " 1 unt of loans on imDroved real estate __ 21'4.1'iiip.^: 1 , Amount of loans on improved real estate. Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have tlOOTl 111 fl (lp i • ■■' __■■ ■■■■ i ■ ■ ■ i "riS,^ K tJ Kmt of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association s ■■■■I lateral security. - 244.200 00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association 230.000.00 as collateral security - --" ■' ■ Amount credited to reserve fund during year. _ - 1 "" 11 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year MM Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock ■liiiiiii; year - 1 ' Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during vear. </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day cf June, 1914. OFFICERS. Vice-President J. P. Leary Secretary A. D. Touzalin Treasurer L. D. Spaldinp DIRECTORS. W. D. Lincoln J. P. Leary A. D. Touzalin L. D. Spaldir.g ASSETS, First mortgage loans * 119,307.00 Stock loans IB Furniture and fixtures blOJfi Cash _ Delinquent interest, premiums .mil tines 427.6G Court costs MJB Incomplete loans 17:! 47 Total _ * IM.ML37 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) .su,7»4.i» Kpaid and matured stock _ 4O.'.tl ' ' ve fund 2O1.TO 201.90 Undivided profits _____ '..'. 233.93 Bills payable 2,000.00 _, . . g j.,^ j^j jj- </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. » RECEIPTS Balance on hand .Inly 1. 1913 $ J.M7.H7 Dues (running stock » _ "'.• Premiums 390.30 Loan fees - _ Loans repaid „ 1.'. : I payable ■lhuipous accounts _ _ immio.iim m 107.35 - laneous accounts _ _ m 107.35 Xotal | 110.2-t2.2d Xotal f 110,242 -''■ EXrKNDITl'ItES. Loans $ 26.74O.US uses \ '.'.IL'H.li; Stock redeemed - 00,01)8.54 Miscellaneous accounts _ 1.9OT.41 Cash on hand Paid up stock redeemed - l.".&gt;s~.T ( » Stock loan 7OO.U0 Total _ ...$ 110,242.28 SUPPLKMKNTAL REPORT. Plan of association _ Peraanrat Btier of shares issued since organization _ her of shares in force at date of last report 2.315 Nuuilier of shares issued during year _ 1.2.14 hit of two preceding items. _ 1.254 Footing of two preceding items Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year _ 2S1 Xumlier of shares (if running stock in force at this date ,"-. Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at this date _ Mf.i this date. Number of shares in force at this date. Number of shares loaned on 1.1'hJ Number of borrowing stockholders tffl XutnlK-r of non-borrowing stockholders Number of loaus made for building purpose! daring year 1 : Number of loans made for payment of homestead niortitartti durini vt'iir *&gt; Par'vnlue of each sbare of stock _ _..$ 100.00 8 Xumber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same, Xo. 1 — iMXio.iKt amount of snine. Xo. 1. Number and amount of mortgages in process Of foreclosure. No. 'J 3,0110.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 119,507.08 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - — JJ»,OltOu |&gt;unt of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 19O.55O.U0 Hint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association iatioii ■as collateral security _ 132.4OO.JW &gt;unt credited to reserve fund during year _ 242.73 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund - — Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3.6M Amount of interest paid on matured anil full paid stock daring year Rate per cent of dividend! declared on running stock during year BR Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock ■* • </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PAWNEE CITY SAVINGS AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PAWNEE CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1914. OFFICERS. President J. H. Shepherd Vice-President J. F. Wilson Secretary R. W. Story Treasurer G. E. Becker DIRECTORS. A. S. Story J. F. Griffith J. F. Wilson H. C. Hassler G. E. Becker R. W. Story J. C. Waddell Edwin Van Home J. H. Shepherd ASSETS Kirst mortgage loans „ $ 13,? C.«h " : ,_= 417.. iM'liiiiiiifiit Interest, premiums anil flues 71. 0 Total $ LIABILITIES Bal stock running (dues and dividends) _| it.8llO.-M red stock kkp.ihi _♦ 0.800.44 Matured stock.. Renerve fund 730.00 Tndivlded profits _ 161.Su Due shareholders on incomplete loans 1.000.00 Advance dues ..._ 1.0K6.16 Interest accrued on matured stock, ilncc iiiii I uri t.v _ 107.18 Interest accrued cm ndvniue payment of dues _. I'lTJ.'.M! Total. ..* 13.998.39 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 RECEIPTS. Balance on hand .July 1. l!tin Balance on hand July 1. 1M1 _ $ 1S9.WJ I Mies i ruuiiiiii: stock ) ~- —— _ l.'f.Hl. ."VI LttMJO Int.-r.-st _ 923.30 - ; _ | 5.«i 2S.W Membership and transfer fees - - - 23.no Loans repaid - 1.(100.00 Loans repaid. 4 4.-_-&gt; Total EXI'KXIM TIRKS $ 1,700.00 Commissions .. Other expense Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earning Matured stock Matured stock, interest Cash on haud Total...- - —I 4,228.37 8UPPLEMKNT AI. RETORT. Plan of association Permanent Xumlter of shares issued since organization .^ Mi Number of shares in force at date of last report — 143 B her of shares issued during year — 22 lag of two preceding items 187 Namber of shares withdrawn before maturity, during ye»r_ 4 Rlier nf shares matured during year - " intr of two nreeedimr items 11 Footing of two preceding items.. Numlier of shares of rsnalng stock in force at this date — 149 Xuinher of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at Number of shares in force at this date. Number of shares loaned on • - '4 Bin in iv'niir.i \&lt;i — z her nf shares on which dues are delinquent — . a Number of shares ■object to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Number of borrowing stock holders - - Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) — 24 Number of minors holding stock in the association _ Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages durin Av.-fail'e running time of stock matured during year — 114 months rear .\*&lt;-|.l^1 I lllllllll.K ! 1 .1.1 .'. ........ - T- .-- ,, l'ar value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders - - Bint of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid. — her of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate .-.::,.,., amount of same. Xo. 1 — ioSkiS imnt nf lnmis on ininroved real estate lo.oso.w Amount of loans on improved real estate. Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been 29.570.00 mmle L"j.om.uu Amount at Ire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ....-.— 14.7SU.UO Amount of tornado insurance in force ami assigned to the association 12,960.00 as collateral security.. 1,000.00 Amount of advance payment of loans during year 50.0. Ent credited to reserve fund during year — JSS nt of dividends declared on running stock during nt of interest paid on matured and full paid stock daring year Mllounr oi mieresi pimi on iiwiiiirn &lt;m&lt;i »«■■ r ..... ..v~. .. ■ - . - iier cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ■ c Kate i er cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year ■••i per cent of interest charged borrower- i </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PLATTSMOUTH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President E. P. Lutz Vice-President R. A. Bates Secretary T. M. Patterson Treasurer Fred T. Ramgc Attorney J. M. Leyda DIRECTORS K. Lutz . Bates Fred T. Ramge J. M. Leyda H. T. Goos T. J. Yanda C. A. Johnson T. M. Patterson E. W. Cook ASSETS Kirst mortgage loans $ M&amp;861.*™ First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure l.dl'.t.V.i Stock loans „ „ * 3,432.1 1 Real estate 578.54 Cash _ _ _ _____ , 1.9M.4I Delinquent dues, interest and fines ijT4.4n Taxes and insurance advanced 524.07 Total....- * 151 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and divldeiulsi $ 1-4 Full paid and matured stock '. .... 24.55O.S4 Reserve fund !_!ZZ 1,750.00 Undivided profits _ 840.56 Total - -..-.$ 151.834.23 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEITTS. Balance on hand July 1. Sli _ _ ? 1.743.' 35.." Dan irminintr stock) Full paid stock - .. - 22,800 "• Full paid stock - .. .. 22.NHI 10 Interest . 9,902.13 Interest ~ 9,902.18 p ill( . s j ,;i :•,(; Fine, ZZZZI '" ' 1 ■ •■"' « Memlversbip ami transfer fees _ - _ Mrmliership and transfrr fees _ - _ I. fans repaid ™ - - I' 1 ''- Tftxes repaid _ Taxes repaid _ 'Jl 1 '.*'^ Insurance repaid _ 1'.'.-'" Insurance repaid _ I'.'.-" Total - * gMSBJ Total _.._ * •.428J- EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURES. I ' $ B8.M000 $ 58.1WX sa la ri.-s ;;:;..:....:....:.:: S^il-i-." _____ 827.30 Commission •*'•' Other expenses - _ i:' 1 !! v Withdrawals, dues 1' i Withdrawals, dues 15.7S3 HO Withdrawal*, earning. — 1.381 -M Withdrawal*, earnings. — 1.381. Matured stock 1 .Ms. Matured stock. Interest - . I'" 1 "-' '«' Matured Mock, interest - - 952 Full paid stock ."...'. .Y7UM«» Full paid stock ...UM Full paid stock. Interest SS"?! Full paid stock. Interest - JOB. ■ hi hand - '', ■ - and insurance advanced - •'-"-' payable N ."' - .state expenses - ■_" Cask "ii hand *'SiS"2 - and Insurance advanced payable s, .,.,«, :.. tv Real estate expon oilier dislnirseinents ' v SS &lt; « 1 1 1»- 1- disbursement T ,,tal * M' *■■&gt;• SI I'ri.KMKNTAI. REPORT. T ,,tal * -'■' ■*■&gt; SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan tt association l'crinanent and Berl Plan of association l'erinanent and Serial Number &lt; &gt;f series issued since organization Number of series issued since mvanizat i ii. Nuinlier of shares issued since organisation - Mil Number of shares issued llnce organisation - Mdl Number of shares in force at date of last report 2,912 Number of shares in force at date of hist report 2,912 Number of shares issued during year - - 7S1 Number of shares issued dnrlng year _ - 7S1 Footing of two preceding items _ "■&gt;'•'■• Footing of two ptccedlBg items Number "f shares withdrawn before maturity, (luring year ,&gt;v_&gt; NiiTiilier nf shares withdrawn before maturity, during' year Number of shares matured daring year 14 Number of shares matured daring year 14 Number of shares canceled during year, hut not withdrawn &lt;; Nuinlier of shares canceled during year, luit not withdrawn h Ing of three preceding items ■■ og of three preceding Item Nuinlier of shares of roaming stock in force at this itate 2.973 Number of shares of running -tori In force at this date Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in fore* at this date - - 1*° Ils this ilat Number of shares in force at this date. Number of shares in force at this date :! ";'l J.001 Number of ibareii loaned on Nuinlier of shares loaned on S - M Nuinlier of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares on which dues are delinquent JjJ Numlier of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Boei "I &gt;n;t I c&gt; &gt;'ii ii n ii ■•■»— *■ ■ * ■ i f^ tier of shares suhjeet to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Number of borrowing stockholders Nuinlier of borrowing stockholders - Numlier of non-borrowing stockholders (Including ininorsi gfl Number of non-borrowing atocknolders (Including minor Bot'i oi miiiiii'iM'niii*. '■' " ■" ■■■&lt; i p. — her of minors holdlnjr stock in association - — -■_' Number of minors holding stock in association - Numlier of leans made for bnildlng purposes during year _ 13 Nnmber of loans made for building purposes during year. _ ■ Number "f loans made for payment of homestead mortgage*} durin Nuinlier of loans made for payment of homestead Mortgage! dnrlng year Wet-age running tin f stock matured during year 132 month* 132 in. •!. 1 1 1 Wefape running time of stock matured during year 132 months Tar value of each share of stock * T &lt;*' l'ar value of each share of stock * -'"' Total amount of dues delinquent at this date -. ■ Total 'amount of dues delinquent at this date .T.'Mll! Amount of dues owing hy borrowing shareholder! H'! 1 .'."', Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders -.. . Vtnoiint of interest, premiums and rines due and unpaid ggM Amount of interest, premium! and tines due and unpaid Number of mortgage! auhjeel to foreclosure, and the akgregati Numlier of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and the agicregate amount of same. No. 7. -• ■ — •' ■;''!■—. 3.«M B mount of same. So. 7. ■■ - • ■ ■ ♦••' .', her and aiuount of mortgage! in process of foreclosure. No. -i l.i'l.'....i NuiiiIkt and amount of mortgage* in process of foreclosure. No. l."i.'..,. .MliniHT aim iiiiiouui "i uviiMin &gt;■■ i ~&gt; -- »« — - ...... ,. Amount of loans on improved real estate - Amount of loans on improved real estate - 14. .X.I ■' Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been lmi which loans have been Appraised value of improved real estate uj 246.S5O.00 made -•o.oou.w Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association _ a a unilateral securitv - - ' k ' l-ltt Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association _ as collateral security — -.- I8T.iM.tJ as collateral security Ainouut of tornado ln*nran«C and assiirued to the association :\s collateral security '^.,iV-- Amount of tornado Insurance and aastgned to the association a collateral security Vmount of advaiK-c payment of loans daring year 1 '■ ■ iL' ". eoiiaH'rai sccuin* fl) . . .. Amount "f advance payme f loans during year 1 i,.ui_,...j Amount credited to reserve fluid during year - SiiiS Vmoiiiit credited to reserve fluid during year - -'i . E| 1 I ('I t*l| I It'll I" li-^*'i'r- mi"! ...t.. . — .. — — - ...»—_ - nt of losses charged to reserve fund during year _ -_i.sj in of dividends declared on running stock during year I'!;', 1 - - n. of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock durtng year l.-'ll..)! .,er cent of dividends declared on runnW s!o,-k durilHJ year per eeat of interest paid on matured and full paid s,ook during Amount of losses charged to reaerre fund ilurinK year _ U-..S. \nioiint of dividends declared on running stock during year _.. J-It', 1 -- Amoun. of Interest paid on matured and full paid stock durfciK year l.-ll.-n 1.211 Rnte tier cent of divid Is declared on running Mock dnriUK year Rate per (■.■nt of interest paid on matured and full paid stock daring Kfltt* |»*t evil i «»r mi* r* m * in i -» •! ■ ' ' </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President D. B. Smith Vice-President F. G. Egenberger Secretary C. G. Fricke Treasurer C. A. Marshall Attorney A. L. Tidd DIRECTORS. H. M. Soennischsen Wm. Holly H. S. Barthold C. A. Mars F. G. Egenberger F. E. Schlater C. A. Marshall Wm. Hassler D. B. Smith C. G. Fricke ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ _ $ 130,323.00 Stock loans IS,"!* 1 .'*! casb ; ;.:..... : -m «? Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines IJfj.M Rent account Jti'.l I Insurance and taxes paid and advanced _ _ MM Real estate contracts f,7SLM Real estate, contracts... Total 9 15-1 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends). _ _ 4 140,625.45 I'nil ividpd nroiits .- 3,710.70 Bills DflT&amp;blc - ,,.. ., ,. _„. J.40".'M) 11111 i*«j«i/*c Total * 154,742.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. K ce on hand July 1. Ml RECEIPTS, „.$ 1O.67-J.O9 I incs I running stock) 23,4^^| Membership and transfer fees I repaid _ 17,696.70 Heal estate contracts _ 625.16 Total I $ 83.494.31 EXPENDITURES. Loans $ 29.960.(0 Salaries _ 1.311.r&gt;0 Other expenses .. 138. 1." W i i lnl ra nn lg, dues_ .. _ _„ _ 10,31 ."&gt;.( m I Withdrawals, earnings 1 1.631.33 Matured stock _ „ „ I* 1 - Mat u red stock, interest - 7.111. W Caiili on hand _ "•■ &lt;; Insurance and taxes paid anil advanced 1. 4611.48 Kent ami repairs 1 444.'. ( _ Total $ 63.41't :;i SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. I Ma n of association 1 _ Serial Nam her of series issued since organization _ Til Number of shares issued since organization 10,174 Number of shares in force at date of last report _ 2,112 Bher of shuns issued during year _ ~&gt;77 iii)r of two preceding items „ _ _ I tM nir of two preceding items. Niiiulier of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 330 Number of shares matured during year _ _ 91 Footing of two preceding items. 421 Nuinlier of shares of running stock in force at this date _ ■_'..'*• Nninlier of shares in force at this date 2.26U Number of shares loaned on 1,2015 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of borrowing stockholders _ -17 Number of non-borrowing stockholder* (Including minors i 316 17 Nuinlier of minors holding stock In the association _ 17 Average running time of stock matured during year 131 months Par value of each share of stock _ Jt 2*15.00 Par value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders .,, 1,00MB Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid. 1.564 ( &gt;* Amount of loans on improved real estate 130,323.01 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 260 Bint of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association s co 11 n tcral seen rit y -._.._ 196, 14i KOO Bint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association s collateral security _ 17 ' Amount credited to reserve fund during year „ Am. ■unt of dividends declared on running stock during year. Am. ■unt of dividends declared on running stock during year Am. unt of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 7 141 .SO Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dating year \if '. Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SEWARD EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION SEWARD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President John Zimmerer Vice-President Geo. F. Dickman Secretary H. A. Graff Treasurer W. E. Langworthy Attorney J. J. ThomaS DIRECTORS. I 1 . Geesen C. Miller H. Smith J. M. Calder Roy R. Schick H. F. Goehner U. H. Franklin ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ * i:«j,600.0tj Stock loans 6,88&lt;MIU Furniture and fixtures _ 80ifl0 Cash ..." 2.4l!(t.i'ci Delinquent Interest, premiums and flues and dues— 855.0H Tax sale certificates - 17ri.tR* Insurance unpaid 43.(10 Office supplies — Total * 14' LIABILITIES. Capital stock running Idues and dividends) * 141.064.17 Beierve fund , Due shareholders on incomplete l":n~ 100.00 Advance dues Advance Interest and premiums ■'" N &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p133">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 133 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YE AR EN DING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1. Ml] _ _| &amp;M&amp;4I - (running stock).* „ _ r-o'tl 1.44 Membership and transfer fees „ _ _ 19OJ0 I.ti;i us rt'p;i ill .. IS,'! I nsuran&lt;*e repaid - Tax certificates paid )"•&lt;; M Total. EX1-KNKITIRES. Loans $ 4 • * *t her expenses _. 1' Ci.12 Withdrawals, dues _ '-'■* - Interest on overdrafts BLM Koii tin nil certificates ance — ....... -'. tj'*&gt; •#'! . _ «a33 Tax certificates ~ Total.. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association _._ _ -... Number of series Issued since organization _ — K her of shares issued since organization — - &gt;'._■-.' '-, her of shares in force at date of last report 1.815 Number of shares in force at date of last report Number of shares issued during year _ T4.'i Footing of two preceding Items. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 417 Bber of shares matured during year — M Ing of two preceding items _ _ _ - 36 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date_ Number of shares in force at iliis date _ - _ Jl'iVj Bber of shares loaned on - '•■'• her of shares on which dues are delinquent _ 71 ber of borrowing stockholders _ _ IM Number of non-borrowing (including minors) Number of minors holding stock in the association Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during 53 year — - ■ Average running time of stock matured during year 314 week Par value of each share of stock _ — * 300.(1(1 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 440.40 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders 309.00 Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 10 ■mount of same. No. 10.. Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 138,730.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ - 225.ftl8.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate _ 1.850.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have l&gt;een made .'. 4.0WMXJ l**en made. Amount of tire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1"&gt; S '■'■"■•" '"' Amount of tornado insuraine in force and assigned to the association ■as collateral security - 61.7'" i '"' Mint of advanre payment of loans during year _ 178.0U 61,790.00 Amount credited to reserve fund daring year 47'iW Amount of dividends declared on running stork during year 9.018.54 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during years Rate |*r cent of interest charged borrowers during year ." M </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SIDNEY LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION SIDNEY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President W. T. Bassett Vice-President J. R. Williams Secretary Robt. A. Barlow Treasurer Robt A. Barlow Attorney R. W. Devoe DIRECTORS. W. F. Bassett J. R. Williams R. W. Devoe Aug. Granneman Louis Jessen L. Neubauer J. M. Swanson L. O. Fundingsland R. A. Barlow ASSETS. B mortgage loans $ 26,80000 Iture and fixtures _ lfio.55 Cash * 461.34 Delinquent Interest, premiums and flti»« 26l!80 Expenses and taxes paid.- _ 3681 Total _ $ 27,72030 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 26,348.83 Reserve fund 1 I... " 632 'To Undivided profits "....." ' 1.1M.M Due shareholders on incomplete loans.-.. t 4m!oB Snspended stock __________■___________ &amp;&gt;.63 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 135 rCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on band July 1. 1913 _ $ taamma Full paid stock _ Membership and transfer fees I Total „ I _..| 7.207.45 EXPENDITURES Loans .. _ . 1 s 2M 7S ~ . , .... ............... .....■._.........„ y v,Mn.iw Salaries lOaOO other expenses „ Withdrawals, dues aud earnings 1.323.57 Cash on hand Total _ 4 7 .1117 .4" SUPPLEMENT AL REPORT. Plan of association _ Permanent Nuuil&gt;er of shares issued siuce organisation - _ 1,007 ■her of shares in force at date of last report 474 her of shares issued during year _ 75 ing of two preceding items .._„. ........ .*49 Kber of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 5 her of shares matured during year _ 8 her of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn 46 ing of three preceding items ia B M Footing of three preceding items Number of shares of running stock in force al this date _ 457 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at thi date _ Number of shares in foree at this date _ 490 Number of shares loaned OB - 151 Xu in tier of borrowing stockholders 19 Number of nan-borrowing stockholder! (including minors) _ 39 Number of minors holding stock in the association s Number of loans made for building purposes during year 4 Average running time of stork natured daring year _ 127 months Par value of each share of stock .' _. 4 200.00 Amount of dues owing by bf rowing shareholders 228.00 Amount of interest, premiums and tines due anil unpaid _ 261.80 Amount of loans on improved real estate. _ - 28,800.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 75.000.00 Bint of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association s col I a Tefal security .. 50,000.00 Knt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association collateral security _ _ 14.500.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ _ MjM Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.S15.45 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock daring year 60.79 60.79 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during; year 8% Kper cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during ear _ M Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION SOUTH OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President J. C. Michelsen Vice-President Wm. E. Davis Secretary Erie B. Brown Treasurer Perry McD. Wheeler Attorney A. C. Pancoast DIRECTORS. Richard DeYoung Jno. W. Koutsky Claud R. Orchard A. F. Stryker Thos. J. Parker C. L. Talbot ASSETS First mortpape loans _ $ 56.376.93 Furniture and fixtures lflOtM fa ah *WMt 1ft Total » $ 64 LIABILITIES Capital stock running (dues mid dividends! .$ M.M&amp;53 Full paid and matured stoik Jl.nOO.OO Reserve fund 628.20 Undivided profits... ........ 2.641.82 LI1U1\IU*'U prums... _.im/« Unfinished loans .._ 2,380.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 137 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on haml July 1, l'.uri _ _ _$ 3.331.K.1 - (running stock i.'. 1S&gt;" Full paid si.uk _ :;.^«i.imi repaid „ it; st...k loam repaid _ Total $ 4.V.41 H EXPENDITURES. - _ $ 12.11 Other expenses 458.55 Withdrawals, dues I _ 12. 4' M mT Full paid stock- I Full paid stock. Interest _ l 508 in Cash on hand _ Earnings credited invest t&gt;rs _ Stock loans.. Total.. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Pin n of association _ .. Per m a n.'iit Number of shares issued since organisation - Niinilier of shares in force at date of last report _ 2.12* Number of sliares issued during year 188 uiz of two preceding items Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 1 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force nt this this dale _ 21", Number of sliares in force at this date 2,OM Number of sliares loaned on T* Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ _ Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors &gt; Number of minors holding stock in the association _ 12 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1 Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages durii I yea r Par value of each share of stock $ ] ( »Mi0 Knt of ilues owing by borrowing shareholders nt of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have Iw-en made _ 1-"- ■&gt;unt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ 66.0.TIU1U as collateral security Amount of advance payment of loans during year Anii.unt credited to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 1,SO&gt;.M Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock aariag year - - M| Rate per mill iif l»l«nnl ifcaifg fclllUWlill ■■■!■! J— I I ii </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CITIZENS BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION SUPERIOR, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President W. S. Young Vice-President W. T. Long Secretary J. T. Robbins Treasurer W. A. Myers DIRECTORS. IS. Young P. Long A. Myers W. J. Elliott J. M. Silver John E. Eyre F. S. Southard Henry C. Devoe J. T. Robbins ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ _$ 88.00O.IW RmI estate — 501.20 Furniture and fixtures 50.01) Total „ _$ 77.460.08 LIABILITIES. Kal stock running (dues and dividends). _$ 40.970.43 paid and matured stock 29,900.00 ve fund 3.000.00 3.000.00 Undivided profits — UH&amp;M </seg>
            <seg id="p139">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 139 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. he( Eir TS Balance on hand July 1, ltl] Dues (running: stock) ,060.M 10,188*2 •j.tho.do 8,384.1* Bpaid stock Loans repaid Total. m EXPEND1 TUBES Loans 10.4O0.H) Salaries Other expense! 61.50 Vlrawals, dues Irawals. earning paid stock ■ paid stock. Interest on hand Total.. SCPPLEMENT AX BEPOBT. Plan of association Perm Number of shares in force at date of last report 1,588 Number of shares issued during; year _ 'JK ng of two preceding items lT'.M Nnmber of ibare* withdrawn before maturity, daring year _ ■bet &gt;&gt;f tfcarei withdrawn before maturity, daring year _ her of shares of running stock In force at this date 1,192 Number of Rhares of running stork in force at this date 1,192 1,182 Number of shares of full paid anil matured stock in force at this date IN Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at Bills date '_".«!&lt; her or shares in force at this date - 1.401 ?x Number or shares in force at this date - Number of shares loaned n!i.._ ......«_••_____..... . i'^i Number of borrowing shareholders 56 NumtxT of non-borrowing vtockbolden (inclndlng minors) Number of minors holrtincr stock in the association _ &lt;; Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate - 68.000.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made 90.0nrt.0i&gt; Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate „ 1.500.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - _ L'.500.i» Kint of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association 8 collateral sciuritv as collateral security Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association ■as collateral security- »unt of dividends declared on runnine stock during year...- Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year IMA3* Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ■»", ■f per cent of interest paid on matured and full paid nock during year M Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year t% </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the TECUMSEH BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION TECUMSEH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President P. A. Brundage Vice- President E. C. Hedrick Secretary J. B. Douglas Treasurer Harry Phelps Attorney J. C. Moore DIRECTORS. P. A. Brundage J. B. Douglas C. W. Graff E. C. Hedrick G. W. Hassett Harry Phelps R. F. Reynolds C. M. Shaw ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ $ 127,400.00 First mortgage loans in process of foreclomire _ - 1,800.00 Stock loans _ 6,300.00 Furniture and fixtures _ 227.9.~&gt; Cash ..." 2.417.M Delinquent interest, fines and dues _ 1.77-'.27 Total— _ $ 142.967.2tt LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ -$ llfi.lM ♦-' Paid-up stock l!».4Ui.ui i v "* w *-™— • ..-,., ., . Kup stock- ___ - 19,4DOM ve fund _ 2.8S1JM Undivided profits I _ 4.629.5&lt;i Advance dues __ _ ......'. _____ I 191.1*) Advance interest and premiums _ _ — , „ 21.00 rv_»— r\n </seg>
            <seg id="p141">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 141 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 i, 1914, llKt I II'TS. Balance on liuml .Inly 1. l ". ' 1 ." I Mies i riimi inir stock) - * 59S.7O 38.ft44.no Kpald stock. »st _ 21.5OO.OU 10,992.14 326.36 47&amp;M Membership nml transfer fe* Lam repaid 32.34(1.00 $ 105.17«.:Sfi Total EXPEND1 TIKES » 52,«15.00 lllKUW Commission! ..... ITS.'. I Other expenses Kdrawals. dues... (irawals. earnin red stock 11.288.00 1.4&lt;H.77 17.2?&gt; Matured stook. Interest Full paid stock- 8.182.78 ino.no 307.40 ■ paid stork, interest on hand 417.04 98.11 Interest on overdraft. Total. sri'IT.KMKN T AL REPORT Plan of association - Serial Number of series issued since organ laatiOB ■ber of sliarcs issued since organization _ TJH her of shares In force at date of last report _ 3.1fifi Number of shares in force nt date of last report.. Number of shares issued daring year _ - — 7 V &lt;! Footlnir of two lirecedliiir Items _ MB Footing of two preceding Items. Number of shares, witlidrnwn before maturity, during year. 3«fi Number of shares uintiired daring year... Footing of two preceding items Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 3.05T&gt; Kher of shares of paid-up stock in force at this date 194 lw»r of shares in force nt this date - -'■-*'■* Number of shares in force at this date. Number of shares loaned on - !■••}•' Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ - - Number of borrowing stockholders _ [35 Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors) 144 Number of minors holding Rtook in the association - - IS Number of loans made for building purposes during ye:ir.._ 7 Average running time of stock matured during year __ _ il'/b I11O1 '"' S P«r vnlne of ench share of stock - — " WO.IIM Par value of each share of stock.. wi.no Total amount of dues delinquent nt this date - _ iSI'Jl! Amount of dues owing hy borrowing shareholders iionU Amount of Interest and fines due and unpaid UXm Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate B mount of same. No. &lt;1 - - ber and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure. No. 1 - ,,yi'Vnr. Ao 127.4O(H»i Amount of loans on improved real estate.. Eised value of improved real estate upon which loans have oiO1 -, m , Ll . t . 1 -I I 1 I . ______ _L ■■■■■■!- - ■ MTV, 1 I''.' T^Il IlliM I " ..-...-..,*.---._-------- — ■._.__■.-•♦...■..-&gt;.-------'---■--■■----*•-----—--*•-•--•-•- - nt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 162.480.00 Kint of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association s collateral security - jl_Vfw\ KB couarerai security - - Voiinn int credited to reserve fund during year - - *.,,'•■' Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year \monnt of interest paid on paid-up stock during year Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest paid on paid-up stock during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the TRENTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION TRENTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President O. E. Reynolds Vice- President S. Hill Secretary J. R. Greenhalgh DIRECTORS. ■E. Reynolds 1. Greenhalgh E. Reynolds J. C. Hurst A. T. McCoy R. H. Pember O. W. DeWald C. L. Allen S. Hill ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ „ „ .$ '.».Tm&lt;uio Cash _ _ ______ ' MLM Expenses and taxes paid- _ _____ __H Total _ _ ....J 10,400.41 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (due* and dividends) 4 BJMJ_ Undivided profits- 2,216.41 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 143 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE SO 1914 RE( EIF TS Balance on hand July 1, 1913 4 SJM8.W Dues (running stock) _ 3,620.00 3.620.00 Interest " _ _ 935.75 Fines _ _ __ 4.10 lOfli Membership and transfer fees _ 10.00 Loans repaid _ S.K » ' .00 Loans repaid. Total $ 14.238.J1 EXPENDITURES Loans - - 4 3.650.00 Salaries _ _ 180.00 Other expenses — _ ~ - 40. s~&gt; Withdrawals, dues 913.00 Withdrawals, earnings 1SJ.00 Matured stock 9,100.00 Cash on hand _ HM Total _ .$ 14,2!S.51 SUPPLEMEN 1 A I. KEI'ORT. Plan of association Serial ■her of series issued since organization 10 ber of shares Issued since organization l,577&gt;4i n „..__ , 10 Number of shares Issued since organization. Number of shares in force at date of last report 314 Number of shares issued during year _ 104*4 Footing of two preceding items m - 418^4 104 Vj Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year 35 I her of shares matured during year 91 ing of two preceding items _ — l-'i ber of shares of running stock in force at this date ber of shares in force at this date __■ ber of shares loaned on _ _ _. MV Number of borrowing stockholders _ 18 Bber of non-borrowing stockholders 32 ber of loans made for building purposes during year 6 of premium ...—..... Bivl age running time of stock matured during year _ 78 month* Par value of each share of stock ! — _$ 100.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ _ 9,050.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 15,000.00 ount of loans upon unimproved real estate 500.00 15.000.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate. Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - _ 750.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 14,000.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ tt&gt;,000.n0 Hate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year Mft </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION VALENTINE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President H. W. Hoeni* Vice-President W. S. Barker Secretary J. T. Keeley Treasurer F. A. Cumbow DIRECTORS. ■W. Hoenig S. Barker r. Keeley F. A. Cumbow W. T. Kincaid E. C. Davenport John M. Tucker L. L. Bivens Charles Lewis ASSETS. First mortgage loans... _ $ 123,930.00 First mortgage loans In pr&lt;xt i s« of foreclorarr _ _ _... ri«'. 10 Stock loans _ 1.WO.O0 Delinquent interest, premiums mid tint's _ „ Total $ 133.47'' H LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends &gt; S 131.201.71 Reserve fund 2.16317 St." k enueeled on account of delinquency and credited to account of party delinquent 115.00 party delinquent Total $ 133. 479. SS </seg>
            <seg id="p145">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 145 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE J 30 1914. RECEIPTS, Balance oa band .Inly 1. IMS _ _$ 1.948.17 1 nifv (running stock i _ 10.4mt.nii - __ ; ;;;....;; ; ;; ; ■&gt; Membership and transfer tee* _ TLM Loans repaid C 192 41 Taxes I _ ur,.", I'r. 'inillnis. insiwaiirc policiM _ _ IT'.i Total S :;•- EXPEXDI I [RE8 Loans $ 31,430.00 S:l hi rit'S _ 425.' ■ ' Other expense! 134.M Withdrawals, duos &lt; 'a sh mi lia ml _ Insurance premiums in ,7~&gt; nit advance pajrmenl Total $ 38 - SI'I'I'I.EMKN I \l. REPORT. I'lini of association. Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares issued since organisation _ :: 133 .Number of shares ill force at elate of last report 1.4js Number of shares issued during year _ 294 Footing of two preceding items _ i.Tj Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year (Hi Number of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn 5 Footing of two preceding items _ _ 71 Somber of shares of running stock in force at this date . UN Number of shares in force at this date _ _ 1.431 Number of shares loaned on _ (t Bber of shares on which dues are delinquent 28 l&gt;er of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues 11 Number of borrowing stockholder* „ 147 Number of non-borrowing stockholders i including minors) _ 17M Number of minors holding stork in the association Number of loans made for building purposes during year 28 Par value of eneh share of stock _ _ $ Linio Par value of each share of stock. Total amount of dues delinquent at this date - 436.&lt;W Amount of ilues owing by borrowing shareholders _ _ L'M.^i Amount of interest, premiums and fines &lt;1ue and unpaid _ 207.90 Kber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, auii the aggregate mount of same. No. 5 _ 2.500.00 Number and amount of inortiraLros in process of foreclosure. No. 2.™ Amount of loans upon Improved real estate _ 123.8 ■ raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 287,061.1 ■unit of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security __. _ 181.710"" ■&gt;nnt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security „ 30.**" 11 "" Amount credited to reserve fund during year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year _ Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 11.081.22 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 1 1 v , Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FIRST BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION UNIVERSITY PLACE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President A. L. Johnson Vice-President E. D. Currier Secretory G. E. Currier Treasurer B. H. Schaberg Attorney W. R. Gaylord DIRECTORS. BL. Johnson D. Currier '£. Schaberg G. E. Currier H. B. Smith Chas. H. Roper W. G. Bishop Chas. F. Homer W. R. Gaylord W. G. Bishop ASSETS. Cash _ _$ l.tioC. 2&lt;i Total- 4 l.Wfl.JO LIABILITIES. Capital «tock running (doe* and dividends) $ MUQ Full paid stock 1.600.00 1.600.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p147">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 147 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RE( EII TS. Dues (running Full paid stock tocki 305.20 1,600.00 Total 1.9O.-..2.. KXl'ENDIT uhes Cash on band 1.905/J0 Total. 1,005.3) SUPPLEMENTAL REPOItT Plan of association Pernian Number of shares Issued since organization 281 Number of shares issued during year _M Number of shares of running stock in force at tins date _ "_'t*j Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force mi tlii date 16 Number of shares in force nt this date HI Number of non -borrowing stockholders (including minors) Number of minors holding stock in the association 1 Pax value of each share of stock 4 MOuM </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WAHOO MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION WAHOO, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Ben D. Rupp Vice-President J. L. Winter Secretary H. M. Stratton Treasurer J. J. Johnson Attorney G. W. Simpson DIRECTORS. Jas. O'Donnell R. F. McCreery M. A. Phelps L. J. Gudrna F. J. Kirchman G. W. Simpson ASSETS. First Mortgage Loans _ $ 130.OTiO.00 Stock loans— .'. _ ——————— [ 300.0U Furniture and fixtures 1 ZZZZZZZ— — __ 1.1 150.00 Cash ■ 1- 1 .403.62 Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines 348.16 Taxes paid I 30.75 Other assets _ 89.00 Total— _ _ _ t 132.41:;. 4:t LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ -4 127,612.43 Reserve fund_ 3.700.00 Due shareholders on incomplete loans- _ 1,100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p149">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 149 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. REC EIPTS Balance on hand July 1. 1013 _ _ $ 1.71". 77 I'm** &lt; ru n u i M;r stork) _ 24 i - 1'reniiums . 1 ! |v^&gt; Members h ip :t nd transfer fees 1 141 7" LoaaM repaid _ mil accounts . 1 0QD.M Total « 41.8*1.1 « EXPENPITTRES. Loans _ * O.IOO.no Salaries flfin.no Other expenses SIS 1" Withdrawals, dues _ 22.6fl2.OI Wit hd rawals. earning** — i n tl 1 7 ii'l '_'l M. 'i tu red stork _ ft4.00 M:i tnred stock. Interest - Cash on hand ■ nal accounts - K.HI Total -* 41.861.flB ST'PPLEMKN T AI. REPOBT. Plan of association Number of atrtai issued since orfmnisatlon - 41 Numher of shares Issued since organization _ - in.152 Bher of shares in force at date of last report 4.OMJ her of shares Issued during year 47T&gt; Footing of two preceding Items 4.580 Numher of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year 003 ■her i&gt;f shares matured during year 33 Ing of two preceding items jM her of shares of running stock in force at this date 3.!WI&gt; Number of shares of running stoct in force at this date Number of shares in force at this date Numher of shares loaned on _ _ - 1.204' Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 246 Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors! _ M Number of minors holding stock in the association _ — 4 Number of loans made for building purposes daring rear I ■aber of loans made for payment of homestead mortsnt-'es during year _ - Plan of premium ., . Monthly. 1." cents per share Average running time of stock matured during year - 12l&gt; n 125 m. Par value of each share of stock _ * lnmw Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 2270n Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders 2O7.&lt;*&gt; Knt of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 2Ki.r53 nt of loans on Improved real estate _ 130.(kV&gt;.nn Amount of loans on Improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 201.380.00 Iinnt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 144.380.00 &gt;unt of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 100.4nn.0i&gt; Ent of advance payment of loans during year 4.086.00 nt credited to reserve fund during year_ _ 350.00 350.011 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 9.133.00 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock durinc year _ Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year _ ._ at _J I _ *W * - _..tl.l_ Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year 15 cent* monthly </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SALINE COUNTY BUILDING ASSOCIATION WILBER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President Jos. Cerny Vice-President H. W acker Secretary J. J. Novak Treasurer F. V. Shabata Attorney J. F. Spirk DIRECTORS V. J. Kohout V. B. Prucha Anton Sagl H. Binger E. J. Prucha Jos. Bartos John Houser Alois Borecky Frank Sasek ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ „ f 80T.t."iiNi Stock loans Cash i,oiS Kl 1.018 Kl Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 18.00 Delinquent dues _ 54.00 Total $ 83,988.49 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) _ t 82,440.85 Reserve fund „ _. _ 1,172.00 Undivided profits .... . .... _ 15.39 Advance dues _ 328.75 328.73 Autnun: uuca m ™..™..™__ .._-...' Advance interest and premiums..- 5.oO </seg>
            <seg id="p151">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 151 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914 KEC v IPTS. Balance on hand July 1. 1913 _ $ 365.10 Dues {running stock i _ 31,835.00 Interest _ - 5,121.11 Premiums _ 20.17 - _ _ KM Membership niwl transfer fees „ 141.75 Loans repaid 25 555 U) Total _ _ _ _ _ - % (B.tiTiVM EXPENDI TURKS * * T .-..—... ..— --.- —V " • ■ Salaries _ 2.mn&gt; other expenses _ _ _ 1SBJ3 Withdrawals, .lues 19.878.50 Withdraw aU. earnings - Mil I u red stock _ 11 ' Matared stork, interest _ -,-':&gt;i;.."&gt;.: Cast on hand 1.018.49 Total - - $ 63- SLPPLKMKN T AL REPORT. Pla n of association - — - Ser ia 1 Number of series issued since organization _ H Nunit&gt;er of shares issued since organization _ UNMi Number of shares in force at date of last report 1.117 Nuiul&gt;er of shares issued daring year iSJVi Footing of two preceding shares _ _ _ 1.4flO'^ 288K Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year Number of shares matured during year _ _ 68H Footing of two preceding Hems _ _ 2W54 88U rUOUUg Ol IWU ptCtTUlUJ^ Jiruin — -- ' J Number of shares in force at this date 1 Mi Number of shares loaned on _ 4.&gt;'-j Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of borrowing stockholders — 88 Xnmlwr of non-borrowing stockholders (including minorsi 164 Number of minors holding stock iu the association— M Bber of loans made for building purposes during year. 1 5 »ge running time of stock matured during year _ 76 months Par value of each share of stock .' - 1 200.110 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date- _ 54.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _ 41.50 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ _ 18.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate _ - T9.O75.no 18.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate. Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ - 15H Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate _ 1, 18ft W Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made — - 8,000.00 Amount of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - 85,650.00 Amount. of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 74.675.00 Amount of advance payment of ioans during year _ _ s.iim mi Knt credited to reserve fund taring year - 1 '-' 1 " 1 nt of divideuds declared on running stock during year 5.i:i.'i.l- Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Vt/% </seg>
            <seg id="p152">TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 152 STATEMENT of the condition of the WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATE : WOOD RIVER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President T. A. Evans Vice-President S. M. Nelson Secretary W. L. Sprague Treasurer M. C. Wingert DIRECTORS. T. A. Evans J. E. Hoye S. M. Nelson John Harper D. V. McKee W. S. Warren H. A. Schwartz C. L. McGlasson J. W. Cunningham ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ _...$ 64,600.00 Stock loans j 600.00 Cash _ _ 52.61 82.81 I&gt;eliiii|ueiit interest, premiums, flues anil dues 346.75 Total _ „ $ 65,599.36 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 63.192.45 Reserve fund _ I l!82l!94 Bvided profits _ ....'....'."...'....'.'.'.' " 159.27 nee dues. _ I 421.80 421.80 Advance interest and premiums „ „ 3.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p153">153 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING I JUNE 30, 1914. JUNE S 1914. RECEIPTS, RF.CEIF ■is Ralance on hand July 1. 1913 Dues (running stock i ice on hand July 1. 1013 _ $ 4 4»1.42 I I r n nn i ni: stock t «. 11'."" pst 4."-" ■ Premiums iu ins 822.70 Membership anil transfer ttt Loans repaid KTslilp ami transfer fees • 3 repaid 1 .'i.itOO.flO Total * M ■"■ Total KXl'KMHTTHKS. EXPEXD1 1 THF.K. s $ 14.-.i»m«. I4.5m.no leg _ 420.00 420.00 Other ex pens r expenses „ _ Rdrawals. dues drawals. earning red stock drawals. dues dra wals. €*a mings _ I s red stock .... ll.2in.flO 11.J1KMKI Matured stock, interest 41 '.&lt;~ Matured stock. interest- Cash on hand 41"T Cash on hand - - B2.U 52.61 Total $ SU4S Total.. rii;..",4j SITI'I.KMKNTAL MBPOBT. 8TPPLEMEX T AL HEITIRT. Plan of association Serin 1 and Permanent Plan of association Serial and Permanent Number of series issued sime organisation _ IT Number of series issued since ori- r :ui iz:U ion _ IT Number of shares issued since organisation 4.W Number of shares in force at dnte of hist report _ I.t571 Number of shares In force at date of hist report _ 1.871 Number of shares issued during year _ 411 Kber of shares Issued during year _ 411 ing of two preceding Items Footing of two preceding items Footing of two preceding items. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, daring year L'"7 ■her of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year L'."7 ber of shares matured during year _ 112 Ing »»f two preceding items - - 3'?-' Number of shares matured during year _ 112 Footing of two preceding items - - Mi Footing of two preceding Items Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 1.713 Number of shares of running stock in force at this &lt;l:n ■ 1.713 Number of shares in force at this date- - 1.713 Number of shares in force at this date- - 1.713 Number of shares loaned on Number of shares loaned on Number of shares on watch dues are delinquent 76 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 76 Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Number of shares inbject '" cancellation for nonpayment of due Number of borrowing stockholders Number of borrowing atockaolden - - Number of non-borrowing stockholders (Including minor Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minor* I Number of minors holding stock in the association 12 Number of minors holding stock in the association 1- Plan of premium — Fixed Kof ]( rein in in — Fixed ire running time of stock matured during year _ 113 months Fixed Average running time of stock matured daring year _ 115 months Average running time of stock matured daring real Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 Par value of eacn snare of stock $ lim.nn Total amount of dues delinquent at this date IC.'.iki Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 162.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders 16O.S0 Amount of dues owlag by burrow lag shareholders 16O.S0 Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid IM.T'i Amount of Interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid 1M.7."i Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 3 _ 2.(100.00 Kber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. 3 _ 2.000.00 amount of same. No. Amount of loans on improved real estate 64.0nn.no Amount of loans on improved real estate. Appraised value of improved real estate ft4.lil»UKi Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 1' "&gt;' upon which loans have been made Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security v " as collateral security Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 83.420.00 Amount of advance payment of loans during year _ 13,900.00 AniMiint credited to resoiye fund daring year - 219.S0 219.S0 Amount of dividends-ttpcllnred on running stock ■■ring venr. Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock daring year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durii - </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WYMORE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WYMORE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President J. A. Reulinsr Vice-President A. T. Sherman Second Vice-President D. A. Lasher Secretary G. T. Stephenson Treasurer W. A. Dawson Attorney E. N. Kauffman DIRECTORS. J. A. Reuling A. T. Sherman G. T. Stephenson W. A. Dawson C. N. Miller L. Bridenthal D. A. Lasher ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ 41.9TiO.iO Stock loans 400.110 4OO.IW Furniture and fixtures 193.00 Cash : 3,492.5i Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 63.75 Expenses and taxes paid _ _ TmAO R5.«O Insurance 1 85 00 Taxes _ I ' MJt Total _ .$ 4tt.336.43 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) i $ 17.779.04 Full paid and matured stock I „ 26.300.00 Interest _ _ . 3.H3S.41 Reserve fund f 35o!o» Undivided profits i 1.907.39 </seg>
            <seg id="p155">155 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. HE( EII TS. Balitnce on band July 1. 1!H3. Dues (running stock) 1 _* S,333.!Ml Full paid stock Interest 13.100.00 53.8.41 Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid 290.50 2.350.0 Incidentals 4.46 Total. * 28.374.40 EXPENDITT l r.s Loans _ _ _ Jf 12,800.00 Salaries I Other expenses „ _ _ 1'St V&gt; Withdrawals, dues — 4.202.80 Matured stock, interest Matured stock, interest 1 :!74 06 Full paid stock _ 4.40o!oO 4.400.00 Full paid stock, interest 1 .211'. 2: Cash on band I nsu ranee — I Surplus _ _ _ Lt&amp;JB Total.. SUPPLEMENT A I. REPORT. Plan of association Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization _ 1.J77 Number of shares in force at date of last report _ 72S K&gt;er of shares issued during year . 351 ng of two preceding items 1 nT'.i Footing of two preceding items Bber of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year.- 140 ber of shares of running stock in force at this date 676 .676 Number of shares of full paid and matured stock in force at tliis date Number of shares in force at this date 931&gt; Number of shares on which dues are delinquent. Number of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of &lt;lucs 40 Number of borrowing stockholders ■ Number of non-borrowing stockholders (including minors i._ S3 Number of minors holding stock in the association 19 Number of loans made for building purposes during year " Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during vear Par value of each share of stock $ 101.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ _ 400.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders _ 294.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 63.75 Bber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of same. No. Lj 1.500.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 41.SSO.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 07.500.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate _ 500.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made- UMUM ■&gt;unt of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security... _ _ M£S0 00 ■)unt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ 47,875.00 Amount credited to reserve fund taring year 139.25 .1UIUUIII ,HT11HC» &gt;'■ ■ ■■■ LB VI lllliil illliiiip. ..*..&lt; m Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year.- 1.374.06 Amount of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during year 1.212.22 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year _ 10% Kper cent of interest paid on matured and full paid stock during ear — - ■ |H </seg>
            <seg id="p156">156 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the YORK MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President George W. Shreck Vice-President Chas. A. McCloud Secretary Hattie S. Reed Treasurer Geo. H. Holdeman Attorney W. W. Wyckoff DIRECTORS. George W. Shreck Chas. A. McCloud Hattie S. Reed Geo. H. Holdeman C. J. Trauger W. W. Wyckoff W. L. White W. L. White H. M. Childs N. A. Dean ASSETS. First mortgage loans $ Ut, f &lt; n i First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure 1.730.23 Stock loans _ j £700i&lt;M Furniture and fixtures ____.„ i Delinquent interest, premiums and fines Total _ _ t 147. til rj ,:i7 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ Mfc258.M Reserve fund 5,114.96 Undivided profits ____ZZ^__Z ... 230.17 Total s 147 • </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1913 _ $ IO5.41 Dues (running stock) ~ „ Interest and premiums .... __„.._„ 10.4t&gt;** 87 Fines _ 736. 7S Membership and transfer fees ?U 00 Loans reDaid 39.300.00 Rents ....'.. - 47 IT. Total „„__.. _ — . .$ 10*. ' ■ EXPENDITURES. Loans $ 67,!&gt;no.o&lt; Salaries 780.00 Other expenses _ .".:i7.74 Withdrawals, dues _ 81.12O.S0 Withdrawals, earnings - 5,180.88 Cash on hand _ 4.J44.-.1 180.*] Cash on band.. Total.. t 108.823.91 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association - Combinati";i Number of series issued since organization _ _4J Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares In force at date of last report „ _.»..... 4 ■ber of shares issued during year 1.211 Ine of two nrecedine items I HI Footing of two preceding Items.. Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during year *47 Number of shares canceled during year, but not withdrawn lit! Footing of two preceding items _ - __ 873 Number of shares of running stock in force at this date 3.113 Number of shares inforce at this date _ - 5.113 Number of shares loaned on 1.411 Bber of shares on which dues are delinquent...- _ 301 ber of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Number of borrowing stockholders — Number of non-borrowing stockholders {including minors).. ■ber of minors holding stock in the association _ her of loans made for building purposes during year 1" ■iber of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during Yen- ■___. _ 24 .* n ' • ■- -—- « ... -.-- — Plan of premium - Weekly Average running time of stock matured during year 85 months Par value of each share of stock _ — $ Hhj.ihi Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders 2S3.20 Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid.. Kber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate mount of sump. No. 3 - - 1 (100.00 Bber and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure. No. •_' 1.730.23 lint of loans on improved real estnte .•-.. 134.800.00 ■ raised value of improved real estate upon which loans have t&gt;een made - Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate I.fiiiO.OO Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made- Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — -— 130.000.00 \mount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ljsomuin ■as collateral security &gt;unt of advuneed payment on loans during year. 39.500.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ,, VlJf ?V Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year _ 9.401..j4 Rate per cent of dividends declared on mining stock during year... Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year — . Jwj_ i-ent of i&gt;rciuiunis diarized borrowers durinir vear.... naie p* r i^ in * i </seg>
            <seg id="p158">158 TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WORKINGMEN'S SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1914. OFFICERS. President C. A. McCloud Vice-President , N. A. Dean Secretary W. W. Wyckoff Treasurer G. H. Holdeman Attorney W. W. Wyckoff DIRECTORS. ■k.. McCloud A. Dean W. W. Wyckoff G. H. Holdeman J. N. Kildow ASSETS. First mortgage loans _ _ :.._ _ j$ N5.70O.00 LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) t 18.741.flB Reserve fund Undivided profits _ 367.19 — ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p159">159 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1914. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1. 1013 Imips (running stock* _ I O7 "■ latereot Preminms 140.00 Plan ______________________ I 6.15 Membership and transfer fee 157.00 Loans repaid... _ _____ - 2.300.00 Money borrowed 1.425.00 Total * 12.JW.71 EXPEND! TT'RES 1 * 6.500.10 fe 50110 Ormmisslons Other expensi (u.as 35.60 Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earning Matured stock 1.152.15 615.M 2.000.00 D hand 4R2.T! wrtfl Interpst on withdrawals Repaid money borrowed Imprest on monpy borrowed. 1,426.0* 15.08 Total Sri'PI.EMEN T AI, REPORT Permanent PUn of association. Manner of iharri issued since organixatl 1.762 n Number &lt;&gt;f shares in force at date of last report _ .186 NuinluT of shares issued during year - 581 FtMting of two preceding Items Xumtier of shares withdrawn before maturity, during yenr Number of shares matured during year Bins of two preceding items 1 ■ her of shares of running slock in force at thlR date — IN* Nuniher of shares in forcp at this date Number of slaves loanpd on - — 167 Number of borrowinc stockholders 27 Number of non -tmrrnwins stockholders i incliidini: minors*. Number of minors holding sio.k in the association _ .. Nnmlier of loans made for holldlnR purposes ilnrinir year Nimiher of loans made for payment of homestead mortsasre* daring year Plan of premium Kof premium....-..- 'On faoe of loan&gt; ge ruiiniTitr time of sto&lt;'k matured durintr year 41 months ■value of earn share of stock * 100.00 nnt of loans on improved real estate - lfi.r&gt;00.00 Kised value of improved real estate upon which loans have &gt;n made - 44.400.00 been made Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate 200.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made .1OO.n0 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the astoeiation as* collateral security - 20.650.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - 2O.6BO.OO Amount credited to reserve fund durinir year ";"'."! ■ lateral security 57.00 Knt cremten to reserve tuim uurinir yeiir .'«.'- - nt of dividends declared on rnniiinir stock during year 1 NMI Rate per cent of dividends declare. 1 on running stock during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year ion face </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>