<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00043.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00043.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Fifth Annual Report of the Secretary of the State Banking Board Showing the Condition of the Building and Loan Associations of Nebraska for the year ending June 30, 1917</title>
               <date value="1917-09-04">1917-09-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE 8TATE BANKING BOARD SEPTEMBER 4, 1917 J. J. TOOLEY, Secretary 1917 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">DEPARTMENT OF BANKING OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA BOARD HON. KEITH NEVILLE Governor, President HON. W. H. SMITH Auditor of Public Accounts HON. WILLIS E. REED Attorney General J. J. TOOLEY Secretary JOSEPH V. JOHNSON Clerk RUTH STREITZ Assistant Clerk ANNA GASS Assistant Clerk TILLIE C. EPPENS Stenographer EXAMINERS S. M. PATTERSON S. A. LAPP M. R. SULLIVAN A. D. TOUZALIN T. P. SMITH CHAS. R. WHITE J. H. WEHN S. M. HALL E. E. EMMETT J. H. DONNELLY </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 3 State of Nebraska, Department of Banking, Lincoln, Semptember 1, 1917. To the Honorables Keith Neville, Governor ; William H. Smith, Auditor; Willis E. Reed, Attorney General; Members of the State Banking Board Gentlemen : Permit me the honor of submitting herewith the 25th Annual Report of the Banking Department covering in a gen - eral way the operation of Building and Loan Associations and showing their condition at the close of the fiscal year, June 30th, 1917. This report is a compilation of the annual reports of the seventy-three associations legally authorized to do busi - ness in the State as submitted to the Department in compliance with the requirements of the Building and Loan Act. By comparing this report with those submitted in years past an accurate and intelligent conclusion may be reached with special reference to the operation, economy of manage - ment and growth of each association. A comparison of the combined statement with that of last year discloses the fact that a very satisfactory growth has been made in total re - sources. During the period covered the combined assets have increased $6,627,782.70 being approximately $400,000.00 in excess of the increase shown in the last report. This uninter - rupted growth and expansion is indicative of the popularity of these associations among home builders and discriminating investors. Coupled with this steady growth is also to be noted the fact that the amount of mortgages in process of fore - closure and those subject to foreclosure shows a slight decrease though not as pronounced perhaps, as it should be, yet indi - cating, at least, a firmer policy in the matter of collecting th« periodical installments. These associations occupy a distinctive field in the gen - eral business scheme and are as a whole, I am pleased to report, under the guidance of men of integrity and business ability. However, the steady flow into their treasuries of investment funds, attracted by the liberal rate of dividends paid on paid - up stock, has in many instances led to the acceptance of loans with an insufficient margin of security and which, no douubt, would have been rejected had not available funds for loaning purposes been greater than the demand carrying the best class of security. It is such loans as these which eventually have to </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Equidated through foreclosure proceedings and not infre - tly at a loss to the associations. Attention is called to the rate of interest charged to borrowers which is altogether too high, the average being as shown in the report, eleven per cent including premium charges. A few associations have, during the year, volun - tarily reduced their rates but unless such action becomes more general and more radical it will become the imperative duty of the Legislature to fix a rate fair both to the borrower and the associations. (Amended Sections of the Law) tThe last Legislature responsive to the necessities grow - iut of an enlarged volume of business of these associations ted amendments to law governing them as follows : 485. Sec. 1. Building and loan associations — name — powers — limitation on loans. Any association of not less than five persons incorporated under the laws of this state, which shall be organized within this state for the purpose of raising money to be loaned among its members, shall in the further - ance of such purpose, and after having complied with the requirements of this chapter, be authorized and empowered to levy, assess, and collect from its members such sums of money, by rates of stated dues, fines, interest and premium on loans, as the corporation may provide for in its constitution or by-laws, and to exercise such other powers as are herein provided; every such corporation may, however, receive pay - ments from its members in any amount, which, together with the balance formerly to the credit of the member thus paying, upon the books of the corporation, if any, shall not exceed the par value of the shares of stock held by him ; provided no per - son shall hold in his own right more than Five thousand dol - iars ($5,000.00) of investment stock in any such corporation and that no person shall vote in his own right or as proxy more than Five thousand ($5,000.00) Dollars par value of stock in any such corporation. Provided further, that in any association in which the value of its assets is more than $200,000.00 and does not exceed the sum of $500,000.00, borrowing members may hold stock to the amount of $10,000.00, and in any association whose assets exceed $500,000.00 and do not exceed one million dollars, bor - rowing members in such associations may hold stock in the </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 5 amount of $20,000.00, and in associations whose assets exceed the sum of one million dollars, and do not exceed the sum of $5,000,000.00, borrqwing jnembers may hold stock to the amount of $30,000.00, and in any association whose assets exceed the sum of $5,000,000.00, borrowing members may hold stock to the amount of $50,000.00. Provided further, how - ever, that at any meeting of any such corporation, where not less than fifty members are present, it shall be lawful for suf - ficient proxies to be held by those present to represent xhe majority of all the stock of the corporation. The words "Loan and Building Association," "Building Association," "Building and Loan Association," "Savings and Loan Association," or "Loan and Savings Association," shall form part of the cor - porate name of every such corporation. The capital stock of every such association shall consist of the accumulated pay - ments made by its members and dividends credited thereon, and shall be represented by shares. 488. Sec. 4. Same — withdrawals. Such constitution shall contain equitable provisions permitting any shareholder wishing to do so to withdraw all or part of his or her stock pay - ments from the association at such times and upon such terms as the by-laws may provide, by giving written notice of such intention to withdraw to the Secretary or managing officer of the association, and at the expiration of thirty days following the period of the next regular payment, or at any time there - after, the member so withdrawing, or, if deceased, his legal representative, shall be entitled to receive, on demand, the amount paid in by him or her, less the admission fee and ex - pense charge, and such rate of interest or proportion of the net profits, as the by-laws may determine, less all fines and other just and lawful charges. Should there have been, however, a net loss including actual and lawful expenses instead of a net gain, then such withdrawing shareholder shall receive the actual amount paid in, less his proportion of such net loss. At no time, however, shall more than one-half of the unloaned funds in the treasury of the association be applicable to the demands of withdrawing shareholders without the consent of the Board of Directors. No shareholder shall be entitled to withdraw where stock is pledged as security for a loan, either from the association or from any other party. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE The directors may, in their discretion, under rules made by them in conformity with by-laws, retire any unpledged shares in the order of their issue, by enforcing withdrawals of the same, and the owners shall be paid the full value of their shares as determined at the last preceding distribution of profits, together with all dues paid since such distribution, less any unpaid fines: Provided, all shares which have reached matured value, and that may be outstanding, shall be first retired under the provision of this chapter. 493. Sec. 9. Same — authorize investments. No loan shall be made by such association except to its own members, nor shall any loan be made to any member for any sum in excess of the par value of his stock, and the association shall have a lien on as many of the borrowers' shares as shall equal at their par value the nominal amount of the loan ; good and ample real estate security unincumbered, except by prior liens held by such association, shall also be given by the borrowers. Provided, all loans made upon the security, real estate im - proved by the presence of building, shall not exceed in amount, two-thirds of the actual cash value of such security, and all loans made upon the security of any other form of real estate shall likewise not exceed an amount equal to two-fifths of the actual cash value of such security. Provided, further, the stock of such association may be received as a security for a loan of the amount of the withdrawal value of such stock without other security. Provided, further, that any association may have the power temporarily to invest its idle funds or any part thereof to any amount not exceeding ten (10) per cent of its assets in bonds or interest bearing obligations of the United States or the Federal Land Bank or of the State of Nebraska, or of any county, township, school district, or other political division of the State of Nebraska, or of any incorporated city or village in the State of Nebraska. And provided further, that any such corporation may deposit its funds or any part thereof in any national or state bank and to receive therefor certificates of deposit or the usual bank pass-book credit sub - ject to check. No evidence of indebtedness taken by said association for the return of any loan shall be negotiable in form, and what - ever be its form, every such indebtedness shall be non-nego - tiable in law, and no such debt or evidence of debt shall be assignable or transferable in any manner so as to prevent the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 7 discharge thereof by payments to the association, except that bonds and interest-bearing obligations in which temporary in - vestments may be made as hereinbefore provided, may be con - verted into cash as required by such associations in the conduct of its business. In conclusion permit me to express my deep sense of appreciation of the splendid co-operation of your Board in all matters pertaining to the Department, the efficient manner in which Examiner A. D. Touzalin has performed his exacting duties in the examination of these associations and the office force for their conscientious devotion to the duties attaching to their respective positions. Respectfully submitted, J. J. TOOLEY, Secretary of State Banking Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SUMMARY Of the condition of the SEVENTY-THREE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS of the STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 48,617,709.19 Loans in process of foreclosure 252,105.20 Loans on stock or pass book security 476,526.79 Office and other real estate- . 897,372.46 Real estate sold on contract 322,173.22 State and municipal securities 424,537.68 Cash 2,840,953.49 Delinquent interest, fines, etc 135,239.20 Furniture and fixtures 37,994.50 Taxes paid 18,092.44 Other assets 255,089.31 Tax certificates 3,336.30 Certificates of deposit 264,500.00 Total $ 54,545,629.78 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 36,946,026.11 Paid-up stock and dividends 14,116,148,21 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 1,556,055.49 Reserve fund 1,309,284.11 Undivided profits 534,399.48 Unearned premium ' 50.58 Other liabilities 55,765.80 Matured stock _ 27,350.00 Bills payable ■ ' '55O.OO Total I 54,545,629.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 9 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ % 2,819,014.88 Dues (Running stock) _ _ 13,174,833.63 Paid-up stock _ 5,346,820.18 Mortgage payments 8*967,570.87 Stock loan payments 706,604.37 Real estate sales 307,908.17 Interest _ 3,171,868.57 Premium 137,573.13 Fines 14,381.20 Rents 10,097.85 Membership and transfer fees 34,854.24 34,854.24 Rents and office building receipts 38,567.71 Other receipts in detail 691,661.76 Tax certificates 4,825.08 4.825.08 Certificates of deposit 278,100.11 Incomplete loans _ 484.971.80 Bills payable , _ 20 745.00 20,746.00 Total _ $ 36,210,398.55 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans % 15,055,470.12 Stock loans 737 510.44 737,510.44 Withdrawals, running stock and dividends 10,400,524.70 Withdrawals paid-up stock 3,545,793.43 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock 590,082.00 Salaries Commissions 265,254.02 49,006.03 Other expense 96,171.68 Real estate account 3S9fiSC)'.no Cash on hand [.'.[ 2,886481 75 Other disbursements in detail li325|827.67 Tax certificates Matured stock 8,760.28 114,956.0n Certificates of deposit 359,878.63 Bills payable ________ 12|808!81 Incomplete loans 422,842!39 Total $ 36,210,398.5o </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association, Permanent 54, Combination 6, Serial 13 73 Number of series issued since organization _ 676 Number of shares issued since organization 2,818,617.68 Number of shares outstanding last report $1,007,346.63 Shares issued since last report 309,869.57 Total 1,317,216.20 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 194,698.19 Number of shares in force this date - 1,122,518.01 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent. 8,915.5 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-pay- ment of dues 1,871 Average running time of stocg matured during the year... 110^ Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders 32,530 Number of non-borrowing 1 stockholders _ 69,399 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 2,646 69,399 Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 4,300 Par value of each share of stock _. .52 of $100.00; 21 of $200.00 4,300 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _... 39,784.88 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 42,891.28 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid.... 162,197.60 Number and amount of mortgages subject to fore- closure No. 528 664,799.39 Number and amount of mortgages in process of fore - closure No. 234 252,105.20 Amount of loans on improved real estate 48,508,756.60 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 97,691,833.52 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 197,095.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 592,570.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 57,375,636.90 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security...- 35,723,000.70 Amount of money loaned on improved farms Amount of money loaned on improved farms 2,019,000.00 Appraised value of land not including improvements 4,458,623.80 Value of improvements 993,435.00 Amount of fire insurance thereon 212,900.00 Amount of tornado insurance thereon „ _ 76,905.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year. Amount credited to reserve fund during year 238,783.83 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 48,102.69 48,102.69 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year .... _ 1,894,694.04 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 769,461.04 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year _ 7.4% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ 6.2% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year.... 8.1% 8.1% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year 2!9% </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">STATEMENT Of total number of associations, numbers of shares in force, and total assets, from 1892, the first year that authentic reports were made, down the to present time. Number of No. of Year Association Shares in Total Assets Force 18»2 71 45,012.5 $ 2,902,557.67 1893 84 61,964.1 3,653,096.83 1894 86 71,231.5 3,888,001.31 1895 81 70,615 3,929,778.27 1896 73 64,891.75 3,771,833.53 i897 _ 68 67,597.5 3,554,788.08 1898 64 79,973 3,428,728.11 1899 60 89,492 3,332,781.67 1900 60 • 105,625 3,697,356.06 1901 _... 59 119,985 4,314,744.86 19C2 58 130,083 4,758,293.97 1903 59 153,424 5,343,429.38 1904 60 174,022 6,217,350.40 1905 _ 59 196,030 7,269,297.48 1906 61 220,648 8,961,788.11 66 315,372 11,422,890.86 68 372,826.77 13,415,822.89 70 438,054.19 17,094,771.57 70 512^44.71 21,327,766.83 69 602,159.94 24,885,285.15 68 668,122.85 28,946,108.63 70 740,925.29 32,746,726.24 72 816,571.25 37,138,413.21 71 891,333.79 41,660,870.53 72 1,007,346.63 47,917,847.08 73 1,122,518.01 54,545,629.78 54,545,629.78 One association organized and chartered: Humphrey Building, was Loan and Savings Association, Humphrey. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATEMENTS Showing the condition of each of the seventy-three Build - ing and Loan Associations in the State of Nebraska at the close of business June 30, 1917. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALBION, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President P. A. Kraus.e Vice President T. F. Martin Secretary F. A. Doten Treasurer :. F. S. Thompson Attorney O. M. Needham DIRECTORS Iu Krause B. Martin 5. Thompson r. Flotree F. A. Doten C. A. Bull W. S. Price H. P. Bull T. F. Martin F. F. Willott G. K. Pittenger ASSETS Flrxt morticafre lo«ni&lt; - * !i7..T«»:.iio Loans on Sea or pasa book security..- - - - — l.iHO.on Other real estate - _ — - 1J644.T0 1 &gt;«'l i iMiUfiit f ntt*rpi*t fines &lt;^tc.~ - — • ■ - — 1 ,(W3.3o Knrnittirv mill flxtnrHK ■■ 11.57 rnh*r asaetg (inanranre advanced) ».3ii Tax sale cfrtlfl&lt; - aten — - 885.87 Total - - - »1OS.4N2.71 LIABILITIES Ruunlug stock and dividends - -... * 96.408.70 KcM-rve fund _ . 5.300.00 fndlvided profiu (coilerted ... . !K».M tndiTlded proflta (not collected) _.. ''JSi' BUli payable 3*&gt;-0° Total——— $108,482.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 15 YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE 30, 1917 KBCB1PTS &lt;"a«h on band last report _ _ f 4,700.&lt;B * anil t'll ilnllll in SI r^lMlri _ amtl t mmwm m f I llv.VK Dues i Running stock I _ _ 28^573.3 Mortgage payments. _B,80O.O» Stock loan payments _ - 12.3llO.0lt Interest _..- _ MM-N Premium _ _ 1.401.QU Flues _____ _ KT7.a» 387.W Kent* _ _ _ _ IM&lt; H»llili«nHja ill Il«_i-T»l ftw — — '■'■ 44U.75 cither receipts in detail (Bills payable) 9SM0 Tax sale certificates - - M8 ♦ Insurance, returned- — _ —. 4JM 4_M Total * M&gt;JW.0S. KISHIKSK XIEXTS Mortgage loans _ _ _ _ $ lo.aoano Stock loans _ _ 3,400.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends H!.M."i .'«• Withdrawals paid-up stock „ _ ;&gt;.7i«M». Withdrawals iTivideu&lt;l on ptMll stock. 4_KTTi salartes „ 1.273.1_ Other expense.. .. _ 7O.3«i Iteal estate account , , ~ 23.40 i ash on hand _ ..._„_._ ...... j*r7 77 Insurance advanced _ _ _ _ 1S.54 Tax sale certificates __ ; B71.S7 Total - f t»,«W.O» SIPl'LKMKNT.M. KKIMUJT Tin ii of association _ Permanent Nniiilier of series issued since organization _ _ _ _ _ Number of shares outstanding last report 4.557 \\iiiiIiit of shares outstanding last report Shares Issued since last report 1,547 Total _ 6.101 Total Inns withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 1,174 VnnilMT of shares In force this date 4.930 Number of borrowing stockholders m _ _ — 122 Number « ; f i'oii I'orrtiwinir stockholders _ _ 390 Number of loans made for huildinjr purposes during year - 4 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during the year _ 18 Plan of premium - '. — — -... Monthly Par value of each shnre of stock _ $ Mt.0D Amonnt of interest, premiums and fines due and unpail l.f-EVJio I'ar value of each share of stock NiinilM-r and amount of niort^ajre* subject to foreclosure No. IS Amount of loans on ini|&gt;rt'Veil real estate tlT.VIO.OI* Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - ,... 193.700(10 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association M6.570 0M a* collateral security- - Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral »ecurity _ 102.1-onn Amount credited to reserve fund during year - Hftti Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 9.0W fM Boat* Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of dividends raid on matured and paid-up st*»ck during ye«r 42R.7- Aate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year .... *V, Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - - -12 Kate per cent interest charged borrowers during year... fJH Kate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year EH </seg>
            <seg id="p016">11 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALBION, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President P. A. Kraus.e Vice President T. F. Martin Secretary F. A. Doten Treasurer F. S. Thompson Attorney O. M. Needham DIRECTORS I.. Krause B. Martin 5. Thompson r. Flotree F. A. Doten C. A. Bull W. S. Price H. P. Bull T. F. Martin F. F. Willott G. K. Pittenger ASSETS KlrM niortifHite InmiK * 87.3UM* Lohiii- on sic" k or push hook twurlty _ l.MM.un &lt;if)i»*r rci 1 e-st'lH' 1 ,r»44.Tl ' i' H&gt; h I „ _ 307 .TT ita-lliKiurnt interest, linen, etc _ - 1.083..TO i-*ii pii it u r** mill fixturvK — 11. 5T fvther aKwts (iimursuce advanced) _ JJJ Tax M!e ontUkatn - MMI Totnl - - *103.4&gt;2.71 LIABILITIES Ruuiiiug stork and dividend* _ - _.. * 9ii.4«l8.7o " .„ fmwi ' 5,300.00 Undivided profits' ' icoilected - - ..... (KiO.M I'ndlTided profits (not collected) _ - _ _.: l.(*B.."io Bllii payable _ 5S0&lt;» Total 1 108,482.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 15 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 ItECBlITS rash on band last report __ $ 4,7nt&gt;.«B Hues iHiinning stork i _ _-M73._6 26,573.26 Mortgage payments. .*!.«»'(«• Stock loan payments . . r.'.'BKMpi Interest _ .'. _ _ _ ».l»*6.a4 tf.lS6.LM ITfmium __ _____ - — ....... 1.4O1.0II Fines 3J7.ai&gt; Kent* _ _ K.M Membership and transfer fees- fj"" 5 other receipts in detail (Bills payable) _ _M_M Tax Rale certificates _ _ ;(--*» ♦ ■Mi Tax sale certificates. Insurance returned _ - - C2 • Total _ f s0.6St.0K. IHSBTHSKMEXTS Mortgage lit;) M" — _ „ _ _ $ 10.ftCO.00 Mortgage loans . . _ f 10.flOO.00 Stork Ion Us „ 3]4nO.nO Withdrawals. rBaabig stock anil dividends - -f .ffitt W Withdrawn I » running stock and dividends _ mM Withdrawal)* paid-up stock _ :» 7&gt;»m»» Wit hdrawals paid-up stock _ '.' 7'»»oii Wit hHr.-iu ;iU dividend on pnidup stock _. 41&gt; TT. WiihHrnwnls dividend oa pmUmp stock _ . 41&gt; 77. Salaries „ „ _ _ 1.U73.16 Salnrtes 1.273.16 Other expense .. , Other expense .. . , Heal estate account „ _ _ „ 23.40 Heal estate account ~ _ 23.40 * *a nIi on hand ~ — ~ ;y;7 77 I'jish on hand _ — .— -__. r«**7 77 Insuranoe advanced 1", |fl Insurance advanced _ 1S.54 Tax sale certificates _.... «7i M Til sale certificates. __.... 071.37 Total „ $ M».tftH iis sriM'LK.MK.NTAI. ItKlMUtT IIM'I.K.MKN I A I. IIKl'UUT I'I;mi i&lt;r nssorjjitiuii m m iVriiiini.-iif I'lan wt assoc iation _ IVruiiiiii'iit Nuinlter of series Issued since &gt;&gt;; -L r :ini/ation _ _ Nuinlier of series Issued since organization _ _ X amber of shares outstnndlnjr last report _ - 4..V&gt;7 Shares issued since last report 1.547 Shares Issued since lost report.. 1.547 Total H.HM Totnl Shar&gt; u it lulrawii. iiiaTuriMi or i-iiliccned since Isist rep(»rt 1.174 Vnni'wT of shnres iii force this ilntr _ 4.9QO Xiiinlier of borrow hit; stockholders - Viiinher « r ron borrowing ■tnrkfaolden - VoiiiImt of loans iimile for bnlMtac pur|ioses duriuir yt^ir 4 Xuniher of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of honipstead-mnrtKHKes (luring the year _ ]■&gt; Plan of premium. _ '. „ Mont hlv Tar a alue of each sliaro of stock $ MSlOO l*ar vnlue of each share of stix-k Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpail Ulm NuiiiImt and amount of mortgages subject to f»tre&lt;-iosure No. l.'J Amount of lonns on improved real estate \fl.7*¥*.it* Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare been made _ - ,... 193.7(10 no Amount of fire insurance in force anil assigned to the association as collateral security- _ lflBJMLflO Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 10C12OOO Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ M— I Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year &lt;&gt;'»I&gt;'M Amount of dividend* laid on matured and paid-up sti'«-k during venr MA.1B Aate per cent of dividends declared on running stork during year.... 0| Hate |»t cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during- year Rnte |&gt;er cent interest iliarmd l.orrowers daring year...- 7 8&lt;&gt; Hate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year- 1 Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p018">16 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ALLIANCE WILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ R. M. Hampton Vice President Jerry Rowan Secretary M. S. Hargraves Treasurer F. W. Harris Attorney Robt O. Reddish Paid-up stock and dividends- __ 133.727.0T) Dae shareholders on Incomplete h.an&gt;. _ &lt;t.ft24.«V&gt; Reserve fund •.'.7-J7.2-J 7-.T.: other liabllitieg 1.668.3S Total - _ $346.&lt;B0.91 t McDonald R. M. Hampton Rowan F. W. Irish Hargraves W. C. Mounts F. W. Harris Chas. E. Wills Geo. E. Davis Mm First mortgage lo»n» Loam in prmetm of (Mariaaan Loan* on &gt;i&lt;«k or paat hook serurity Other real estate -«~— . iKHiiMiuent interest, fines, elf Furniture and fixtures T^ixett pjiid - District ooart 1 usurancc Total :;.vimii 1,400.00 5,784.67 L'.Wl.TT l.atss.ss ~.S8.(» 1,049.30 81.00 him |MMMM LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ — 1101,573.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 17 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash un Iinml hist report $ IO.HKi.L'T Dues illumiiiiK stock! - - l»..V_-.i 'C Tii ill ill i stuck , _ Murtfiiijfe iuiyineut*i - N^MlLM Stuck I Oil Ii p;i V Ilieilts _ _ _ i jlMMO Stock loiiii p:i vuients - _ _ i :i."jO.i*i filter « .'. iT.lSvm Flues _ . iVl(l&gt; Fines l,V»1.00 Routs _ 750i» Taxes _ _„ 1.451.21 Taxes _ MBLH I umni nit* ."Ufi liit I urn ni iHt* .uici ;{it Court costs 'ill' \*t Court rusts 'Ill' \*) Interest paid _ - IM| I'rotit a mi low liC'.'L' M iM't*lla ueoiis IIH Expense ..' 34.00 Total $1&lt;MM19 IHSBt KKt :ments Morrmi^p loans - -Ml.ois.v* Incomplete luans W..V.1.7:! | 77, MOJO Sttn-k loans - _ 1 Jtmm Withdrawal! running stork ami rtliiffc ■&lt;!■ _ 11.13t».47 Witbdrawala paid-up stock-.. 1- . _-J i • » * Withdrawal* divideiul ou paid -op «t*efc .. „ 17.7iH.st Salaries - l.'^M 'Z* Furniture anti fixtures 4»)4 ♦ *» Otlwr ex peiww? ■V*4.M5 Real estate aceou nt , ■ —-- Ifc^.d'i t "a*&gt;li ou liiiud. .._... 2.ft41.^i" Misi ellaiieous - » ~ Taxes I.l*r7."jn l^[_mi-i(-j court — — HI Reserve lusuranii- ...- 3O1.4J Xotal *163J«9UlTI SIPI'I.KMEXTAL REPOBT Pl»n of association Permnoent Nunibcr of .shares laMMd or^auiziiiioii Xuuilicr i&gt;f sh:ir«-s outstauiiiDj; last report - 4,774.38 Shan-s issued since last report WTT.31' Total :u:.l T'i Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report _ _ 7-1. i&lt;&gt; Numlier of sliarea in force this date _ - 2.&lt;?7O.7o NuuiIkt of shares on which dues are delinquent i^.V- ; Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 7&lt;j Average running trine of stock matured during the year 117 months Number of borrowing stockholders - ™ 111 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — 88 Numlier of limns made for hufldine purposes during year 14 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 17 Par value of each share of stock _ f 300100 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date a^OL'.SO Amount of lines owing by borrowing stockholders _ Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ l.MKflR Number ami amount of mortgages subject ti&gt; foreclosure r Xn. I HMMi Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 4 UMM Amount of loan* on Improved real estate - - 233,0(0.70 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - - - - - - 4B6v25O.O0 AnwM of tire in-urnni-e in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — - - — OT.23O.0O Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association •a collateral security - 114,100.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1,527. 3f» Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year.— '_\4:n» s\ Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 10..VH43 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 17,794.89 Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ».9% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - - "' - Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year — - M&lt; r </seg>
            <seg id="p020">18 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SOITIIKASTERN NKHRASKA WILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AUBURN, NEBRASKA On the 30th clay of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Wm. B. Smith Vice President R. E. Harmon Secretary J. M. Gillan Treasurer B. C. Howe Attorney Edgar Ferneau DIRECTORS Wm. B. Smith E. M. Kerns R. M. Gillan J. M. Gillan B .C. Howe R. E. Harmon ASSETS rir»i murtmam lauM $i-04.-j:'.."..no - in imrMi of terertoavrv _ _ 2,ti5O.5D L— ■ on st"&gt;«k or pas?; Imok ■wrlty _ .. iMTTi.liO i Hh**r rt*ul e**tu!e 1*i.i^.M».Hi Other real estate Itml «-MMtl* MlM "II Mil I m - - ■_\--|l."i.i*O lt«iil o«ff m»M "ii t&lt;—U«il - - -... 2,315.90 Cmmk 11.7H*.ht» IMIaqacnt imerest. tlneg, etc _ 3.388.78 I n-i iin|iifii i liner***!. lliii*J«, en' — ,],.ki;i.i^ Kn mil tire and flxtupe«_ _ - _ -jxYiiii Tulefc paid - - 31T.T4 Total J-'fi.«iTi.U2 LIABILITIES Huniiinir Rtock and dividends _ % 5K.44O.4O Paid-up stook and dividend* _ _ _... irj.'J(X&gt;.UI Kewerve fund »-«»»«_»«— - H.7JO.O1 indiTided profits _ - U.JuYtc; I'nparned premium _ - 40.98 Total.. SM:t.026.uc; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 19 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS &lt;"ash on hand last report _ _ f »JUM I Mies I K ii lining stock) _„ Jii. ."*•:!. V. Paid-up stock „„ _ * **■' ■ Mort Lai;e payments _ IsvMB '■&gt; Stock I oit n pay incuts _ , 4f»T» 'it Interest, premium ami liner. _ 1:, ."&lt;«&gt;■ x ■Cents _ _ _ 7u: m Rents _ _ Tit; Hi Membership 11 ml transfer fees _ _ _ 1\'; in Foreclosure account _ _ .iinn Foreclosure account _ MfiaV Iiisuriiin-e 11 nil taxes _ .'7 in 1 Insurain-e and taxes _ .'7 IK' Kefll estate contracts _ drti.nl Total - fl."iU.3UU.M&gt; Kefll estate contracts „ tPLYm Total... mm/mm DI8BIUSKMKXTS IHSItl I SI- MEXTS Mortgage leans .. $ 44; ' M&lt;irti::i^f trails _ 9 -Hi ' stiM-k loans l.om.mt stiM-k loans l.om.mi Withdrawals rmitiiiiK stock and diriilemlx 1T.MTJB Withdrawals running stock and dividends lf.MT.3B Withdrawals paid up stock _ v. 7n &gt;*• Withdrawals paid up stock "■*. ?&lt;■ '»• Withdrawals dividend on paid-lip stork _ MsYJO Witlidrawiils dividend on paid-up stork _ tJKM Salaries _ _ _ Salaries _ I'lilnmissioilH - CoiUllliMttioilS - * Hlier PI IM-nse _ 744.M 1 Kl'cr PI |»clis«' _ 744. U"'. Itefll estate account _ 765 JW Real estate account _ 76tV^SH Citsh on hand _ „ 1 l,TttJCS Cash on hand „ 1 1.TW.W Insiirani** and taxes 1TJS Insurani-e and taxes 17.."rf» Foreclosure account _'.vji.v.i Total *1SOjae.8« Foreclosure account _ _'.h'ji.7.i Total ■MM SIPI'I-KMKXTAI. ItKPOItT SUPPLEMENT. AI. UKPOKT Plan of association PerntmicMit Plan of association 1'ernuiK-iit Number of shares issued since organization _ _ 1MB Numlier of shares issued since organization _ __ ji .4: NuuilK-r of shares outstandinK l»*t re|xirt _ _ -S.171 Shares issueil since last report _ 1.274 Total _ tl. ti". Shares withdrawn, matured or iiineelled sin.r ln»t report _... 1 nun Number of shares in force this date _ „ ."i.41'i Average running time of stock matured during the year _ Class -A" M'Mo. : CIum "B" 144 mouths Number of borrowing stockholder*. _ BJ Number of non-morrowlng fttockholdeni _ -V. Numlier of loans made for building purposes during year 1.* Number of loan* made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year...- _ 26 Plan of premium - Monthly Par value of each share of stock..— - _ f Mft.00 Amount of interest, premiums and flues due ami unpaid .TWO.iK ■ Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 10 ia.8SA.0u Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 2 2.tiuO.5B Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 2flO.. l &lt;t5.0O Appraised v:ilue mt improved real estate upon which Itmns have i»een been made ...— — ~~«~— _...—.. ~... _—...—..........._ -MAJtBR.OO Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 3.400.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have t&gt;een made III1&gt;^ M _...„_„. ...„._. —....__ — ......«_ I^HUsV Amount of Ore Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 266.700.00 Amount of tornado insurance hi force and assigned to the association a* collateral security 24O,40a«0 Amount credited to reserve fund during year l.lJSOO Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 306.60 Amount of dividends paid mi matured and p:iid-u|&gt; stork rl nrinir year UBTJi .TOB.flO Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year _• asj | Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year.... W, Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid sfock «/~, Rate per cent charged borrowers during; year •""-, Hate |ier 1*111 of premiums charged borrowers during year — ,, !■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p022">20 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the AURORA BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AURORA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President B. A. Munson Vice President W. E. Reber Secretary Jas. Schoonover Treasurer. W. E. Lounsbury Attorney J. H. Grosvenor DIRECTORS W. E. Reber B. A. Munson J. A. Isaman H. E. Newton W. E. Lounsbury N. J. Ronin E. C. Rhinehart Joseph Johnson Jas. Schoonover ASSKTS First mortgage loan* _ S 7+,7on.*»&gt; Louia in process of foreokiKure l.Sfj.+n Loan* on stock or paaa book sm-urity _ l!-nr.j«i other real eatate - — _ , 1,1N4.m_ CagQ „ ______ 4 497 _S Furniture and fixtures. _ - - .. ________ 170 _o Taxes and insurance paid _ _ 47!4&lt;&gt; Bills receivable - _ Tii.75 foreclosure . m Total — - 1 K4&lt;ti4V» LIABILITIES Running atork and dividends | 8R.2O1..T7 I'aidup stock and dividends _ 14.8no!no Reaerre fund _ _ tt!4 85 t'ndivlded prnfitK _ks.3S -KS.3S Matured atock _ :&lt;0o!oo Total $ St.0tM.36 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 21 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 receipts Dues (Running stork) _ _ .._ - $ 10,705.50 Paid-up stock _ _.._. 4.10.00 Mortgage payments — — • 6.«MIO.*X&gt; Stock luau. payments - _ iiJiM" Intirvt 5OI0JB pines _________________« _— _ M ■ Re^nts "" SAOD Mt&gt;iuli«rsi.ip »nd transfer fees _ _ "^S Profits on withdrawals anil interest on eourt decrees- _ - — il&gt;J» Settlement foreclosure mse« - _ slum Bills receivable June :to, !!►!«.. !. _ _ IMttM Bills receivable J»ei\ :H.' !!•!«! - &lt;1J (Xl « 2G.T73.18 Total DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans * 2 -2S?!£ W loADA - ■■■- -......,. ...........,..~... i . i . i ■■. ,t n*iO-0*» j^toot loflns . — -— -•- — , , . fc ■ » i ■ » Withdrawals running stock and dividends. 5.2BT.77 Withdrawals Mtd-Bp sttwk — _ t*..V«" in* Withdrawal* dividend on paid up stork _ 1 ■?'- .4 '■'■ S&lt;llari«*s — — --...——— T'^7 '■' Other expense _ ._ - 'US Real estate account - - ,}SS Cash on hand — — 4. wT.i'i Ii ten tMi ti /*o ni Irf *. *. -V^ ' Cash overdrawn June »», li)W. '"SI- 3 ? Court decree unsettled .'. - 1J3B.45 Total » 25,773.18 SUPPLEMENTAL. ItEIH)RT Plan of awociation - - 8 * rt «J ■ N'uuilier at series issued gince orfraniiatton.- ._.** Numher of shares issued since organisation _ .*■.!•_. Numher of shares issued since organisation. Number of shares outstanding last report _ 1&lt;&lt; I}. Shares Issued soince last report 1KW4 .««.,, i whi - - - ■,;"j'""ill_ "\ * , M ii' 96V4 Shares, withdrawn', matured or cancelled stno* last report ?*liS Number of shares Id fore* this date - ' *•■* Numl#r of shares on which dues are delinquent — - Numtier of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues ITS Averste running time of stock matured during the year Ifl6 months Nunil-er of I orrowlng stockholders NO Nnml'or of roil i&gt;( 'rowing stockholders - - - Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment or honiestend-unrU'ages during year nw»&lt;£ Par value of each share of stock __ - » •JJJ-J5 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date - ! »■ Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders.... .._ VyI H \niount of i.reininms, interest and fines due and unpaid — _ '-rS'JS Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 9 14 -25'.« Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 1 -V2Si5 flM.OO 1.445.16 .Mliniper turn ninuuni. ui umi v^-^ro u. K .^~~ — — — - -Y-i*\m Amount of loans on improved real estate - — .ii'lISMJ, \pnralsed value of real estate upon which loans have been made 182.460.00 Amount of (Ire insurance in force and assigned to the association 162.«0.00 8T7.2m.no as collateral security . .. 87.2no.no Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - SsW Amount credited to reserve fund during year--..-. - . tSU Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year J-j£Mi Vmonnt of dividends paid °&lt;&gt; matured and paid-up stock during year 1 - 20^? 34.V71 1. 202.43 T» Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year _ Rate per cent of dividends paid on mature and full paid stock e per rent oi uiiiucuub pom "■« »«««i«ic ■«« »«.. 9 ■ — — during year - — — - •■ — " Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring year — 8.4% </seg>
            <seg id="p024">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 22 STATEMENT of the condition of the STATE SAVINGS AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION- BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President A. H. Kidd Vice President T. J. Chidester Secretary E. L. Hevelone Treasurer Louie Graff Attorney Rinaker &amp; Kidd DIRECTORS E. L. Hevelone A. H. Phelps W. C. Black, Jr. A. H. Kidd T. J. Chidester ASSKTS Kir-t HMgl Ionn&gt; $1.1811.225.00 Loan« in proves* nf f.&gt;re&lt;li&gt;*lire - aMKIO.KI Loans on stork or puss liook aecuritjr - _ 778.00 Loans mi stuck or pus* liook security _ _ TTkiki K.:.l estate "ffi.-e _ _ _ $ 0,1 1 M.I K Real .'state office „ _.. * tt.KW.ln: Other real estate - - IT.ITi; I 2S.IT8.NU Other real estate - - 17.17' - 2S.1T8.HII Beat mate sold on coMract— . - 1 1.1 •"*♦.! 14 Real estate sold on ■ ■(■■■tract.. - - ll.MKM I'aHh - '.- '.'.'.'. — -1Hi.411.10 __ _ 'JtMI.411.10 DdlaqneBt Intcreat. tim-s etc - — - 5.338.78 Ddbtqaeat Interest, tim-s ete - — - 5.338.78 Furniture ami HxIuivk l.sdO.OI T, IM ..Hi,] 1 ITS.', &amp; Other assets Xi5.NI Other ijiitl ".-. __________ - JO5.MI Office supplies - - .-&gt;7S.OO Offlc* supplies _ - - - .7JTi.no LitKTt v bonds - - 5.000.00 .-)75.(» Libert y bonds - - 5.000.00 Total - »1.54«.'&gt;tU.S&lt;: I.llxriy bonds Total - *l.M«.W0.K7 LIABILITIBS LIABILITIES Runulng stork and dividends _ _ tl.nH.2fiK.aO RuDulng stork and dividends _ _ HJHJBLM Paid-up stork and dividends _ &gt; XXi.ir75.0ii Doe shareholder* on incomplete loans. *_'l.&lt;W7.1f&gt; Reserve fund ltVJM.eB I'ndlvidpd profits Other liabilities — _'..— ".. I'ndlTided profits _ _ - 36.0f&amp;73 W.OB Tot :il *1,M6.94O.ST </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 23 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KBCE 1 1*TS Ca»b on IihikI lawt report... - _ M|]BI| Omm I kuinitng sUnki _ _ - 417,300.10 Paid-up Mock ...- „ _... IOK.OuO.OU Paid-up Mock _ _ _... 10K.uSO.flO Mortgage i.a.vinenti* 14O.74V.74 Mortgage Will l-W.7-ltf.74 .•iv.. i_..^i I 1 ".' 111T-UIW l-¥\7. l-W. !"» Keal estate tulles „._... 1 .BIB. 11 Keal estate Males „. _ ."» '.mh 5] Interest .. IOK^MKUr? Interest _ 1MUKUS I. nan dues _ ' 112.30 I.o:iii 4am „ . 112.30 Fines ."..7 -I:, Fine* 97.00 Kent* „ _ aM « Kent* _ v;l;", Membership and transfer fee*. „ , SvMft.Ot Membership and transfer fees _ .~..:u.~&gt;.&lt;&lt;) Kent?* ami offi«t' building rwvipts _ _ Relit!* mid offii*e buildLutc rweiptn ~ „ Other receipts _ fl77.17 Other receipts _ „ 677.17 Abstrm-t fees - iVhttrari 9*m Real estate on cuutract 1.7MJI7 Real estate on contract .'. 1.7M.II7 Tax Mtl6 otrtiflcat©* - Ml 'ft T*t«i n nm —or Tax sale certificate** _ _ ___ Ml i&lt;7 I. .!■ I DISBIHSKMEXTS niSBIRSEMEXTS JHortsraK** !oau» $4K'..*Mtl.74 Mortgage !oau» $41J Stin'k losna - . _■"■• &gt; • ■• Stni'k l"»:in&gt; _ 2AO.O0 Witltdrawalu ruiiiilm Mock aud dtTMenrfa "...'. Z!.. 14!1.J»O.3» Withdrawals niHiiiac Moo* and dlrMeurfa n;i .".«■.-• Withdrawals aaM-aa Mark _ / IIT.KOjM Withdraw ala p:ifd -up stck . _ i 117.1fiOjlt Witlidrun-nU dividend on pnid -up st«»«-k 11D.189.4W Withdrawal* divideml on paid up stoek , 1(1.1 »4» Salaries in Salaries _ 4'iiIllllli"*Mt&gt;IIK .- . CoMMtaalotM v _ * *ther t'xpftiise I Ither expense 2.IW.44 Keal estate h&lt;'&gt;'«uh| I !»■;(! estate aeeouut Cash on IiiiikI _ 200.41 1.1O Cash on hand , 2IN&gt;.41 1 H) uth.-r HlrtTWUti ••• HIjH uth.-r dlabaranneflta Traveling expense . '. Traveltii(r rapfMM* ColltN'tion 11 ml exchange Collection uikI exehaiiue : Furniture ami fixture* T_T "." Furniture anil fixture! Office tint Id i 11 j; iK*&lt;*ount „ „ 7VT +&lt;» ortife hutldin£ aorouiit „ 7"-'T -M» Bwordln^ f ( '** s - - '■** ''••"• RpiMirflinir fees , „ 31I&amp;.33 Tux &gt;«a It* &lt;"**rtih*&lt;iitt's m Tax Male '"ertiiliiitt's 1 * «j» » 4 1 Forwlowure exiwnne MOUM ''7* IB Lllwrty bonds S.00QM Toi;,i 1 0 LilMTty bonds S.00OMI i mumm 8UPPLEMENTAL KK1*OBT SUPPLEMENTAL RF.I'OUT Plan of nssociation Perni:iitent Plan of association Permanent NunitM-r of slum's \mmt4 *in«-v orL';inir;iti«»ii. rj3,711&gt;4 Number of shares outstiindint: lust report 4»W&gt;&gt;*4 shares laaoad since lust report lt*,HR Shares issued since lust report itt.NK! Total - &amp;-..:»*!*, Ti.tal - tfl.JWl*. Kharea wlitnlniwn. uintnrod *»r i-aiicelled alme la^t npori „ 9.422 Sh.ires wilhilriiwn. matured i&gt;r cancelled aline lust report _ 0.422 Numl.er of shares in force this date _ , V. &gt;.'•.-•, Number of shares in force this date _ T-.v"'.-^ Average riiiiniiif time of st*K-k uuitured durlnjf the year _ . 112 months Average running time of stock matured during the year . 112 iiionthx Number rrf borrow iuc ?*i or kliol tiers 1.01(1 VnmlNT of Uorrowiue s^orkholtlers l.olu .\nm&gt;l*r of tinn-bon owin^ Ktock holders m 7t,135 \i'inl»er of lonns made for hnildtnp purp&lt;is»-s during yeiir Till Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of l&gt;oniestead-mom-:".-es durl&gt;c year - M Par value of each ahare of stock. - &gt; luiui Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders *JM t" Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid ULU NuinlM-r nuil amount «&gt;f lortgagaa subject to foreclosure No. 3 Number and amount of mortf?ni?es In process of foreclosure No. 12 2ft.0flO.0Tk Amount of loans on improved real estate l.'2U"&gt;.tf75.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - _ 2.2fin.-4«Uin r&gt;u»'t "»f lonns im unimproved real estate - — _ — . .ViO.00 a.SVl-^.fln AmoiP't i»f loans on unimproved real estate Appraised ralue of unlmproTed real aatate upon which loans have been made - - - . S.600.00 lu^n made Amount nf fire in*ursnc«&gt; ia force and aasiened to the association as .•ollateral security...- - — - 1.4».(loaoo Amount nf tornado imnnmce In force and aaaltrned to the association as -ollsteral security - - 1.S74.IH).&lt;1O Amount credited to reserve fund durtnir year _ 4.4.V».4&lt;! Amount of losses chanted to reserve fund during year. 2.MR.23 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 0 MaVsa 1 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during; year - 1!&gt;.M».4» Rate per cent of divldendo declared on mrnlmr stock during rear t% Rate per cent of dividend* paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ _ 1st half «%. 2d half M4 M Rate per cent of Interest charted borrowers dnrlnc year. — •% </seg>
            <seg id="p026">24 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ C. P. Fall M. D. Vice President Ernst Schaekel Secretary E. F. Kimmerly Treasurer F. B. Sheldon Attorney F. B. Sheldon DIRECTORS C. P. Fall, M. D. C. A. Janssen H. E. Sackett ASSETS MrM mortgage loans _ $4M, 115.41 Loans in prowss of forfi-lnsnre „ _ 17[l4H.'Ji* Loan* on stock or |»as*s book swurlty 'SQD.flO Otber real esttate _ __ __ ___ 23,8».«7 Real estate sold on contract _ _ lO.its'oo State and municipal nwuriiii-s.. _ 3^000.00 »^«h - 1~,HV2.31 Furniture and fllxtnres _ _ _..!_... W)h!j6 Total _ _ .*. $5CM,L14.53 LIABILITIES KuuuLng stock aud dividends. _ _ $251,144.03 Paid-up ««'k and dividends ! ."......... "«V.nii He*prve fund _ 4 « * r -■&gt; w»_j._jj_j -4 _ _^*^T^*1V Undivided profits _ _ „ _ 1*5,190.74 Other liabilities _ _ _ _ ......L.........!........ 1U0.ID Tn^al $3fifT,114.68 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 25 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report _ _ _ _ | m. sag Jf Dues (Running stock) _ „ ________ 81 010:14 Paid-up stork _ _ 1~..~.~. . va.ata.ot Mortgage payments , _____________ njSES Stock loan payment* _ 55 Real estate sales __—_—_ 1U..:1'.'S; 1 nterest _ _ 37 _u ,S3 IM-Iinquent Interest .__ . .... _ .- '''lIMLISfi Rents .... T i'ik :«i M&lt;*» Membership and transfer fees. -__—__—_ 4_M» Other receipts in detail {loan fees) Foreclosure account - 810.00 Foreclosure account - 20,870.28 Contract account 67&amp;30 Taxes repair ,. »!•&gt;. ft; •»•» ■ Sundries — 7i ii ■j.'t Total „ f UQ.iMfr^fr DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans |161.._1.60 Stock loans _ 'z~ in Liberty bonds _ - _ _ _...! ;.mu»&gt; Withdrawals running stock aud dividends _ 127,2S7_4 Withdrawals paid-up stock- _ 4S.DSO.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock ll!M3.«B Salaries 4.iino'.oo Commissions _ 1.177.70 Other expense _ 1 /.mi :~ Real estate account 14016.98 Cash on band _ - 17,81_31 i7,8__n Furniture 7.50 Small losses not charted oft" 111.48 Reserve fund _ _'.3i»i .*** Contract account — 9.29&amp;0S Foreclosure arc-mint - — - 21.8S5.75 Other disbursements l tiv, •»." Total 9_HLM—Ji SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association. Plan of association - _.. _.. Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 3H,(~1S Number of shares outstanding last report 14.71ft.2B Shares Issued ainee last report 4.013.50 Total ~ lvT'Jt* 7." Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 2.S7OJSO 2_70_0 Number of shares In force this date KJ—Ui Average running time of stock matured during the year 114 month* Number of borrowing stockholders 3W Number of non-borrowing stockholders 1.051 Number of loan* made for building purposes during year- .. 31 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year - _ 44 Par value of ench share of stock _ - - - f WO no Number iiiiii amount nf niortirnges in process of foreclosure No. 10 17.148_&gt; 17.146_9 Number ami amount of mortjrages sub-feet to foreclosure No. 11 */••*►'■( Amount of loans on Improved real estate _ _ _... 4,"H.l 15.41 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - - — - l.O».79n.OO Amount of Ore Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ _ _ sno,4V&gt;.no Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ 4.77.7SO 00 Amount credited to reserve fund during- vear _ 1.541.30 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year -..1*4.58 .»mc&gt;"&gt;" »' iHvlnVmls derlared on running Moi-k during year 13.291. M Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock daring year 11.513.65 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during vear Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock T* during ymr . . a . . . Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year Mfl </seg>
            <seg id="p028">26 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the GERMAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS OFFICERS President Philip Graff President Philip Graff Vice President J. E. Lang Vice President J. E. Lang Secretary _ M. F. Eickmann Secretary _ M. F. Eickmann Treasurer Carl Sonderegger Treasurer Carl Sonderegger Attorney Rinaker ft Kidd Attorney Rinaker &amp; Kidd DIRECTORS DIRECTORS Philip Graff J. E. Lang Philip Graff Carl Sonderegger Henry T. Jurgens Carl Sonderegger Henry T. Jurgens J. E. Lang John Huttenmaier John Huttenmaier A88ET8 ASSETS Flrit mortgage loans ta«.aO(&gt;.00 Cash _ _ 40,828.07 I M'liiH|uent interest, Hues, etc.- -. „ 1,137.06 Furniture and fixtures _„ 4W7.70 Tax Mile certificates 1.^S4.67 tVrt ifleates of deposit _ 81,000.00 Total „ $330.!M8.0B LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ _ f W, 487.06 Paid-up stock and dividends _ 225,675.00 235,875.00 Due shareholders on incomplete loans , 792.80 Reserve fund _ _ „ 1.325.00 Undivided profits _ 8,008.24 Total _ _ $330,048.09 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 27 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS &lt; ii&gt;li &lt;&gt;n luiiiil last rt'imrt _.. t 33,l&lt;.d «i l&gt;u»*s t ICnn niii^ sliM'kt . ... ."K&gt;,UCtt».14 l"«i&lt;l up st...k ________ - 1XI.VJT&gt;.&lt;» Mortgage pajaktatfi _ - 18.Wm.00 | merest * - l s .~i71..T_ Fines _ _ _ ■ 7 '•■ Membership :iiul transfer fees - ™ --..—_— *f7H.5O |,i ;il: fees « ...„......„__. 'iJ"J."O other receipts in .letiii' 1.38 T:ix sille »-erl iri.ates Z1&amp;J5 IlH'OlllpleTe 1 1 'II IIS IMI'OUllt — -~ .. iJ..'*^i..'V4 Certificate- ■'{ deposit — 4&lt;i.:!38.44 1 1. -line in. -lit Interest - 14X1 ■ Total DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans — _ - - Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ _.. Withdrawals paid-up stock — — - »" M ■ Withdrawals dividend on paid-up »twk — — Salaries __ _ - - — l.Tln.i.i Other expense - - _ i.l.Vi l.". Cash on hand — Certificates of deposit » 71. «i Tas ':'i&lt; i iht i i rim i i's — 1.H—.3C Incomplete loans account — - _1.7-».74 Rmpftp fnn__ — - ___________ _____ _______ _____ _ i '■ ■ ' " ' AW^^^t" » T _&gt; U __ »* ■...■■■H-M. HII|P|_I ■■ ■ ■■■ P ___-*--■_..*-■-- I ■■**._ — — _____ ■■■■ Dividends credited I' — 4.13MB Total. SUPPLEMENT AL KEPORT Plan of association _ _ - — Permanent Number of shares issued niuoe oriranizatioii- 1U.MW.7 Number uf nham aataaadtag la&gt;t report — 4.738 Sh:iri&gt;s laaacd siu.p last rt-port - 3,136Vi Total .— - - - ■ x '"'t Shnrvs withdrawn, aatured or caafMIM siucf hist repurt '• 52 **_&gt; Xuml&gt;er of shares in force this clnte »tl% Average running tln_e of stock matured iluriiig the year — 1_8 uioiiths Number of borrowing stockholders - — — Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ _ "'-'". Number of loans made for building purpose* during year...- 10 Number of loans made for parcaaatef of homestead*' or payment of homestead mortgages during year Par value of ench share of stock...- - - $ ]••._■ Amount of does owing by borrowing stockholder^ '" v j '" \nninnt of interest, premiums anil fines ilneu ,unl unpaid 1.1.17.06 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure — No. « &amp;,&lt;■&amp;« 1.1.T7.0B Amount of lojins on improved real estate 2O5.000.W \ppralsed v.ilue at nniinproveil real estate upon which loan* haw been made - - - .•____■__! \mount of loans on unimproved real entate _ ~ Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have 1.--1U.UU ,l|l|ll_l!^U l """ : "» m«_|».v._« __... ._--... r~— , . - been made ..»■*' '■ Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association _._„,_, as collateral security - - . 23U.21U00 Vmount of tornado insurance in force ami assigned to the association ____ as collateral security US- IS Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ _-''"' Amount of dividends declared on running stock .luring year .... i mm Mnoiint of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year MB "" Rate ner cent of .llvlrlerds declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and fall paid stock during year year __ _ _ - — -■■• ■'■_•■* Rate i&gt;er cent of Interest charged borrowers during year * W </seg>
            <seg id="p030">28 TWEXTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HLAIK miLI)I\(i AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BLAIR, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President. ... ; E . R. Stewart Vice President F. W. Arndt E tar &gt;' John Schmaling urer C A. Schmidt ne &gt;' Clark O'Hanlon Clark O'Hanlon DIRECTORS BCraver ueller E. R. Stewart John Schmaling F. W. Arndt C. A. Schmidt Clark O'Hanlon ASSETS Klrst mortgage loans Loan* on stock or pa»» book wnurlty ToUl. LIABILITIES Rnnning stock ami ilirt&lt;lcu&lt;l» Paid-up stock and dividends. _ _ Kegerve fund Undivided profits ToUl __ t 98,932.41 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 29 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 UFA KII n I'iish on ha in) last report _ $ 2.M2JV I&gt;mw iKuniLiii^ stocki .. - !t;*»^J s J l':i itl -up stuck M'TtLTi'l — •' p;iVIlieUt8 ■ _ iT.'» v OHI IlltlT.-St -. KitK'S «.____ tm '.Mt.Ty Mt'in bcrsUiii and traus/er fees. llo.j." Total. I'l.-i-.i i:sl MEMS Morlsage loans _ _.- - - - — * K-STSkOO Withdrawals running stock anil dividends _ IvlIT Withdrawals paid-up stock _ _ _ Salaries - - - -"^' '"' Other expense _ —.. — _—.»_.«— ~ . ltH.tt! TunIi on baud _ Notes paid — Paid-up stork interest Interest on notes lU Total - 8LPPLEMKNT XL Ui:i'OUT Plan of association...- _ — _ — Permanent XmnluT of shares outstanding last report _ 2,322 Shnrt-s Nsiifil *incc l:ist report — 301 m.*_i " it ■ Total _— _~~— ~~— . —- - ~- - I I Share* withdrawn, matured or ciimrllfd sim-e last report M Nmnlicr of shnrfs in forco tkla ilnlf - Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ — JJ Number of shares subject to cancellation for non .payiueut of due*. 2» Average running time of stock matured during the year 10S month* Number of horrnwin^ sioi-kholihT-* — I' 1 -* Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ - _ - l : '- ; Par value of each share of stock _ — $ ini.mi Total amount of dues delinquent at this date — — 5SS Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders. _ - .\iiti'i'&gt;i i** in*. ■••••it premiums nnd fin«"* line and unpaid HftM Amount of loans on improved real estate — — '•«&gt; .' " A|ipi ;i i^t'ii vnliif of Improved rt-nl t i st;n»* upon wliii-h loans have been made . — ■ — 168,730.00 mtide Amount of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association 9fl.iT: as collateral security \mount of tornado insnirance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - — - - - HIM rvp ''mill tllirintr year - 1-^O.nO •lared on running stock iluring year Q^MMI \ Amount of dlTidend* declared on running stock iluring year QMM| i.':iim tier cfiit of itiviilt'iMls dcclnreil on runninir stuck during year _ s ' c Rate per cent of interest charged borrower* Ball— year </seg>
            <seg id="p032">30 TWENTY-FIFTH AXNUXL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ENTERPRISE LOAN AND HIILDING ASSOCIATION CAMBRIDGE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President W. H. Falin K Vice President R. H. Rankin Secretary D. L. Tallmadge Treasurer James Kelly Attorney...."..... B. F. But'.e- DIRECTORS J. M. Hollingsworth D. F. Neiswanger J. W. Hammond A. A. Moosel W. H. Faling H. E. Day C. M. Brown R. H. Rankin A. E. Thorndike ASSETS First mortgage lo«ns * IM.eoaOd Ci&gt;h _ _ t.»i;d Delinquent Interest, flnea, etc - MJI Taxes paid ."pl'.lo Liberty lo«n _ l,ou&lt;&gt;.00 Total * :».ft«.7s LIABILITIES Running stock und dividends .. * J«.i "-'-' »'• Doe •bareboldera on Incomplete loan* _ _ 400.1K1 Keaerre fund _ — IV.M indiTlded profit* __«_ _ :t.4OS.7s Total , $ .TO.6iie.TS </seg>
            <seg id="p033">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 31 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RE&lt; EIPTS Caih on band last report - Due* (Running stock) f iftMB Mortgage payments _ MHN Stock loan payments — 6— Interest IJM IS Fines - - 17--' StfembersbiD snd transfer fees .... — l s &gt; 1 1 am Membership and transfer fees DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loan* f ll.wn.no Stock loans .............. '■**■"■ '•' Wltiarawalt running stock - 4.:u7 it Withdrawals of interest 2M.V. Commissions - — ■ M ' Commissions Ml Other expense - 4-. 11 Otber expense Cash on hand T_ '.'. '.'. ♦JM3- [s-lllj loan __ , 1.000.00 Total - - ♦ __^8IJMI SUPPLEMENTAL. REPORT 1^1 _tn nt jiflsiocl_it_on _______ — - PSTB£O- &gt; nt Numl&gt;er of shares issued since organiziition 1.484 Number of shares outstanding last report , _■ Shares issued since last report — * Total l.*14 Sbart-x — itlidrawu, matured or (MftlM slm* last report - M Nuinlier of shares In force this date - - 8M Number of shiires on whk-h dues are deiliniueiit _ _ — .. Xumlier of l&gt;orrowing stockholders. _ 3fl NunilxT of noil -borrowing stockholder* - Number of loans made for building purposes during year- 1« Par value of curb share of stock - 9 IOOlOO Total amount of dues delinquent nt this date - Sfi Amount of dues owing bv borrowing stockholders - _ V s "" Amount of interest, premiums and fines due mid unpaid. _SM" Amount of loana on improved real estate - IM— — Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have „_,_, been made _ - — - • L..S0O.0O Amount of lire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as ct.llateral security - - — •-— - — 27. 330.0" Amount of tornado Insurance in force ami assigned to the association as collateral security - S"?H"SS Value of improvements _ - - - — '„",' !5' 30.wn.oo Amount credited to reserve fond during year - OlJJi Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year S% </seg>
            <seg id="p034">32 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CENTRAL CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CENTRAL CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ E. E. Ross Vice President _...R. Tooley Secretary F. K. Sprague Treasurer _ J. W. Vieregg Attorney E. E. Ross DIRECTORS E. E. Ross J. W. Vieregg P. A. Duffey F. K. Sprague ASSETS First mortgage loans.. * IK.lMO.IIO 7,138. tt Delinquent Interest, fines. He. LtJ3.90 Total * 23,442.0a LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend,. Keserve fund ...- * j:;.M'.&gt;.:u 1.1M.TS Undivided profits ■1T1.W Unpaid Interest and tine* M\.'M&gt; Total.. * ii.44^.l» </seg>
            <seg id="p035">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 33 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report - ♦ 4.41UB Due* (Running stork' - _ - uues Miunning stocki - -. -.!.-■ -'i Mortgage puymettts —.—••«_«•—•--—•. v'iMM^ Intent ....... H- I** ■■" Kiues ."........". 31.40 Membership and transfer fees _ — - - ls *t5J Unearned dividend* _...... _ 110.30 Total $28,4».» DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans ........ * !•»»«&gt; Withdrawals, ruuulug stock and dividend* _ - 14,411.10 Salaries '. _ £H Commissions - -i ■*' - - - — _ S-?9 other expense Cash on hand - i.M*.l» Total fx,im.n Cash on' band _^___-______— — _ __ T.I iM» Total. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - Permanent Number of shares ts«ued since organization 2, MO Number of shares outstanding last report _ _ 856 Shares issued since last report .261 Total - 1.13? Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report _ — Number of shares' In fom' this date - - -... Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ - — — 12* Number of Khares subject to cancellation for iiou-payment of dues. •&gt; Number of borrowing stockholders - — - - 11( Number of non-borrowing stockholders - - — 84 Number of loans made for purchasing oif homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year ... - - - «*«« l'ar value of each share of slock _ - - - — $ J2J55 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date - _ !r t?"S? Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders - _ — Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid - j»Jt!»&gt; Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure Xo. 1 J.UO.OO Amount of loans on improved real estate - lK.04tt.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have ,-««/«» been mad.e - - 4l.ioO.no Amount of fire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - ■' : '""" Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association _«~w,»« as collateral security — - - 21l ?S??5 Amount credited to reserve ftiml during year - 1* -J3 -\nmuiu frt*iin«Mi ivrrwitr mini &lt;i&lt;iiu&gt;* .nr«n ;^.™ Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year ..imijw .MUOUIll Ul Un ItiriniB un mini mi iimum*. ~i*nm ••u.ihm .- • IVji, Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year naitf p«?r itui ul »ii» »u«:»«ww u^uku «&gt;» ■.■..■•i,. r . ....... ■ ■ , m j^— - Riite |&gt;er cent of Interest charged borrowers during year M </seg>
            <seg id="p036">34 STATEMENT of the condition of the CLAY CKXTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CLAY CENTER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President E. W. Orr K President _ C. D. Ellis tary J. L. Camnbell J. L. Campbell ™ ■■■ -™« j «# . aj. v&gt;*»uijJL«rii Treasurer J. L. Campbell DIRECTORS J. W. Whitlam L. B. Sluyter N. W. Johnson J. L. Campbell H. B. Campbell George S. Ward ASSETS First mortgage loan* 47,'»O.&lt;»1 Loan* lu process of foreclosure. oih«r real estate :.4&lt;u.in uOO.Ofl Drltnquent interest. flu««, etr. Taze* and Insurance paid Total LIABILITIES Running stock and iliviih-mls. BsxiTf fund _ Cndlrlded profit* Total </seg>
            <seg id="p037">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 35 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 HBCE IPTS &lt;':i&gt;h on hand laxt report. _ * ."i,.".1."i.hi Dili's i Kiiiiiiiiiu atarki _ - _ 11(I7«.1.*&gt; Hues I Kuiinhii; stocki _ _... _ 11.076.15 I'aiil -up stock _ _ _ _•.&lt;«» i i«i .Niorttfafrp payment* ~ _ _ « . ll^MV Mortgage payments - _ _ - _ 1 IJ&amp;toAM Re«l estate gale* JcBOO Re«l estate gale* __ . JcBOO Interest Premium 1 11 1 ere* t _ _ _ I 1'." J.~. una Premium _ .... . siit '.»."■ KiDea .... ... 41.25 KiDea 41 JB Rents - _ _ 21.ID Kents _ _ _ il.OO MeuiberAbip and transfer fees. _ _ :if&gt;.4&gt;» Taxes and insurance repaid. 'Jo.65 Sundries - .- K* '.&lt;! Total $ -*■ '.»!!» .'7 DISBl'Ii SK :mexts Mortgage loans $ T.111.M Wirhdntwals running stock and iliviiicmls Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawal* dividend on paid-up stock 111.70 Salaries 1.T0.III f"aajaj|aaU»aja '..:■•■ Other expense IKS.H1 &lt; 'ash on hand :t.i**.46 :u &lt;• Taxes and iusuramt* Total J ■ '»)'.» '7 lUPPLKXSlfTAL RKPORT rinn of association _ _ I Vr mm tent Number of »hare« outstanding l;im report .... 1,112 Shares Issued since last report 1*6 Tuial 1.207 l.iial Share* withdrawn, mature*! or &lt;*H»celled simv la*t report _ J7** Number of tvhareR in force this Mate _ — . ■•_".&gt; Xumber of shares on which dues are delinqaeirt M Vumher of shares subject to cancelUtlon for non-pajment of dues 15 Average running time of irtook matured during the year 74 month* Nan ikwr of horrow injr jftm-kholden* €1 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 54 Number of loans made for building i&gt;ur|»otte*t iluring year. Number of ln;um made for purrun*iug of honieKtead'* or payment of bomeRtead- mortgages during year.— 4 Plan oi premium - - - Monthly I inu »&gt;i | »rt- in ill hi .. - - ———„-_. — —■—■»! Tar value of each share of stock _ ...- - $ NMUH) Totnl Minoui'T of dues delLmiuent at thin date - 1.J4O.UJ Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholder 1.210m Amount of rntere»t, premiunui and fine** due mid unpaid MMi Number and amount of mortgages *ubje«-t to forecltwure No. 6 4.7Hhin&gt; Number and amount of mortgage* in prore*H of forevhmure No. 4 :i,4&lt;*).0ll AiiHUint of loans »)ii improve*! real estate .~iO,flMM)li Appraist&gt;d value of improxed rent SS-ttstS Bpas] which loaiiH have Im»«»ii Tunde _ _ l(M..10(M&gt;0 1 ■♦-* - » i made Amount of loans on unimproved real estate _ 3uU«0 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon wihch lonns hare be*'ii made _ - liunn Amount of fire iusurRnce in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - «_..VK&gt;.nn aft ruiiairiai ui i hi »»j -■ Amount of tornado insurance in force ami asaUgDed to the association as collateral security - i;l..TiO.(lll Amount credited to reserve fund during year 2«M» Aiiimuiii "' .Hvideiiils dwhireil aa rumiiiig stm^k liuriuK vmr .... 4.*8J« Amount of dividends paid on matured and pald-uu stock ilurinv 111.70 year Rate ywr cent of dividend* declared on running stock during rear Rate per cent of dividend* paid on matured and full paid stuck durtiifr vpAF __ ___ _ _„ ___ _. M _«. «* --_, „._ ..,.■■ ■ I.... v*# K.ite |wr icnt if iutcre*t charged borrower* during year »% </seg>
            <seg id="p038">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REl'ORT CF TH" 36 STATEMENT of the condition of the 0OLUMBU8 LAND. LOAN AND BlILDINfJ ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ J. H. Galley Vice President G. W. Viergutz Secretary -.Henry Hockenberger Treasurer E. H. Chambers E. H. Chambers DIRECTORS L. F. Gottschalk Theo. Moersen E. P. Dussell A. L. Rollin J. H. Brock J. H. Galley G. W. Viergrutz Henry Hockenberger E. H. Chambers ASSETS First mortgage loans. Lotus In process of foreclosure.. Loans on stock or pass book security other real Mtate I'nitfil Htmtca mill iminitipiil m-curltlrs Cash Delinquent Interest, lines, etc-. Insurance premium paid _- Tntml. LIABILITIES RannlngT' stock and dividends.. Paid-up stock and dividends.. Reserve fund _ ll'.l!-J*N&gt;.«Nl s.im.n&gt; Undivided profits ■171.78 TotaL. f4.stMUW.0K </seg>
            <seg id="p039">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 37 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1917 ■H Cash on band last report- - Kir ■TS ',£;££ Dues I Running siorki Paid-up stock t;.a&gt;iot«&gt; Mortgage payments 13S.0OU0O Stock loan payment Real estatt- saics Interest Prenihini Fines Rents Membership and transfer fee: Mortgage foreclosure Total niSBO Mortgage loans SEMKNTS $106,900.1)0 Stock loans Ki.'.««iiii 165.M0..1O iw.ioo.no Withdrawal* running s4ork ami iii\i»lt\ d» Withdrawals paid-up stock 7.7TO TO Withdrawals dividend on paid-up ~to. k Salaries Tjmn Other expense 4-.T.2S Real estate teeovBi 40.104.)%! Cash on h;uul Insurance premium M.m&gt; Interest refunded .-.•-«, U. S. Government bond .-,„..,.. Mortgage foreclosure ajm m Total »3TO,1».61 SUPPLEMENTAL UKPORT Plan of association .. _ Permanent NuiuWr of shares issued sim-e organization _ 31.510 NiimlxT of shares miistnmlinK last report....- 10.S01 Number of shares issued niinv orjrniiiuition 8hares Issued since last report - 2,085 Total _ 13.1S8 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report- 2,511 Number of shares in force this date-. _ lo.irrr. Number of shares on which ilm-s are delinquent — .■•**• Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues.... B Average running time of stock iiiiiture&lt;l durius the year _ 98&gt;4 months Number of borrowing stockholders _...„__ 283 Number of non borrowing stockholders _ £3 Number of loan* made for building purposes during year 9 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment &lt;&gt;f hrtinesteiHl-iiMirrgages during year — — - — H Pir value of each share of stock - _ $ 10*VQ9 Total amount of due* delinquent at thU date _ _ Ul 't; Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders - ."&gt;.!&gt;h* ■ Amount of interest, premiums and one* due and unpaid — 4,17N.«t Nmlwr and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure \". 36 4iSn».t«&gt; Number and nmtiun-t of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 3 4.744.1*1 Amount of loans on improved real estate - - 400,700.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loan* hare heen made . _ SM.sr7.3O Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 5.000.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon wfbch loans have been made — — -— ........^.. ............ —— !."» 4 ■"**'. 0* • Amount or fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - _ -... 390,910.00 Amouut of tornado Insurance In force and assigned t» the association as collateral securitj - 302,730.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year IJAiXK Amount of dlvldemln declared on running" stock during year 2 - -\33».S&gt; Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock &lt;lu rinif year _.._ _. 7. 1 10.70 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year &lt;'■ 7.'-, Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during vear —...-..— —._....... S*% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year - — 7 H </seg>
            <seg id="p040">38 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING. LOAN AND BAVINO8 ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President.. Henry Ragatx Vice President W. A. Boettcher Secretary.... J. C. Echola Treasurer.- G. B. Speice Attorney Louis Lightner DIRECTORS J. C. Echols Henry Ragatz W. A. Boettcher G. B. Speice Louis Ligrhtner ASSETS Pint mortgage loans wrr.4.-.o.oo Hfl7.-KiO.00 -J.-MMMXI 4.661.12 Loan* on stork or paa« liook m unity •-'.4«».00 &lt; it her real estate 4.681.12 a) to rj lfl 3.1U8.77 W.UU.W Delinquent intWMit, Biik, Kc 3.1U8.T7 T«x»« paid , - - F. R. Liberty Bond 1 1O.97 110 97 1.OM.00 l.mw.oo Total «4M(.13S.0I! J49H.12S.0e LIABII-ITIK8 Running ■tork and dividends l*aiil up fitock and ilividt-mN Rcaerre fond - j-.r.as.wiT.*) L»«;.Sj&lt;).00 K36.HOT.90 ...... 2tt! S3O.00 _ _.. _ 1O4.T6.22 1O.-W6.22 Cixllvided pmflta _ _ :O.90 :n.90 $48B.12S.0e Total </seg>
            <seg id="p041">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 39 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report. _ a 48,880.40 Does (Running stock) - _ ~. 'ri.GSn.'n Paid-up stock , _ , 43!7Sl(jn Mortgage payment* _____ ______ "MitS).!*} Stock loan payments _ _ _ _ 4.3T5.0O *4\45O.0O Interest _ _ .. . " _!" _ s&amp;_H ~i&gt; Fine. .'I _Z _ " 4^:5, Bent* . .'. _~~!_ "^'.n 222.W Membership and transfer feea. _ .'.til &lt; Interest on deposK ■ ".'. - 55».M Taxes paid _ ..' _ _______ it .vi TotaL. DISBURSEMRNTS Mortgn E e loans - _ _ _ , »123.3.V».no Stock lunns 2,600.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividend* _ 43,053.% Withdrawals paid-up stock ..._ ~. IHl.-Mtl \Vith&lt;irnw;ils diTldend on paid-up stock lA.392.9fJ Salaries _ _. _ . 2.9M.78 Com m in Unions _ _ - _ _ _ 1441.14 Other expense _ _ _. - „ +11 16 Real estate account _ _ _ 1.4S3.51 Cash on hand _ '.'. .... _... 2O.40C.M6 Interest returned - _ 27.00 Taxes paid 133.18 D. 8. Liberty bond - - _ 1,000.00 Total *2K7,211.47 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of nMtociatlon _ _ „ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization. _ 11.11™ Numlwr of sbaer* outstanding lut report 11,860 Shares issued since last report _ _ . 1,321 Vi Total -a i«ow Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report- - - -' "-Ih Number of shares in force this date - _ 11. (w Number of shares in force this date- Number of shares on which dues are &lt;lelinqu-nt _ ST2 Number of shares nuhject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 16B Average running time of stock matnred during the Tear 113 months Number of borrowing stockholders - - -UK: 113 months Number of borrowing stockholder- Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ _ Xffl Number of lonns mitde for building purposes daring year 11 Number of loans made for puri&gt;h»»ine of homestead* or payment of ■ homestead-mortcrages during year &lt;B Pa." value of each share of stock - - * IOOiOO Total amount of dues delinquent at this date +.138 4&lt;1 Amount of dnes owing by borrowing stockholders 4.13G.4O Amount or iin™« owinK uy nurrowinK wifi* 'iDoiarn ».i.mit i» Amount of interest, premium and fines due and unpaid _ — *'.luft &lt; . Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure...- No. 22 '.'4.2&lt;ionn Amount of loans on improved real estate. - -..- _.. 461,fl6O.fln Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made ..._ _ _ M3.nonn» Amount of loans on unimproved real estate _ _ rt.40000 Appraised value of untmproved real estate upon wlhch 1mm have been made _.. _ • _ _ _ H.flOO.flft Amount of tire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ '. 411.0N&gt;.Ort Amount of tornado inau'rance in force and assigned to the association 9M collateral security _ _ - _ _ 3B6,34O.fln aj* 'uiuiifrni »— f-iirit.T _ - _ - *t&gt;i,-*k'.'"' Amount credited to reserve fund durlmr year _ 1.477.*** Amoum cr»— men to renerv— runa aunrv year _ i.tii.— . Amount of dividends declared on ninnlne stock diirirrif year l.i.lfH &lt;T&gt; Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year - - - - l&lt;l.«r&gt; M&gt; Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dnrtng year T% Rate per cent of dividend* paid on matured and full paid stuck during year - - - — •% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year _ _ 7 In </seg>
            <seg id="p042">40 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION CRETE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President. _ Geo. H. Hastings Vice President F. J. Rademacher Secretary and Treasurer _ W. S. Collett Attorney _ Geo. H. Hastings DIRECTORS W. K. Hopkins F. J. Rademacher W. S. Collett Geo. H. Hastings B. G. Miller Robt. R. Hastings Ed. J. Steidl V. J. Shebl Ed. M. Parker ASSETS First mortgage loans - - $127,810.00 Loans on stock or pass book security _ - 2.180.00 LtUfliis uu siwi ui p«B» Dtsuk »r* unij — - - ..inu.w Ca»h _. _ ™. 200.90 Delinquent interest, flnet, etc — 75.10 r^lino"**nt duts — - . 01.00 Tax sales _ . . .... . 708 88 Insurance __._._... 206.17 708.88 Total _ - $131,311.05 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ _ _ $118,600 36 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans-.- - 1.74fl!51 Reserve fond - - - - 2,^6.39 UndlTlded profits - 4.89 Certificate of Indebtedness (Issued for matured stock) _ 8,700.00 Total-— - - - $131,311.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 41 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report - Duet (Running stock) „______ t 2.73675 2i4*.30 Mortgage payments , _ 22.400.00 Stock loan payments _ _ _ .1.1X00 Interest . Fine* t^M .,.;.-„ Membership and transfer few S0B.75 Delinquent dues. Inn-rest anil fines _ tfl4.se insurance and tax sales — - ~. Certificates of indebtedness (matured stuck) — — v7"O'TO Incomplete loans _ „. _ l.»I13 41 T ; -.44 Total _ _ $ 0P.KO.M DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loan* _ $ 24 tro 00 Stock loans - j.4.'ti&gt;no * SMMff Stock loans w f ■■•r,m ;,is. ruiniiti; Mink uud iliviiltniln 40,62967 Salaries _ _ *«.flb Otner expense _ _ - r_V4.ft6 Insurance and tax sale* .-...- __.__ Incomplete loan* _ au 10*. 11 Total..- _ - - • •.-•OiJ*) SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT flan of association ...-_. , _ .... Serial Number of series issued since organization _.._ _ _.. Number of shares issued since organization _ v.To I.". Number of shares issued since organization Nuinlwr of shares outstanding last report — 3.302 l&gt;uuiiH^r 01 snares ouismimiii]; nisi rfrpuri. — — ,— ■ »— S&gt;-»-es issued sim* last report _ 1,086 Total - - 4.460 ToUl Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report ."HO Number of shares In force this date. — MP NumtK-r of shares on which dues are delinquent 51 Avenge running time of stock matured during the year _... 140 months Number of borrowing stockholders NTS Number of non-borrowing stockholders .— 1-T Number of loans made for building purposes daring year _ IT Par value i.f art share n! Mack. ..._ — I !•_«• Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. _ - ■ B Amount of dues owinjr t&gt;y borrowing stockholders - — . *H '*&gt; Amount 6f interest and fines doe and unpaid 7R.10 Amount of loans on Improved real estate - — 127.810.00 Appraised value of lmpro— &gt;d real estate upon which loan haTe been made _«»«»_—«—»—». „ * - 23*V_B0l0O Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association a« roltnteral security 14B»J*5.0O aft collateral security Amount of tornado insurance in force ami assigned to the association as collateral security - 119/iOOft) Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ ill- 1 * Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year _ Ppt-O IAMMQ Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock LM during year Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year — _. •% </seg>
            <seg id="p044">42 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the DAVID CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION DAVID CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President W. F. Delaney Vice President J3. J. Hyatt Secretary and Treasurer _ G. A. Bryant Attorney R. C. Roper DIRECTORS W. F. Delaney S. J. Hyatt B. J. Sheldon H. F. Anderson Jno. Eberly C. H. Ammon C. F. Clark G. A. Bryant J. B. Hookstra ASSETS Pint mortgage loan. $ .TJ. 128.70 Cash _ __ ___ __ ___________________ _____ 1,217.31 Furniture and lii'urn ________________________ 30.00 Total $ .TS..I96.01 LIABILITIES Kunnlnc stork an&lt;J dividend* _ - _ lrt.118.55 •* ■ a i •- * ■■ •■ ■ iUIIIAJ IK Paid-up stock and dividend* _ __ i*.«(H.15 nmiiTi fond _ 285.00 I'ndWlded profits ". .__ __HH .... 390.31 Otkar llabllltie* '. _ 13,500.00 1S.500.00 j ■___ </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 43 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING PJan of association - — - Permanent Number of sl'nrvs outstanding last NMft »ff"U, Kliiin-&gt; issued since last report - * 1.2»**4 Total Shares withdrawn, "matured or cancelled since last report MM Number of shares in force this dau Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders Number of loans made for lmildinir purposes during year _ _ 1 Number of loans made for purchasing of homestead* or payment of homestead mortgages during year ——__—. 3 a of premium - - - *P»' "".".'■ ■ Plan of premium par value of eni-h uliarc of stock - - $ UJ2 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders- - «Mi Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid. _ Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 1 - ■ Amount of loans on ImproredT real estate. Apr rn Wed value of improved real estate upon which loans haTe __ been made - - - - — . j. 101.500.00 Amount of fire Insursnee In force and assigned to tk« assocUtion .,„&gt;„. as collateral security - - - »*""" Amount of tornado inmiranoe In force and assiirned to the ajasoclatiou as collateral security Amount credited to reserre fund during year. AJUOUUl ciruiiru iv nun »tr iuuu uuiuifi j r " M — Air-n'-nt of iHvlrtepdii deilnre&lt;t on running stock during year l.W».» Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock farina- a^ssjMa T64r , , . _ Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rite per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock •K during year «-. Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year H jl.ml au, iyiv RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report Dues (Running stock) - - - - Paid -un stock ...- - - — — Mortgage payments - - - Interest _ «. ~ Membership and transfer fees _ BHIb payanla Total ■ 8.10 MM.M 32.31J. «T&gt; 14600.00 $ T0.2W 14 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - - Withdrawals running stock and dividends Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock ...- Salaries - Commission* Other expense __.._ Cash on hand Interest on notes payable - Outstanding checks in last report («-3O-l«&gt; Bills payable - 4.J4J .8. 17.231.SM M Total - T^7&gt; SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT </seg>
            <seg id="p046">44 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FAIRBURY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRBURY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS A&gt; v&gt; -»-■■■■■*■■■■-.-—»■■»■■•.■•■■••■■■■■■■»»»» ■■■«*■«■■■ •&gt;•••■■»■ ■*a»»_ B ***v******»«__*w_v»* — -- -^^La V • K *~Bp^ Vice President E. L. Simpkins Secretary _ Max Merrell Treasurer H. H. Me Lucas Attorney..- a Max Merrell DIRECTORS A. V. Pease H. H. Lodt J. H. Bond S. H. Diller J. C. Lien J. A. Axtell F. L. Rain E. L. Simpkins H. H. McLucas First mortgage loan* _ t 55,450.00 Loans on stock or past book security- - U65.00 State and municipal securities — _ _ 1,3)2.40 1.3W.40 Cash 4 &lt;L*tt.St _ •■"•° l " Total _ S &amp;J.134 24 w ~~*»~~»— - LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ $ 52,786.41 Paid-op stock and dividends - _ _ 7,400.00 Reserve fund 1.700.00 Undivided r*"**^ '24S.8S Total...- _ f 82.1S4.34 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 45 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 HKI'EII'TS Cash on band last report- f 1.TOTJT Due* (Running stock) _ _ l!».."i&lt;»t. 14 l!»..-K«t.U l'am-up hi..c_ 1.S00.00 Mortgage payments - - — - IMMtM Stock loflD piiyments _ __— ™ — - *[l'N.tii Interest JT-— _ -.. .... 5,115*0 Pines ».T1 KilU'N _ _ m _ ft.Tl Membership and transfer fees.. ■_"7 1 .u«i Total - »4M8».T1 Total - «4M8».71 DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ $ 14.900(10 Mortgage loans _ $ 14.9uO.iiO Sotck loan* - ; M.\U&gt; Sotck loans ■ ; M.\U&gt; M.-..WI Withdrawals running stock and diTliiends _ _ 26.lWf.SB Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ _ 2t.im.av Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock v.i l : Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock 551.13 Salaries _ _ _ _ _ 300.00 Commissions ..'.'. - 1W.."ki Com missions — « ~ ■ 144J.."m» Other expense — _ . ... s?,i I"» X . K ——————— ———————— — ~uw.air Other expense ™ _ Sf,i I"» Cash on band _ 4.1^0 m Cash on band • . _ 4 yen m County warrants _ lJ3tin.4i&gt; Total - $48,886 71 SII'IT.EMENTAL, REPORT Plan of association »__■»«■ . Permanent Number of shares issued since organization. - _. -','JKi Number of shareg outstanding last report — — 1.820 shares issued since last report 2Ki To*al — - _ 2.108 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report --J!' Number of sbares in force this date. IJM Average running time of stock matured during the year 77 mouth* Xumlier of borrowing stockholders , 52 Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 14.1 Number of loan* made for building purpose* during year. Nuiulier of loans iiiaile for purchasing of homesteads ur payment of homestead mortgages during year I value of each share of tt«l:. - _ I 100.(iC) » Par value of each fin of Man Amnnnt of interest nri milling nml tines ilue and unpaid 002.91 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreiosure No. 11 H.nuu.ix Amount of loans on improved real estate 95,4SO\00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hare been made _ _ — - W/HtM Amount of tire insnrM nee in lace* ami assigned to the association as collateral security - - 06,730.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ .'7 .snu»i Amount credited to reserve fund during year- - 3" 1 " Amount of iliviilemls declared on running stock during year 3,744.18 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year ——— ——————————— — - .'.^' i '. Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year T% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during ««r - •% Rate per cent of interest Charged borrower* during year _ — - 4- . </seg>
            <seg id="p048">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 46 STATEMENT of the condition of the FAIRFIKLI) BULDI.Mi AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION* FAIRFIELD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President C. L. Lewis Vice President Wm. Ashby Secretary and Treasurer F. Anawaft DIRECTORS J. E. Spatz Wm. Hoevet C. L. Lewis Walter Hogue » F. Anawalt ASSETS First mortgage loans 'MImt real Mtafi - Rf:il estate sold on contrart Taxes paid and insurance.. ■Liberty Bonds Total.. LIABILITIES Banning stork and dividends Paid-up stort and dividends Reserve fund Undivided profits Other liabilities ... Total $ .K1.8K.M </seg>
            <seg id="p049">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 47 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RE&lt; EIPTS Cash on band last report. $ 480.15 Due* I Running stock) .-..245.40 1 'a id -up stock 1.7CW.0O 9,isaoo Mortifape payments Imprest 4.455 flU K i lies MUO \lt* mtMTttliip nil;! transfer fe&lt; Taxes, la— mw and loan feei Total. $ BJsKM DISBIRSEMKNTS MnrUcHge loans Mortgage loans $ .1,*OO.M&gt; Withdrawals running itock and dividends vil* Withdrawals running stock and dividends Withdrawals pald-as stixk ;.»«■&lt;•. Withdrawals pnid up stoefc Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock i*."**.?*.' Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stork Salaries _ _ _... MuM Salaries . 300.00 Other expense Other expense ..._ „ _ 3RS 1 ««■ Real estate account _ - JS.("&gt; Real estate account •js.» Cash on hand _ _ Cash on hand S.13S.M Other disbursement* in detail Other disbursements in detail -i»": «&gt; 3CIW i;i\f*. nibiirauve. recording mimI ;il»strn&lt;t fee* TiOO.OO Total - $ 2l.3X!.!»7 laifH. lUMiimn I-. iih-oi ditiv Mini abstract fi ■»■* Total * .'1 ..V.J '.'7 i SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association .. „ Permanent Plan of association - - _ Permaueitt Number of shares issued since organisation .. -'".!&gt;] Number of shares issued since organization QS Number of snares •&gt;utstainlintr last report .888 N'omber «f Hlinrex outstanding last report 886 Share* issued since last report - - 88 Shares issued since last report - - 8* Total _ - - -... 97"-' Total _....... — — VT"— Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report - 147 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report - 147 Number of shares in force this date _ sSi Number of shares in force this date Number of shares on which ilue« are delinquent - HM Number of shares on which duet* are delinquent !■■» Niiml.fr of Rhares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues. 53 Number of xhares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues. 33 Average running time of stock matured during year 94 month* Average running time of stock matured during year 94 month* Number of borrowing stockholders ....._____..____...___.__ 81 Number of borrowing stockholders .... _._..___...___.__ 81 Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 44 Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 44 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 2 Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for puri-haxinK of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ Number' of loans made for puri-haning of homesteads' or payment of Par value of each stiuic of sn»ck _ — _ — S HMI Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ _ _ 1.117 l."&gt; Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders „ l.l-TT.ir* Amount of interest, premiums and fines doe ami unpaid _ 1.1H.1M Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 7 4,!fc"iO.u» 4.!«.-.O.i«&gt; Amount of loans on Improved real estate _ 4&gt;VRU.U&gt; Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare been made — - Hfr.«»IMiO Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - - t.yjfioii Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security BJM II Amount credited to reserve fund during year -. -"-I 1 " 1 ■ Amount of dividend* declared on running stock during year - ljK5 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during . . J*" : r= -■;■■.: ,- -•■•■- V : •ll"x-i . -— Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ - - - •"* Rate per cent of interest chaired borrowers during year o </seg>
            <seg id="p050">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 48 STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME Bl'ILDIXG AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FALLS CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President J. H. Hutchings Vice President R. R. Rule Secretary W. L. Redwood Treasurer P. B. Weaver Attorney _ R. C. James DIRECTORS K Hutchings Rule W. L. Redwood P. B. Weaver W. A. Greenwald ASSETS First mortgage loans - _ ? 30.713.(10 Louna on stock or ihihh book security 30B.OU Other real estate - 2.913.W Cash O.. w »v_\ Delinquent interest, lines, etc - i::s.ut Taxes paid and Insurance premiums _ _ 330.20 Total $ 61.1v-\:!&lt;&gt; LIABILITIES Running xtork nnil dividends _ | 50537.36 Paid-up stock anil dividends _ _ 8,030011 I»ue sharelinlde tr on bscosaptata loan* !»4.2.*&gt; Reserve fund - - 1.3wi.7:t X* ii ij 1 v id* 1 *! profits .°!-Wiw&gt; 1^11 uuuput lnt?r?4t ■ ._...„-. lriw.oo Tottl....- .._ f 61.182.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 49 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Casli on It mi (I Inst rpport «. - $ 2.&lt;H.~».H) Dues i liuiiniui; stock i __ _ P]|M|.||i. slOl'k „ 'J.-'"". 1 *) Mortpnpe payments _ „ MUOMtM Stock lonn p:i y ineutit — — — .._»_ ..-_ lli'im Real Mat* aaMa - l.W*.8B Interest — ,. _. _ Jlentu _ _ Membership mid transfer 1W* - ~ - Tmxea and fnsu ranee repaid — - - Ml *'•-' Loan expenses „ .. — _ SJ.flO Profit on withdrawn Is - ■" &gt; 1" -'** Total $ +4, **■►"•_' DISBURSEMENTS Mort pupe Ion us ...._... «. — — - 9 7.71 fi.^-^ Stork loans "* — — „.- (TJO.nn Withdrawals rannlac stock and dividend*. - 85,1!*.' 77 Withdrawal! paid-ap stock _ .'.Jim no Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock IH -i Salaries — — Commissions other expra Itenl estate account - - - "yr,r •&lt;•• Cash on lmnd ___________ _ _ _ M* Delinquent ta-es and insurance paid MM Total » «.*»7_ SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association — - - - — Permanent NnmliiT of shares mil st:uiciinir lnst report l.SBO'-i ■&lt;&gt; or.. s issued since lnst report 377 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled nince last report Number of shares In force tills date Number of shares on which dues lire delinquent Number of pharva subject to cancellation for nnn=T&gt;!ivment of dues -M Averntre running time of stock matured during the year MG month* Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-horrowlnp stockholders — ''j Nmnher of loans made for hnllilinir purpo«e« dnring rear Number of loans made for pnn-hnsinir of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortirapes during year Pnr value of earli si. ire of stock..' - - ♦ JSCIS Totnl amount of dues delinquent nt this date l.lfTTVflft Amount of due* owlnfr by borrowing stockholders -. JJJ '*' Amount of interest, premhims and fines due and unpaid _ ____! Number and amount of mortitages subject to fore&lt;-losure No. 3 _!fl?_5 lssm Amount of loans on improved real estate — 80,360.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate npmi which loans have been made M _" '*' Amount of loans on nnlmprored real estate — — S«s.i» Apprsised velne of unimproved real estate upon wthch loans hare oift#¥» been made - ■ ■■ •■■- _-_: Amo'i't -ce ll fHff »• —It-ri to the association ai collateral aecarity • -— ■— ■■_•§ Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association &lt;hotooo i*rtl 'r&gt;' -nl JaaiH I credited to reserve fund durine year iZil'-f Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year... Ma_M Amornt of dividends paid in matured and paid-up stock durlnc r y*r — -— - _ . — : _.__. -_-_-_= ■ J V..'" Ypn r _„ _.„_. .™—« - Put- t.er p»-t of iH-Mo-rt, ,iei'l»-ed on rui'"iii_ sti&gt;ck durlnv vear Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year onrinjr year o _*- Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year » I </seg>
            <seg id="p052">50 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President- _ Frank Hammond Vice President _ Frank Fowler Secretary _ Arthur Truesdell Treasurer Chas. B. Veazie Attorney Geo. L. I.oomis DIRECTORS Fred Bader Jas. A. Donahue Arthur Truesdell Frank Fowler Frank Hammond Frank Hanlon Geo. L. Loomis Fred H. Richards Chas. B. Veazie ASSETS Fir»t mortgage loans _ t"4o:i-Vi im Loans od stock or paas book security - ! ~ l.tiiOOo Loids od stock or pass book security - !1... Z~~....... .~~....~~. ' l!hi»)0i Cash !»'i&gt;47 01 nplliiquent iuterest, fines, etc _________ l|aU&gt;!tK Delinquent interest, lines, etc Furniture «nd fixtures _ 275.00 Other assets _ _ „ Ms\M Liberty Bond _ _ _____ l.inuuc Total OMJ-T-I LIABILITIES Running stock and diviileiulK $214 7^7 51 Paid up stock and dividends. " ' .el sVt Xi Reserve fund _ „ _ _ ri'dtn'm $214,727.51 r.,(NIO.(«l Undivided profits _ _ ' 'we,;£i Total *264.237.(_ </seg>
            <seg id="p053">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 51 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECKIPTS I .Wo on MnrlyiiKP payments .. Stock loan payments Interest Fines Mi'inluTsliii" »n«I transfer feti Other receipts in detail l'.rj..-ji 1.-..14S.!*; DISBIRSEMKXTS Morttface loans stork loans Withdrawals running stock and dividend Withdrawals paid-up stock . m Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stink Salaries - Other expense &lt;'ash on hand li.iHT.C'l in.in3.tt: Other disbursements in detail Over draft - Total SIl'l'I.KMKXT A I. IIKI'HUT Plan af association (serial or permanent I Serial and Permanent Number of series issued since organisation - -W Numlier i&gt;f share* aBtataadtac laal lapart - L'.ifiiv, Share* Issued sln&lt;* last report - — 8*it4 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sin. .■ last report ."^T" Number of shares in tan* tills date Number of shares on which dues are delini|u&gt;'i&gt;t Averaire raanlog tiin.- of sto&lt;k inaturid durlnir the M-ar 11!&gt; BWatka IWi XuraWr of loans made for liuildinc paraoaM •lurinii year ■ \u, .- ,.f Inn ni.nlf fur pniYhaatnir of homi-strads ,&gt;r pavinent »f homestead mortcageg during year 41 Par value of each share of stark * :- i.. Total amount of dues deliliiineiit at this dale iSerial" ■»'•'" Amount of dues owinir I&gt;v horrowlaa ■torkkoldrn iSeriaK -ill!. Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid 1. .«»•«• Vimilter and ainouliT of uiorteak'cs sulije&lt;-t t" forecliisure No. li SJMJ0.HI Number and ■moaal "f BMrtsaina suiijei-t tu tmrtttmmn Amount of loans on Improved real estate Appraised value of improved real eatate upon which loan hare been made Amount of ' Ore insurance in force and aaalaaai to the ass.Mlntl.ni „_,-„ as collateral security . ■ aa* Amount of tornado inmirance in force and as«Uned to the association ,_••-, 1!W.7I1K». as collateral security Amount credited to reserve fund during year - — Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year...... Amount of dividends paid on matnrM and paid-up stock dtirtiw n.ini i.itn.9T year m Rate per «-nt' of dividends de&lt;-iareii on running ptnjfc *■«*■«. ""J-j Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid Mock M during year Rate |ier cent of Interwt chiirged borrowers durlnit year. Tjfl 1 &gt;iii&gt;s i Running Mack) Paid-up stock $ M T". 1 " 4&gt; Number of borrowing Htorkluililern NuiiiIht of iioii-borrnwinjr *torkboldm :4n..i.V.t». KtJMHn -*).&lt;*&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p054">52 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA STATE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President...- : T. L. Mathews Vice President Ross L. Hammond Secretary D. D. Rowe Treasurer. J. T. May Attorney W. J. Courtriffht fColson E. R. Gurney es H. Hawley T. L. Mathews /. Stephens J. T. May Ross L. Hammond W. J. Courtright D. D. Rowe AS8ET8 t mortgage loans i in process of foreclosure i on stock or pass book aeciirlty r»':tl estate estate sold on contract ijuent interest, fines, etc Total _ $l.S7O,2!rr.53 7.3ne.."ii 1,140.0(1 21,180.20 4 744 93 ee.Tns.ae 4,896.77 fl,U7IS,12OU LIABILITIES Ping stock and dividends _ up stock and dividends- shareholders on incomplete loans Te fond rided profits Total tl.226.lfl9.74 OSMXIO.OO 9.311.40 4a.n0o.0n 70,643.76 $1,976,124.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 53 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ _ $ 67.&amp;M.67 Dues (Running stock) - - «. - 4**MtJT&gt;.19 Pm.. in. M... ► 171.40O.0t Mortgage payments _ _ 421,7TS.2M Foreclosure - _ _ _ _ e&gt;.:iMMSt Heal estate sales i::.h:j l'.&lt; Interest IX irJO.S.' — — — • •— • •• — — — — — — • ■ TTT'zr Fines _ M&amp;ll Membership and transfer fee* IJBJM Other receipts In detail _ _ _ Incomplete loaas _ - - J4.774 4T Total. DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans . — _ $ H&amp;M&amp;M Kunuiug stock dividends - -7r«i_'4 Wltimawala ruinintr stock anil &lt;iiviiieiids _ _ - 3S9.9O4J6 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ M.30O.W Withdrawals dividend on paid-up start - _ Salaries _.._ _ — v"«7 mi Commissions — - - — _— Other loans - ltt^KJ.OT Real estate account - - - W^iMIMKl Gash on hand - - - fMLTV.SW Postage, rent and fees _ - — 3..'W&amp;4tf Examiner's salary and traveling expense — _ J.0W.41' Foreclosure s.JlT.t*". Xofal - $1,276. 43&gt;.ttl SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - — — Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report _ - —46,4*7 Share* issued since last report — 12.M5 Total - - - M Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report -.rtTl Number of shares in force this date -HM41 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent - 220 Average running time of stock matured Vi months Number of borrowing stockholders _ - — — !.*»&gt; Number of non-borrowing stockholders. 2.1JW Number of loans made for building purposes during year _ 1&lt;4 Number of li ails made for purchasing of homestead* or payment of homestead-mortgages during year — - - 3M Par vnlue of each share of stock - ♦ IfrSS .fjnount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ 4.'!x&gt; . . Number and amount of mortirages subject to foreclosure-— No. 1» 22.000.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 7 ■ MAM 22.050.00 7.30*51 Amount of loans on improved real estate - - 1JBT1.005.SO Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - - - ~"~" 4.111J8HII Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — - 3,11».1«100 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association „„»«. as collateral security — »i2kS as conairrai bwuiuj — — -» — Z'z^rzz Amount credited to reserve fund during year- » fvJvSS Amount nf I. ■«!■« charred to reserve fund during rear 1.135.SS Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during s7.r.n&gt;-'4 „_._ HyH H * c * - : . ,.■ "til j__»__Ti __■_ _ -*~kb jxiM «&amp;»» Rate per cent "of dividends declared on running stock during ye«r Rate per cent of dlvMends p»id on matured and full paid stock •M during year —....-. — — JJ^- Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year _. T SA, </seg>
            <seg id="p056">54 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION GRAND ISLAND, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Chas. G. Ryan Vice President Richard Goehring Secretary C. W. Brininger Assistant Secretary John A. Ferguson Treasurer S. N. Wolbach Attorney James H. Woolley DIRECTORS K. Barr . Geer R. R. Horth C. B. Norris August Kruse Guy L. Harrison ASSETS Fir»t mortgage loans $s68.0K&gt;00 Loans od stock or p«M book aecurlty 22,7Wfl0 ttt'«*r real etHnte - „ 12,000.00 Cash . _ _ 14,if&gt;4.+6 Delinquent interest, lines, etc _ 1.O0B.1O Taxes Dald - 315.86 Liberty Loan Bonds 5,000.00 Mortgage loann— settlement kalanm UKM •r o tal _ _ _ »»2S,se'7.52 LIABILITIBS Running atock and dividends |7-K,«S».lf&gt; Paid-up stock and dlvldenda _ 1M.OHO.00 Doe shareholders on Incomplete lonus 13.800.00 Reserve funds - 36,KT»«&gt;.0o Undivided proflta - 1.718.T7 Interest paid in advance - - - •?■• «• ■ m Total _ _ Kfi.Mi:;iL' </seg>
            <seg id="p057">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 55 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Chan on hand last report.. Cksh on hand last report. - — - _ - $ 10.ttl9.25 Dues (Kuiming i _ _ 1MO.K21.8O MMO.M .Paid-up stock _ _ 34.400100 Mortgage payments ~ .— — ... „ „ 134,7t&gt;1.12 Stock loan payments - _ - _ .V.« Ml Interest - - - - (t.! r "'.in Flue* _ 426 96 \reml&gt;ertfhip and transfer fees .. _ .. ii.au Rents and onice building receipts. 43U.00 Tax sales redeemed — - "»*t.«i Payments on settlements balances accounts 1.619.80 Decrees of foreclosure paid _ Total.. DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - - - $222^0Bl&lt;0 Stock loans _ KJ.90U.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividend*- t*:.74*.44 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ 74.90O.0O Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock..- .' l.aw.15 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up atock..~ .' l.aw.15 Dividend on paid-up atock. - \2.:if;.:*&gt; Salaries _ - •JBOlM Salariea _ - «,TaOM Otbe r expena© _ '*■"" *T Other expense _ '*■"" *T Ken I estate tuvoulit ....... — ■"►■SJ.7^ Kettl P8tnte uwouut •- - ■— — • ■"►■Sj 7^ Cash uu hand ___ _ _ 14.-M.4* Cash uu hand I4.«».«i Tux snips pcmliaseil - 577.15 Tiix «n les puri'liuiMMl - 377.13 Liberty Loan Bonda _._ _ - S.mHT.ii Matured shares paid off — . »4.llOI).&lt;tt Matured shares paid off — M.0M.M Insurum .• premium advanced - 14.40 Total _ _ «4Uk.l'14.!"U SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association iserlal or permanent) Serial and Permanent N'umber of series Issued since organisation (if sertah 44 Number of shares Issued since ort-'anlxatlon _ HMH Yumber »if scares outstanding last report _ .24.718 Shares Issued since last report ...- O43 Total „ ?Ai 'Hjl Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 7 17:i Number of shares In force this date Number of shares on which dues are delinquent .— 9 Average running time of stock matured during the jwmt laaMMI 74 montua Number of borrowing stockholders - &amp;&amp; Number of non-borrowing stockholders - - l.(&gt;4»&gt; Sumlier of loans made for building purposes during year _... 143 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortKaxes during year - 90 Par value of each share of stock — — — ♦ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at tbis date _ (Seriall 4WI.36 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders. (Seriall 4HH.:S Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid l.mB.10 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ HtJH,:JUO.tt&gt; Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 1 - w ?-?5J'ff Amount of loans on unimproved resl estate UMI Appraised value on unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - — 7. -'.-■"'&lt;&gt; Amount of flre Insurance in force and assigned to the aiwo.-ls.tion . as collateral security ...- - !W,BMi Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - 8H2.4cn.0O Amount of money loaned on improved farms. ._ _ «.««).(» 8H2.4cn.on Appraised value of land not Including improvement* S.OIAOn Value of Improvements - - — » - 1HKX Amount of flre Insurance thereon 5!5t"22 Amount credited to reserve fund during year... .3 - .Vi ) 'SS Amount of dlvidenda declared on running stock during year Amount of dividend* paid on matured and paid-up stock dnrimc 47.271.«l Uste per cent of dividends declared on running stock during vear Rate per cent of dividend* paid on matured and full paid Mock e per itui \n uiviwuu* i#m«« w»» ■»»*«...« _— .... , during year ...^^ ..._ „ .--~ late per cent of "intereiit charged borrowers during year - If, </seg>
            <seg id="p058">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 56 STATEMENT of the condition of the IIARTINGTON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ M. E. Eby Vice President H. D. Spork Secretary F. O. Robinson Treasurer W. S. Weston F. O. Robinson Treasurer. DIRECTORS M. E. Eby W. S. Weston G. F. Scoville J. G. Beste H. D. Spork ASSKTS Flr»t mortgage loans t '.n.'WVOO Loans on stock or pass book security _ ljOO.On rfcsta _ 2.Mti.~i&lt;i Delinquent interest, fines, etc :i."iT.-W Insurance paid . - SUi Total - $ y".;t:ti.7o LIABILITIES Running utook and dividend! t 89.7V-.lt', Paid-up stock and dividends - -l.TdO.cxi Due shareholders on Incomplete loans _ mkuxi Reserve fund - l.ino.no Undivided proflti - _ - - - - »-7.29 I&gt;aes paid in advance 386.25 3S6.2S •Total ♦ 1*7,931.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 57 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report DufB (Running stock) Paid-up stock _— _. Mortgage payments Interest Fines Membership and transfer fees. Money borrowed Total. DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ * K.7"0.fl0 Withdrawals running stock and dividends - - UMH Withdrawals paid-up stock tf.WO.nn Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock _ - '*H 55 Salaries _ ■ ' _ _ 000.00 Other expense tf — . flC.40 Cash on hand _ 2.M8.SO Bill* payable and interest _...... 1.838.81 Stock matured - _ 13,800.00 Insurance paid - - -—. — . 20 SO Total |H ::T8 06 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) — Both Number of series issued since organisation (If serial) Number of shares issued since organization I '■*'•&gt; 21 Nnmber of shares issued since organization Number of shares outstanding lant report -23H0 Share* issued since last report _ . #70 Total - - 2.OT© Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report— rtan Nntnher of shares In force this date - 2.505 Number of shares on whicb dues are delinquent M jtverage running time of stock matured during the year - _ 90 months Number of borrowing stockholders _ _ _ 101 Nnmber of non-borrowing stockholders - 176 Number of loans made for building; purposes during year • Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads' or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ _ MM Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders — l"."-0 .- Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid — IMm Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 2 1 """n Number snn amount or mortgages suojecr to Toreci&lt;»*ure no. i - Nnmber ami amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 2 1.*00.nn Amount of loans on lmproveo renl estate _ _ fln.Timno Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare ll(^Oll Ilia '1C ■»»- --■■ *__■«**"»»—^^—■■» **•■ bibh ■** ■■... . . .»■■»-**«--- ..,. ._.■. ,**«■_■.. """*' ■■ • Amount of lire insurance In Ww and assigned to the association as collateral security _ - 118.730.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ - !&gt;T."W&gt;nn Amount credited to reserve fund during year \mount of dividends declsred on running stock dnring year 7.1W&gt;.&lt;!&gt; Amount of dividends paid on matnred and paid-up stock dnrlnir Year — — •-•- • - ■ jww 10 Hate ner rent of dlvidenrtji declared on running stock dnring year in*"?. Rate per cent of diTWends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - — — JJ^* Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dnring year 10% </seg>
            <seg id="p060">58 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HASTINGS Bl'ILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HASTINGS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President H. B. Cornelius Vice President W. M. Lowman Secretary ,, J. o. Rohrer Treasurer J. O. Rohrer Attorney John Snider John Snider Henry Siekmann Ezra Langevin George H. Pratt W. M. Lowman H. B. Cornelius H. C. Haverly . AS8ETS f mortgage loans „ on stock or pas« book mM-urlty .. „ ure and fixtures paid _________ Total F.MB.IICH.U) il.8io.on 16.1X1. n I7r&gt;.o(i 42.0B *'41 Ml 1*1 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends - Reaerre fund ., „ Undlrlded profits _ .!! ........" *23O.S37.71 6.!l3iOH 3.51J.(» (Z4LWLM </seg>
            <seg id="p061">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report. „ $ ft.3B7.34 I tues i Running stock ► ..." ...."". 44 J4;( ."&gt;o Mortgage payments _ ■ 98&gt;tT.C Stork loan payments ".. Woi.'ton Interest _____________ m'vi— i Fine* _ _ _ _ »j ,,„ Membership and transfer fees ...." _______________ Kl.« Taxes paid _ _ _ ______ __ Total _ _ _ *H.!.931.4.*&gt; DISB! lUSKMKXTS Mortgage loans f &lt;_^_3O.0t Stock loana _ _ _ - ltV^vxt Withdrawals, running stock and dividend*. _ _ _ M.M».M 8alariea — _ 1,178.75 Other expense — including rent _- 4fiO_8 Cash on hand - _ — 16,138.73 4oO_B Cash on band Directors' fees _ - (H.OO Rebates _ ~ - - tilt. HI Total - -... »143,9CU.4_ 81 TPLEMKXTAL ItKI'OKT Plan of association _ - Permanent Xumlwr of shares issued siui-e organizatidn _ 19._8&lt; \uml»er «tf uutstmulinff last report — ..?-fl»M iS Khar*, issues ■!■•« lust report Total - \926 Shares withdrawn, matured or &lt; ancelled since last report ~ 1,236 Number of shares In force this date - — "■*!£ Number of shares on which dues are (ie)lnquent - Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Jl Average running time of stock matured during the year 134 months Number of borrowing stockholders - — IHUmoer OI UOrruwiIlK siuriuuiurrn - — Number of non-borrowin* stockholders -» *- Number of loans made for purchasing of home»teads or payment of homestead -mortgages during year ~ ._m___Z II U lilt" MrUUUIUl IKBKC* "lU""f jxrm* ~ Par value nf each share of stock * "I,,-. rar vmur mi **m ■!! niiiiir &gt;&gt;i bum-. - mmii Total amount of dues delinquent at this date : -_■ '■'■• 17O.«», Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders.. - Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid -_ Number and amount of mortgeges subject to foreclo€ure No. S ",- .Ml 3,200.00 IHUmner aim aUlOUUl Ol mutmrgcB »uu;n.i m »w»»^»---»* *Mv/7t»i iui Amount i»f loans on improved real estate- - _ib,u_i.uu Appraised value of improved real esute upon which loans have anono 3r..«»).no Amount of lire Insurance in force and assigned to thie asmxlatlon 21 rv.tWO.no Amount of tornado Insurance in force and aligned to the assoiiatlon im.-moo as collateral security ■mm Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ - u'wrii \mount of dividends declared on running stock during year — ,-'!v Kate per cent of dividends declared on running slock during year I!:,!,. ,,er ml of interest charted Iwrrower. *__jg^*y^, -j % . .- mo ,. C *% S mo.. «.•» </seg>
            <seg id="p062">60 STATEMENT of the condition of the IIAVELOCK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HAVELOCK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Samuel Hinkle Vice President Arch Adams Secretary V. F. Hofmann Treasurer F. B. Young Attorney _ F. B. Sidles DIRECTORS B. Adrerman Kroehler Adams G. W. Anderson C. F. Ballard V. F. Hofmann E. E. Anderson Samuel Hinkle F. B. Young ASSETS First mortgage loaim Loans on stock or pass hook security Cash Delinquent interest, lines, etc Other assets Total. LIABILITIES Running stork and dividends Paid-up stock and dividends. . B shareholders on incomplete loans :ve fund Undivided profits Total </seg>
            <seg id="p063">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 61 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Dues l Running stock) * 5_S_5 Paid-up stock — &amp;9Sfi Mortgase payment* - — W Mortgage payments . . _ — ' Stock loan payments _ _ _ _ _ -... :;. : '.i '&lt;' Stock loan payments — _ — _ _ -... i; A' '.V Interest — Sili^.T." Interest . — 23.9R5 73 Fines :::.::::....;;;; _ :: z ■***&gt; Membership and tranMer fees - .MM. Other receipts in detail _ '.'..... _____ '-'■ 2.ir_ti.«l Xotil - $1»»,7(»!.7: l.ISIU HSKMKXTS Mortgage loans * 4S.rw.no Stock loans '" '"' Withdrawal!, running stock and dividends 18,707.11 Wiihrtrnwnls paid-up stock...- - - M J "*"-.'. Interest on paid-up stock - 5,4*1.' Salaries ... - _____________ — 1.7no.fln Commissions - 4*&lt;6.&lt;H) Other expense ..-.___...._— — _ _..—.. .■" 1 'i* Caah on bandZ — 12,_ffJ8 Other disbursements In detail .... - - MM_» Dividends credited _ .___ ___ _ ir..nin.m Total -..._ M34.763.73 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of Association _. _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since oriraniiation _ MM Niiliil-er (if snares outstanding last report - _.W6 8fc*r«*s issued since last report -.- - 1.081 — * ntni , ___„_.. 4.f*^fi Si':"-..*. issued since last report Total ■bare* withdrawn, matured or cancelled »inee la»t report— &lt;•* Nuniber o' shares'ln force this date Number of shares on which dues are delinquent - ■■ Average running time of stock matured during the year — .. l'^O month-* Average running time of stock matured during the year. Nuinher of borrowing stockholders - - Ml N'lmber of non-borrowing stockholders :R\ Number of loans made for building purposes daring year t 200.00 Pir Ttlne of each share of stock $ 300.00 Total ninount of dues delinquent at this date... «Tn Total ninount of dues delinquent at this date. Amo'int of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid l.HaVTT Amount of loans on Improved real estate- 24MB Mi Appmlyeil vnlue of improved real estate upon which loans have been uiiide .. _ _— - — WOJOfMiO Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collnteinl security 27O._ri»m Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association ns collateral security ...._ 270.1 &gt; S0.«l Amount credited to reserve fund during yenr ~ l.i'* '." Aironnt of losses charged to reserve fund during year — ITS n 17.-. 1J Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1S.O1O.01 Ainount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock durtuir i.W year - ■■ ■"•' ■ Rate i»'r cent of dividends de&lt;lnred on runnlnir stock during year 0 wfk Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dnr'PL' v«*nr — •% dur'i'L' yenr Kate per cent of Interest charged borrower* during year I '«• I </seg>
            <seg id="p064">62 STATEMENT of the condition of the HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HOOPER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President John F. Heine Vice President B. Monnich Secretary - - Geo. W. Heinie Treasurer Jacob Saunders Attorney Win. Meyer DIRECTORS ■. M. Tillman Stipsky Jacob Kusch R. L. Schwab Geo. W. Heine H. J. Vlasak John F. Heine Jacob Saunders B. Monnich Wm. Meyer ASSETS First mortgage loam - $ B.MMI Cash ""..." _ 1.58 Furniture and fixtures — - 4(^.00 Total _ - : t £1 441.32 LIABILITIES Kunnlng stock and dividends. $ 1T.WT.76 Paid-up »took and dividends !&gt;41.9e Tlf+f i if fund - , , Bills piyable _„ _ — H17.2« itOTiOO ToUl - $ -J2 441.ru' </seg>
            <seg id="p065">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 63 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand lust report Does (Running stock I f .170,47 .vm.i». Mortgage payments Interest - _ 8S5 Fines Memliersbip and transfer ft-&lt; Other receipts In detail Bills payable Total KISBIItSK MENTS Mortgage loans t 7.H..,., Withdrawals running stock and divideu I Withdrawals paid-up stor 1.^34 Salaries lon.oo Other expense _ - Cash on hand Rl TotaL ? fcMMa SUPPLEMENT AL RE I "OUT Plan of iissori.-itit'ii Permanent Number of shares Issues since organization MM Niimlii'i- of share** outstanding lust report Nun»lter of shares issued since Inst report - _.. •© Total _ .... _.....'.'. J12 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last rtffcMri Number of shares In force this date. _ "_■&gt;■." Average running time of stock matured during the year 1M months Nmnl&gt;er of horrowini: stockholders Nunilier of non-borrowing stockholders _ _ I Number of loans made for building purposes during year 4 dumber of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year S value of each share *&gt;t stock _ 9 Jtlivui I Par value of each share of stock ' Amount of loans on improved real estate - _ 2^.-WW.fl0 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans bare been in:Mle 47.7TiO.0il Amount of lire insurance in forre and assigned to the association as collateral security „ _ ITJMtM Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association ;is collateral security BJMM Amotint credited to reserve fund during year vino Amount of dividends declared on running' stock during year. 1, KIOTO Rate per cent of diviilends declared on running stock during year fi\ Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year I I </seg>
            <seg id="p066">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 64 STATEMENT of the condition of the IlI'MBOLDT BUILDING. LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION HUMBOLDT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President L. S. Hackett Vice President Otto Kotouc Secretary H. E. Boyd Treasurer. I. Shirley DIRECTORS Jas. B. Davis N. C. Campbell E. S. Cope B. Stramer I. Shirley L. S. Hackett Otto Kotouc H. E. Boyd F. R. Butterfield ASSETS Fir»t mortgage loans „ $ 44.1.V&gt;.ti5 Loans on stock or pas* book security _ J.470.4o * Nt'er real cgtate „ l.fino.00 Cash — _ _ 7BH IB Xottl _ __ $ 48,.*i.'&lt;l.X) LIABILITIES Running stork and dividends _ t 47.74.«.7fi iteflerre fund _ Tili.:.^ i'udivided profits ~.'.J~.'~"."..~1 ____—«_ « 3^43 Total $ 4K331.3U </seg>
            <seg id="p067">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 65 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report $ 1,094.47 I Hies I Running stock) - 12^MT.8O Mortgage payments _ T,7tB.M .11 1 IJCUltC UA f UlVjLllB --« »...*....... _. . ., ...»»* ■■!■!■ ), , ■ ■■ ■■ I I I I ■ I I I ■■■■!!■■ -• • t • 4**lJ«» " * Stock loan payments 256.00 I nterent Membership and transfer fee: Total _ - - * »jm»m DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ 9 8.1ODJ1O Stock loans ..'.'.. .'.'.'. " 170.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends. __ 15.0To.lB Salaries - _ _____ iwn nuv.w 136.90 Other expense _ _ _ _ ('ash on hand ._. 29&amp;2» Interest " L'.'. &gt;•»• 74 Estimated" dividend ..." __™___________________, 319 50 Total . $ 2Svtflk\M SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Serial Number of series issued nines- organization (if serial) _ 26 Number of shares Issued since organization.. _ 4,43B Number of shares outstanding last report _ 1.218 Shiires Issued since last report - _ 253 Number of shares issued since organization... Total ' 1,471 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report jr&lt;i Number of shares in force this date _ 1,215 Average running time of stock matured during the year 77^4 months Number of borrowing stockholders. _ _ 61 Number of non-borrowing stockholders „ 66 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of hmnestead-iuortjfages during year % Par value of each share of stock.. _ ....... f 1(10 00 9 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders !!Z~. '. 1.14700 Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid— '■:. " Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 1 200.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate ...... KJTAJ. Appraised value of improved real estate npon which loans have been made _ _ _ _ _MBM* Amount of loans on unimproved real estate...- „ "HO.OO Appraised value on unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 1 -&lt;jiino Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral wcnrlty _ _ _ _ .17 050.00 Amonnt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 48,300.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ li^.Vl Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2.444.8B Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year __Z Z. " Wl </seg>
            <seg id="p068">66 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the Hl.MPHREY BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION HUMPHREY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President N. J. Steffes Vice President Chas. Schueth Secretary.... W. M. Condon Treasurer... W. W. Ladd DIRECTORS K. Steffes Krebs Chas. Schueth A. A. Benham W. W. Ladd W. M. Condon ASSETS Flrit mortc**e loans * 10,.V&gt;&lt;U&gt;0 Cash S2O.37 Expense* _ - - - 115.4.! Tot»l_ - $ njMM LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend* - * 7.«t!.0i« Paid-up stock and dividends.. Undivided profits iiirali 2Xt.»t Total f 11,°J3T&gt;.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 67 YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Dues i Running stock) _ _ _ f 4,410.00 raid-up stock _ _ __ ___ Z._ 4,000.00 Mortgage pay— t» , , — — ?ES I Merest _ _ UC80 SiS&gt; Membership and transfer fees - ~ 3T.40 Advance dues _ - - 380.00 Total _ _ __ f 11,203.80 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans — — % 10,300.00 Other expense _._......_ __ _.«...______ ~...~— 115.43 110.43 Cash on hand fSSM Total I II.WBIf SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ - Permanent Number shafM issued since urgaiiiuition _ 1,37* t,.,,i _ ■ " i;s7x Number of share* In force this date _ UN Number of borrowing stockholders — ■"• Number of non-borrowing stockholders - SB Number of loans made for building purposes during year Par value of each share of stock ._»..„_„.„_ „„ , „ „ „ $ 100.60 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ lo.300.0u Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans nave bc&lt;?n instil — - — — -."-' ""' • ' • ■ Amount of Ore insurance in force and assigned to the auoclation aa collateral security — — — _ 7.300.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 8.200.00 Rate per cent erf Interest charged borrowers during year _ 7.2% </seg>
            <seg id="p070">68 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THK STATEMENT of the condition of the KEARNEY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION' KEARNEY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President S. A. D. Henline Vice President _ John W. Patterson Secretary and Treasurer Willard F. Bailey Attorney John N. Dryden DIRECTORS S. A. D. Henline John W. Patterson Willard F. Bailey John N. Dryden N. P. McDonald Gilbert E. Haase Frank Hollingsworth ASSETS First mortgage loans — 1 57.fiW.00 " 3,l\i.^t Total S 61.344.S7 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ _ $ 37.fttO.46 Paid-up stock and dividends 19Mt).IK&gt; One shareholders on incomplete loans _ _ 1' 2"4 DO One shareholders on incomplete loans _ _ ___________ /,?14.00 Tlef 1 1 1! fund . „ 54° iifi Undivided profits 1 " 1.737146 Total $ 81.W4.ST Undivided profits 1 — ..'.'".'.' , _!___._ "~7 1,737!*6 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 69 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR. ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash fin hand last report.- _ _ f 15.00a.0C Dues l Running stock) .. _ _ _ 10.268.ftt Paid-up stock _ ',"'",'," — ______ &amp;,600.00 MortfraRe payment* _ _ 11,000.00 Mortgage payment* _ _ 11,000.00 Interest . 4 31013 Fines _ _ _ 4O.4O Fines .'.'.' _____ _ ... 4Q.4O Loan fee surplus _ - 187.30 Loan fee surplus _ - 187.30 Total _ $ 47.030 49 DISBURSEMENTS DISBfRSEMEXTS Mortgage loans __™ $ 51.306.00 Mortgage loans - - $ 3UMJW Withdrawals running stock and dividends &amp;0HO90 Withdrawals running stock and dividends &amp;.OH040 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ .. _ 4,490.00 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ „ _ 4,430.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up ■took- - _ _ 1,239.86 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock- - _ _ 1,299.68 i:»'« m— 1 III il pjj 1% n J s tliilUtrllU V9U L'«ltI~UI' IL111 HH ..........,^ .. HH^&gt; i t ifw TTTT Other expense "»_k .'14 Other ex pens© ..._. __- 36&amp;34 Cash on hand _ - 3,714-8T Total _ _ $ 47,069 46 Cash on band _ _ 3,714-_T Total— I 47J0MI SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of %nmnd**tinn , _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization _ _ _.'..-ni l -j NuiiiIht shares outstanding last report. 1JB4 Sharps issued since last report - - Tfl&amp;H Total . J.4""..' 1 _ Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report «___■ PHi 7«M_ ViMpLtT «»f shares In force this date l.T.'s Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 190 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of duet.... 110 Number of borrowing stockholders _ 49 Number of non- borrowing stockholders _ _ 141 Number of loan* made for building purposes during year 3 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads' or payment of hoinestead-inortKHKeti durin? year _ _ _ '.T&gt; value of each share of fft*v*k , ___..___ . .. , .... % 100.01) sr. Par value of each share of stock.. Total amount of dues delinquent at thlg date_ 715.00 Amount of due* owing by borrowing stockholders 600.00 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure — So. 3 4.000.00 MM! Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 57.630.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans lave been made - — _ 112.900.01) Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ ■ MM Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to toe association as collateral security _ 56.775.00 Amount credited to reaerve fund during year — S-».7» Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year l.TSCi.TT _»_ Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 1 lTS. ■ Hate i»er cent of dividends declared on running stock during year tjttff Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during Tpnr _ _ G^ Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year ».•% to May 1st; after May 1st T.8% </seg>
            <seg id="p072">70 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LAUREL, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President J. B. Felber Vice President C. F. Furley Secretary Guy Wilson Treasurer Guy Wilson Attorney F. P. Voter DIRECTORS 1. B. Felber F. P. Voter C. E. Nevin C. F. Furley W. T. Graham Guy Wilson C. C. Sackett ASSETS Ftrst mortgage loan* _ g 33 73O00 Ctih _ ....... «!37000 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc. _ _____________ 232.05 Total.. I 40,352.05 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends.. ... • -j-wor-m !!■■■■ ■!! fiinH ~ — ~ * °''5_r^ Bcwrre ' tuni I * wrS Undivided profits „ 1 _■!_ LJMJi Tot - 1 — — S 4O.3S2.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 71 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report i v».« Dues I Running stock) Mortgage payments £SSi8 Interest and premium Fines iii Membership and transfer fee Bills payable -A75 1,000.00 Total * 'jl.tfJ **'.*»&gt; DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage Ion us „„. _. ( 6,200.00 Withdrawals running: stock and dividends _ Withdrawals paid-up stork _ . Salaries , "ZTZZZZZ.. f..~rJZ!V/l™3"...V™V™l~.— 7... IMUsl Other expense _ Mf l^&lt; Cash on hand _ -- fi..T7" mi Bills payable paid - 6,070.00 Total _ „. „ 9 T1.&lt;fHM SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association . .,.. _ _ _ S«-ri:i I Number of series issued since organization (if serial) 15 Number of shares issued since organization 2.1T2 13 N'umhfr of wliiires outstanding last report _ 1.4H5 Shnrca i-wn.-.l nlmv last report - 229 Total _ \.XH Shares witbdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 181 Number of shares In force this date - _ _ _ 1,1-43 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent NumBer of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of due* 23 Annff nintim: time &gt;&gt;f start nmtuivd iluiing the year _ 92 months Number of borrowing stockholders - 31) Number of non-borrowing stockholders - 111 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ _ » Par value of each share of stock _ _ _ t innmi I r»r miue vl em 11 hdbiv ui biuck - - # i'»m«' Total amount of dues delinquent at this date_ - Mm Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders- iS3.7T&gt; Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due anil unpaid 832. IS 1S3.7S Number nnrt amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 2 2.300 00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 33.730.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made — _ _ 70.7?iO.OO Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _...^. _ 44,500.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as eolloateral security „ „ +1.N0O.0O Amount credited to reserve fund doling year _ 1T7.0K Auivuui i itruncw lv rt*»eivtf luuu uuriuB jrnr...... .._._. --...........^.— jii.v« Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3.22A.O1 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock daring year ( semi -annual) 4% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year #% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year. 4.5% </seg>
            <seg id="p074">72 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the XEBRAKA CENTRAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ Homer K. Burket Vice President John Gibson Secretory _ M. W. Folsom Treasurer T. N. Burket Manager Agency _ E. P. Leonard Auditor J. A. Piper DIRECTORS Homer K. Burket John Gibson T. N. Burket E. P. Leonard M. W. Folsom ASSETS First mortgage loam .. „ $3,471..S8B.52 Loaus In procesa of foreclosure „_ ' sg',900.00 Loins on stock or pass book fitly - lt&amp;rr&amp;su Otber real estate _ _ _ 48,548.06 Real estate sold on contract 49,677.10 United States Liberty Bonds % 55,Ol&gt;n.OO Real estate sold on contract.. 4 Sa.0UO.OI Ca»h .". - .Z. ".:...~.L....mt.*MUM 207.446.56 Office building mil furniture and fixture. _ 20,380.77 Total— $3,870,000.63 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends Paid-up stock and dividend* -.'- *2,159,22O.S7 1.421,228.26 Reserve fund _ _ _. _ _. 126,106.15 ('■•divided profits to pay July, 1»17, dividends '.'..'..'. ~......'..Z.~. 164.'442.56 Total. S3.S7O.U0O.S3 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 73 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report _ I 173,170.26 Dues (Running stock) 824,886.3* Paid-up stock ~.Z 413,247.77 Mortgage payments _ - l,OK&gt;,ut&gt;7.*7 Stock loan payments _ - - ?i~ 0&lt; J Real estate sales Interest K.TOfcM a».-«.a&gt; Real estate . _____ ___________ d4,«4.MO Fines and transfer fee _ 1.675.1*1 Benin of real estate _____________________________ 4.3W.7S Bills receivable _________________________________ 1.342.8O Reserve fund ZLJBUO Total_ _ *2,S&gt;_,4__.«8 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans ll.342.lM.70 Stock loans — _ 1 T.tCo **i IiMllvi.l.-il profits, dividend credited to running stark. 14S.4SO.68 i iniiviueu ttronrs. niviueiHi rremien in running kiih-k ~ i-t;-. *-■&gt;'•&gt;- Withdrawals running stock and dividends — 7S7.iao.13 Withdrawals paid-up stock .-. " 19S.27S.78 T'mllrlilml profits, reserve fniiiT......._ 30.000.01) Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock- - 76.O42.4S Salaries _ .... _ 25.S72.ao Commissions _.—_____—. . ....___.—..—_—- — ..._• — y,737.Mfi Other expense „ — . - lO.O0B.ie io.na.ie Heal estate account _. _ S2.798J7 United States Liberty Bond* I M.M».«l Cash on band _...._ _ 152,446.8© 207.44«J» Cash on band.. Reserve fund _ _ _ _ - 4,J."&gt;1 &gt;iT Taxes office imtuSmg _____ __ tBS.ll Bills re.-rivable - - _._ _ l,342.»0 Bills receivable _ - Real estate sold .-M.itKiif. Office building and furniture _ - 2,54)0.61 Total _ - _ n.HII.Wn M SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ — Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization Number of shares issued since organization - 317.330 Xumlwr of shares outstanding last report ...8R.1O2 nharea issticil since last report .2&amp;291 Shares w itlidrav.ii. matured or cancelled since last report HV«M Numtw»r of shares In force this date — 10u.!HfT Number of shares In force this date.. v MTMi'f rtiPDlmgC lisa *&gt;f sto&lt;k luaturfd during tbe year 117 months Number of borrowing stockholders ■■■■ ,,,..i „_ 2,*&gt;74 ?.«♦ Number of non-borrowing atockholdera S.-ftl Number of loans made for building: purposes .luring year _*» Number of loans made for purchasing of homenteads or payment of tHiniPKtt'iti) iimrtfratres durlnp year 4V» p»r value of each share of stock..™..-...... _^_ „ „ .„ $ 100.00 $ ino.no ViiK-nm uf luteifst and Hues due and unpaid 16,011.45 Number ami amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure..— No. 30 46,900.00 Number and amount of mortsafires in process of foreclosure No. 45 56,900.00 56.900.00 Amount «»f lojiiu* on iniproven real estate - •1.471,94B.0S Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans Wave lK*en made _ 9,076. SI 0.00 Amount of fire and tornado insurance in force and assigned to tbe ■worfatloTi us ■•iilliiternl ne«-urlty 5.370,»0_.0_ ii*s&lt;M-inti"ii as roitnierai wruru.v _&gt;,_.iu,j-w.i-ap Amount credited to reserve fund during year — 21.flB8.55 Amount of losses ohareed to reserye fund during J*»r..._ 4.2.M.C7 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year - 149.4-O.~&gt;- «51.« Amount of dividends paid on matured ami paid-up stock durinc year - - "•' M • year - - - i-.u--.-m Rate per ivnl of dividends declared on running stock during year.... T'&gt; Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid sto.-k during year - — ** Bate per cent of Interest charged borrowers daring year IS </seg>
            <seg id="p076">74 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the AMERICAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION- LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President W. A. Selleck Vice President E. W. Brown Secretary E. F. Snavely Treasurer E. F. Snavely Attorney E. W. Brown DIRECTORS W.A. Selleck J. H. McClay J. T. Dorg-an E. W. Brown C. J. Olson E. F. Snavely L. C. Oberlies ASSETS First mortgage loans $346,100.00 " •«"* ■««•*«»»»; avauo — ftnO,lUU.UI' Loam on stock or pass book security 460.00 C»ih _ ____ ______________ 2,9(10.25 Delinquent Interest, fines, ate. ____________________ 1 '604 02 Taxea paid _ 1,381.78 1,381.78 Other assets . 100 00 TotaL. MM It LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. _ 1 91,441.30 Paid-up stock and dividends „ _ _ 244.275.00 244.276.00 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans 1_.___________!1..._."."~ 13JSG&amp;70 Reserve fond ___________________ 3 f ,n9&amp;79 Undivided profits _____ ______ 1,'8T7.8S Total _ $354,549.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 75 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KECKIITS Ctth on hand last report _ „. Dues ( K u iming tttock) „ 9*2*9 m.T-M.-fc! Paid-up Htock _^____'_ZL'™~ 13fi!4Oo!uii Mortgage payments _ 10n. " Stork loan payments 475.00 Interest L_ _ _ __ _ 19.i-fl7.30 Taxes - _ I flgf l" Membership and transfer fee«_ _ — l.Ms.Ki Other receipt* in detail- 1.741 'J*» TotaL r „ WIT, 441 UK DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ f]S9JflB&gt;49 Stock Iiimijs „ _ ~r*&gt; .mi Withdrawals running stock and dividends — - 131,M*O.W Withdrawals paid-up stock - _ 30,181.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock il.T24.4T Salaries - - l.uVat i*&gt; Other expense _ _ :.i4.V.M Cash on hand - .. _'.'.•• Other disbursements in detail __ __• _ l.»T .-'T Taxes - 1.H3H.W. Stock dividends — _ O.0TKI4) Total _ _ W17.441 00 SUITLEMKNT AL REPORT Plan of association _ „ B Permanent NuihIht of shares mitHtan&lt;liii£ hist report Xumlter uf ithures iiuisiaii'linu lust report : 7,100.56 T,ll»)56 Sim res isKiied since la«t report Slinri-s iswucil MiM-e laMt report 4.JSJ Total _ _ Total IhtNl wHMlHI. mature*! or &lt; ;hm elle^l si Shares withdrawn, inaturetl or « am-elled iilic-r last report- 3.014.S0 iuc-e last report- 3,014.80 Nuinl&gt;er of sharvs hi fune this date XumlM&gt;r "f shares In fnrre this date. 8^)8.75 Number of borrowing stockholder* Number of borrowing stockholders saa Number and amount of mortsat-es sulijeet to foreclosure Xo. 18 W.WW Amount of loans ou improved real estate 542.2SO.0O Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hare been made - - 738.900.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate.. - BtflMt Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon whk-n loans have been made - - - 15.45O.0O Amount of lire Insurance In force and assigned to the association, as collateral security 400.335.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the associ- ation as collateral security 24fi.9O0.0O Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1.441..TR Amount of dividends declared on runninc stock during year .1.IITS.0B WMM Amount of dividends) paid on matured and paiil-up stock .luring year 11.724.47 Rate |xr cent of dividends declared on running stock during year &lt;Kr Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year ~ •'•' I Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year _ _ T.5^4 during year Number of non-borrowinu stockholders 615 Number of loans marie for bwlMtef pnrpos^n dwtalf year. +1 Number of loans made for purchasing of lioim^tenilit or payment of homestead- DiortgafC^B Uuriug year J7 Par value of each share of stock _ $ 100.00 Amount of interest, premiums ami tine* »lue and unpaid l.tSm.t'J </seg>
            <seg id="p078">76 STATEMENT of the condition of the LINCOLN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President E. W. Brown Vice President H. H. Wilson Secretary _ E. F. Snavely Treasurer Frank Parks Attorney _ Burkett, Wilson &amp; Burkett DIRECTORS E. W. Brown Frank Parks L. C. Oberlies H. H. Wilson Charles Olson E. F. Snavely E. C. Hurd ASSETS Klr»t mortgage loans _ $588,475.00 Loans in process of foreclosure _ 24,400.00 Ijmi on stock or pass book security 1,900.00 • &gt;ther real estate _ 18,04.44 Real estate sold on contract - 25,3'.!1.54 &lt;'anh -. _ 52.464.52 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc 7.S0O.95 Furniture and fixtures J. _ tT7i so Taiea paid....- "' ." Z....Z 4,140.79 Other assets „ :'.,'.»H4.72 Certificates of deposit- - _ 15,000.00 Bonds _ - — — - - 10,100.00 Xotal - 9708,013.76 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends- J357.X7B.52 Kup stock and dividends _ 328,810.00 shareholders on Incomplete loans 1,623.75 1.623.75 Reserve fund " .". _......'..."....-...._.! 10;33&amp;44 Undivided profits _ 4.365.06 Total - _ $703,0X3.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 77 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RKCKH'TS Cash on hand last report. Dues (Running stock) ■tnut 151.3SH.4S Paid-up stock _ _ 7tt[575.00 Mortgage payment! _ _ _ __._.__....._. l*&gt;«.aB7.2R Stock loan payments _ Real estate sales. ............_ l.WR.tn Yt.tttM Keal estate sold on fniitrMct .. „ „ &amp;[o70.U6 Fines - - """" "TW^ Taxes . .. _ m l.:tO4 w Membership and transfer fees - .._ _ " 2,O-».O3 Abstracts _ _ nmmii Loss and gain _ _____ MSB_1 Hun. Is _ MM Furniture and fixtures. „ _ „ _ 'i" "*&gt; Reserve _.. ______ ___________ 1 gfiui Certificates of deposit ________________________ 50,30000 DelinQuent Interest __- t' V' .V&gt; Total DISBURSEMENTS Overdraft last report _ _ f ia.213.tt Mortgage luaus _ _ 124,975 00 Stock loan* stock loans - 2 31000 Withdrawals ruuninK stock and dividends. 13S.8TB.Or 135.878.OT Withdrawals paid-up stock _..." lUMSs'oo Withdrawals dividend on paid. up stock _ _ 19A3884 Salaries _ _ __ .vmikii Commissions _ — _ Ijmt 13 Keen - „_« 75.75 Other eipense _ !!i . S.r.7l!2G Real estate a&lt;*count - - „ lojwc'fl8 Reai estate sold on contract— _ _ _ 12,6D_K&gt; fash on hnnrt _ fXl.^iUSi IjOSh ami giiiu 7 183.(17 Furnitiirt and fixture* _ _ __ LV..MI .Abstracts „ _ ]... 744*00 Til xt'S „ _ J 4WK 39 Bonils _ .'. '. _____________ 'lQO.00 Delinquent interest _ _ 1 7.YS33 Other assets _ 1 '»W7 .".6 Certificates of deposit _ ____________ 34tioOOOO Total ... (5M.aW.S0 8OPPLEMBXTAL RKl'OHT Plan of association _ IVrfi^^-^t Total Xuniher of shares issneil since organization _ 4A.!H2 74 Number of shares outstanding la* report _ llt/«Ti.7() njm.io Shares issned since last report.. Shares issued ulnoe last reports BASi.TB 5J_6.1B Totnl „ Total Shares withdrawn, matured or caiicfHfil Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled ilnc* last re|K»rt _ TMM ilm-e last re|K»rt _ TM_ Xumlier of shares In force this date... Number of shares in force this date 18.075.10 ilurhit- the yeai 113 rnonthn AifTHf ruiiiii»£ tinif if «*t«&gt;&lt;-k matured Alfftlgl running time _f stock inutured • 111 lintr the faat 113 m. .nth. 113 months Nuinl»er of borrowing stockholders. N urn t&gt;er of borrowing stock hoi derm. 444 Namlter of n«n- borrowing stockholders Number of non -borrowing stockholders. N'uiiihpr of |—i niMilf for liufldinjr pur ji Xiiinbcr of loans made for building purj meii during y«ir SI me* iiiirin. year. Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads' or payment of houiesteail- mortgages during year _ 35 Par value of , each share of stock _ $ 100.40 ■ Amount of Interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid 7,8TiO.flK Xumlier and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure- _...No. 56 92.500.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 1ft 24.4OO.0O Amount of loans on improved real estate _ _ Appraised value on improved real estate upon which loans hare mjmm been made _ M8.973.O0 Amount of lire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ „ 630.413.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 447.330.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ _ — -. w ... 1.M9.00 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year ™™__... 'X\~ .TO Amount of dividend* declared on running stock during Tear Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 19.838.M Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year &lt;% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year _ 6% Hate per cent of interest charged borrower* during year.. ___ t% </seg>
            <seg id="p080">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 78 STATEMENT of the condition of the SECURITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President L. C. Oberlies Vice President _ J. T. Dorgan Secretary and Treasurer E. F. Snaveley Attorney E. W. Brown DIRECTORS L. C. Oberlies W. A. Selleck J. H. McClay E. F. Snavely J. T. Dorgan E. W. Brown ASSETS First mortgage loans $306,906.00 Loans In process of foreclosure _ 1,400.00 Loans on stool: or past hook security l.OtO.OU Other real estate _ - - 41,'J37.06 Real estate sold on contract 21.249 06 st;itc and municipal securities- 5.026.87 &lt;-a«h _ _ 12.570.75 Delinuent interest, flues, etc._ S.:i(iR.26 LnrllllurlJl lJIl"lt^M, Illl"f* "H...... ..--....,.. . .... . _.-*... - .... a . i ■ , ■ .,,■».-.. D,tiF*,BU Furniture and fixtures _ _ ._ _ 300.00 Taxes paid.... »_ j» VO1.4O Other assets „ _ ' 920.98 Cert Incut et* *&gt;f deposit _ 16,000.00 Xotal _ _ $319,750.37 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ *107.0«4 «3 Paid-up stock and dividends-. _ 114,285.00 Reserve fund - 8,404. 88 Undivided profits 4.86 Xotal — $319,750.37 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 79 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report - „ a H,lflB.t9 I&gt;ue8 ) Running stork) _ 71.-fttf6.96 Paid-up stock ™ 200.00 Moriuajrf payments _ _* _ „„ 7V.J5O.00 Mortgage pay men t» _ _. _ 7y.JOO.00 Stock loau payment* ..._ 1.UU.M) Stuck loan payments I.13U#JU Keal estate _ _ _ 22,SHM.7:i Keal estate ~ - _ _ _ - 22,901.7:1 Interest _ ». 24,500.12 Interest _ _ _ L'4,500.12 Keal estate on contract — - 5,TW).31 Keal estate on contract — - 5,7W).31 Membership and transfer fees - HUi Membership and transfer fees .. ~-S&gt; JC&gt; Other receipts in detail.. - - I '*•" II Other receipts in detail _ _ I HI Tl Taxes 748.12 Taxes 748.12 Total.. DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ _ 9 7j0ML77 Mortgage loans _ _ t 7.6JO.77 Sttxli loans _ .. _ . l.UOC.OO Withdrawals running stock and dividends 108.0(5.43 Withdrawals running stock and dividends HB.0t5.43 Withdrawal* paid-up stock _ 21.XS.tU Withdrawal* paid-up stock _ Ul.ZJi.Ui&gt; Withdrawals dividends on paid-up stock. 7 :t&gt;.'i"&gt; Withdrawals dividends on paid-up stuck. 7.M&amp;X Salaries _ 1-.400 00 Salaries - - Z.4MM Com miss ions „ ,.. 347.17 ' did in issioliM _ _ ,.. 347.17 Other expense _ _ 1.7k 1 14 Other expense _ _ 1,781.14 Keal estate account _ 24,132.22 Keal estate account _ _ M^SSlS Cash on band - — 12^570.75 Cash on band - — U.'.ToTj other disbursement* in detail _ _ 3,747.37 other ili.-liurseiueuu in detail _ _ 3,747.37 Taxes _ _ 733.K7 Taxes _ _ 733.OT Keul t'Ktate on contract _ l.~&gt;,-ftU0.r&gt;4 I Vrt IH.ate of deposit _ 1 l.immi Stock dividends 12.UB.M8 Total - _ _ $223,482.1* SUPPLEMENTAL BEI'OUT Plan of association Permanent Numl&gt;er of shares outstanding last report „ - 79TO.1O Shares Issued since last report — 77 Total _ - _ - _ _ 8,047.10 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report '.isi .i* Number of shares Id force this date _. T.inKl.V* Number of borrowing stockholders _. :y* Number of nou borrowing stockholders.. „ 41** l'ar value of each share of stock f 100.00 l'ar value of each share of stock.. Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid _ -... MHrfflT Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. OS KMN Number and amount of mortgagee in process of foreclosure No. 1 1 44 ■&gt; * ■ ■ Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 210^306.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hare been made ... r M1,3M.OO Amount of Ore insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - Til. MOW Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 171.100.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ U4X0U Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 1. -■»»"».."►!» Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 12.0ttu.88 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during Rate per cent of dividend* declared on running stock during year •&gt;' . Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock &lt;iu ring year ~ #% Kate per cent of interest charged borrower* during year •% </seg>
            <seg id="p082">80 STATEMENT of the condition of the UNION LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President A. W. Miller Vice President W. B. Ryons Secretary Loyd A. Winship Treasurer L. J. Dunn DIRECTORS A. W. Miller L. J. Dunn W. B. Ryons Loyd A. Winship John M. Stewart ASSETS First mortttnife loans. ..." 1882,625.00 Loans in praam of foreclosure ' - 5,500.011 Loans on stock or pass book security 1,505.00 other real estate - 14,1B.-&gt;.4S K estate bold on contract.—- — - ~ 3,999. t&gt;6 and municipal securities 103,830.55 3,U99.66 Mate and municipal securities Oish _ 15,230.52 Delinquent interest, fines, etc - - 4,:&gt;9.75 Kurulture and fixture* ...— - _ 1.548.31 Taxes paid 3.566.47 other assets. 300.8B Interest due on certificate or deposit 1 .&lt;&gt;"&gt;.». l'.i Xotal - $1,018,096.82 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ - $287,131.95 raid-up stock and dividends 6«,JI75.00 Due shareholder! on incomplete luana_ 133,502.03 Reserve fund - 10,025.73 fudivided pronu — - - 1.375.11 Total MUM </seg>
            <seg id="p083">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEHTS C«»h on hand last report - - - - _ __ * 22, $ 22.296.36 lshu uii uunii iasi it-pun - - - - — 9 rr,r^n *w Dues ( ltuiiniiig Stock) - __' 15O.0S6.S6 Paid -up stock - _ 3ft8,0Ou.OU Mortfin'f payments - - . 311,775.00 Stock loan payments- ~ - .. _ _j 3,5W&lt;.U6 Real wC«l« sales _ !!_ n!53041 Interest ... . . . 57 457 WJ BilU receivable —Z — ., _ __ '.'. ....'. ' W.HO Pine* 107.43 Itmiu - SB6.45 Furniture and fixture* IBtLW Certificates of deposit - - - 39.336.5o Kem-rve _ „ „ _ 2,161.00 Tax certificates and insurance _ _ -\'J&lt;».77 Kem*rv»- -\'J&lt;e.77 Heal estate coutrartii.- _ - MM H Total DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans .. - _ — $518.1cft &gt; .4Jl Stork loans - -,'*&gt;! »»J I'udivided proflts __ tJHJI WitlnlrawnU running sttx-k and dividends 121.977.2U Wit bra wain paid- up stock _ 17J.tKJU.iai Withdrawals dividend uu paid-up stock _ _ 2R.431.Vi Salaries ..._ _ _ _ 5,700.1)0 i *uiu iii i ss i&lt; ills .. — — hm M ■ ■ ,. i . I, _"_*t». 4*i i U In r el i if list* ~ „. ..., _.__^_. rt.44 J.N1I R**;i I t'sttl 1 t" ."ici'oii ii t _ — _. l.'i. 4.TJ Til (_*JlSll O|| 111] 111 1 _ _ mmmm .-— 15,230.52 U. 8. Lilwrty 1 &gt;• • it ■ I _ S4jbU &lt;»■"&gt; T«x cvrtlftratc himI tmmmnkWtm ailraiu-e*! — - — - 4,.l7v7«i Reut - _ '.i 1 ,"").* furniture a nil fixtures. !_'■"&gt; i« • Real MtaU NU bj eoDtract - MVJI T«&gt;t jt 1 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association.. —_....._. , I'tnim ii»*nt Xuuil&gt;er of shares issued since organization — 53.3U4.Uo NiiiiiImt if shares outstanding lust report _ 19.JIC.&lt;R&gt; Shares issued since last report .10.901.00 T..ial - - - 3O.1M.0O i'olHl Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 4,4110.50 NumUer of sbareti iu force tbi» date _ 25,7(Ci.. r »O Niimlier of borrowing Htockhoiilers _ _ — ... 633 Number of non- borrowing stockholder! 1U18 Number of It'juis mnrie for building purposes durtus year —.—.._ 1^0 m NiiiiiIht of luiins mntie for l'iiil«linp purpose^ tluriue year. Number of loans mnde for purcbaain^ of tiotnrstr.-uls or payiin-nt of homestead-mortgages during ye»r_ 411 vuiue of earli Hliare of stovk $ 100.00 411 Par vuitie of ea&lt;*li share uf Htnek.. Aincuiit of int«Tt'st. premiums and fin* * iluc :iml unpitid 4,".»4 it M NumbtT and ihomI of mortgages subject to (andnm No. 8 13.flQO.00 Number ami aiimuut of mortgages in process of forei'losure No. 2 Bjjjjtjj A inou i' t of 1 naiis on Improved real estate - 8ftMfi&amp;o6 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans lwve iH^n mjHle - - 1,523.415.00 Amount of Io«bs on unimproved real estate - — MlfcAS Appraised value on unimproved real estate upon which loans have M.75O00 itfi-ii niHite Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association us ■■ol'atiral security - TSt,tt&amp;M Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 722.070.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1M8I.10 Amount of l.is&gt;cs rharged to reserve fund during year iyG.27 722,070.00 Amount of iliirlflenilK declared on running stock during year — IS.TTUI Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock ilurini; 28.UH6 year Rate per rent of dividends declared on running stock during year. H Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured ami full pni-l stock during year _ *^&gt; Kate per cent of Interest charged borrower* during jear »% </seg>
            <seg id="p084">82 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FIDELITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President W. A. Forsyth Vice President - Fred D. Mason Secretary C. E. Bardwell Treasurer H. B. Treat Attorney Fred D. Mason DIRECTORS Fred D. Mason J. G. Horning H. B. Treat W. A. Forsyth C. E. Bardwell ASSETS Klr«t mortgage loam _.. $152,650.00 Otber real estate _ _ _.... _ 1-.1-8. To Seal estate sold on contract - - - 700.00 t - M h _ „ _ _ „ 7,578.26 furniture and'flxtures - - — 400.00 Taxes paid and insurance _ - _ -... 136.80 Other assets .'. .'. 1,116.06 *174,710j87 Total.. LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends _ $ 73,266.02 Paid-up stock and dividends. - - 83.300.00 83.300.00 Due shareholders on incomplete loans — — _ _. 12.736.fS Reserve fund _ - — — — — ■■■— "' 1,646.00 Undivided profits ..._ _______™__________ _____ 3,772.08 Total — - $174,710ir7 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 83 Plan of association - - Permanent .\uliiln i ol .si.a.cs issued since orjraitUat ion it.^O.'iU N'mnlier . f shares outstanding In si report _ - 4."i«7.jO Shares issued since last report - IHMt Total MBLM Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sincv last report l.'»«uo Number of share* in force thin date NuoitMT of borrowing stockholders — _ — Numlier uf uoa-borrowtag stockhcdilers... _ - — 400 Nuinl..-r of loans made f..r l.ulldin(r purposes duriiis year. 8 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of lioii.csieail-iuortKairis daring year _ _ Par value of each share of stock. ' — - _ - S MMi Amount of loans mi improveil real estate 1.VJ.8EA.M Appraised value of improved real estate upon which leans have 1 ti inafle . 308*400.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - — — — lff»,150.rt) Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association llaieral security _ 151.000.00 4«L&gt;.00 Amount credited to reserve fund llailBl year - - - — -WL'.OO Amount of dhridemls declared ,m running stock during year 4.UV4.60 Amount of divideuds paid on matured and paid-up stock ilurinc y H |, r _ ...'.I.TS S7 Rate per cent of dividends decl»re&lt;l on running stock during year 8% .". '.'.'!&gt; s7 Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock diiriui: &gt;iar - - nr ' Kate |ier i-ent of interest charged borrowers during rear &lt;■ xvcj^rjir i o n.r%u r.Ai Tj^ui i tnijc r \ji\ ± n &amp;11U111U JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash &lt;»n Ii;iimI last report - Dues 1 Illuming stock) Fa Id -up stock _ _ - Mortcaue puymeuu - Ufa I estate b«leit — ~ - Interest _ _ Kt'iits „ .. Membership and transfer fees Ki-ius iiinl office building receipt* _... Delinquent interest and expenses Incomplete loans Total— t 7,338.30 106.4UO.il 37,S3O.UO Kusoaoo \jmji 12.810.OT CL-; iw Ml l.::i».-K&gt; 5U.1M.90 »W7,0*0.76 DISBURSEMENTS Mnrtcace loans Withdrawals running stock anil dividends _ Withdrawals paid-up stock — Withdrawals dividend on paid-up aMck Salaries* — - I '0111 missions - - — - - Other expeuse - - lit'ii I estate acoiili t • - i'jisIi on hand • Tai and furniture and fixtures Incomplete loaiiH - Total $ H5 79000 SUPPLEMENTAL HKI-OKT </seg>
            <seg id="p086">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 84 STATEMENT of the condition of the GERMAN BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _...Wm. Seelenfreund Vice President -...Frank E. Gillen Secretary F. B. Sidles Treasurer Fred Whittemore Attorney .F. B. Sidles DIRECTORS Fred Whittenmore F. B. Sidles Frank E. Gillen Wm. Seelenfreund ASSETS First mortgage loans *4d4.STO.OO Loans In process of foreclosure - _ r2,30O.0O Loans on stork or pass book security _ 1.100.00 Other real estate - _ 1,627.44 C«sh 14,631.32 Furniture and fixtures ".V-.W Taxes paid - _ 400.(18 Certificates of deposit — - 75.000.00 Total.. $.-,To.i»-T :;&gt; LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends-. $345,679.49 Paid-up stock and dividends .Z.........1.... sxi.is6.oo Reserve fund - - .". .. _ _ 3,794.31 Undivided profits _ _ _ llo63.58 Total... $570,087.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS r«sh on hand last report.. $ 92,132.30 ■ mu t'ii iiniiu ihbi nr|»uri 9 ott,ij&lt;. jm Dues I Running Stock )„ _ 141.343.0d Paid up stock 19.1SO.00 Martgas* payments _ !W,O75.OU Interest - ~ _ 38,978 &amp; Klnes _ g».lfi Membership and transfer fee*. - _ _ l.iir.uM) Taxes »4T ■* Total. . $3T3^3BJkv DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans .•- — tl.TJ.17o.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends — 74.725.54 Withdrawals paid-up stuck 51 .5AO.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock.. 14.173.5o Salaries - - ti.'.Oo m) Com missions - - l.flW.OO Other expense _ - — _ 1,151.44 Kt'iil estate account 574.05 Cash on hand _ - 14.tBl.32 Oertiflcates of deposit- — 75,000.00 Taxes „ - - 529.38 fur nit u re aud fixtures..— •«_ — ...— .. _....— 183.9T Total _ (tnm SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ . _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 41.526^ Number of shares outstanding last report 14,745% Shares Issued since last report- _ 4,134ft Total _ _ _ Is. s^) Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report XJKMk Number of shares In force this date __ _ 1M.5H4V4. Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 518 Number of borrowing stockholders _ _ — 396 Number of non-borrowing stockholders „ _ 1,101 Number of shares in force this date.. Number of loans made for building purposes during year 16 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ 59 Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 5U Total amount of dues delinquent at this date ."i.M»10 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders ~ 5,819.10 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid tt.»-9.56 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure _So. 12- 20.025.00 tt.««.56 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 8 12.300.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate _ __ . 474,120.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ - — - — - 53N,250.&lt;10 Amount of loan* on unimproved real estate S»flMbM Appraised value on unimproved real estate upon which loans have been maile -• . ™ — — .-.—..... '&gt;.j.~iO.ijo Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 500,530.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security -. 521.245.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1 .;hmd Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 1,815.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year l&gt;;.'~.ol Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year i.;..-.'oi Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up Mock during y,-ar - - - ~ 14.175.55 Rate per cent of dividends declared en running stock during year 8% 14 1^% K&gt; Bate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock *\ u riit ti yt*sr ~- .. ... .. .„ , ,.. *5 r^&gt; e per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">86 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President.— H. T. Wilson Vice President J. Y. M. Swigart Secretary _ Frank Mills Treasurer E M. Bair Attorney J. A. Brown DIRECTORS H. T. Wilson J. A. Brown Frank Mills J. Y. M. Swigart R. E. Harrington George Hager ASSETS Flrot mortmain 1 Imius _ $ 63,400.(10 Loans ou itock or i&gt;a«« book security 620.00 Cash - - 3,(Mi.4O Iieliliquellt interest. Hun. *tC 459.90 furniture and fixtures _ _ 161.3G Total $ 67,736.66 LIABILITIES Running stock aud dividend! f 18.798.87 Pddup stock and dividend* 47,:. &gt;OO.OO Heaerve fund - L'60.15 Undivided profits _ 1,477.88 Total.... f ir»Mi </seg>
            <seg id="p089">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 87 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash nil hand last rejort $ 461.87 Dues i It mini iiu stock) 1«,&lt;K16.88 Paid-up stock _ _ 47.W7.M Mortgage payment! _ - 4.BS4.91 IntiTi'st ."&gt;, 4*53.28 Membership and transfer fees _ l.lttl.iD) Total * mjmm DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans $ 2&amp;3B4JM Stork lonn* - _ i;:imii Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ _.._ 7.J.-.S !«» Withdrawals paid-up stock _ MkflYJM Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stork __ UaS.ll KalaEies .. 510.00 Commissions _ Other expense __. _ 1.7*1.18 112.08 Caah on hand - _ _ ri.ir.i.",. |i&gt; Other disbursements In detail - - 1,217.01 Rent _ _ _ flO.OO Total _ _ _ _ - f 75,385.87 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association. _ _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organlxatlon. „ :M9 Number of shares outstanding last report IJtTTM Shares issued since last report 1,910.5 Total MB Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report _ •'►Wi Number of shares In force this date _ _ 3,043 Number of borrowing stockholders 60 Number of non borrowing stockholders- 2S5 Vuni-ner of loans made for building purposes during year _ 4 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads' or payment of homestead mortgages during year 90 value of each share of stock - .. _ S 100.00 S(i Par value of each share of stock Amount of Interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid _ _ flKH Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 2 IJMjM Amount of loans on improved real estate UHM Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which limns have been ninrte . . lfl8.110.00 Amount of Tonns on unimproved real estate 500.00 Appraised value on unimproved re«l estate upon which loans have been nS _ _ - 3.000.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral secnrlty...- - 84,000.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 83.nr».fln Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1W..T0 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.007.76 Amount of dividend* paid on matured and paid-up stock during year - _ - V^ s 10 Rate per cent of dividend declared on running stock during year 8% M Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid atock during year , ft*^. Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year _ 8.4% </seg>
            <seg id="p090">88 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MIDWEST SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Julius Reusch Vice President Dr. H. P. Wekesser Secretary E. C. Boehmer Treasurer Nicholas Ress Attorney F. A. Boehmer DIRECTORS Julius Reusch T. H. Berg Nicholas Kess Dr. H. P. Wekesser F. A. Boehmer M. Wagner Adolph Lebsack, Jr. ASSETS First mortgage loans First mortgage loans $ 89,400.00 Casb 4^042.61 4.0*2.61 Total - t U3.442.81 LIABILITIES Sunning stock and dividends $ 10.0Wi.25 Paid-Dp stock and dividends- _ 78,975.00 Due shareholders on incomplete loans M0JM Reserve fund _ _ ___________ 10o!o6 Undivided profits 221.46 Prepaid stock 188.53 Total $ 03,442.61 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 89 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ Duel (Running stock) * uu «**« Paid-up stock _____ tn.9-JS.U0 Mortgage payments 10.060.00 Stock loan payment*-.. Stock loan payments* . *. . .. 50 00 Interest _ 4,(82.82 MemtMTship and transfer fees - „ 142*30 Prepaid stock _ _ _ _... 119.1)6 City National Bank, loans-. „ _. 5,000.00 Total _ - - | Ml. 1W DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - — _ - 9 fl5, 707.41 Stock loans ... ,. __ _, _. 90.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividend*- - _ 4,360.38 Withdrawals paid-op stock _ - 1H,900lOO 4.W0.J8 n iluu ru nais jjhiu. - u p block .. ..... __ ..., m,ttmKW Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock. _ 3,626.11 Com missions _ 143.75 ...... i ,.._... ... i .... i .... w&gt; ____ &gt;^ 1 X^O Iv Other expense ."Jit 45 Cash on hand 4.O4Z81 4.O42.61 City National Bank, notes 5,000.00 Total _ IIM.M. m SUPPLEMENTAL RBPOET Plan of association - Permanent Number of shares outstanding laat report - ..*7Mt Sbarea issued since last report. - _ _ _ 1886 Total __ __________ — .-— ■ mm — -- — — — l^fc Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 342 Number of shares In force this date - ~ 2-3ML Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ - 298% Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues *•■_ Number of borrowing stockholders — 57 Number of non-borrowing stockholders- MB Number of loans made for building purposes during year Par value of each share of stock _ - — - 9 100.00 Sbarea Issued since last report- Total Number of shares on which dues are delinquent. Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Number of borrowing stockholders. Number of non-borrowing stockholders-. Total amount of dues delinquent at this date . 8GO.6I Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 23B.44 Amount of interest, premium and fines due and unpaid 181.10 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 2 730.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate-. 87,900.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have btf u nisme - .. __ _ 164.675.00 Amnui't if loans on unimproved real estate l.OOO.OO Appraised value on unimproved real estate upon which loans have have been made _ - 3,800.00 Amount of lire Insurance in force and assigned to the association ;is it! l;i tcral security- .._... 87,706.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral wnurity siMir.4 • ■ » t Amount credited to reserve fund during year - 100.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 300.01 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during .i.rtXll year - - - 3.025.11 Rate Jut •i-iit of dividends declared on running stock during year * - Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock durlnc year - _ _ *"• e Her ivnt of Interest charged borrowers during year. — — T L"" 4 V. Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year... </seg>
            <seg id="p092">90 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the McCOOK CO-OPERATIVE BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION McCOOK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS » President John E. Kelley Vice President „ J. A. Wilcox Secretary F. A. Pennell Treasurer L. Thorgrimson DIRECTORS John E. Kelley J. A. Wilcox H. P. Waite F. M. Kimmell C. J. O'Brien L. W. McConnell W. B. Mills C. L. Fahnestock M. Lawritson ASSETS First mortgage loans ._ Jl'.Ki.r/iO.no Loan* on stock or puss bouk security - _ _ 100.00 &lt; Hlier real estate.. _ _ 735.97 Cash — - - - 7,922.90 Tiim paid _ _ _ _. 254.34 Expenses paid _ _ - 218.00 Interest paid on matured stock - _. _ _ 50.00 Total _ - 92UM.1M1.2B LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends -_ $194,383.25 Keserre fond 7,858.97 I'ndlTided profits — 6,820.0* j^ (jyg ncc dues «... „ _ _. .„_.„._ ____._„..„. .„ ..„„. _ TS 00 Total - $208,1*41.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 91 YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash ou band last report - I 1&amp;3MM Dues ( Ku nniug istoflc) _ _ - _— 42,96wJW Mortgage payments _ 36,615.06 Stock loan payment a „ SiUM»w Real estate sale* _ - _ J.L'aS.24 iw?ai esiaie saiea - -.-.*»..*» Interest _ . 17,«B6.10 riwi»_i _ i,067.ia i.ir.7.12 Fines _________________ - .'.'.'...- '-.'.. :i«.2S Rents from real estate :rjl :» Membership and transfer fees _ _B_I ueoiDeraaip ana transfer lees _ . i*» -^ Tax sale redemptions ......_ . ..__...____-..»• 49&amp;o&lt;i Received on tax loans In foreclosure — — — 3,437.36 Total - - - $121,223.44 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loan* ...._ _ * *» WOO 900.00 Stock loans _ _ - W0.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends. 44427.06 Withdrawals matured stock — _ 18,700.00 Withdrawals dividend on matured stock — 50.00 Salaries _ - - 540.00 other expense .- — — 153.25 Expenses paid - — — 1 15.15 (."ash on hand _ ~ - - 7,922.96 Tax sale certificates..... - 236.04 Total flZLJUiM SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ — - - ■• 8 * rl £i Number of series issued since organization __.!? Suiulter of shares issued since organisation — — — 11.7(17% Number of shares outstanding lsst report 3.214 Shares issued since last report — l,0K Total - — — - — 4.-4O Total - - — - — * 4.-4O Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 517 Share* withdrawn, matured or canceuea since mat repon j^ Number of shares In force this date - — 3,iJ» Average running time of stock matured during the year_ __ 122 month* Number of borrowing stockholders - — Number of non-borrowing stockholders - - 324 Number of loans made for building purposes during year _ _ 6 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during the year _ on&lt;»2\ Par value of each share of stock - - - *im»__!MX Amount of loans on improved real estate - lHU.HOU.OU 1!) Amount of loans on improved real estate- Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have beeu «— ;«, made - - - 381,00.00 Amount of flre and tornado insurance in force and assigned to the .,,,_»_ IHMIl OI lirV null iuimuu iubui_ui«t i — iwivb _uu ..=«,. _..... »„ __» |m«aj» association as collateral security.. _ - - tol,wmm Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ _ .i.u .1 Amount i-reuneu io re_:i»t: iuuu uuhuk ,»^«. - --- -—- Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1..-4.. ... Amount of dividends paid on matured stock during year..' 5O00 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year — Wt I\8i\kr ptrr 1^*111 ui ill » lucuiia &lt;it-v.i_ii *r_i vm .uuhiub —■••»—-—• -•_»_■-•-» j- —__-—— - .— Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured stock during year — ' KHie per cem UI umueuus I'oiu wu u»t"'™ »iw^» uu ..~ n j~ — — Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year I I Kate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during y*af — r ** </seg>
            <seg id="p094">92 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MADISON COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION MADISON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President C. S. Snyder Vice President Jacob Henderson Secretory A. E. Ward Treasurer. _ Jas. L. Grant Attorney M. B. Foster DIRECTORS C. S. Snyder Jacob Henderson Jas. L. Grant F. M. Yeaiel F. H. Davis D. O. Nickolson ASSETS First mortgage loans *125,700.00 Loam in process of foreclosure _ _ 1,000.00 Loans on stock or pass book security.. _ 250.01) Cash _ __ 4,700.14 Delinquent interest, fines, etc- 'J4S.9G Furniture and fixtures _ _ 371.60 Tax sale certificates- _ 109.32 166.32 Friable account 8.16 Total _... $132,444.13 LIABILITIES Running stock snd dividends _ $ 81,243.82 Paid up stock and dividends. _ OTJSO.00 Reserve fund .- _ _ _ 1.598.96 Undivided profits .... "" 1,847 87 Other liabilities _ 3.89 3.89 Total $132,444.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 93 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report - _ - I 6.044.82 Dues (Kuniiing sto«-k)_ MJMMI Paid-up stoi'k _ 4 4.K."iOW&gt; MurtL-iitri- payments _ - _ SUtWM Stuck loan payments _ — *"•&lt;&gt; &lt;»' Interest -*- — - - l tl .J'.l l .+ .4C Fined ami membership - - -T7. 1« Tai salt- certlncates redeemed - 1TJ.K8 Fronts f..rfeiteil - 31.30 Other soureet* „ _ _ m "^ TotaL *10M,610.30 DISBURSEMENTS Ifortcage loans t 63,4*. li Stock loans - - ■ : flCiO.UU Withdrawals running stock and dividends - l.'.im J4 Withdrawals paid-up stock. . HUMuM Withdrawals dividend on paid up stock- _ _ _ _ 3.tK&gt;.0* Salaries . '.t.lo.'JM Commissions — — — — — S.OO Other expense — . — ..——... _—- . J" 1^ 31 Cash on IiiiikI _ - l.T^iH Ta\e» &lt;iu mortgaged premise* _ — 14."i*5 Collection charges _ _ 30.32 Membership refunded - I -~&lt; TotaL *1&lt;K.61O.W SUPPLEMENTAL XIEPORT Plan of association - - Permaa»«t Nnmber of shares issued since organiiatlou 3. sal Number of shares outstanding last report l.:E»&gt;*» Shares issued since last report _. 409% Total 1 '.""U^ ■ S Lares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — 'JKO'rt 1*?^ Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report. Number of shares In force this date- ...- - 1,701 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _ — 74H Number of shares subject to conciliation for non payment of dues S% ™» Number of shares subject to cancellation for non payment of dues. Average running time of stocks matured during the year i 117 months Number of borrowing stockholders *&lt;6 Nuaulx'r of non-borrowing stockholders — — — - 30 NumlH-r of luaus made for building purposes during year- 34 Number at loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of hounsleiid mortgages during year _ _ Par value of each share of stock. - _ $ M0.M Total amount of dues delinquent at this date. 136.50 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders — _ 156.30 Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid— MJf Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure _ No. 1 S00.00 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure — No. 1 I &lt;&gt;«hm&gt; Amou't ef Unns en improved real estate _ - _ lJfi,7U&gt;.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been IMi'.le JOC.OM.10 Amount of flre Insurance in force and assigned to the association us epMnteral security _ 130,030.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - _ _ 101,000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 250.00 Ann "it o' (T'vVWhhU decliired on running stock during year 4,403.02 250 00 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock durintc year - - -.- 3,888.0* Fate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 9% M Rate per &lt;xnt of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during &gt;ear •% Bate per cent of Interest charged borrower! during' year t% </seg>
            <seg id="p096">94 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Henry Fastenau Vice President J. W. Butt Secretary Wm. H. Pitrer Treasurer H. F. Meyer Attorney Wm. H. Pitzer DIRECTORS F. M. Cook H. F. Meyer E. H. Buhlman W. W. Metz H. D. Thiele George Bader E. G. Mueller John H. Petring Wm. H. Pitxer ASSETS First mortgage loans _ H53.M0OO Loans in process of foreclosure - _ ii.ti4JO.00 Loans on stock or pass book security _ 10,532!26 Other real estate _ _ 1,538.98 Keal estate sold on routract— ~ _ 6,731.87 State and municipal securities— _ 4.70B.76 Cash — 17.07B.44 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc- 2,Wi2&gt; Furniture and fixtures _._ KKt.OO Taxes paid ~ ...'. 170.96 Other assets - - 149.96 Total - _ $201,900.53 LIABILITIES Sunning stock and dividends _ *144,353.34 Paid-up stock and dividends. - _ 4«,86O.O0 Due shareholders on incomplete loans _ 2,083.36 Htm m fund - - — —— 5,017.61 Undivided profits __ _ - 3.W2.33 Total- $a»l,S66.53 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 95 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hnnd last report - $ 17.-SfO.74 1 &gt;uei i Running stwk &gt; _ _ 30.384.04 Paid-up stock _ _ '.»..Vi&lt;m«&gt; Paid-up stock _ _ tf.530.U0 Mortgage payments _ S1.OM.0U stock Inuu pu \ mei.ls ~ _ 7.U2&amp;UO Interest ....'... _ 13.W8.4O Kents " ._ 317..TO Membership and transfer fee*. __ 127.7T) Contract! - M&amp;M County warrants redeemed i.'.xn :«&gt; I uhu r;i tic*** repaid - '■' '" Taxes repaid M ■ Total 1115,350,71 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans - - t 21JMJB Stock loans HUJ1.23 Withdrawals running stork anil dividends .- 3L',!)33.11 Withdrawals paid-up stock- 13.7MO.i»&gt; Witlnlrawals uiviileuil ou paid-up slack _ -... i.irjfi 71 Siiliirics _ _ l.Tjoim I 'tiler tXpeBM - - ''- 1 " "'*» Real estate acre, nut J1n:I7 Cash on hand.... _ ~ 17,t»7t*.44 Insurance - 121.58 Taxes _ - - - _ - 4O3.4.S County warrants _ - - - y.irtu.Wi Kregel Contract! - 4.500.00 Total »115,aoo.71 SUPPLEMENTAL RKPORT Plan of association _ _ Permanent Numb r of shares issued since organization _ •J.ZlH-j Number of shares outstanding last report 3.'i.'44 Shares Issued since last report 45»H Total - _ MMI Total Total - - ...'-M' 4 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancellend since last report M Number of shares In force this date - 3.196Vi ivmfi runniim rime of stock matured during MM year 134 mouths Number of borrowing stockholders „ - jm* Number of non-borrowing stockholders 230 Number of loans made for building purpose* during year - Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of 4 homestead -mortgages during year _ _ 25 Par value of each share of stock - - - f 200.01) Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 2.M7.2B Number and amount of mortgages Id process of foreclosure No. 1 2. ftno.no .\mourt of lunns on improved real estate - 155,049.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare been made — _ _ _ ZCl.OOO.OO Amount of lire Insurance In force and assigned to the association ;.&lt; col'ii'enil wiTitv 224.600.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral iecurltj_ 138.900 no Amount credited to reserve fund during year M1.71 IKMH Amount of lo»w« charged to reserre fund during year 21O.23 Amni&lt;rt of dividend! declared on running stock during year '.&gt; mime! •.. -it. rt.1 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during yen r - — 3,0GfV71 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 7.5% Rate per i-ent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - « r % Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during ye«r _ 8.4 ft 7M </seg>
            <seg id="p098">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 96 STATEMENT of the condition of the NUCKOLLS COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION- NELSON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President... _ Geo. Lyon, Jr. Vice President W. C. McHenry •Secretary C. R. Imler C. R. Imler Treasurer Henry Fox, Jr. Attorney T. W. Cole DIRECTORS Geo. Lyon, Jr. W. W. Hawley W. A. McHenry E. D. Brown H. E. Goodrich F. E. Bottenfield J. B. Goodrich H. G. Smith Thos. Graham Thos. Graham First mortgage loans Loam on stock or pasa book security Delinquent interest, tines, etc. Taxes paid _ Interest paid Expense Total LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends g 70.3^7.54 Full paid-up stork _ _ Reserve fund _ l."&gt;.45O.0O 1.476.00 Undivided profit* -'.!**&gt;. 43 Total. * Ml.^aa.97 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 97 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS »'a»h ou band l»t report - - _ - $ 1,11111 Dues c Uunuing muck) '.%-S-.tiu raid- up slock _ _ .. „ 13,300.00 -McrtjiiiK*' | my men ta _ - .. — 1 1,36U.— 8 Stork if a n |ui vuieuta — ~ 1,130.00 Interest -. 7,lttV.96 Membership and tranter fee» - 127.50 Tux sule redeeine&lt;l - - — - M • • 1 Total ¥ ~O I Ml* l\* 1)ISIH'HSKMKXT8 Mortgage loans f 15,570 00 MiTtuage loans $ 15.57Ti.UO Stork loans — 1,— jS.UO Stork Ian n &gt; — 1 /J55.QU Withdrawals running stock and dividends - - 'J.aR.BB Withdrawal!* runniutf vtock aud dividends _ _ _ y,W6.H6 Withdrawals* paiil-up Htwk _ «-— 10.U0U.U0 Withdrawal* puid-up atut'k - lo,uou.uu Salaries _ _ JOUUO Sal in if&gt; ...- _ — _ _ MflLtt Other expense „ _ 7—.30 Otht*r «. — 7B.3O Cauli &lt;&gt;u hiiml - :t.3(H.74 Cash ou bund _ :i..-ii&gt;«.7» Int t*rt*Ht [lit ii i „ _. _ _ —~™.... 1 .4 Ji '.Oil Int t*rt*Ht [lit ii I _. _ _ „..--..... l ,4_li i.uii Tux ah catttacan - mja Tux sale certlUciitr ... .'.'......' _____ - 173.-1 Matur.Ml stixk W.ia7.(J6 Total - f 3»,O»8.11l SUrri-EMBXTAL RKl'OUT Sl'PPI.EXIUNTAL REPORT l'lau of association Periuauent l'lau of MM(Wb&lt; I'eriuaumt Nuulx-r of sluiren UsuhiI since oritauiiation — „ M*V Number of sliareB Issued since orgauixatlou — _ .Number of «har.-s oiitxtandinK last report - 1,&gt;51.U&gt; Number of abarea uiitxtandinK last report - 1&gt;M.1O Number of sbarea oiitxtandinK last report Shares isiiueil ailue laat report MU ■I otal _ :: M.HI Shares wltlidriiwn, maturetl or cancelled since lam report _ Nuuilier of .-liin'g in force this date _,UW.J Number of share* ou which dues are delinquent 137 Number of shaies Miliject to cancellation tor non-payment if dues OD ATvracc running time nf stuck inatmed (luring the yea; 1-C months tn Number of bt&gt;rrowin^ stockhoUlcrs. „ 108 Number of uonborrowiliK stockholders. 1O1 Number of loans made for building purpose* during year - 3* Par value of each share of stock - _ ♦ 100.01) Total amount of dues delinquent at this date ____ 33b.78 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholder- 33X7J* Amount of Interest , premiums and tines due and unpaid _ 3-4.7S Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 3 Amount of loans on improved re»l estate _ - M.17B.74 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made .173 ■.135.0&amp; Amount of lire lusurann- in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - - l_Ufio.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to tbe association as collateral security 1-1 .-50.00 Amount of dividends paid ou matured stock and paid-up stork durluic 5.13B.-9 year 3 - 1K S Amount credited to reserve fund during year 273.00 Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year N Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stuck 6*7% durini: year - - I * ~ r ' e per cent of interest charged borrowers during year - IKi Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">98 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEWMAN* GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Charles Letheby Vice President C. J. Petersen Secretary E. H. Gerhart DIRECTORS Charles Letheby C. J. Peterson E. H. Gerhart A. L. Doty C. E. Barrett Edw. W. Lyon ASSETS First mortgage loan* - $ 30,000.00 C«sh :..._ „_ 93.4&lt;&gt; Delinquent interest. Ones, etc 77.00 Bxpruse* 177.80 Total -... f 38.347.90 LIABILITIR8 Running stork and dividends f2ft.233.OO Running scors. anu uitiuimiub 9 m,±.x&gt;irv Paid-up stock and dividends _ 2,350.00 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans _ fi,40f&gt;.00 Reserve fund - - - 735.90 Undivided proAta - - 2,828.50 Total _ - - f 3&lt;^347.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 99 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KECEIIT8 Cash on hand last report _ - 9 19.25 i&gt;ui-» iKunniiiK *tock) IZ_.JI~IIIIII~ 1 Him «,8»!ao MortKiige liHyineiits &amp;700.00 interest JlM'jT Premium _ _ _ .*&gt;J&gt;.&lt; 93 Fines :«■-, Sundries _ _ 17V on Profit account t&gt;5 44* Total _ _ f 1C3M.2O IMSBIHSKMEXTS Mortgage loans 9 13,600.00 Withdrawal! running stock and dividend* 2.41V3O Other ex pens© _ , __. 27.50 t 'j| f.|i mi band — — mm '**^ "W Incomplete loans - — _— — ...~— — — _. — 100.00 Total - - - _ _ _ f M.I— ' W SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association - Serial Number of series Issued since organisation _ 24 Number of shares Issued since organisation. _ 1*07 Number of shares outstanding last report- — JM0 Shares issued since last report -MS Total - - - Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — 33 Number of shares In force this date. _ *I5 Numlier of shares on which dues are delinquent - — • Number of borrowing stockholders — - - Number of non-borrowing stockholders- -. 25 Number of loans made for building purposes during jear. 8 1 'Inn of premium- - - — - Monthly Par value of each share of stock _ __ I 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this dmte — 2(100 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders. — _ 38.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 51.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate— - — 36,000.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 3Q.86O.00 Amount or lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — _ 34,700.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ — 36,500.00 mint credited to reserve fund during year— - - — 1J9.05 38.ri00.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year.. .\uiMMiii iTeuiieu 10 reserve iuuu uutiuk y«r - - — i_w.w Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year — - 1 t'.l.uu Amnuur or uiviuenas aecmrea on ruuuing biock uunu&amp; jmr - ..wi.w Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year — 10"^ Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year _ — {■ Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year 1 6'i IB Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p102">100 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President H. A. Pasewalk Vice President J. C. Stitt Secretary C. B. Durlaml Treasurer W. J. Stafford Attorney Mapes &amp; McFarland DIRECTORS H. A. Pasewalk I. M. Macy S. G. Dean John Welsh W.J. Stafford J. C. Stitt G. B. Christoph Burt Mapes Anton Buchholz ASSETS First mortirnge loans _ fM2.300.oo Loans in process of foreclosure _ 3,02068 Loan* on stork or pan* book necurlty. Loans on stock or pass book security _ _... ZJBM.00 Real Ktllle. offl.-e _ *H,375.00 uthir real estate - - 9,110.74 17,515.83 Heal estate sold on contract _ _ 1,070.00 Cash _ - - 5.52O.8B I »«"llni|in'Mt interest, fines, etc « - 2,N*Wi.7i Furniture aud lixturen 300.00 Taxes paid _ 201.60 Total Total.. *o75,S7C.« LIABILITIES LIABILITIES Kunolug- stock and dividends. _ _ (UMUJH KiiMiituic st»-k and dividends. _ _ HNWJI Paid up Htock nnd dividends Z~Z 224.14^.(10 I'aiit-up Htock and divldenda 224.14^.(10 Due nharebolilers on Incomplete loans _ ll.lXKMJO Reix-rve fund N.NXi.ft.' rndlvided proflta - - 2,477.50 Earnlncs 1S.8B2.72 Total _ $573,076.66 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 101 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KrTKIl'TS Cash on hand last report. $ 10.0CM.4t: Dues I Running stock) 97.543.i«&gt; l'aiil-up stock - 2O4.2Sl.Ul 1 it HI- up BIW.K - — Mortsak* payments lafMttw Stock loan payments — 9JM «■» S 1 1 } I 1 II fc" l'&lt;" * 1£1»11LJ5 -- •* .»....**........---..» !■■■ ■■■■■■■! ■■■....I ■ 1Mli ...... .,.,,.,_ . ... ........ x&gt; W," ■&gt; ™ " Stoct limn payments _ "•"J? '_"' Real estate sales. ~ 1.47o.."4&gt; Real estate sales. - 1.475. "4) I ntercst , 4{t,4M !.'[" I ntnrcst .«~~~~«. 4ft.4^i&gt;..t7 Bills payable - 1.M0.W Bills payable - l .'»&gt;'»&gt; KilH'M - - KV&gt; -VJ (■'lues -- — - -■ Wrf* ."Vj Certificates of deposit I4HUM Certificates of deposit 4.UHUU Incomplete loans ._ - - - - M IH II Incomplete loans ._ - - - ■ IH Rents and office building receipts. MM 'itiil t 'I Vt*K _ II. • TO Rents anil office building receipts. va i«' 'itiil t 'I Vt*K _—_ 4ir&gt; TO L^U | |'l IIP U 111* ■ €4 II ™" ---■---*--"-" .■..■-_.« L^U | |'l IIP ■! Ill* ■ €4 II ™" ---■---*--■•-- .»..■._.. Runuiug •tock - '^ T i Xotal- - - - $531,SM.'J8 Rlliiliiug stock - -IS' 71 Total _ _ _ |531,tS4.M DISBIKSKMKNTS Mortguge loan* $2a*.«W.ui&gt; Stock loans - &gt;&gt;.'3M '«&gt; Withdrawals running stock and dlridenda _ 8B.386.6S Withdrawals paid-up stock l'A&amp;iiKJ.t*) Withdrawals dividend on paid-up-stock 12.0t3.71 Salaries _ 3,000.00 Bills payable l.««&gt;.m Other expense ~— ..— - 3.' ft". 1*0 Real estate account - 17.KC08 Cash on band 5.5JO.S6 Incomplete loaun - 7 t 4-42..T7 Misct'l!:im-i&gt;u8 accoiini i fi35 Surplus and taxes - »jl" Jl Total.. 8VPPLKMKXTAL REl'ORT Plan of association - - — - Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report _ ™ 8,7-»5.7 Shares issued since last report - — 4,!Wu.U Total _ - - — 13.741.6 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report tVOTM Number of shares in force this date.. - _ — '.».;C4 i.i Number of shares on which dues are delinquent _. 1.11O Number of shares subject to cancellation for lioii-lmyliient of dues 1VJ Average running time of stock matured during "the year 124 month* Number of borrowing stockholders _ .". _ _.. !M N"uuil)*r of non-borrowing stockholders.. _ 410 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 31 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 87 Par value of each share of stock. — $100 and fJOM Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ _ $ 4.430LS Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders — _ 3.017.23 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid _ 2.8H.7B Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure -No. 5 5,300.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. '.' 3.irj&lt;iM Amount of loans on improved resl estate 5&amp;i,K&gt;0.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans bare been made _ - - - — 93T&gt;,."i7G.u0 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate - TJMM Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans bave been made „ - _.. 19.LS.0U Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - — .._.........•.... — ..._ O0Tafl0SLsV Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — 334.200.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ 2,163.74 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 419.90 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 34.H74.2L' 2.!«J4 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 12.0AT1 Hate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ' 10% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year . — - - t% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year I *Jj 'or 3 Mo \ !«• ; for !. Ho </seg>
            <seg id="p104">102 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the ELKHORX BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Dr. H. J. Cole Vice President F. E. Davenport Secretary _ T. E. Odiorne Treasurer _ Dr. H. J. Cole DIRECTORS Dr. H. J. Cole A. D«gner F. E. Davenport C. E. Doughty T. E. Odiorne H. T. Donner ASSETS First mortgage loaus _ $ 52,080.00 C lb ._ _ _ " 4,156 67 Delinquent interest, fines, etc _ WUH Tiixt^s paid —. ..... .... ... _ 122JB Total _ | 56,*!. 19 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends. _ ; 16,993.77 Palil up stock snd dividends _ _ 30,500.00 30,500.00 ■ — — —w- • ~ — —..,.. ... , __ du,iKiu.UV VndlTided profits _ 927.42 Total — - | 56,621.19 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 103 YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report - - • 2_5'5 v-«bu uu uniiu nai r-pun ~ - - — ii i in - Dues ( Running stock) - - ,?•*&gt;■„, Paid-up stock ~ _____ ___________ 11^80.00 Mortguge payments - - — 5"2J?S2 Interest ' ~ — ■• (C1 }'' Taies repaid _ _ ** 15 Total - - ♦ —f.81— — DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ - _ * ?-2_?)2 .u"[i|(,i|ir ii'uiin _ — t ~t— --- -- Withdrawals running stock and dividends. . ,t&gt;..i.-.&gt; Withdrawal! paid-up stock - - !___! Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock _ — - -"-"■' ♦'- i»i Salaries _____ ________ '"«"&gt;" Ooni missions _-«.. __.~. a •— — — — — -- -- — _J Other expense - _ _ _ _ — - - ?S*2 Cash on hand _ - - - - 4,136-^ Taxes paid __ ZZ..Z. ZZZ.ZZZZZZZZZZZZZ^ - — JJJ Interest paid _ _. '•"_"' Dividends paid to running stock....- - 1.ik»7i&gt; Total _ - t II .MB "I SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report - - -- T6» Shares issued since last report .- - ■— 1% nuuira iBaut-u auiue iusi reuori - -_-»/« •J'qJjjI l.U^V^t Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — -"li*^* Numher i»f shares In force this date Number of shares In force this date m Number of borrowing stockholders ~ ■ Number of n on -borrowing stockhoMers Number of loaus made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of - homestead mortgages during year --■ «*wm« Par value of each share of stock — - — -- • sJMJ? Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid — _5vi'. Number and amount of mortgages subiect to foreclosure. No. 2 vVSvIiii Amount of loans on improved real estate - — ~ i aB.lMJ.W V**w&gt; Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association mtnnm as collateral security - •- — - — W.tMiJW Amount of ternado insurance In force and assigned to the association OUni OI l-ruauo IIIRIirainr in iupt aim -Bni.ucu iv *_.. — «».. «ft«Vlim as collateral security - — _m»SJ Amount credited to reserve fund during ye»r «_fT5 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year i.™».«» Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid up stock during *W.CI) -.^P« Rat/p" cent "of dliri-eDdii declared on Vanning stock during year 6 " Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dar- Rate D pe/ cent "of' interest charged "borrowers daring year _ — • * </seg>
            <seg id="p106">1 104 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NORTH LOl'P BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH LOUP, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President , Geo. E. Johnson Vice President E. A. Hutchins Secretary E. J. Babcock Treasurer E. J. Babcock Attorney E. J. Babcock DIRECTORS B. Babcock . Jones S. L. Clement Geo. E. Johnson E. A. Hutchins Geo. S. Mayo H. C. Sample ASSETS Kirrt mortgage loan* * 18.RS6.00 Loim ou stock or paim book necurity C»«h _ - M&gt;.U) l.:&gt;l7.-3 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc.. 3U2.9O Total * wumxt LIABILITIES Running utock and dividends Paid-up stock and dividends * l«.!)«).-4 ■J..1OO.00 BHharpholders on Incomplete loans rre Fond i-ooo 03R.8S 709.13 Total $ 2O.-J75.7S </seg>
            <seg id="p107">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 105 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KE( K I ITS Cash on hand last report $ 474.IM Dues (Running stock) ZZZ Mortgage payments _ Interest Fines Membership anil transfer fern Incidental ~ Loin feet _ * MM Total. DIRBL'II 8EMENT8 Mortgage loans. $ 2.5O4.M Withdrawals running stock and dividends Interest on paid-up stock Salaries Other expense ('ash mi hand Interest on matured stock Withdrawals on matured stock * s.».M Total SVPI'LKMEXTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or perninnent ) Perm^SS5'J Nnmlwr of shares Issued since organization 164«H Number of shares outstanding last report — j6TO&gt;- Shares issued since last report - -85 Total * ■ 1 1 Total a Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 40 Number nf HhiireH in force this date - if7 ' : Number of shares in force this d;tte .&gt;un»r&gt;er nr snares in rorce mis iiaie ,.fl Number of shares on which dues are delinquent - - Average running lime of stark matured during the year 132 months XumlKT of borrowing stockholders - Numl&gt;er of non-borrowing stockholders - 31 Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 1 Par value of each share of mock - — $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date - 17-JOO Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid - Nnmlier and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure — No. 8 3K.«n Amount of loans on improved real estate , Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of loans on unimproved renl estate •--- Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have 15O.00 been made Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — - — ; — ; — Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association 2O.wnt«&gt; as collateral security Appraised value of land' not including improvements 8.!&gt;jr,.Oll . K.ir.SM»l •&gt;4.(T7r,.(»i Value of improvements Amount credited to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during Tear Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ... Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring year • ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p108">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 106 STATEMENT of the condition of the MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Thos. C. Patterson Vice President Victor von Geotz Secretary Sam Goozee Treasurer _...W. Horton Munger Attorneys _ Wilcox and Halligan DIRECTORS Ira L. Bare Geo. W. Finn Milton J. Forbes Frank T. Redmond Joseph P. Larson Win. R. Maloney Thos C. Patterson Victor von Goetz Claudia O. Weingand ASSETS First mortgage loans _ tsrj,800.00 Loans iu process of foreclosure l£,2OO.O0 Loan« on stock or pats book security 0,900.00 0,000.00 Real estate office _ _ 3O,xn.80 Cash _ _ _ _ rj.Mo.K8 IH-Ilnqueut interest, fines, etc _ _ 787.30 Kurnituaw aud fixtures „ 1017 37 7.X7.3O Foreclosure account - MM Total *X7u.l-j-j.oo LIABILITIES Running itock and dividend* *4©3,«&gt;1.84 Paid-up Mock and dividends _ - 417,800.00 Iteaerre fund !."_ 19.SO0.00 IndlTlded profits Advance Interest... 35.1 14.« 115.80 Total - $87«.2a2.O» </seg>
            <seg id="p109">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 107 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KECEIFTS Cash on baud last report .... ._ .... _ t ifl.KJuc; Data iltuuniug stock) ...._ I I "™ U7,lUM» lruu-uo PaM-ay stock . .... ".'. I 7m.uu.0U MortK»fc-e payments _ . . . M.1M.M Stock loan payment* _ _ _ __ l,«12.ia M.MM.M 1,«12.« Ueal estate sales ... ......V.....'. ____ 1 _ 1.SM.70 Interest _ __ " _ _ at.VMM Fiue» ;::. ziz_.zzzzzzzzzzzzz:z.z ! «-.»» Membership and transfer fees Rents office building „ Taxes and Insurance paiii _ hJO.71 Total _ _ _ fMMM.1T W.sm HMEME.NTS Mortgage loans tl'M.'J'UVU block luaus '" suujUU Dim t lUBUH | ——.—_..._—.. ■■ . _..•--. ■jajsjjajv Withdrawals running stork and dividends - - 3B,M»» 4W Withdrawals paid-up stock .— ———. — ... Hh^JUO-taj Withdrawals dividend &lt;&gt;ti paid-up stock _ 'J6.8X 41 Withdrawals running stock autl dividends Salaries . _ — 2JS0.00 Other expense s. .. _ 416.16 Real estate account _ ~ _~ ™ WS6.W Cash on hand - ___—__—_ _____ ' _ 12.G4O.0H Taxea and insurance paid ....»». ..- _.__.. .. _ .............. (JHE).(X&gt; Toui _ |8»»,*B.3T SLFl'LEMENTAL KEPOKT Plan ol aiboclatlou (serial or permanent Permanent Number of series issued since organization tif serial) Number of shares issued since organization 3*u«» Nuiuher of shares outstanding last report 1O.0WJH Shares issued since last report - - _ 2.10H Total _. i- 26^ Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 1.V27 Number of shares in force this date — — 10,323^ Number «&lt;f shares on whirb dues are delinquent _ 3t»H Average miming time of stock matured duniiu the year 1M mouths 2,108 Total Number of borrowing stockholders _ — *60 Snmber of non-borrowing stockholders - — *'♦*'■ Number of loans made for building purposes during the year . 90 .Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of huiufftteud niortKUKes during year - U Par value of each share of stock ..._ - • SP'" Total amount «;f dues delinquent at tills dale - 'I** 1 '" Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 52S2S Amount at interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid — 737 -3D Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure, No. 4 4.S00.4O N'uuilier and amount of mortgaKes la process of foreclosure No.3 2^00.00 :woo« Amount of loans on improved real estate _ - — 824.20O.0O Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been imui Amount of loans on improved real estate - MM Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans ha»e -„„ been made - - — 1,500.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - - — 9M,T30.00 Amount of tornado'lnsurance In force and assigned to the association -__.„_ as collateral security - - •»5*!K Amount credited to reserve fund during year - JI-JSP'??. \niount of dividends declared on running stock during year _ 27-2SP Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year »:-.4l *«M? M,83o.41 Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during •ft Jfc J I (» V* C IT I ■ • | J | m 1111 9 ■ | j| | | | I'll III i&amp; I U t ■ ■ m |i |i a %^ ■ * «4 ■ «4 » «« *^ »• V » «^^f year -.---" a ■■ - _ 'Jlf Rate per Mat «f MMM mmV«mI borrowers diariog je«r TJ3% </seg>
            <seg id="p110">108 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Thomas A. Fry Vice President _ Robert S. Wilcox Secretary _ John R. Brandt Treasurer George E. Haverstick Attorney Edgar M. Morsman, Jr. DIRECTORS O. D. Kiplinger Bartholomew Jolien William G. Ure Thomas F. Godfrey Byron R. Hastings Thomas J. Fitzmorris unn First mortgage loans Loans on stock or pass book security Other real estate B estate told on contract and muuiripiil securities Delinquent interest, fines, etc. Total LIABILITIES Running stork and dividends Paid-np stock and dividends Due ihsreholders on incomplete loans Heserve fund - Undivided profits. Total </seg>
            <seg id="p111">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 109 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash ,iu hand last report ._ 1 5UMA4 Due, iKunnlng stock) ~ v35S3 PUI&lt;|-!1|) MIiH'k £j°rtKacc P»ir»Mita ., ," ~~~~ 23i',tttU Stock loan* payments "jn'o-j&amp;tirt Heal ♦•state snles* 1,(111.90 Hfni Mtate on contract IIZZHZ^IIIZZZIZZIZIIZIZZIZHZIZIIZ TBb!«1 $''rj™'.&lt; /- i r- ■■ - ■ 7a.433.41 Hereived from meniliern In loan — —^ 'ttCM Preflt mid loss account ca»h over "~ Meml&gt;erslilp .ml transfer fees ** 2,461. 23 Fur. closure ZTmTZHZTZZZirZIZI^ZI^ZZZZ!^ &amp;,&amp;W)ji Delinquent Interest .. ........ 1 -IT "I Miiiil&lt;-ip;i] ImuhIs and warrants .. " !."„".!!"".„._""!! ...... !"!!"L"~!..""""".i!l"™!!"[!^l"™ B*442.1S Total „ ttk44l&gt;7V !31 Total _ _ , I»l»Bl R8EMENT8 DISBIUSEMEXTS Mortfrage loans $47K,:»73 4r i»i»-i.»L n.-i..iir..i i .^ Mortgage loans $47H.:t73 M' 2S.aK.» WithitrnwalK riiiintiiK stock and dividend* ...!..." '".....'..„ 2M&gt;'m&amp;M Withdrnwals rtuuiliiK stmk ami dtvirteinU L^waoi Withdrawals pnid-up stock ~~i.""""!!"Z_r.~"~~r.!~"l.. MH3.0T WitlxlrawalB pniil-up «nck . . MLM&amp;.M Withdrawal* dividend on paid-up atock ;~ !!!!!"!! "!!!! !!i"~!!!!"^ '.'.'.'.'"".'.'.'. '.'.'.'. ... n'-"'t ; . Withdrawalu dividend on paid-up stork .. 1» '■".• I". Salurivs S«To l»&gt; Snliirles SalnrleH 3 673 00 &lt; ttlier expense _ !»'noi SW &lt; ttlipr expense _ *&gt;'ft01 Ng 2.901. S8 Keal estate account "'1:14 1." ( .isli (in hanil :)0«l". ••? Real estate account 21S4 13 &lt; :lsll mi tlMliil __ , .'I061-""'? Fnrf&lt;-l&lt;iHiire aci-ounts ..." . n luo^f* Profit and loss account _ .Z S7.M Profit and loss account _ _. , __ ' S7.M «'nsli slutrt ;md ilividfiuls correct Delinquent Interest and taxe* _ l.lllT.'tn Delinquent Interest aiul t:i\.~ _ \ t HJ7.33 Mini&lt;'i|i:i! linrids and warrants _ l!M.'i!IV! Total _ 9MO&gt;7&gt; a* Mti ii.-i |.a ! lumils and warrauta _ l!l.4.'i!l V! S1PPLEMEXTAL REPORT I'lnn of aftftoclatton (serial or permanent I'lan of association (serial or permanent lVrm.i:ient Niimlipr &lt;if shares inil&lt;tanillii(t last report 2».«7»4 Shares issued since lust report _ ..____U,wrii Tuti.l ZZ— H "~ Z 41JWiW SliHrc&gt;« withdrawn, niattired or ranoelled since last report «, S.W»S \unil&gt;er of shares in force this dnte .'Mill.'t*. V umber of tiomiwinjr Hto&lt;-khotf]ers _ Vsabn of Bea-borrnwtnK stockholders „ m 1 I'tn v mni»pr of loans mud? for tuillding purposes during- year - **91 NuniHer of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or itayment of homestead mortjrnjres dnrinjr year * i*» I'tir vMliic »f fit'-h Hlnre of Htiu-k : __ 9 10000 *ii'onnt af intcrrsr. pr^iniunis ai'd fires rtwe and unpaid BMjH Vi-mber and nmoiint of mortcurps snippet to forW*losnre No. 7 t\7io - *t Amount of loans on improved real estate 1,2X7.47." lit Appr:iN*"t vnlue of Improved real estnte ufmn which loans faare heen made _ 2.M«JW.'i 0) Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as rnlliUernl security 1.607 -W.** in Amount of tornado in«i&lt;mnre In force and »H&lt;«iirnt&gt;d to the association aa collateral security _ 1 P" - Amrui'i cr^dit&lt;'(| to reserve fund during venr 0,fi07 M »irni' -t of fMvider.'l* dednrpd o» rvn&gt; frg «tock dnrinc vear 4^!44A9T Amount of dividends nnld on matured nnd paid-up rtock dnrlngr year 14 v* *ft Hate i&gt;er «*ent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dlvhlends paid on matured and full paid stock durinjr «and.Vr year __ « and R*T- Rate per cent of interest charred borrowers during year „. n.6and 9T 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 110 STATEMENT of the condition of the OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President John F. Flack Vice President R. A. McEachron Secretary _ E. N. Bovell Assistant Secretory John T. Brownlee Treasurer George C. Flack Attorney T. F. Wiles DIRECTORS John F. Flack George C. Flack K. A. McEachron Robert Dempster E. N. Bovell ASSETS • mortgage luuus _ _ J5,liS.'.«f&gt;.J5 i in prix-ess uf foreclosure 1V_ M ,«;.«&gt;1 ; ou stuck or liubs book 25.riUi.0D real estate 9,345.18 Loans in prm-ess uf foreclosure 18,11*0.61 Other real estate _„ _.„ 9,845.18 Mtatt .-ulil mi I'liutrui't Tu,'.K*i.4&lt;j State niul municipal securities _ .'{7.1W.IW Catili 737,13 Delinquent &gt;MM«jajL fines, etc :(7.t)02.35 Liberty loau bonds lON.aiu.ou Total w,-io,:xi.iy LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $2,4O0.-WU.&lt;B Paid-up stock and dividends ...J...JL... sl.VBi'-'lfi!* Doe shareholders on incomplete loans ..._ _ .'. ' 9S.SO.S0 Reserve fund — 200.000.00 Undivided profits _ _ _ MSfl Total $6,210,361 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 111 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on haud last report . _ _ - » 804,143.43 l&gt;ues l Running stock) _____ '.'..'. .'.'.'.' Zl 8HO,3Ot.W Paid-up stock _ ..... .-■■'". l,*O»,t»_91 Murlttaiff payments _ _ _ 1,150,865.08 Stork loan payments __ _ 4-,7WiS8 Beal estate sales _ _ _ .... _3.:ts4.M&gt; Interest _________ Premium ™ J8-.534.3O 1J».»1«.S_ Fines __IIIZ_____Z__III__-__ZIIZ_Z____________. 1.1SJ.7* Membership and t— mm— ■» — ■— tt.W0.S7 Heal estate contracts, other receipts In detail 3B.297.« «.»«».S7 Fi.reclm.urc ' ..." .__...___!.__ .'..-- 2»^B8l_1 Loan fees anil expense „ „ m , _ _ l.~i.7.Yi._l Liberty loan bonds Liberty loan bonds _.. _ 3,500.00 State and municipal securities - - 43,871. 5H i let pa I ftecuritle* - 43,671.SB Total _ ™ IMMUMMfc DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans **'™** ~ . .^1 Stork loans 44.984.86 Withdrawals running stork and dividend* t~.**v47 Withdrawals paid-up stock MW.-14.41 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock l».__«.9n Salaries 4«,i_a*a Commissions Other expense _. -4,4fiO.-rt 19.790 W Real estate account _:*?♦__ Cash on hand 737.137.7- Tarr.iw.T. in detail 726.89 Heal estate contracts, other disbursements Foreclosures 6.WIB.07 Profit and loss 45K.M Mileage and expense R.178.73 Liberty loan bonds ll-.cmom State and municipal securities 4N1O7P. Total (•■■•"I" ",I«J SUPPLEMENTAL RErORT Plan of association (serial or permanent _ Permanent Nuiniier of shares outstanding last report H0.N67 l_i/*» Shares Issued since last report 36.3G0 .*MS/tiOO Total _ __. 97.2O7-4TO/«0 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report _ 15.ffl?7 MO/MO Number of shares in force this date _ „ _ 81.M0 110/000 Average running time of stock matured during the year 108 months 108 months Number of borrowing stockholders ." \'m.', Number of non-borrnwinn stockholders ! _i 6..TT4 Number of loans made for buiMlng purposes during- the year _ 721 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homesteads mortgages during year- _ _ 940 Plan of premium _ —Monthly with interest Par value of each share of stock _ $ am.OO Amount of interest, premiums nml fines flue and unpaid 37.WB.3B Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 44 4S.I00.fl0 Number and amount of mortfrnc^s in prtcess of foreclosure No.84 lSJIWdl Amount of loans on Improved real estate 5,185.1)06 35 Appraised value of Improved real estate npon which loan* have been made 9.2O3.4On.0O Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 5.74*.&lt;MM» Amount credited to reserve fund during year _ ' 4A.338.AS Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during vear Isl4-"i«3 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1 17 ..141 .S3 Amount of dividends naid on matured and paid-up stock" daring year 170,!W»*I Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 7.5% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur - ing year _ _ — *jt Kate pef cent of Interest charged horrowers during year •% Rate per cent of premiums charged horrowers during year i.*% </seg>
            <seg id="p114">112 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION- OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President G. W. Loomis Vice President W. S. Wright Secretary W. R. Adair Treasurer W. R. Adair Attorney F. H. Gaines DIRECTORS John H. Butler Joseph Barker G. W. Loomis Charles Black E. A. Parmelee W. S. Wright R. J. Dinning M. M Robertson W. R. Adair AMETB Klmt mortal «e inn ii« s •.MSJO&amp;.O0 Loans in pro&lt;-esB of foreclosure :t.irJ4 &lt;r* Loans on mock or piu book security ISOJU'.M Loans on mock or pass book security I_ii.ft4~ .'M Heal estate office - -» -JSHMi.UKI la) (Hlicr renl estate _ J^..V»5I.'m; _12,rM(i.!Hi (Hlier reiil estnte J^..V»5&gt;'m; _l_rM(» !Hi Ke»l estate Bold on contract "O.IMO.BJ Keal estate Bold on contract _ TO.IMO.BJ I 'axh _ _ _ S4B^7B^8 &lt; ;i^ii _ _ Ma\STB.28 State and municipal spcuritieu : ______ 3ljflS.S6 State and municipal securities : ______ 1L81SUS4 Delinquent interest, fines, etc - r»,638.tS3 Delinquent Interest, fines, et&lt;* - fi.638.tS3 Kurnlture and fixtures _ l.!«3.8u Kurnlture and fixtures -... 1JM.GC LilHTty bonds 6,000.00 Lllierty bonds 6,000.00 Total *lO.707,30L'.'&gt;4 Total _ *10.797,30-.!H LIABILITIES LIABILITIES KunniiiK stork and dividends f tMMJKLM Kunnine "took and dividends s !),(KT .371.28 Paid-up MiM-k and dividends 713.24S.4T. Paid-up utixk and dividends 713JMSI4T. Due nharehoiders on incomplete loans "Kl.jlXi 40 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans 730,506 46 Kenerre fund 2S0.a)0' v i Inilivided profits ....- kMHTT Total - $10,797,30-.»4 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 113 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KKC '\isli on band last report Dues (Running stock) Paid-up stock Mortgage payments Stock loan payments Real estate *iles Interest um.iZH.rA Certificate of deposit Warrants - 143.4ZT.17 Miscellaneous earnings Beats and office liulhliiig re«-eipt Foreclosure account S3SS Incomplete loau ledger Lllierty loan receipts Total DISBll si MKXTS Mortgage loan*. 8tock loans r.'..-M7.«MLST 2.M4J3J* Withdrawals running stock and div! Withdrawals paid-up atnttk In Is Withdrawals dividend mi paid -up stuck Salaries ...... tjm -.-■ ,f)7:t.-J0 other expenses. 1il.7Wl.4S Renl estate accimnt Oaxh on hand tt.ttC.31 M» r mL2*&gt; Furniture and fixture* Office Imflding expense Foreclosure ari-ounl Ortiflcntes of deposit l.runvx-, SHS21 :t&gt; 12.MS.ffl «.ne7.!w Warrants on hoMds .-,-_• m 11; Total SrrrLEMENTAL. RF.POKT IMan of association (serial or permanent I N'lmbcr &lt;»f shares Isued stn&lt;*e oririiiiiKation NuiiiImt of shares outstanding last report Shiirvs issued since last report ■MMT7H*. 117.1.TK Total VuinlMT of shares In force this date. Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report. XuniliiT of Ihmiis m:idi' for liuildinir purposes during year. Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or \ ay men t of honw»stPad-mort(rajres durftiff yt»nr. Par value of each share of stock Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Numlter and amount of mortal ges in preeaM of foreclo*nr*&gt; %'•» IK Number idmI ,'itnonnt of mortim^es In process of foreclosure No. .1 Amount of loans on improved real estate 4.'. »T1 to x:-um !).*T*.4tO.0(&gt; Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hive been made Amount of loans on unimproved real estate mimm Appraised value of unimproved re»l estate upon which ioani bare heen made _ _ mumm Anx'ii't cif fire insurance In force and assigned to the association as cnllatvraJ secvrUr - .... Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association v2.iH.3an3* as collateral security s.7M,v&lt;) in Amount credited to reserve fund during year OJM.M Amount of dividends declared on running stock during rmr Amount of dividends nald on matured and paid-up stock during year Rate l&gt;er \*ent of iHvi'lends ilectnred on rur'tli'tr sto--k 'lnrinc* vear Rate |&gt;er cent of dividends paid on matured and foil paid stock dnr- .'..."I SI: ing year .-1.5 and .V, Rate p*r cent of Interest chargei borrowers during .rear «.6 and r. KIPTS 11U.MTiO.III l.AV!.r&gt;4«i.H0 210.'&gt;1«.'JU </seg>
            <seg id="p116">114 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CONSERVATIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President. Geo. F. Gilmore Secretary - -... Paul W. Kuhns Treasurer Paul W. Kuhns Attorney - William Baird DIRECTORS Geo. F. Gilmore Paul W. Kuhns William Baird E. A. Benson A. W. Bowman Robert Dempster John F. Flack Byron R. Hastings J. C. Robinson Randall K. Brown Charles C. George J. A .Sunderland C. M. Wilhelm H. A. Thompson A. P. Tukey ASSETS First mortgage loans. $rJ,61o,4U!.&lt;io Lubdh in proven of foreclosure _ - 46,471.40 Loans on stock or paa» book nerarlty _ 100,350.10 Beal estate, office - fNUKKKXW Other real estate ' _ _ _ 5c!.24O.!« 123,210.85 Keal estate sold on contract 2.'t,8sy.57 State and municipal securities -.'. '..'.'. .'..'. 205.119.05 Cash _ .'.'.'.' _ _ 631,2&gt;S.16 I&gt;eliiiquent interest _ • 22.SS3.98 rertlflcate* of deposit in'banks __ :i7.5Oa«) Iteal estate purchased for future office use 190,000.00 Rents Wo.ll Total *14.J&lt;&gt; .f.H.1.3 LIABILITIES Kunninp stock and dividends *10.*Sf&gt;.449.80 »10,*BT..44B.S0 2,337,812.81 raid-up stock and dividends - 2,337,812.81 Dne shareholders on incomplete loans — 3aB.922.ftl 2,3.17,812.81 389. 922.01 STB.000.00 ■"C306.ll I HIP snnrpnniticrB on iin"uiiii»i»rif iwiii^ ow.. »•_.:'! Reserve fund 376,000.00 I'ndlvided profits - - "C.306.11 Total »14.OOn,-IOl.«3 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 115 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 kkceipt» Cash on hand last report T 9 TOTV ; Dues i Ku lining Mack) 4,127.Bt_".35 Paid-up stork .... ......r.!_....lZ..-I 64«!©47!27 Mortgage pay mem * 2.ii*GitJK73 Stock loan payments _ .. ._. L"J4,7s~J.!M Heal estate sales _ _________ »!x«!!&gt;l Interest "..".'.'. 732,*J*B.JK2 Foreclosure account »&gt;6.r.i^..i4 Real estate 4fi.MB.18 &lt;"ertifl&lt;"Ues of deposit HMI Loan fees „ l*O'u- i-i Rents nnd office building rwelptu tXJCUtl Bipense _ , _ 70 |g Profit fnnii llfll» ilepartiueiit - ... (JlUi Profit and loss- account 1 7,"' T'.» State mil municipal securities _... 173.41.VTft Total _ _ f8^M0.7.~1.4_ IMsr.l KSKMKNTS Morts-ge loans _ stock loam - . wn.'Tt&amp;M Withdrawals nuuiag stock and dividends _..........l.. ...... 3.1.T2J210.»7 Withdrawals paM-ap stock and dividends _ _... HK.K40.tf! Taxes anil expense of office building « „ 3.&lt;s_jii Rentals of real estate purchased for offi&lt;-e use 11.373 71' Salaries BRJMV *3 Foreclosure account ...- .. &lt;Jt 'k-j ci Real estate sales rt'* 1^ 1'' Real estate account „... iv, Hi n fash on hand —- 631 V^"* Itj Interest ...- - _ Vnitel Stntcs 1 iovcrnnieut. state and municipal securities Mfi " General expense , Real estate for future office use ______ Reserve fund __ ni71*.W Total - $R,s«&gt;.7-l 4J SUPPLEMENTAL REPOKT Plan of association (serial or permanent - ' Permanent NuuiImt of shares issued since organization l ?,■ &gt;.-j.v. VunilHr "f shares outstanding last report ._v90R Shares issued since last report : TlStfi Total m Shares cancelled since last report !~ "1 vr. Number "f shares In force this date 347JR1 Xumlier of liorn.w iiiu- stockholders ."'..V* Xumlier of nonliorroning stockholders IT.W Numher of loans made for building purposes during year 134 Nuinlicr of loans made for purchasing homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages dnring year _ S» Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 Number and amount of mortgage* subject to foreclosure No. 35 71. :««&gt;&lt;«&gt; Number :uid amount of mortgages in prow of foreclosure . No. 18 45.471.40 Amount of Interest due and unpaid Amount &lt;&gt;f loans on Improved real estate l_,filO.4&lt;&amp;ai Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans bare- been made ?7,O42.103.M) Amount of fire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1.1,Q0»,M_$3 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security ft.T31.iro.no Amount of money loaned on improved farms 2,&lt;iO3.4O0.0B Appraised value of land not Including improvements „ 4.'.?r&gt;2.O7**.8i&gt; Value «' Improvements _ 72«.4iV. i«&gt; Amount credited to reserve fund dnring year flfVTls'M Amoui't of losses charred to reserve fund' during year Amoui't of losses charped to reserve fund dnring ye«r _ 10.711. r&gt;6 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 477.473 &lt;! 477.473«! Amount of dividends nald on paid-np stock during vear ' ___ 117.341 4S Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 5.5CJ U« Rate per cent of dividends nald on full paid stock during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers drulng year.. •.&lt; and 9.4% </seg>
            <seg id="p118">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 116 STATEMENT of the condition of the BANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President W. D. Lincoln Vice President - N. A. Spiesberger Secretary A. D. Touzalin Assistant Secetary A. A. Tenopir '1 reasurer L. D. Spaulding Attorney Thomas D. Crane DIRECTORS W. D. Lincoln A. D. Touzalin L. D. Spalding C. D. Hutchinson Thomas D. Crane John C. Wharton John P. Leary Chas. F. Kuncl J. J. McMahoi J. J. McMahon KASSKTS uiortuiiee loans :. *4'JO.7:i."i.&lt;JO Loan* in process of foreclosure 4.S00.00 Loaua on Mack ur pass book security 13,21i).M Other real estate — s.'.KHi.'J* KhI estute until on contract _ _ 1,400.00 State and municipal securities _ _ _ liJ4.49 Cash _ _ ls.'.tJT.mt Delinquent interest, fines, etc I,4t».lti l^imlture and fixtures 1.NH0.T5 Taxes psid - , 630.OT ♦Cfi3.9O6.TS) Total LIABILITIES RunuinK »«oek and dividends _ f3M.Wr.-10 Paid-up stock and dividends - 132,583.36 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans _ 3t,AB&amp;85 Reserve fund - 2,774-HB VndiTlded profits — - _ — 1 „_ 120\90 Insurance commission _ 73.18 Total *V&gt;.V.»06.S9 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 117 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 ItKt'KIPTS Cash on band last report $ 'Jl.633.2Ci Due« i Running stock) „ iXO.lfl7.7f&gt; Paid -up stock _____________________________ 4&gt;-'.li:(!3&lt;&gt; Mortgage paj meuts „ _ _ 8t\*Ml00 Stork loan payments _ 5,787.88 Real estate safes ___ * , L',433!47 1 merest ..." I .. 3U.144.T!) Taxes paid . _ _ L'49.71 Fines .'..'. _ ss.yn Delinquent Interest . 1,721 *C other receipts in detail. commissions 371.44 Incomplete loans „ 19*1.' Kxpcnst 7'1'J.3T» Insurance commission _ _... 1J^ "T Total - IS7x.MJ8.5B kishirskukxts Mortgage loans _ _ $19.",, 7(15. 00 St tH'k Ion ns - 1 S«3&gt;H • "' With 'rawnls running stock and dividends — _ — 22&gt;. i Withdrawn!* j aid-up Htnrk i&gt;."»0n.«0 Withdrawals dividend on pald-ap stmk 7,«1«.12 Salaries _ _ - 2,800.00 ( "din missions - ■ — • . —-• --■ .. . •'( o Rent — — - - 1.800.11) Otli**r t*x|H*u#e l.KJS 11* Other expense l.-*O* \'.' Ken 1 put ate account - *l,ir»2.78 Cash on hand - - lvrj" «i 'l";i \c^ paid - ~— . - 4»W. 11 Delinquent interest - - J.JT." Tii City warrants £M.49 Incomplete loans 1W,757.-1S Total SITPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) - Permanent Niinilier of shares !«■■«&lt; »inre organization ._ - _ 0J.4M 4 Number of shares outstanding last report 11.200% Shares Issued since last report - - 3.9&lt;Hl/3 Total - - : M,»4 5/« Totnl Shares nithdniwii, matured or cancelled since last report '-MM! Xumlver of shares In force this date - — 13,128 2/8 Xuinl»er of borrowing stockholders _ _ — — Nuinlx^r of non-borrowing stockholder^ — ■*■*" J.OM Xuinlie-r of loans made for lMiildlng purposes during year » Xumher of loans made for purchasing homesteads 'or payment of homestend-mortgaKes during year _ - SS Par value of each share of stock _ - — I iwmf&gt; ■ Amount of interest, premiums and fines doe and unpaid — l.-kn.W Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 3 l.«.V&gt;.nn Number and amount of mortgage* In process of foreclosure _..No. 4 . ifiOO.fln Nuinher mm amount oi inorigaK*^ ■" prw-mB w mmiuiutc _...iv. ■» . ■»■•«-_" Amount of loans on improved real estate - SO4,23.».ni) Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - --- ■ - --■ 572,737.10 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 44 ?-rJ',".!!! Amount credited to reserve fund during year - 1&gt; 12i2 Vmount creoue*l to rricn-e ninu uuruijc \mr - *:i«ik Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year JSJI Mn&lt;iunt of dividends declared on running stock during year 'iS?5?I Amount of dividends paid on matnreil and paid-up stock during year i, Sin 12 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year *"» Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during uumst 7.«1« 12 e per CPI1I OI UHUiriMlB |&gt;nm ,'ii umiu-™ h«« ■«■ ,— .« ' • ■■ ■ year -— - -■- i . — — . Z2" Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7 1% </seg>
            <seg id="p120">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 118 STATEMENT of the condition of the COMMERCIAL SAVINGS AND LOAX ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Patrick J. Sheehy Vice President W. P. Adkins Secretary Jas. J. Fitzgerald Treasurer _ F. W. Thomas Attorney A. H. Murdock DIRECTORS ■ . Sheehy J. Coad W. P. Adkins E. C. Kohansky T. F. Quinlan Frank Koutsky L. F. Etter A. H. Murdock Jas. J. Fitzerald ASSETS First mortgage loans $l,(J7&lt;i,tk£.(JO Loans on stock &lt;ir jmsb hook m-curity .„ lti.'JOT.SO Other real estate - - 1S.ULT.73 Other real nun - - 13.UC7.73 U*»mI estate sold ou contract _ li,:£J6.77 Heal estate sold ou eoutract 'l^X.77 Cash _ .... _ 33,107.70 Cash _ _ 33,107.70 Delinquent interest - 573.75 Ifeliuijuent interest - 573.75 Cert ificatcs of deposit I.......". 40,000.00 Cert iflcates of deposit - 40,000.00 Liberty bonds 3ri.K48.00 Liberty bonds ICi.MS.OO W a rants and Investment stock _ ■£&amp;&amp;.&amp;! Warants and inrestuient stock _ 4,«36.8^ Total |l.Jl'J.ii70.07 Total fl.'Jl'J.uTtt.U? LIABILITIES LIABILITIES Huniiiiig stork and dividends _ $*M.l'.t0 W) Huniiiiig stork and dividends _ lNSt.190.80 I'aid up itocki and dividends 288.MB.34 Due shareholders no Incouiplete loans _ 17.4O7.16 Rcaerre fund ir&gt;.&lt;m0.(X&gt; Undivided profits _ 4,574.77 Total $l.L &gt; 19.e76.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 119 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 HKCEIPT8 Cash on band last report f 69,373.81 Dues iKliunllii; stock) _ 312.U76.S3 Paid-up stock ______________________________ 9^:J4O.0O Mortgage payment* 301.3dO.00 Stock loan payments _ _ _ isisti&amp;K Heal estate safes _ ~..._ _______ ",1110.-8 iutere« _ _ _ :::: :::: 7«jm« I,on ii t*x pfliM* . ..... ..__„_ l.UOl.tK Real estate on contract ...- _ _ _ 4.M4.2S Interest aud earnlngH ,. - 1,137.14 Undivided profits _ _ Ml Incomplete loans _ _ 68.rjS.9O Expanse 154.8* Cash exchange _ __ _ _... 27.4MA6 Liberty bonds _ - lire 00 i5«.a&gt; Liberty bonds Total - - $887,30—13 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans Mortgage loans .... _ . $185,780.00 Stock loans - _ 31.835.lii «:«»4» Withdrawals running stork aud dividends 33S,57»24 Withdrawals paid-up stock __ 4*..:»2.O8 Warrants and investment stock 4,890.(8 Salaries - - - - ~ 2,041,66 delinquent interest — _ _~. 47.10 Cash exchange _ _ 27,406-96 9,284.47 Other expense - — — - ,..„ ,, . rt._&gt;4 47 Real estate account — _ 10, -438.88 Cash on band _ _ — _ 33,107.70 Interest and earnings ~ . :.£l 30 I ..inert y bonds «_ 36,00000 ifinPn V U Oil fin .. _„. ___ __ ».■■■■ Ju.UUU W Real estate on contract - - — _ 4.366.50 lieal emaif on cvuiraci .. - ■ , + *■«» ■■' Loan expense _ _ — — _ _ 1.901.6S Iiioomplptt* loans — .—.._ l_)O,3*Vi 9t Certificates of deposit — . _. 4*d[O0O.O0 Tot«i - imn.Mi ii SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) _ _ Permanent Number of shares issued since organisation Wj/Sk Number of shares outstanding last report — 19.273*4 Shares issued since last report -. 3,872% Total _ - - 28,144ty Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report MP__i Number of shares In force this date _ iy 47H*. NuiiiIkt of borrowing stockholders 885 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 1.497 Number of loans made for building purposes during rear M Number of loans made for purchasing homesteads or payment of Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report Nnmliei* of shores in force this date homestead-mortgages during year - _ 121 Fnr vnlne of each share of stock ..— — $ 300.00 l!ir \ II IMC HI fUCII Slinir UI Blw» 9 iJur.W Amount of interest and dues unpaid 573.7S Amount of loans on improved real estate _* 1,071,775.00 573.76 Apprnlxed value of improved real estate npon which loans hare been made - 2,136JIHi.0O Amount of loans on unimproved real estate UM 2.126JB1.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made — - ™ - 10,630.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 1,445,316.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ — 1, 196.72609 Amount of money loaned on improved farms — _ 5,000.00 "\]uir:iisfd vnlue'of land not Including improvements _ Kt.Onft.00 Value of improvements l.nnonn Amount of fire Insurance thereon _ i.nonnn Amount of tornado insurance thereon ._ - — „_ 1,36000 \mount credited to reserve fund during year _ 5.060.00 Amount of dlvidenda declared on running stock during year 4l.737.57 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 15.4SB.4g ■»•'. I ■■! .'I 6.nd5_% Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 6 and 5JS% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during yesr _ _ T.2 and 616% </seg>
            <seg id="p122">120 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PRUDENTIAL SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFlfcERS President W. C. Bullard Vice President C. R. Sherman Secretary D. H. Christie Treasurer D. D. Miller Attorneys Smyth &amp; Schall DIRECTORS W. C. Bullard D. D. Miller W. W. Mace C. R. Sherman E. A. Blum D. H. Christie T. E. Wood Klr»t murtifiiKe loans Luaua In process of f&lt;ireclonre Louns on stock or paa*. lunik security Other re»l entate Ubm U iioniis Furniture and fixtureti T«l« p.id Other men Total LIABILITIES Running stock and dlvldendK :;i.ina ■shareholders on incomplete loan* rve fund - •-•.aiio.oo 1.121.441 rndlvliled profit* Loan fees 152.37 Total *M0,4T&gt;1.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 121 YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE 30, 1917 ItKCEIPTS Cash on baud last report _ - - $ M10.M Kues i Kunnlug stock) .".'.'.\.\\""~~~.'™.''—~~LZ'.'.'..— 1*1,4*41 Stork loan payments .. - tt&amp;Mt Interest _ _— 1K.M1.92 Meinliership and transfer few -. ."-•&gt;. 4T Mis«-ellaneous 1_'.M' ■ * 1 Total IHSIllItSKMKXTS M'TtRilKe l»;ilis S1MMKY22 srork loans _ :. „ ?rio.(P&gt; Withdrawals ruuniug mwk anil dividends — .".T714.M Stock loans _ :. _ ».iO.Oi&gt; Salaries __________ - ' Other expenw. rent, etc - Hi Otf &lt;";i*li mi hand I'.', Ml Atf Office «-»--«- lT-.'.l". Mi: ' flllllK-IIUS ' _______ _ 11, 1711 J» Loan fees -- «»ti_.3*) Xotal - $20i,l#lJW SITPLEMEXTAL RKPOKT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Perm-Bent \umUT of shares Issued since organization - - ~ 14.730 Num1&gt;er of shares outstanding last report _ — 8,604 Shares issued since last report — 2.17S Totnl _ 10.782 -8,4104 Shares issued since last report Totnl Slinres withdrawn, matured or latwelied since last report - "*; Xnroher of shares in force this date _ _ I M Number M brrow l»g sto«'khnliiers „ _ — — 3rt* \unil&gt;er of non-lnirrnwinc stockholders WC Numlicr of linns made for huildinir purposes during year 30 N'umhi-r of loims innde for purrhasin^: homesteads or payment of ■ homestend-mortgapes durinff year value of each share "f stork % 100.00 Par value of each share of stork Number ami iiiiiount of mortK«)res subject to forclosure No. 2 2.200.00 Number nmi amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure Xo. 1 3,005.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate S7l,Mti4O Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made i+«.24O.no Amounr of luiins on unimproved real estate 3,775.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare lieen made 11.800.00 Amount of fire insurance In force and assigned to the association as rollaternl security SM^TWlW Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association us collateral security.. 3XWIW.0O Amount ireilited to reserve fund during year SOOrti Amount of dividends declared on running stock cinrtne Tear 14.7W7* Rate per cent of dividends declared cm runnlnir stock during rear &lt;5t Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - — - - - I -' ; year </seg>
            <seg id="p124">122 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION- OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Samuel Rees Vice President Henry M. Beall Secretary _ Irving G. Baright Treasurer _ Irving G. Baright Attorney E. C. Hodder DIRECTORS Samuel Rees E. C. Hodder Henry M. Beall H. C. Getscher Irving G. Baright ASSKTS First mortgage loans sioti.riJl.lS L— n« In process of foreclosure 1,200.00 Loans on stock or pats book security 11.918.20 Real estate sold on contract B12JSB Cash _ _ _ _ _. .-. 13,831.96 Delinquent interest, flues, etc _ 2,014.34 Kurni t lire and fixtures 600.00 Other assets 287.26 Total 1196,7-15.79 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $122,192.32 I'alilup stock and dividends .._ 70,962.90 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 1.370.17 RM*rw fund 1 412 43 neserve iuuu .— -.-. 'AnT™ Indlvided proits 786.67 Other liabilities _ 32.40 785.67 Total 1 196,745.79 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 123 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on baud last report _. Duei (Running stock) _ _ » 1 ti '•■ 4 4* l'aid-up HtiH-k ~. ZZHZIH "... ZZZZZZZZZZZIZiZZZZZZZ itjhmi Mortgage payments ________________^_____ . 14.SodoO Stock loan payments ..... ........ !._'"".'._1.!..~"..Z — I"l~™.!l_IZI".7."IZr.'.!!" :s!:.'10.00 Real estate sales on contract „ _ _ _ _ _ (3.96 Interest ""** 12.007.27 Delinquent Interest— ..."_ 397 .86 Incomplete loans „ _ 1.175.26 Total- tmjm ii IIISBIRSEMENTS Mortgage loans $ 3ti.732.GD Stock loans __ _. ___ 1 1 Ml M Witbiirawala running stock and dividends _ 7O.3M2.S7 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ 14.7.13.30 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock - ~ -,43K.3b^ Salaries _ _ _ 1.4JM8 &lt;'oniinifw*lons - 33.M lt«':il sststc account _ ■■f» &lt;C Other expense — - - - 1.MK3!! »'ssh on hand 1.1.SI1.M Other disbursements in detail _ 1IMI Furniture and fixtures •43.74 Attorney fees ..._ _ - 1.1O00 I'plilMIUfMlt ill tPlTP 8t - - ........ — —...„ 1 ..17ft. 16 traja ■ Total. SUPPLEMENTAL KKPOKT Plan of association (serial or permanent) _ - Permanent Number of shares outstanding fast report - 4.1^1 Shares Issued since last report - - 1.SW- Total _ _ 6^13 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 513 Number of shares in force this date - 5.70*. Number of borrowing- stockholders - : Numl&gt;er of non-borrowing stockholders — ■*^' iK Number of loans made for building purposes during year JO Number of loans made for purchasing homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year — ,~»S Par value of each share of stock _ — * 10H.OO Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid "J.irl4JJ4 Number mid amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 1 ! ••»""' W*A* Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 1 1.3U0H Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 147.721. 16 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been ,™-™,— been made — — — 41J.st.lH Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 21h.2"-.«.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned fo the association as collateral security - - ' ,-;!!!!M5 Amount of money loaned on improved farms — i'VUMI 1 \nionnt of money loaned on imprnveii tarms - -— — — '■'TS-Z; Appraised value of land not including Improvements 5«RS Value of Improvements _ jJSf'SJ m» Amount credited to reserve fund during year ■f2?'!2 i... ..,,., i nf .llviilenilu declared on running stock during year " 4X1 nt Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 2.8ot.3tt Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year n Rate per ifnt of interest charged borrowers during year &lt;Bc per 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">124 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION- OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President J. C. Michelsen Vice President Wm E. Davis Secretary H. Earl Cox Treasurer Perry Wheeler Attorney A. C. Pancoast DIRECTORS J. C. Michelsen Wm. E. Davis Perry Wheeler A. C. Pancoast F. A. Cressey Richard DeYoung A. F. Stryker Claud R. Orchard W. S. Shafer C. L. Talbot ASSETS First mortgage loaua $ S4.0O1.CK) Lou iii&gt; uu slock or pas* book security - 1.61S.44 CmMh _ _.!. * _____ 3,44!».:tO Furniture "and fixtures -_ 34O.V4 Other asset. - _____ -...-. - '■'■'■■ - 2.UUO.00 jotai _ _ $ 91,410.28 LIABILITIES Kuiiuiuit Btcx-k and dividends - I fl-,—M.'.&gt;- I'aiii up stock and dividends _______ 22,080.00 I&gt;ue xhareliolders ou Incomplete loans WR5.00 lte«erve fund — — - — HSS Indivlded H— Ml 2,356.58 Total » 91.410.28 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 125 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT l'lan of association (serial of permanent) Permanent Number of BMicfl issued since organization (if serial) On* Number of shares issue;! since organization UDI Knottier of shares outwtnnilinc lnst report 22Mt\i Shares issued sinee last report l.."«J7 Total Share* withdrawn, matured of cancelled since last report il|IOn-B « II ll'II .1 •« II. IIIpIUI'"!, «» .«»hv«;..«.u — — • -»B • - t _ Xunilier of shares in force this date - -''.&gt;; Nuuilwr of slmres on which dues are delinquent ■ Number of borrowing stockholders Number of loans made for building purpose* during the jear 11 Nnmber "f liums nuide for purchasiuit homesteads or payment of homestead-morteaKes during year - mnn!! Par value of each share ot stock - * Jem^e 1*.."B fatal amount of due* lelli Muent at this date Amount of loans on Improved real estate - fAtiaXM Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been uiade Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as mwo.ui collateral security = ••;•:•. 120.W0.Ui \motiirt of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ,Si'i- .ls col lateral set urn j lii A~ Amount credited to reserve fund during year — »to Ji Amount "f dividends declared on running stock during year Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year fi and 0.3% Rate per mart of dividends declared on runnine stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during 6 and 5.2«%- year Bate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 8 snd fH NiiinliHr of iH&gt;tt-l&gt;orr&lt;&gt;wili&lt;5 st«"'k linliltrs JUNK 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report IMit-s I Ruiiunii." slock) l'ald-up stmk Moi-i^it^re payments Stock lean paynieuts - _ Interest Total - S &amp;J8H.V $ 7X««&gt;.« IMSBritSKMKXTS Mortgage loans Stork li ilHH Withdrawal! running stark anil dividend* Withdrawals palil -up stock \Vitliilrawals dividend on paid-up mock Salaries Other expense - — Cash on band ~ Furniture and fixtures Interest credited - Total - :::: nil 'IV </seg>
            <seg id="p128">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 126 STATEMENT of the condition of the PROTECTIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ORD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President M. B. Goodenow Vice President - - Geo. R. Gard Secretary Jos. P. Barta Treasurer Job. P. Barta Attorney Claude A. Davis DIRECTORS B. Firkins B. Gard C. A. Hager C. A. Davis M. B. Goodenow Jos. P. Barta utm Fint mortgage loans. _._ _ - f 51,700.00 Cash __ 5,501.80 Taxes Paid - . _____ 1.92 Llberty bonds _ ".". 500.0ft Total * 57,783.81 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 2B.44&amp;20 Paid-up stock and dividends 26,fl-S.o6 Dae tbareholders on Incomplete loanii 5,550.00 Reserve fund 117.07 Undivided profits . .......... _ 26.54 Total _ * 57,703.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 127 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report _ _ $ 3,0(0.24 iHn-s i Ituiining stuck I . ZLHV.W Paid -up stock 38.12S.00 Mortgage payments _ 1,000.00 Stuck loan payments 125.00 Interest .'. _ Mtt-Tl M«'iiilMT*lii]t and transfer fees _ - _____ MB*_I Loan fees - _»1 .'■" Total * mjttM I.ISBUIi ISEMKNTS Mortgage loans ...._ $ 38,984.00 Stock loans _ 126.00 Withdrawals running stock mid dividends _ 1.4541.6- Withdrawals of pald-np stork 16.MO.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock _ 1.117.06 Salaries :vhi 110 I'nnitiiissiuMs . _ .—.—..... 12H.78 Other expense flBRflB j...ri t..mr — _ ___,"~ k Cash on hand _-, Liberty bonds - — 6.5*1 tl 600.00 Total _ - $ 85.8B2.in SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) - Permanent Numlwr of shares Issued since organization - 14— Mi Number of shares outstanding last report - — LOW* XumlxT of shares issued since organization Shares Issued since last report ._ 5,8-814 Total _ - TOBOVj Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — — Number of shares in force this date 6.r&gt;7Sl« 477 Number &lt;&gt;f shares In force this date Number ..f shares on which dues are delinquent Mf| Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowins stockholders. HJ Number of loans made for building purposes during year 8 Number of loans made for purchasing homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 2J Par value of each share of stock _ - - $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at ths date — ■' J _i"!_l Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ - -"■' -'" Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid -J5JS Amount of loans on improved real estate 51.700.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been maile 1O1.ii0O.00 Amount of fire insurance iu force and' assigned to the association as _.-_--. collateral security _ — _ 4.&gt; X.. 'in Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security — i7V_S Amount credited to reserve fund during year }11_2 .WIltHllll CITrtlll— 'I »W IC^lIC IUUU UU&gt;*U|« J^« « "" -" Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year ll l_M? Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid up stock during ye«r. 1.0O4J1 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dnrlng ».»* Rate per cent oif interest charged borrowers during year *% </seg>
            <seg id="p130">128 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PAWXEK CITY SAVINGS AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PAWNEE CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President J. H. Shepherd Secretary A. S. Story Treasurer G. E. Becker DIRECTORS A. S. Story J. H. Shepherd G. E. Becker J. C. Waddell J. F. Wilson J. K. Waddell G. A. Sawyer M. L. Van Home H. L. Flory Kir»t mortgage Irani* Loam on itwk or pa*a book security other real estate Delinquent Interest, fines, etc Total LIABILITIES Running atock and dividend* $ Ui.437.S&gt; Htagi ig fund STTi 0(&gt; I ndivlded profit* 18O.7K Advance interest 2.4O Total » 17,4O&gt;.N» </seg>
            <seg id="p131">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 129 SI TTLEMEXTAL RKTOHT I'lan of assoclatli.n iserlnl H permanent ( — Permanent 1 ISt II OI IIKSIH Idlll'U II»«"llill i"r |iriiimiiriiij "To NuinlKT of shares issued sim*e «iriranizatit&gt;n - ~Y-i ' .Nuiul.er of shares outstanding last report _ - l"j MhnnM is«n«*tl sim-e lust relmrt - *••• Shares issued silne last rept.rt m Total M Shares withdrawn matured ur can&lt;fll«-d NuiiiImt uf shiires ill force this date Average running time of stock inntilred Numlier of borrowing stockh' Iders Niinil.er of null -liorruw iujr stockholders Xtimlier of loans made for piircli:isin« lince last report m luriUK the year lit 1/6 moiithe .■4 .T, homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during- year Par value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at this d:lte 13«i \inouiit of dues owIiik l..v borrowing stockliolders . . Amount of interest, premium and fines due and unpaid r.'.oo Amount or interest, premium "'." ■""•» &gt;■•"- ■&gt;"" "••■■■■ lBlMOno Miiount of loans on improved real estate - - - 1»j»mw \ppr.iised value of improved real estate upon which loans have heen A mount "of "fir* "innriiiMa IB lM»» tmt aaalajsjasi to the a»«oci«tion as AinoiV u'"!7''l!.r' &gt; mido i iusur»iM-e in for.*' and'aMigi^d to the asioctatloii 24.fl»t.fr. as collateral security Amount cre&lt;llte&lt;l to reserve fund during year .. ,. . — Vmonnt of dividends paid ■&gt;■ matured and paid-up sto.k during nu Amount of dividends not paid «,n matured and paid-up stock rturiiii.' ■ r.T year i.an.v&gt; \moiint of dividends de&lt; lared on running stock during year . Hate |.er «-ent of dividends declared on running stock dur ng jear 1 ate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock durintf M Itate*p*er i-ent of iiit'erest cliarged borrowers during year . d m aUKMMM inw.rjii 10 j\s*u r.ArL.suiiunriO run 11 JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash mi band last report _ I&gt;ue« i kunuing st.uk I _ Mortya jje (i ay incuts _ Interest Fines _ KeutM Memliership anil transfer teta Total _ l»i 4S.77 1M 43.00 IHSIiriiSKMKXTS Mortgage loan* - - Withdrawals runuinic xtock anil dividends Withdrawals, paid-up stock, matured stock Withdrawals dividend mi paid up stuck, matured stock Interest paid oil matured stock » 'ulinnissinlis _ — Real cstitte account Cash on hand - — Bank examiner's fees - Publishing ;u. mi. il statement Total - ai'.&lt;» l.MW t 1111 23 i oiai - </seg>
            <seg id="p132">130 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PLATTSMOITII LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ E. P. Lutz Vice President R. A. Rates Secretary _ _...'..".T. M. Patterson Treasurer Fred Ramge Attorney _ ZZ...J. M. Leyda DIRECTORS K. Goos . Lutz Ramge T. J. Yanda R. A. Bates J. M. Leyda C. A. Johnson T. M. Patterson ASSETS Flr«t mortgage loana _. $236,060.67 - .. .« _"»v muuuo fiOO,U1V.DI Loans on utovk or pts« book aerurlty 6.192.11 Other real eatate ~ ...I.!.!*. 6J40o!oo Keal estate sold ou contract „ 2,278.00 • 'ash _ _ _______ 2,_*X80 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc _________ "Z62M ToUl J263.734.S1 LIABILITIES Running stork and dividends $200,106.88 P«ld • np stock and dividend*. ~ "" .."' 48,000.00 Reserve fond _ 3,'aOO.OO Iirwi • -; _uuu - -.-.... . . „. . __ „ t&gt;,\KtU UU Undivided profits - _ 1,O24.S3 Total $JM.734.51 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 131 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KEl'EIPTS Cash on hand last report ... _ - _ 9 10,fl88.7l Him (Running stock) 41.2TL0O Paid-up stock _„______________________ l«.00O0&lt;» Mortgage puyuients - _ 3R,165.0O Stock loan |in.vmeiitH ._ „ _ 706.00 Interest . . - ___"__ 1&amp;2S14S Kent* . _ 419.2ft MemlN^mliip and transfer t9*9 - - 25. QD tvlnu ffrrHJl III aIMI IiH IlSIPr I Ww -- -.- ■ ■■ , M ..■...--•-----«,•+_•»,•„«*• J ■ '■' &lt;Hb*r receipts iu detail - K86 Total »1»J*TJ« I&gt;ISBt ItSEMEXTS Mortgage loans _ - f «,9B0.0O Stork loniM 11- 1.8BO.0O Withdrawals ranninfc stork and dividends _ J7.961.SS Withdrawals paid up stock - ?1.400lOO Withdrawals dividend on paid-op stock - SJ41.11 Salaries ._ - - l,_#).00 other expense - - — — ltl.48 Real estat'e account — "'•ft Cash on hand _______ - I.MMI Other disbursements i in detail _ - 100.00 Total - »1».M7.» SrPPUEMEXTAl, REPORT Plan of association (aerial or permanent) Serial Number of series issued since organisation (If serial) - • Nnmln&gt;r of shares Issued since organization lUflSi^ Number of shares outstanding last report _ 3,H5 Shares issued since last report &lt;~* Total •■ . ™ !*v* Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report J2J Number of shares in force this date - I Number of shares on which does are delinquent — Number of share* subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues a&gt; Average running time of stock matured during the year - 132 month" Number of borrowing stockholders - - tiUlllin-l Ul uuMirwiui iitniuvmrii -— Number of non-borrowing stockholders - aaa Numl&gt;er of loans made for building" purposes during the year _~ • Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of s homesteads mortgage during year — — «~v,J! Par Talue of each share of stock - - • jSyJJJ Total amonnt of duea delinquent at thUi date Jl'IS Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders Amount of Interest, premiums ami fines doe and unpaid _— ;■ S_ Number and amount of mortgage!) subject to foreclosure No. 2 •O'225'JJt mj« 4LO.O Amount of loans on lmprored real estate -■ ■■■ Appralwd value of Improved real estate opon whicfc loans have been Appraifwn value oi iaipro»rti n-«i rwv«ir- u|iuu «u&gt;i" iv— h» «-.* MR-00O00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to toe association aa scprore) collateral security ; -~,N»».«i Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - - ySKKm as couaierai seruru.v -- - — omm Amount of money leaned on Imnroved farms - — 7'wwwi Amount oi money icbiumi *iii iiiuiritTt-u unui - — 7»ortAn Apnratsed value of land not Including improvements 4-~j&gt; Value of improvements - - value or improvement* - Amount of fire Insurance thereon - Sjnwr Amount or nre msurnm-e in«-rf«ni - w-mc*- Amount credited to reserve fond during year — rm_ Amount cremten to reserve nimi uurui* »~r — rAln Ainonnr of loses charged to reserve fnnd during year TiiriS .\mi'lllir or H'«f1« Clinricru hi rr-^-i »v iuuw uuiiu» .'^« . 1OTU Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year HE!, Amount or (UVHieiMl* mrinrni on ruiiiiuin m»n » ■»» .^- — iiiii Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock year ?«J- Kste per cent of dividends declared on running stock daring year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during Hate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring yemr •* </seg>
            <seg id="p134">132 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President D. B. Smith Vice President F. G. Egenberger Secretary C. G. Fricke Treasurer Dr. C. A. Marshall Attorney ......A. L. Tidd DIRECTORS E Smith Hassler Marshall F. G. Egenberger Harry Barthold F. E. Schlater H. M. Soenniscl H. M. Soennischsen Wm. Holly C. G. Fricke AHET8 Kirxt mortgage loans *203,&lt;»4.74 Loans on utork or pass book •ecurlty - 14.0W.U0 Heal entatr mild on coiitrart 3.U95.13 (.■■■h _ 12,330.70 Total $33,43a57 LIABILIT1ES Kunninf «tock and dlTldmdg $16«JW.T3 Paid-up atook »ud dividends «•,! 18.00 K^^erT* fund - - - 10.W4.M I'ndivided profits 9.400.2S Xotsl $233,430.57 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 133 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 ltKCKIl'TS Cash on hand lust report , Orerdrswn Imi.-s iKunning Mm-kl $ SWMOlTO 1'aid-up stock 27.3B3«.0d Mortjraire payments 42.4B2-00 Stock l.ian payments 4 T"«i.i»l Heal estate contract* _ 1.024.67 Interest - Iff 1H W Kines ________________________ _ , I." J«i Membership ami transfer fees _3.35 Total $1273M.» DISB1 RSKXCENTS Mortgage loans $ BMlMt Htock loans !._____._ _ USJi Withdrawal! runniut: stock nnd dividends KMM Withdrawal! dirldead on paid-np stock .... - ■«&gt;] II Withdrawal! paid-up stork !___! Withdrawals dividend ou paid-up stock I'.IHUTJ Salaries - - I.MM (►tlier expense 1.0IM.30 Iteal estate account - 1 HI M Cash nverdrawn -V.V.HS Other disbursements in rietnli 12^30.70 Insurance and taxes paid and advertising 2.X&gt;7 TK Rent and repair — MM! Total $127,(«H.iT SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) _ s * rl 5i Nuuilier of series issued since aigl-l-allaa i if serial) — ■ NumlMT of shares laaued since organization . ._ . ■• Number of shares outstanding last report - SM* Shares issued since Inst report *«4 Total a-* 30 Shares withdrawn, niaturwl or cancelied since last npaM . 4 ' Nam her of shares' in fore* this date - 3,(»«( Arena* runuinic time of stixk matured durioe the year _ 131 mouth-i Number of borrowing stockholders - 131 month-. .^UIMIMT III imiikimiub mii-mwniTin -~ - Number of non-borrowinjc stock holders - *^ Nunii.er of loans made for Imlldlns purposes daring year __ Par viilue of each 'sharp of stock -- '«_5J-5J I ill lillllT" \'t t.n u -ii.iii- vi n*w» mtim fji I l ATiioimi &lt;&gt;f loans M Improved real estate - JB,«H.i4 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been mini*- - . '.—. ess *M 'ul™ Amount of fire insurance la force and assigned to the association as „__„_ collateral security Jw-t« »'.(■&gt; Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association us collateral security - — ,2'25'nn Appraised value of land' not Including improvements _ JJSiJSnn Appraised *aiue m uinu m juviuunm ihik 1 "' 1 ••««»- iMti«iiMi Value of improvenielits SinSK'm! 2io.«nr&gt;no Amount of fire Insurance thereon Anionnr or nre nisurnii&lt;-»- nirreuu «m&gt;m Amount of tornado Insurance thereon •• ■ I'SmSi 4.9R3OO Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year t'sSiS Amount of dividends naid on matured and paid up stock during year . '*,/." Ttnte per cent of dividends (leclarpii on ninnlnc stock dnrlne rear 4 and tft&gt; Hate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year — r ■?■ — -.- 'L™ 4 an,! tr. Rate "per cent of interest charced borrowers during year - - •* </seg>
            <seg id="p136">134 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION SEWARD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President _ John Zimmerer Vice President J. F. Geesen Secretary H. A Graff Treasurer W. E. Lang-worthy Attorney J. J. Thomag DIRECTORS K Miller Ort J. M. Calder H. D. Landis Roy R. Schick S. D. Atkins i. V. Willis RECEIPTS First mortgage loam _ _ % 145.210.00 Loans on stock or pass book security 10.060.00 Delinquent Interest, fines, etc _ 993.23 Furniture and fixture* _... 235.00 Office supplies - _ 161.40 Tax sale certificates -. _ __ 297.K6 I MIC V«TI L|[m|d ......................................... .... ....._....._ ..... ............. ........ I • &lt;O j nsu ranee unpaid - ....... 9.79 Tots] — .. _ - 1156.9M.94 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend* $14.5,633.12 Reserve fond _ _ _ 5.286.77 T'ndtvided profits _ „.. 1.90 Advance does _ - 848.75 Advinw interest •• „_ 107.27 Tressurer overdrawn _ 5,087.13 107.27 Treasurer overdrswri Total - - *166,9«g»4 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 135 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 KECEI1TS Cash on bind last report _ _. f 1.340.M Duct (Running stock) \Z\ZZZZZ7..Z..ZZZZ.Z'~ZZ'.Z~'ZZZZ7--JZZ— M£C_7S Mortgage payments _ ii,tf77.%4 Stork loan payments _ _ 1,158.91 Mortgage payments Interest _ _ _ Fines __ 11591.81 I«MP Membership and transfer fees _ _ _ 3W.0S Tax sale certificates - - - 88-.41 Treasurer overdrawn - „ _ _„_ 5,087 13 Insurance paid _ _ _ use Total « MM I DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ $ 3ft.9OO.OU Stock loans - _ 4._GC_aQ &gt; Withdrawals running stock and dividends 58.113.21 Salaries „ ....... ..... i«V&gt; 01) Other expenM - _ _ _ _ 117T1 Supplies - _ _ _ 104__l Tax certificates - _ _ _ 231.14 Total - - - _ I W.OMSl SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) _ Serial and Permanent Number of series Issued since organisation (If serial) SI Number of shares Issued since orfianization _ _ 1 m««,\ Number of shares outstanding last report _.._ 2.3S1 •J.3.-11 .luiuuvr vi buiici uuisiauui-g lusi report _,--i Shares issued since last report - - 1J0-H Total _ _ ■ '-Ji^-t Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled iiince laat report -Us- Number of shares in force this date _ 2 77".;-, Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 8BU Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues .... V Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since laat report Number of shares in force this date Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of does Average running time of stock matured during the year - 74 month* Number of borrowing stockholders - - — 183 Number of non- borrowing stockholders — 244 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 8 Number of loans made for purchasing homesteads or payment of •* homestead-mortgages during J**r _ - 34 Par value of each share of stock. Serial • _••.•• * mm Par value of each share o&lt; stock. Permanent ltfcOO Total amount of dues delinquent at this date — 607.26 Amount of due§ owing by borrowing stockholders 407.26 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid — 306.98 Amount oi imprest, premiums auu itues uue iuu uupaiu — &lt;md,pb Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosuure No. 2 #75.00 MimDer ana amount or mortgages suDjeci to iorecio»uure &gt;" * oio.w Amount of loans on improved real estate _ _ - 137.18&amp;.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans bare been made — — 22K,fl08.OO Amount of loans on unimproved real estate - 8.0BMO Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loan* have nsmm been made - - - Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association aa collateral security - 1«e,dto.wi Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 74.«SO.OO Amount ciwdited to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year IJM II M Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year — _ M Rate per cent 6f Interest chanted borrowers during jsar ________ . ■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p138">136 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SIDNEY LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION SIDNEY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President H. T. Doran Vice President A. Granneman Secretary Robert A. Barlow Treasurer L. Neubauer Attorney H. T. Doran DIRECTORS Lena Jessen M. Lancaster J. R. Williams L. Neubauer Loren Jessen H. T. Doran C. P. Chambers A. Granneman Robt. A. Barlow E ASSETS mortgage loans $ 3J.4SW.00 •„• mmm ; ;;;; .... .v.»u.23 ueut intereift, fines, rtc - - 7J7.2O ure and fixtures ~ l*K).5fi Other assets _ __________ '.'.'. l.C-.OO Total _ f 37,39-.96 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends - - - I 33,304.08 I»ne shareholders on incomplete loans i.000.00 Hes^rve fund - - 974.47 Indivlded praflU '. '. ■'■- 1 ' 0a ?-55 Other liabilities ~ Ho.63 Total _ $ 37.392.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 137 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECE1ITS Cash on hand last report - ♦ TUL86 Dues I KimniUK stock) _______ 5,tWl .74 Mortgage payment* _ — — - — 891.60 Interest __. - _ „ _... 2.17&amp;M Ifembergbip tod transfer f*ea M.OO Total _ f 8*M.1» DISBIRSKMKNTS Mortgage loan 8 $ S.tSiO.OO Withdrawal! running iiork and dividends '■!..V&lt;7. I J'J Salaries • _ _ 100.00 Other expense .. _ 1U.OU Cash on hand ______________ — 3.914.3 Total * 8.SW.1J NTPPUM— KTAL REPOHT Plan of association (serial or permanent Permanent .Number of shares outstanding last report ". - 4M Shares Issued since last report «" Shares withdrawn, mature*! or cancelled since last report Nuinlwr of shores in force this tlate 4J8 Avernice runninc time of ■tarfe inatnre&lt;i liurtntf the year 127 months Nuini&gt;er of borrow lag at wit holder. XuinUer of non-liorr»»wltijr t*to&lt;-khnlder^ 2B Hnb*t cif Iomiis maile for liulliliiiK purposes ilurlnr year . Manner of laaaa iniule for parchasi-i of lioineste«il» or payment "f hoinesteiiil inortirnjres during year l I'ar value of each share of stock 9 j^f^ Amonnt of Interest, preniluni. nnd flues due and unpaid - Numt&gt;er ami amount of niorttrajces subject to foreclosure No. 4 Amount nf loans on improved renl cwtnte ■ M Appraise:! value of unhnproveil real estate upon which loans have been made »V4 i ■ « i fa » Amount of fire Inaurauce in force and assigned to the aaaociatiou aa collaterul aecurity - «s.UU&gt;.0i&gt; Amount of tornado insurance in force and nmdi-'iied to the asaoclatu&gt;ii ,»»„«,„ OUIH HI lur I*' lllMlinmr in ivi«.t- nun __w—_i _■ • ■" — — w—^— . as ...llHternl security . r ,^./ Amount credited to reserve fund durlnic year I** 1 Amount of dividend* declared on running stock during; year • 2.SBM2 Rnte per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year — ■ 9 nate per i-ent of interest charged borrowers during year I « r - </seg>
            <seg id="p140">TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 138 STATEMENT of the condition of the CITIZENS BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION SUPERIOR, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President W. S. Young Secretary J. T. Robbins Treasurer J. T. Robbins J. T. Robbins DIRECTORS W. S. Young John Eyre. Henry Devoe J. T. Robbins W. J. Elliott W. A. Myers J. M. Silver F. S. Southard ASSETS First mortgage loam • 51 agn qq Loam on stock or past book security .ZZZZZZ.'".. l'lOttOO 1,100.00 Other real estate ~ 5Je«S Real estate sold on contract 23n000 2,300.00 Casb — _ „ 2_{K9i'%) Furniture anH f&lt;Tinr UL *" rV.c! Furniture and fixtures LZIZZIZZIZZIIIZ BaOO *•*■&gt; - f 68,573.71 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends i aiMWm) Paid-up stock and dividends ZZZZIZ7Z.ZZ.ZZZ 27400.00 27,400.00 «««";J»«"i ■■.- fcooaoo E*f 1 l!i* d . pr^ flu -————-___—_______ i.o»:« T»U1 _.... _ | 63,573.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 139 YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE 30, 1917 KECEII'TS Cash on band laat report _- $ U1LIU Dues, lltuunlng stock) _ _ _ M34.1* &amp;334.19 LSUt-B, (IVUIIIIIIIK BlUCII «&gt;*»»*■.*» Paid up stock _ 7,60*00 800.00 Stock loan payment! _ - 500.00 Mortgage payment! - - 10&gt;^£!M£ Mongaire payments - _ - "r'Yi'iX Interest _ 4, ISM. 86 ,191. Ml 247 JR Renti Ken i s . _ .11 j' Dividends from First National Bank ... ._ _ - *Xt &gt; Total DISBVRKK IMKNTK » "-a??? 0 . Mortgage loans Withdrawal* running Mock and dlTiileuda Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock ....... Salaries Other expense i»X IUW&amp;32 2.9B5.3* 20R1S l.ow.ae Real estate account Cash on hand 308.16 To reserve I'udivided profit* Total $ mmm SUPPLEMENTAL, RKPOKT Plan of association I serial or permanent) - Permasieijt Number of shares issued since organization — — 1,677 N'uiuber of shares outstanding last report 1.12B Vumber of shares outstanding last report Shares issued since last report 387 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sine* last report 302 Number of shares In force tills date — — I, 111 Average running time of stock matured during the year 78 montbs Number of borrowing stockholders « Number of non-borrowing stockholders : » Number of loans made for building purposes during year S Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year - — Par value of each share of stock — ' - 9 JJJ'UJ .,;;;;:;; Amount of loans on improved real estate - - .'onmo Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 9SJ2 Amount of loans on unimproved real mtate HUM Appraised valoe of unimproved real estate upon which loans ha« Amount" of°flre insurance in force and assigned to the association aa collateral security - ■ •■■•••; 53.000.0ii 2.500.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in fore* and aaaigned to tta# association 50.1101)00 as collateral security "^IJEVi Amount credited to reserve fond during year -■■ 2E"JS Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year J-SS-S Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year l.7«J&gt; Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year .... 6 and 8% Rate per cent of dividend! paid on matured and full paid atock l.tm.Tl 1.743.30 6 and 8% &lt; and *•«. during year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during ye«r </seg>
            <seg id="p142">140 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the TECTMSEII BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION TECUMSEH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President P. A. Brundage Vice President E. C. Hedrick Secretary J. B. Douglas Treasurer Harry Phelps Attorney - J. C. Moore DIRECTORS P. A. Brundage E. C. Hedrick C. M. Shaw J. B. Douglas Adolph Kovarik W. M. Sherman G. W. Hassett R. F. Reynolds Harold F. Sullivan ASSET* First niortiraite loans $12-1.4.10.00 Lou [i.- on stink or pass liook security 3,796.00 Kreal estate 3.0T&gt;r«.{&gt;!ii Cash _ 1,173.73 1,173.73 qtieut interest, fines, etc. - 3n7.62 Furniture anil fixtures 338.90 Total $133,150.88 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividend* — $101,228.08 Paid -up stock and dividends 25.(«X_M«) Honerve fund _ . 2 917 62 Undivided profiu 3,914.17 Advance due* 91.00 Total »m,150.S8 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 141 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 sri'l'LKMEXTAL REPORT i'lan nf Association (serial or permanent ) Serial .Niiinltir of series issued winee &lt; ruanization (if serial) 47 Number of ttbares issued idiu-e or^anlxatiou _ &gt;.&lt;*) Naiulief nf ikam ovtstaodlac last report i,t*K Shares iusueil Kinct* last report Mi: Total ______________ 3.TW Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sinc-e lnnt r* -p»n Nuinlier of shares in force this date 3.047 NuiiiIm'T iif shares &lt;&gt;n which dae* are deliinjuer-r Vfi Average runt'injc time of stork matured during the j-rar 78 months Xmnlier of iMirmwiiiir t&lt;t«Mklndders 152 Nu in I &gt;*t of n«»u- borrow ins *to«-k holders 194 Number of loans made for huildin*; purpose** during y*-ar 4 NuinlrtT of loans maile Tor purchasing of homesteads or payment of lioineslead-MK'rt^aues during &gt;ear M Par value of eaclt sliare of stwk $ 100.00 Total amount of doc* delinquent at this dnte _ 19K.M Ainntiiit of dues owing by borrowing «t"&lt;"k holders 18MM Atnount of inttTe^t. premiums and fines due and unpaid 1W!W Numlter and aini&gt;iiut of mortal?**" subject to foreilosure Xo.2 1^00X90 Amount of loans on improved real estate •- 124.43O.W Appraiseil value of improved real estate upon which loans liav ■ lw»e:i made 19O.WO.0O Amount of fire Insurance in force and ansl^ned to the av«o&lt;&gt;latiou as collateral securitj 130.4T5.CO Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the assox'iatlon :i&lt; ollnti-rnl securitv 1SI.-WO.0O Ainiiiiiit rreilltcd to reserve funil ilnrlnir year 41t.W as .ollateral security 411.W Ainiunit of losses i-linrRPil to reserve funil ilurlnfr year -V' &lt;f&gt; Amount of dividends declared on running stork during year MM AiDount of dlvidendfi paid on matured and paid up Hto«-k during year • i&gt;m Rate |&gt;er &lt;-ent of dfviilenda declared on running nto&lt;-k during year S1% Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year I PS. Rate i»er cent of interest charged horrowera during y«ir I 4% KE.IE.11 1» 1'ash on haud last report I Mies i 1: ii mi in l' stock) l';i ni up stock _ _ Stock lujlll pavmelits Iteal estate sal&lt;-&gt; Interest _ __ Kinew Kent* _ Memlx-rsliip and transfer fees l'olle&lt;*ted on deficiency Judgment _ Totml 1.-&gt;,:kjo.c»&gt; 3ll.7«0.t»&gt; iUOO.ui ltl,474.« IMSUIUSKMEXTS Mortipa^e and sto&lt;-k loans _ Withdrawal* raaalac stuck and diviilendii __._ Withdrawal! paid up stock _ Wlllidrawuls dividend ou paid-up Mock Salaries » 'niHiiil— liiaa „ _ other expense lie: 1 1 estate account _ Cash on Land _ Furniture anil fixtures Loss ou settlement of loans in foreclosure Total $ltrj.l»&lt;:.M </seg>
            <seg id="p144">142 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the TRENTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION TRENTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President O. E. Reynolds Vice President - -". C. L. Allen Secretary - J. P. Allen Treasurer - A. E. Reynolds DIRECTORS O. W. DeWald A. T. McCoy J. C. Hurst R. H. Pember ASSETS rir»t mortgage loan* * 10.7SO.00 C..I, _._.... _ _ _ _ 7.843.78 Total i 1* ,093.78 LIABILITIES Bunnina- atock and dividends t 1&amp;1T8.00 Cndlrtded proflta - - S.+16.78 $ 16.178 01) Total _ f 1K.58S.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p145">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 143 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report _ _ $ IJTKM *~mou vu uiuu inn iruwi _ „_„ 9 »ulto.3» Dues (Running stock) .h*.'* 1 Interest - _ .. 1,077.36 Total .. _ $ S^Dt.10 DISBIRSKMENT8 Withdrawal* running atork and dividends % M«i Salaries 1MM» Other expense _ _ 94.00 Cash on hand _ 7.M.! &gt; Total f o.^ir.' l-i SUPPLEMENTAL IlEPOKT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Serial Number of seriea issued since organization lif serial) 12 Xunilier of shares outstanding last report _ S3OH Total _ - I'fc) 1 -* Khares withdrawn, matured or cancelled nince laat report Number of shares in force June 30. 1917 _ _ — XS&gt;±, Number of borrowing stockholders. 20 Number at non-borrowinf stockholders _ _ _ 3o Par value of each share of atock f 100 (X) Amount of loans on improved real estate -.. H.960.00 Khares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since laat report Number of shares Id force June 30, 1917 Number of borrowing stockholders. Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real eatate upon which loans hare bee* made 17,000.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real eatate - NtO'Ai Appraised value of unimproved real eatate npou which loaua have been made l^WMfr Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - • ■ 18.000.W* Amount of tornado Insurance in force and aasigned to the association aa collateral security - i.,i«»i'i' Kate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year lii^o </seg>
            <seg id="p146">144 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FIRST BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION UNIVERSITY PLACE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President A. L. Johnson Vice President E. D. Currier Secretary B. H. Schaberg Treasurer M. B. Myers Attorney W. R. Gaylord DIRECTORS B. H. Schaberg W. G. Bishop Chas. F. Horner A. L. Johnson M B. Myers S. H. Chism E. D. Currier W. R. Gaylord C. H. Roper ASSETS First mortgage loan* * 86.730.00 Loans In process of foreclosure 9110.00 Other real estate 2.WM.96 '."no Total _ - $ 86.TO0.S0 LIABILITIES Running Mock and dividends » 22.WC08 Paid-up stock and dividend! , — &lt;B.aGO.OO l"-"«-r*t- *«" u :;■;■■ — uo m» X*n«llvtd&lt;Kl profits ■■■ r4i.0fl Prepaid •took ... _«—__-. — &lt;W.21 Tott l t _ _ „ $ M.780.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p147">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 145 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS rash on hmiil last report _ _ f 7.18BJ4 Dues &lt; Ku 11 11 i 11 e stuck) _ . J- .'«n -V '■'"* .UUmilUg MIOCKI „ m _ -TV"M_^ I 'a id -up stock _ „ _... 4O. lOUOU Mortgage payments „ _ 17.000.00 I n terext ___ ________________^_____^__ 4.4«k74 M**wl«* rnlii|» mihI transfer fee* „ l"w&gt;. 7." Kent estate .... ... 9.CD nrni **j»ijii** . . ... ... .... .... ir \mi Al.sinu-t nii.l filing fees _ _ _ ■£■ Al»sir»&lt;-t mid riling fees _ _ _ 1.-^ TO I*repnid stiM*k .". 3 OR I • rt»[ &gt;ii i 4 1 KtiH'k .*. ■'t Keserve fund „ _ 7&lt;i(»3 ToUl • »6,444.21 ToUl 9 1*4,444.21 DISBIKSKMEXTH Mortgage loans 9 4a.40O.00 Mnri^iiL'c loans $ 4a.40O.00 Withdrawals running stork and dividend* 17. +71 Ifl Withdrawals running stork and dlrideud* 17+71 Ifl Withdrawing paid-up stock - - 11.43O.0U Withdrawals paid-up stock ll.4oO.OU Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock _ _ - 3,4*H.5H Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock _ _ MM W Salaries - - - - 150.00 Sh I ; i ri »•&gt;&gt; _ _ — 130.00 4 i i IM 111 iSH t* 1 118 « — — 1** "* I tea I fstntp account ......— — Sjfl ■* H &lt; H lit*r ex.wnse _ 192.98 f "fish on fcfl nd — 1T,3G6 .3T Interest on prepaid stock ._.— —.. »._ -^ ***^ iiii**r**^i on prepain siock _.. „._ a. no Al.strart nnd flUn* fee* • 1MJSB &lt; 'ol lection and exchange ~ - - Mtfi PicpaM «toik ." - tt'.TS Utwi&gt;rw* fit ml — . ■ i ' ' 'j^- % 3B 1 14 21 TuUl SriTI.KMKNTAL IIKI'OHT I'hin nf MHdMhi iirrUI or permanent) _ - - Perm«B«t NimiiIht of sluices isMiled nilK-e orkraniziltioll '_'.**42*^ XiiiiiImt of sliiires our sta u il 1 ti|f loat report 1.3OH4 Sh«re» issueil since hist report - l.H5&gt;4 Totnl !•*? Shares wltbilrawn, matured or cancelled »inre last reiMirt *34 Nuinlier of shares in force this date - ir r '* Nnmlier of shnres on which dues are delinquent - 23H Niiniher of borrowing Ktwkbolden* - Number of non-norrowlnf ntwkholdera — WT Nnnil&gt;er of loans made for Imtliliiifc purpo«e« ilurlnc year I XuiiilK-r of lonim inaile for |&gt;nrihasiii)r H lioniesreadu or payment of homestead mortiraiies during year ,»-Jt Tar value of each xhare of stock ' $ i2SJ5 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date T8B SO Amnulit of dues owlnic liv Iwirrowlng ato&lt;-khoiders 7flB..10 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Si'"* Number and amount of inortKaires in prncens of foreclosure No. 1 SnO.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 67.360.00 Appraised vnlue of Improved real estate upon which loanii have been _^ made ,. ■ ■ •■ • - '- 4 i:^^ Ainoiint of loans on unimproved real estate 81)0.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare ,«„»«&lt;« been made ■•■ •• --• -■ -_, ' &lt;&gt;"&lt;*' Amount of fire insurance In force and sssirned to th» association as -,«„,»« collateral security - - - -■■ r— s 7x.w«uw .\ in. u in of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to tbe aswH-iation as collateral security -n!« Ml Amount credited to reserve fund durlnit year -^ rf (.;« \inoiint of dividends declared «n runnlne stock durini.' yenr : !*7T M \niount of dividends paid o" matured and lald-up stoik iluring year ■• .km ■ ilnte i&gt;er cent of dividend* declared on rvaln stock dnring rear Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during Rate'ler MMJ of interest "chii'iiited" borrowers durlnj: year, riaaa ;'A" ».•* Kate per ceni or iim-m.i .■...■*&lt;-.. ........_..„ •■•■■■•■• '■;■• i..~~ ..•&gt;•• -—■ Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year, &lt; las* B . - &lt;■ </seg>
            <seg id="p148">146 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION VALENTINE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President H. W. Hoenig Vice President _ M. T. Kincaid Treasurer. _ _ F. A. Cumbow Secretary J. T. Keely Attorney*. Walcott &amp; Walcott DIRECTORS L. L. Bivens Chas. Lewis E. C. Davenport E. B. Foster J. M. Tucker ASSETS Kim mortgage loins _ il29.3S«.53 5.9S1.76 Delinquent !■«■«■&gt;. ■—. ati awiw Inaannce premiums _ ————_____ "\b.8O ToUL... $135^43.73 LIABILITIES g«ijjn« "toek and dividend! »1(»,«7.13 Bcserre fund 2.686.97 UndlTlded proflu . ~ Smm lUtored i^ck _ _ ZZIIZZZ1 __" »SnS JW.W ae^so.oo Total I13S.943.7S </seg>
            <seg id="p149">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 147 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 REPEHT* Cash on hand last report 9 4,986.23 \,mmu uu ukuii lam repon * *,»ml.m Dues ( Running stock ) 17,18150 Loan payments _ _ ~ 9,996.00 Interest _ _ 12^8S.8B i mcrvai ,. . „...,. ......... u,jih.od I'rt*mi u ill insurance — 2JT.7O i r** i ill u 111 lllsurHnit* *n ■ iw Membership and transfer fees 33 5o Tot«i itumm DISBt KSKMKXTS Mortgage loan* I 13.6MS3 Withdrawals ruuuiug stork and dividend* 21.WB.J6 Salaries .._ _ «00.00 Other expense - - 288^18 Cash on hand - _ 6,W1.7€ t^ssB Ml a§nu _.. „ ..... u.wi.iv Interest 2,216.3a Discount advance payments 3&amp;07 Total _ - * 4t^8i22 SUI'PLKMKNTAl. RKPOBT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Serial Number of series Issued since organization (if serial) _ __. M Number &lt;&gt;f shares Issued since organization - *.&lt;*■ Nunit&gt;er of snares outstanding last report .... ' ■■"'■?.' Shares issued since last report 138 yp Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — -1M» Number of shares in force this date — '■ 4 "*J* Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares In force this date Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 53 Average running time of stock matured during the year 123 months Number of borrowing- stockholders J8 Number of non-borrowing stockholders — 112 11 Number of loans made for building purposes during year -n,*!. 1 Par value of each share of stock .,. - — • ***?■•*' **ar value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at thla date _ — — 52"B2 M».0» Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ i2S Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid __ xv&gt; M Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure Xo.» ,Ji'22?2 Amount of loans on improved real estate - - 12»J3»JB Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made ■■■• ••; »l.ls»»» Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as ,__._ collateral security ■• -■ - nw.zw.uu Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association M0.2aa«&gt; as collateral security - Srfr' Amount credited to reserve fund during year — 7X'-n '■«.7U Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year J,!iiV Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year oSSSi Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up atoc* during year . J&gt;r_u Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during vear BViW* Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock - tm. 2.MSS1 77*". Uate V " cent'of Interest ''charged "borrowers during ye»r •-•» </seg>
            <seg id="p150">148 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WA1100 MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION WAHOO, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President B. E. Hendricks Vice President J. L. Winter Secretary H. M. Stratton Treasurer J. J. Johnson Attorney G. H. Simpson G. H. Simpson DIRECTORS Jr.s. O'Donnell R. F. McCreery L. J. Kudrna M. A. Phelps G. H. Simpson F. J. Kirchman ASSKTS First ni(irti::iut- ln;iiis Loan on Murk or puns book mh uiiu I »il i i. &gt;l iicn! hili'n-sl, flneH, *•!*•. Furniture and fixtures Taxes paid uti.ua l'emoual aci-ouutii H'i'mi Total 1147,177.36 LIABILITIES Kuiiiihift mock and dividends I(e«erve fund tu:i&lt;t'li ft.14S.00 Total $147,177* *n ;. ! .Mini -'.tVrfMIU !&gt;!.&lt;■: l&lt;fc!.7i l.'iK.im </seg>
            <seg id="p151">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 149 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report Dues i Idi n ill n ic stock) Mortgage payments Stock loan payments ... Interest Premium Flneii .... Membership and transfer fee* Personal accounts Taxes Total DISBIRSK MKXTS Mortgage loans Stock loan* Withdrawals running sttx k ami dlvMei Salaries Other expense Caah on linml Insurance Interest Taxes . Total I'!an of association iserinl or permanent) Number of series Issued since iinaBlaallai lif seri;;li Number nf shares issueil siiMi 1 organization N'uiiiticr iff shares outstamlinir last report Sliarea issue*! since last report Total Shares wlthrlrawn matured nr camelled wince last report Nmnher of shares In force tbis date Nuinlier of shares on which (lues are ileliiii|iient Xuinlier nf shares subject to cancellation for non- payment Averaire ruuuiniE time of stock matured iluriim the year Niiinli'M- of horrotriag stockholders of .In.- a l.m mouths 11- Manner of noii-liorrowln£ stin-khnlders XuiiiImt c.f leans made for building purpoaev during ye«r n Number "f leans made for purchnsini; of homesteadi or payment of homestead im&gt;rlL'a|tes dnrins year - » riMii of premium l.V per share monthly _ * '«&gt;".&gt; Par value *'f each share cf stock Total nmnmit of dues ileliiHiuent nt this date — — _ 1*1.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders — Amount if iniiTest. pniniums and fines due and unpaid 241.HO Xumliir and amount of mutimi mibject to foreclosure Xo. 2 !m i-i .Xn onnt cf Icrins on Improveil real estate *I4:s.ll"i0.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loana bare been made 224Jm\fW Amount of fire Insurance in force and nxM|rnt*d to the association a» collateral security 170.V7R.OO Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 12B.KS.on Amount nf losses charged to reserve fund during year MO'Hl as collateral security .110 m Itate per cent of dividends declared on runninc stock during year 7.75*5- Kate |&gt;er cent of interest charged borrowers during year *"r Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year 16c per share monthly *r IT I. KM K VI" A I. '•'•:■•&lt; I !!T </seg>
            <seg id="p152">150 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SALINE COUNTY BUILDING ASSOCIATION WILBER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Jos. Cerny Vice President V. J. Kohout Secretary Fred Shunerda Treasurer J. J. Novak Attorney Stanley Bartos DIRECTORS K. Borecky Borecky Sasek Anton Shimonek Wm. Bohacek E. H. Houser Chas. Pospisil H. Binger H. A. Greer ASSETS Flr»t mortgage loans _ : '. $ 77,loO.OO Loans on stock or pass book security !M6.00 Cash — _ 1.173.0ft Delinquent Interest, fines, etc 10.00 Arrear dues _ - 3JS0 Total * 7s.trii.w LIABILITIES Ruuuing atock and &lt;llviden.li. f 76,426.49 ReaerTe fund _ 1.9CO.0O I'ndirided profits Adranred duea — 1-J6.60 :».on Adranced iuter««t - 4.50 Total - - - $ 7H.6IU.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p153">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 151 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash on baud last report - $ 46.43 Dues i Running stork) _ 31,753125 Mortgage payments ' 31.300.00 Stork loan payments _ W10.00 Interest "H.....L." ..."... I.....".. „ „ B^flUuB- Premium „ _ J1J6 Fines __ __ ________________ ______ - Mi Membership and tranfer fee« - — !■"•" ''• Total $7JJ80.« DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans $ -MMlOB jaui i(}acr iinu' _....—__ - m M|W.w Stock 'oaua _ 3.40S.M Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ _ _ 46.»1«.74 Withdrawals running stock and dividend, - - - 4S.M6.74 Salaries _ - 27O.IW1 Salaries 2TO.IW) Other expense _ _ __ 1+4.7O Other expense _ _ _____ 144.7O Cash od hand „ - 1.173.0U ToUl - $ T3.»&gt;O1 Cnsh on band - 1,173.0° SVPPUMEXTAL KKPOHT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Serial Number of series Issued since organization lif serial) 22 Number of shares outstanding last report 1.IWS Shares Issued since last report 311H Total _ _.....„. 1.304 Shares withdrawn, matared or cancelled since laxt report - 371 Number of shares in force this date 1,13ft Shares Issued since last report Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 7 Average running time of stock matured during the year — TO month-* Number of borrowing stockholders ~ — OH T Number of uon borrowing stockholders 116 Number of loans made for building purposes during the year 'r \ Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages daring year — I Par value of each share of stoc-k • 300.00 Total amount of dues de'lnquent at tbfs date - SlBO Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ X Aiuouui in uufs uwiiik '•&gt; uorruwnis »l*H nuuiurri . .ji' Amount of Interest, premiums and fines doe and unpaid _ 10.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate - 73.15O.0n Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been ITMMI made - - - - - _ — — \T%J&lt;toM ount of loans on unimproved real estate _ 4i»m» Amount of loans on nnimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - — - 1.00D.00 Amount of fire insurance In force and assigned to the association al collateral security _ - - - 8_v_36.T&lt;i Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 73.08R.TO Amount of money loaned on Improved farms _ 1,009.00 75.0Sn.7(i Appraised value of land not Including Improvements ... 7^09.00 Value of improvements _ - 1,500.00 Amount (-refitted to reserve fund during year W7«i Amount of dividends declared on running stock dnring year 4.T74.O7 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 6.4^- Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowera dnring year - 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p154">152 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND LOAN' ASSOCIATION WOOD RIVER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President T. A. Evans Vice President S. M. Nelson Secretary W. L. Sprague Treasurer W. C. Wingert DIRECTORS T. A. Evans J. E. Harper C. E. Towne j. E. Hoye S. M. Nelson J. E. Ayer W. S. Warren D. V. McKee J. W. Cunningham ASSETS First mortgage loans f 74,700.00 Laaaa on stock or i&gt;a»n hook security _____ 400.00 I'mli _____ 9B.00 Delinquent interest, fines, etc -.. _____________________ 6."!X( Delinquent dues _ „ 7O.'JO Total _. $ 75,:cjy.io LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends __ $ 97,fi97.fiO Matured stock and dividends ./jilMiu ..■jin.tM Itewrve fuud , ________ IMHftOO Tnillvlded profit* _ ' 00.20 r iif:i rnt**i premium .. ~ „ .flO Inmirned Intermit _ _ _ __ _ 3.30 Advance did _ 2.SS7.41 * 7T».."K».1O </seg>
            <seg id="p155">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 153 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash un liuuil lust report $ l ■ Hue-, iltunnliiB stock) I4JMM1 Mortgage pa v men 1 8 „ ll,j&lt;JU.0U Stock Itiiiii payments .. „ l!&lt;IOU.OO Interest _ _ ."Vnl.VM Premium '* «» 77i Fines 1 /.' 7') Membership and transfer fees ml 50 Total * SJAM DISBI'ItSKMKNTS Mortgage lomis ................ _ 9 UMN Stock ld;i us „ 1' ■&gt;(■► Withdrawals runninK stock and dividends _ _ 7.457.CG Withdrawals matured stock _ ll.3U.in Withdrawals dividend on matured stork 473. W Salaries 41O.00 ( nlier expense „ _ H 4"&gt; f 'i'lsh on linn d ~ — .- !tt.(B) Interest m advance does - - 131 JB Interest on withdrawals - — 314.S9 Total $ 33.^t!.14 srrlM.KMKNTAL REPORT Plan of association {serial or permanent) - Serial and Per Number of serif;* issued since oiganlzatlon lif serial) 17 Number (tf shares issued since organization - 5,536 Numlier of shares outstanding last report - 1,781 Shares issued since last re|Mirt _ _ - Jl&gt; Tot ill „ 1MN0 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — 214 Number of sharcsin force this date I M ■ Xuinlier of shares on which dues are delinquent *• Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of duea.... Average rannlaf time of stock matured during the year — - 114 months Number of borrowing stockholders _ - Number of non-borrowing stockholders • Number of loans made for Imlldine purposes during year • Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead inortHnee during year ♦ Plan of premium - - — Par value of each share of stock - -— 9 4 Par value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ — JMJ Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ .J.'-^' Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid „ 'S Number and uinout of mortgages subject to foreclosure ...- No. 4 -!•_,£!!? Amount of loans on improved real estate r~-- i4.iOO.OI) Appraised value of improved real estate upon which ioana have been ,_,-__, made - - • : ■■•■■,■ UHOmw Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the asaooiation as _,___«_ collateral security ■ ■- — 8j.IKW.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and aaatgned to tbe asmx-latlon —n-n^. as collateral security - - *"',*..',, Amount credited to reserve fund during year - — . t,., i. \mnnnt of dividends declared on running stock during year 4 'Ail iK Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 4 "J!' Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year I • Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during Rate per cent of interest charged tiorrowers during year Hate per c**m OI nut-rest i iinrKni i"'i i v»»i-i n '•*■■•■•» ..*«. - t Rate per cent of premium charged borrowers during year 1 -V» </seg>
            <seg id="p156">154 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WYMORE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WYMORE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President.. J. A. Reulin* Vice President D. A. Lasher Secretary M. J. Moran Treasurer J. w. Smith Attorney E. N. Kauffman E. N. Kauffman DIRECTORS J. A. Reuling C. N. Miller A. T. Sherman W. A. Dawson M. J. Moran D. A. Lasher G. T. Stephenson ASSETS First mortgage loam _ $ 93.42B.00 C»«h _ _ _ _ 5,88B/il D«linqnent interest, fines, etc _ S»OT Furniture and fixtures _' 3MO0B Taxes paid ______________ s!«B Insurance „„ „ 3 00 Insurance Aflti Uu&lt;olleoted fees - Its!*) 16.40 TOTAL $ 9»,TR1.S8 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 32,907.36 Paid-up stock and dividends _____ '- O_,aoaOO Due shareholders on Incomplete loans 8&amp;90 Beserve fund _ _ 1 106.40 Undivided profits _ 3 4T9.02 H8.60 Undivided profits TOTAL * 90,781.68 </seg>
            <seg id="p157">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 155 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 UK&lt;-K1I&gt;T* Cash on hand last report _ _ $ 3.SOT.7W I'ues (Running stock) 19.U9M Paid-up stock .".'"."." . __ . 18.4flO.tX&gt; Mortgage payments -. lO.ono.no Interest i 7,443154 Insurance _ _ _ |t«) Personal accounts _ „ _ I 1 * w Membership and transfer feea „ 4M.75 »«• Membership and transfer fees Delinquent interest Taxes _ _ UB.M *■« Miscellaneous _ !'.'. - 72 30 Total f 9*,M2.tT DISBIRSEMEXTK Mortgage loans _ f 24_7&amp;&lt;0 Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ 16,19181 «•!?&lt;"» Withdrawals paid-up stock •,200.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock . 3,701.90 •**«» Salaries _ _ _ 1.300.00 Commissions „ 1 ?** Other expense 24LOO Canh on hand _ tM hi 5.WB.81 Furntltnr* and fixture* _ ~ _ 164.45 Total _ _ f N,M_flT SUPPLEMENTAL RKPOKT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent Number of shnrea Issued since organtMtion _ _ 3.W78 Number of share* outstanding laat report _ _ 1JKK ijm Shares Issued since last report _ _ H» Total _ ■_' .:*«6 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since lant report !'.«&gt; Number of shares In force this date _ 2.IM Number of shares of which dues are delinquent _ 1-1&gt; Number of borrowing stockholders 12S Number of non-borrowing stockholder* - 16R Number of loans made for building purpose* doting .rear _.. • Number of loana made for purchasing of homestead's or payment of honip&lt;4tend-mnrtirageK during year Par value of each share of stock - _ $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date MMi Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders — IHMK a Amount (if Interest, premiums and fines dne snd unpaid **&gt; UT Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 1 liTai'Tt ».«■ Number and amount of mortgages subjec Amount of lonns on improyed real estate Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loani hare been made MB.ramo Amount of loans on unimproved real estate __M Appraised rnlue of unimproved real estate upon wklch loans bare been mnile W*)Cii Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 110,000.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assls-ned to the association as collateral security &lt;. - _ SROHOiOO ■B CUIIHienii Briurnj a _ -. w,nuv Amount credited to reserve fund durine year _ 30S.4O Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2.4B0&gt;? Amount of dividends paid on matured and nald-up stock during year :i.T&lt;&gt;i M Rate per rent of dividends declared on running stock during year •% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stork yeif - - 7 and •B'* Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year - — t% </seg>
            <seg id="p158">156 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the YORK MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President Geo. W. Shreck Vice President C. A. McCioud Secretary Hattie S. Reed Treasurer Geo. H. Holdeman Attorney W. W. Wvckoff DIRECTORS W. L. White W. H. Read N. A. Dean H. M. Childs Geo. W. Shreck C. A. McCloud Hattie S. Reed Geo. H. Holdeman W. W. Wyckoff ASSETS First mortgage loans $120.000.«l Loan* in process of foreclosure !to4.70 Loans on stork or pass book security — S'^^'uU lither real estate 3.:MI&gt;.H8 Cash ' ~ U.71O.S1 3^ti !£I Kellnquent Interest, fines, rtc _ Furniture and fixtures 255.56 Taxes paid .'. '•'• Total »14O.061.&lt;* LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends * 1S 2-|!f«Sl ItlllllllMR BIW» nil.l UK^rim- - fl «-| «J K..vt»rv*» film] Ti.lKtt.'*^ .-..-,7 Indlvlded profits Total *14aO61.OB </seg>
            <seg id="p159">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 157 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING SUPPLEMENTAL REfORT 1'lan of association (serial or permanent) Combination Number of snare* issued since organization 3O.iX&gt; Number of series Issued since organization - #* NunilMT of shares out siumliiiir last report MM Shares Isaueil since last report 1.1-S67 Tot'tl - ■■ '•.'* 1 Shares «lthilra\vn. matured or cancelled alae* inat report 2 iii Number of shares In foive this date _ 5 '*?I Number of shares on which dues are delinc|uent 1JBT Xunilier of shares sulijert to cancellation for non-payment of dues 3 Average riiniiiuir time of stock matured during the year «&gt; month* !2f. Nunilter of liorrowinjr stiw-kholders Nuinlier of non-borrowing stockholilers Number of loans made for building purpose* during year Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or pajnieut of IIIHT »FI M'.IIIS 111, lilt" liri |riii' ••••.^■■• n wv ...-u.^— » « ■■ I homeste!id-inortjrn&gt;.'es during year n Weekly Plan of premiuin $ MM I'ar value of each share i&gt;f stiM-k Total amount of dues delinquent at this date mm Amount of dues owitiL- by borrowing sto&lt;kholders — - \mount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. Number and amount of mortiranes in process of foreclosure Amount of limn» on improved renl estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loana have been Amount of leans on unimproved real estate • Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans nave MM Amo'lTnt" of'fi're insuraii'-e in i force and assigned to the association as collateral security 122.0ll0.no Amount of tornido insurance In force and assigned to the association l-jn.ono mi as collateral security Amount of dividends declared on running stock 'lurinir vear S..V.T.11 hate m&gt;r cent of dividends declared on running stock during year. Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 110,700.1 » raiHfll UllUf in mi|'iu«ni ir«i *r«.«.* « K ~» „-.„... _ MK./WW\rt* made -&lt;■ - - - - ...i.t ,xf i...itw mi iiiiiiiiiirnvHit rt'nl t*i»tiite — •'■ (ri JUNE 30, 1917 RKCEirTS i':i&gt;h on liiiiiil hist report Dues I Kuiiiiinu stock) _ Mortgage and stock loan payment* Interest ami premium Fines Itelits „ Membership sad transfer fees Real estate sales „ „ Foreclosures _ Note iiulil - Total ..---. * 6.SW.10 -,- XMI.-JK 46,T'»"«i u,tt.-.».s- NUi LM.OO 5TA25 MM TO.00 ■JSU.00 niSBl R8KMENT8 Mortjraue iiiiil stock lonns _ Wir h:lrn\viils ruiiiiiiiK i*tock ntul tliviiletnlH Salaries - ( It tier ex pell w -. _ Hc:i! fsl:ilc ;n -count Cash on luiml — Total : </seg>
            <seg id="p160">158 TWENTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WORKING MEN'S SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1917 OFFICERS President C. A. McCloud Vice President N. A. Dean Secretary ■.._ W. W. Wyckoff Treasurer. Geo. H. Holdeman Attorney. W. W. Wyckoff DIRECTORS C. A. McCloud N. A. Dean W. W. Wyckoff Geo. H. Holdeman W. E. McCloud ASSETS First mortgage loans. .. $11,400.00 Ct»h - 3,488.00 Total - J17.flHB.00 LIABILITIES Running «tock and diridend* _ *16s6«.J3 Running vtocK ana amaena* — — — »iwbj« Due ah*rehold«ri on Incomplete loana — 700.00 W^^KAI*WA Til Tiil *- . **^*^TJl indlTided profits - 80.00 Tottl....- $17^f».00 </seg>
            <seg id="p161">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 159 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1917 RECEIPTS Cash oo hand last report Dne» (Riming Mock) Mortgage payments... -; *.-ip.&lt;- l»*».» IIICUIS Stock loan payment*. Interest Premium Fines Membership and transfer feei Total DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans Withdrawal*, running stock and dividend Examiner's fees C'afth on band Advertising . Interest on withdrawal* Exchange on draft* Total. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (aerial or permanent) _ _ _ Permanent N'umtwr of shares lsaued since organisation ipt.'i Number of shares outstanding last report _- JSJBIt Shares Issued since last report „ „ 36 :»•&gt; Total -.. _____________________ MK Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled aince last report _ -... 18* Number of sharea in force this date Number of shares in force thla date 41.1 N'umlier of shares on which duea are delinquent _ 12 Nnmher of shares subiect to cancellation for non-payment of dues. li Average running time of stock matured during the year &gt; TH months 12 TH months Number of borrowing stockholders _ _ .1.. ft Number of Don-hnrowinc stockholders Number of Don-hnrowinc stockholders &gt; Number of loana made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ I Plan of premium _ _ _ _ _ 2% on face of loan Par value of each share of stock _ _ f 1OO.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this dtt* _ 144 On Amount of dn*» owing by borrowing stockholders 144.00 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 1 nuiuurr nuu nui'imii in uiori kh jc*** suujni io [uraiumrr .&gt;" i Amount of loans on improved real estate ■ 14,400.10 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made _ _ _... nT.mon Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to toe association as collateral i«eouritv __ _ _ ■.'i.miin Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association collateral security __.„__„ H 'HjuOU Amount credited to reserve fund during year. — Amount of dividends declared on running stock daring year 888.T4 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock florin* Tear N Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers daring year ~'\ Rate per cent of premiums charged borrower* daring yesir *% on fa«e of loan </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>