<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00084.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA BIENNIAL REPORT of the Nebraska Public Library Commission TO THE GOVERNOR December 1, 1936 to November 30, 1938</title>
               <date value="1938-11-30">1938-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">STATE OF NEBRASKA BIENNIAL REPORT of the Nebraska Public Library Commission TO THE GOVERNOR December 1, 1936 to November 30, 1938 </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Honorable R. L. Cochran, Governor of Nebraska. Dear Sir: Complying with the requirement of the law, the Nebraska Public Library Commission herewith presents the following report for the biennium ending November 30, 1938. Respectfully submitted H. L. Webster, President </seg>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014">NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION Members of the Commission H. L. Webster, Tekamah, President Miss. C. AY. llevxei!, Franklin, Vice-President Mits P. L. Cady, Arlington, Miss Ax me C. Kramph, North Platte Joins W. Deleiiaxt, Beatrice Staff Nellie M. Cakey. Executive Secretary Dorothy W. Lessknhop, Assistant Secretary and Reference lAbritriqn CiAha B. .Jonxsox, Assistant m Charge of Extension Jessie Robertson, Assistant m Charge of School and Com &gt;n unity Loans Raphael, Tayi.ok. Stenographer (Part time) .Tajiks Au.ei.y. Shipping Clerk Office Room 1508, The Capitol Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p015">200,000 I 1 -i 1 1 n 1 -i 1 # 175,000 j I 150,000 r^— 125,000 7^ :' / ' ---- 100,000 y 75,000 7^ &#132; — •fr - -50,000 — —a to &gt;fi c- o&gt; r-tto m c- oj w w w woj to w w to to &lt;j&gt; A to m c- O) Mio m t&gt;- HW &lt;M CV2 O2 M tO tO tO tO OJOJOJO&gt;OiOTOSO&gt;O&gt;OJ r-l HtH rH rH i-l f-H rl &lt;"H r-H This table shows comparative statistics for number of volumes circulated, number of volumes m book collection, and amount of ap - propriation received over a twenty year period. A-~~_ Appropriation B Volumes m library C .Volumes circulated </seg>
            <seg id="p016">E. SOUTH DAKOTA ) 673 \ \ YiSßsr-J lfe * 5 . 1860 1149X1.1159 2914 !_ r-t=i: jsa. ' ■■ jTas=— jiSsßr~|iis— t-iiw j-aarf I " 1 } 5a «-kl|B=L U |^X- iowa _, | i piSsi~ pBSKs pas— jSBK™ J wit.. . war: 745}sag — psslrraiii -, — ? Colorado ■""' 7~™ [ma. pu^^.^-gar-jag — i*=wrj='T^^"z96o\.- fe- . ' KANSAS NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARZ COMiaSSIOII Number of books loaned, 1936-1938 </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">9 REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA LIBRARY COMMISSION December 1, 1936 to November 30, 1938 What It Did Circulated books as follows: Borrowers Bequests filled No. of voL Groups of residents 203 14,495 Public libraries 1,274 50,963 Schools 1,846 78,480 Study clubs 2,234 4,776 Other organizations 23 1,258 Individuals 14,047 30,350 19,627 180,321 Increased circulation over previous biennium by 44 per cent Sent books to all counties m the state Visited 91 counties Staff members gave 90 talks on reading andi library problems Made 375 library visits Sent out 41,166 letters and cards Catalogued 9,037 books added to the library. Withdrew 1,745 worn out books and ended biennium with a total of 51,259 vol - umes m library. How Service was Given To the libraries the Library Commission served as an informa - tion bureau and clearing house on library matters, provided copies of the library laws, secured legal opinions when requested to do so, loaned professional literature including aids for cataloging and book selection, helped plan library buildings, gave assistance through con - ferences with librarians and library trustees and through correspon - dence. Traveling libraries were loaned to supplement small local collec - tions of books and loans were made on request to other libraries. Annual statistics collected from the libraries m the state have helped librar - ians to measure their service and growth m comparison with other </seg>
            <seg id="p019">libraries. These reports have served as the basis for surveys con - ducted by the American Library Association and have provided in - formation for library directories and for the Nebraska Blue Book. People living where there is no local library service have depend - ed largely on the library Commission for books, and shipments have been made to every county m the state. Nebraska, which is an agri - cultural state with a large rural population and many towns too small to support local libraries, has not developed county or regional libraries, and consequently 50 per cent of the population are with - out local library service. Books were loanedi from the Library Com - mission on request to local libraries, communities without libraries, schools, clubs and other organizations, and to individuals. Increase m Circulation of Books At a time when many public libraries reported decreases m cir - culation the Library Commission had a 44 per cent increase over the preceding biennium m number of volumes circulated. Several fac - tors have contributed to the growing number of people making use of the Library Commission. The service has become better known . through the use of the Commission Bookmobile which has visited al - most every county m the state contacting people through county fairs, state and district meetings of organizations, visits to librar - ies, schools, etc. The Bookmobile, which is Nebraska's first "library on wheels" was a gift to the Commission m the fall of 1936. The present day curriculum, of the schools requires a great deal of supplementary reading. Few schools are able to supply all of the books needed and many of the rural and small town schools do not have access to local libraries. During the past biennium 78,480 books were sent out m 1,846 loans to schools. Three hundred seventy-four of these schools were new borrowers. There is a growing emphasis on adult education. The state as - sistance department has relied largely on the Library Commission for professional reading material for employees and for those who were preparing for merit examinations. The state recreation department has made extensive use of books to help m its program. A large amount of reference work was done for members of study clubs and the number of requests taken care of by the reference librarian in - creased 115 per cent over a two year period. Nebraska was chosen m 1937 as one of nine demonstration states for closer cooperation between libraries and the American Home 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Economics Association. A state wide reading project sponsored by the Library Commission and the local libraries m cooperation with the Home Demonstration Project Clubs under the direction of the extension department of the College of Agriculture has stimulated wider interest m reading and has brought many new patrons not only to local libraries, but also to the Library Commission. In 1937-38 approximately 15,000 Project Club members were enrolled m the reading project. Twenty- five thousand are participating this year, and as others m the families represented refid the books, the number of people touched by the project is much larger than the membership of the clubs. A slight increase m the amount appropriated for the hook fund for the biennium made it possible to do some much ne«d«d replacing and duplicating of standard titles needed by the schools, as well as to add a larger number of the important current publications. The supply of books is still far from adequate, however, to take oare of all requests. Other Activities The addition to the staff m July, 1937 of a trained assistant to be m charge of extension work has made it possible for the first time m many years to visit all of the public libraries m the state at least once during the biennium. Altogether 375 visits were made to librar - ies by members of the staff. These visits had several objectives: to confer with librarians and trustees on library problems; to give)libra - rians and trustees an opportunity of examining the new books carried on the Bookmobile for suggestions of books to be purchased by the local libraries or borrowed from the Library Commission; to gain first hand information about library conditions m the state as a basis for plans for improvement of library service; arid to make the ser - vice of the Library Commission better known. Eighty-six of the ninety-three counties m the state have been visited by the Bookmo - bile. Members of the staff have frequently been called on to speak on topics related to reading and library extension. During the bien - nium 90 talks were given before national, state and district library meetings, at eighth grade county commencement exercises, rural teachers' meetings, dedication of a library building, leader training meetings of the Home Demonstration Project Clubs, and before other groups. One address was given over a local radio station and scripts 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">were prepared for several radio talks to be given by people out m the state. Three study lessons were prepared on request for state wide use by clubs. Exhibits were arranged for several meetings and material loaned for other displays. A monthly mimeographed news letter sent to librarians and trustees contained information about national, state and local library movements, book notes and other items of in - terest. Participation m Professional Organizations The Library Commission cooperates each year with the Nebraska Library Association m holding a series of eight district library meet - ings, and works closely with all other activities of the state associa - tion. All professional members of the Library Commission staff are members of the American Library Association, the Nebraska Library Association and £he Lincoln Chapter of the American Library Asso - ciation. They have been represented on committees m each of these groups. The assistant secretary and one member of the Commission at - tended the annual meeting of the American Library Association held m New York City m June, 1937. The executive secretary attended the midwinter meetings of the American Library Association m Chicago m December m 1936 and 1937, and the assistant m charge of school and community loans also attended the 1936 meeting. SchetViles were arranged to make it possible for all of the staff to attend part of the sessions of the annual conference m Kansas City, Missouri m June, 1938. Several members of the Commission as well as the staff mem - bers attended the annunl meetings of the Nebraska Library Associa - tion m Omaha m October, 1937 and m Fremont m October, 1938. Library Conditions m the State There were an unusually large number of changes m librarians m the state m both public and school libraries during the biennium. Of the thirty-three changes m the position of librarian of public lib - raries, two were caused by death, five by retirement, five by change of residence, and miscellaneous causes accounted for the remainder. Several people holding assistant positions m the larger libraries re - signed to accept positions at higher salaries m other states. The University of Nebraska. Dana College, State Teachers College at 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Wayne, and the Omaha Municipal University had new librarians dur - ing the biennium. Emphasis is being plneed on improving library service m the high schools m the state and nn increasing number of high schools are making provision for the organization of libraries and nre em - ploying librarians or teacher-libarians who have had some training m library work. A course m "Library Education" given by Dr. Robert A. Miller at the University of Nebraska m the summer of 1938 was- well attended by school superintendents and teachers. The voluntary certification plan started m 1934 by the Nebraska Library Association continued m force, but an attempt to secure legal certification for librarians will probably bo made during the 193!) session of the Legislature. Buildings The Union College $60,000 library building was opened m tin: fall of 1038. The library of the Omaha Municipal University is housed m the new University building which was dedicated m November, 1938. A new community building at Valentine provides space on the second floor for the library. A, residence at Culbertson, a filling station at Gretna, an old schoolhouse at Knstis and a bank building at Edgar have been remodeled for libraries. The North Branch library m Omaha moved into a new $25,000 building m January, 1938. A corner brick building formerly used for a bank was remodeled for the Bethany Branch of the Lincoln CSty library and opened m October, 1937. ■.' ■ •' ' '■ ''' ' ' '■.'■'■ Financial Report ■ Several of the newer libraries received a tax levy for the first time during the biennium, but the amount received m most cases was so small that the burden of the support still rested on some spon - soring organization. A few libraries m small towns found it impossi - ble to secure continued support and closed their doors, m some cases transferring their collection of books to the schools. Local clubs sponsored the organization of libraries m a few other small towns. Since practically all towns m the state large enough to finance libraries now have them the Library Commission believes that effort 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">should be made to strengthen existing libraries rather than to organ - ize new libraries unless they can become a part of a county or- reg - ional library with a larger tax-supporting basis. No county or reg - ional libraries have been started since the permissive law was passed in 1935, probably due to the continued drouth condition in Nebraska. State Wide Library Projects •11 V^^ th t U 1 G ° f WPA funds a P r °J ect has been st «ted which mil help to make books in the larger university, college and public libraries more accessible through inter-library loans. A union cata - log of the holdings ofabout twenty-six libraries is being compiled at the state capitol by WPA personnel under the direction of a trained cataloger. When completed the catalog will be in charge of the Li - brary Commission. Another WPA library project which will be sponsored, by the Lib - rary Commission will be started early in 1939. This calls for the ex - tension of hbrary service over the state through the use of WPA personnel supervised by trained librarians. The project will be a demons ration of library service on a. larger tax basil forTupport and will conform to the plans made by the Nebraska Library pTa" mng Board and by the Library Commission. 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Financial Report of Library Commission ■ ■ . ■ ■ .. ■ .1 ■ ■ ■ ■ *■ ■ ■ . ■ ; . . ■ Expend, from From Approp. Approp. 1935-37 for 1937-38 Salaries . $3,908.98 $11,288.30 Supplies 344.02 984.59 Expense . 860.55 3,185.13 Materials and repairs 155.24 203.00 Equipment (Books, magazines, etc.).... 2,492.63 12,443.39 $7,761.42 $28,104.41 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">No. 1 TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES Receipts Expenditures n I i ii 1 1 1* mill i p Over 30,000 populatlot ~ 75,933 Lincoln Lulu Home 142.258 27.C02 571,560 7.5 $54, 100 $6,938 $81,710 S 8,238 $31,737 $57,683 $ .76 214,006 Omaha Bertha Baumer 201,507 47.146 587,138 2.7 80,000 2,573 82,573 12,636 42,080 82,573 .3» 10,001-30,000 population 10.327 Beatrice Madge Evans 24,359 4,117 111,16010.8 7,000 7,000 2,446 2,329 7,079 .68 11,407 Fremont Mildred Palmer 17,001 5,000 74,632 6.S 5.504 586 6,090 1,596 1,981 6,779 .59 18.041 Grand Island Daisy Houck 21,629 6,882 85,492 4.7 9,500 ... 9,500 2,278 4,045 8.620 .48 15,490 Hastings Mrs. Ellen D. Smith 22,418 7.967 102,700 6.6 8,500 807 10,047 1,834 4,870 9,025 .58 10,717 Norfolk Laura Durland 13,570 12 061 North Platte Eleanor M. Wheeler 12,550 3,036 100,714 8.3 8.C12 ... 10,806 3,590 3.538 8,612 .71 4,001- -10,000 population 6,669 Alliance Mrs. Blanche Prettymnn .. 14,691 5,612 70,07110.6 .5,320 ... 5,320 1,217 1,217 5,283 .79 4,606 Chadron Mrs. Lole Sklles 12.509 3,000 41,014 8.9 2.877 237 3,114 !i29 1,200 2 924 .63 6.898 Cohimbus Rose Rlddell 13.873 5,472 56.668 8.2 3,507 1,190 1553 4*291 62 6,192 Kalrbury .Mrs. Naomi Ellsworth 13.447 2,624 76,15112.3 5,332 515 6,847 2,142 1,674 5,405 87 5,787 Palls City Blolse Ebert 19,531 67,53811.7 3.800 378 4,178 1.110 1,863 4,178 .72 8,675 Kearney ...7 Mrs. Mary Early O'Brlnn.. n.flr.S 3,003 43,075 5. 4,500 200 4,914 547 2.495 3,716 .43 6,688 McCook MiUlcent Slaby i 10,068 5,217 32.830 4.9 4,0Sfi 176 5.163 710 1,500 4,020 .60 7,230 Nebraska Cltv .... Anne Stevenson 18,500 1,674 30.190 4.2 3,2R!i 412' 6,443 1,166 1,776 4,206 .58 8,4165 Scottsbluff Mrs. Nellie Wilson 20.201 5.000 34.18S 4. 4,929 ... 4,929 1,127 2,693 4,814 .57 5,712 York Ada Hapgard 1C..S52 2,000 22,227 3.9 2,140 35 3,991 870 1,397 3,554 .62 2,5O1--4,000 population 3,068 Auburn Lorene Anderson 9,606 3.683 31,785 10.4 2,375 IBS 3,181 618 905 2 543 .83 2,716 Aurora Lillian Moore 6,815 1.809 13.890 5.1 1,452 126 2,519 413 756 1,954 .72 2,791 Blair May McQuarrie 6,921 2,500 21,134 7.6 1,300 ... 1,300 400 735 1,703 .61 *,7io Broken Bow Mrs. Zuie Thompson 6.516 23.959 8.8 1.570 313 2,356 885 643 2,270 .84 •2,865. .Crete Mrs. C. F. Baker 10,!&gt;!&gt;0 800 16.7S7 5.9 2.193 175 2.742 399 739 L7O4 .59 2.531 Gerlmi Mrs. Nellie M. Perrlnc .... 7,812 3,177 45.77818.1 1,465 290 2.104 742 660 1,453 .67 3,263 Holdrege Hettie Backman 10,102 2.698 47,123 14.4 2.385 264 4,106 861 840 2,445 .75 2,962 Lexington Mary I. Cooper 8.603 503 23,816 8. 2.339 ... 2,575 691 807 2,386 .81 ..3,973 Plattamouth C*. Olive Jones 27,254 2,193 38,708 9.7 2.8.10 ... 2,850 204 1,552 2,636 .64 2,588 Schuyler Mrs. Alice G. Carl 12.041 2.107 9.427 3.6 1.807 79 2.046 285 540 1,126 .43 Includes endowment and trust funds 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">No. 2 TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) Receipts Expenditures m 2,737 Seward Mrs. Emma Bredekamp . . 7,003 1,805 24,563 8.7 $.... $... $.... $604 $ 600 $1,617 $ P. 306 Sidney Mrs. Cbnstance Corbett . . 4.776 852 11,972- 3.6 2,100 G8 2,168 466 660 1,961 .59 3,927 So. Sioux City Mrs Marie Murphy 5.823 2,149 18,230 4.6 1.365 61 1,625 160 360 912 .23 3 044 Superior * Mrs ER Towle 12 - 913 l - m B 2' 362 17 - 2 2 - 240 139 2 ' 409 224 1 - M 4 11681 •" 2689 Wahoo Mrs Grare Oldham 10.447 218 16,054 5.9 1800 2 .... 432 7»0 1.261 .47 1 17B 1 ' 0 A I|n«^^&gt;1 |n«^^&gt;, POPUlatlon W» W P ClhrnlH, 5 ' 080 92() X*' 002 7 - 3 69 ° 147 986 259 35 ° 788 - BB \V,I fiw wS i rS 6 - 499 •••■ I 2' 299 B -« 2 - 202 ••• 2 ' 202 364 63 ° i- 362 - 62 ; 2 -" 2 A "on Mrs. Jennie Grador ... 6 „ 2 ,„ 6M j „„ gg 1 1,235* Almot Mrs. Jennie *&#132; t/peiston .. 1C . C &#132; , fto . ,_ ■ &#132; -. 0 - '&#132;. &#132; ! 1.238* Anselmot Mrs. Mildred English 1 - 808 201 2 - 098 U1 180 •• 78 96 210 " ' I'M?" iiSShoP M™' T; SWeT 7 WS l'.«0 9.793 V.6 * "MO « "279 120 ' "180 ' 326 .32 f" A ™^? c MreC F DlrtSichi 6 ' 410 J- 580 8 . 902 7 - 8 738 186 L" 8 296 48 ° 1 - 546 »- 18 ?fi7fi* Araofd? Mra Emily Wehr?eV 4.681 800 6,394 3.8 1.000 ... .... 139 360 760 .45 IMB JWhtaSd mESTiKXSU'"": 4,232 1.313 16,050 8.4 1,177 ... 1.342 410 360 1.156 .65 1559 Rwd "■■■"Mrs Jennie TAtham 4.276 342 13,252 8.6 846 89 1,052 256 320 845 .64 1024 Be^rCity Mrs. Cleo M. Brown 2.363 260 4.314 4.2 140 172 834 90 68 246 M 10T Beemert Mrs. Ben Martin 1.546 150 4,470 4.1 100 11 230 69 79 187 .17 1017 Beflevue Frances E. Smith 1.508 450 3.244 3.2 175 14 211 96 60 146 .14 i I4IR Wnnmfloifl Mrs. E. L. Durbln 4,110 732 18,075 12.6 1.102 23 1,283 106 606 988 .6» liii £rMn«nnT? LoulseEstlU 4,583 1.481 8,131 5.7 1,691 48 2,025 363 468 1.212 .85 1156 Burwell Mrs. Jessie Tlgenfrltz 2,892 .... 14,990 12.9 734 98 888 260 892 863 .76 1.433* Callawayt ".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Mrs - Vera Stephenson .... 2,086 222 2,624 1.8 .... 74 259 58 105 202 .14 2 474 Central Cltv Rennle Ayres l'o6l Chat) Dell Twlla Stegeman 3,969 516 9,790 9.2 1,094 65 1,825 382 466 926 .87 1484» Clarkst " Mrs - Cleo Schank 5,627 742 6,723 4.5 800 3 1,048 65 360 781 .68 l'Bl3 Cozad Mrs. S. D. -Wareham 6.102 1.800 14,300 7.9 1,600 300 ....• 1,149 .64 1703 Crawford'"" Mrs. Maude Smeak 4,283 832 12,248 7.2 581 76 866 323 275 683 .40 1,888 Crelghton II." Mra ' C- T- Brltt 2,400 393 5.903 4.3 646 ... 769 323 240 759 .56 t Township library • Includes township population 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">No. 3 TAX-SUPPOBTED LreRARIES— (Continued) Receipts Expenditure! ■ i i i f fl s i 4 lite i !i 1,565» Croftont Mrs. Frank Holder 7777. 777. 7777. 77! * 220 $ 25 * 248 f 63 $ 120 $ 195 $ .14 2,333 David City Mrs. Laura V. Paul 11,958 1,929 26,003 11.1 2,100 106 2,703 933 875 2,383 I.OJ 1,177 Deshler Kllen Pegpee 1,160 200 ... 200 190 47 .... 1,103 Franklin Mrs. Delia M. Carter 8,802 361 11,847 10.7 670 68 1,049 190 610 853 .77 1,214. Friend Rotha Doner 3,344 1,149 8,951 7.4 1,000 30 1,030 266 300 985 .81 1.680 Fullerton Mm. I. M .Torgensen .... 5,880 1,024 23.737 14.1 1,000 ... 1,373 114 420 1,373 .81 '1,662 Geneva Mrs. Isabel Blxby 6.999 1,515 14,347 8.6 1,500 250£ 1,976 190 900 1,758 1.06 1,089 Genoa Ella Mnnson 2.494 352 7,515 6.9 319 50 309 156 525 .48 1,363* Gibbon* Mrs. Lou H. McLaren .... 4,153 589 5.136 3.8 1,000 54 .... 202 360 991 .73 1,958 Gordon Mra. Grace Hummel ...... 4,517 1,200 9,327 4.8 1,298 ... 1,298 431 300 .2,322 Gothenburg S. Frances Botkln 4,638 3,061 9,144 3.9 2,000 1,080 '1,668 Hartlngton Mrs. Kate Bryant 1,804 Hebron Mrs. May Mcßeth 6,036 1,719 1,423 42 1,621 201 462 1,246 .69 1,026 Hemlngford Mrs. Grace Olds 3,066 112 1,793 1.7 139 43 435 ... 82 229 .22 1,435 Humboldt Mrs. Ruby Reid 5,273 563 12,240 8.5 723 83 1,192 168 385 1,008 .70 1.711 KlmbaJl Mrs. Alice G. Irwin 6,393 .... 10,008 5.8 1,000 45 1,045 343 614 977 .57 2,054» Loup City* Harriet Gallaway 9.550 1,827 38,370 18.7 1.682 720 1,682 256 720 1,594 .78 1,842 Madison Mrs. Anna D. Johnson ... 8,492 1,320 26,362 14.3 2,217 96 3,302 622 1,039 2,306 1.26 1,415* Mason City* ..:.... Mrs. Will VanZnmlt 927 132 1.960 1.4 219 20 242 69 87 191 .13 1 322* Mernat Mrs. J. V. Rldenour 9,219 211 4,534 3.4 1.130 2 1,143 64 360 994 .75 1,079 Mlnatare Mrs. G. R, Meyers 3,067 .... 6,011 6.6 .... 183 .... 44 120 330 .31 1,716 Mlnden -Florence Curtis 5,012 1,768 18,312 10.7 865 80 946 469 429 981 .57 2.058 Mitchell Mrs. Isabel Lane 6,595 1,350 18,250 8.9 862 94 1,208 342 420 967 .47 HBo*»Mullenf Mrs. Mary A. R. Nonl . . . . 3.210 .... 3,400 2.9 433 1,649 Nellsh Mrs. Bess Galloway 6,890 .... 20,765 12.6 1,250 184 1,495 361 527 1,475 .89 1,147 Newman Grove ....Mrs. Marsnret Dlllman .. 3,508 698 9.201 8 -797 33 1.011 168 293 .... .... 1108 North Bend . . . T-aura Roump 3.402 500 9,869 8.9 1,000 100 1,150 120 573 1.14 Inn 1,143 North Loup Blrdlno Tngerson 2,984 55 .... 94 -0» 1,433 Oakland T.ydia Hill 7,073 IHO 1U.554 13.6 1,163 9a 1.821 563 320 1.208 .S3 1.112* Ocontot .....Mrs. Ruth Thompson .... 1,154 ....• 100 ,35 .... ... 1,631 Ogaliala Mrs. O. Parker 2.449 Sl!i 13,541 8.3 777 89 1.056 187 241 787 .48 t Township library •• Includes county population A Includes endowment and trust funds • Includes township population I County library 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">No. 4 TAX- SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) * Receipts Expenditures B I i i M II j ll 11 1 ii I ill f iilllil I S 2.74G* O'Nellil Mary McLauglilin 5 572 2 000 $1,200 $... $1,200 $250 $600 $1,200 $.59 2,664* Ordt Elsie Wibjrg 1,500 11,428 5.1 1.988 420 1,439* Orleans! Dorothy M. Mahn 6,740 402 7,182 5. 500 828£ 2,203 377 920 1,788 1.24 1654 Osceola t#ulu Hendrlcicson 5.255 429 6,595 4. 257 ...■ 406 137 91 235 .15 1,573 Pawnee City Mary French 5,666 1,200 27,299 17.3 1,200 367^ 1,567 736 600 1.567 1.00 1,006 Pender Aleda P. Bents 5.981 .... 4,323 4.3 100 12 .... 107 25 133 .13 1.271 Pierce Mrs. Haima MasUllr 4,477 839 2,780 2.2 451 36 .... 314 300 614 .48 1216 Plalnview T.illlan Lerura 5.445 627 17.682 14.5 1.707 161 1,977 363 480 1,212 1.00 1145 Randolph ....Mrs. C. A. Kerr 4,265 650 8,361 7.3 980 ... 1,620 174 300 887 .77 1,559 Ravenna Nellie V. Clark 6.414 1,179 20,989 13.5 1.089 85".... 228 600 1,060 .68 1519 Red Clond Tola Swartz 6.705 1,359 16,411 10.8 1,300 ... 1.300 150 720 1,300 .86 l'oo6 Rushville Mary W. Mohr 2.407 1,048 3,154 3.1 570 833* 1.492 ... 180 1,526 1.52 1,030 St. Edward Gertie A. Anderson 3,225 902 10.633 10.3 400 57 457 75 300 375 .36 1621 St. Paul Mrs. Ina M. Lulck 2.855 .... 5.886 3.6 257 11 337 97 138 236 .15 1 644* Sanrentfl Mrs. Flora A. Cropper 3,g63 1,071 3,763 2.3 950 154 300 6!&gt;5 .42 1066 Scribner Kvelyn Lahmann 2,640 4,392 4.1 567 58 680 66 300 642 .60 1,434* SheHonJ ..Mrs Jessie M. Burkcrd .. 5 824 .... 10,356 7.2 900 101 373 .806 .56 1254* Spencer! Mrs. Hlldor M. Ogren . . . . 3.55585!LJ2J10 9.7 935 37 1.366 128 285 697 .56 1479 Stknton Mrs. Jean D. Hollstien ... 5.095^116 7,725 5.2 1.750 ... 2.359 230 480 1,191 .81 1320 Stromsburs Ruth E. Bantu 2.145 800 5.155 3.9 683 54 738 130 300 699 .53 1,540 Sutton Sibyl B. Jarrett 4,053 350 5.450 3.5 950 ... .... 99 480 ?R8 .64 1,829 Tecumseh Mrs. R. "W. Campbell .... 3.690 500 9.500 5.2 1.200 5 1 356 307 480 1.202 .66 1.804 Tekamah Mrs. I.uclle Gates 6.186 1,500 16.169 9 994 94 1.854 433 390 1,292 .72 1106 Tilden Anna St.inton 2,423 1.488 13.688 12.4 700 25 360 uoI'myVsW"::::::::::::^. Martha f. wither.,., j.™ .... gg; p mo m m 99 m m .« 1.672 Valentine Mrs. Emma A. Sheldon .. 4.898 . 7,664 4.6 282 24 404 70 157 244 .15 1039 Valleyt Mrs. Anna Howard 3.817 80ft 10.219 9.8 286 640 1.112 Wakefield E. Ruth Collins 6.491 d6l d.687 5.1 . ... ... ... ... .. ... 1 IA9 WnitMU Afro Hnrn' Tj Keefe 2,759 .... 3,325 2.9 233 10 - 349 96 ... 246 .21 ijS»wi!S!i ::::".::.:::{£s Sis »..^. .."■ «■«» 79410.012 8.3 S oo 7 8»« 937 212 325 m .n f Townshin library ~ Includes endowment and trust funds • Includes township population " Includes contracts with townships t Support divided between town and school 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">No. 5 TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRABIES— (Continued) Receipt* Expenditures n I • I §2 II I H fea -all 5?I 111 ■a 18 2.381 Wayne Mrs. B. S. Blair 7,293 1,493 18.G61 7.8 J2.361 $146 12,607 $296 $1,660 $2,380 $ToO 1.02S Weepine Water .... Mildred Hart ?.«« • • • • H. 600 14.2 813 27 840 152 300 840 .82 2,225 West Point Minnie U Frahm &lt;.M 5 1.381 10,969 4.9 1.100 295 480 970 At 1,352 Wllber Carrie Savage 2.417 218 4.155 3.1 100 50 130 .... 1,327 Wlsner Clara Nickerson 3 - 195 300 '.719 5.8 400 55 465 148 180 5 35 Le Adam8 n1 : 000 .. POPU ! a Ca O^eß. Barmore ....... }.«« "? 4.83 C 9.. 200 20 224 62 144 212 .40 ■121 Alexandria Faye Burch If® fff •;••• ■•• 150 20 170 27 93 160 .38 622 Arllnßtoa Mrs. Blanche W. Keller .. *■"! \ s .l "&lt;» 9 290 12 302 113 141 271 .44 vni. A T t»iif Mr« C R nrmii.it '''•' l " ' •' 3.051 . .!.,. 200 ... 419 56 150 219 .25 060 Bhie Hill Mre Carl Huffman "■ 1 ' 741 ' 203 4 -°° 8 «• »« « 27« 80 »» 2" - 3 7S7«a!S.™!ckf"::::::::Berthra,SS" .::::::: b™ .;« *.o« |-« ;« 2 302 124 v, m m 4ni r^nrmii M n r&gt; m inn«q t.vui iOi) 3,685 9.2 225 ... 225 ... 75 .... 4 0 J ceSVpYdV-::::::M™:RUMewin •:::::::: ?,•?«■ «g »■«« ".* joo ... 427 144 210 36 i .49 9M Clay Center ...Bertha F. Jessup '•*» 2 =» ?.724 4. 749 ... 963 ... 480 .... 730' Comstockfl Marion Stevens .. 2.240 400 5,693 7.8 346 13 362 35 186 308 .42 820 Culbertaorl .... '.'. '.'. Mrs. Elmer Mcßee 2^'S 2 " ?' 382 78 800 74 598 108 134 478 .58 417 Dakota City Mrs. Elizabeth Neiswanjrer 2.J99 330 3,863 9.3 298 12 351 145 51 233 .56 634 DeWltt Mrs. Hazel A: Bent 3&gt;39S 125 279 36 700 60 94 282 .63 633 Dodffc Mrs. Roy I,udden 1.2*3 423 3.866 6.6 109 37 150 49 65 115 .17 917 Elgin Mrs. It. D. Wilcox 2,707 11,216 12.2 300 73 373 150 120 373 .41 515 Elmwood Mrs. Karl E. Horton 979 485 52 177 .35 509 Elwood Mrs. I,ueila B. Dow 3,612 622 7,204 14.1 95 ... 121 109 114 .22 891 Emerson Mrs. F. 1,. Gibson 1.345 510 4.138 4.6 409 ... 409 158 120 4 409 .46 497 Eustis Mrs. A. 1,. Hathaway 1,832 223 6,679 13.4 106 230 656 158 563 1.11 825* Ewlncil .....Florence Ponton 1.334 425 1,311 1.6 J5B 6 266 ... 180 284 .8S 757 Fail-field Mrs. Alma Ewlng 3,784 250 4,026 5.3 506 41 1,065 46 420 598 79 740 Fairmont Zola It. Shoemaker ...... 3,860 600 6,825 9.2 250 52 302 45 96 246 JS 690 Ouide Rock {Catherine Guy 3,703 415 6,744 9.S 347 112 552 67 277 560 84 Stir, Harvard ; Mrs. Paul R. Whlscnand ; H Township libraries ■ — ■ • Includes township population 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">No. 6 j TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) Receipts expenditures X 863 Hay Springs Mra Mary C. Goff T^ti 222 3,145 3.7 %.... » 93 * 224 «... $180 ».... *TT 229 Hayes (Jenter Mrs. EJvalyn Barker 805 • 208 144 5 149 ... 60 138 .60 452 Homer Mrs. F. M. Church .... 2.448 300 3,811 8.4 120 986 Hooper Mrs. H. F. Waterman 2,641 583 6, HO 5.2 298 27 336 73 180 282 .29 946 Imperial Mrs. Norma Heebner 3,263 199 6,391 6.8 497 238 1,074 168 260 630 .67 864 Laurel R. L. LtfthroD 1,688 454 243 16 682 86 240 326 .38 692 Leigh Mrs. J. J, Tesar 1,362 5,025 7.3 325 ... 325 136 120 317 .46 187 Lewlston Wllla Glfford 1,536 311 3.139 16.8 100 85 185 113 52 179 .96 404 Lltchfleld 1.231 100 .... .... 155 436 Lodgepole Mrs. Frank Bngrlert 1.254 .... 1,825 4.2 .... 104 166 61 39 166 .88 937 Long Pine Mrs. M. J. Potter 969 Louisville Bedella Stander 3,366 .... 6,201 6.4 250 14 378 59 88 211 .22 985 Lyons FranWe I* Pwi'tJi 4.000 5,146 6.2 550 40 673 100 178 608 .62 362 Merriman Mrs. Esther F. Leach .... 1,210 .... 1,640 4.5 .... 32 245 51 96 187 .52 832 Mllford Mrs. L. S. Chamberlain .. 2.254 187 7,031 8.4 575 38 647 121 105 330 .40 676* Monroe! Beatrice Fleming 988 65 1,954 3.4 122 IB 210 48 72 120 .21 756 Morrm Alma Wlckman 3.224 590 7,946 10.5 285 80 1,211 216 245 601 .79 903 Nelson ' ' Alice B. Ruddell 2,600 693 197 110 364 115 121 .... 761 Nlobrara " ' "i.Elva Randa 1,198 400 6,730 8.8 148 37 220 201 .26 663 Oakdale '' " .Gertrude B. flovp 1.442 140 17 157 26 103 152 .23 544 Palmyra M.-b. S. Menrln 3,000 120 123 223 718 PamTVlon "" «• F. Klmr 2,144 805 2.780 3.9 120 28 120 155 .22 632 Polk "'Mm J. E. MoDaniol '.- ..•' WO Ponea Mrs. M. Llpe B.SIS 350 2,828 2.9 336 ... 336 ... 120 *.... KIR £„?*;». Mrs. W. T. Sloan 1.700 171 37 244 25 39 211 .41 474 Scotia Elisabeth Hlett 2.943 : 184 41 274 50 60 153 ..32 *M RMcHev" Mathilda Llchtl 1,442 .... 3.334 R. 6 200 11 272 132 51 198 50 90R« Silver Cr»»V» LuclßeAbel 3.R44 728 7.R94 8.7 1,000 ... 1.880 ... 360 1.083 1.19 458 SnySer ..: Mrs. Elmer SchlnWe SOl .... 1.064 2.3 100 20 120 18 30 90 ..29 83» sSaldlne"': :::::..: Mrs. Frank Dunning 2,772 I.OSB 9.423 11.2 182 105 326 ... 180 295 .35 419 Springfield Mrw. Vprlla Boicn I^. * Township library 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">No. 7 TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) ■ B Receipts Expenditures 702 Sterling Mrs. Mary R. Hollenback . 2,622 ~ 4^76 6l *300 $77! TTi TT! |24O jTT! ~ 663 Stratton Mrs. Ray Huffman 2,812 211 121 333 206 104 310 .47 763 Stuart Mrs. A. C. Bemer 150 ... 758 Sutherland Mrs. Jennettc Wilson 2,965 ... 7,430 11.2 ... 180 947 Syracuse Ruth Kramer 3.084 818 0,015 B.3 560 52 805 191 180 717 .76 673 Table Rock Mrs. Allle Wood 1,468 116 2,517 3.7 232 87 691 50 91 573 .85 474 Talmase Sophia Moller 1,776 300 2,847 C. 338 17 466 50 180 252 .63 865 Trenton Mrs. A. T. McCoy 2,696 214 5,811 C.7 . 100 58 182 150 ... 178 .21 623 Valparaiso Mrs. Madge Porter 2,077 125 40 171 40 77 165 .32 432 Waterloo Mrs. W. H. Jacobson 1,509 ... 2,602 C. 100 10 109 21 52 109 .25 723* Wllcoxf T -eah T.lppstrew 1,002 200 6 H56 129 93 264 .36 483 Winside .: .Mrs. Etta Pcrrln 2,550 500 3,418 7. 559 138 698 58 195 276 .67 .751 Wood River Snhra J. Abbott ■ ■■■■■■... 4. 258 3fi!&gt; 7.8!&gt;7 10.5 380 18 398 105 165 404 .54 t Township library " * Includes township population AMERICAN LIBRARY ASSOCIATION STANDARDS Percent of population Number of books rpplstpred ns borrowers lent per capita Cities of 200,000 to 1,000.000 Inhabitants. 30 7 Cities of 100,000 to 200,000 Inhabitants.... 35 8 Cities of 10,000 to 100,000 Inhabitants 40 . 9 Cities of lesR than 10,000 Inhabitants . BO 10 Minimum annual Inoomc — $1 per capita . Recommended division of total Income: Salaries (not Including Janitors, etc.) ;,..G5&lt;K Books, periodicals and binding . .Ke? r All other expenditures 20&lt;^, 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">STATE LIBRARIES ■ Department Location Volumes Librarian or Director Legislative Reference Bureau Lincoln 35,000* Edna D. Bullock Public Library Commission Lincoln 51,259 Nellie M.' Carey State Historical Society ..Lincoln 60,000 Mrs. C. S. Paine State Library Lincoln 106,233 George H. Turner U. S. GOVERNMENT HOSPITAL LIBRARY • Chiefly pamphlets and clippings Veterans' Administration Hospital Lincoln .-. Mrs. Grace Darby ~~ HIGH SCHOOL, COLLEGE AND UNIVERSARY LIBRARIES Alliance High School Alliance 1,800 Juanita Lang Beotrice Schools Junior High School Beatrice 2,000 Margaret E. Rutledge Senior High School Beatrice 2,300 Eula R. Merwin Broken Bow High School Broken Bow 3,250 Inez Dean Concordia Teachers College ...Seward 7,035 H. O. A. Keinath College of St. Mary ...Omaha 7,206 Sister "Therese Marie Columbus High School.: Columbus 1,989 Mary R. Rankin Creighton University Omaha 53,795 Mary C. Hunt Dana College : Blair 9,893 Sena Bertelsen Doane College Crete , 27,322 William B. Hunt Duchesne College Omaha 13,500 Katharine Kevin Fairtrary High School Fairbury 3,554 Robert L. Pullen Fremont High School Fremont 2,549 Ruth D. Harris Garden County High School Oshkosh 1,007 Daisy Novotny Gering High School Gering '. 2,300 Mrs. Amanda McHenry Grand Island Schools R. J. Barr Junior High School l...Grand Island 3,100 Catherine Glade Senior High School Grand Island. 4,690 Alice E. Paine 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">__ HIGH SCHOOL, COLLEGE AND UNIVERSITY LIBHARIES (Continued) Bchool Location Volumes Librarian Walnut Junior High School. ...Grand Island 5,000 Florence C Reese Hastings Collope .Hastings 25,140 Marguerite" Nesbit Hastings High Schools Hustings , 6,045 Glen H. James Hebron Junior College Helm,,, 3,770 Frieda Damrow Holdrege High School... Iloldrcge ..........:. 3,7,33 Mrs. Belva L. Melvin Hooper High 5ch001..... ...Hooper „ 1,025 Mrs. S. L. Whitcomb Kearney Schools Junior High School. Kenrncv ..,1,.;....,..; 2,000 Katharine Major Senior High School Kearney :......, 2,911 Lueile Hrubeskv Lincoln Schools Bethiiny High School Lincoln •&gt; 111", „ n ■, „ ~ n „ &#132;. ■ ... .„, , , .....'■» jf rs Q Ja( ]y S v an Camp College \iew High 5ch001......... .. Uncoil :,:.'.. 1800 pi mo p,,,,u Everett J.inio, High 5ch00........ Li,,,,,,, 'I^2 S Fr3&gt; thmZe Hayeiock II w h School L neoln .'i.SOO 1 ;, lian Griffiths Irv,ng Junior U^h School... ; ... .Lincoln ..,.;....,.... 2,900 Aimee Johnston Jnckson H.gh School ..Lmcoh, Arm Mur.son Uneoln High School.: , 1.i,,, ( ,1,, .;..; !...,. 6,709 Emma E. Snyder Wh.tt.cr Junior High School Lincoln &#132;,., 3.9J5 Anna H. Bethune Lexinston ,gh School ...Lexington 2.500 Jesse B. Thorpe /T n,, S ° ■• I " Ul|) City • - • ■ 3 ' 700 LLouies c Hilsabeck Luther College... _. WMhuo 0,000 Emma W. Peterson McCook Junior C011ege........ : McCook &#132;....;., Mrs. Noreen Anderson M,dland College. .[.&gt;„,„„, . ; . ..-. ■.;:„;..-. 15i840 Dorothy H _ Dysinscer Nebraska Central C011ege..... Centra! City : ...4,325 Milo H. Crosby Nebraska Wesleyan University,......:.,.,. ...Lincoln .....:.. 29,331 Mrs. Ethol Langdon Bishop Norfolk Senior High School.. ......Norfolk ....:.....,... 5,165 Mrs. Lora Heald 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">HIGH SCHOOL, COLLEGE AND UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES (Continued) School Location Volumes Librarian North Platte Schools Junior High School North Plntte Carol Wilder Senior High School North Platte 3,376 Velma Disbrow Omaha Schools Benson High School Omaha 5,293 Elsa Smith Central High School Omaha 25,000 Mrs. Hazel C. Stewart North High School Omnha 7,310 Catherine Nichol South High School Omaha 13,200 Ivae Walker Technical High School Omaha 19,207 May Ingles Omaha Municipal University Omahn 52,000 Robert F. Lane Oxford High School Oxford 1,596 Vera Quig Scottsbluff High School Scottsbluff 3,000 Ethel Pflug Sidney High School Sidney 2,800 Verna Robinson State Teachers College Chadron 23.700 Harriet P. Wirick State Teachers College Kearnov ...., 32,748 Anna V. Jennings State Teachers College ..Peru 45,893 Grace M. Petersen State Teachers CoUege Wayne 26,285 M. Lois Crouch Superior High School Superior 1,600 Irene Underwood - — «..•'" Union College Lincoln 24,000 D. Glen Hilts \. University of Nebraska Lincoln 327,500 Robert A. Miller York High School York Jessie Stewart York College York .....13,925 Edith M. Cone 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">LIBRARIES NOT TAX- SUPPORTED m th?St'3 tex N s ÜbraSi?U braSi ?, a .I?* B ."™*" o* Varies not included £~ sir jst- Brock Decatur Nehawka BrownvUle Dorchester Nemaha Bruning Douglas n^ &amp; Anje t Oak^ Edton S Bartlett E, m Creek ? a t er Bassett Ericson PaTton Batt,e Creek Exeter ?r,^ n Belvidere Grant Primrose Benkelman Qresham Ra]ston B™ Gretna Republican City Ber^n Haigler * BurSpnng. H alsey Rosal i c V Bmrtam Hardy Royal Bloon»n B ton Henderson Ruskin B «tte Herman Salem Campbell Hildreth Shubprt Carleton Holbrook Snyder Chambers Howells Stapleton as..-, ssu .;■ ,-s ■ Cody J Hyannis Tobias Concord Indianola Uehlin^ Cook Ithaca Verdißre Crab Orchard Keystone Waco „"** Lindsay Wauneta Creston Madrid Western Melbeta 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p036"/>
            <seg id="p037"/>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039"/>
            <seg id="p040"/>
            <seg id="p041"/>
            <seg id="p042"/>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>