<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00024.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00024.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>REPORT OF The Nebraska Prison Association For the Year 1909</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">REPORT OF The Nebraska Prison Association For the Year 1909 December 31, 1909 Lincoln, Nebr. &lt;• </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OFFICERS PRESIDENT Honorable If. R Reese VICE-PRESIDENTS Hon. A. 8. Tibbets I Ion. A. J. Sawvcr Hon. George A. Adams Hon. Victor Roaewater SECRETARY-TREASURER A. E. Darinon SUPERINTENDENTS Rev. M. A. Bullock, D. D. Captain W. M. Clifford </seg>
            <seg id="p003">I) COMMITTEES Rev. If. A. Hullock, I). I). II«n. A. S. Tibbefa Hon. C. F. Ilarphaiu FINANCE .1. R. Hazard, IL D. Hun. If. J. Wangfa Hun. .1. K. Miller Hun. II. V. Iloagland Hun. ('. F. Ilarpliam A. K. Davissun CRIMES AND LAWS I Ion. Geoge A. Adams Judge A. S. Tililxts II. ii. J. K. Miller VISITATION AND DISCHARGES Rev. It A. Hull.iok. I). I)., Chairman Mrs. Margaret Carnes, Sec- Mrs. Elizabeth Oifford Hon. T. W. Smith Rev. J. W. Jones 1). Rev. II. II. Harmon, D. D. Mr. A. E. Howard Rev. Father W. W. Bradley Captain W. M- OitWd EXECUTIVE Hon. Geope A. A&lt;l;iiiH I). II. ,n. M. .1. Wu.ifrl. IIuu. .1. E. Miller A. EL Davissmi linn. A. .1. Sawyer </seg>
            <seg id="p004">BOARD OF DIRECTORS Hon. XI. B. Reese Hon. M. J. Waugh Hon. J. E. Miller Dr. IT. B. Lowry Dr. P. ('. Jokmmm Hon. H. V. Hoagland Captain W. ML Giflord Mr. W. E. Hardv Hon. Geotge A. Adams XIr. C. F. Harphain Rev. M. A. Bullock, D. D. Dr. J. R. Haggard Hun. J. A. Piper Mr. A. E. Davisson Mr. E. C. Bruce Hon. F. L. Halfer Mr. P&gt;. Boamthal Mr. W. H. Ferguson Hon. A. J. Sawyer Hon. Victor Rosewater XIr. E. J. Wightman Kev. B. XI. Long, D. D. XIr. E. R. Gurney Rev. H. U. Harmon, D. 1&gt;. Rev. J. \Y. Jones, I). D. Rev. Father W. W. Bradley Hun. Paul Jessen Hon. W. J. Bryan Hon. G. \Y. Wattle Mr. E. W. Dixon Hon. W. T. Aiild Hon. T. W. Smith Mr. H. J. Xichols Hon. A. S. Tibbets Rev. 8. Mills Haves, 1). I). </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Nebraska Prison Association LINCOLN. NEBRASKA The Nebraska Prison association was organized on May 2, J!M)2 for the pflrpoie of helping discharged priaonen to secure jx.sitions where they may earn an honest living; to give them the glad hand, say the helpful word, inspire in their hearts, on c more, hoj&gt;e, and make them feel tliat they have a chance to h ■- come respected citizens. The association U also interested in pris - on reform work and in all things which pertain to the rescue of men and women from the criminal classes. It takes a deep interest in the prevention of crime, in the protection of society, in the physical condition and moral envin nment of jails and reformatories in the state, and in the state |&gt;eniteutiary. Xat:ir - iillv its larger work is in eouMetii n with the state penitentiary and in securing employment for the discharged prisoners. There are three classes of men in the st;ite penitentiary; the confirmed criminal who cares little, if any, for help ; the man who has means and friends and knows where he is going when discharged anil desires no help; and the unfortunate man who may not be at heart a criminal, but is suffering for his first wrongdoing. This last class represents the men who are assisted by the association. If they have friends and are unable to reach them they are sent to them. If they have no friends to whom to go and desire work, work is provided for them by the superintendent. To do this often requires considerable correspondence or perafMul soli - citation, but the work is found. The question is sometimes a»ked, "How do you find out what the men want ?" This is done by the committee on visitation and discharges, two or more of whom visit the penitentiary each month, have personal inter- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">r, rim with the prisoners who will be discharged the coming month, direct those asking help to the office of the association vhere the siijx'rintendent meets them as they are discharged and remit them to the place provided. The association has nothing to do with politics nor the pr &lt;if the courts, except to work in conjunction with the courts in of suspended sentence and in such other ways as would make it a helpful agent in the betterment of the condition of the unfortunate class who are in prison or in danger of becoming convicted criminals. The organization has been the means of iulping between four and five hundred prisoners since its organ - ization. Many of these are now in honorable positions, earning a living and making for themselves a good name. In helping these men and women the association has doubtless saved the state thousands of dollars which otherwise would have been spent in the criminal courts; but, letter .still, it has been the means of rescuing these pamM from the criminal class and helping them to become producers of wealth instead of destrnv - ers of property. In doing these things the association has also been an efficient agent in protecting society and, it may be, sav - ing human life as well as property. The association has not, however, sought the public eye. For obvious reasons it has done its work quietly and with little, if r.ny, publicity. Its former superintendent, Dr. George W. Martin, was exceptionally efficient in the work. Since his death last July the work has been in charge of the assistant superin - tendent and the chairman of the committee on visitation and discharges. The character of the association will be recognized by the personnel of the board of directors and officers elected at the an - nual meeting last Monday. The organization is meeting, as effi - ciently as it can, a great need in our social system. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 PRESIDENT'S REPORT To the Board of Directors and MembeN of the Nebraska Prison Association : Another year has passed befonj us in review and has gone to Ix-coinc a part of the Eternity of history. Neither it nor the ♦■vents contained within it can ever 1&gt;;- recalled. It ha* carried vith it the blessings, the joys, the sorrows, the errors, the mis - takes and the crimes of its days. What humanity has enjoyed, -suffered and perpetrated within that time may long l&gt;e remem - bered, but never repeated. The books are made up and the balance has been struck. No change or amendment can ever be made. The judgment has been fully entered of record and must and will stand unappealed from, unrepealed and uniin - pt ached. A retrospect is always profitable if made from good motives and in the right spirit; the principal benefit being the oppor - tunity given which will, or may, enable each to avoid the pit - falls, snags and dangers which constantly beset the pathway of man. This is one of the main objects and purjxKses of on ciatiou — not to remind others of their faults, shortcomings and crimes, but to lead them away from the temptations by which they would otherwise l&gt;e surrounded and to point and assist them \o a higher, better and holier life; to induce the wayward to guide his life by higher and loftier motives, the ciminal to seek forgiveness for past offenses and establish his lines on the basis of righteousness and correct living; to induce them to realize and understand that they were created in the image of their Creator and that they can yet arise to the state from which they have fallen. These are some of the objects and purposes of our association. The reports of the officers and committees will inform you as to what has been done during the last year. How we have vis- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 i;ed and encouraged those who were in need of our advice and iissistiincc. How some have been induced to prefer the ways of the law-abiding citizen and leave our prisons reformed and on the right road to honorable citizenship instead of pursuing the road of the law-breaker and out-law. A men intimate acquaint - ance with those who have been so unfortunate M to "go wrong" and suffer the penalties of the law will demonstrate that they are not all essentially bad. Many have made mistakes, and, in tx.ine degree, unwillingly violated the law without any deliber - ately formed purpose of injuring anyone or their property rights. Those are usually young men and are, in a sense, suffer - ing unjustly. As a general rule such are quite ready to accept tnd receive our aid and re-adopt habits of correct living. A shurt time ago the b:&gt;ard of directors received information that many of the inmates of the state prison had received in - correct information as to the objects of this association. They had been informed that our purpose was not to reform or aid, lint to secure the reimprisonment of those who were discharged and, therefore, tl.ey hestitated to accept our assistance, fearing the absence of good faith on our part. Acting upon this in - formation the board requested me to go to the prison on a suit - able occasion and represent to those there confined the objects and aims of our association. I did so ard was well received by the warden, the chaplain and all the prisoners present which, I think, included all except two. 1 met them in the chapel at the usual Sunday morning service; the chaplain giving me the whole of the time usually taken by him in delivering his sermon, and I am persuaded that my efforts have borne and will bear good fruit. I cheerfully commend tlie management of the prisoners by the warden. He appears to be actuated by motives of phil - anthropy and an intense desire to render the penitentiary a re - formatory for those who can be reformed, instead of a place for coercion and punishment. I think he should receive the sup - port of our association in all his good endeavors. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 • V During the last year the hand of death has fallen apon a number of our best and most effective workers ami mftporteML Ainouj; those who have fallen I mention Rev. Dr. QeotgB W. Martin, our worthy and efficient sui&gt;erintendent. He was. in truth and faet, a most faithful man. Prompted by no selfish motives, his highest aim was to render the world better bv his having been a part of it. His great effort was to kelp, aid and .i-sist those who stood in need of assistance. His pathway is strewn by the thanks and blessings of the hundreds of men who, through his instrumentality, are today engaged in honorable employment and are enjoying the confidence and esteem of their fellow men. We cherish the memory of Dr. Martin. He had his foibles — who has aotl He made mistakes — who does not '. lie has suffered the foul sting of slander, but where is the man &lt;&gt;r woman engaged in fighting evil who has not. Our records and the memory of his associates and those whom he assisted will c institute his ini]&gt;erishable monument. Warden Heemer was known to you all. Faithful, true, reli - able, kind in spirit, yet firm in discipline, he seemed to I. pecially fitted and prepared by nature for the position he tilled &gt;«o well. His death occurred at the close of his stewardship, before the time for leaving li is post of duty, but I think he died i:i the belief that the work of reformation so well began by him would be followed up and, if need l&gt;e, improved upon by his successor. It would be impossible for me, in this rejx&gt;rt, to itemize or specially name flu- reforms inaugurated by Warden Ueemer. The stripes, the lockstep, the hand-out meal anil many other relics of barbarism are no longer disgracing our state prison. To Warden Beemer and to his memory belongs much of the credit. Judge Crounse and former Governor Povnter of our board have also answered their last summons on earth. While not to actively and publicly engaged in our great work of reform as some, yet they gave their hearty support to all our </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 efforts and the association was, in Urge degree, benefited there - by. We can but revere and cherish the memory of those men. We would not do otherwise if we could. They were worthy and what they did was for the good of humanity and their work will long be reniemlH'red and recognized. The regular annual meeting of the Xational Prison Congress will not be held as an indepudent organization this year, as it has been wisely decided that the meeting be held in connection with the International Prison Association which will be in ■wioti In Washington city in the month of October. At some suitable lime, either now or hereafter, we should select a delegate or delegates to that assembly. As to the time when you should take this action I shall not advise, but suggest that a delegate lje elected and provided with the necessary funds to defray proper and necessary expen.-t Respectfully submitted, M. B. REESE, President. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 ■* SUPERINTENDENTS' REPORT Lincoln, Nebraska, Jan. 10, 1910. Mr. President : The first six months of the year l'.tOit Dr. GeOffgB \V. Martin was sii]&gt;erintendent of tlie Nebraska Prison Association. His severe illness early in the spring incapacitated him from active service and most of the work was assumed bv ('apt. W. If. Gilford, the assistant sii]M-rintendent. So far as we have been able to find the records of these months, six prison - ers were helped to places by the association. There may have ben more, bur if so the record was nut found HMg Dr. Mar - 1 in's pajK'rs. The new parole law has much to do with the com - paratively small number assisted during the year, as the pris - oners when paroled were quite generally provided for Ix-fore the lime of their discharge, and those who remained in prison until the time of their discharge represented the class most difficult to provide for, and the class who did not want help. The death of our lamented sujK'rintendent, Dr. Martin, was ;; ~evere blow to the association for he had its interests at heart, .»nd had a happy faculty of getting on with the boys in prison, securing their confidence and providing places for them. It takes time and e.\]&gt;erience as well as natural tact to become as profi - cient in these things as was Dr. Martin. His death occurred just on the eve of the July meeting of the Board of Directors. By vote of the Board of Directors, the Assistant Su]&gt;erin - tendent and Chairman of the Committee on Visitation and Dis - charges were made acting joint superintendents in charge of the work. They have served the association as best they could, de - \oting to it such time as busy men could give and have sought to avoid neglecting any duty. They have found employment for all the men who asked for it and have helped others to their destination outside of the state. It should be said however that several of the men for whom places were found failed to come </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 to the office as they promised, to meet us that we might direct them to the places secured. Some had found employment through personal friends, torn* had received money to take them to their homes or to friends who were interested in them, and others for reasons unknown failed to come for work after it had l&gt;;t'ii secured for them. We recall two men who, unles&lt; they could have railroad switching did not want work. Wo could not get for them the but offered them other work which they declined. At no little effort we secured carpenter work, at good pay, for one man, who especially wanted such employment and when I he time came for his freedom he failed to come for his job. It is supposed that his wife came for him, as he thought she might, with some money, and the longing to get away from the near environment of his prison life was greater than the desire for immediate employment These incidents help to show some of the difficulties which we have in trying to provide work for the men. We have found employment duing the past year for twenty six men, and assisted eight men to go where they could get work in other states. It was thought at first when so many of the men failed to come for the help which we had secured for them, that some person or persons were circulating malicious stories about the object of our association, claiming that we put the police on the track of the men. It is now very evident that such falsehoods were circulated and that many of the prisoners looked upon us with suspicion. We have been informed as to the origin of these report*, and some of the prisoners freely talked with us about them. Recently our president, Judge Reese, visited the penitentiary and talked to the men on a Sunday morning and explained fully the object of our association, and since then we have noticed a marked difference in the way the men have received us, and the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 frank way in which they express themselves, their suspicions having been removed. We wish also to express nnr gratification for the cordial way~ in which Warden Smith and Deputy Delahunter receive us and c!o all they can to help us in die work we are trying to do for the discharged prisoner*. We give below extacts from letters received from discharged prisoners : June 25, 1909. W. -M. Gifford, Kind Friend and Sir: I arrived home this morning at seven - forty and believe me, I cannot express in words of writing how thankful I am to you in so aiding me to get here. I am very tired but exceedingly happy. 1 do not intend to try to begin work until a week from Monday, and it will be with the great - est pleasure my first act to write to you when I go to work. With the best wishes to you and your great organization of which you are the assistant superintendent, and trusting that our beloved friend Dr. Martin will somehow pull through, I remain, Yours Most Sincerely, )&gt; Aiidther writer — "I have been trying to look up my folks but they are not here now, and I don't know just where they have gone. I thank you very much for your good opinion of me and I will try to conduct myself in the future in such a way that von will be justified in having it. «&gt; Such letters which come to us from time to time are the re - ward in part for a work which is done in large measure quietly and unobserved by the general public. We deem it a great saving to the state as well as a benefit to the individual when we help even one man to redeem himself and become an honest and productive citizen of the state. It is a source of gratifica - tion that not only one man but many have thus been helped by the Nebraska Prison Association. ____ __ _ T _,_.^,,^ WILL M. GIFFORD, Superintendents. M. A. BULLOCK, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 IN MEMORIAM. In recognition of the services of Dr. G. W. Martin, gal - lant soldier, pioneer minister in Nebraska, the founder of pris - on reform in Nebraska, organizer of the Nebraska Prison Ass. &gt; ciation — one who has, in the last seven years, taken by the hand more than a thousand men whose feet had slipped from the highway trodden by those who are law-abiding citizens in - to the mire of lawlessness and crime, the Nebraska Prison ftfi ciation has, by action of its Board of Directors at the regular quarterly meeting held July 6, 1909, ordered the following memoranda to be made : Dr. Martin's life was remarkable because he was one of the first of those who heard the call to preserve the flag in its pris - tine glory and to make the union of the states a reality. When Nebraska was in peril, because of a threatened In - dian uprising, Dr. Martin by his services to the state in pre - serving it from harm, made himself one of those to whom Ne - braska owes much. To his own church, Dr. Martin gave distinguished and efficient services. To his ears first came, so far as heeding the cry was con - cerned, the voices of those who because of adverse circum - stances, weak wills, or deliberate intention, incurred the law's displeasure and its penalties. To them he gave his heart — not condoning their lapses from the path of rectitude but to show forth a spirit of helpfulness that would enable them to return to the ranks of those who are called good citizens. He thus exemplified the spirit of Him who said, "Inasmuch as ye have done it unto the least of these my brethren ye have done it unto me." By them he was loved. Their hearts paid tribute to him. To him they looked not in vain for counsel and for help. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 They mourn him because in the busy rush of modern life, in the decadence of altruism, he recognized in all their force the Fatherhood of God and the brotherhood of man. It may be that persons exist who, because of their pride of place and the fortunate spheres in which the lines of their lives have been cast, will not miss Dr. Martin but these "little ones" who felt the brotherly touch of his hand, who have heard the tones of his voice encouraging them to strive to return to the ranks of law abiding citizens will mourn him and refuse to be comforted. Dr. Martin was a man like Abou Ben Adhem of whom i.eigh Hunt said : "Abou Ben Adhem (may his tribe increase,) Awoke one night from a deep dream of peace, And saw within the moonlight in his room. Making it rich and like a lily in bloom. An angel writing in a book of gold: Exceeding peace had made Ben Adhem bold. And to the presence in the room he said, 'What writest thou?' The vision raised its head, Answered, 'The names of those that love the Lord." 'And is mine one?' said Abou. 'Nay, not so,' Replied the angel. Abou spoke more low. But cheerly still: and said, 'I pray thee, then, Write me as one that loves his fellow-men.' 'ihe angel wrote, and vanished. The next night It came again, with a great wakening light, And showed the names of those whom love of God had blessed, — And, lo! Ben Ad hem's name led all the rest!" It may indeed be said of Dr. Martin, he was one whom "love of God had blessed." </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 TREASURER'S REPORT January 4, 1910. To the Pesident and Board of Directors of the Nebraska Prison Association. Gentlemen : I beg leave to submit my annual report as Treas - urer of the Nebraska Prison Association. Amount of money on hand January 1, 1909 $ 455.36 Amount of money collected in 1909 1007.00 Total resources for the year 1909 $1462.36 Total expenditures for the year 1909 1023.05 Amount of money on hand January 1, 1910 $ 439.31 The members of the Finance Committee make the following statement : This certifies that we, members of the Finance Committee of the Nebraska Prison Association, have carefully audited the books of Treasurer A. E. Davisson and find them well kept and correct. We also certify that the amount of money reported is actually in the possession of said officer." Signed, J. R. HAGGARD, Chairman. M. J. WAUGH, C. F. HARPHAM, J. E. MILLER All of which is respectfully submitted A. E. DAVISSON, Secretary -Treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 SUBSCRIBERS TO AND MEMBERS OF THE NEBRASKA PRISON ASSOCIATION 19O9 Henkle Joyce Hdw. Co. II. K. Burkett Farmers &amp; Merchant* Hank George E. Haskell Mrs. Margaret Carnes L M. Keene State Journal Compaaj W. C Wilson Col. F. M. Woo. is Peter MeNioo] C. C. Quiggle A. J. Sawyer E. B. Andrews M. J. Waugh Harpham Bros. E. R. Gurne.v W. J. Brvan A. II. Armstrong L C Burr A. W. Clarke Woods Invcstinciit C«v H. J. Nichols T. L. Root A. L. Hoover &lt;ir Son C. H. Morrill A. C. Shallenber»:ir II. V. Iloagland Willard E. Stewart \Y. I). Conist«K-k George Bros. A. R. Talbot McVey Ptg. Co. E. R. Sizer A. S. TiblKM^ F. M. Tyreil F. Jouvenat W. M. Leonard (i. A. Adams Charles Strader W. E. Barkeley J. R. Haggard M. W. Folsom L. D. Woodruff Guy W. Green OL J. Guenzel H. II. Harmon H. C. Lindsav Xebraska Paper k Bag ('&lt;• J. E. Miller J. L MePlieely J. M. Armstrong ('. M. Branson Julius Keusch Htl|mwi Mercantile ('■&gt;. Thomas C. Munjier W. T. Aiild J. M. Stewart P. L. Hall </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 A. C. Townsend Dr. H. B. Lowry W. G. Roberts O. J. King &amp; Son Castle, Roper k Mattbewt II. Herpolsheimer &amp; Co. Security Investment Co. W. H. Wallace A. 1). Benway Co. Omaha Packing Co. The Nebraska Teacher G. \V. Holdrege W. E. Hardy Clarkson State Bank R. S. Poudfit }I. A. Bullock Lincoln Gas k Electric Light First Nat'l Bank — Lincoln \V. C. Shinn C. E. Lawrence The Nebraska Fanner (V Silas R. Bartoi E. Royce Swift &amp; Co. Victor Rosewater E. B. Cowlos Paul Jessen Korsmeyer Co. Gillen A: Boney Thompson Hotel Co. E. J. Wightman E. W. Dixon TlioiTpson k Belden The People's Store Tlios. Kilpatrick Co. .1. L. Brandeis &amp;: S. n W. Davidson Hall Bros. Hdw. Co. Globe Delivery Co. Dre. Orr k Pojator A. E. Howard Landy Clark J. H. Millard Beebe k Kiinvan M. E. Smith k Co. Merchants Bank — Winsido J. A. Piper K. C. Hurd Bryne Hammer Drv Good* Co. Lininger Implement Co. National Ptg. Ca Clay Robinson k Co. W. J. Blystone McCord Brady Co. II. O. Barber &amp; Sons W. G. Whitmore I'nion Stock Yds. Natl. Dank Wood Bros. Co. Roscnbaum Bros, k Co. (icorge W. Bonnell E. R. Gurney Martin Bros. &amp; Co. Omaha Printing (V Paxtnn &amp; Gallagher Co. E. E. Bruce Armour &amp; Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 o, Curtis Towle &amp; Paine J. W. McDonald . \ . Lewis W. II. Ferguaon F. II. Woo* 15. M. Long W. A. Selleck .1. .L. McBrien J. B. Barnes C. E. Haynie II. E. Byram W. M. Gitford G. W. Wattles ('. II. Boyle Journal-Stockman Co. Charles F. Manucison T. W. Smith L. ('. Paulson Griswold Seed Co. E. C. Bishop Fanicrs 4: Mor. Ins. t C. B. Letton i'r. A. P. Furfrason II. Porter A. L. Johnson E. J. Hainer A. E. Davisson William Wallace Henry Sevmnur Hon.' II. B. R« Mrs. Georsn&gt; W. Martin I lav ward Bros. Shoe Co. G. II. Payne P. ( '. Johnson J. W. Jones II. P. Hanson \V. K. Sharp </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>