<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00025</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eighteenth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Nebraska Home for Dependent Children</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Eighteenth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska Home for Dependent Children LINCOLN. NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">564 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS Amy V. Stevens Superintendent and State Agent B. A. Finki.e Physician Blanche M. Him Secretary and Bookkeeper Minnie McMahox Matron EMPLOYEES Mollie Oldberg Day Baby Nurse Rebecca Bkeidexstein Night Baby Nurse Emma K. Graves General Nurse Mart E. Hoixahax Girls' Governess Anna Franxis Boys' Governess Bbidget Kilcoy.xe Dining-room Girl Liljje McGoogan Seamstress </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 565 NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To hi* Excellency, Honorable Keith "Seville, Governor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Commix - mixxionerx of State Institutions, Henry denies, Silas A. Ifoleomb, and Eugene 0. Mayfield. Gentlemen: I hereby submit to you the eighteenth biennial report of the Nebraska Home for Dependent Children, covering the period from December 1, 1916, to November 30, 1918. EXECUTIVE AND STAFF CHANGES Several changes have taken place during the past biennium. Miss Etta Caton, who had served as State Agent since September, 1909, was relieved from duty in April, 1917. She was succeeded on May 1, 1917, by Dr. W. H. Crutcher, who was appointed Superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital and Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. Mrs. Carrie M. Benbrook, matron of the Ortho - pedic Hospital, was asked to serve as matron of this in - stitution also. On May 1, 1917, the writer, who had assisted Miss Caton since September, 1909, was appointed State Agent and was to assume the responsibility of receiving and plac - ing all children. Dr. W. H. Crutcher found the work of superintending both institutions too heavy. He retired as superintendent of the "Home" June 1, 1918, but attended to the physical needs of the children until September 20, 1918, when Dr. B. A. Finkle was appointed. The vacancy created by the resignation of Dr. W. H. Crutcher was filled on June 1, 1918, by Miss Amy V. Stevens. Aside from the changes made in the executive head of our institution we have had five different matrons and three different secretaries during the biennium. These changes have left their effect upon the work. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">566 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF OUR NEW HOME Iii 1914 the Legislature appropriated $27,500.00 for the construction and furnishing of a new building near the Orthopedic Hospital with the view of bringing together all the dependent children who for the past five years had been boarded in private residences throughout Lincoln and its suburbs. The building was completed in February, 1917. However, it was not completely furnished so that it was impossible to gather the children in at once. By May 1st all had been removed from their boarding homes and pro - vided for in the institution. The building is a reinforced concrete, fire proof struc - ture 69x85 feet. It consists of four floors occupied as fol - lows: 1st floor, serving kitchen, children's dining room, boys' and girls' play rooms, dry storage rooms; 2nd floor, girls' dormitory with dressing room, bath and toilet and girls' governess room adjoining, general reception room, em - ployees' and officers' dining room, matron's office and super - intendent's offices and apartments; 3rd floor, boys' dormi - tory upon the same plan as the girls', guest rooms, officers' apartments, nursery, sun parlor and diet kitchen; 4th floor, sewing room, general store room and employees' rooms. There is a large porch at the front of the building and two at the rear. There is no kitchen at the Nebraska Home for De - pendent Children. Owing to the close proximity of the Orthopedic Hospital, food is prepared and cooked in their kitchen. At the time our building was constructed it was considered more economical to have the one kitchen supply food for both institutions and to have an underground tunnel connecting the two institutions. The tunnel has not been built so the food is transferred in a cart. The arrange - ment has not proven very satisfactory as it is impossible to get the food over in good condition in cold and stormy weather. The Orthopedic Hospital supplies our building with heat and also does our laundry work. All our sick people are cared for in their hospital. The building is lighted by electricity supplied by the State Penitentiary. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 567 PURPOSE OF THE INSTITUTION The purpose of the institution is to care for all children under sixteen years of age, who are dependent for support, neglected, abandoned or ill-treated, who have been perma - nently committed to its care by any juvenile court, district or county court acting under the juvenile court law. The institution also provides for the care of children who are received as temporary wards. The Board has the power at its discretion to receive such children upon the payment of their board and care from their legal guardian or in case the legal guardian is unable to pay the county commissioners assume the responsibility of the child's main - tenance. Such children are not subject to adoption but are kept in the institution until some other arrangement is made for their care. During the biennium we have received $2439.82 for the board and care of temporary wards. We have found it much more convenient to care for the children in the institution and have been able to place them out in permanent family homes more readily. It also gives us the opportunity of making a more careful study of the child, to build him up physically, socially and morally. The child is now under our immediate supervision so that we learn to know the individual child better, hence, can prepare him more quickly for his permanent home. In order to do good child placing it is necessary to know the child as well as the home in which he is to be placed. EDUCATIONAL AND RELIGIOUS TRAINING The children while living in the institution attend a public school which is about three blocks distant. We consider it much better for the child to attend the public school. He takes more interest in his work and has the opportunity of meeting and associating with other children. Miss Lena Merrill, principal of the Saratoga school, where our children attend, and her corps of teachers have been most faithful in co-operating with us in the teaching and training of our children. On account of the movement of our population and the contagious diseases in the insti- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">568 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF tution, the attendance at school is necessarily quite irreg - ular. The children also go outside of the institution to attend Sunday school and church. ENTERTAINMENT Diversions are provided for the children in various ways. Our children have attended the state fair each year and were taken to the two best circuses which came to town during the biennium. Occasional entertainments are given by visitors and a program in which each child takes part is given upon special holidays, such as Christmas, Thanks - giving, Hallowe'en and the Fourth of July. IMPROVEMENTS Even though our building is new it has been necessary to have a great deal of work done upon it. Several clothes closets and medicine chests have been built. Tiling has been laid under ground from all drains and connected with the common sewer. The grounds have been graded and enclosed with heavy steel wire fencing. Cement walks were laid to the front, side and rear of the building. There has also been a large cement floor laid underneath the rear porch which has added greatly to the sanitary condition of the grounds. Three drinking fountains have been installed and the drinking cup abolished. A new play ground outfit consist - ing of see-saw, slide and swings made of heavy steel piping has been installed upon the play ground. This was pur - chased with the gift of $100.00 from Elsie Murphy, a good friend of the children. New trapeze and turning poles have been purchased and will be installed in the boys' play room. The interior of the building, aside from a few rooms on the fourth floor, has been painted and most of the wood work done over. The building at present is in good condition and it is our thought to keep it so. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 569 PLACING OF CHILDREN The state agent, who at the present time is superintend - ent of the Home," is authorized to consent to the adoption of any child who has been committed to the state as a permanent ward. These children are placed in suitable family homes as soon as possible after they are received into the institution. If all the children received were normal it would be quite an easy matter to place them. We have a few children who really belong in an institution. By this I mean the child who is slow mentally, who lacks the ability to distinguish right from wrong. He is not feeble-minded nor is he delinquent, but he does not fit into the family home, as he is unable to withstand temptation and, if placed, is sure to be returned within a short time. We find that such children are especially gifted in music and art and many of them are natural mechanics. If they could be given special instruction along such lines they would no doubt be artists in their profession. During the biennium we have placed 382 children and out of this number 277 have kept their home. There have been 100 adoptions completed and 11 contracts signed. Twenty children were returned to their parents or friends, 20 transferred to other institutions, 21 died, 29 reached their majority and 2 married before they reached their majority. INVESTIGATION OF HOMES A careful investigation is made of a home before a child is placed. Care is also exercised by the institution to place the right child in the right home. All children are placed on four months trial, after which time if every - thing is satisfactory some permanent arrangement is made for the child to remain in the home. The younger children are always adopted but the older ones are simply taken into the home as a member of the family and we expec* them to be treated as such. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF During the biennium we have had 731 applications to take children. Of this number 104 were withdrawn, 99 were rejected. We investigated 382 homes into which chil - dren were placed. FIELD WORK Our field work has been somewhat handicapped on account of not having a worker in the field all the time. However, we have all worked hard and given as much time and thought to the field work as possible. It is quite important that we have a good, conscientious worker in the field all the time. I recommend that an appropriation be made for the salary of a worker who can spend as much time as needed in the field. It is too much for one person to assume the responsibility of the institution and field work alone. During the biennium we have visited 374 homes into which children have been placed. Paid 472 visits to chil - dren and called upon 154 while they were in attendance at school. PLANS FOR THE FUTURE It is very necessary that we have an isolation cottage erected close to the "Home" to be used as a receiving cottage for the children when admitted. We receive chil - dren from all over the state and many of them have been exposed to some contagious disease and no matter how cautious we are in receiving them and disinfecting their clothing we will have more or less of the exanthematous diseases. In order to build an isolation cottage we must have more ground. I would recommend that the two lots just north of the "Home" be purchased and the cottage erected. If the Orthopedic Hospital is to supply our institution with food, we should have an underground tunnel con - necting the two institutions. However, we are asking for an appropriation of $1000.00 to build and equip a new kitchen at our institution. We feel that it would be much more satisfactory to have our cooking done in our own </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 571 institution as the food could be served while hot and would be much more wholesome. Below is a brief and itemized survey of appropriations required for the biennium beginning April 1, 1919, and ending March 31, 1921. For salaries and wages $15,000.00 $63,100.00 CONCLUSION I desire at this time to give full credit to my faithful officers and employees who have ably and conscientiously assisted me in the care and training of the children en - trusted to our care. Dr. A. B. Finkle, our physician, has given most excel - lent care to our sick ones. During the influenza epidemic he cared for forty-five of our people who were stricken with the disease and not one case resulted seriously. In every way he and his assistants have co-operated with us in the care of our sick and I wish to assure them that their services are greatly appreciated. I wish to thank you, Honorable Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, for your wise counsel and advice, kind treatment and the interest you have taken in our institution and children. You have done much for us during the past biennium and I know you will consider wisely our needs for the future. Respectfully submitted Amy V. Stevens Superintendent. Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. General repairs 1,000.0( Traveling expenses 3,500.0( Other maintenance 32.000.0C Furniture and equipment (furnishing and equipping new kitchen ) 1.000.0C Improvements to buildings and grounds (enclosing second story porch in rear of building) 600. (it New building (receiving cottage) 5.000.0C Land 5.000.0C </seg>
            <seg id="p010">572 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE INMATES' FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918 Note— These are the personal funds of the Inmates held in trust by the Institution (or these inmates and received and expended tor their sole benefit. Approximate average number of accounts December 1, 1916 to December 1, 1918, was 40. PERIOD Debits Credits Ledger eredit balanee on hand December 1, 1916, (615.30 December, 1916 January, 1917 . February, 1917 March. 1917 December, 1916 I .15 I .05 59.41 9.72 28.88 18.38 I -ii | .05 59.41 9.72 January. 1917 February, 1917 28.88 18.38 March. 1917 2.37 237 April, 1917. May, 1917 June, 1917 July, 1917. . August, 1917 April, 1917 .26 10.00 44.31 17.80 30.25 51.50 60.87 114.43 49.01 16.69 12.»5 58.36 .26 10.00 May, 1917 44.31 17.80 June, 1917 30.25 51.50 July, 1917 60.87 1U.4.-I August, 1917 49.01 16.69 September, 1917 October. 1917 November, 1917 September, 1917... 12.95 58.36 October. 1917 8.06 15.30 14. 96 37.04 8.06 15.30 November, 1917 Tout for year 14.9* 37.04 Tout for year $ 309.31 ! $ 361.64 $ 309.31 * 351.64 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1917, $657.63. Ledger eredit balance on hand December 1, 1917, $657.63. December, 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 March. 1918 ... December, 1917 S 41.87 $ 4.60 $ 41.87 $ 4.60 LSI 36.75 13.44 38.76 120.85 2133 1.91 36.75 January, 1918 February, 1918 13.44 38.76 March, 1918 120.85 21.33 April, 1918. May, 1918 June, 1918 July, 1918. . August, 1918 April, 1918 4.54 3.54 7.55 15.66 9.24 2334 16.26 29.02 4.64 8.54 May, 1918 7.55 15.66 9.24 23.34 June, 1918 July, 1918 16.26 29.02 8.20 39.12 Aufust, 1918 8.20 39.12 15.64 18.41 ttM 32.22 20.88 in.21 September, 1918. . . September, 1918 October, 1918 November, 1918 15.64 18.41 October, 1918 ttM 32.22 20.88 10.21 November, 1918 Total for year Total for year $ 28126 % 272.96 $ 28126 $ 272.96 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, $64933. Grand total for two years $ 657.63 $ 64933 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 573 RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918 AMOUNTS RECEIVED GENERAL SOURCES Total Dec. 1, 1916 Dec. 1, 1917 Dae. 1, 1916 to to to Dae. 1. 1917 Dae. 1, 1918 Dae. 1, 1918 Board of children Vegetable. $ 1475.99 $ 96S.8S I 2439.82 28.08 28.08 Steel safe 65.1)0 I 66.00 Washing machine. Meals and lodging Medicine cheat . 4.60 | 4.50 34.66 i 34.55 26.70 26.70 Drew goods Gift 44.54 27.54 72.08 106.00 105.00 Adding machine Dresser 3.97 2.78 6.75 176.40 I 176.40 16.76 15.75 Miscellaneous 54.28 32.37 I 86.66 Total. t 1875.93 | 1185.35 $ 3061.28 INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS. FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE - MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE November 30, 1918 Acres Acres Cultivated Uncultivated j Total Eati- 1 ■ — Acre- mated Orchard Campus Waste age Value Garden j Farm Land owned by institution .21 Land rented by institution .65 8« $ 4300.00 (cash) Land rented by institution (shares) Total .21 .65 .86 $ 4*00.00 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING , 1 AND IMPROVEMENT Building Furniture Equipment Improvement Total Main building t 23000.00 S 5000.00 1 6400.00 S 34400.00 100.00 J 1072.00 1172.00 Ground improvements Total * 23000.00 I * 5000.00 $ 6600.00 % 1072.00 $ 35572.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 574 TABLE 1— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION *In the seventeenth biennial report " Present at beginning of period" was interpreted to mean all in the care of the Home rather than those actually in the institution as counted in this report. TABLE II -AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED MOVEMENT •Present at beginning of period Admitted: For first time Readmitted Returned from parole Returned from escape Returned from other institutions Total Died in institution Discharged from institution Eseaped from institution Paroled Transferred to other institutions Tot al Present at end of period Total under care Returned from trial homes in which placed before beginning of period Placed in trial homes and not returned during bien- nium Returned to parents or friends Adopted Died. Attained majority Married Discharged by transfer to other institutions For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. tO, Nov. SO, for 1917 1918 Biennium "if. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. t7 . . 47 SI 78 24 IS S7 47 SI 78 67 47 114 34 36 70 101 83 184 1 I .... 1 1 .... 2 2 50 59 109 50 73 123 100 132 232 3 S C 1 7 9 1 10 . . 27 18 46 38 29 67 65 47 112 . . 194 156 S50 152 153 305 322 296 618 2... 2 1 2 S S 2 S 11 8 19 13 14 27 24 22 46 I. ... S 6 1 7 « 1 10 115 108 223 76 86 162 191 194 385 . . 39 27 661 32 26 58 71 53 124 170 143 313 128 129 257 2S8 272 570 24 13 37 24 24 48 24 24 48 207 156 363 185 140 325 185 140 325 17 23 40 1 26 38 64 43 61 104 78 76 1531 49 60 99 127 125 252 5 4 9| 7 4 11 12 8 20 21 20 411 35 24 59 66 44 100 7 5 12 4 5 9' 11 10 21 4 9 IS 6 10 16 10 19 29 1 .... 1 ... 1 1 1 1 2 527 49 13 9 11 20 i i i AGE For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, [or 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Jnder 1 month 1 and under 3 months 3 and under 6 months .4?. . . 6 and under 12 months 1 and under 2 years 2 and under 5 years 5 and under 10 years 10 and under IS years 15 and under 18 years 6 IS 1» » 11 20 16 24 39 4 4 8 4.... 4 8 4 ZI ».... 2 i... i a.. os 1 . 1 2 1 I 3 13 12323535 16 6 22 3 5 8 19 11 34 25 6 31 9 10 19 84 16 53 .. 11 14 26 2 6 8 13 20 37 134 213 340 . . «7 48 116 34 37 71 101 86 186. Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 575 TABLE 111 EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE IV— SEX AND RACE OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE V -NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED i i i EDUCATION For Yaw For Yaw ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. None Below 3d grade 3d frmde 4th grade 5th grade 6th trade Tth grade 8th grade High school Totals 27 25 52 24 22 46 51 47 98 . . 24 5 29 « 9 15 30 14 44 76 12 246 99 18 1 2 &gt; 1 2 3 4 7 11 1... 1 6 7 12 2 ... 2 1 1 2 t 1 4 2 I .... 1 I.... 3 3 2 2 2 2 2.... 2 2.... 2 . . 67 48 115 34 37 71 101 86 186 _l I I I I I Whit* ndian '.'.'! ... Roumanian . . Mixed RACE For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov.*. Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Bwnnium M. F. T. M F. T. M. F. T. 65 46 111 31 SO 61 96 76 172 t 1 S 1 2 S S S « t 1 .... 1 1 1 1 •. 1 1 I 4 5 1 4 S 1.... 1 1... 1 . 67 48 US 34 87 71 101 85 186 Totals 1 NATIVITY Mebrmska United State* other than Nebraska Jnknown For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, lor 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 44 41 86 22 28 SO 66 69 135 . 11 6 16 6 8 IS 16 13 29 12 2 14 7 1 8 19 3 22 67 48 116 34 37 71 101 86 18* Totals ■ ) ' </seg>
            <seg id="p014">576 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year TABLE VII— PARENTAL CONDITIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE VIII— ACE AT DEATH OF PARENTS For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. SO. Nov. 30, (or AGE OF CHILD 1917 1*18 Biennium It. F. T. If. F. T. II. F. T. Age at death of father: Under 10 yean 314 123 437 10 and under 15 years _ Age at death of mother Under 10 yean » « 16 1 4 5 10 10 20 1/\ __J J__ It .____ Ill * t 10 and under 15 yean 1 1 1 1 Totals IS 7 20 2 6 8 16 13 28 r or i ear r or i em r ending endinr Total NATIVITY OF PARENTS Not. SO, Not. 3D, (or 1*17 1*18 Biannium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. United State* both praU 42 40 81 17 SI 48 69 71 ISO Foreif n, both pimu S14 S47 6 S 11 Mind 1 1 2 lit Unknown 22 7 29 IS 1 U 16 I M Totals 67 48 116 S4 37 71 101 8S 186 PARENTAL CONDITIONS For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. SO, Nov. SO, (or 191T 1918 Biennium M. F. T. If. F. T. M. F. T. Both parents dead Father dead Mother dead Parents liyinf together Parents divorced Parents separated Has stepfather Has stepmother Unknown Parents living but unmarried Totals 2 1 S 213 4 2 6 I.... 2 1 2 S 3 2 5 7 5 12 13 4 8 8 16 .... 13 5 18 2 5 7 16 10 25 2 3 I.... 1 1 2 4 6 ... 19 14 33 12 12 24 31 24 57 4 2 6 1 1 4 3 7 1.... 1 1.... 1 2 2 4 7... 7 9 2 11 . . . 15 16 31 9 12 21 24 28 52 . . . . 67 48 115 34 37 71 101 86 186 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 577 TABLE IX -ADMISSION FROM DEFECTIVE OR DELINQUENT HOMES For Year For Y«r ending ending; Totml Not. SO. Not. SO. lor 1*17 1918 Biennium M F. T. II. F. T. M F. T. 1.... 1 1 S 4 2 S S 3 2 6 1 1 4 X « . 2 X X X 1 1 1 1 X 1 S IX* S S 6 2 1 3 1 2 3 3 3 8 Both parenu Intemperate: 4 X * 4 2 « 4 2 6 4 2 « Father Mother 6 10 18 .., 6 10 16 3 1 4 8 1 4 Both parents Delinquent: 1 1 1.... lilt Father Mother 12 2 14 8 » IT 20 11 ai 13 3 16 S 2 5 16 5 21 27 32 59 17 26 42 44 57 101 a 1 4 I.... 14 15 Both parents Brother Sister 1 1... 1 1 (nknown 5 2 7 1 1 2 6 3 9 Totals 79 60 139 84 43 77 113 103 216 CLASS Pmble-miiuted: Mother Brother Sister niane: F.ther </seg>
            <seg id="p016">578 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE X— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM TABLE XI— CHARACTER OF ADMISSION COUNTY Adami Box Butt* Burt Cam. I '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '■'■'■'■'■'■'■'■'■ Odar Cb»e CuaMr Dim DoufUs Fillmore Gage Grmnt H«U Hamilton Howard Jefferaon Kearney Kelt h Knox LucuMr Lincoln MePheraon Madison Nemaha NuekoUs Otoe Pierce Platte Richardson Saunders Seward Washinitton Webater York Totals For Year For Year All ending Riding Total Remaining Not. 9b, Nov. SO, for Nov. 30. 1917 1*18 Biennium i 1918 M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. S.... I S ... 3 I... I 1 1 .... 1 1 .... 2 « .... 2 2 2 2.... 2 2 I.... 1 1.... 1 1 1 1 5 6 1 6 T .... 1 1 7 4 11 7 4 11 1... 1 1.... 1 I.... 1 2 1 S 1... 1 3 1 4 S.... 3 3 .... 3 ».... t 16 10 26 10 8 18 26 18 44 8 5 13 3 4 7 t 2 5 4 9 1 1 t I 1 1 3 3 1 1 I.... 1 1.... 1 3 2 5 I.... 2 6 2 7 1 .... 1 1 1 .... 1 1 .... 1 1 1 1 2 2 2 X 1 1 2 1 1 2 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 1 1 1 15 13 28 9 11 20 24 24 48 3 9 12 1 1 2 1 1 2 2.... t 1 1 1 2 3 1 3 4 .... 1 1 I.... 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 I... 1 1... 1 .... 1 1 3 2 6 1 2 3 4 4 8 I.... 2 1 1 .... 1 1 1 1 1 1 4 2 • 4 2 &lt; 1 1 2 4.... 4 4.... 4 1 1 1 1 . . 67 48 115 34 37 71 101 85 186 24 24 48 i CHARACTER OF ADMISSION [Ynnane nl liy deer** of court rempcrsry by rontraci W Ith T.arent Ey or lir of court T **!■■ For Yemr j For Y«tr ! ending ending Totul Nov. 30. Nov. SO, : (or 1917 1918 , Biennium M. F. T. j M. F. T. I M. F. T. 60 48 10! 29 31 60 89 7* 108 6. ... C i 4 I 11 4 15 1 Ij ... t Z. 1 2 3 j 67 48 116 34 37 Tl! 101 86 186 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 579 Suppuration middle ear ■2 TABLE XII— DISTRIBUTION OF CHILDREN DURING BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, IMS For Year For Year ending ending DISTRIBUTION OF CHILDREN Nov. SO. Nov. SO, 1917 1918 M. F. T. M F. T. In institution 24 13 S7 84 24 48 In hospital 8 8 14 2 3 S In school (or the Wind 1 1 2 1 1 2 On contract 1 2 5 4 2 6 In trial homes 171 134 SOS 164 110 864 Total under care at end of period 207 156 363 185 140 325 ' I TABLE XIII— APPLICATION FOR ADMISSION Application (or admission 117 Permanent can 228 Admitted Id Mile. 99 Females T» Not admitted M Parents persuaded to keep 8 Family homes secured under parents supervision 9 Referred to court M Sent to other institutions 5 Aged people — information and advice riven 7 Application withdrawn after beint advised 1" Placed in homes by court 7 Temporary care 99 Admitted II Males U Females « Not admitted tl Parents persuaded to keep 4 Family homes secured under parents supervision IS Referred to C. O. S t Referred to court IS Referred to Orthopedic S Placed with relatives 11 Sent to other institutions S Pregnant women 6 Family homes secured • Applications withdrawn 9 TABLE XIV-PHY5ICAL CONDITION OF CHILDREN WHEN ADMITTED Normal 80 Eyes 7 Adenoids 36 Crossed 1 Abdomen distended 1 Conjunctivitis S Atuemis . S Strain S Anterior fontanelle large 2 Trachoma 2 Birthmark 1 Gonorrhea S Bow legs 1 Heart trouble 1 Bronchitis 3 Hernia 4 Catarrh 1 Intertrigo t Couch 'Chronic S Kidney weakness 5 Deaf and Dumb 3 Masturbation 1 Defective speech 3 Mental defect ' S Deformities 5 Pregnant 1 Feet 1 Premature birth t Hip 1 Scarlet fever S Lsf 2 Small pox X Shoulder 1 Syphilis 11 Eczema 1 Teeth— bad condition M Erythema 1 Thrush S Ear 4 Tonsils (enlarged) S9 Chronic discharge 1 Tuberculosis t Fissured 1 Whooping cough S </seg>
            <seg id="p018">580 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XV— APPLICATIONS TO TAKE CHILDREN For Yew For Year ending . ending Total Nov. SO, Nov. SO. ' for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Babies 46 79 126 58 91 149 104 170 274 102 96 197 86 134 220 188 1S4 417 Other children Colored children 5 21 26 9 5 U 14 26 40 18 51 72 21 11 32 39 66 104 20 29 49 21 29 50 : 41 58 99 119 107 226 72 84 156 191 191 382 Applications withdrawn Applications investigated and rejected Homes investigated and child placed . . TABLE XVI— FIELD WORK DURING BIENNIUM Traveling: Number of miles by rail and livery Rail 36392 nNt 2436 Livery M. F. T. Children: Placed in homes for adoption Placed in free homes 70 60 130 121 131 252 90 104 194 Returned from homes Removed 8 7 16 18 20 38 10 3 13 Transferred from one home to another Left home in which placed Visits to children 472 Number visited in which children have been placed Prospective homes visited :)74 1X2 Schools visited 154 Special cases investigated 15 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>