<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR OF 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">HENRY C. GLISSMAN President Nebraska Dair.v men* Assooiali </seg>
            <seg id="p002">! i i i ■ i </seg>
          
            <seg id="p003">anmal Report OK TIIK N KBK ASK A 1 &gt;A I RYM RN'S ASSOCIATION iiiK mi: YKAH OF UMMi I'Kl'il'A^^" M^ &gt;.. ( . liASSK'IT. Sborbtaby aska Dair Association </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Gibbon. Nebr.. Feb. I. 1907 * i ade ami N \ssocia ASSETT. S </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">• 5 TABLE OF CONTENTS 5 M n* and Maiiatririi; a Dair.v ", .[. A. Harris * liik Si-»!h, in t:i- Stable" L. I). Stilson 32 Uair.viuan of the Future". W. W. Marple 1'rof. iKcar Kr( atiuent of ' ' tinmlttixi i % of Auditing Committee (j4 &gt;ili, M • (I l)»ir&gt; Legislation Dist-ussion ) \ inn- \ -,, &lt;&gt;»•■.. IVof. Hujfh (i. Van Helt </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">A. C. Jones. Blair S. C. Bassett. Giblxin Directors </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">List of Members. Honorary Life Members M Han. Korl Atk &lt; Hisah;. Life Members &lt; tiniilia. Ni i Gtfaboi VVab ;i Gibbon, N* (iil.lK)n. N.-I.i oinalia. Nebi Cilibon. N.I. I Sutton. Nebr Gibboi ork. hnaha, Ntl.i Kurt Dodjfe. [ova Gibboi Sutton Gibboi Ijineoli I i.Tinantown. NV^&gt;i '.. ( )inaha. ( ;ilil&gt;&lt;&gt;: Gibboi (;ii&gt;h(.i Station 15. &lt; Unalia. Nc Uliion. NVl)i </seg>
            <seg id="p012">10 K. J. Hainer. K. F. Howe.. W. H. Ijams \ N nha. N aha. N r'schliaum A- Son W. Lessentin . . aha. N Dr. George L. Milhr M. H. Noble. ■I. H. KushToi S i r&gt;. H. Silverna H. Stouff.-i . . . South &lt; linal Annual Members «i.-o. Airxeni IK. # Anderson E. Amer S. M. Arnold 111. Anderson. W. Aldcriuaii A. Arnistronj; W. H. Brookovcr E. Hrodeekv '. UrinUin . Blair.... N&lt; K. K. I). No. 2. Lincoln. Net Irvintrton. Nebf IH. Bechord.. H. Uellows... W. Bailey... i. Bredehoff. M. liiicknum L'tit-a. Krbv Fairmont. Ncln Kearnev. Nebr Waco. Nebr Stiu- I'liion Line. Omaha. Nebr i &gt;mulia. X Sutton. N &lt; &gt;Miaha. N I. &lt; . Merrill Iilliani Sutton H. Wli,-,,,. • &lt;;. Wliitmor H. Win-'.... It;. Pttnr&gt;MH H. Vau^liiiii .1. Kin_ Krlen W. Htei I Allison K. As|&gt;t'yci-ii </seg>
            <seg id="p013">11 Havelock. Kairliehl. Nehr K K. I). No. -.'. Lincoln. Nebr Chapman. K K. I). No. ii. Lincoln ElKin, Box 7.W, Lincoln, NVIn- Ife-than&gt;. ' Albioi husiha. Nebr Waterloo, Waterloo, Nt-in l{. Win N. L'S. Lincoln Klkhorn iwnw t 5W N. 12, Lincoln l!ai nionii Kavinoml Fremont Madison Stai I'niiin Line. Oinaha (. Staplelinr-t i: (.. H Ta\ lor ly-xinjrton . K.lton Ha Inavale Han »12 s. r_&gt; st. oiuiihu. Nebr Huvelm-k. P. I). No. J. Havcloi-k. Nel.i ... Lincoln. Station l&gt;. ( &gt;malia tli and &lt;,&gt;. Lincoln •riinent Station. Lincoln K. K. D. No -. &lt; . nti-al &lt; it \ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">12 A R. H. Hall Hunli \V. I.. Hunt Jensen III. H. .la F. Judkii ( '. .Turn \V. June « . 1'. .1. ffor A. J. Johnson Val Kuska J.I. Slopping ink Ki'ivoliLi! L. Kauffman V. KautTman \V. KanlTinan BP. Mill.T H. Mi fli. Murrav . E. If yen.... . .\U-Arclle . . \V. Martin.. C. Mulenhoff C. NU-Nar... K. Mullov ... St. 1 Dor. Mak Kolit. W. McGinnU. tHtioii )&gt;. • &gt;ma l.avcriu-k \V K. Leighton &lt; W. Ls« A La vert v l.aml (A. MOfTM} Mitchell... K. Mann... </seg>
            <seg id="p015">13 Kene&gt;a». I&gt;e« . ..on). Lowells, Norden, Herman, m vilU cl Island. Ccizad Inavale St. I'aul Loup &lt; itv . .Lincoln . Malcolm Malcolm Tekamah Kiiiilmll .Ctvte Tecumseh mer\ Co.. I I . Grand Island I) . No. I, Omaha Fairtielil Carlisl . Noriuul ( huk'n • i. Lincoln Kisinir C'ity ' inaha It ri. ken Bow Sehawka Kunk IT:!". Kuclid A-.f.. Lincoln Ktljrar S. Funk. &lt; larkxni. &gt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p016">14 John Sneddon. \i. .1 Strawn . . Ko\ T. Sl)ot«»41 ;i 1-W- — \ ment St \ St. -arn Wm. Schomer N.I - I Will A. \V. Tyl T. Thomp&gt; ■ Tttoup* Tucker. riiii- K. Vanderbfi Wollvford H. \V. Wilaoa.. \V. \\". W'liitnuu El Wnt . s Vu-t i'ounn I. A. Vouag A. /iniinerci- 14 S I Sballroberger -•III . \V. l». St.-U-k ■■ r ■ Sackschewsk.i Stn-it/ . T. Tlioli:} • u. k. ni&lt; .1. Temp V. P. \V. Wood Win. WSJtMT A. Wu\ M Wilson Win. Wulf A. K. Wilkinson. Wh.-linyr... </seg>
            <seg id="p017">15 • 'uuacil HlulT&gt;. &lt; mim-il Uluff-. .Dm M.. ( lu-vcnne. \V\ Storm Lakf. Des Moines, [ova Johnstown. -.11 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">16 Nebraska Dairyv ATIOV l Nebraska Dairy m\ C. ( Twenty Second Annual Meeting of the men's Association iid W ■ ■n&lt; ht-lil in U Tuesday. Jdnuary 15 Addn Report of &gt; Appointment of &lt; &lt; Starting and Hani \Vh\ I l"s.- the Mi Sunn Kimlii Mac- At :i:tl«i 1". M. rum « 'nee nf the aadtenee and th ;u-k &lt;if riioin admission t&lt;« ation will b atioii on Wednesday, .ianuary 16 Report of t 'onunittei Klection of CMk i Address Mr. B. D. White. FWnnwentini! Kuirv l&gt; parttm-iit of Agriculture l:.u&gt; i Feeding Dairv C'owa Prof. H. G. Va What a Dairvman Saw in Europe o»" .Iuiit r ii &lt;1 Dain Legislation mil' </seg>
            <seg id="p019">w \ini Headquarters of For iiroirrar innn of so point iroportion to the nuiu - tter and cheese exh not later than January iboTc the minimum. All hi by express, charges prepaid \. I.. Haecker. K.\|)erimental Station. Lincoln. exhibit will !*■ held in the dairy building at K KM AUKS Htion. Meml' be held in the live stock pavilion at the State Farm. facilities between the city and the State Farm. the Association will be at the Lindell Hotel, other information in regard to the meeting address. tarv, (iibbon, Nebraska. ;tv become ■ member of th ■\V JUDGING toNTKST , th&gt;- AsxociMion only. premium will In- divided amon-r Ihoae scoring 35 point* 4 '.I V.&gt; points, iii proportion to the number of i-oint* - ■d. that of tin- pro rata fund no contestant shall i of •!&amp;.«. &gt;ill be done on Wednesday, Jamiarj IS, at :i:iu p. m. at &gt;■ BUTTER EXHIBIT RafvlatkMa of the Association only. n. ( ivainerv Butter in. I);iii'\ Hutter $25.m&gt; : *rt-m . M 3d Prem. ub Prem *.").(&gt;&lt;) W.IMI M i-r 5.M 4. tNi :i.mi :,.m 4.i"&gt; :t.i»i |.M il&gt;its for pro rata premiums shall consist of MM - dairy of not less than 5 pound. a premiums no exhibit shall recei mi ts for Butter: Flavor 4"). grain 3ft, color 15, salting 1". md packing "i. Total l(Kt. iremiuma will In- divided aiuon^' th&gt;- entries in competi- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">18 Proceedings of the Twenty Second Annual Meeting of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association Meeting called to mder in the Live Stock I'a coin, at !t:.'hi A. M. bv President Heur\ ' Ulissman. who delivei annual address as follow I'KKSIDK.Vrs ADDKKSS When the immUrs of thi&gt; association eboae ktle thought &lt;■• nt of eml for to be fiank. I feel »»&lt;lly &lt; ■ ami consequently of in. :i i- for this very hij. r h position. 1 to 1m- made President of tlii~ influential l» .ml of which I sible. miu ruv fullest appreciation and thank- I welcome \ou. nemberx of tlii~ Association . the welfare of the great Dairj Industry of it Dkirj [Ddustrj ol •li that unlv by your coi effort* i-at :«r in tbe fatal*. a~ we liiiv«- in tbc |&gt;;i&gt;t. for irord. We arc li\ . known. &lt; &gt;ne discovery follows another nnti r what will come next. Thi&gt; is not onlj t known. One discovery follows anotht odtaga in (lairv machinery and appli ■toads out i&gt;aramount ax th&gt; inieni station* relati s, which are such a lai^'e factor in the alfalfa alone. Ten jemrn atr&lt; &gt; a field of alfalfa » i nd even those who . that it contained. To-dmj thousan in our state, anil brinirinff a re ami dairymen, and this without robl ntrarv enriching it. so that when plowed up. the s Wt .ore corn, more oats, more wheat or oth of anything; than it ever did sii vation l&gt;vj_'ai -t \ear&gt; following the break A few years ago farming, butdairy farming especially »a ui&gt;on as a life of dradgcry, comhini d with isolation from a (her &gt;ocially or mentally . But the position that occupies to-ila&gt; is far different from what it WM in the | pa* phone. It. F. D. ami agricultural educatioi &gt;m a </seg>
            <seg id="p021">19 e for more li;;lit in hi* i. mnt of profits that any .-• d in it ■ profits that any »'ho u _'.-il in it ' any i &gt;ut; tlit- city folk&gt;. that farm v folks, that farm it or tht; prollW I if in farming ai doubt giwlti in prop. ■ . 1 1 \ other or profession. No farm it i liter in prop profession. N. ii rj industi ir ju«t clo-.-.i. And srhj not? Nature haa I and climate nmiirp»i»»d bj aii in the world. We can raise ever\ \mi win m and climate unsurpassed bj an,\ mtv \\ world. We i-;, rat Uie Icit-t possible co&gt;t. ftiiUwmofi iepartinent of our agricultural Knool are _• Dumber of strange faces, in the 11 of our ,-tate upon vhoM iepartment of our agricultural school an- att- u|Min irliosf should' I in thii 1 1 ranch art* iH-i-onung r in this 1. liyrht on tin- ver- Hid liifht on tin- vci-\ i •iiuiiif r to those of von who aiv liei-e ii roader at the enthaslaaa anil toy- it~ heiv n «. shown our aiutociatioD in the pa&gt;t. both hi i and (he part JO9 have taken in our proK i efficient an instructor as our I'm' ave taken in our protri n ■&gt; our I'l-i. : hardened and prejudiced best cattlemen anil f cattlemen anil elp but &gt;ee at !• niiny: traits in the try that »h I' i^rlit \&gt; I airricultural &gt;chool. 'I -ii you to take advantage of all na that yow Bourse here may include, tann \ou will lind that the teachings of no .lit in thi^ -chool can l«e I Irj de|iartment. I will not take ui will linil that the I • •lit ai i of the wonderful f our state, for iu advancement i- plainly nt la plainly a Iva ra more cow • •« BMH :tiL r plac. » our adi ancement ha- i • ■ I all trj : i- advano am a little more into our i ;u ing pluct-tl at nt lia^ lieen in th*" i mil all tr\ to make still ''I mi i ■mill ow a g for her just a little better, treating her j' our wile or sweetheart, and I am confident atinj; her j Jin confident thai or kn i and can n bjf the in- satUf,: an </seg>
            <seg id="p022">To liiii I'd i-a~li 185 annu To esah Beatrice To essl E TO l-il-li Sl; ; r\ t I'o l-ii ~ - -I. Ktat I'aiil H A \V. P. 1! A . ' iU'r&lt; Fred Bit James AUlri \\" i. A i •! H. Brown, Vernon Blair. It. (). Beekman. Earnest K. Bonn .T. li. Roberts. &lt; '. K. Uowman. Carl Buehler. H. G. Burke. Joseph Bleol F. C. Boyd, \V. ( . Barnes. ( '. K. Bifrelow. K. K. Hrodtfky. A. L. &gt; Oail. Nkhraska Daikymkn 8 Ass&lt;miatio.v :o The ['resident: The next in order on our prosrran I-eiietary and treasurer. Mi-. S. V. I4ii--ttl. tin- » ial report, which i&gt; a&gt; follows: n and 1/ Herewith is preaented I »• lina:u- Btion lor </seg>
            <seg id="p023">21 ■ M .To I.M 1.25 Ml M 3.76 • it I.... ■ ■&gt; 4.-, S .1 no 1.0.. S I. Jan X </seg>
            <seg id="p024">■» W. G. .lull H M. .lain H. 1mm s. L. Joi John M \V. K c w ( . .\U-K c. V ii s. Mil ii. &lt;; j. ( P. C. M&lt; Ed. Mi Hoy Minpus K. .1. Mevliaru M. McDowil Geo. M&lt;&gt; Max McKe L. K. Maisl H. .1. Mjrsrabui M. K. My J. B. Miller Nerod M. N« K. E. Nash A. .1. Nelson P. A. Nicker </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Ml 2.1.. 2.13 ... MNI 1.1.1 •.'..!.. 1.1'n •1 " o.-, ■» 3 1.20 ■«. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">' lias. Versa* premium A. Way ne Wilson ( '. L. Woodbririsrt 11 Wt ii Ya P. K. I'iert Arthur .1. V Ka\ &lt;nna ( 'roaiuen &lt; Fairmont ( 'reamery DanDebroK &lt; naimr .1. ( . Merrill. &lt; . W. K;m IT Hone* w»-l) ,v i : W. 1 1 has. [jeiult-rs. .Ii Mrs. I). M. Strawn E. K. Anderson, in bra ska A. L. Hawk.-r I-. P. Stone. Supt. of l);iii \ 1. W. Brevnter, Lindell Hotel. cnt&lt; -rtaintn I{ A. St. tlolin. stationery si nl ■ K. I). Heed, stationer; and T. A. H. Herky. material and mounting map ■11 .1. K. Roberta, premium J. D \V. .1. A. Warren Rudolph Witt Fred UV- L. I!. While T. I, .f Min in^r i&lt;&gt; deliver an kddre Whiteliead ft Hoatr &lt; J. B. Trickey &amp; ( &lt;&gt;.. untHi &lt; nlher A ( '(&gt;.. huttvr u^t-d I-. H. Stilson. ex pens J. C. Merrill, expenses attend Harry Porter, material for -itati&gt;tk-a U.io </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Ill B ■ . i r_v for II month-, from May l!HNi annual report 177. "o M.30 iil map + doz. statistical maps -I. in halftones for report rculara r\ ami printing &gt; xchange on lx."&gt; drafts &gt;f trip from Gibbon to Lincoln on the Association ntert f trip Gibbon to Lincoln on March lin-r annual report xpenaea of trip to Lincoln on April 1'itli t.» leetinjf of ilitiftors pzpeniiM i)f trip Gibbon t&lt;&gt; Lincoln &lt;Vt 12th to •■•■tiiij.' of i &gt;i-L f anizfil Africa 1 tare nj» of directors ezpraaeN «&gt;f trip Gibbon t&lt;« Lincoln December tl meeting of direol urrmaga pro- trip Gibbon to Uncoil Decimlier inj{ of din pro- :t ■s of trip (iiblion to Lincoln D'H-ernlier expeoaea ftf trip Oibboa to Lincoln DNtato ;.^ of committee on legislation 1 legislation expenses att^ndin^r me^tinjr of diraajlaca on attendin meeting of ili rectors on &gt;alur ftary from April 1st. lVMHi to salai retar 20»&gt;.l i T, al »l,44O.*i that this itemi/eil report together with the an auditing committee composed ol meml» report and report to the as« n was duly seconded and carried, ami i&gt; mil mill j to make a it k. but -houhl have been givtta to an </seg>
            <seg id="p028">islation : i rl\ all of \n rs mak r, that «■ nd at tlii j ei - vuu [•■il and i" an 1 wo ma . iMAimic a pai TRIBUTE TO THE COW ••&lt; ii-and and oobl it. To yoi channels &lt;&gt;f our </seg>
            <seg id="p029">of the tra; ,. would ha Our tables would lilt to of in n* eh siuokint! her, l\f\ won cow a thin* for tin' i;- t i' lion our l»-«-t . hri !l IN t!,. i ■!' lilmm J ami ink to iv-rlitw an.l :i~ in ir i hat "\Vp&gt; . Who *av- that much of wh»i bv Mr. J - n-tin^ and Ma . TARTIJVC AND MANAGING A DAI^Y which But wh n b\ &gt; foi • -- I lunl bo experience that I lia«i an I I o.nld not </seg>
            <seg id="p030">28 I I had to work at the ear|&gt;- : support tu\ fa _h ahead t:&gt; start iii the dairy business, anil I found ■auuRU aneau K start u. MM daii-y business, anil I •what expeuiTe wmj to start In : when I 1" of other* an&lt;l was able to attend th ■ dairj association m-'et of others anil was khie to attend the dairy associat rt^ from the different state dair ,&gt;ns. - of other* a:i 1 I \ iih. by exchanymy ideas with each oil The first tiling I would do in »tartinir a dairy, if .ild take a term at a good dair) wehool. If iy or aloDp in \ears Ml that 1 c 11 •mm of ol much bv ii The first thin^ I would do in utartini; a dairy, if it paper I could ye' and all th .1(1 jfet hold oi . visit a&gt; I '-sibly could. ;i \ one It!. 'n .ut daii ■irn 1 .ilile both -uiiiin -I- and winter. ( &gt;ne uilli pi, nill lie warm in « k Hour for th&lt; hind them and i (or them, if I oni\ bad ■ straw shed, foi v lo keep a cow c • d and m;lk. If H,- you k Hoot n for thriii &gt; and in ■liking &gt;o -ouii. 1 would a &lt;1. then I would itta and will have lo f|o on wha tuilkiiiir s&lt; I loi-a m ■ and will ha vou ha \ what you have learned alioui ■ cow vourseK. 1 ha\ ■ &gt;n my own judyiiient biter than on what tl about his cow. .lu^t take your picture oi at picture with the &gt;i&gt;w and examiip DX wrong there and you will not ;M ! 1 would - od dairj • f breed lor the dairy than ■ carpenttr has iliout his cow. .lu^t tuki breed lor the da duild a house with. duild a house with. I he dair\ breed* baving U-.-n bred for milk and I he dairv breeds ha\ ii tK'en I the I.eef breeds having been bred lor beel for y&lt; be quantity and quality of beel from a dairj br • I breed; neither can you e.\|p nrei-ii lliat you can ;ret from a daii \ breed. W pur pone cow in both dairj or l»-.-l breed but ya I breeds liavi»&gt;r been ii ■ (juautitv and quality of lieef froi • -il that you can ;ret from a da purpose cow in both dairv o ii |iui|&gt;.i&gt;e herd and never will in raising eown for the •ll bred cows as I posaiblj could buy for II tor the show rinjr. but by buyiny: a pedigreed cow vi have done and you can then exp tor the sliow riaff, but by bu.viny: a pedigreed cow vou i-a &gt;r&gt; have done and you can th&lt; than her ancestors. We always raise o 'hem. too. The m you possibly ,-an Ret of hav </seg>
            <seg id="p031">■ r are for at voi .11 det r cow and it w rm or chase * b one of c pounds c ay he will use h wn w aner you kee and your cows wil ins 1 or 9 yea- what kind of heifer he will bring, and \ou uper when another man i&gt; through with him. ■w years, you are bound to lose by it. &gt;w by eroaaiBg ■ dairy hived bir. from. If you get a good daii with that same hived you will be sure to get batter • 1 want a BOW, heifer or sire for the dairy u a cow that hns to have a nui ilf. Why if it wasn't for the dairy breed the would have to raise their calves on hay tea or bean let two cows raise one calf and do with- at oleomargarine. a dairy select a dairy breed, the best to eed. If you want to raise beef f«t I milking but get a good dairy cow to tuppl \ family. Some one has said breed for milk and pray for milk and your prayers will be an - i.tiry requires very close attention. A ss if he has other work (crowding him contiuu ed to and attended to at the right time lairying you must have a scales and tester and w's milk. It is the only way to tell what a cow will lie best and you will soon have a nan their board. You will also continually t for diseases that will break out in your herd. t lungs that you dare not neglect or it will ruin n.l a good barn with good cows and your ' profit uany men in managing a dairy is that they want to lirst few months or the Hr&gt;t year. It takes ■nanaging ! ,,,,! dairy herd. Hut there is n *•* h&lt; '-he better you will care for your cows yourself and do the milking y, Jng all right, but if you have a number of MM some one to do the work and it is very often hard l u can always depend on doing his work right. ?ct the poor feeder or milker just as quick as it will 11 also tell you not to turn your cows out in a cold e them with a dog or mistreat them in any way. 1 ir cows one morning with the milk stool: thatcomb - f milk and I tell you where a man gets rewarded s milk stool to sit on to milk and not to comb a ep your cows and cow-barn the happier you will rejoice with you and it is a pleasure to know that aciier income. rain or shinn, than a her.l of </seg>
            <seg id="p032">30 J &gt;u i a I \v O ert. K:ii-h i ■t. Kin i- am when your cow us f, \ Soin* k i'n th.' tn » mil your warm you mix it. These are the I ■ mu»t ■ ill not !«■ a Biiecewi. If you w or sell milk thev must I n Tin worst thing to taint \ yarn dowa and if yon gtt in a well nore fnul smell than there i V 1 u ran liar K*train your milk b :i or 4 tliu-kno 1 not perfect as it can pi liarn. You can c&lt;&gt; into somt </seg>
            <seg id="p033">31 barn that holds 40 rows and I '&gt;ie barn hi :it p and th • liavr in a dairy barn, rafters where the.\ tw n he little tilings that con barn. It make a success or a fail:. ;trt with tl and t en \ou will make a MM i 1 1 ling b'ttar will mi-; -a fail- n itnd what can a man pursue with his i at* it ami when he wants it? ii^k Mr. Harris ih f his barn 1 on the ground. Tin but on the side wul In hav i inches wide between ■ my rafters are Sat an. ■r over the plati- HI :S ii And then ra\ raft* the ventilation. I ! &gt; we have plenty of liffht. and that coinit Mr. Ihur til following discussion took r hat when I put up ray barn this idea struck me iMtween the rafters, th the rafters rest on the plate, and ding: my barn is 52 feet wide and "nfeet long •enter sufficient to hold UK) tons of hay that le cows: I thought of putting - t on each side where cotnL- up a«rainst the wall: but I haven't it floored !■ »nd tha t draft t!i said that if I didn't Ml«*r I &gt; try to k &gt;r OOe man to taKe care of tiiun i •"&gt;. A man rotit with 1 I of in an) if )ou have your own help never keep ain •an tai. I without nejrlet-tinu &gt;"ine part of an can rai- anil fruit without in- lave his fresh, clean ftft lonjr. I have a ha) hav. l(Jx of ti aw through. Also tit of tow of Us Mr. Harris woul' studding ami I have a ' untiling 1 real I v ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p034">32 it up my hay would be continually frosty &gt;a hasn"t been a bit of frost and sometimes on ttorau davs »&gt; i in the barn all day: the manure was only frozen one* w was as little foul smell in the barn as it dairy barn. I think this is proof that my barn is built riffhl Question: You also have an i Answer: V,». I think the open roof of the barn The President: The next thins: on our program is a Ison. of York, Nebraska WHY I USE THE MILK SCALES IV TNE STABLE TWa time lasot lonj; lap- ;i number of eowi he kept, with hard number of cows he kept, with ha w business or not. and. if pare! le ahead at tin business or not. ami. if pervhai a little ahead at the i dairyman. Well &lt;lo 1 moiled visiting in i-ii New York, n'eloeh in ti dairyman. Well do 1 Moollect risiting in bo v hood dl out at three o'clock in t and Dm when the nhiofctii ttk at niylit. only getting five and then when the chickens went to rex k at night, on I if that were nece&gt;-ary to Ix- a sine, to be one In my own work I I tad to chore-, and elimin;i • r could mt any fun in k if that were necessary to be a &lt;i be one In mv own work ted to chore-, and elimina ar could see any fun in k l&gt;rolit from three ar lour. Aiui tl oneti were the money maker-, lantity. and some honey bottl profit from three ar four. Am :l\ . Thes. ■ were a great improvem heard of, and with (hi found that one-third of mv cows &gt;cw- to sell. With half the cows »i i » as much butter as befor I was reading Hoard's Uairyman a me. I had never seen one, but I -.amples of milk Amused myself rainy day at 11 p and pants from a spilled bottle of aci but I was learning someih One thing of especial interest to ti ■ was the difference betwt them and the reading of til comparative tests as I had b'-en nainjr .1, cock test, sometimes the bottle show the thickest cream w not show as high a reading in the Ha be )ck bottle as one showing I like V &gt;e of the st a thickness in the set bottle, and I would 1 Why?- jet </seg>
            <seg id="p035">33 X ving rue so much of a surprise that 1 » ration still farther and the scales next came art cup. Then, the idea of a record sheet. I I ruled out permanently. The figures would [thin a month I wanted something different and the printing office and before dinner I had which we have used ever since. I take 2t&gt; i board which can be hung up by the scales i'i record as it is made and on Saturday copy and begin on a clean sheet Sundaj fht year- since we l&gt;egan our work along n think of not milking at all as not to weigh of milk of each cow at each milking. This makes a i constant surprise all the time. First, there is an B. A cow has given very nearly the same amount xt milking &gt;he goes down 2, '.i or 5 pounds — what's and you begin to look around for the and tests you may know every night what your cow ir the day. and when Satuaday night comes you can he week. 1 say profits, for if you figure up everx *■ whether the cow is in debt to you or whether lintr your way. and unless you can find a way to r. -he will go on a visit somewhere. Perhaj man's table in shai*&gt; of "veal loaf." With the you that you are running in debt, you wil! hing besides milking cows just for the fun inning the use of the scales and Babcock test, we lirty-nve cows which we had that year. In buying o buy the best and still not over one in five were we had set our ideal too high. A man will never We had ours, but when we got that we wanted \is content with 250 lbs. of butter we wanted 300. Xi». we hail cows giving us nearly 1,0(10 lbs. of rich milk weight, and some of them giving butter fat sufficient weight in commercial butter. I wish some of these ne what such cows are actually worth. Take for in hing about MOO pounds, freshening twice in 12 months. . of •"&gt; per cent, milk equal to ;ti»0 lbs. commercial butter h of skim milk, or another weighing about 750 with 5,400 &gt; her credit testing 5.4 per cent. These are small cows and big a mow of hay as a 1,500 cow, but how does the profit Lit luntiy was wild over the steer Challenger and the growth he had the amount of human food produced and how little it had cost </seg>
            <seg id="p036">\l Aith a uiii in nies that an i-( I Han Bmy in WOl, I ha i-ow. tift income, was fl'hi- President : iiiomv b] the burning nht out many i ■ ph'iit.v of timf befon in- part of hi^ paper In could l« j more profit* would like to h. i mil tl Bl Inur a man M to on • of In or h that f 4&lt;i tin- ftverag Mr. Poynter: I </seg>
            <seg id="p037">35 ■It. hut I • w. that can cat a * proportion iiinl the I'llW. f alinii \er now a i - &lt;&gt;w ;n e with u I x *. ■ t ( •[■&lt; .&lt;i m-Li &lt; &gt; ri. What nee I will ■ lii'i :ill a I »l ii- it would in. .. Law*. it-at mi- »»iit»-r an I'nt » of turniii. ;»t th we ■ . jet I ; WH, ■«(&gt; 1 II profitable l« . In' )&gt;' (fht, that fi "Hi li:i hung ' •ft Iba .c i-aivas-.. then it this 53 i" I'K' |&gt; i m\ father has *■■ (at* mid nulidii iii fin </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nkuraska I) ■ I !l tl w h;i Answer: Tl &lt;&gt; \V ti«»n to her wcitrlit tl Answer: I don't V QU( </seg>
            <seg id="p039">ami all i of III i hav.n't the data a I think has Home m.l tip tie i-n^t o( Illl .1. that it I cai r thf IK with l\n- ■ i i.-i " have a limit t tin- a limit- il aim Hint - a i'i- i'i i . j that think j Food uutri- .v that Uhail kni pounds, the i-om- ilKT tllHt I Will ,terl\ imptiKsih </seg>
            <seg id="p040">38 ciiur I- :. "THE DAIRYMAN OF THE PtTURE inai format Kr entertaintnei r officiaU, ;um Iji respoodinx to tl all those on tlie imemk&gt;g» have ehoMB Ita om 1 full] rfiili/.cil the magnitude win) wir'f ' ■ as ii : t»vt-r\ titi.e v on Et« j i- the inspiration thej ration from breathing p in&gt;))iratiini tliat alwa i Nebraska jmm •[&gt;(.•. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">ksHinrat in mj at- a N'-Ih 'nee I would lit- Mipmni » of l\ llllMlill. »ail tlirouu'h ail tii lid tin IliOIIIflltUIll Wi i, ( i. the ». a !•&lt; i.ioun BWSJ I h - i\ out on n-n ccnlir of en • .ti pt •crom tin- I'ountrv. I will ati country i, 11 it will sti « e. 'I'ln dark cli tj ;u' broken. A I A L'lin. approval ami appreciation is ap- udaj * to transmit to you thia . of the 3ttb iri.mn. "'I'lie Am tunDrl, his in'c&lt;&gt;!ii|&gt;li&gt;liiiicnt&gt;. his ty, :ni(i hiit coDKtantl] |fr«» ; i.\ tl»i— Nebraska Ini - njj popularity. beraiMc oi dim u (ortrH tliut lit- ia thf ■» t li i ■« \ r\. " r l'he Ami 1 fro* ing in bracks In ;n tboritj boj a to t. ikIit their di - of this i: \ this ii i&lt; •vmptthj with their ever) pfforl f«'i 1 uf (if the da i r\ ilepart - bml branch of agricultu rj effort foi f the (hi 1 1 f .iti.-h of BLTtril i the pennanrnt proaperitj Trans-Missiaaippi Kap&lt; &gt;ar|te of the in-titute work. ;n i -ka ha r a i ;t- fharvf at tin «ork. and i xpprimi • rj pamun eoi rj person coin not &gt;H roinpittc until I have dental | of tin- association for tin tbown to take up ami d ■ — itiin: shown to lakr up ai ;i importance Ui the -'im^- and bappineKa of th - as I cleliv |TB I i'iin iniatriru- the exprcaaed lift.v tlioiisand mothers ir. r lio_\ s of being Jmi </seg>
            <seg id="p042">t w;t*h I ■f I) r i.ii I </seg>
            <seg id="p043">41 "Mm. and urn door Did !.. » 11 1m Hit a - iiuii? Did D ) .Mill :. !) &gt;ill lit did h.- t;i Ik in.-. i rymanV ¥es, nt-art i it for. Hi- muii who L'ot ;iii idea that the In .-nt i — t why it in &gt;ii i lit- *m) -. "Thej don't: hreshinj; machine, or . it and t-aclier - &gt; at- aching ttmm phj &gt;i- Now" your mouth to talk. ml your teet to run." A litt »t \ t-liar that hoy. or d - ■ per- - of mischief/ Would mm ffll dim lorsY . i'\nian of are a trreat main t&gt;a«l and there are a mt) hi&gt; boj eoi l&gt;&lt;&gt;\ U iik, it man who (ears hN ~lm-t Im i </seg>
            <seg id="p044">h IJ While I I. | ■iluirtconi II 'II MM so much, it's a ■brave i&gt;&lt;&gt;,» ,ti rorld what \ o native haunts. I know what </seg>
            <seg id="p045">43 a 1 i elationsbip with the world as well as .lined. I remember when he was stormy, disagreeable night. ause he took cold, an had to walk the floor with him » he kicked for beiag left for ftv I without an; nutio or att. oi world us well M rained tormy able night. He th old he took cold, and id to wall; the fl jor with him wher kicked for bcMn.2 left for flv without any nutio or at: etful child that ever lived. Wht ■: tful child that ever lived. When h t chen floor while th he fire-place hearth through th •hild in the world. Finally, whe he caught hold of the :. effort to keep from falling he pulled i floor while they were scrub the fire-place hearth through the ( t child in the world. Finally, when pulled the dishpan off of the table fi llled the dishpan off of the table full nti) the washtub and came very near the washtub and came very nearly I for not having more b&lt; n nit to bed for not having in. i ratched. He pinched the dog's ear ai died He pinched the do -trap and got his hand caught. He g rap and got his hand caught. He got i Baser. He fell off of the i&gt;orch. and is tacer. He fell off of the ]&gt;orch ll business, till he was twi ■e." and all because the little simple dal business, till he was two mae." and all because the little simp and take care of himself, lid take care of himself gill because the mone&gt; necessary h &gt;ecause the none) MNMT] i man to watch some jroang . s of a man to watch some youn? i Ing into mischief and gettinu rem&lt; mber anything the only pta having anj special att' and gettins h tting into mischief only |i pecial att' I 1 some neighbor woman dropped in n dropped ml petted him trying to net - nav fo Imost alone in the world. His bn ool, and I) i awake, and continued until lo His entertainers were inanimate. ; 1 His broth loin und I) ontinued until Ion inanimate, and Us entertainers in the way of ay of as otwithstanding these resistances Aithstanding tlu distances X continued to grow He got too big He got too big t. 1 mtinued to iirow ;l ir ,- of his lather's, tbal 1 father's, thi of first pair of pants made licit' iant (eH&gt; , . not very strict about Ct about M before he « 1 about six months before he v inon department, nnde i«l put in the nursery department, nn npetent conscientious. e:\ t in the ntir jntiou- •Cher, who had in chart."- fift\ or s the mntfleett sum of f mtfleeat sum of fort ear. while his h iround </seg>
            <seg id="p046">44 ) a horse to trot, that if lie would s 1 or :: iiiiniii.' This boy's introduction to tement, i of some Importance, 'I to haul a eaadidml aid thereb :itilll« I) \ i( ' Ion tluit ■ uiii t &gt; Jiiid Kminutt is boy's introduc ti( ■ii to la - and ther U ion tl ■ • nti'l tint ill and h&lt; i III! tl hour taking in the thlni if he did! 'ill I" ill d him up with a k would friphti ■ md M mi Id fright D it HI Hi ii' at her brother's i'-rnoranoe ;ind evervthing n lit attrartlng c ■Ufa- Tin i n'ion. II rrenlng. He is a inn. He is uked If b&lt; ■Bed with having to stay at 1 | with having to stay at hon&gt; !lr1 v ho said to li« ' Hke paiia"" Her mother ' If 1 don't marry will I ha when she was teld ye&gt; &lt;li&gt;' h V 1 world on us women ain't i |, ;U( | f ( ,. to deride ))&lt; tw . ■ ry butterfly 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">45 1 Irin n a t l n em i li i neighl he d in a A k on d I tiniatior ;in sin !•! :l ,1 little kid II sit on He has no I He has noth and spends V B-C s Do ii n anil I la drinl ing too much, al how isn't than e the men about ■d out of a thou - is ex]iect-'d torture is almost ears old ilace where th \ &gt;. and do hi kinir at n .irt was fair to him Irth? Was it fair t Was it fair the tea-her ' from all the back tc in hatlc nc it u has it never iay thi to feel it. The anied with sunn holidav If som family to California n. that tr our flesh and tl i lid- tc il ake on nn: he can o n mi unknown mnection with the Recording: nain s of mil r stewardshi) eht ■t h. r you only inter lied today, or are or is he |&gt;la&gt; heljiiiu hin aids, and if do you com and chide him to. :&gt;rtment is to him a Ion •riod of tim. if the world and his life ha bis to kiss tin ininui.' 'i ■ il:i in and si wonder that th~ Mav I had ohh. anil asks i nd when I and nint- tmndr I am only M s» . of old to it —when I If should be 11 houid be accoi mily a legal with thfin tr tal soul, lies hf Io'a lot nirtKt rittt'ii up Immediate!) after \&gt;\&gt; up into oblivi ililici Ui ;i leh to vote Tht </seg>
            <seg id="p048">46 t im 11 in t Id w n lY to hut He ha for him until he EUe daught. sufficient wtalth to l&gt;u t nvelope with an invi ,1 i : lie fellow's opinh him ha omnmnity. Oh the flowt .1 fill would ith th Iple Hi !i anvbodj in wi There are t I kiio it. When the til bed period, and had to ha ,■ B »a- t« Did it li | the Boy. I'm 'I"" 1 oa sun wonl il would strike him little inconvenient to pet I to go U|&gt; the back st Mat I'sed to be in hi thai he has ;i hf h be ti;is is evldenc could she would add nul I won (It niri laiK&gt;' b*J window on a l»;i all riitht for a 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">47 uldnt come in without waking crooked, and wh. got fast, and required an immen.s and required an inunens ; something- One of the rollers warf nettling. ( )n f the rollers was esulted in spilling water, or sliding il i water, or sliding 11 this bureau had lost a 9»u4 deal o in this bureau had 1 s ■ leopard. One corner was brokeii. ) l liter, whicli mad it impossible In There were two splint bottom chairs tails. There • L and a brush with the li ringe around the edge. His ward NDAY that his fathei tied in. and t of overalls and jacket and a pair of sal it he didn't get till he was nearly was on ••■ his uncle wore for ten n nloaded it onto the first fellow over whoi tv to make him take it. His ridln 1 colt, that he was permitted to use to as He had to tie him with a chain so as to b* and his saddle »a- an old worn-out saddle the time he had to ent lo church th re was just enough to he aforesaid steed Every precaution ha ind his horse etc., to curb his prid 1 to make him hardy my by not Riving him an 1 under the canvas at a circu he main entrance. He has b from the time he was six years old t hile his father was in the legislator n ,. prevent child labor l lie world this boy has been taught the 1 ntmp.nl the dailv admonition that tr want anything but what you have eood deal • asier tl"ie avfng a : if his father had enjoyed his advan If on the top wave. Once even 1 as afflicted with the same old A of the house about what a time he arefooted until he was twentv , ar until he wa« of age. and how he went four is married t and evening. Ht 1 mornin to tell n hov that inal offens i I would send a man to the pen </seg>
            <seg id="p050">48 joining a little town in which HUH was Smith. There Ill family I ever knew. One das ill old Finalh ; Kid. You had a lull a dan ■til told the trutl SOw bulk 1 lister mi ii Centu » from the ■tag lia cm work at t i perf heard ili- heard si they wen tiistio i nd \v h we have i the boy .Ti upplying th literally to chained to on tin outcoi ithout an\ 11 i«e |ih sustained pin with corn ir the boys, and i their idols and fd. Phil Armour said. "A bo; e is an army of boys who ar freight on the elevators of 1 landing them safeh at an in&lt;&lt; ssant talker, and he went l&gt; tl If I hail ta Bithorit e slot- I will do that, lizini: i ition to do tti is just alwaj e </seg>
            <seg id="p051">49 UV 1 news that unto tin of yesterday today ins the nnvs of each ;ind this irr si. conn a i)&gt; th to be ran oyer, when hi&gt; ii him by taking tin is life hut saved the iitfl** ■d why he did this, and his The legend of t! tll'T lia, and V imposed the music that it is the bo Ph is victory, and made iity tha !l t was the Nebraska boy that followed rni of and shell, anil life (if B » regiment renowned in history, and made N English tongue is s]&gt;oken ■d the plow and provided th th.- necessaries of life. It was a boy that put ft a widow, and as he drew who wa ked into b( iday in the shadow of these magnificent structures and Sciences, and I contemplate the wonderful * Is. where loyal men are guiding human destinies sdom, touching human hearts with the touch of the greatest degree the highest aspirations, and 2! ice wa.Vr it's a of the nisht, wli he &gt;ad ni'ivs of a lovi il ll and industrial Bfo, tin nents. And m ■ love him for lii&gt; i ■isim; was iibont t (1 on him and shi II • nve m&gt;&gt; his i^t he x a beautiful story of a boy's SrtclII commutd. It fM i bo-, that - -.iVd rtee banner with tin- ili&gt;M» Mivi •■ 'KXi'KI. ;i|i|i(&gt;;ils to abandon the perforiraro.' of a rtain (1 nth. !t a^ r. bOJ tl th. on mi o vi-t(-rv and , and NMK-1 to att'i 1 ■ 'h»- P» hoir. It be*l thi ba.i il hi- hveast n t!i" human carnal ■ oj B1 ■ '■"■. ,mrt of irer tV ai&gt; ami folio itained face, and swore al </seg>
            <seg id="p052">50 Nebraska Daikyv i-owning human heads with U dedicated to the improvement and u Horn everywhere, and I stop to think with prid and as 1 see the arini ofboj Mruments ol warfare for th in trei (One of tii nt ulion a chine, in th I mac! follow* MILKING NES Owin wit ilker *ill allow I drawback dairymen either to d ratus that will do the t the dairy Ims: Within rec tm in this direction and milk practical under present ng machines has b&lt; ■ ly evident that it will lie a D K Before we can go into detai ing machine it is n«&lt; of the (ow's udder and its EVOLUTION OF THE MILKING ORGANS OF MAMMALS The cow has the highest developed milk producing organ to k § class of animals. This has umentality of man. - particular organ best devek) The udder is a gland, wh 1 ;.ilded in the birthi ; Eiei&gt;- duty, in tnei aelighi tl ury Boy ntly ninki' [ which, perh </seg>
            <seg id="p053">X TH »v r teria r . 1 * 1 ng asair irivi n through! t ii the rii-ttrr fluct Even niilkii ine of three principl &gt;nd th In th.&gt; f t .11 back to the class of animals known as orthor- •ting organs were simply skin with en (if this particular class of animals secured their modified skin blotches, which excreted a sub - lilk. These pores Decani" enlarged into ducts cted by means of an apron in the marsupial class kangaroo and oposuni. As we follow the evolu - ous classes of animals we find a marked develop- ■ which is known as the equine order, to and the horse belong. This gland has reached il« the goat and cow E STRUCTURE OF THE UDDER he milk securing organ of a cow is rather complex nilk ducts, follicles, veins, arteries, lymphati ifficipnt tissue to supi&gt;ort th? mass. As excessive ders the highest development of an udder. The ud ral in form, for it is in this shape that the g eatest an be stored with the least extent of surface exposed erminus of the milk cistern. The milk cistern is a n which the milk is stored. Froii this milk ctste-n ) the tissue in a form similar to that of the limbs of rd of each of these little branches is a cluster ol &gt;se milk follicles the milk is produced. Each '« ■ hich furnish the material out of which Um ■s stimulate a"d causr&gt; activity of the follicles. It ;u ranges th~ secretion of milk and hence it is very rsest possible amount of stimulation be brought lkir/; operation. Any mechanical device that i*- orcVr to produce the most favorable results, be of will not injure or discommode the cow in the least. ! attendant that operates the milkins; machine f • does the milking, also has a great deal to do wiui •ase cf the milk flow Therefore, the first and most five to the milking machine is to have a man that the MM 'n such a manner that it will indue-- thf mutation on the cow. MILK EXTRACTION milk extraction is one that is very simple when ™n sical stand|Kjint. It is merely the force of gravity ■ surface of the udder, thus causing the liquid to he ducts into the milk cistern. The removal of milk 11 result in more milk being brought down through ichine invented in the past has been based ui&gt;on •s. The first is known as the milk tube system, the lirinrii'ln. and the third the suction principle. uto the end of the teat, and M </seg>
            <seg id="p054">52 s the force of gravity acts uron the surface of the udd out of the teat, or in other words, allows it to run the ud force of gravity is not sufficient to milk the cow dr r great objection to any style of milking machine built Another objection to this system is the insertion c !• to the udder. This is a painful opt iu me uaaer. l nis is a painful operation to the cow, U ii flammaikn. thus rendering the milk unfit f i to This method is only used at the precast tim ■ ir nly used at the present tim ■ : rdders or tea's wh i rdders or Ua*s where the sphincteral mm must, however, be thoroughly stt rilized in boil re the sphincteral muscl i sti rilized ir n case before it is us=&lt;d ond similar to hand milking. hand milking V : and by first closh,-* the fore finger the Brat cloair* the fore finger tr 11111 of " ! &lt;1. :ird by applying 11111 of &lt;•" &lt;1. :ird by applying press finger, the nrlk is forced out of the tower lf this I ufacturfd but i'(d mechanism Involved th y mn impractical. The third principle is similar to that of a us? machines ar based upon this principle and t xttd so as to imitate the calf sucking the teat. ' finger the nrlk t The third principle milk ng machines ic ted so as of the teat and fir-- e big draw, the uj. of the teat and firs of the tf at ard the tongue b low. with th- M up against the teat it forms a complete nilar to that of the suction of a machine, whicl i of the air, th &gt; pr the milk into i the milk flows into the mouth the calf swallow: of the teat ard th le up against th rs similar to that i of the air. th When the milk flows in lief to the teat by allowing the a:r pressure around th &lt;d. This is one of I al featuies of the milkiti i n is applied the blood is drawn down with the action this blood remains in the vascula &gt; &lt;d. This is one of th ntia on is applied the blood is dr action this blood remains in th finally distendin gthe teat to such an extent as to th Anally distendin gthe tea tc portion and causing a temporary sw»llin.a; Thi^ portion and causing a temporary sw injure the cow. and this is win- machines of this I njure the cow. and this is whr maehin * Hussey, have not been successful. * Hussey. have not been successful DIFFERFNT KINDS OF MACHINES ON THE MARKET AT PRESEIN CIFFERFNT KINDS OF MACHINES ON THE MARK There are a number of milking machines on the i There are a number of milking macr I wit time, many of which have obj?ctionable points a ent time, many of which have obj?ctiona 1 proved. The Burre!l-Lawr&lt; nee-Kennedy machin- factured by D. H. Rurrell &amp; Company. Little Falls. N. Y that has been used largely at our Station, and ha v the most successful and simple machines. The Ulobe machine ha been tested at this Station, but it has not proven to be as practical a seems to be a little more difficult to regulate than the Rurwell-Lawren Kennedy machine. A number of other machines are being tried, but are not yet ready to report on them </seg>
            <seg id="p055">53 T lkfd a ence-Ktnnedy machine consists of the following for creating vacuum. There are various kinds different ways roducing vacuum. First, by means of a erated by any motive power. Second by Third, by means of a water vacuum pump. The ictcd similar to that of an air pump, except that finer and the valves are mor • &lt; loscly fitt d and or pumping air. ThU pump can be operated bv in engine, bull tread i&gt;owt, swevp i&lt;o» • in fact any form of powe • that is practical wer is by all nans the cheapest, but it re ■ to &gt;rr&gt;in an anin.al to produce a steady and uni i.ietd by means of a steam air exhauster has proven ical thing for the average farm. It is simple in mech- ; n. and works with certainty, providing thfre can TW same principle involved in drawing water by l-o I) ■ used in drawing air. e\c &gt;pt that It needs a rrangement of the steam jet in relation to the ev can also be produced by means of a vacuum a i;ount of water and the great pi hardly possible to produce vacuum economical n iuni chamber is to keep a constant suj . , vid" for th" rush of the a! ■ through the teat [&gt;n or taking off the cups from the teat. ;1 nhowl the number of inches of vacuum M The safety valve regulates the vacuum pressure 30 h'.^h. An excess of vacuum will Injure n order to maintain a constant pressure this regu ntial nt that thrre should be a steady and constant vacu ration. Dairvmen well know that in the case e to stop for a time when the cow is pa-ttallv w gin again and finish, the chances are that there would n the yield, but the milk would be of poorer qual A similar effect is produced in the case of machine milking. If th»- ■mplovpd to work the pumps stops durins inw milkirg onrat'cn thtit is a narkfd dfrrrase In the yield of milk. ■ of the pipe which runs in front or k </seg>
            <seg id="p056">54 .■ ed between the cows taken in pairs, and to which the milkers ma attached. The vacuum pressure is conveyed through th t The milker consists of a can or rec&lt; ptacle with a close fittin jv pulsator. and two stop cocks, to which are attached rubber tul are connected to the tf at cups. The parts of the milker consist pail upon which is placed a cover containing th" ulsator. and t spfction glass for determining when spection glass for determining wher the cow has been allked dry. The the cow has been i-.iilkt-il tiry. Tht are two milk cocks on each cover, a are two milk cocks on each cover, a nd attached to these are rubber ho d attached to these are iub which lead to the cow and to which which lead to the cow and to which the test cups are Conner ber hose connects the vacuum pail ber hose connects the vacuum pail with the vacuum cock, allowing t with the vacuum cock, allowing t nil By opening the vacuum cock t suet on to be communicated to the suet on to be communicated to the p exhaust* d from the pail, whic ail. By opening the vacuum cock t air is exhausted from the pail, whic h sets the pulsatnr in operat- the palaator in operat the pulsator works up and down, it the pulsator works up and down, it applies suction to the teat and th applies suction to tb^ I relief. Whin suction is applitd it draws the milk milk tube from the teat and depoe tion of the teat assists us murk dlv in making the machine teat cups are made of tir wr with a flexible rubber mouth-piece which adjust of the teat and thus seals the a a teat cup must fit the teat perfectly and it is Bgood operator co idual cow. THE FITTING OF TEAT CUPS AND MOUTH PIECE Eie teat cup of a machine is 5 the teat.and in fitting tht ter as to receive the teat lc lactation, and should fit ra The chief objection to a teat that the vacuum expands the tea the teat, but the pulsation is i more than a part of the milk to flow from th&lt; - the releas on the pressure of air causes the t and forth into the cistern. Henc r milk is churned back and forth ir the t cup fits the teat snuetlv it prevents th vacuum being exerted largely at the lower end *pletely removed from the teal The slant of the teat Stt3 niu* if the teat cup is fitted loosely at ihe n&gt;"\ :i inline amount of blood rush es to this point and causes a temporary inflamniatioi ing sore ends. This can be . ntirely avoided by fitting the cup so t the apex of the teat is similar to the incline of the teat cup. If th cup Is too small the milk flow is obstructed, and consequently th .1 will not all be removed. The mouth piece should be large enough allow the free flow of milk into the teat, and in case the cow is adv£ :in ing toward the latter part of the lactation period the mouth piece she </seg>
            <seg id="p057">55 end of the milking operation it is necessary to mm are taken in these points the teat cups will k CLEANING OF MACHINES. are very tasily cleaned if a systematic oper - attaching the machine to the vacuum and al with luke warm water and then with a boiling sum ■ washing powder. In the Burrell-Larence- le milker needs to be cleaned. The tube is then washed and thoroughly sterilized. The pulsator i cleaned with a rag. and then placed in the sterilizer •an. The rubber tubes, which are the hardest part of chan. are then scoured by passing a brush through ine solution. It is very essential that rubber should ud by adding salt to water, it acts as a preservative and entation. These tubes are then rinsed with boiling water n leady for operation THE KEEPING QUALITY OF MILK. d by these machines, if properly cleaned, contains from it less germs per cubic ct ntimeter than ordinary milk [1. It is. therefore, extremely desirable and practical standpoint to produce milk with one of these machines. LABOR. iv c cows at one time. One milker will milk t«n to iepending somewhat upon the kind of cows and the ire producing. The average rate of hand milking is as per hour. Taking all conditions into considera ichine milks as fast or a little faster than the average hand achines may be applied to a system. Four milk 'rated by one man, thus milking eight cows at a the labor included in starting the machine, taking ting up the milkers, transferring the milkers from nd cleaning the machine, fully 40 per cent of the a machine work is another factor which should be takes Mion. Hy the use of the milking machine the monotony of a great extent removed. The work becomes easier and usant THE EFFECT MACHINE MILKING HAS UPON THE COW. t Machine milking is very much easier on the cow than hand milk - ; for the simple reason that the suction being applied upon the teat lot as painful as the pressure applied by the hand, and the movements the hand arc not as steady and as uniform as the movements of tfce </seg>
            <seg id="p058">56 v POWER WITH WHICH TO OPERATE N, ILKERS K: is never advisable to operate a milking man two milktrs. In this case it require* about a t engine. Gradually as the nuuibe. of milker., mate powtr may be decrtastd. Instead of cal; every milker, a flve-horse power engiu&gt; ii COST OF A MILKING MACHINE sential This, to a certain extent. Mill .i.ake a niil n actual ior hand milki The c of tift I. Three milk* Pip ng pon t^ \ Kitrhi-n stove If Hi. milk( iUiup would cos easoline en B power, about f we take the ■i« would be about $16 per cow. Fo tor a herd of fifty cows it would &gt;e $8.50. The above figure a-e a into consideration HARD MILKING COWS Cows that are hard milkers, tut tf milked more easily and more quickly work a little longer, and with a small teated cow care should t hat the teat cup is properly fitted. Occasion '&gt;r other, refuses to give down her milk. This d to the nervous temperament. It is possibly tru&gt;' that th»" chan hard to machine milking is too radical for these particular indiv'd Impractical for dairii Knt is i ase it so as to makt condition »■( The motive iiov ition th.&lt; total co^t of the mil! &lt;1 a boiler can be purrh nakfng ■ total cost of r.t machines mflkin^ t\v&lt; milked more easily and more quickly by a machine i hard milking cow it is simply a qu stion of ket </seg>
            <seg id="p059">57 objection to the machiue being applied to i .el a. low thd iiiacnine to puuip away with lS the cows that give this trouble are few • an to d.spo.it of them. COaS THAT KICK. habit of kicking during the time of milk tly broken by the use of the milking ma s trouble when milkt d by ma liand I the milking machine are Mr. Gurler of DeKalb Co., of Monroeville, O.. and Mr. MoCr^ery, of Ur DISCUSSION. I's stay up there when the air is not on n the mouth-piece that prevents the teat cupi :his operation better than hand milking? isier on ;he cow than hand milking, when you have all the milk from the cow? p ction glass, a glass tube which is located neck of the pulsator. When no milk passes Iking operation is completed io if one cow gives more milk than the oth&lt; ful to leave the trat cups on the cow for a limited k has already been drawn, for the reason that r a'lows the free circulation of the blood and late the Uat rather than to do it harm. Manip in the case of milking with machines, the sanit ■alf cannot secure any more milk, is it not cu: udd^r ntin°; attachment to this machine. -;iry in the formation of milk when the calf on process with machine milking takes the place ase of the calf suckirg the cow. at about rower pow« r required for each milker is approximate!} ■. If you are using more than four milkers the rate of decreased to two-thirds horse power per milker. The that operates the milkers that you see here is produced by an tor in the dairy building. The ejector is attached to a steam boiler also be operated by means of the vacuum pumps installed here •orner cf this room and operated by means of an electric motor ler under which this vacuum is produced generates 50 pounds of irossure to produce the desired 15 inches or IVi pounds of vacuum Q. How do you work the milking machine with the gasoline engine </seg>
            <seg id="p060">58 A. The gasoline engine simply takes the pla ■necessary to have a vacuum pump in connection w ;, but with steam it is only necessary to have an ej&lt; stalling cost is cheaper, depending upon the cost of the coal and ization of the exhaust steam. It is p obably a litt cheaper to produce vacuum by means of steam ]&gt;i Q. Then that necessitates a farmer getting ■ A. Ye: tDo you think a steam boiler is essential on a dair Yes. very much so. because it is extremely nee hot water fo- washing utensils, and it U also essential -terilizing. Furthermore, the exhaust steam from the milk i an be used in winter for heatin the water from f eezing in water tanks, etc Q. Can vacuum be prductd in ar VI A. Yes. We are working nit ans of water by having a pump that forces wat water to flow through jets which sucks th&lt; m, but thus far we have found [i Kt of wat r that it What difficulty This is done v ■s ■ini. a"d drop t! a h:it solution' BtPiillx? th" can and Ee teat c-ips In a solutic I'd bv ninniti!; ;&gt; tiush isible skum that niav ha ■tntion in operating the machine A. The most ini|K&gt;rtant part Will not nin successfullv u Q. What machine would you A. I do not want anv of yoi \\ interest in them at all. We do no von know how to run th°m for a t -I success of the machinf Q. Would st'ch a machine bf net A. No. not unless you have at least fi a men would rather onerate a milking machine, however than to do ha"d milkin,?. even though it were more eostlv Some people li these machines for the sake of convc Q. How many machines do you nienc rows ? KA. Two milkers would be suffic &gt;r. and four can easilv be operat. [ conditions one man can as well Three wo it ■d h in Q. What is thp most im» niarhirps. This is not our husinf 111. H»n&lt;*e undf </seg>
            <seg id="p061"/>
        
            <seg id="p062">59 1* teat biiuul .it biiuuld have pkiiiy o ir»e. Liiitaa u ■g«.-. Luitss a teat cup in ■at cup in .1 ; noroughly milked, :ked. M machines do you liud k.-d i milking with one of these uiaet nes do you liud i milking with one of these uiact sing or lUt reusing . i iinu Lk iiic \: of milk increased to in- ilofcd IO tile e.\ k IK u tho. e milked by machine 0 .vita ou&lt;; year s it any tale we thiuk that Oow of milk with at least 1)0 per uachiue o.er those milked hi one year s lest. The iv e thiuk that machine milt I it) least 1)0 per cent o the cows milked hi .11 r The rev ii on. i nachiue milkloi :eut o the cows lay iaie we thiuk tha th at least K ihat do not respond to machine pond to niariiiii. 1 to machine milking. 1 milking. Th j machine milking better Iking better than d to machine unit: tit tows uh&lt;n being mi.ki ;i decided inti until b being mi, kid in the m d in the si 1 d a decided in i decided in&lt; mil in the tlo» In th&gt;- How time in inevious iieriodd. iodd. id s too expensive. Can you no oline pow t 01 iiut j is too ex| V Can you not r with you &gt;ou that sttani •oline pow&lt; r u !lt Stt i: ai il power, 'i he fust cost with h ,t cost with hand or foot po» hand or foot uow cost with itallation of s:eam or sisolin cow by hand is not r. or s-isolint 1 lower than the installation of s nstallation of :i r operation o, required to milk a cow by ham 1 not n land it loot pow&lt; i- ma. hinr. Tin ma, hiii.-. The saui'- lime • ;i •"urthrmort'. th? friction of th it is transformed. Kurtlnmort . tl Kurthrmor friction of th« n &lt; d to thi^ iiiently. it reqn 1 by hand than it ost of i'ii.- s&gt;- betweee steam itntly. it require* more energ than it d-&gt;es to milk by han ii steam power and ham ( juently, it req morp ent o milk by hanc sited ii steam iiower and hand :l Faking one as the unit for st lit for ■team power, han. I )vver. han! unit for . It is best to apph P|)ly st- re not availabl • use a tread or irt of the period of lacta lactation od of lactation the teat of the milk ha r ff without iiffen-nt size mouthpiec required, for different siz and what teat cup to fit on a cow A isitr to milk with a milking niachin pie reason that the sphincter mu iirly dry thp t will d hould apply his systematic work iind doubles ovpt itsplf , pr </seg>
            <seg id="p063">60 tDo you have any trouble with cows but this problem is easily solv remain attached to the cow. It takes 1MB h k a COW that holds up and alter the system of the cow ha lax sh milk tasily Yin n I take it that an rather than to the av A Y kinir from the present stand it to dair A Dair level ani liould futility in th h to remo dd I red cows and put the milk A. Such an arra' ■k it would i&gt; ■ practical vou think that in.' milk* rs that milking machine, but good milkers on.- in fifty of the present farm labc Q. What would it cost A. This depends upon tli ?7.Y For forty f BC would cost you $22". plus tr aavee. vacuum pumps, if you intend t ;ind an ejector if you intend t&lt; of minor im]&gt;ortanee and probabl Q. Am I to understand that an ■ to one milker, say milking four c&lt; A. Yes this could be done if thf i.-f point in hand milking is th machine it merely costs a litth Woul Q. If you could available V This would be ttif But the machines at preacn </seg>
            <seg id="p064">( 3U desire to milk four cows at ont milke eaper, then, to gtt another milker: ins I should advise you to get another milker. In ire impractical, and at the pres it u in the other machines with the same pipe? d twenty-fire to fifty different milkers from th nough vacuum to operate the machine iouth pitces fit the teat cups? will fit any size teat cup. They ar it, would you have to milk that Wl \ oae-teated row emu be milked 1&gt;\ a machine the sam as In jnprofitable in tith. ne wear out very rapidly? hing that wears out rapidly on th ■ milking machine These curtains can be easily repla mouth piece. These curtains can be easily repM it time cost but 1" cents a piece. Th •&gt; will nonths, d HHillilM upon Oke usat&lt;e. In buying ne best to buy a small kind, for gradually as they ar ths, d 'pending upon the aaa(e. In buying new buy a small kind, for gradually as they ar id can be used for larger teated cows. This is a poin mi be used for larger teated cows. This is a point tiling else that wears out? importance, except iio^sibly the spring which o tile pulsator. This sometimes needs to be replaced else that w ars out? Bg of importance, except possibly the spring which op pulsator. Th sometimes needs to be replaced very cheap and it requires only four to be pit t requires only four to be placed cheap and osen of them for a nickel zen of them for a nickel. t of the rubber tul&gt;e on the machine, and of the rubber tul&gt;e on the machine, and does tube on the machine is very exi&gt;ensive. costing abo line is very exi&gt;ensive. costing about l the mat per foot. These tubes last, however, for a long tim We have used ours for over a year, and they ha ents per foot. These tubes last, however, for a long time lave used urs for over a year, and they have n.sh different sized mouth nieos with the macliin I am not familiar with the purchasing of I different I am not familiar with the purchasing of the* t of my line. lir DENT: We have with us Mr. F. M. Deford. who h ENT: We have with us Mr. F. M. Deford. who has V IU he has invented and we will give him an op|K&gt;rti laehine and show how it works, how it works poke as follows: DEFORI ind Oentlemen and Indies: I am not here to enter with my machine, but I have a machine here that 1 n ked on for four years or more. I at one time had a farm in the iwa and a good many cows, and I thought then n better way than to do the milking by hand and I got the idea of tryine ■ft i hanical appliance upon them. T installed a machine which I oper </seg>
            <seg id="p065">\ ) ► i changed the mtnoi Khs that I used it I l&gt;r to lie milked that « 1 i id t! ■I il thi .1 &lt;1 off. t' at ha l in this pipe 1; it pipe and run ko along and put t: he will find that the first oi ii off as th '\ are throng* and AUDITING COMM1TTRR: N RBSOLXTTION COMMITTEK I had '!'&lt; cows Ik '!"&gt; to M co" LBY THR PRESIDENT: B I'lmittees </seg>
            <seg id="p066">i Sm'rtdwi (lllfSlI </seg>
            <seg id="p067">64 SECOND DAY Dairy Building. State Farm. Wednesday January 16. 1907 9:30 A M KE8IDEXT C.I.I - w listen to reiio nomination, am I right EHK PRESIDENT: As I undei I these p rsons in nominatiot 1 ■p way. ettber by risiiiK vote or by ballo MR. DOW: Mr. President : I move til that we accept the nominations lak Carried. MR. CLARK: Mr. President i upwrl of tin' Committee on Me </seg>
            <seg id="p068">I).' instructed to cast the vote of the As officers for the ensuing year, and th&lt; nded was carried President: Your Secretary has cast the vote II. C. Young; Vic»-President, A.C. Jones: ('. Bassett. Directors: C. A. Clark, A. I C. Glissman. John Sneddon. the report of the Committee on Resolu solutions not t ing present and ready to report ■ next paper on our program is entitled by Prof. A. U Haeeker. Chairman of the Prof. Haecker not being present and it being &gt; be read. I will ask our Secretary, Mr. Bassett. nittee was appointed to draw This committee has pr - we are in hopes that it will paper is in the shnv&lt;. 01 a \SSI T time ago a con needed legislation me this line. Thi Imture ii"w in session lor the appoint mid Drug Commission. *t we are in favor of repealing the present statf natter and having enacted something similar tc United States The National law WOOld extent ■lent, it k lid by those who do not his is a creameryman's association. I contend &gt;ointed by the Governor should be a man reron. &gt;v the State Dairymen's Association, and I wo. lid President that be prepared a bill to be Dairy Commissioner and elim lature asking for drug ' part of it •ond that montion &gt; ready to make a strike for a thing to do with this bill and put in our hill for a Da'r* AKC'KKR: 1 believe we art hat the prope r nd drug part of Mr Presid if you stipulate the kind of shall possess and you dairv it nations the appoint d let the Governor appoint a man. that it would pft to the association to say every year, you one n an and in that respect I think you will id drag the association down i ON: I hope we can have this matter arranged so shall appoint ■ good man for the place. I do n&gt; ' ct to having tl iation. whose heart and soul TI.KIN t complete, but </seg>
            <seg id="p069">66 .1 A i :i :»rr 1 i politician, he would want to cot if he is a bad politician vou should stipulate that the a| "i ■•• along dairy lines. MR. CLARK: Tlft for a man. Th e in other statt HAS.SK, that he cannot do ntlre time to be de\ interests of Xebrask loj eil constantly ;il &gt; have two men to c; h. dairy and Lhe other for mi call them, but tl r and hundred other thir .UK. WHITE: V ■dairyman with piuc m that for th&gt; n compelled to d crk. A practical dairy ill to be p 1 to bt adopt, d or eadorm d by thi: Mow, before it is adopted a discussion. The hill one particular i: My commissioner of non-pe work yet to be done I not had time to do tl "what the dairy ii oil, Mr 1'!-. I ident. t that it shall be the duty food and drug eotum Nebraska MR. WHITE: 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p070"/>
           
            <seg id="p071">67 1 h 1 iipnpTirl hel ARK v Y kin? a law 1 he d ssible 10 crtau- two couin.. 'uographers and two offices to be f the pivsenl Legislature would have to combine the two under on. t there is suffieitni work for a dairy coin I don t know whether we could secure the point I make is that he shall be a in xeeotlve ability and of large dairy expert if you incorporate that in the bill that he rience along dairy lines you will get a good leal of expert) nee in Minnesota. Some and accomplished nothing beeaus. ualified This is our first step in this direction in regard hat exist in our line in this state and I think we and not take any fal - id n suits, and, in a year or two, we will be able and get something better. I do not und wo commissioners. I know this bill is worthv shown clearly to the bill become a law. I ■w we could get good ectors we shoul ■ity of having this jmmission. I bell ;1 and with four ins[ ult it the two commissioner do not seem to Mission and I b nt'i d ■ dairv co but if we have a Pure Food, Dairy and Dru would bo asking too much of the Governor I'lect the man as the Dairy Commissioner here they have those two commissions combined — they hav»- believe the two commission* aeh other I am merely suggesting this as «• the facts will sustain my views. urtily in favor of what Prof. Erf recommend - ir an independent commission Of course, w T e a^e stating what we believ we ought •&lt; nterests of the state need. This proposed Mil slators. and if it can bt attend those meetings as wp wish they would in selecting a commissioner they can come In I beli»ve this Association would be better ist man than anv one man would be. 1 good we should have strictlv a dairy conrnW v b« allowed to express my views in this mat in favor of strictly a Dairy Commission. I ook sota and Wisconsin have done. Take Illinois </seg>
            <seg id="p072">68 Bnot understai f his duty. On the other h (established. 1 don't b '. that is the way it kx nderstand. I would I ission for I ha Commissions in Wise 1 reports from all the s matter. I have seer ia Dairy Commissioner than w loner. There will be no part &gt;r. Everybody recognizes the The packing houses are op] d fle;ht us and we would have ment to get a Dairy Commissi Drug Commissioner. PROF. HAECKER: There are about forty tr braska who are interested in the dairv bm many people interested in the da is no doubt in the v Tld but what Ki matter. I have seen a s it of not having qualified R. JON"ES: I think we w am in favor of asking for a separate commission and i wo they can do it. Let it be understood that the E . ion \&gt;ant adaiij commi do not m t it in the future. Mil. WILKINSON: I believe this A— OfUltofl is own basis. I( we do not get a dairy conuuislui ft for it in the future, ll w« | binalion i : tlian none at all Other Mates have tried the it b I l 'rug Commission if w ■ cannot | I th cut i,ut ilie Food and D.ug Comniiukmei in ■ Dall him a]i|ioint h PROF. ELAJECKBR: It la ■ ion would l» created by oui iin a ma t&gt;us ■ \t i \ 1 &lt; d&gt; Bted in ; </seg>
            <seg id="p073">69 r. Joii bat the packing indust.y ii the bitterest eiie L. Miller m the audit-no i d in &gt;r the | i listen at and i ound the jtat.- Farm buildings. Prof, at ■aid here is the place where I but Lbe machin rv, except that which is in front ! v.ould be quite worthless. When y attention I cannot but think of a friend early and long life has been spent among Che niaehin rv except that which is in front of v. ould lie quite worthless. When your tention 1 cannot but think of a friend of irly and long life has been spent among tht i lien a man milks forty cows every night a n a man milks forty cows every nigln "uggle for success and without expen. truggle for success and without experteni n&gt;. he is worthy of great re-pect. Th j at re-pect. Th mtter in early days were very crude. Th itter in early days were very crude. itter with dogs on a revolving wheel. When churn vith do-;s on a revolving wheel. When chu the dog gets on the wheel and walks there until, as they ts on the wheel and walks there until, as th The churns in those days were as you kn The churns in those days were as vou know i old-fashioned, but they used to butt .ishioned. but they used to get some butter ;s come up to me when I notice the advan ntifie principles and when 1 think of - and wh,n 1 think of the made in the development of the cow, tli nt of the cow, tht :ow. in ericultural hall and was told by Dean Hum sricultural hall and was told by Dean Burnt done by your agricultural school and da agricultural school and dairy i that is being accomplished for the dairy inter* 5 being accomplished for the dairy intt ■ •o you in another place about another mat in one sense, and that is our winter wht nt and I congratulate the state upon lace about another matter uid that is our winter wheat jngratulate the state upon iw given in the direction of agriculture and [Jirection of agriculture and al! ate and for the result o ave always been weak. It b t landed in this country dy believed that the upland in this country would xpetience in a valley near Omaha ome water. They said that no other land would !&gt;• d when we got to Columbus that was th.- anie thin:.; was told me when I firs! hat i nothing west of the rv 4 tha. a man was foolish to ero farther But I ca:;i </seg>
            <seg id="p074">70 • BM nt our state has made I 11 ■ thank you for your kind att wish you progress and sue n dair HE PRESIDEN K V. IIITK: Mr. ( ted in your &lt; tl it and will was nnt indispt hat on the rack and t I wish to mak laturc I am not g trying to do and is doing itfd Ptate« is r°ally in it I rarried on all over the co inre dairying has taken a foothol they have daried for centuries and how thev r the value of their land from five hundred dol ho ,'ollars and even to two thousand dollars per acre. They have d Pfd dairying. Vvt you people will ha head fore you will be able to raise your land to that hr V is good land I've, better, tha Ru Bu good morniiu K. PRESIDENT i^pirine Kiroi ostd dairy an JUN3OX: ' ion in preparing a that t ns all of tills disru inornui&lt;r became it !&gt;• fore you. I may tefl you sonifthir dairy line that up fird so we find changed eondit ■ talked against tt-n My tortav that we advooat«-il </seg>
            <seg id="p075">win, i iuar oasiUi-o.i »o You are going to do u but you than you did a tew years a^o nk very ofttn of the ad\. pie in the east, where they ar Y and Pennsylvania — P. nnsylvan:a t and i&gt;ioduces a large an i farming is fo.- garden purpost hat do these gentlemen h. t to Nebraska and buy your grain, your bran ! from your corn. They bu d make butt r in competition with Could you afford to buy your corn and New Y'ork here to fetd to you th( re is one of you who thinks ht v iber of farmers who are wondering • the grain that they rai &lt;&gt;■ on thei 1 own farm to , is not that true.' \W hear it tnrj year that dairyina it true? We hear it every year that dairyina thos i astern paopta pay th &gt; freight on their feed frorc [Stern people pay the freight on their feed frorc tion with you. What else do you think they &lt;li t competition with you. What else do you think ttu y di Nebraska is one of the f^w states that ine of the few states that tensively. So you don't appreciate the advantage thai you don't appreciate the advantage that yins. may sav "that's all right but the K«l o ni&gt;ar to market." That is true, he is; but 1 ■\ou nay sav "that's all right but the New market." That is true, he is; but I m&gt;a o tell yo'i what it costs to ship liis butt r to market, and shit) his butt-r to market, and . It costs the New York farmer just as much to put hi&gt; v York farmer just as much to put hi&gt; n York market as it coal &lt;&gt;|&gt;le in NVhraska. Y Whats that? I will tell you how I know of opfratins; creameries in New York and also ii ivhat I mil talking about. Thev don't run r their refrigerator cars which are fill as and Minnesota batter ro take on but our butter through their own towns 1o the flyer. Their butter is picked up locallv a"d They are compelled to ship it b^ our Nebraska freight rate Now. &lt;\i Yes i I-aught SPEAKER: What I was going to say about the Dairy Division wa- ll nt work. In the first place the poor milk en up. The milk for the city — you are going to come t&lt; hat in a short time, and there may be some dairymen here who supph towns and cities, possibly, Omaha or Lincoln, with milk. That is a lint that we are verv much interested in. It is a line of work that w be interested in because so many of the dair&gt; ■nen deliver such poor stuff to the market or to their customers rather </seg>
            <seg id="p076">72 the city, the milkman w ho d mer months that milk does not k. a r ■it sweet and he adslteratei it with forniald to llie d aler. The dealer has 1 aintd 1 J x does a man get win n In Vties they ar is a den, and Prof. Hat n who ha ly .1 demai Bie Dairy I)i\ States w of so that on the European brand or make. E What d( an farmer and tr tad 'pap the profits that n rents ;i pound. Tr the dairyman to make us ■ the creamery line furnis plans of oi Kani7ation and Bd hams: dairy ban not burden von vii Thp Division does not do that .rate with the Dairy D1 viator !&gt;lv because I have followed th thn manufacture of hutfpr. \ have made butter for man\ l&gt;e|ieve r am in position to know about the quality of buttt ■ rly ciean. n, ,t 10 thj ■ i in tht uently tl . man by patting in torn aldeh is goin^ to b n% to demand lK)und. Th lwt will sini|il&gt; sr\ that it ind in co-operation with sta ilonif. Thero is one thinir </seg>
            <seg id="p077">atter. I am here to tell you that the quality of That is wrong. We are going the far as quality is concerned. I: k-ery day we are making poorer butter ever&gt; mean? It simply means that people will not want to say to you that within the last few iropped four and five cents a pound. Why butter. People are willing to pay high willing to pay high prices for i&gt;oor butter arket is being overloaded with undergrade.-; Xot that only. The ordinary con Hitter. You dc n't want poor butter. You sit &gt;d but r and you use a large amount little or none Other people are just like you st like them. There is no means of decreasing the con sooner or later eat oleomargarine in preferenct thereft that these conditions oov \ this state you had i ide butter, but you r i. j s scattered through »ve now changed the Todav you don't i ther it is poor, bu ?em to care a cent whether ihe ereanieryman seems to ke it and continue to take it. There is somethin nd dairymen need to get n. fa tion. You a both interested, but you other until ill have worked up much fric And 1 wa ay to you that the majority of plain as I can state it This matter is md I sincerely hope vou will do so. It is not i tell you what to do* You know the cream is know it that vou arp both d either one c on. A good deal more can lias be n said. Excellent n 1 man r uld be sent over the countr\ better methods. Things are going to when we will make better butter butte il! Tl lads are too slow in carrying our milk and R: Yes and sometimes they are too slow in carrying pa 3ed. The railroads would have reduced -.neers lone ai;o if they could, but they did They did not have enough to keep them busy the fact is they have so much business they cannot handl» has grown so fast, much faster than the not able to handle the traffic: so that part Along the line of furnishing good cream by the </seg>
            <seg id="p078">ou. if you have an\ to off Xi 1 diiection; and sometim ag OTty-flve miles to gather cream V. going to do who furnishes Bra THE SPEAKER: That PROF. HAECKER: Tl MR. FARXAM: Suiipc Eilk any more, then wt R. WHITE: Farmer! lont;. \&lt; &gt;r lator this whole proposit ■the dairy business again and kf «R. I.EIGHTOX: About the I man. I think there is some fault at •:eard the other day of a man bringing 'en sallon cans of mam. He hail his not pay it. He took his cream back •irought It in again to another crean ■ rice the farmer wanted. He took it offered a little better price, but the f l.roueht in in again on Thuredav ;•■:] \v ano i &gt;.f.mf1;iv until Tr i cent better, the farmer held i)' - nnd then got a better price for it by «d it. fI&gt;auBhter&gt;. The price *«■ held it nix days. hen r use th _ . . . , . , - . . with a tank oil a wagon — on ry and dumped In eiior grade and C. porhap Ing tojegulate tha &gt;e his judgment an l.-cideil to grade all PROF HAECKER: </seg>
            <seg id="p079">mi it he had held his cretin ■ leamerymen were so eager for the were so eager for th- amerymen it. but the older it got the higher the price . he older it got the higher the prie - market up. Led the market up. sure the Ant fellow did not offer enough. How did not offer enough * can settle the proposition in this way — you have settle the proposition in this way — you have aw. There is only one thing 1 am sorry about and lere is only one thing 1 am sorry abou ammended more inspectors, I would a.: nit in your benefit. Just as sure as poor imerynian, he will make poor butter. The not recommended more inspectors, I would advise till result in your benefit. Just as sure as poor the creameryman, he will make poor butter. The er: the creamery man will not be the loser— there aineryman will not be the loser— there medy the condition. I would advise you to to remedy the condition. I would advise you to &gt;r this proposed bill tor inspectors and enough of good cream is delivered and manufactured into this proposed bill tor inspectors and enough of ;ood cream is delivered and manufactured into i\v 1 l&gt;elieve you will &lt;1 in the rieih* oad to success t: What do they do in Xe« Yoi . : 1 1 a man lat do they do in S( They prosecute him \i ■11 thai is the way tiny ought to do with mil at is the way they ought to do with mil ■inn in this taulaeav Of cour «et all I can. Sometimes I grt en am that I this bu Of con all I can rfo times I cream that I u Id refuse all oream that would not inak. If I had my way I would Impose ■ fine on th- 1 refuse all cream that would not niak. AKF I had mv way I would Impose a fine on tr at kind of milk or |x&gt;or cream. hi think the creamer? people ship cream to&lt;&gt; bly. If on account of railroad facility iily. If on account of railroad facility liver that cream in .'*ood condition then the « too far. lat cream In good condition then th- ;u : I would like to show mj brother som ■ good would like to show mj brother som ■ good •onie down to oi rv I will show him mery I will show him erean nlle«, and it is the best cream we have ever I v a f l w words in connection with my rental Lind it is th cream we have ever had ;i f w words i onneetion with my rental ; distance. It is a point I believe this con ommendi the Improved quality of am and shipping it to us On VI eceived froM that station the \,,-M cr an- on station man ha~ giv n that work his careful nt:on. and of gifting the cream skimmed thick by the separator, ii thin which accounts for the good quality of c oa»'i as ni'.ich en we started out a year ago to Krad(* cream, it wa articular points and that was density and freoupn^'- of d it thin cream was iniuring the quality and that dflivo Aice p week was also an injury. So. we decided that I </seg>
            <seg id="p080">76 Nebraska Daiuymkn \s it should test not less than l'A) per ceat, in Hut we found, however, that this plan )f our best friends, who live near k perfectly swt right. I believe it would bt in this convention. We want will greatly help to improve the quality of butt A VOICE: It was only a few days ago sir ngton County. They were i morning rreani in with the night cream, and i and sent to O ' can when we did it that way." As long as thai annot gel a roc KROF. HAGCKE t unanimii ■ i &lt; tn be graded ■d out ay thai it w ;is a fin have backed op that the grading of cream is fair, -and it seems to me thai thi th" grading of c .am. We &lt;•; :&lt;i not represent am creanx rj braaka Honestly, I bcl ■ion. and I believe In order to «et on a K ad n. It raise. We mitrht as well aaj I break*. Honestly, I ion. and I beli get on a K ad'! value. We might ■ commodity is f i other commodity la the same. It a ■ graded and until nit sec how we can Impri w n creamery — and 1 dot PROF. ERF: In on&lt;&gt; of our la &amp; fimded and until i do not see how we can own creai PROF. ERF: In on t d man was found one morning a 1 in the paper, a bod; found d man was found on 1 in the paper, turned up missins om' morning. • turned up missing one n in the body. They were well to the l&gt;ody. They were will to do lK)dy carffully concluded that tl. instructions that the undert; loffin he had and have him f ter the undertaker had gone to much trouble he asked th&lt; and see if he was laid out as they d« Tl they were looking at him the lower jaw iled the fact that he had false teeth. ■Why." tl "that is not our father! Our fath </seg>
            <seg id="p081">t i v t r had i ndertaker was somewhat rexad to of laying out the man he would n a rough lox, opened up the nice cof- k. i&gt;ulled him out and threw him you old fool, had you kept your I a decent burial." (Laughter). So, 1 outh shut. I might go away from here :i very hard matter to resist. We as and I believe a little worse than you are the grading system as we are situated at •tern that wi&gt; can adopt, but you hav* sequence has been. It has bsen a loss to I will tell you right now that I know of situation, except legislation. And I hop* Ahich has been discussed hire this morn- .v ; not only for your own good, but also Ue in getting a similar law in our state utor has its difficulties, but th. lifflculties that have arisen lenient and to the few people I am glad to say that there are 0 so into the dairy business. If we had : in the business that then set much in that way. T! an make this business miote that interes o into It would be profitable -n countries they c veryone dairies there •cause almost 'am and they makf y fears about th&lt; do in the • inted I 1 if there are any crean &lt; upon I go around th« &gt;t a great many cream agents cream re the cream business?" "O, fair: r n don't pay the price they ought to to th leering them." The farmer goes in a business where he is being tght flown in our territory, a territory that ation for experiment work. He went now that th experiment station Team?" I tell you to the Experiment hev were being cheated. N'ow. I wish finest example in the world of keeping ere are the books, and here is the man I the man who keeps the books, th ■nt interest of the profits and uch good throughout the oo'intr&gt; yon S'Tid us your ilairymen ramp up </seg>
            <seg id="p082">78 .: 1 s reasnry. They would not gobble up a h th y can do it. That visit did t there. lint what about the result? Tw I did not come to the Experiment Static « riment Station is cheatin Now, gt ntlemen this is all wrong, we ought busini than drive them out of it: and I hope that every cream&lt; not dai &lt;lair w down ml fforts mil rr THi: PRKMDF t AFTERNOON SESSION II 0. Van I ml letnoi s Hoi FEEDING DAIRY COW Prof. Hugh Van Pelt It always giv K;. One reason for this days that are now son sing till seven at night hanical way.— mixing fetd rutting ;ind recklessly throwing out to "act the shortest days I ever spen mv own mind her individual nece i di&lt; ati d would aroust d an nterest and &lt;ntl lollar that you get is paid drectl And that i sit&lt; d the coi imsino K( lit like the orn' ■y fir.d out he is (loins ii of thai kind of Kdpoiat of the feeder, and si to her individual requiri n:&lt; i would have be-.-n t&lt;r- </seg>
            <seg id="p083">ad to have the pleasure of speaking on ast importance of dairy farming in this pg demand for dairy products insuring n and lastly, but of even greater ii re intensive and more economical cott- ars the lumber of milk cows in the United nd numbers, from twelve million to twenty nt. and even at that we find the prices In a recent address on the sub Mr. James J. Hill made the statement, "Ii his moment the United States will have 134, ins an increase in our population of about &lt;"&gt;ft, - dering this fact, and judging from the increast prodsee in the past twenty-six years, one need n to prophesy the great future in store for the increasing demands necessitates a revo- er producing business, of this country. We d&lt; mws. and better methods of feeding. Ov and one-third million milk cows and pra [i pounds of butter a year, but we cannot ur cows produce an average of only 14'&gt; n amount such that if sold on the market the keep of the cow are to be found all over the United States, - imunities and far worse in others. In som ne for her lack of milking ability, but it is to blame for his lack of feeding ability. I asing demands for dairy products it is a dut; dairy industry, and to ourselves as producer the cows we milk and our methods of feedin of cows the milk and butter supply may be ncreased many times. Facts will bear nu ible as well as necessary. To brin t. however, there must be a definite starting home and put forth your best efforts ti rd in the next sixty or ninety days yovi agement. Oows far advanced in lactation ;itisfactory manner to the better care and feed lard to learn an old dog new tricks, and so is ii the milk flow of a cow far advanced in lacta i mind, the first essential and the starting nilk flow of the herd becomes evident. At least time turn the cow dry and give her a rest. Do ause she is not giving milk she needs little care and n d that during this resting period she should be placed paration and training for the coming years work.-much the saim </seg>
            <seg id="p084">80 distinct puriroses for which food and care are suppli First. To complete the growth and development of tt rid. To rest and render most healthful the digest! Second. To rest and render in Third. To store up vigor, ■trength, stamina and fat ir Third. To store up vigor, strength, stamina and fat ifter freshening : after freshening. The feeder should bear in mind the fact that the Ultt The feeder should bear in mind the fact tha gestation marks the greatest growth and developing •ion marks the greatest growth and develoi r he fo« that this growth is mainly of bon- and car-.ilagin that this growth is mainly of bon and other feeding nutrients except protein will suffice ft parts of the infant body. Foods Hke clover on al other feeding nutrii t protein will suffi these parts of the infant body. F i liran, and oil meal, should be suppli. d to furnish thi nutriment to pro|&gt;erly accomplish this purpose, ainl I 1 nutriment to properly accomplish this purpose, and attention would make their a attention were glrm tliis point, fewer weak, puny m would make 1 1 1 • toward calf scours and tb ion towaril ci the dairy cow. All through the period of lactation ! ,,f he heavily tax. d as tl to continuous work ami hi B dairy cow. All through th &gt; heavily I to contin Knowing this to b limner tii ind early winter, so that substitui 1 have a laxati'. I condition, that Indicate Knowing In sunn fall an to use at t condition, that the body. the body. The last porpO Bgth. vigor, stamina and fat that I tninial's body deteri t extent t! - after freshening. Not The lasi pur p. ilmal's body detf after freshening. \ot a l«xir polio to have i I ■ united the covv to lay oi iiise a plethoric condition Invites milk fever, and it ha that was the dairyman'! w very best rows. At the present is no cause for worry, for a ■liilcklr restores the cow to a normal condit those who were certain that when future usefulness, from the producing star trials, however, have proven to m can be stored up in the form of stan the better, as long as such foods are used that do not und Restive organs. It is no difficult mat t the body to the milk pail after the cow freshens, and all the strength and vigor that can be placed in reserve will be called upon during the co ing milkinp period. To accomplish to best ad\ </seg>
            <seg id="p085">81 1 I 1 I :i i a 1 h iv that pro i 1 with corn silage and clove or alfalfa unt will, of course, be governed by the is of the grain mixture. ::0 pounds of silage The bran, oil meal and silage digestive tract, part of the bran, oil meal. are utilized for the growth of the foetus. and is stored up in the body of the cow, i that they go to replenish the vigor and is one of the favorable properties of oats: ther animal they increase the power of per- n tne grain lation should be changed, and must satisfy herself with a few pounds of il meal mixtd op in a mash, for this holds ion at a minimum, and with the water she t prepares the cow for th.' critical tiim t well he will be many times repaid ind well developed calf tugging away at wded to greater proportions than it has ever beer rm the cow's entire svstpni is fpIhyaH anrt uho la lr *'« entire system is relaxed and she is ii dition. The use of bran mashes and heated ntinued for two or three days and the calf should be al the inflammation has left the cow's udder, at a away and taught to drink from the bucket lours after the cow has freshened the ; &gt;r it is at this time that milk fever attack* symptoms of this dreaded disease, which are HI riiiE? in the hind quar - ati d with air and thoroughly robbed and ma - and carefully done there will be no further 1 the cow will soon recover from all effect* a d for her yearlv work o record ft hen the feeder is in a position to take ad instincts if he has successfully prepared the nature of the mother to supply sustenance fir~t thirty days after freshening these in- linence. according for the fact that at ;isk to stimulate the milking functions obstacle in the way even at this time: er and strengthen from the effects of part that heavy feedins at this time will usually her hand, for the cow that has been favored suitable resting period, heavy feeding is un - ler is simply to supply functions of the ill convert the fat of the body into milk and his result a ration rich in protein is neces- t«in stimulates milk production. When the ran mashes to a food more solid, she should </seg>
            <seg id="p086">i meal or otli it this time is mostly of corn and Bher encouraged to fatten. T now tie in which to mi ( com cobs in ti luit Ix'tause the siound cob tidea ol main ;i|&gt;art. thlU all throuu'l mor ■ thoroi k npon "I Nert day. and do th ible hnw a cow wll re ■ grains Kho ilil be eroun (liRfsiid:!. K cperlmentt </seg>
            <seg id="p087">M f mm V I 8 1 | ■o I m I % ? = 1 1 I </seg>
           
            <seg id="p088">1 alone it enters tht t 83 i r ml ither b the (1 d. For fattenn • d lot. but th- ■d lot. but the to conic, so it t and undigestible no &gt;n. ■ .■plies niu. i with the grain I tons of alfalfa hay cut ui ".iuN mixed with tl.. nt that a pound of sood alfalfa hay int of bran and is aqaall] ns of alfalfa hay cut up iii i with th. ind of good alfalfa hay and d the cow il for the vol ■il her feed box b el to adhere to tli&gt; d ration. If he has dose In- I'd her limit l lone b l)od ■ ipoadlt I gain to be found in ideal i d in ideal ;i»K proi livities of iii. mtput of the dairy herd ut of the dairy herd ii-cin.' th.r ■ terrific speed. If this train ine thai pay a penalty so it is all Imj all iin the line. This fireman toM • pcwsda of steam in ord p before 1. Ill he could hold over the enti d that I can k 't Dp onl ■ is Impossible i the run is a slo» trouble keeping o analogous to that nd M pout'ds for tl hat mark dBrtl t her pa-;t that mark dur D pound mark is reached duriu &gt; iv ■ ■ lbs. for tho tirv .&lt;H . </seg>
            <seg id="p089">84 r limit of ability and an to be dc sirid in the work of a Kill and continuous study on ihe part of th« iind ;in occasional ch i slight na as th ■h. while other in weight li d fo it Of C In flesh the first thirty days whin crowded to t thirty i i ir ability The careful feeder, hoi tpMly in fl ! sli he will de too rapid bohydr 01 dittos in to work through t i. £ us. ran of th ■ corn n .imI. When the feeder thus studies d ■ ci for another but •1 ia part ■ pound- i i .lit of hay and &lt;&gt;uld f \o man can il mill individual •t profitable results, and the I nd sila ibilit profitable r a f v ins which I have dealt » &lt;',ive the stions which I r Cive the cow a I and feed her well during this tiin may later be derived from I limp. After freshening, study the and feed her well during this time. After freshening und r your control and work her • rid to get up steam in the form &gt;r this can be done at n Lj Mi carefully, paying particular und r your control and work davs. for this can be done at slowly and carefully, paying par l«latal)ility of the ration fed. at the si :iles and churn, — supplyin suits at the scales and churn, — sup tun a profit and no more. As ti ■stency of milk flow by the use o tun a profit and no more. As the cow a&lt; lacta iK-rsistency of milk flow by the use of a variety of foods. Chan proportion of the protein and carbohyd the ratic w retain her strength and stamina but not become fat. Nothin gratifying than to know the cow is under your control and to know tr flow instead of dependtn. the ration you supply governs tht </seg>
            <seg id="p090">85 ■&gt; 1 lie milking l«riod and rare for h.r untideiit that in a year from the time the v will find you; herd has pratoead fift* ;ui they did th previous. This in th ther or not DISCUSSION. i like to ask you lie t method or rule t&gt; Tin- tlr-t thin Tin- tir-t tiling I to, ationt si\ to turn her out in the |,a rn tor out in the pasture, lint I at milkers and are eery diff'i istent milkers and ar dilT'e:: 1 tli th. rows hink ' ills to ilo would be to gel im ik the b st thing to &lt;lo would be U) I would »ns»'T you fuith t that it i - weeka between the period of la would an A i ii the peril d ol Im is stronger and idition for tl. nl to dry ii|i. if jroa ha lat are hard to dry up. if you 1 pat tilt in on a ration of &lt;I rv food entir. to ;mt them in a dry lot and atao .■\rry oth- r da; ;i' d i tt . r awhile ! 1 ilr j tin. vou set tin- tiinothv li , it wou'd &lt;■■ i'V.t in !■ it them on i lull nt them in ,i dry lot and al»o t j t the timothy 1 n Iowa e timothy hay in NVI.rusVa as «.ll : fat hay in NVI.rusVa as «tll nerally r t inimend brand nia-li' s for I hi the 'iP'-l I .1 ua and I wfB also recomm -nd oil m a. ■ \\ 111 B ;&gt; &gt;'|&gt; i'|i n|i|ietite ai d Rood fk&gt;» of i the re f m.lU sir. thej need varv-i iliev liav oaBt of t 1 -h ■ n a 4 ' orn liild r ru'i or da for ArySnx un niilN" rhi • .'.out it i ■ orn witk it il' wi it 11 ti' I'.!'' ■ti not afraid of eon n« the-n ar </seg>
            <seg id="p091">tlvi .■h*r tube li then is a nick' 1 plated niilk tu ■ king you </seg>
            <seg id="p092">87 Insert th&lt; BU that po another teat, and ill of air. Then take hold of illing the full a&gt; . and whei rt ton 1 out (ii ur n • - ter the calf ot tie milked for a tittt ;t 1 think there is I think yoi r risk the air tr ;r lul f«vt r w rtion of th&gt; like t- i|ip:»ralu&gt; ii sucking. If &gt;. (1 with so nt too lir ation be likely to affiv is thin and d and it would in ,!lk. and I think you wil r fat. I think it i M time in • rtion of th shoulrl tlil&gt; dd«-r. A^ i </seg>
            <seg id="p093">88 ■ n good condition when she comes in PROF HAECKER: 1 would like 1 fever line. I have now been her a i one will bear me out in saving that we ha milk fever in all that tim I trouble by a ver »i the big herds, like the I have but something th not f&gt; ar milk fever d here for t&lt; i lirought on th udder that th* in that way and I do ik THE PRKSIDEN KHE PRESIDENT that you would of the l"n on the banks ■ Nebraska water and and with dairy cows. of mine when 1 was elected l'resk aliout twenty or twenty-fi II ■a i have been just about as much a never lost my interest in th I take a great deal of pleasur. rdder the first two or three &lt;i:. •uking in the mid ■ this rale. MEMBER KdayK, but ind thm I rOF. HAE&lt; MEMBER: B'lild not g&lt;-t op, R vax r: *OF HA1 :' I had hat he knows about our indi MR. WHITMURK: Cntl tuiptined ;i* I am. I I* a 11 surh a way as thi -:iid. "Well, you am a hell of a da </seg>
            <seg id="p094">s cognized in the front have west of the Mi notice that I am carsful to in ned to think that we can say agriculturists in the h School of Agriculture here in or in any other country. (Ap- deal action to me as on? of the old i has been grinding away with not more than twenty fam b these mid-winter me 'tings and of disco ira - it come up to what i: scarcely a 100 n in those premise* big enough to accon a eacea that come her,' manifesting such intense I &lt;!ltur;il work. We a e working ktong strictlv am ienco and rxperinnee meet if th&lt;\ earth, and experience, recorded expert me from y t -a it come her,' manifesting such intense intn oiking along strictly and •deuce and experience meet if th' ice. recorded exi nee from yea t it here, is about all there is in the science. about all there is in the science eel a great deal as the agricultural member and the onl; ld of ' r ' 'h's great University of ours did no of this ert ftt I'niversity of ours did not tulating you the representatives of the agricultural in .1 the representatives of the agricultural in -ka. but 1 feel like asking you in Gods name and in tht nska. but I feel like asking you in Gods name and in tht- ry to bring every possible influence you can to bear ui&gt;oi •re in the Legislature to see that no narrow gang. &gt; ! '1 to govern the Legislature of thK ng every possible influence you can to bear ujx&gt;r ure to see that no narrow gang. n the Legislature of this stait our history. What would yo;i and I think of a farm-r tory. What would you and I think of a farm t splendid half section or more of land with his youni if land with his youna ip around him who. because he happOMi to be in d 'hi ■ or so and his land was worth twenty thousand dollar- around him who. because he happened to be in d"h md his land was worth twenty thousand dollar - the best of credit in his community — if, becaus. lod had the best of credit in his community — if, beeaus. »-■ in d-bt a thousand dollars he would stand up and sa' a thousand dollars he would stand up and sa' t afford to iesd his boys and "iris to school? He would ml his boys and girls to school? He would ■ words of — sometirm s calling a man a fool don't expres- to call him a dam fool. (Laughter). \\"h«n I take th. a dam fool. (Laughter). When I take th. ■ it right here of the state bureau of statistics for last here of the state bureau of st.-ui R tjp S f or la^t a. and read that upon the verv best information obtain the value of the agricultural products of our state for I am surprised that any man or ordinary intelli ad that upon the verv best infor;nation obtain tV a surprised that any man or ordinary intelli iff would sav. •extravagance" when the Reeents of th- report to the gov. rnor appeal to him and the Legis the eov nor appeal to him and the Legis &gt;ropriation aggregatir.g possibly a million dollars for al &gt;n aggregating possibly a million dollars for all ty. Three hundred thirty-seven million dolla-s I'niversity. Three hundred thirty-seven million dollar i all agricultural products alone and what is the paltr&gt; dollars, gentlemen, for promoting educational interest' cultural Ktl alone and what is the paltr&gt; &gt;f a million dollars, gentlemen, for promoting educational interes a biennium. It is absolutely ridiculous, and it ought noi he Regents to go to our legislature and beg for ng th ought to be eager enough in their interest in our state tr </seg>
            <seg id="p095">RM with memtM or iiit'inli 11 Nebraska iifn for the want of dollars \ THE I'RK &gt;air\ man it had COW JUDGING CONTESI Al UU\L MEETING Of TME \EB D4IRYMEVS 4SSOCiaTIOIM •■ allowed to slia » Ajrer \llde Arm i A. Broderic all over each otner in th&lt; I hop' i i] li iii That br \. \V. Alii' \l. R. Reckon Wendell Mrinton Win Bred«hoff </seg>
            <seg id="p096">91 i Kearnev Howells, Lincoln, Bethany, a ! Lincoln, Chapman. Lincoln Albion, Waterloo Waterloo Havelock. Council Bluff la 43 Havelock. N br 45 &lt; &gt;maha, 42 Klkhorn. Lincoln, I Lincoln, Madison. lta&gt; iiionil I'awnee t it) ill •■iil»'ii'«-i- Nebraska Cit i Idvlwil.l A, : Staplehtir t Lincoln. Kavmonii Lincoln Lincoln I IlllVitl) Lpxingt H. Hall . ..Lincoln «:. ffm-ii- .Lincoln SI .Vtn. .lens.ii. ' Miiaha, W. .lame&gt;c.ii . Lincoli I illU|t : I K. .1 u&lt;lkii&gt;~ V.»s! ienr\ ilwmmi . &lt; •malui M. M. H -I Jin-— -n Lim-oli • i Krank Kiiviihlsink I&gt;i&gt;rvli»\-,t« M B. Kinir Vcrk. Krank KI&lt;&gt;|&gt;imiii&gt; Wa&gt;ii&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p097">92 B. V. Kauffraan Rokeby. 4 Val. Kuska Lincoln. 0. W KiiiitTiuan Rokeby D. L. KaulTnian Rokeby . Elmer J. Lamb. . . .Tecumsel C. Lavcrac.k Heaver i I ' \V. I .aw -on Idelwilil. C. B. Lazure Blair B. Murray Mivliani El wo K.I vi . Martin ' Hi. ill, Korrasy Moore Doreht IK' Mullenhoff IK E Myers. Mulloy. Mo M arc Noble Ml'. Newcomb Ii. W. M. Ollis i leroe J. U Pray I'ayn Line John K. Hi ■ Inav Peterson. Hernia L. .1. Poitevin Nord U. Pedrett Kiraba S. 1'hillips Tecuniseh Peck Cozad .J. ( Hoot Omaha. 4 Klbert Rothrock.. Carl is Oao. K. Hitohey Lincoln, 4.1 H. J. Keiiuers Lincoln. J. R. Roberts Normal 41 J. A. Reedy Lincoln. m a 4" 43 Schuyler Ransom Lincoln, B. B. Rice Grand Island. W. D. Stelck Grand Island. C. V. sjogren Funk, 39 Roy Strawn . . Wymorc, 4.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">93 i Clay Center, " « Kagle, '• 41 ciarkson, " 43 a Nehawka, " 45 Funk, " 45 York, • 45 Kdgar, " 41 Grand Island, " 45 Grand Island, ' 45 Anoka, " 3s Lincoln, " 43 Princeton, " 39 Lincoln, " 45 .Lincoln, " 47 Cni. Place, " 41 .Lincoln, " 4« V .Lincoln, " 41 .Broken Bow, " 35 Lincoln, " 17 David City, " 39 Belvidere, " i\ Sutton, :: "uiitf Lincoln, AWARDS IN DA exhibits were judged (scored AWARDS IN DAIRY EXHIBIT judged (scored) by Mr. B. D. ted the dairy division White. an expert in butter, who represented the &lt; of the U. S. depart agriculture at the annual meet the annual meeting. Butter was judged on the 'ol- jrt t icale of points, viz: Flavor 4ii viz: Flavor 45, grain 2-'t. color 15. salting In Peking ."». total MO package and packing ."». total CREAMERY . Lincoln. ■irimry Co., Ravenna life HI 1 BITTER Score. tLf U •:;;; avenna Creamery Co., Loup ( ity i Creamery Co., Loup City. . . DAIRY K crrER ta Stelk, Grand Island Score 94.0 Stelk, Grand Island £ W. KaufTman, Rokebj A Son. T&gt;*.Tington. 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">94 \SKA DAIRYMKN'S ASSOCIATION PRIN T M'TTKR KStrawn, Wymore . . t &amp; Son, Haveloek . s A Son, Lexinsrton 1st prerniun 2d prern prem Beatrice Creamery Co., Lincoln 4th pr ORNAMKN tal ih'ttkr Mrs. c. W. Kauffman. Rokebv The following resolution-, a lions, were adopted: RKSOLVKD. That we are in favor of such ar r Kood Commission law as w i latins; to food, dairy and relating to smrh prod nets a ■ pure food law- by the nat WHKRKA8, Tlie I f« ■ ask for certain appropriat for additional buildii - 11 1 &gt;-»t .it i&lt; &gt;n in the w ■ farmers' institu WHKRKAS, w lay by leading to improved pit our agricultural |n-ople: at EHKRKAS. the investitfat rt of the -.tate and the ii in jrreat benefit to our EHKKKAS. the disseminati Idinif of Fanners' Institut* rihutinj; the results of iti v&lt; stag the agricultural pract &gt; l';i BK IT RKSOLVKD, that the Nebraska Da annual session assembled in connection with urirai that this request for the appropria INN fund of the state makes no unreasonable demanc and we respectfully ur^e upon the le^islat passaji full, without reduction of the amounts requested for any of the purpow - I WHKRKAS, the educational interests of Nebraska have verj lar profited in the past thru the furtherance of agricultural eduestioi »nd equipment fur tin- School Ihe agricultural projrrv** of tl </seg>
            <seg id="p100">95 i ». tha List of i I ) • 'ream Kimtaiiellf Creamery ■ o, Hampton I reamer owth in the demand for agricultural education la ate and is making unusual demands upon th&gt; and. il appropriations made by the legislature of thi* rtlt-ieiit to meet the needs of our university; and. that no money appropriated by the federa development of agricul - education and research: we heartily endorse senat* if the liftv-nintli congress. tile No. tttWtt; intru. vhiefa looks to the fur - n-t of industrial eduea- I.- -ei-retarx of this association be instructed t lion to each meml&gt;er of t'ontfress from thi n every possible way the pasaire of this bill. Creameries and Cheese Factories KXTKALIZKD CRKAMERIKS ( KKAMKH1KS reamerv ( ftfiwroai return in th*&lt; iiimi-i tppropriMed for ul funits for tilt* sii|i|&gt; yt". now established; tihtj &lt;v Supply &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p101">96 Home Dairy Creamery Henderson Creamery . . Lyons Creamery Loup Valley Co-Op. Creamer kmm McGinnis Creamery Meadow Grove Creamery . Vorfolk Creamery Co Seligh Creamery Co Pierce Creamer v In City Creamery Ct irton ( 'reamery ( o Cloud Creamery Co lyler Creanjen, I it Clover Creamery ( Hygenie Dairy Waterloo Creatr ( We»t Point HutUr k CreaiiR CHEESE FA N»m^ \I ,n»t llethany CV»— Factory, (' K. Kettiny Friend Cheese Kact&lt; i ry, &lt; \V Smitli Harbine Cheese Factory. J. M. Wildha I^eijrh Cheese Factory, Jenny Broa Plymouth Cheese Factory, .1 If. Wildha </seg>
            <seg id="p102">97 Two Good Records are those of Karen II and her daughter »• wo Holstein cows in the University of Nebraska dair* duction tables are given in periods of approximate K allows us to mak? a comparison of performance as lac - and shows the uniformity of milk Dow from month to KAKKN II— DROPPED NOVEMBER 10, 189»— CALVElt JANUARY 21, 190«. Puunds Butter l 1* ). 1 »vr f. F KATY OERBEN — DROPPED DECEMBER 7. CALVED JANUARY 13, 190ft Pounds Butter IS 59.34 Mifl IK 12 3.15 50.80 9UR \pr. 14 y 12 10-July 7 28 i:&gt;90.8 3.17 50.47 MM 1557.J 3.22 50 24 MM UBCl 3.25 43.91 51.23 1210.3 3L« 44.56 UM Sept. 1 28 al and avr. . . . 365 18,573.4 3.34 620.44 723.*-. milk Test fat Butter 11C7.1 3.12 60.11 70.13 1K4U.H 33.3 55. 95 1684.2 3.11 63.43 UM l&gt;t. 1 S«?pt. 29 tOOet. 27. 1190.B 3.40 40.50 47.2: n x,, v 24 28 10C6.0 3.57 37.71 44.01 iVDec. 22 28 limn.9 3.65 38.75 46.21 Dec. 23-Jan. 16 25 921.8 3.75 34.67 40.43 milk I8B.1 1*5:!. 1 17H.7 Test 3.54 3.55 (&gt;5.74 (i&lt;t.87 I 1703.9 3.34 37.55 lt&gt;30.7 3.3tt 3.14 H - 51.31 iaw.« 3.10 43.93 1121.3 X2H *&gt;..)7 1U1.8 3.3J L1M.S 3U.69 tu7.2 OS. I 7U.4 :i.4.-&gt; 3.4!t 32.70 29.32 .SMkl 3.40 »01 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">k ■a three-yea ;i two thousa of estimate ulls. Tho' Ka v &lt; '.erl I r f ;i NKHRASKA DaIKYMKN - Katy Gerben excelled her mother Karen II. in 1 production.makinfr * new record for performance a - all breeds. Karen If has in the past five years produced fifty -six thousa hundred a -wo tenths (5«,300.2| pound* of milk at hundred M^Pfchty-one hundredth* i-.VJim.Hl ) pounds •.he has dropped ti»e calves, two heifers and three h - a jrrand cow, her calves are Mill better and Ka o |&gt;erfection. Katy fivsheneii Jan 13, KHHi and prod pounds ef milk and T23.06 p&lt;nin&lt;U of butter. She ha&gt; p« ixiunds estimated butter The following is a cond w&lt; K\H not only the omount of thn l&gt;utter. at twent.\ t ntunn in ••ac' case: TABU Karen II :«'•"&gt; 17,MO,« 3.3« wil M 71)8.18 * Katj Orbeo. 385 l s .."&gt;-;::.4 3.34 83B.44 T.'.! Hiffeii'nce "•&gt;!' Itoth animals tln&gt;w a Bi&gt; exceptionally high. eat up clean. This ac Kialely *70.iMi pt-r cow Both nd this point toirether with ' vim ) liiiiii to t»-at &gt;wo years *he has bera in milk. 29.S41.0 p </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>