<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRCULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA, Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs.</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska BULLETIN or the AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA VOL. XIV. Article IV. Mm and Horses, and Lite on Hogs. By A. T. Peters Distributed Mat 26, 1KK CATTLE DIPPING TANK. LINCOLN. Nl U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CATJLk COMINi </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Psoroptic Scabies of Cattle. By A. T. Peters. HISTORY. There have been numerous reports of a skin disease among cattle and horses from various parts of the State of Nebraska. The first reports received by the department were in 1896. Since then the inquiries have become far more numerous and upon investigation we find that this dis - ease has been prevalent on the ranges of Colorado, Wyo - ming, Montana, and Kansas for a great many years. Dr. If. E. Knowles, in a paper read before the American Veterinary Medical Association in 1900, stated that cattle men had re - ported this disease as existing to some extent for the last twenty years. It was generally regarded by experienced cattle men to be of little or no consequence, but they admit - ted that it had increased in the last two or three years. I have found the same conditions existing in our own State. "A number of reputable cattle men who have been in the range cattle business for thirty years or more believe that the infection came from the buffalo, and describe the disease as having affected the buffalo in the same manner. Old buffalo hunters still residing in Montana have described to me such a skin affection, claiming to have killed buffalo where the hide was worthless from a complete absence of hair, and covered with ulcers. They also relate that the disease ap - peared to be worse on the neck, withers and the base of the tail." 1 This disease is also described by Dr. N. S. Mayo in his Bulletin No. 69, Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station, as early as 1897. He suspects that it was introduced by Texas cattle. I am also informed by cattle men that this disease exists in certain parts of Canada. In our own State the dis- BULL. 74, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR., VOL. XIV., ART. IV. 'Proceedings of the American Veterinary Medical Association of 1900. p. 101. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Mange in Cattle and Hortes, and Lice on Hogs. 4 En confined largely to the range districts. It has spread remarkable rapidity within the last three years. This 36 has been described by European authors as early as CAUSE. Psoroptic Scabies of the ox is a skin disease affecting cat - tle only and is caused by a minute animal parasite, PtoropU* comma ni.s, var. Inn-is. This cattle mite is very closely re - lated to the mite that causes scab in sheep. Both belong to the same genus and species, but are of different varieties. It is not known that the sheep mite ever infects cattle, nor will the cattle mite injure sheep. ibe cattle mite is very small, barely visible to the unaided Ranchmen of long experience with this disease on N&lt; - ska ranges maintain, until shown the little mite, that the ase is due either to freezing in hard winters, or to scar - of food, causing derangement of the stomach. The ; can very readily be detected by scraping the crust of skin with a sharp instrument and allowing this crust to ain from five to ten hours in a clean, wide-mouthed bot- tie. Some white specks will appear on the surface of the glass, which, wh.n examined with a lens, show the details of the para- The accompanying illustra - tion, Fig. 1, shows the cat - tle mite, adult, female; Fig. 2. the first right claw of the same specimen, showing disc more highly magnified. "In young specimens t discs appear to have a per - fect bell form ; in other Fig. 1 — Texas itch mite, Ptor - optes communis. var. boris. Adult female, greatly magnified. 1 (After Mayo.) —First right claw of same :nen. showing disc; more high - ly magnified. (After Ma Simons it appears to have the form of a lily ; while in y adult specimens it has the form oi a trident, as shown he drawing." 2 I have kept specimens of cattle mite Bit should be noted that the disc on second left leg was 'cut out' by l graver." •Kansas Bulletin No. 69, by Dr. N. S. Mayo, p. 104 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs. 5 Fin a small glass bottle in the laboratory at ordinary - temperature from five to eight days. Exposure to bright sunlight seems to kill them in a very short SYMPTOMS. Iittle mange seems to be more troublesome during the fall and winter than at any other time of the year. It illy disappears in the springtime when the cattle are led on the pasture. Cattle of all ages may become affect - &gt;ut the disease seems to be more pronounced in yearlings especially in bulls, because the bulls come in contact 1 most animals on the range, thus being more liable to ction. It has been stated by ranchmen that it is not so , 7 alent after a mild winter, but our experience does not fy that statement. It is certainly not due to lack of I or to severe climatic conditions, but the true cause is cattle mite. The first symptoms noticed are intense itching of the skin, usually in the region of the neck and shoulders, and shed - ding of the hair on the neck and withers. The irritation may extend to the shoulders, the sides of the chest, and in very aggravated cases over the entire body. However, the most prominent points where the disease first appears are, the base of the tail, the neck, withers, and shoulders. The skin becomes thickened and very dry in places. It is not uncommon to find the skin becoming wrinkled, and the hair dropping off, leaving large bald patches of thickened and callous skin. As the disease progresses there is an in - tense itching and the animal will be seen rubbing itself against another or on wire fences or posts, sometimes caus - ing large, bleeding scratches and sores In the advanced stage the animals may be entirely void of hair. This pro - duces anaemia and if the animals are allowed to remain on the range without shelter losses are sure to occur. E wording to Dr. Mayo, if the hair comes off, the parasites that part, the bald area gets well and the hair starts ow again. Animals in the advanced stages of the dis - eat very little. They spend most of the time rubbing selves on posts or licking each^other. This disease spreads very rapidly throughout a herd. Our </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hog*. observation has been that, if animals have been exposed, it takes from four to six weeks before the disease makes its ap - pearance in the herd. It is natural that thrifty animals should resist this disease much longer than cattle in a poor, debilitated condition. There is no doubt that this disease spreads by direct contact of infected with healthy animals. It is also true that railroad cars, stock yards, mangers, sheds, posts, chutes, and fences may be sources of infection. Gerlach and Mueller have remarked 1 on the modifications occurring in this form of scabies by change of season, recit - ing an instance where the disease prevailed among cattle ry year, commencing towards the end of autumn, when the animals began to be housed, reaching its maximum in February, and diminishing in the spring, when the oxen •were employed at labor. The crusts then became detaohed, the hair grew, and there remained only a few patches at the root of the tail and on the neck. The train of symptoms reappeared each autumn. Neumann observed that these parasites (j ) persist during the summer, although the cattle appeared to bn cured. Gerlach and Mueller found the parasites in great numbers on the neck and around the horns. The writer has also found a erreat number of these parasites during the summer months at the base of the horns and on the neck, the animals showing no symptoms whatever of in - convenience from these parasit' I Dr. Knowles in the Proceedings of the American Veteri - 7 Medical Association of 1900 states that he found the ksite in great numbers during the summer months and surprised at the slight amount of skin irritation during time. It must be borne in mind that one must observe r closely to discover the parasites. In three herds in :h the disease had existed during the winter and noth - had been done in the line of treatment, the writer found ng the month of June in every instance the parasites on places named. It may be that these mites seem to dis - ear during the summer months, as the ranchmen have overed, but from our observations they still infest the Eeumsna's Parasites and Parasitic Diseases of Domesticated An- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Mfinge in Cattle and Horse*, and Lice on Hoy* animal, but cause no noticeable inconvenience during this hence, it must be that they feed on the surface hair of the animal; whereas, during the fall of the year a begin to burrow into the skin and produce this hi itching TREATMKNT. The problem of successfully stamping out this disease on our ranges is a very serious one. When only a small num - ber of animals are to be treated, any efficient liquid remedy can be successfully applied by means of a swab, brush, or f pump. This method has been employed in controlling lisease on the average ranch for a number of y neen found to be both expensive and impracti* Hies necessary to so over a large herd of affected with mange, then the above method will be found wholly inadequate. Therefore I believe there is but on. tion of this problem, one practical and certain way to wipe oat rouble on our ranges, and that is to erect dipping so that cattle can be thoroughly immersed in a solution that will kill these mites and yet be harmless to the animal. Dip - ping is becoming very popular, wholly on account of its prac - ticability. Dipping tanks are now a common sight on our s in the western part of the S' ittle men a: ginning to dip, at regular periods, cattle affected with mange, the same as sheep affected with scab are dipped. Baere are a number of co-operative dipping tanks in op - ion in different parts of the grazing country in our v Fig. 3. -Ground plan of the oattle dipping plant I they have proven to be a great benefit to the wers wherever they have been operated. The operation dipping cattle is not a difficult one but is precisely like t of dipping sheep. All that is necessary is a crowding i and a corral with a chute leading to the tank, the end of the chute is a sloping surface on which the ani- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 .r/ d TIQ€ lit O CL% ( *c (2 flu XI Or&amp;Ko, CLnOL X- 10c OJl xj OQ $ . mal slides into the tank, swimming through the preparation. See that the head as well as the body is thoroughly immer- A simple plunge in and out of the bath is sufficient for or ticks, but immersion of from one to three minu'es should be given for mange The process of simply dipping in v without the previous breaking down of the scales with brush or broom, will not allow the liquid to reach and destroy tin - ova and young acari, and their continued presence must in - evitably cause the itch to reappear after a short time. I this reason it is well to insist on the breaking up and moval of the scab by means of a scrubbing brush or broom before dipping in vats. It is well to leave the animal in tank from a minute to a minute and a half, and in very bad cases I would suggest longer On reaching the other end of the tank the animal ascen Is another inclined surface, which starts at the bottom of the tank, and which has cro - to help the animal's progress, as he walks into a dripping pen. The cattle are allowed to remain in this pen for a few minutes for draining off and then they are turned out. The 'tu-fluous dip is allowed to run back into the tank or vat, as the floor of the dripping pen has a slope toward the tank for that purpose. In order to make this operation a success the dipping should be repeated within ten days, to kill the parasites hatched out in the meantime before they become old enough to lay their eggs. The same process is employed that is used in eradicating scab in sheep, regardless of the kind of dip used, for the life histories of the parasites are practical - ly the same. Cows and heifers heavy with calf should not be dipped after they are more than three or four months advanced, and even previous to that time care should be taken to avoid crowding in the chutes. The plunge itself does not seem to be of any consequence. We have found that warm solutions are practicable when - ever they can be employed. The temperature should be from 110' to ilo° Fahr. Of course this depends largely on the local atmospheric conditions and somewhat on the condition of the cattle. The cost of dipping has varied from five to eight cents per head for each dipping and the results have </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Mange in Cattle and Hones, and Lice on Hogt 9 been most gratifying, so that no stockman should allow his cattle to go through the winter without dipping them. THE BEST TIME TO DIP. I is advisable to dip cattle twice in the fall and again e in the spring of the year at intervals of ten or twelve i. Usually we find that it is difficult to persuade owners ip cattle twice at an interval of ten or twelve days. We this to be especially the case when the herd shows no ked symptoms of the disease. Experience has taught us it is best to dip twice in the fall of the year regar le condition of the cattle. In the spring of the year there lot so much necessity of dipping twice, as the animals not then so liable to reinfection as in the fall and winter. There are numerous dips on the market at the present time, and, no doubt, they all have some merit, but there have been a great many failures in dipping, possibly due to the fact that the dip was not efficient. We have made ex - tensive experiments with the coal tar preparations and have found them effectual to cure cattle mange. The dips that have been employed by us are chloro-naptholeum and zeno - leum. When using coal tar preparations, such as zenoleum or chloro-naptholeum, it is well to test the water. Where soft water cannot be obtained, add to the hard water suffi - cient washing soda or sal soda to break the water. This is best done by taking a small sample of water and determining whether it will saponify readily; otherwise these prepa - rations will not perfectly mix with the water. IiTe have conducted experiments in which we have dipped en thousand head of cattle with chloro-naptholeum that ■e very much affected with cattle mange, and the results ■e been very satisfactory. We have numerous letters on from parties who have dipped with the same prepa - ions and have had good results. There have been a few iplaints made of cattle becoming reinfected in a short e after being dipped. Stockmen that have gone to the &gt;ense of erecting a dipping vat and using dips of various ds on cattle once or twice and then have found that in tiort time their cattle showed unmistakable symptoms of </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 reinfection have sometimes lost faith in the efficacy of the dip and method of dipping. The reason for these rein! tions may be illustrated thus, — Mr. A has done his part in dipping the cattle to eradicate this disease; his neighbor be - ing the disease not a contagious one will not dip but will allow his cattle to roam at large, and thus Mr. A's cattle be - :ie newly infected by his neighbor's cattle. I have had my attention called to a number of just such c This, of course, cannot be the fault of any of the preparations in which the cattle were dipped. Failures have also reso in the use of these dips because the solution was not of - proper strength and the capacity of the tank not accurately mated. The parties were under the impression when dipping their cattle that the solution was of required strength, about 3^ per cent, but upon examination I found these solutions were less than '2 per cent and on I account no good results were obtained. I further beli that, when cattle are in the advai: of the dis - and have large areas of crust, it is advisable, no mai what dip is used, to have the fluid in the vat warm. It the penetrating power of the dip and certainly ilts. Iie benefits that are received from the use of dips are ■ numerous. One of the old ranchmen in western Ne - ka stated that since he had dipped his cattle they had e larger gains than in any previous year since he had i in the stock business. Another ranchmen stated that a number of years since he began dipping cattle he id that it is not only beneficial in the destruction of ge but that it is also very beneficial in ridding the cattle ce in the summer time, and it lessens the liability of be - molested by flies and gnats. A 4 per cent solution of chloro-naptholeum was used in our field experiments and we recommend that these coal tar preparations be used at that strength. I have known in - stances where a much stronger solution of these coal tar preparations was used by mistake without any injurious ef - fects on the animal. There is no danger at all conii with the operation of dipping. However, it is not advisable to dip animals that are in the advanced stages of pregnancy </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs. 11 Ifter cattle have been dipped they should not be allowed e down in the old infected corral, nor to mingle with dis - d cattle. It is better to wait for some time before tak - them back to the old range to feed. If these precautions not heeded I doubt whether one or two dippings with the • best dip that could be secured would assure the ov )lute safety from reinfection. For thi n it is of it importance to use all necessary precaution against reinfection ; otherwise the procedure of trying to stamp this disease becomes very expensive and discouraging. In conclusion I wish to mention a few conditions resulting from mango. The writer has seen numerous herds that reported to be dying with some mysterious disease. These animals were a pitiful sight to behold. They were thin, iated, very much debilitated, and hardly able to exist under range conditions of the most favorable kind, simply i hey were one mass of running sores and i They were too poor to go over a large territory each d pick up their food, and soon would die. Trw also ts of infection to the remainder of the herd and cially to the young stock. Animals that have been at 1 with mange need more and better food to carry them through the winter months. Pimatic conditions are of great importance. Animals ted with a very bad case of mange very often die I storms, because they have lost the natural protection, hair. The young calf crop is also an important consider in mangy herds. It stands to reason that cows affected with mange and having to endure some of the above-named con - ditions are very apt to abort. The writer has seen a num - ber of herds on the range in which abortion occurred on ac - count of lack of vitality to* carry the young the full time. The writer has also observed that when mange existed in herds it was not uncommon to find that the young calves were born weak and with less vitality. For this reason a large number of them would die three or four days afterbirth with what is commonly known as calf cholera or white scour - is also a fact that in herds where mange exists the fir - imal to become infected is the bull. If nothing is done to </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Mange in Cattle and Horse*, and Lice on Hog: 12 E r e the bull of this parasite, he will soon run down in and, if allowed to remain in the herd, not only will he s the whole herd but his get will be of inferior quality. Taking economy into consideration, we find it costs con - siderably more per head to winter animals affected with this disease. The facts that are in favor of dipping cattle^for mange are overwhelming. In conclusion, I wish to say that dipping is, on general principles, a treatment that is most beneficial to cattle and one that will certainly become more fully recognized in the future. A ranchman that has seen its effects in the healthy, glossy coat of an animal regularly dipped will not hesitate to put his herd through the dipping vat. The appearance of animals that have been dipped speaks for the efficacy of this treatment LICE ON CATTLE I 4. — Short nosed ox louse, -—Hcematopirms eurytternut ■■ a, f ■rum; e, ventral surface of the &gt;-nts of male; d, same '&lt; female; e, ejfg; f. surface of same greatly enlarged. (From Osbom, I S. Dept of Art. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Mange in Cattle and Hones, and Lice on Hog* 13 Pig. 4 is an illustration of the short-nosed ox louse found on our ranges. Fig. 5 represents the long nosed ox louse, which we find to be just as numerous. The meth - ods employed in eradicating scab are just as successfully used in destroying lice on cattle, and there - fore should be used to protect the stock against these parasit DESCRIPTION OF A DIPPING VAT. Fig. 5. — Long-nosed ox louse,- Hamatopxnua vitu "We manufacture a dipping vat it: female, under surface - . ~ , . , , jjjj of last segments of abdo- madeof 2-inch lumber and dadoed n» n of same, showing and dowel pinned staves, in the bnish-1 ike or trans — en- , , larked. (From Osborn, U. same manner as a supply tank 18 pt. of Agr.) made, with four girts or ribs on each side. The top rib is a 4x4; the others are 2x6 stuff. B&gt; pass through the bottom of the vat holding the staves on tight. The ladder end is 15 feet long and well cleated, mak - ing exit for the animal easy. Six bolts pass through the vat just under the ladder, making a strong clamp. Three bolts pass through the vat at the square end, holding that portion firm. The top 2 feet of the staves are tongued and grooved, to save the splash in case the staves shrink in that part that stands above the ground and above the liquid. This vat is 24 feet long at the top, 9 feet high, 18 inches wide at the bottom and 46 inches wide at the top. When filled to the depth of 6 feet it holds 1520 gallons. The slide is made of 2-inch stuff with sides of the same material. The bottom of the slide is covered with galvanized iron and when kept wet is very slippery. This slide is 24 inches wide and 90 inches long, with a lip of iron that fastens on the under side of the slide to the vat to prevent a leak. This slide enters the vat at the 6-foot or liquid line, thus avoiding the splash and danger of the former trip board that threw the animal down three feet to the liquid and often out into the center of the vat. Now he slides in at the end with - out jar and gets the benefit of its whole length. The top </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs l i I •N I ;—#.?—&lt; ! MX, ,^__^^_ _____ —1 I _i llJ _ i s o i^ n -H J^ FR- i . — m 1_ -- * . - i TIT rnTa ■^ Q Ti^ 1 S </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs. 15 edge of this sHde should be even with the top of the ground, so that the animal walks in on the level from the chute and crowding pens, until he touches the iron and sli ly in - to the tank. The draining pen should be made 16 feet square, of 2-inch material tongued and grooved. This floor or pen should be divided into two parts of equal size, with a gate that will swing each way on the center fenct on*&gt; pen can be filled while the other is draining. W&lt; make seven strii go under this floor, which are con - cave so as to cause this floor to dish to the center; then by having the outer end of the floor about 8 inches higher than at the vat, the liquid will first run to the center, then back to at. This floor should be so placed that ti plank shall just rest on and lap over the end of the v. t hat there will be no place for the liquid to leak out. Around &lt;lge of this floor should be nailed a strip of 2-inch to prevent the liquid from running off the floor. Build a good high fence around this floor. I The chute leading to the vat should be not less th : long besides wings or crowding pen at the outei ; last 10 feet of the chute, which contains the slide, uld be tight and smooth, so that after the animal !&gt;• lide nothing in the construction will give him a chai •h anywhere and hang with his weight down in th&lt; s chute should be just 2 feet wide at the bottom and ugh at the top to allow a large animal to paw. A chute feet long with wings S feet long and material to f«" r as stated above, will require 55 posts 2x6-16, 8 posts -12 and 22 good 10-foot posts. "DIRECTIONS FOR SETTING VI' A DIPPINU VAT. "Excavate a hole 8 feet deep, 24 feet long at the top, 13 feet long at the bottom, 3 feet wide at bottom and 5 feet wide at the top. Place the bottom of vat within a few f - the pit as near level as you can, and block it up from the ground three or four inches. Place the square end anci it with a brace; then, as you stand at the outside looking at the square end, on the left side place the staves that are let - tered and on the right side those that are numbered, b nin" with the letter A and the fi ir ure 1 vou place a </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lite on Hogs. stave, tack the lower end — after the dowel pin has been placed — to the bottom of vat, but leave the nail out far enough to be drawn later on. When the long staves have been placed and you have reached the other end of the bot - tom, place the ladder with the foot just to a line marked on the bottom and raise the outer end up eight feet and prop there. Put on staves enough to reach out to where the second rib from the bottom will extend, place the 2x4 on each side and tack parallel with the ladder. Put the cross pieces on and tighten enough to hold the vat in shape. Draw the nails in lower end of the staves, place the lower rib and the bolts that pass through the vat. Do not tighten any of the side bolts until the vat has been completed and tightened at the end rods. The other ribs can now be placed and the balance of the staves. The cut on lower end of the stave will show you as to the height of the ladder, as the edge of the ladder and end of staves should be even when the staves are all placed and the long bolts all entered and drawn up. Go on the inside of vat, and should there be any signs of an opening under the foot of the ladder, drive in a little oakum (placed in the box of bolts for that pur - pose), then place the block over the foot of ladder and turn down the lag screws. Place the slide flush with the inside of the vat, nail the iron down on the under side and nail the sides to the vat. ' 'By Forest Lumber Company, Geo. W. Clark, Agent, "Alliance, Nebraska." Pie material required for the tank proper will amount to following: 550 feet of 2x12 tank lumber, 100 feet 2x6 yellow or white pine, 80 feet 4x4 and 64 feet 3x4. Twenty pounds of 20-penny nails will be required besides the iron bolts purchased of the company. The cost of this material will be governed by the local market prices. rtie pig dipping tank shown in accompanying cut may constructed similarly to the cattle tank heretofore described. A galvanized tank can be built by any tinner or can be purchased on the market from firms handling dips, and may be used in place of the wooden one, but the setting and approaches will remain the same. The iron tank is highly recommended on account of its cheapness and dura- </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">18 Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs. bility in all kinds of weather and climate. A wooden tank will require 240 feet 2x12 tank lumber, 12 feet 4x6 white pine or tank lumber, 40 feet 4x4, 16 feet 2x6, 16 feet 2x4, J4 feet 3x4. For the approaches and dripping board will be required 10 feet 2x12 tank lumber, 100 feet 4x4 yellow pine, 60 feet 2x6, 114 feet 2x4, 162 feet fencing, 17 pounds penny nails and 7 pounds 10-penny nails, 10 square t zinc, 4 T hinges 8 inches. A canvas curtain hung at the juncture of the crowding pen and the slide will serve as a blind and facilitate the driving of the animals. til details of construction may be ascertained from the ac - panying cut (page 17.) Sarcoptic Scabies in horses is a disease similar to the one described in cattle, the difference being in the mite. The ecord that we have of this disease existing in our State is in 1895. It has not spread very rapidly in this State and has existed in very few herds. SYMPTOMS. The animals are found rubbing themselves against fence posts, sheds, wire fences, and the like. Upon closer exam - ination one will find the skin elevated and somewhat rough. A number of elevations and many papules around which the hair has matted can be felt. When the crust is removed it leaves a moist, red surface. These papules increase in number and cause intense itching. With the loss of hair large, dry areas are formed covered with debris and thin crusts. These patches extend, and finally invade the entire surface of the body. I have not seen a case where the dis - ease extended to the knees of the animal. The coat of the animal is dead and over a large portion of the body aggra - vating ulcers and sores are seen. These ulcers vary in size from that of an inch to five inches in diameter. The skin in - variably becomes thickened, especially in the region of the neck, where it is attached by loose connective tissue and then appears in very large folds The irritation induced by rubbing and scraping is the important factor in extending the lesions of the skin. ■i, Hi uses </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Mange in Cattle and Horten. and Liee on Hog* 19 144 The young larvae and the ovigerous females live in the intra-epidermic galleries or grooves which, in man, are indicated by a fine red line, from 10 mm. to 20 mm. long. These galleries are not ible in the horse, because of the pigmentation of the skin and the thiel the epidermis. They are ivated by the female immediately after copula - tion; and they are rapidly formed, for in from 1 he work is i pleted, and all the i promptly if the tempera - ture br i. It ifl for this reason that tl ■ asites have been consid&lt; noctambulent; if I torment animals more by night than by day, it li cause then the condit of temperature — warm stable, litter, and probably clothing — are more fa able. At the point w tli«* sarcopt peseta inflammatory papule fo but the parasite is not to be found beneath it, but at the other extremity of its gal - lery. ' Our experience with the disease has taught us that it exists in both warm and^cold weather. K6 — Sanopt of man. A fecundated e («) forming its nailery or burrow A iliaciammaiic figure partly aft From before to behind are seen the Increasingly older III, thtn empty egg cases. e\ o. opening for tbe e of the larTa; e, excrements. (Afte-r tann ) We have employed the same method that Dr. Knowles iNeumann's Parasites and Parasitic Diseases of Domesticated An - imals d 188 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Aiiingc itt (s(xtti£ and Hot8€9. Qtid l^tcc on Hoqz prescribes in the Proceedings of the American Veterinary Medical Association of 1900, namely, that of scraping. His method has been very satisfactory and we give it in full. "During cold or windy weather it is extremely diffi - cult to discover the sarcoptes ; therefore, to not meet with disappointment it is advisable to have warm, sunshiny weather in which to make the search. It is necessary to make skin-scrapings to the blood and through the entire thickness of the epidermis with a sharp instrument. When the scrapings have been collected, they should be placed in a well-heated box, or in a window exposed to a strong sun - light. A small quantity of the debris, after it is well warmed, can be spread on a slide, and examined with a mi - croscope with one-third or two-thirds objective. Should the slide and stage be warm, the sarcoptes will disengage them - s from the debris, when they may be removed with a needle and placed with a drop of glycerine on another ." Fig 6. (page 19) shows how this mite bur - rows under the skin and produces these tunnels mentioned above. We have had the very best success by using the coal tar preparations, either as a wash or as a dip, using them at a four per cent solution. In the several hundred cases treated, we have had success with one application of dip, but I would recommend two dippings in very severe cases. The same kinds of tanks and dips that are employed in the eradication of mange in cattle are very successfully used in the eradication of mange in horses. (See prepara - tion of tanks and dips in eradication of mange in cattle. ) The Value of Dipping Hogs for Lire. It has been known to the intelligent hog breeder that the presence of insects on the hog is a very serious matter. It is a fact that very few hogs are free from lice, and that breeders have been accustomed to use various remedies for the destruction of the pest. The favorite seats of lice on the hog are back of the ears, along the neck and under the beast. These vermin are bloodsuckers, and they produce in a short time a very weak, debilitated condition of the animal, mak- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Mange in Cattle and Hortea, and Lice on Hog* 21 ing him far more susceptible to other diseases that the an - imal is heir to. The louse has not been credited with occa - sioning serious loss, but of late years more attention has been given to this little insect by the Department of imal Pathology. We have found that the hog louse becomes a more serious enemy when hogs are out of condition, above stated, it is a bloodsucking insect. If the accom - panying conditions are bad, especially if the pens ar cessively dusty and through the inhalation of an exct amount of dust there should be a slight pneumonia of the lungs, the animals badly affected with lice will be all the more apt to die. apt to die. E. T. — Hog louse,— Hiematopinut urius: a, femu atral Tiew terior segments of male; c, leg, showing protractile disk of tibia, e&lt;l. (From Osborn, U. S. Dept. of Agr.) We have also found that where animals affected with cholera were free from lice there was a much smaller per - centage of loss sustained than where the herds were largely affected with lice. This has been brought to our attention after examining numerous herds in various parts of the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 jaCLnQt xn Cattle and Hovsei, and L\C6 on Hogs- Eduring the last five years. The first rule that we now upon when we visit an outbreak of cholera is to ex - ; for lice and, if present, to thoroughly destroy these I s. The breeding pens and hog houses are also thor - oughly disinfected. All the bedding that is found in pens and hog houses at time of disinfection is burned. The method that we have for disinfecting the hog pens and hog hous&gt; follows: For the stables we prefer to use hot water and any of the coal tar preparations, such as zenoloum, So-naptholeum, and similar preparations. This i&gt; - by making a 3 per cent solution of either of these prep - ins and using it liberally with broom and brush and with a spray pump. If you have any of the spray )S used for spraying trees they will answer the purpose rably. Efter the stables and pens are thoroughly disinfected the uals should be disinfected also. This can be done by . jing them, which is a far easier method than any other. Of course it necessitates a dipping tank. These dipping tanks can be bought on the market very reasonably. If one is not in favor of using the dipping tank, or does not feel warranted in spending the amount that it would cost to pur - one, a spray pump will do the work; but in spraying hogs one should have them on a wooden floor and must have quite a large and forcible pump, so that they can be thor - oughly saturated with the liquid. If sprayed, they should also be rubbed with a broom immediately so that the fluid will soak well into the skin. The solution that we recommend is from 3 to 4 per cent for grown hogs and about 3 per cent for small pigs. In our experience we have not found any harm resulting from dipping very young pigs. Spraying and dipping for lice can be highly recommend - ed, as it is the only safe, rational thing to do if hogs are in any way infested with lice; and, as stated above, there is not a breeder of hogs who has not been troubled with this insect. The remedy is to dip, and dip often. It aids the very best balanced ration that can be given to a hog, by en - abling him to thrive and assimilate the food administered. Breeders who have begun to dip their hogs find it very eco - nomical and a very efficient method of ridding the animals </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Khese insects. The coal tar preparations which have i mentioned — chloro-naptholeum, zenoleum, Lincoln dip, Lee's carbolic dip — leave the skin in a very soft, pliable lition, and I believe that it is a very economical and sen- sible way out of this difficulty. In conclusion, I desire to say that I do not wish to convey I idea in this article that it is absolutely necessary to pro - s a dipping tank. I have known instances where our arican farmer, with his genius for making theme surroundings, has soon improvised a proper dipping c with a very little cost. It is the purpose of the writer to urge every grower of swine to dip his hogs at least i Se to four weeks to have the very best success, and also se liberally any of these dips in his hog pens; and he attain the very best results and in a great measure pre- vent infectious diseases from gaining any foothold on his premises. We herewith mention some of the well-known sheep dips {, have been tried by the Government and found very jtual in the eradication of scab among sheep. However, sh to state that the lime-and-sulphur dips are somewhat ajerous. They must be prepared exactly according to formula given, for, if not, they are liable to produce bad ilts. It is not uncommon to find cattle with eyes swol - shut after being dipped in too strong a solution of lime and sulphur KEROSENE EMULSION DIP Hard soap or whale oil i pound Water 1 gallon Kerosene 2 gallons Dissolve the soap in boiling water and while still hot add the kerosene and agitate thoroughly until cool, when the stock emulsion thus obtained should be of the consistency of thick cream and without the presence of free kerosene. When ready for use, dissolve in about twenty times its vol- ume of water. "LIME-AND-SULPHUR DIPS Under the term 'lime-and-sulphur dips' is included a K Department ol Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bui- No. 31. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Mange in Cattle and Hortei, and Lice on Hog* large number of different formulae requiring lime and sul- phur in different proportions. In general practice all of these dips are spoken of as 'the lime-and-sulphur dip, ' but in reality each separate formula represents a separate dip. "To give an idea of the variety of the lime-and-sulphur dips, the following list is quoted, the ingredients being re- duced in all cases to avoirdupois pounds and United States gallons : "1. The original 'Victorian lime-and-sulphur dip' pro- posed by Dr. Rowe, adopted as official in Australia : Flowers of sulphur 20| pounds Fresh slaked lime 10^ pounds Water 100 gallons "2. South African (Cape Town) official lime-and sulphur (ill') * Flowers of sulphur i minimum ; 15 pounds Unslaked lime 16 pounds Water 100 gallons "3. South African (Cape Town) official lime-and-sulphur dip, February 4, 1897 Flowers of sulphur 21 pounds Unslaked lime ... 16} pounds Water 100 gallons "4. Nevada lime-and-sulphur dip: Flowers of sulphur 16} pounds Lime SMJ pounds Water 100 gallons "5. Fort Collins lime-and-sulphur dip : Flowers of sulphur 38 pounds Unslaked lime 11 pounds Water 100 gallons "6. A mixture which, used to some extent by this Bu- reau, contains the same proportions of lime and sulphur (namely, 1 to 3) as the Fort Collins dip, but the quantities are reduced to : Flowers of sulphur 24 pounds Unslaked lime 8 pounds Water ... ..100 gallons </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Mange in Cattle and Hortes, and Lice on Hog: 25 DANGEROUS FORMULAE. California lime-and-sulphur dip : Flowers of sulphur 100 pounds Lime 35 pounds Water 100 gallons "8. A very dangerous misprinted formula to be found in several books and journals, probably due to a typographical error : "In case of fresh scab, formula No. 6 will act as efficacious - ly as the dips with a greater amount of lime, but in cases of very hard scab a stronger dip, as the Fort Collins dip, should be preferred, or, in unusually severe cases, an ooze with more lime in proportion to the amount of sulphur, such as the Victorian (No. 1), the Nevada (No. 4), or the South African (No. 3) dip might be used. "Many other formulae might be cited, but these are enough to show the great variations in the dips which have been used ; and to prove that when a party simply states that 'liiue and sulphur' is an excellent dip, or that it is a dangerous dip, or that he has succeeded or failed with it, or that the lime-and-sulphur dip is injurious to the wool, his statements cannot be taken as definite, unless he also states which lime-and-sulphur dip he used and how he used it * "If a lime-and-sulphur dip is chosen, it is better for or - dinary cases to use the solutions containing a small amount of lime and three times as much sulphur as lime, as the Fort Collins formula (33 pounds of sulphur and 11 pounds of lime to every 100 gallons of water) or the Bureau of Animal Industry formula (No. 6) (24 pounds of sulphur and 8 pounds of lime to 100 gallons^of water), rather than the formula with a greater proportion of lime. "If the stronger solutions, as the Victorian formula 1), or the present South African formula (No. 3), or the Ne - vada formula (No. 4) are used at all, their use should be con- Flowers of sulphur 100 pounds Lime 150 pounds Water 100 gallons </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Mange in Cattle and Horse*, and Lice on Hog*. 26 stances should the California formula (No. 7) or formula No. 8 be used. They are too strong, and the latter is espe - cially liable to kill the sheep. * * *. "PREPARATION OF THE MIXTURE. ''Almost as many different methods of preparing the liquid exist as there are different formulae, some of the methods laying great stress upon sifting both the lime and sulphur, others laying great stress upon allowing the liquid to settle, others leaving out of consideration both of these points. The method ■which has been found in the Bureau to be the easiest and most satisfactory is as follows : "A. Take 8 to 11 pounds of unslacked lime, place it in a mortar box or a kettle or pail of some kind, and add enough water to slake the lime and form a 'lime paste' or 'lime putty." ' 'B. Sift into this lime paste three times as many pounds of flowers of sulphur as used of lime, and stir the mixture well. Ee sure to weigh both the lime and the sulphur. Do not to measuring them in a bucket or to guessing at the IC. Place the sulphur-lime paste in a kettle or boiler i about 25 to 30 gallons of boiling water, and boil the ture for two hours at least, stirring the liquid and sedi - it. The boiling should be continued until the sulphur ppears, or almost disappears, from the surface ; the solu - is then of a chocolate or liver color. The longer the ition boils the more the sulphur is dissolved, and the less stic the ooze becomes. Most writers advise boiling from ty to forty minutes, but we obtain a much better ooze by ing from two to three hours, adding water when neces- "D. Pour the mixture and sediment into a tub or barrel 1 Many persons prefer to slake the lime to a powder, which is to be •ifted and mixed with sifted sulphur. One pint of water will slake three pounds of lime if the slaking is performed slowly and carefully. As a role, however, it is necessary to use more water. This method takes more time and requires more work than the one given above, and does not give any better results. If the boiled solution is allowed to settle the ooze will be equally as safe " </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Mange in Cattle and Horse.*, and Lice on Hog* 27 placed near the dipping vat and provided with a bunghole about four inches from the bottom, and allow ample time (two to three hours, or more if necessary) to settle. ' 'The use of some sort of settling tank provided with a bunghole is an absolute necessity, unless the boiler is so ar - ranged that it may be used both for boiling and settling. An ordinary kerosene oil barrel will answer very well as a small settling tank. To insert a spigot about three to four inches from the bottom is an easy matter. Draining off the liquid through a spigot has the great advantage over dip - ping it out in that less commotion occurs in the liquid, which therefore remains freer from sedinif nt. ■ "E. When fully settled, draw off the clear liquid into the dipping vat and add enough warm water to make li ! Ions. The sediment in the barrel may then be mixed with water and used as a disinfectant. I should it l&gt;r used fin dippii "A double precaution -* allowing the sediment to enter the vat is to strain tne liquid through ordinary bag - ging as it is drawn from the barrel. "In watching the preparation of lime-and-sulphur di| other parties the Bureau investigators have found some per - sons who laid great stress upon stirring the sediment w»ll with the liquid before using the ooze. This custom is un - doubtedly responsible for a great deal of the prejudice which exists at present against lime and-sulphur dips; and considering the preparation of these dips in this way there is no wonder at the immense prejudice against then in cer - tain quarters." Accepted for publication April 1_, Erratum — Foot note on page 23 refers to the extended quotation beginning with headline "Lime and Sulpher I </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030">No. 19. 'Farm Notes for 1891." No 21. -'Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska. No. Jb, 'Detassellne Corn." 1 K 'Experiments in tbe Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska "Cost of Farm Crops." • No. 10, "The Influence of Changes of Food and Temperature on the {Quantity ami Quality of the Milk of Dairy Cows." No. 32, "Wheat and Some of Its Products." No. JS. '"Meteorological Observations for 1893." No. M, "Chinch Bugs." No St. "Experiments In the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska No. 17, "Nebraska Weather Review for 1894." S "Nebraska and the Beet Sugar Industry. Report of Dr. Max Hollrung. Halle. rmany. Translated from 'Zeitschrift des Vereins tuer Ruebenzucker Industrie i Deutschen Beichs." 1 No. 39, "Some Obstacles to Successful Fruit Growing." No. 40, "A Preliminary List of tbe Honey-Producing Plants of Nebraska." N'o. 41, "Water Supply In Nebraska." No. 42, "Nebraska Weather Review for 1896." No. «, "The Conservation of Soil Moisture by Means of Subsoil Plowing. " No. 44, "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska." No. 46, "The Rainfall of Nebraska." No. 48, "Nebraska Weather and Climate for 1896." No. 48. "Windbreaks." K "Suggestions for Chicory Culture." "Notes on Pruning;." B, "Observations on the Codling-Moth." . "Cornstalk Disease." No. S3, "A Preliminary Report on Experiments with Forage Crops." No. 54, "The Effect of Certain Method* of Soil Treatment Upon the Corn Crop.** No. 56, "Ornamental Planting." No. 56. 'Methods of Tree Planting." K, "Proceedings of Agricultural Students' Association, 1898-1899." , "Annual Forage Plants for Summer Pasture." No. 59. "The Homemade Windmills of Nebraska." No. 80, "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska. No. tl, "Hungarian Brome Grass (Bromut intrmit)." No. 86, "Blackleg, Its Nature, Cause and Prevention." No. 60, "Sheep Feeding Experiments in Nebraska." No. 07, "Experiments In the Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska." No. 68, "Feeding Skim-Milk to Calves." ■09, "Some Forage Plants for Summer Feed." 70, "Locusts or Grasshoppers." No. 71, "Sheep Feeding Experiments in Nebraska." No. 72. "The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat." No. 71, "Experiments In the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska." Address, AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION, </seg>
            <seg id="p031">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD THI RiatNTt OF THC UNIVERSITY ) E. v. FORELL, President, Kearney GEO. F. KENOWER, Wisner EDSON C. RICH, Omaha JOHN L. TEETERS, Lincoln E. C. CALKINS, Kearney C. J. ERNST, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director and Animal Husbandman T. L. LYON, B. S. A., AMoeiate Director and Agriculturist J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING 9TAFF A. T. Peters, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist Hudson H. Nicholson, M. A., Chemist A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman Lawrence Brunek, B. Sc., Entomologist Erwin H. Bakbouk, Ph. D., Geologist R. A. Emerson, B. Sc.. Horticulturist O. V. P. Stodt, C. E., Irrigation Engineer G. D. Swezey, M. A., Meteorologist A. T. Wiancko, B. S. A., Assistant Agriculturist H. R. Smith, B. Sc., Assistant Animal Husbandman J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist Henrt B. Slade, B. A., Assistant Chemist </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>