<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Cost of Tractor Power on Nebraska Farms</title>
               <date value="18??">Novemeber 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Cost of TRACTOR POWER On nebraska Farms BULLETIN 324 NOVEMBER 1939 f W.L.RUDEN / C.W.SMITH gfgfgfgfg UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA/COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STAHON, LIMCOLN; NEBRASKA I W.W BURR. DIRECTOR </seg>
         <seg id="p002">II OW can I make the most economical use of my tractor power? The studies reported in this bulletin show what can be done by the applica - tion of two methods. One is by the reduction of "overhead" or fixed cost—such costs as deprecia - tion and interest on original cost. The study shows that on two farms this cost was greater than seven cents per drawbar horsepower hour, while many farmers kept this cost well below two cents per drawbar horsepower hour. The more the tractor is used the less this cost will be. The tractor is less expensive if it is adapted to a large number of uses. Another common source of high expense results from failure to adapt the load to the size of the tractor. Failure of this sort may easily double the cost per acre of tractor power. Proper adjustment has been made when the tractor is pulling nearly its full capacity. A light load and low fuel consump - tion mean greater, not lower, expense per acre. This study is based on farmers' records. The tabulations show cases of economical use of power and also very uneconomical use. A study of these records will show that large economies are possible in tractor power use. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Cost of Tractor Power on Nebraska Farms FRANK MIXER, W. L. RUDEN,.and C. W. SMITH TDECAUSE OF THE SHIFT in the power used on farms in recent years -"^ many questions arise on the cost of tractor operation. In order to answer some of the questions a study was begun in September, 1937. Groups of farmers in three counties located in different areas of the state were asked to keep detailed records of tractor costs for a period of one year 1. Information was obtained on 23 tractors in Nemaha county in the eastern part !of the state, 26 in Buffalo county in the central part, and 31 in Cheyenne county in the western wheat-growing area. ¦ ." For purposes of analysis the tractors on which: records were obtained were divided into four groups according to rated drawbar horsepower. 1 Because farming operations in the western part of the state require large power units, 21 of the 31 tractors studied in Cheyenne county were rated at 21 to 30 drawbar horsepower. In the central and eastern parts of the state most of the tractors studied were from 11 to 20 drawbar horsepower. These may be described as medium-sized farm power units capable of pull - ing two-bottom gang plows arid other equipment of similar draft. In each o£ the counties records were obtained on a few tractors in the 6 to 10 drawbar horsepower group. These records were most numerous in Buffalo county. Details are given in Table 1. ¦; An effort was made to obtain information on recent models of the most common makes in use within the communities. A list of the tractors on {which data were obtained is given in Table 2. The wheel equipment is also indicated but no effort has been made to determine the difference in cost of operating tractors on steel as compared with rubber. The Nebraska testing station has found that rubber tires reduce the rolling resistance of a tractor so that less power is required to move it over the ground than when steel wheels'and lugs are used. This leaves more engine power available for useful work at the drawbar and accounts for the superior fuel economy of rubber over steel, particularly in the higher gears.* If it is assumed that the hours of life are the same on steel equipment as lon rubber, the added investment in the pneumatic tires increases the overhead cost and may offset the saving due to fuel economy and increased ¦ power. The variable cost factors in the problem arc too numerous to per - mit valid conclusions from the data obtained in-this study.Thirty of 78 'At the beginning of the incur icitinj work it the Univenity of Nebraska in 1920, ail tractors were rated arbitrarily by the manufacturer!. Since that time a tractor testing code has been set up Jointly by the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers andjthose desiring. to do so have rated their tractors.according to the code; it has not been compulsory. Rating tractors'according to the code has gradually increased since the code's adoption .until today practically all are rated by it. The code specified that the drawbar horsepower rating shall be 75 per cent] of the tractor's absolute maximum drawbar horsepower corrected to standard conditions of pressure and I temperature. "Ratings used in this report were all obtained according to code with the exception of Test No. 142 (Table 2). . ,'¦¦ . See* results! reported in Nebraska Tractor Tests, a bulletin published annually by the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station.. . ¦ ' . . .-;. </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 Table I.— Tractors represented — number of each size in each location. County Part,,, Drawbar horsepower rating Tota , Nebraska 6-10 | 11-20 | 21-25 1 26-30 No. Wo. No. No. No. S'enuha Eastern 3 18 2 0 23 HulTalo Central 6 19 0 1 26 Cheyenne Western 2 8 15 6 31 Table 2. — Ma\e, type, and size of tractors studied with fuel consumption at rated load. 1 Xci"- Number of tractori Horsepower Galloniof fuel Tractor Tracior 1 per hour (riuke and model) Test Rubber I Steel I Track Draw- I Brake Draw* I Brake No. tirci IwhccUl layer bar 1 bar 1 AMis Chalmers \VC ' 223 1 .. .. 15.)5 20.91 185 206 Allil Chalmers WC» 223 .. 2 .. 12.15 20 31 IXI 1M Ca« &lt;C 169 3 2 .. 17.88 27.37 2.36 2.60 lasc L.. 155 2 1 .. 26.28 .40.22 4.03 4.12 Caterpillar RD«. 273 .. .. 2 16.80 35.61 2.28 2.57 lohn Deere A. 222 1 7 .. 16.31 23.63 2.22 2.25 John lleere B. 232 2 .. 9JB 14.30 1.47 1.3» lotm Deere U. 236 7 2 .. 24.64. 37.51 3.36 358 M» I»m Of. 190 .. 2 .. 15J4 24.14 2.43 2.62 MXormLk Drerine F-12. ... 220 .. 3 .. 9.71 13.59 US 1.43 McCormick-Dcermi; Fartnall ...117 I 5 .. 9.35 18.03 1.79 1.87 McCorm.ck Dccrinc F-20. 276 3 14 16.12 24.13 2.26 2.30 McCormuk-Dccring F-jO. 198 3 2 .. 20.88 30.31 3.15 3.33 M.Curmuk Decnni: 10-20 * 142 . 1 .. 10.90 20 46 179 204 McCorm.ck Derrinj W-30. 210 3 I .. 20.23 31.62 2.87 3.02 McCormick-Dcerinß 22-36. 156 2 1 .. 22.78 36.15 3.69 3.90 McCorraicl-Dcerinj WD-40 2-16 1 .. .. 28.09 44.10 2.79 3.00 Oliver—Hart Parr Row Crop 18-27 176 I .. 18.10 27.11 2J5 2.75 Olner—Hart-Parr 18 28. 1M) 1 1 .. 18.99 28.30 2.14 2.83 Ohicr—Hart Parr Row Crop 70 KD 267 1 .. 16.45 24.80 2.27 2.38 M-M-Twa City FTA 270 1 .. .. 27.34 41.26 3.44 3.63 H-M-Twii City MTA 248 1 1 .. 19.43 29.77 2.78 3.00 Tot.ll 30 48 2 1 Rare&lt;l-I&lt;j.t&lt;i figures are those secured for the tracton while being tatcd at the University of Nebraska. 1 Tested in Third gear at 4.45 miles per hour. 3 Tested in second gear at 3.79 miles per hour. ' Nuc mcd according 10 code. wheel-type tractors on which records were kept were equipped with rubber tires. CLASSIFICATION OF COSTS The items which enter into the total cost of operating a tractor may be divided into two general classes: (1) fixed or overhead costs and (2) variable or operating costs. The overhead costs are depreciation, in - terest, taxes, insurance, and housing. These are termed fixed costs but this classification is somewhat relative. A tractor decreases in value both from obsolescence and from use. Depreciation from obsolescence takes place </seg>
         <seg id="p005">..¦•;' . Cost op Tractor Power / whither the tractor is in operation or not, but the.decrease in value aside from obsolescence is more rapid when it is in use. Variable or operating cosls change in approximate proportion to the amount the power unit is used, and cease when it stops operating. This class includes fuel, oil, grease, and repairs. . . . ; UNIT OF MEASURE FOR CALCULATING TRACTOR COST Most ofl the tractor work on farms is done on the drawbar. For this reason all of the expenses, except fuel, incurred in operating a tractor are placed on the basis of costs per rated drawbar horsepower hour. The power ratings for jail tractors included in the study are given in Table 2. The fuel cost for each type of work and for all farm jobs is figured on a tractor-hour base by taking die average rate of fuel consumption for each size group of tractors. ; \ Table Z.—lJfe of wheel-type tractors according to size on the basis of ¦ \". ¦ ¦:!.' ¦¦ •¦ hours operated. Raring o£ ! Hours operated _V Average life 1 tenX'^A tractors j in year No r ¦¦¦ ' rcquirca jHP) ; -Range. 1.-Ay. lev* hrs. operation 6-10 i 100-199 174 1 20 3,480 36 ; 200-299 246 .'.-•¦ 2 11 2,706 25 I .300-399 338 3 15 5,070 18 | 400-499 -434 2 10 4,340 14 j j 500-599 584 1 10 5,840 11 ¦¦"{:¦¦.¦¦. ! Over 600 691 2. 12 8,292 9 Total or weighted average .410 . 11 ¦ ¦ 13 5,019 .. 11-30 ! 100-199 115 3 14 1,610 .54 . • 200-299 251 9 14 3,514 25 1 300-399 346 . 8 12 4,152 18 I 400-499 453 ' 10 13 5,889 14 ! ' I. 500-599 556 15 . 13 7^28 11 i • /I Over 600 744 ' : 22 12 8,928 8 Total or weighted average 516 ; 67- 13 6,469 Total or weighted average .: ¦ tor all tractors 502 78 13 6,264 ¦lEilinuted by tractor onrncrf. , • ; "I 1 ' ... DIFFERENCES IN COST The average cost per rated drawbar horsepower hour is higher for small tractors than for those rated over 10 drawbar horsepower. There is no significant difference in costs per unit for machines over 10 drawbar horsepower 1. For this reason the tractors are divided into two groups in Tables 3, 4, and 5. There was no difference in costs per drawbar horse - power hour as between counties or makes of tractors. All makes and models in the three counties are grouped together throughout the study. Power costs only are considered. Wages for the operator are not included, and no equipment charge is added to the data showing power cost for specific farm jobs.- </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 The greatest variation in cost per rated drawbar horsepower hour is associated with the number of hours tractors are used during the year. In calculating overhead cost the years of tractor life estimated by the operator were used. These estimates with the average annual operating hours and the years of life that would be required to obtain the weighted average hours that all tractors were used are given in Table 3. In the group of tractors which were operated very little, the years of service were probably underestimated. The average estimated life of 78 wheel-type tractors in the study is 6,264 hours. If it is considered that the average standard power unit has this number of hours of service built into it, the time required to wear it out under conditions of use found in the cost records would vary from 8 to 54 years. Obsolescence may be less important in the life of recent tractor models than it was 15 years ago, but it is still a factor. Most of the tractors which are used less than 400 hours a year Table 4.-— Overhead or fixed costs per rated drawbar horsepower hour (wheel-type tractors). Ruing of Rjngc ; n nrs M Costs pei» raled drawbar horsepower hour (dTZr ,°P" atcd ' tractors *P~«ion I nsuranC e k Hp) during year . and and taxes HousmS loal Cents Cents Cents Cents 6-10 100-199 1 5.5 0.6 0.6 6.7 200-299 2 4.4 0.2 0.4 5.0 300-399 3 2.8 0.2 03 3.3 400-499 2 2.4 0.1 0.1 2.6 500-599 1 1.6 0.1 0.1 1.8 Over 600 2 1.4 0.1 0.1 1.6 11-30 100-199 3 6.3 0.4 0.5 12 200-299 9 2.8 0.2 02 3.2 300-399 8 2.2 0.1 0.2 2.5 400-499 10 1.5 0.1 0.1 1.7 500-599 15 1.3 0.1 0.1 1.5 Over 600 22 1.0 0.1 0.1 \2 will probably be discarded before they have reached the limit of their intrinsic hours of service. Fixed costs per rated drawbar horsepower hour recorded in Table 4 are based on years of tractor life estimated by those who kept the cost records. If these costs were calculated on the basis of 6,264 hours of service there would be a change in the figures. The years of life for tractors which were used very little would be increased and the fixed costs de - creased. The years of life of those used a great deal would be decreased and the costs per rated drawbar horsepower hour increased. There are no additional data on the life of tractors to support new estimates. For this reason the figures turned in by the record keepers are left unchanged. COMPUTATION OF FIXED COSTS The annual charge for depreciation and interest is found by taking the amount of money that the operator would have to lay aside each year at </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Cost of Tractor Power Table s.—Fixed costs and operating costs, except fuel, per rated drawbar horsepower hour according to hours operated (wheel-type tractors). _ ¦ 1.. , '. -.'¦-.. Cost per rued drawbar horsepower hour Rating of Range . ¦' —r 1 = —¦; p tractors inhrc. No. Av-h£ „ Faedcostrf (driwbar ! operated -tractors "P"* 6 Repairs Gr"«" Tat\ opcMWg HP) !duringyr. V&gt;t/ai p landoil cost 1 cosUxcept ii ¦ ¦'.-.. ¦";:"• Cents Cents Cents Cents - 10 ! 100-199 1 174 0.4 0.8 6.7 7.9 200-299 2 .246 0.4 0.7 5.0 6.1 J3OO-399 3 Hi 0.4 0.4 3.3 4.1 ; 400-499 2 434 0.4 0.4 ' 2.6 3.4 . . ;¦] 500-599 1 584 0.4 0.3 1.8 2.5 ¦ lOver6oo 2 691 0.4 ; 0.3 1.6 23 11-30 i 100-199 3 :". 115 0.1 0.1 7.2 7.4 200-299 9 251 0.1 0.3 3.2 3.6 ¦300-399 8 /¦ 316 0.1 0.3 2.5 2.9 ,400-499 10 453 0.1 0.2 1.7 2.0 500-599 15 556 0.1 0.2 1.5 1.8/ Over 600 22 744 0.1 0.2 . 1.2 , 1.5 JFroin Tablei.. ;. . 6 per cent interest in order to replace the original cost,of the tractor at the end of jits estimated life. 8 The sum of this annual amount and interest is then divided by the hours the tractor was used during the year in which the record jwas kept and the quotient by the rated drawbar horsepower to obtain the!depreciation and interest charge per drawbar horsepower hour (Table 4)i : . ,j. Insurance for a year is estimated at six-tenths of one per cent of one-half th: purchase price, and the taxes at one per cent of the same base. The sun of these two amounts is divided by the annual hours of use and the quotient thus obtained by the rated drawbar horsepower to obtain the cost per drawbar horsepower hour. ;; • , : A few of the tractors in the study were not housed. Some of them were shedded in driveways of farm buildings and in sheds with other machinery. -A few were kept in special sheds; This lack of uniformity inj housing practice and difference in value of buildings made it difficult to compute a proper charge. The figure used in Table 4 is based on a percentage of the purchase price ( of the tractor. To obtain the annual charge one-tenth.of the original tractor cost is used as the value of a satisfactory shelter and this amount amortized in 20 years with interest at 6 per cent. Tlie charge is then reduced to cost per fated drawbar horsepower hour., Data in Table 4 show that fixed costs vary with hours of use. As the hours of operation increase the cost per hour decreases. The overhead cost for small tractors varied from 6.7 cents per drawbar horsepower hour for tractors operated 174 hours to' 1.6 cents for those Used 691 hours. For tractors between 11 and 30 drawbar horsepower, the cost varied from 12 I * C. W. Smith, Tractor operating colt, Cooperative Tractor Catalog, Ann. cd. 1938-39, p. 106. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 8 CODE PEPA.RS I HOUSING p INSURANCE % DEPRECIATION H &amp; INTEREST m TRACTOR RATED — " 100 200 300 400 500 600&amp; I 100 200 300 400 500 600&amp; -199 -299 -399 -499 -599 OVER -199 -299 -399 -499 -599 OVER TRACTOR OPERATING TIME PER YEAR, HOURS Fig. I.—The division of tractor costs (except fuel) per rated drawbar horsepower hour for two size-groups of wheel-type tractors and the relation of these costs to the number of hours operated annually. cents for those operated 115 hours to 1.2 for machines used 744 hours. The relationship between hours of use and cost per rated drawbar horse - power hour is shown graphically in Figures 1 to 3. It will be noted that cost per hour mounts very rapidly if the tractor is used fewer than 400 hours a year. LOAD AND COST Another important factor in tractor cost deals with the ratio of used power to available power. Tractors are built to do work at a given rate. Under farm conditions they do not operate at constant loads equal to </seg>
         <seg id="p009">¦ ! ¦¦: ' J ¦ '¦ ¦ ¦ ¦•¦•.•"-. ' ' . : '&#132; Cost of Tractor Power .¦•'¦¦¦ !'¦'¦'¦'.¦.' ¦ ¦ ¦ ' ¦¦¦¦'¦ capacity. The load for a given job varies, and different kinds of work have a wide range in power requirements. A tractor is chosen large enough to do the heaviest work required. It runs partially loaded on many other jobs. This j surplus of available power results in high cost for the power used. There are two contributing causes: (1) Large machines are ex - pensive; If jonly a part of the capacity is used the overhead cost per power unit is high. (2) Operating costs per unit of useful power increase if the tractor is not used at or near its capacity. ,I-tV— ——— ¦si ;¦ ¦N¦' -. ¦ ¦ '".-"¦¦¦ \ ¦¦. ¦ y&lt;: i¦ .; ¦ ¦ \l* ; ' ¦ - - "¦ ""' . S3 .11 ..V ¦ — ¦- .;. , .- ¦ a- '- i ¦' -, •'¦" ¦ -.;. . ..: -. ¦ ga - ;,l I "^^V ° : I. (L ¦' '¦ j. • ¦ " ."¦(.--¦ ° . ¦ . Ql " ¦ . ' _' ' ——«_ _ ; _- *-- 0 .;. 100 200 300 400 500. . 600 700 000 500 •¦¦!.-.-¦ TRACTOR OPERATING TIME PER YEAR, HOURS . Fio. 2.—The relation of tractor costs (except fuel) per rated drawbar horsepower hour to the number of hours of operation per year for tractors rated at 11 to 30 drawbar horsepower. Costs included: depreciation and interest, insurance and taxes, housing, grease arid oil, repairs. . .:.-;¦; Fuel is the principal operating cost. In the opinion of some operators low daily fuel consumption means low power cost. In most instances the opposite is true. The lowest fuel consumption occurs when the engine is idling and no useful power is developed. The rate of fuel consumption is highest when the tractor is operating at maximum load, but the developed power which can be used is also greatest. Power declines from this maxi - mum to zero as fuel consumption decreases. The rate of power decline is more rapid than the decrease in fuel consumption. For this reason the fuel cost per unit of power is higher when the tractor is operated under partial load than [when used at full capacity. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 The rated-load fuel requirement in Table 2 may be used as a guide in obtaining low power cost. If the tractor is in proper operating condition, the engine load can be checked by comparing the rate of fuel consumption with the fuel requirement. In order to obtain low power cost the fuel consumption per hour should be near the rated-load fuel requirement. Data in Tables 6 to 9 give the fuel consumed per hour for different types of farm work listed in the tractor records and the percentage that the fuel i 8 A * I o 5 7 ¦ 3. \ —V v 4 A^ | 3 p a Q. °o Too oo 300 300 ioo ioo too aoo TRACTOR OPERATING TIME PER YEAR. HOURS Fie. 3.—The relation of tractor costs (except fuel) per rated drawbar horsepower hour to the number of hours of operation per year for tractors rated at 6 to 10 drawbar horsepower. Costs included: depreciation and interest, insurance and taxes, housing, grease and oil, repairs. used is of rated-load requirements. In many instances the power cost could be reduced by using a higher percentage of the available power. The load may be adjusted to the rated power of the tractor in several ways: (1) The width of equipment may be increased. (2) More than one piece of machinery may be pulled at the same time. (3) A higher gear may be used and the job completed at greater speed. (4) The tractor may be run in a higher gear and throttled to the speed required for the job. . Two points in tractor cost should be emphasized—ihe number of hours the power unit is operated during the year and the load in comparison with its rated capacity. If low cost is desired the tractor must be kept busy at work that will use a high percentage of its rated power. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">...-;'¦ Cost of Tractor Power OPERATING COSTS The most important operating cost is fuel. Other items are grease, oil, and repairs. In keeping the individual records the method used in tab - ulating cost items makes it easy to find the amount spent for fuel in each type of farm work. Other operating expenses are not so easily allocated. As!a.rule oil was changed after it had been used in the tractor a number of hours. In many instances several jobs of work were completed within the time. Grease and hard oil for chassis lubrication were used in small quantities. It is difficult to determine the rate of consumption of these materials for different kinds of work. For this reason the annual expense for oil and other lubricants is distributed uniformly to the hours each tractor was used, on a horsepower-hour basis. (Repair expenses reported in the cost records varied from minor adjust - ments to complete overhauling. Several tractors which were being used the Table 6.— 'Average acres per hour, fuel requirements, and cost of operating tractors rated at 6 to 10 (average 9.45) drawbar horsepower at various [ types of, farm wor\—all types-of tractors. . ' ¦ I Equipment ¦ ' . Fuel consumed Total power No. . " Qai ¦ . Pern-nt cost (cents) 1 Used Size tractors £ Qm per rated Per I Per '¦¦- ¦¦' -. .'" -- ' • ¦¦ hour load* hour I acre Binder, grain 7to 8 ft, 6 1.7 1.24 77 43 25 Cultivator 2-rowB 2.0 . 1.42 88 45 22 Diik,sing[e . 7to Bft 4 1.9 1.34 83 44 23 I :. ¦ 9toloft 5 2.4 1.43 89. 45 19 Disk, tandem 10ft 1 2.9 1.64 102 47 16 Drill . .7to Bft. 7 2.0 135 84 44 22 I- . 9toloft. 4 2.6 1.24 77 43 17 Float Bft. 1 3.8 1.34 83 44 12 Harrow, peg tooth Btol2ft 4 3.5 1.34 83 44 13 15tol6ft 5 4.2 1.38 86 44 10 20ft. 1 8.6 1.98 123 50 6 Lister 2-row 8 1.8 1.47 91 45 25 Lister cultiva or 2-row 8 2.1 1.34 83 44 21 I 4-row 2 4.0 1.69 105 47 12 MWr 2to7ft. 1 4.5 1.22 76 43 10 Plmv.moldboard M6in. 1 0.5 1.26 78 43 86 2-12 or 2-14 in. 7 . 0.8 1.43 89 45 56 Rake 2-12 ft 1 83 Ul 69 42 5 Roller lift. 1-3.6 1.55 96 46 13 Stalkcutter 2-row 1 2.7 1.34 83 44 16 S\|reep,hay 12ft. 1.. 1.24 77 43 .]¦ ¦•¦ ¦ ' .¦'..' : ¦•¦ ' .':.;¦ : belt jobs ¦' . ¦¦ ¦ - Ensilage cv ters ¦ .3 ¦ ... 1.34 84 44 Grinders .'.•'.¦• ¦' ¦ .:' ¦ ;..'. ' '¦'.¦¦ '¦' r.;'.. .¦¦,'¦ . Burrmil Borloin. 5 : .. 1.32 83 ' 44 j Hammer null ; . :. 1 -'.'. : . 0.64 40. 38 Pump, irrigation ; 6 in. I .. 1.43 90 45 Saw.circular V 3 ..: 0.95 60 41 Thresher | 22b. 1 .. 0.95 Y6O 41 .. . I * Fuel co« ill figured at 9 centt per nllon. ¦ ','" ¦ . 'Based on fuel comumpdon at rated load, in the tractor toting laboratory. : </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 first season required very little expense. An operator may have spent nothing for repairs during the accounting period but a charge should be made in computing cost per hour. As a rule large bills are the result of cumulative wear. They should be distributed to all of the hours the tractor was used. The cost per rated drawbar horsepower hour charged in Table 5 is an average of the repair expenses for all tractors in each size group. This amount plus the charge for grease and oil is added to the fixed cost to obtain the total cost except fuel recorded in the last column of the table. The fuel cost for work done with a given tractor varies with the Table 7.— Average acres per hour, fuel requirements, and cost of operating tractors rated at 11 to 20 (average 16.63) drawbar horsepower at various types of farm wor\ — all types of tractors. Equipment , Fuel consumed Total power I No. A'"S Ra l. p-rcn. COSttenttJ 1 Used Size tracto" hour Per "ted Per Per hour load' hour acre Binder, corn 1-row 3 0.7 1.25 54 45 64 Binder, grain 7 ft. 6 1.8 1.58 68 48 27 8 ft. 12 2.0 1.62 70 48 24 10 ft. 5 2.8 1.69 73 49 18 Combine sor 6 ft. 7 1.4 1.69 73 49 35 Bor 10 ft. 4 2.2 1.86 80 50 23 12 or 14 ft. 8 2.6 1.51 65 47 18 Cultivator 2-row 22 2.3 1.62 70 48 21 Disk, single 8 ft. 6 3.4 1.67 72 48 14 9to 11 ft. 12 3.7 1.74 75 49 13 12 to 16 ft. 8 4.6 2.04 88 52 11 21ft. 1 7.6 2.18 94 53 7 Disk, tandem 7to 8 ft. 9 2.5 1.88 81 50 20 9 to 10 ft. 8 4.4 1.83 79 50 11 Ditcher 3-row 1 2.7 1.65 71 48 18 Drill 7to 8 ft. 18 2.5 1.65 71 48 19 9to 10 ft. 16 3.5 1.74 75 49 14 12 to 13 ft. 4 4.2 1.62 70 48 11 23 ft. 1 4.8 1.37 59 46 10 Harrow, peg tooth 11 to 12 ft. 2 3.8 1.65 71 48 13 15 to 16 ft. 10 5.4 1.62 70 48 9 18 to 22 ft. 13 5.9 1.88 81 50 8 34 ft. 1 9.4 1.95 84 51 5 Harrow, spring tooth 10 ft. 1 4.0 1.58 68 48 12 Lister 2-row 32 2.1 1.81 78 50 24 3-row 2 3.0 2.02 87 52 17 4-row 1 4.2 2.32 100 54 13 Lister cultivator 2-row 14 2.4 1.69 73 49 20 3-rmv 1 3.8 2.27 98 54 14 4-row 1 3.6 2.97 128 60 17 Mower 7 ft. 1 2.3 1.02 44 43 19 One-way disk 4to 6 ft. 3 1.9 1.86 80 50 26 8 ft. 3 2.9 1.86 80 50 17 Plow, moidboard 2-14 in. 27 0.9 1.81 78 50 56 2-lfior2-18in. 5 1.0 1.93 83 51 51 3-14 or 3-16 in. 10 1.3 1.81 78 50 38 4-14 in. 1 1.8 2.32 100 54 30 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Cost of Tractor Power Table 7.— (Continued.) I Equipment , Fuel consumed Total power . NO. A"" -fi.l P,r,,nf COSt (W^ 1 Used Size tractors ]£ ur per rated Per I Per ¦-¦'"' '• . . '•'..- . hour load' hour I acre Potatodigger 1-row 4 0.3 . 1.51 ; 65 47 157 Po&amp;to planter 2-row 3 1.2 1.48 . 64 47 39 Potato sprayer .\' 6-row 2 3.2 1.37 59 46 14 Ralweeder 12 ft 7 4.6 1.97 85 51 II 24ft. I 4.7 1.74 !'. 75 49 10 Roler :. 10to 12ft. 3 .4.0 1.39 i 60 46 12 Stalk cutter 2-row 1 3.5 1.93 83 51 15 : 3-row 3 5.2 1.72 74 49 9 5-row, 1 5.5 . 1.48 64 47 9 Summer-fallow machine 10 or 12 ftJ 2 3.9 1.88 81 50 13 Disk with harrow or drill 7«o9ft. 7 2.5 1.81 78 50 20 Diskwithdrill 10tol2fc 4 3.5 1.79 77 50 14 Drill and roller Bfc.! 1 1.9 1.51 65 47 25 Harrow and roller 15 ft. 1 1.6 1.48 64. 47 29 Lister and basin attachment 2-row 1 1.6 1.72 74 49 31 ¦ • ' ¦'[..¦':'¦: - ('•"• BELT JOBS '¦• Ensilage cutters ' ; : 4 .. '¦' 1.56 64 47 .. Grinders .' ¦'¦ ¦ :. ; '.. 1 - ';•¦';. - ¦-..-¦¦¦ : Burrmill .: Btol2in ; 13 .. 1.59 65 48 Hammermill *:: V 3 .. 1.63. 67 48 ¦ .. Pump, irrigation 6toBini 10 .. 1.95 80 51 .. Saw.circular . : 16 .. 1.46 60 46 Sheller.corn '-. 2-hole 2 .. 0.61 25 39 I ;.; ¦ 4-or6-holc 3 ¦ .. 1.78 73 49 Thresher 22t028in. 8 .. 1.85 76 50 ? Fuel cost is figured at 9 cents per gallon. . : ' ; : . :' ? Baled on fuel consumption at rated load in the tractor testing laboratory. quantity used and the price per gallon. The amount consumed in a unit ofj time depends upon load, ;which may vary with a number of factors. Among these are size of machinery, depth at which it is operated, physical condition of the soil, moisture content, nature of vegetative growth, and speed of operation. Not all of these factors can be controlled. The price ofj fuel varies with the general market situation and with selling conditions within.a locality. The average price per gallon, including gasoline used for starting, paid by Nemaha county operators who kept cost records was 8.9 cents. In Buffalo county it was 8.8 cents, and in Cheyenne county 10.2 cents. . •'¦¦¦.;'.¦¦''¦.'.", :1' ¦:-¦¦',.:¦::¦- -¦¦ ' |: The average fuel consumption in gallons per hour and the cost of tractor power for doing different kinds of farm work with varying sizes of equip - ment are given in Tables 6 to 9. Most of the farmers who kept the cost records, used their tractors more than 400 hours a year. In arriving at the ayerage figures the total cost,;except fuel, associated with 400 to 499 hours of operation in Table 5 Is used. A fuel cost is added which is obtained by taking the average number of gallons used for particular kinds of work at 91 cents per gallon.. .' '¦¦[/'. ¦¦/. •¦¦ V , ¦¦¦'.',.-.'¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 Table 8. — Average acres per hour, fuel requirements, and cost of operating tractors rated at 21 to 25 (average 2321) drawbar horsepower at various types of farm wor\ — all types of tractors. Equipment Fuel consumed Total power No. A™ »., „. cost (cents)' Used Size "dors oac per rated Per Per hour load' hour acre Binder, corn 1-row 3 0.8 1.14 34 57 71 Binder, grain 7or 8 ft. 4 1.5 1.88 56 63 42 10 or 12 ft. 3 23 1.88 56 63 27 Combine 12 or 14 ft. 5 2.7 2.35 70 68 25 15 or 16 ft. 4 3.4 2.15 '64 66 19 20 ft. 1 4.4 2.08 62 65 15 Cultivator 2-row 2 12 1.95 58 64 20 3-row 1 4.6 2.72 81 71 15 Disk, single 10 ft. 2 5.3 2.08 62 65 12 JBft 1 8.6 2.42 72 68 8 21ft. 3 9.6 2.55 76 69 7 Disk, tandem Bor 10 ft. 5 3.1 2.39 71 68 22 12 ft. 1 3.8 3.19 95 75 20 20 ft 2 8.6 2.35 70 68 8 Drill 7or 8 ft. 2 2.4 1.68 50 62 26 12 or 14 ft. 11 4.9 2.32 69 67 14 15 to 17 ft. 2 4.0 1.75 52 62 16 20 ft. 2 6.4 2.89 86 72 11 Harrow, peg tooth 16 ft. 1 6.0 2.76 82 71 12 18 to 21 ft. 7 7.4 2.49 74 69 9 30 ft. 4 13.0 2.99 89 73 6 34 ft. 2 5.2 2.49 74 69 13 40 ft. 1 6.9 3.36 100 77 11 Lister 2-row 3 2.4 2.59 77 70 2° 3-row 5 3.2 2.49 74 69 22 Lister cultivator 2-row 1 1.8 1.21 36 57 32 3-row 4 3.5 2.32 69 67 1&gt; 4-row 2 3.4 2.02 60 65 19 5-row 1 8.8 2.76 82 71 8 One-way disk 7or 8 ft. 5 2.3 2.55 76 69 30 10 ft. 1 6.2 2.86 85 72 12 Plow, moldboard 3-14 in. 8 1.3 2.45 73 68 52 4-14 in. 6 1.9 2.79 83 72 38 Rodwceder 10 or 12 ft 10 4.7 2.62 78 70 15 14 ft 1 7.6 2.96 88 73 10 20 to 24 ft. 4 7.6 2.72 81 71 9 Stalk cutter 3-row 1 5.2 2.05 61 65 12 Summer-fallow machine 8 ft. 2 2.9 2.96 88 73 25 Disk with dammer, drill, orrodweeder 10 or 12 ft. 6 3.6 2.45 73 68 19 Disk with drill 14 ft. 2 4.5 2.96 88 73 16 Disk with harrow 21 ft. 2 7.3 3.06 91 74 10 Drill and weedcr 12 ft. 1 4.0 2.62 78 70 18 Oneway and dammer 8 ft. 1 1.8 2.62 78 70 39 Rod weeder and dammer 12 ft 1 4.2 2.45 73 68 16 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">, Cajst of Tractor Power . TableB.—( Continued) " . . I Equipment • ; Fuel consumed Total power No- D« rCS GaK Percent coster/)' Used . Size tractors QUr per rated Per Per ¦ ' ' I ' - '. hour load' hour acre " ¦ .'¦'. '. ¦ ¦¦.- ¦'.'¦¦ I' BELT JOBS ' '¦:¦. Grinders . '. j. [Bun-mill lOin. : ' 3 .. 2:32 66 67 Hammermill ¦¦... 1 " .. 2.14 61 . 66 Sa*. circular .. \ 1 v 1.97 56 64 Tlresher 28 in. 13... 3.12 ,89 74 .. 1 Fuel con is figured at 9 cents per gallon. * - ';':¦-- ' * . ! Based on fuel consumption at rated load in the tractor testing laboratory. . - The computation for tractors having 11 to 20 drawbar horsepower is as follows: The average rated drawbar horsepower for tractors in this group of records is 16.63. In Table 1 5 tractors of this size fall in the 11-to-30 - -drawbar-horsepower group. The average of all costs, except fuel, for tractors operated 400 to 499 hours a year is two cents per drawbar horse - power hour. The cost per tractor hour for all items except fuel is therefore 33 3 cents (16.63 drawbar horsepower X 0.02 = 0.3326 or 333 cents per tractor hour). Twelve tractors of this size used an average of 1.62 gallons of fuel an hour while pulling an eight-foot grain binder. At 9 cents a gallon the fuel cost is 14.58 cents (1.62 gallons of fuel per hour X 0.09 = 0.: 458 or 14.6 cents per tractor hour). The sum of the costs per tractor hour is 47.9 cents (33.3 cents + 14.6 cents = 47.9 cents); The average pc|wer cost for pulling an eight-foot binder with tractor between 11 and 20 drawbar horsepower is recorded at 48 cents in Table 7. The average acres of work accomplished per hour with the various sizes of tractors and equipment are also given in Tables 6 to 9. These averages are taken from the; records which were kept by the operators. Tne cost of tractor power per: acre may be obtained by dividing the hourly cost by the acres of work accomplished. For example, the tractor cost per hour for pulling a seven-foot grain binder is 48 cents. Six tractors, each pulling equipment of this size, cut an average of 1.8 acres an hour. The cost per acre is 26.7 cents (48 cents ¦*• 1.8 acres = 26.66+ or 27 cents an acre)..; ¦ .-. ¦ , : ; : ...;]' : •¦ ' ¦ . -.:.¦¦,: ' \' ' ¦ J In several instances the power cost for specific farm operations listed in Tables 6 to 9 is based on the report of a single operator. The number of tractors on which records were obtained for each type of work is given in the tables. If the number of operators reporting is small, the cost figure may or may not be representative for that kind of work. AVERAGE COSTS Data presented in Table 10 show the average annual and hourly costs of operating tractors of various sizes from 400 to 499 hours a year for all </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 Table 9. — Average acres per hour, fuel requirements, and cost of operating tractors rated at 26 to 30 (average 26.85) drawbar horsepower at various types of farm tvor\ — all types of tractors. Equipment . Fuel consumed Total power No. A"cs Gal. Percent, cwtfrnwj' Used Size tractors p. t nle &amp; Per Per hour load' hour acre Chiselcr 7 ft. 1 1.6 3.77 103 88 55 Combine 6 ft. 1 1.9 2.96 81 80 42 16 ft. 2 3.4 1.79 49 70 21 20 ft. 3 3 A 2.53 69 76 22 Cultivator 5-row 1 7.0 2.74 75 78 11 Deep tiller 6 ft. 1 1.8 3.81 104 88 49 Disk, single 16ft. I 10.0 3.88 106 87 9 27 ft. 1 7.8 3.66 100 87 11 Disk, tandem 10 ft. 1 4.2 1.90 52 71 17 20 ft. 1 8.2 2.78 76 79 10 Drill 14 ft. 1 4.4 2.05 56 72 16 30 ft. 2 13.4 3.95 108 89 7 Harrow, peg tooth 17 ft. 1 4.5 3.26 89 83 18 20 ft. 1 8.1 3.15 86 82 10 30 ft. 1 12.5 3.15 86 82 7 40 ft. 1 12.3 3.84 105 88 7 Lister 2-row 1 2.5 2.12 58 73 29 3-row 1 3.0 2.42 66 76 25 4-row 2 5.4 3.84 105 88 16 Oneway disk 10 ft. 4 3.7 2.96 81 80 22 Plow, disk 6 ft. 1 2.5 2.42 66 76 30 Plow, moldboard 4-14 or 4-16 in. 3 1.8 3.15 86 82 46 5-14 in. 2 2.8 3.00 82 81 29 Rodwcedcr 12 or 14 ft. 2 5.1 2.42 66 75 15 20 to 24 ft. 2 10.0 3.40 93 84 8 Summer-fallow machine lift. 1 5.1 3.77 103 88 17 Wccder (blade harrow) 18 ft. 1 10.0 2.67 73 78 8 Disk with drill 10ft. 2 6.2 2.45 67 76 12 16 to 19 ft. 2 4.1 3.11 85 82 20 Drill and one-way 10 ft. 1 4.8 3.66 100 87 18 Plow and dammcr 6 ft. 1 2.5 3.33 91 84 34 Rod wecder and dammer 20 ft. 1 9.2 3.73 102 87 9 BELT JOBS Ensilage cutter 1 .. 3.09 75 82 Saw, circular 1 .. 1.90 46 71 ¦Fuel cost is figured at 9 cents per gallon. 3 Based on fuel consumption at rated load in the tractor testing laboratory. kinds of farm work. Table 11 gives the variations in average cost per hour at fuel prices from 7 to 11 cents a gallon. All of the cost figures in Tables 6 to 11 are averages based on groups of tractors in a narrow range of sizes and hours of annual operation. They arc probably reliable for the conditions represented, but the cost of operating individual tractors will vary somewhat from them. The annual and hourly operating costs are not constant even for machines of the same power rating. The amount that should be charged per hour for the use of each tractor </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Cost of Tractor Power Table 10.— Average annual and hourly costs of operating wheel-type ¦ ¦ \" tractors 400 to 499 hours per year. . jten, Range in tractor sizes (rated drawbar horsepower) 1 6-10 | 11-20 | 21-25 | 26-30 Average tractor size (drawbar HP) 9.45 16.63 23.21 26.85 ) VARIABLE COSTS PER YEAR Fuel 1 ....:... $55.00 $72.00 $96.00 $108.00 Crease and 0i1..... .:........; 17.00 15.00 21.00 24.00 Repairs 17.00. 8.00 10.00 12.00 JTotal variable c05t5.......... , 89.00 .95.00 127.00 144.00 OVERHEAD COSTS PER YEAR Depreciation and interest. 102.00 112.00 157.00 181.00 Taxes and in5urance............ 4.00 8.00 10.00 12.00 Housing .......;.. 4.00 8.00 10.00 12.00 [Total overhead c05t5......... 110.00 128.00 177.00 205.00 Total costs per year. $199.00 $223.00 $304.00 $349.00 : variable costs per hour Fuel 1 .....!., .123 .161 .214 240 Grease and oil .038 .033 .046 .054 Reriairs..... .038 .017 .023 .027 Total variable c05t5.......... .199 .211 .283 .321 J . . OVERHEAD COSTS PER HOUR Depredation and interest........ .227 .249 .348 .403 Taxes and in5urance..;......... , .009 .017: .023 .027 Housing ¦;• .009 .017 .023 .027 [Total overhead costs '.¦ .245 .283 .394 .457 Total costs per hour .444 . .494 .677 .778 1 Fud is charged at 9 cenu per gallon for the avenge gallons uicd. , Table ll.— Variation in average total cost per tractor hour for all\inds of farm wor\ with changes in the-price of fuel—tractors operated 400 to 499 hours a year. . . .'•¦..":.. Range in tractor sizes Fuel price per gallon (cents) (rated drawbar horsepower) • •¦•"¦ ' I 6-10 f 11-20.J 21-25 I 26-30~ ''.'¦': Cents Cents Cents Cents I ¦•....,.: 42 ,46 63 72 I :••¦• 43 48 65 75 ,9. •••¦•••• ;......,........... 44 49 68 78 }?••¦•••••••• &gt;.-&gt; 46 !51 70 '80 11 ¦¦¦¦^¦. : .^. : ... ............ 47 53 72 . 83 ddpends upon its fixed and operating costs. These vary with the hours of operation and the price that must be paid for the materials used. A tractor which is used more than 500 hours a year has a lower fixed cost per hour ¦ than is used in compiling the tables. If it is used fewer than 400 hours,.. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 324 the fixed cost is greater. In Tables 6 to 10 the fuel is charged uniformly at 9 cents a gallon. The price is not the same throughout the state, and it changes from time to time in a given locality. Because of these differ - ences some operators may want individual costs. The range in total cost, except fuel, per drawbar horsepower hour is comparatively narrow within limits of 100 hours of operation. Table 5 presents average figures. If an operator knows the drawbar horsepower rating of his tractor and the number of hours it has been used during the season, he can calculate his own approximate cost per hour, except fuel, by referring to the table. A careful check on rate of fuel consumption for a given kind of work will make it possible for him to add the fuel cost at the price he pays per gallon. The sum of the two items represents his total cost per tractor hour. The method of computation is the same as that presented on page 15. CONCLUSIONS As a rule tractors used in the western part of Nebraska are between 21 and 30 drawbar horsepower. In the central and eastern parts of the state the most common size is between 11 and 20 drawbar horsepower. Tractors smaller than 10 rated drawbar horsepower show a higher total cost per unit of power than those over 10 drawbar horsepower. The cost per tractor hour is lower for the small tractors because of the low power rating. There is no significant difference in cost per rated drawbar horsepower hour for items except fuel in tractors between 11 and 30 horsepower. There is no significant difference in cost per rated drawbar horsepower hour as between counties or makes of tractors. Overhead costs per rated drawbar horsepower hour vary inversely with the number of hours the tractor is used annually. Total costs per used drawbar horsepower hour increase as the tractor load decreases from its rated capacity. If low cost per unit of useful power is desired the tractor should be kept busy at work that uses a high percentage of its rated power. One or more of several methods may be used for adjusting the load to the power of the tractor: 1. The size of equipment may be increased. 2. More than one piece of. equipment may be pulled. 3. A higher gear may be used and the job completed at greater speed. 4. A higher gear may be used and the tractor throttled to the speed required for the work. The cost figures for particular kinds of farm work in Tables 6 to 9 represent averages taken from the records kept by the operators. If the number reporting is small, the figure given may or may not be represen - tative of the cost for that type of work. From the material presented an operator can find his own tractor cost for particular farm jobs by observing the number of hours his tractor was used during the year and the rate of fuel consumption while doing the work. [BMI </seg>
         <seg id="p019"/>
         <seg id="p020"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>