<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  CARE OF MILK AND CREAM ON THE FARM.</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">ETIN NO. 1JJ. KXTKX81ON BUIXETTN NO. 8. I I'm I \ivi.i;sity OP Nkbkaska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION op NKBRASKA. k XXV. Article III. CARE OF MILK AND CREAM ON THE FARM. By .1. H. Kkan Distkibited October 21, 1912 INOOI.N, XKBRASKA i: a. A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">&lt;. &lt; »1 NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD BBLE CHAK. BLK GEORl BLK t I1AI: BLfc \\ U.I THE STATION OFFICERS THE WORKING STAFF - t tout. M. ■ilture. M. II dnsi K. K. Link. A s Hopt, B - .1. A. K\i&lt; C. B. LJM. I I.. B. 8tlbim:va\t, A. M., M WAKD. B. - Westcatk. A. M.. Assist: Jamb- Cowan. M. • Fbitz Kmiiu:. B s. Uwperit hell </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CARE OF MILK AND CREAM ON THE FARM. ii i r: \\ INTRODUCTION. rnd machinery have done mueli to improve but Mi,- must skilful hull.'i - n cannot overcome tlio .vil Itby nicilioils followed by mm weans liryroen 'In not realise tliis condition • ■■• which really exist* between tin- ennm n prodiic ••) Im 1 1 •• r eannoi be made from an mil The better the i|uality of the batter will be the demand. The hiprh (pude lmt ■yen when the markei i&lt; well if butter. If t In* 1 ,-it a lower price owing to the | n .&lt; ir need, it follow* thai the creamery eanno&lt; ■ fat. Tli.' dnirymeii of Xebraaka :.i|'\\ (In* 1 iii tlti- '&lt;t\\t r price paifi \\I.I\KSS ,st wh.ii in t- in; nrtaiil feature Hip llrialll Teal III')' in tnilk. Sjieeial (rtremi may be plai-i-il I -viirss is allowed to iw iiinsi painstaking eare would eonnil ilts. ictors "' Hmi imports upon ' be laid. Ii is impossible to prmhict' l""&gt;'I mil .mi if ilirt of any kind is allowed ' into ii I ■ i faken at milking tinn-. ■ liri ami cliisi a\ il I Ur tlanks and ndd&lt; Phe greater par) of this filthy matter ilk. giving it noi only undesirable odors ami nniits but tcnlating it with various kinds of bacteria. Tli' • stagnant water. iiiin may </seg>
            <seg id="p004">not be disca* rmful should they be they arr milk. Fill! disease f&lt; carelessness that al lows it i* :&gt;t as nearly clean I largely by brushii all tl but a moniei I Bfllino rom tlif i ootations illetir .Its. milkers on 1 1 ■ well in i of 'lirt thnt linp Altho sonic l;iiiii. i&gt; tbinl ■ ry-iiian can. in - mysterioiis way. n n dirt and Is. it remains a fact thai the containing rom dissolved washiil udd&lt; i us from tli. um«* 1 1 &gt; I &lt; I ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p005">have of the • ■ contaminating milk from their person or I such work as feeding, cleaning the barn. the hands and clothing are sure to have on 1 filth which in many cases abounds in disease milker interested in a pure, wholesome product taking his hands before milking and on suit while milking. This suit need not be a • such a suit lias the advantage of at least showing ■oiled; and furthermore, if the milker is to he will soon be forced to keep everything about ■lilkiiig with w.t hands is a dirty practice, especially udder or hands are dirty, as the filth is washed into the The warm milk as it comes from the cow offers a splendid .m for the favorable growth of all kinds of bacteria that &gt;_rain access ts it In order to lessen this development, milk - 1 he don. ■« carefully and quickly as possible and the -'•Mined thru a metallic strainer. Do not use a cloth '"or even miller good conditions this soon becomes a i for bacteria. The milk should be removed from the and barn atmosphere as soon after milking as possible. To thorolv clean milk utensils they should first be rinsed ....... .. — ■ \ water to remove all particles of milk. Then they r-.i!v scrubbed with a brush in wans water to which ■ 101I washing powder lias tieen added. A r, itn m fat is much to he preferred. After ,uiM(l '&gt;r at least rinsed in boiling water, itk of any kind should be allowed to come in eon- ■ ■•m after the Maiding pr -unlight is one of ants and when possible all utensils should be innlight and pure air. Tl Mirse. must also be thorolv cleaned. No •hoiild place any confidence in an agent 's claim of separa- g able fo wash themselves hy simply running water thru — ; i «- li claim are not made hy men who have the dairy - inen'i in' I heart. Washing a separator is not a very difficult task if dotn' soon after separating. The water for wash - ing should be warm, but not hot enough to cook the curd on any of the parts. If it is not convenient to wash the machine im - itely after separating, the bowl should at least be taken apart and immersed in water. This will loosen all the curd and make washing comparatively easy. Tf the parts are scalded with hot water '&gt;r steam after washing and left in a sweet, clean place ♦o dry. no wiping with a cloth will be necessary I'ARK &lt;&gt;K MILK ITKNS11.S. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">rlirt falling all-top pail m hi. i \ ■ miil i miiiKT ti lud«- all II IcriologicHl c| - ■ • </seg>
            <seg id="p007">/ . il and ' here ii aim) smaller I'.n- these reasons it is I i |n-r &lt; - • - 1 1 T to Ille t I-Ool low temper;' E-v, ill of mml iT'i nis. and 1 li.it much longec than when i1 ■■■riiu'-htv to determine ill" \\ ■ ili\ i I • I .Mil in &lt;-■-&lt;-.- 1 1 1 1 iluit \\*s been &lt; ili-&lt; I in i I ;is being extremely undesirable, ■ - 1 ii | &gt;•- •'&lt;• t uri 1 id' tin- wlioli loriimni baeteria to activity, eaoa in niiilii|il\ rapidly. [ - r-&lt; •&lt; 1 1 1&lt;- i i ■ *r large muoantii of .iciil inlfsirnhlf tiiiMini.il idiis before t li&lt;- cream is • l.'il In .i |ioiiii wliciv (heir growth is clii'rkffl Wjirm - nilil In lin&gt;rol&gt; • liil before ii is added to the eol&lt;] </seg>
            <seg id="p008">« v |'i|"' » it It in ;ilxnii "&gt; inehea of ■ the inlft pipe, and ottoin it is distribuii'il thru th«&gt; t;ml •■ is plian. g table : T vhi.k 1- - shou in&lt;i 1 1 - .^n^ M \ M \ • ■ . - in side with ■ I'll HS ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p009">§ » Tank for keeping cream cool while held at the farm. - observed, it is possible to keep cream in _-o,)(l condition for several days, even in very warm weather. In those parts of the state where it is ax - '■t'dirijrly difficult to leeare ■ good supply of .ulil Mater, or in the newly settled sections where as yet not enough dairying is done to rani the building of a milk house and cool- - pits or shallow wells could be used u r milk and cream as shown in Fig. f&gt;. nts indicate that these pits may have faperai - : an 70 degrees when the actual temperature M F When these special pits are used - i he milk and cream is usually of a much I be the case if it had been stored in the cellar containing vegetables of all sorts. i that milk and cream readily absorb odors thiiif that niay stand near them. A well or pit suitable for the cooling of the cream should • ■ n feel deep and can be cemented, bricked, or boarded up as seems best under local conditions. It is not expel ! no particular skill is required to construct a pit of this kind. Fijr 5 illustrates one of these pits and sho simp' g apparatus with counter weight. The two guide - running from the upper framework to the two stakes in the botto well keep the elevator in place. The size of the elevator and of the counter weight depends of course upon the load to be carried, and can be varied to meet the needs of prac - tically all conditions. The writer knows of dairymen who, because they realize the importance of &lt;jiiick cooling, and by keeping the cream in cans </seg>
            <seg id="p010">11 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">12 chance to escape. protection from flies having strong odors -nch odors are readily I less than three times a ■ii is hauled to the station - protected by covering with a oiicl to tin 1 creamery or station, the nabied to deliver am at a much lower would otherwise be possible. During the • il not be delivered oftener than two ' e:i n cream, cold cream, and ricli words wliich tell the secret of producing lieved that -ions and such others as intelligent fanner will aid him in producing a • sanitary and wholesome, and one that should market priee, whether it is sold for whether it is to he used for liiitter-makinir SUMMARY to produce clean milk and erera unless the ■lilker. utensils, and separator are eleaa. ■ utensils use, first, .old water for rinsing: containing ;i small quantity of good w ■ninir: third, lioilinu' water or steam Kly impossible to ki-t ■ i ! clean and free from bacteria. &gt;ihle. and cool tin :o 4o per rent the richer iln- By skimming ■ rieh cream, iimr.- K ■■■■'!. and there is also smaller bulk l&gt;' am with cold cream until it separator thorol.i after each separation I )• 'vain station early iu in i tank &lt;&gt;t' eold \v;itt-r until tiim rv. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">13 Car, ,,f Milk and Crmm on the Furm Deliver th&lt; ■ r.am not less than three times a week dunutt the summer, and twice a week during tht- winter Protect the cans of cream from the sun by covering wit* •■anvas or with a </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>