<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF GEORGE LAWSON SHELDON GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE 31st Session Nebraska Legislature 1909</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">OF GEORGE LAWSON SHELDON GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE 31st Session Nebraska Legislature 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">» lentlemen: — You will be confronted with serious and profound (| which vitally concern the material and moral welfare of this commonwealth. In the solution of these questi iiat you will act as you conscientiously believe is the express wish of your constituents. Such recommendatii ■ ntained in this m»-&gt; ■ made believing their enact - would be in the ii &gt;f the p of our state. Pardons, Commutations and Paroles. I During my term of office ITS application* have been made ■xi'cutive clemency. I have given one unconditional ti conditional pardons and 2(1 c omiinltations. There application! made for reprieve. Both were denied. I granted paroles with conditions which varied according le circumstances of the case, and of the character of the ,-idual convict. IAt the present time there are 28 convicts on parole. Of number 20 were paroled during this administration, and ring the previous ones. I Hearing and passing upon the applications that are made re the Governor for executive clemency are anion^ ; serious and trying duties of the office. I The Governor is required by law to set a date for hear - for every convict who applies, even though the Governor be already satisfied that executive clemency should not extended. Cases of this kind simply take up valuable I without any beneficial results. Of course, even under the </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 wording of the statutes, tl, nor may. if he f that it is not worth whil ■ date for a hearing, but when the applicant is insistent, through himself, inten - friends or by attorney, there is nothing for the Governor to do but to set the date as required by law. When a man charged with an offense has been given a fair trial and a just tenee, it does not seem to me that the Governor should be compelled to review every case and pass judgment un there is some good and sufficient reason. I suggest that the word "shall" be changed to "may." In the applications that have come before me for &lt; clemency, I have observed that the hearings almost altogether are more or less ex parte affairs. It is very seldom that anyone appears at these bearing! to protest against the application. In order to get the other side of the case the trial judge and the prosecuting attorney have been requ to furnish such statements and recommendations as thev ed. T!&gt;e testimony given at the hearings has been taken in shorthand and transcribed. All the papers received in ■n with the applications have been filed together and bound with the testimony. These papers are herewith trnns - 1 to you. and it is requested that after you have sidered these applications they be returned to the Governor's office that they may be there kept on file. II have made it a rule before granting paroles to hi ?ment from the prosecuting attorney and trial judge. This been done because a parole is a sort of conditional pardon in order to become acquainted with the history of his , the better to determine whether the convict was de - ing. I There is herewith transmitted a complete list of tli i given, containing the convict's name and number, the e for which he was convicted, the length of his sentence </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 public way, to give the names and residence of the individuals to whom the convicts are paroled. This information can ured by anyone who desires it, by examining the records in the office of the Governor. In considering the applications that have been mad &lt;)in time to time for different forms of executive clemency. I have noticed Ute difference in tlie length of sentence of '■nt convicts for the same offences, when apparently the circumstances were the same. This, no doubt, comes partly the temperament of the different judges, and partly from the sentiment in the different localities where the various cases are tried. I have also observed that some of the who are given short sentences are real criminals. The ends of society would be best subserved if their sentences were lengthened rather than shortened. There are others who ■ ived long, and apparently just sentences for the OS committed, who are prepared to go back into society and lead a useful life loug before the expiration of I According to the biennial report of the Warden, there 65 of the convicts in the Penitentiary who admit having sd previous sentences. There are five reform school grad - s; 33 who have previously served one term; 13 two terms; , three terms; three, four terms, and two, five terms. Cer - y the demands of society and the cause of justice would est subserved if these men who have served from one to terms could be retained when once sentenced, until they reformed. I am firmly of the opinion that reformation is one of the great objects to be attained through confinement. K Without further discussing the question, I recommend the indeterminate sentence be substituted in place of the lties now provided by the criminal code, as soon as pro - n can be made for a Board of Pardons to determine when </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 itied to become a useful citizen. As long as the Governor has the sole power to pardon and commute, indeterminate sentences would be impracticable and probably more unjust than the pr stem, be rnor could not find time to properly perform the work that would be imposed upon him, and attend to the other ■ of his office. The first thinpr to do. then, is to submit an amendment to the ((institution providing for a Board of Pardons, or thougrh enactment empower the Governor to ap - men to act as a Pardon Board. While under the constitu - tion they could not be given the power to pardon, they could .mend to the Governor, and if they were appointed by him. he no doubt would have confidence in their recommendations. In my opinion, such a provision would not be in conflict with on 16, Article 5 of the Constitution. cording to the biennial report of the Warden, there 90 prisoners received under twenty-one years of and 186 between th&gt; f twenty-one and thirty. There ived daring the biennium 423 prisoners. Therefore. 65 per cent, of those who have been received during the last two years were under thirty years of age. Of the 423 re - ceived a sentenced of one year, and 141 from one to three years. No doubt a good many of these young men bore good reputations, and led fairly good lives, as the ways of the world go, prior to their conviction. iThe Penitentiary is at present over-crowded. There are cells, and 446 convicts. This necessitates placing two in many of the cells. Such a crowded condition neces - ,y compels the placing of first-offense men and men who not real criminals at heart in close contact with hardened natural criminals. ■ If the number of convicts continue to increase in the next years as it has during the past few years, it will be quite </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 isary to make some additional provision to care for them. Your attention, therefore, is particularly called to inendation of the Warden in his biennial report in ref - erence to the establishment of a reformatory so that the ned criminals may be kept separate from that Dvietl which can he more easily reformed and redeemed. Employment of Convicts. tl'he convicts at the Penitentiary at the present time are y employed by the state doing work around the institu - and on the farm attached thereto, and partly in the ifacture of brooms under contract. I On the 5th day of January this year there were 46ti . Of this number 270 were employed in the manufacture rooms under contract, and 124 by the state. Fifty-two are. therefore, unemployed. tWhen the contract with the Lee Broom &amp; Ouster I expired last summer there was an effort made to secure tter contract, but no prison contractors, except the one red to, made any offer. The existing contract on hie le office of the Secretary of State was the best coi: could possibly be secured. In the preparation of the contract with the Lee Broom &amp; Duster Company care was taken so there would be an 0] t unity for this legislature to provide work for the convicts other than by contract labor if you deemed it wise to do so. I have always felt that the state could profitably establish a plant at the Penitentiary for the manufacture of goods in the different institutions in this state, and therefore, : i mend legislation along that line. State Institutions. ■The state institutions of this state are in a splendid treat improvement has been made during the last </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ment of the stock at all of the institutions. I The buildings are in good repair, and in almost every mce the sanitary conditions are excellent. The health he inmates and the wholesale* appearances of the build - and grounds demonstrate that it is good policy for the &gt; to keep its institutions in first class condition. I The present excellent condition of the state institutions je largely to the fact that trained and experienced men : been at the head of them. For eight years those men have made good as Superintendents have been retained, the careless ones have been removed. During this administration each superintendent has been the recognized head of the institution. He has not been hamp - ered by the Governor with appointments of incompetent ami undesirable employees. This policy was inaugurated in order that the superintendent could be held wholly responsible for the management and conduct of his institution. As a harmony prevails in all the institutions. The superintendents, feeling the responsibility reposed in them, have taken keen in - terest and pride in the conduct and management of the in - stitutions. IThis administration has endeavored to keep the institu - i within the appropriation made for maintenance, and in the Board of Public Lands &amp; Buildings has co-operated, deficiency bills required for maintenance will bi - usual. I am pleased to inform you that the reports made by the different institutions on the 30th day of November, 1908. that all the institutions with the exception of three, had in excess of 16 2-3 per cent of their maintenance appropriation unexpended. This indicates that those institutions if properly managed between now and the first of April, 1909, will have no deficiency. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Oeneva, which had but t 1- &lt;£per cent of its maintenance ap - propriation remaining; the State Penitentiary, which had 4 14 per cent of its appropriation remaining, and the Home for the Friendless. The report of the Girls' Industrial School at i in - dicates that the cyclone which destroyed the laundry i &gt;t her out-buildings, last summer, was partly responsible for the present depleted condition of its maintenance fund. Since the inmates of this institution are all girls, it has not been le to make as good use of the land in connection with the institution as might otherwise have been done. Any one who visited that institution previous td the time that it was &lt;1 under the present management, and is familiar with ndition at the present time, will not find fault with the deficiency. The deficiency at the State Penitentiary is not due to the management of the Warden. The Nebraska Penitentiary is sanitary in every respect and has been well managed. The reason of the deficiency there is because the appropn was made two years ago on a basis of 340 inmates. Two years ago there were 327 convicts. Now there are 446. Inasmuch as there are 119 more inmates in the Penitentiary at the present time than there were two years ago, it is quite re - markable that there is not a greater deficiency than will be presented to you for payment. There was received during the biennium from the con - for convict labor, $74,223.90. This money was paid into the state treasury. The cash paid into the State Treasurer by the Warden was $12,556.07. The expenses for maintenance and repair during that biennium amounted to about $117,000, according to the Warden's report. This amount includes the expenses incidental to the establishing of a better lighting plant, the building of the hog and cow barns, and other im- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 the tax-payers of this state any great amount to support the convicts at the Penitentiary. Inder the law th nor has the right to parole as he sees fit. and to commute and pardon, after a hearn conformity with the law. as his judgment dictates. A suf - : number of convicts could have been paroled, pardoned and commuted to keep the expenses of the institution within the appropriation, had I desired to adopt that policy. I have lit it best to have proper regard for the decisions of juries and courts and for the demands of society, rather than to show mercy when such would not be in accordance with justice. Regarding the deficiency that will be incurred at the Home for the Friendless, your attention is respectfully called to the explanation made by the superintendent in her biennial i. Her recommendation that the two institutions be separate should be adopted. Insurance of State Property. Section 6, Chapter 83 of the Compiled Statutes, author - izes the Governor to insure public buildings and other prop - erty belonging to the state, but inasmuch as no appropriation was made for that purpose, none of the state's property has been insured. No doubt the legislature from time to time has thought that the state could best afford to carry its own insurance. In that opinion I concur wherever suitable fire protection is provided. I Your attention is called to the report of the Superintend - of the Industrial School at Kearney in reference to the ruction by fire of the barn and its contents, including all le horses, and also to the destruction of the laundry and &gt;uildingB by tornado at the Industrial School for Girls eneva. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Superintendent of the Industrial School at Kearney in ref - e to water supply, and respectfully recommend that either additional fire protection be provided or that an appro - priation be nude sufficient to insure th i property at that institution. National Guard. I The National Guard is largely composed of young men are rendering the state a most important service at eon - !-al)le sacrifice to themselves. The National Guard is en - ;1 to the greatest respect and the most loyal support of citizens of this state. It was the training the hoys of First Nebraska received in the National Guard that en - 1 them to perform such splendid service in the Philippines. It is a ttrnggle for the officers and men of the companies to keep their number up in accordance with the requirements of the federal law. I feel that in many instances employers ■sponsible. for they do not wish to sustain the loss of time incurred by a faithful guardsman. It is hoped that in the future these employer! will be more lenient with the guards- Ee federal government now contributes largely to the t of the (Juard. This is all the more reason why you provide liberally for the maintenance, the support, of the property of the National Guard. It re - more sacrifice on the part of the young meu to become men than should be imposed upon them. The question of having a suitable place to drill, and other expenses incidental to maintaining a company with proper efficiency, are now largely borne by the individual members of the company, and especially so the larger cities. Kis really a shame that there are not better companies aha aud in Lincoln. In these cities there can be and be companies equal in efficiency to any that may be </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 state would do its part we could get the men. The question of armories is of vital importance. I do urge with all the force at my command that this legislature adopt a policy by which an armory shall be built at the state \ expense in those cities where it has been demonstrated that a company can be properly maintained. In this connection. I suggest that you either provide a small annual levy running until this purpose shall have been accomplished, or make such an appropriation as in your judgment you feel that the state at this time can afford. Another recommendation that I desire to make in regard to the National Guard, is that the law be changed so that the officers shall be appointed directly by the Governor after com - petitive examination conducted under such regulations as may be provided by law. In my opinion, this is of prime import - ance. In making this recommendation I am casting no re - flection upon anyone connected with the National Guard. Under the present system I feel that there is as little abuse in the election of officers as possibly could be. Under the present arrangement for the selection of offi Guard politics have often destroyed its efficiency. Tm often, it has occurred that a majority of a company dictate the officers and non-commissioned officers with disastrous rer Baits. Too many men in times past, who have rendered service, have been voted out of the National Guard. Tin- Guard and the state have suffered accordingly. The merit system should be adopted. Spanish War Claims I The statement of the monies received and disbursed dur - my administration, which is herewith transmitted to rour consideration, and made a part of this message, shows there is still a balance of $7,894.52 due Nebraska soldiers served in the Spanish-American war. This amount </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 over by my predecessor $23,i&gt;37.41 on this account. The Ad- jutant General has endeavored to locate as many of the sol- diers as possible. They are scattered all over the country, and in all probability it will be a long time before all of them will be found and paid. The following is a statement of all moneys received and rsed by me corruneneimr January 3, 1907, and ending January 7, 1909: Executive Office t Reserve $ 3,079.30 5 per cent sales of P. L 3,000.39 U. S. Soldiers and Sailors 76,505.37 idition Fees 167.00 Com. Deeds 30.00 Total $82,782.06 Treasurer's Receipt on file in office $82,782.06 Spanish War Claims— (1907-1908). Balance, January 4th, 1907 $23,537.41 ved during year 1908 6,243.04 ved during year 1908 140.00 Total $29,920.45 Paid during January, 1907 $ 5,069.86 Paid during February, 1907 2,786.72 Paid during March, 1907 1,258.24 Paid during April, 1907 1,091.90 Paid during May, 1907 944.70 Paid during June, 1907 585.75 Paid during July, 1907 364.16 Paid during August, 1907 116.88 Paid during September, 1907 342.54 Paid during October, 1907 130.81 Paid during November, 1907 241.76 Paid during December, 1907 198.25 $13,131.57 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Paid during March, 1908 213.13 Paid during April, 1908 514.30 Paid during May, 1908 480.26 Paid during June, 1908 3,461.10 Paid during July, 1908 2,564.7:* Paid during August, 1908 329.70 Paid during September. 1908 150.87 Paid during October, 1908 266.68 Paid during November, 1908 74.77 Paid during December, 1907 225.38 $ 8,804.88 Outstanding vouchers issued by Governor Sheldon. . 89.48 ■•nut on hand in First National Bank, Lincoln, January 7, 1909 7,894.52 Total $29,920.45 General Barry Claim. Received from U. S. Government $ 2,511.81 Paid to Calhoun &amp; Sizer, Attorneys $ 502.36 Paid to General Barry 2,009.45 Total disbursements $ 2,511.81 Conservation Commission. The movement that is now under way to conserve the natural resources of the country is one that should be en- couraged. In many instances the few have been permitted to exploit the resources of the country for their own individual benefit. A far better policy and which is imperatively de- manded is that the natural resources of the country shall be conserved and developed for the common welfare. This state can do much to help in the solution of this problem. We have many resources, some of which are undeveloped. Care should be taken to carefully guard and conserve them. It is of prime </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 I Having tlii.s in lnincl. I have appointed a e commission, composed of mm who by their works have en themselves competent to -rive advice. The conini serve without ]&gt;ay and report to the Governor as they de - or he may desire. Alaska- Youkon Exposition. I The Alaaka- Youkon exposition will be held in Seattle summer. That portion of the country has developed rapidly, and will, no doubt, have use for many of the Beta that are produced in this state; and for that r&lt; i other, you will be justified in making provisions to have &lt;tate represented. Should you determine to make an appropriation for tlu-t purpose I recommend that a part of such appropriation : lo duplicate the prizes that may he won by Net stock, and especially cattle. Such a provision will encourage some of our best stock raisers to show their cattle at that -it ion. which, of course, will redound to the credit of our state. State Fair. E'rom our observations the Nebraska State Board of ure are constant in their efforts toward the "betterment riculture." Under its management the State Fair has i to exposition proportions, of which Nebraska's pro - ve citizens are justly proud. I ['here is great need for some important permanent build - on our fair grounds, such as other states enjoy, and we the conditions may be such that our state fair may luipped with permanent structures as becomes our ral position. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 I The National Corn Exposition was held in Omaha. De - ber 9 to 19, 1908. In March. 1908, I appointed Win. Ernst. E. Burnett, R. Rogue and W. R. Mellor a commission t&lt;&gt; note Nebraska's interest. The state was organized for the pose of growing better corn so that Nebraska mi$*ht credit - ' fill the place occupied by her as the third corn state in Union. Nebraska had the greatest number of exhibits shown. The exposition was an educational feature of credit to our commonwealth. The commission and also the managers of the exposition are entitled to much credit, and their 1 in this regard have been praiseworthy. The exposition was a success in every way and certainly will redound to the credit of the state at large. Silver Service, The legislature of 1905 made an appropriation of $3 to purchase a silver service for the battleship "Nebraska." That silver service was purchased in accordance with the pro - s of the law, during the administration of my prede - cessor, but was not presented because the ship was not placed under commission until early in the year 1908. Arrangements then made to present the gift at San Francisco where the battleship joined the fleet for the trip around the world. and accordingly the silver service was presented on board the "Nebraska," June 8, 1908. I am pleased to inform you that a large number of the sailors are Nebraska boys; that her commander, Captain olson, is recognized as one of the most efficient commanding officers in the American navy, and that the "Nebraska" is one of the best battleships in the American fleet. Lincoln Monument. In 190? there was organized an association of state ofii known as the Abraham Lincoln Centennial Memorial Associ- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 should be the president, the Secretary of State the sec - j, and the State Treasurer the treasurer of the as I The object of the association is to raise a fund for the tion of a monument and statute upon the State Capitol inds, in memory of Abra^im LincolO, for whom our capital rained. About $2,500 has been .subscribed by popular eription in small amounts, and more is pledged to be D needed. What has been accomplished is largely due to efforts of Addison Waite, the Deputy Secretary of 8 to F. M. Hall, who was appointed by the officers of the ciation to confer with reputable sculptors. Mr. Hall has vn considerable interest in this matter, and at his own ■use made a trip east to confer with noted sculptors. thas been determined that it would cost from $20,000 to X) to erect a monument and statue worthy of the e. 3 only $2,500 has been collected, it is confidently beli if the legislature would appropriate ' the balance be raised by popular subscription. KThis monument, when dedicated, will be the property of itate. Therefore, it seems to me that you will be entirely fied in making an appropriation for this purpose. Biennial Reports. Krhe biennial reports of boards, executive officers and •intendents of institutions are herewith transmitted to you our consideration. E reports will give you a splendid idea of the way fairs of this state have been managed during the last urn, and also give you a good understanding of the ; and the conditions of the state. I sincerely trust these reports will be carefully read. The early days of tli&lt; . could be well improved by a care - ful examination of these reports. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 I The state has installed a plant at the Penitentiary capable irnishing electricity to properly light the Executive Man - the Orthopedic Hospital, the Home for the Friendless, the Capitol grounds and buildings. Your attention is fctfully called to the remarks concerning this subject con - ?d in the biennial report of the Board of Public Lands and iin^s. This subject requires immediate attention for, if deem it advisable to complete the wiring for the Capitol ling you will see the i y of acting at once. KYour attention is also called to the necessity of properly iring and improving some portions of the Capitol, and ; particularly the basement. State Veterinarian. Your attention is respectfully called to the report of the Deputy State Veterinarian, and to his remarks concerning a live stock sanitary commission. I concur in his recom - mendation. AnJTna-1 Quarantine, For a considerable length of time the United States Bur - eau of Animal Industry has kept cattle in western Nebraska under quarantine for scabbies. The supply of cattle is usually fed in eastern Nebraska is secured largely from the western part of the state. When the quarantine was first established the government endeavored to control state shipments as well as interstate shipments. Soon after the last legislature ad - journed, it was decided the federal government had no right to interfere with state shipments, and thereafter the govern - ment inspectors looked after interstate shipments only. The South Omaha market being a public market was under the control of the Bureau of Animal Industry, which required separate division for "clean and unclean" cattle. During last winter when cattle were being shipped from </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Bareta of Animal Industry thereupon decided to quarantine thi' whole state. In company with the president and secretary of the Live Stock Exchange of South Omaha, and Mr. Myers, of Hyannis, ■ I went to Washington and conferred with the Secretary of Agriculture, at which time it was agreed that a quarantine -hmild be established across the state and maintained by the co-operation of the state and federal authority. It was also agreed that the state should enforce local quarantine in ii Nebraska where necessary. Under this arrangement conditions were materially improved, but they will always be ■ aggravating until the whole state is cleaned up satisfactorily to the Bureau of Animal Industry. ■ . therefore, urgently recommend that you make such &gt;priation as in your judgment will be sufficient to uarantine. Hog Cholera. The United States Bureau of Animal Industry now claims to have a sure cure for hog cholera. At the present time, how - ever, the cure is more or less impractical because of the cost and the lack of means of producing sufficient serum for the purpose of inoculation. I am informed that the present cost of a dose for one hog is $1.14. Some of the Bureau's field men and Dr. Peters, at the Nebraska Experimental Station, conducted experiments with remarkable success. It is claimed that a hog once inoculated will remain immune for six months, and that experiments indicate that from 90 per to 98 per cent of infected herds can be saved. Ehe enormous loss that has been sustained by farmers in ate from time to time by hog cholera, and the gratifying s of the experiments that have been made by Dr. Peters te field experts of the Bureau of Animal Industry, prompt </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 investigation you will come to the conclusion that it is worth while to make an appropriation so that our Experimental Station may be in a position to help the hog raisers of this Public Health. KThe public health of the people of this state during the two years has been excellent, and as a rule always has . The present Board of Secretaries to the State Board ealth has served the public well and wisely. I There has been wonderful advancement in medical science ng the last few years. So far as possible this state should n a position to take advantage of the new discoveries for prevention and treatment of diseases. I Your attention is especially called to the recommendation e by the Secretaries of the Board of Health for the estab - nent of a bacteriological laboratory. In times past, we i appropriated money from time to time, when occasion lired, for the prevention and cure of animal diseases. In opinion the state has not done as much as it should for « things which concern our physical life. I, therefore, urgently recommend that this legislature pro - vide liberal means for this purpose. Education. I The people of this state have reason to be proud of their •ational system. The tax-payers are certainly to be com - ded for the generous disposition they have displayed at imes in willingly voting upon themselves heavy taxation for ■ation. We are spending about $6,000,000.00 every year the common-school system. During the past few years •ts have been made to provide instruction in our public ols that will better equip our young people for the prac - affairs of life. The movement in this direction should </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 are annually contributing to the support of the public schools, jroa will be justified in making liberal appropriations to pro - the professional training of teachers in the I'niversity Btete Normals. The University, the two nornial schools, ami the private normals are doing excellent work in the onal training of teachers. II have observed, however, that the greater proportion of t who come from these schools and enter the prof - ■aching find positions in the graded schools of the cities towns. The country districts should not be negl&lt; ii my opinion, the greater per cent of the country and girls receive no higher education than that which receive in the rural schools. It is, therefore, of prime importance, for the future i fare of this state, that we provide means so far as possible so that the country schools may have up-to-date and better teachers. Having this in mind, the legislature two years ago •priated $50,000 to assist our high schools in establishing normal training. This act has enabled about one hundred high schools to qualify for this work. The results accomplished have been highly satisfactory in every particular. I urgently recommend, therefore, that you make a liberal appropriation for this purpose. Junior Normal Schools. I For a number of years, $15,000 has been appropriated for purpose of establishing what is known as junior normal ols. I have visited these schools from time to time and v that great good is coming from them. Here the teachers gathered together from the different parts of the state, receive instruction of the best methods of teachings i our very best educators. The work that is being done </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 priated for this particular purpose. Weak School Districts. In some portions of this state, where the population is sparse, and where the property within a school district is not of sufficient value to raise enough revenue, it is not pos - sible for the tax-payers to keep the schools open for more than three to six months in the year. Most of these districts are in the western part of the state. Two years ago the legislature appropriated $50,000 in order to assist these dis - tricts so that they could have at least seven months' school. As to the amount needed for this purpose, you are respectfully referred to the Superintendent of Public Instruction. State University. You have every reason to be proud of our great State University. The state has profited much through the higher education that has been afforded through it to young men and women. While at times it may have seemed to some that the cost of building up the University has been considerable, I feel you will agree with me that that cost has been well worth the while. We should not forget tht some members of the faculty, who are classed among the best educators of this country, through loyalty and devotion to the Uni - versity, have remained at a much smaller salary than they could have commanded if they had accepted offers from other Universities. I The increased valuation of the assessment of property in state this year will probably well care for the normal rth of the University, and provide means of increasing the ties of some of the professors whose services during the entitle them to better compensation in the future. Your attention is respectfully called to the urgent need </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 any place for the cadeta to drill, and unless some ade - i|iiatc jirovisiuii is made to provide a drill ground the will, in all probability, lose the appropriation that is being by the general govenuaeat, under the condition that military instruction be given at the I'niversity. The time has now conie to enlarge the University campus. It is not likely that the surrounding property will be any cheaper than it the present time. It is more probable that it will ad - in value. Therefore. I strongly recommend that a suf - ficient appropriation be made to buy the five blocks which in the campus on the east, north, and north-east. I If. after due consideration, you find that any part of the ,111 be provided for out of the one-mill levy, all good. If this cannot be done, in my opinion, you will be tied in Baking an appropriation for that purpose out of general fund. Agricultural Education KOur boys and girk and our fertile soil are our gn We have done much for the education of the boys girls, and have taken considerable precaution to surround i with a wholesome and moral atmosphere. The productiveness of our soil can be greatly incre;i without destroying its fertility, by improved and more - 1 1 tit- methods of agriculture. The State Agrieulturai Expen- Station is doing great work in giving the boys and girls from the farms knowledge along these lines. It is also doing a great work for the farmers in this state in disseminating the results of the experiments conducted at the State Farm and at the Experimental Station at North Platte. The fact that on the State Farm they have been able to raise an average of over 70 bushels of corn to the acre for the last five years, while the farmers of Lancaster county were only able to </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 average of 35 bushels to the acre during the same 1, furnishes a striking example of what we can ex improved methods of agriculture. Another work that the Experimental Station is doiiu in conducting Farmers' Institutes. The benefit that is coming from these institutes is already being felt in those portions of the state where the institutes have been held. Appropria - tion for continuance of this policy should not be negl&lt; This is certainly additional proof that the agricultural college should be liberally cared for. Experimental Stations The results obtained by the Agricultural Experimental Station at North Platte, Nebraska, have more than justified its establishment, and signify the importance of establishing other Experimental Stations in the western part of the state. I hope that every one of you will secure and read the bulletins from that Station in reference to the experiments that have been made in the conservation of moisture in the soil, and the wonderful results that have been obtained in raisin gf grain through scientific and improved methods of farming. The wel - fare of the people of this state is a common one. The pros - perity of each section is beneficial to all other portions of the state. The pioneers and settlers in western Nebraska are to be commmended for the great work of demonstrating that there is no remaining portion of this state not suitable for home building. The wealth produced in our western coun - ties can be greatly increased. There can be no better way to obtain this object than by establishing additional experi - mental stations. In my opinion, one such station should be established in the sand hill district, another in the extreme western part of the state on the high plains, and a third in the irrigated section. In regard to an experimental station in the irrigated trict, I have had some correspondence with the Secretary of </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 trip xDt f nor concern 1 n £r &amp; t rjici oi i&lt;i nci t licit is now Acid in reserve by that Department for its use while constructing the "Pathfinder" ditch. This particular piece of land is school land, and therefore properly belongs to the state. The Secretary of the Interior states that it will be necessary to secure an Act of Congress before water can be furnished gratis. Such an act will, no doubt, be passed. The corre - spondence in reference thereto is herewith transmitted to you for your consideration. Western Development and the Herd Law, There has been rapid development and substantial pro - gress in the western part of Nebraska. The results that the settlers have attained there demonstrate beyond any doubt that a portion of the state is well adapted for the making of pros - perous, happy and contented homes. Taking advantage of the Kinkaid Act many settlers have gone into northwest Neb to establish homes. That portion of the state in the past has been largely devoted to the raising of cattle. The settling of the district is highly desirable and the settlers should be pro - tected, but it is for the general welfare that each portion of the state be made to produce as much as possible without destroying the fertility of the soil. The present Herd Law requires all stock to be kept under fence rather than that the crops be fenced. It occurs to me that if the present law be amended so that either the County nniissioners, or the people of a county where the majority of the land is, or may be, used for grazing purposes, could re - quire the land upon which crops are raised to be fenced, it would be a marked improvement over present conditions. In this way the cattle might be permitted to run at large and not injure the growing crops. Of course, the owners of cattle should be required to do their part towards fencing the crops. If some such plan as this could be carried out, there is no doubt but that the conflict which now occasionally arise* </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Dr&amp;SKA IN O \ 1 ) (.1 0 1S3 1) jJPci r. I II Pn , X ( m » , III II** n xnOrc Ufft I COlil (J be produced, because, under the present arrangement, there is much grazing land that cannot be used. KI respectfully call this to your attention with the hope you will take such action as, after investigation, you kbest. Geona Indian School. I he Commissioner of Indian Affairs has informed me that government intends to abandon the Indian School at Genoa, requested information whether the state could make use his property. It will require an act of Congress to accomplish this. Evidently it will be necessary for the legislature to determine wh&amp;t use the State desires to make of this property before congress will act. The correspondence is herewith transmitted to you, and I trust you will give the matter immediate consid- Estimated Receipts and Expenditures I There is herewith transmitted the estimated receipts and •nditures for the next biennium, as compiled by the Auditor ublic Accounts. The estimates for expenditures are based i the requests made by the several departments, and by superintendents of the different institutions. Estimated Receipts. General fund levies for 1909 and 1910 $3,163,263.88 General fund collections on back taxes 700,000.00 Collections on obsolete funds (House Roll 204) (Senate File 50) 3,000.00 From interest on deposits 25,971.49 From miscellaneous collections 8,150.00 From fees Governor 198 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 \ 1 1 * 1 ) I ' ' ' ''I I 'lit" -\'*&lt;*'M ....... Prom fees Com. Public Lands and Buildings.... i').'« From fees State Oil Inspector til'. 14 Prom fees Department &lt;&gt;i' Banking 27.4 From fees State Food Commissioner From fees Board of Irrigation 14.03 From fees Board of Equalization and Am meat From fees State Board of Health Kn.m I". S. Government "aid" S. &amp; S. Hume 76,5* From Penitentiary special labor 64,:W1.2i&gt; From Temporary school fund tax collections.... 6,0&lt; ' From interest on school and Saline land 237. 1 1 From lease on school and Saline lands '-i'2'2. 12!*. Tti From interest on bonds, school fund 425,746.66 From interest on warrants, school fund 114,181. 70 From game and fish licenses 16.44H. 00 B miscellaneous temporary school fund- eol - ectiotis 19.16 From temporary University fund taxes 672,512.35 From interest on University land 11,3$ From lease on University land 5.17 From interest on Agricultural College lands.... 19,3' From lease on Agricultural College lands :i.2. From interest on bonds. University fund _'"&gt; . 4:&gt; From interest on warrants. University fund 16,1 From University cash fund 177,764.17 From I". S. Government Agriculture and Mechanics Arts fund 65,000.00 a I'. S. Government aid Agriculture and Ex - periment Station fund 48,000.00 From I". S .Government, aid Forest Reserve fund 3,07 From Normal interest fund 6,67 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 From State Library 6,84.1 . 75 From Hospital for Insane fund 9,678 7!&gt; From Institution cash fund 59,093 . 38 $6,654,393.18 From total income of $6,654,393.18 The General fund derives $4.389.928. 64 The School fund derives 1.124.1 . The University fund derives 1.044,269.05 The Normal School fund derives 17,38 The Forest Reserve fund derives 3,079. 30 The State Library fund derives 6,845. 75 The State Library fund derives 6.845. 75 The Hospital for Insane fund derives 9,67 The Institution Cash fund derives 59,0: $6,654,393.18 Estimate of expenditures for the fiscal period commencing April 1, 1909, and ending March 31, 1911 : New Actual Permanent Current Improvements Expenses Legislative expenses $100,000.00 Governor 25,280.00 Treasurer 22,580.00 Auditor 35,300.00 Insurance department, Auditor 11,680.00 Superintendent Public Instruction 24,280.00 Junior Normal School* 30,000.00 Normal Training in High Schools 100,000.00 Aid Of School Districts 100,000.00 State Board of Examiners 2.500.00 Secretary of State 20.580.0A Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings... 28,880.00 Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings 42.100.00 Board of Educational Lands and Funds 5.000.0 ■&gt; Board of Purchase and Supplies 150.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 Attorney General Adjutant General Supreme Court In) State Library ■Department of Banking 37.4 State Board of Irrigation 16.080.M flame and Fish Commission 23,:' State Railway Commission 60.000.00 University 1.23k Soldiers and Sailors'" Home, Milford 51,1' Soldiers and Sailors' Hom«, Grand Island % 18.000.06 171 State Penitentiary 140 • Hospital for Insane at Lincoln 61.000.00 198.' Hospital for Insane at Norfolk 79 179 _ Asylum for Incurable Insane at Hastings... 418.7 Institution for Feeble Minded Youth, Beatrice 108.250 Hi).: Girls' Industrial School 53.7 Boys' Industrial School 5.000.00 113 ." Normal School at Kearney 100.000.00 119- Normal School at Peru 50.000.00 157." Home for the Friendless 26.00u 45. f. Institute for Deaf and Dumb 50,703.04 89." Food Commission 26." Geological Survey 2.500.00 State Historical Society 20." Nebraska Library Commission 10." State Board of Charities and Corrections.... 5.5' Expense of Normal School Board 2,5' Laws and Journals, etc 42,4 Revenue Books and Blanks 6.0' State Board of Equalization and Assessment. 6."' State Board of Health 1 5.000.00 Fugitives from Justice and Officers' fee* 20' District Court 252 For support of State Poultry Association 2.000.00 For support of State Board of Horticulture. . . 5,0' For support of State Board of Agriculture 4.000.00 For support of State Dairymen's Association.. 2.000.04 Commissioner of Labor X. 280. 00 State Veterinarian Procuring and transcribing abstracts of lands l,i" Institute for the Blind 44. s Nebraska Industrial Home 39. &gt; Hospital for Crippled and Deformtd Children 45," </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 iFrum this estimate it ippean that the estimated re somewhat larger than the appropriations up to this time •h ha\ sked for. There will, no doubt, be pre - vour consideration additional requests and bills for appro - tion not contained herein. The matter of making appropriations is one of the most im - nt duties of a legislature. It has been my observation in times past that in most i it would have been better if ■ propriation bills had received earlier consideration, ippropriations are the very last bills passed and &lt; quently have not always had proper consideration. Ehe st. rowing and appropriations must, of ne&lt; : ial thing to keep in to it that the appropriations do not exceed the I of the state. Another essential tiring is that only such oiild be appropriated as are actually needed. Care Hntomolo- .... 4^11 ■ Estimated Deficiency, (wolf bounty claims).. 50,000.00 Miscellaneous claims (estimated) Forest Reserve Fund S,n ; Institution Cash Fund 59,093.38 al School Fund 17,:: $498,453.04 $4,772,528.67 Total 5,270,9^ Adding state school apportionment to be dis- bursed during 1909 and 1910 1,308,5' Total $6,579,f, From the above total of $6,579,543.57 the amount chargeable to the General fund is $4,010,426.06 the amount chargeable to the University fund is 1,173 ■ the amount chargeable to the Library fund is 8,000.00 the amount chargeable to the Forest Reserve fund is 3,07 the amount chargeable to the Institution Cash fund is. ... 59.093.3S the amount chargeable to the Normal School fund is IT the amount chargeable to the Temporary School fund is.. 1,308.561.80 Total $6,579,543.57 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 what in the long run will be best for this commonwealth. The present superintendents of the various state institu- thoroughly familiar and have prove] with the needs of the different that they are capable of man - ■fore, presume you will find that -unable re - for repairs and mainten I The advisability of making appropriations for new build - is a matter for you to determine, but permit me to make I ion in reference to the appropriation asked for to t an administration building at the Soldiers' Home at id Island. There is a greater demand there for additional ities to care for the sick than there is for an administra - building. The report of the superintendent shows that during the biennium ending November 30th, 1908, there were 93 deaths in that institution which was an increase over the preceeding biennium of 10. The average age is given as 71. The health of the members in the Milford Home has been much better than the health of those in the Grand Island Home. It is generally believed that the sanitary conditions and the general surround - ings is principally responsible for the difference. If it is deemed advisable to erect additional buildings so that more soldiers may be cared for, or so that those who are now in the institutions may be better cared for, I strongly urge that such buildings be erected in the future at Milford rather than at Grand Island. This is not a question of favoring a particu - lar locality, but it is a question of doing what is best for a clan of people who have given this country the greatest pos - sible service that a citizen can render. them prudently. I. ther </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Finances and Taxation. Public Funds Safely Kept. The finances of the State are in most excellent condition. The policy of the State Treasurer in keeping money on hand in a great many banks instead of a few is to be heartily com - mended. The December report of the State Treasurer shows $411,086.73 deposited in eighty-eight banks. During the last biennium there were no losses of State funds, but instead there has been some gain on account of the Treasurer requiring the state depositories to pay three per cent instead of two per cent as formerly. The State Debt. There was a greater reduction during the last biennium in the state debt than ever before. On November 30, 1906, there were warrants outstanding against the general fund amounting to $1,916,671.13. On November 30, 1908, this had been reduced to $768,630.72. The reduction in 1907 amounted to $531,606.69 and in 1908 the reduction was $616,433.90, making a total reduction of $1,148,040.59. The one mill levy, provided by law to reduce the debt, produced during the biennium, $636,123.85. Therefore, the levy which was made for the general fund produced $511,916. - 74 more than was necessary for the general expenses of the state government, and that amount was applied on the pay - ment of the debt. The levy for general purposes during the biennium was five mills, the same as in previous year. I The money for the expenses of the state government dur - the last biennium was raised from the assessment made for years 1906 and 1907. In round numbers, the assessment in 5 was $8,300,000.00 more than in 1905, and the assessment 907, $16,400,000.00 more than in 1906. The total increase, •efore, for the grand assessment roll during the biennium $24,700,000.00 which would produce $113,500.00 more for </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 therefore, a reduction in the state debt of 1400,000.00 w'nh- OUt any increase in taXCl OfOT and above that paid by il, is in 1905. Taxation. IThe State Hoard of Eqalixation under this adiniir has endeavored. SO far as it was poauble, to make the unents of property uniform, so that each class of property Id bear its just proportion of the bnrdena of taxation. tTo this end. the Union Pacific Railroad property, in increased twenty-fire per cent. Increases were ma': r railroad property. Altogether the assessed vali oad property in 1!KI7 and 1!K)8 was increased by the B .4.441.00. Anyone who lias given the question of railroad assess - ment, much consideration, and has familiarized himself with the facts, must realize that the railroad companies an comparatively speaking, equitabh (L Some of the M earnings are small are prohabl; d at a higher val - ue than some of the other and greater railroads whose earnings are much larger. However, these inequalities must i continue to exist until the railroad companies fall out with eaeh other. At present there is an apparent disposition am&lt;&gt;n&lt;r the railroad companies to stand together and not give informa - tion concerning another company that would be helpful to the id of Equalization. I In 1907 the lands of this State were assessed at apj&gt; . ly #201,700,000.00, an increase of $3r&gt;,700.000. This UK ely $201,100,000, an increase of $55,700,000. This in. brought about from the fact that lands had not been as - ?d since the year 1904, and because since that time there been a great increase in the value of lands throughout tiie </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 MMMors had not used the same measure of value. The I endeavored to correct that condition and to perform its duty as the law required. It is the duty of the Board of Equalization to equalize all classes of property so that the burden of taxation may be equally shared. tlf it is proposed in this legislature to make any aniend - t to the revenue law pertaining to the power of the ■d of Equalization in this particular I earnestly request yon give the matter careful consideration before ■ ken. The first essential in a just system of taxation is to pro - vide means for a unifoni unit. No class of tax payers will complain of their assessment if the property is assessed uniformly throughout the state. The question of taxation is not an easy one. But anyone familiar with the history of the ■wnmrnt of property of this state during the last ten knows that the property at the present time is by far more uni - ily assessed than it was under the old revenue act. It is true that it is difficult for the Board of Equalization e in all instances, because no one can have knowl - edge of the actua 1 value of all the property in all parts of the ■tate. But the Board of Equalization is composed of officers led by the people of the state. There need be no fear that ii a board will deliberately and intentionally do an injus - to the tax payers in any portion of the state. The Board should not be deprived of the right to lower any class of proper - (»r all classes of property returned for a county. Neither should the Board be deprived of the right to raise all the prop - - or any class of property of a county, when compared with other counties such property has been undervalued. When the revenue law was first enacted, the Board could </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 Experience demonstrated that it was necessary to change the law, and experience has also demonstrated that the change was a wise one. The law in this respect should be left alone. There is no necessity for any change in the law in this par- So far as the assessment of land is concerned, it is a mat - ter of common knowledge that the per cent of increase in the ■■■eminent of land values in 1908, with the exception of some parts of the sand hill districts, increased from the east to the west. It is also a matter of common knowledge that the lands in the eastern part are assessed at more nearly their actual **alue than they are in thp western part of the State. There should be ra complaint that such is the case because the peo - ple in the western part of the state are still in that period of development where many sacrifices must necessarily be made, a good many of which are for the welfare of the whole state. So far as the lands and the railroads are concerned, I am firmly of the opinion that the railroads, with the exception of the Union Pacific Railroad Company, are assessed as high in proportion to their actual value as are the farm lands of this I believe the assessment of the Union Pacific Railroad Company should be still further increased, in justice to the other tax payers of this state, and have so maintained while acting as a member of the Assessment Board. So far as the election of assessors by precinct is concerned, that is a different matter, and to that I have no objection if you deem it wise to make the change. If any amendments to the revenue laws are made, the object should be to secure, if possible, a more just and equi - table system of taxation. A glance at the grand assessment rolls of this State will convince anyone that it is more necessary to devise ways and </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 meant whereby the owners of personal property may pay more nearly their proportion of the taxes than to make amendments which will restrict, and tie the hands of the Board of Equali - n. Id 1906 the personal property of this state, other than railroad and private car service, was $75,053,000; in 1907, $83, 186.000, and in 1908, $82,593,000. Any one who is at all fa - miliar with the conditions in this state knows that the actual value of personal property in 1908 was greater than it was in 1907, yet the grand assessment roll shows a decrease of - I The holders of the invisible personal property evidently ! discovered various ways of concealing their property. &gt;n the new revenue act was passed in 1903, and first put force, there was a great increase in the assessment of onal property. It is well worth your while and attention nd out what manner and methods the personal property ere are employing to conceal their property from assess - t, and to amend the law, if need be, bo that such action be prevented. I also repeat the recommendation made in my inaugural address, as follows: I "Under the present law real estate that is mortgaged is ssed for taxation purposes at its full value to the owner le land without any deduction whatever for the amount of _rage. In addition to this if a mortgage is held by a Jent of the county or of this state the mortgage is also aged at the full value. There is no good reason why a e of real estate that is encumbered with a mortgage should •urdened with greater taxation than a piece of real estate he same character and value that is not mortgaged. Again, under the law if the mortgage is held by a non - resident of the state, and a great many of them are, no tax is levied against it because mortgages are construed to be per - sonal property. Personal property is supposed to be nnnrnrid </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 b« taxed then certainly foreign mortgage! should ■ xed. The sensible thing to &lt;lo is to tax all mort inures. both foreign and domestic, as an intervst in real estate. Being assessed as an interest in real estate they would then be as - 1 for taxation purposes where the land is and not when 1 Iht- mortagee lives. The value of the SBortgBge should then he deducted from the value of the ■Mftglgwi estate anil the own - f the real estate I upon the equity lie pea It is contended by many that the result of such a law would increase the rate of interest because Nebraska is not yet a creditor state. If such is the case the possibility of an increase in the interest rate may be avoided by permitting the privilege of contract whereby the owner of the land, may if he pay the tax on the interest of the BMHtgage. He eould afford to do that and be none the worse off than at present. Certainly if all the domestic capital that is available for the investment of mort&lt;*a&gt;res is driven out of the non-residents may be oxpecte&lt;l to raise the rate of in - as they no doubt will do when there is no longer compe - tition by domestic capital. During the past ten years we have been bountifully blessed with good crops and prices. The people of this state have been paying off their indebtedness and accumulating capital which should be invested at home. The present law discriminates st domestic capital and in my opinon it is forcing th&lt; I of this state to invest their capital in securities and lands of other states. The present system plainly imposes a double tax upon mortgaged property, when the mortgage is held In - dent of this state and to that extent it increases beyond ire the tax upon that class of property. It is not fair to the residents of our state and it is against good public policy ntinue the pernicioi m of the present law in this </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Under the present law a man who is in debt is taxed for all that he possessed and for all that he owes. The debtor class of party holders should not be compelled to bear extraordin - ary burdens of taxation. Notwithstanding the fact that aln 'v other state permits the deduction of bona fide debts in some form or another, we are still discriminating agn the debtor class which is neither fair, right, nor just. Permanent School Fund. There was on November 30. I9&lt; '4.746.25 in the permanent school fund, all of which was invested with the ex - :ion of $11,121.81, in securities bearing different rates of interest. In this connection your attention is respectfully called to the fourth paragraph on page 30 of the report of the nmissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, to the effect that the permanent school fund should be reimbursed to the amount of $325,587.50. There was in the permanent University fund $189,020.17. all of which except $7.02 was invested. There was also $497. - 956.97 in the Agricultural Endowment Fund, all of which ex - rept $17.15 was invested. In the Normal Endowment Fund there was $778,189.00, all of which except $2.80 was invested. There is, therefore, in all about $8,290,000.00of trust funds. The investment of this fund that has accumulated from time to time is in the hands of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. I The amendment adopted at the last election in reference le investment of permanent school funds will open a new safe field for the investment of that fund, and one that produce a better rate of interest. Under this amendment » has been purchased $192,473 of school district bonds ing four and one-half per cent which was bene - 1 both to the permanent school fund and to the tax payers </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 Funds were called upon to make investments, it was found that about the only investments available were securities of other - and these wore in the hands of brokers. In order to break up what appeared to be a combination among the brok - was decided to purchase bonds directly from the states whenever possible. In consequence of this determination the ircisiirir w;is authorized in April, 1907, to go to Idaho to purchase bonds that were to be issued by that state. As a result $279,000.00 of Idaho bonds were purchased on the 25th of April, 1!M)7, bearing 4 per cent interest, and in September, 1907, from the same state there were purchased $60,000.00 more. ing 6 per cent. Following up the precedent in the Idaho case, in June, the state treasurer was authorized to go to California and purchase $500,000.00 worth of bonds that were to be issued by that state, and on July 2nd the purchase was made. The bonds were delivered on July 27th, 1908. These bore 4 per cent in- iThis action on the part of the Board had the desired effect, thereafter when funds were to be invested better bids were ived from the brokers who had securities to offer. During biennium of 1905-6 the average interest secured on invest - t on the permanent school fund was 3.485 per cent. Dur - 1907-8 it was 3.98 per cent, an increase of one-half of one cent. Security of Public Funds. EJnder the law, the state depository banks may give either sonal or surety bond. The usual procedure is to furnish ety bond. ■ The surety companies are doing business in all parts of country. In most instances their risks are enormous, and </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 in all probability many of the surety bond com - isrht not be able to meet their obligations. If the state funds can be protected in some way by which bankers would not have to pay a premium, as they do in the case of these surety bonds. the state would either secure more i its deposits, or the banker profit by the amount of iums paid. The surety bond proposition is neither satisfactory to the banks nor to the state. I therefore recommend that you amend the law so that state depository banks shall furnish first mort - gages on real r other securities of equal value in place of those now provided by law. Savings Banks. There is need in this state for a law that will encourage the establishment of private savings banks. The conditions are such in most of the smaller towns of the state that a savings bank of itself will not pay, and consequently none are established. Two plans occur to me which are suggested to you for your consideration. Either the enactment of a law providing for the establishment of mutual savings banks with the privilege of having branches in various parts of the state, or a law au - thorizing and providing for the establishment in commercial banks of a savings department but requiring the business to be Neparate and distinct, would in my judgment, be of great benent. The class of securities in which a savings bank could in - vert funds intrusted to it, should be either designated, or -left to the state banking board to designate. If the savings of our people in this way could be collected, and loaned judiciously upon Nebraska real estate, the security would be just as gooJ as the security offered through proposed postal savings bank*. and would bring a greater return to the depositors. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 IA number of report* from different counties of t)ii&gt; • been mad.' to me by reputable citizens, which ind there is considerable suspicion in those eounties that the ity treasurer is receiving more interest on the county funds •sited in depository banks than is being accounted I respective count ■ I The suspicion is that in some instance! the county m been placed in the depository banks, receiving from then 4 per cent and accounting to the county for only t\\ , the minimum as provided by law. It is not altogether easy to detect such misconduct, and tod in some instances it might be practiced iii ninny others. There cannot he too much publicity eoneerning the care and keep of public funds. Inasmuch as there provision in the law at the present time requiring the county irer to publish a statement giving the name of the de - try bank and showing how much county funds are in each bank. I I hat Sections 95a and 96b of Chapter IS. Article 1 of the Compiled Statutes be amended so that the tie of the county will know where their money is kept. KThis will, in my opinion, produce a wholesome effeef, and e the people of every county in this state to receive the benefit of the interest derived from public money on de- Usury, In some of the cities of this state, wore pari larly Omaha and Lincoln, then- are ;i n.unber of us, known as "loan sharks." ! ng alvai of the destitute circum.stanees of Door people. In money on chattels at enormous rates of interest. Son stances have been Balled to my attention where as high ■nt has been paid on loa ■■&lt;! by absolute!;. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 ii ."». Chapter 44 of the Compiled Statutes be MMMM n that when nsiirious rates of interest are charged the principal as well as the interest shall be forfeited. Records of Legislature of 1907. I am pleased to inform vow the Railway Commission timaies that shippers and pMMOgMN of this state have .+6.(*Ki.(H»il as h result of legislation passed by the last stnre, reducing' passenger fares to two cents a rm'". &lt; c - press rates 25 per cent; and freight rates on grain, live - fruit, lumber and coal, and other commodities in ear load lots 15 per cent. K Experience has demonstrated that the terminal taxation which was passed by the last legislature has provided a. ; equitable system of taxation, and on the whole has rieial to the tax payers residing in the cities and vili The last legislature also passed an act to control lobbj and to prevent corrupt practices affecting legislation - T abolished the free pass evil by enacting an anti-pass law: enacted ■ state-wide primary law requiring political parties to nominate their candidates by direct vote of the people, and gave the Railway Commission power to put an end to rebates and dis - criminations in transportation, to make and to fix rates, and utrol them properly in all particulars. Telephone, tele - graph ■ and street railway companies wen also piacul under the control of the Railway Commission. I That legislature also passed a pure food law, and an em - en' liability act. It enacted laws providing for a juvenile t to care properly for neglected children ; provided for high school privileges, for normal training in high schools unce for weak high school districts; prohibited t&gt;y bridge contractors; and provided a way to remove of - s for wilful neglect of duty and failure to enforce laws. All these laws are in full force and effect. Experience has </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 h, and they should be permitted to remain as they are i it is possible to improve them. Work of Attorney General. In the enforcement of laws during the last biennium, the attorney general and his department are entitled to prai - ability displayed and for their conscientious devotion to duty. One instance, worthy of more than passing notice, is the part the attorney general took in establishing the right of the state to enjoin corporations from violating state laws to the injury of the public. This doctrine is laid down in the supreme court &lt;&gt;n in the case of the State vs. Pacific Express Company, reported in the 115 Northwestern Report, Page 619. Primary Law. The primary law should not be repealed, but in some par - ticulars should be amended. Provisions should be made for a rotated ballot. The precinct committecnicn should be selected by the voters at the primaries instead of being appointed by the county candidates, as now provided. There should be a different provision than that now contained in the law re - garding platform conventions. Now, each county is entitled to one delegate. This is not representative. Another objec - tion is that the platform convention is not held until after the primaries. A party platform should be made so that the plat - form convention shall be held before the primaries or the mat - ter of platform making left to the candidates nominated by the respective parties. Constitutional Amendments I Our state has grown greatly since the adoption of the titution which on the whole is a most excellent one. D.ir - the last few years three important amendments have been iosed and adopted. One created the Railway Commission, enlarged the supreme court, and one provided for a larger </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 were excellent amendments and were needed long before adopted. The state now has the machinery by which it can :vely regulate and control the railway companies operat - ing within this state, as well as an able, honorable and just supreme court commensurate with present needs. I The salary of all the state officers is fixed by the constitu - . The business of the state has grown immensely since then, iries and wages in all occupations have increased inaterial- This state has the resources and should pay state officers ries commensurate with their services. A poor man with .mily cannot afford to hold state office. This is not right, erefore recommend that you propose an amendment chang - the section of the constitution in reference to the salary of e officers, and suggest that the amount to be paid each be for the legislatures to fix from time to time. Sterilization of Delinquents. I Those dependent upon the state have been increasing year r ear, and more particularly the insane and convicts. This matter for exceedingly serious consideration. Society is justified in adopting such policies, and in enforc - ing them against individuals, as will in the long-run tend to help elevate and perpetuate the human race. Careless and ill - &lt;d marriages have had a great deal to do in increasing the dependent classes and in producing untold misery. I therefore recommend for your earnest consideration a change in our marriage laws so that it will be impossible for any man or woman to marry until a health certificate from a physician licensed to practice in this state, has been presented. Such cer - tificate should contain a statement that their health is good and that they are capable of producing healthy offspring. Those who are a burden upon society should not be per - d to reproduce themselves. In order to prevent the con- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 -sity of passing a law providing for the sterilization of that class of people. Regulation of Liquor Traffic. In my opinion, the tin; one for advanced legislation t&lt;&lt; better regulate and control the liquor traffic. At the pres - ent time there is no political party which publicly will "stand on the Slocumb law. The demands of the hour call for ation to control and regulate this traffic in accordance with the present conditions and needs of the This qnes- not be permitted to drag along until legislation is ed that will satisfy only the extremist. In that the legislation will probably be that which a minority rather than a considerable majority approve. Experience in the en - nent of the liquor laws demonstrates that it is difficult to enforce these laws in any community where public - inent is against such action. I While I have been governor a great many applications ' come to me from convicts in the penitentiary for executive lency in some form or other. I have been impressed by fact that many who came before me did not appear to be linals. In most instances when I asked them the qm they happened to get into the penitentiary, the reply wu their downfall was caused through the use of intoxi - tig liquors or through associations formed in the environ - t of the saloon. BThe saloon as it now exists is indefensible. It break - . corrupts our politics, degrades our men, and fills our &gt;ns and asylums. KThis question must be met in a practical way. After care - onsideration 1 have come to the conclusion that the proper ? to do at this time is to pass a state-wide prohibition act. ing provision so that any municipality may suspend such </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 dispensed as may be provided by law. This will put the burden upon those who desire to make a profit ont of the saloon busi - neas, rather than upon the people of the state who desire the saloons abolished. I therefore recommend that you pass sucli an act, and that you also submit to the people of tli constitutional amendment embodying such provisions. The Anti-Treat Law. In the early part of my administration I was leiflMi by numerous petitioners to enforce the Anti-Treat Law. To [ replied that I stood ready to do all in my power to en - that law, but that under the present law nothing could be done unless those who had knowledge of its violation would themselves take the initiative in securing- the evidence, pre - senting it to the prosecuting attorney and standing behind the complaints. This particular section of the Slocumb law has become obsolete and is a dead letter. If it could b&gt;' enforced it would be one of the best possible measures to prevent intemperance that could be proposed. Therefore, I recommend that amend this particular section known as Section 31 of the Com - piled Statutes so that the authorities who grant the saloon li - cense will be compelled to revoke a license whenever any per - son drinks liquor in a saloon that he has not himself paid for. tA complete list of the pardons and commutations of sen - e given during my administration are herewith transmitted made a part of this message. This list contains the name number of the convict, the crime for which each was con - d the length of the sentence, the date of the pardon, or nutation and a brief statement of the reasons for executive ency. Respectfully submitted (Signed) GEORGE LAWSON SHELDON. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 I The following is a complete list of all the commutfltions pardons granted by me doling my administration, giving lame of the convict, the crime for which he was convicted, sentence, its date, and the date of the commutation or par - lier with the reason for such action. Unconditional Pardon. ■Jesse ('. Sillick. No. 41 1'."). Sentenced from Douglaa County. le, burglary. Term, thn . Sillick escaped from the penitentiary after serving ah tire sentence. Since that time he has led an honorable and useful life, serving three years and ten months in the army, wi 1 two honorable discharges showing honest and faithful service. He returned to Omaha, was married and settled down and became a useful citizen. lie voluntarily red himself and asked for a pardon, with the intention of returning to the penitentiary and serving out the balance of his time if executive clemency was denied. Having every :i to believe that Sillick had reformed in every way he was granted an unconditional pardon on the 28th day of De - cember, 1908. Conditional Pardons. ■ Paul Claycomb. No. 40f&gt;4. Sentenced from Douglas Coiui- Crime, robbery. Term, three years. I Conditional pardon granted upon recommendation of W. Slabaugh, prosecuting attorney, who presented petition conducted hearing. The minimum sentence imposed by trial judge states that he would have imposed a lighter ence if possible, under the law, application endorsed by y of the leading citizens of Douglas County. Young man lty-two years of age, his first offense. Prison record exem - y. Pardon granted upon the condition that he seek im - iate employment, abstain from the use of intoxicating </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 granted on December 27, 1907. Raymond Kennard, No. 4965. Sentenced from Madison ty. Crime, uttering forged check. Term, 1 year. nditional pardon granted on the recommendation of Wm. V. Allen, former United States Senator, Anson A. Welch, trial judge and Jack Koenigsten, prosecuting attorney. Nu - merous petitions signed by hundreds of men of the highest type of citizens in the community of the crime were also pre - sented. The prison physician strongly urged executive clem - ency on the ground of typhoid fever. He was thoroughly re - pentant, prison record good. Granted a conditional pardon, September 25, 1908. K William A. Cate. No. 4963. Sentenced from Nuckolls lty. Crime, cutting with intent to wound. Term, 1 year, nth*. Cate was convicted after two jury trials in Nuckolls coun - ty. Evidence indicated assault and battery more than that of felony, of which he was convicted. Executive clemency recom - mended by several hundred good citizens of Nuckolls county, where crime was committed and from other parts of the state. Had served over half of his sentence, and the spirit of the criminal law had been fulfilled. His prison record was good and pardon recommended by attorney general and warden A. D. Beemer. That he might return to his wife and family and again enter into the practice of his profession, a pardon was granted upon the express condition that he should pay all the costs incurred by reason of the prosecution. Conditional pardon was granted December 31, 1908. Arthur Leedom, No. 5017. Sentenced from Boone county. ie, statutory rape. Term, 6 years. I Petition for executive clemency recommended by many linent citizens of Boone county, where the conviction was After a full consideration of all phases of the case that </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 51229 HI TTPIT pFCT lllliT it W&gt;» riot an unconditional pardon, but with the nnmii penitence of the applicant, thv needa oF his family, thv interest of society in his two hoys, it appeared that the v committed to society ha&lt;l bevn fully expiated. Therefor on the riunwing made, anil that he miirht have an opportnnity to return to his wife and family, dependents upon hi - for maintenance, a conditional and restricted pardoa granted on the 1st day &lt;&gt;f January, 19 ■ George Von Ilaller. No. 4438. Donglaa County. Crime, wur - ■eeaod degree. Sentence 12 Von Ilaller was convicted of the crime of murder in •: free, on the 28th day of April. 1903, in the district ••ourt of Douglas county, and sentenced to twelve years in the penitentiary. This man does not claim to be innocent, but he claim that he knows nothing about the crime. There ft] affidavits offered to the effect that his coni|». committed the crime. Since he has been confined in the itentiary his conduct has been good. The doubt as to just what Von Ilaller played in the crime, and believing that he has reformed, and therefore will conduct himself as beeoi ! member of society. I have concluded that it will h&gt; to L'ive him an opportunity and have therefore granted him a Conditional pardon, keeping him under the custody of the nor. He will not be restored to his citizenship right until the expiration of his sentence. ■ James Gallagher. Xo. 46!&gt;7. Sentenced from Donglai Crime, grand larcency. Term. 3 years. A young man nineteen years of age at the time of his virtion, and prior to that time had, so far as known, led an honorable and upright life. Record discloses he was simply an accessory, and that the theft was planned by an okta experienced man. The district judge who pronounced . recommended a pardon and says that Gallagher </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 prosecuting attorney also joined iu the recommendation. Tlu - ■heriff of Douglas county appeared in i»erson and testified ir» behalf of the defendant and urged that the prayer be grtmtmL The attorney general recommended executive clemency ou the ground that the sentence was txetamvt. Therefor, his sen - was commuted from three years to one year, two mouth* and eighteen days on the 31st day of August, 1907. ■John Loar, No. 4428. Sentenced from Garfield county le, rape. Term, 4 years. B Application recommended by prosecuting attorney anc! mber of the members of the jury, also Warden A. D. Beeni- er. Having served the greater portion of his sentence, his prison record good, and an aged mother dependent upon his x'liteix-e was commuted from 4 to 3 years, 2 months. on January 13, 1908. ■ Albert Atkinson, No. 455L Sentenced from Douglas coun- C'rinie, robbery. Term, 3 years. Application recommended by district judge, Hon. (ieo. A. and Prosecuting Attorney A. EL Murdock. The judge stated that in his opinion the sentence was excessive, and the prosecuting attorney stated that he believed young Atkin - son had been sufficiently punished, being a young man and did not fully realize the seriousness of the crime. The attar - general concurred in this opinion. He received condi - tional commutation providing that he should avoid evil asso - ciates, abstain from intoxicating liquors and enter upon hon - orable employment on the 25th day of January, 1908. ■ Harry Strickland, No. 4589. Sentenced from Cherry eoun- Crime, robbery from person. Term, 3 years. Granted a commutation conditioned that he enter at once honorable pursuit of labor, abstain from evil associates and restricted to remain within the state. Commutation rec- </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 Valentine, Nebraska, where the crime was committed. He is a young man. prison record was exemplary, reformation had ompliahed sufficient to deter him from the comm of crime, and for the further reason thai he had 1 pun - ishment commensurate with his off&lt; -i 'ommnted from three years to two yean, one month and 27 days on Jan - uary 29, 19 Thomas IfeQuiggan, No. 4O7'2. Sentenced from Dou_ eounty. Crime, murder in the second degree. Term, ten j Application for executive clemency recommended by Ju 'stelle. who appeared in person at the hearing and ,tive clemency; also by Jaa P. Engiiah, prosecuting at - torney. Attorney General W. T. Thompson and Warden I er. The court, prosecuting attorney and attoi of the opinion that the evidence did not warrant convicti the crime of murder. The law vindicated, society pro' and for the further reason that he had been sufficiently pun - itenee was commuted from ten -nary 11. 1908. John B. Martin. No. 44!)7. Sentenced from Lancaster county. Crime, robbery. Term. 5 years. Application recommended by County Atty. F. M. Tyrrell. Kx-County Attorney J. A. Caldwell. Trial Jud&lt;re Lincoln A Frost. Warden A. I). Beemer and other prominent citizen- Lincoln, where the crime was committed. Was a model p r, both in the county jail and the penitentiary. Sent' commuted from 5 years to 3 years, 3 months and 23 days on February 14, 1908. 1 Henry J. Smith, Xo. 4895. Sentenced from Cedar county, le forgery. Term, one year. Sentence commuted on the recommendation of attorney general and .a great many citizens of Randolph, Nebraska, </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 tion raised as to his sanity at the time he committed the crime. Conditions indica mplete reformation and that he had been sufficiently punished. Wife and family dependent upon him for support. Sentence commuted from 1 year to 5 months and 3 days on April 1, 1908. ■Frank Wood&gt; nteneed from Dawes county. le, assault and robbery. Term, 12 years. (Application for executive clemency recommended by Hon. a G. Fisher. E. N. Satiety, prosecuting attorney, and Hon. EL Westover, trial judge: All of the county officials of es county. Also by every member of the jury that c&lt;&gt;n - (d. He was a model prisoner. The ends of justice had been mplished, as he had been punished sufficiently. Sentence nuted from 12 years to 5 years on April 25, 1908. ■ Bert Chandler, No. 4629. Sentenced from Douglas coun- Crime, robbery. Term, 3 years. Sentence commuted upon the recommendation of Judge Sutton, trial judge. F. W. Fitch who prosecuted the case joins in the recommendation and urgently requests executive clemency. Attorney general joins in the recommendation. Chandler is a young man,— his first offense, and the evidence disclosed that he was counselled and advised by older and ex - perienced men, and primarily was not responsible for the offense. Sentence commuted from 3 years to 2 years, 6 months and 16 days, on April 27, 1908. K. Coursey Richards, No. 3916. Sentenced from Lancas - unty. Crime, rape. Term, 12 years. I Sentence commuted based upon the sworn affidavits of ilaining witness. The testimony of physicians tending to icate and establish innocence. He is an old man ; served le war of the Rebellion; was paroled to the Soldiers' and &gt;rs home at Milford by Governor Mickey. His conduct </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 ! conclusively that if jruilty In ,1 sunV. &lt; onimutation granted that he mighi spend his declining ■with his family in Pennsylvania. Sentence commuted fro 10 months on June !■"&gt;. 1 Logmn Lambert, No. 4948. Sentenced from Dakota Crime, assault to do bodily injury. Sentence, 1 year. I Application recommended by trial judge and att. I'sentinjr the prosecution. Petition signed by many oil akota and Thurston counties. Trial court of the opinion sentence was excessive. A wife and family in destitute nnstances. Record disclosed he had lived an honest and &gt;rahle life, was industrious and law abiding prior to the n of the crime. Sentence commuted from on ntha on July 22, 1 James J. Reed, No. 4620. Sentenced from Douglas County. Crime, murder in the firs) degree. Term. life. The trial judge, Hon. C,eo. A. Day. of Omaha. app D and recommended executive clemency. The county at - torney, »Ias. I\ English, joined in the recommendation. Attor - •al Thompson also recommended clemency. The court and the attorneys representing the prosecution were of the opinion that the evidence did not justify a conviction for the «-riine of murder, hut the verdict should properly haw murder in the second degree or perhaps man slaughter, tot the n ated Acting GoYeraor M. \l. Hopewell commuted sentence for life to ten years from the twenty-first day of De - cember, 1 -I. B. Adkins. No. 4fiof). Sentenced from Douglas county Crime, rape. Term. ~&gt; \ • K Petitioner a man of nearly 70 years of age. Served :{ j •nths in the Civil War. Record tends to vindicate the ap - mt on account of physical condition. His personal de- Mr and frankness at the trial, together with prison and </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 rds challenges consideration, and inasmuch as h« had already served a considerable portion of his term recom - id executive clemency. Sentence commuted from 5 years year*, 3 months and IS days on December 29, 190B. IM. R. Kairn, No. 4 i from Gage county le, obtaining money under false pretenses. Term, 2 year Application for executive clemency recommended by ; • frauded. The attorneys for the prosecution appeared in person at the hearing and ui •_ ■mency. A nuni - f the jurors, the county attorney, wkfl filed the informa - joined in the application for pardon. The trial judge, ut hesitation recommended the same. Attorney gOMral mends unconditional pardon. Had already served a lone: n addition to the tine served in the penitentiary and had been sufficiently punished. K.iirn was not a &lt;1 criminal, and was not primarily responsible for the mission of the crime. Sentence commuted from 2 years, 6 the, to 1 year, 1 month and 20 days on January 1, 1909. ■Louie J. Hossmau, No. 4451. Sentenced from Douglas 1 rime, burglary. Term, 4 years. Applicant was convicted of the crime of burglary and ry and received 4 years sentence on each count. He had d the full sentence for the first offense and a portion of the sentence of the second. The ends of justice had been well rred. Prison record good, young man of limited exper- I'pon recommendation of prosecuting attorney and dep - • uuty attorney, together with affidavits from members of the jury and approved by the attorney general, second sen - commuted from 4 years to 7 months and six days, on January 1, 1909. ■ James Sullivan, No. 4291. Sentenced from Cheyenne coun- C'riine, murder in the 2nd degree. Term, life. Applicant plead guilty to the charge of murder and was </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 sentenced to imprisonment for life in the penitentiary. Two other men were implicated in the crime. At the time of the ar - rest there was considerable excitement among the citizen some apprehension that they would be dealt with summarily. Neville, one of the defendants, claims he had the promise from the prosecution of executive clemency. By affidavit and i testimony he asserted that Sullivan did not participate in the commission of the crime. His innocence was not thoroughly established, but upon the showing made and the recommenda - tions submitted, the petitioner was deemed deserving and a fit subject for executive clemency. His prison record was above reproach. Sentence commuted from life to 10 years actual time, on January 1, 1909. KChas. Brown, No. 3818. Sentenced from Sarpy county. le, rape. Term, 15 years. -ipplicant had served over ten years of his sentence, al - lowing good time. Conduct in penitentiary had been exem - plary. Prison physician recommended executive clemency on account of ill health. Upon showing made at the hearing and recommendation of attorney general, sentence was com - muted from 15 years to 10 years, 3 months and 4 days on Janu- Frank Thomas, No. 4620. Sentenced from Douglas county. Crime, forgery. Term, 5 years. Was a model prisoner in penitentiary and received parole August 1, 1908. No known previous criminal record. Appli - cation for commutation of sentence recommended by trial judge, prosecuting attorney, the arresting officers and many citizens of Omaha by petition, where crime was committed, to - gether with the further fact that the amount involved was very nominal and the sentence excessive. Sentence commuted from 5 years to 3 years, 6 months on January 1, 1909. ■John McCormick, No. 4033. Sentenced from Otoe County, le, murder in the second degree. Term, 19 years. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 ration was made. Having starved 1 year for the crime which he committed, he was returned to Otoe County and sen - 1 to 19 years, making in all a 20-year sentence. During that time he had by skill and industry performed valuable and &gt;rious services to the State of Nebraska as a stone mason, mic and plasterer. The State Board of Public Lands and Buildings, to reward him for the splendid services rendered, recommended executive clemency. A great many prominent is of Nebraska City joined in the recommendation. He had been a model prisoner and has determined to lead an hon - orable and upright life hereafter. His sentence was commuted a 19 years to 9 years, on January 4. 1909. ■Michael Ford, No. 4613. Sentenced from Douglas County, le, assault with intent to rob. Term, 7 years, 6 months. Applicant had served a mimimum sentence and was incar - cerated and had been on parole over 8 months. The County ney of Douglas County, the District Judge before whom Ford was tried, and a large number of respectable citizens of ias County joined in the application for pardon. Hia i-onduet has been good, both in the Penitentiary and during the time he was out on parole. He had reformed and was disposed to lead a law abiding and industrious life. Sentence com - ] from 7 years. 6 months to 5 years, 7 months on January Jail Commutations August Schroeder, (Book No 519). Sentenced from Lan - r County. Crime, larceny. Term, 6 months. Application recommended by Judge Lincoln Frost, Trial Judge, and Frank M. Tyrrell, Prosecuting Attorney, and E. R. Mathews. whose store was burglarized. Schroeder is a young man and this was his first offense. Conditional pardon granted that he should accompany his father to his own home, there enter into honorable employment, avoid evil associations, obey </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 fur retaining such ■ youth, because of associations with Kl. hardened and habitual law breakers. Conditional pardon nted December 21. 1907. The following is ■ complete list of all the paroles granted during the biennium of I'M &gt;7-8 showing the name, number and date of paroles, indicating those whose term has expired and still running on parole, not yet disehi Paroled Convicts Not Discharged ». McMUlan Rnpert . . . 4120 April 20.1007 4681 Sept. 17. 1007 • I Keeler 42L'f» Dee. 18.1007 KTetteringrton Ford . 4742 Jan. 15,1908 4613 April 14.1008 John Font 4550 \pril 2."). 1906 I Owen 47&lt;2 April 2."). 1906 ■ ii Penton 3828 May 12. 1908 John Font 1 'well . . ton Denton Prank Nooman Ziemers . Frank Donner Frank Thomas Harry 0. Brown Walt DeGarmo TI Ishida Prank Nonman 4649 June 16. 1906 Jack Ziomers 4421 Julr 30. 1906 4421 Julr 30. 1008 Frank Donner 4596 July 31. 1908 4596 July 31.1008 Frank Thomas 4620 Lug. 7, 1908 Brown 4685 Sept. 21, 1908 DeOumo 1676 Oet 12. 1908 Aug. 7,1908 Sept. 21,1908 4(»7n Oct. 12,1008 II l^hida 47H") Dec. 3,1908 47o.-. Dec. 3,1908 Eiond Stone E. Walls.. E. Foster. Bode Kiiymond Stone 4527 Dec. 15, 1908 B. Walls 472.") Dec. 16, 1908 4527 Dec. 15,1908 472.") Dec. 16,1908 Sam E. Foster -1717 Dee. 29, 1908 4717 Dec. 29,1908 E. O. Bode 4897 Dec. 31, 1908 Dec. 31,1908 Harry Cummings 4714 Jan. 2, 1909 By Cummin ?s iam Crawford 4714 Jan. 2,1909 "William Crawford 4743 Jan. 7, 1909 Paroled Convicts Discharged. m 4599 April 3,1907 Williams 4563 June 28, 1907 Wilson 4432 Inly 1, 1907 474.1 Jan. 7, 1909 Paroled Convicts Discharged. April 3,1907 June 28,1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Alex Burrell 4i S 4 Dec. 24, 1907 Ward Quigley 4658 Jan. 7, 1908 James Nichols 4740 Jan. 18, 1908 Chas. Owens 4371 Jan. 27, 1908 W. Slatin 4436 Feb. 24, 1908 8. Irwin 4208 Feb. 26, 1908 ChM. Fair 4708 Mar. 7, 1908 K. Yeck 4470 Mar. 11, 1098 Frickey 4557 April 10, 1908 Bert Valentine 4660 April 14, 1908 q Sellers 4919 April 15, 1908 Richard Sindt 4767 April 30, 1908 nbeck 4340 June 13, 1908 Wm. C. Beames 4838 July 22, 1908 A. Rabe 4792 Aug. 10, 1908 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>