<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00059.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00059.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Report of the Department of Public Welfare Nebraska for the Biennium Closing June 30, 1926</title>
               <date value="1926">1926</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
         
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">REPORT OF THE Department of Public Welfare NEBRASKA FOR THE BIENNIUM CLOSING JUNE 30, 1926 LINCOLN FROST, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002">rthe Honorable Adam McMullen, Governor, State of Nebraska. I hereby transmit for your consideration a report of the activities of the Department of Public Welfare for the recent biennium. Some changes in the laws relating to those activities are suggested. Respectfully submitted. LINCOLN FROST, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 3 INDEX Appropriations 7 Beet Fields, Child Labor in 21 Child Hygiene, Division of 34, 68 Child Welfare, Bureau of 18, 43 Defective Children „ __48 Maternity Homes and Lying-in Hospitals 51 Mentally Defective 50 Some Typical Cases 45 Community Nurses 20 Custodial Farm 36 Department of Public Welfare, General Powers 35 Special Powers 35 Epidemiology, Division of 31, 53 Examinations 10, 41 Examining Boards, Bureau of 9, 38 Examinations 10, 41 Examining Boards 11 Embalming Apprenticeship __ 40 Financial Statement 13, 15 Law Enforcement 10 Reciprocity 41 Revocation of Licenses 9, 42 Embalming Apprenticeship 40 General Statement 8 Health, Bureau of 30, 53 Correspondence and Other Activities 54 Places Visited 54 Publications Prepared 55 Jails, Inspection of 36 Juvenile Court 45 Juvenile Court Law 28 Laboratories, Division of 32, 58 Law Enforcement 10 Letter of Transmittal 1 Llcensure Act ..13 Maternity Homes and Lying-in Hospitals 51 Mothers' Pensions 23 Questionnaire _ 25 Nursing 12 Accredited Training Schools of 39 Probation Officers 20 Reciprocity 41 Revocation of Licenses 9, 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 REPORT OP THE Roster .. . . „ . .,....■....„ .... ......... 5 Sanitary Engineering, Division of 34, 71 Secretary's Resume, Commencing 9 Venereal Diseases, Division of 31, 56 Vital Statistics, Division of _ „ 32, 61 Improvements Made 62 Voluntary Committees 20 INDEX OF TABLES Page Births and Deaths by counties for 1923 and 1925 65, 66, 67 Causes of Death _ 64, 65 Child Placing Agencies Licensed 44 Child Welfare, Bureau of — Afflicted Children Reported 48, 49, 50 Child Placing Agencies Licensed 44 Number Children Placed _ 47 Disposition of Children Placed _ 47 Contagious Diseases Reported 53, 54 Examining Board, Bureau of — Bureau Fund, Source and Amount -.15 Receipts and Expenditures 39 Licenses Granted 41 Licenses Revoked .........._....................... ..........42 Health, Bureau of — Contagious Diseases Reported 53, 54 Correspondence and Other Activities _ 54, 55 Places Visited for Quarantine, etc 54 Publications Prepared „ 5 5 Juvenile Courts — Classification of Activities 44, 45 Laboratories, Division of — Examinations 1920 to 1926, Inc 59 Detailed Examinations for 1925 and 1926 59, 60 Mothers' Pension Questionnaire, Summary of 25, 26, 27, 28 Nursing, Accredited Schools of 40 Number and Causes of Deaths due to Childbirth 63, 64 Sanitary Engineering, Division of 71 Plans approved for water and sewer systems 72 Vital Statistics, Division of — Activities 63 Births and Deaths by Counties for 1923 and 1925 65, 66, 67 Causes of Death 64, 65 Number and Causes of Deaths due to Childbirth 63, 64 Venereal Diseases, Division of 56 Statistical Summary .................. 57 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 5 N.» ROSTER DEPARTMENT SECRETARY Lincoln Frost BUREAU OF HEALTH: Chief W. H. Wilson, M. D. Director Division Venereal Disease.—P. H. Bartholomew, M. D. Director Division Vital Statistics Miss Hattie M. Summers Director Division Child Hygiene Miss Louise M. Murphy, R. Director Division Laboratories L. O. Vose, M. Sc* Succeeded Mrs. C. H. England July 1, 1925. Succeeded Miss Lila B. Love January 1, 1926. BUREAU OF CHILD WELFARE: EXAMINING BOARD MEMBERS f Dr. H. F. Gartner, Lincoln \ Dr. F. F. Funder,* Omaha | Dr. F. E. Silvers, Omaha | Dr. C. F. Schmidtmann, Omaha Chiropody. f Dr. S. L. Ashworth, Lincoln •] Dr. J. P. Laub,* Chapman Dr. F. H. Berhenke, Fremont Dr. L. N. Carpenter, Omaha / Chiropractic. fDr. Ferdinand Griess, Sutton Dr. M. O. Fra8er, Lincoln Dr. George Boehler, Omaha Dr. E. W. Fellers, Beatrice Dr. W. A. Cox, Omaha Dentistry.. [Mr. W. M. Hill, Hebron I Mr. E. L. Troyer,* Lincoln { Mr. W. H. Dorrance, Omaha | Mr. E. C. Carstensen, Curtis I Mr. E. R. Haggard, Blair Embalming. (Resigned in 1925) Chief Mrs. Emily P. Hornbei lerge rge IUREAU OP EXAMINING BOARDS: Director Mrs. Clark Perkins </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 REPORT OF THE | Dr. H. J. Lehnhoff, Lincoln Medicine &amp; Surgery -I [ Dr. J. E. Spatz, Fairfield Miss Bertha A. Bryant,* 1 Grand Island Miss Jennie Higgins,* Li Miss Charlotte Burgess, i Bertha A. Bryant,* Grand Island Jennie Higgins,* Lincoln Miss Charlotte Burgess, Omaha Miss Edith Salin, Omaha Sister M. Consolata, Lincoln Nursing. Mr. G. S. Dunlap, Lincoln Mr. Ray C. Kingsley, Omaha Optometry. [ Mr. M. L. Jones, Fairfield fDr. Charles Hartner,** Madison | Dr. E. M. Cramb,* Lincoln •! Dr. J. T. Young, Fremont Osteopathy. Dr. R. H. Cowger, Hastings Dr. Ezra M. Ingham, Wymore fMr. George Strelow,** Long Pine | Mr. William Clayton,* Grand Island ■I Mr. C. A. McVicker, Gothenburg I Mr. Robert Hardt, Hastings i Mr. W. B. Walter, Beatrice Pharmacy [Dr. Floyd Perrin,** Lincoln I Dr. H. L. Feistner,* Auburn ■! Dr. T. P. Rose, York I Dr. P. L. Cady, Arlington [ Dr. Carl J. Norden, Lincoln Veterinary Medicine &amp; Surgery 'Indicates term expired * 'Indicates term expired November November 30, 1926. 30, 1925. DIVISION OF ATHLETICS: Director Mr. John Kilmartin STATE RACING COMMISSION: Secretary Mr. N. J. Ronin Dr. E. T. McGuire, Mead </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 7 APPROPRIATIONS Departmental Salary $10,000.00 Total $10,000.00 Bureau of Health Salaries 42,000.00 Maintenance 22,800.00 Total 64,800.00 To these funds available for the Bureau of Health should be added the money received by the Division of Vital Statistics for transcripts furnished Washington which amounts to approximately $1,200.00 per year; also the money received by the Division of Child Hygiene under the provision of the Sheppard-Towner Act. Under the 1925 fund, we received $11,915.00 from the federal government Bureau of Child Welfare: Salaries $ 9,200.00 Maintenance 5,500.00 Total 14,700.00 Grand Total $89,500.00 Bureau of Examining Boards: Fees to cover all expenditures. Division of Athletics: Fees only. State Racing Commission: Fees only. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 REPORT OF THE GENERAL STATEMENT The official year closed on the 30th of June. The reports ot some of the Divisions close the biennium on June 30th, 1926. Others hare given their figures to include a large part of 1926. Perhaps each of the reports will indicate the date to which its statistics re - late. The latest published report of this Department is for the biennium ending June 30, 1922. Very likely the former head sub - mitted a biennial report to the Governor for the biennium ending June 30, 1924 but if he did we find no copy of it in the departmental records. It 1b certain that no report for that time was published. The activities of the Department are covered by three Bureaus, — Health, Child Welfare, and Examining Boards. The Bureau of Ath - letics is also placed by law with this Department. Its director has submitted a biennial report. As he doubtless concurrently submitted that report to you, it is unnecessary to refer to it further herein. The State Racing Commission is required by law to report to this Department. However, when that report is filed its relations with the Department apparently are closed until the date for another filing comes around. The Commission has submitted its report which is available to all who care to examine it. In this report the Secretary of the Department has reviewed its activities and has made some recommendations as to its future needs. He has also suggested some changes in the laws relating to those activities. This is followed by more detailed statements relating to the different Bureaus and Divisions. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 9 A Resume of the Activities of The Department of Public Welfare FOR THE BIENMUM ENDING JUNE 30, 1926 Bureau of Examining Boards: This Bureau has a director as its chief executive officer. It has supervision of the giving of examina - tions and the licensing of those who successfully pass in ten different professions, i. e., Chiropody, Chiropractic, Dentistry, Embalming, Medicine and Surgery, Nursing, Optometry, Osteopathy, Pharmacy and Veterinary Medicine and Surgery. The efforts of the Department have been directed along the line of maintaining the standards established for these by law. No attempt has been made to raise those standards beyond that point, except where the official leaders gave a ready approval. We have taken the position that the several professions must themselves assist in bring - ing their members fully up to those standards and to a proper under - standing of the ethics of their several professions. We appreciate that it is impossible to advance a profession further than its most progressive members. However, it is a misnomer to denominate any group as members of a profession unless a standard of ethics is main - tained which is above mere subserviency to practices which put dollars into the pockets of its members. REVOCATION OP LICENSE The practice acts provide a penalty for non-payment of annual registration fees in the several professions. During the biennium 172 licenses in Pharmacy, 63 in Dentistry and 91 in Embalming, or a total of 326 licenses, were revoked for non-payment of annual registra - tion fees. The penalties imposed by these practice acts for non-payment of the annual registration fee vary, and some seem unnecessarily severe. Where it appeared that the failure to pay was due to an oversight the Department, with the approval of the Examining Board, has rein - stated the licensee upon the payment of back fees. However, the forfeiture provision in connection with one profession is so definite in its terms that it is doubtful if the Department has power to rein - state, except upon a compliance with the conditions named in the statute. This is a point on which the law should be made uniform for all professions. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 REPORT OF THE LAW ENFORCEMENT If the members of a profession deal honorably with the public and especially with their patients, then the public owes to that pro - fession and its members protection against quacks who illegally under - take to trespass upon their field. In line with this a Field Agent was appointed November 1, 1925, to run down those who are attempt - ing to practice any of these professions without a legal right so to do. This investigator, because of the financial situation which will be discussed in greater detail later, has given his attention more especially to certain of these professions. During the first year of his service he prosecuted eighty-four cases and in each of these cases so prosecuted he secured a conviction. In no single case filed by this investigator was there a failure to secure the fining of the defendant. This simply means that the investigator knew when a law was being violated and what evidence was necessary to secure a conviction. He filed no complaints except where there had been a violation of law and he had the evidence to prove such violation. The professions and the number of convictions relating thereto are as follows: EXAMINATIONS During the biennium ending June 30, 1926, the Bureau issued 1175 licenses. Of this number 1,013 were accepted after examina - tion and 162 through reciprocity. In each one of these cases an application was filed which was studied by the Director of the Bureau. Frequently such study showed that the information given was in - complete and much correspondence followed to secure the necessary facts. Often an educational equivalent was asked. This meant that the things comprising that equivalent must be evaluated. In these studies by the Director many applications have been re - jected and so do not appear in the number licensed. It would seem that an equivalent for a high school training or any part thereof was unnecessary today when a high school education is readily accessible to every child. It would be the recommendation of the Department that the equivalent for a high school education or two years of high school be dropped in those professions where it is still allowed. One who is not willing to secure the required high 'harmacy lentistry Ihiropractic ledicine &amp; Surgery Embalming : 'otal </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 11 school training should not presume to become a member of any of the professions. There has been some complaint on the part of the Examining Boards that the Secretary of the Department has adhered too closely to a technical construction of the law in passing upon applications. This has been especially true in cases of reciprocity. Under most of the practice acts we can accept by reciprocity only from states having standards equal to those of Nebraska. When the present Secretary assumed charge it had been customary to accept applicants by re- Cprocity who had the individual qualifications required to take an Lamination, even though the state standards were not equal to those of Nebraska. It was necessarily held that such a course was illegal and, in a written opinion, the Attorney General's office approved of that ruling. It would look as if interested parties should have been satisfied but the fact is that one Board especially has felt that more "common sense" and less law should be applied. It might be well to relax by changing the law and give more consideration to individual qualifications of applicants; but as long as the law stands as it is the individual qualifications cannot be considered in passing upon reciprocity. In the examinations supervised by the Bureau the relations be - tween it and the different Examining Boards vary somewhat. How - ever, in general the Bureau passes upon the applications and de - termines who can take such examinations and assists in the arrange - ments for, and in the handling of them. The members of the Board of Examiners prepare the questions for the examination. Usually one or more members of the Board assist at the examination. At its close the answer papers, are turned over for grading to the member of the Examining Board who has charge of the particular subject. It is- a source of great annoyance to the Bureau and to the ap - plicants that these papers are frequently retained an undue length of time by a few members of the Examining Boards. The members of these Boards are all active in their several professions, but when one accepts an official position he should perform with reasonable promptness the duties that he assumes. It might be well if the law required these papers to be returned, properly graded, within a rea - sonable time, — say within ten days. After the grades are received back from the Board the Bureau prepares the licenses which are then signed by the members of the Board, the Secretary of the Department, and the Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF THE NURSING Recent examinations in nursing show that there has been too great a percentage of failures. It is possible that this is because the P examinations are too difficult; but an investigation does not indicate that this is the case. It appears more probable that the instruction is not as good as it should be. There may be some truth in a com - plaint from a member of the staff of one of the hospitals that a number of the student nurses accepted by the hospital were incapable of satisfactorily taking a training course. However, the main reason for these failures is apparently inefficient leadership among the teaching force. Even where the superintendent of a training school is fully competent to conduct it, still she may be given too many other duties to perform. The hospitals should appreciate that there is an obliga- tion on them to pToperly train these girls who are giving them much service. The Secretary very much wishes that there were sufficient funds available to put in the field an Educational Director for these train- schools. That director should be a person who not only knows technical phases of nursing but also has demonstrated correct tiing methods. Some additional funds could be secured by raising examination fee from five to ten dollars. Then the hospital Id be willing to pay a reasonable amount to cover the per diem expenses of such a director for the time she gives to its train- ing school. If the money could be secured to pay a director the work of the training schools could doubtless be much improved without increasing the faculty. The results to be gained would amply re- state for making a direct appropriation to pay for such that too much time is required for a nurse to secure registration and that as a result she must charge too much for her es. The law requires that an applicant for the State Board have completed two years of high school and three years in an accredited training school for nurses. It also requires that she be twenty-one years of age. Any girl of ordinary ability should be able to complete a full four year high school course before she is eighteen years of age. This would leave her three years for her pro- fessional training and it would seem that the completion of two years of a high school course is little enough. That much general education is needed if a nurse is to properly comprehend the theoretical train - ing required of her. Then again, no one should presume to take up life work under twenty-one years of age. It is inadvisable to er the requirements, nor are they so exacting and prolonged as to justify a registered nurse making excessive charges for her services. She should be entitled to an adequate, a living wage; but if she </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 13 charges more than conditions warrant then others will be led to enter training, while there is always the menace of the practical nurse who is frequently willing to work for less. In any event, the nurse should not be made to bear all the blame for the high cost of being sick. FINANCIAL STATEMENT The Director's report shows that the receipts for the biennium were $34,112.00 while the expenditures were $27,779.72, leaving a surplus for the biennium of $6,332.28. The receipts come from fees paid for examinations, for reciprocity, for certificates to secure reciprocity in another state, apprenticeships and from annual regis - tration. It should be borne in mind that the state does not contri - bute anything toward the support of the Bureau of Examining Boards. That should be modified as the Secretary who gives a portion of his time to that Bureau is paid by the state. In general, the funds received from examination go to pay the expenses and per diem of the several Examining Boards; also any other expenses which relate particularly to the Board from which such fees are received. The fees for certificates, for annual registra - tion, for apprenticeships, and for reciprocity go into a Bureau Fund out of which is paid the salaries and expenses of the help in that Bureau; also for needed equipment and supplies. Formerly the funds received from the different examinations were mingled; now they are kept in separate accounts. The funds that are used for paying the help and maintenance of the Bureau are kept in. what is called the Bureau Fund. The Bureau is the financial agent for the entire Department. The Division of Vital Statistics of the Bureau of Health receives money regularly from the federal government for transcripts made of birth and death certificates. This is handled in the Bureau of Examining Boards as are also funds received from the licensing of maternity homes, though the work in this connection is handled by the Child Welfare Bureau. A GENERAL LICENSURE ACT There are ten separate practice acts relating to the professions whose licensing is handled by the Bureau. A uniform licensure act covering all of these would simplify the work. Now the procedure outlined in one of the ten laws must be studied before determining how to proceed in any given case. Very likely the next application to come before the Director relates to a different profession and an - other law must be studied. There seems to be no good reason why the procedure in connection with licensing should not be uniform ?s </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REPORT OF THE to these ten professions. There could be a uniform set of rules cover - ing examinations, issuing of reciprocal licenses, revocation and for - feiture of licenses and law enforcement. There could also be separate sections covering the things which relate exclusively to a particular profession. Iowa has such a uniform practice act relating to nine of the professions handled by this Bureau, Veterinary Medicine being the only one not included. The Iowa law could well be considered in drafting a law for Nebraska. Such a general law need not change the relations now existing between the Department of Public Welfare or its Bureau of Examining Boards and the several Boards, excep where some Board possesses different powers than do the general run. In such a case the uniformity rule would require that the one be brought into line. The powers and duties of the Department towards these different professions is very much the same, while the work of the different Examining Boards is almost identical. However, where any given Board has unusual powers, then those should be made to conform with the powers held by the majority. The purpose of such an act, therefore, should not be to add to or to take away from the powers of the Department except where it is necessary to bring about uniformity. A law following this plan would not take from the Examining Board any of its legitimate functions in connection with the examina - tion. No agency is contemplated which could properly take over the work of preparing the questions and reading and grading the answer papers. The routine work of evaluating the qualifications of an ap - plicant as set forth in his application and from other evidence be - longs to the Department, as does also keeping records and making rules relating to examination as well as rules to supplement the statutory provisions. No one who has examined the old records kept by the separate Boards before the Department was organized would think of recommending a return to those methods. Little information can be secured from those records for an inquiring licensee. A law based on this uniformity plan would require an annual registration fee from all professions. As it is now such a fee is paid by six, i. e., Chiropractic, Dentistry, Embalming, Nursing, Optometry, and Pharmacy while the other four, — Chiropody, Medicine and Sur - gery, Osteopathy and Veterinary Medicine do not pay such fees. The annual registration fees furnish the main support of the Bureau of Examining Boards. As already indicated, the state is not taxed for that support. Not only is there a good deal of feeling over the fact that the Bureau is supported almost entirely by the funds contributed by the six professions but there is a spirit of resentment when any of the funds are used for the special benefit, — as in investigations and prosecutions — of any of the four that do not contribute. Heed, must </seg>
            <seg id="p015">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 15 - be paid to this resentment because it is grounded upon lack of fair treatment. An official audit was made of the books of the Bureau of Examin - ing Boards for the year ending April 30, 1926, by the State Account - ant connected with the Auditor's office. This report showed that fo.  - the year there was paid into the Bureau Fund by the ten professions $9,362.00. This same audit shows that the annual registration fees paid in by the six professions amounted to $7,455.00. This would leave but $1,907 contributed by all the professions out of endorse - ments, reciprocal registration, apprenticeship fees and certified copies. The following table gives the basis for these figures: Table showing source and amount of Bureau Fund. From From Profession Total Annual Other Receipts Registration Sources * Professions so designated have no annual registration fee, con - sequently it is impossible to give the number actively engaged in them in Nebraska. Any fair-minded man must see that the ten professions should contribute their proportionate part toward the support of the Bureau or none of them should contribute anything. In that event it would be up to the State, if the work of the Bureau is to be continued, to make a direct appropriation. In support of this, the argument is that the work of law enforcement is in the interest of the people, as for example preventing quacks from preying upon them, and should be financed by the state itself. The argument has a strong appeal but with the counter economy cry it is doubtful if the Legislature can be persuaded to make an appropriation of at least $15,000 per year, the amount necessary to maintain the Bureau. An appropriation made to care for the needs of one profession only would but accentuate the feeling of resentment now existing. Chiropodists* $ 2.00 $ 2.00 280 Chiropractors 695.00 130 Dentists 1,567.00 778 Embalmers 1,685.00 | 574.00 1,278.00 1,576.00 121.00 289.00 109.00 Physicians* 550.00 550.00 221 Nurses 1,813.00 1,331.00 482.00 410 Optometrists 434.00 428.00 6.00 Osteopaths* 143.00 143.00 1248 Pharmacists 2,411.00 2,268.00 143.00 Veterinarians* 62.00 62.00 "otals $9,362.00 $7,455.00 $1,907.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">of permits to practice after application is filed of holding tbe examination. Permits are two of the practice acts; while in the absence r no permit can be granted. Then again, take r: three of the laws do not provide for it. The when appealed to, has advised that in the absence allowing reciprocity no one can be accepted simply been authorized to practice in a sister state, but he Nebraska State Board Examination. Prior to the ck of legal authority was not a sufficient granting of permits or the extending of particulars in which the present practice acts be made to one more here. The members of ning Boards are paid for their services a per diem other boards "split" the fees received from the another source of irritation between the lureau or Department consulted the convenience of would recommend that the Boards be allowed to as that is much the simpler method for the admin - sver, we believe that tbe fair method is to require all to accept a per diem for their services. That per not necessarily be the same in all professions. It would seem that the members of these Boards should be willing to serve without receiving any large compensation therefor. The position should be looked upon as one of honor. It has appeared, however, felt that it was encumbent upon them to get could for their services and expenses in these professions largely recommend those who are i Boards. Why not choose those who look upon be rendered as honorary, rather than remunerative? ought of the Secretary that the members should not be a certain amount of Board members when more than the circumstances and law really justify. with your approval the Secretary purposes to prepare lsure act for presentation to the Legislature. This be a matter of considerable labor but the result, if it is success - will be ample recompense. It would seem that the simplifying of ought to have ready approval, even when the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE 17 If a general licensure act is not adopted, then there will be a demand for material amendments to most of the individual acts. In fact, a number of the professions feel that the entire acts relating to their several professions should be rewritten. But when this is done most of the inequalities will still remain; while in drawing a uniform act many of the deficiencies in the individual laws would be remedied to meet the demands of the several professions. * </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OP THE » BUREAU OF CHILD WELFARE Outline of the Work of the Child Welfare Bureau: Section 8326 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922 gives an outline of the work of the Child Welfare Bureau. We quote the salient provisions of that section: "It shall be the duty of the director who is in charge of the working organization of the State Child Welfare Bureau to devise ways and means for securing and placing playground equip- ment in urban, village and rural communities where needed The State Child Welfare Bureau shall endeavor in every possible way to lessen and prevent penal trials and punishments of children. It shall assist in equalizing opportunities for the children of Ne- braska The Bureau shall be a unifying agency, through which the state may co-operate with individuals and organizations among all classes of people on matters pertaining to children's aid and benefit No representative of the said bureau shall force its authority over and above the recognized head of any household." A reading of this quotation from the Statutes conveys an idea of the wide scope of the activities of the Bureau. To do all this we have but three employees who are devoting their time exclusively to that work: a chief, an assistant chief and a stenographer. The serv - ices of the chief and of the stenographer are given almost entirely to the office. This leaves but one person to do the field work. Office Work: It is the duty of the office force to keep in touch with the general situation relating to child welfare over the state. In order to do this licenses must be issued to the various agencies from whom regular reports are required. The reports are made upon blanks furnished by the Bureau; these blanks have been care - fully prepared to secure the essential information. A large amount of correspondence is carried on with officials and committees over the state for the purpose of keeping in contact as best we can with the local situation. All kinds of information relating to child and family welfare is asked of the Bureau. A careful study is made of these inquiries and advice is painstakingly given. Frequently the inquiry is as to how to handle a certain situation which is explained in the correspondence. The information given should be studied and reply made by one who </seg>
            <seg id="p019">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 19 is fully conversant, not only with the problems inquired about, but also with the state laws as they may bear thereon. Field Work: Often the cases inquired about are too complicated to be handled from the office. It then is necessary for the field worker to go upon the ground and study the situation first hand. Most of these requests for assistance come from courts and officials. The Judges and County Attorneys expect the field worker to be competent to advise as to what should be done with the children involved in the cases investigated. If the field worker is to keep the confidence of these officials she must have broad knowledge of the problems related to child welfare and be able to apply that knowledge to the case in hand. Therefore, the wider the experience and the better the judgment of the investigator, the more successful will be her work. As desirable as it might be, the Bureau is unable to go out seek - ing things to do for there are more requests for the services of the field worker than can be supplied. For example, one day recently requests for assistance came from four different parts of the state; two of these requests came from county attorneys, another one from a district judge and the fourth from the superintendent of a city school. Investigations were made in all of these cases and suggestions given as to how conditions could be improved. Public officials or - dinarily want to do the very best thing that can be done to improve any given situation. Many of them have not sufficient experience iti handling such cases to have confidence in their own opinion. Hence their readiness to accept the recommendation of a real expert on these problems. The Bureau has the very best cooperation from the officials with whom it works but we do wish at times that these officials might be more free to act on their own judgment. Perhaps they feel the need of having the advice of a representative of the State Bureau as a shield to protect them from the possible hostile reaction of an uninformed public. That may be too harsh a judgment but some of the cases appear so plain that it seems incredible that the local authorities cannot act on their own responsibility. It may be that lack of experi - ence in dealing with this kind of problems makes the authorities hesitate. An Additional Field Worker Needed. The Bureau is very much in need of a second field worker. In addition to responding to re - quests for assistance, to which reference has already been made, the Bureau must inspect all Maternity Homes and Lying-in Hospitals </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE once each year. There are one hundred five of these institutions. This in itself involves much travel and expenditure of time. Much should be done to assist the different communities in organ - ising their social iorces. They must be shown how to work and this can best be done by seeing how an expert meets their social problems. ORGANIZATION OF VOLUNTARY COMMITTEES The Department of Public Welfare has long felt the need of some organized assistance in the several counties of the state. How to the facts touching a particular case in a remote locality is a dus problem. Meager appropriations and a limited personnel make it impossible to send a representative from the Department to investigate every individual case. To meet this situation local com- es are being organized in some of the counties. This is being in cooperation with the Extension Department of the University of Nebraska. The thought is to get a small group which will really Interest themselves in some of the problems of their community. Then through this group the Department can learn of the help needed. We recognize that this is a makeshift and that we must not expect too much from it. However, it will be a beginning and in some communities we shall get very satisfactory service. The ideal to be looked forward to is an official Child Welfare Board in every county. These Boards would then organize for local service, and be available at the request of the Bureau for needed investigations; and in turn could call upon the Bureau for assistance in the more serious cases. COMMUNITY NURSES Under Section 8234 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922 authorities of any -city, village, township or county can employ a community nurse and can levy a tax for the purpose of paying the salary and expenses of such a nurse; while the following section pro - vides that if the authorities are unwilling to proceed, a petition signed by twenty-five per cent of the electors shall compel the sub - mission of the question to a vote of the people. A number of com - munity nurses have been employed over the state following the with- drawal of the Red Cross support which was furnished during the war. Many of these nurses have rendered excellent service, PROBATION OFFICERS Douglas and Lancaster Counties have paid juvenile probation officers. These are of great assistance to the juvenile courts of those counties. There is no provision for paid juvenile probation officers in the remaining counties of the state. However, Section 10,170 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922 provides for the employ - ment of adult probation officers by the judge of any court of record. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 21 « i These officers ordinarily do not concern themselves with the care of the child, as they are appointed for service in connection with the criminal courts of the state. However, in counties under fifty thou - sand population it is provided that such officer shall perform the duties of probation officer for the juvenile court. Therefore, in these smaller counties the juvenile courts can get assistance from these adult probation officers. The amount of their compensation in coun - ties of over twenty thousand population is fixed by the statute at not exceeding $720.00 per annum. In counties under twenty thou - sand the county commissioners may authorize the county judge to appoint such an officer. Here again is available assistance in doing the proper work and it would be well for every county to use it. In these times when living expenses are so high the limit of the salary, — $720.00 — is too low. COMPULSORY EDUCATION AXD CHILD LABOR IN THE BEET FIELDS For a number of years this Department has taken considerable interest in keeping the children of the families accustomed to go to the beet fields in school as long as possible. Our efforts have been directed along the line of preventing the children from leaving until the expiration of the spring term of school. There has been quite a scramble to secure the families who usually work in the beet fields. Quite large colonies of them live in Omaha, Lincoln and Hastings; smaller groups elsewhere. One would not expect that the Beet Companies would take this labor from the places where it had wintered to the beet fields before it was needed; yet the fact is that they will so take it. The companies have felt that con - tracts made with this class of labor were of little binding force and that the only safe plan was to take it to the fields before some other company had a chance to do so. A study among the children con - vinced us that when no one interfered they were taken to the fields from two weeks to a month ahead of the time when their services were needed. i, On the other hand, most of the companies are reasonably well satisfied if they know that everyone is to have a fair chance to secure the labor desired when the time for shipment has arrived. In other words, when some state authority steps in and says the migration shall not take place until a certain date, these companies are satisfied to abide that order provided it is about the time when the help is really needed. During the years 1921 and 1922 the Department of Public Welfare made an effort to restrain the annual migration until the time when the children were really needed and in this way keep them in school until the spring term was practically completed. In </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OP THE - 1923 and 1924 a new administration came in and the restraining band was relaxed. Therefore, when the present administration took charge in 1925 the fight had to be started all over again. Early in 1925, after consulting the agricultural agents of the Sugar Beet Companies operating in Nebraska and the superintendent of the Lincoln City Schools a date was fixed as the earliest time that the children could be taken out of school. In fixing this date con - sideration was given both to the time when the spring term of school would be ended and to the time when the children were actually needed in the beet fields. May 22nd was finally settled upon as the date. The school term would not actually close until early in June but by holding the children until May 22nd they would lose but one week of school work. After the date was fixed in this way one com - pany, The Rock River Sugar Beet Company, determined to move its contract families on the 5 th day of May. Before the Department knew of the move, these families had their household goods, etc. loaded into a railroad car and the children had been taken out of school preparatory to leaving that afternoon on a special train for the north. Complaints were thereupon filed against the heads of the fourteen families involved, who were required to appear in court foi violating the Compulsory Education Law. This law requires all chil - dren between the ages of seven and sixteen in cities of the class of Lincoln to be kept in school through the entire school year. At the hearing of these cases the judge fined the' defendant fathers whom the testimony showed were leaving with their families for temporary purposes and suspended the execution of the sentence with the state - ment that the defendants would be discharged provided they put their children back in school and did not attempt to remove them again until after May 22nd. The families which we were unable to show were going away temporarily were discharged. This was on the theory that the Compulsory Education Law did not purpose to restrain the permanent removal. This very sensible action of Judge Chappell of the Municipal Court stopped the exodus and the families there - after abided the date already fixed. Early in 1926 the Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare again took up with the schools and the Sugar Beet Companies the question of fixing a date for the annual migration of the children employed in the beet fields. By this time the superintendents of the public schools in Omaha, Hastings and Havelock had been interested and were consulted. After canvassing the situation and after careful consideration of the answers to a questionnaire sent out by Super - intendent Lefler of the Lincoln Public Schools a date — May 21st — was fixed which was reasonably satisfactory to all concerned. There was no attempt in Lincoln to leave prior to that date except in the case of four fathers who left a day or two in advance by automobiles </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 23 with one or more of their older sons. Complaints were filed against these four fathers and an officer was sent to a point four hundred miles distant in the state to bring the defendants back for trial. However, at the importunities of the defendants and the farmers for whom they worked, the officer was persuaded to leave the defendants and let the cases stand until the defendants should return in the fall. Three of these fathers returned in November; a hearing of their cases was had and each was fined five dollars and costs, which included the expense of the officer in making the long trip to where they had gone. The costs and fine in each case amounted to fifty - three dollars. As the fourth defendant had apparently gone away with the intention of staying permanently the case against him was dropped. Thus, it has been demonstrated that if some state official will assume authority to fix a reasonable date for this annual migration to the beet fields there will be little trouble in having that date ac - cepted by all concerned. But some one says that it is against the law to take a child out of the city schools at any time or for any purpose. This, of course, is true. However, this migration has been sanctioned for years and a rigid enforcement of the law in that regard would meet a considerable opposition. This Department has at no time assumed to authorize the removal of the children before the expiration of the school term. It has simply said that it would not ask the proper authorities to prosecute after a certain date and that it would ask that a prosecution be instituted against all cases leaving before that date. We fully recognize that the labor of pulling and topping beets in the fall is a more serious interference with the educations of these children than is the weeding and thinning in the spring and summer. However, that is another problem and will have to be met in another way. Perhaps it can best be met by the school authorities in the communities where this kind of labor is demanded maintaining sum - mer schools, or by requiring them to attend the regular term of school while in session and make a vacation period to cover the time when the pulling and topping season is at its height. At best, we appreciate that this is a very serious problem and that the use of children in the beet fields interferes materially with their proper education. It seems incredible that the parents who take their children to the beet fields are so ready to jeopardize the latter's future. MOTHERS' PENSIONS The use of mothers' pensions is of recent origin. The first law authorizing such pensions in Nebraska was the enactment of a brief </seg>
            <seg id="p024">REPORT OP THE P amendment to one section of the Juvenile Court Act. The brevity of this paragraph made it impossible to give any of the safeguards which today are thrown around the expenditures under such laws. The present law, which was enacted in 1919, is much more elaborate and includes all the essential provisions of a good mothers' F pension act. Indeed, the Nebraska Act was one of four that were approved without amendment by the Conference of Child Welfare L Committees of America held in New York City in May, 1925. This does not mean that that Conference regarded the Nebraska Act as a model but it does mean that it was considered as having all the provisions that it was thought expedient to ask for at There are some things in the act that could well be changed. One of them is the limitation that to be eligible for a pension a child must be "under the age of fourteen." It is inconsistent to deny a child the right to work and compel him to go to school and at the same time deny the mother of that child the benefits of the mothers' pension law. This law should be amended to include all children under the age of sixteen. Another amendment would be one raising the amount that can be paid to any child from ten dollars to fifteen dollars and the amount that can be paid to any one family from fifty dollars to seventy-five dollars. The higher cost of living would seem to demand this change. The Department has sent out mothers' pension questionnaires ering the years 1924 and 1925. The answers do not indicate that thers' pensions are used to the extent that they should be. Some counties do not use them at all, though the County Board does pay out a considerable amount in the form of charity. Other counties use their poor funds to supplement the payments under the mothers' pension to too great an extent. The following tables summarize some of the data that can be study of these questionnaires, </seg>
            <seg id="p025">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 25 GENERAL SUMMARY OP MOTHERS' PENSION QUESTIONNAIRES FOR 1924 AND 1935 1924 1925 Number of counties reporting out of total of 93 S5 90 Total number of mothers receiving pensions.... 85S 1,023 Total number of children involved 2,483 2,929 Average number of children of pension (under 14) in family. 9 2.86 Total amount paid out as pensions. $175,908.10 $188,006 Classification of mothers: 1924 1925 Widowed Deserted . Divorced Unmarried 554 or 64% 631 or 61.6 % .108 or 13% 169 or 16.5 % 74 or 8% 99 or 9.6 % 1 or .1% 3 or .29% 55 or 6% 70 or 6.8 % 28 or 3% 45 or 4.4 % 38 or 4% 6 or .58% Husbands incapacitated ... Husbands in penitentiary Not classified Total _ 858 1,023 TEN COUNTIES PAYING LARGEST NUMBER OF PENSIONS 1924 Number Pensions 1925 Number Pensions County County Douglas 174 Douglas 204 Gage 42 Lancaster 53 Saunders 30 Gage 43 Lancaster 28 Cass 30 Cass 26 Custer 28 Custer 26 Madison 28 Cedar „. 21 Saunders 28 Lincoln 21 Cedar 23 Madison 20 Brown 21 Buffalo - . 18 Jefferson 21 The following table gives the amount paid out by the several counties for 1924 and 1925 and the number of children to whom paid. 1924 1925 County Amount No. Children Amount No. Children Adams $ 2,220.00 29 $ 2,640.00 33 Antelope 1,288.00 23 1,770.00 27 Arthur 290.00 7 380.00 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF THE 1924 1925 County Amount No. Children Amount No. Childrei P Banner 000.00 0 Blaine 000.00 0 Boone 2,485.00 47 Box Butte 600.00 5 Boyd 1,585.00 41 Brown 875.00 21 Buffalo 2,625.00 30 Burt 1,612.00 17 Butler • • Cass 5,000.00 92 Cedar 5,735.00 48 Chase 1,400.00 19 Cherry 900.00 9 Cheyenne 2,160.00 25 Clay 1,002.00 10 Coif ax 3,460.00 37 Cuming 820.00 8 Custer 4,806.00 89 Dakota 1,500.00 20 Dawes 1,260.00 25 Dawson* Deuel 468.00 4 Dixon 2,915.00 27 Dodge 700.00 8 Douglas 31,134.60 563 Dundy •• 5 Flllmore 000.00 0 Franklin 264.00 8 Frontier 360.00 • 3 Furnas • • Gage 9,785.50 101 Garden 1,030.00 19 Garfield 000.00 0 Gosper 840.00 7 Grant 840.00 7 Greeley* Hall 2,015.00 19 Hamilton 2,250.00 32 Harlan 510.00 10 Hayes * . * Hitchcock 1,380.00 14 Holt 1,530.00 41 Hooker 180.00 4 Howard _. 420.00 ** Jefferson 2,688.00 36 180.00 126.00 2,918.38 840.00 2,340.00 840.00 3,105.00 2,255.00 1,525.00 4,540.00 5,680.00 1,560.00 * 2,955.00 1,344.50 3,700.00 680.00 4,860.00 100.00 1,580.00 420.00 2,520.00 400.00 35,378.24 360.00 000.00 240.00 510.00 1,230.00 6,262.50 1,565.00 000.00 940.00 480.00 2,830.00 1,796.00 1,380.00 100.00 1,260.00 2,000.00 90.00 320.00 3,246.00 : 54 7 21 24 ■ 75 25 26 51 57 • ;:• 21 41 12 81 ; ; 34 8 681 i ii 135 23 17 !i 38 i </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 27 1924 1925 County Amount No. Children Amount No. Children Johnson • • 1,630.00 21 Kearney 2,640.00 22 2,260.00 25 Keith 740.00 13 840.00 14 Keya Paha 60.00 2 645.00 12 Kimball 600.00 5 210.00 3 Knox 4,115.00 50 4,180.00 52 Lancaster 6,825.00 99 9,565.00 143 Lincoln 4,286.00 62 3,131.00 65 Logan 000.00 0 000.00 0 Loup 000.00 0 000.00 0 Madison 3,390.00 56 3,845.00 58 McPherson 000.00 0 000.00 0 Merrick 3,100.00 41 1,085.00 20 Morrill 1,200.00 31 1,205.00 26 Nance 2,210.00 37 2,300.00 32 Nemaha 1,893.00 29 2,391.00 47 Nuckolls 1,471.00 35 2,460.00 41 Otoe 2,898.00 30 2,608.00 30 Pawnee 1,404.00 •• 000.00 0 Perkins 2,170.00 17 690.00 8 Phelpa 1,200.00 12 960.00 12 Pierce 2,125.00 41 4,080.00 34 Platte : 3,600.00 58 3,480.00 58 Polk 2,390.00 27 2,580.00 25 Red Willow 2,180.00 15 2,000.00 20 Richardson • • 1,250.00 45 Rock • • 360.00 5 Saline 000.00 0 2,566.35 20 Sarpy 1,010.00 15 000.00 0 Saunders 7,125.00 76 6,420.00 62 Scotts Bluff 2,064.00 35 2,640.00 63 Seward 1,701.00 17 540.00 9 Sheridan 2,100.00 28 1,926.00 20 Sherman 1,035.00 20 1,182.50 . 19 Sioux 000.00 0 210.00 5 Stanton 320.00 4 220.00 4 Thayer 1,800.00 •* 1,460.00 24 Thomas 000.00 0 000.00 0 Thurston 300.00 9 690.00 13 .^J^felley 000.00 0 000.00 0 Washington 1,913.00 17 2,610.00 31 Wayne 50.00 1 290.00 7 Webster 2,000.00 30 2,160.00 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029">29 DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE amended and still contains the provision that a child may be com - mitted "if under the age of sixteen, or after he pleads guilty to or is convicted of a crime." The County Attorney of Lancaster County has held that this leaves a doubt as to the right of a juvenile or county court to commit a child sixteen years of age or over, unless convicted of a crime, to one of the industrial schools. We therefore recommend that this clause last quoted be stricken from the two sections of the statute, to wit: 1180 and 1182. As a matter of fact, the entire juvenile court act might well be rewritten. It was adopted more than twenty years ago when juvenile courts were young. Several amendments have been made, some of which have left the meaning of the statute uncertain. As the sections referred to above need amending this would be a good time to remodel the entire act. INCREASED USE OF JUVENILE COURT AND OP MOTHERS' PENSIONS It has been the regret of the Secretary that he has been unable to give more time to the Bureau of Child Welfare. He feels that the courts of the state are not making full use of the juvenile court statute. This is perhaps largely because of a lack of understanding of its scope. Children are still being tried, even in the juvenile court. The parental character of that court is apparently not fully under - stood. Then the use of the mothers' pension law might be extended. There seems to be a misapprehension as to the purpose of that law. A mother's pension is granted as a matter of right to all deserving mothers who come within the law's provisions. No such a mother should be given charity. That should be reserved for those who can - not qualify under the mothers' pension act. The mothers who come within its terms should be regarded as being in the honor class. The reports received in answer to the questionnaire sent out by the Department show that too many counties are doling out charity in cases where a pension should be granted. v #• </seg>
            <seg id="p030">BUREAU OF HEALTH This Bureau, as organized at present, has a chief as its executive officer, four directors as heads of different divisions and thirteen other employees who are classified as clerks, stenographers and field K workers. It does all the public health service that is rendered by the state. It has too small a personnel to give the service that is given by many of the states; but it strives to cover a limited field in an up-to-date way. When the present administration took over the Bureau in Janu- ary, 1925, the work was very much in arrears. The Division of Vital Statistics was in the worst condition. This was especially unfor- tunate as it is the agency which gathers the statistics as to births and deaths. The Federal Census Bureau gets transcripts of these figures and from them compiles its statistics relating to Nebraska. It was particularly deplorable that Nebraska should get so far behind in its vital statistics as she had but recently been taken into the federal registration area and continued inefficiency would mean being dropped therefrom. Being in that area has more than a senti - mental advantage for the states that are included get certain frank - ing privileges to assist in the work which amount to a considerable during the year. In spite of the urgency of keeping these records up to the minute indexing of birth certificates was behind four months; during time 9,745 certificates had accumulated; the death certificates were behind the same length of time and 2,500 had accumulated. The stillbirths had not been indexed for two years during which time 1,817 had accumulated. It was no small task to bring this indexing up to date as additional information had to be secured on more than a majority of these certificates. The correspondence was very much behind and even the transcripts which we furnish the Federal Bureau The emergency was sufficient to induce the Children's Bureau at Washington to sanction the employment of three extra clerks for four months each, to be paid out of the Sheppard-Towner Funds. This extra help was employed during the first half of 1925 and the humiliated averted. by being dropped from the federal </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE I EPIDEMIOLOGY The table giving the number of contagious diseases reported during the years 1925 and 1926, which appears later in this report, shows that Nebraska has too much of such diseases. The local Boards of Health are asked to assist in educating the public in the use of all well recognized immunizing processes. It is not best to recommend the employment of any measures as a prevention of disease until the efficacy of such measures has been thoroughly demonstrated. How - ever, those whose success are beyond question should be urged on all occasions. The total number of cases reported for 1925 was 4,521; for 1926 was 7,761 as shown by the table given on page 54 of this report. The large increase in measles in 1926 would in - dicate that sanitary precautions had been neglected while the slight decrease in mumps lends encouragement. The considerable increase in chickenpox is offset in a way by a slight decrease in smallpox. The table shows a large increase in pneumonia and in both scarlet and typhoid fever; while a small increase is shown in influenza and tuberculosis. The Bureau of Health is anxious to assist the local Boards, not only in the diagnosis of these diseases but also to locate the source of the contagion. Frequently a stranger can come upon the ground and locate the source of trouble which a local investigator will over - look because of some preconceived notion. VENEREAL DISEASES Educational methods are being used to prevent the spread of venereal diseases. The medical profession can be of great service to the race if it will fully cooperate in this educational program. Under the law the doctors report these cases by number. The name of the individual remains the secret of the doctor. We have no desire to know that name as long as the person continues taking treatment or whenever he is cured. The law requires the reporting of the name only when the individual fails to take treatment as long as needed. The doctor that does not report that name when the individual fails in his obligation under the law does not do his part in the eradication of these dread diseases. Whenever this failure to report becomes willful the doctor should be prosecuted to the limit of the law. It is only just to say that the Director of this Division feels that he gets fair cooperation from the profession and that it is only the few who are derelict in their obligations under the health laws of the state and the rules of the Department of Public Welfare. </seg>
            <seg id="p032"/>
            <seg id="p033">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 33 ing a period prior to the time when the Nebraska law on this subject was enacted. It has been customary to accept all offerings of this character though they were without legal sanction. The use of such records has increased materially during the last twenty years and the state should accommodate in that regard those born within its bound - aries. The statute should determine the method to be employed in establishing such births and deaths or it should be left to the De - partment of Public Welfare to by rule determine the procedure. It should not be necessary to pass a law to require a local registrar to furnish on request of the Director a birth or death certificate ahead of his monthly return. However, some registrars stand upon their legal rights and refuse to expedite their return no matter how urgent is the need. The law should be amended to require them to furnish these certificates upon the request of the Director. The Secretary does not recommend the employment of a field agent at this time as there are other places in the Bureau where the need to increase the service is greater. He has asked in his budget for an additional clerk for this Division. Very likely there are cases where some whose duty it is to report the facts as to births and deaths are wilfully derelict and if so there is no reason why an example should not be made of the worst cases. However, that can be done without employing any additional help. It would seem that the local registrar should send in certificates only after they are complete. No others should be accepted by the Director. The Iowa statute declares the standard form adopted by the U. S. shall be the official form. There is no good reason why a charge should not be made for certified copies of birth and death certificates. This is generally done. For example, there is no good reason why an insurance com - pany should not pay for a death certificate which is wanted for busi - ness purposes. This is quite an important item as in 1926 there were Biz hundred death certificates and twelve hundred birth certificates issued. The present vital statistics law for Nebraska was adopted in 1905. The amendments that have been made since then have not changed any of its essential features. It is the recommendation of the Secre - tary that a new law be adopted which would include the suggestions made above. Doubtless there will be many other provisions which might well be included and which are in the laws adopted more recently in many of the states. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OF THE CHILD HYGIENE The Division of Child Hygiene administers the Sheppard-Towner Funds. The law under which these funds are administered takes its name from the two members of Congress who sponsored it in the respective houses. It is legislation in the interest of maternity and infancy. It is widely recognized that too many infants die under one year of age. Medical science has already accomplished wonders in lessening infant mortality but there are still too many deaths from pre - ventable causes. There are also too many deaths of mothers at childbirth. The deaths are preventable and no public two principal causes of such health official should be satisfied until such deaths are materially lessened. No mother should be allowed to lose her life in bringing into the world her offspring if it is humanly possible to prevent it. It was this feeling, doubtless, that prompted the enactment of the Sheppard-Towner Law which appropriates a fund to be distributed among the several states who accept the provisions of the law. Ne - braska's quota during the current year is over $18,000.00. Of this amount, $5,000.00 is given us while any remaining sum which we receive must be matched out of the state appropriation. Last year we spent out of the state appropriation $6,915.00, giving us $11,915 from the federal funds. We hope to have an equal amount of money for use during the current year. The Sheppard-Towner bill provided for the continuation of the appropriation provided for therein during five years, which term expires June 30th, next. There is a bill before Congress to extend the appropriation for another two years. It has passed the House of Representatives and is now pending in the Senate as unfinished business. If it does not pass the work of this Division will be very much decreased unless the state increases its appropriation. The work is too important and means too much to our mothers and infant children to be dropped.* Since this was written Congress has passed a bill authorizing the extension of this appropriation to June 30, 1929 SANITARY ENGINEERING A statement relating to this subject by Dr. Wilson, Chief of the Bureau of Health, is incorporated in a later part of this report. The Secretary agrees with that statement. Without a sanitary engineer Nebraska cannot do all that she should to safeguard the health of citizens. It is a short-sighted policy to adopt a niggardly course health problems are involved. The amount spent by campaign to conserve the health of her citizens is small </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE 35 compared with the amounts appropriated by many of her neighboring states. The lessening or prevention of disease is the end sought in any well organized public health program. A sanitary engineer should have a place in such an organization. POWERS OP THE DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE GENERAL POWERS Section 8159 of the Compiled Statutes for 1922 reads as follows - "The department of public welfare shall have general supervision and control over matters relating to public health, sanitation and the general public welfare; and shall provide for examination as in this title provided; and enforce the provisions of this title; and have supervision over all matters of quarantine and quarantine regula - tions." Various sections of the statutes give the Department specific rule making powers. Such provisions are included in many of the prac - tice acts relating to the professions. Such power is also given in the act relating to venereal diseases. SPECIAL POWERS Section 8272 of the Compiled Statutes for 1922 reads: "The De - partment of Public Welfare shall inquire into the whole system of public charities and methods of and practices in the correctional in - stitutions of the state and counties to ascertain the condition there - of from time to time by inspection or otherwise, especially of prisons, jails, infirmaries, public hospitals, asylums, reformatories and in - dustrial schools; and the officers in charge of all such institutions and any officers for the distribution of public outdoor relief shall at all times furnish to said board, upon its request, such information and statistics as it may require. To secure accuracy, uniformity and com - pleteness in statistics, such department may prescribe such forms of reports and registrations as it may deem essential. The plans for all new jail buildings, lockups, infirmaries, or reformatories shall, before the adoption of the same by the state, county, or municipal authorities, be submitted to the department for examination and ap - proval. The department may at any time inquire into the manage - ment of any state and county penal, reformatory, or charitable institution in the state, and such department, in making such in - vestigation shall have power to send for persons and papers and to administer oaths and affirmations. All investigations undertaken by such department shall be directed wholly toward the betterment of methods pertaining to the health, punishment, education and reforma - tion of the inmates of the various institutions described in this ar - ticle and the procuring of legislation to that end." </seg>
            <seg id="p036">REPORT OP THE 36 The section just quoted is largely the same as section 5827 of le revised statutes of 1913, the latter section being a part of the cle relating to the powers and duties of the Board of Charities Corrections. With the adoption of Section 8272 the powers for- held by that Board were transferred to the Department of Welfare. A reading of the Section shows that the powers transferred are varied and far-reaching. Little use has been i of them during the current biennium; much could be done the funds and assistance available. The right of inspection of institutions under the control of a rdinate department is one that should be exercised with great Qspection. However, it is a right that might, at times, safe - the interests of the state's dependent population which is for in its institutions. The requirement of this section of the statute that plans for all n jail buildings, lockups, etc. should be submitted to the Depart- has been ignored. We presume the Department has been ct in its duty in allowing this practice to continue. None of the regularly employed officers of the Department have ten able to inspect the jails as this section authorizes. However, at nest of the Secretary, Mr. A. I. Jones, Superintendent of the for the Friendless, has visited a number of jails and has written reports of his investigations. This has been done it expense to the Department. Many of the jails are in a deplor- tion and it is hard to believe that the authorities knowingly therein. This power of inspection is' a valuable one but should go with it the power to order closed the jails which are ily unfit for human use. It is unfortunate that so many of our ns feel that any place is good enough for a criminal. Those who such a belief surely have not given much thought to the subject, ility has never reformed any man; while decent treatment has much along that line. A CUSTODIAL FARM FOB MISDEMEANANTS Draska needs better jails, — modern, up-to-date institutions the inmates can be segregated and their surroundings made sanitary. However, these jails should be constructed only for the short-time men and for those confined, pending trial. who are sentenced for thirty days or longer be confined upon a custodial farm maintained by the state. rm should provide work for the inmates that they might keep physical condition and at the same time earn something to the support of their dependents — if they had any, — to the state a sufficient sum to pay the expense of </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE 37 keeping them. This is not merely an ideal, as a large number of such farms are maintained in the United States. Indiana has had one for more than a dozen years which has worked out splendidly. Although it is not compulsory in all cases to send the misdemeanant to this farm, the result has been, nevertheless, that the county jails have been almost depopulated. Work of a varied character is pro - vided for its inmates. A custodial farm is a most needed institu - tion in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">REPORT OF THE BUREAU OF EXAMINING BOARDS Mrs. Clark Perkins, Director I herewith submit a brief report of the activities of the Bureau of Examining Boards for the biennium ending July 1, 1926. The work of this Bureau has been continued along lines similar to those followed in previous years with such minor changes seemed beneficial. Corrections and i development of the Bureau improvements incident to the growth and have been made with the cooperation several Examining Boards. Each profession has an Examin- consisting of three members, except dentistry, which has five members. BUREAU ACTIVITIES The Bureau activities include the keeping of records and filing of documents; promulgating and enforcing rules and regulations pertaining to examinations; holding of examinations; the issuing of licenses and collecting of the following fees: Examination, annual registration, apprenticeship, reciprocity, endorsement and for certified The Bureau also investigates complaints of infraction of the practice acts and prosecutes the guilty party where a violation DIVISIONS OF BUREAU iureau is divided into ten divisions, as follows: Chiropody, :tic, Dentistry, Embalming, Medicine and Surgery, Nursing, Osteopathy, Pharmacy and Veterinary Medicine and STAFF The staff at present consists of the Secretary of the Department Public Welfare, the director of the Bureau, one part time steno- two clerks and a field investigator. FINANCES is self-sustaining. Consequently it has the responsi- :y of collecting and expending the moneys which accrue from the professions. This necessitates the keeping of a complete set of The revenue of the Bureau is obtained from fees derived </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 39 from the following sources: Annual registration, apprenticeship and reciprocity, and for endorsements and certified copies of records. This money is deposited with the state treasurer twice each week. All examination fees are credited to the different Boards of the pro - fessions from which they accrue, while all other fees are credited to the Bureau Fund. The Board members are paid a per diem and expenses or by a division of fees, as provided by the different statutes. There follows a statement of the receipts and expenditures for the current biennium. Those relating to the Division of Vital Statistics and for maternity homes are omitted as not properly a part of the funds of this Bureau. Total Expenditures $27,779.72 TRAINING SCHOOLS Nebraska now has twenty-eight accredited training schools for nurses. A yearly inspection is made of these schools and a report of the result submitted to the Bureau. Before entering training a student nurse must submit her educational Qualifications upon a blank prepared by the Bureau. If the data submitted shows that the applicant has the required qualifications, then a student nurse certi - ficate is issued to her. These are not issued to applicants under eighteen years of age. It is useless for one to commence training as a nurse at an earlier age for the reason that she cannot take the State Board until twenty-one years of age and only three years are required to take the training course. During this biennium 1119 student nurse certificates have been issued. Of those receiving these certificates 858 presented proof of having completed four years of high school. The smaller training schools and those having a limited class of patients are required to furnish affiliation for their nurses in training. Much of this is obtained in hospitals in neighboring states. However, the training schools connected with the University of Nebraska Hospital, with the Chiropody $ 77.00 Chiropractic 2,29 6.50 Dentistry 2,626.00 Embalming 980.00 Medicine and Surgery 4,340.50 Nursing 4,253.00 Optometry 329.00 Osteopathy 795.00 Pharmacy 3,380.00 Veterinary Medicine and Surgery 194.00 Total 2 $34,112.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">REPORT OP THE Hospital of Omaha, with the Lincoln General and with the eth'g Hospital of Lincoln, offer affiliation. The training f the West Nebraska Methodist and of the Lincoln General are the most recent ones to be accredited. following is a complete list of the hospitals conducting ac - training schools for nurses: EMBALMER'S APPRENTICESHIP embalmer's apprenticeship system was promulgated and be - ffective August 1, 1925, and a complete set of rules relating were adopted at that time. An apprentice must be eighteen &gt;f age and must furnish a statement to the Bureau within after entering upon his apprenticeship or after any r. During the eleven months that this system has to July 1, 1926, 113 certificates were issued. Hospital Location University Hospital Omaha Methodist Episcopal Hospital Omaha St. Joseph's Hospital Omaha St. Catherine's Hospital Omaha Clarkson Memorial Hospital Omaha Wise Memorial Hospital Omaha Nicholas Senn Hospital Omaha Paxton Memorial Hospital Omaha Lord Lister Hospital Omaha Swedish Mission Hospital (now Evangelical Covenant ) Omaha Immanuel Hospital Omaha St. Elizabeth's Hospital Lincoln Dr. Bailey's Sanatorium Lincoln Lincoln Sanitarium Lincoln Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln Lincoln Hospital Lincoln Lincoln General Hospital Lincoln Norfolk General Hospital Norfolk Lutheran Hospital Norfolk Lutheran Hospital Beatrice Beatrice Sanitarium Beatrice Mennonite Hospital Beatrice St. Joseph's Hospital Alliance St. Catherine's Hospital McCook St. Francis Hospital Grand Islam Mary Lanning Memorial Hospital Hastings West Nebraska Methodist Hospital Scottsbluff Lutheran Hospital York </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE 41 EXAMINATIONS The State Board examinations are held twice during each year except in nursing, in which examinations are held three times each year. One of these examinations in each profession is held just fol - lowing the spring graduations while the others are scattered through the fall and winter. Most of the examinations are held at Lincoln. However, some are held at Omaha to secure better hospital facilities and to accommodate the students from schools at Omaha who desire to take the State Board. The exact time and place of these examina - tions is determined by the Secretary of the Department who tries to meet the convenience of the applicants and of the members of the Boards. The qualifications of applicants for licenses are fixed by the several practice acts, supplemented by rules of the Department. All applications are evaluated by the Director of the Bureau. If the ap - plication is approved the applicant is notified to appear for examina - tion. A representative of the Bureau attends all examinations and meetings of the Boards, except in Dentistry. The law places more power in the hands of that Board. Graded examination papers are returned to the Bureau and are kept on file for two years or longer if for any reason that appears necessary. A record is kept of all grades and a license is issued to each applicant who passes. An exact copy is preserved in the files of the Bureau. This Department may grant registration by reciprocity to applicants from other states in all professions except in embalming, optometry, and veterinary medicine and surgery, provided the requirements of such state, territory, or District of Columbia are equal to the re - quirements of this state. In two of the professions there is a further condition that a like courtesy must be extended by the other state to applicants from Nebraska. There follows a statement of the number of licenses granted for the biennium. Chiropody 4 15 Nursing „ 298 70 368 Osteopathy </seg>
            <seg id="p042">REPORT OF THE 168 17 185 Medicine 12 5 17 In Veterinary Medicine 6 6 Totals 1,013 162 1,175 REVOCATION OP LICENSE The practice acts provide a penalty for non-payment of annual registration fees in the various professions. The different penalties imposed by these acts are quite unlike and some seem unduly severe. ■ There follows a statement of the ment of annual registration fees. Pharmacy There follows a statement of the licenses revoked because of non-pay- licenses revoked because of non-pay- ■ ment of annual registration fees. Pharmacy .172 172 ■ Dentistry 6 3 Embalming 9 1 Embalming 9 1 Total 326 One medical license was revoked for unprofessional conduct, LAW ENFORCEMENT Reports of numerous violations of the different practice acts have been submitted to this Bureau. Usually the one complained against by the Secretary of the Department and asked to explain. explanation is unsatisfactory, then he is notified to desist from practices. If that fails, then the complaint is turned over Pto the Bureau's fie facts justify, he t This investigator 1925, and during .'s field investigator who looks into the matter and if the takes the case up with the proper county attorney. commenced working for the Bureau November 1. the following eight months he successfully pros- ecuted the number named in fendant in each case was fined. the following statement and the de- Profession Number Fined The fact that four of the professions have contributed very little the support of the Bureau has caused a hesitation in spend- funds for prosecutions for violations of those four prac- acts. The professions that have contributed — which contribu- are made largely through the payment of annual registration objected to the use of the funds in aid of the four pro- not contributing. The fairness of this contention will be Ihiropractic 5 •entistry 3 ledicine &amp; Surgery 3 'harmacy .......... 58 'otal 6 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE 43 BUREAU OF CHILD WELFARE Mrs. Emily P. Homberger, Chief It- is the duty of the Child Welfare Bureau to investigate cases reported to it and to assist in the care of dependent, neglected, abused, abandoned, defective and delinquent children. Indolent parents who are content to live in dirt and with poor, ill smelling, sleeping accommodations cannot raise alert and healthy children. During the habit forming period the way a child lives affects the way he feels and this in turn affects his individuality. When the home environment prevents the child from growing into sound manhood, then every effort should be made to improve the surroundings. When all efforts to strengthen the home have failed and a child must be removed, then a great responsibility rests upon the organization that takes him; for it is encumbent upon that organ - ization to evolve methods for the child's development that will com - pensate him, so far as may be, for the immeasurable loss of his own home. The ties of love in the ordinary home mean more to an af - fectionate child than do material comforts. This Bureau works with homes that lack parental control and with the children from homes wrecked by divorce or desertion and by the mental or moral breakdown of one of the parents. However difficult this reconstruction, we try to remember that the children of today are the citizens of tomorrow and as we strive to make strong the superstructure we often tremble for the founda - tion that has been started in childhood by inefficient hands and that is liable to show fatal defects later because of the inferior workman - ship. Poverty alone should never be the vital reason for removing a child from his home. A wise and honorable father and a good and kind mother are the richest possessions a child can have and when misfortune strikes a home thus endowed it should be left intact. We hear much about taxes and the curtailment of expenses; but we question the economy that fails properly to care for boys and girls who as a consequence, through no fault of their own, are likely to become incapacitated by lack of opportunity. The children of the feeble-minded, grown to manhood without custodial care, will in- </seg>
            <seg id="p044"/>
            <seg id="p045">45 DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE Assisted in miscellaneous cases.. 31 JUVENILE COURTS The Child Welfare Bureau has worked with district and county judges in thirty-seven counties and appreciates thoroughly the fine cooperation given by these judges, as well as that given by the county attorneys of the state. Desertion, non-support, divorce, hasty marriages and illegitimacy put a real burden upon the juvenile courts of the state. The judges have long since learned to use our investigators to get the facts in any case before them. A good investigator must have a genuine love of people, a desire to be of service to them, and the ability to work out their problems. It is the faculty of being able to put one's self in the other's place, rather than technical knowledge, that makes the ideal investigator. TYPICAL CASES The C family living in a rural section of the state furnish typical case of feeble-mindedness. Both the father and mother have the mentality of eight or nine year old children. Tet under the Clubs 6 Nurses 16 Physicians 1 6 Officially 16? m These cases were settled: kBy correspondence 159 By contact 21 2 «, The children involved in these cases may be classified as: Neglected or dependent 671 Delinquent 118 Feeble-minded 71 Otherwise afflicted 26 886 &gt;perated with officials: District Judges ~ 20 &lt; County Judges 37 &lt; County Attorneys 71 &lt; cases cases </seg>
            <seg id="p046">REPORT OF THE laws of our state, these grown-up children were permitted to marry and the mother has given birth to twelve children, ten of whom are living. This family presented all the problems which go with the un - ervised feeble-minded, — poverty, neglect, filth, dishonesty and ;y. The two oldest daughters were mothers of illegitimate the one having given birth to her first child at the age of fourteen years, PThe entire family were in need of institutional care, which it was impossible to give owing to crowded conditions in our state institu - tions. This case was brought into court; the four members of the family a need for custodial care was most apparent, were sent to our Institution for Feeble-minded and an attempt was made to the four younger children placed in an orphanage. Because of mentality, the orphanage refused to receive them. They were, therefore, left in the home for the present, with the hope that in the near future adequate provision may be made for the care of all such unfortunate children. In an isolated part of the state a family consisting of father, mother, and five children lived in the greatest poverty. It is hard to imagine more wretched conditions than those under which this family lived. The oldest child was a helpless cripple, confined to a wheel chair scarcely able to lift his hand to his face. The mother had be - b discouraged and had seemingly lost whatever pride and am - m she may have possessed in an earlier day. The responsibility family rested lightly upon the father, he evidently feeling would in some way be cared for without effort on his part. During the preceding winter the family had frequently been re - ted by neighbors as being in a starving, freezing condition; on one occasion they 1 With the approach had nothing in the way of food but parched corn, t of another winter county officials declared them- Ives unwilling to send further aid to a man who was too shiftless even attempt to provide for his family, and asked that the children removed to an institution. worker from the Bureau of Child Welfare, in company with workers, visited this home and in talking over with the mother is for the future, learned of a sister' who might be interested in children. Correspondence was started with this sister who lived a distant state and the problem was solved in a most satisfactory </seg>
            <seg id="p047">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 47 manner. The sister possessed ambition and initiative, as well as little home and was not only willing, but anxious, to take the mother and children under her supervision; thus working out a practical plan whereby they would be able to live comfortably, and the chil- dren have good school advantages. This arrangement provided tor the family, leaving the father to shift for himself. Up in the sand hill country a high school boy of sixteen years, born with club feet, was discovered by a worker from the Bureau of Child Welfare. The parents of the boy were too poor to afford hospital and surgeon's fees and the boy had been allowed to grow up carrying this handicap. The family did not realize that the State of Nebraska has made provision for the cure of children so afflicted. Application for this boy's admission was made to the Orthopedic Hospital and in due time the lad arrived, underwent a successful operation and has now returned to his home. All this was done with- out expense to the family. CHILDREN PLACED DURING THE BIEXXIUM A summary of the reports received from Juvenile Courts show3 that: 60 counties placed or committed 507 children; 23 counties did not place or commit any children; 10 counties did not report. DISPOSITION OP CHILDREN BY THE JUVENILE COURTS Girls Boys Committed to Girls Industrial School 55 Committed to York Reformatory 6 Committed to Nebraska Industrial Home 6 Placed in private institutions 29 24 Placed in Institution for Feeble-minded 12 23 Committed to Boys' Industrial School 48 Placed in private homes 96 82 Placed in Home for Dependent Children 44 58 Paroled 15 9 Totals 263 244 Grand Total 507 </seg>
            <seg id="p048"/>
            <seg id="p049">• DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 49 Feeble- . Speech County minded Crippled Deaf Blind Defect Franklin 7 5 12 0 0 Frontier •... 0 6 12 0 Furnas 5 0 3 0 0 Gage 5 13 12 0 0 Garden 0 2 0 0 0 Garfield 0 0 10 Gosper 3 3 5 0 0 Grant 0 0 0 0 0 Greeley 2 3 10 0 Hall 7 25 1 1 3 Hamilton 7 9 7 0 0 Harlan ... '. 3 0 5 0 1 Hayes 1 0 0 0 0 Hitchcock 2 10 0 0 Holt 2 6 5 0 0 Hooker 0 0 0 0 0 Howard „ 7 15 3 1 0 Jefferson 12 10 0 Johnson 2 3 10 0 Kearney 7 8 2 0 Keith 9 1 0 0 0 Keya Paha 0 0 0 0 0 Kimball 0 10 0 0 Knox 7 6 12 0 Lancaster 7 34 3 5 0 Lincoln 4 4 4 4 0 Logan 0 0 0 0 0 Loup 2 0 0 0 McPherson 0 0 0 0 0 Madison 5 4 2 0 0 Merrick 7 11 2 1 0 Morrill 1 .. 3 0 Nance 4 4 1 o Nemaha 5 3 5 0 0 Nuckolls 5 15 6 0 0 Otoe 2 0 110 Pawnee 5 2 0 0 Perkins 4 7 0 2 Phelps 4 11 0 0 Platte 6 8 2 6 3 Pierce 9 9 1 0 0 Polk 1 7 1 1 l Red Willow 2 _ 2 0 0 Richardson 13 110 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 REPORT OF THE Feeble- Speech County minded Crippled Deaf Blind Defect by the Child Welfare Bureau to assist these chil- wherever they are in need of help and to notify the parents of Subdivision "c" of Section 6508 of the Compiled Statutes of Ne- for 1922 provides that "All persons of from seven to twenty of age who are residents of this state, and who by reason of or total blindness or deafness are unable to obtain an educa- in the public, private, denominational or parochial schools of shall under the provisions of this act be required to attend the blind or the school for the deaf, until graduated by the superintendent of such school unless such per- being privately or otherwise educated, or unless by reason of or physical incapacity they are not subjects for admission to roblem of the defective children in Nebraska is becoming one. They are found in every county and the Bureau is </seg>
            <seg id="p051">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 51 constantly being asked to help place them. The Institution at Beatrice is crowded and it is not possible to care for all of the mentally de - fective there. This class is in need of constant supervision although all do not need the close custodial care given by the Institution. Many subnormal children cannot receive proper instruction in public schools. This has been recognized in some of the cities by the opening of 'opportunity rooms.' Here the child can be taught and advanced according to his capacities. It is unfair, both to the pre - cocious child and to the subnormal child, to attempt to teach them together. Then the subnormal child is usually incapable of any great mental development and he needs to be taught some industry that is suited to his mental and physical capacity. When properly taught many a subnormal child can be made self-supporting if given the needed supervision. A reference to the table heretofore given shows , that the census enumerators in 1925 and 1926 reported four hundred forty-five mentally defective children to the Child Welfare Bureau. This is a little more than half the number now in the Home for Feeble-minded. It is certain that the sum of these two fails to cover the number of feeble-minded in Nebraska at this time. MATERNITY HOMES AND LYING-IN HOSPITALS The Bureau has been assigned the work of visitation and super - vision of Maternity Homes and Lying-in Hospitals. This work comes within the purview of the Sheppard-Towner Act relating to infancy and maternity. At this time there are ninety-four Lying-in Hospitals and eleven Maternity Homes in the state. These lying-in hospitals and maternity homes must all secure a license from the Department of Public Welfare. The work of licensing them has been assigned to the Bureau of Child Welfare; before they are licensed they are in - spected by a representative of that Bureau. This inspection takes place annually and the institutions that measure up to the standards fixed are given a license for one year. During the biennium rules and regulations for the government of these hospitals and homes were adopted. These rules fix a minimum standard for their equipment. The standards were made low enough so that any ordinary home will not be overburdened in equipping to meet them. At the same time, they require a reasonable amount of equipment. These lying-in hos - pitals and maternity homes make a monthly report to the Bureau. All births are required to be reported promptly and blanks are fur - nished which outline the data to be given. It appears from the re - ports that during the biennium 4,388 boys were born in these institutions, of whom 4,194 were legitimate and 194 were illegitimate; that 3,985 girls were born in them, of whom 3,830 were legitimate and 155 illegitimate. </seg>
            <seg id="p052"/>
            <seg id="p053">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 53 BUREAU OF HEALTH W. H. Wilson, M. D., Chief Soon after the beginning of the biennium, the Chief of the Bureau of Health made application to the United States Public Health Service, and was appointed Collaborating Epidemiologist to that Serv - ice. This carried with it the franking privilege, thereby making a material saving to the Bureau in the matter of postage. All letters and pamphlets pertaining to health have been franked as a result of this privilege. Lectures were given in both the Medical Colleges at Omaha on state medicine and hygiene. The Bureau of Health as at present organized has six divisions, as follows: Epidemiology, Child Hygiene, Laboratories, Venereal Diseases or Social Hygiene, Vital Statistics and Sanitary Engineering. Four of these have directors as their executive officers. Two of them, Epidemiology and Sanitary Engineering, have no individual head but are supervised by the Chief of the Bureau. The work in Epidemi - ology is carried on by the Chief with the assistance of P. H. Bartholo - mew, M. D., who has done most of the field work. Assistance is given to all communities which ask for aid in diagnosing any pre - vailing epidemic. Nebraska is an unusually healthy state; however, it occasionally has an epidemic which could be avoided if better sanitary measures were employed. The following table will show the extent of contagious diseases within this state during the years 1925 and 1926. CONTAGIOUS DISEASES REPORTED TO THE BUREAU Disease 1925 1926 Chickenpox 805 1,194 Meningitis C. S 12 13 Mumps 321 301 [phtheria ncephalitis Lethargic 425 "I rysipelas • srman Measles .fiuenza easles 5 193 97 i </seg>
            <seg id="p054">REPORT OF THE 1925 1926 1925 1926 Oph. Naonatorum Paratyphoid Fever Pellagra Pneumonia Poliomyelitis Rabies Scarlet Fever „ Septic Sore Throat Sleeping Sickness Smallpox Tetanus Tracoma Tuberculosis Typhoid Fever Whooping Cough Total 1 2 41 125 1 851 5 5 831 9 1 201 94 496 4,521 2,069 20 1 224 144 915 7,761 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 55 Rules and Regulations ». 4681 1973 ■•■*■ Pamphlets on Diphtheria &amp; Scarlet Fever 289 School Reports Received 2465 3578 PUBWCATIONS PREPARED FOR DISTRIBUTION* Rules and Regulations relating to Sanitation, Quarantine and School Inspection 10,000 copies Rules and Regulations relating to Distinterment of Human Bodies 2,000 copies Pamphlet on Diphtheria and Scarlet Fever 5,000 copies • </seg>
            <seg id="p056"/>
            <seg id="p057">DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC WELFARE 57 With a high degree of cooperation upon the part of the medical profession reports show a decline in the number of new cases of venereal disease. This is attributed to several factors: better and more adequate treatment of cases; earlier detection of sources, thus affording an opportunity to render them non-infectious and less of a menace; better cooperation from local authorities; sustained dis - semination of correct information concerning the disease. The last factor mentioned is a very important one. The method of reporting cases by key number rather than by name is considered the preferable procedure. The agitation for re - porting primarily by name has ceased. STATISTICAL SUMMARY OF CASES REPORTED Disease 1925 1926 Male Female Total Male Female Total During the biennium there were over 16,000 doses of arsephenamina products distributed for the treatment of syphilis in clinics, institu - tions and to indigents. Approximately 19,000 treatments were admin - istered for syphilis. A total of over 60,000 visits made by patients is an indication of the effectiveness of educational efforts in im - pressing upon them the importance of adequate treatment. For the purpose of brevity figures and percentages which, with - out detailed analysis, might be misleading have been omitted from this report. These are available, however, for those interested. Venereal diseases are controllable — their elimination depends upon recognition of this fact with individual and collective cooperation. ronorrhea inorrl yphilis lhancroid 718 52 393 2 1111 54 540 49 343 1 S83 50 Total 64 862 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF THE DIVISION OF LABORATORIES I*. O. Vose, M. 8c., Director I The laboratory is a Division of the Bureau of Health and is main - tained for the purpose of aiding the prevention of infectious and communicable disease. During the year 1925 Miss Lila B. Love was Director of the Division, L. O. Vose taking up the work January 1, ■ 1926. The personnel of the laboratory consists of the Director, a technician, a laboratory assistant giving halt time, and a stenographer. The work of the laboratory includes examinations to aid in the diagnosis of infectious and communicable diseases; examinations to ■ determine freedom from the infectious agent prior to release from quarantine; examinations for the detection of "carriers" of infectious agents and of examinations of water, sewage and ice. The specimens examined during the period reported herein were submitted by free clinics, State Institutions, Federal Institutions within the state, local Boards of Helath, schools and practicing During the year 1925 nine hundred thirty-two and in the first nine months of the year 1926 nine hundred nineteen practicing physicians furnished approximately half of the specimens examined. The remainder of the specimens came from sources as mentioned above. During 1925 water samples of public supplies were received from eighty-four cities and villages of the state and in the first nine months of 1926 from eighty-nine cities and villages. Containers and directions for the submitting of specimens are furnished by the laboratory, as well as information relative to the interpretation or significance of the various examinations made. The following table classifies the examinations made during the period from 1920 to 1926, inclusive EXAMINATION 1920 1921 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 blood 6699 10779 11420 12845 16438 16769 16481 115 161 207 318 437 422 466 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 59 EXAMINATION 1920 1921 EXAMINATION 1920 1921 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 82 74 117 121 160 Blood tests — Blood tests — Gonorrhea 55 86 Gonorrhea 55 86 82 74 117 121 160 Smears-Gonococci .... 1157 1495 Smears-Gonococci .... 1157 1495 1628 1502 1415 1849 2762 162S 1502 1415 1849 2762 535 5 28 4 745 Misc. Venereal 137 325 Misc. Venereal 137 325 535 5 28 4 745 Blood cultures 2 46 Blood cultures 2 46 22 47 14 7 35 22 47 14 7 35 Agglutination tests 133 416 Agglutination tests 133 416 447 275 237 243 316 447 275 237 243 316 Blood tests for T. B. 70 60 Blood tests for T. B. 70 60 60 42 47 73 244 60 42 47 73 244 Faeces for Parasites 1 0 Faeces for Parasites 1 0 0 7 115 0 7 115 Faeces — Faeces — Bacteriological 7 76 Bacteriological 7 76 39 10 22 43 45 39 10 22 43 45 B. Diphtheria 1560 8053 B. Diphtheria 1560 8053 7361 6414 6746 2054 2094 7361 6414 6746 2054 2094 40 41 20 4 28 Cultures — Meningococci 382 115 Cultures — Meningococci 382 115 40 41 20 4 28 Sputum for T. B 504 560 Sputum for T. B 504 560 461 477 445 438 490 461 477 445 438 490 Misc. Infections 141 176 Misc. Infections 141 176 109 136 126 213 24S 109 136 126 213 24S Water — Bacteriological .... 755 888 Water — Bacteriological .... 755 888 1246 1389 1152 1118 1433 68 39 26 14 33 1246 1389 1152 1118 1433 Water — San. Chemical .... 85 151 Water — San. Chemical .... 85 151 68 39 26 14 33 Ice — Bacteriological 2 8 Ice — Bacteriological 2 8 4 7 11 18 17 4 7 11 18 17 Other examinations 9 4 Other examinations 9 4 0 0 0 13 18 0 0 0 13 18 Totals 11814 23499 23729 23628 27282 23404 25620 Examinations as shown in the following table were made during the year 1925 and the first nine months of 1926: 1925 1926 EXAMINATION Posi- Unsatis- Total Posi- Unsatis- Total tive factory tive factory tive factory Wassermann tests (blood) 3467 493 16769 2718 346 12370 Wassermann tests C. S. F. .. 110 33 422 140 13 366 Comp. Fix. for Gonorrhea.. 14 11 121 30 3 194 Smears for Gonococci 474 15 1849 617 5 2066 Miscellaneous Venereal 0 0 4 0 0 549 Blood Cultures 0 0 7 4 0 21 Widals 54 1 243 54 0 257 Comp. Fix. for Tuberculosis 18 2 73 76 4 157 Stools for Parasites 0 0 10 0 2 Stools Bacteriological 1 0 43 1 0 29 Cultures for B. Diphtheria 307 132 2054 147 16 1211 Cultures for Meningococci 1 0 4 3 0 26 Sputum for Tubercle Bacilli 42 1 438 54 0 393 Miscellaneous — </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 REPORT OF THE 1925 1926 EXAMINATION Posi- Unsatis- Total Posi- Unsatis- Total tive factory tlve factory Infectious DiB 0 0 213 0 0 180 Water, Bacteriological . :.. 306 0 1118 327 0 1055 Water, Chemical 0 0 14 0 0 12 Ice, Bacteriological 0 0 18 0 0 13 Other examinations 0 0 13 0 0 13 Totals 4794 688 23404 4171 387 18814 The number of negative reactions are not given in the foregoing table but may be found by subtracting the sum of the positive and unsatisfactory columns from the total. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p061">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 61 DIVISION OF VITAL STATISTICS Hattie M. Summers, Director A monthly or even a quarterly bulletin would be of great benefit to this Division in order that the public might be better advised as to the service which is available. People should become familiar with the many ways in which the certificates and statistics are of benefit to them. The Nebraska law requiring the recording of births and deaths did not take effect until 1905. The question constantly comes up of how to handle births and deaths which took place prior to that date. It would seem advisable that some law be enacted to make official any record made in due form covering these earlier births and deaths. We do accept them at this time, but our acts in that regard have no official authority. Provision should also be made to secure the data along this line in the offices of the local registrars. This would more especially apply to Omaha and Lincoln. There should also be some provision for securing from the local registrar the record of any particular birth or death upon request of the Director, without waiting for the monthly report. A field director would be of great advantage to this Division, as a means of putting it in personal contact with the local registrars Ed others having to do with vital statistics; such an official would of considerable assistance in enforcing obedience to the provisions the vital statistics law and the rules of the Department. It would seem from the mistakes made by the doctors in their returns that that profession does not appreciate the necessity of accuracy. Frequently we must guess at the name of the mother and they are careless even as to the spelling of the surname and giving the date of birth; quite often the wrong sex is given. Mistakes like these cause complications and a large amount of extra expense in getting necessary corrections. The Director very much wishes there </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OP THE re is a great demand for certified copies of the records, especi - birth and death certificates. At one time a charge was made for these copies. Later the statute was amended and, whether that I was the intention or not, the interpretation has been made that no charge could be made for any certified copies. The result is that the privilege of securing free copies has led to a great abuse and entails a needless amount of work upon the office force. The Director recommends that a fee be charged as is done in most of the other states. It might be advisable to make some exceptions, as is done now in the statute, the legislature evidently understanding that a fee was usually paid for a certified copy. We are unable to get from the clerks of the district courts, the ■mation desired in divorce actions, which is entirely along the required by the Federal Census Bureau. As a matter of fact, of the ordinary divorce suit would not give the informa- vhich the federal authorities ask of us, and the only way the of the court can get such information is by inquiries outside Some provisions should be made for the securing of this This information could be secured by the clerk at the time divorce is granted and recorded in a book kept for that pur- same course could be taken by a county judge issuing license. Iowa gets the information In this way. ig the biennium the Division has made a considerable saving postage and in clerical help by the introduction of better ods. This has included the adoption of the certificate of registra - recommended by the Federal Census Bureau, which we are frank; also the use of cards and form letters. The folio w- SAVING OP POSTAGE THROUGH FRANKING PRIVILEGES On Certificates of Registration $ 631.30 On Name Cards and on Postal Cards 321.28 $1,030.22 ring the biennium the following improvements have been made work of the Division: A card index of local registrars and undertakers is kept. This is valuable as a means of checking up on delayed reports. If re- i not received promptly, a postal card is sent to the de - individual. A printed data postal card has been evolved and is used to </seg>
            <seg id="p063">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 63 Form letters of instruction are sent to local registrars. Each volume of birth and death certificates is plainly marked with the month and year, which facilitates file searching. We have refused to accept certificates made in lead pencil. We have increased our use of the Hollerith tabulating ma- chine to meet the demand for reports and statistics. The following tables show some of the activities of the Division: Certified Copies Letters Year Births Deaths General Form 1921 307 197 2224 1180 1922 385 292 6476 1591 1923 358 398 6438 1624 1924 372 484 2984 1546 1925 775 561 6995 3321 1926 1200 600 3350 6946 Mailed Disinterment Franked Cards Packages Permits Sent to Secure Supplies Child's Name 1921 1462 185 14171 1922 1114 185 12803 1923 1168 112 11422 1924 1122 100 13487 1925 1759 225 14546 1926 1658 326 17997 The following tables give the births and deaths as reported: 1924 1925 Total Births* 30,036 29,179 Attended by Physicians 29,361 28,581 Attended by Midwives 521 478 Attended by others 154 120 Hospital Births 3,769 4,377 ♦Exclusive of Stillbirths. NUMBER AND CAUSES OF DEATHS DUE TO CHILDBIRTH 1924 1925 Accidents of pregnancy 1 0 Abortion 21 10 Ectopic gestation 8 5 Others under this title 6 9 Puerperal hemorrhage 21 18 Other accidents of labor, Cesarean section 5 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p064"/>
            <seg id="p065">65 DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 65 Ulcer of Stomach &amp; Duodenum 56 71 Diarrhea &amp; Enteritis 287 363 Appendicitis &amp; Typhlitis 244 245 Hernia &amp; Intestinal Obstruction 200 137 Nephritis (Acute &amp; Chrenic) 759 752 Diseases of the Prostate 94 61 The Puerperal State 146 160 Malformations, Hydrocephalus &amp; Congenital 153 177 Senility _ 487 228 Early Infancy: Congenital Debility, Icterus &amp; Sclerema 185 139 Pmniiitiini DlrtVi ATR EA1 Premature Birth 476 504 Injury at Birth 35 80 Suicides: (All Forms) 160 172 TTnmirirlM; I All Fnrm^ K* Kfi Homicides: (All Forms) 52 56 Accidents : Railroad Accidents 64 73 Street Car Accidents 3 6 Automobile Accidents 127 125 Excessive Heat 6 24 Excessive Cold 1 4 Legal Electrocution 0 1 1923 1925 Total Deaths Reported* 12,620 12,475 •Exclusive of Stillbirths. BIRTHS AND DEATHS BV COUNTIES 1923-1025 1923 1925 1923 1925 COUNTY Births Births Deaths Deaths Adams (Hastings Excluded) .... 190 191 159 146 Hastings 308 337 197 182 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 REPORT OF THE 1494 109K 1923 1925 COUNTY Births Births Deaths Deaths ■ Cedar 445 399 Chase 133 . 121 105 100 48 32 Cherry 212 200 Cheyenne 261 269 Clay 322 256 Caming 299 294 Custer 614 626 Dakota 204 200 Dawes 229 212 Dawson 367 377 Deuel 59 80 Dixon 267 241 Douglas (Omaha Excluded) 176 184 Omaha 4893 4918 Dundy 140 136 Fillmore 248 250 84 67 58 83 133 115 98 79 134 132 ' 195 208 72 56 68 76 133 131 18 82 73 231 222 69 57 2696 2810 28 42 109 107 Franklin 202 222 Frontier 200 173 Furnas 291 278 Gage 627 621 Garden 115 130 Garfleld , 93 83 Gosper 121 97 Grant 55 41 Greeley 233 192 Hall (Grand Island Excluded) .. 142 169 Grand Island 358 373 Hamilton 295 296 Harlan 234 230 . 88 90 47 46 109 111 321 352 252 225 Hayes 60 75 Hitchcock 161 175 Holt 409 392 Hooker 29 23 Howard : 251 229 Jefferson 338 311 Johnson 196 184 Kearney 180 152 Keith .?. 138 136 Keya Paha „ 84 65 Kimball 96 110 Knox 422 410 Lancaster (Lincoln Excluded) .. 597 578 14 17 44 59 125 129 96 65 172 153 83 78 86 79 33 45 27 11 33 32 286 32 2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">• DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 67 1923 1925 1923 1925 COUNTY Births Births Deaths Deaths Lincoln 1392 1318 699 781 Lincoln (North Platte Excluded) 245 272 58 72 North Platte 261 220 128 119 Logan 37 35 19 10 Loup 38 16 12 8 McPherson 21 23 4 7 Madison 556 545 283 301 Merrick 225 229 98 82 Morrill 207 264 55 59 Nance 230 232 71 75 Nemaha 232 253 116 106 Nuckolls 315 277 111 110 Otoe 385 358 190 156 Pawnee 213 219 76 96 Perkins 105 124 27 20 Phelps 179 214 87 89 Pierce 293 276 75 76 Platte 562 526 187 195 Polk 235 187 67 80 Red Willow 286 355 89 119 Richardson 403 .381 182 161 Rock 79 71 20 14 Saline 317 308 138 138 Sarpy 154 147 53 55 Saunders 406 362 175 162 Scotts Bluff 608 637 167 177 Seward 407 379 176 145 Sheridan 239 214 63 70 Sherman 212 213 68 52 Sioux 76 51 24 16 Stanton 170 162 41 31 Thayer 328 270 113 132 Thomas 40 32 9 5 Thurston 309 277 126 147 Valley 218 186 68 60 Washington 234 218 125 102 Wayne 220 220 84 62 Webster 247 222 107 89 Wheeler 61 54 18 15 York 368 349 186 171 TOTAL 30,171 29,179 12,621 12,475 </seg>
            <seg id="p068"/>
            <seg id="p069">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WELFARE 69 investigation indicates that about thirty per cent of the defects have been corrected. In the examination of children, local doctors and dentists gave freely of their time and it would have been impossible to do the work successfully without their free assistance. Miss Witchen rendered splendid and effective service and the interest and desire for improvement which she aroused will stimulate the establishment of permanent spring conferences in many counties. While we have had splendid cooperation from many physicians, others have been slow to realize the great advantage these health conferences are to a community. Each autumn numerous conferences have been held at County Fairs. This is the only means of reaching some parents. During the summer and fall of 1926 we gave two and three weeks' time of a nurse in isolated communities where the infant death rate is high. In McPherson County at the end of a three weeks' campaign, a Child Health Conference was held at the county seat and fifty children were present for examination. The one resident physician gave splendid cooperation. In another county, Hooker, forty-six children were examined. Thomas and Scotts Bluff Counties were visited in the late fall and winter and similar results were obtained. DISTRIBUTION OF LITERATURE Ninety-two of the ninety-three counties of Nebraska are receiving the free bulletins distributed by this Division. This is the only con - tact which we have with some of the counties. A questionnaire was sent out in 1925 to the doctors of the state to the number of 1453. It is a source of much regret that few of the doctors responded, as the information sought would have been of material assistance in helping alleviate conditions. The questions related to puerperal in - fection, to stillborn babies and to care of babies dying under one month. The answers to the question relating to puerperal in - fection indicate that a majority of the mothers did not receive proper pre-natal care and that of those who did receive care, a majority did not intelligently carry out directions. In the case of stillborn babies, the answers indicate that four - teen had received pre-natal care of from one week to eight months, while thirty-three had not received any pre-natal care; and that twenty-nine of this class of mothers had borne only one child, while twenty-seven had borne more than one. </seg>
            <seg id="p070"/>
            <seg id="p071">DEPARTMENT OP I SANITARY ENGINEERING \V. H. Wilson, M. 1)., Acting Director. For some five years prior to 1923, the Bureau of Health had a division with a sanitary engineer as its executive head. Since June, 1923, no such engineer has been appointed although every other state in the union having an efficient Bureau of Health employs one or more sanitary engineers. The Department's Rules and Regulations relating to Sanitation, Quarantine, and School Inspection, adopted July 1, 1925, commencing at page 128, gives an outline of the duties imposed upon such an officer. Among others these duties included: 1. An examination and approval of plans for waterworks, sewage </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 REPORT OF THE</seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>