<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908 TO HON. GEO. L. SHELDON, GOVERNOR AND THE HONORABLE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">■Hlh.Wl.1L REPORT at The Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FOR PERIOD ENDING \()l h.MBh.K TO HON. GEO. L. SHELDON, GOVERNOR \\i&gt; nil. HONORABLE BOARD OF ITBI.IC LANDS AND BUILDINGH </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SH. M. Eaton. . . . Load &lt; ommistioner, ( nairman (iK«&gt;. ('. .IiNKiN &gt;«'iretarv of B( \V. T. Thomi-smn Attorney (leneral L (i. Hkmn . Stato Treasurer --*■*■■ ■ 1 . I. BCRG1C \1. STAFF l.MKn. M. I). . Orthojjedic Surgeon and Sup't. H. \\ INNKTT ()HH. M. I) VL'RSES Anna K. Hakdwick . Head N Minnie Vandehflute N (iladys Turner.... n - Adele Barnes .. Nurse P f A D A A X' n O 17 ■ V 1 1 1..-C I i\ \ .~\ .&gt; it u r. L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Lincoln, ! ..t. Nov. :-&gt;u. iimiv Bl Honorable (Jeorge L Sheldon. Governor, and to the Hoi ble Board of Public Lands and Buildings: Bentlemen — In compliance with the statutes, the -■ al report is herewith submitted. Very respectfully, .1. P. Lord, Superintendent and Orthopedic Surgi H. \V. Oku. Assistant. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">c p .;■ r* 1 i i *3 i t ! . .. i b L^aL </seg>
            <seg id="p005">wax designed to provide hospital care for the crippled and deformed of this state who by such hospital treatment might be converted counties from which they came another mijiht liecoii ■ from wards of the municipals into individuate who in one way n taining and independent. provided thai it should lie The law creating the Hospit located at the Home for the Friendless in Lincoln and specifiei certain other conditions under which the work of the Hospital waa to lie done. A sum of $10,000 was appropriated for the establish inent of the Hospital and for maintenance during the first twi It was found necessary to spend practically one-half of th&lt; amount during l!»&lt;).-&gt; under the direction of the Hoard of Lands am Buildings in providing quarters in the hoy's dormitory at the Horn for the Friendless. The basement and part of the first floor wen remodelled in such a way that fairly satisfactory quarters were ob tained and on October 1. 1905 the work of the Hospital was begun your Board and to the Governor f the first fourteen months of the reviewed and a program for the Lin the report submitted t ■mber W. 1908 the work nee of the Hospital v needing biennium pro) Briefly during the first f irteen months the otiict Hospital were able to report a total number of patients applying for treatment at the Hospital of (1&lt;&gt;6) one hundred and -i\. eighty - one of these patients were accepted and received treatment in the ital for varying lengths of time. The amount of work .lorn- k don* at the Hospital during the first fourteen months may !&gt;e rep. in the following way: euppoang each patient in the Hospital for one day to represent a hospital day the report for the first foil months showed a total of 8,850 hospital days. This amoui work was accomplished in spite of the fact that during nun the time we were hampered not only by the fact that we were lulled to do our work in an incomplete building but the lack ot funds during the first biennium rendered it necessary tor us to do our work without such apparatus or hospital equipment as was reallv needed. The present report up to November .SO. 1908, represe: fore, the work of the Hospital for the first complete biennium ot its </seg>
            <seg id="p006">382 STATISTICAL FORM FOR STATE INSTITUTIONS PREPARED IN ACCORDANCE WITH A RESOLUTION OF THE NATIONAL PERENCE OK CHARITIES AND CORRECTION, ADOPTED MAY 15, 1906 rMK OF INSTITUTION NEBRASKA ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL NOVEMBER 30, 1906 TO NOVEMBER M). 1908 Male Female Total Nunbtr of inmates present at lieginning of period 15 17 Nu in tier received during the period 72 79 Number discharged or died during period. . 70 72 142 Number at end of period 20 21 s Daily average attendance during period :ige numtier of officers and employe 8 EXPENDITURES Current Exp 1 Salaries and wages Clothing about $11.000. 00 None :&lt;. Subsistence about 1,000.00 4. Ordinary repairs •ffire. domestic, outdoor drags. . Total ■lordinarv Expenses — New buildings, land, etc 2. Permanent equipment and improvements to build- about $21,500.00 ings Total Grand Total I TIVE HEAD Dr. J. P. Lokp Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p007">383 Eie legislature of 1007 made generous provision for the work Hospital for the biennium just closed. In addition to an nev appropriation of $3,000 provided to close our first ending April 1, 1«»()7. the legislature set aside 146.000 I m for the biennium from April 1. l!tO7 to April 1. 1009. The following table shows the disposition of the funds appro - priated: The Board of Public I.auds and Buildings soon after tin journment of the legislature reapportioned the space in the build - &lt; cupied jointly by the Orthopedic Hospital and the Hon. the Friendles . niug to the Hospital the basement and the id and third floors of the building. This assignment of - rendered necessary very extensive alterations and improvements inasmuch as the second and third Boon had to be practical! tirelv rebuilt to render them suitable for hospital work. The rooms in the basement formerly used as a school and play room and the rooms occupied by the engineer and other men em - ployed at the Home for the Friendless were remodelled to make a children's dining-room, a nurses' dining-room and a diet kitchen. The space occupied by the x-ray room and the store-room was used as the beginning of the elevator shaft. The entire first floor of the building, including the first floor of the solarium, was vacated for the l&gt;enefit of the Home of the Friendless. Ehe entire second floor, including the second floor of the im which was extended up that far. was remodelled to make •rs for patients. The north end of the second floor was divided into two parts, the larger of which is used as a ward for girls and the smaller for boys. The solarium is also made to serve as a wait) for the tuberculous lied patients and contains about twelve l&gt;eds. Nurses' quarters anil rooms for the head nurse are also on this floor. All the inside bath rooms were torn out and four bath rooms Hal: Appn &gt;| &gt;ri;it ci I 1907 Expended November W. 1908 $12.&lt;MMI (Ml 19,156.00 S2.S44 (Ml Maintenance 27,000.00 25,291 •")&lt;» 1,708 11 Alterations and repain 7,000.00 6,923 tiT Emergency i Fund .. :h.(KH) (M( J.'lSt; M\ IS ti4 </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">built on this Boor, two Large ones for the two wards and &lt;&gt;nt for the nurses' quarters and for the head nu ■ The third floor of the building, formerly an unfinishi partitioned off into additional quarters for nurse-, room the other helpers in the work of the Hospital, store-r i detention ward. This Latter ward contains about ten beds ami ordinarily as sleeping quarters for the older hoys wh able to 1m- up and about during the day. In an emergency this ward can be used at a quarantine ward for patients Buffering communicable disease »r for the detention of newly arrived pal who have Ix-en exposed to disease which mighi be transmit!' the other children. It was found necessary to put a large sky-lighi in the i of this floor and the elevator shaft had to !&gt;&lt;■ extended some t &lt;&gt;r fourteen feet above the level of the roof. Finally the old FouikI to Ih&gt; in such condition that the entire building had I covered by a new tin roof. This third floor, however, when I pleted furnished an extremely valuable addition to our space with - out which the amount of work which has Keen done could not sibly have been accomplished. Among the alterations rendered necessary by the changi our building was the installation of an elevator. The work of the ital having been distributed from the basement to the third permission was obtained from the Hoard of Lands and Build - in electric elevator of the most modern type by a system of push buttons. This elevator not only dispi with the necessity for an elevator attendant, but is so const: that it is practically impossible for accidents to occur. The entire aiiism of control is automatic, so that a door can only In - opened at the floor at which the elevator is standing and tin cannot be moved except when all don Lghtly cl This elevator has now been in constant service for about five months during which time it has been most satisfactory and no mis.li; any character whatever has occurred. Upon completing the remodelling of the building, including painting and the installation of the elevator, on July 17, 1908, the Governor and the Hoard of Lands and Buildings together with a number of other friends of the Hospital were entertained at the Hospital at dinner. On this occasion the Hon. H. M Eaton, (hair - man of the Board of Lands and Building- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">386 ami a number of those present gave short after dinner talks, pleat ndomag the work to far done at the Hospital and encourag - ing the officers in their efforts to build up and develop the institu- Ob the Mine evening the building was thrown open to the general public and several hundred people availed themselves of the ort unity to inspect its interior. During the time that the alterations were in progress, which more than a year, the care of the children was rendered difficult. In spite of this, however, a considerable in&lt; in the number of patients cared for lias Keen made so that the ige nuinl)er of patients in the Hospital for the bienniuin just I has been thirty-two (.82) while the total number of bos - ported for the period is over 24,000. A corresponding increase has been made in the variety ami our work. The total number of patients received at the Hospital up to • tit time has been 226, while the number actually tn ispital in-patients during the past hiennium has been one hundred eight i I' The total number of operations performed at the Hospital the beginning ha.- lx-en one hundred thirty-five (135) which almost without exception resulted in extremely gratifying results. An important part of the work at the Hospital consists in the appli - n of plaster Paris dressings to maintain the correction of i of the deformities which we are called upon to treat. A review of this work for the bienniuin shows that a total number of three hundred eighty &lt;8S&lt;)) plaster dressings have been applied. The x-ray apparatus which was made a part of our equipment early in the history of the Hospital has proved a most valuable adjunct to our work. Especially during the last two years a con - siderable ntiml&gt;er of patients coining to the Hospital for treatment led conditions regarding whom, full information for uld not have l&gt;een obtained except by the use of this table apparatus. A large number of valuable x-ray negatives are now on file at the Hospital. These are very valuable not only as a record of our work but many which illustrate rare, unusual utions have a scientific value which deserves consideration. En effort also has !&gt;een made at the Hospital to preserve M praci record of deformities of the extremities by of plaster P A considerable number of these </seg>
            <seg id="p011">have now been collected making ■ comparison between th&gt; fortuities before operation and following the same. For information in detail regarding the conditions from whicl &gt;atients seek relief at the Hospital reference must be made to the able herewith. This shows a list of conditions arranged alpha &gt;etically together with a list of patients by number who have l&gt;eei xamined or treated. The table also indicates the age and m he patients, whether treated as in-patients or not, the number o &gt;laster Paris dressings applied, the results of treatment and the number of days of each patient in the Hospital. X i» i _ Adenitis. see tuberculosis Ankle sprain Kil (0 K 1 4.-&gt; »s 1 ■• I is K I) 0 n not treated 0 (I 0 not tn i) o &lt;&gt; \ \ I I 0 X Appendicitis Ann incision 209 :&lt;•") K Arthodesis. so*- club foot Bow legs X 4 0 X 22 1 H 1 M Club font, contrenital 101 9 M X 8 (• X X lti (i X 143 1(14 2 M 107 3 F 2 14 II X _» 10 (I X X 119 II K 130 (» M 0 0 0 not treated 0 1 7:&gt; 1 1 M x i.-&gt; x xx a» 190 14 M X 8 X X 199 1 M X 4 0 X 83 0 0 0 not treated 0 201 ii M C'lul) foot, paralytic. 2 8 ¥ (I (I 0 X 9 * * 0 0 0 * .t&lt;) 4 F 0 (I 0 X -'13 7t&gt; 13 F 0 t&gt; 0 X 148 77 15 F _&gt; 11' 0 X X .-&gt; F 0 1 0 X SI lti M 0 0 0 X 136 0 » o X 180 v _&gt;o r 1 ft 8 • , i | ' I a 3: * 1 I I'll x 2 - - - =. J149 4 M II 18 &lt;&gt; X t. Cancer of. !St&gt; :i&gt; FIX (I &lt;• X 1 t wound 1X1 .') f I ; 6 I 3 X 68 &gt;n 223 27 I X (l X X a 197 § M 0 0 0 X X HO palate 106 1 F X 0 0 X 110 1 M 3 0 0 XX 174 1 F 0 0 0 not treate.1 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">388 .4 7 5 i r 3 A K r. / c t * £ x X X s treated \ X " X treated X X 0 X X X s X X X X IS u * X X X X o (I X X 0 X -i treated treated 0 12 treated treated 0 0 0 X X X X 1 X treated X treated t reated J X X X 1 1 * * * § S-.S ? ur&gt; 13 F (i ) n llti s K X 21 (i 7 M X 8 0 X \M 25 F 0 0 () not 133 15 F X 10 0 16 II X _• 0 17 M II II (I not 10 M X I 0 216 5 M X I 0 iikI. roiigrnital . . 117 2 M X 1 0 190 * * (I (I II v-tM 202 7 M X 0 o 211 7 M 1 .') 0 Elbow, wet Tuboeul Ettmw dislocation .'17 10 F X 1 X X :&lt;_&gt; F X o o X His * * o o (i Pni(!*r. roin|Mninil frarturf 139 16 F X (I (I X Flat f 17* 11 F 0 is o 227 20 F . o o o i- in 141 23 F .' o X X 17.' is 1 o I o Heart disorRanic .'1.' 28 F (I 0 0 not .'1'.) 3 1 o o o Heroin Inguinal 1 lti M X 0 0 X 1_&gt;7 I M 0 0 (I not 142 1 M 0 0 0 not •iiri-mtal dislocation. 3 6 1 1 -i X X iJ :, M _' 6X X 113 8 F o () o not 157 :&lt; M o o o not Tubetvulo Hi.' t; M i not .'07 1.' 1 0 (I X 1.' F 0 o X ■M I 1 1 1 K-t'Cillosw 19.') l M X o o x ■ &gt;c&lt;-|&gt;li:ilu- 134 1 F 0 0 0 151 .' M 0 0 0 not Mi 1 * ■ Koee. Me Tufaercuk ho&lt;leniti&gt; MinwIUnwHis 128 _' M 0 0 0 not 137 F not 159 I6fl Paralysis, facial I'M S M 0 0 0 Paralysis .■■.■• ■ * * * </seg>
            <seg id="p013">f. 7 s X /. y ■j. it hi m it (i ii \ cjo :&lt;n in i n -' ii x \ * * 77 * * * * ii • 7* (I * ♦ n4 10 I 0 10 XX 115 :? 1- ii ii n \ X llii * * * * * ** • 11^ I-' I J in it \ X 121 .". 1 n !■_&gt;.•, * * * * * 131 -'_» i n o a x 132 * * 0 ii ii not treated n 133 * * : " * * * ni g m ii ii ii 152 2 M 0 0 I ii 1"&gt;4 X M ii ii II nol treated n Hit ( 1- i ii n ii ir,s • * ♦ * * • 173 • • 0 Iss 2 1 ii ii U X X 180 * . * ii it II nc ,i treated n 198 ****,, * * m J02 * * * * 205 6 M (i I ii Jll -'i:{ i \ \ 213 * * 61 I" \ 114 tpastir H\ * * * * 102 * * * * ** * 14 F X in M n_&gt; e .: ,i ii i 1 L'.&gt; 2-i ! •' 1 1 i ' X 114 136 _' :! ii ii n 158 9 &gt;J (i n (I in.! (i 100 \ 1' ll I) (l X X it.T 171 12 M o (i i) \ X 177 IS M _' 1-' (i X 1 ii ii X 21ii 12 .1 ti n ii 211 t I &lt;i (i 0 nut treated it 215 .'."&gt; K (I (i n ii &gt;i treated u 221 2 1 (t I) o X X -.':; .' F ii li I) X X I.) F X t) 0 X X ParalvM ParalVsi Paralysi spiiia liilula npinal hemor tuber 111 6 I' 0 ii n n &gt;• treated u S2 * * * * * * * !!.-&gt; 14 ii II II (I \ 19.S 8 M ii _' ii XX 212 ivcliia 17f. 19 F X (i li X 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">1 , I % ! i If i -. I ± as z ■-', i fc I I - - -I - ft E fc j s | J-l g § 111 it:il .lilor 2IM&gt; |J M \ J X XX 1J&lt;| •litis |s 1 ****** • 14»i I ! M X 0 II X 1 147 I M X 0 (I X 1 149 • * X * (I X * rvical ghuMk 194 * * 0 I) (I * * * -'211 .') M X I) I) X X || &gt;ov. 114 I) M X s O X X M.i i|&gt; IS 16 M X 1 X X X 29 17 M X 17 X X 71 7 K (I 4 X X :«4 &gt; * * ♦ * * * (»4 9 F .1 '.) X X X :&gt;ttl 103 8 M 0 1(1 X X 111 11 F (I (i X X lil' IS M 0 •"&gt; X X X 123 8 I (I .■» X X X 14.-&gt; Us 4 F (I &lt;i X X X I7u Ht3 7 F 0 0 X not treated n ls«i 8 1 o :i X X X 191 ti M o _' X X X 216 _&gt;&lt;&gt;:&lt; ") Mo I \ X .'is :&gt; M (i l X X X Tulierculosi.v humerua 29 * * * * * * • rculosLs kne&lt;' 114****'* ♦ * 12(1 K) M 2 -i X X X »77 ulnionary !« 26 F 0 1 X X l.Vi Km Hi M 0 (I II not treated 0 Tuberculosis, sarcoiliac 17!) SI F 0 1 X X 72 Tul«erTiilo*iv spine 24 ti F 0 7 X XX 717 W 17 M 0 0 (I X 7 t»2 7 F I 1 X X X 7(1 ,s-_&gt; ***** * * 9.5 * * * * * * * Kiy***** ♦* * 1 4() * * * * * * * * 155 15 K t) 0 O not treated II 193 ***** * * * 225 »•**♦ ** * l&gt;ia 33 ***** * * 156 8 M (I II I) not treated II 182 14 M X IX- X X 204 11 F X IX X aw • ! • • * •His tU 16 M II (I X X X 27 Total No. 2 years. 1.519. T&gt;tal N I ot \&gt;st\enl&lt;. Hi: Ffnmle. 74: Male. 72. ■:t£e age. 10 years. H(m treated, 10X. Vvermge </seg>
            <seg id="p015">In tlio above table the asterisk indicates that the inforn properly belonging in that apace lias been listed elsewhere. Some patients have been listed t\vir&lt; nuM's hut duplication of othei by the use of the asterisk. r three times under different ifoi tr.ation in the table is a\ Under the column headed patients improved " the angle &gt;een discharged from the Ho - double cross that the patient has indicates that the patient has in an improved condition, th&lt; been improved but is still und treatment The number of beds for patients now in the Hospital, including lie detention ward, is forty-five. We have made it a rule when vorthv patients applied who could be benefit ted by treatment, to larole those of our patients in the institution who could spend ime at home without serious injury to make space for the new pplieants. In this way we have always a larger number of patients nder treatment than are in the Hospital. At the present time, &gt;r example, the number of patients actually under treatment is iftv-two while the number in the Hospital is only forty-one. P During the past biennium a considerable number of patients e applied at the Hospital for examination who for one reason or ther we have been unable to accept for treat n e A certain number of pati &gt;ecause of the fact that they p »■ alle\ iated or improved. A f it the Hospital with the hope hem but the results in such ca: nta have bee 1 admittance ions which cowl w such patients have been ace that something might !&gt;:■ don • from satisfactory During the bienniuni just closed very few pay patient* have been accepted for treatment, it having been our practice that preference should be given to those pati -nts who are unable to seek care or medical treatment elsewh The following table is furnished to show the distribution of patients from over the state. Adams, 107 Dodge, 94. I7."&gt; Antelope. 131, 22:5 Buffalo, 207. 208 DouglM, 2, 13, 76, 7s. 94. 109. 177. 190. 192. 193, 194. 198 49. 61, 74. 77. K2, 1 13. 173 FUlmora, 138, 204 Clay. 3, 191, 211 Colfax. .-)(). llti Frontier. 140 Hall. 39 r. 102. 105 Hamilton, 133. 224 Dakota. Ki7 Holt. ! </seg>
            <seg id="p016">"^j !J - V i •■ £ lfm 4 v- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">393 iThe strikingly large number of patients from Lancaster eti eatee not only the fact that the people of the home county of Institution are awake to the possibilities of treatment in the pital but also that a number of poor families from over the e come to Lincoln and secure employment here with a view to ng crippled or deformed children in their families treated at institution. These families all acquire a residence in Lancaster ity an I th ■ application Manks for admission to the Hospital filled out by Lancaster county officials. The salary appropriation made by the last legislature rendered it possible for us to employ a teacher and establish a school in the ital. Miss Claire Boydston was accordingly employed Apri 1. l'.»07. At that time the Hospital was badly hampered for space School exercises were held, however, in the small basement toon which served also as a play room. The only entrance to the oh solarium was through this room and the school exercises were con - stantly disturbed by those who were obliged to minister to the patients in the solarium. A temporary change in school room was necessitated by the 4 the solarium for a time as quarantine ward for diphtheria. Later when the reconstruction of the building began August 16, 1907, school exercises were held at different places throughout the building. When the basement floor of the solarium was completed it was turned over to the school to be used for regular school i Jefferson. 101. IDS. 1 17. 170. 214 Merrirk, 104, 126 Nance, 71. 136, 210 Knox, 125 Otoe. 1. 14s. 14(1 Lancaster, 38, 42, ."&gt;4. 81,93, 103 Polk. His. 157. 201. 226 111. 112. 114. 1 15, 1 is. |22. Saline. 12.'). 171. 180. 189 127, I2K, 132, 134. 139. 143, Sarpy, S4. 206 144. 14l». 147. 1.")!). 151, 153. Saunders. 17. 218 154, 156, f ."is. |(J4. 165, Kill. Sewanl, 124. 215 169, 172. 176, 17s. 181, ls_\ Sioux. 24 Is:}, 184, ls."&gt;. 188, l ( .t7. 199, 200. 202. 203, 205, 209. 212. Thayer, 62 Washington. 12-i 216, 219. 221). 221. 225, 227 Wheeler, 29 Lincoln. 106 York. li. I l'.t Madison. 1 10. 213. 222 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">•7. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">The school in session presents a striking appearance. The various forms of apparatus worn, plaster Paris casts, and the children who are badly deformed present a strong argument in favor of providing these children with all the knowledge and manual dexterity that they can acquire in order that they can do aomt ful work in spite of their crippled bodies. Several children on ac - count of complete paralysis of the lower extremities are compelled to attend school and do their work in wheel chairs. As a rule the children are at least up to the average in intelli - gence and some develop unusual ability along special lines. Many have had small opportunity or none before coming to the Hoe and nearly all are eager to learn. Khe work done has ranged from kindergarten work to high studies. Regular exercises are held in the school K morning. In the afternoon the teacher gives her att&lt; K who are bed patients, going from one bed to anoihei citations and directing studw An especial effort has been made to teach such subjects as will develop skillful use of the hands. Mild gymnastics, approp to the children are used. Mirny of the children have become quite expert in banket making. An exhibit of the results attained along this line was made at the State Fair in September HMls where about eighty baskets, all made by the children under the direction of liias Boydston. were shown. Simple sewing, embroidery, drawn work. pyrograpby, with some instruction in printing, wood carving and clay modelling, have been given and the results obtains justify the conclusion that these children are quite capable of de - veloping into self-sustaining individuals if their diseases and de - formities are improved or cured. On March 14. 1908, the nurses training school of the Ho* graduated its first class of nurses. These young women had in constant attendance in the Hospital for a period of two and were graduated with appropriate exercises in the rooms of Hon. H. M Eaton, Commissioner of Lands and Buildings at the S Capitol building. Mr. Baton awarded the diplomas to the 11 with remarks suitable for the occasion. Short addresses wen made by Dr. John IV Lord, superintendent. Rev. \Y. M. Baleh and \. K. Hardwick. head nurse. Of the five nurses graduat. inc. Misses Bixby, Mullen and Capron are pursuing post grad - study in Harlem and Fordam hospitals, branches of the </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">Rrue Hospital in New York City. Mrs. Luella Stahl has lx the wife of Mr. Frank R. Miller, of Load. S. 1).. and Mi - beth Rogers is engaged in private nursing in Omaha. The report of the Hospital for the bienniun would be incomplete without an acknowledgement of our obligations to the Hon. ( ;. Sheldon. Governor, for his interest in our work. Especial acknowl - ueiit is also due to the members of the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings who have untiringly devoted themselves to the problem of affording the Hospital a suitable building and providing it with proper equipment and supplies for the conduct of its work. The members of the Board have been zealous in their efforts in nection with the somewhat difficult task of remodelling an old building into a modern hospital. They have at all times consi the welfare of the patients and methods of economizing our fin and our efforts. A word must also be said in appreciation of the work 0 head nurse and her pupil nurses who even in the trying tin ■ remodelling our building did not spare themselves in an attempt ve the best possible care t&lt;&gt; our patients. Pliss Boydston has accomplished much by her fidelity and genee in the instruction of her charges. On the whole the &lt; of the work of the two years must be a source of gratification who have followed its progn I It is urged upon the Board that during the coming biennium nsion be made whereby the Hospital can be made independent he Home for the Friendless in the matter of providing and wring food for our patients. As this is done at present all the I must be carried from one building to another and is usually ed cold. Moreover, the rations provided for the healthy ehil - 1 in the Home are not always such as would be chosen with a v to the altered functions of the children in the Hospital. - itional space in our present building and additional help for purpose would be required. If a new building is provided for Home for the Friendless we could expand our institution to in - ks the first floor of our present building to very great advai Respectfully, John P. LOBD, Superintendent. </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>