<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00047.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00047.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Public Documents 1919-1920 Volume 1</title>
               <date value="1920">1920</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Public Documents of Nebraska / 1919-1920 VOLUME 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TK2 : NT VOHK PUBLIC LIBRARY AifTOR, LENOX AND TlU&gt;tN KM SDAT1OS8 K 1949 L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1920 1920 CONTENTS VOLUME 1. 1. Governor's Message. Samuel R. McKelvie, 1921, 1922. 2. Secretary of State, Biennial report, 1919-1920. 3. Auditor of Public Accounts. Biennial report, 1919-1920. a. Appropriations, etc., 40th legislative session, 1921 4. Insurance Bureau, Annual reports, 1919, 1920. 5. Treasurer, Biennial report, 1919-1920. 6. Board of Control of State Institutions, Biennial report, 1919 - 7. Superintendent of Public Instruction. Biennial report, 1919 - 8. Board of Education, Biennial report, 1919-1920. 9. Building and Loan Associations, Annual reports, 1919-1920 10. Department or Public Welfare. Biennial report, 1919-1920. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Inaugural Address OF Governor S. R. McKelvie 1921 DELIVERED TO THE 1 Fortieth Session Nebraska State Legislature </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">3 INAUGURAL ADDRESS OF GOVERNOR. S. R. McKELVIE To the Fortieth Session of the Nebraska State Legislature: We are met upon this important occasion charged with the duty of noting upon legislation designed to support and promote popular govern - ment the foundations of which were laid when this Republic was estab - lished. Our duty is a solemn one, but the way is clearly marked and w»&gt; heed only adhere to first principles &gt;ts they were enunciated by the Fathers if we would progress along safe and sane lines. • The hour of our meeiing is an auspicious one. We have pass^l through a period of great stress, during which the strength that is in us as a nation has been sore tried by the problems that have gathered .-..bout, us. Now we can see the rift in the clouds. Out of the great test to which we have been put we shall come rejuvenated in the faith that, baa consumed our every effort, and we shall rededicafe ourselves to Liu uri dying task of preserving here a free government, of, for :ind by Un - people. As a commonwealth we are prosperous — not as much so perhaps :&gt;.s we have been at some times in the past, but comfortably situated, and 'our resources are unimpaired. We nted, now, only employ the age ohi principles of thrift, industry and unselfishness of purpose in order tlirit we may go forward at a rapid rate. This I think we will do, and it is m: sincere hope and belief that we arc entering upon in era of unprecedented good feeling. Before cataloging the recommendation that 1 shall have to make to &gt;ou bearing upon specific subjects, permit me to make a few general Observations regarding legislation: First: Let us enact just as few laws as possible. Our statute books are encumbered now with laws that are obsolete and unenforceable. Moreover, we have legislated so much that the people have come to fe&lt;rl they have a never-ending source of relief from their ills through the en - actment of new lavs. Such a condition of reliance upon the state de - stroys initiative in the individual, and develops a citizenship that is (if - pendent, flabby and discontented. Second: Let our legislative acts be stimulated oy a desii ■- t;&gt; serve all the people without regard 1o class or creed. We must con - stantly bear in mind that regardless of vocation, station or religion there exists among us a bond of interdependence which means that when an tosition is worked upon the least of us, the ills that result are felt by rest of us. In other words, the little benefit that we may derive as </seg>
            <seg id="p007">4 *• cihss toon j , li it "w ones cin in just icg or iitirfisii ip upon cio j*ont^ ■ ■ is* 1 , conn 'S back to plague us tomorrow. Third: We must not mistake agitation for progress. Aud wo t&gt;hou!d not forget that the only worth while progress we have ever made has been built upon the firm foundations that underlie our republican form of government. CONFERENCES The specific recommendations that I shall have to make to you have been 'developed principally through two sources: (1) My experience as governor during the past two years; (2)- Conferences which I have had with the governors of other states, and with the representatives of nearly every organized interest in the state, including agriculture, trade and commerce, labor, law enforcement officials, district judges, ex-service men. commercial travelers, banking and insurance interests, sportsmen, wo - men's organizations, professional groups, and officials in the different de - partments of the state government. These conferences have been hela within the last thirty days and were attended by no less than 500 people from all parts of the state. Thus I am enabled to reflect to you in these reccommendations the general desires of the people of the state re - garding legislation. CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENTS The work of this session of the legislature is made peculiarly impor - tant in that since the last session was held a constitutional convention met and submitted to the people forty-one amendments to the constitu tion. All of those amendments were approved. Those amendment." should be carefully studied in relation to the work of this session so thai their full purpose may be carried out, and that your acts may not be de clared unconstitutional. TAXATION Taxation is perhaps the most important subject that you wiil be called upon to consider during the entire session. Our tax laws have long been obsolete and in their operation have worked many Inequalities among the people. Heretofore the way to their proper revision has been effectually closed by the limitations of the old -constitution. Now, how - ever, under the amended constitution the way to adequate administration and wise revision of the tax laws is opened. At once I would recommend that the complete revision of the tax laws of the state be not undertaken at this session. This subject is so filled with ramifications and is so far reaching in its effect that I think you may- be fairly satisfied with a few initial revisions, contenting your - selves beyond this with the setting up of adequate administrative ma - chinery. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">5 The amended constitution provides for the office of tax commissioner. This is a very important department and should be set up for operation entirely outside of any other department. The t»x commissioner should have wide powers of investigation and review and should be given sufli - i-ient operatives not only to enforce the tax laws r&gt;nd get the maximuiu amount of taxable property upon the assessment rolls, but to gather du: - rns the present blennium the information that will enable a thoroughly wise and complete revision of the tax laws at tl&gt;" next general sfssioi. of the legislature. One of the fundamental changes that might he made in the l&lt;i&gt;v at ihis session in harmony with the amended constitution would be the classification of intangibles. We are .convinced that a relatively small amount of these assets have been listed for taxation in the pa.~t, ami small blame could be attached to those who did not list them, for if they were listed it must be at their full, face value while tangibles have gen - erally been listed at a much less percentage. Now these intangibles may be classified upon a percentage or low fiat rate basis, and if this is done the experience of other states will no doubt be felt here thiougli a. very largely increased listing of such properties for taxation. Allow me to recommend further that in considering this subject iv.e committees on revenue and taxation in both houses' of the legislature sit jointly and recommend a committee bill carrying ell of the amendments and new legislation that you would have enacted now. CORPORATION LAWS 1 would recommend the following changes in the corporation laws of the state. First: lnus'much as non-profit corporations art permitted to fiie ar - ticles of incorporation for a fee of $2.00, under the present statutes snd 'ire charged with a fee of $5.00, the same as corporations for profit, for filing an amendment, no matter how brief, we suggest tnat section 2324, which provides for these fees be so amended as to permit non-profit cor - porations to file an amendment for $1.00. I Second: !n the matter of dissolutions, the books of the Secreicuv State are encumbered with a large number of corporations who are ctically defunct, and have been so for a number of years. That ofure is not have the address of any members of the company and cannot ceed in reaching them with any kind of a notice, and often when some mber of such company is found, he declares they have no organization, doing no business, and have no officers. For this reason, we suggest t the statutes be so amended that the articles of incorporation be auto - tically canceled upon the non-payment of ccupation taxes for three sue give years, and that a statement from any member of such corporation, attorney for such corporation that the corporation is not doing busi </seg>
            <seg id="p009">i i I 6 it has held no meetings, and expects to hold no meeting 10 perpetuate the organization, may be filed by the Secretary of State as a certificate of dissolution of the said corporation. Third: In the matter of collecting occupation tax from foreigu cor - porations, as provided in paragraph 766, Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913, there is apparent contradiction, and this section •with Section 779 are so complicated that I would respectfully advise a restatement of the entire proposition. Paragraph 766 plainly states that the occupation tax of a foreign corporation shall be based upon its entire paid up capital stock. Paragraph 779, however, has been interpreted by the courts to mean a pro-rata, rather than the entire amount of capital stock, is the basis lor computing such occupation tax. This was clearly brought out in the recent Rock Island case, in which Judge Clements or the Lancaster district court handed down an opinion sustaining this interpretation. For this reason paragraph 766 should be clearly restated, even if the basis of taxation is not changed. In view, however, ot' the fact that large foreign corporations with Kl up capital stock reaching into the millions, who do a large business his state, get by on the payment of a very small tax, in some instance* as low as $5.00, we would suggest that a new basis for the computing of occupation tax for foreign corporations be provided and suggest that these companies in making their annual report, instead of being required to show what portion of their capital stock is used for doing business in Nebraska, be required to show the gross receipts of their Nebraska busi - ness and that the tax be based upon this showing, rather than upon their paid up capital stock. t Fourth: The administration of the corporation laws is distribute.! ng so many departments of government that some change ought to be e providing for co-ordinated and unified administration of all thpsp EXPERT ACCOUNTANT Inasmuch as it is provided that an expert accountant, shall be em ployed, whose services shall be devoted to the state under the direction of the State Auditor, I recommend that the law be changed so that the E ointment of that official shall be made by the State Auditor without approval of the Governor. v LAW ENFORCEMENT Law enforcement lies at the very foundation of good government To the extent that there is a proper respect for and enforcement of th3 law. we are made secure in the rights of life and propeity. These ends can only be attained through the support of an enlightened, intelligent, un - prejudiced public opinion. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">7 lu point ol public respect for the law. Nebraska is mori- than a uieas - urably good slate. The people generally are law abiding and there is :i disposition to support public officials who are eterged with the responsi biliiy of enforcing the laws. Recently, however, we have been passing through a crime era lhat has crowded our penitentiary to the guards and has created in the public mind a determination lo see the maximum ol penalty imposed upon all offenders against the law. This latter conditions has assumed such propoitions that it has be - come well nigh impossible to properly execute practical reform nwasuros in handling prisoners. Pardons, Paroles and Commutations. Elsewhere in this message you will find a list of those who have been granted pardons, commutations or reprieves during the past bienniutu. For your further information I here give the figures by two year periods, which show the number of prisoners released from the penitentiary o: shown clemency through pardon, parole, commutation or furlough dur ing the last ten years: 1911-12 1H13-14 1915-16 1917-18 1919-^ Of those on parole during the last biennium only 6 per ceni violated their paroles by committing other offenses. This, I think, is the smallest percentage of parole violations in the history of the state and it is proli ably the lowest of any state in the Union having the lmietermina'o sen - tence law. Thus it is seen that the late outburst of public disapproval of paroles cannot be the outgrowth of a lax administration of the law. It comes about, no doubt, from two sources — first, the prevalence of crime, and second, the play that has been made upon this subject by unscrupulous, sensational newspapers. But the source of the protest is not of such great inipoi tan.ee as is the fact that any law which elicits the genernl condemnation of the people when it is properly enforced becomes un - workable, and this, I think, is the condition of the present indeterminate sentence act in this State. The general disapproval of the parole of prisoners has moved me at times to recommend the entire repeal of the indeterminate sentence law, but knowing the good that it has done, not only in this but in other s'.ates, I cannot satisfy my conscience to pursue such a course. Instead I shall Pardous 32 2 3 Commutations 16 ** 3 13 b\irloughs 1 37 30 23 li Paroles 114 361 428 590 30R Totals 163 402 462 629 325 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">8 u\e li li is to De continued upon tne statute dooks. First: I would remove from the list of parolable offenses all crimee or attempts at crime against the person. It has been my observation that public opinion will not tolerate the release of such criminals except upon the terms that are specifically imposed by the court. Especially is this true of crimes against women, and I hold that it is utterly unreasonable to impose upon public officials, other than those upon the bench, the re - sponsibility for disposing of such criminals. Second: I would remove from the parolable list any except firai of - fenders. Third: I would leave to the discretion of the court the question ol tither to Impose a determinate or indeterminate sentence, and if the er, the court should be allowed to fix the period of the indeterminate tence within maximum? and minimums provided by law. t Fourth: I would require that no one might be subject to consider* - for parole except that his formal application be made in writing and it be approved in writing by the prosecuting attorney and the trial Fifth: I would make it a felony for anyone to approach any member of the Board of Pardons and Paroles or any of its employes upon the sub - ject of granting a parole, pardon or commutation, except at a public hear - inpc of that board. t Sixth: All hearings of the Board of lVrdons and Paroles should be t&gt;lic and should be announced at least two weeks in advance of thf :e of hoaring. At such hearings any citizen ought to be given the right appear and be heard and the board should be given the power to issue jpoenas for witnesses and to compel their attendance. Seventh : The board ought to be provided with a reporter, who would make a transcript of the proceedings at such hearings, and all of tu« i ecommendations, investigations and testimonies that are considered by the board, in regard to such application should be reduced to the form of a single, complete, permanent record in the office of the secretary oE the board. The board should be its own judge as to what testimony it would receive. Eighth: A heavy penalty should be imposed against any one, who, by the printed or spoken word, makes a misleading statement regarding the acts of public officials in the administration of this law. Ninth: The administrative machinery of the Board of Pardons and Paroles should be set up entirely apart from any other department, and should be provided with sufficient funds and help to properly carry on its work. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">9 Capital Punishment. 1 would repeal the law which provides the death penalty, except as it applies to criminals, who, after being sentenced, v commit another capital offense, and I would not permit the Governor or any one else but the court to alter the sentence pronounced by the court for such crimes. In addition to this the way should be left open for a rehearing, should new evidence of a material nature be developed. Prison Reformatory. The need for a prison reformatory for first offenders is partially iudicaud by the following figures: Within the two year period begin - ning January 7th, 1919, the number of men iu the penitentiary has been increased from 2S3 to 550. This means not only that the present quarters are crowded beyond the point of properly meeting the housing i squirt ments, but it renders almost impossible the segregation of young and first offenders from the older and professional criminals. Under such conditions prison reform cannot possibly be carried on properly, aud it is of the utmost importance that relief be afforded at once. Therefore. 1 shall include in the budget a recommendation for an appropriation lor such a reformatory. I am greatly in hopes that it will meet with your approval. I might add that an appropriation of $150,000.00 was made for this purpose by the Legislature of 1913, but the refonnatory was never built. Prison Labor on Roads. During the past year, Nebraska made its initial attempt in the use of prison labor on roads. 103 men were placed out in road camps under guard, being given, in the camps and at work, practically the same liberties as Tree labor. Of this number only four attempted to escape, and the work done by the men was of an exceptionally high order. It is doubtful that any state has ever conducted such a successful initial experiment, and it is highly important that legislation be enacted that will encourage the extension of this policy. It is the experience of prison officials that nothing serves quite so well to enhance the good behavior of prisoners as the assurance that faithful service and trust - worthiness will hasten the day of their release. Therefore, I recommend that legislative provision be made for the granting of additional good time, to be deducted from the terms of those who prove trustworthy in this capacity. Further Provisions for Law Enforcement. The budget will contain a provision for a continuation of the Law Enforcement Division. This, I think, is highly toportant, not only in </seg>
            <seg id="p013">10 be adeqautely enforced, but in order that professional assistance may be given to local officials in certain matters of law enforcement and the apprehension of criminals. I It is of more than passing interest to note that during the past uniuni the activity of the State Law Enforcement Division in co - ration with other law enforcement officials against violators of the tor laws has resulted in returning to the couniy school funds of the :e, fines of |387,221.00 and stolen automobiles of the value of $145, - ,0u have been recovered and returned to their owners. It is also an jresting fact that in spite of the general wave of crime that has n sweeping the country during the past two years, automobile thefts Lincoln and Omaha have been reduced 20' ; during the past year, tie recovery of stolen cars has been increased 9%. It :s fair to assume t this percentage has been maintained throughout the entire state. it is the opinion of the Attorney General, and I am inclined to agree with him, that it will be well to etsablish in the Department of Justice a Bureau of Investigation, composed of professional investigators and detectives, much along the same lines as the Federal government now provides. These operatives would servo in a purely secret service ca - pacity and their work should not be confused with that of policf men. sheriffs or other law enforcement officials. I As a further aid in enforcing the law, I believe it would be well ive to county attorneys practically the same inquisitorial powers as now given to grand juries. Not only would this result in a very it saving to the counties that must now call grand juries for such lisitions, but it would greatly facilitate the gathering of necessary rmation for prosecutions and would speed up the work of law en- AN AGRICULTURAL PROGRAM tTwo years ago I called into conference the representatives oi all e-wide fanners' organizations in the state and consulted their opin - before making my recommendations to the Legislature. As a result this conference, an agricultural program was prepared and the immendations there contained were enacted into law, with a single sption. Such a conference has again been held and the recommenda - s that follow are largely the outgrowth of the opinions there ex- Cooperation. (1) Prohibition should be imposed against the use of the term </seg>
            <seg id="p014">11 "cooperative," except as it may bo rightfully applied to auy couceru organized under and within the cooperative laws of Nebraska. "cooperative, (2) The organization of banks on a purely cooperative basis should be legalized. However, in justice to banks that are obliged *o operate under cetrain restrictions of the present state guaranty fund law, it is obvious that cooprative banks may not share the benefits of that law. for true cooperation means the distribution of benefits on a patronage basis, and this might easily violate the. percentage limit that is placed upon the payment of interests on deposits. (3) Further encouragement should be given to the organization and work of county farm bureaus. A recommendation regarding this will be contained in the budget. (4) ' To facilitate the distribution of farm products over the con - suming period and avoid gluts upon the market, it is necessary that every practical aid be given to the farmer to hold that portion of his crop which consumption does not demand. This will be encouraged through the issuance of warehouse receipts as a basis for credit. I would recommend, therefore, that a law be passed enabling the issu - ance of warehouse receipts against grain that is stored in warehouses on the farm or in other privately ownei warehouses. &lt;f&gt;) The Railway Commission should exercise control over site tor elevators on railroads. (Ci The law should more clearly define as cooperative concerns those that are constituted of a collection of cooperative companies. (7) Farmers' elevator concerns should be privileged to carry their insurance mutually. (S) The University regents should be authorized to make, buy or (9) Bovine Tuberculosis has become so prevalent and the effects of this disease are so disastrous to domestic and human life that the state is justified in redoubling its efforts to eradicate it. I shall, there - fore, recommend in the executive budget an increased sum for the indemnification of owners of cattle, who meet the requirements of this law. Furthermore, proper restrictions should be mrown about the use of Tuberculin, both as a safeguard to the State In indemniiyiiiM owners, and against Its use by ones who are not tramed to properly (10 The present pure seed law is impractical of enforcement. It should be amended to protect the interests of farmers and growers of the state against unscrupulous methods of dealers from without as well as within the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">12 thai have developed in its administration. This is a very valuable law and every practical thing should be done to make it workable and fair. (12) I shall recommend in the budget that the appropriations tor the several agricultural groups that are conducted tor purely promotional purposes, be consolidated for administration under the State Board of Agriculture. I think this will effect a decided economy and ma&gt; greatly enhance the efficiency of the work that is now being done along this line. WAR VETERANS The obligation of the state to its ex-service people is not easily discharged nor can it be discharged through the mere rendering of material aid. The state should hold these people in the deepest regard for the patriotic service they have rendered, and no opportunity should be lost to honor them as the defenders of the nation. tOur duty lies first to those who are sick or disabled as a result ilitary services. Hospital facilities should be provided to adequately for their every need, and entrance to those institutions should b« uraged in every practical way. The state has been maintaining two homes for veterans of our past wars. These have been used principally for civil war veterans. We view with deepest sorrow the narrowing thread of blue and of gray that marks the passing of this body of gallant veterans, and nothing should be left undone to provide for their comfort while they remain. tin making provision for the members of the more recent wars, it he general opinion of ex-service men that home and hospital facili - ; should be developed at the beautiful site of the Soldier's Hmr.e ar ford. Nor would I ignore the needs of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Grand Island, so far as concerns the comforts of those civil war srans who have come to look upon it as their home 30 long as they Of next iniporU-nce are the interests of our ex-service men and wo - men in a way that will enable them to re-establish themselves as a part of the material life of our commonwealth. It has been our custom in the past to provide homesteads for ex-service people. That was at a time when there was an abundance of free land to be had merely for reclaiming it. Now relatively little such land exists and it devolves upon us to provide some other means for the procurement of these homesteads. I Therefore, I recommend to you the raising of a fund from which s can be made to ex-service men and women for the building of es. For this purpose, I believe it will be entirely practical to place at </seg>
            <seg id="p016">13 the disposal of the proper officials the money that is derived from the sale of school lands, and I would recommend that the school lands of the state be sold and the money turned into this fund. Not only wiil this ultimately provide an ample fund, but it will very greatly enhance the income from the investment that these lands represent. If the school lands are sold, it should be at public auction to the highest bidder and at an amount not less than a legally established percentage of an appraised value fixed by competent public officials. Pending the receipt of returns from the school lands, it might even be practical to encourage the sale of certain low rate, interest- bearing securities, in which the state now has some of its school funds invested. I have in mind now that the state owns about 1800,000.00 of Massachu - setts bonds, bearing only %Vz'7c interest. If these bonds could be dis - posed of at a discount that would enable their reloan at a nominal rate, no loss would accrue to the state and the soldiers' home building fund would be promptly started toward establishment. The veterans of the world war are very earnest in requesting that boxing, under proper supervision, be legalized. If this is to be done, I feel that the enforcement of the law should be fixed in local officials under the supervision of the Department of Public Welfare, without thft creation of a separate department for this purpose. THE CIVIL ADMINISTRATIVE CODE The last Legislature enacted a Civil Administrative Code and set up in it the machinery for the administration and enforcement of cer - tain laws, the responsibility for which was theretofore largely fixed in the Governor. The operations of this plan of administrative organiza - tion have proven its practicability. Not only has it added greatly to efficiency in the administration of the state's business, but it has ef - fected a genuine economy in the cost of administrative government within these departments. Moreover it has provided for an adequate control over reporting, auditing and expending the public money, so that I am able to report to you that for the first time in years the cost of government in these departments has been kept within the appropria - tions made by the Legislature, and a balance of $135,644.80 will have been saved, to be returned into the various funds at the end of the biennium. A few minor changes need to be made in some of these depart - ments. I shall discuss these under the department heads as they shall occur in the following: Department of Finance. The Budget. In a few days I shall present to you the budget, containing my recommendations for appropriations to be made by your </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 me to recommend that the preparation of the budget (now authorized by Constitutional act) be continued in this department, and in order that the work may be improved, I recommend tint legislation be added making it mandatory upon all spending agencies of the state to report their expenditures monthly to the Department of Finance, distributed according to expenditure accounts and forms approved by the Depart - ment of Finance. t Reports. The present system of printing the reports for the dif - mt state officers and departments is very unsatisfactory and un sssarily expensive. I think it would be well if the Legislature aid provide that the Department of Finance be required to prepare ear book of Nebraska, which would contain the reports of all the ;s of government of the state in a single volume. This would enable building of a real history of Nebraska state government. The law now provides that the Department of Finance shall as - semble, classify and arrange for publication the laws, joint resolutions and memorials passed at eac!v session of the Legislature. This activity properly belongs with the Secretary of State and provision should be so made. Civil Service. Civil service requirements, as they have been gen - erally applied to the public business, have not operated in the interests of efficiency or economy in government. I think, however, that a system •of limited civil service could be worked out for the civil administrative ■code departments so that standard qualifications and eligible liats could be maintained for positions with the state of those who may pass satisfactory examinations, or qualify under the standsrd qualifications. and eligible lists could be maintained for positions with the state of those who may pass satisfactory examinations or qualify under the standard requirements. If this is done, employes should come into the state's service for one year's probation, and after one year's time it should be provided that they could not be discharged except for cause, with a further pro - rision that any employe thus discharged could have, at his request, a public hearing before a board of review. t Central Purchase of Supplies. The law now provides that, with the sption of the normal schools and the university, all printing and :e supplies be purchased through the Division of Purchases and plies In the Department of Finance. Under a cooperative arrangement, we have extended this work to include all purchases for the Civil Administrative Code departments. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">15 This has worked exceedingly well and the plan should be legalized, not only to include the Civil Administrative Code departments, but all state activities, other than the normal schools, university, Board of Control and possibly one or two others. Central Bookkeeping and Accounting. Under a cooperative agree - ment, the Department of Finance has bean, doing the bookkeeping tor the different Civil Administrative CodeCjdApamrents. This plan se - cures uniformity in accounting and bookkeeping and it should be legal - ized within these departments. Department of Agriculture. Dairy Laws. It appears that some changes ought to be made In ilie laws affecting dairying and allied industries in the state. (1) The coloring of substitutes for butter enables manufacturers of these products to engage in an unfair competition against the dairy farmer. While I would not deprive anyone of the privilege of using any product he may choose, I do feel it to be highly important that these substitutes should be sold and consumed upon their merits. (2) The present law requires that temporary permits to cream station operators may be issued for a period of only two weeks. This period should be extended to thirty days or left in the discretion of the Department of Agriculture, in that it is. In many instances, impractical, if not almost impossible, to examine these operators for licensing within so short a period. (3) There is a good deal of opposition to the present law which requires the licensing of dairy herds, but I am not prepared to say that the law is not a good one. If the small fee of $1.00 each for these licenses seeme burdensome, it may be removed, but inasmuch as dairy - products are the most easily contaminated of all food products and serve as the medium through which many dangerous diseased germs are most easily conveyed, it is of the utmost importance to the public health that inspection should be carried along the entire line from tho farm to the factory. The Department of Agriculture has inspected during the past biennium 1920 dairy farm-s, and this at no cost to the producers except for the $1.00 license fee. I cannot help feeling that this is a service that contributes to the general public health onrt ought to be continued. (4) It is now required that ice cream shall contain 14% butter fat. This requirement seems too high to be of practical benefit, either to the producer of dairy products, or the consumer of ice cream. It is quite apparent that ice cream is not consumed for the food properties contained in it, but rather as a refreshment. Therefore, the more fat that it contains, the greater the heat produced. Also, this requirement </seg>
            <seg id="p019">16 product at so high &amp; price mat tne consumption or ice cream is inereDy greatly lessened, and this in turn is reflected in a reduced consumption of cream. It therefore seems practical that this percentage be materially lowered. (5) An egg candling law ought to be enacted. It is figured that at the present time there is 15 to 20% loss of eggs for food purposes through improper handling. Compulsory candling wou.u encourage im - proved methods of handling and would stimulate the price in foreign markets for Nebraska eggs. Several states have such a law now. Fish and Game. The fish and game laws should be entirely re - written. Some of the necessary changes that appear to me are these: U) The open season for' Prairie Chickens should be made to con - form to the open season on Ducks. This would greatly facilitate the enforcement of the law and would not necessarily mean too great a destruction of these birds. The same is true of the open season on Plover and Doves. K(2) Permits for taking Beaver should be issued only in instances which these animals are proving destructive to property, and it uld be required that the one who takes Beaver should divide equally li the state the proceeds from the sale of Beaver peltw. t(3) A size limit should be fixed on fish that in taken for food oses. Under the proper protection, certain kinds of fish will make eral contribution to the food supply of the state. t&lt;4) At the thirty-seventh session of the Legislature, a law was :ted providing for the establishment and marking of all school ions as game 1 reserves. If the school lands are to be sold, then provision should be protected to the state. Also, it seems highly rabJo that certain lakes in the sand hills region be designated as sanctuaries where the birds may rest without disturbance during day. (5) I would recommend, also, that certain lakes be designated as public waters where anyone may be permitted to hunt or fish. Unless this is done, we shall soon find that the numerous lakes in the sand hills region of the state will have been taken over by private individuals and one of the avenues for recreation and sport will then have been closed to the general public. (6) We should proceed at once to establish about the state of Nebraska a system of parks and recreation places that may be later developed in the interests of all the people of the state. I think the law that now provides for a forestry commission may well be amended f o place the administration of this subject in the Department of Agricu'- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">17 ture, not with a view to entering now upon any large expenditure of money in the development of forestry or public parks and recreation places, but with a view that trees may be cultivated and protected and recreation places designated, which, as our highway system is developed, may be made accessible to the people and developed as the conditions seem to warrant. Department of Trade and Commerce. Bureau of Banking. It is gratifying that during the present period o( financial stress Nebraska should have had so small a number of bank failures, and those failures that did occur were the direct result of un - scrupulous and, in some instances, criminal practices on the pait oi bank officials. The Bureau of Banking has been greatly hampered in its work through inability to establish a corps of permaaent examiners. The ' compensation for the services of examiners has been so small that many changes in the force have resulted and this has made it extremely difficult to maintain a well trained force of experienced men. I shall recommend in the budget an increase in salaries for examiners. I recommend these further changes in the present banking laws: (1) Active officers should all be required to give fidelity bonds iu the sum of not less than $5,000.00, these bonds nfter being approved by the board of directors, to be filed with the Department of Trade and Commerce. (2) The minimum capital should be raised to $25,000.00, in the granting of all new charters, and all existing banks with a less capital should be required to increase their capital to this minimum within five years. . , (3) Sale and transfers of shares ol' bank stock should be. appiove&lt;i by the board of directors and should be made a matter of record. Directors should be held personally responsible for any transfers of stock approved to one who is unable to show the required, legal, financial responsibility over and above all debts, liabilities and exemptions re - quired by Section 35 of the banking code nor should the seller be re - leased from his double liability until this is done, and in no event should he be released if the bank's capital was impaired at the time of sale until such impairment is restored to the satisfaction of the Department of Trade and Commerce. (4) No organization, association, corporation or individual other than chartered banks should be permitted to use the word "bank." "bankers" or "banking" as a part of their business name or title, or fo designate their official position or business. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">18 to susp^QQ 1U6 xunc Lions ox D&lt;inK. oniciiiis woo or iit'rsis -t ntiy violate any section of the banking law, after such wilful or persisted violations have been called to the attention of the majority of the bean. of directors. Failure or refusal of the board of directors to act, after having been duly notified of such violations, should be justification for lor the Department of Trade and Commerce to take the action herein ttemplated and continue to supervise the transaction of the bank's Iness until such time as the cause for complaint shall have been (6) The depositor's guaranty law should be to amended fiat, the guaranty fund, after paying the deposits of a faiW bank, would have a first lien on all the assets of the bank, including the stockholders' double liability, until the fund was fully restored. This wsp evidently the inten - tion when the law was passed, but the phraseology of the law and ths court decisions have made the guaranty fund atoramon creditor in the distribution of the bank's resources. 1(7) The Department of Trade and Commerce should have authority require banks, building and loan associations and trust companies to &gt;pt and maintain systems of uniform accounting for convenient auilii and checking by examiners and for a permanapt, comprehensive rec . of the bank's business. t Building and Loan Associations. The lav requires that the funds oi ding and loan associations shall be loaned od real estate and on r own stock. Inasmuch as real estate is taxed, it would appear that ax all of the stock of these companies results in double taxatioa. To ove this condition without removing from the assessment roll the jerty of ones who ought properly to bear a share of the tax burdens he state may be accomplished only through the application of an in - e tax. This is a subject that should be considered under the head Temporary relief against this condition might be effected by re noviug from taxation, installment stocks of building and loan association* while continuing their paid up stocks for taxation at a classified n.i&gt;_- as in - tangibles. t Insurance. It is generally admitted that Nebraska has a splendid ranee code, and I have only a few recommendations to make for ndments to it. t(l) Section 28 of the insurance code should be repealed and in its e provision made giving the Department of Trade and Commerce the er to prescribe the form upon which an agent shall apply to the In - nee Department for license to write insurance in this state. (2) A short rate table of cancelation should be contained in all in- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">19 -■iurance polity contracts, with the exception of IKe insrance. The lav now permits the use of any snort rate table or cancelation and as a re- sult, there is no uniformity in the various tables applied. (3) Insurance companies organizing under the laws of thij, stale should be required to have as their executive officers ones who are known to be capable of running the affairs of an insurance company. The re- quirements ol -good character and known business ability, as well as a practical knowledge of the executive might ■well be demanded of executive holders and policy holders. duties of the insurance business. officers, in the interests of stock (4) The retention ot premium collected by agents should bo deemed larceny Hail Insurance. The hail insurance law in thi^ slate has never oper- ated satisfactorily 10 the insured, and the amendments that were made 10 it at the last session of the legislature made it even more unsatisfac- tory. This law should be entirely rewritten in an effort to overcome tha obstacles that have been encountered in the state's practical experience in writing hail insurance, and if it cannot be made to be self-sustaining and .capable of practical operation, it should be repealed. Presently it is provided by the law that the premiums on hail insur- ance shall be payable at the time when personal taxes are paid. This means that the. return of these funds to the State Treasurer comes at sucli a late date that a very great delay is necessitated in making the returns on losses to the insured. This condition might be overcome by providing a revolving fund out of which the losses could be paid, pending the return of the premiums to reimburse the state. But even more business-like would be the require ment that the premium be paid in cash at the time when the insurance is applied for. The necessity for this is indicated by the fact that the state already has, in uncollected premiums and commissions cha.-gect by'County Treasurers, the neat sum of $16,271.64 yet to be paid. The relation between premiums and hail losses for the past biennium are ae follows: 1919 premiums $782,714.47 1919 losses 687,732.20 Total excess premiums over losses.. $ 94.982.27 1920 premiums $615,937.51 1920 losses 760,441.78 Exce&amp;s losses over premiums $144,504.27 For the biennium the total losses exceed the total premiums to the amount of $49.52200. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">20 undoubtedly result in widespread complaint among me Insured, but it was inevitable that it should be so, for, on the one hand the ratet charged have been too low in some zones, and on tbe other hand the system of adjusting the losses through local adjusters has been reck - less and unbusinesslike in the extreme. The Department of Trade and Commerce should be giveu authority to adjust and equalize the rates to be charged in each zone on an esti - mated basis that would yield a surplus, until such time as a fund couiii be created that would serve as a revolving fun&lt;1 for the purpose of operation. I Also, provision should be made for a chief adjuster to take charge the work during the hail season. The chief adjuster should be ap - nted for a term of one year at least, and should be an experienced 1 insurance man with authority and means to employ assistants by : day during the season for adjusting losses. I Securities. The present law governing the sale ot securities in thia .e is in its operation in many instances much worse than no law. The lance of permits for the sale of certain securities that hive bern sed by the Bureau of Securities is regarded by purchasers as a guar - *e of the worth of these securities, and securities salesmen are aiak - the most of this opportunity to appropriate the name of the state heir own selfish purposes. This in spite of the fact mat every p3rmii the sale of stock issued by the Bureau of Securities has printed across face in large red type the following: "The Bureau or Securities does recommend nor disparage investments in any securities licensed It." Also, in the administration of the law the necessity for carefully in - vestigating applicant concerns has imposed not a little loss and hard - ship and inconvenience upon legitimate concerns through the delays that are thus occasioned. I Again, after securities have been legitimately sold under the authority the stale, it is not unusual that companies have been systematically ibed from within. Consequently, if the state is going to assume rcspon ility in these matters, it is just as important that it should be given hority over the conduct of these concerns after they are organized as s to auhorize the sale of their securities. The present Bureau of Securities has done splendid work .consider ing the limited funds with which it has had to do, but it has been sadly handicapped in its work by the hampering restrictions that hare - resulted from insufficient funds to employ adequate and competent ope&gt;- But in spite of these handicaps it is an illuminating fact that oJ </seg>
            <seg id="p024">21 the $80,286,553.96 of securities, the sale ol which has been authorized bj the present Bureau of Securities, less than $200,000.00 is represented in companies that have since become bankrupt. Also, permits for thf&gt; sale of approximately $50,000,000.00 in securities have been denied. All of this has been accomplished at a net cost of less than $20,000.00 to the state during the past biennium. ■ The principal losses that have resulted to security purchasers in. this state during the past two years have come from two sources: (1) JFter - eign securities over which we have no control; (2) Local securities that were authorised before the present law was enacted and me presenr Bureau of Securities came into existence. The biennial report of the Bureau of Securities should be carefully studied for it contains very valuable data and abundant valuable infor - mation bearing upon this entire subject. These are only ;: few of the many important criticisms that are made against 'he present law. I believe that these defects in the law and in il« enforcement can all be remedied through the enactmenr ol" an entirely new statute, which shall contain the modern remedies for governing the sale of securities, and provide adequate punishment fo; fraud. Publicity of an educational nature should also be enabled. Bonds. Surety companies should be released from liability when the principal* of the bond request that the same be cancelled. Also, surety eonivs-nies should be allowed to write bankers' blanket bonds. DepartrPint of Labor. li is gi v ;i »rmily conceded 11. at Nebraska has an unusually prai .'.iou". and up-to-date group of laws relating to the subject of labor, and I have only a few r.ni'.lll&gt;.;&lt; r.is ;&lt;, i • commend. The t.ning of grea : et iuifor tance is a full enforcement of the labor laws that we already have. Great progress has been made in this direction during the past biennium. as io shown by the figures covering the administration of the workmen's com - pensation act alone. The activity of the Labor Department, as compared with former years, is quite clearly shown in a comparative table which sets forth the compensation, medical and hospital expenses paid to in - jured employes in the various years since this law was placed upon the statute books: In order that the labor laws of the state may be properly adminie L916 _ $ 61,167.37 .916 116,988.34 L917 ._ 153,031.73 .918 „ _ 141.M7.47 919 _ _ 345,476.24 L920 540,213.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">22 propriation for the Labor Department. As a result of aVecent supreme court decision in this state, .cerlaiu employes in the public service are removed from protection under the K loves' liability and the workmen's compensation act. This condi - should be removed by an amendment to the present law, making employes in the public service compensable the same as those who are privately employed. Occupational diseases should be made coinpensable As a measure of public safety, there should be stale inspection of IThe safety and health laws of the state should be extended to apply roper protection for workers in excavations, wells, etc. I An amendment has been made to the Constitution, enabling the islature to create an Industrial Court. I am not prepared to recom - id such legislation al this time, unless such a body should be pro- Hi to sit in a purely inquisitorial capacity. Public opinion is the itest deterrent to a continuation of those unfriendly relations br - en employer and employe, which result in an injury to the public. 3, therefore, of first importance that the facts in each case should developed, meanwhile, protecting the legal rights of life and prop - ■. We now have provision for a Board of Mediation, and 1 have no bt that this will suffice to cover the requirements of Nebraska foi thn sent, at least. Department of Public Welfare. I Bureau of Child Welfare. The last regular session of the Leglslatui &lt;j ted a Children's Code Commission and charged it with the duty or aring and recommending to this session of the Legislature an eattre i of laws relating to the subject of child welfare. This commission done a tremendous amount of work and is entitled to unbounded se for its industry and integrity of purpose. I think it has formu- I some well worth while recommendations for legislation, and in or - that this entire subject may be properly considered, I recommend there be created a special committee upon this subject in each ich of the Legislature. The thing of first importance in connection with all such legisla tlon is to set up a practical, workable, administrative plan. The work should be continued in the Department of Public Welfare, as it now is, and those in charge should not be unduly hampered in the administra - tion and enforcement of the law. I would make the general observation that child welfare laws should </seg>
            <seg id="p026">23 not in any sense be designed to relieve parents of the respon?ibilit\. which ihey properly owe their children; nor should the state assume such an attitude of paternalism that the more substantial elements oi industry and thrift will have been neglected, discouraged or abridged. The children of today represent the men and women upon whom i lie success ol" our government is dependent tomorrow. Therefore, t.hej should not be environed with such an atmosphere of dependence that they will lose the qualities that make for independence. When parents properly supervise the welfare of their ■children, there will be little necJ for legislation affecting the outward influences that contribute to tlieii delinquency. 1 am hopeful that an effort will not be made to enact too ruan&gt; laws bearing upon this subject just now. Let us address ourselves to the fundamental task of developing the home and surrounding it with the proper environment. When we have tlone this, we shall have t:.keu a long step forward in removing the ills that today threaten the genera lion of tomorrow. Our duty just now is to the unfortunate ones who do not and &lt;jSui - not. care for themselves. This, with sane laws governing health and marital relations together with encouragement to parents to do their duty, will largely suffice for the present. Health. The placing of tiie administration of the health laws vi. tin - state and the grouping of the professional examining boards under the Department of Public Welfare has proven highly satisfacory in the en - forcement and administration of the health laws of the state, it is gratifying to note that through the aethities of the Bureau of Vita' Statistics Nebraska has been placed within the registered area of the Federal government. J * r Th)e law relating to this subject ought to be strengthened so that these who are charged with the responsibility of making vital returns rtmld in no sense avoid the discharge of their d'-.ty. The scope of the activities of the sanitary engineer should be &lt;\\tended Also, something ought to be done by way of requiring tht municipalities of the state to provide and care for public comfort sta - tions. This supervision should, no doubt, be accomplished through the l«.cal boards of health, The state should encourage any practical raising of the standards of the professions that have to do with the public health. Th^ mem - bers of practically all professions in this state are agreed upon this point, and amendments to the present laws, looking in this direction, cught to be carefully considered by your honorable body. Five of the professional groups . now require annual renewals of licenses. This ought to be a requirement in all professions. In turn, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">24 amount of the fees paid in. The members of all examining boards should be placed on a flat per diem basis of $10.00 with necessnry expenses. Department of Public Works. I Roads. The thirty-seventh session of the Legislature ena/Heu the st comprehensive group of road laws the state has ever had, and ler this legislation, supported by adequate appropriations and careful ervision of the work Nebraska has made as much progress in road elopment during the last biennium as was made during the previous ade. If we are to have a continuation of this program or progress 1 development, it means a continuation of appropriations for carrying the work, as well as practical distribution of and supervision over the enditure of the funds. Under the present law, the money that is received lor automobile license taxes is paid into the County Treasurer and then forwarded tu the State Treasurer. I would recommend that, inasmuch as all of this money, with the exception of 5 per cent for purposes or administration, is spent in the county in which it originates, it should be left with the County Treasurer, to be paid out on warrants approved by the State Department of Public Works. This would remove an unnecessary trans - fer of these funds and would allay a criticism that now exists. tThe criticism is also made that a larger percentage of the auto - ile license tax. money should be spent on county roads, other than federal and state aid roads. This may be accomplished In a sense, it would be highly unwise to designate by law a much lower per of this money than is now provided for use on the federal and 3 highways. In my opinion, it should be provided that up to, perhaps, the pres - ent percent: jc county boards and the Department of Public Works may use this fund for the maintenance of the state and federal highway system, but that at their discretion a smaller percentage might be used and the balance returned for use on other county highways. My reason for making this recommendation is that there Is a wide variation in the .cost of maintaining roads, dependent upon the lenglli of time that they have been built, conditions of soil and weather and other elements. No one can anticipate exactly what these condition* will be or what the cost will be to maintain the roads generally throughout the state. Therefore, maintenance being of at least 50 per cent importance in any good road program, it would be most unwise to hamper the proper authorities in maintaining our state and federal high - way system after the money has been spent to build these roads. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">25 Irrigation. There is little need tor amendment to the present irri - gation laws and such amendments as should be made will, m duo time, be brought to your attention by the secretary of the Department 6t Public Works. One quite important thing is that ;i law should be enacted pro - viding that plans and specifications for improvements contemplated in connection with public waterways shall be approved by the Depart - ment of Public Works before the state purchases the bonds issued iheretor. THE DIRECT PRIMARY The Republican party platform, adopted at the state convention held in Lincoln May 18th, 1920, contained this pledge: "We favor material amendments to the primary election laws, which v.-ill increase the functions and broaden the jurisdiction of the ccunty ;ind state conventions, and we favor further amendments to prever.r the manifest abuses of said primary." The thirty-seventh session of the Legislature amended the primary law in such a way as to provide for the nomination of all state officers under Governor at a titate convention, with the further provision thai. delegates to precinct and county conventions should be elected by the direct vote of the people, and in turn only those elected to the county convention might be eligible for election to the state convention. These amendment &amp; were made in good faith to extend the opera - lions of the direct primary in such a way as to make it more practical in effect than under the present system. It remained, however, fo - the referendum to be exercised against a certain section of this law, thus rendering the balance of it practically inoperative, in that when the incentive was removed to nominate these certain state officers in the state convention, the incentive was also removed to oe a candi - date to the local or state conventions. Although only about two-fifths of the vote for president was cast on the referendum, the fact that it pre vailed by so large a majority may be taken by some as significant that the present primary law is in high favor. The very opposite is true, and the advocates of representative government by majority expression can not approve its operations. It is not necessary to enter into an extended discussion ni this subject to remind even the most casual observer that under the present system the nominees for the major offices are minority candidates, and as these minorities become better organized, it at once becomes possible for them to practically dominate the election of the principal public officials. Such a system is just as dangerous to popular gov - ernment as was the old system of nomination by the special interests and may even be much more far-reaching in its harmful effects. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">26 not ueiieve in political parties, iney admit tncir aonercnc© to Bction through minorities, a system that is absolutely contrary in principal to the fundamentals upon which out form of government has been built. To be sure I would not ignore the rights of a minority, but political parties, under the present disposition of the people to vote miepen dently, are sufficiently responsive to any real demands for governmental reforms that these rights will be amply protected. I believe in political parties and in party responsibility. And ihc only way to obtain it is to give political parties an opportunity to pre - sent their principles of government and their candidates for office, through the expression of a majority of their adherents. I If we are to bring about a majority expression in the nomination our candidates, then it seems to me that one of two courses must pursued, and in each of these courses the principle of the direct nary will be preserved: (1) We must have primary nominating ventions to select one candidate for each of the several offices, but ving the primary open to all other entrants who may not have per ted their names to go before the nominating convention, or (2) we st have two primaries, the first to be an elimination primary out which two candidates only would be chosen, subject to nomination the second primary. I It is no longer wise to follow the politically expedient course of liding this issue, and 1 predict that those who come forward with h mg practical solution for this problem will receive the general ap bation of the people NON-PAID ELECTION OFFICIALS. We pr.y our election officials only $3.00 per day for their services This is scarcely enough to attract anyone who has anything else to do. Considering, however, the total number of these officials and the man\ elections held, the expense involved amounts to a tidy sum each year. §1 now recommend to you that election officials be drawn for serv - much after the plan followed in selecting juries, with certain pro- Ions as to qualifications and exemptions from service, and that they non-paid. iAt ISast two benefits would result from such a plan. First, bat ol ndary importance, would be the saving of money thus effected. In holding of the state-wide elections alone this would probably amount to J250.000.00 per year. Second, but of first importance, would be the Increased inteiest thus aroused in governmental affairs. This, I think, strikes at tbe very </seg>
            <seg id="p030">27 heart o£ one of our foremost present day ills — the people do not take enough interest in helping to run their government. To serve the slate in such a capacity one day iu ea^h year would work no great hardship upon anyone. In many instances it would pro - duce the services of muc-h more competent help than it Is possible to obtain at the present low rate of pay, and it would stimulate in the hearts of those who serve a deeper interest and respect for their gov - ernment. INLAND WATERWAYS. Cheaper transportation facilities for the marketing of grain from the great cornbelt is of vital importance, and means a very great deal to the grain "producers in Nebraska. The financial saving that would re - sult to Nebraska in the development of a waterways system that would enable the ocean carriers to reach the western port? of the Great Lakes is shown in the following facts which I Quote from Julius II. Barnes, former President of ihe United States Grain corporation: "The present rail rate from Buffalo to New York is 12c per bushel. Also, to reach Montreal, the rail rate from Georgian Bay is approximately 12c per bushel. Ocean carriers may be secured at the san«e rate rrom Montreal as from New York. The opening of the St. Lawrence watei - way and the Improvement of the Welland canal, already undertaken by Canada, would enable the lake carrier to Buffalo to extend its trip to Montreal — only Cortyeight hours longer — at a cost probably not exceeding 2c per bushel. This promises a saving of 10c a bushel during part of the year. Its influence may reasonably be calculated to affect and im - prove the farm price by 5c a bushel on the entire grain crops of that se.ction of the country, whose arc of competitive rail rate would thus be centered on the Great Lakes ports — Duluth, Chicago. Milwaukee. De- This would produce an estimated saving to NebraskH of over $10, 0OO.OdO.OO a year on shipments of wheat and corn alone. With these facts before us, it seems to me highly desirable that thia state should give substantial support to the mcrvement for the oeyelopment of the Great Lakes-Si. Lawrence Tidewater project. Also we might very properly make recommendations to Congress, bearing upon water transportation to the Gulf of Mexico via the Missouri river. REVISION OF STATUTES The statutes of Nebraska must be revised. They havt- beco.rue so cumbersome that they should be entirely revamped. This ought to be done in a careful and business-like manner under the supervision of the most competent authorities. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">28 The Constitutional Convention included among its committees one ou tit j It* and phraseology. It was the duty of this committee to pass upon each proposal as to style and phraseology before it came up for final passage. I think this was an excellent provision and I racommena that such a committee be created at this session of the Legislature. This committee might also be .charged with the duty of seeing that proper legislation is introduced looking toward the carrying out of the purposes of the recent amendments -to the Constitution. Kin closing, I commend to your thoughtful consideration the recoui - [iations that I have here made, and if I can be of service to you Hp course of your deliberations, I am yours to command. SAMUEL R. MeKELVIE, Governor </seg>
            <seg id="p032">29 MONEY RECEIVED BY THE GOVERNOR FOR BIENNIUM ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1920. REPRIEVES, COMMUTATIONS AND PARDONS. In keeping with Section 13, Article 5 of the Constitution oi Ne - braska, 1 herewith submit a list of the names of those who have been pardoned or whose sentences have been commuted, and those who have been reprieved, giving the name, crime, date of sentence, character of the release and the date thereof: Chas. P. Hoover, No. 4832; murder; sentenced January 28. ittO &lt;ommuted April 14, 1919. Van Wilson Goodsell, No. 5202; murder second degree; sentenced February 20, 1909; commuted to 15 years April 14, 1919. Chas, H. Briley, No. 5605; murder 2nd degree; sentenced Februa;j 4. 1911; commuted to 20 years May 12, 1919. Clarence Clawson, No. 6170; murder 2nd degree; sentenced Octobc; L'4. 1913; commuted to 7 years, 3 months April 15, 1919. Tom Collins, No. 3548: murder; sentenced January i. 1900; par t'.oned July 4. 1919. Frank Dinsmore, No. 3741; murder; sentenced April 30. 1901; par doned July 4. 1919. Alson B. Cole. No. 7298, and Allen Vincent Grammer, No. 7299; mur - der; sentenced in March, 1918, to be executed on July 12, 1918; reprieved until January 17th, 1919, by Governor Neville, and both have been re - prieved from time to time until December 20th, 1920. Harry Willis, No. 7370; hog stealing; sentenced September 15. 1919; pardoned June 19, 1919, by Acting Governor Barrows on petition of citizens and endorsement of the trial judge. All of the foregoing have been granted after careful consideration Fees for Register of Deeds $ 20.00 Fees for .conducting warehouses 24.00 Extradition, fees..._ _ 140.00 Agricultural settlement 743.70 Proceeds — Sale of public lands 3,815.78 Miscellaneous items _ 19.0'i Total : 14.762.48 For liquoi permits to druggists 1,548.10 Total ;. $6,310.58 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">the Penitentiary. Ray Sandlovich; receiving stolen property; sentenced from one to two years, June 19, 1918; pardoned by Acting Governor Barrows before en tering the Penitentiary. </seg>
	           <seg id="p034"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>