<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00057.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00057.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the State Industrial School Kearney, Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE State Industrial School KEARNEY, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions For the Period Ending June 30, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">FOREWORD To His Excellency, the Governor : The Board of Control herewith transmits the Fifth Biennial Report of the State Institutions of Nebraska for the period ending June 30, 1923. The biennium formerly ended on November 30 of each even-numbered year, but this date was changed by an act of the legislature, so that this report really covers a period of thirty-one months from December 1, 1920, to June 30, 1923. During the period, no change has occurred in the personnel of the Board, but several changes have been made in the chief officers of institutions. Dr. Beverly A. Finkle, superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, resigned to enter private practice, and was succeeded on August 23, 1921, by Dr. J. H. Matthai. Miss Amy V. Stevens, who had been superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska, for a number of years, resigned on July 5, 1922, being succeeded by her sister, Miss Nellie Stevens. The latter served until February 19, 1923, when her resignation was received, and Miss Lena Driever was appointed to the position. We call attention with pride and pleasure to the fact that the report shows the institutions to have gone through the bien - nium without incurring any deficiencies ; although the cost of living, and consequently the cost of supporting the state's depen - dents, has certainly not decreased since the appropriations were made for the biennium. Some improvements of a permament character have been made at the various institutions during the period covered by this report. A hospital building, bakery and scullery have been erected at the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded, Beatrice, Nebraska ; a cottage for girls at the Girls' Training School, Geneva, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska; a gymnasium building at the State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska; a hospital building at the Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska; a farm house and a barn at the Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a warehouse at the State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska ; a kitchen building at the Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk, Nebraska ; a main building at the State Reformatory for Women, York, Nebraska. These buildings were badly needed, and they will have to be followed by others in the very near future if our wards are to be properly, efficiently and economically cared for. The legislature just past made provision for two or three buildings, but failed to see the necessity for several others that were urgently requested. Brief mention was made in the last report of the establishment of the Reformatory for Men at Lincoln, but the importance of the institution calls, we believe, for rather more extended notice. This institution was established as a result, primarily, of a wide recognition of the need of segregating young first-term offenders from more mature criminals. The legislature of 1921 authorized the establishment, therefore, of such an institution, making an initial approproation of $300,000. Of this sum the Board ex - pended $37,500 for 10 acres and a brick building known as the Hayward Military Academy, later buying about 152 acres of contiguous land for the sum of $49,531.25. This land is used for farming, stock raising, dairying, and intensive gardening. Various trades are taught such as tailoring, shoe repairing, carpentry and joinery, brick laying, electricity, automobile repairing, launder - ing, engineering, firing, and barbering. The manual labor about the institution is, of course, performed by the inmates, of which there are at this date 189. Mr. A. W. Miller, the superintendent, is doing much constructive work with the young men committed to his charge, and we believe the institution is amply justifying itself. The difficulty of employing the penitentiary inmates at suitable labor that does not conflict too much with the prerogatives of the free workers of our state, has been pretty well overcome. The state still operates the fibre furniture factory which has been at the prison for some years, and has also established relations with the Oberman Company by which shirts are made and disposed of with a minimum of competition with free labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 INMATE POPULATION There are seventeen institutions under the control of the Board, and at this time (July 1, 1923) the inmate population is 5917, as compared with an average of 4980 for the biennium ending in 1921, and 4907 for the biennium just prior to that. The following table will be found of interest as showing, the population of the different institutions during the past two biennia : Av. pop. Av. pop. Largest liu-imiuin biennium number Institutions ending ending at any one (With "Key" Letters) June 30, June 30, time past 1921 1923 two years A— Institution for Feeble-Minded 607 725 756 B— Girls' Training School 106 173 189 C— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 409 353 412 D— Hastings State Hospital 1152 1193 1219 E— State Industrial School 217 214 241 F— Hospital for Tuberculous 78 102 106 G— Lincoln State Hospital 837 971 995 H— Orthopedic Hospital 64 88 102 J — State Penitentiary 363 586 596 K— Nebraska Industrial Home 73 86 99 L— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 148 162 195 M— School for the Blind (a) 47 53 57 N— Norfolk State Hospital 646 733 768 P— School for the Deaf (a) 171 178 187 R— State Reformatory for Women 9 18 28 S— Home for Dependent Children 53 91 107 T — State Reformatory for Men (b) Not open 150 192 Total 4980 5876 6249 (a) 19 months (1921, 9 months school; 1922, 10 months school.) (b) Open only 21 months; started October 1, 1921. EXPENDITURES The following table reveals the expenditures at the various institutions for the past biennium, the item of salaries and wages being included under Maintenance in all instances excepting the first. Capital outlay represents permanent improvements to the realty and equipment Board of Control, Lincoln — Maintenance $ 5,151.87 Salaries and Wages 42,529.53 $ 47,681.40 Institution for Feeble-Minded, Beatrice — Maintenance 253,843.43 Cash 27,524.49 Capital Outlay 93,899.95 375,267.87 Girls' Training School, Geneva — Maintenance 111,808.47 Cash 4,964.20 Capital Outlay 42,000.00 158,772.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett — Maintenance 176,14828 Cash 67,846.61 Capital" OutiayZZZZ...^ 115,000.00 358,994.89 Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside — Maintenance 501,184.46 Cash 99,853.78 Capital Outlay...- 38,850.25 639,888.49 State Industrial School, Kearney — Maintenance 161,200.06 Cash 26,345.72 Capital Outlay 43,44024 230,986.02 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney — Maintenance 106,076.45 Cash 30,794.13 Capital Outlay 1 17,826.18 254,696.76 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance _ 375,095,50 Cash 89,072.43 Capital Outlay 74,803.84 538,971.77 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 122,286.28 Cash .._ 25,627.53 Capital Outlay 4,490.17 152,403.98 State Penitentiary, Lincoln — Maintenance 229,205.92 Cash 161,633.02 Capital Outlay _ 390,838.94 Capital Outlay. Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford — Maintenance 61 ,306.38 Cash 2,578.26 Capital Outlay 63,884.64 Capital Outlay. Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford — Maintenance 94,406.99 Cash - - 29,700.29 Capital Outlay 15,934.10 140,041.38 School for the Blind, Nebraska City — Maintenance _ 57,82522 Cash _ _ 3,989.06 Capital Outlay 3,952.01 65.76629 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk- Maintenance " 321.060.71 Cash 50,535.76 Capital Outlay..- 59,999.01 431,595.48 School for the Deaf, Omaha — Maintenance _ 137,695.55 Cash 16,819.16 Capital Outlay 4,500.00 159,014.71 State Reformatory for Women, York — Maintenance 28,489.38 Cash _ 2,733.39 Capital Outlay . 46,996.15 78218.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln — Grand Total. 4,538,783.65 At its various institutions the state owns something over 4000 acres of land, of which in excess of 3500 are in farm and garden. About 800 acres are rented in addition. Details of operation are given in the reports from the several superintendents which are appended hereto. The health of the inmate population has been generally good during the past biennium. We are pleased to be able to report that no epidemic has broken out at any of the institutions, and our medical men have been able to cope with such sporadic cases of contagious disease as have appeared. In conclusion we wish to express our appreciation of the efforts of the officers and employees of the various institutions in striving to bring about a betterment of the living conditions of the wards under their care. We wish also to thank the Governor for his manifestations of interest and for his assistance in the work of this department, and we trust that he will continue his efforts to help us provide better means of caring for the wards of the state. Board of Control, KATHERINE F. WORLEY, Chairman, A. E. ALLYN, L. C. OBERLIES. Attest : E. B. FAIRFIELD, Secretary. Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay 65,026.59 7,584.94 72,611.5. &gt;tate Reformatory for Men, Lincoln — Maintenance ; Cash Capital Outlay 72,188.46 6,959.45 300,000.00 379,147.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AVERAGE DAILY POPULATION STATE INSTITUTIONS OF TOTAL POPULATION 5,876 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 EXPENDITURES FOR 1921-1 922 SALARIES and WAGES OPERATION and MAINTENANCE FURNITURE and EQUIPMENT NEW BUILDINGS LANO M87H8.O8 FIXED CHARGES and STATE AID UM2 .276.9 H 2,272,^65.46 I96,O93.9H 6O3.6H9.60 6,848.53 PERMANENT IMF TO BUILDINGS and GKOUND5 1 1 1 ,02570 TOTAL 4,491,102.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 INCOME FOR 1921-1922 STATE FUNDS CASH FUNDS FEDERAL FUNDS TRUST FUNDS 3,841,348.13 598,304.90 66,960.00 48,100.56 4,554,713.59 TOTAL • UNEXPENDED BALANCE OF CASH , FEDERAL AND TRUST FUNO (CL0THIN6 FUNO.INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLEMINDED) RERPPROPRIATEO </seg>
	           <seg id="p011">11 (a) Opened October 1, 1921. 21 months. EXPENDITURES, STA July 1, 1921 to June 30, T Institution for Feeble-Minded.... Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School _ Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary _ Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital School for the Deaf. — State Reformatory for Women.... Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (a).... f Salaries and . Wages 89,737.78 31,660.01 77,410.19 226,534.52 60,739.65 45,281.20 178,107.10 56,464.88 93,393.20 19,294.61 35,009.08 32,444.05 137,841.88 77,242.53 9,137.15 19,53925 52,439.86 $ Operation and Maintenance 186,411.64 82,797.68 155,198.27 351,306.24 120,474.65 87,490.63 269,172.04 89,805.58 288,860.20 42,879.03 88,144.78 28,007.41 229,413.66 74,549.12 19,058.85 49,977.47 108,918.21 Furniture and Equipment $ 25,232.79 9,782.66 8,110.35 15,447.16 10,568.22 16,452.47 16.898.41 4,786.04 4,309.18 520.59 5,468.85 676.87 38,443.00 7,223.06 3,470.00 1,003.35 27,700.94 Permanent Improvements to Bldgs. and Grounds $236.00 16.08 150.50 8,557.31 10.72 2,124.19 28.624.45 1.347.48 3,776.36 1,165.66 10,552.41 685.95 3,634.66 New Buildings $72,778.39 34,512.84 118,115.58 37,872.07 39,192.78 103,348.27 45,077.86 Land $ 871,27 3.40 10.00 171.19 Fixed and State Aid Charges I 375,267,87 158,772.67 358,994.89 639,888.49 230,986.02 254,696.76 538,971.77 152,403.98 390,838,94 63,884.64 140,041.38 65,766.29 431,595.48 139,014.71 78,218.92 72,611.53 379,147.91 Total for Diennium Per Ccnf 8.3 3.5 8.0 14.2 S.I 5.7 12.0 .3.4 8.7 1.4 3.1 1.4 10.0 3.5 1.7 1.6 8.4 i~09l"91 ' 847.26'" 500.00 24.75 19.00 3,952.01 200.00 22,062.28" 7,500.00 2,091.46 50,552.47 39J0S2S2 90J&amp;J3S 48,747.68 Total . $1,242,276.94 $2,272,465.46 $196,093.94 $121,025.70 $603,649.60 $48,747.08 $6,843.53 $4,491,102.25 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">2 POPULATION AND PER CAPITA REPORT OF STATE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1921, to June 30, 1923 Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 Average number Inmates during Biennium Number of employees June 30, 1923, Average number employees during Biennium Average number Inmates to each employee Average per Capita Cost for Biennium Average per Capita Cost per month Average amount Pay Roll per month Institution for Feeble-Minded Girls' Training School _ Soldiers' Home, Burkett. Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary.... Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the BKnd (a).... Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf (a) State Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (b) 747 183 301 1,200 207 103 981 93 579 63 154 53 767 187 25 87 187 725 173 353 1,193 214 102 971 88 586 86 162 53 733 178 18 91 150 66 20 72 160 40 36 132 49 55 11 32 24 90 49 7 14 26 61 19 62 158 38 35 131 48 53 11 31 24 88 48 6 13 25 12 9 6 7 5 3 7 2 11 8 5 2 8 4 3 7 6 $ 380.89 661.60 659.00 484.27 846.80 1,301.68 460.63 1,662.16 652.31 722.95 760.20 1,140.59 501.03 852.76 1,566.44 763.92 1,075.72 $ 15.87 27.57 27.46 20.18 35.28 54.23 19.19 69.25 27.18 30.12 31.67 47.52 20.87 35.53 6527 31.83 51.22 $ 3,562.47 1,319.17 3,225.42 9,438.94 2,530.82 1,886.72 7,421.13 2,352.70 3,891.47 803.94 1,458.71 1,351.84 5,743.41 3,218.44 380.01 814.14 2,497.13 Total 5,917 5,876 851 $ 598.15 $24.92 $51,896.46 (a) Average during school year. (b) Open id October 1. 1921—21 months. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 AGE Or THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIHST TIME •erii lini une Under 5 years 5 to 9 yrs. inc. 10 to 14 yrs. inc. 15 to 17 yrs, inc. 18 to 24 yrs. inc. 25 to 34 yrs. inc. 35 to 44 yrs. inc. 45 to 49 yrs. inc. 50 to 59 yrs. inc. 60 to 69 yrs. inc. 70 to 79 yrs. inc. 80 to 90 yrs. inc. Over 90 years Unascer- tained Total astitution for Feeble-Minded iirls' Training School oldiers' Home, Burkett [astings State Hospital tate Industrial School [ospital for Tuberculous incoln State Hospital. irthopedic Hospital tate Penitentiary. febraska Industrial Home. oldiers' Home, Milford. lebraska School for the Blind. (orfolk State Hospital febraska School for the Deaf. tate Reformatory for Women [ome for Dependent Children tate Reformatory for Men IS 67 70 28 38 134 33 » 6 6 " 1 I 1 246 162 135 472 333 229 586 384 369 92 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 ~~ 13 204 18 17 57 13 59 33 41 60 54 41 37 31 112 80 i 36 9 5» 16 58 "' 79 61 30 15 2 " 3 6 ~ " ■"" 17" 9 65 .14 63 185 17 223 28 135 10 61 16 SO 3 18 "~ \2 70 8 43 1 1 ... ™. job™ 89 """ '31 I 2 14 i . — r-1 7 1 4 3 12 2 8 6 15 4 27 1 39 1 3 6 « '66 "» 4 .... T 25 80 74 36 41 "38 34 i 121 r • "■■« i i " 3 i 180 46 Total 211 293 324 599 581 743 399 172 212 181 76 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Y OF 1 HOSE ADI ITTED rOl FIRST TIMS Biei inium Endin; I June 30, 19; i. VMM* lllodtd Girt.' alnlng aehool goldkra ■ad8_Uon &gt; Home Barkatl Hutlnn SUte HcuplUl 8Ut. IndiaMil School Hospital for Tuberculou* Llneoln SUte HotpiUl Orthofmlie HoapiUl suu PtnlUntiary Ntbruk. InrtuatrUl Home Solditn anda»llor»' Bom* Mlifonl Ntbruki School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nehraaku Ucboo] for the Dauf Reformatory for Women Home tor Dependent Children Reformatory tor Total •■■" ■— •• ••—— . Aatfrta TTi 3 " 6 _ i 14 7 20 12 3 28 1 18 24 28 3 'j 95 7 1 4 21 4 6 1 21 1 1929 1 4 14 30 1 S 1 2 1 2 44 (i 1 1564 124 30 ... Bohemia ' Bulgaria . I ' '""I. _ ™ 2 2 i 1 „ h r i "7 12 " "3 l"~ « nfii _... r wHHKSkmiki. Dcaattrk PiaUa. France . ,. , , Gaf___av « _ _ _ Greece _ Intliml -__ ~... hannr ( If n Macedonia Mexico _ Nebradca , „ » Netherlands Norway Poland _ _ Rutti. Spain ZIZZZZ. Sweden Sm-k-erland Turkey • I S. other than Nebraska. &lt; nkiinwi) Countries Tout „. i 7 6 17 8 6 2 1 " ~ i .. 1 ! ■ 3 "T~ i 4 1 ~""i i 4 5 1 2 27 _ I 1 — ~- 2 __J 1 19 1 .... 2 2 „„. 1 1 3 2 1 1 "i 2 i 2 "H i , 3 7 ..._ ' 5 i" i 3 1 i i 3 2 __ _ _ — " ' 4 i ii ______ ______ ~ i ii ..... ~~ » "i 1 1 119 1 3" 2 i i' 209~ — jg 2 " - -jj7~- w 201 339 74 66 i 12 103 26 30 '232'""' 72 ~~ 1 2 3 8 1 2 l 4 "1 10 2 1 -" 2 1 2 5 ~H i ... __ i "4 i" "~ i _j i '■■ " "i l i 2 2 13 2 4 2 9 i ""* i' 13 1 i 32 56" 4 . „..„ 205 26 i 137 76 209 42 4 42 256 5 20 1 iiis '8 129' 9 29 5 1 116 45 472 333 229 384 369 ~ 125 26 162 135 586 92 21 344 35 62 238 241 - 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">IS CLASSIFICATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOB FIRST TIME Biennium Ending June 30, 1923. County Institution for Keeble Minded Girls' Training School Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Burkctt Hastings BUte Hospital State Industrial School I Hospital for Tuberculous ! Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital | I ! State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' ; and Sailors' Home Milr.nl i Nebraska », _, ,, School Nurfolk for the tStait i I Nebraska School for the Deaf ! I I Reformatory Home for for Dependent Women Children I Refoimatory for Men Total Adam* , ArthttTZZ ZZ BUine Pftftnf ____»_ Box Butte... _ Boyd Brown Buffalo Burt Butler Cm Cedar f&gt;l»f Cherry c3L» turning Cutter Dakota Oawet Oawioa Deuel Dixon Dodge Dandy , ..... „ Fillmore. Franklin Frontier Furnai Gage Garden Garfield Gotper Grant Greeley Hall ..._ ______„. Hamilton HarUn Hayes . Hitchcock ...... Z Halt _.._ Hooker _ Howard _._._... Jefferson ..... Johnson , . kSST*Lzz: ' Keya Paha _ Kimball _ „ Knox Lancaster .. Lincoln _ ..ZZ Loop ffi__aiin~ ' McPherson Merrick Nebraska Industrial Home Morrill Nance Neman* ' 1 Nnekolls Otoe Pawnee Perkins Ptielps _. Pierce Platte Polk _ _ Red Willow _ Richardson Rock Saline ..._ Sarpy Saunders ... Scotts Bluff. Seward _._._ _ Sheridan 8 1 2 6 10 43 5 1 1 1 _ 4 7 _ i 2 J_ I I - . i 1 1 I I " 1 97 35 1 2 2 26 20 27 19 8S 31 3S 40 38 1-4 1') 51 32 19 a v, 23 26 46 8 13 58 810 9 36 27 14 27 110 7 9 5 1 12 112 39 22 4 18 31 5 22 29 11 30 14 8 12 29 726 4o 3 37 / 19 1 29 21 4J 33 49 20 16 22 20 -' 40 12 39 68 8 38 11 39 44 • 53 28 27 7 17 32 16 25 1 43 19 16 19 1 1 55 8 3 1 9 3 2 2 W I 5 I I I _.. i I I 3 2 4 1 5 3 7 4 2 " 1 1 i 1 4 3 4 1 3 5 6 1 4 1 6 9 2 1 2 1 6 2 6 1 9 13 125 i i i 8 1 i 12 3 9 » 1 f 3 4 "' : 1 25 12 ______ 1 10 4 1 9 3 2 1 1 1 3 1 5 2 1 1 2 3 1 2 1 3 l l l i 2 9 ~"I 2 6 I i i l 1 i 2 5 1 2 2 5 1 10 "" I 2 3 1 f i i' 3 4 2 19 2 4 2 2 1 16 2 4 2 4 4 i 2 I 16 1 1 6 I 1 9 4 ~ 16 3 2 i' 2 l i 2 2 4 I 2 ™" 2 7 14 1 2 12 1 6 1 3 4 19 4 6 6 i I 3 10 3 4 j 8 7 i 4 i 2 2 4 1 2 "2 5 1 2 32 id 3 2 44 2 1 2~ 6 1 4 7 5 " 109 4 1 17 2 13 5 1 9 2 7 3 1 1 2 4 4 68 1 1 2 2 S 1 18 211 1 1 1 2 2 6 1 3 5 2 1 8 3 8 i i 27 3 1 5 1 1 5 76 l * I :: T :::::: ZZ 9 — 6 68 2 12 ... 3 1 i 2 1 2 56 1 1 4 1 1 1 2 8 i — =t ::::: ! " 2 2 4 _ i i ... 3 ... _ .... I _ i" 3 1 2 2 _ i _ 32 5 &gt;. 5 25 6 12 3 10 3 2 ' 1 F s 2 2 3 3 11 5 1 1 3 5 i i i 8 3 2 1 " 1 3 6 2 8 2 4 1 2 2 i" 3 1 1 3 2 8 11 2 1 12 2 4 1 ......... 1 1 1 1 3 62 4 3 1 - 4 4 8 1 3 2 2 2 1 3 1 4 1 2 ... zzzzz is "" 1 2 1 2 4 1 2 1 i :=::=::: 1 1 2 2 "' i ' 7 1 3 6 i * r~ 1 1 4 24 5 "2 i zzzzzz 2 ZZZ....__ 16 1 ! 2 1 z__ 1 ZZZ 1 49 3 1 2 1 2 3 25 3 145 1 1 1 214 1 3 1 12 14 1 1 16 2 1 38 i - 2 " ' 1 z 15 102 i'4 0 4 1 3 1 1 2 3 4 3 4 2 1 I i 1 " 2 3 1 2 I I 1 ! 21 * i .., 1 2 i 3 I I ! ■ i _. _ I i __ i' i ~ 3 1 ;.; 1 1 2 20 1 1 3 1 4 " 5 8 i ' - 5 9 14 3 1 7 1 4 3 1 1 - 15 18 9 4 ' 3 2 7 1 6 1 4 1 7 3 1 2 2 1 1 1 1 6"" 1 ....zzzz~ 8 ' 6 : !.=■::, I I ! 2 8 2 zzzzzz 1 :z."zzzz." 2 3 s 2 2 1 J 2 "7 1 i 2 1 1 1 2 2 i " i 10 10 zzzzz 3 1 12 2 5 1 5 "~ 3 6 o i 18 4 3 2 5 2 ... i Z"Z........__ 3 l ... ZZZZZZ i 2 4 5 IS 1 1 1 ... \ 3 zz.zzz 3 """ i 17 6 19 4 2 i ! i 2 i 2 1 2 ~"6 3 5 ZZZ i 11 3 3 1 "To 4 l 7 9"' 1 4 6 1 7 3 2 4 2 1 2 s ZZZZZ... i 3 1 6 11 7 i 8 5 1 6 2 2 2 zzzzzz 8 Sherman Sioux „ „__„.„. "2 2 zzzzzz s j 6 2 Stanton i 2 1 1 4 - " 2" 1 17 2 2 """ i i 3 2 1 i 2 1 Ttojwr Thomas -— 2 6 _ 2 2 4 i ThBMton _____ 1""" "s"""" ' 16 2 ■■■""■■ *•- t — -».— * 1 13 1 7 z:zz.z_.:j n i' Unknown Valley ZZZZ Washington Wayne Webster '" 7 ~1 2 2 4 5 1 2 2 1 i " 2 ' ~ Z!_ ii io 1 2 Z. ZZZZ! i 2 1 f 1 1 1 11 2 ... 1 L. _.._. . Wheeler J Other States York r 4 1 ..._ _.._ | ZZZZZZ 1 ■■ ■ " 1 it ~8 T ~1 4 -• I Total ... 162 135 472 333 369 125 21 35 238 241 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">17 STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL Kearney, Nebraska OFFICERS R. V. CLARK F. R. DICKSON S. W. BISSELL J. L. BENNETT Superintendent Assistant Superintendent Steward Physician MRS. MINNIE ALBRIGHT Matron MisceLaneous Statement Boys' and Girls' Industrial School 1879-1891 Established as State Industrial School for Boys 1891 Number of employees 40 Number of inmates June 30, 1923 207 Highest number of inmates 241 Per capita cost per month $ 3528 Number of acres 602 Number of acres rented 60 Number of acres under cultivation 602 Value of lands and buildings $ 423,496.34 Principal Industries — Farming, stock-raising. Particular attention is given to manual training. Visiting Days — Afternoons from 2 to 5, excepting Saturday and Sunday. Admission to the school is through commitment by court and is confined to sane boys under 18 found guilty of crime (except homicide) or boys under 16 who are beyond parental control. Boys are required to remain until 21 years of age, unless sooner released by court order or paroled by the Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">19 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska : I respectfully present the Superintendent's Report of the State Industrial School for Boys for the period ending June 30, 1923. Our school opened this year with an enrollment of 212 and closed with 218 boys. The school work included the grades from one to ten inclusive. Four rooms are devoted to the teaching of school subjects, one room to the teaching of music and fourteen rooms to the teaching of trades, or manual training. The manual training and trade departments are as follows : Baking, cooking, carpentry, laundering, mechanics, painting, print - ing, shoemakng and tailoring. Each boy attends the graded school one-half of each day, and works in the trades school the other half. Under supervision the boys learn the practical art of baking. This department contributes annually 53,000 loaves of bread, besides cakes, etc. A demand constantly exists for experienced bakers. Our boys learn a practical trade which will later demand for them a living wage. For our colored boys, especially, many of whom will follow this line of work as men, culinary details furnish good training. The carpenter shop is a place of industry. The cutting, fram - ing and joining of timber is taught ; farm implements, furniture, etc., are repaired, windows are replaced about the institution. The wood work for the forms of the new tunnels were built by this de - partment. The laundry is well equipped. Washing, cleaning, dyeing, ironing, pressing, marking, counting, sorting and delivering are here taught, and the clothing of 250 people is laundered. The workers of the laundry are paroled with a trade which will bring a living. There is a world-wide demand for real mechanics. The machine shop and boiler room offer training to our boys. Three large boilers are fired and accompanying machinery kept in repair. An efficient engineer directs the work in this dpartment. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 We are proud of our painting detail. Upon these boys and their capable instructor depends the neat appearance of the school both externally and internally. Mixing paint and skillfully apply - ing same is a good trade for the boys. These boys are furnished practical work which gives them experience. The school printing office furnishes some of the printed forms used by the seventeen institutions. It does all the printing for this school and also publishes a monthly paper. The boys in the print - ing office become proficient in a desirable and profitable trade, and are holding paying positions throughout the state. The office is equipped with two good job presses and one modern cylinder press. One new up-to-date Intertype machine has been added to the equipment. About $1700 has been earned for the state by our printers in the last twelve months. The department of shoemaking is also of commercial value to the institution. The boys of this detail save much which would otherwise be spent to purchase shoes. Our handmade shoes are of better leather, stronger material, and are more thoroughly sewed. Some of the boys learn the trade so thoroughly that one can make a pair of good shoes in a working day. For our 200 boys not one shoe is purchased on the market. Each boy of this school has two pairs of shoes, one pair for work, a second pair for Sunday. Har - ness and other leather repairs are attended to by the shoemakers. The tailoring department makes the clothing for the boys of the school. Excepting caps, stockings and collars, all articles of clothing are made by the tailors. They work of course under the direction of an expert cutter and tailor. Music is furnished by a twenty-one piece band under the direc - tion of an able instructor. The band is a source of entertainment to the boys of the school, and to the citizens of Kearney and neighboring communities. For its services in the last biennium the band has brought the state $684.65. The school has twenty-two horses and mules. The boys of the barn detail pride themselves upon the care of these animals. The man in charge, as well as the boys and teams, are busy almost daily with the institution hauling and farm work. The dairy comprises 62 tuberculin-tested Holstein cows. The entire herd consists of one hundred and thirty-five. It is valued at $14,000. The boys of the dairy detail gain valuable experience </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 in the feeding and care of cows. Milk and cream have been sold netting the state $9125.53 during the period ending June 30, 1923. The boys of the school generally have been healthy and strong. The marked improvement in the physical condition of many boys after entering has been noted with satisfaction. The Merit System The merit system is a marked aid in maintaining discipline throughout the school. Each boy is required to earn 1S,OOO credits before he is entitled to parole. The better his behavior, and the more diligent in work and study, the more rapidly he gains his credits. Each boy determines to the greatest possible degree the length of his stay in the school. Some boys have earned their paroles in nine months, others in fourteen months and a few have remained seventeen months. The boy who receives no demerits for twdve months is rewarded by the gift of one month off his term ; truthfulness for twelve months gains two months' credit. This syste n serves the dual purpose of securing good deportment and minimizing the necessity for corporal punishment. The employees have been mindful of the moral training due the boys of this school, and constant endeavor is made to encourage them to lead pure lives. Their spiritual welfare is nourished, we hope, by means of the chapel exercises each Sunday afternoon at three o'clock, and by the Sunday School lessons taught in their companies. Ministers are invited to speak who will encourage the boys to live Christian lives. Our farm of 620 acres provides more work for our boys than any other department. Certainly the boys who work on the farm will be forcefully impressed with the resourcefulness of rural life and its advantages. Two notable improvements were made in our institution in 1922-23 : A new brick gymnasium 55 feet wide by 109 feet long furnishes ample opportunities for athletic sports such as basket ball, wrestling and boxing; also permitting an ideal arrangement for the giving of the weekly picture show and other entertan - ments. On Sunday the auditorium furnishes facilities for the chapel exercises. The second marked improvement is the tunnel system com - pletely installed by our own boys and men. One hundred three rods of tunnels extend all around the campus rectangle and enter </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 each cottage, the main building, the trades building and the new gymnasium. These tunnels, which are six feet three inches high in the clear and six feet wide, furnish ideal channels through which run the new heat pipe lines, and also the new hot and cold water lines. More than that ; the boys can march during storms and darkness comfortably and safely. The boys having done the work, the State expended money for material only at a total expense of $6000.00. These tunnels are the most beneficial material improve - ment to the State Industrial School made in the last two decades. Our sincere thanks are hereby given to faithful co-workers who have assisted and encouraged the Superintendent in this important work with delinquent boys. R. V. CLARK, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Movement For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Present at beginning of period Admitted : For first time Re-admitted Transferred from other institutions Returned from parole granted before commencement of period Returned from escape made before commencement of period 2Z1 333 4 2 101 6 Total 683 ischarged : Expiration of fixed term Reached majority Transferred to other institutions On account epilepsy Rescind order of Judge Released to parents or friends Died Paroled and not returned during period Escaped and not returned during period 0 11 7 1 1 4 1 433 19 Total 477 emaining at end of period .verage number under care .bsent on parole or escape at commencement of period or during period and later discharged without returning to school 206 207 0 TABLE II— AGE AND COLOR OF THOSE AD ITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Age and Color W. C. T. Under ten - Ten and under twelve Twelve and under fourteen Fourteen and under sixteen _. Sixteen and under eighteen : Eighteen and under twenty-one 8 23 45 91 124 0 3 3 7 17 11 1 11 26 52 108 135 1 Total 293 42 333 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 ADMITTED TABLE III— EDUCATION OF THOSE For Period Ending Education June 30, 1925 Below third grade and including third. Fourth grade 37 38 42 Fifth grade Sixth grade Seventh grade. Eighth grade- High school 45 57 56 58 Total .. 333 TABLE IV— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMIT ED Nativity For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Nebraska United States other than Nebraska Canada Denmark England Greece Mexico Poland Russia Total 188 137 1 1 1 1 1 2 _J 333 TABLE V— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE A MITTED Nativity For Period Ending June 30, 1923 United States (both parents) Foreign. Mixed Unknown Total 262 52 17 2 333 TABLE VI— PARENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE A MITTED FOR FIRST TIME Parental Condition For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Both parents dead _ Father dead Mother dead - Parents living together Parents separated Parents divorced _ Parents unknown .'. Total 15 68 42 127 26 51 _4 333 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">TABLE VII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF THE lDMITTED ERIOD County Total for Period Remaining June 30, 1923 Adams Antelope Boone Brown Buffalo Burt Cass Chase Cheyenne Clay Custer Dawson Dawes Dodge Douglas Dundy Fillmore Frontier Furnas Gage Garden darneld Hall Hamilton Harlan Hayes Hitchcock Holt Jefferson Johnson Kearney Keith Keya Paha Kimball 5 1 4 1 12 1 4 4 4 3 4 3 3 7 W) 1 2 1 2 7 1 2 6 3 3 0 3 1 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 62 3 4 I) 0 2 1 1 3 1 5 1 S 3 7 3 1 3 2 0 1 1 5 0 2 2 2 0 3 4 4 7 75 0 1 1 0 2 0 0 7 1 1 1 1 0 1 0 2 1 0 1 1 42 1 0 4 1 2 0 1 3 0 0 0 7 0 2 3 0 0 Knox Lancaster Lincoln Loup Madison Merrick Nemaha Nance Nuckolls Otoe Pawnee Perkins Pierce piatte ;::;.:; Red Willow Z! Richardson Saline Saunders Scotts Bluff _._ZL!_I__1_ </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 TABLE VII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF THE PERIOD— Continued County Total for Period Remaining June 30, 1923 Seward Sheridan — Stanton Thayer Thomas Valley Washington Wayne Webster York .3 1 1 2 2 2 1 1 1 8 0 0 1 2 1 1 0 1 0 5 Total 333 206 TABLE VIII— CAUSE FOR ADMISSIO OF THOSE DMITTED Cause For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Dependency and neglect Unclassified Assault Breaking and entering Bootlegging Burglary Felony Forgery Grand larceny Horse stealing Incorrigibility Robbery Mendicancy and crime Theft (stealing) 6 105 1 18 1 11 1 27 1 2 27 4 4 125 Total 333 ... TABLE IX— STATISTICS OF PAROLE PUPI Paroled during period Returned from parole : For cause Escaped from parole and not retaken Died while on parole On parole June 30, 1923 474 41 34 3 396 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 TABLE X— DIVISION OF LABOR OF ALL PUPILS During Biennium Ending June 30, 1923 6 Bakers Barn . 19 Boiler House Carpenter shop. 7 5 Cooks, boys' kitchen and officers' kitchen Dairy 39 24 Force 132 Green house- House, boys. Laundry 20 99 23 Paint shop... Print shop... Shoe shop Tailor shop. 6 8 12 16 Total 416 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 I — I S§ 1 1 Hi &gt;on i i • 51 qo oo *-* '. '. : O\ oo oT i i j *- T «■ cg&lt;M ; i iincsi 8 o •a a 2 r. 3°. inSs_ 3 0 2 e2 s 3 en r3 U S si 3 SOOQ :OOO .^h o : o oqo p4 &lt;rj *o ! «" oC c5 -h o : in in o 5 a 3 00 : u a •o c oo m 3. a Vr -I Si S3 i ! ! iS8. I !^ - ! | | |5 CO H o p o O 0 h u u U no k t 4 3 3 H 3 5 ( i &gt; M H &amp; O a, a &lt; M u O H •O.2 II u 6 | s 8.S88.8 jS ! oooo cm :\n : s H O c M &gt; 13 88. I ! i§8. voS : i :r&gt;*in » ill i i i £) 00 : ': I in ■d 5 8 3 E C d 2; 8888888 (Nl rC rr in io o 00-h t^.t*a 8 1 V9- y a d 2 "j-^oooc^wcm — eg N Q V : I- I ' |'{ I I | : «i : : : • MJ3 3«3 CO UUQOOXK o o H </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 ll I I 1 o a 1 3 &gt; 00 pj "itn tvf cfl c c •J. '-z 69- - E 3 3|2||||| || S !8s8.2oKg8 I «9- • o X — — r— u u 2 ?; :§k§o°-N 8 : !$ ! o i^ vo\o*2 «"i co i •3 c CJ 88 ! i8888 !88. S3 ; ;S8S2 Ig" &amp; | ( «r-— | 8 i 8 rl U en s. s. r. -j-. -r. tn • •O ■ •O-O-OT313 :-O • 5 : S 5 5 3 5 5 • 3 1 0 ISOOOOO :O '• o. !£c.q.cco. j 5. ! M M I i I M ! I I i I ! H 1 1 1 1 J 3 « f t5 a* E % 2 1 2 £ &lt;CQCQfflUUWOO,^cn </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 O TO V en g a '5 1) r«s •—I SO I *(9- 2 c p D x | .-3 oo «2 oC -h* vd »h i?\' no op c&gt; H \d &lt;i o c^i •-« t^ o\ c4 1^ o" ■* t&gt;I o" t&gt;T ac ?' no" — " If. 5? ■&gt;!■* 13 V I £ •» U no loio ooNO^f*^f*5i— i*ti- tcoCvj o *o no «*} no *^" u^ no no oo cc „ ir e*; oo&lt;^"^"o no^u^c^no^oo No^fs p)CNi fc m cnononoi^«-h^o w .o^ cvfvd'NO'pq'cvfod'-Jui'vb"^'^' oo"c^&gt;o'No''&gt;^r"T'— r&gt;W»-&gt;"— " •^ r N"fc""— « I "3 14 i 1$ 1 1 1 ! 1 1 !§ ! i )3 is ! ! is ! ! i i i SS i i 00 I i i i I i iS i ! ;8 18 i i :?3 I i i i i &lt;M ;: ! : ; : : ; : ; :*■*:: : ::::: * ! ■ | MINN i i r* i 1 1 ! MM! cfcvf I; \ : j j j j \fi \ i \*i \tn \ \ j iiiij • I ;il = ii: -i = i I i i I i i I I '• : • ! i - : ■ : : : : ■' I • : • : : ■ I : § 5 3 V : 15 W Q sscficecccccccecesesscccc cj-.c .s 3333333333;J33333333333333'5''&gt;&lt;' - - 00000000000000000000g00003»3 • ••;■{; ri i :i i i :;• i i :: i ■:: i :•:: I I J M|i I i U 1 1| i 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1. iJilllliilJirt lilllliiliil S S S « « o s tl^fJ c c « u o o 3 ** ESo 3 aj= g ; : i 5 3 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>