<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION NINETEENTH ANNUAL REPORT 1927</title>
               <date value="1927-10-01">1927-10-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION NINETEENTH ANNUAL REPORT 1927 John C. Trouton . ....State Fire Marshal L. J. Butcher .Assistant State Fire Marshal Sigrid Rasmussen . Secretary E. E. Hayduk Deputy State Fire Marshal Thomas L. Wilson Deputy State Fire Marshal Ray E. Eaton Deputy State Fire Marshal A. F. "Jack" Rhanney...,. .Deputy State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ILAFLIN PRINTING CO.. Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">. , | _',-■•■ ADAM McMULLEN . . Governor of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">_____n.*^A.v — — ™si*-_*T_____________________________________________________________________* WW WW ; av_\_\ 85 IK -&gt;^^bH H IV .-^^ j£_1 cl I Cr d^l Ww m m I I: XW? II I P''/ j 1 ■ ■ &gt; .'L*__Wm\\\\ ■ __________! ____h *^^?wl ____________________________S_h ___________ '*'*■&amp;&amp; * Hi I __k A*-' II ■ ___k ' /L_fc ; il I __________k I &gt;^___j__k " ____________________________________________________________________________________________ JOHN C. TROUTEN State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">NINETEENTH ANNUAL REPORT of the ' STATE FIRE MARSHAL Office of State Fire Marshal, State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska. To His Excellency, Adam McMullen, Governor of the State of Nebraska. """""-"--- -— Your Excellency : In compliance with the law governing this department, which provides that a report of all business transacted, orders issued, and acts performed by the State Fire Marshal, his deputies and others constituting the Department be made to you annually, I take pleasure m submitting to you, this the Nineteenth Annual Report, covering the activities of this De - partment which you have placed under my direction. . It has been a pleasure to have had the manifestation of your continued interest' and helpfulness m this great work of Fire Prevention and I take this opportunity of expressing my appreciation of the continuation of your confidence m me, and of your great help to this Department. This report will show a marked reduction m fire losses throughout the state. This we feel is due to the assistance rendered to the Division of Fire Prevention by the fire chiefs and members of the fire departments m the various cities, towns, and villages of the state, by the county attorneys, sheriffs, the Nebraska State Fire Prevention Association, and all their fire prevention agencies who have aided m the elimi - nation of fire hazards and the investigation of incendiary fires, and I. take this opportunity of thanking them for their aid and assistance. The inspection work of this division has been more effec - tive this year than heretofore as the reduction m fire losses will prove, and as a result I am pleased to report that our </seg>
            <seg id="p008">State of Nebraska cities and towns are cleaner and freer from fire hazards to - day in Nebraska than ever before, and I look forward hope - fully to the time when this work can be extended to the farms and rural sections of the state, to the end that farmers and others may have a greater knowledge of the value of fire prevention work. This extension of our work has not been possible due to the limited amount of funds at the disposal of the Division of Fire Prevention. The Department has been operated in a business like man - ner and well within the funds at its disposal, and whatever measure of success has been obtained has been due to the courteous, loyal and uniting efforts of everyone connected with the Department. Assistant Fire .Marshal Lynn J. Butcher, Deputies Ed. E. Hayduk, Thomas L. Wilson. Kay E. Eaton, and A. F. "Jack" Rhanney, and our secretary .Miss Sigrid Rasmussen, have worked earnestly and consistently in an effort to reduce tire hazards and I am pleased to report that their efforts in this direction have been rewarded in ;t very gratifying manner. In submitting this report for your consideration. 1 want to thank you for your continued confidence -in me and for the helpful advice you have from time to time given to me, and that I may always continue to merit this confidence and esteem is the most earnest wish, of Yours respectfully. JOHN C. TROUTOX. State Fire Marshal. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Division of Fire Prevention FIRE PREVENTION WEEK Every year the nation's burden of property loss by fire con - tinues to increase and, in 1926, it involved a day-by-day de - struction of values aggregating $560,548,624— a new high rec - ord. In addition to this enormous waste of material wealth, thousands of lives were lost and thousand", of persons were injured by burning. Since a proportionate share of this tre - mendous toll is borne by our own state, and since the greater part of all fire loss is avoidable, if reasonable care be exer - cised, therefore, I, Adam McMullen, Governor of the state of Nebraska, by authority in me vested do designate and pro - claim the period from October 9 to 15, 1927, as Fire Preven - tion Week, and I wish that each and every one of our citizens would take an earnest, active interest in the occasion. Cham - bers of Commerce and other civic organizations, as well as busgf§ss associations,- school authorities, women's clubs and allwier bodies interested in public welfare should assist in furthering this important observance with even greater energy than heretofore. I hope that the newspapers and the churches. will join hands in impressing on the residents of our commonwealth, the serious economic and humane aspects of the situation created by our unprecedented burning rate. Given under my hand and seal at Lincoln, the capital, this 1st day of October, 1927. ADAM McMULLEN, GOVERNOR. (Seal) </seg>
            <seg id="p010">State of Nebraska FINANCIAL REPORT Provisions for the support and maintenance of the Fire Marshal's office has been made by law and provides that: "A sum equal to three-eighths of one percent of the gross premiums and assessments received for fire insurance, less reinsurance and return premiums." The law states further that "the state shall not be liable in any manner for the salary of the fire marshal, deputies, inspectors, clerks and other employees or for the maintenance of the office of fire marshal or any expenses incident thereto, and the same shall be payable only from the special fund pro - vided for in this section," this "special fund" being the money collected from the fire insurance companies on business done in the state as explained above. The taxes received by the state fire marshal in 1927 are as follows: Aetna Fire Insurance Company $ 743.98 Agricultural Company y^ 4 g Allemania Fire Insurance Company 39.22 Alliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia .. 95.63 American Alliance Insurance Company 34.22 American Central Fire Insurance Company 142.74 American Druggists Fire Insurance Company 6.69 American Eagle Fire Insurance Company 57.58 American Fire Insurance Company of Newark 392.86 Atlas Assurance Company, Limited, of London 26.40 Automobile Insurance Company of Hartford 183.36 Bankers and Shippers Fire Insurance Company 9.86 Boston Insurance Company * 84 Q9 British American Assurance Company 58.94 Buffalo Fire Insurance Company 43 45 Caledonian Insurance Company 84 96 California Fire Insurance Company 12.58 Camden Fire Insurance Association 69.63 Carolina Insurance Company j 06 Central Manufacturers Mutual Insurance Co 26.29 Chicago Fire and Marine Insurance Company 36.45 Citizens Insurance Company of Missouri 29.62 City of New York Insurance Company 38^24 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Division of Fire Prevention Columbia Insurance Company.: 10.26 Commerce Insurance Company 9.42 Commercial Union Assurance Company 155.32 Commercial Union Fire Insurance Company e ' 13.64 Commonwealth Insurance Company 118.05 Concordia Fire Insurance Company 55.25 Connecticut Fire Insurance Company 415.86 Continental Insurance Company 426.83 County Fire Insurance Company of Philadelphia 12.25 Detroit Fire and Marine Insurance Company 10.23 Dubuque Fire and Marine Insurance Company 94.35 Eagle Fire Insurance Company 2.70 Eagle Star &amp; British Dominions Insurance Co 51.36 East, and West Insurance Company..., 15.76 Employers Fire Insurance Company -..-. 74.15 Equitable Fire and .Marine Insurance. Company 82.17 Eureka Security Fire and Marine Ins. Company 1.96 Farmer's Fire Insurance Company 24.75 Federal Union Fire Insurance Company 19.10 Fidelity Phoenix Fire Insurance Company 491.65 Fire Association of Philadelphia 149.52 Firemen's Insurance Company. 153.11' Firemen's Fund Insurance Company 142.90 First American Insurance Company 13.12 Fitchburg Mutual Fire Insurance Company..... 8.03 . Franklin Fire Insurance Company. 152.94 Franklin National Insurance Company 12.56 General Exchange Insurance Company.. 111.48 General Insurance Company of America 4.86 Girard Fire and Marine Insurance Company. 55.11 Glens Falls Insurance Compdny..... 305.27 Globe and Rutgers Fire Insurance Company 1,059.05 Grain Dealers National Mutual Fire Ins. Co 173.44 Granite State Fire Insurance Company 53.06 Great American Insurance Company 447.54 Great Lakes Insurance Company.... 12.68 Guaranty Fire Insurance Company 12.75 Hanover Fire Insurance Company 126.24 Hardware Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Co 112.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">State of Nebraska Hartford Fire Insurance Company 871.88 Henry Clay Fire Insurance Company 20.92 Home Fire and Marine Insurance Company 13.47 Home Insurance Company 1,087.88 Hudson Insurance Company 50.10 Imperial Assurance Company 21.76 Importers and Exporters Insurance Company 27.35 Insurance Company of North America 596.15 Insurance Company of State of Pennsylvania 38.33 Inter Ocean Reinsurance Company 20.55 Law Union and Rock Insurance Company 34.49 Liverpool, London and Globe Ins. Co 354.23 London Assurance Corporation 32.58 London and Lancashire Insurance Company 118.08 London and Scottish Assurance Corporation. Ltd.. 4.29 Lumbermen's Mutual Insurance Company 5.69 Maryland .Motor Car Insurance Company 8.90 Massachusetts Fire and Marine Insurance Co. 10.32 Mechanic's Insurance Company of Philadelphia 81.29 Mechanic's and Traders Insurance Company 27.65 Mercantile Insurance Company of America . 332. 30 Merchant's Fire Insurance Company ... 14.13 Merchant's Fire Assurance Corporation 67.23 Merchant's Insurance Company 21.23 Mercury Insurance Company 27.81 Michigan Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 34.81 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Association .. . 31.45 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 6.38 Millers National Fire Insurance Company 57.73 Mill Owner's Mutual Fire Insurance Company 88.73 Milwaukee Mechanics Fire Insurance Company 193.75 Minnesota Implement Mutual Fire Insurance Co 32.37 National American Fire Insurance Company 585.82 National Ben Franklin Fire Insurance Company 102.56 National Fire Insurance Company of Hartford 2,143.44 National Implement Mutual Insurance Company 4.08 National Liberty Fire Insurance Company 131.64 National Reserve Insurance Company 37.11 National Retailers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 11.03 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Division of Fire Prevention National Security Fire Insurance Company... 417.27 National Union Fire Insurance Company.... 289.30 1 The Netherlands Insurance Company 42.85 Newark. Fire Insurance Company 28.50 New Brunswick Fire Insurance Company.. 27.47 New Hampshire Fire Insurance Company 146.53 New Jersey Fire Insurance Company 6.04 New York Underwriters Insurance Company 264.99 Niagara Fire Insurance Company 87.12 North British and Mercantile Insurance Co., Ltd 205.11 North Carolina Home Insurance Company 10.49 Northern Assurance Company, Limited 59.00 North River Insurance Company 124.60 Northwestern Fire and Marine Insurance Company.. 77.93 Northwestern Mutual Fire Association.: 15.44 Northwestern National Fire Insurance Company. 144.15 Norwich Union Fire Insurance Company 50.10 Ohio Farmers Insurance Company 4.14 Ohio Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company 65.61 Ohio Millers Mutual Insurance Company 33.70 Old Colony Fire Insurance Company 17.40 Orient Insurance Company 138.44 Pacific Fire Insurance Company 12.34 Palatine Insurance Company 31.94 Patriotic Insurance. Company of America 9.76 Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company 160.10 Pennsylvania Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Co 5.47 Philadelphia Fire and Marine Insurance Company.... 40.86 Pheonix Assurance Company, Limited, of London.... 66.48 Phoenix Insurance Company 669.34 Potomac Fire Insurance Company 42.97 Preferred Risk Fire Insurance Company. 15.98 Providence Washington Fire Insurance Company.... 29.91 Provident Fire Insurance Company 3.63 Prudential of Great Britain 43.40 Queen Insurance Company 290.88 Reinsurance Company Salamandra...... 153.19 Reliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia 14.52 Republic Fire Insurance Company 20.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">State of Nebraska Retailers Fire Insurance Company 1.26 Retail Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company.... 110.88 Rhode Island Insurance Company 83.34 Rocky Mountain Fire Insurance Company 5.17 Royal Exchange Assurance Company 36.05 Royal Insurance Company. 338.69 Safeguard Insurance Company 17.46 Scottish Union and National 102.13 Security Insurance Company 201.45 Security Mutual Fire Insurance Company 9.25 Sentinel Insurance Company 12.27 Springfield Fire and Marine Insurance Company 667.27 Standard Fire Insurance Company 1.3'» Star Insurance Company of America 62.7!/' State Assurance Company, Limited, of Liverpool 19.15 St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance Company 625.6;") The Stuyvesant Insurance Company of New York.... 13.4,s Sun Insurance Office of London 130.07 Superior Fire Insurance Company 4.74 Svea Fire and Life Insurance Company, Limited. 35.70 Tokio Marine and Fire Insurance Company 6.95 Transcontinental Insurance Company .60 Travellers Insurance Company 148.21 Twin City Fire Insurance Company 93.54 Union Assurance Society, Limited 18.99 Union Automobile Insurance Company 52.84 The Union Fire Insurance Company of Paris 23.44 Union Insurance Society 23.47 United Firemen's Insurance Co. of Philadelphia 4.60 United States Fire Insurance Company 262.99 U. S. Merchants and Shippers Insurance Company .... 19.06 Victory Insurance Company... 14.97 Westchester Fire Insurance Company 114.90 Western Assurance Company 61.92 Western Grain Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Co 72.25 World Auxiliary Insurance Corporation, Limited 11.45 World Fire and Marine Insurance Company 6.93 TOTAL TAX COLLECTED $22,247.63 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Division of Fire Prevention Balance on hand January 1st, 1927, in treasury 20,609.45 TOTAL FUND JANUARY 1st, 1927 $42,857.08 The above figures show the amount of tax money on hand to cover the expenditures for the year 1927. These expendi - tures were as follows: Salaries $13,498.21 $13,498.21 Office Expense Printing 330.97 Stamps 260.00 Supplies and Equipment 193.10 Telegraph :... 5.30 Telephone 133.83 ' Miscellaneous : 20.50 Total : $ 943.70 $ 943.70 Inspectors' Expenses (Traveling) Railroad Transportation 695.63 Hotel Expenses..... ■ 3,503.46 Auto Expenses, Taxi and Carfare 2,924.06 Miscellaneous 115.35 Total $ 7,238.50 $ 7,238.50 Expenses Incurred in Investiga - tions of Fires Temporary Services $ 165.85 $ 165.85 Fire Report Fees Paid to Fire Chiefs for Reporting 1926 Fires $ 713.50 $ 713.50 Total Expenditures for 1927 $22,559.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">State of Nebraska SUMMARY OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Inspections made 16,547 Orders issued 14.06E 1 Orders complied with while inspectors were in town 5,817 Buildings demolished by order of this department 138 Buildings repaired by order of this department 756 Hotels repaired by order of this department 228 School buildings equipped with new fire escapes, by order of this department 25 Buildings other than schools equipped with fire escapes by order of this department . 11 School buildings repaired and otherwise altered. In - order of this department . 446 Theatres repaired and altered, by order of this de - partment 273 Fires investigated 132 Persons arrested for arson 12 Persons still to be tried 1 Persons convicted of arson -1 Persons acquitted 4 Dismissed ."&gt; Persons bound over from 1926 still to be tried 7 CAUSES OF FIRES AS REPORTED DURING 1927 Balance of Omaha Lincoln State Total Unknown causes 188 41 141 370 Sparks from chimney on roof 193 67 148 408 Defective chimney 73 4 49 126 Gasoline and Kerosene stoves 62 9 57 128 Overheated stoves and furnaces 94 12 64 170 Communicated 33 9 20 62 Defective electric wires 98 7 50 155 Spontaneous combustion 33 12 25 70 Children and matches 29 3 27 59 Cigarettes, cigars and pipes 37 3 21 61 Inflammables too near stoves 19 2 39 60 Bonfires and burning grass 11 2 7 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Division of Fire Prevention Balance Omaha Lincoln of state Total Incendiary 29 1 30 60 Gasoline explosion _ 24 0 21 45 Hot ashes against wood 26 3 18 47 Oil burners 8 1 6 15 Sparks from engine 9 * 0 6 15 Lightning 12 1 12 25 Stills— overheating 3 2 2 7 Brooders and incubators 17 4 11 32 Oils and greases on stoves 6 0 7 13' Miscellaneous ....: 12 5 12 29 Starting fires with kerosene and gasoline 16 0 10 26 Motor back fired 14 0 10 24' Mice and. matches 4 0 3 7 Electric curling and flatirons 5 0 4 9 Motion picture films 4 0 3 7 Fireworks 7 0 6 13 Smoking in bed. 2 0 0 2 Thawing out water pipes 4 2 7 13 Washing clothes with gasoline 7 1 4 12 Static electricity 2 14 7 Rubbish , 29 3 8 40 Careless use of matches 17 3 7 27 Total number of fires 1127 198 839 2164 Less communicated fires 33 9 20 62 1094 189 819 2102 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">State of Nebraska FIRE LOSSjES BY COUNTIES County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Adams $182,750.00 $117,500.00 $ 29,352.00 Contents 155,240.00 52,900.00 77,047.00 Antelope 38,400.00 19,000.00 18,470.00 Contents 26,235.00 7,085.00 7,395.00 Boone 46,250.00 28,100.00 31,550.00 Contents ... . 24,500.00 15,000.00 20,640.00 Box Bute. ... 74,600.00 47,800.00 10,810.00 Contents 164,675.00 62,700.00 48,231.20 Boyd 11.200.00 9,100.00 479.00 Contents 15,400.00 700.00 82.00 Brown 15.025.00 4,500.00 1,840.00 Contents 12.500.00 5,200.00 7,600.00 Buffalo 176.925.00 99,500.00 39,717.03 Contents 123.625.00 65,150.00 56,210.46 Burt .... 9,600.00 4.450.00 2.435.00 Contents ... 4.000.00 800.00 105.10 Butler ... 27.135.00 16,350.00 1.476.00 Contents 19.575.00 8.000.00 656.00 Cass 72.500.00 37,450.00 14,241.53 Contents 50,750.00 30,400.00 12,482.11' Cedar 45,000.00 36.500.00 15,290.00 Contents 26,900.00 20.500.00 6,715.00 Chase 4,000.00 3.600.00 2,500.00 Contents 6,000.00 4,000.00 4,000.00 Cherry 64,900.00 44,350.00 15,605.00 Contents 18,450.00 11,100.00 5,300.00 Cheyenne 23,450.00 15,050.00 4*498.54 Contents 16,200.00 9,215.00 3,075.00 Clay 15,500.00 12,300.00 10,025.00 Contents 8,100.00 6,000.00 3,650.00 Cumming 58,475.00 33,650.00 14,975.00 Contents 34,050.00 19,000.00 7,280.00 Custer 50,625.00 21,800.00 9,011.25 Contents 31,615.00 16,650.00 4,528.86 Dakota 8,250.00 6,675.00 4,450.00 Contents 4,100.00 2,700.00 3,300.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Division of Fire Prevention County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Dawes :..... 33,250.00 17,150.00 16,450.00 Contents 18,200.00 5,100.00 4,445.00 Dawson 35,340.00 20,250.00 4,285.75 Contents 20,200.00. 10,600.00 2,585.00 Deuel 250.00 150.00 250.00 Contents 500.00 . 500.00 500.00 Dixon 14,000.00 10,400.00 180.00 Contents 5,500.00 2,500.00 350.00 Dodge 631,030.00 441,991.00 39,872.63' Contents 61,935.00 43,544.50 13,007.56 Douglas .- 3,035.00 1,600.00 570.00 Contents 1,500.00 1,245.00 500.00 Fillmore :... 53,150.00 45,700.00 9,950.00 Contents 90,100.00 69,000.00 18,710.00 Franklin 3,100.00 1,700.00 615.00 Contents 425.00. none 425.00 Frontier 6,000.00 6,000.00 6,000.00 Contents 1,500.00 1,500.00 1,500.00 Furnas 12,200.00. 8,550.00 6,100.00 Contents 9,050.00 3,550.00 8,300.00 Gage 235,900.00 129,000.00 30,785.00 Contents 182,850.00 75,700.00 11,240.00 Garfield 15,600.00 7,300.00 7,900.00 Contents 12,800.00 7,450.00 9,000.00 Grant 900.00 500.00 150.00 ! Contents 500.00 none 150.00 Greeley 7,000.00 4,000.00 4,300.00 Contents 6,000.00 1,400.00 6,000.00 Hall 178,625.00 81,950.00 10,994.97 ; Contents 68,135.00 54,700.00 6,766.00 (f Hamilton 18,040.00 11,450.00 3,570.00 1 Contents 14,914.00 9,600.00 1,979.00 &lt; '' Harlan :... : 7,000.00 5,150.00 5,250.00 Contents ' 4,500.00 1,150.00 4,400.00 Hitchcock 24,050.00 11,700.00 2,910.00 Contents .. 4,375.00 3,000.00 1,771.00 \ ' Holt 34,050.00 20,600.00 9,375.00 \ Contents 46,725.00 32,200.00 24,975.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">State of Nebraska County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Hooker 1,500.00 1,000.00 30.00 Contents 200.00 none none Howard 20,000.00 8,700.00 3,000.00 Contents 18,000.00 15,050.00 6,000.0(f Jefferson 63,210.00 51,100.00 13,547.65 Contents 77,980.00 71,175.00 7,190.00 Johnson 13,550.00 7,650.00 6,596.85 Contents 13,345.00 9,200.00 970.00 Kearney . 13,500.00 7,600.00 5,650.00 Contents . 7,225.00 2,250.00 5,790.00 Keith .... 1,000.00 500.00 1,000.00 Contents 2.500.00 2,000.00 2,500.00 Kimball 14,100.00 11,150.00 902.50 Contents 11.950.00 7,575.00 488.51 Knox 38.775.00 21,150.00 9,034.00 Contents 53,630.00 37,995.00 22,763.00 Lancaster . . 57.800.00 39,550.00 15.710.33 Contents 31,875.00 18,315.00 7,819.50 Lincoln 7O.OO0.00 45.400.00 4.860.00 Contents 75.275.00 28,825.00 11.685.00 Madison 105,375.00 75.950.00 14,930.44 Contents 69,893.00 44.lO0.0o 13,139.15 Merrick 18,250.00 13,700.00 1,106.20 Contents 16,700.01) 9,125.00 1,410.00 Morrill 12,000.00 8,000.00 5.175.00 Contents 23.500.00 18,000.00 3,650.00 Nance 16,400.00 7.800.00 4.425.00 Contents 8.500.00 3,300.00 3,200.00 Nemaha 80,100.00 52,200.00 4,496.00 Contents 92,130.00 82,150.00 13,580.0.0 Nuckolls 47,900.00 25,400.00 2,643.00 Contents 23,700.00 14,950.00 1,970.00 Otoe 30.500.00 13,000.00 9,341.00 Contents 9,300.00 2,500.00 2,261.20 Pawnee 11,800.00 5,900.00 1,500.00 Contents 3,275.00 950.00 724.00 Perkins 13,500.00 8,000.00 1,150.00 Contents 4,700.00 2,000.00 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Division of Fire Prevention County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Phelps 8,400.00 5,900.00 670.00 Contents 4,550.00 3,100.00 2,100.00 Pierce 71,360.00 49,300.00 9,113.65 Contents 15,438.0.0 8,300.00 2,790.95' Platte 118,075.00 72,800.00 5,168.20 Contents 47,140.00 21,961.00 3,240.00 Polk 44,050.00 29,600.00 7,885.00 Contents 26,400.00 12,500.00 1,583.00 Red Willow 31,700.00 . 23,535.00 7,145.00 Contents 10,150.00 6,800.00 2,955.00 Richardson 90,650.00 73,450.00 19,395.00 Contents 58,925.00 36,700.00 14,295.00 Saline 40,425.00 20,800.00 14,976.00 Contents 22,875.00 8,280.00 7,926.91 Saunders 60,225.00 32,300.00 5,804.05 Contents 30,075.00 16,750.00 4,273.00 Scotts Bluff 53,740.00 34,750.00 10,132.00 Contents 69,430.00 .50,000.00 11,890.00 Seward 92,300.00 48,300.00 28,528.00 Contents 47,260.00 21,850.00 25,724.45 Sheridan 42,400.00 30,840.00 19,235.00 Contents 49,700.00 33,500.00 22,475.00 Sherman 14,800.00 8,000.00 5,805.75 Contents 14,150.00 8,700.00 6,180.00 Sioux 1,000.00 none 250.00 Contents ; 100.00 none 20.00 Stanton' _. 8,000,00 3,850.00 495.00 Contents :.... 5,000.00 3,300.00 280.00 Thayer 3,125.00 2,500.00 40.00 Contents 440.00 none 6.00 Thomas .: 20,000.00 13,000.00 1,000.00 Contents 5,000.00 2,000.00 500.00 Thurston : 16,500.00 14,157.00 1,678.00 Contents 5,750.00 1,600.00 1,900.00 Valley 10,200.00 6,650.00 2,775.00 Contents 13,900.00 7,900.00 8,840.00 Washington 44,900.00 ' 27,150.00 8,054.75 Contents 24,500.00 10,900.00 3.555.0C </seg>
            <seg id="p022">State of Nebraska County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Wayne .. . 50,550.00 30,700.00 12,965.00 Contents 51,600.00 27,500.00 18,240.00 York 99,450.00 62,200.00 16,320.60 Contents 59,785.00 47,950.00 21,852.75 FIRE LOSS FOR 1927. VALUE, INSURANCE, AND LOSS AS REPORTED BY COUNTIES Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Total $ 3.702,730.00 $2,350,298.00 $ 664,999.24 Value of Cont. Ins. on (ont. Dam. on Com. Total $ 2,383.575.00 §2,572,266.05 $ 633,103.70 Value of Bldgs. Ins. un Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Omaha $ 8,790.739.80 $5,454,050.31 $ 363,465.63 Value of Con!. Ins. un font. Dam. on Cont. S 6,870,286.20 $6,067,150.69 $ 288,554.37- Value of Bldgs. Ins. tin Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Lincoln .$ 1.055.665.00 ? 677.430.00 $ 159,857.10 Value of Com Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont. $ 595,403. 00 $ 435,975.00 S 351.266.00 Value (if illclgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Grand Total $13,549,334.80 #8,481,778.31 $1,188,321.97 Value of Com. Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont. $ 9,849,264.20 $9,075,391.74 $1,272,924.07 TOTAL DEATHS FROM FIRES Men 23 Women ■ 10 Children 12 Total ... . -•■ -- 45 CAUSE OF DEATHS Kerosene 16 Gasoline 4 Bon fires 2 Playing with matches 3 Electricity 13 Total 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Division of Fire Prevention TOTAL INJURIES FROM FIRES Men , :. 57 Women 23 Children.: 25 Total 105 CAUSE OF INJURIES Kerosene 16 Gasoline 3L* Fire works '. 3 Torpedos and dynamite caps : 9 Bon fires.... 2 Playing with matches... : 4 Film fire in booth 2 Miscellaneous 18 Firemen injured and burned at fires..... 19 Total :". 105 DEATHS FROM FIRE Ainsworth — Mrs. L. A. Smith and her five year old daughter, were burned to death when a can of kerosene ex - ploded. : Albion — The four year old son of Mr. and Mrs. Ed Beck - with was burned to death, playing with matches. He exploded a nearby can of gasoline, Mrs. Beckwith was also injured. Arapahoe — Tom Penn a blacksmith was instantly killed when his acetslene welding torch exploded. Ashland — Mrs. Robert Klotz had placed a can of varnish in the oven, her husband started a . fire in the stove, Mrs. Klotz smelling the varnish burning, opened the oven door; the liquid ignited and exploded and Mrs. Klotz was burned to death. Auburn — Arnold Chard saturated himself with kerosene and then ignited it. He was burned to death. ■■■• </seg>
            <seg id="p024">State of Nebraska Beatrice — Mrs. Walter Hogue while filling an incubator lamp, was burned to death. Beaver City — Marvin Fults was instantly killed when he shot into a can of nitro glycerine that had been hidden under the ticket office at the county fair grounds. Bridgeport — B. D. Lindorf was electrocuted while en - gaged in removing a transformer from a high tension circuit. Broken Bow — Mrs. Caroline Monroe, fifty-four, was burned to death, she poured kerosene into the kitchen stove' - to hasten the fire. Bruno — Mr. and Mrs. Frank Havlovic and their four year old son were electrocuted, their car came in contact with a fallen high tension electric wire. Creighton — William Shaffer started a fire with kerosene, William and his two year old daughter Shirley were burned to death. Firth — Earl Tyler was burned to death while he was en - gaged in setting off lire works in a balloon two thousand feet in the air. Fremont — A can of parrafine exploded as Frank Sasse was removing it from the stove. Frank was burned to death. Grand Island— J. L. Klein died from injuries receive* starting a fire with kerosene. Grand Island — Edwin McMaster, nine, died from burns received while lighting a bon fire. Grand Island — Mrs. Neidfelt tried to hasten a fire in the kitchen stove by pouring kerosene on it, Mrs. Neidfelt and Mrs. Deput were burned severely and Nietta Deput was burned to death. Hastings — A gasoline stove exploded and Mr. and Mrs. Thompson and their eleven months old baby were burned to death. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Division of Fire Prevention Hastings — John Easter of Ayr was electrocuted, he was trying to remove a high tension wire from the highway. Hershey — C. E. Carlson saturated his clothing with gaso - line, ignited it and burned- to death. ! Holstein — John Heimberger burned to death in a straw stack fire. Hyannis — Nellie May was burned to death in a fire which! destroyed the home of her father and mother, Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Cantley. Lincoln — Thomas Brick was electrocuted when engaged in cutting high tension electric wires at the Iowa, Nebraska Public Service company's plant. Loup City — Gregory Miller put a lighted pipe in his pocket, it set fire to his clothing and he was burned to death. Milford— Jacob Kiebler burned to death in an elevator fire, the cause of the fire was unknown. Omaha — Wilbur Brunei- burned to death, starting a fire in a stove with kerosene. Omaha — Dorothy Marie Ransarro, four, burned to death playing with a bon fire. Omaha — An oil stove explosion caused the death of Nathan Somberg he was confined to his bed for two months, then he died from his injuries. Omaha — A gasoline stove exploded causing the death of J. Dan Tikalsky. Omaha — Roland Brodbeck, three, while playing with a box of safety matches, set fire to his clothes and burned to death. Omaha — A gas explosion in the apartment of Mrs. Clara Fields burned her so badly she died. Omaha — A heating stove ignited the clothing of Mrs. Delbert P. Gifford, she was burned to death. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">State of Nebraska Omaha — A spirit stove exploded burning A. Larsen to death. Omaha — Ed Rupke after lighting his pipe, threw the match into some waste paper that had accumulated in his room, it ignited and he was burned to death. St. Edward — Fire destroyed the home and burned Mr. Pearson B. Smith to death. His body was fjund in the ruins. Sidney — Miss Florence Rogers was burned to death, starting a fire with kerosene. Stockville — Mrs. Euretta Long and her daughter Mrs. Chancy Ryan were burned to death and their home destroyed. Mrs. Long upset a can of kerosene, it ran thru the floor to a stove in the room below, it became ignited and caused the fire. Tecumseh — I, M. Mason died from burns, his woolen night shirt was ignited in the flame of a coal oil lamp. York — Mrs. L. B. Preston was electrocuted when she held an electric wire in one hand, and the water faucet in the other. INJCRIES FROM FIRES Alliance — Margaret Goings burned when an electric light set fire to the bed, in which she was reading. Alliance — Tom Carroll was severely burned when an ex - plosion of dust occurred in the city plant where he is the fireman. Alliance — The two young sons of Fay Allen were severely burned in an explosion which occurred in the kitchen range. Beatrice — Fred Borland seriously injured, starting a fire with gasoline. _, Beatrice — Clifford Murray seriously burned in a fire which destroyed the cleaning plant of Roy Wilcox. Bruno — Jimmie Prchal, ten, severely burned; he exploded a torpedo cap with a hammer. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Division of Fire Prevention Bridgeport — Oscar Carlton was burned about the hands and face. when the gasoline tank of his car exploded while he was filling it. Bloomfield— -Leo Blank struck a match to see how the alcohol was in the radiator of his car, he was severely burned about the head and face. Burwell— A gasoline explosion burned Mrs. Erington about the arms and face. Ceresco — Frank Denes, eight, picking a dynamite cap with a knife blew off his thumb and two fingers. Columbus— Mrs. Smith burned both hands in a gasoline explosion. College View — Mrs. Roy D. Kile suffered some bad burns, the gasoline stove exploded. Deshler— The three year old daughter of Albert Krei - mier, put a torpedo in her mouth and bit it, an explosion oc - curred and burned her. . Elmwood — Mrs. Reeder suffered severe burns about the arms and legs, her face was scorched and most of her hair was burned away, Mr. Reeder and his small daughter, Shirley, also had minor injuries, starting fire with kerosene. Elm Creek — Two firemen were injured by broken glass fighting a fire. Falls City — Mrs. Earl Chambers started a fire with kero - sene, her five year old daughter Nioma was permanently dis - figured. Falls City— Freddie Farrington using a revolver with blank cartridges severely burned Mary Huston. Fremont — A gasoline explosion in a washer severely burned Fred Hipke. Fremont — Val Rosengren set his bed on fire with a cigar - ette, he was injured. • </seg>
            <seg id="p028">State of Nebraska Fairbury— Mrs. Frank Nider of Jansen was severely burned starting a fire with gasoline. Geneva— Darrel Scott accidentally exploded a box of dyna - mite caps, he may lose his eyesight. Geneva— Burdette Higginbotham blasting stumps on the highway, was burned about the face. Grand Island— Mrs. Neidfelt and Mrs. Deput were severe - ly burned when Mrs. Neidfelt endeavored to hasten a fire with kerosene. Hay Springs— An oil stove set fire to the home of Joe Hanson and he was burned while rescuing his children from the fire. Hadar— Corrinne Leland, four, badly burned when she upset a kerosene lamp, her brother, two, also burned both hands. Hartington— Lawrence Roskopf poured gasoline in a blacksmith forge to accelerate the fire, it exploded and Law - rence was severely burned. Havelock— Mrs. Duffy burned when a fire cracker ex - ploded in her hand. Homer— Mrs. H. H. Blacketer permitted a gas burner to fill the room with gas, when she tried to ignite it, an ex - plosion occurred which burned her face and hands, singed her hair and blew her clothes off. Hoskins— Robert Fenske was severely burned when a fire destroyed his home and outbuildings. Lakeside — Ernest Leeds was severely burned working on his automobile, he brought a lighted lantern into the gar - age and exploded a can of gasoline. Lake Ericson— William Couton, Jr., was preparing to take a bath, a practical joker fired a fire cracker thru a knot hole and injured his eye. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Division of Fire Prevention Lincoln— Keith Schroeder was leaning over a can oi powder, some person threw a match into the can, an explosion occurred and Keith's eyes and face were severely burned. Lincoln — Sarah Cotton cleaning clothes with gasoline, was burned when the garment she was cleaning came in con - tact with a stove. '■ -. . Lincoln — Simon Young poured gasoline on hot asphalt, he was severely burned. Lincoln — George Koster in lighting a gas heater was badly burned and may lose his eye. Lincoln— Edward W. Putoff cleaned a rug with gasoline, it became ignited from an electric heater, Putoff was burned in his efforts to extinguish the blaze. Lincoln — Mrs. A. Z. Martin severely burned when waste paper piled under a stove became ignited. Lincoln— Jacob Von Busch was severely burned, thawing out his automobile with a blow torch, the torch exploded. Lincoln— John B. Mulligan may lose the sight of his eye, metal heated to a temperature of six hundred degrees splashed into his eye. Lincoln— Charles Poska slightly burned when static elec - tricity ignited garments he was removing from a gasoline cleaning machine. Lincoln — J. E. Ackerman a farmer living ten miles south - east of Lincoln, was badly burned when filling his tractor with* gasoline, he had a lighted lantern in the garage. Litchfield— Theodore Minshull and E. P. Kennedy suf - fered burns in a moving picture house, the building caught fire from a film igniting in the booth. Marquette — Ray Guilford was burned when he attempted to take a truck out of the Farmers Union warehouse when it was on fire, the fire was started by an oil stove' exploding in the cream testing department. ' </seg>
            <seg id="p030">State of Nebraska McCook— Clifford Wilocott lost two fingers and part of his thumb, he was playing with a dynamite cap and an ex - plosion occurred. Nebraska City— Rudolph Nosky, a fireman, severely in - jured and may lose an eye, he was fighting a fire that had been caused by a defective flue. Omaha— R. C. Farrow in an effort to thaw out his car by burning newspapers caused the car to explode, his face was cut and burned. Omaha— George Williams had a rib broken when a string of box cars hit his truck which he had left on the railroad tracks, the truck caught fire and the fire was communicated to a large hay barn, five firemen were severely injured in this fire. Norfolk— Delmont Horn, twelve, put kerosene on the kitchen fire, the kitchen was destroyed, and Horn's clothes became ignited, he saved himself by rolling in bed clothes. Octavia— George Hahn was severely burned, he was fill - ing an oil stove when the stove exploded. Omaha— Freddie Gernant and Ernest L. Underwood were seriously injured, they were washing the floor of an oil sta - tion with gasoline. Omaha— Mrs. W. M. Giller was cleaning a dress with gas - oline, it ignited and Mrs. Giller was severely burned. Omaha— While taking a bath Mrs. S. E. Isaacson grasped an electric wire attached to a heater, she received a severe shock and was badly burned. Omaha— Mrs. George Taylor poured kerosene on a fire to help it along, she was severely burned. Omaha— Keith Lyons lost his left hand when a gas pipe cannon exploded on the Fourth of July. Omaha— Helen Epstein, seven, was seriously burned when a sparkler set fire to her dress. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Division of Fire Prevention Omaha — Francis Wear, eight, son of John Wear, re - ceived serious burns when he undertook to turn off an oil burner in his home. Omaha — Billy Wills, nine, was seriously burned when he dropped a lighted match in a paint can, and then tried to put the fire out with water, an explosion occurred, his mother saved his life by rolling him in a rug. Omaha — Captain John Donohue, Louis Krajicek, Mike Sheehan, John McKernan, and John Ryan, firemen were seri - ously injured in a fire at the Scarbo Block in South Omaha. Omaha— George Dewey was washing the wheels of a car with gasoline, it exploded, damaged two automobiles and burned George severely. Omaha— Harry Metcalf, William Sexton and Melvin Brick were badly burned when a gasoline can exploded. Omaha — Jake Greenblatt was badly burned about thd hands, head and feet, he kicked over a gasoline stove causing an explosion. Omaha — Celluloid combs becoming ignited from a gas heater caused Mrs. Sam Cardini to lose her hair. Omaha— Irene Huntington, four, was severely burned playing; with matches, her mother was away. Oakdale— Albert Michaels and Orville Coulthard were both burned severely when a spark from an electric switch ignited gasoline in an oil storage station. Pawnee City— Bert S. Etchison suffered severe burns about the neck and right hand, he was filling a gasoline heater when it was lit. Pender— Mrs. W. A. Racely badly burned while at work in her kitchen. Plattsmouth— Mary J. Hyatt burned while playing with a bonfire. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">State of Nebraska Plattsmouth — Ralph E. Hill, four, burned his hands in a bonfire. Randolph — A fireman was injured when the fire truck ran over his foot on its way to a fire which destroyed the hotel. Shubert — Alta May Worthing suffered severe burns, when her car caught fire, static electricity ignited the gaso - line when the tank was being filled at a filling station. Shelton — Phil Mosser and his twelve year old son were severely burned when the little boy put gasoline in the kitchen fire. Stella — Delbert Burns suffered severe injuries to his eyes, he lit a match to see how much alcohol was in his radiator. Superior — Junior Bradley, four, playing with matches ig - nited his clothing and was severely burned. Surprise — Mrs. Belle Coleman burned her face and hands? in a straw stack fire which she had started. Sidney — Helen and Ida Johnson severely burned by an explosion of a gasoline torch which had been placed on the stove. St. Libory — Mrs. Philip Glause severely burned about the chest and head attempting to rescue articles from her home which was on fire. Tecumseh — Picking up a live wire Wanda, thirteen months old child of Mr. and Mrs. Ray Zimmer burned her right hand. Winside — Dave Glasscock was using a leaky gasoline torch, it exploded and he was badly burned. Winside — Richard Moore was seriously injured playing with matches and kerosene. Wymore — Charles Hochenstein was badly burned when he tried to light a fire with kerosene. The explosion blew him part way thru a window. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Division of Fire Prevention Yoder— The exhaust from the engine of the Denver Bus set the bus on fire, J. D. Kelley the driver suffered severe burns. York — A gasoline stove in the blacksmith shop of W. H. Bovey exploded and burned him severely. INVESTIGATION OF SUSPICIOUS FIRES During 1927 the Fire Marshal's office made investigation into 132 suspicious fires. Of this number investigated it was believed that 67 of these fires were of incendiary origin, with - out doubt. Twelve men were arrested and charged with ar - son; four confessed and were sentenced to the penitentiary; four were tried and acquitted ; three dismissed, and the other case will be tried in. the next term of District Court in 1928. Of the remaining 51 cases, up to date, no charges have been preferred, as the collecting of evidence still continues. Forty - five of the fires investigated proved were not of incendiary origin, but in most cases were carelessness on the part of the occupant in allowing fire hazards to exist. The other twenty fires were listed as unknown or doubtful. In the investigation of these fires the utmost care was taken to avoid publicity and reflections being cast on any in - nocent party or parties. It is a greater satisfaction to the investigator to be able to exonerate the suspected ones than it is to bring charges of arson against them. Murray— Carl H. Lange was arrested February 22, 1927, and charged with having set fire to the Earl Lancaster barn, three miles northwest of Murray, on February 13, 1927. He pleaded not guilty and waived preliminary hearing and was bound over to District Court in the sum of $1000.00. The case was dismissed before it came to trial. Callaway — M. C. Wind of Callaway was arrested on March 11, 1927, and confessed having set his restaurant on fire on the night of March 4, 1927, to collect the insurance. He later repudiated his confession and was tried on May 3 and 4, </seg>
            <seg id="p034">State of Nebraska 1927, and acquitted. Three weeks later he shot his wife and then committed suicide by cutting his throat with a razor. Mrs. Wind recovered. (Note: This goes to show how difficult it is to convict an on arson charge.) Lincoln— George Frickle, a tailor, was arrested for hav - ing set fire to a vacant duplex residence owned by him at 16th and J Streets. Preliminary hearing was held June 1, 1927; was bound over to District Court on $2,500.00 bond; was tried on December 14, 1927, and acquitted. Gordon — Henry L. Myers confessed to having hired Roy Wilson and Floyd Cordwell to burn his blacksmith shop in Gordon on the night of June 22, 1927, shortly after midnight. This was the second attempt. Wilson and Cordwell were caught in the act and confessed that they were to receive $100.00 each from Myers. All three were sent to the peni - tentiary for from one to seven years. This case was handled by R. E. Johnson, the fire chief, and sheriff and county attor - ney of Sheridan County. Broken Bow— Jerome Griebel and Alfred Shafer were arrested October 7, 1927, on the confession of Shafer that Griebel cancelled a note against him for $75.00 and promised him further remuneration if he would burn the dwelling on Griebel's farm, 22 miles north of Broken Bow. Shafer said that he moved all of his household belongings outside the door, then used five gallons of gasoline and two gallons of kerosene and touched it off. When the neighbors arrived it looked as if he had managed to save his goods and they helped him carry them to a safe distance from the burning building. The fire was set at noon on August 30, 1927. Griebel and Shafer were tried in District Court during the December term and the jury brought in a verdict of acquittal stating it was an accidental fire. Hildreth — Hugo Ohms was arrested November 28, 1927, having confessed to setting fire to his restaurant, in three different places, on November 4, 1927, to get the insurance. The loss was settled by the insurance company to Ohms and the owner of the building. Ohms was bound over to the Dis- </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Division of Fire Prevention. trict Court and was sentenced to one year in the penitentiary and paroled from the bench. Omaha — Tony Manzitto was&gt; arrested and charged with attempting to burn his barber shop on November 19, 1927. He was bound over to District Gourt to be tried in 1928. Omaha — Nick Salistean was convicted June 16, 1926, for having set his hotel on fire June 1, 1925. He was sentenced to five years in the penitentiary for arson; the case was car - ried to the Supreme Court where the decision of the lower' court was affirmed. He started to serve out his sentence on November 6, 1927. Kenesaw — Chas. A. Valkenaar r who was charged with the burning of his restaurant on May 3, 1926, was tried in Dis - trict Court at Hastings, February 18 and 19, 1927, and the jury brought in a verdict of not guilty. Crab Orchard — Paul Skraback, who was arrested and charged with having burned a neighbor's machine shed on May 16, 1926, was bound over to the District Court for trial. Charges were dismissed by District Judge J. B. Raper of Johnson County on February 26, 1927, after the case had been postponed a couple of times. Skraback at the time the charges were dismissed was serving time in the Johnson County jail on a charge of illegal sale of liquor and is also to pay a fine of $500.00. Omaha — The arson ring composed of Wm. Bartlett, Clarence Headley, Walter Headley, Jas. C. Sebastian, Mike Toth, Samuel Girt and Merle Livingston, all of Omaha, were arrested August 25, 1926, and charged with arson. Thej were bound over to District Court to be tried in 1927. How - ever, their case has not yet been tried owing to the dis - appearance of a couple of the witnesses. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">State of Nebraska THE VOLUNTEER FIREMEN Another year has passed into history, and we are pleased to note that the fire losses in the State of Nebraska are almost a half million dollars less than in 1926. This proves conclusively that losses can be reduced, and it is edifying to find that the points in the State that show the most creditable reductions are the towns where the firemen have supplemented their duties of fighting fires by instituting inspections of all buildings in their own towns. Fremont has made a splendid reduction this past year and this is true of Omaha also, and in both places the firemen are inspecting buildings for fire hazards. The work of preventing fires by inspections is pref - erable to being called out in the night to extinguish fires that have been caused by hazards that might have been removed had they been located and ordered removed by the firemen when on inspection tours under more favorable circumstances. Defective chimneys are easily noted from the street, and whenever found the owners should be required to put them in repair. Sparks on roofs have caused the various state fire departments to travel thousands of miles in 1927 to extinguish fires that never needed to have occurred had the repairs been required. We are proud of our record for the year that has just passed and we wish to place the credit for this improved showing where it properly belongs, and by far the largest portion of this saving was brought about by the Volunteer Firemen. The United States as a whole shows an increase of many millions in fire losses and Nebraska is one if not the only one of all the states that can show a reduction. For this great service to the state rendered by the Volunteer Firemen of Nebraska we are sincerely thankful, and take this oppor - tunity of extending to you our appreciation of the noble service you performed. Trusting that in 1928 we may do still better. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Division of Fire Prevention DANGEROUS FIRE AT VALENTINE, NEB. August 25th, what might have been a serious conflagra - tion was started by static electricity igniting gasoline in an oil truck that was being filled at the Nicholas Oil station. The volunteer fire department responded to the fire alarm prompt - ly and soon had the fire under control. The building was practically destroyed, it being of frame construction. The fire was extinguished by the use of water only at a pressure of 74 lbs. The Nicholas Oil Co. sent the fire department a check for $25.00 as a token of their appreciation. This Office recommends the use of foamite for the ex - tinguishing of gasoline and oil fires, or if foamite is not avail - able tetra chloride. This fire teaches us another lesson, that oil stations should be of fire resistive construction. We take this opportunity of thanking the volunteer fire department for their prompt action. Too much credit cannot be given to them for their good work in saving the City of Valentine thousands of dollars. THE NEBRASKA FIRE PREVENTION ASSOCIATION The Nebraska Fire Prevention Association is doing a great work, in the winter months their scout committee select from the numerous invitations extended to the Association to inspect the various cities of the state, those cities that appear to be most in need of such inspections as the association con - ducts, then once a month plans are laid to inspect the City selected. Inspection blanks are furnished so that each child in the schools shall have one to inspect the home. Prizes are given to the child or pupil turning in the best report, then when the inspection day arrives numerous inspectors, mem - bers of the association, start in to give the town a thoro going over, the report of the inspectors is concentrated and the results given usually at a banquet in the evening, and usually the newspapers carry the story of the conditions found, and </seg>
            <seg id="p038">State of Nebraska a word or two as to why fire hazards of the various kinds are considered dangerous. This is one of the best methods of carrying on the work of fire prevention as the large number of inspectors and the work they accomplish has a very bene - ficial effect and is easily noticed in the resulting decrease in fire losses in the towns so inspected. This department appre - ciates very much the work of the Nebraska Fire Prevention Association and it is also a pleasure to be able to thank them for the recognition of our assistance by appointing one of our deputies as Chairman of the Publicity Committee. It is hoped that the year 1928 will show still greater improvement in the reduction of fire losses, and the Nebraska Fire Prevention Association is doing more than its share of this work. INCENDIARISM Incendiarism has, at last, been getting the attention it deserves! Fraudulent fires are far too prevalent for the eco - nomic progress and development of the country. This dan - gerous form of crime, practiced not only against the insurance companies but against society, has been dealt a body blow in the formation of arson squads all over the country. The close co-operation of the police and prosecuting officials with representatives of the National Board of Fire Underwriters has resulted in many convictions and prison sentences in the past few years. Although the very small loss of $2,202,492 is given, many losses of suspicious origin cannot be proven to be arson fires at the time the reports are sent in and these losses are put in the " unknown " or " miscellaneous " column. It would be a conservative estimate if twenty per cent of all fire losses were considered as of incendiary origin. (Safeguarding America against fire.) </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Division of Fire Prevention INCENDIARY FIRES Bulletin for Fire Department It is desired to call the attention of the members of the Fire Department to the increasing number of fires of sus - picious origin occurring in cities. Some officials have gone on record as making the positive statement that more than 30 per cent of the fire loss is incendiary. This is undoubtedly an extravagant statement, but it is conservatively estimated that 10 per cent of the number of fires show evidence of incendiarism. It occurs to me that by cooperating, together and by thoroughly investigating every fire of suspicious origin we may materially decrease the fire waste in this state and make the crime of arson so unprofitable and so unpopular that it will be seldom attempted. Arson has always been considered one of the most serious crimes and has been classed with murder and treason, and in some states, even now, a conviction of arson carries with it the death penalty. Incendiary fires can, for ordinary pur - poses, be separated into five classes, according to motive: 1. To conceal evidence of some other crime. 2. Malice or revenge. 3. Malicious mischief. 4. Pyromania or some other form of insanity. 5. Desire to defraud the insurer. Every fire is presumed to be of accidental origin, and as the firemen are the first to reach the scene of the fire, it is usually within the province of these men to overcome the presumption of accident and to discover evidence to show that the fire was incendiary. One of the first and most important steps in an arson trial is to prove what the lawyers call the " Corpus Delicti ", or the body of the crime. In other words, before evidence of a motive, or even a confession, can be introduced in a criminal trial it must first be proven that the specific crime charged has been committed. In a case of arson the specific charges is the burning of a building or other property. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">State of Nebraska In the investigation of a fire care should always be taken to ascertain the character of it, in what part of the building it originated, how it burned, and other facts and circum - stances which may be suggestive of the nature of the fire under investigation. The incendiary origin of a fire is some - times shown by direct and positive evidence, such as the sat - uration of the premises with kerosene or some other explosive compound. It may be shown by the fact that there are two or three separate fires, one having no connection with another. It sometimes manifests itself to the firemen by the manner in. which it burns, or by the presence of dense smoke, indicating the use of oil. The appearance of the interior of a building frequently shows whether a fire is the result of accident or design. The articles of furniture may have been placed so as to retard the work of the firemen, or there may be evidence that a considerable part of the furniture, fixtures or stock had beer.' removed previous to the fire. The Supreme Court of a western state, in commenting on an arson case, said, " Where the same person has a series of fires and collects insurance it furnishes a basis for an inference of more or less strength that the fires are not acci - dental." In the investigation of a supposed incendiary fire it is frequently thought important to eliminate insofar as is pos - sible all the accidental causes which might possibly be put forward as the probable cause for the fire. . It is highly im - portant to inspect the heating and the electrical equipment of the building, to see whether such equipment could possibly have been the cause of the fire. It is thus important to know that the electrical equipment is intact or that there is no electric wire near the origin of the fire, as some of these things will undoubtedly be advanced by the defense as the probable cause. Any of these things, and many others not here mentioned, may tend to excite the suspicion of the firemen that the fire </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Division of Fire Prevention was not accidental, and in such a case a thorough investiga - tion as to its cause should be immediately made. If any physical evidence of incendiarism are found they should be immediately taken possession of by the officer in charge and held for the Fire Marshal, or his Deputy. It frequently happens that the remains of a "plant" arranged by someone to start or accelerate the fire is found in the building after the fire is extinguished. It is highly important, in the event candles or oily bottles, or things of that character are discovered, that they be left exactly as found until they can be photographed. If the candle is to be picked up, lift it by the wick and turn it over to the Fire Marshal's office for examination for fingerprints. The same care should be exercised in handling any other articles which were plainly used by the incendiary, for their examination for fingerprints. All cases of suspicious fires should be immediately re - ferred to the State Fire Marshal for further investigation, but the members of the Fire Department should bear in mind that, being the first at the scene of the fire, it is their duty, if the fire is incendiary, to collect and develop the evidence to support this fact. Of course it is impossible to properly in - vestigate the cause of a fire during its progress, but where the circumstances are suspicious, as soon as the fire is ex - tinguished a watchman should be placed in charge of the/ building until such time as proper investigation can be made/ (Signed) JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p042">State of Nebraska SOME OF THE UNDERLYING CAUSES OF FIRE GAS OILS ASHES LITTER MATCHES GASOLINE FIREWORKS EXPLOSIONS ELECTRICITY CARELESSNESS DON'TS DON'T use make-shifts instead of proper fuses in your elec - trical circuits ; the fuse is the safety valve of the system. DON'T leave electric flatirons or other heating devices turned on while attending to something else. DON'T look for gas leaks with an open flame light; you will be sure to find them. DON'T use gasoline or other volatile liquids to remove spots from clothing or for other purposes. It is cheaper to pay for dry cleaning than for a funeral. DON'T throw your matches or lighted smoking material where they can possibly start a fire. DON'T smoke in bed ; even if those guilty of this practice are too green to burn, the beds are not. DON'T let the children play with matches or bonfires. DON'T fail to have your defective chimneys and flues mended ; they cause numerous fires in our state. DON'T forget to have your smokepipe cleaned of soot; if clogged it may overheat and start a fire when you operate the furnace. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Division of Fire Prevention DON'T neglect to protect walls, ceilings and partitions from the overheating of stoves, furnaces and pipes. DON'T put hot ashes into wooden boxes or barrels. DON'T fill oil lamps or stoves by open flame lights; many lives have been lost by this form of carelessness. DON'T let rubbish accumulate ; uncleanliness and fire go hand in hand. - DON'T fail to keep a bucket of water and a bucket of sand in a convenient place for use in case of fire; they may save the lives of your family. DON'T fail to purchase a good fire extinguishing chemical (one or more) for your home. DON'T fail to look after chemical extinguishers; see that they are immediately charged after being used. A 2V2 or 3 gallon turnover chemical can be used by man, woman or child and one or more should be installed in every home. REMEMBER, IN CONCLUSION, "FIRE IS A DANGER THAT NEVER SLEEPS", SO BE CONTINUOUSLY ON YOUR GUARD. SLOGANS America never has been licked — except by flames. A match has a head, but no brains. When you use its head, use your brains. A fire extinguisher on hand is worth two in the store. Fire loves a disorderly housekeeper. A tree will make a million matches, but a match will start a fire which destroys a million trees. Clean property seldom burns. A man steals a few dollars and is sent to prison, but when a man through carelessness and indifference causes a fire which results in the loss of thousands of dollars worth of </seg>
            <seg id="p044">State of Nebraska property, and sometimes the loss of life, he is not punished. Which is the greater criminal? Careless smokers burned over millions of dollars worth of property last year. Do not smoke where smoking is for - bidden. Fire prevention protects your home and family. Fire waste is not paid by insurance companies ; they only distribute the money that is paid by the people when they buy merchandise. The cost of fire tax is concealed in the price of the goods. If we all use precaution and teach our boys and girls the hazards of tire, it won't be long until the fires will be reduced to a minimum. Fire ix not the only form of waste, but it is the most malignant. If we are careful in all things we will avoid waste, and carefulness does not cost a cent. From little sparks may burst a mighty flame. Courting Danger. " How'd they come to bounce the fire chief?" asked Abe Hinkle, who had been out of town for a couple of days. "He took too many dad-blamed risks," answered Joe Mudge. " Why he even wore his celluloid collar to fires." If your fire insurance rates are too high, see that your city conforms to the state law the state marshal is called to enforce and then watch the results. (Kansas State Fire Marshal's Bulletin.) A tumbledown wooden building cobwebbed and trash - bedecked in the rear of a block of business houses is more expensive luxury than a perpetual marble fountain bedecked with vari-colored lights by night, set in the public square. (Kansas State Fire Marshal's Bulletin.) </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Division of Fire Prevention FIRE DEPARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX " Section 4469. Compiled Statutes for 1922. FIRE DE - PARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX. All cities of the metropolitan, first or second class or village, organized under the laws of the State of Nebraska, shall have power and authority to levy a special tax of not more than one and one - half (V/2) mills each year upon all taxable property in said city. Such special levy shall be made by the same officers or board and shall be. levied in the. same manner as in the case of general city taxes. Revenue raised by such special levy may be used only for the purpose of purchasing equip - ment for a fire department of such city or for installing and equipping a fire alarm system, or in payment of bonds as hereinafter authorized. • (Note. Sections 5820 and 5910 C. S. Neb. 1922 now fix levy at twenty per cent of one and one-half mills actual valuation.) " Section 4470. BONDS — AUTHORIZED. Any city or village having levied a tax as herein authorized may antici - pate the collection of such tax so levied, and for that purpose may issue bonds with interest coupons attached, in a sum amounting to 90 per cent of the tax so levied. Such bonds may run for a period of not more than five years, and may bear interest at a rate not to exceed 5 per cent per annum. Bonds so issued shall be secured by such tax so assessed and levied, and shall be payable only out of the funds derived from such tax. In any case in which bonds are issued as herein authorized, it shall be the duty of such city, on receipt of such tax when paid, to hold the same as a separate fund to the amount of the bonds, so issued, and the interest thereon, for the purpose of paying or redeeming such bonds." </seg>
            <seg id="p046">State of Nebraska NEBRASKA BOY SCOUTS AND CAMPFIRE GIRLS The Fire Marshal's force want to compliment the Boy Scouts and Camp Fire Girls on the fine teaching they received in their respective organizations, and the splendid way in which they help the older members of their household to ob - serve the very important teachings of fire prevention. Your good work has been brought to our attention and we urge you not to be lax in your efforts along these lines. There is so much the boys and girls can do to assist in the great work of combating carelessness. Over five hundred million dollars worth of property is being destroyed each year, thousands of lives lost, and thousands injured for life, JUST BECAUSE OF CARELESSNESS. The time to learn to be careful is when one is young, for then it becomes a habit with us and we do it without thinking. Let each of us make a solemn promise to do more good this year than ever before in this particular line of work. FIRE DANGERS The state law requires that teachers of public and private schools and educational institutions shall hold at least two fire drills each month. The fire alarm should be distinctive in character and never used for any other purpose. When sounded the pupils should not be permitted to stop for wraps or other articles but should be instructed to leave the building in a quiet orderly manner. Fire drills are very essential to the pupil's education. The law also provides that thirty minutes of each school month be given to the teaching of fire prevention. A booklet on " FIRE DANGERS AND PREVENTION LESSONS " has just been completed containing a lesson in fire prevention for each month of the school year. Sufficient copies will be fur - nished the County Superintendents for the needs of every teacher in his district. These booklets will be a great bene - fit to the teachers and will enable them in the teaching of fire prevention. Teachers are largely held responsible for the safety of the </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Division of FIre Prevention children who are confined to their care. It is, therefore, their duty to call the attention of the school board to any fire hazards that exist in the school room. Inspections are made of all school buildings by deputy fire marshals and fire chiefs and orders issued on fire hazards. These orders should have immediate attention and compli - ance, thereby making our schools safer for the pupils and teachers. School buildings should be properly constructed so they would not burn, and if the contents did burn the children would all escape easily and safely. It therefore behooves each and every one of us to use every precaution within our power to lessen the fire dangers in our immediate sur - roundings. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>