<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1935</title>
               <date value="1936-01">1936-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 296 January, 1936 NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1935 BOARD OF TRACTOR TEST ENGINEERS E. E. Brackctt, C. W. Smith, E. B. Lewis ENGINEER IN CHARGE OF TESTS Carlton L. Zink ASSISTANT IN TRACTOR TESTS C. F. Adams I •' v ' : - !r '* -' : '■ : ' J -v- ■ ,. :■ "' : ■■■'"■ ■ '. ! ' • ' ' ■ * ' : "■■■'■'■■' '. ' ■ ' ■ ' ■■ ". .'' ; '■'■.... • • —■ Some equipment used m making drawbar tests on rubber-tired tractors- THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction 3 General Procedure and Rules m Testing Tractors 4 Belt Tests 5 100% maximum belt tests 5 Operating maximum belt tests ." 6 Rated-load belt test 7 Varying-load belt test 7 Drawbar Tests 7 100% maximum drawbar tests . - 7 Operating maximum drawbar tests 8 Rated-load drawbar test . 8 End of Test 9 Drawbar Testing Equipment 10 Comments 10 Drawbar loading machines 10 Farm Tractor Rating Code — A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. Standard 11 Tractor rating specifications 11 Testing procedure ". 11 Fuels 13 Lubricants 13 Belts 13 The Law 13 Tractor Specifications 16-31 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Nebraska Tractor Tests With the close of the testing season for 19?"5 « m . *u' j t , Mxteenth year of tractor testing J the Units^of Sb^ka "hei bers of complete tests conducted and reported forVe yea" are IsL W ? f? T ff T »? -? -ff T «? - T T »? t T i§§ll reports. All other nins are Ldc „ « '" "" ap I &gt;ear '" &gt;•"» 193 5 100 per cent, or, TL uLX the cL°LT" g SMdng&gt; " , Which m " te specifications filed with thr Tr!!!v 7 c SC reports and bom *** three-page repom are avtflabEf^ 1 " ° f *« ori g inal from Ae Department of TJric^ U^ rCP ° rt ( ° n One Lincoln, NcLZ Bfr^TuofT'T?'- 00^ ° f A^ CuIture ' out delay will receive for v 5 1 - 0 . 0 those desmng future reports with - one copy of all^ reports TL Z/?' ?*"? K * UCSts or oth « ~« one w£^ tCStS; </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 GENERAL PROCEDURE AND RULES IN TESTING TRACTORS When a manufacturer wishes to test a new tractor, application forms are obtained from the Agricultural Engineering Department of the Uni - versity of Nebraska. These forms call for detailed specifications of the tractor to be tested. They are filled out and returned, together with a request for the assignment of a testing date and check for $500.00 to cover the test fee. Dates for test are given in the order in which the application for test, specifications, and testing fee are received. The actual test date depends on the arrival of the tractor and suitable weather con - ditions. Tractors that are shipped by way of the C. R. I. &amp; P. in Nebraska will be switched to the Agricultural College loading dock with minimum delay. It is assumed that the application for test is made by the tractor com - pany with the knowledge that it is not an experimental but an official performance test to be run under specifiations submitted with the ap - plication and under the testing rules in force. One of the rules is that there shall be no revision of specifications after the test starts nor any change of parts or equipment except to make replacement for that which may be defective or broken. Experimentation desired by the manufacturer must be deferred until after the official test is completed and is then con - tingent on available time. All such experimental work is charged to the manufacturer on an hourly basis. Any data and results thus attained are for the information of the manufacturer and will not be included in the official report. A representative of the manufacturer should be present during the test. His duties include unloading the tractor, installing wheel.equip - ment or other accessories, operating the tractor during the "limber-up" run, making such adjustments as he may deem necessary before the test, making repairs when necessary during the test, and at the conclusion of the test disposing of the tractor. In addition to these duties, the manu - facturer's representative makes all decisions involving permissible choices or company policy relative to the current test which are not covered in the application for test. Before any tests are made the lubricating oil is drained from the crank - case and is replaced with new oil. This new oil is selected by the manu - facturer's representative from the brands generally available in Nebraska. It is of the viscosity specified in the application for test and is purchased by the Tractor Testing Department in sealed containers. The oil is weighed as well as measured and the weight per gallon at 60° F. is determined. All figures in the test report showing consumption of either oil, fuel, or water in gallons are based on the amounts used in pounds and the weight per gallon *t 60° F. Tr- used is the lowest grade recommended by the manufacturer for use in the tractor being tested. For instance, if the application for test states that the tractor will operate on gasoline, kerosene, and distillate, distillate will be used. The gasoline used is of the lowest commercial </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska Tractor Tests grade available and in no case is a premium fuel used in an official test except in those cases where it is recommended by the manufacturer as being essential to the successful operation of the engine. Fuels and lub - ricants are supplied by the University and charged to the manufacturer at current prices. «i- 1 ?* C fir » t tCSt rUn " ° ne made on thc drawbar an d »s known as the limber-up" run. ' The principal object of this test is to take out the stiffness likely to be found in a new machine and give an opportunity to check the condition of the tractor and ascertain if all the parts are work - ing normally. The tractor is operated at approximately one-third load for four hours, two-thirds for four hours, and full load for four hours. A reasonable amount of additional time is granted if desired. Each one of the forward gears is used for some portion of this test. The manu - facturers representative is responsible for the operation of the tractor dur - ing this test and may make such adjustments as he may feel are necessary provided they do not conflict with the specifications in the application for test. . rr Adjustments that are permissible include setting the valve tappet clear - ance and the gap of breaker points or spark plug points, adjusting the clutch, and making other adjustments of a similar nature. This shall not be interpreted to permit the installation of new parts or accessories with - out having the same mentioned in the official report of the test. BELT TESTS The tractor testing engineer then takes charge of the tractor and it is belted to the cradle-mounted Sprague electric dynamometer used in de - termining the belt horsepower. The top radiator tank is drilled to take a gas-nlled indicating thermometer, a fuel line is installed from tractor fuel system to the fuel-weighing equipment, and measurements are taken of the belt thickness and of the circumferences of both the engine and dynamometer pulleys. No allowances are made for belt losses. 100% Maximum Belt Test— The engine is then run at full load until it is thoroughly warmed and has reached a condition of constant operating temperatures. All adjustments are made to secure maximum output from the engine at rated r. p. m. Rated speed is that number of revolutions per rrunute recommended by the manufacturer for normal operation. The governor is set to hold the throttle valve to the extreme open position the spark is set to give the best results, the manifold heat control, if present, is set at the most favorable position, and the carburetor is carefully adjusted to that point at which an additional amount of fuel gives no increase in power output at the rated speed of the engine. After uniform operating conditions are reached, this test, known as thc 100 per cent or rating maximum , is continued for two hours. The object of this test is to check or establish ratings and to determine adjustments for maximum horse - power. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 At ten minute intervals readings are taken or observations made of engine belt pulley and brake speed, load on scale beam of dynamometer, temperature of water in top tank of radiator, air temperature at a point approximately five feet in front of the center of the radiator and weight of fuel used. Barometer readings are taken every hour. The water level in the radiator is measured at the beginning and at the end of the two - hour period, and the necessary amount of water is added to raise it to the same level as at I the start of the two-hour test. Water, if used in the fuel mixture, is cheated in the same manner. Results of this test are used in determining the highest belt horsepower rating permissible under the provisions of the A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. tractor rating code. This rating is obtained by correcting the observed horsepower to standard conditions (temperature of 60° F. and atmospheric pressure of 29.92 inches of mer - cury) and then multiplying the result by 0.8^. This corrected horsepower is sometimes known as sea-level horsepowei nd is occasionally advertised as such. Many engineers feel that a true comparison of the performance of tractors can be made only by the use of figures corrected to standard tem - perature and pressure conditions. The correction formula used may be found in the A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. Farm Tractor Rating Code, which is included in this bulletin (page 11). The observed maximum horsepower as determined in "this initial belt test has not appeared in the published report of each test nor in the sum - mary sheet of the annual tractor test bulletin from 1928 to and including 1934 except in those cases where the manufacturer elected to use the 100 per cent or maximum power setting throughout the complete test. On either the first or the third page of the report and in Column 10 of the summary sheet are figures indicating whether the carburetor setting used was 100 per cent or some lesser value. If the 1D0 per cent setting is used through the complete test, then the second hour of the 100 per cent or rating maximum is used for the operating maximum and appears as such in the report of the belt test. In case the manufacturer wishes to use a car - buretor adjustment leaner than the 100 per cent setting, a series of trial runs of 20 to 30 minutes at leaner settings are made and the manufac - turer's representative is permitted to choose from these an' "operating set - ting". This operating setting of the carburetor is used throughout the remainder of the test with the exception of the 100 per cent maximum drawbar test in rated gear (to determine the drawbar rating) when the adjustment used is the 100 per cent maximum power setting as obtained on the belt. Operating Maximum Belt Test. — The first run on this operating setting is a one-hour maximum power test known as the "operating maximum belt test". The object of this test is to determine the maximum power developed and the fuel consumption at a carburetor setting that is prac - ticable for field operations. The radiator cover, manifold heat control, and spark are set at the most favorable positions, the engine is run until operat- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Tractor Tests ing conditions have become stabilized, and then readings are taken at ten minute intervals over a one-hour period. Rated Load Belt Test-The next belt test is of one hour duration and » known as the rated load belt test. The object of this test is to determine whether the tractor will carry its rated load in the belt and to secure a record of fue consumption and other operating data. The tractor is given, as nearly as possible, its rated load. The carburetor remains set at the operating setting. The governor is adjusted to maintain rated engine speed at rated load. Rated load is determined in one of two ways If the tractor is rated by the manufacturer, sufficient load is applied to develop rated horsepower at rated engine speed. In case the manufacturer cither does not specify the rating of the tractor or elects to accept the highest belt horsepower rating permissible under the tractor rating code, then rated load becomes 85 per cent of the corrected maximum 5s calculated from the results of the 100 per cent maximum belt test. vaJnT^ 1 ? 311 *S T ? t - The last ™ °* *e belt is known as the varying-load test. All adjustments are as in the rated-load test. The object of this test is to show the governor control of the speed and also fuel consumption when the load varies. It is comprised of six twenty - minute runs made in the following order: The first is rated load, which is the same load as the one-hour rated load test just completed; in fact, if conditions are favorable, the rated and varying load tests are continuous twl£ rfi nty - TT of the rated - load mn are used for fi«t nTwd ™ e v ff77 g i? ad test - ™* is followed b y twentv mi ™&lt;« « W * .? , 3nd , reS J StanCC Circuits o£ the dynamometer are open and the power deve oped ordinarily is something less than one horsepower The next load applied is one-half of the rated-load torque and this^ lowed by a maximum horsepower test in which enough load is applied on the dynamometer to pull the engine far enough under rated speS to Wh TfT me f T le OP fT^ The l3St tW ° ™ ns are made « °ne - tourth and three-fourths rated load torque respectively nv, -f U^ g thC ar yi n g- load test the al »o«nt of heat applied to the intake mamfold may be changed according to the load if an easily controlled rTrSL ad) r tn T' S - UCh a j 3 IeVCr O^ tia S f™m the driver's seatTs provided. An effort is made to maintain the recommended temperature on^he "^ m Cn P ° SSMe ' by reguIatin S ** amount °^«&gt;ver! mg on die radiator m those cases where an adjustable cover is provided S^be exSteTf" "IT nO ""^ attenti °n than may reasot ably be expected from a careful operator. When possible the friction at^hTeTJ o? d th he COm PT- P rcssu - at rated engint speed are checked Report of the te« Varymg " Ioad tCSt " ™** «P™« d ° not appear in the DRAWBAR TESTS ™xh!^ 1 £ aXimnm DKlWbar Tcsts - The *&lt;« tests made are maximum horsepower runs at two carburetor settings, operating and 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 per cent. The 100 per cent maximum test is made in one gear only, that designated by the manufacturer as most suitable for plowing or ordinary farm work. It is commonly known as "plow gear", "working gear" or "rated gear". The results of a test in this gear, with the carburetor adjusted at 100 per cent as found on the belt, are used to determine the highest drawbar horsepower rating permissible under the provisions of the A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. tractor rating code. The observed 100 per cent maxi - mum drawbar horsepower is corrected to standard conditions, multiplied by 0.75 and the result is the code rating. The results of this rating maxi - mum test have not appeared in the published report of each test nor in the summary sheet of the annual tractor test bulletin from 1928 to and including 1934 except in those cases where the manufacturer elected to use the 100 per cent or maximum power setting throughout the complete test. The manufacturer's representative is permitted to select the wheel, lug, and extension-rim equipment from that supplied on stock tractors or that regularly offered to the trade in Nebraska but at extra cost. The same wheel and lug equipment must be used on all the drawbar tests. In the case of the crawler tractors, a choice may be made in the type and width of track and the type and size of cleats, subject to the same restrictions as obtain for wheel and lug equipment. The drawbar specifications as to dimensions and adjustments for height and point of attachment must be the same for all of the drawbar tests. They must also conform to the spec - ifications in the application for test. Operating Maximum Drawbar Tests. — Operating maximum drawbar tests are made in all of the forward gears, using the operating carburetor setting selected and used on the operating belt tests. The object of these tests is to determine the maximum horsepower the tractor will develop in each forward gear with the carburetor adjusted at the operating setting with engine running at rated speed. After the tractor is thoroughly warmed and brought to a condition of constant operating temperatures, at least two suitable drawbar runs are secured over a measured distance of 500 feet on the testing track. A suitable run is one in which the operating temperatures are normal, the throttle is open to the extreme position, the load is relatively constant, and the average engine speed is at or very close to that specified by the manufacturer. The tractor rating code recommends that the average engine r. p. m. be maintained within 5 per cent of its rated full load speed. Very seldom is a pull used in which the variation from rated speed is more than 1J-4 per cent and in each test in each gear an attempt is made to obtain an average r. p. m. which does not deviate from rated speed more than '/2 of 1 per cent. Rated Load Drawbar Test — The last run made on the drawbar is the rated-load test. The duration of test is ten hours' actual running time (as nearly continuous as possible) with constant load. A record is made of the time and reason for each stop, and also of any adjustment or repairs </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests made on the tractor. The object of this test is to determine whether the tractor can pull its rated load continuously and to secure a record of fuel consumption on drawbar work. The governor is adjusted to give rated speed of the engine with the tractor pulling rated load and in the gear recommended for plowing or ordinary farm work. The carburetor remains at the operating setting. Rated load is determined in one of two ways It the tractor is rated by the manufacturer, sufficient load is applied to develop rated horsepower at rated engine speed in rated gear. In case the manufacturer either does not specify the rating of the tractor or elects to accept highest drawbar horse-power rating permissible under the tractor rating code, then rated load becomes 75 per cent of the corrected maximum as calculated from the results of the 100 per cent maximum drawbar test in rated gear. Once each hour during the rated-load drawbar test a chart is taken by means of the graphic recording drawbar dynamometer, of the drawbar pull; and observations are made on the time required to travel 500 feet the revolutions of the drive wheels over this same measured course, and the temperature of the air and cooling medium. From the chart and observations, calculations are made for the drawbar pull in pounds, the rate of travel m feet per minute and miles per hour, the drawbar horse - power, the engine revolutions per minute, and the drive wheel slippage in percentage. The testing operator maintains the load as nearly constant as possible and by following the progress of the test applies such a load as will be sufficient to develop horsepower equal to or slightly in excess of rated horsepower. END OF TEST At the conclusion of the rated-load drawbar test the lubricating oil is drained from the crankcase and weighed, the specific gravity at 60° is determined, and the number of gallons drained is calculated. A record is kept throughout the test of all oil added or drained. The test report shows the total number of gallons of new oil put in the crankcase and the gallons or used oil drained, as well as the number of times the crankcase was drained. At this time the tractor is inspected. This inspection is not extensive it the tractor is apparently in normal condition. Particular attention is centered on spark plugs and valves, loose parts and leakage of fuel, water, and lubricants. The manufacturer's representative, when so directed by the engineer in charge, disassembles any part of the tractor or its access - ories in order to facilitate inspection. During the drawbar tests, usually on the completion of the rated-load drawbar test, the tractor is driven to a government-inspected farm scale on the Agricultural College campus and weighed. The weight which appears in the test report is the observed weight plus the weight of the operator and the amount of fuel necessary to completely fill the fuel tank. When all of the tests have been completed and the inspection made, the engineer in charge may release the tractor to the manufacturer's represen- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 tative or at his discretion may withhold the release until the test report is issued. DRAWBAR TESTING EQUIPMENT Comments. — All of the drawbar pull exerted by the tractor being tested is transmitted, by a hydraulic piston-cylinder mechanism called a draft unit, to the drawbar load. The pressure in the draft unit is carried through flexible metal tubing to the draft-recording instrument. The essential mechanism of this draft-recording unit is a gas-engine pressure indicator which has been so adapted to the requirements that it leaves on a special chart a continuous record of the drawbar pull of the tractor. From this chart, showing the pull in pounds, and from stop-watch readings showing the time of travel over a measured course, the horsepower developed is calculated. Rotary switches having ten contact points are attached to each drive wheel and connected to magnetic counters which record to one-tenth of one revolution the number of revolutions made over a measured dis - tance. From these same readings are calculated the engine speed and the drive wheel or track slippage. In determining the slippage the tractor is driven without any drawbar load for a distance sufficient to give at least 10 revolutions of the drive wheels or crawler tracks. This distance is then accurately measured and is used as a basis for computing wheel slippage. The computations are as follows: The distance covered at no load is divided by the number of drive - wheel revolutions to obtain the number of feet advanced per revolution. The number of revolutions made in advancing 500 feet is recorded by the electric counters. This number multiplied by the feet of advance per revo - lution at no load gives the distance the tractor would have traveled had there been no loss due to slippage. However, the tractor actually ad - vances only 500 feet. The difference between these two distances is divided by the former, and the answer multiplied by 100 is the percentage of slippage. (When speaking of rubber tire tests, some prefer to use the term, "travel reduction".) Drawbar Loading Machines. — In determining the drawbar horsepower of a tractor, it is necessary to provide a source of load which may be readily varied. The loading machine, which is used in the major portion of the tests, is built about a McCormick-Deering 15-30 tractor. A gear type pump is mounted on the platform and driven by a roller chain from a special sprocket which replaces the brake pulley. The discharge line of the pump is carried up and forward to valves mounted on the top of the radiator. These valves may be closed or opened to increase or decrease the amount of power absorbed by the pump. A return line from the lower radiator connection to the inlet opening of the pump completes the system. Ad - ditional load may be obtained by placing the tractor in gear and operating the engine against compression without fuel or ignition. If a light load is desired, the tractor may be placed in gear, the fuel and ignition turned on, and the throttle set to give such assistance as will result in the desired load. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Tractor Tests The design of this equipment is not original except as improvements have been made from time to time. The International Harvester Com - pany had built two similar machines and at the time the Tractor Testine Department needed a new machine were able to furnish the plans and part ot the special equipment necessary to make the conversion. Another loading machine built about a rubber-tired 15-30 McCormick- Deenng tractor will be available for the 1936 testing season. A four-speed transmission mounted in the power line from the tractor rear wheel? to the gear-type pump permits the use of this machine at travel speeds up to approximately 25 miles per hour. Still another machine, a smaller one has a range of load from about 200 pounds to 1,600 pounds and a possible top speed of 40 miles per hour. The essential parts of this machine Vre the rear axle assembly and transmission from a heavy-type passenger car a gear-type pump, a radiator and fan, a supply tank and suitable controls' 1 his machine is pictured on the front cover of this bulletin A close coupled four-wheeled vehicle, called the instrument car is used to carry the recording instruments and an observer. A small gear pump mounted on this chassis, and driven by the rear wheels through a reversed transmission, provides drawbar load for the very small tractors. FARM TRACTOR RATING CODE A. S. A. E. AND S. A. E. STANDARD TRACTOR RATING SPECIFICATIONS Belt Rating.— The belt horsepower rating of the tractor shall not exceed cighty-nve (85) per cent of the maximum corrected horsepower which the engine will maintain by belt at the brake or dynamometer for 2 hours at rated engine r. p. m., the test to be carried out as specified herein. Drawbar Rating.— The drawbar rating of the tractor shall not exceed seventy-live (75) per cent of the maximum corrected drawbar horsepower developed at a rate of travel recommended for the ordinary operation of the tractor, under conditions of testing as specified herein. TESTING PROCEDURE Nature of Tests.— The following rating tests are to be conducted in the order given on three or more tractors picked at random from factory stock run by the engineer or engineers conducting the test; the averages of all tests are to be used in determining the results. Test A (limbering-up Run).— Before a test is undertaken it is import - ant that the tractor shall have been in operation for a sufficient length of time to attain proper operating conditions throughout so that the results of the test shall express the true working performance. The tractor or tractors !i° J tC c io therefore •* submitted to "limbering-up" runs on the drawbar of 12 or more hours' duration. Drawbar loads of approximately one-third, two-thirds, and full load shall be pulled by the tractor during the runs, each load being drawn for approximately an equal length of time, the lighter loads being used first. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 Test B (Maximum Brake Horsepower Test).— The tractor engine is to be tested in the belt with the governor set to give full opening of gov - ernor valve, and the carburetor set to give maximum power at rated engine crankshaft speed. (The rated speed is that which the manufacturer recommends for the engine under normal load.) The test shall begin after the temperature of the cooling fluids and other operating conditions have become practically constant. The duration of this test shall be two hours of continuous running with no change in engine adjustments. If the speed should change sufficiently during the test to indicate that the operating conditions had not become constant when the test was started, the test will be repeated with the necessary change in load. (The term "load", as used in this connection, means pounds on dynamometer or brake scale.) Minor changes in load to be made to maintain rated speed and the average load and average speed for the period shall be used in computing the horsepower. All belt horsepower tests must be made with an electric dynamometer, or with an accurately tested Prony brake or other accurate power-measuring device. Correction shall be made for tempera - ture and altitude effect on horsepower output on maximum test only. Standard conditions of barometric pressure of 29.92 inches Hg. and a temperature of 60° Fahr., or 520° abs. T. shall be used. The following correction formula shall be used (on maximum test only): BHPc = BHPo X (Ps ■*■ Po) X V.To-s-.Ts where BHPc=corrected brake horsepower BHPo=observed brake horsepower Po=observed barometric pressure in inches of mercury Ps=standard barometric pressure in inches of mercury To=observed absolute temperature in degrees Fahrenheit Ts=standard absolute temperature in degrees Fahrenheit Test C (Maximum Drawbar Horsepower).— After the tractor has at - tained proper working conditions it shall be subjected to a series of draw - bar tests, preferably on level ground and of such a nature that it will pro - vide a firm footing and offer a tractive resistance simulating that of grain stubble ground in good plowing condition. The loads shall be successively increased or decreased to a point where the tractor can sustain a constant pull for a distance of not less than 1,000 feet with the average engine r. p. m. maintained within 5 per cent of its rated full load speed and a wheel slippage of not more than 10 per cent, the wheel slippage to be secured as follows: The tractor shall be driven without any drawbar load for a distance sufficient to give 10 revolutions of the drivewheels. This distance is then accurately measured and is used as the basis for comput - ing wheel slippage. The number of revolutions of all drivers shall be counted for the entire distance through which the load is pulled. The drawbar pull shall be measured by means of an accurately calibrated draft •dynamometer or draft measuring device placed between the tractor and the load. The actual distance traveled shall be used in calculating the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests horse power, no allowance being made for wheel slippage. During this test the tractor shall be run in the gear recommended for plowing under favorable conditions. '. ' FUELS These tests will be made on the lowest commercially available grade of fuel which the manufacturer recommends. LUBRICANTS The lubricants used in these tests shall be such as are regularly recom - mended by the manufacturer for the tractor. BELTS The belt or belts used in these tests shall be such as the manufacturer recommends for use with the tractor in ordinary operation. No allowance will be made for belt losses. THE LAW Purpose of the Law.— The Nebraska Tractor Law, known as House Roll 85, 37th Session (Art. 10, paragraphs 5531-5543 inclusive, pages 1751 and 1752, Compiled Statutes of State of Nebraska, 1922), which became effective July 15, 1919, was enacted to encourage the manufacture and sale of improved types of tractors and to contribute to a more successful use of the tractor for farming. It was thought that the best method of accomplishing these objects would be to require a tractor of each model sold in the State to be tested at the State University and to have the results of these tests made public Provisions of the Law.— Stated briefly, the provisions of the law arc- That a stock tractor of each model sold in the State shall be tested and passed upon by a board of three engineers under State University management. That «ach company, dealer or individual offering a tractor for sale in Nebraska shall have a permit issued by the State Railway Commission The permit for any model of tractor will be issued after a stock tractor of that model has been tested at the University and the performance of the tractor compared with the claims made for it by the manufacturer. That a service station with full supply of replacement parts for each model of tractor shall be maintained within the confines of the State and within reasonable shipping distance of customers. Nebraska Tractor Law.— Full text of the law as found in 75-901 to 911 inclusive, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, and revised by House Roll 526, 49th Session (1933) is as follows: Section 1. That on and after July 15, 1919, no tractor or traction com - pany shal be permitted to sell or dispose of any model or type of gas gasoline, kerosene, distillate or other liquid fuel tractor engine in the state of Nebraska without first having said model tested and passed upon by a board of three competent engineers who are or shall be under the control of the state university management. Each and every tractor pre - sented to the state university management for testing, shall be a stock </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 model and shall not be equipped with any special appliance or apparatus not regularly supplied to the trade. Any tractor not complying with the provisions o£ this section shall not be tested under this act, nor the results certified. Provided, no official tractor tests shall be conducted during the months of December, January and February. Applications for the test of a tractor shall be made to the testing board of engineers and shall be ac - companied by specifications of the tractor required by said board of engi - neers, and by the fee specified in Section 5535, Compiled Statutes of Ne - braska for 1922. If the application with specifications and fee is submitted during December, January, February or at any other time when the test can not be started at once, the State Railway Commission, with the ap - proval of the said board of engineers, may issue a temporary permit for the sale of tractors of the model specified in the application for test, the date on which said temporary permit shall terminate to be fixed by the said board of engineers. All temporary permits shall be conditioned upon such tractor as is covered thereby being tested at the earliest available date, and the tractor company to which a temporary permit has been issued shall submit a tractor for test which conforms to the specifications filed with the application, said tractor to be delivered for test at any time specified by the board of engineers. Upon failure to do so, all such fees deposited by said companies shall be forfeited to the State of Nebraska, and in addition such companies shall be liable to the penalties prescribed by Section 5540, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922, and shall never thereafter be issued any temporary permit whatever. Provided, however, that all sales of tractors upon which a temporary permit has been issued, shall be made subject to the final official test and approval of the model. Section 2. Such tests to consist of endurance, official rating of horse - power for continuous load, and consumption of fuel per hour or per acre of farm operations; the results of such tests to be open at all times to public inspection. Section 3. The State University management after having duly tested any model of liquid fuel traction engine shall certify the results to the State Railway Commission. Prior to the issuing of a permit by said com - mission to any liquid fuel traction engine company to do business in the State of Nebraska, the official tests of the University shall be compared with the representations of the tractor company as to. horsepower rating for not less than ten consecutive hours of continuous load, fuel used for developing such horsepower, and any other representation such company shall make, and in case any such representations shall be found false the State Railway Commission shall deny the company manufacturing or assembling such tractor, the right to do business in the State of Nebraska, except as hereinafter provided. Section 4. Likewise, the State Ra'ilway Commission shall deny to any liquid fuel tractor company the right to do business in the State of Ne - braska which shall be found, on complaint of two or more bona fide cus - tomers residing within the State, to fail to maintain an adequate service </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor Tests station with full supply of replacement parts within the confines of the State and within reasonable shipping distance of said customers. Section 5. Application to the State University management for test of a tractor shall be accompanied by a fee of five hundred dollars (§500.00) paid to the State University management as a partial reimbursement for the cost of such test. Payment shall also be made upon presentation of the proper statement for costs of all fuel and oil consumed in making said test. Section 6. Provided further, that the failure of any model of tractor to come up to the representations of the company manufacturing or as - sembling same, shall not prevent said company from placing on the market, other models of tractors that do comply with specifications and ratings. Any model of tractor that fails in the official test to come up to the company's own specifications, may be retested after alteration and remodeling. Each and every permit issued under this act shall specify the model or models included in such permit to sell. Section 7. The report of the official tests herein provided shall be posted in the Agricultural Engineering Department of the State University and in such other places as may be designated by the State University man - agement. The same shall be incorporated in the annual report of the State Railway Commission. Section 8. Provided, that no tractor company shall use the results of said tests in such manner as would cause it to appear that the State Uni - versity management intended to recommend the use of any given type or model of tractor in preference to any other type or model. It shall be unlawful for any tractor company operating in the State of Nebraska, to publish extracts from such official tests for advertising purposes, without publishing the entire report. Any infraction of the foregoing provisions shall result in the suspen - sion or denial to any company so offending the permission to do business in the State at the discretion of the State Railway Commission. Section 9. Tractors shall be tested by the State University management in the order in which they are presented for such tests, and no discrim - ination shall be made for or against any tractor company in any manner whatsoever. Complaints against the violation of this provision shall be heard and adjudicated by the State Railway Commission. Section 10 After July 15, 1919. any gas, gasoline, kerosene, distillate or other liquid fuel tractor or traction company selling or offering for sale in the State of Nebraska or any automobile, implement or other company or individual operating in behalf of such tractor company or on their own behalf who shall after the date specified, sell or offer for sale in the State any model of liquid fuel tractor engine, without having in his possession a permit from the State Railway Commission to sell such model of tractor as he is offering for sale, the same shall be deemed guilty of a misde - meanor. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 On conviction such misdemeanor shall be punished by a fine of not less than $100.00 nor more than $500.00 for each offense in the discretion of the court. Section 11. The State Railway Commission shall have full authority to enforce the provisions of this act, both by denial of permit to do busi - ness in the State and by due process of law to compel compliance there - with. , TRACTOR SPECIFICATIONS The following tractors were reported by their manufacturers as being on the market January 1, 1935. The results of the tests are on the folded summary sheet. Test No. 28. BEEMAN MODEL G 2-4, Bccman Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; June 22 to July 2, 1920. Hcinzc "AX1" magneto; Kingston "J" carburetor; Donaldson dry centrifugal-type air cleaner; no governor. Engine vertical, L-hcad, mounted crank-shaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 4&gt;A" width 3'A", rotates at engine speed. Chassis: two drive wheels in front, 2 caster wheels in rear; own clutch, both external and internal expanding. Rated speed 0.75 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comment: Replaced carburetor. Test No. 29. LA CROSSE 12-24, La Crosse Tractor Company, La Crosse, Wiscon - sin; August 2 to 5, 1920. Atwater-Kent "K3" magneto and dry batteries; Stromberg "MB3" carburetor; Ben - nett dry centrifugal-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine horizontal, valvc-in-nead, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 11", width 7 'A", rated speed 900 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers; own clutch contracting-band' type; open gear drive. Rated speed 2.5 miles per hour. Comments: Line drive attachment was used. Operator had reasonably good control or tractor with 4 lines. Replaced fan belt, changed 2 spark plugs. Replaced governor springs, changed ignition timing, ground valves. 12 TiT'l N °' 73 ' WETMORE 12 * 25 ' H - A ' Wetmore, Sioux City, Iowa; April 6 to Splitdorf Aero magneto; Schcbler "ATX47" VA" carburetor; no air cleaner; Weidely Hy-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 6/,", rated speed 1088 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, Fuller disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2 0 in - termediate 3.5, high 5.9. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Hand operation of throttle was necessary to control speed within safe limits of loads three-fourths rating and under, when carbu - retor was set for best fuel economy. Heavy-grade oil was found necessary for the engine. Test No 117. McCORMICK-DEERING "FARMALL," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; September 14 to 19, 1925. x, J^fJ* ■','^°" 93795 ° ma S nct °: Ens 'S n "3DA600F" 1" carburetor; Pomona Model 118 oilcd-fibre-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14", width 6Vi", rated speed 696 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers - enclosed gear drive; own multiple dry disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2, intermediate 3, high 4. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 122.. TWIN OTY "AT" 27-44, Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery com - pany, Minneapolis, Minnesota; May 20 to 27, 1926. American Bosch "2»4Ed26" magneto; Wheelcr-Scheblcr "A" carburetor; Donaldson Duplex oiled-fibre-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve- </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Tractor Tests in-head, removable head and cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 21", width 854", rated speed 466 r.pjn. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc clutch, 7" extension rims. Rated speeds, miles per hour; low 2.20, high 2.90, reverse 1.87. Comments: During both the rated load brake test and the rated load drawbar test the fan belt tension had to be readjusted. Test No. 126. HUBER 20-40, Hubcr Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; September 7 to 16, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto; Kingston "L3" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" oil-spray - type air cleaner; Kingston fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 Vi", width 8", rated speed 666 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.47, high 3.48, reverse 1.94. Comments: During the rated brake test the fan belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. Test No. 135. HUBER SUPER FOUR 40-62, Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; May 17 to June 24, 1927. Eisemann "G4" magneto; Ensign "A" carburetor; Pomona oil-spray-type air cleaner; Kingston fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter \5Vi", width 9K", rated speed 733 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.00 to 2.50, high 3.00 to 3.50, reverse 1.75 to 2.25. Comments: During the rated drawbar test and after approximately 25 hours run - ning, ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced with new ones of the same make but did not remedy the trouble. The Stitt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were then replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was experienced. The left spindle arm sheared off, causing the front axle to bend somewhat; the axle and spindle arm were replaced with new parts. The packing-gland nuts on the water pump were tightened several times during the test. The flexible oil tube leading to the clutch throw-out collar was leaking at the end of the test. t Test No. 137. SHAW MODEL "T45," Shaw Manufacturing Company, Galesbure. Kansas; June 7 to 23, 1927. Own magneto; Tillotson "MS7A" carburetor; no air cleaner; own pneumatic-type governor. Engine vertical, air cooled, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 3", width 2 l A", operates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: two wheels, both drivers, open gear and chain drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.00, high 1.43. Comments: In the advertising literature submitted with the specifications for test of this tractor we find the following claims which arc not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit "B" "T45": "DRAWBAR PULL 650 lbs. On low gear, this pulls a \Vi ton load on a light cart or wagon." Test No. 142. McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20, International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October 3 to 8, 1927. Own-make "E4A" magneto; Ensign "R" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" Model 118 oil-spray-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 %", width 7", rated speed 661 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own multiple dry disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2, intermediate 3, high 4, reverse 2.75. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 148. LAUSON "S2" 20-35, John Lauson Manufacturing Company, New Holstein, Wisconsin; April 2 to 16, 1928. American Bosch "ZR4" magneto; Tillotson "R2" carburetor; Taco fly-ball-type governor; Taco water-type air cleaner. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 697 r.p.m. Chassis: four </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Twin Disc, dry plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.25 to 2.50, high 3.25 to 3.50, reverse 2.00. Comments: All spark plug gaps were adjusted to 0.025". At die end of the belt tests No. 2 cylinder had a leaky exhaust valve. All valves were ground and carbon removed. The carburetor float valve was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 149. CLETRAC "40" 40-55, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; April 24 to May 10, 1928. Delco-Rcmy battery ignition system; Wheeler-Schcbler "AT" carburetor; Pomona oil-spray-type air cleaner; Taco fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15", width 13", rated speed 851 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, Borg &amp; Beck single-platc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.0, intermediate 3.5, high 5.5, reverse 3.0. Comments: The battery cable insulation became defective on the rated drawbar test, causing the ignition to become shorted. The insulation was repaired with tape. Two grease cups on the clutch throw-out collar sheared off during the limber-up run. Oil was leaking from the clutch shaft in front of the transmission and also from the crank - case where the front drawbar is connected, at the end of the test Test No. 152. TWIN CITY "FT" 21-32, Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; October 1 to 8, 1928. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto; Stromberg "M3" carburetor; Donaldson and own centrifugal and cypress-moss-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-typc governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16", width 7'/i", rated speed 651 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry - plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.36, intermediate 3.17, hich 4 45 reverse 1.74. Comments: Before the maximum belt tests were run, the packing gland nut on the water pump was tightened. During the maximum low-gear drawbar test, the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 155. CASE "L" 26-40, J. I. Case Threshing Machine Company, Racine, Wisconsin; March 16 to 27, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto; Kingston "JL3" carburetor; own oil-fibre-typc air cleaner; own fly-bali-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width &amp;%", rated speed 780 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, R ear and chain drive. Twin Disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour - low 2.50, intermediate 3.25, high 4.00, reverse 2.75. Comments: Before the official belt tests were run, the weighted air valve in the carburetor was given a few thousandths inch end clearance. Approximately 5/32" was removed from the crown of the belt pulley. Test No. 156. McCORMICK-DEERING (Model 15-30) 22-36, International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois; March 30 to April 9, 1929. Own make "E4A" magneto; Ensign "RW" carburetor; Pomona oil-filter-typc air cleaner; own fly-ball-typc governor. Engine vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16J4", width 9", rated speed 593 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own single-platc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.50, intermediate 3.25, high 3.75, reverse 2.25. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. ■ja T?io N °" 161 " BAKER 43 " 67 &gt; A - D - Baker Company, Swanton, Ohio, May 16 to Eisemann "G4" magneto; Stromberg "M4" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" oil-filter - type air cleaner; own fly-ball-typc governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 Vi" , width 854", rated speed 774 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc singlc-plate-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.0 to 2.5, high 3.0 to 3.5, reverse 2.5. Comments: It was necessary to lock the gears in mesh during the high-gear max - imum and rated load drawbar tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 164. WALLIS 12-20, The Masscy-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin, June 18 to 27, 1929. American Bosch "U4Ed2" magneto; Kingston "L3V" carburetor; own oil-filter-type air cleaner; Kingston fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "1" head, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 17", width 6 5/16", rated speed 540.5 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry threc-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.33, intermediate 3.33, high 4.33, reverse 2.33. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests the carburetor and fuel tank were removed and the entire fuel system thoroughly cleaned. 12 toTo*^ 167 ' ° ASE " C " 17 ' 27 ' J&gt; L Company&gt; ***** WucOMkS August Robert Bosch "FU4ARS" magneto; Kingston "L3" carburetor; own oil-filtcr-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10%", width 654", rated speed 973 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive, Twin Disc plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.30, intermediate 3.28, high 4.50, reverse 2.59. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests, the clutch was adjusted. During the rated drawbar test, the fuel line to the carburetor became clogged and was cleaned out. Test No. 168. HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36, The Hubcr Manufacturing Com - pany, Marion, Ohio; August 19 to 24, 1929. Eiscmann "GV4" magneto; Stromberg "M3" carburetor; Donaldson oiled-fibre-typc air cleaner; Waukesha fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 17", width 8H", rated speed 616 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 232, high 3.08, reverse 1.83. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 169. CASE "CC," J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; September 10 Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto; Kingston "L3V" carburetor; own oil-filtcr-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10 !4", width 6 l A", rated speed 973 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive, Twin Disc platc-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.60, intermediate 3.72, high 5.14, reverse 2.95. Comments: It was necessary to raise the oil level in the transmission approximately one inch for the belt tests. Test No. 173. FORDSON "F" (Kerosene), Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michigan; March 11 to April 8, 1930. Robert Bosch "FU" 4BRS29 magneto; Kingston "MD2" carburetor; own water-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 9H", width 6'A", rated speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own multiple-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.75, intermediate 3.12, high 7.75, reverse 3.00. Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the cylinder head gasket was replaced. The original governor spring was replaced by a heavier spring after the rated load belt test. Test No. 174. FORDSON "F" (Gasoline), Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michigan; March 20 to April 10, 1930. Robert Bosch "FU" 4BRS29 magneto; Zenith "IN5F" carburetor; own water-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, L-hcad, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 9J4", width 6 l A", rated speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own multiplc-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.12, intermediate 3.12, high 7.25, reverse 3.00. Comments: During the rated-Ioad belt test, the water pump gland was tightened approximately one-fifth turn. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 Test No. 175. TWIN CITY 11-20, MODEL KT, Minneapolis-Molinc Power Imple - ment, Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; March 24 to April 12, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2V7" magneto; Stromberg "UT1" carburetor; Donaldson Z-unit centrifugal and oily-fibrc-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-typc governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 715 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc singlc-platc-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.10, intermediate 3.13, high 4.15, reverse 1.80. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 176. OLIVER HART-PARR "ROW CROP," Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa; April 14 to 24, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto; Ensign Model "K" carburetor; Donaldson 2 - unit centrifugal and oily-fibrc-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-typc governor. Engine vertical. "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14 %", width » '," • f 1 ", 700 np - m - chassis: fol « wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Bore 7 ™ CC u- s i n f 1 =; plate - typc clutch - ** ted "Pee* 15 . mil &lt;* Per hour: low 2.60, intermediate 3.20, high 4.15, reverse 2.90. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. In the advertising literature submitted with tne specifications and application for test of this tractor we find the following claims arc not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit "B"— Folder A 135— "They do end wheel slippage" and "They do not slip." Exhibit "C"— Folder A 143— Same as above. Exhibit D —Folder 4 144— "Positive traction at the tiptoe wheels assures de - ii? 7 , evely ouncc o£ cn S&gt;n e power to the drawbar." Exhibit "F"— Folder A 146— 'Tney do not sup." Test No. 1 177. MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PURPOSE," The Masscy-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; May 5 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto; Zenith "94TO" carburetor; Masscy-Harris oil - ctfculatcd-over-wool-type air cleaner; Hercules fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, J"?JZ mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 654", rated speed 802 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc sinclc - rcvcrsc yl 2 5 C 0 ! SPCCdS&gt; "^ *** h ° UI '' '° W 2 ' 2 °' intermediate 320 &gt; hi 8 h 4-00, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. TeS ' N ?' "?• OLIVER HART-PARR (2-3 plow), Oliver Farm Equipment Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa; July 7 to 15, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto; Ensign "KZ" carburetor; Donaldson 2-unit "^T^^l. a . nd . oJ y- fibrc - t &gt;Pe air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine vertical I head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14 &gt;A", width 7 A .rated speed 726 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, mX* !? jas^ta tt Rated spccds&gt; miies pcr hour: iow 2 - 6 - inter - The^rw^^a'cTwS jS^S*" ~ * "" '° St and "« be - OctoS 2 N to 23 8 . 2 i93^ LETRAC 8M0&gt; CleVe ' and TfaCtOr C ° mpany&gt; Clevcland . OW°; Delco battery ignition system; two Scheblcr "HDX12" carburetors; Pomona-Vortox otl-spray-type ail -cleaner; Kingston centrifugal-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 24", width 15", rated speed 477 rpm. Chass*: tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, Bork 8c Beck single-plate clutch Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.75, intermediate 2.5, high 3.6, reverse 2 1 tJ&lt; C ° mmcnts: ( Mt " *= rated load drawbar test and before the maximum drawbar SS.^aTA . aUSt VCS W " C . 0Un d t° be leaking. The cylinder heads were removed, all of the valve seats reconditioned, and the valves ground. Because of a change in weather cond.tions, die S. A. E. No. 50 oil was drained from the transmission! differential, and crankcase at this time, and S. A. E. No. 30 was used in its plaaT </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 183. OLIVER-HART-PARR (3-5 plow), Oliver Farm Equipment Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa; October 13 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4" magneto; Ensign "K" carburetor; Donaldson 2-unit centrif - ugal and oily-fibrc-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16%", width &amp;%", rated speed 596 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Borg &amp; Beck single-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.23, intermediate 3.30. high 4.33, reverse 2.63. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 184. EAGLE "6A," Eagle Manufacturing Company, Appleton, Wisconsin; October 21 to November 1, 1930. American Bosch "U6" magneto; Zenith "96ATO" carburetor; Pomona-Vortox oil - spray-type air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal-type governor. Engine vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 625 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry double-plate - type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.50, intermediate 3.33, high 4.50, reverse 2.50. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 186. BATES STEEL MULE "35," Foote Bros. Gear and Machine Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; April 6 to 18, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto; Schebler "HDX" carburetor; Pomona-Vortox oil - spray-type air cleaner; Waukesha centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 9", rated speed 920 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry-plate - type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.90, intermediate 2.85, high 3.80, reverse 2.65. Comments: No repairs nor' adjustments. Test No. 187. BATES STEEL MULE "45," Foote Bros. Gear and Machine Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; April 8 to 28, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto; Schebler "HDX" carburetor; Pomona-Vortox oil - spray-type air cleaner; Waukesha centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 9", rated speed 920 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry double-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.92, intermediate 2.92, high 3.87, reverse 1.40. Comments: After 15 hours of operation a leak was discovered at the connection between the oil line and the pressure gauge. The connection was tightened and the leak stopped. Four quarts of oil had been added prior to this time. Test No. 189. ALLIS-CHALMERS "ALL CROP," Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; April 17 to May 13, 1931. Eisemann "GL4" magneto; Zenith "C5E" carburetor; Donaldson and own centrif - ugal and filter-type air cleaner; Continental centrifugal-type governor. Engine four - cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10", width 7!4", rated speed 1095 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Rockford dry-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.33, inter - mediate 3.33, high 5.00, reverse 2.66. Comments: After 25 hours of operation it was necessary to tighten the fan belt. {The belt tests had been completed.) Test No. 191. MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PURPOSE," The Masscy-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; May 22 to June 12, 1931. American Bosch "U4ED2" magneto; Zenith "TO94E" carburetor; own oil-circulatcd - ovcr-wool-typc air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 654", rated speed 802 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc plate- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.2, intermediate 3.2, high 4.0, * "• crsc j-.j. Comments: Just before starring the rated belt test, the key which holds the belt - pulley bevel gear to the power take-off shaft sheared off. The shaft, gear, and key were replaced with new parts. During the preliminary drawbar tests one of the dif - ferential brakes was found dragging and was adjusted at this time. During the 100 per cent intermediate maximum drawbar tests the connection on No. 3 spark plug was broken. A new plug was used in its place. The spark plug in No. 2 cylinder wai cleaned twice during the maximum drawbar tests. During the drawbar tests three lue bolts were lost and replaced by new ones. Test No. 192. BRADLEY "GENERAL PURPOSE," The Bradley Tractor Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; June 10 to 18, 1931. United American Bosch "U4ED4V3" magneto; Kingston "Z" carburetor; Pomona- Vortox oil-circulated-over-wool-type air cleaner; Waukesha centrifugal-type governor, fcngine four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 7", rated speed 798 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, en - closed gear drive, Borg &amp; Beck singlc-plate-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.50, third 3.00, fourth 4.50, reverse 1.50 and 2.00. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 193. ALLIS-CHALMERS "EK," Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; June 18 to 25, 1931. Eisemann "G4" magneto; Zenith "C6EV" carburetor; Donaldson and own centrif - ugal and oily-fibrc-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder « V^' i, j' , m n r tcd CTan kshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width 8/2 , rated speed 1,000 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive wersr^S g ' '^ dUtCh ' RatCd SPCedS&gt; mil " P " h ° Ur: low 2 - 50&gt; high 3&gt;25 ' Comments: During the preliminary drawbar runs the head gaskets on cylinders No. i and 4 were found to be leaking and were replaced. Test No. 194. McCORJUCK-DEERING INDUSTRIAL "20," International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois; July 20 to 27, 1931. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "C5FE" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 %", width 7", rated speed l\urrh P '^ t A Ja foUr ., wheels&gt; 2 drivers - enclosed S«r drive, .own single-plate-type revere 3^)0 P " - 2-50 ' " ltermediate 3.50, high 5.00, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Ju.y^o August g^ " 4W C ' CVeIand TraCt ° r C '-'- d ' Ohi °= Delco-Remy battery ignition; Tillotson "Y7A" carburetor; Pomona-Vortox wet-sumo vScT^ S^ Clean ," : H l rC K U 'f f ntri , fu ? al W" « ov " nor " En 8ine six-cylinder I'fi r,,A he **'™ umcd crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width S/z , rated speed 943 r.p.m. Chassu: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Borg &amp; Beck S5.Tf g h^4t t r^ U 2.28. Rated h0Ur: '° W 2 ' Q6 ' »'™e£ Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. T ° t ™°: 197 - MINNEAPOUS-MOLINE "UNIVERSAL" MODEL MT Min - "o^S^^r" Imp ' Cment C 0 ™^' Minneapolis, MinnesoU; September 30 unit A d^nfriftf 1 ," U '!f D - l V iu magnet °- : hebler " Tr " carburetor; Donaldson 2 - umt, dry, centnfugal and oily-fibre-t&gt;-pe air cleaner; own centrifugal-tvpe governor Engine Wcyhnder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise? bdt puHey diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 715 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 driven "n- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Tractor Tests dosed gear drive, Twin Disc singlc-platc-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 2.10, intermediate 3.13, high 4.15, reverse 1.80. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 198. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F 30," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October 9 to 23, 1931. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "K5" carburetor; own oil-washed wirc-fiher-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14%", width 7", rated speed 682 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own dry single-platc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.00, second 2.75, third 3.25, fourth, 3.75, reverse 2.50. Comments: The pin which holds the splined end of the steering rod in the splincd sleeve sheared off twice, once during the limber-up run and again during the ratcd-load drawbar test. Each time the pin was replaced by another. Test No. 199. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor, International Harvester Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; October 10 to 26, 1931. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "K5" carburetor; own oil-washed, wire-filtcr-typc air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1514", width 7", rated speed 682 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate, dry-disc-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: low 1.75, intermediate 2.75, high 3.75, reverse 2.00. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 200. ALLIS-CHALMERS MODEL "L," AUis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; March 17 to April 11, 1932. Eisemann "GV6" magneto; two Zenith "C6EV" carburetors; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 20", width 15", rated speed 580-1232 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - closed gear drive, own double-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.94, second 2.45, third 3.05, fourth 4.10, fifth 5.20, sixth 6.47, reverse 1.45-3.07. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test, the fuel flow was restricted by a flake of solder partially covering the outlet in the bottom of the supply tank. The obstruction was blown away from the outlet and the test completed. Test No. 201. CLETRAC "25," Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; April 9 to 30, 1932. Delco-Rcmy battery ignition, Model "643V"; Tillotson "Y8A" carburetor; Pomona- Vortox wet-sump and wirc-mesh-typc air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal -type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 614", rated speed 937 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long double-disc-typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.95, second 2.80, third 4.00, reverse 1.83. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 202. CLETRAC "15," Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; April 9 to May 4, 1932. Eisemann "GL4" magneto; Tillotson "P1B" carburetor; Vortox wet-sump and wire - mesh-typc air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10/4", width 614", rated speed 1042 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Borg &amp; Beck dry singlc-plale-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.95, second 2.80, third 4.00, reverse 1.83. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 203. CATERPILLAR "Twenty-five," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; May 16 to 23, 1932. Eisemann "GV4" magneto; Ensign "AeLc" carburetor; own, under Vortox patents, centrifugal, oil and matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 \ 11%", width 6!4", rated speed 836 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own dry single-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.8, second 2.6, third 3.6, reverse 2.0. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 204. CATERPILLAR "Fifty," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illin - ois; May 18 to June 11, 1932. Eiscmann "GV4" magneto; Ensign "Kc" carburetor; own, under Vortox patents, centrifugal, oil and matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13/4", width 10", rated speed 753 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own dry single-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.6, second 2.4, third 3.4, fourth 4.7, reverse 1.9. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests, a valve rod tube yoke was found to be loose. This was tightened. Test No. 210. McCORMICK-DEERING "W 30," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; July 26 to August 10, 1932. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "K5" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 %", width 7", rated speed 681 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, own dry-disc single-platc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second 3.25, third 3.75, reverse 2.75. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 211. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor "T 46," International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October 11 to 20, 1932. Robert Bosch "FU6BRS 540" magneto; Zenith "K5S" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1634", width 9", rated speed 603.8 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own dry-disc single-plate - typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.25; third 2.75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the cylinder head gasket was found to be leaking and was replaced with a new one. Test No. 212. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F-12," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; May 1 to 10, 1933. Own "E4A" magneto; own "A-10" carburetor; own oil-washed wirc-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12%", width 654", rated speed 800 rpm Chassis: three wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Rockford single-plate dry-disc - type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.00, third 3.75, i c &gt; crsc jl t£ j • ■ Comments: Before running the varying load belt tests, it was necessary to adjust the governor cross rod. ' IlluS Z™ 'to^^f " SEVENTY «" Tractor Company, Peoria, Eisemann "GV4" magneto; Ensign "Keb" carburetor; own, under Vortox patents, combmation centrifugal, oil and matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type^ governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15" width 11", rated speed 700 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, endowed gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour- first 1 7 second 2.3, third 2.7, fourth 3.1, fifth 3.7, sixth 5.0, reverse 1 7 and 2 7 , J hC cxhaust c val , ve s P" n S °n No. 2 cylinder failed at' the end of the - rated-load drawbar test after 51 hours of operation. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 214. CATERPILLAR "DIESEL FIFTY," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; May 17 to June 2, 1933. Own fuel system; Vortox combination centrifugal, oil and mattcd-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13%", width 10", rated speed 753 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.6, second 2.4, third 3.4, fourth 4.7, reverse 1.9. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 215. ALLIS-CHALMERS "K," AUis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Springfield Works, Springfield, Illinois; September 21 to October 4, 1933. Eisemann "GL4" magneto; Zenith "C6" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter - type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width S'A", rated speed 1050 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.08, second 3.10, third 4.50, reverse 2.39. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 216. ALLIS-CHALMERS "M," AUis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Springfield Works, Springfield, Illinois; September 23 to October 9, 1933. Eisemann "GL4" magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter - type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 8'A", rated speed 960 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.23, second 3.20, third 4.15, fourth 5.82, reverse 2.55. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 218. CATERPILLAR "DIESEL SEVENTY-FIVE," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; October 10 to 31, 1933. Own fuel system; Vortox combination centrifugal, oil and matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14 7/16", width 13", rated speed 820 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7, second 2.3, third 2.7, fourth 3.1, fifth 3.7, sixth 5.0, reverse 1.7 and 2.7. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 219. MASSEY-HARRIS "3-4 PLOW," The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; October 24 to November 10, 1933. American Bosch "U4ED4" magneto; Kingston "L-3-L" carburetor; own oil-circu - lated-ovcr-wool-type air cleaner; Kingston centrifugal-type governor. Engine four - cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 19", width 7Vt", rated speed 525 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry singlc-plate-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second 3.25; third 4.00, reverse 2.50. Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the spark plug in No. 1 cylinder was replaced with a new one. Test No. 220. McCORMICK-DEERING FARM ALL "F-12" (Kerosene), Interna - tional Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 1 to 16, 1933. Own "F-4" magneto; own "A-10" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12 Vt" , width 6%", rated speed 800 r.p.m. Chassis: three wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Rockford single-plate dry-disc - typc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.00, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. Comments: During the belt tests the spark plug in No. 3 cylinder was replaced with a new one. On the rated-load drawbar test a bolt connecting the drawbar to the drawbar-adjusting plate was lost out. This was replaced. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 CnJT N r^ L FARMALL "F-20," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; April 3 to 16, 1934. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filtcr-typc air rr^Th T! 1 ee ** n *°* al ?n* governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft : leqgthwise; belt pulley diameter 14", width 654", rated speed 654 r P m SlST* S U&gt; 2 .. dAvm ! cnclosed Bear 'drive, own single-plate dry-disc-type" rivSe 275 ' m " "" h ° Ur: first 2 - 25 ' sccond 275 ' third 3 - 25 ' f °"« h 3 75, Comments: No repairs nor- adjustments. T™V NO ' 22i v!?* 1 ? D x EERE GENERAL PURPOSE MODEL "A," John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; April 19 to 27 1934 ..,n7?n» an M S " M T!," D - RV | A " ma S n «°: Wheeler-Shebler "DLTX-8" carburetor; Vortox 2071D oil-washed wire-fi ter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder honamteJ, "I" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise" bd? pulley diam^er doirf I ' H ld 7/s • j? ted s P= ed 9 75 r.p.m. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, en- milcs " W: first 2-33 - „. C iP" I i ments = Durln 5 *&lt;= drawbar »»t» Kr^c leaked from the left end of the rear aiarai^risss sisryr^ connection he - me loose and wat 5 }?S " Chaln - &gt;^«^ tvo/afr^n^K"" 0 ; 4 " m^fo- Zcmth "124'A TO" carburetor; United oil-bath - typc air cleaner, Kingston centnfugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" sr^d U70 r!f m Cr^ ' engthw ,. ise i M * P ull =y d i=«"«=r 9", width 6 14", rated Phtetjnc cS " £rT ' "T" W . eClS&gt; 2 u^" 5 ' enC ' 0Sed gear drivc &gt; Rockford d^ - fou"thT 9 .25 U ;«; e S 2^0.^ ' m " h ° Ur: fim 2 - 50&gt; SCC ° nd 3 - 50 ' thW 4 -75. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Operating Maximum Load Tests Horsepower Drawbarpull Speed driv^wheels Pounds M.p.h. Percent STEEL WHEELS \ 2 4 H 1921 2.51 H35 sJS:::::: 'Z lil ™* y84 5.08 8.96 RUBBER TIRES* 17.59 }S5 3.07 15.92 i9.i7 ::::::::::::::: ! gJ Jif 13^ More detailed information is available in the test report. Julv T r2 t to°20 22 J934 CATERWLLAR " R ' 5 '" Cata^ Uat Tractor PeorU, Illinois; governor. Engme four-cylmder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lenSwhe; beh 1 Not recommended for iteel wheels. weight per wheel ™ limited ,o 500 pound,. Three wheel weight, per wheel we« </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Tractor Tests pulley diameter 12", width 8 54", rated speed 950 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer type, en - closed gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.9, second 2.8, third 3.6, fourth 5.1, reverse 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 225. CATERPILLAR "R-2," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; September 24 to October 16, 1934. Eisemann "CT4" magneto; Zenith "K.5A" carburetor; own, under Vortox patent, combination centrifugal, oil-and-matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10H", width 6'/z", rated speed 950 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - closed gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.6, third 3.6, reverse 2.1. Comments: Because of excessive friction in the tracks they were replaced by new ones of same specifications before the official drawbar tests were run. Test No. 226. CATERPILLAR "TWENTY-TWO" (Distillate), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; September 25 to October 9, 1934. Eisemann "CT4" magneto; Zenith "K5A" carburetor; own, under Vortox patents, combination centrifugal, oil-and-matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1054", width 654", rated speed 950 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - closed gear drive, own single-plate, dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.6, third 3.6, reverse 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 227. CATERPILLAR "R 3," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; September 26 to October 15, 1934. Eisemann "CT4" magneto; Ensign "Ke" carburetor; own, under Vortox patent, combination centrifugal, oil-and-matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1154", width 654", rated speed 836 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - closed gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.8, second 2.6, third 3.6, reverse 2.0. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 228. CATERPILLAR "TWENTY-TWO" (Gasoline), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; October 17 to 30, 1934. Eisemann "CT-4" magneto; Zenith "K5A" carburetor; own, under Vortox patent, combination centrifugal, oil-and-matted-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1054", width 654", rated speed 950 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - closed gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.6, third 3.6, reverse 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 229. McCORMICK-DEERING "W 12" (Kerosene), International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October 23 to November 9, 1934. Own "F-4" magneto; own "A-10" carburetor; own oil-washed-wire-filtcr-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1354", width 654", rated speed 787 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Rockford single-plate dry-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 2.75, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 230. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor "T-40 Diesel," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October 25 to November 13, 1934. Own "P 40" fuel system; own oil-washed-wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrif - ugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16J4", width 9", rated speed 591 r.p.m. Chassis: </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.25, third 2.75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 231. McCORMICK-DEERING "W-12" (Gasoline), International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 13 to 16, 1934. Own "F4" magneto; own "A-10" carburetor; own oil-washed-wire-filtcr-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13 'A", width 6!4", rated speed 787 r.pjn. Chassis: four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, Rockford single-plate dry-disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 2.75, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. Comments: At the end of the rated load drawbar test the manifold bolt, which holds the choke rod bracket, was found to be loose. Test No. 232. JOHN DEERE GENERAL PURPOSE "B," John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; November 15, 1934 to April 19, 1935. Fairbanks-Morse "DRV-2B" magneto; Wheelcr-Scheblcr "DLTX-10" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed, wire-filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder horizontal, "I" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 10%", width 6", rated speed 1150 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; own, disc-type clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.33, third 4.75, fourth 6.75, reverse 3.75. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 233. M-M TWIN CITY "JT," Minneapolis-Molinc Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; April 17 to 29, 1935. Fairbanks-Morse "RV-4" magneto; Zenith "124-14 T" carburetor; Donaldson oil - washed, wire-filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "F" head, mounted crankshaft lengdiwise; belt pulley diameter 15%", width 6'A", rated speed 730 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc gear-type, single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.2, sec - ond 2.65, third 3.13, fourth 4.57; fifth 3 12.1, reverse 1.19. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 234. PLANET JR. GARDEN TRACTOR, S. L. Allen and Company, Incorporated, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; June 5 to June 19, 1935. Eisemann "71-F" flywheel-type magneto; Tillotson "M-20-A" carburetor; Air Maze oiled-screen air cleaner; no governor. Engine one-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 3 3 A", width VA" , rated speed 1800 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear and open roller chain drive; Twin Disc dry-plate, disc clutch. Ground speed varied by changing speed of motor with hand throttle. Comments: After the belt tests and before the drawbar tests were run, the cylinder - head cap screws were tightened. During the maximum drawbar tests, the fuel line became clogged and was cleaned. Test No. 235. CLETRAC "40" DIESEL, The Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleve - land, Ohio; June 13 to 24, 1935. American Bosch "APE6B70 A300S91" fuel system; Vortox oil-washed, wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengdiwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width 11", rated speed 884 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; Long two-plate, dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 1.8, second 3.0, third 4.3, reverse 2.2. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 236. JOHN DEERE "D", John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa- June 26 to July 2, 1935. • Not recommended for steel wheels. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Tractor Tests Splitdorf "246 T" magneto; Scheblcr "DLTX6" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed, screen-filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder horizontal, "I" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 13W, width 814", rated speed 900 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive; own, double-disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.5, second 3.5, third 5, reverse 2. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 237. ALLIS-CHALMERS "U", Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; July 15 to August 5, 1935. Scintilla-Bendix "C-4" magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed, wire - filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10", width IVi", rated speed 1094 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Kockford single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.33, third 5.0, fourth 10.0, 4 reverse 2.67. Comments: On the limber-up run, it was found that of the two bolts which hold the left fender to the supporting saddle on the axle housing, one was lost and the other loose and worn. Both bolts were replaced. On the maximum tests (steel), one of the same two bolts on the right fender was broken and the other loose. One was replaced and the other tightened. On the maximum drawbar tests (steel) it was observed that the brazed connection between the exhaust pipe and the exhaust pipe flange was broken. Operating Maximum Load Tests Slip on Horsepower Drawbar pull Speed drive wheels Founds M.p.fi. Per cent STEEL WHEELS 23.78 3428 2.60 9.62 23.06 2415 3.58 14.57 19.58 1333 5.51 12.86 RUBBER TIRES • 13.40 2389 2.11 20.72 20.49 2452 3.13 15.07 26.64 2179 4.59 18.31 30.07 1037 10.87 2.84 More detailed information is available in test report. Test No. 238. ALLIS-CHALMERS "UC", Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Com - pany, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; July 16 to August 8, 1935. Bcndix-Scintilln "C-4" magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor: Vortox oil-washed, wire - filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10", width 7Vi", rated speed 1094 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.33, third 5.00, fourth 10.00, 4 reverse 2.67. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests on rubber tires, gear grease began to leak from the final drive. This continued to the end of the test (15 hours). Over the same period of time, grease leaked through the seal around the steering-gear worm shaft. •Not recommended for iteel wheels. • Additional weight per wheel was limited to 500 pounds. Three wheel weights per wheel were used. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 296 Operating Maximum Load Tests Horsepower Drawbarpull Speed dnveXels Pounds M.p.h. Percent STEEL WHEELS 22:5?:::::::: .;;: I'll lf A 6.87 ,07c ■'l/o 3.86 415 1875 ; H78 5.92 278 RUBBER TIRES « JtR:-:;:::::::: gg jg 17.20 28.-J4 ,„? |06 16.49 28.85 :::::•::: ::::;:: 2 jg ,;•;* More detailed information is avalable in test report ' 2 ' 10 Spri^,timnokri S sfr^n S 35" M " A1HS - Chal — Manufacturin, Company, Comments: No repairs or adjustments. p«.sr'i,£ l! f 4 i«s^'^f ,s? SEl for "' c ""' m " t »°» °»».n,. mini" ISite "JT^ " F ° RIV " C ""' i "" T '«»' tak. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. jm2fa&amp;£ 18^2?^? " F ° RTy "' d "* Peoria, </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Tractor Tests Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 8 l A", rated speed 1000 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear; drive; own, single-plate, dry clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.9, third 3.8, fourth 5.4, reverse 2.2. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 246. McCORMICK-DEERING "WD-40", International Harvester Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; September 23 to 27, 1935. Own, "F-4" magneto (for starting only); own, "R" (modified) carburetor (for starting only); Donaldson combination oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengdiwise; belt pulley diameter 16%", width 9", rated speed 588 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; own, single - plate, dry disc clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.6, second 3.4, third 3.9, reverse 2.4 Test No. 247. M-M TWIN CITY "KTA", Minneapolis-Moline Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; October 2 to 9, 1935. American Bosch "U4" magneto; Schebler "TTX-15" carburetor; Donaldson combin - ation oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type gov - ernor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.1, second 3.1, third 4.1, reverse 1.8. Comments: After the belt tests were begun it was observed that the pulley shaft housing and bearing were cracked. A new pulley unit was installed and all data shown in this report were taken after the replacement was made. The air cleaner stack broke off during the preliminary drawbar tests. This was repaired by welding. The right hand tie-rod bolt started to work out during the rated load drawbar test. The cotter key which normally holds the bolt in place was lost. The bolt was put into proper position and keyed. Test No. 248. M-M TWIN CITY "MTA", Minneapolis-Moline Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; October 2 to 17, 1935. American Bosch "U4" magneto; Schebler "TTX 15" carburetor; Donaldson com - bination oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis: four wheels, two drivers, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate clutch. Rated speeds, miles per hour: first 2.1, second 3.1, third 4.1, reverse 1.8. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. [5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>