<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00017.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00017.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirteenth Annual Report of the Department of Banking, Showing the Condition of the Building and Loan Associations of Nebraska For the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1905.  Submitted to the Governor and the State Banking Board September 20, 1905.</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Department of Banking, Show ing the Condition of the Building and Loan Associations of Nebraska For the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1905. Submitted to the Governor and the State Banking 191 ILL1NS Pm\ Board September 20, 1905. By E. ROYSK. Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OK THE ! K OK NEBRASKA UOAH1) HON. K M SEARLE, JR HON\ I'KTKK MORTENSEN MORRIS BROWN Auditor of Public Accounts ami l'r Me I Attorn E KOYSE ADDISON WAI I MAIDK HOGE Chief ( EXAMINERS </seg>
            <seg id="p003">IK NKHIEASKA. Dk.I'AKTMKNT UK Ba N K Lincoln, September 80 To Hit y, John II. Mickey, G bradca, an E. M. - Peter M Banking Board of tht stnl, of \ tQnrrLuna: — Iu compliance with section 3a of chapter 8 of Compiled Statutes of the State of Nebraska for 1903 reijuir - the Secretary of the State Banking Board to make to the ernor and State Banking Board annual reports, I have the &gt;r to submit herewith the thirteenth annual report of the de - ment of banking for the period beginning July 1, 11)04, and ng .lune 30, 1 i»05, showing the condition of the building and nations of the state of Nebraska at the close of bu.si i 30, 1005, compiled from annual rep &gt;rts of the several building and loan associations submitted to the State Banking rd, in accordance with the provisions of the bniiding and loan net. approved April 4, l,s'J9. Tabulated statements, detailed re Is, and such information and comments touching this report i deemed beneficial will be found on the following pa. Very respectfully e. i: </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 STATEMENT HAI. Nl MBEK Or ASSOCIATIONS, XIMBEKOK SHIKE-S IN VOMM AM) TOTAL A-KI-. KKOM 1802. THE KIKST VEAK THAT ALTHKNTK KE'-OKT - « KKK MADt. DOWa TO THE I'KESENT TIME. tYEAR YEAR " &lt;&gt;K SHAKES TOTAL ass'ks in roaci 71 45.0121 H.MS.H M 61. 964.1 8,65.'i M 71.231* vOOl ai 70.015 3.Sf_&gt;H.77- 87 71 45.012i H.M3.H ''-'■'- M 61.964.1 8.6:.' r,4.891| 3,771.833 f&gt;3 68 tt.tMi 8,554 88 ti7."&gt;H?i X 554 788 08 MM '14 79.»7.'i I.4S8 "•'•' . •» Mil. 492 3]3,«!7H1 H7 105.lii5 j 3!(!97.35(i Oti ■ IM 4.314.744 8ti '' 15.1 SMS.4MM </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SUMMARIES COMPILED FROM THE AH N UAL REPORTS OK BUILDING AND tl.OAN ASSOCIATIONS FOR THE YEARS FROM 1892, THE FIRST YEAR REPORTS WERE RECEIVED. TO 1905 INCLUSIVE, SHOWING THE TOTALS OF ALL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS IN THE STATE FOR THE YEARS AB STATED </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BITILIIING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS SUMMARY OK THE CONDITION OK THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS or the STATE OK NEBRASKA On the 81st day of December, 1*92 (JMttl Loans wcured by stock of mnriitiou Liabilities ■k paid up mis paid </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 MMMARY OK SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT - RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1892 Receipt!* Balance on hand December 31, 1*01 161,250 26 176.:.. io.«»9 km 197.40tt 14 M.M6 57 Loans repaid Other receipts Tota *l,(«4,tW0 IS Expenditures •■xpen Withilrawali »l.(«4,«00 81 Total Kecapitulatiou Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares issued during year 14 Number of shares matured, withdrawn and cat. Number of shares in force at this date. s= Other expenditures :i hand </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 SI'.MMARV or the -tatkmext &lt;&gt;k the BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK TIIK STATE OK NEBRASKA On the 30 h ilay o! Ih'i'emliei Assets iiirtgaffe loan- R»^l estate -es aud la&gt; t i ciimcrated above J'otal 96 83 Liabilities ■ k paid up i pai&lt; 443. 07» 74 511.4 BI.M1 86 • st received </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT - RECEIPTS EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDINC DECEMBER 30. 1893. Receipts Balance on band December 31. 18M iTU.059 08 683,74 21&amp; i : Loans repaid.. Other receipts Total Expenditures *T41 • 41 U Other expense Withdrawals in hand laneous expenditures in.it-; Total UMTULATJ.ON OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS F'JR THE YEAR IMS Elier of shares in force at last report, bar of shares issued during current year her of shares matured, withdrawn and canceled l&gt;er of shares in force at this date. . Keeapit illation Bher of associations in force December 31 brr «&gt;f associations discontinued during year. . &lt;iations during i associations in forc&lt; I </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 SUMMARY Or THK CONDITION OK THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS &lt;&gt;K TUt STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 31st tiay of December. 1*94 Ansel. s ■iinrtffajre loan »!(»&lt;! by stuck of association 271. (J 1 IT . lea and tav rer 180.4 - 70. li 4G3.605 (Ml Total • Mil 31 l.ial&gt;iliti&lt;-&gt; k paid up urns paid «i,694 411. li- ler liabilities 601.1' </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 SI MM\R\ OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT — RECEIPT"" AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 81, ism Balance on band December 31, 1898 IS Loans repaid Other receipts Total SK Total RECAPITUL4T1ON OF SHARK TRANSAt 1 IONS FOR THE YEAR KNUING DECKMBkK 31. 1MI4 Nwaber of shares in force at las' Niiml&gt;erof shares issued tlurinir year . . Bhvi vi Baat^ i»nnu uuim^ JCW lierot shares matured, withdrawn, and canceled ber of shares in force at this dad Kecapi tulatiou Iljer of associations in force December 31, 1S93 ber of associations discontinued during year, her of new associations during year ber of associations in force December 81, 18M Kr ixpiMi- drawals r expenditures on hand </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Bl'II.I \ ASSOCIATION? S! MMARV Of THE CONDITION OF BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the IM day of December. 1896. ASBPtH nge loans 267 .54 ISO.MI 20 Loan- secured by stock asMjiialioi^ and taxes paid I Total $8.»'i» Liabilitie» k paid up iius paid. $2,744 418 83 188.048*58 E'«t received collected. . . . her liabilities 505. 1H2 46 OH M MM) U8.i 19 13.929. TT- J7 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 tMMAKY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, If WllTLVnON OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDINt; DECEMBER 81, 1805 Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares issued during year M,M44 Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and canceled Number of shares in force at this date. .. ... 70.615 Recapitulation Number of associations in force December 31, 1894 . . .86 Number of associations discontinued during the year Number of new associations during the year 8 Number of associations in force December 31, 18W Receipts Balance on band December 31. 1 S '.M Loans repaid . . Other receipts -&gt;5CI '. Total ..$1,445,26 Kxpeuditures Salarie Other expen- - Withdrawal- Other expenditure- Casli on hand Total . ..$1,44 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS or nit I E OK SKBKA&lt;KA On ihf :il-t day ■■! DecfinUr \ss»&gt;ts Kfrom sharrholdtTs. d taxes paiil r assets Total Liabilities Duel paid - iicearm-ii ■ uilinff reserve fund ts aj&gt;|Mirt, mied to shares in force shareholders on incomplete loans JO 47 Other liabilities Total •8.771.S33 E3 Sl'MMAKY ' H- THE O ' V 1 &gt;1T1&lt;J\ • &gt;h (Ml ' Ktire </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 81, 1896. Receipts Balance on hand December 31, 18M 216&gt;2 tS 7IC&gt;1 04 repaid . Other receipts .ml «1,4»M Kxpenditure.s Br expi dnwtl, due: tirawals. earnings red stock, di red stock, earning on hand ler of shares in force at last report Dtjemi oani maile for payment of homestead inortga in current year Number of shares issued during eu vear Number of shares withdrawn and car I miring current y ;it Kif loans made for building purposes during current l&gt;er of shuicholders Supplemental Kepnrt zatior BB of stock issued &gt;ince organization. . ber of shares of stock withdrawn and can a Blier of mortgages in process of foreclosure int of mortga|r*g in procos of forecloanre mprovenients a 4.4l-»).y«9 1(1 Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the asso. i.ition ollateral tecurity ■-'.444.115 0t( -Ul 4u Value of other real estate held by tl associate Shares Statement B number of series issued number of shares issued number of sh res withdrawn number of shares loaned on. . number of sliares outstanding Keen pit illation Number of associations in force I), eember 31, 1895 ■-] Number of associations discontinued during year lu Number of new associations during year Number of association in force December 81, 1896 » Total APITULATION OF SHVUK TRANSACTIONS FOB THK YKAH END IN(i UECEMBKK 31. 16 KImt of shwM luaiured dorioK cu her uf •tuuta in Force at ill ber of loan- made for Daymen! .V&gt; of shares of stock issued since nrira 1111.7 Kmt &lt;&gt;i mnrtfnW'-x i» prooe** 01 lorecloson I appraised value of real estate and impi uritv </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SUMMARY OK lilt CONDITION OF Tilt (IK THE STATE OK NEBRASKA On the 3Nt day of December, I Assets mortgage loans ■ mortgage loans in process of foreclosure. Furniture and fixtures ■■nsea and taxes paid from shareholders. . r asset* Total Liabilities Dues paid Premiums unearned. is undivided including reserve fund. Profits apportioned to shares in force. Due shareholders on incomplete loans 7.854 74 Other liabilities 463. -'00 49 854 74 Otter liabilities. Bl'ILDINCV AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Balance on hand December 31, 1896 $55,717 16 Dues 786.1- Interest 280.142*1 Fines 7.91H 17 Loans repaid 427.440 7? Other receipts 128,704 86 Total $1,631 : Expenditures Loans . . $607. Salaries 26.248 91 Other expense* 150 : Withdrawals, dues 400 i Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Maturt d stuck, earnings 95.'." on hand Total $l,t&gt;31 REl AI'ITILATION OK SHARK TRANSACTIONS KOR THE YEAK ENDING DECEMBER 81 Number of shares in force at Ia9t report U.5M1 Number of shares matured during the current year Number of loans in force at this date ■ of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages dur ing fiscal year Number of shares issued during current year 81.144J I shares withdrawn and canceled during current year. .le tor building purposes during current year. . . Number of shareholders Supplemental Report organization . . . series of stock iwaed since organization ... Niiinl&gt;er ol indrawn a Number of mortgage Amount of mm $76,5" ■i. appraised value of real estate and improvements held M lecurity Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security 2 ■as collateral security - le of oilier real estate held by i it ions 1*3. 114 2 Shares Statement Total number of series issued i&gt;44 number of shares issued . . 11.'. Total nnmlier of shsres withdrawn number of shares loaned on Total number of shares outstanding Recapitulation Num!&gt;er of associations in force December 31. 1896 Number of associations discontinued during year ft Nambes of Dew ass ciations during year Number of associations in force December 81, 1891 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 SUMMARY UK TIIK CIIMMTIIIN &lt;l OF THK CONDITION OK THE UI T ILD1NG AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS BUILDING AND LOAN i M FBI ut rut. ! K OK NKBKASKA WK OF NEBRJ On the Hist day of I On the 31st day of Decent Iwr. 180* A«H«M * Assets oans in process of ind fixtures from shareholders. . 4* 47.4K4 114.047 04 Ti»t»l Liabilities l*J st(K-k paid up I2.9H6.863 53 Profits undivided, including reserve fund 330.247 31 urn* unearned 47.517 51 Due share: incomplete loans . . 19.475 18 Advance payments 5.09.) 44 Matured stock unpaid 110 120 »&gt;6 Bills payable 5.550 00 Otuer liabilities 3,85*48 •8,438.728 11 Total . . </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 BUILDING ANI&gt; LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL VKAU ENDING DECEMBER 31, It Receipt* Balance on hand December 31. - Inters Loans repaid 1:7 Other receipts Total . Expenditures Loans. .. 1757.104 07 Salaries . . Withdrawals. dOM Matured stock, duel Matured stock, earning ■ii hand. Hi Total KECAITJTL.AT1ON OK SIIAKK TRANSACTIONS FOR THE 1 ENDING 1)K( EMHER 31 ier of shares in force at last report NuiuIht of shares matured during current year ■&lt;r ol shares issued during current year .... ... M.M04 Numl&gt;erof shares withdrawn and caofled during current year her of shares in force at this date ■abet of loans for payment of homestead mortgages during current year • ;*»r» current year f loans made for building purposes during current year . . ier of shareholders Supplemental Report Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure. . . . Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure *iil,461 &gt;*4 Total appraised value of real estate and improvements held as •ecarity 5,188.347 10 Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security ■collateral security 2.U2tt.R.S.'&gt; 00 ue of other real estate held by the associations 163,54* 86 Recapitulation Number of associations in force December 81, 1HU7 . . .68 Number of associations discontinued during year ... 4 Number of associations in force December 31, 18a- . . .64 4 Number of associations in force December 31, 1808. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 BCILOIIO AMI LOAN ASSOCIATIONS SUMMARY OF THE COSDITION OK THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS oh THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. A. D. 1899 Assets inortgaf?? loan Hint mortfiape loans in process of f&lt; ireclosuro 50 165,094 95 Furniture and lixmres M Kand taxes jiaiH from sharetiol'i ToU •8,882,781 fi Liabilities :al stock paid «p . . . I2.8OX.310 44 - undivided, including reserve fund . . . S79.1SJ Premiums unt-ariji-il 45. 3M SB Due shareholders *&gt;n incomplete loans tl.TS Advance payments' 24.K31 1* Other liabilities. 4. 617 5t Matured *t&lt;xk unpaid 78.0 payable 9.7' </seg>
            <seg id="p021">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 21 RKCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR I HE SIX MONTHS Receipts Balance on hand December 31, 1893 Interest Loans repaid. . Other receipts. 2S9 4(14 76 169.9»4 74 Total Expeuditures I iirios . Other expenses Withdrawals, du&lt; Withdrawals, earnings. Matured stock, dues. . . . Matured stock, earnings Cash on hand Total Recapitulation Bber of associations in force at tli her of shares in force at this i)at&gt; Number of shareholders ENDING JUNE 30, 18M S 135.1; 573 - 123.9H-, « 2 874 o» *1. ■-".•) </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 SUMMARY OK T1IK CONDITION OF THE Bl'ILDINd AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA \-». ture anil tixtur . l.ial.iliti.-&gt; 1 ind... |irnti ■ on incompleti ■ Aih a luiun On the 30tli day of Juue, A. L). 11KMI "i'tt;a^e loans in prooett of furec - Real estate Kqnent ••uiiums, and lin. d taxes pai! </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1900 Balance on hand July 1 tM inning stock) Dues (full paid stock) Interest 1'reiimini Membership and transfer fee; repaid B estate sale; &gt; Other receipt Total Kxpenrtitures iiissioni Other expen I red stock, earnings paid stiK'k. dues paid stock, earning ou hand pavab rota SHARES STATEMEX I I shares in force at this di ■ tharea matured during Sscal year. . . . res withdrawn during fiscal year. I running stock in force at this dati ; lharei of full paid stock in force at this date 4.441 ■ -hares loaned on I -hares subject to cancellation for non-payn Withdrawals, dues Withdn Matured stock, due Kf shares issued since organizutio f &gt;liare&gt; issued daring tiseal year shares on whh'li ilnca suv liiliiKjuent . . </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 SUMMARY Of THK CONDITION OK THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK THE STATE UK NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. A. I) 1901 Asuets mortgage loans 641.45 tt.4M.ai - of foreclosure. .Stock loans ita.6ii.rn I1O.M0 47 Real estate I nire and fixtures 2.849 11 l»li.&gt;t»0 25 33.019 00 tl.Stt 18 l&gt;elinqnent interest, premiums and tine: Kxpenses and taxes paid . . ranee paid 164.01383 Total Liabilities «ck runuiug $3,391 ' ■aid stock ........ Reserve fund Advance du^s Advance interest and premiums Hills payable r liabilities *4, 8M.T-J4.x6 K profit- 184,1 i &gt;lders od iucomplei. |8.( unearned . </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BUILDING AND LOAN A9SOCI ATK &gt;S~ 25 5 RECEI1TS AND EXPENITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1901 Receipt* D&amp;I&amp;DCt* OD Il&amp;DQ Ullly 1, ltfOO Dues (running stock) t 106 - 1.31* full paid stock) m si Premiums 4.60(1.41 Kbership and transfer fees s repaid 4.50*1.14 Other receipt Total 12.851 Expenditures Salaries Com mission T OH II Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings . . ;red stock, dues .red stock, earniugs. Foil paid stock, dues . . . Full paid stock, earnings on hand Bill&gt; payable Total •2 951 SHARES STATEMENT ! shares in force at this date 1 Bf shares issued since organization f shares issued during fiscal year f shares ni itureil flu ring tiscal year . . . I shares withdrawn during tiscal year f shares of running stock in force at this date ' shares of full paid stock in force at this date. . . . shares loaned on I shures on which dues are delinquent ■ thttW subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues ■ estate sales s </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS ST. M MARY O» THE CONDITION OF THF BIILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK Tllh On the Wth &lt;iav ol June. A. 1) 1908 Assets mortgage loans *4 lure and fiztnrc t,423 premiums and fine* ToU Liabilities 4S.II41 7.082.44 l.T.il 89 STATK OF NEBRASKA ' loans in p Real estate 41 K70.W 1 1 stock ruiniini; incomplete loans lied .... Advance &lt;iues : ami premium- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 FUILDING AND \TI&lt;&gt;!«- RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903 Receipts Balance on hand July 1 1901.. - (running stock) Dins (full paid stock Interest 818. 1T8 VI p™...* :« !KKJ ;» n.96k HO 8.849 ',i Membership and transfer fe repaid f&gt;96,294 92 B estate sa • I7.07S 7* 5 081 4-"i Other receipts 1'OU • r v\\&gt;t Withdrawals, due Matured stock, du Matured stock, earning •S; in liab • SHARKS STATKMKNI r&gt;s of running stock in force at this dat I full paid stock in force at thN dat i cancellation for non-payment of du 370.41H 10 *3 6«0.7?l Hi Expenditures Withdrawals, earnii I of shares iu forte at this date nf »barei issued since organization of pbarrf issued durinif tiseal year, of shares matured during ti.-.a! nf shares withdrawn during liscal yea 'laneil ■i which liiu". are delinqu </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 BCILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS SUMMARY OK THE COKDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATIC OK NKBKASKA On the 80th day of June. 1903 AsitetH •rtjrage luans in process of fore' uire and stationery Delinquent interest premiums and tines .-es and taxes paid Total MubiiitieH Capital stock running (Dues and dividends Full pai&lt;l stock. •■ fund I'uilivided protits B shareholders on incomplete loans itoat* unearned Advance dues. -t and premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1903 Receipts Balance on hand June 1, 1902 f 176,776.22 Dues, (running stock) 1.773,242 23 Dues, (full paid itock) 340.lls.99 Interest 358. * Premiums 39.500.68 Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid 884,888.06 Real estate sales Other receipts Total $3,90-' Expenditures Salariei Commission M.Tll.-&gt; 4» Other expenses 18.070 ko Withdraw als. dues Withdrawals, earnings.. Matured stock, due - red stock., earning Full paid stock. due- Full paid stock, earnings &lt; a»h on hand 144 428.88 -Ul.W Oilier expenditures Tota SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT I shares in force at this date ... f shares issued since organization ■ of shares issued during BmmI year. .... of shares matured during fiscal year .... A shares withdrawn during fiscal year ... No of shares of running stock in force at this date 114.47* f full paid stock in force at this date f shares loaned on • shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues. . utii; No. of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 'J08 amount of same. No. 'Jon. No. of mortgages in process of foreclo gate amount of same. No. 48 No. of mortgages in process of foreck lure, and the aggre - ... t-U. ure. and the aggre- gate amount of same. No. 48 124.154.63 f borrowing stockholders ti I borrowing stockholders No of non-borrowing stockholders. . . No of non-borrowing stockholder ■•••• No. of minors holding stock in the As No. of minors holding stock in the A lOOiatlOn charged borrowers lociation Average rate per cent of interest during fiscal year Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year I Average rate per cent of dividends d&lt; c Average rate per cent of dividends d- c ared during fiscal year ared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during tiscal year loTf^months 8.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 BriLUlNU AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS SUMMARY Of T11K &lt; ONDITION OK THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS I &gt;K T1IK STATE OF NEBRASKA On the Nth day of June. 1904 Assets ?age loan *s of foreclotun ■_»; 227 iture and stationery K5-J.12 20O.2sG.02 H 121.78 J4 7M 48 116,122 47 lucnt interest, premiami iud taxes paid Total 350.40 Liabilities il stock running. I Dues and dividends t4.851.576.89 paid stock K«3 S31 13 refund ,.. uao'sii 144. 3£&gt;. 60 Undivided pron'ts lU1.0i:-i.08 Kshareboldera on incomplete loan» ...... 85 485 *9 liums unearned ou aio , r. 2u.933.ir&gt; Advance dues Auvanceaues ... 10 627.15 Advance interest and premiums 1457 70 1.457 70 other liabilities ;... :.::;:::;;;;;:;;;; Total •6,217,350 4U </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAr EN I)IN(i JUNE 30. 1W04 Receipt!* Balance on hand July 1, 1938 Balance on hand July 1, 1933 Dues running stock i. 9 217.20 80 Dues running stock i Dues (full paid stock) . . K'full paid stock ■st Interest -ti: 447. 1 - Premiums 45, ti 5.14 Premiuuis. - 5.(i Membership and transfer fees BiiiTship and transfer fees s repaid Loans repaid 1,115 " Real estate sales. : receipts. Total. I Real estate sales Other receipts 1'oUl *4.4i-.M.» Expenditures Expenditures Loans a; Salarie- 1(51.47 54.161.47 CommU 1 -xiK'nse: niasioiu. . . Withdrawal* dues . . Withdrawals, due: Withdrawals, earning* 5] Idrawals. earnings, red stock, imm -:ock, earnian&gt;. paid stock. dOM . . . . paid stock, earnings on hand Matured stock, dues :i • Matured stock, earning- J4 84.824.SI Full paid stock. dOM Full paid stock, earnings on band Other expeudituii - Total. SUPPLEMENTAL STATKMKX I I :it this -date Other expeuditun 1'ota SliTLKMKNTAl STATEMENT tome at this -date organization organization luring fiscal vear Miiiiitr Bsoal tear. . . . I share* matured during fiscal year ■ of shares withdraw* during fiscal year. of shares of runninig stock in force at this date I shares of full paid stock in force at this date f shares loaned on - i which dues are delinquent I shar •■* subject to cancellation for non-payment of due- No, of mortgage! subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate am. unit of same. No. 224 $147. • f mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 39 ... .... gy No. of borrowing Stockholders 10 198 No. of non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the Association M ■rage rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year (H Average rate per cent of dividends during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured daring fiscal year 103 months No. of loans made for building purposes during year 1.061 No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 SUMMARY &lt;&gt;h THE CONDITION OV THE FIFTY SINK BFILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK THE Reporting oil the 3(&gt;tli day of June 1905 •aid stock . 1,134.813 14 e fuiui ......7.7" !.'.'.*.". .'.'.'.'.'. 'nt.m lity.TTti nare holders on incomplete loans ]4\Vi91 172.344 W Other liabilities I7.soa.an 4- STATE OK NKBRASKA Bnare holders on incomplete loans 14S.U91 7S» nuns unearned '.'."..'. 28*244 (Ki n-e dm j - ; )M - -,, ace interest and premiums \*sets nge loans :ige loaus in process of foreclosure -late ...'.'..... Kurniture and fetation. ] _ _ ,. uent interest, premiums and fines i&lt;l taxes paid 3.S58 in . 4&lt;3.'46O UK Tota: Liabilities Capital stock running. (Dues and dividend') auts.e7« n </seg>
            <seg id="p033">X N Kc«-i|.T I ( I'.sik ■■&lt;! it ii ri ! ( N s N \ \ </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Lition at the close of business June 80, l'.i05. being an in - ereue of one over the number reporting last year. During the period covered by this report five new MM :is have been organized and authorized to do business and four have discontinued and paid all liabilities in full. The following are new Associations organized during the L.lumbus — Equitable Building, Loan and Savings As - tiun. 2. Fairburv — Fairbury Building and Loan Association. 3. Lincoln — Securitv Savings and Loan Association. 4. Nelson — The Nuckolls County Building and Loan As- The following Associations ceased to do business and paid all liabilities in full: 1. Ashland —Ashland Loan and Building Association if. Huruphiej — Humphrey Building and Loan Association. 8. Msjwood — Maywnod Building and Loan Association. 4. Wahoo — Swedish Mutual Building and Loin Aasoci IThe following Building and Loan Associations have 1 :al years to ree])oiid to calls for reports of their condition, the State Bank Examiners have been unable to locate their Ee of business, and it is presumed that they have liquidated affairs and discontinued business, and they are now stricken the records of this department as Association! in force: Kl. Lincoln — Western Mutual Home Purchasing and Build - ciation. 2. Omaha — Mechanics Savings, Loan and Building As- sociation. KECAl'ITlI.ATIoN iber of Associations in force June 80, 1 904 60 iber of Associations organized during the year 5 iber of Associations discontinued during the year. 4 :ber of Associations stricken from the records as in force. 2 bir of Abbo( :i force June 30. 1H05 59 son. Stratton — rrudential Building and Loan Association. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">K2G. There were 196,03d shares of stock in force with only t! shares delinquent, and only 351 shares subject to cau - tion for non payment of dues. There were 199 mor nting to $135. '.'4. and 32 lore amounting to $45, 52(5.34. ttg one — a demonstration of the romoting thrift and home owner - wbich reflects association Practically every item ri with the currents of robust vitality and increasing strei Increased aaaeta, the amount of business done at small i decreased real estate account, and the sharp increase m number Eiareholders and shares in force blend in delightful harm notes of prosperity and progress with which the state trv are blest. tHere we have gratifying evidence of the fruitfulness of cite D in years gone by. .Much energy, time and talent i. devoted, unselfishly to a large extent, in making secure the dation of association work in eliminating speculative metl curing fostering laws and their enforcement. subject to foreclosure amoi mortgage* in process of foreclo ITlie showing is a Hatteri e of cooperative effort in \ -eel and diminished during the year, as follows: onroet increase $1,051,94' First mortgage loans increase 809,597 18 Stuck loans decrease 37, (i Real estate decrease . ... 4,3: Furniture and stationery incrc&gt;: ; .... 12,411 09 Cash increase 203, 174 06 nqnenciei increase . . 3^1 Expenses and taxes increase 10'J 19 Other assets iiurease . . 54 ? 4 Running stock increase t&gt;7l,3' Full paid stock increase. . ... 271,482 01 rve fund 27.'.' Undivided profits The Associations did a business during the vear amounting (5,289,488.64 at an expense, including salaries, of $ 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">i i i t ) _■ Boar •nt Investment Company 1 N </seg>
            <seg id="p037">( &lt; Attorney &lt;• i i i fATE OP KA )RXKV &lt; i x \ V f r If.. ( iV v m\ &gt; ) i, and ir i i i i v. tlia i i r ition with tin v ot sta Very </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">STATEMENTS BOWING THE CONDITION OF THE FIFTY NINE BUILDING AND LOAN \ [(INS IN THE STATE OF NEBRASKA AT IHK •SE OF BUSINESS ON THE 8Jth DAY OF .11 \ </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 I ATKMKNT ALBION WILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION O \I \\ I (TKN ■HAM \ *•*• h T-» i i \itn 1 1 1 1 - m « NKBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p041">BUILDING AMI LOAN AS-;- 41 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1906. ■tKCBIPT*. Balance on band July 1, 1904 Dims, i Running stock ) MM M Dues, (Full paid Auckl Prrmiutr MM fl m Members I...uns rfL lll« it.*w «&gt; Insurance r KXHKMIITI l!K&gt;i. Other expen-. I Withdrawals, due-* Withdrawals i-Hniiti-'- Witbdru- Premiums returned borrower- ims return Kail panl gtocte, dm Fall paKi stock, d Full paid stock, earning •. hand Full paid stock, earnir ha Tax male certuieates bought . Insurant- ■ paid Total Ins jfiii 'J SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT SUPPLKMEN'J AL RKI'OUT A a now nermuWBI No of Ktiar - -h»resis«u. :il year... &gt;t»ares m»t 4 of tioij sha in IHfi -.h none h.i '«! shiirt ~ of fnll pmkl stock in for k aid siook in fo l~ of *A«J sharps and &gt;3.&gt;r t\ir. - jf *A«J shan n' i^uent H &gt;r qod -a for non-payment of d(. Total at: ■ amount or * sin" '&gt;' umounc ol Amouti A m wtih'h loans hai t&gt;een m the As-ociation as col! T l&gt;ui.dinK ; :« No of ■2 So of mtrmr- »Tcr»ee rate of inn &gt;r: mrin-' Use;. 1 3-lu : LiriQi.' ti- p Plan of premium m iLiml diir1nj{ flscu^ l withdrawn from ; month i ilurinif flsc i </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 STATEMENT CF THE CONDITION OF THE ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA. On the 80th day of June, 1935 B. r. OILMAN W H. BARTZ A f. BALDRIDGE SMITH GILMAN LMAN a. r. ualdkilm;e ;eo e. davis Bmongw* letDK in pr. &lt;■&lt;* lo«M -ire and stationery DeMaqoeM Inu-rr-t. prem Wiptnw and tun-* paid ■tal stock runnio*. (Dum and divic DMIvMrt profits None M ■ ■i iiu'i&gt;iii|i eii-lonns l'r&gt;ro,um- unesriml . . N ■il*bi Adr«K» ■• •• rest and premium IS* i.ioo iiu IM </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 UUILIMNd AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL TEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1906 RKCKICT8 H hand July 1 I3H S4 8 31 ' (O 2.IKI6 07 full paid Motk Premiumi .... None None •J6II Membership and Iransfe f. m Loans ri|i:ii ■ : Real estate asln Borrowed 2.2i»&gt; M Horrowed ir T 1 inmnui 1 VFIMIITIKKS »»3t5 OO v,,ne ■ N'une Commission* Num- Num' &lt; »thf r expense- 117 Sfl Withdraw]*, i am hit i HIT l» Withdraw)*. • Matured stock Matured stock Full paid stock Witbdrawls. earDinr^ hi Nrae Matured stock. N'sne Matured stock, i :.rr.in*« None Nose Pull paid si 3,300 00 ua ■ Full paid stock earnliifK M4 M Full paid stock earn «« I'a-hmt hand I IS J ha is a i.souuu Tot... HS.9M m RCPF1.F.MKNTAL RKPORT. T. •isflo* &lt;e SUPPLEMENT AL REPORT Plan of Association (serial or i Perr ilue of each share ■■ titiOD - issued since onranization, (if serial) not sTiai hares in foroe »l H 4a« Plan of Association (serial or i Pern ilue of each share ■ # 1 0ciiio - issued since on.'»ni/.at!on, (if serial) not serial hares in foroe at H 4a« No of shares -anon Aft?\ hares i^suetl tlurinif flsral year 130 uares matured during fiscal vear None ■him withdrawn 'iurinr fl«e^l year % -hares of mnnlni.' stock In force at this date 3l^H iivm of full paid st«ck in fora* at this date. . . 7S% -hares loaned on 14044 -hiires on which dues are delinquent (M4 • shares subject 1 1 cancrtlatioB for nonpayment of Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owinr nv borrowing skaretkolders. . lief .vi Amount of Interest, premiums aud fines due and unpaid I9K M !«o. of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the wfrrefrate amount of same No. 1 'ofO 00 No. of morlL-iMff. ir re. and the amrrevate amount of am«C Amount of loans on improved real estate 9*t Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been maie * &gt;.9S0 Of Appraised value of lmprovem--'its not appraised separately ■ of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value &lt;-f unimproved real estate upon which loans h iv" been ji -:i 1c .... * one Amount of insurance In force and assigned to the Association ascollb 1 v $30,430 •• No. of loans made for buildinsr purposes during fiscal year. ... 3 No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during tisi Amount of advanoe payments of loans during fiscal year . 31,34" m) No. of borrowing stockholders :«• No. of non-borrowinir stockholders 43 No. of minors holding stock In the Association A veraee rate per cent of interest chanted borrower* during fiscal rear Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year None Plan of premium &gt;■ Amount credited to reserve fund daring fiscal year 117 40 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during flMml vear Hope Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year Sl,3»* P3 Amount of dividends declared on full paid stook daring fiscal year. 964 9b Average rate per cent of dividends declared daring nacal year Average running time of stock matured during fi-*al rear None matured Average running time of stock matured during t*a«al year </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 BUILDING AND LOAN A88OCIATI I STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE £OUTII-EAST NEBRASKA Bl'ILDING AND LOAN 'CIAT1ON AUBURN. NEBRASKA, Oa the 30th day of June. 10(5. nrm i its. EB SMITH ELLOTT . GILLAM hay .... Presided President Secretary Treasurer . Attorney CHAS. O FKENCH Doe !&gt;h»rr holders on iDctimplete 1 Ortiaeu* fees . . &gt;rent and pren Interest P. A I </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 ECKIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL VKAIt No. u£ serif* issued since oncuDizttiion ..: No of nhares to force at tbis date i;v, No. of shares issued since onranizatiuu MM shares issued during Oscal year . . . i«t • Ne. of Rharee matured during tisc-.ii year. «a No of shares withdrawn during flseal year i(m h&amp;res of mnoinic stock in force at this date MM aaraaof ftrii paid stock in force »i ihis date ItTT No of share** loauifd on 17.it Aiiiount of interest, premiums aod flues due iind uni ! $&amp;M* OC ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. 10, KK&lt; KII'T*. Balance on hand Julv 1, 1904.. Does &lt; Runnier •took i Dnei (FuL paid stock Mrmt*f rship and transfer fees .... Loads repaid Heal estate tmke* . . Reuis applied on real rs a'r accounts. .. Kemi estate iwynit-nt- on c bt ran- Undivided profits Insurance and taxes I6.XKI 19 78 50 4V») 00 «,475 00 124 OS 747 » M SI 7 50 Total *in.»7» » i:\l-KNDlTOiLKS. Otter expense* . - Withdrawals, daes Wttbdrawals. earning Matured stock, due - . Matured Mock. enrBiogs.. Full paid stock, dwes Pull paid stock, earnings. . Gash on hand T*n&lt;ltTldt d prottts J i. -urjncT and taxes . Keal estate purchased Real estate r pairs and other expenses M 57 TO* 00 i m is 2 . 8.S80 00 Total .- ms - SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. il or pt- rmaner ■ Par v;»; hare of stock . . iiorU-'a.'f^ si, -cUMure an.l the ftinrr^jrute amount of sa &gt; • No of ttortjriAtfes in process of foreclosure ami the aggregate amount ol Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon whu-h loins h;* . Appra'srd vahie of improvements Amount of ltnios upon unimproved re»l es aJ App-aisei value of unimproved real estate unon vrhirn 1-uins have b«---n m i I Amount of insurance in force and a8&gt;lifneri to the Association as collateral security No. of loans made for huildin* purposes duriav flscal jrea No of loam made for payment of homestead moTtgmge* during B^cal \nr No. of borrowing stocUboldera No of non-horrowinK siockhohli ; No of minors holdtntc Htock in the A*s x-i*t inn . . Average rate per cent of interest charped orroven during tittcal rear.. Averatre r4te uer cent of prsmiams charged borrowers during I Plan of premium . Amoant credited to reserve fund durii Amount of lows'* 1 - cha p re4 to reserve fu Amount of dividprul-* d^clare-l on runn Amontu of ti -ir Average rate per cent ot dividendii cci-uml duriair fiscal veur i durtOK ttscal year Class "A" 71 mo , ] Oi none ♦S.I 07 M&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 •CILDUTO AND L«AH ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF HIE AURORA lU'ILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AURORA, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 190"). OKI l&lt; KKv President Vice- President tOONOVEK . LOUNSBURY GROSVENOB Secretary Treasurer Attorney UIKM TIIKS I J II HL'X N J KoN'lX \ J W. E Kl ANI11XI1ENKIKS.N. J SSCiiOONOVl tSSFTS, Bmortnre io&gt;os Id proca»s ut forec : . &lt; and atatiuoe IUIL-, am) di i.i » iniiriK-. running (dues and dividen Full pa « &gt;n Inoomph u Alvunr.- J -t*st and pren: </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS BUILDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR RECKIPTS. Balance on hand July 1. 1901 Dues (Running stoii &lt; Dues (Full paid stock &gt; Interest Premiums Fines I ... Membership and transfer Loans repaid M Heal estate sales Rents . Total EXPENDITI KKS. I Loaaa Salart* 100 UO Commission! Otber expen: OS Withdrawals, dues 2ie« »*, Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings . . . Pall paid stock, withdrawn Fall paid stock, earnings . . Cash on hand 1.500 00 106 i.i • 13.810 « 'ola; SUPPLEMENT AL REPORT. Serial Plan of Association (Serial or permanent) Par value of each share of stock — ' No of sei ince organization (if serial No. of shares in force at this date 1IKI7 1013 No. of shares issued since organization :ifi) hares matured during fiscal year — None No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year Nc. of shares of running stock in force at this datt ■ hares of full paid stock in force at this date m Amount of 1 1- i urns and lines due and unpaid. No of morurii. i foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No ■nrue Nom X Amount of loans on improved real estate f-.'.SWOO Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loan* have been ma.it II*. UP Appraised value of improvements Sl.MROil A mount of loans upon unimproved real estate None None Appraised value &lt;&gt;f unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security erm M No. of loans male for building purposes during nscai year a No. of loans made for payment of ho-nestead mortgages daring fiscal jr:ir Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year O00 No of burro* ing stockh No. of non-borrowing stockholder; No. of minors holding stock in the Association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during ftacai year . rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses chan?ed to reserve fund during fiscal year None Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year *W t» Amount of interest paid on full paid stock during fiscal year. ■i Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year .9 Average running stock matured during fiscal year none matured ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. No of ■! during fiscal year .irts loaned on ■ i&amp;res on which dues are delinquent None 'ibject to cancellation for non-payment of dues None Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues &lt; »winp by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest. Dirtniums and lines due and unpaid. ire, and the aggregate amoun PIud of premi </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 BU1LD1XG AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OK TI1E BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION, BEATRICE. NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1C05 orrici ks. FALL INEST SHAKKEL E WILLIAMS i SHELDON IV SHELDON. E. SACKETT . IHRECTOKS. [ALL, C A. JANSEN I«1T&gt; F\rM murtizaRf Inan Bmurteatre lows In process of foredoMire Ee»l MUU Furniture and su&lt; '• nt interest premMim&gt; and tiii Expanan and taxes paid Other assets Tot L1AHI1 ITIKS. Capital Btoek r. nninc (Does and dividends) Pull paid stuck ■aaerre fund.. UodiTided profile Da* shareholder* on Incomplete loan*. Premiums unearned Adraoce dues Advance Interest and premiums. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAH i process of foreclosure, and the aKsregate amount of Attio real estate 41.W5 vo ■ ite upon which loans have be&gt;M it» to Appraised value of impr :- Amount Appraise Amount of insuran&lt; e ENDING JUNK .10, 1905. :ti HKCKITTv Iuand Julr I, MM (Kunnin (Full paiil Block Hums . . !K-rshi|j and ti 1 Total KVI'KMIITI UN I- • - expenurs rawkls. dues kid stock, ili.' - lid stock, earning o hunt! . t»,7«i to 44ii -:t Tula. BCPPLKMENTAL RETORT. PlanofAmc W or permanent) ; ■Lich share *'t sutc^ omanizatton. (if Hcriall ~ in force at t hi - tell ■ organization.. Li year .r.d during Uscal \ car -Nitres withdrawn during fiscal year tock in force at this d:itp No of shar- -■ 'i-k in force at this dut' No. of s harm loan..: No. of shares iin « hich du's are delinquent Mo or - tncellatlon for nonpayment of dui - Am. ii.- indOne»d»&gt; and unnaii] ■. ami the aiKret'nt* amount of sani-- and the aggreg%ie amount of None 7 '' None ' homestead mocuue* ■ : j| Amount of ■ None No or )» ta No or \ iciation. . . AvcmiE raw? ; rowers durit:. ■ g Areraee rate i»m cent of \&lt; g Plan of premium. . ■]■■:■ i&gt;t per annual, pavahle monthly Amount credited i. 1,11*6 ISO (M i of Iosms charp i»cal vear . None Ann i 1 . urtng Hscal year to Jan. 1. 1806. . «ni ag to*J«. I'lU' i90S **% </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 BUILDING AND I.OA ' STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 1905 I Hi 8. J. CHIDISTER F U. KRES B. WUA OX IE GRAFF L M I'KMBKKTON DIRKt TORS 1H1OISTER K.C. LEONARD - rtoce loans in prore ire uid sutionery i. premiums and On &gt;• s aod taxes paid. . . . Toul I-IAIIILlTIK-i. i Gibing (Dues and dividend y u ■ 1 paid stock re fund -i1 profit! Due •■arenolders on incomplete loan: Preajtunis uiieamod Adraore interest and premlun: ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 ASH LOAN A8SOCIA RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITl/RES FOR THE FISCAL YEAK ENDING JUNE 80. 1905. RECEIPTS N 973 13 41311 M M.?«l 00 7.««3 M 3,i~0 ft"-. Balance on hand Ju les (Running stnc ie*t (Full Iriurt"*t Premium* 480 -5 Membership and in Loans r.-t M.4M 'jO H. vn »o 5.0VI 11 ittaer recei[ ■FINISH V K\1'E&gt; IT1K1 8. l,&lt; rim. »\ 1 1 hi irn» ;»N ■ ;ir k, eaniiii xppnditnn SUPPLKMKN AL RKPORf l'tan of Ass. permanoa v ear matured during tlscal year - withdrawn during tlscal -iires of running stock in force at this &lt; at this S a 41 Ami Man &gt;nd unpaid Amount be agKrexate amount of sam n.i. ..f mart So. of m(irt4Taxes in proce* rid the atrifrewate amount of &gt;ui; Amou- .■*» 00 Appraix 'I value o( n which loans have been mad&gt; t.7«t 0* Amoui Appraiwd value of unimpr -n which leans hare been mn: Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association at collateral security No of loans made for building pi No. of loan* made for payment of honi. Amount of ;i 'f loans duni'- No. of borrowing st&gt; No. of in- I** 7 No! of minors hoi' : '' Cannot tell Average rate per cent of interest charged t«' Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrow Planofprtri c per »IOO 00 Amo'. 1 rid during fiscal year.. 300 00 Plan of premiua MO ,«j Amouii' '-rve fund dur ng fiscal year 3003 87 Amount of dividend k during fiscal year rk during Umm iring fiscal y- Amount of dividends declared on full paid sum Average rat. : vidends declared il Average rum ock matured durlni fiscal year. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 OF THE CONDITION OF THE HLAIR BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BLAIR. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1005, K. KKN.NV SB . ARNDT. President V.ce-President BLIAM KELLY . . . SCHMIDT Secretary Treasurer IliKKCTOKS, r. W. ARXDT. WILLIAM KELLY. P. A. SCHMII.T HAUKISON E. R. STEWART J. W. N'EWELL i-n- First mortpncc lo*n x&gt; ■ :: ■ loans in j.r-'C' lO«Ds . 1 Rmi f-sLaie Furnit u rv and stationery Drltnr,i mills aid bat ■ Tot I ! \ Illl ITII&gt; ■ml stock running. (Dues and paid Kloo B— 1 1 i p fuud Undivided proflt^ ■■c -hare holders on Incomplete lu; Pren. 'iOis oocarDAd Advanc* does Advaorc Interest and premiums t Dt interest, premiums and nne expenses and taxes paid s STATEMENT &lt;&gt;l I II ERS </seg>
            <seg id="p053">RKl'KIPTS AND KXI'ENDl i VISES H)U THE FISCAL YE ENDING JUNE 80, 1!H)5. It I &lt; KII'T li«H I)Ut^ ( full li . Interf^t Premium* . Fine* r*hip and tm l*oans rrpiiiil Renl estate salt - M'l- \ i l I I i: l otle-pip' Withdraw Withdntw Mat Miilu Full l V k. e rnl a. beat .;iid a rv:3 uo Sll'Pl.r M V. N AL UK I n:r 'i [■ n force at No &lt;X s No N uir^of full paid v No of - Amoui Morrow •\mouu m&lt; N Am API Ann A fl«al ..ii, &gt; ma. It- ' At: N N • he As: Dt of premiums cha Amouut t*n -jue&lt;i to reserve fun«i ■' #IM 10 Amount A mourn none -a.inual matvir ar W n </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OK THE CLAY CENTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CLAY CENTER. NEBRASKA, Oq the 80th day of June, llKij E McDowell . C WARD.. CAMPBELL , CAMPBELL I- H SLC YTER .V AIID, ■nvirtn«e louu In pror«si of foreclosure losan Pnraliure Bad »t»l t pri-miums and t; Kimm uini tax. . Otbf r ftssct&gt; Tc 1.I4KII.ITIES. Capital stock running (Dues and dividend: IMh .l«lpr..fli« Due »b»rehold»T- on incomplete loa Praninmi ueamrd A'lviinc -lues Attvuioe ioteieat and premiums :*7«bto </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND KXI'hNDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YAK ENDING JUNE 80, 1906. KKt KIITS, Balance on hand July 1, 19 Dues (Running stm ih« Duo (Full paid stock Interest Premium: Fines . . »»: Membership and lr; Loaos repaid S3 M 2,900 00 Real estate Rents WUtadrawalfeeji Sundries Hills payable ... Total IU.41-3 S! EXPKNUiTI KKS. EX PEN It Tl RES. Loans Ui.oc :&lt;u jans Salaries ;irie: 10« M Commissions Comraissioni Other ex pem Other ex penses ... Withdrawals, due- Withdrawals, d Withdrawals, earninirs Wit luirawals. earm Matured atoek, due: Matured stock, due.- Matured slock, earning- Matured Mock, earning Full paid stock Pu;! paid stuck, earnim Cash on hand . Full paid stock, duos Pull paid stock, earnui. - C&amp;sb uc haod Bills payable .... Total SUPPLEMENTAL KKI'&lt; &gt;|; I Bills Total SUPPLEMEN Plan of Association (Serial or permanent 1 Permanent V 1'ar value of each share of stock . $100 10 Tganization (If aerU ires in force at date of last report M 1 organization •*?■* - ssuetl during fiscal year ■ - .: ,',1 during fiscal year 14 Irawo during fiscal year hares of running stock in force at this &lt;hit&lt; -hares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent 'tares subject to cancellation for uon-payment of dm x Total amount of dues delinquent at this date **\\ id Amount &lt;■ f -lues owing bv burrowing shareholders 45 On t interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid m 02 mortgages nubject to foreclosure, and the aggregate aaaunt of same, No ,1 M0 00 process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same in proved real estate :6 NO 00 d real estate upon whicn loans haye been made 4. mprovements Amount i'f linins up&lt;jn unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been mad&lt; Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security 3\.'.y80 00 P.O. of loans ma&lt;li- tor buildintr purposes dnrint; fls-al year No. of loans made for payment of homestead morttfagres during fiscal year Amount of advance payment of loans during fisr IBOd 10 No. of borrowing stockhoiders No. of non-borrowimr stockholders 3fi No. of minors holding stock in the Association Averaire rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. Plan of premium 10 per cent ef loan, payable in M) equal month; \ p . menu Amoum fuBd during fiscal year «•■ hi Amount &gt;e fund during fiscal year Amount running stock during fiscal year l.drs « Amount of di. ed on full paid stock during fiscal. year Averaire rate per cent of diririem s declared during ;otal for year » Average runniui; time of stuck matured during fiscal year 70 months </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 STATEMENT or THE roMUTIOK OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING LOAN &amp; SAVINGS ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. &lt;&gt;l Mill BliHAM 8PEK BECHER.. H 8 ELLIOTT. Sei-retary freasurer I SULLIVAN DIBK4 TORS. JAM G. I) J. G HECHER. H. S ELLIOTT JNi) J SULLIVAN- \"l T~ pud ■ad taxes paid I I Mill 1 I II V ■ •■earned rest and premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p057">5 7 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. KKCEIPT3. Halance on hand July 1, IE I i ItunninK st fci.oio on 8,20m M Full pa I 'rt'iui tin. *■*; ■rship and transfer LoanB repaid -pa it Tax ceriiticat- Insurance repaid Advance Premium and Jr in EXPENDITURES. I « w W Full ;mi.: stock, earnir. 1T« hand Wl, M SUPPLEMENTAL KKPi »RT Ki ■■ or pern y - matured dui i withdrawn during ' 'iinfcr SUK-k in fori-e :i tl this dat N N payment of di t -' . rt' :in.i Ma amuun of :n&lt; :ire»rat amount of sa: me been m, ,.1. Association as . ■ hi. .rlirainw iin 4 lunr ttscul yt ,r •I N A 6 per A ill' borrowers Jurin-' fl year ... S6-IH 1- jmpetitive . e fund durini? flsrail year. ■al year. :&gt; ■.., \ ear k a </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 STATEMENT OF THE COSDITIOM OF THE COLUMBUS LAND LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS. NEBRASKA, On the 80th day of June, 1933 OFFICERS. BHART... BOOTT. HENRY HOCKKNBERGER i BECHEK W. M CORNELIUS DIRrCTOUS. A SCOTT W M CORXELIU C. L. LrND ■»orl«ofc loan* to process of foreclosure • ure mm) stationery iflol lnter«Nt premiums and an Mi and uin pair! I I Mtll.lTIKS. r»ajW stock runciDK (Decs Fu i . paid stock . . linmrre fund None UadlTided proflu None Dae hhsrebolders on iacomp etc loan Premiums unearned. . Nil! Adnnoedaes «rrso Admnt*e interest and premiums 1"! &lt;) </seg>
            <seg id="p059">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 59 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YF AK ENDING JUNE 30, 1905 RKf ElfTS Balance on hand July 1 IU04 47.h 7 rfU None rut stuck) Dues, (full paid stock) I H.58U W&gt; Premiums ,T 3 «&gt;S Membership and u ansfer fee* Loans repaid 270 75 10X00 u&gt; None Real estate ■ Total I'XI'EN IMTl KK&gt; ss None * &lt; ither expense Withdrawals. MO ,S 59*40 None None Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, dues None ■paid stock earning on hand «". 1 SUPPI.KMKN 1 AL REPORT wUttaa (serial or peraa&amp;t q, (if serial; tetel is . hi. (it serial; 0g/g : since organization %§/§ No of shares i-*un] &lt;iuriD8T fiscal year 7^ -hares matured during fiscal year. Ulj withdrawn during flsc&lt;il year ]« ulng stock in force at this date 43 « ill paid stock in force at this date... None No of shares i-~uml 'lurine nsi-al year 7^ lilt withdrawn during flscil year Ig ■ I iik r stock in force at this date 43 - ; paid stock in force at this date . . . None s MM l«* eni &lt;sc laai A4 r nonp«yaieut of dmm 46 r nonpayment of daai 46 bis date I4JM 00 Amount of dues owing b • 493 All 1 1 of interest, premiums and tines due ;m&lt;i unpuiu t&gt;i -'n ' ■nor'tfu-'fs subject to forecl&lt;*ure and the asKregate amount of same 1 Eit of intereNt. pretniuma and rtn»'s due ;m&lt;i un[i.. t&gt;i (HJ m&lt;l the a«(trrK»ie amount of sai mo!-:_'»*f. I the mggregate amount of sin. t of loans on in * .;..; the a#grec ute amount of s im- ile 9Mi.(MiO US a mourn or loans od improved real e^taW fMi.ar Appraised value of 1] estate upoa which loans have been mai«- Apprujseti value of imp r ute upon which loans have been made »' MOM Appraiseti value of .^ 4&lt;B M Appraiseti value of improvem* ■ Amount of loans up , Amount of loans up ilW)n which loans h iv* 1 t&gt;een 11; . Amuunt of in _-neti to the Association ascollat ral securii No. of loans n ■-. during UscmI year t% No. of i !i»*nt of homestead mortgages durio»* fiscal rear _f» Amount of advanr- if loans during fiscal year ffuf No. of borrowing stockt. ■ .&gt;ifl No. of non-tKM k holders. . . No of minois k in the Association 45 Average rau? per cent of interest charged borrowers during n&amp;cal vear T *M0O Kwe rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year, 3M00 of 1 p-r^nt 1 if premium premium is bid, and lump sum deducted from loan credite&lt;l to reserve fund durinx fiscal year Amour ' 'Tve fund during fiscal year Am. &gt;ut . running stock during fiscal year. . . Amoun 1 full paid stock during fiscal ye.ir. Averatre rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year &gt;■ m I </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 STATEMENT of Tin: coMiirios &lt;&lt;t n CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION CRETE. NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June. 13C3. M H PLEMIN c B ANDKUSO /. WATKRMAN im.nwiN t. HAK.I! Firsl morti!" 1 MM premium: p.i,. - »n.i taie&gt; Capital atook running (Dues and divider incomplete 1c </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 [ITS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAfc F.NUING JL'NE 30. 1905 RKCEIFTS D J»rc Fun Men ill TURKS. til 4M 00 00 00 54 38 ft! 78 Kull M ,-T UPPLEMENTAL REPORT rr N ,Ji in furt-e at this d»it -tock in force at this date N ii. Amount N ■ul A Appr . T i which limns have been mailt At .indassi.-M' lution :i« i-. w llttVt ir 3 N .:**fes duriii. An N N A N 1 1. I i-ha wers durii: of premiums charged borrower^ dur Plan An t c Amount ' -c»l yen Ai I Of ral \ear lared du ■n during titf.i </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 BUILDING AND LOA HuSS STATEMENT OF TI1E CONDITION OK TOE FAIRBCRY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRBURY, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June. l'JOJ. PHIL S. EASTERDAY A V l'EASK PHIL S EASTERDAY J O EVANS J W. HAMMOND. rtcace loans "or*»&lt;^ of fnreclosu Furnilur*- . Delinquent lateral, premiums and Expenses sod taxes pskl Other ssseu To' LIABILITIES OspltsJ stock ninrlrr (T&gt;jes sad dtridend« tun p»ld stock 173-1 » Beaerrr fund Dodl Tided proflu Dae stars koMsrs oa Incomplete losn PtwhIiibm — ssrsrd A. :&gt;...-.,-.• -u.- Adritaix interest sad premiums SAXTKLI. KVAN HAKTIGAN </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1905 KIPTS. REC I a anw on band July 1, 1904 Dues (Running stock) K! Full paid &gt;tock st Premiums Fines Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid Keal esta' Tota KMKNDITIBBS. Loan: Salarie Conm Other expenses Wltbdrawa s. dues Withdrawals, earning.. Matured stock, due- Matured stock, earning: Full paid stock, dues . . Full paid scock, earning Cash on hand Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent Par Tain . ire of stock . K serits issued sinoe organization (if serial shares in force at this date I shares issued sinoe organization shares issued during fiscal year . shares matured during fiscal year. . shares withdrawn during fiscal year &gt;hares of running stock in force at this date snaresof full paid stock in forre at ihis date . 1 on No of shares on which dues are delinquent iDcvllat;un for non-payment ol Total a* dues delinquent at this date.. . Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholder Amount of in mortgages subject to foreclosure and No of mortgages Id proeess of foreclosure and unpaid. the aggregate amount of sai ■ and the aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate . Appraised v . eal estate up. Appra s»&lt;l value of MM ■ as a which loans have been made Amount of loans upon unimproved real es'ate App aise.1 value or uiiimp ite upon which loans have been made Amount of ■ dasslKned to the Association as collateral security «S0 00 No. of loans : Una purposes during fiscal year No of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Amount of advance pavmeotaof loans timing fiscal year No. of b. ers 1 No. of r. No of miners holding stock in the Ass ciatlon I Average charged i orrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiu •■ s charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year. Amount &gt; ve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year '-~i« of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fl^*%] year </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 STATEMENT UK THE CONMMTION • I AIRFIELD. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of ,1 O' • ICKR [I II A A. BAKKK - A \\ ALT. J P. SHIVELY ..President Vice President Secretary Tmntct DIRECTOR' ... LI. d;:. j e. spatz. \VM. IIOEVET B. HKY O. VV TIN W,| I» 3 I I Mill I 1 [I rapitul -uxk running; (dues am) di\ i * ■ n taoomplc T \N'!&gt; LOAN ASSOCIATION J I.. KPPKKsoN M&gt;.\ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 IPTS ASH EXPENDITURES FOK THE FI- KNDING JUNE 30, 1905. KKC'K I 1'Tj*. on hand Ju'v I, I9W i Full paid hi mms — IS Membership and transfer fees. I,&lt;&gt;aiis repaid Total i;\i'i;m&gt;iti ici Ti i:\i-i NDITI RES 21 ■ _ - Full paid stock, dm Full paid stock, rarmnps . d hand Recording and abstract Pm Tolal SUPPLEMENTAL. RKPOBT II W.eiy is' srmu \I .\ Al. HK1'.)K1 - i .i 1 "- *» jn f ■ • of full paid stock in force at this date . i • •n which dues are dellnqu* 17 -payment of duci i unpaid. No of moiii.'ai.'*-' subject to force ;&lt;&gt;su re, and the aitKreitate amount of same. No re, and the aitKregate amount of ■oreclosure, aud the aiftfregate amoui ■» in i it u id -iregiiw air *ppr;. il f^tute upon which loans In Appraisal vulueof impr v i re»l estute upon which loans li . A p; r ; - t- i of lo ins up&gt; upon which loans have WhU'h h&gt;UD8 have bet*n n ■ or iDsuram ttoDtisooklaU -tion iis tans mo&lt;le : 3 •rtttaves during *a«6a during tlscal Hm-bI year I luana during d&amp;cal \ ear rs N kb holder: i-k in the A- • it charged bo m of premiums charged borrower* d i ■ ear • ■ ar . ear •'•'■ A l&gt;er t*»nt df -.ared during flscal year ■ iDK fiscal year tziutured di. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION, FREMONT, NEBRASKA, On the 3^th day of June, 1900 OFFK t l:&gt; S H MAY President Secretary Tr**a&gt;»urt*r FRANK HAMMOND. ARTHUR TRL'ESDELI. CHARLES B. VEAZIE. GBOBGE L LOOM IS IIIKKCTOKS. CHARLES H. MAY, FRANK HAMMOND, .HAKLKS H. VEAZIE, UrXllMK L. IX&gt; FirM mortcag&lt; I..an IW.7W)» None Bmort«M« louis in process of fore&lt; LOOU 00 Baal eaUM LM 5* Furniture and stationery 4.7IIV 45 DellDquent int« re&gt;t premiums and Hi • EipeDst's and taxes p»M 4IX 15 None Other aaaata «4i 48 DeUaqaetit dues 3MJ «U Cootrwu for real estste sol' 1.430 48 T ■ LIABILITIES. Oaoltai Moek r&gt; nninc (Dues and dividend None UndiTlded profltx Due shareholders on Incomplete loan Premiums uneanx 4rt 35 5 00 A^ll llljCt" &lt;iU»"« L'Ni ai Advance interest and premiums Other Uabilll liw ;o 65 » </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION'S RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YK AR ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. KECEIPT&gt;. Balance on hand July 1, 1004 Does (Running stock) Balance on hand July 1, 1004 t 2.W «« H.03I ao None Does (Running stock) Full paid stock* l-'ull paid stocV Interest 4.W0 *&gt; Premiums Premiuir M .10 SO» Membership and transfer f Loans repaid Membership and transfer ' 37 a&gt; Loans repaid... io.mo ao None Bcal estate sales Real estate sale: nx oo Profit on 70 shares withdrawn Profit on 70 shares withdraw 139 SO Sundry other receipt- Totii. Sundry other receipts 5.0+1 M ■ inmimiBi EXPRNIIITI'KKD. f ii&lt; :• ii 00 600 OO None - . Commissions Commission* Other expen: Other expenses |U4 &gt; Ml U&amp; ItdrawmJa, du&gt; idruwats earning red stock, dm ired slock, earninr paid stock, du paid stock, eurnin, on hand- . . 3.SI13 (JO Withdrawals earning 7&gt;!4 7B Matured stock, dues . . .V.u 00 Matured stock. ftmrnlB*! •-•*&gt; 0O Pull paid stock, dues. . Pull paid stock, earning ' "a*th on hand MM 5« Sundry other payment - Total sri'l'LKMEN TAL REPORT. v other payment ■ SUPPLEMEN I AL REPORT P'an of Association (Serial or permanent ciation (Serial or permanent . Serial l'iir val n force at th . - t£00 UO 36 n force mt it, 807 No of sb iurinn tisca\ yemr No of si . 35« 143 No of shares matured durins tlscnl year. barai withdrawn during fiscal year - area «f ru- nine stock in fort-e at this date area of full paid stock in force at thi- • hares matured during tlscnl year. 55 withdrawn durinK fiscal year - 70 ,ii,res wf ru' nine stock in fort-e'iit this date 807 f full paid stock in force at thi- lal ' on hurts on which du»*s are delinquent . r nonpayment of du i nonpayment of du n :ti It Total amount of dues a : &lt; Total amount of d , I3H0 *W Amount Amount of d B H Amount of U»u ms and fines due and unpaid Amount of ii i ind unpaid mortsagvi - ra, and the — gragate amount of hub *00 00 N of mortieu^ ind the awRn-triit-- amount of sac No. of ii. ''tfate amount of - 1 the HLV't'k'iHe amount &lt; • ed real estate upon which loans ha\ ' ed real estate upon wnich loans have be-n mm ■ • None ■ «1 value of unimproved real estat#-upon which loans have been made ■ .1 value of unimpr - »n which loans h;n Amount &gt;n as collateral Amountof in ■' ion as collateral security |7U,I26 05 No. of 1 it S r So. &gt;&gt;f l&lt;&gt;. ' homestead moruiw &gt; during fiscal yea Amount of a . !l0 55OOO Ko of b. 97 No of !.■ -vholders 73 k in the Association Average rate per cent uf interest charged borrowers durio 7 3-10 ■ of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year M (0 Amount k! during fiscal year... Amount of d u running stock during fiscal year I -cm 8S Amount of di i "ed on full paid stock during fiscal je per cent of di ared during fiscal year. Ax 'iiatured during fiscal year- - - 13U-I31 Mo. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Advance tnteieti huo prcmiuius </seg>
            <seg id="p069">• RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL I ENDING JUNE 80, 1905. Rinnm Hal;incp on h.in&lt;l July 1, I 1 . 1 t * . . inning stock) . Z2.*7*t ] 13, *» I»r Membcnthip and transfer r* - Loans repaid . R ■ r\ r mini ■ ■!■— i &gt; i-i n n Tl KB i 1 V,' M K • S 1 I ■ SIIMM.KMKN UPPLEM ENTAL KRH &gt;KT. 1AI. KKI'ORT ur ■ I N N I N N 4 N n. &lt; re gate amount of same. No. 4 1 Sou r A I - have b-en r i:ltioD»8Ci rily \bA ' home»le;»l mort*fa*.'rs during : No ■ciatiou Unkno rrowera during tiscal year 9 «»f premiums ciiaixecl borrowers durinr fiscal yet Am uii! 710 Aiuoui. . &gt; | j j | t • n ill i^ t W 1 1 u r i tr t * old </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION III TITE GERINQ BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 KF.CEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. II r &lt; ' K I I 18. Balance on hand July i , 1901 Dues (Running stock) Dora (Full paid stock) Interest and ii Sll 50 Premium 303 7S none Membersblp and transfer fees Loans repaid Loans repaid T)On*' Real estate sales . ■■■■ Real estate sal Total.. . i:\PKNDITt KK&gt;. To EXPEND I TIRES. i. f3.-.'X)0O Salaries and expesjaai ' JJ Salaries and exj ' ommissions i.'H;«- none K expense Withdrawals . *'* Withdrawals, earnings . ■ ! ' Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues . Matured stock, dues . n«&gt;r&gt;»* s Matured stock, earnings n " n/1 Matured stock, esirninp Pull paid stock, dues . . Done Full paid stock, earnings ii-'ni Own on ban A-nount to I rash on ham I A-nount to balaaei r&gt;l To al . BUPPUCMKNTAL REPORT. •y H.5C8 T» SUPPLEMKN I AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent Serl Serial Plan of Association (Serial or permanent Par value of each share of ■! *3U0 Par value of each snare of stock tSUU 0&gt;&lt; No of series Issued since organization (if serial). No of series Issued since organization (if serial) No of shares in force at this date 1 1.5 No of shares in force at this date No of snares issued since organization no account ke tiiire.s issued during fiscal year wmm No of shares issued since organization . . M account kept bvaa issued during fiscal year '■■"■' No. of shares matured during fiscal year M ■■ hares matured during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal yeir ... hares »f running stock in force at this date. I » No. of shares »f running stock in force at this date "* No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date none No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date none .a No. of shares loaned oo No. of shares loaned on No. of shares nn which dues are delinquent . none No. of shares on which dues are delinquent new No of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of d^ I No of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of tai I none Total amount of dues delinquent at this date no»e Total amount of dues delinquent at this date none Amount of dues owing bv borrowing shareholders nooe Amount of dues owing bv borrowinK shareholders none Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid. none Amount of interest, premiums and fines doe and unpaid n« »ue Nc of mortjfnsres subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amouui of same. No none Nc of morttrasres subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amouui of .^ame. No none No -&gt;f morti:. ; sure and the aggregate amount of - No of inortya^ts in process of foreclosure and the aggregate amount of No DOS* Amount of loans on Amoui AppraU d va ue of imp' »le upon which loans have oeeu wade. no a ii estate upon which loans have been uuulc no acoou Apprawil value of Improvements no Amount of Joan* upon unimproved real estate none Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans bave been me Amount of in-uranue in force and assigned to the Association as collateral account not kept ty No of luans mad' for building purposes during fiscal year noaccour; No. of loans made for payment of h imesiead mortgages during fiscal jear Amount of advance pavment of loans during year. nune No. of borrowing stockholders I" No. of non-borrowiny stockholders No of minors boldinM stock in the Association . . . none Average rate per «'nt of interest charged borrowers daring Qscal Tear Average rat" p r cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of prt-mium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year none Amount of luNses charged to reserve fund during fiscal Tear none -* declared on running stock duriug fiscal year .. none Amount of : hired on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rat* per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year Boot </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 OF THE COSKITIOX uK THE EQUITABLE BUILDING &amp; LOAN CIATION GUAM) ISLAND. NEBRASKA, ic i i i»ii; m i ih:v H i(D P. MILI.KTl. RICH A H'lllKliT J UAHK BAI.I'H H 1 i&gt; i:t&gt;. Krai .«l«« premiums %t Dl L.aliin T I I A ICI I I I II v Dues ar on Incomplete 1om A u • uLiC** lotcrot ti i. ' ; ■■ ■ ■ - STATEMKST On the 30th &lt;l«y of June &lt;&gt;1 1 &lt; HAH1.KS W. BRINIMGK! ( HAKI.KSF BKNTLKV JAMES H WOaLI. B mortgage Ion- murwfture kmas in pr&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p073">BDILDINO AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 73 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOK THE FISCAl ENDING Jl"NE 30, 1905. KIPT3. Balance on band July 1, 1804 IMJM 6e .inck) lull paid .stuck A4.VS 10 .Membership and transfer Loans repaid •0 21 J.-.7 30 5 UJ nont .ure. Interest ;ir. i;iu it T 431 iU HIT 3&gt; l':i meiit.- on -ettleineni bal T (170.173 » ihti ici:s. L&lt; 110.000 (JO w i*5 m Withdrawals, earniri Mature. Full paid stock. fun Cash on han h V .. |ITU,!73gi I1TU.IT3 8&gt; SDPPLEMENTA SUPPLEMEN A I. KKI'ORT PAL REPORT &gt;f Association (serial or [ormanent Plan of Association rmanen Serial I' tlue of each sli. issued slattorna rial' . issued since organization - - issued durintf tiscal year. . Ut No. of series Ksued stKir shares matured during tiscal jear N Bterea withdrawn during fiscal year h m shares of running stock in force at this dat N shares of full paid stock in foic at this dm none none 1637 :tD shares on which dues are delinquent I it ion for non-payn ;*y ymentofdue- . none ment of dt none T it of d hart-holders p rs 330 M) it of i i :um.H and mm--*, due and u 1 unpaid -jff qq unpaid tir -&lt;j N the ay agKretfute amount of same. No. . none aggregate amount of same. No. . none the aggregate amount of same none moriL- »ure. and tl the aggregate amount of same none it of loans on ml estate al estate upon whU IMJM '» Ap hie h loans have been made &gt; we makf no for- I mal apprainl ich loans have been made- we male no fo» A, «ed value of improvements : » -n unimprove&lt;l real estate m&amp;l appraisal nis uixm unimprovexl real ostat i which ioans hare been made no formal appraisal improved real estate upon se*i Talue of unimproved real estate upon m which loans have been mac t of insurance in force and assigned to the , no formal appraisal Amount of insurance in force and as.si^'ned to th e Association as collateral As-ociation as collateral H-urir. . 310,450 on 810,450 on &gt;r No of l stead mortmes during fiscal yea Amount of ad I loans during fiscal year. . No of minor- wefation Areraffe rate i&gt;cr Dent uf interest charged borrowers dnrinp fiscal yea Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal ye* no pre Amount cred ve fund during fiscal year „ 9791 53 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund durtntf fiscal year pom on running stock duriag fiscal year 21.ftt« 70 red on full paid stock during fiscal year. Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year .*. 314 ff) KK&lt; redeem EX I'lV </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HARTINGTON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION On the 80th day of June, 1905. OFFICERS. El OX . . GABLK... ROBINSON ra nelson DI1KTOI1S. A. B. GABLE, GCO. F. SOOVILLE. \nnKT&gt; K.rv. monner loam Bmorutavr losos la process of for' ■ um »nd ustiooerj. • nt Intemt. dues and On. Expenses sad taxes paid T..tal 1.1 Mill I I II S. stuck nmniDK. (Duns and dlTidenOs) jid stock ... ■525 ■warn fund •J«i M CnalvU.-.! proflls 1.4KH I Dw saafoaoUars on iuoomplete loans b(«i None II-' Haas Advance Interest and premiums HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA, </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 RECEIPTS AND EXPKNDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1006 RECEIPTS lialanro on hand July 1, 1904.. f MS M Dues, (runntnir .773 M Dues, (full paid s lock) ... Sone Interest tjttt 05 Premiums N'one Finf 4110 Membership and transfer f. ■ ,-y, ,, repaid 3 352 US K'-al estate sa: Kent* Tota EX TEN DITVKES f iTtma ■ Salarl. 150 00 None Oimn: 'ther exp&lt; 27 50 Withe Withdrawals, earnings MOlS Matured stock 1,880 00 Matured stuck, earning! 9H&gt; 00 Nooe Full paid stock, dues Pull paid stock earning Cash on hii Bills payable T SUPPLEMEN TAL REPORT. Plan of Association (serial or permanent) Par value of each share of stock No. of m since organization, &lt;lf serial &gt; It No. of shares in force at this date rifio No. of shares issued since organization iu.s N o. of shares issued during fiscal year 128 No. of shares matured during fiscal year 2H withdrawn during fiscal year i&amp; ism of running stock in force at this date &amp;o ik ires of full paid stock in force at this date. . None ■M which dues are delinquent 34 No of - ■■collation for nonpayment of dues) 15 Total amour nt at this date |i«9 65 Amount of du&lt; iders 189 65 Amount of in f ind nnpaid 130 40 No. of morti: 1 the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 1.500 00 No. of mortya*.- r*»closure, and the aggregate amount of same. . . None Amount of loans on improved real estate Amount of loans on improved real estate »*?5 oao 00 Appraised value ol upon which loans have been made fc*,noo oo Appraised value of impi 00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real e-tate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans haye been made Amount of insurant'" in f o the Association as coUafral Hecurity 94- No. of loans made for buildin*.' purposes during fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year 1 Amount of advance oa&gt; meats of loans during fiscal year f 1.500 00 No. of borrowing - 43 No. of non-bor ■ holders No. of minors k in the Association 19 Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during nscal year 10 Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. . N'noe Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during ns. Plan of premium.. Amount credited t- nd during fiscal year *ft • 00 Amount of Iok-m-s charsed to reserve fund during fiscal year IhM Plan of premiutr Amount of d n running stock during fiscal j-ear t.199 00 Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal ye.ir.. None Average rate per cent of dividends declared during tisoal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 Bl'ILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB HASTINGS BCILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HASTINGS. NEBRASKA. On the 30t.li day of June, IMS. OFFICERS. H.PRATT. Presideut RY SIKKMANN Vipe-President WM. M LOW MAN. Secretary J H FLEM1NI Altorut-y DIRECTORS H. PRATT EZRA LANGEV7N W. F. BfCHANAN H. 11. COIJNi ■Btorumcc loans in proofs* or furecl lout .. UgllBUMWH iatarasl. premtunu and TM««pn.l No arrouril 31 Other »»«:l~ Tu 1 I Mill 1 I II - Cipifl stock running (Dues and dividr t u u paid »urk . I70.MS K won* Ion on incomplete 1 E Ativaoee iaiarest mad premium* ■ HENRY JSo i: Heal ruw Kurottare and union ry &lt;- Cwk oa haad Hd la bukv </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Bl'ILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION;; 77 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE HIDING JUNE 30, 1905. FISCAL YEAR KK«KII'TS. Balance on hand Julv I. 1MW.. * 8.41SI 94 Dues &lt; Running stock ).... full paid stock) ins rship and transfer M ■ ■ Full paid Interest -a) ao - -N'one 7J 55 Membership and trar Loans repaid 45 00 Loans repaid IU.li/7 U0 1- eal estate sales Ve,' of 'attorney ' ]^^ s leal estate sale None .None 57 50 Delinquent taxes repaid m tx Delinquent interest repaid Total 13 15 Tota IVI70 30 KXiKMHTlRKS. KM'KMIITIRES. u 1 usurer and secretary, WOO 00; attorney, $99 96. ...... rer and secretary, Wou U0; ai ;V jrney, 189 96 yjj 96 I&gt; an U&gt; None i u - |i .1 45 r.iwii H.V&lt;7 50 ;tjiw ho None Matu: y utt pa-,1 su&gt;ck, dii None None None l-'uH paul stock, dues Tf . - n-k. earning* hand and in bunk-*. i SB paid stock, earnings ii hand and in bunk I.IH ■ Delinquent taxe 9d 41 Lt-linquent insurance. Total .. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. i.'.uent insurance 13 15 'otal SUPPLEMEN 1 AL REPORT Plan of ..or permuiu'i Plan of . or permanent Permanent Par vu. I.UCKIO jtion (if serial .ition &lt;if serial) . . . None e at this date organization ■ . oe orKanizAtioQ S ■ lu'iiik' nvc;ii No. of shares matured durinir fiscal \ ear -hurt's withdrawn during fiscal yeur •s muluretl during Oaf N'one ;s withdrawn during fiscal year Ha No. of of run nine stock in force at thi-. - i 4 full paid siock in force at i his date ... ha&gt;-es of rmin i ult stot-k in force at th Mi N full paid sioc I date N'one No of shares loaned on tbarea on which dues are delinquent sh aned on ll« No of iibarea un which dues are delimiti' xS :i;iymeni of d lent of dues Total amount tal am Auiuunt of inn '■&lt; furecln-urp and the antfrefrate amoui u of foreclosure and the aggregate a i tMl real estate . . . •I real estate upon wu&lt;ch luans ha?e tn 1 tO fu! in pn and tb&lt; iMrwrt-Kate am&lt; the aggregate uut of amoun nd same real estate . :y*&gt;t 96 Appm :&gt;1 estate upon wli.cli lu^ns hate been made li3T3j 00 ™ rr-ai rsuabc upun wu.i'u luans nare Deen maae IJ3.73 " nLS Not appraised separate v moun: -d real ea'ate Appra ■ Not appra ~ci real es'ate ■al estate upon which loans have vs^i^neti to the Association as col. - during fiscal year v.ead moruaxes durinc a* of unimproved real - pon which loans hare been iu*d- he Association as collateral secui fiscal year g moruaxes durlnc nscal year. 27 - ■f advance ; &gt;anb during fiscal year fiscal year Lotu 1.1) holders i at No of n ciation per cent of interest charged orrowers durin. ■r cent of preniiu us charged borrowers during tiitci premium ... . • k in the Assfwiati lu ent of interest Chan ■rowers during li**i-»l \t»i 8 .' of premiu us charti premium . . ■ rowers during Uscal year *cal year -*'Al year. \ear :aiured during tlscai year </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OK TI1E CONDITION OK THE HAVELOCK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HAVELOCK. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 1905 01 i i&lt; i u. SAML HINKLE President A1U HIE ADAM^ Vice President F. L. SUMPTEK Secretary F B. Y(»r.N(i. Treasurer F L SUMPTEK Attorney DIRECTORS F. L. SUMPTEF ARCHIE ADAM SAM L HINKI.K FKKD KKOEHLER, r HOFMAX F. B. YOCX UilAN THOM. LtlBin A*»*KT ■morteace loans . . . '.:.■ rv*- inans In loses . ■ ■ Real i— tan ■ uent latere»i, premiums and fl ■ LIABILITIES. ■:»! slock running (Dues and divider paid sux •53 Cndivided profit- 10,2-3 40 none Doe abareholderti on lnoomplet^ Premlom* unearned. .. , AdTarii-r du'-^ Adraaee interest and premiu W. AUDI </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 80, 1905. RKCEIPT8. Balance on hand July I, 1804 Dues (Running stock' f M Dues (Full paid stock) Premiums 5 70 Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid *5» WJM uo }{■ ..i aM EXI'EN DITIRES. HMil uu •»« Other eiper 49 * 1.616 0* Iidrawaln, due - idrawals. int* red stock, dues. . . red stock, earning paid stock. &gt;1 paid stock, earnin: on hand l.SMU none *:Xu oo Bills payati T SUPPLKMEN I AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent) ... . permanent Par value (•' k . ■ MD OC No. of series issued since orxanlzatkm (if ser ■I - organization .......... .no record No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of sharat matured during fiscal year -■■■■■ - ".ares withdrawn durinir fiscal yeur. H No. of shares of rut) . force at this date Ml shares of full p.iW stock in force at this dab hurt'.. lilMHPil nn m !i ares loaned 172 jareson which dues are delinquent 45 No of shares w ■ .: . • iution for nonpayment of dues 4 Total ani"U: t at this date 1163 00 »lns by twrrowtnir shareholders. No. shares Hi ■ «i Amount nf interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid ... M '3 to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. S No. of ■ of foreclosure, and the ag(Te(a&gt;e amount of same none Amou i improved real estate 57.MS 00 Ai&gt;pri»:** ■: value of improved real estate upon which loans have been madr ttjouo uu Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estar 3&lt;&gt;&gt; 00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made — 750 00 Amount of Insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security 5'J,sou 00 No of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year 8 No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages daring fiscal year 9 Amount of advance payments of loans during tlscal year 110,390 00 No. of borrow i 74 .* ■ -.u.efc holders 99 Miners holding stock in the Association 4 Average rale per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year. . rate per ceat of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year 10 Plan of premium Amount credited to reserre fund during fiscal year iwnt of losses charged to reserve fund during t) seal year Amount of dr. red on running stock during fiscal year Amount of div«ends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate i ■ i v idends declared daring fiscal year . II Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year.. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">BUILDING AND LOA&gt; ITI0N3 STATEMENT Ot THE CONDITION OF THE HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HOOPEK, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1905. President U'KKS Vici-President v\ HEINE. Secretary I KHLING. Treasurer B MONNICH .... Attorney DIRECTORS HOFFMAN CO FRITZ, JXO S \ AUG. M. TILLMAN CARL KROEGER Assf.Tv &gt;rl(an kj«as ■■»np|e to»ns In process of foreclosure Hnl tMilt N lire and stMionery )» « lx-lmyuf nt interest, pmnluma and an Kipety^ and tawrii paid LIABILITIES. .. stock running (dues and dividends .id stock . Mom l*D&lt;livideii profits None M« em interest and premiums &lt;&gt;H ICERS. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">ULIM1ING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION* 81 RECEIPT8 AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL NE 30, 1905. REf K I ITS. on band July 1, 1904, i.«31 00 1 DM s' Total K.4I* ■ EXPI N 1 &gt; I 1 1 RE8 ■ 13,400 00 75 00 Other expt MM Withdrawals, du Iidrawals. earnings . . :red stock, earnings paid stock, i] . paid stock, earnings on hand I.SM 19 :jm •* Total •7,418 SUPPLF.MEN Al. REPORT Plan of . Serial or perrrauent Par value of each snare of stock No. of shares In furce at this datt No. of shares lowed since organization 715 - issued during fiscal year ♦* ed during fiscal ;•« No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal M AmuuDt of dues owiiiy by borrowing shareholde Amount of interest, premiums and lin^s d No of mort*ra*:es subject U* forec No. at morttri^res in process of foreclosure and unpaid the aggregate amount of same. No ,nd the aifKregate amount of same N Ei on improved real seO value of improve*! real estate up&lt;. &gt;f improvements upon unimproved real estai &gt;*iA \ aluc «&lt; f unimproved re;, t of insurance in force and assigned it •n which loans have been mad&lt; I4JM CO upon which loaos have be«n nade &gt; the Association as collateral security 'f hon)estea&lt;i mort^ates during fiscal year.. Amount of a I loans during fiscal year i No of b. No. of D&lt; bolders -•3 if No. of ii k in the Association 19 ■ ' char^eil borrowers during llacal year.. .. ■ per cent of premiums charged borrowers during Bncal year., of premium. Amount credu e fund during fiscal year Amount to reserve fund during fiscal year. Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal' year re- 1 on full paid stock during fiscal year yr cent of dividends declared during flscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year ENDING JL . nnintr stock) -ill paid block .!I1S Membership unit trans: Loans repaid Heal estate salrs IS 75 15 10 WT 06 as rganization (if serial tire, f 13.500; tornado ;&lt;urposes during fiscal year I shares of running stock In force ut ihis date . Of full paid stock in force at this date '■h dues are delinquent.. I to cancellation for non-pa&gt;ment of dues ... • delinquent at this date None None s3 3 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TI1E HUMBOLDT BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION HUMBOLDT. NEBRASKA, On the 80th day of June, 11)03 J ¥. WALSH .President K. A. TPCKEK President F E. BUTTERFIEM) Secretary A. A. TANNER .Treasurer nun &lt; tiiks. J K WOZAH J. r.WALSH E. A. T- XLA.K. F. K. BUTTERFIELD, A. A. TANNER. RANE J. B. DAV1 !«,( 7&amp; I u Pint — rtgtf loam ta proeaw of f or*. )«. CO Parmttan: *ad MUiiwr 45 &gt; 0 Dallaqarat interest premiums and Kipaa»n and taxet&gt; paid . &gt;ther n»x?ts Tou «. ".I LMIIIIMIKv Uasital stock runninc (Doe* and dlTidena'K PaUpatd nock ■»■ rrf fund... urn ■« UaatTMed proAu i4 DaaakareaoManop iocomptete lomns Advaoos duQB 9E&gt; ▲*ranee Interest wl premlun. - ■ins payable of » l( * KM. H. E. BOYD ASSETS. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 AND LOAN riON3 BUILDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. RECEIPTS. llalance on hand July 1, 1901 . * MM 1» Does (Running stock) ■ t.MI SO lull pale ■ 474 W Membership and transfer f - M '■»&gt; Loans repaid *t uu i.oan~ ray K.al estat -i\able ■-• I.W0 •) Tol 1 \ IKS KIT! IlK* ».'.««.- .o 118 00 Comni: ss Other expens Withdrawals, dues -.iwals earnin. Full paid stock Pull paid stock, earnin l.ieooo Total . . . tlO.718 S» SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. • L REPORT SUPPLEMEN 1 A : Association (Serial or jK'rmanent Serial Serial I1"U 00 I'lan of As: ial or iN^rmaneDt -prlem Uiucd since nrcanizs I during fiscal year - 188 w s matured durinff fiscal year ■ None urithdrawn during I 'M ' running stock in force at this date Mi if full paid stock in force at thi- None M w No. of shares luaned on ... 11* shares on which dues are delintiueni .. 10 N IU m which du*s are delimiueat nun's subtect to cancellation for nonpayment of d -liar™ Mihjtvi to cancellation for nonpayment of due- .. None None Total amount nf dues delinquent at this date • *. W3 50 Total amount of dues delinquent ut thi^ date 3i50 2144 Am.'ui; hareholders 32 50 Amount of ' shareh' Amount of ititerest. premiums and tines due and unpaid -1 44 :imi Amount of interest, pren: nnpaii No of mortjiaires »u .'rebate amount of same. No. [kKgregate amount of same. So. inortgatfes subject I tnd the aggregate amount of same il aggregate amount of amf ins on Improved real estate 9,075 00 9,075 00 ADDraweu value of lmpr n which loans have been madf IS.TO 1 ! 00 . ed real estate upon which loans have been made 1S.7OI 00 Ap,, ril II 000 00 nt of loans upon ui ilMMM None II 000 00 None t uf loans upon uni Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made None Appraised value of unimproved real t Amount of insurance in f &gt;n which loans have beeD made None Amount of .ion as collateral security 110,500 00 is collateral security tlO.600 00 No. of loans made for bui, e* durlnu fiscal year • i .f homestead morttraces during fiscal year t acea duriRK nscal year t Amount of . None Amouir iuringfl None No oft" No of borrowing stock hole 15 No. of non-borrowing stockholders 77 No of minors holding stot-k in the Association '9 19 Average rate per &lt;*"' °' Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 10 Average rate per cent of interest charged b» rowers during fiscal year. &gt;orrowers during fiscal ye Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal ym Somt Plan of premium. ■ No«e Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year . None Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year. . None Amount &lt;&gt;f ning st&lt;x-k during fiscal - .. 348 05 Sis U5 Amount of dividends d™ 1 *^ &lt; JJ, fu ( j^J!| r^ t d^r in 1U fls e ' a f %f r y ' No^ MB Amount of dividends declared on full paid k during fiscal yea ring flv. fiscal year matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 SOCIAT1UNS BUILDING STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LAUREL, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June. 1905. OFfK l.liv ...President re- President Secretary Treasurer &lt;.IV WILSON 1)1 K EC'TORS. C F FDBLBY C. E. NEVIK. W. T. GRAHAM. UY WILSON li. S.U F P. VoTth ISSE1 ■». B mortgage k&gt;aus In process of fuf Purouan and stationery Delinquent . um.s auu lin&lt; Kxpen-*"- anu ta»r- j.anj N Tula; I I Mill II ll&gt; k running (Dues and dividends N -Ne ice totei ett and premiunu -• and premiums No 31 nlple«&gt; tKKLBER . . GRAHAM VOTER . . . n lncotnp.tric </seg>
            <seg id="p085">85 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDINi JUNE 30, 1905. ECEIPT8. Hjiiunce on Ii.umI July 1. 1 UN None Duel i Kunnini.' st Uui- (F U •--.■ I « i.v&gt; is 1 ») V ship iirnl transfer fet *£- Loan repu Real estate ,u EX I IN I) I I iti:s. Wilt ,3 18 IS M IT SI Pl'LEM NTAL UF.I'&lt; iRT K Plan of Ass Serial tlUU iu r sh N 3 M No 3IA No N 76 None N - N M S .aid anfi) on N u A N N -trait- ami .irfgreK-ul'. t5 iso no . &gt;ie upon which loans bare been mude..-. \ hich loans hare b^en a ■i uion as collater:i : Homestead n»in«»-s during fiscal year 4 Nothing ■s A ; ion :&gt;orrowers during fiscal yen borrowers during tlscal 041 Hid Ha Am Am Am al rear </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TIIE AMERICAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905, hi i i&lt; i us Bnvrr . LANL I»II1K&lt; liii;«. W. A SF.LLKCK. FARXHAM J H. WltSTCOTT, A. W. I.ASE E. H. MARSHALL Firs: mortKurt li.an Ffi»i atimji' lo*ns In process of for. ma Hf». MM ure mini s'aUufcei j ■rt Intenwt pramlkmt »od Ones hp»»». ana l*-o» paw Total II .IT Capital stock running (Due* ud divi.lenn- KuU paid Moek Dtteakar* koktecB on ic;omple«e loan* AdTsore iaiiat b&gt;\ pmnlums Qtvu liaotUuca </seg>
            <seg id="p087">BUILDING AND LOAH ASSOCIATIONS 87 j RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. RhCEIPTS. Balance on hand Ju'v ' . 1 901 k) Membership ar, I^oanR repaid . Real .-stilt Tot I Ml V III Tl RES. II0.M II Other expen Withdrawals, dur Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, earning 1 Full puid stuck, due* Full paid stock, earning: Ca»h on ban nm Earnings pmid 41 M MM SUPPLEMEN T AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent permanent 1100 00 :i.- of each snare oi No of series Issued since organization No of shares in force at tbis date BE since ortfanizatior ng Use «! in*r fiscal year S3 hare* ma IS* withdrawn during fiscal ji if running stock in force at th 1&gt;U 1175 &gt;f full paid stock in force at ib m lat&lt; No. of shares loane s» No. of shares on which dues are delinquent 139 to cancellation for non-payment of dues. rt ■ anil the and uni )rt k T and ate amount of Mini the aggregate amount of same No. nf mortgages In i none M im of loans on improve' 45,210 00 Apprais' il va ue of impi i ite upc w i&gt;een ma: uprovement in '.nun; pon which loans have been mede Amount of insurance in force and a be Association as collaterdi itv No. c f loans made for hi. ur ax fiscal year. .tans made for payment or hume mortgages during fiscal year all other &gt;r purchase Amount of advance payments of loans duriE •&lt;TrowintJ ki fiscal year irrowera during fiscal Tear., borrowers during fiscal j car none at year ring fiscal Tear. ock ilurinK fiscal year ... itock during fiscal year . during fiscal year all running stock 8 per cent, fully paul. T per cent A Vf ruift ruiining time of stock matured during fiscal year .no running stock mat u ret! I «6 7J (,.•■-« to II. MB! §1 r ill paid stock - ■ Total amount of dues delinquent at this date — Amount of dues owing bv borrowing scareholde Amount of tat* i ? due and No. of non-i No of minors boldinu stock tn ■ nt 01 premiums chained Amou: rve fund during tlsc harired to reseive fund di ■ n running si Am-&gt;- n full paid : </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 STATEMENT OP THE CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA CENTRAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of Juae, 1903 OFFICERS. HOMKK K BUBKRT J(»HN GIBSON Vice Presideu M \V FOLSOM Secretary BURKET Treasurer :.::::::Man ager ofA^c niBKCTons. x ARD, T JC. BURKliT M. W. FOLSOM JOHN GIBSON' HOMER K. BUKKET V^-l I- &gt;nuiii:e lmiofi in process of fore Office and oft i BS9*Mai .in. i l;,x. - paid T. LIABILITIES. k running. (Dues and dlviden.l OMJM 49 hit 123 87 apleteloc univ unt-arij- raal and premium </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 UUILMSG AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YF.AK ENDING JUNE 30, 1905 KMKIUS Balance 01 band July I, 1 t 28 217 MM H ' &gt;:■ t \PKNnlTI RR1 I SUPPl v MENTA I. ItKI'i HI I r Pi Penrno' nt X w A r ■)f s»m &gt;unt of sum amount N the aggregate an in w &gt;ans have ■ 1 1 pstai n which loa: ■ - M nfm during B :ti year loans during fiscal year N N durfn? fiscal •ar -■•M borrowers during flst-ai year Amttut- '-fund durfn? fiscal year Amount rve fund during Hscal year ; during fiscal year, 9 per cent pi An Bk during fiscal ye r. 6 per eent per no ninths </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 BUILDING AND LOAN AS8OCIATION9 STATEMENT Or THE COSIUTIOIC OF TUB SECURITY SAVINGS &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. hi i i' W. A. POVNTER President L. C. OBERL1ES Vice President I. H. HATFIELD Secretary W. E. JAKWAY Treasurer I. H HATFIELD Attorney OIRKCTORS. W. A. POYNTOR, L. C. OUKKL1ES. W. E. JAKWAY I. H. HATFIELD, W. E. LOWER. ASSETS. First morurrw loans I son oc Pint miintwc lowi in prooos of for' Stock lows . u K- :,. '--■»;'- uuce Furniture and Statiouery Cuk MHO if* 30 none Delinquent Interest, premiums and fine* lipmii and taxes paid 3® Other »»^els none Total •813 75 LIABILITIES. Capital stork running. (Dues and dividends) Full puiil Mock ( 45 00 uu Reserve fund n&lt; Dnaivided proflts. ■ Due akare holders on Incomplete loaas Prrmiumf unearned 5 Advanre due* Adrmnoe interest aad ptemiums </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 BlILbl.M. AM) LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 80, 1906. KKCEIPTS. Ila];ince on band July 1, 1904 RunninK stock* i ( 45 in TOO UO none none none « m none Ijoatis r«-p; none ttooe Tut $m:i 7S EXPENDITIRES. I ?00 0O none m&gt;ne 67 45 none none Withdrawals, due Withdrawals raruini Matured - none &amp;one none none Matured stock, earning; Full paid, stock, due* Full paid stock, earning! Cash on hand «M 31) Total. •813 TS SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of Association (serial or permanent) permanent Par value of each share of stock ... $ me uu No- of series issued since organization if serial / No of shares in force at this date \ta No. of shares issued since organization 1M No of shares issued during fiscal year \m No. of shares matured during fiscal jear Boat No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year bob* No. of shares of running stock in force at thi-- date lil No. of shares of full paid stock in foroe at this date 7 No of shares loaned on j No. of shares on which dues ar« delinquent. MM No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues mm Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders . none Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid. bom No. ot mortgages subject to foreclosure and the aggregate amount of same. No. . soae No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate ... (300 oo Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans nave been made ; Appraised value of improvements H00 00 Amount of loans UDon unimproved real estate none Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loaa* have boan ankle none Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security 100 00 No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year none No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year none No. of borrowing stockholders none No. of non-borrowing stockholders if No of minors holding stock in the Association No. of minors holding stock in the Association.. MM Average rate per cent of interest charged borrower* utiring u*o*i &gt;t«w Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year. Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fikval year. Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal yea* Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal yeax .... Average running time of stock matured daring nscal year. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 BUILDINO ADD LOAN ASSOCIA STATEMENT Of TOE CONDITION OV TUB MADISON BUILDING &amp; SAVING ASSOCIATION MADISON, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1903. OKFII I K» PETER RUBENDAU President S. JENSEN Vice President H H. MAI.ONV Secretary Treasurer DIKKCTOR8 M F. THOMAS VF1LEY HAWKINS JACOB HENDERSON. A. SCHWAXK \»M I- Flrn Bon^uc lou (14.700 00 Done W Furniture and sUtionerr * ■ w W ■ LIAIMLIT1ES. runnine (Ilu, c r icomr 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE I 4.0OT 7» n. noi ,o J10.4TI IT N.TH 00 payment* . Total -i\ or permanent) 257 10 tiO^irTTr SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT 117 &lt;7 'n matured d i withdrawn ■ ■ -hart-s of running . _ - of full paid stock fn force at this data .■I on l it* i S !.;c? .™ MdaD « due and unpaid ne aK^-Ttvate aniouni of same, A same. v 1 ;*«rreg»ie amount of same ntof same 14 too on e upon which loans have been which 1&lt; inn. have be ■ . r ion aa collateral security 12.600 00 ■ Amour'' urinKBical . D " r "' No of bo m, -s during fi» Arer»»fe rale per cent of premium* chaived borrowers ilurins tiscal vear Pl»n of premium Amount credited to resprv.- fund duri- ,. ~&gt; Amount of li&gt;s»e» &gt;•■ * ™ 'lackl'nar' ' »■&gt; Amount of dividend- Average rate per cent of dividt : fiscal year. . Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 120 -"rmfcj </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 BUILDING AMD LOAN A88OCIA STATEMENT Or THE CONDITION OF TI1« MADISON COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION MADISON, NEBRASKA, On the 30tb day of June, 1905. orn&lt; i m KSNYDER GRANT GEU. E. RICHARDSON ARTHUR P. PILGER. DIRECTORS C S SNYDER, OEO E. RICHARDSON, J L. GRANT. F. A. MATSOH Firat mongngt lo«* BMortcsire lonnv in pro4*»«« of foreclow lO»Bk Rnl ouu ure and •utiooer: •-Bt lnterent. premiums aod tine' T»iei- wle eertiBcsles Toui! LIABILITIES Capital naek raonlac iDjh and dlrldcudi i-ull paid stock K&gt; Roerrr fund tTDdivi.ici pr^'ftt*. 1.3 Dae share huldii on UcoB^lete l—m* HrfaiuniN uieirnfld .... .V: ■■ .*iji-&lt; duei Advuwe Interest and premiun-- </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS KKCKIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1906. RECEIPTS. Balance on band Julv 1, 1904. Dues (Kunnir.e stock) Dues (Pull paid stock) Interest Premiums Fines 47&lt;-H SI Membership and transfer Loans repaid 3.SS.' « Keal es Rents . Tax certificate To DH« EXPENDITURES. Loam ■ Co mm I Other exp Withdrawals Withdrawals, eurni Matured stock, due: Matured stock, earnings. Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand "5: Tax certificates.. Real estate Total $10,914 16 SUPPLEMEN r AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent Serial tsooo Par Talue of each share of stock No. of series issued since organization (if serial X! No. of shares in force at this date MM 1W7S No. of shares issued s&gt;nce organization. No. of shares issued during fiscal year 36 No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at ihis date N No of shares loaned on No of shares od which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues ■ Total atnuunt of dues delinquent at this date. li Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders .... Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid wing by borrowing shareholders l of in No of mortgages subject to foreclosure and the aggregate amount of same. No., 8 of foreclosure and the aggregate amount of same »f mor ■a proved real estate LtMOt 00 veil real estate upon which loans have been tj ,* Apprai&gt;ed value of improved rea n unimproTedreal « - u r. unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made ... ' to the Association as collateral security 30,450 00 No. of for building purposes during fiscal year No of loans mad** for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year. . t Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year $4,800 ( No. of borrowing stockholders ifc No. of borrowinK stockholders No. of non-torruwing stockholders 41 No of minors holding stock in the Association 13 Average rate per cent of interest charged horrowers during fiscal year. Average rule per cent of premiums charged borrowers during ti- Plan of premium Monthly Amount -eserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year None Amount of.: nintf stock during fiscal year M5 03 Amonnt of *i: ■ red on full paid stock during fiscal year ■ None Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year r stock matured during fiscal year... . None n A\ </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 STATEMENT Or THE CONDITION OF THE rOOK CO OPERATIVE BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION McCOOK, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. OF* k » iiv r. B. CAMPBELL BENNETT \;rcl 'resident t A. PEN N EL Secretary KHOKUKIMSON . ELDRED '.Treasurer Attprney DI.1WTIIKS W. s. PtKRV F. M. KIMMELL J E. KELLEY. J A. WI W B. MILLS, E. HAN ON GEO B. BERRY First manmm !":irj &gt;rt«itge loans, in process ot fort X ureand gtal 4 :■&gt; T LI « HI I ITIKS. running (due !&lt;&gt;nd N ■i lncompii i Premium" uD.iirn.il N Adv&amp;ooe Inierrst and premium * ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 BUILDING AND LOAN VT1ONS VEAR RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE KISt Al KNDIXG JUNK. 30, 1905 RECKIPT&amp; nand Julv 1. 1901. II. or hull paid si .i ■ a T 1 Ml MUll RES • w ss aruin, rn^-s I.SUOOO 1&lt; SUPPLEMENTAL REPi »K I Plmn of Association ( - - Jiare of stoc ■ issued slnee organ ■ HMW 19. 10* 7S a Uhilrawn d 1257 ,t this &lt;1at of running stock in force lit this d»M -hares of full paid stock in force at thU d»t (ianetl on No of shftres on which dues are deling u&lt; ni No of - -paymeot of c None W7 00 Total anio ,» Amoun' ; S,,'..!m."..-a.-' : -■' ' - lor.e- v,r&lt; lad tk* wttri't-atc smoant of ma*. N" !••■( No of mortoces ta proee&gt; 'gate amount ef same. — ■ ; r«T-«Ii a value of imi' tale upon which loans have been m;i value of improvement* .V'.** 1 n No"of D loaiw nude for building purpo*.- ioi« SS? for payment ot ho^tead morttaw during ascal jear. 7.M 04 No of borr. No. of i. i Ho of n •&lt; in the Association ■ -&lt;resl charged borrowers durintr flsc. Averat'e rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year 9 !&gt; I premium ■•■d to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses char •&gt;■' I to reserve fund during fiscal year red on running stock during fiscal year li 01 5,(X1 Amount of dividends d clare-i on full paid *tock during fiscal yaar AvanMt r»tti i**r ci-nt of iivhk-uds deoiured during ns&lt;*»l vear. .", (J r'liitunc i ' ' s mulurtii i.iuriDf.' fiscal \fiir </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 BUILDING AND LOAN \T1ONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA, On the 3Ctb day of June, 1905 OFFICERS. HENRY FASTENAl M SELZER Vice President W H HITZER H. F MEYER.. W H. PITZER Secretary Treasurer Attorney DIRECTORS. H. F. MIYER. JNO. W. STEINHART, S. T. DAVIES, W. A. HADER, W. W. MKTZ. E. H. BUHLM AN E. U. MUELLER, J W. BUTT, W. H. PITZER ummwn. Flrat morteage lo»ns Flret rourunce loins in procets c Stack loam. if fore. !osur&gt;- Furniiure and ttatlonenr Caab Dellnqornt lntereat EipeuM-k and taxea paid T ax Certiflcates. ■ Total 182,550 9) LIABILITIES. Capital stock r&lt; nning (Durt&gt; Full paid stock •42.147 00 . dcd proBU lers on incomplete Premiums unearned . loan^ Advance interest and premiums DiTided Proflta </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1906. RECEIPTS. Jtelance on hand July 1, 1SXM I«.7» 9* Mint so 10,838 H llakince on hand Julv 1, 10O4 -inninn stock) . . Does (Running stock) ... 10,838 86 K i Full paii ■t lull paid stocti Interest 3,347 IS i m ».• Premiums Ift S&gt; Premium 1» a&gt; Fines 1 ■&gt; I HO Membenhip and transfer 1-e* M Si Membership and transfer It I...ativ repaid M » Loms repaid 6.452 SI 6.452 SI Rt-al estate sales Rt-al estate sal Rents M» 16 308 18 Total KXTKNIHTI KE.S. BXPKM IHH l!K-i Loans . IIS.771 M IIS.77I M I.. 812 to en km Commlssiims Commission Other expense-- ''*"' -0 M ;o eipen Withdrawals, dut's 3.R76 QU Withdrawals, dues un «i Withdraw^! 6T2 « ana Matur*M stock, ttu* 1 J» M 2» M Matured slock, ear: ■.. ITS S7 IT- J7 Full paid »u Full paid stock, earnings. Full paid stock, eai Cashonham; «,1&lt;« «• Cash on hui Real estate improvements N A Total ■ BDPPLRMENTAL REPORT. f Association {Serial or permanent i [•• :■• Tot AL REPORT i-iation (Serial or permanent' !'• n ♦-0J M •k f.&lt;v&gt; M ution, (if seri i -sued since organization, (if serin :n force at this date 1.037 1.0* ■ rganization - J. .'«? . ■ - issued during fiscal year IM - hares niiituml during Aacil year ... S hares withdrawn during fiscal year 1*8 of rui ninw stock in force at this d»te 1037 No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this en £•'" Km which (Jum are delinquent in for nonpayment of dues ii nonpayment of duel Total amount of dues de; A moUTi i ' art-holders None Amoun md unpaid 917 »* So. of i(^ amount of same. No 15 «.0» S .nd the aggregate amount of same Note ana on imp- »,38» 57 Appraised value of improved n n which loans have been made Ti Appru, about 50,0 "0 00 A uf loans upon unu 75 00 K,Ked vaiue of unimpro\*-.i real e-tau upon which loans have been made.... 550 Ou ntof insurance in f oolUteral security 57, '200 00 Amount of insurance in foi ans made for building purposes during fl&gt;i 1U No. of loans made for payn ent of homestead mortraces during fiscal year- 21 Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year 5,050 00 No of borrowing stockholders 78 No. of non-borrowing st&lt;»ckholders — 19 No. of minors holding stock in the Association it Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 9.6 Arenuce rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Amoun! • e fund during fiscal year 15&lt;J ft io reserve fund during fiscal year 2M M Amount of &lt; ..irod on running stock during fiscal year 2.844 33 Amount of dividend* declared on full paid stock during fiscal year : ter cent of dividends declared during fiscal year *K itft running time of stock matured during fiscal year IB months </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NELSON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION NELSON, NEBRASKA On the 30th dav of June, 1905 01 i ii i R8 DIKKCTORK. OOWBCH. .IB. E. D BROWN l.. j. n ASSETS jreclosure I. ' I.I A11II.ITIKS. runiiinu. (Du«s and divi ■ck EGOODUCH.. RT VOX JK... V STOMBB H\ B . BHOWN IB. E. D BROWN, C. R STON'ER. I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 tl RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL VKAK ENDING JUNK SO, 190S UK 'El ITS. II July I, ISXH I.U* « Kull paid st-.i I M U I \I-I.MiI1I Kl -. u 7110 DO IHUOO -n m 97 ma urn » SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. -■rial or permanent l» ntlon II a i 17 2-2) 1 Ai um » " A :m.s ha\ of insurance in force and asMuneil to the A- ir one luring luri I p r cent or pren: itn iwersduriui! I s= m </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION! STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB NUCKOLL8 COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NELSON, NEBRASKA, On the 80th day of June, 1905 OFFICERS. CBO. LYON Jr. . T W. COLE IMLEK :Y FOX Jb E U BllOWN.. .Vice-president Secretary Treasurer Attorney III KM TOIIS. OBO. LYON Jb E. D. BHOWS H. E. GOODRICH W. W. HAWLEY, J. T. DYSANT F. E. BOTTKNKIf.LD Wm. A. VOIGT, THOS. GRAHAM VELTK. Pi rat mortgage loan I m Bmorvcage luuu la process of foreclocure losus Furnilurv sud &gt;i«l.i.nery — fi»Mn]»ti«t Interest, prpmiums aud one Kzpeaan »nd Uixes psid OiketHWU TOUU 1.IAHI1.IT1KS. ■ml stock running (Dues sod diridends) paid stock f 73.50 fund .rrtaolden ud iuoompleM loan* Premiums unearned Advance iuteiest sad pt«miuuu ASMOT*. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 80, 1906. KECKIPTS. KECEIPTS. Halance on band July 1, 1904 Dues ( Runni wr stock i Ba:;incf on hand July i. 1904. Dues (Runnlm? stock) .... 736- Dues (Full paid stock). . Dues (Full paid stock Interest Interest M Premiums . Premiums Fines Kines Membership and transfer tew Membership and trans: Loans repaid Loans repaid Real estate sales Real estate sales Rents Rents Advance dues. .. ■ Total Advance due B* T'.ta: KXI'ENDITl'RKS. EXI'EX HI II MS. Loans Loans Salartei Commi: Salaries . ... Commission^ Other ex penses ... Withdraw Withdrawals, due^ Withdrawal^ Withdrawals, earnimp Mature.i &gt;t.*:k du.-&gt; Matui Matu Full I- Full paid ■ Fuil I Fuil pu Cash on hand Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPOR1 SI7 6. Total IMO ■ SUPPLKMKN I AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanentj Par value of each share of slock No. of h -ince organization (I li No. of shares i is date S7fl No. of shares Issued since organization 378 No.ofsharesis.su- al year jts .ires matured during fiscal year .ares withdrawn during fiscal jri iff Noll* ■. force at this d»tr 376 . paid stock in force at this date None .... 4 '.ares on which dues are delinquent . . 10 I to cancellation for non-payment of dues None Total ;n '" •!&amp; 00 Amour. -T- Amount • f Fnti 1 fines due and unpaid. No. of mortgages su: i he aggregate amouul of mw No. of morura^es in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same Somt Amount of loans on Improved real estate MM 60 Appraised n --A real estate upon which loans have been made M ■ Apprn 1. IOt 00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate.. None Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have b Amount of insurance in force and assigned : aion as collateral security MOM No. of loans made for building purposes ilor No. of i.ians made for payment of homestead riiurt*ai.'rs during fiscal year. 1 fiscal year None Amount of advance payment- of loans durl: XIrt nt luirr.ili'inL' tit ■ &gt;!' I; h . i ' I \f T^ No. of borrowing stockholders I No. of non-borrowing stockholders 41 No of minors holdine stuck in the Association . .. S Average rste per cent of interest charged borrowers during nscal yea Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during nscal year. None Pi an of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year. . . . Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . . . Amount of di i iderids declared on full paid stock during nscal year . Arerage rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TOT NEWMAN (iUOVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY NEWMAN (JKOVK. NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. III! i&lt; kks. A I HODMAN. . LETHEBT ( \ KANDAIX. E H GBKHABT. &lt; A RANDALL. . PtmIiI-i Vice President Secretary Treasunr ..Attorney III 111 CTORS. II MAN. THEBY C A. RA.S'DAI.I. E H. (IK BOBKBT I'. PEARSON. S M JI . int mortCM* lt»Ds in pnirw ■■ of for Stock k&gt;Bi K&lt;-al MtM J j I i &gt;. « ;itiii tDK**- \i r j»~&lt;-t~ K.-..1 -*i»l LIABILITIES. K ruiniDg. (Duas sad dividend mptele loan* it tfcDd prrmiuu. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 IMS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 80, 1906 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 BCILD1NG AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TTIB ELKHORN BUILDING &amp; SAVINGS ASSOCIATION- NORFOLK, NEBRASKA. On the 80th day of June, 1905. OFFK H. J. COLE Presided A DEGNEU Vice-president T E ODIORXE W. A WITZIUMAN XresAurt r DIRECTORS. I M. C. B. J. COLE A. DEGKER, WALKER. H. C. MATRAU T. E OPIOKNE ALKER. F. K. DAVENPOKT AHET8. ASMTs First mortoce loans Pint morttrw Imh 52- SM uo Done S-3(O First mortgag* loans In process of foreclosure Fint mort«*s« loans In process of for&lt; Stock loana . Beal esi»u- . -re»n&lt;l Stationery ture and Sutloner Delinquent li.v ■■■::, urns and Hues Delinquent Mums sod II I4SS1 Certificate of deposit l.ioo U) County warn. 4«0lC ReaJ e*tate contract 182 10 T.n. i-».o«» i.iahii n ii s. Capital stock running. (Dues and diridends) U Ddl Tided profl si! "."."!!!!"!!!!!" '. '.'.'.'. Dweahare holders on Incomplete iouns ........... i ▲draDoe Interest sod premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. RKCKIIT*. Balance on band July I. 1904 Dues, i It n nn in* stuck &gt; Dues. (Pull pidst Premiums Fines Membership and trans: Leans repaid Heal estate sa T K\ I-KNDITI RES. Loan« Sulwtrii CororaissK Other exjx Withdrawals. dtMM Withdrawals rarnin Matured stock, dues Mauir** itock. earn ng: Kull m"' itock. nn Full paid stock, earnini. Cash un hand . . . Bought certificate Bought warrants Tuta] SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Pi of Association (aerial or permanent value of each share of stock No. of series issued since organization (if ser a: No of shares in force at this date No. of shares Issued since organization Bof shares issued during nscal year of shares matured during fiscal year of shares withdrawn darin* of shares of running stock in for of shares of full paid stock in fore- at it: f shares loaned on No of shares on which dues are del; • No *&gt;r sh»r-s -ubjeei to canceli* ~ Total • Amount of does owing bj Amount of interest, premiums and tines :ue ;md unpaid No. of mortgages i •'closure and the aggregate amount of same. No. No. of mortgages In process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of kam Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have bees made Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans UDon unimproved rea Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been ■■ Amount of insurance in foroe and assigned b the Association as collateral 17^1 ... rily No. of loans made for building purposes dur: No of loans made for payment of homesteac og fiscal year.. . . « mortgages daring fiscal Tear 3 Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year 5.500 00 No. of borrowing stockholders J9 No. of non-borrowing stockholders SB No. of minors holding stock in the Association 3 A Terage rate per oent of interest charged borrowers . in rim: ti - 0 per cent Average rate per oent of premiums charged borrowers during li • Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year &amp; per cent of nrotlta Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year none Amount of dirtdeads declared on running stock during fiscal year "percent Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year. I per ,-ent Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running tine of stock matured during fiscal year. Rests Warrant* paid Tax oertiflcale: </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION' OK TUE NORFOLK BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION NORFOLK. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1905. 01 i i&lt; i i; LEX BEAK. ( li DL'KLANU. Pr. Vioi' President = HAZEN lilltl &lt; TOI : ALK, J. A. WILLEY DEAN. AN AFFORD, OS :abuhle B. CHB1STOPH DK. A I. EN A* I T- F"lr«t n. : &gt; M I I \ I'.ll ITU 46 .L, </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 EIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE r. V ENDING JUNE 30, 1 RKC EIPTS Ju I *4 an »l Fine Men Lou s B IM M I XPEX in i:tv H Witndrawj Wllhdrawi M.itun-il sti mi . Ins Prc 347 -M 8DPPI EM EN I AL HKI '( )K 1 Plan of Assi ■ial or pern ■h share of si ■■ Nc No N UC.1 (1 «!S N.) iatured duriiu is No indrawn dur Ml ruunn , »oir full paid stock in for No. of shart dat No. of st mat which dues are deliri N. mrnt of 5 inquen Sorrow u Ai: Amou . lums and f.- unpaid »'?h vi» Al N\ ite amount of same. No. 1 4lm&gt; 00 3 amount of rule amount in. N 1 No. o: cm of foreclosurf, and the aggregate amountof same — none No same Amount &lt;-t lnuns on improved r&gt; Appr.. " ai estate upon which loans have been made 34.MU Otf ;ate upon which loans have been made 112440 00 ll-J4f(l UO Amount of loans up&lt;»n unimpruved real estate none up* in unimj.r Appr ipon which loans have been made l upon which loans have been made Amount of in-uriincein forcf and a.vot.*nr«l to the Association as collateral security 86.190 00 ■macs In force and &amp;a he Association as collateru No of loans m;nle for building purpo-^-s during fiscal year 6 X le for building pur ng fiscal year « ur No. of loans maile for payment of homestead mortgages during fi&amp;tu none No. of loans mude for payment of taon iiiorti-'iiges during tlscol yaar n Amount of advance payments of loans during Hscal year ,nce payments of louus duric tisciil year No. of borrowing stockholders ]W stockholders No. of borrow! e IK No. of non-borrowiu 107 No. of non-borr 197 No. of minors holding stock in the Association 30 No. of minors h Average rate pe t ceot of interest charged iwers during fiscal year 10 per cent Average rate pe t cent of premiums charged b arrowers during tiscal year 1 per cenj level Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year .50 UO Amount of loaaM charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stuck during fiscal year t.Wl 13 Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal j ear none Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year. . Aver time of stock matured during tiscal rear 10 yean and ; months *&gt;*&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 Or THE CONDITION OF THE NORTH LOUP, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. OFFIf eus EMMET LOVE. a. t. torn i E J. BAI'.' GBU 8 MAYO. BABCOCK V i-f-Presidaiit ft I— !■ Attorney Him &lt; Toll S. MAYO A. i W. THORNUATE. ■MVIE Y DANS T». ' loan* in prongs uf (..rt urns and fii LIAKII I I I I - •dt interest and dues r v Full i i --d profits. Total * PremiumH unearned Advance dues AdTanoe Interest .u,,: premlun « STATEMENT NORTH LOUP BCILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION orunge loan* in p Kxpenanuu ,t«l exp. Capital slock runni.NK Inn ud rtividpudsi de </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1906. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand JuIt 1, \90i.. Balance on hand Jul? 1, I004 Dues (RunniDR stock) Dues (Full paid stock) Dues (Running stock) Dues (Full paid stock) Premiums Premiums Membership and tr. Membership and In Loans repaid Lotos repaid Real estate sit Heal estate Examination Abstrat : - Total Examination Abstracts Total lAI'IMHTIKKs. I Ml N in TURKS. amimrle* '.'.'..I'..".'.'.'. Examination Abstr . Examination Abstrs Other expenses ... . Other expenses Withdrawals, dues . . Withdrawals, du&lt; IiJrawals, earnings red stock, dues red stock, earnings paid stock, dues paid acock, earnings. Withdrawals, earnings . ■ Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings • 'ash. on hand: Treasurer's hands, $47. 1 1 ; Secretary's hands, $37.9( ■i on hand : Treasurer's hands, |4' certificates arj's hands, U7.9U Tax certificates Real estate Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Tot tl.MS *S SUPPLEMEN T AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent) Plan of Association (Serial or permanent) permanent Par value of e -&gt;tock Par value or - : stock No. of aeries Issued since organization (if serial) No. of aeries issued since organization (if sen not serial a: No of shares in force at this date No of shares In force at this date No. of shares issued since organization. No. of share* issued during fiscal year 61 No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year No of shares withdrawn during fiscal year No of shares withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this date • ares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at thi ■ lares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares loaned on No of shares loaned on H No of shares on which dues are delinquent No of shares on which dues are delinquent 11 .ares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 3 V i of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date.. mount of dues delinquent at this date. 118 00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders ues owing by borrowing shareholde A. m Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid, no delir fines and «: Auount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid, no delinquent interest fines and dues ■■ No. of mortgages subject to foreclosure and the aggregate amcmnt iubject to foreclosure an he aggregate amoant of sa-ne, N No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure and the aggregate a No. of mo; 'oreelosu the aggregate amount of same il estate , al estate Appr.i. -iii estate upon which loans have been made in- ft] estate upon which loans have s , ins upon unimproved real estate ie of unimproved real estate upon which loans have ed to the Association as col unimprov at ■iroved real estate upon which loons have been made — M i^rnetl to the Association as collateral security 3.I5U 00 uk purposes during fiscal year No. of 1" rig purposes during fiscal year No. of loa No. of it :injc purpose^ during fiscal year No of loans mail* 1 for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year. . 4 No of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during flu Amount of advance pavments of loans during fiscal year Amount of advance pavments of loans during fiscal year No of borr. No of b. era No of n&lt; 41 No of n - stock in the Association the Association Average rate per cent of interest charged sorrowers during fiscal Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during ftsn Average r*te per cent of premiums charged borrowers during Umm Plan of premium fund during fiscal year B&gt;f pr^'mium &gt; reserve fund during fiscal year Amount rve fund during fiscal year i reserve fund during fiscal year Amount red on running stock during fiscal year &gt;red on full paid stock during fiscal year ividends declared during fiscal year A: # time of stock matured during fiscal year. </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 ; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION OF THB MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. OFF1CKRS. •Use. PATTERSON.. Pre»ide D t KRANK K. HL'LLAKL) Treasurer WIL-COX&amp;HALL1OAN Attorneys DIRECTORS IRA L BARK, J. F. CLABAUGH. GE W. FINN. ARTHUR MrNAMARA M RANNIE FRANK T. REUMO THOMAS C. PATTERSON. JAME VICTOR VON GOETZ, LESTER WALKER tatm *J0«. Pamlture and stationery Delin&lt;)u«t)t Interest, premiums an&lt; Exp«oses aad uues paid Total li a mi ITIE9. Capital stock running (does and divldeadx rail paid stock ■■mil f ) CDrtlvid«-i proBw Daeskan holders on Incomplete loans ajAssjBM itu-rt-&gt;i prfiniums BTOR VON GOBTZ. President DELOUUZKE Secretary Pint aiortcwe toMt Pint nortoce loans in process of foreclosure </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL TEAR ENDING JUNF. 30, 1905. KEOEII'T Balance on hand Julv 1, 1 Dues (Runnimr Kto i ull pa -ras Membership and trai Koiiiis repaid Real estate sales Other expen Iidrawals, dues . . Kir;iwals. earnin ■ red stock, dues, ired stock, earni paid slock, due&gt; Full paid stock, earnin, r*-»h on hand I7J»W 3 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT I'lan of Assc elation (Serial or permi i. 1905, thence the Da&gt; ton plan Par value of since onraniut , ires in Jurce at tb;- liuring fiscal year liJ.s matured during Use No. or shares withdrawn during flsc.il year li* No. of shares of running stock in km at rrm No of shares of full paid stock in force at this date »JJ4 No of shares loaned on 75IH No of shares on which dues are delinquent 4rt No' of shares subject to cancellation for non- payment of dm 6 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date HO «u Amount of dues owing bj borrowing shareholders M •• Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid. 101 » No of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 1.SU0 ft) No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same No.! „„ no Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been mail Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Kised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made None Qt of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security 131 ,!A5 00 E loans made for building purposes during Hscal year loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during nscal tear £! nt of advance payments of loans during fiscal year. Average per month 806 u) No of Dorrowing stockholders is« No. of non-borrowing stockholders 1 W No. of minors holding stock in the Association 4 Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during flacal year 6 Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal raw Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal rear Knt of dividends declared on running slock during fiscal year . :'\20C 49 nt of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year N'ooe Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year. . . Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 STATEMENT OF Tilt CONDITION Or TDE BANKERS' SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NEBRASKA, ollll t Hi P. CRONK. President W D UNO )LN Vice-President -MITH. Secretary L H. KOKTY .Treasure TUoS D. CRANE Attorney DIKKCTOKS. JOSEPH 8YKES JAMES AIN »W, FRANK U. .1 J. D. FOSTER HERMAN PETfcKS A«tT». First morttwre loans in process of fore&gt; lo-ure Stock lt»n&lt; MM m «4 I Fomiture »nd iui : uent laterest, premiums and n Expaoaes sod uia pan! OUier As-:- Tutal LIAB11 .11 IKS. Carrfttl stock running (Dues and dividends) Pull pmtd stock . . m IS CndiTKted proHte S Duraban-buldera on Incomplete loans . ii Advance Interest and premiums Stupatue account. Ob the 3Cth day of June, 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEirTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEA! ENDING JUNE 30, 1906. RKC EIPTS. flsJance on hand Julv 1, 1004 Doe* (Running stuck i 904 m l.'.-Ua 17 1.300 00 3.367 2* Does (Full paid Ist*rest Premiums Membership and tra Loan* repaid !■:■■&lt;■ oo Baal .-stai Tota: imjm io BXPKNDITI7KE3. 110 .*» 80 1.315 UO ■ Other upa Withdrawn 710 M I.*M i» 11,113 83 Withdru- - llalum! 3M 43 ■paid stuck, due paid stock, ear on hand 6'«) 00 s* * 1.174 OS )U I33.0M5 10 8UPPLEMEN \L I' El 'ORT Plan of Association (Serial or pern Permanent Par value of each share i ; i« -bares issued since organization Kiia i issued during fiscal year 0 21(1 -Uaresof ru' ■ TC« ill ■ikl NO. Of Sl: Ho -hares on which due iq E*r non] ■ U this date a T: an ■K rival J amount of same. Ko :e amount of &gt; ■ *if r which loan: have t&gt;een i! ins have been made . in as collati Amount "f icsuntm e he Asswi'ia! i H No of bormwmtr s: minors holding stock in the Associa » Avera-'e rate per cent of interest ch-ir^ owers durin M Average rule per cent of premiums charged Trowers during fiscal year Plar Amount cr*diied to reserve fund during fiscal yoar Amount of losses chartred to reserve fund du rig fiscal year •k during fN&lt;-;tl year ck during fiscal year iring fiscal year Amount of divi lends declared on full paid stt Average rate per cent of dividends declared d « Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 101 months ■imres Id force at tb hares matured durin* fiscal yea -Hares withdrawn durio* fiscal &gt;■( No. of skares of full pa MM i»&gt; 9UUU0 moru»rts - ■ uf loans up Appraised value of unnn -&gt;n whic No. of loans made fur builii _■ rival ye:ir No. of loans made for p*yn ent of homestead mortrases during r Amount of advanee payments of loun- during fiscal No. of non- borrow inif stockholdc Amount of &lt;iivi&lt;lcn&lt;ls declared on mnnir </seg>
            <seg id="p116">STATKMKST Of THE CONDITION OF THE iLVATIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION- OMAHA. NEBRASKA, On the 30tb day of June. 1905. Ol I Its Pro- K.rst Vice-Pn Secretary I.Mtl I TORS. KHA1RD. A. W. BOWMAN. RANDALL K BROWS, ROBERT DEM UILMOBE E. A liKN: First lMp|i i &gt;in First mortcmce lea - .lums a* ,1 tin .i i. uU- HOlU OD C Capital itock ninaing. (Due* and d ,aid stock. :i inoom Premiums, unearned Adranc* interest sad premium* . DERLAND I G1LMORE . nil VicePresiilent J. A SUND-KI-AN H. A C. R. URQUHART, CHAS. M WILHKLM. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 RECEIPTS AND KXPENDITUKKS FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1805. KMKII'T: Balance on hand Ju 17.U56 «3 I-rein (res m » Membership and trans SJTV!* Rial "SlBlt: ■ H To F m Ki:s. MM iM M ro I 1*..»7 f ■ PPLKMKNTAL REPORT i' « M ») N a ...Da 3U JO 4 i' Loan* rej&gt;; .mount or sa? -■att; amount </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. OFFICERS. CHAS P. SOUTHARD. President \V. J. CKKNYON Vire-President G M. N ACTING EB - . etary-Treasurer I'lllllTUIts. CHAS. E. REYNOLDS, THEO. L. RING WALT G. M. NATTINGER, CHAS. P. SOU I t W. J. RVSER CHAS. P. SOU I HARD. First mortgage loans Bmortfmce loans In procesi of fot real estate contract Furniture aod st. Delinquent Interest prvmiumi and u Expenaes and taxes paid Tula- LIABILITIES. Capital stock running (Dues and dirldends Fiill paid stock ■— fund Due abarebolders on Incomplete loan', l^rein iums unearned] Advance inteien and premiums Bill- parole 40F, &amp; aim W. J. C. KEKYON, '-ndlvid«-&lt;ll"-''fltB M '•u Adv»nc&lt;- &lt;iu&lt;-* </seg>
            <seg id="p119">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 119 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCA1 ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. RKCKIPTS. Balance on h*nd July I, 1904 Dues i Kutinni. MM 641. -:i Dues i Full paid Interest 4* M Premium: Fines Foreclo; Loans repaid Real estate sa Rents Hll n payable Suodr. Tota: I M-K.N li TURKS. I-oan Salarie Coma Other l wm 4.7M H Wutdnixi Withdraw mm F.xpenv Matur Full paid M. Full paid stuck, esrnin Cast on hao 190 SS 490 II 1UJM Foreclosures. Sundries Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent) Serial Par\- f stock "^unization &lt;if No. of shares issued since organization MM No. of share* tout*! durin. None No. of shares -^-al year •lares withdrawn during fiscal year fi#H No. of shares of running stock in force at this date -" No. of shares of full paid stock In force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of re delinquent -, -payment of dues Total amount ■! this date Ami.:. .haw-holders 1186 00 ind unpaid 615 10 No. of mortgages « "closure, and the aggregate amount of same. No 1 1.800 00 No. of niorurage^ in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on lmprored real estate.. ■ tS.000 00 Appr.i iil estate upon which loans have been made 2. W0 00 A ppr: i vements 2.500 00 Amount of loans up ed real estate Appnti real estate upon which loans have been mail Amount of insur.u iJ assigned u&gt; the Association as collateral security 2,700 00 No. of 1 »r buiUItntr purpt&gt;s»-s dnrin^ fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Amount of ad ' loans ouring fiscal year No. of borrow I No. of non-bor -4 No of minors holding stock in the Association Average rate | ..-harmed borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during nscal year Plan of premium Amoun* -pserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year H-6 "3 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amoun ? red on running stock during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Arerage rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA LOAN &amp; BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA, l» K KNNIS Treasurer HON. JOHN L. KENNEDY Attorney DIRECTORS. PRY. KOBERT S. WIL D R EXX JOHN' K BRANDT. H. VANCE LAXK, THOMAS F. GODFREY. L. M. TALMAGE. DAVID ( I"!T •« I; I -14 '4 I otal i i \ mi n ik T8 0C Adruice tnwrgiil and premiums « On the 80th d»y of June, 1905. Mm KKv TBOS A FRY Pre^Hrnt KOBT. S WII.COX Vice-Presideut 1&gt; H. CHRISTIE Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 80, 190S. itKCKIl'TS. BftluncP on hand July I, IKM. Full p: I're Km ■ansfer n, V EXP1 MUTI RES. i n .i SUPPLEMENTAL KKl't )KT N ■4 N N N N ans have been m A 103 N A I" ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 BUlI.ni.NG AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA, On the 80th day of June, 1905 OFFICERS. JOHN F. FLACK.. Pn- Vice- President Secretary J A. Sl'XDEKLAND Treasurer GILldOKE Attorney DIRKTOKS. J. A. SCNI ERLAND, R. A McE.\ JOHN F. FLACK. GEO F. GILMORE tanm. FH»i mortgage loans In process of foreclosure Stock loans 7.074 II IMS 75 Real estate . are and Stationery Delinquent interest a n&lt;1 premiums Fiatim ■ and taxes paid other asset— real estate sales on contract Certificate* of Deposit Tc M LIABILITIES. ■irt running. (Dims and dividends) ■ S5M SO ..trebolders on incomplete loans r"rem i um* unearned .. Adranoedues Adrance interest and premiums Incomplete (bnildiuK, loans turn m F CILMOKK ■ GILMOHE </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 RKCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNK 30, 1906 KM Klt-TS Balance on band July 1, 1904 « MH » Dues, (running sMck) .. full paid slock) - 4 - i full paid stock .2.700 f» 3rt.tn H :w.i8s m Premiums.. -.3,777 » Premiums 28,777 SO Kin. IiO.m expenses . \,9tH i.*» Ixun expenses Membership and ; aawtfe '» &lt;•&gt; . Membership and ; u ass Loan Fees . . . i'.MH 01 LdftB Fi Loans repaid Loans repaid Real estal** sales on cof.lra,u 747 flr» lit* sales on * 747* Real i S.I49 7* Warrants a- vposlt -r «70 l» warrants. Certificates of Deposit' I.W9 W - irr»nu. Cer Insurance commlsstoo It » Prom and li&gt;-- :\» ii Prom an M ■ ♦ ■ 155 42 nitnini KXl'KMIIl i 1 r.«.on .&lt; s » i rets N C'omn i".a:2 a&gt; th»r pxpenftei I - Warrants hi Warrant- ii s of 1&gt; Reml estate salts on . ontrait 92 IS K*-ul f'Hiate sales i in i-oNirai 1 Keal estate and foreclosures . 1,978 26 'oreclosure 1,878 M Interest «&gt;n warrants Cash od band Interest on warrants 91 230 *» ou hand "MO T» i».mi a In.omplete loans I9.MI a Incomplete loa Profli and loss Profltand lo- Hi ft&gt; us*: RCPPL.EMKNTAL REPORT. SCPPLEMKN I A I. REPORT Permanent *J0" IJU Permanent s - N'o ol 14.101 1-20 H.303 1-20 . &lt;.. Records prior to our contract with Records prior to our c ■ntrac:. » ith i &lt;:urintr Hst*al yfar . .. 5 S70 3-10 : red during fiscal year. :t ired durintr fiscal year. i wn during fiscal year ■ -Irawn during flsc&gt;»l year : paid stook in force at this date 1.307 3-8 l n force at this date I paid stock in force at tbis date 1.307 3-ft MM «.i&lt;* jo which dues are delinquent which dues are delinquent . ■ ion for non-payment of dues. none ■t to cancellation for non-payment of dues none Total an at this date No record of this except for bor- Tutalamiu! t at this date Norecordof this except for bor Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders 19 SOP 97 Amount bT borrowing shareholders.. tesnppr Amount of Interest, premiums due ;ind unpaid lOUDt of interest, premiums due and unpaid No. of morti!aji-» subject to foreclosure. und the aegri itate amount of same. So 1 1 i foreclosure. and the aggregate amount of same. So 1 1 No. of morttnges in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of sume. No. I" No. of mort+nges in proo -ure. and the aggregate amount of same. Amou 713. ■;•: ill estate upon which loans bare been made I , ,. - iTtana , 145, Amou 713. Appni al estate upon which loans hare been made I . ... vfmmita i ' "' 1 estate.. Mm o&gt; Appru unimproTed real estate upon which loans hare been made 3 Appru upon which loans hare been made S Amiuntofn. roe and aiwlgned to the Association as collat ral security MUK OB Am 'iint of insurance in foroe and aiwlKned to the Assoclattoo ascollat nil security MMG6 &lt;"&gt; Nu. of loans made f"' - during fiscal year 154 N«j. of i - during fiscal year 154 ias made for purchase of homes and payment of homest* ad mortgages N ins made for purchase of homes and payment of homestead mortgages for purchase of homes and payment of homesti ad mortgage: Amount of advance payments of loans during nsca! year non-borrowintt stockholders M«&gt; minors holding stock in the Association none interest charged borrowers during n seal year 6 Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year No. of t ■ Mon-borrowlng stockholders u**j No. of minors holding stock in the Association none interest charged borrowers during fiscal tear .. . fl premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year SOe pertlflO verai&gt; premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year SOeperlino if premium ('aid monthly with interest S c pertno : led to reserve fund during fiscal year .. 0.5A3 "S Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal rear Amount rve funtl during fiscal Year . IB Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year. . . 38.1 IK On Amount of Dividends declared on full paid stock durlug nscal year. ■ 14,973 ' B Average rate per cent of dividends declared during nscal Tear. 10 per cent run </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 OF THE CONDITION OF TI1E OMAHA LOAN AND BCILDING ASSOCIATION On the 30th day of June, 1905. offici i:s Pi Vioe-lV &amp; in i:i ( 1 1 &gt; i H. J. PK For BN H 1IUILER, \V R K BRYSON, Gl EO. M. NAT IIS \«l^. : 44 LIAIEII.ITIKS Capital stock running ( D jes and divldead* Dae share Holders on lnoumplete inn i.nearned 41 Adranec faterent and premiums STATEMENT OMAHA. NEBRASKA, OEO W. LOOM IS. BLMEB K BUY SON M. SATTIGEF LEWIS 8. KKKD FRANK H. 6AINES </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. RECEIPTS. llalance on bard July 1. 1904 131.733 » S67.44T 87 Dues (Running Due* (Full paid r-tc 41.198 IS 3.0 88 -.hip and L 1T7,!1O 07 1.34U ■I.* us 3.7-Jll M 3.113 a K il T ■?42,2&gt;4 33 KXI'KJi DITIKKS. Oih»T expen irawal: Irawai! Matured sum Matured Ma dues mprovement . tlups ;ir IM u&gt; .p rovemen R 1.417 SO a SITPLKMEN I ,\L REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent i permanent It -*h:ir&gt; #JU&gt;00 l if serial). . . 178 !!»■* No. of sbar&gt; - e organization. . - i&gt;su»-d during fiscal yeur — lixX No. of shares matured during tisciil year 47« No of shares withdrawn during fiscal year "s of running stock in force at this data 17,?T3* paid siock in force at i b if, 5538 No of shares on which dues ar f inn-payment ' ■■■ holders le aod unpaid $ 2,906 Of aiotreeate amount of sa ne. No 47 4.V.W a) N No oi Uiur&lt;- and the aggretfate amuUDt of same n.o-rr 4S '6 77 Amount of limns on improved real estate .. - ffi 77 ■ niti upon which loans have been made — HR44S UO Appra I.I07.SM 00 ■ improved real es'ate of unimproved real estate up V.TfM U0 in whicH loaoa ha»e been made ... W.o&amp;O 00 Appraise:! value of unimproved real estate upon watc* loaoa bare Been made ... CT.iau &lt;*&gt; Amount of nsurunce in I &gt;'ned to the Association as collateral sixurity 1,115,215 00 No. of loans mai'e for huildinv purposes durinK fiscal year ISO jj o ' of 1 mortarairex dorhi* fiscal year. lflB .••nt« of loans during fiscal y»ar . . ockholdera Mortgage loans 10UI: Stock loans IS4 us S No of • « in the As- ' j( mi-T'-' 1 ■ iwiTsdurimr tlseal year.. Average r^be per rent of premiums chanced borrowers during rtacal year 6 Plan of prem monthlj pavmeot Amount credited to reserve fund dunn* 0s*5«l ymi Amount of losses charged to reserre fund during tlHcal year l Amount of flii : ' ciiired on running nu&gt;ck during fiscal year Amonnt '-d on full patd stock during ft»eai year Aver. it- vidfnds declared during fiscal year. . 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 OK THE CONDITION OF THE PAWNEE CITY SAVINGS AND BUILDING PAWNEE CITY. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1905 ItlKEC'lultN ' i.i.ARr A S. STORY &lt; KER, .orUMC loans io i kea and taxes paid. LIABILITIES. Capital si. irk runninc (Due* and DirideDda) dues *;,I7« 85, dividends tJ.178.45 f».a» a ) ■ r : ■ ■ M none 007 50 I'M U STATEMENT ASSOCIATION §. IH1.LARD BECKER.. . STORY... McMASTEB. ure and rtailooerr &gt;ex and taxes paid. </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand Juy I, 1901 Dues (Running stock' • 47 a 2.078 86 none Due* (Full paid stock) SI3I It Premium DODC lr. 27 il transfer fee: 49 50 3.43.1 U0 none none *«.»7 06 T EXl'EN 1'ITIKKS. turn &gt;u none C4 80 xperi rrM I.M 50 raw 4-y. M rawals. i &lt;ii nntrs ,tock. ik Matured su* k i ,.r\ .:,*;-. .rnings notie Full paid stock . dues none PuUp aid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings ... none Pull paid stock, earnings Cuh od hand fw* 7* tat Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMEN 1 AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent » permanent Plan of Association (Serial or permanent) permanent Par va of stock fc*C0 00 TKanization(if serial) &gt;■ at this date — 174 Par value of nach share of stock tSCO 00 realization (if serial f at this date — 174 :iATe»lMna&lt; since organization M -haw iMwei since organization ufi No. of shares is&gt;m-d during fiscal year 46 No. of shares K&gt;mdduring fiscal year 46 No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year So. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year .3 No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year 9 No. of shares of running stock in force at this date 174 No. of shares of running stock in force at this date 174 No. uf shares of full paid stock In force at this date . . none &lt;f full paid stock in force at this dat&lt;&gt; none 84 64 n which du&lt; tout 10 ■n Which dll- it:Ut 10 No. of st. ■ to cancellation for nonpayment of du&lt; - 3 .mediation for nonpayment of Total amou: n« at this date 121 95 Total amount of dues .1. 121 95 k ;areholders SI 06 Amount ':areholders 21 t* Amount ims and fines due and unpaid 14 W Amount ims and lines due and uopald 14 (M ! the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 400 00 re and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 400 00 and the aggregate amount of same .... none No. of r: &lt;'j the aggregate amount of same — none Amou □ improved : ■ Appr:i ipon which loans have been made. — 3.wH&gt; 00 Appr:&gt; » &gt;n which loans have been made . . 3.M06 00 Amoi. &amp;1 estate — i.ue of un m. proved real estate upon which loans have been made — none Amounts loans u]&gt; -d real estate ~-d value of ui on which loans have been made. ... none ition ascolla 1 y 12,000 00 t ion as coil. v 13,000 00 • s durintf fiscal year 3 • s during fiscal year. .. 3 No. of 1 nent of homestead mortgages during fiscal year 4 ment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year * Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year 13,436 00 Ami» payments of loans during fiscal year $3,436 00 No. of I" " No. of no ■ No. of iji ■ No. of ii jooiatlcm... No. of n oiaiior. -r charged borrowers during fiscal year 9 ent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year none Amount 1 during fiscal year W 'JO ■ rve fund during fiscal year. . Amount of on running stock during fiscal year now in force. 9U M ired on full paid stock dur&lt;riK fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year none iired during fiscal year II k matured during fiscal vear none matured auring year </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OP TUB THE LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1903. OIFK I K&gt;. 1&gt;. B. SMITH K MARSHALL. RY R. GKRING . EB1NGEB Vice President SeereUiy T— —__„___ THOMAS WALLING .Attorney DIRECTORS. -MITH C. A. MARSHALL. F. W. EBINGER HENRY HEROLD, NRY HEROLD, WM. HOLLY, WM. A. WHITE WM. HASSLfcR. H. M SOENNICHSE.M, HENRY R. GERING IN ASSETS. First nortfmge in»n» n Bmuncwe lo»»s in i luans For»iiurt mad m« 1 premiums ai. Kx pemie*. and taxes paid 1,138 OtlM-r aasets— rent aocoaot Ee»l estate oontraru S74 M Insurance and uxds paid and advancec ToU LIABII.ITIKS. Capital nock runnlnc &lt;Dues and diTldends Full paid stock BHarre fund r CodiTided proflts Dweaharefaolden on Incomplete loans 39 Advance dues • e Advanct interest and premiums. J </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS UL'II.IUXG TS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL VI \R RECEII ENDING JUNK 30, 1905 KK&lt; KIl'TS. I M J4 on h.intl Ju: I IM m ■» BXPI N IllTl KK.-. none « w M MOO none l,ft!5 $1 fu 1 i&gt;iiiit tttoclc, car I»W II*) Kandrepaii ance and taxes paid and adva T ital SUPPLEME NT A I, RE POUT. t'.u:. r taMC ■ --rial or pfrn Par v»l ■:■ .nization (if H ■cm »tt ia Glares oYru- » 15t)l ce at this date nooe ment of dues • at of dues II f388 00 Ml ..i Xo of morutaters ■* • t ne awcregate amount none So of 11 ;|J the HfCrexate amount of \O- - t - i- • - . and the aggregate amount • Amount of loans on improred real estate — • Amount of loans on improred real estate. ; ■»•■ T* .le upon whicn loans h»Te been made — 13.116 &lt;■ Appr.i ite upon which loans have been made — u.jkj uu real estate u lie Upon WQICU 1U1H13 UMC Lnrrru lumic... ■■■•■■■ Appr .. ■"■ noo« : real estate upon which loans have b*en mi one .-nedtotheA .^ collateral security ftl.OUJ 0» Appr.i nta on _ : real estate upon which none I ion as collateral security K!,0uO uo r payment ot &gt;0WMlnii1 Bortffftgw during fiscal year 27 No. of ' Averse A \ erase rate per ceni of premiums charged I .t! A\thi. owers durinp fiscal year. . 10 ' Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durinx flacal vpa&lt;- none a \ erase riite per cent of premiums chanced borrowers durinif Oaml vp»r none Plan of premium - : .ted to reserve fund dur noo* i to reserve fund during flaeal Tear t 00 *!!! •• i reserve fund during flaeal year • oo^rt •• mnin*r sum K,lon full pa '« fiscal year.. : .luring fiscal year Average rur.:.iufe' t. aured during flaosi year. </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 STATEMKNT Or THE CONDITION OK T1IK PLATTSMOUTH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1905, OFFICERS. PwMMrt Vice President K. PATTERSON BARWICK ... WINDHAM. Secretary Treasurer Attorney DIRECTOR* TH, CHAS. RVDBKR 1. WM BALLASCE, J H HALL - • US. AND C A Pint morteace loans in process of fore ■ 51 • ni interest, premiums and ones Tua adranced Profit ani Total % I I M-.l I ■TIES. Capital stock running. (Dues and divt ' n ne n incomp Adva: «0 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 l*I'III*I »i {t A N D LO AH ASbOC I A X 1O 9 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 10, 1905. RfcCEIPT! Balan Dues' Dues i Interf Prem re on hand Ji KlIIinitlL' StLH itm Fine Men t.oar Real Rents Taxes Inter L. oinn. ii her Witbi Wlthc Matur Matut Full f Fullp [1 stock, earn id stock .d stock, earn none &amp;M3 SI Cash Taxe 'C iwo m Jvamed Total SUPPLEMENTAL RKPOIIT. Plan ot AssiK-iation (Serial or perm 41 n force at this d 4.193 oor»u 1U8 i ares issued durimr Had 3 no rawn during -^iares of runninjr &gt;t»K k in force at th 7S0 -hares of f\;: : n force at this date none 3i N :i S 1314 00 T 314 U0 closure, and theatre, ate amountof same. No 8 S.b28 00 WS 20 t, " o , ni , ,d the aggregate amount of same. v- . . none Amounl of joiin^ on ■V™' ion which loans have been ma. : none ,. ;, upon unir. uvuv tie uixm which loanR have been made. . . . none Al DOM - during fiscal year 1 N 3.524 M An 111 N 173 S 9 premiums en Plan al year ;il \ea mount . during fiscal year ■ ack durinK fiscal year All nds declared during fiscal year AV wk matured during fiscal year. -iv • ;ich snare..: ; .1 1 h &gt;n </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 STATEMENT Or THE CONDITION OF THE SCUUYLER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION On the 30th day of June, 1905. orrn M. L \\ EA &gt; ER PEN&lt; K President Viee-Pres K E. MOOKE, Succeeded by I'M AS. If. JOJI J J GARTH Secretary Treasurer .Attorney PHELPS. DIUKCTORS U. L WEAVER J. A. P] FRANK E. MOORE, V MALT. N. WHITE J. S. JOHNSON E- H. PH AsSKTs. 301 3x 743 60 premiums and fli CTtlDi-d Tot I I AIIII I TIES. .; running (dues and divk on Inoomplci n KM ar.-l iiri-mums SCHUYLER, NEBRASKA, ARTHTR VAN H( I JOHN J. GAKTH ort«a«e loans ... Mrtcace loans In process of fora ■ Real rsiate </seg>
            <seg id="p133">133 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPT8 AND EXPBMDITURE8 FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNK 30. 1905. Bi Membership smd transfer fe« - &lt;*paid </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SEWARD EQUITABLE BDILDING AND LOAN SEWARD, NEBRASKA, On the 8Ctb day of June. 1905 OFF I' JOHN ZIMMERER GKO. t. DRKMAN H. A GRAFF.. President Vice- President Secretary Treasurer I.ANGWORTHY J J THOMAS Attoruey DIRECTORS. J. F. GEESEN, C. K. HUMPHREY. G. H. TERWILLIGER. JOHN AM - U H. FRANKLIN. F. W. GOEHNER, THOMAS GKAHAM uim FirM mort^mj* 1 loan* rtt-ane lout* in process of forei losure stock louu uont ii.it r.-i premiums and Uut Insurmooc paid Other Assets Total LIABILITIES. Capital nock r nnin« (Does and dividends) stock •n-.: prolu Dueshar.hildffm on liwmplme loans 4«7 78 L&gt;4 ■ Advance Interest and pteoiui Total (&amp;1.702 M ASSOCIATION MMM '0 none 4,4.1=. It none R-tJe-Uile . Fumlturr and stationery </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 BU1LDIH0 AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS KIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE KI ENDING JUNE 30, 1905. i:k I IPTS. I ice on band Julv I, 1904 Kunimii; stock) . I Pull paid stock).. »er»hip and tran»(er fees I repiid overdraw n 1 if ■ 10.5M 05 iverdrann B I Full paid MOC wt Premium Membership and tran»Ier Ire I»aii* repuid Tax sale certiticai InMirnuce repaid T h\l'r \ HI II BBS. ■ rdrawn Ju! SU5UU Wit f u* ■ ami ea E arnini ■rK. 'arriin In-ur i- Inn rest on overdraft Total SUPPLEMENT AL REPORT. lion n (Serial or permaD. r ■ serial MO 00 —ii.-,l since oraanlzatlon. (If serial) 12 ■oao^i No of shares issu«*d sine*- otfrani nation. . SMMC 46B No. of shares matured during 1! - ;ir»-s withdrawn during tlscal year. k in force at this date I090H No. of shares of full paid slock in force at this date i in H : to ranee nation for nonpayment of du- none t\T7 50 3»in*r by borrowliur shan-holder^ iiiums and fines dut' and unpaid — No of mortmires su. and the &amp;ggreg&amp;le amountof same. No process of f&lt;: d the a«rfrre«raie amountof Name, No insonimrr . ed real estate upon which loans have been made ,750 OJ Amount uf loans upon anil ■ ii value of unlm; poo which loans hare been madi Amountof insurance in: .nedtothe Association as collateral security U.106 00 No. of loans made for building purpose* during fiscal year made for pavn ent of hom&lt;&gt;steud moru ages during fiscal year Amount "f advance payments of loan- during tlscal year . - . No of borrowintr stockfcolders 106 No of non-borruwin* stockholders. . 1T-1 iiiors holding stock in the Association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 7 v*" Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. . ..1 3-10 pi Plan of pre " Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year . . •-' '3 34 Amount of Jt-s-es char^rd to reserve fund during fiscal year none Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year 4.140 2.' Am.urit &lt;.f &lt;.!:■. : : - . . red on full paid stock during fiscal &gt; ear Averac* rate per east of dividends declared during fiscal year » HO per cent A veriure running time of stock matured during fiscal year b years, 10 mtti </seg>
            <seg id="p136">A , i tu&gt; [ATION \ ice Pn secretary AHAN 1 IUILDING AND LOAM AS8OC1A : STATEMENT Dr TIIK CONDITION OK THE SIDNEY LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOC SIDNEY, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. OFKJi [{A XX KM AX &amp;DCLIFF. ( AU.AHAN ASK Dlltl &lt; TORS M CH K B \»-l T&gt; stationer LIABILIT1E1 Dremtum </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIA KIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL 1IKC KND1NG JUNE 30, 1903, i ECKIPT8. llalat land Jn'y 1 n_' stock . ion Dues [ Kunni Dues (Kull p Interest and Fines aid stock) premiums Membership Loans repai and tran:»fe 1 EXI Loan Con Wit Withdrawals. &gt; arn ings Matu Matured stock, earning Full paid stock. A &gt;ck. earning T SUPPLKM Plan of Association (Serial or permanent i pern Par v if serin ■ r none No. or share* with No. of shares of runnu k stock in force at this dal No! of shares of full paid stock in force at this date none No. of shares . ■■■■■ ivment of due .3 No Amoui oldeim, ..... 1 reml estate upon which loans have been mac i\ estate upon which loans have been made 1 to the Association as co lateral security 1U.2UO CO ic.i /\f limns m:i(l f ' for tiutulintf DuriMDses durinir fiscal year Alt No of luiins miidf' for bututintr pun*&gt;ses durintr fiscal year No of loiiiis mad- for payment of homestead mortgages durins Hsinl ren « immint ,.f ;, f loans durinir ttscal year woo 00 « of loans during ti- Amoi No of l&gt; ■ » holders 1 i-ent of premiums charged borrowers .luring fiscal year SOcierl AVIT Plan fund during nsc.i An Amoui, oiaen, ..... Amouin md unpaid ho M No O | .te amount of sunn-. No. 1 T45 31 Ho O ' ;iq&lt;1 the ugtregate amount uf -.. '&gt;ne Aip'ouni ' ■-■■ • ■ • No of i - rs ;•■ he Assnclatton... -i churned borrowers during fiscal year Amoui :. seal year., none Amount r&lt;f &gt;rmit fiscal year. ■» M Amount i.f «» ne 10 Average rui- ! "*f tlscal veur none ( </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SOUTH OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING SOUTH OMAHA. NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1905. OFFK I IC&gt; EU1CK J. SHEEHY ENKY LOECHNEB J FTTZGBKALO. ■ ltlLLKR. I resit! t j ii t .Vice-president A. H. Ml'KDOCK DIRKCTORS. W P. ADKINS R. C. WALKER, E L. HOWE. J E. O HERN !ITH, J. HKXKY LOECHNER. D. E. TRACY C. A. MKI.IUEK. P. J. SHEEHY X^l l» 1111 in* i-j 3.0M 00 I.Mt n ■ id on nmtract ture and »t»ti mss and tux - Other *.s^u- Total l.i \ ui in i k» Capital Mock running (Dues and divldeuds Full paid stock I &gt;ue share holuers on itir. ,tljj..t it- loai ASSOCIATION . . Secretary .Treasurer ..Attorney ■mortgage loans ,■•• loans in process of for. loans </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS EIPTS AND KXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YKAK ENDING JL'NE 30, 1905. BKCKI FTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1904 t xxh as ill paid -tocki ■:•.-■ 37 H tan ss and tr: I 40 Lout . contract ! 30 OC 315 00 Pront ami 1&lt;&gt;^ M OC 51 00 u.mo no Total * 5«.(RV 79 T Ht -&lt;j KM'KNUITl RES. EX II.XDITIKKS, Loans | 3^.60S M I 3-'.ftJ5 S3 Siila- 1' 1 003 t« Mon 1.000 00 i .«e oo Other • ■ :■ ■ : .-. - HI" fiB &lt;;i7 % With 13.309 OU 1.1.309 OO Will 2,81ft 28 2.815 t» Full paid S' 2.245 00 2.245 OO Pull paid stock. earning Full paid stock, earning Cash on hand July I, 1U06 J.T61 08 ided profits Cash on hand July 1 J.T5108 Interest 20 4i Total - *56,&amp;79 79 20 42 T :.i. SUPPLEMEN SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. T AL REPORT. Plan of Association (Serial or permanent) on July 1,1806, permanent •ient! on July 1,1905, permanent Par v.i, #3JU 00 Par value i'' • K seiiul) wat I if uerittlj wa&gt; serial . . rj ial ■ atthUdut. , • M OOT if 8 8 ,ares withdrawn d t'ur 720 tharee withdrawn durtnit flNcal year 720 l.ares of rum 1019 l.ares of rui.: force at this date 1619 N Hoi full paid siock in force at this date No of - ■ ;&lt;jvj 'in which dues are delinquent - »n which dues are delinquent for non-payment of dues Tota. amount of du«*s delinquent at this date ir non-payment of uu. Tot&amp;i amuunt of du I at this date it of dues owinfr t&gt; -harrholders Liirrholders ... - I SJ*7 90 No. of mortgages subject to foreclosure and the afr(;regate amount of sa-ie, No. none ■ I SJ*7 SO No. of mortnapes subject to foreclosure and the aggregate amount of sa r &gt; e. No. none So none No. of mortga^os in process of foreclosure and the aggregate amount of same No. of mortgaKes in pro* iosure and the aggregate amount of same Amoi;- a.- Amount of iomns on imp ;ue Appni late upon which loans hare been made 214. 44B 0© Appni late upon which loans have been made 214. 4A 0l&gt; Appr.i 11. Appra Amount of loans u] .1 cs'ate. M o Amount of lo • 900 00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made I ■it of insurance in : fc neil to the Association as collateral security 13:* Appraised value of unimprovc*) real estate upon which loans have been made I :ii of insurance in 1 »neil to the Association as collateral security 133 No. of loans ma&lt;!e for huildintr purposes during fiscal year No. of loans ma&lt;!e for huiMmir purposes durioif fiscal year No of loans mad* 1 f&lt; &gt;f homestead morUEaves during tlscai year. 15 No of loans mail'' for payment of homestead mortxaues during fiscal year. 15 amount of advance pavments of loans during fiscal year flO.3^0 n .* mount of advance pavments of loans during fiscal year $ 10,330 41 No. of b No. of o. No. of n&lt; No- of r No of n lie Ass&lt;»ciation t No of n k in the Association Averu^ -it charged iiorrowers dtirinv fiscal M fi per cent nt of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year 'I 4-\0 per cent Plan of i . monthly reserve fund during fiscal year f 400 00 Amount • • «ed to reserve fund during fiscal year none Amount of d. :ared on running stock during fl b.i&amp;2 16 Amonnt of d irod on full paid stock during fiscal year . 54S TO Average rat. dividend* declare during fiscal year. 5H per cent Average running time of stuck matured during fiscal year II years . </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE PKl'DENTIAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION STRATTON, NEBRASKA. On the 80th day of June. 1935. OFFICERS. ItrROTTOM President I R DARNRU R H HALL. Vice President ■S2S 1)1 R&gt; (TIIIK J W. R It ATVI.IKF I H 1I.M1NKLL, W V. VAN T *svi;t&gt;. Bnorurmm loans in pi D' D' -e and stations 4- •■nt imprest, premiums *nd fin&lt; Kip&lt;-ii~-« and uiea. paid n ta l.IABII.ITIK-i. runnini (DuM and di\ s«35 n n : VK.NMM </seg>
            <seg id="p141">KM KIrlS AND KXPhNDIll KKS FOR L'HK FISCAL YMAK ENDING Jl XK 80, 1!H)5 KKC't II'TS. July I, 1904 stock ) ... m 3s cone Pull pa i so I 36 run tx; 40 EXPKNDITI RES. &gt;l(O Other exp. 31 OS Withdraw ins rurnin Matured stock, with. Fuiir Pull paid stock, earn bund 144 80 Tot *:-2 ii) SUPPLKMKN I AL REPORT itlon (serial ,1 ■ N shares in force iit 11 143 43 U6 h ira tsyueti since organization •-sued since organization 146 &lt;lurin« fiscal year 145 (tamres matured during ti&gt;cal&gt;ear none 1 indrawn during fiscal year. . . % ares matured during ducal jea me ■i.ires withdrawn during Q X .hare- of running stock in force at this date 143 dat running roe at this u:i full paid stock in fore ■ at this date . none s ■s of full paid »t at thi none N hares loaned mi g which dues are delinquent. . none o cancellation for non-payment of fliiw none uent at this date, interest ami * MM rowing sharehold' MMM ayment of nterest and ti N '.&lt;1 th- &amp;4fffre*r*it«' ucnuunt of same. No Done - ;*nd the aKgrt'irate amount of same h- ttcgretnkle amount of same. N and the atmreirate amount of name w h loans hmve bees made *al ostai 12 .e which loans nave been made As-.H-iutiun as collateral and a.-.f.ii.'neil th No of li an-* made for pavmt-ni of hoaeatead mortmires durteg fiscal year Amount of advanct- ■ ■ k in the Association I charged borrower a of premiums charged borrowers durtag fiscal yea rwon durtag tlsciii year Plan of premium . monthly Amount Am»u: &gt;red on running stock ilurint? fiscal year Dooe Amount - bod* dividends declared durinc fiscal year rage running time of stock matured during fiscal yew none </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 BLILDINU AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE CONDITION OK TOE CITIZENS' BUILDING, LOAN &amp; SAVINGS SUPERIOR, NEBRASKA, On the 80th day of June, 1905. OFFICERS, IS YOUNG P. LONG.. I UBS A. MYKRs I 8TUBB8. President Vice-President Secretary Treasurer Attorney niiti;&lt; -tors. - ! lveb. A. B. JIA11SHALL. F S SOUTH A BI J H. KZSTERSON W. J. ELLIOTT \»»l T~ Flr«t mortmice loa tea loan* In pr. v « ■o ■ ■ aad taxeH p»ui . . I IAIUI IT1K.V r»pual stock running (Duet and divWendu) A&lt;» ded prolts . are boldera. on incomplete lomnn Pr«Mnium8 uneumetl r. r-rest and premium: il 00 Total STATEMENT ASSOCIATION </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS KISt AL YEAR RECEIPTS AND ELPESDITURE8 FOR THH ENDING JUNE 30, 1906 KKCKIPTS t 1.834 1» Balanee on band July 1, 1904 15.115 «S running stock) 'ill paid stock) .t urns .hip and tran * .U.4SJ EXI I- Mil Tl 111 - 10.830 00 I, a;-- ■M s n *S * M h W KO is.' T REPORT SUPPLE M E NTAL p. Plan of Association (serial or permanent No. of series lssurtl - -at km. (if -»-ri:»li ■ izatior hi ion I .luring fiscal year nares matured during fiscal year — none K: during flM-al year. . . nares matured during flM-al yea . n force at this dat.' n force at this data A , in force at this da •an share* on which dues are delinqm a aliment oi Ji p%jva&lt; T S N aggregate am. .i D m. ■,,i the ajrgrei aenregut .:■ NO I* LnMnitliwl nr" 1T* h»S***" •' upon which loam mnroved real estate upon whioh loans hav A \ ... ■ . 'ilch loa J . . . i which loans have b .r during t ■i*: fiscal yea: il ye»r. riation ... '. .,. rmMoari • •• ' • haitei r. .flowers during tisoal i months, an \\.-r mi rastpar »a»l ■•&lt; latsml charted i ■ fnnw durin m sti months. an&gt; Mr six months x mnn ATeratte rste p&lt;r cent of premiums charged borrowers dur ■ rat« per cent of premiums charged borrowei wersdur premium dispensed with Jan. 1 Plan of pren ted to leaei ve fund during flscsi jca K'-serve fund during fl*c»l yew. Amount of loss«&gt;s chanced to reserve fund durinff fiscal ye mount of los- :.g fiscal ye»r . i. lenda declared on runiir ing flaoal year.. . n per cent ring fl» lends declared on full p:, lug nioal ye».. 718 00 luriuKBi luring dscal year. lurlnff II seal 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 STATEMENT Ot THE CONDITION OF THE TECUMSEU BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION TECL'MSEH. NEBRASKA On the 80th day of June, 1005. P A BRUNDAGE -1UN J B DOUGLAS • AM &gt;.\ AI-. N. DAFOE. L. li. DA VI prrmiums. Dors an Tot Capital xtoek running (dues and dividend* Full p&gt;Ul stock ■ mortcMe loan* njcirt«age loan* Id process of lore loaaa led profits . </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITI/RKS FOR THE Dues (Runnin-' Due* (Fu Interest I'rv Fll* Membership and t r: Loans repaid K L. Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues. Matured stock earning': uu &lt; SUPPLEMEN I AL REPORT Serial or permanent) • aen sbare of stock ■ries issued since organization (if serial No of shares biased since organization shares issued during fiscal year matured during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year Nc. of shsires of running stock in force at this date No of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No or shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owinK by borrowing sburebolde .tul unpaid. none Amount of interest, premiums and fine No of morura*res subject to foreclosure, an&gt; the aKgret;ate amour ind the aggregate air of san inl of saniu No. of mortKajrea in process of fori No. none Amount of loans on improved rt 2S.375 00 Appraised value of improved real estate up &gt;n which loans have been uiw Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been ma 114.100 00 Amount of insuranre in force and assigned t&gt; tion as collateral security No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year So. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year No. of minors holding stock in the Association Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year • 3 11 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during 8* M Amount of dividends d- clare*! on full paid sti»ck during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared durinj Average running time of stock matured durli exper Irani share* in force at this datt NO Of r No. of non borrowing stockholder: Aveiw charged borrowers during liscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 STATEMKNT OF THE CONDITION OF THK TRENTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION TKENTOX. NKHRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1805 REYNOLDS .A IB HILL. OULLETT. REYNOLDS. KEY SOLD: A E REYNOLDS, C. L. ALLEN .ort«»ge !o»n' of [oreclosurt IM MBi aii'i MMMI iinums mud II - pa I T r nning u incomplete loans Advance interMt and premiums Membership fees Mifi flc </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL TEA] ENDING JUNE :», 1905. RECEIE TS RECEIPT Italanceon hand Julv 1, 190* « I ,733 00 Ml W 1 fill r Men, tx- rub lu I nan at mi 50 T u .4*1 10 expkn HI Tl II KS ... MM &lt;H)OU 34187 Other Wtt I IflT W M r E t w SUPPLE MENTAL KEPOKT A ■n n ♦ i. r ur ui w ,\ none on nun&lt;' none * A I MM No none ■ ri which loans have been n ... .;- - i • J value of ui ch loan^ h:i\ • -' 3UU 00 Amount of r i;ition as couai :i»tlf for iii -'aites durinc fiscal 1 N ■ Amount of advum 3 ■ Kne Association • rowers durintr fiscal year 10 premium* charted borrower! durini; Useal year I0H per cent bid ,,! el loM(km4 M nmr—tmmt darta* n-. .1 ;rired to reserve f none n AiDount Average running time of atock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p148">STATEMENT VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION VALENTINE. NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1903, OFFK I R8 K KNELL H. YKAsT KEELEY Presiden Vice Piesi.len rwmm m DIKKI THUS. UiKEB. R H V. H DAILEY ASSK1 - PlHI ni'Tii: i'j*- l.iin BK&gt;rt«*i{« luaiu in proeea* o !n:ins • UiUiH.erv Iin-niiums and flnt-s .ixes i,u I I IBIUTUB (Dues and dividenasi . &gt;nd prcmlun . Hank of Valentin. laterast, nne&gt; mad membership fees . . &lt;1U r nit coxditiok "t toe i . Jers km Incomplete loui i uearned </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 RECEIPTS AND BXPEND1TURK8 FOB THE FISCAL YKAK ENDING JUNK 80, 1985. Other eipi Withdraw Ainoui , Vr nf inopI-'airf-Nsnt.it'i-I to for' int ot sanif, -No . 1 l,_l» IB N&lt; No of mortuM. ! »1 l"« ttKgreifate amount of - Mo I (l '■' N • Amount of loiins on inn pml estate upon which loans havt' b**en ma*!* 1 Api muu , Appraised v.ilue of unimproveil real estate upon which loans have bei- none Amount of in-urance in force and assigned to il .ter.il Amount of in-urance In force am No. of loans mad- for hulldin-' ) No. of loans •■s during Bsti . nor Amount of udi lurinif Hscal year . N N No of minors .ciation • it of interest churned borrower* during flsca! year y«-iu ■it p r cent of premiums charted borrowers during tlscal year DOM Plan of prcmiur Amoiu: alyear Amount : during fiscal year • ■ : during tiscal year . . </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE WAHOO MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION WAHOO. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1905 OKn&lt; i B8 BEN D. KUPP .... R. F. McC'KEERY H M BTKATTOH ERNST HA K K GOOD LIABILITIES. O*!^*^' stock running (Dues and dividends Pull paid stock UnclividiM prottw L»ur sharih.'l'l'-rr. on iDoomplete lmui&gt; Adraoet InMieM auU premiunu </seg>
            <seg id="p151">151 UKl KIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YE ENDING JUNE 30, 19U5. AK i;i ( ii TTS. id July I, 1904 * MM M MIS 44 50 1M 10 io au mm m MPEMII Tl RK». .«. » Puil paic wk ■amli. axes paid uniljaiU 4 au i 63 .56 35 f SUPPLEMEN I AL REPORT : ial or permari MOO 01) uf stock iiu'e organization ■u a at this date 2SM 607. mm n ,tured durinn !i- N ii wn during fl^i W running stock in Tore la • i.i- k in force al t No of share none '1 otal amour t w» m Amour MM k mount &lt; f inn No. of mortgages subject lo foreclosure, and th« unpaid aggregate amount of same. No. the aggregate amount of ure. and Amount of loans on imp ii i. 700 00 Appra il e.st:ite npon which loans have been mi.. A ppru Ail "Ulil ( -■(I value of ui ed value of ui tie upon which loans have been mail.- none which loans have been mm !•- none Amount of insurant**' *ans made fur building purpov s during t lins made Tor payment ol Association aa collateral security 71,800 00 Association as collateral security 71,000 00 nans n: Bsi-al year J3 luring tlscal year 8 &amp;\ your 13 ii s during fiscal year ■ Amount of ;id\ nt of adv teal year none ical year none No. of doi No of nj L'iation (harmed borrowers during tiscai year 8 i of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. . nt &lt;rf interest charged borrow tfaar^ed borrow rers .turiiif tlscal year a durintr fiscal year rowers during fiscal year. . Plan of prnt highest bidder durin t tlscsil y« ,r r\e fund during fiscal year red on running stock during fiscal year Amount of AmuuDt of div iring fiscal year Arerage rum, . during tiscal year. Uiitfl: V\ Witlxiruwa &gt;Vitb&lt;lraw;il nee organization urint' Us, r share* k»B&lt;v i, No. of e aelinqufni !i-paymoDt ol </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 BUlLDlNti AND WluXa O- THK COKD1TIOM OK THE SALINE COUNTY BUILDING ASSOCIATION WILBER. NEBRASKA On the 80th day of June. 1003 nil ■&lt; I RS. ■H CERNY .1 W. HOSPOnsKY Vice I': J K MAI.LAT I. .1 SI'IKK •I- .„ J f SP1RK Notary IIIRKCTOKS V J PRUCHA CHAS STASTSY J. H. BRT. JulIN VAN DCYN. HKN14Y BIN'Gl J. J. MELCKR FRANK SASEK VSSKTS -u'lrtgavr loan: Bmurtgwe iuwis in g RemlFKlmte in u&gt;d statiunery . premiums and fine Total LIABILITIES ■ k runninc &lt;Due« and Dirtdenda) paid slock. . *• fund i] profltK Premiums unearned ... Advance dux 112 no II &lt;M) STATEMENT </seg>
            <seg id="p153">, Ql • A N A ■ lnd loan associations \SU KXI'KNDITURES FOR THE FISCAL TEAR ENDING JUNE 80, 190}. </seg>
            <seg id="p154">II LOAN i '" •I I I- * VI lND LOAN A88OCIATIO] STATEMENT &gt;V T1IK 0OMPIT1OM OF THK WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND ASSOCIATION WOOD RIVER. NEBRASKA, • if i n i it- \l NRI.SON fl. SPKAGUK &lt; \\i\(;ki:i UIRKCT(IR!t B. M. Nl I \M. OB HAKKIi l»»l l» i i &lt;-t i.x • r.v. ~ tmd text's I&gt;;« I I.I \IIII I I II • , ud .In i On the sotli day of Jane ..] «u»rk i ui itun&gt; unearned Advance Interest and tin nrum- </seg>
            <seg id="p155">BUILDING AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION 155 RECEIPTS AM) EXPENDITURES FOR THE f KND1NU JUNK 30, 1905. uuirn KK&lt; KIl'TS. Balance on band Julv I. 1WM t ~~ , 1WM Does (Running M.H-ki . " ! " ■ Due* (Full pmd &gt;tocki Interest . ■■ .rshipand-- *J J I D ' 4 Real i". ' ''&lt;&gt; I Tula I \ i-imiiii i;i v I \ l-l S III II lil *. i:to " J H none rii&gt;rie nntjc est on advani Toim, SUPPLEMBMTAL REPORT. I 3- l-.-v* M u U n &gt;D which du ■ • - . ore-closure :mrf the i~J^T f « ™. ' 4 foreclosur. '„ "* °° ! l»in which loans h»yp b. nVi'm. ,■ * PP J!J I"" 1 which ltians haire been made .... »o •vc been mude 30.01 Amo.i . |i &gt;n uniaip- '"■ •d unit: MM iwoo ";.° f "'i' 11 ? 1 '; v-beramaii,'.:;: no ° Vo of 1 « I Am. n mt T t^ i»or«a«e&gt; during fiscal rear N ck in thi- As- ictatlon . . ?T intort^i charged Ix.rrowers dm i^r cent of premiums charged borrowers durlna fiscal year ". . '. ". '. '. 1 j-io per cent No of i Av A hargeti liorrowers durlm u. pioui.uiiif.cnar K e»i borrowers clurlna fiscal year 1 J-IO per cen » Amount of Iomi chanred to reserve fund .1 ti full paid - Average rate per cent of dividends declared during liscal yea'i - ~T,rzLt ■e running time of stuck matured during fiscal year Average rate j&gt;er cent of dividends declared iluring liscal ve Avenure running time of stock matured during fl^n»i ir&lt;.»^ til- nmi </seg>
            <seg id="p156">156 OF THE CONDITION OK THE YORK MUTUAL BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION YOKK, NKBKASKA. On the lit day of July. 1905. ol M( I R8. GEORGE \\ SHRECK CHARLES A. McCLOUU :&lt;.K R. RKED Vtoe-Pr, KGE W POST WIIJ.IAM \V WVCKHKK IIHtM T(IK&gt;. ■ H1I.I) ALFRED U (IIHISTIAX HANIKI. \ OHAH! - WALTER F RKV.VOI I. \V M1K1 WILLIAM \ IT I I \ 111 iii|,u«i Mock n ■ Due nhaiT holders on torompleU' loans s Adrmaoe interest and j.r STATEMENT KHUCK W POST \V. VVYCKMKh I.ITIKS. </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR Ol'R FISCAL YEAR KK( KIFTS Balance oo hand Jul&gt; I, IU04 Dues, (rmiuinK Btoeli 11 paid nock) Premium Membership and transfer Loans repsid. . tate sale t njm w Total KM-KMII Tl KK&gt; I HlMi •« 7*0 U) iomiDissi, othrr expenses M ■ Irawmls, dues. Withdrawals, earnings, ii Matured stock, dues ■ red stock, earnings, paid stock, ta paid MMk, earnings od hand none none 3.:!Tf. 3U Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of Association (serial or permanent ■ hi. (if serial) :&lt; I snares Isasw shares issued during fiscal year - matured during fiscal year shares withdrawn during fiscal year shares of running stock in force at this date, of full paid stock in force at this datt shares loaned on.. none i :*-s on which dues are delinquent 3J ' shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues none B mount itf due** delinquent ;*t ihl - » owlrw bv arrowing .hareholde mortKa. - foreclosure. and the morttrages in process of foreclosure, and unpaid nffgngate amount of same. No the aggregate amount or same. so Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised vulue of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appru ' improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved reul estate ApprmNeti value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of insurance in V jned to the Association as collut ral security No of loans made for huIMini nt- fiscal year. 74.IKS 00 i K loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year t of advance uaymenis of loans during fiscal year n |I!'..=*W UO ■' irrowing stoekh&lt; . No. of non-borrowin»r stockholders »&gt; III ninors holding sunk in the Association, estimated 15 Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during liscal year, fixed rate * jm cer.t 1 pet .em Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal ye»r Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per i-ent of dividends declared during fiscal year. Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 8.6 per cent 386 weeks ENDING JULY 1, 1906 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>