<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Second Biennial Report of the Nebraska State Insurance Board LINCOLN NEBRASKA DECEMBER 23, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Second Biennial Report of the Nebraska State Insurance Board LINCOLN, NEBRASKA DECEMBER 23, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page Nebraska State Insurance Board _ 3 Letter of transmit tal 5 Authorized companies. Jan. 1, 1917 11 Companies withdrawn, etc _ 22 Companies admitted and licensed ..._ 32 Financial statement, disbursements - 39 The insurance code 54 Workmen's compensation law of 1913 62 Agents ' license fees — disposition - _ 64 Securities deposited with board _ 66 Report of examiners 67 Financial statement, receipts 69 Index _ 104 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">f &gt; the Board NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD (Jan. 7, 1915, to Jan. 4, 1917) Hon. Hon Hon John H. Morehead, Governor, Chairman ; Wm. H. Smith, Auditor of Public Accounts Willis E. Reed, Attorney General. (Jan. 4, 1917, to Jan. 9, 1919) Hon Hon Hon Keith Neville, Governor, Chairman; Wm. H. Smith, Auditor of Public Accounts Willis E. Reed, Attorney General. The Insurance Department Wm. B. Eastham, Commissioner and Secretary of Charles Q. DeFrance, Actuary. James Murphy, Examiner. Harry N. Sprague, Examiner. B. R. Bays, Assistant Examiner. Mrs. Mary Fairchild, Bookkeeper. M. Lina Shirley, Stenographer. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 5 LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Lincoln, Nebraska, December 23, 1916. Hon. John H. Morehead Governor of the State of Nebraska. Lincoln. Nebraska. Dear Sir: Pursuant to the provisions of Section 18 of the insurance i:ode of Nebraska (G. S. 3154, Revised Statutes 1913) On behalf of the State Insurance Board, I submit herewith information as required by said section. The first subdivision of Section 18 requires the Board to transmit a statement of all insurance companies authorized to do business in this State during the year ending the 31st day of December next preceding. This will be found under the proper heading elsewhere in this report. The second subdivision of Section 18 requires the Board to submit a statement of the insurance companies whose business has been closed since making the last report and the reasons t'or closing the same, with the amount of their assets and lia - bilities so far as the same are known or can be ascertained by the Board. This will be found under the heading "Companies withdrawn, changed or merged during biennium. " The third subdivision of Section 18 requires the Board to report the names and compensation of the officers and employees employed by it and the whole amount itemized of the expenses of the Department during such period. This will be found in detail under the heading "Financial statement for biennium «&gt;nded November 30, 1916." The fourth subdivision requires the Board to report any iimendments to this chapter which in the judgment of the Board may be desirable. This is covered in two parts headed respec - tively, "The Insurance Code" and "Agents' License Fees — Dis - nosition." </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT The constitution of Nebraska requires that all fees must be paid in advance to the State Treasurer and this has received judi - cial approval in the case of Moore v State 53 Nebr. 831 ; and in State v Home Ins. Co. 59 Nebr. 524. In actual practice, however, this provision works considerable hardship on many persons and companies having business to transact with the State. In this Department the practice is to require remittance made payable to the State Treasurer and when the remittance is received an entry is made in the Department cash book showing the amount received and for what purpose. The draft, check or money order is then taken to the State Treasurer who issues his numbered receipt therefor, returning the original receipt to this Department and uuch receipt is then forwarded to the company or person making the payment. The necessity for this procedure will be apparent when it is known that the income accruing to the State on ac - count of the Insurance Department is more than $350,000 every two years. And if the remittances were made direct to the State Treasurer instead of this Department it would necessitate an ■jxtra clerk in the State Treasurer's office to ascertain the char - acter of the services demanded by the remitting company, be - cause the fees and other moneys accruing to the State through this Department are now placed in three distinct and separate funds. Therefore it has seemed best to the Insurance Commissioner to include in this biennial report a complete itemized statement of all cash received, so classified that Your Excellency and the Legislature may find all necessary statistics for use in an intelli - gent handling of the question of insurance in this State. Section 18 provides also that the Board shall report in a condensed form the statements made to the Board by every in - surance company authorized to do business in this State •••• as audited and corrected by the Board and arranged in tabulated form or in abstracts or classes according to the kind of insurance. This portion of the report will be found in two pamphlets en - titled respectively "Summary of Insurance Business in Nebraska for the year 1914" and " Summary of Insurance Business in Ne - braska for the year 1915", which summaries were published in 1915 and 1916 respectively and which are submitted herewith and made a part of this report. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 7 An examination of the detailed report of receipts and sum - maries thereto will show that during the biennium ended Novem - ber 30. 1916 there were 412 insurance companies doing business in the State at some portion of or during all of the biennium. Three hundred eighty-one insurance companies, associations and societies were licensed to transact business in the State of Ne - braska during the year 1914; and three hundred and ninety-two were licensed for the year 1915; detailed statement of the busi - ness done during these years may be found in the summaries for 1914 and 191."). respectively, published in 1915 and 1916. At page 130 of the summary for 1915 (published in 1916) will be found a recapitulation of the business in Nebraska for the years 1914 and 191."). classified by nature of business done. Con - solidating these figures for the biennium 1914-15, the following pertinent facts are shown : Omitting the risks carried by companies writing accident and health, liability, surety, fidelity and kindred miscellaneous lines, the people of Nebraska, on December 31, 1914, were insured for $1,593,670,048 upon their property and lives; and one year later they were insured for $1,697,138,768, an increase of $103,467,720 during the year 191"). It is not improbable that the increase for 191C will be considerably over the hundred and twenty million mark. Classified as to the nature of insurance, the people of Ne - braska were insured as follows: IN 1914 On their property On their lives $1,052,440,532 Total IN 1915 On their property On their lives $1,120,039,695 Total The increases in 1915 were as follows INCREASE IN INSURANCE, 1915 On property $67,599,163 On lives 35,868.557 Total increases, 1915 $103,467,720 541,230,316 $1,593,670,848 577,099,073 $1,697,138,768 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT The various classes of insurance companies increased their in- surance in force during 1915 as follows: INCREASE IN INSURANCE, 1915 Stock fire companies $ 40,535,306 Mutual fire and hail (a) 3,079,475 Assessment hail and plate glass 2,110,231 Farmers' Mutual assessment 28,133,101 Stock legal reserve life 4,128,712 Mutual legal reserve life 28,870,370 Assessment life (a)..._ 2,916,000 Fraternal beneficiary 5,785,475 Net gains for 1915 $103,467,720 (a) Loss. The greater increase in insurance in force in mutual legal reserve life companies is only apparently true. During 1915 the Metropolitan changed from a stock company and one or two smaller companies changed from assessment life to the mutual plan, and this caused the stock life increases to show relatively smaller, and an actual loss in the assessment life companies. In the matter of premiums received and losses paid, the companies gained $359,559 in premium income in 191 .'&gt; and paid out $746,272 more in losses than in the preceding year. So that the year 1915 was relatively not so good for the companies as 1914. Stated in percentage, the three hundred eighty-one com- panies in 1914 paid 48.5 of their premium income for losses; and in 1915 the three hundred ninety-two companies paid 51.6 per cent of their premium income in losses. Tabulated for easy reference the exact figures follow : PREMIUMS AND LOSSES, 1914-15 381 companies, "1914 premiums $18,313,344 392 companies, 1915 premiums 18,672,903 Total premiums $36,986,247 381 companies. 1914 losses 8380.281 392 companies, 1915 losses 9,626,553 Total losses - 18,506,834 Gross cost to the people, two years. ..$18,479,413 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 9 According to the definition of insurance in Section 1 of the code, it is "the business of apportioning and distributing losses arising from specified causes among all those who apply and are accepted to receive such services." Section 1 further declares that insurance is "public in character." The figures heretofore given show, therefore, that for the two years, 1914-15 the people of Nebraska paid approximately one dollar for the distributing of fifty cents in losses. In other words the apportionment and distribution of losses cost as much as the losses amounted to. Whether this is ecoaoaunl or extravagant is a subject upon which people may honestly differ. It must not be forgotten, however, as to the life insurance companies, the policy holders had a reserve value which would tend to cut down the dispropor - tion between the losses paid and the cost of distributing them. By reference to the summary entitled "Taxes, statutory and reciprocal" it will be seen that 139 foreign companies paid taxes on a little less than thirteen million of premiums collected during the years 1914 and 1015. These taxes amounted to a grand total of $262,488.04, but of this sum only $238,009.93 was paid directly to the State Treasurer, the other $24,478.11 having been paid by thirty-two companies as local taxes in various counties. Of the amount reaching the State Treasurer, 41 fire companies paid $19. - 822.50; 40 life companies paid $181,609.44; and 50 miscellaneous companies paid $36,577.99. These taxes comprised $210. 269.78 levied under the statutory provision in General Sections 6355 and 6356 and *27.740.15 was mposed under the provisions of the reciprocal tax law, General Section No. 3293. In this connection it seems advisable to call your attention to the fact that General Sections 6355 and 6356 provide a certain method of taxing foreign life and accident and surety companies doing business in this state; and General Section 6357 provides for the local taxation of all domestic insurance companies, includ - ing life, fire, accident, or surety. General Section 6354 provides a method for the local taxation of foreign fire insurance companies but has no provision what ever for any tax to be paid to the State Treasurer. Notwithstanding this, during the past biennium there was paid into the State Treasury of Nebraska the sum of $19. - 822.50 of taxes collected by reason of General Section No. 3293, commonly known as the interstate reciprocity or reciprocal feat- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT ure of the insurance code. Ami in addition to the sum just men - tioned the foreign fire insurance companies paid in local taxes .$24,478.11 in various towns and counties of this state. It must be noted, however, that this reciprocal tax was im - posed upon only .'M of the 111 stock tire insurance companies do - ing business in Nebraska in 1915 and 2 foreign inutuals. And it occurs to the Insurance Commissioner that a different system of taxing tire insurance companies might very properly be adopted. It might be well to impose a tax of 2 percent on gross premiums and exempt these companies from local taxation altogether, if such can be done without violating the constitution. This would produce a revenue of approximately $180,1X10 each biennium. I'nder the provisions of Section 42 of the code. 28 domestic insurance companies have securities deposited with this Depart - ment for the benefit of the policy holders. These securities total the sum of $3.156.658.f&gt;9 as shown by a tabulated statement else - where in this report. The Examiners make a statement as to the work accom - plished by them during the biennium which appears elsewhere herein under the caption, "Report of Examiners." Respectfully submitted, W. B. EASTHAM. Insurance Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 11 NAMES AND ADDRESSES OF ALL INSURANCE COM - PANIES AUTHORIZED TO TRANSACT BUSINESS IN NEBRASKA, JANUARY 1, 1917 (The words "Insurance Company" omitted only at end of name.) STOCK FIRE INSURANCE COMPANIES— 112 Aachen &amp; Munich Fire New York, N. Y. Aetna Hartford, Conn. Agricultural Watertown, N. Y. Alliance Assurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. Alliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia Philadelphia, Pa. American Newark. N. J. American Central , St. Louis, Mo. American Druggists Fire Cincinnati. O. American Eagle Fire New York, N. Y. Anglo-American Reinsurance Company Chicago, 111. Atlas Assurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. Boston Boston, Mass. British America Assurance Company Toronto, Can. Buffalo German Buffalo, N. Y. Caledonian New York, N. Y. Camden Fire Insurance Association Camden, N. J. Citizens St. Louis, Mo. City of New York New York, N. Y. Columbia — Jersey City, N. J. Columbia Fire .-. Omaha, Nebr. Commercial Union Assurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. Commercial Union Fire New York. N. Y. Commonwealth New York, N. Y. Concordia Fire _ Milwaukee. Wis. Connecticut Fire _ Hartford, Conn. Continental - New York, N. Y. County Fire Philadelphia, Penn. Dubuque Fire and Marine Dubuque, Iowa Equitable Fire &amp; Marine Providence, R. I. Farmers .' C«dar Rapids, Iowa. Federal - Jersey City, N. - J. Fidelity-Phenix Fire _ New York, N. Y. Fire Association of Phildelphia Phildelphia, Penn. Firemens Newark, N. J. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Firemen's Fund _ San Francisco, CaL Franklin Fire : Philadelphia, Penn. General Fire Assurance Company New York, N. Y, German Alliance New York, N. Y. German-American New York, N. Y Germania Fire New York, N. Y Girard Fire and Marine Philadelphia, Pa. Glens Falls Glens Falls. N. Y Globe ft Rutgers Fire New York, N. Y, Hamburg-Bremen Fire New York, N. Y, Hanover Fire New York, N. Y Hartford Fire Hartford, Conn Home New York, N. Y Imperial Assurance Company .'. New York, N. Y, Indemnity Mutual Marine Assurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. Insurance Company of North America Philadelphia, Pa. Insurance Company of the State of Pennsylvania Philadelphia, Pa. Law, Union ft Rock _ New York, N. Y. Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe, England Chicago, 111 Liverpool ft London ft Globe, New York. .....New York, N. Y. London Assurance Corporation New York. N. Y London &amp; Lancashire Fire New York, N. Y Mannheim New York, N. Y. Mechanics Philadelphia, Pa Mechanics ft Traders New Orleans, La. Mercantile Insurance Company of America New York, N. Y. Michigan Commercial Lansing, Mich. Milwaukee Mechanics Milwaukee, Wis, Minneapolis Fire &amp; Marine Minneapolis, Minn. National-Ben Franklin Pittsburg. Pa, Nationale Fire Providence, R. I. National Fire -• Hartford, Conn. National Security Fire _ Omaha, Nebr. National Union Fire Pittsburg, Pa. Netherlands Fire and Life _ Chicago, 111 Newark Fire Newark, N. J New Brunswick Fire New Brunswick, N. J. New Hampshire Fire Manchester, N. H, Niagara Fire _ New York. N. Y. Nord-Deutsche New York, N. Y. North British and Mercantile New York. N. Y. Northern Assurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y, North River New York, N. Y. Northwestern Fire and Marine Minneapolis, Minn. Northwestern National Milwaukee, Wis. Norwich Union Fire Insurance Society New York, N. Y. Old Colony Boston. Mass. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 13 Orient __ Hartford, Conn. Palatine Insurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. Paternelle Fire New York, N. Y. Patriotic Assurance Co Chicago, 111. Pennsylvania Fire Philadelphia, Pa. Peoples' National Philadelphia, Pa. Phenix Fire Providence, R. I. Phoenix Hartford, Conn. Phoenix Assurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. Providence Washington _ Providence, R. I. Prussian National Chicago, 111. Queen Insurance Company of America New York, N. Y. Reliance '. Philadelphia, Pa. Rhode Island Providence, R. I. Royal _.....: Chicago, 111. Royal Exchange Assurance Company New York, N. Y. Salamandra New York, N. Y. Scottish Union ft National Hartford, Conn. Second Russian New York, N. Y. Security New Haven, Conn. Springfield Fire ft Marine Springfield, Mass. Standard Fire Hartford, Conn. St. Paul Fire and Marine St. Paul, Minn. Sun Insurance Office New York. N. Y. Svea Fire and Life New York, N. Y. Tokio Marine Insurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. Union Fire Providence, R. I. Union Marine Insurance Company, Ltd New York, N. Y. United States Fire New York, N. Y. Western Assurance Company Toronto, Can, Westchester Fire New York, N. Y MUTUAL FIRE, TORNADO AND HAIL INSURANCE COMPANIES— 12. Capital Fire Mutual Lincoln, Nebr. Farmers' Fire York, Pa. Federated Merchants Mutual Omaha, Nebr. Grain Dealers National Mutual Fire _ Indianapolis, Ind Millers Mutual Fire Alton, 111 Millers National Fire Chicago, 111 National Hail Lincoln, Nebr. Nebraska Hardware Mutual Lincoln. Nebr. Ohio Farmers' _ LeRoy, Ohio. Retail Merchants Mutual Fire Omaha, Nebr. St. Paul Mutual Hail and Cyclone _ St. Paul, Minn, Union Fire Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT ASSESSMENT HAIL AND PLATE GLASS INSURANCE COMPANIES— 2. Fanners' Co-operative Hail Grand Island, Nebr. National Plate Glass Falls City, Nebr. ASSESSMENT FIRE AND TORNADO INSURANCE COMPANIES— 73. Antelope County Assessment Association Neligh, Nebr. Battle Creek Mutual Battle Creek, Nebr. Boone County Farmers' Mutual Albion. Nebr. Boyd County Farmers' Mutual Anoka, Nebr. Cedar County German Farmers' Mutual Fire Hartington, Nebr. Clay County Mutual Clay Center, Nebr. Cuming, Burt and Dodge Counties Fanners' Mutual Oakland, Nebr. Dawson County Farmers' Mutual Lexington, Nebr. Dorchester Farmers' Mutual Dorchester, Nebr. Dwelling House Mutual Lincoln, Nebr. Farm Central Mutual Fire Hastings. Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Hamilton County Aurora, Nebr. Farmers' Assessment Tornado Insurance Association Wahoo. Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Assessment Association of Nebraska.. ..Big Spring, Nebr. Fanners' Mutual Fire and Lightning Insurance Company of Burt County Craig, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Thayer County.. Carleton, Nebr. Farmers Mutual Insurance Company of Fillmore County _ Fairmont, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Association of Dodge County Ames, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Home Hooper, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Home Tornado Hooper. Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Buffalo County. ..Kearney, Nebr. 'armers' Mutual Insurance Company of Nebraska Lincoln, Nebr. Farmers' Fire Assessment Insurance Association of Madison, Pierce, Wayne, Stanton and adjoining counties Norfolk, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Madison, Platte and Stanton Counties Madison, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Plymouth Plymouth, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Fire and Live Stock Plattsmouth, Nebr. Fanners' Mutual Insurance Company of Saunders County Wahoo. Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Scotts Bluff County Scottsbluff, Nebr. Fanners' Mutual Insurance Company of Wausa Wausa, Nebr. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of York County York, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 15 Farmers' Storm and Tornado Assessment Insurance Association of Pierce, Madison, Wayne, Stanton and adjoining counties Norfolk. Nebr. Farmers' Union Mutual Insurance Company of Saunders County Fremont, Nebr. Franklin County Farmers' Mutual Franklin, Nebr. Furnas County Mutual Beaver City, Nebi. Gage County Blue Springs, Nebr. German Farmers' Mutual Fire Elkhorn, Nebr. German Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Sarpy County, Nebraska Gretna, Nebr. German Farmers' Mutual Insurance Association of Seward County, Nebraska Seward. Nebr. German Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Associa- tion of York County, Nebraska .-. York. Nebr. German Mutual Insurance Company of Dodge County, Nebraska Scribner. Nebr. German Mutual Insurance Association of Nebraska Johnson, Nebr. German Mutual Insurance Company of Saline and Seward Counties Milford, Nebr. Grange Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Washington and Burt Counties, Nebraska Blair, Nebr. Grange Mutual Insurance Company of Custer County, Nebraska Broken Bow. Nebr. Hammond Precinct Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Nuckolls County, Nebraska. Davenport, Nebr. Interstate Automobile Fire Insurance Association Hastings, Nebr. Jefferson County Assessment Association Diller, Nebr. Kearney County Farmers' Mutual Minden, Nebr. Lancaster County Farmers' Mutual Bennett, Nebr. Lancaster &amp; Gage Mutual Fire &amp; Lightning Firth, Nebr. Leigh German Farmers' Mutual Leigh, Nebr. Madison County Farmers' Mutual Battle Creek. Nebr. Mutual Fire Insurance Company of the German Farmers of Saunders County, Nebraska Colon. Nebr. Mutual Protective Fire Association Seward, Nebr. Nebraska Lumbermen's Mutual Insurance Association Lincoln Nebr, Nebraska Mutual Lincoln, Nebr. Nemaha County Farmers' Mutual Fire and Lightning Auburn, Nebr. Nuckolls County Farmers' Mutual Nelson, Nebr. Nysted Farmers' Assessment Dannebrog, Nebr. Pawnee County Mutual Pawnee City, Nebr. Phelps County Fire &amp; Lightning Mutual Holdrege. Nebr. Pierce County Farmers' Mutual Pierce, Nebr. Platte Mutual Plattsmouth, Nebr. Polk &amp; Butler County Farmers' Mutual Osceola, Nebr. Richardson County Farmers Mutual Fire and Lightning,..Falls City, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Roman Catholic Farmers' Mutual Fire Petersburg, Nebr. Scandinavian Mutual Insurance Company of AxtelL Kearney County, Nebraska .?. Axtell. Nebr. State Farmers' Mutual South Omaha. Nebr. Sterling Farm Mutual Adams, Nebr. Svea Fire and Lightning Assessment Association of Saunders County, Nebraska ... Wahoo, Nebr. Washington County Scandinavian Mutual Kennard, Nebr. Western Union Mutual Insurance Association Wilber, Nebr. Wilcox Farmers' Mutual Fire and Lightning Wilcox, Nebr. STOCK LEGAL RESERVE LIFE INSURANCE COMPANIES— 35; BURIAL, 1. Aetna Life Hartford, Conn. American Central Life Indianapolis, Ind. American Life Des Moines, la. Bankers' Life Lincoln, Nebr. Bankers' Reserve Life, The Omaha, Nebr. Capitol Life Denver, Colo. Central Life Assurance Society Des Moines, la. Central States Life St. Louis, Mo. Commonwealth Life Omaha, Nebr. Continental Life Salt Lake City, Utah. Equitable Life Assurance Society „ New York. N. Y. Equitable Life Insurance Company of Iowa Des Moines, la. Fanners' Life Denver. Colo. Franklin Life Springfield, 111. Germania Life New York, N. Y. Guaranty Life Davenport, la. Home Life New York, N. Y. Kansas City Life Kansas City, Mo. Manhattan Life New York City, N. Y. Merchants Life Burlington, la. Michigan Mutual Life _ Detroit. Mich. Midwest Life Lincoln, Nebr. Missouri State Life St. Louis, Mo. National Life Insurance Company of the U. S. A Chicago, 111. Old Colony Life .„ Chicago, 111 Old Line Lincoln, Nebr. Pacific Mutual Life - Los Angeles, Calif. Peoples' Life Chicago, 111 Prairie Life Omaha. Nebr. Protective League Life -...Decatur, 111. Provident Life &amp; Trust Company 1 Philadelphia, Pa. Prudential Insurance Company of America Newark. N. J Reliance Life Pittsburg, Pa. Travelers • - Hartford, Conn. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 17 Union Central Life Cincinnati, O, Western Indemnity Company Omaha, Nebr. MUTUAL LEGAL RESERVE LIFE INSURANCE COMPANIES— 27 Bankers' Life Insurance Company of Des Moines Des Moines, la. Columbia Life Fremont, Nebr. Connecticut Mutual Life Hartford. Conn Elkhom Life and Accident Norfolk, Nebr. Fidelity Mutual Life Philadelphia, Pa. Fidelity Reserve Company North Platte, Nebr German American Life Omaha, Nebr, LaFayette Life LaFayette, Ind Massachusetts Mutual Life Springfield, Mass Metropolitan Life New York, N. Y Minnesota Mutual Life St. Paul. Minn Mutual Benefit Life Newark, N. J Mutual Life New York. N. Y, National Life Montpelier, Vt, New England Mutual Life Boston, Mass New York Life New York, N. Y Northwestern Mutual Life Milwaukee, Wis Northwestern National Life Minneapolis, Minn. Omaha Life Omaha, Nebr. Penn Mutual Life Philadelphia, Pa, Phoenix Mutual Life Hartford, Conn, Scandia Life Chicago. Ill Security Mutual Life Lincoln, Nebr. Security Mutual Life Binghamton, N. Y State Life Indianapolis, Ind State Mutual Life Assurance Company Worcester, Mass Union Mutual Life Portland, Me ASSESSMENT LIFE ASSOCIATIONS— 5 Guarantee Fund Life Association Omaha, Nebr Illinois Bankers Life Association Monmouth, 111, National Life Association Des Moines, la, Nebraska State Life Grand Island. Nebr. Scandinavian Mutual Aid Association Minden, Nebr. CASUALTY, SURETY AND MISCELLANEOUS COMPANIES— 69. Aetna Accident and Liability Company Hartford, Conn. Aetna Life Hartford, Conn, American Casualty Company Reading, Pa. American Credit Indemnity Company New York, N. Y, American Fidelity Company Montpelier, Vt. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT American Indemnity Company Galveston, Texas. American Mutual Surety Company Lincoln, Nebr. American Old Line Lincoln, Nebr. American Surety Company New York. X. Y. Automobile _ Lincoln, Xebr. Bankers' Accident I Des Moines, la. Casualty Company of America New York, N. Y. Chicago Bonding &amp; Surety Company Chicago, 111. Continental Casualty Company Chicago, 111. Employers' Liability Assurance Corporatioi. Ltd. Boston, Mass. European Accident Insurance Company. Ltd New York, X. Y. Federal Lincoln. Xebr. Fidelity &amp; Casualty Company of New York New York, N. Y. Fidelity &amp; Deposit Company of Maryland Baltimore, Md. Frankfort General New York, N. Y. General Accident Fire and Life Assurance Corporatioi ...Philadelphia, Pa. Georgia Casualty Company Macon, Ga. Globe Indemnity Company N «w York, N. Y. Great Eastern Casualty Company Ne •• York, N. Y. Great Western Accident Des Moines, la. Guardian Casualty &amp; Guaranty . Salt Lake "ity. Utah. Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company Hartfo -d, Conn. Hartford Steam Boiler Inspection and Insurance Company Hartford, Home Casualty Company Omaha, N^br. Indiana &amp; Ohio Live Stock Crawfordsville, Ind. Inter-Ocean Casualty Company Indianapolis, Ind. Kansas City Casualty Company Kansas City, Mo. Lincoln Accident Lincoln, Nebr. Lion Bonding &amp; Surety Company Omaha. Nebr. Lloyds Plate Glass New York. N. Y. London Guaranty &amp; Accident Company. Ltd Chicago, 111. London &amp; Lancashire Guarantee &amp; Accident Company. ..New York. N. Y London and Lancashire Indemnity Cowipany of America New York, X. Y. Maryland Casualty Company Baltimore, Md. Maryland Motor Car Baltimore, Md Masonic Protective Association Worcester, Mass. Massachusetts Bonding &amp; Insurance Company Boston, Mass. Merchants Life and Casualty Company Minneapolis, Minn Metropolitan Casualty New York, N. Y, Metropolitan Life New York, N. Y National Accident Lincoln, Nebr. National Life Insurance Company of the U. S. A Chicago, 111 National Surety Company New York, N. Y. Nebraska Manufacturers' Mutual Casualty Association Omaha, Nebr. New Amsterdam Casualty Company Baltimore, Md, </seg>
            <seg id="p019">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 19 New England Equitable. Boston, Mass. New Jersey Fidelity &amp; Plate Glass Newark. N. J. New York Plate Glass New York, N. Y. North American Accident Chicago. 111. Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corporation, Ltd New York, N. Y. Pacific Mutual Life Los Angeles, Calif. Pioneer Lincoln, Nebr. Preferred Accident New York, N. Y. Red Men's Fraternal Accident Association of America. ..Westfield, Mass. Reliance Life Pittsburg. Pa. Southern Surety Company Denison, Okla. Standard Accident Detroit, Mich Standard Live Stock Indianapolis, Ind Travelers Hartford, Conn. Travelers Indemnity Company Union Accident Hartford, Conn, Lincoln, Nebr United States Casualty Company New York, N. Y United States Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Company World Life and Accident Baltimore, Md Chicago, III ASSESSMENT HEALTH AND ACCIDENT ASSOCIATIONS— 18 Brotherhood of All Railway Employees Chicago, 111. Business Men's Accident Association of America Kansas City. Mo. Business Men's Protective Association Des Moines, la. Central Business Men's Association Chicago, 111 Central Health Company Lincoln, Nebr. Conservative Health and Accident Company Grand Island. Nebr. Fraternal Protective Association Boston, Mass, Inter-State Businesss Men's Accident Association Des Moines, la. Mutual Benefit Health &amp; Accident Association Omaha, Nebr National Travelers Benefit Association Des Moines. la Omaha Health &amp; Accident Association Omaha, Nebr. Physicians Casualty Association Omaha, Nebr. Physicians Health Association of America Omaha, Nebr. Travelers Health Association Omaha, Nebr. Universal Protective Association Columbus, Nebr. Western Travelers Accident Association Omaha, Nebr. Woodmen Accident Company _ _ Lincoln, Nebr. World Accident Association Omaha, Nebr. FRATERNAL BENEFICIARY ASSOCIATIONS— 46. Aid Association for Lutherans Appleton. Wis, Ancient Order United Workmen Grand Island, Nebr, Ben Hur Crawfordsville. Ind Brotherhood of American Yeomen : Des Moines, la, Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Peoria, 111 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Cleveland, Ohio. Catholic Knights of America St. Louis, Mo. Catholic Mutual Benefit Association Hornell, N. Y. Catholic Order of Foresters Chicago, 111. Catholic Union of Daughters of Columbus Omaha, Nebr. Catholic Workman _ New Prague. Minn. Court of Honor Springfield, 111. Danish Brotherhood in America. Omaha, Nebr. Degree of Honor, A. 0. U. W. of Nebraska Lincoln, Nebr. Fraternal Aid Union Lawrence, Kan. German Baptists Life Association Buffalo, N. Y. Independent Order of Foresters Toronto, Can. Independent Order of Vikings Chicago, 111. Knights of Columbus New Haven. Conn. Knights ft Ladies of Security Topeka. Kan. Knights of Pythias Indianapolis, Ind. Ladies of the Modern Maccabees Port Huron Mich. Ladies Auxiliary to Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Columbus, O. Loyal Mystic Legion Hastings, Nebr. Maccabees, The Detroit, Mich. Modern Brotherhood of America ! Mason City, la. Modern Woodmen of America Rock Island. 111. Mystic Toilers Des Moines, la. Mystic Workers of the World.... Fulton, 111. National Fraternal Society of the Deaf Chicago, 111. National Union Toledo, O. Polish National Alliance Chicago, 111. Railway Mail Association Portsmouth, N. H. Roman Catholic Mutual Protective Society Ft. Madison, la. Royal Arcanum Boston, Mass. Royal Highlanders Aurora, Nebr. Royal League Chicago. 111. Royal Neighbors of America Rock Island. 111. Sons of Hermann Columbus, Nebr. South Slavonic Catholic Union Ely. Minn. United Commercial Travelers of America Columbus, O. Western Bohemian Catholic Union Spillville, la. Western Bohemian Fraternal Association Cedar Rapids, la. Woman's Benefit Association of the Maccabees Port Huron, Mich. Woodmen Circle Omaha, Nebr. Woodmen of the World Omaha. Nebr. RECAPITULATION Stock Fire Insurance Companies 112 Mutual Fire, Tornado and Hail Insurance Companies 12 Assessment Hail and Plate Glass Insurance Companies t </seg>
            <seg id="p021">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 21 Assessment Fire and Tornado Insurance Companies 73 Stock Legal Reserve Life Insurance Companies 35 Burial Insurance Company - X. Mutual Legal Reserve Life Insurance Companies 2T Assessment Life Associations 5 Casualty, Surety and Miscellaneous Insurance Companies _ 69 Assessment Health and Accident Associations _ 18 fraternal Beneficiary Associations 46 Total 400 Domestic Companies _ _ 130 Foreign Companies _ _ 270 Total 400 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT COMPANIES WITHDRAWN, CHANGED OR MERGED DURING BIENNIUM Includes all companies which were licensed and doing business in Nebraska December 1, 1914, and which have voluntarily Avith dr;i\vn: or were refused license in I'll 5 or l!)lti; or were placed in hands of receiver. Also includes correct ion of errors in Sum- maries for IMS, 11)14 and 191") as to names of companies: and changes of MUM and nature of business or character of corpor ations. The tallies following shows changes made durum the present biciinium : Change of Merged Change in Name Classification Stock Fire 1 1 Mutual Fire 1 .. 2 Assessment Hail Farm Mutual 12 1 l Stock Life 2 1 ;&gt; Mutual Life 112 Assessment Life 1 .. 2 Casualty i ..5 6 7 Mutual Accident 2 .. 4 Fraternal 4 11 Totals .29 11 24 License Omitted from Withdrawal and Refused Prior Report Receivership Assessment Hail 1 Assessment Life 1 Casualty 15 Mutual Accident .. 1 Fraternal 1 Totals _ 2 2 6 STOCK FIRE INSURANCE COMPANIES Deduct for merger 1 Change of name 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 23 Columbia Fire Insurance Company, Omaha, Nebraska. This com- pany makes regular statements, pays its fees, and receives license each year, but has written no business since 1911, because of a re-insurance agreement with the National Fire Insurance Company of Hartford. Imperial Assurance Company, New York. N. Y. This company was formerly the Pelican Assurance Co. Name was changed October 16, 1914 by amended Charter. Business for 1914 is shown in Summary under new name. Pelican Assurance Company, New York, N. Y. Business for 1913 and prior years shown in 1913 Summary under this name. Name changed October 16, 1914, to Imperial Assurance Co., and subsequent Summaries shown business under new name. Williamsburg City Fire Insurance Company, New York, N. Y. Merged August 24, 1916, with United States Fire Insurance Co., New York, taking latter name. MUTUAL FIRE, TORNADO AND HAIL INSURANCE COMPANIES. Deduct for change in Classification 2 Change of name r. 1 Automobile Mutual Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Name changed January 28, 1916, to Automobile Insurance Co. Listed in 1915 Sum- mary under casualty, surety and miscellaneous companies. Nebraska Lumberman's Mutual Insurance Association. Lincoln, Ne- braska. Listed with mutual (ire, tornado and hail insurance companies in Summary for 1913 and with farm and village mutual assessment fire and tornado insurance companies in 1914 and 1915 Summaries. ASSESSMENT HAIL AND PLATE GLASS INSURANCE COMPANIES Deduct for refusal to license 1 Nebraska Hail Insurance Co., Hastings, Nebraska. License for 1916 refused May 1, 1916, because of unsatisfactory management of company during 1915. FARM AND VILLAGE MUTUAL ASSESSMENT FIRE AND TORNADO INSURANCE COMPANIES Change of name 12 Add for change of classification 1 Deduct for merger ....- 1 Antelope County Assessment Association. Neligh, Nebraska. Name changed February 13, 1915 from Antelope County Farmers' Mutual In- surance Co. Cuming, Burt and Dodge Counties Farmers' Mutual Insurance Co., Oakland, Nebraska. This company was erroneously listed in 1913 Sum- mary as "Farmers' Mutual of Burt, Cuming and Dodge Counties." Name has never been changed. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Farm Central Mutual Fire Insurance Co., Hastings, Nebraska. Er - roneously listed in 1914 and 1915 Summaries as "Farm Central Mutual Insurance Co." Fanners' Mutual Insurance Company of Hamilton County, Aurora, Nebraska. Name changed March 1, 1916, from Farmers' Alliance Mutual Insurance Co. Erroneously listed in 1913 Summary as "Farmers' Al - liance Fire and Lightning Mutual Insurance Co." Farmers' Assessment Tornado Insurance Association. Wahoo, Ne - braska. Erroneously listed in 1914 and 1915 Summaries as "Farmers' Assessment Tornado Association." Farmers' Mutual Fire and Lightning Insurance Company of Burt County, Craig, Nebraska. The words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Thayer County, Carleton, Nebraska. The words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted from Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Fillmore County, Fairmont, Nebraska. Articles of incorporation show name as given above, but the Company's letterheads, policies and reports show variance. Letterheads and policies give name as "Fillmore County Farmers' Mutual Insurance Co." and sometimes add the words "of Geneva." Summary for 1913 gives name as "Farmers' Mutual of Geneva." Farmers' Mutual Home Tornado Insurance Co., Hooper, Nebraska. Name changed June 19, 1915, from Farmers' Mutual Home Tornado and Windstorm Insurance Co. Incorrectly listed in Summaries for 1913 and 1914. Farmers Mutual Insurance Company of Buffalo County, Kearney, Nebraska. Words "Insurance Company," erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Nebraska, Lincoln, Ne - braska. Words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Fire Assessment Insurance Association of Madison, Pierce, Wayne, Stanton and Adjoining Counties. Norfolk, Nebraska. Name changed March 3, 1915 from Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Madison, Pierce, Wayne, and Stanton Counties. Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Madison, Platte and Stanton Counties, Madison, Nebraska. Words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Plymouth, Nebraska, Ply - mouth, Nebraska. Works "Insurance Company" and "Nebraska" er - roneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Saunders County, Wahoo, Nebraska. Words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 25 Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Wausa, Wausa. Nebraska. Words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted from name in Sum - maries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of York County, York, Ne - braska. Words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Farmers' Storm and Tornado Assessment Insurance Association of Madison, Pierce, Wayne, Stanton and Adjoining Counties, Norfolk, Nebraska. Name changed December 14, 1914, from North Nebraska Mutual Tornado Insurance Co. Farmers' Union Mutual Insurance Company of Saunders County, Fremont, Nebraska. Erroneously listed in 1913 and 1914 Summaries as "Farmers Union Mutual of Mead" and in 1915 Summary as "Farmers' Union Mutual of Fremont." Furnas County Mutual Insurance Company, Beaver City, Nebraska. Erroneously listed in 1913 and 1914 Summaries as "Furnas County Farmers' Mutual." Gage County Insurance Company, Blue Springs, Nebraska. Name changed May 7, 1915 from "Gage County Fire and Lightning, Tornado and Cyclone Insurance Association." Summary for 1913 erroneously includes word "Mutual" in name. Mutual Fire Insurance Company of the German Farmers of Saun - ders County, Nebraska, Colon, Nebraska. Erroneously listed in Sum - mary for 1913 as "German Farmers' Mutual. German Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Sarpy County, Nebraska, Gretna, Nebraska. Erroneously listed in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915 as "German Farmers' Mutual of Sarpy Co." German Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Association of Seward County, Nebraska, Seward, Nebraska. Erroneously listed in Sum - maries for 1913, 1914 and 1915 as "German Farmers' Mutual Ins. Assn. of Seward Co." German Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Association of York County, Nebraska, York, Nebraska. Word "Insurance" erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. German Mutual Insurance Company of Dodge County, Nebraska. Scribner, Nebraska. Name changed January 12, 1915, from "Mutual Fire Insurance Company of German Farmers of Dodge County, Ne - braska." Erroneously listed in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1914. German Mutual Insurance Association of Nebraska, Johnson, Neb - raska. Name changed January 26, 1915, from "German Mutual Insur - ance Association of Nemaha County and Vicinity in Nebraska". Word "Fire" erroneously included in name in 1913 Summary. Name erro - neously, listed in 1915 Summary as "German Mutual Association of Johnson, Nemaha County". German Mutual Insurance Company of Saline and Seward Counties, Milford, . Nebraska. Words "Insurance Company" erroneously omitted </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT from name in 1913 summary. Word "Association" instead of "Company" erroneously used in name in 1914 and 1915 Summaries. Grange and Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company, of Washington and Burt Counties, Nebraska, Blair, Nebraska. Summaries for 1913 and 1914 erroneously omit from name the words "Insurance Company of Washington and Burt Counties, Nebraska". Summary for 1915 erro - neously omits words "Insurance Company" and "Nebraska". Grange Mutual Insurance Company of Custer County, Nebraska, Broken Bow, Nebraska. Word "Nebraska" erroneously omitted from name in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Hammond Precinct Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Nuokolls County, Nebraska, Davenport, Nebraska. Name erroneously shortened to "Hammond Precinct Mutual" in Summaries for 1913, 1914 and 1915. Jefferson County Assessment Association, Dillei-, Nebraska. Name changed January 12, 1915 from Jefferson County Mutual Insurance Com - pany of Diller, Nebraska. Originally Harbine Mutual Insurance Com - pany, name changed January 8, 1907. Kearney County Farmers Mutual Insurance Co., Minden, Nebraska. Word "Mutual" erroneously omitted from name in Summary for 1915. Lancaster and Gage Mutual Fire and Lightning Insurance Co., Firth, Nebraska. Words "Fire and Lightning" erroneously omitted from name in 1915 Summary. Word "Farmers" erroneously included in name in Summary for 1913. Nebraska Lumbermen's Mutual Insurance Association, Lincoln, Ne - braska. Listed with mutual fire, tornado and hail insurance associa - tions in Summary for 1913; under present heading in 1914 and 1915 summaries. Nysted Farmers Assessment Insurance Co., Nysted, Nebraska. Name changed Janaury 14, 1915, from "Mutual" to "Assessment". Sum - maries of 1914 and 1915 erroneously use word "Association" instead of "Company". Phelps County Fire and Lightning Mutual Insurance Co., Holdrege, Nebraska. Word "Farmers" erroneously included in name in Summary for 1913. Scandinavian Mutual Insurance Company of Axtell, Kearney County, Nebraska, Axtell, Nebraska. Name changed January 11, 1915, by dropping word "Fire". January 11, 1915 reinsured and took over Scan - dinavian Mutual Life Stock Insurance Co. Scandinavian Mutual Live Stock Insurance Co., Axtell, Nebraska. Reinsured January 11, 1915, and merged into Scandinavian Mutual In - surance Co., of Axtell. Svea Fire and Lightning Assessment Association of Saunders County, Nebraska, Wahoo, Nebraska. Name changed March 20, 1915, by substituting word "Assessment" for "Mutual" and inserting "Fire and Lightning". </seg>
            <seg id="p027">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 27 Stock Legal Reserve Life Insurance Companies Deduct for merger 1 Add for change in classification 4 Deduct for change in classification 1 Change in name 2 Central National Life Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Organized as an assessment life association; changed to mutual legal reserve basis; and on July 11, 1914 reorganized as a stock legal reserve company. Reinsured January 28, 1916, and merged with Central States Life Insur- ance Co., St. Louis, Mo. Merchants Life Insurance Co., Burlington, Iowa. Changed from assessment to stock company February 20, 1915. Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, New York, N. Y. Changed from stock to mutual legal reserve January 6, 1915. Mutual Protective League, Decatur, 111. Fraternal beneficiary society changed Nov. 1, 1914, to stock legal reserve life insurance company, named Protective League Life Insurance Company. Old Line Insurance Company, Lincoln, Nebraska. Formerly Old Line Accident Insurance Co. Name changed May 25, 1915. Re-incorporated June 22, 1916 to write life, accident and health insurance. Protective League Life Insurance Co., Decatur, III. Changed to stock company, Nov. 1, 1914, from fraternal beneficiary society. For- merly Mutual Protective League. Western Indemnity Insurance Company, Omaha, Nebr., Stock legal reserve company doing burial association business included with mis- cellaneous companies in 1913 Summary. Mutual Legal Reserve Life Insurance Companies Add for change in classification 2 Change of name. — 1 Deduct for merger 1 Central National Life Insurance Company, Lincoln, Nebraska. Re insured Jan. 28, 1916, and merged with Central States Life Insurance Co., St. Louis, Mo. Organized as an assessment life association; changed to mutual legal reserve basis; and on July 11, 1914 reorganized as a stock legal reserve company. Fidelity Life Association of Nebraska, Lexington, Nebraska. Licen- sed Mar. 4, 1913, as an assessment life association. Changed to mutual legal reserve company Dec. 11, 1915, and name changed to Fidelity Re- serve Company. Fidelity Reserve Company, North Platte, Nebraska. Reincorpo- rated Jan. 19, 1916, as a mutual reserve life insurance company. Formerly Fidelity Life Association of Nebraska. Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, New York, N. Y. Changed from stock to mutual legal reserve Jan. 6, 1915. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Assessment Life Insurance Associations Deduct for change in classification 2 Add for omission in prior report 1 Change of name _ 1 Fidelity Life Association of Nebraska, Lexington, Nebraska. Licen- sed Mar. 4, 1913, as an assessment life association. Changed to mutual reserve company, Dec. 11, 1915, under name of Fidelity Reserve Co. Illinois Bankers Life Association, Monmouth, 111. Admitted as an assessment life association June 26, 1913, but not included in Biennial Report for 1913-1914. Merchants Life Insurance Co., Burlington, Iowa. Changed from assessment association to stock company Feb. 20, 1915. Nebraska State Life Insurance Company, Grand Island, Nebr. For- merly Prime of Life Insurance Company, Omaha; name changed May 18, 1915; place of busines changed July 21, 1915; accident business reinsured by Pioneer Insurance Co., Lincoln, Jan. 1, 1916. Prime of Life Insurance Association, Omaha, Nebr. Licensed July 11, 1913, as an assessment life insurance association. Name changed May 18, 1915. to Nebraska State Life Insurance Co. Casualty, Surety and Miscellaneous Insurance Companies Deduct for change in classification 2 Add for change in classification 5 Deduct for merger 6 Deduct for receivership _ 2 Deduct for withdrawal 3 Add for omission in prior report 1 Change of name 5 American Accident Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Name changed Jan. 24, 1916, to American Old Line Insurance Co. Changed from assessment association to legal reserve stock company, July 21, 1914. American Bonding Co., Baltimore, Md. Did not request license for 1915 or 1916. Reinsured June 27, 1913 in Fidelity and Deposit Company. American Fidelity Company, Montpelier, Vt. Reinsured its surety business Oct. 2, 1916, in National Surety Co., New York. Notice Oct. 13, 1916, that its accident and health business will be reinsured. American Old Line Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Name changed Jan. 24, 1916, from American Accident Insurance Co. Automobile Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Name changed Jan. 28, 1916, from Automobile Mutual Insurance Co. Listed under mutual fire, tornado and hail companies in 1913 and 1914 Summaries; put in casualty, surety and miscellaneous companies in 1915 Summary. Bankers Accident Insurance Co., Des Moines, Iowa. Changed from assessment association Aug. 24, 1914, to legal reserve stock company. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 29 Columbus Accident and Health Association, Columbus, Nebraska. Licensed July 19, 1915. Reinsured and ceased business Dec. 1, 1915. Employers Mutual Liability Insurance Company of Nebraska, Omaha, Nebraska. Licensed Dec. 24, 1914. Ceased business July, 1915. Equitable Surety Co., St. Louis, Mo. Merged with New England Casualty Co., Boston, Mass. June 11, 1915; under name of New England Equitable Insurance Company. Federal Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Formerly Frontier Acci - dent Insurance Co. Name changed March 7, 1916. No Business written in 1914 and 1915. Frontier Accident Insurance Company, Lincoln, Nebr. Licensed Feb. 17, 1913. Reinsured in Lincoln Accident Insurance Company, Sept. 26, 1913. No business written 1914 or 1915. Name changed Mar. 7, 1916, to Federal Insurance Company. Great Western Accident Insurance Co., Des Moines, Iowa. For - merly Great Western Accident Association. An- assessment health and accident association; incorporated as a stock company February 1914. Illinois Surety Co., Chicago, 111. In hands of receiver April 20, 1916. London and Lancashire Guarantee and Accident Company of Can - ada, Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Business reinsured and taken over by London and Lancashire Indemnity Company of America, New York, Sept. 15, 1915. National Fidelity and Casualty Co., Omaha, Nebraska. Taken over by State Insurance Board June 10, 1915, because of impaired capital. New England Causalty Co., Boston, Mass. Merged with Equitable Surety Co., St. Louis, Mo., June 11, 1915, under name of New England Equitable Insurance Company. New England Equitable Insurance Co., Boston, Mass. Name changed June 24, 1915, from New England Casualty Co. Merged with EquitaWe Surety Co., St. Louis, Mo., June 11, 1915. Northwestern Live Stock Insurance Co., Des Moines, Iowa. Rein - sured April 30, 1915, in Iowa Live Stock Insurance Co., the latter not admitted to Nebraska. Old Line Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Name changed May 25, 1915, from Old Line Accident Insurance Co. Articles of incorporation amended June 22, 1916 to cover life insurance as well as health and accident. Red Men's Fraternal Accident Association of America, Westfield, Mass. Changed from assessment association to stock company, Jan, 1, 1915. Southern Surety Co., Denison, Oklahoma. Merged with Southwes - tern Surety Co., DenUon, Texas, Dec. 31, 1915. General offices at St. Louis, Mo.; home office, Denison, Okla. Southwestern Surety Co., Denison, Texas. Reinsured by and mer - ged into Southern Surety Co., Denison, Okla., Dec. 31, 1915. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Union Casualty Insurance Company, Philadelphia, Pa. No business in Nebraska in 1914 and 1915. Discontinued all business outside home state February 18, 1916. United States Health and Accident Insurance Co., Saginaw, Mich. Absorbed by Massachusetts Bonding and Insurance Company in May, 1914. Omitted from Biennial Report for 1913-1914. Western Indemnity Insurance Company, Omaha, Nebraska. Stock Legal reserve life insurance company, doing burial association business included in 1913 Summary with miscellaneous companies. Under proper heading in 1914 and 1915 Summaries. Mutual A isessment Health and Accident Insurance Associations Dedu ,"t for change in classification _ 4 Deduct for dissolution _ 1 Chai.ge of name 2 American Accident Insurance Co., Lincoln, Nebraska. Changed from assessment association to legal reserve stock company July 21, 1914. Name changed Jan. 24, 1916, to American Old Line Insurance Co. Bankers' Accident Insurance Co., Des Moines, Iowa. Changed to legal reserve stock company, Aug. 24, 1914. Great Western Accident Association, Des Moines, Iowa. Changed to legal reserve stock company, February 1914, with name of Great Wes- tern Accident Insurance Co. Nebraska Workmen Accident Association, Aurora, Nebraska. Licen- sed Aug. 14, 1912. Dissolved by Board of Directors July 30, 1914. Red Men's Fraternal Accident Association of America, Westfield, Mass. Changed to stock company Jan. 1, 1915. Fraternal Beneficiary Insurance Associations Deduct for change in classification 1 Deduct for merger 1 Add for re-license -.... 1 Change of name 4 Ben Hur, Supreme Tribe of, Crawfordsville, Ind. Not licensed in 1913. Licensed 1914, 1915 and 1916. Fraternal Aid Association, Lawrence, Kansas. Merged with the Fraternal Union of America, Sept. 12, 1914, under name of Fraternal Aid Union. No report in Summary for 1914. Fraternal Aid Union, Lawrence, Kansas. Made no annual state- ment Dec. 31, 1914 and was not licensed in 1915. Licensed Jan. 31, 1916. This society is a consolidation of the following ten companies: American Nobles American Order of Protection Sons and Daughters of Protection American Home Association </seg>
            <seg id="p031">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 31 Modern National Reserve Peoples Fraternal Reserve Court of Columbian Circles Western Bees Fraternal Aid Association Fraternal Union of America. Fraternal Union of America, Denver, Colo. Merged with the Fra - ternal Aid Association, Lawrence, Kansas, Sept. 12, 1914, under name of Fraternal Aid Union. No report in Summary for 1914. Knights of the Maccabees of the World, Detroit, Mich. Merged July 20, 1914 with Modern Maccabees under name of The Maccabees. Merger approved Jan. 27, 1915 by Nebraska Department. Ladies of the Maccabees of the World, Port Huron, Mich. Name changed July 28, 1915 to Woman's Benefit Association of the Maccabees. Maccabees, The, Detroit, Michigan. Merger July 20, 1914, of Mod - ern Maccabees with Knights of the Maccabees of the World, approved Jan. 27, 1915. Mutual Protective League, Decatur, 111. Changed from fraternal beneficiary society, Nov. 1, 1914, to stock legal reserve life insurance company named Protective League Life Insurance Co. Woman's Benefit Association of the Maccabees, Port Huron, Mich. Name changed July 28, 1915, from Ladies of the Maccabees of the World. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT COMPANIES ADMITTED AND LICENSED DURING BIENNIUM. Includes all companies, domestic or foreign, licensed to do business in Nebraska, covering the period commencing December 1, 1914, and ending November 30, 1916. During this biennium three companies that had been admitted previously, and after - ward withdrawn or refused license, were readmitted. The Farmers Life Insurance Company of Denver, Colo., was admitted July 11, 1913, by the Auditor of Public Accounts, just prior to the transfer of the Insurance Department to the then newly created State Insurance Board. This license expired April 30, 1914, and renewal was refused May 1, 1914. In the meantime the company had joined with certain other companies in a suit to have the new insurance code declared void, and, being thereby precluded from appealing to the District Court of Lancaster County under the code provisions (Sec. 13, Gen. Sec. 3149. Re - vised Statutes, 1913,) obtained a restraining order from the United States Court preventing the Insurance Board from in - terfering with its business in Nebraska. Under the rule requiring three federal judges to sit in a ease involving the constitutionality of a state statute, the injunction suit dragged along until early in 1916 an agreement was reached whereby the company dis - missed its suit, and license was issued May 1, 1916, and all fees paid for 1914 and 1915. Tabulated by nature of business transacted 42 original licenses were issued as follows : </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD Foreign Foreign Domestic Admitted Readmit- ! Licensed Total ted Stock Fire : 5 2 18 Mutual Fire 3 — — 3 9 Farm Mutual — —22 Stock Life 3 1 — 4 Mutual Life — — 1 1 Casualty 9 — 2 11 Mutual Accident 4—59 Fraternal 3—14 12 4_' Totals. 21 Two domestic companies, the Employers' Mutual Liability, of Omaha : and the Columbus Accident and Health, of Columbus, wrote only a small amount of business and then re-insured the same and withdrew. The following list of admitted and licensed companies is ar - ranged alphabetically under the several classifications: Stock Fire Insurance Companies Admissions foreign companies 5 Re-admission foreign companies 2 Domestic organizations licensed 1 Alliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pa. Ad- mitted October 20, 1916. Capital $750,000. Incorporated December 5, 1904. Commenced business Jan. 1, 1905. Writes fire, marine, tourists' baggage and motor vehicle insurance. American Eagle Fire Insurance Company, New York, N. Y. Ad- mitted August 10, 1916. Capital, one million dollars; surplus, one mil- lion. Organized July 14, 1915. Writes fire and marine insurance. Mercantile Insurance Company of America, New York, N. Y. Ad- mitted as North British and Mercantile Insurance Company, December 18, 1914. Name changed to present title October 28, 1915. Capital $1, - 000,000. Incorporated Aug. 4, 1897 as the North British and Mercantile Insurance Co. Commenced business Oct. 1, 1897. Writes fire, tornado, automobile and sprinkler leakage insurance. North British and Mercantile Insurance Company, New York, N. Y. Admitted December 18, 1914. Name changed October 28, 1915, to Mer - cantile Insurance Company of America. (See Mercantile Insurance Com- pany of America for data). </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT National Security Fire Insurance Company, Omaha, Nebraska. Li - censed June 14, 1915. Capital $248,875. Incorporated September 12, 1914. Commenced business June 12, 1915.. Writes fire insurance. Paternelle Fire Insurance Company, Paris, France. Admitted Jan - uary 18, 1915. Correct Name: La Paternelle Fire Insurance Company, Ltd. United States branch, New York, N. Y. Capital $1,200,000 author - ized; 480,000 paid in. Established in 1843. Entered United States in 1913 to write fire re-insurance. All assets of the company are liable for payment of losses, wherever incurred. Writes fire, automobile, sprinkler, leakage, hail and tornado re-insurance, in the United States. Salamandra Insurance Company, Petrograd, Russia. Admitted Jan - uary 18, 1910, but did no business until after re-admission January 18, 1915. Capital five million rubel, all paid in. All assets liable for pay - ment of losses wherever incurred. December 31, 1914 capital $2,550,000; net surplus $2,136,028. Established in 1846. United States branch, New York, N. Y. Writes fire, hail, sprinkler leakage and tornado re-insurance, in the United States. Second Russian Insurance Co., Petrograd, Russia. Admitted Jan - uary 18, 1910, but did no business until after re-admission January 18, 1915. Capital $1,159,794, all paid in. All assets liable for payment of losses, wherever incurred. Net surplus $323,201, Dec. 31, 1913. Estab - lished in 1835. United States branch, New York, N. Y. Writes fire, tornado, hail and sprinkler leakage re-insurance in United States. Tokio Marine Insurance Company, Tokio, Japan. Admitted October 29, 1915. Capital one million yen ($500,000) paid in; four million yen authorized. All assets liable for payment of losses, wherever incurred Surplus and underwriting reserve $7,433,612, Dec 31. 1914. United States branch, New York, N. Y. Established in 1879. Writes marine, motor vehicle, tourists' baggage, and registered mail insurance in United States. Mutual Fire, Tornado and Hail Insurance Companies Admissions foreign companies Farmers Fire Insurance Company, York, Pa., admitted September 2, 1915. Net cash surplus $496,079.49, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated April 6, 1853, under a special charter. Writes fire insurance. Ohio Farmers Insurance Company, LeRoy, Ohio. Admitted May 17, 1915. Net cash surplus $1,226,482.71, Dec. 31, 1915. Commenced busi - ness July 8, 1848. Writes fire, windstorm and tornado insurance. St. Paul Mutual Hail and Cyclone Insurance Company, St. Paul, Minnesota. Admitted April 4, 1916.. Cash surplus $129,923.69, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated and commenced business in 1897. Writes hail and cyclone insurance. Farm and Village Mutual Assessment Fire and Tornado Insurance Companies Domestic Organizations licensed 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 35 Farmers Mutual Assessment Association of Nebraska, Big Spring, Nebraska. Licensed April 8, 1915. Admitted assets $135, Dec. 31. 1915. Incorporated April 8, 1915. Writes fire, lightning and tornado insurance. Interstate Automobile Fire Insurance Association, Hastings, Ne - braska. Licensed August 14, 1915. Admitted assets $1,078. Incorpor - ated August 2, 1915. Writes automobile, fire and tornado insurance. Stock Legal Reserve Life Insurance Companies Admissions foreign companies Re-admissions foreign companies 1 Central States Life Insurance Company, St. Louis, Mo. Admitted December 29, 1915. Reinsured and took over Central National Life In - surance Company, Lincoln, Nebraska, January 28, 1916. Capital $390, - 000; surplus $153,252, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated June 5, 1909; com - menced business Jan. 2, 1911. Writes annual dividend and non-partici - pating life insurance; American 3 l ,i%; modified preliminary term (Illin - ois standard). Continental Life Insurance Company, Salt Lake City, Utah. Admit - ted June 5, 1916. Capital $208,875; surplus $73,970, Dec. 31, 1915. In - corporated Feb. 19, 1904 and commenced business Mar. 1, 1904. Writes annual dividend, deferred dividend and non-participating insurance; now American 3*4%, full preliminary term. Farmers Life Insurance Company, Denver, Colo. Admitted July 11, 1913, license refused May 1, 1914, and May 1, 1915. Re-licensed to cover whole period May 1, 1916. Capital $254,756, surplus $332,584, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated Nov. 4, 1911; commenced business July 7, 1913. Writes non-participating insurance only; American 4%. full prelimin - ary term. Franklin Life Insurance Company, Springfield, Illinois. Admitted February 15, 1915. Capital $100,000; surplus $504,065, Dec. 31, 1915. In - corporated July 23, 1884, as an assessment association. Reorganized as a mutual legal reserve company July 1, 1898. Consolidated with the La Salle Insurance Co., July 27, 1910, as a stock company. Writes annual dividend, deferred dividend, and non-participating insurance; American 3%%, modified preliminary term (Illinois standard). Mutual Legal Reserve Life Insurance Companies Domestic organizations licensed 1 Omaha Life Insurance Company, Omaha, Nebraska. Licensed Jan - uary 27, 1916. Incorporated Dec. 28, 1915, and commenced business January 27, 1916. Writes participating insurance; combined \°!o, full preliminary term. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Casualty, Surely and Miscellaneous Companies Admissions foreign companies 9 Domestic organizations licensed 2 American Indemnity Company, Galveston, Texas. Admitted July 29, 1916. Capital $500,000; surplus $66,841.51, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated April 29, 1913 and commenced business May 15, 1913. Charter provides for writing fidelity and surety bonds and general casualty insurance. Employers Liability Assurance Corporation, Ltd. London, England. Admitted December 16, 1914. United States branch, Boston, Mass. De - posit capital $250,000; surplus $2,130,316.43, Dec. 31, 1915. Organized in 1880 and entered United States 1886. Specializes on liability and compensation insurance, but writes fidelity and general casualty insur - ance. Employers Mutual Liability Insurance Company of Nebraska, Omaha, Nebraska. Licensed December 24, 1914; ceased writing business July 1915. European Accident Insurance Company, Ltd., London, England. Admitted May 1, 1915. United States branch, New York, N. Y. Deposit capital and surplus $725,000, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated May 10, 1911. Regularly admitted to write re-insurance in United States in 1911. Writes re-insurance only on multiple lines of casualty insurance. Guardian Casualty and Guaranty Insurance Company, Salt Lake City, Utah. Admitted September 8, 1915. No business written in Ne - braska in 1915. Capital $300,000; surplus $232,079.99, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated May 14, 1909, and commenced business the next day. Writes accident and health, liability, plate glass, burglary, workmen's collective and compensation insurance, and fidelity and surety bonds. Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company, Hartford, Connecticut. Admitted May 1, 1916. Capital $800,000; surplus $370,993.41, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated and commenced business August, 1913. Writes gen - eral casualty lines, fidelity and surety bonds and in conjunction with the Hartford Fire issues a policy covering all indemnity on live stock. London and Lancashire Indemnity Company of America, New York, N. Y. Admitted October 27, 1915. Capital $750,000; surplus $525,188.08, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated June 2, 1914; commenced business June 15, 1915. Writes accident, health, plate glass, burglary, liability and work - men's compensation, automobile, property damage, and fidelity and surety bonds. Maryland Motor Car Insurance Company, Baltimore, Maryland. Ad - mitted May 1, 1916. Capital $300,000; surplus $47,343.71, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated and began business March 1, 1910. Writes automobile in - surance only, covering fire, loss or damage in transportation, theft, col - lision and property damage. Listed in Best's Insurance Reports under fire and marine insurance companies. Merchants Life and Casualty Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Ad - mitted August 2, 1915. Capital $100,000; surplus $106,788.46, Dec. 31, </seg>
            <seg id="p037">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 37 1915. Incorporated June 23, 1908; commenced business July 25, 1908, as an assessment company. Reincorporated and commenced business as a stock company July 3, 1914. Writes accident and health insurance only. Nebraska Manufacturers Mutual Casualty Assn., Omaha, Nebraska. Licensed January 21, 1915. Net surplus $2,423.47, Dec. 31, 1915. Writes workmen's compensation business on mutual plan. Began business on day license was issued. New Amsterdam Casualty Company, New York and Baltimore. Ad - mitted October 26, 1916. Capital $750,000; surplus $200,077.71, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated in New York, Dec. 30, 1898 and commenced business Jan. 31, 1899. Writes all lines of casualty and surety business. Mutual and Assessment Health and Accident Associations Admissions foreign companies 4 Domestic organizations licensed 5 Business Men's Accident Association of America, Kansas City, Mis - souri. Admitted March 18, 1916. Admitted assets $134,005, Dec. 31, 1915. Incorporated June 28, 1909; commenced business July 1, 1909. Writes accident and health insurance only. Central Business Men's Association, Chicago, Illinois. Admitted August 17, 1916. Admitted assets $47,785.75, June 30, 1916. Incorpor - ated and commenced business in 1907. Writes accident and health in - surance only. Central Health Company, Lincoln, Nebraska. Licensed October 21, 1916. Incorporated and licensed under the assessment insurance laws of Nebraska. Writes health insurance only. Columbus Accident and Health Association, Columbus, Nebraska. Licensed July 19, 1915. Reinsured December 1, 1915 in Pioneer Insurance Company, Lincoln, Nebraska. Conservative Health and Accident Company, Grand Island, Nebraska. Licensed January 28, 1916. Incorporated Jan. 19, 1916, and licensed un - der the assessment insurance laws of Nebraska. Writes accident and health insurance. National Travelers Benefit Association, Des Moines, Iowa. Admit - ted October 20, 1916. Admitted assets $50,431.30, Sept. 30, 1916. In - corporated and commenced business in 1907. Writes acccident and health insurance. Omaha Health and Accident Association, Omaha, Nebraska. Licensed March 9, 1916. Incorporated Nov. 1, 1915 and licensed under the assess - ment insurance laws of Nebraska. Writes accident and health insurance. Universal Protective Association, Columbus, Nebraska. Licensed January 4, 1916. Incorporated Dec. 1, 1915, and licensed under the assessment insurance laws of Nebraska. Writes accident and health in - surance. World Life and Accident Insurance Company, Chicago, Illinois. Ad - mitted July 29, 1916. Name changed June 15, 1916 from World Casualty </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Company. Capital $100,000; surplus $60,011.21, Dec. 31, 1915. Incor - porated Aug. 30, 1911; commenced business July 1, 1912. Writes health and accident insurance. Fraternal Beneficiary Associations Admissions foreign companies 3 Domestic organizations licensed - 1 Catholic Mutual Benefit Association, Hornell, New York. Admitted June 8, 1916. Commenced business October 1876. Rates substantially in accord with NFC 4%. Membership, 64,187, Dec. 31, 1915; insurance in orce $82,748,000; assets $1,854,344.26; liabilities $403,014.83. Catholic Union Daughters of Columbus, Omaha, Nebraska. Licensed August 13, 1915. Incorporated Aug. 11, 1915, as a fraternal beneficiary society for "white female persons of Bohemian nationality and Catholic faith." German Baptists Life Association, Buffalo, New York. Admitted June 3, 1916. Incorporated June 17, 1899. Commenced business in 1883. Admitted assets June 30, 1915 were $150,521.04; liabilities $109,780.86. Rates readjusted April 1, 1911 on American 3V4%, select and ultimate basis. Membership 1903, June 30, 1915; insurance $1,703,583. South Slavonic Catholic Union, Ely, Minnesota. Admitted August 25, 1915. Commenced business July 18, 1898. Rates about 95% of N F C 4%. Membership 7,284 Dec. 31, 1915; insurance $6,028,000; assets $192,090.18; liabilities $5,005.51. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 39 FINANCIAL STATEMENT FOR BIENNIUM ENDED NOVEMBER 30, 1916 Salary of Insurance Commissioner Dec. 1, 1914, balance of appropriation Dec. 21, 1914, L. G. Brian $ 937.51 $ 208.34 206.33 208.33 208.34 Jan. 30, 1915, L. G. Brian Feb. 27, 1915, L. G. Brian Mar. 31, 1915, L. G. Brian April 1, 1915, Appropriation ... May 7, 1915, L. G. Brian May 28, 1915, L. G. Brian June 30, 1915, L. G. Brian July 24, 1915, L. G. Brian July 31, 1915, W. B. Eastham Aug. 31, 1915, W. B. Eastham Sept. 30, 1915, W. B. Eastham Oct. 30, 1915, W. B. Eastham Nov. 30, 1915, W. B. Eastham Dec. 22, 1915, W. B. Eastham Jan. 27, 1916, W. B. Eastham Feb. 29, 1916, W. B. Eastham Mar. 30, 1916, W. B. Eastham April 29, 1916, W. B. Eastham May 31, 1916, W. B. Eastham June 30, 1916, W. B. Eastham July 29, 1916, W. B. Eastham Aug. 29, 1916, W. B. Eastham Sept. 30, 1916, W. B. Eastham Oct. 30, 1916, W. B. Eastham Nov. 20, 1916, W. B. Eastham 5,000.00 208.33 208.33 208.34 147.85 60.48 208.34 208.33 208.33 208.33 208.34 208.33 208.33 208.34 208.33 208.33 208.34 208.33 208.33 208.34 208.33 208.33 Total expended $ 5,000.00 Total appropriated * 5,937.51 Less lapsed of 1913 appropriation 104.17 Net available * 5,833.34 Present appropriation available 833.34 $ Salary of Actuary April 1, 1915, Appropriation * 5,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT April 30, 1915, H. S. Wiggins $ 341.25 June 2, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 356.25 July 31, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 326.25 Oct. 8, 1915, H. S. Wiggins ..._ 260.00 Oct. 8, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 230.00 Oct. 8, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 120.00 Nov. 10, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 190.00 Dec. 10, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 200.00 Jan. 27, 1916, H. S. Wiggins 145.00 Feb. 29, 1916, H. S. Wiggins 150.00 Mar. 29, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 109.67 April 5, 1916, H. S. Wiggins 115.00 April 29, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 156.66 May 31, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 96.77 July 6, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 86.67 July 29, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance i 151.61 Aug. 29, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 180.65 Sept. 7, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 12.90 Sept. 30, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 160.00 Oct. 30, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 148.39 Nov. 17, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 19.35 Nov. 29, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance 200.00 Total expended $ 3,756.42 Total appropriated $ 5,000.00 Present appropriation available $ 1,243.58 Salary of Bookkeeper Dec. 1, 1914, Balance of appropriation $ 400.00 Dec. 21, 1914, Lillian E. Peters $ 100.00 Jan. 30, 1914, Lillian E. Peters 100.00 Feb. 27, 1914, Lillian E. Peters 100.00 Mar. 31, 1914, Lillian E. Peters 100.00 April 1, 1915, Appropriation 2400 00 April 30, 1915, Lillian E. Peters 100.00 May 28, 1915, Lillian E. Peters 100.00 June 30, 1915, Lillian E. Peters 100.00 July 24, 1915, Lillian E. Peters 70.97 July 31, 1915, H. N. Sprague 29.03 Aug. 31, 1915, H. N. Sprague 100.00 Sept. 30, 1915, H. N. Sprague 100.00 Oct. 30, 1915, H. N. Sprague 100.00 Nov. 30, 1916, H. N. Sprague 100.00 Dec. 22, 1915, H. N. Sprague 100.00 Jan. 27, 1916, Mrs. M. G. McCune...- 100.00 Feb. 28, 1916, Mrs. M. G. McCune 100.00 Mar. 25, 1916, Mrs. M. G. McCune 80.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 41 April 29, 1916, B. R. Bays May 30, 1916, B. R. Bays June 30, 1916, B. R. Bays July 29, 1916, B. R. Bays Aug. 29, 1916, B. R. Bays Sept.' 30, 1916, B. R. Bays 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 Oct. 26, 1916, Mary A. Fairchild Nov. 29, 1916, C. L. Morrison Total expended $ 2,380.65 Total appropriated * 2,800.00 Present appropriation available 419.35 t Salary of Stenographer Dec. 1, 1914, Balance of appropriation Dec. 21, 1914, Maynetta Marks _.. $ 280.00 70.00 * 16.00 Jan. 30, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune .... Feb. 3, 1915, Maynetta Marks Feb. 27, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune... Mar. 31, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune April 1, 1915, Appropriation April 30, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune... May 28, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune... June 30, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune... July 31, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune .... Aug. 31, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune ... Sept. 30, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune.. Oct. 30, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune ... Nov. 30, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune ... Dec. 22, 1915, Mrs. M. G. McCune... Jan. 31, 1916, M. Lina Shirley Feb. 28, 1916, M. Lina Shirley Mar. 29, 1916, M. Lina Shirley April 29, 1916, M. Lina Shirley May 31, 1916, M. Lina Shirley June 30, 1916, M. Lina Shirley July 29, 1916, M. Lina Shirley Sept. 8, 1916, M. Lina Shirley Sept. 30, 1916, M. Lina Shirley Oct. 30, 1916, M. Lina Shirley Nov. 29, 1916, M. Lina Shirley 54.00 70.00 70.00 1,680.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 70.00 Total expended % 1,680.00 Total appropriated $ 1,960.00 Present appropriation available 280.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT EXTRA HELP April 1, 1915 Appropriation $ 4,000.00 April 30, 1915 H. N. Sprague $ 100.00 April 30, 1915 Mrs. M. Fairchild 65.00 April 30, 1915 Mrs. O. V. White 57.50 April 30, 1915 P. M. Scott 58.75 April 30, 1915 May F. Hyland 23.75 April 30, 1915 Lenore Daly 17.50 May 28, 1915 H. N. Sprague 100.00 May 28, 1915 Mrs. M. Fairchild 60.00 May 28, 1915 Mrs. O. V. White 62.50 May 28, 1915 P. M. Scott 6.25 May 28, 1915 May F. Hyland 62.50 May 28, 1915 Lenore Daly 62.50 June 30, 1915 Mrs. H. N. Sprague 100.00 June 30, 1915 Mrs. M. Fairchild 65.00 June 30, 1915 May F. Hyland 57.50 June 30, 1915 Lenore Daly 57.50 July 24, 1915 Lenore Daly - 3.75 July 31, 1915 H. N. Sprague 70.97 July 31, 1915 Mrs. M. Fairchild 65.00 Aug. 31, 1915 Mary A. Fairchild 65.00 Sept. 30, 1915 Mary A. Fairchild 65.00 Oct. 30, 1915 Mary A. Fairchild 65.00 Nov. 30, 1915 Mary A. Fairchild 65.00 Dec. 22, 1915 Mary A. Fairchild 65.00 Jan. 10, 1916 Minnie E. Seybolt 6.87 Jan. 31, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 65.00 Feb. 29, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 65.00 Feb. 29, 1916 Minnie E. Seybolt 4.00 Mar. 29, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 70.00 April 21, 1916 C. C. Towne 7.50 April 29, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 70.00 April 29, 1916 A. A. Engalls 51.25 April 29, 1916 C. L. Morrison 45.00 April 29, 1916 E. J. Moyer 23.75 April 29, 1916 J. Jasin _... 12.50 May 8, 1916 R. W. Israel 2.50 May 5, 1916 Geo. H. Moyer 27.50 May 13, 1916 E. J. Moyer , 27.50 May 13, J. Jasin 30.00 May 16, 1916 Geo : H. Moyer 7.50 May 31, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 70.00 May 31, 1916 A. A. Engalls 65.00 May 81, 1916 C. L. Morrison 65.00 May 31, 1916 E. B. Zimmerman 67.50 June 30, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 70.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 43 June 30, 1916 A. A. Engalls 65.00 June 30, 1916 C. L. Morrison 65.00 June 30, 1916 E. B. Zimmerman 65.00 July 20, 1916 Hazel A. Foss 15.00 July 29, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 70.00 July 29, 1916 E. B. Zimmerman 57.50 July 29, 1916 C. L. Morrison 57.50 Aug. 12, 1916 E. B. Zimmerman 35.00 Aug. 29, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 70.00 Aug. 29, 1916 Dora Geistlinger 27.50 Sept. 8, 1916 Dora Geistlinger 6.25 Sept. 30, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 70.00 Oct. 25, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 15.00 Nov. 29, 1916 Mary A. Fairchild 56.00 Total expended $ 2,929.09 Total appropriation $ 4,000.00 Present appropriation available 1,070.91 OFFICE EXPENSE, POSTAGE, BOOKS, TELEGRAPH, ETC. Dec. 1, 1914 Balance of appropriation $ 3,734.64 Dec. 7, 1914 Woodruff Bank Note Co., Printing Workman's Compensation Law$ 42.00 Dec. 7, 1914 Harry Porter, supplies 7.75 Dec. 7, Postal Telegraph &amp; Cable Co 2.58 Dec. 8, 1914 Jacob North Co., Printing Far- mers Mutual Blanks 18.00 Dec. 14, 1914 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co 8.35 Dec. 15, 1914 State Journal Co., Printing Letter Heads (2000) 10.50 Dec. 15, 1914 Lincoln City Directory Co 6.00 Dec. 14, 1914 L. G. Brian, Revenue Stamps 10.00 Dec. 21, 1914 State Journal Co.. Supplies 5.00 Dec. 17, 1914 Wm. B. Howard, traveling expen. 106.45 Dec. 21, 1914 Mrs. M. Fairchild, extra help 37.50 Dec. 21, 1914 H. S. Wiggins, Nov. salary 337.50 Dec. 21, 1914 F. A. Stephenson, electric lamp.... 4.25 Dec. 22, 1914 Geo. 0. Hearn, postage 200.00 Dec. 31, 1914 Mrs. M. Fairchild, extra help 25.00 Dec. 31, 1914 M. E. Logan, Printing tabs 6.75 Jan. 7, 1915 Lincoln Paper Co., paper boards.. 4.85 Jan. 7, 1915 American Express Co 9.08 Jan. 8, 1915 Harry Porter...- 3.55 Jan. 8, 1915 Postal Telegraph Co 1.18 Jan. 8, 1915 Jacob North Co., 1000 blanks for Neb. Annual statement blanks.. 16.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Jan. 12, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co., 8.25 Jan. 12, 1915 Leon Huckins, printing affidavits 14.00 Jan. 12, 1915 State Journal Co., Letter Heads .... 14.03 Jan. 30, 1915 H. N. Sprague 65.39 Jan. 30, 1915 Mrs. M. Fairehild, extra help 65.00 Feb. 8, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co 7.70 Feb. 3, 1915 State Journal Co., gummed labels 8.75 Feb. 8, 1915 Harry Porter _ 19.20 Feb. 8, 1915 Postal Telegraph &amp; Cable Co 1.02 Feb. S, 1915 H. S. Wiggins, Dec. and Jan 472.50 Feb. 12, 1915 R. H Gillespie, printing 1500 biennium reports 69.20 Feb. 13, 1915 Illinois Printing Co., annual state- ment blanks 276.00 Feb. 15, 1915 Brandon printing claim schedule val. and printers blanks 48.27 Feb. 13, 1915 State Journal Co., 5000 litho- graphed letter heads 34.25 Feb. 13» 1915 Munson Supply Co., keys for typewriter 3.50 Feb. 27, 1915 Mrs. M. Fairehild 60.00 Feb. 27, 1915 H. N. Sprague 100.00 Mar. 6, 1915 Lincoln Telephone ft Teleg. Co.... 6.45 Mar. 8, 1915 Harry Porter 10.50 Mar. 16, 1915 Geo. O. Hearn, postage 200.00 Mar. 31, 1915 H. N. Sprague, extra help 100.00 Mar. 31, 1915 Mrs. M. Fairehild, extra help 67.50. Mar. 31, 1915 Underwood Typewriter Co., re- pairs .60 Mar. 31, 1915 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co 12.30 Mar. 31, 1915 Sanitary Towel Supply Co 4.50 Mar. 31, 1915 Western Union Telegraph Co .59 Mar. 31, 1915 H. S. Wiggins, Feb. salary 246.25 Mar. 31, 1915 Sterling Electrical Co., repair alarm .' 22.10 Mar. 31, 1915 H. S. Wiggins, Mar. salary 322.50 Mar. 31, 1915 Minnie E. Seybolt, stenographer.. 19.37 Mar. 31, 1915 Harry Porter 8.90 Mar. 31, 1915 Jacob North Co., printing pre- liminary reports 118.30 Mar. 31, 1915 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., standing desk and table 29.25 Mar. 31, 1915 F. H. McMaster, Pro Rata Na- tional Insurance Commissioners Convention 50.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 45 Mar. 31, 1915 Frank Hasbrouck, pro rata valua- tion of securities _ 100.00 April 8, 1915 Lincoln Telephone A Tele. Co. 7.40 May 7, 1915 Kosemeyer Co., lights 62.00 May 15, 1915 State Journal Co., license blanks and enc 155.55 April 1, 1915 Appropriation $ 8,000.00 May 7, 1915 American Express 1.62 May 7, 1915 Harry Porter 4.30 May 18, 1915 Lincoln Paper Co 2.16 May 1, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Teleg. Co 7.00 May 18, 1915 State Journal Co., printing names of license cards 22.00 May 18 1915Klopp, Bartlett Co., recording paper 26.50 May 2(1 1915 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co. 7.45 May 20 1915 Burroughs Adding Machine Co. Western Union Telegraph Co. . 1.00 May 20, 1915 1.06 June 2 1915 L. G. Brian, Expense N. F. C. Co., trial Omaha 8.25 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co. June 9 1915 10.00 June 9, 1915 Harry Porter 9.65 June 9 1915 American Express Co. 3.45 June 9. 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Postal Telephone &amp; Cable Co 8.05 June 9. 1915 .72 June it; 1915 Geo. O. Hearn, postage 200.00 July 1, 1915 Western Union 1.48 July 7, 1915 Spectator Co., Digest 3.50 July 1-1 1915 Alfred M. Best Co., Life Ins. report _. 10.00 July s 1915 Office Equipment &amp; Supply 12.40 July 8, 1915 Harry Porter 13.70 July 19, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph 7.84 July 19, 1915 Western Union .45 July 29 1915 T. J. Thorpe Machine Co., open- ing desk lock .65 29. 1915 L. G. Brian, Expense State July Agents convention 6.25 Aug. 5, 1915 Geo. O. Hearn, postage 50.00 Aug. 9, 1915 Harry Porter, supplies 7.65 Aug. II 1915 W. H. England, premium bond of Insurance Com ■ 450.00 Aug. 14, 1915 Harry Porter, office supplies 11.55 Aug. 14 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph 6.00 Aug. 14, 1915 Geo. Brothers 6 Griffith 2.25 Aug. 14. 1915 Western Union Telegraph Co. .88 Aug. 25, 1915 Geo. O. Hearn, postage ~. 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Sept. 14, 1915 Mrs. M. G. McCune, 1 standard diary _ 1.50 Sept. 14, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph.... 6.00 Sept. 14, 1915 Western Union _ 1.16 Sept. 22, 1915 Geo. Bros. &amp; Griffith, die for dates .60 Sept. 22, 1915 Jacob North Co., 6000 lithograph 5000 letter heads 85.40 Sept. 22, 1915 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co. 30 books (deposit slips) 13.00 Sept. 24, 1915 R. H. Gillespie, 2500 annual re- ports 1,117.56 Sept 24, 1915 R. H. Gillespie, 2500 reprint of page 25 7.50 Sept. 24, 1915 R. H. Gillespie, supplements 2500 66.72 Sept. 24, 1915 R. H. Gillespie, slips 2500 5.50 Oct. 1, 1915 Woodruff Bank Note Co., 2500 envelopes 26.25 Oct. 8, 1915 Harry Porter, 1 box manuscript covers, 1 box eyelets 1.25 Oct. 8, 1915 Spectator Co., 1 set year books 10.00 Oct. 14, 1915 Western Union Telegraph 1.44 Oct. 14, 1915 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co 31.30 Oct. 14, 1915 Alfred M. Best Co., Subscription to Best's Insurance News 2.00 Oct. 22, 1915 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co 5.45 Oct. 22, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph 6.00 Oct. 22, 1915 Spectator Co., Fire Ins. laws, fees and taxes.— 5.00 Oct. 30, 1915 Geo. O. Hearn, postage 255.00 Nov. 27, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph.... 9.00 Nov. 27, 1915 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co. 35.50 Dec. 1, 1915 Sanitary Towel Supply 4.50 Dec. 13, 1915 American Express Co..._ .38 Dec. 13, 1915 Western Union .74 Dec. 13, 1915 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co 7.00 Jan. 4, 1916 Brandon Printing Co., annual statement blanks 209.25 Jan. 1, 1916 W. B. Eastham Expense to Omaha 4.20 Jan. 4, 1916 Wells Fargo &amp; Co., Express on blanks 21.66 Jan. 10, 1916 W. B. Eastham, expense to Co- lumbus .._ _ 6.02 Jan. 17, 1916 Western Union Telegraph 2.62 Jan. 17, 1916 Lincoln Paper Co., cardboard for annual reports 1.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 47 Jan. 17, 1916 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph. ... 8.75 Jan. 17, 1916 Adams Express Co .38 Jan. 17, 1916 H. S. Wiggins, expense to Omaha (Omaha Life) 4.70 Feb. 5, 1916 Harry Porter, supplies 1.85 Feb. 5, 1916 State Journal Co., senate pads.... 2.25 Feb. 5, 1916 American Express Co., express on statement blanks 49.61 Feb. 7, 1916 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph... 9.85 Feb. 7, 1916 State Journal Co., 1500 letter heads 60.75 Feb. 7, 1916 Postal Telegraph Co .84 Feb. 29, 1916 State Journal, Excelsior dairy 1.45 Feb. 29, 1916 Western Union Telegraph 1.89 Feb. 29, 1916 Brandon Printing Co., Frat. Valuation blanks 2.75 Mar. 1, 1916 State Journal Co., 12,000 env 58.50 Mar. 1, 1916 Milburn &amp; Scott, 500 special envelopes „ 7.50 Mar. 3, 1916 Woodruff Bank Note Co.. enve- lopes 29.40 Mar. 3, 1916 Adams Express Co _ .30 Mar. 14, 1916 Duncan's Printshop, 10000 license cards, 3000 applications 130.00 Mar. 14, 1916, Western Union Telegraph Co 2.26 Mar. 14, 1916, Lincoln Telephone &amp; Tele. Co 8.30 Mar. 25, 1916, Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co .... 26.45 Mar. 31, 1916, Sanitary Towel Supply 3.50 April 6. 1916, Woodruff Bank Note Co., 1000 record sheets and binders 29.50 April 11, 1916, George Bros, numbering machine 5.00 April 8, 1916, Adams Express Co., report blks. .23 April 8, 1916, Klopp Bartlett Co., ledger sheets 45.00 April 15, 1916, Lincoln Telephone &amp; Tele. Co 7.00 April 15, 1916, Western Union Telegraph 1.68 April 15, 1916, Duncan's Printing Shop, 4,000 agents' applications 12.60 April 15, 1916, Geo. O. Hearn, postage 155 00 April 25, 1916, Underwood Typewriter Co., oil... .20 April 29, 1916, Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co.... 20.70 May 1, 1916, American Printing Co., prelim- inary reports _ 180.00 May 5, 1916, Jacob North Co., authority blanks 21.25 May 8, 1916, Adams Express Co .23 May 8, 1916, Lincoln Tel. &amp; Telegraph Co 7.00 May 25, 1916, Postal Telegraph &amp; Cable Co.... .86 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT May 19, 1916, Omaha Printing Co., numerical record books 92.70 May 25, 1916, George Bros 1.60 May 26, 1916, McKinnon Office Supply, Dandy sharpener 4.00 June 23, 1916, Adams Express Co .23 June 9, 1916, Jacob North Co., agents' regis- tration blanks 28.50 June 9, 1916, Harry Porter, supplies .50 June 9, 1916, Harry Porter, supplies 9.35 June 9, Lincoln Tel. &amp; Telegraph Co 7.70 June 23, 1916, Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co., supplies .90 June 23, 1916, Woodruff Bank Note Co., printing code _ 79.80 June 23, 1916, Burroughs Adding Machine Co., repairs 1.00 June 23, Western Union .96 July 10, 1916, Adams Express Co .28 July 10, 1916, Western Union Telegraph .66 July 10, 1916, Jacob North Co., printing license card 4.00 July 20, 1916, Alfred M. Best Co., insurance re- ports 12.00 July 24, 1916, Lincoln Telephone &amp; Tele. Co 7.00 July 29, 1916, George Bros &amp; Griffith, seal 6.00 July 29, 1916, Geo. O. Hearn, postage stamps .... 68.00 Aug. 10, 1916, Lincoln Telephone £ Telegraph... 7.95 Aug. 25, 1916, J. C. Brady, watch case receiver for telephone 3.00 Aug. 31, 1916, Office Equipment ft Supply Co., pens _ 1.50 Sept. 8, 1916; Harry Porter, supplies 5.00 Sept. 8, 1916, Milburn ft Scott, printing power of attorney blanks 11.25 Sept. 8, 1916, Lincoln Telephone ft Telegraph... 8.25 Oct. 9, 1916, Harry Porter, supplies 1.25 Oct. 9, 1916, Sanitary Towel Supply 4.50 Oct. 9, 1916, W. B. Eastham, traveling ex- pense , 21.23 Oct. 9, 1916, Adams Express Co., reports to Omaha .35 Oct 11, 1916, Geo. O. Hearn, postage stamps... 133.00 Oct. 11, 1916, Lincoln Telephone ft Tele. Co.... 9.00 Oct. 25, 1916, Office Equipment ft Supply Co., supplies 11.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 49 Oct. 25, 1916, Hon. Jesse S. Phillips, N. Y. val- uation of securities pro rata ex- pense for Nebraska 100.00 Oct. 25, 1916, F. H. McMaster, pro rate ex- pense National Conv. Ins. Comm 50.00 Oct. 30, 1916, Postal Telegraph &amp; Cable Co .38 Nov. 3, 1916, Harry Porter, supplies 2.40 Nov. 10, 1916, Adams Express Co .60 Nov. 10, 1916.W. B. Eastham, expense to Rich- mond _... 105.79 Nov. 17, 1916, Western Union .45 Nov. 20, 1916, Jacob North Co., printing 1,240.65 Nov. 22, 1916, Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph. ... 10.40 Total expended $ 9,653.38 Total appropriated % 11,734.64 Less lapsed, 1913 appropriation 60.38 Net available $ 11,674.26 Present appropriation available $ 2,110.88 Cash Fund Disbursements Dec. 1, 1914, Balance on hand _... $ 920.06 Dec. 7, 1914, C. S. Clayton % 51.95 Dec. 18, 1914, C. S. Clayton 166.68 Dec. 18, 1914, H. S. Wiggins, work in Sept., Oct., Nov., 12 1-2 days 125.00 Dec. 19, 1914, J. W. Jones, Jr 166.68 Dec. 19, 1914, J. W. Jones, Jr _... 54.50 Dec. 21, 1914, L. G. Brian 6.00 Dec. 31, 1914, C. S. Clayton 22.40 Jan. 18, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr. 36.95 Jan. 18, 1915, C. S. Clayton 37.35 Feb. 1, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 166.66 Feb. 1, 1915, C. S. Clayton 166.66 Feb. 8, 1915, C. S. Clayton 41.20 Feb. 9, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 39.00 Feb. 12, 1915, L. G. Brian, for Pacific Coast Casualty _ 16.00 Feb. 17, 1915, Geo. W. Bonnell, B. ft M. mileage books for J. W. Jones 40.00 Feb. 26, 1915, C. S. Clayton _ _... 166.66 Feb. 26, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 166.66 Mar. 1, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 56.60 Mar. 1, 1915, C. S. Clayton _ 54.30 Mar. 19, 1915, H. S. Wiggins, Columbia Life 54.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Mar. 29, 1915, H. S. Wiggins, Commonwealth Life 69.85 Mar. 29, 1915, H. S. Wiggins, Columbia Life 25.20 Mar. 29, 1915, H. S. Wiggins, Bankers' Reserve Life 38.75 Mar. 29, 1915, L. G. Brian, expense attending meeting 10.50 Mar. 29, 1915, Geo. W. Bonnell, mileage for Clayton 40.00 Mar. 29, 1915, C. S. Clayton 166.68 Mar. 29, 1915, C. S. Clayton _... 7.90 Mar. 29, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 166.68 Mar. 29, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 28.40 April 30, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr. 166.66 April 30, 1915, Chas. Q. DeFrance 114.15 April 30, 1915, C. S. Clayton 166.66 April 30, 1915, C. S. Clayton 27.75 April 30, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 39.65 May 4, 1915, C. N. W. Ry., Jones mileage 40.00 May 5, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 84.18 June 1, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr., May salary 166.66 June 1, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr 83.75 June 1, 1915, C. S. Clayton, May salary 166.66 June 1, 1915, C. S. Clayton 87.50 June 19, H. S. Wiggins, Bankers' Life 90.00 June 19, H. S. Wiggins, Elkhorn Life 56.26 June 30, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr., June salary 166.68 June 30, 1915, C. S. Clayton, June salary 166.68 July 1, 1915, C. S. Clayton 46.70 July 22, 1915, L. G. Brian „ - 3.50 July 22, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr., June expense. ... 50.20 July 22, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr., July salary 118.28 July 22, 1915, J. W. Jones, Jr., July expense 10.33 July 31, 1915, C. S. Clayton, July salary 166.66 Aug. 31, 1915, C. S. Clayton, August salary 166.66 Sept. 1, 1915, Geo. W. Bonnell, mileage Clayton 40.00 Sept. 13, 1915, C. S. Clayton, expense 64.05 Sept. 29, 1915, C. S. Clayton, Sept. salary 166.66 Oct. 7, 1915, C. S. Clayton, Sept. expense 59.75 Oct. 30, 1915, C. S. Clayton, Oct. salary 166.66 Nov. 1, 1915, C. S. Clayton, Oct. expense .41.90 Nov. 13, 1915, H. S. Wiggins 201.40 Nov. 27, 1915, C. S. Clayton, Nov. salary 166.66 Dec. 24, 1915, C. S. Clayton, Dec. salary 166.67 Jan. 4, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, Commonwealth Life - 28.90 Jan. 10, 1915, H. S. Wiggins, Nebraska Hail... 64.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 51 Jan. 10, 1915, C. S. Clayton, Dec. expense 57.75 Jan. 27, 1916, C. S. Clayton, Jan. salary 166.66 Jan. 27, 1916, H. N. Sprague, Jan. expense 29.47 Jan. 27, 1916, H. N. Sprague, Jan. salary 125.00 Feb. 9, 1916, C. S. Clayton, Jan. expense 33.60 Feb. 9, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expens to St. Louis and return 35.46 Feb. 28, 1916, J. W. Jones, Jr., Feb. salary 280.00 Feb. 28, 1916, J. W. Jones, Jr., Feb. expense 31.30 Feb. 28, 1916, C. S. Clayton, Feb. salary 166.66 Feb. 28, 1916, J. Murphy, Feb. salary 166.66 Feb. 28, 1916, H. N. Sprague, Feb. salary as assistant examiner 125.00 Feb. 28, 1916, W. B. Eastman, exp. to Omaha...., 3.85 Feb. 28, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, expense per diem Columbia Life 50.57 Feb. 28, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, expenses and per diem Prairie Life,. _... 32.95 Feb. 28, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, expense Com- monwealth Life 45.35 Mar. 16, 1916, H. N. Sprague, asst. examiner, expense for Feb 30.15 Mar. 16, 1916, C. S. Clayton, examiner, expense for Feb 48.68 Mar. 16, 1916, J. W. Jones, Jr., salary 135.00 Mar. 29, 1916, H. N. Sprague, asst' exam, sal- ary 125.00 Mar. 29, 1916, H. N. Sprague, expense 6.45 Mar. 29, 1916, C. S. Clayton, salary 166.67 Mar. 29, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expense 5.35 April 3, 1916, J. Murphy, salary 166.67 April 3, 1916, J. Murphy, March expense 67.53 April 3, 1916, J. W. Jones, March expense 44.07 April 8, 1916, C. S. Clayton, March expense 42.45 April 27, 1916, H. N. Sprague, salary. 125.00 April 27, 1916, C. S. Clayton, salary 166.67 April 29, 1916, J. Murphy, salary 166.67 April 29, 1916, J. Murphy, expense April 99.13 May 3, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, valuation Bankers' Life _ 47.50 May 3, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, valuation Bankers Reserve Life _ 13.60 May 31, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, examination Elkhom 52.57 May 3, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, examination Auto Mutual _ 20.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT May 3, 1916, H. S. Wiggins, valuation Amer- ican Accident 15.00 May 3, 1916, John W. Jones, Jr., examina- tion 6 days 48.00 May 3, 1916, John W. Jones, expense 18.10 May 25, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expense to Om- aha 11.05 May 27, 1916, J. Murphy, salary 166.67 May 27, 1916, H. N. Sprague, salary 125.00 May 27, 1916, C. S. Clayton, salary 166.67 June 27, 1916, H. N. Sprague, salary 125.00 June 27, 1916, J. Murphy, salary 166.67 June 27, 1916, C. S. Clayton, salary 166.67 July 3, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance, balance salary at $200 in April 43.34 July 3, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance, balance salary at $200 in May ..._ 103.23 July 3, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance, balance salary at $200 in June _ 113.33 July 3, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance, expenses W. O. W. May and June 59.85 July 3, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance, expense W. O. W 72.86 July 10, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expenses to Om- aha 8.35 July 20, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expenses to Om- aha 7.30 July 27, 1916, J. Murphy, salary 166.66 July 28, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance, salary W.O.W.... 48.39 July 28, 1916, C. Q. DeFrance, expenses W.O.W 34.30 July 28, 1916, H. N. Sprague, salary 166.67 July 28, 1916, C. S. Clayton, salary 166.67 July 28, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expense to Om- aha W. O. W 4.40 July 29, 1916, J. Murphy, expense Lion Bond- ing Co 38.10 Aug. 10, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expense to Om- aha 4.55 Aug. 28, 1916, C. S. Clayton, salary 166.66 Aug. 28, 1916, H. N. Sprague, salary 166.66 Sept. 2, 1916, J. Muphy, salary 166.66 Sept 5, 1916, Chas. Q. DeFrance, expense Royal Highlanders 13.02 Sept. 5, 1916, H. N. Sprague, expense to Om- aha _ 70.85 Sept. 6, 1916, J. Murphy, expense to Omaha... 29.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 53 Sept. 9, 1916, W. B. Eastham, expense to Om- aha 2.25 Sept 26, 1916, Chas. Q. DeFrance, per diem Royal Highlanders 40.00 Sept. 26, 1916, Chas. Q. DeFrance, expenses W. 0. W. 3.69 Sept. 26, 1916, Chas. Q. DeFrance, Royal High- landers 14.57 Sept. 26, 1916, H. N. Sprague.salary 166.68 Sept. 26, 1916, J. Murphy, salary 166.68 B. R. Bays, expenses for Sept. Oct. 3, 1916, 36.87 Oct. 3, 1916, J. Murphy, expense for Sept 19.51 Oct. 3, 1916, H. N. Sprague, expense for Sept 68.20 Oct. 23, 1916, B. R. Bays, salary as Asst exam., Sept 12.50 Oct. 31 1916 Chas. Q. DeFrance, per diem N.F. C. Omaha _ 12.90 Oct. 31 1916, Chas. Q. DeFrance, expense N. F. C. Omaha 11.50 Oct. 31, 1916, H. N. Sprague, salary 166.66 Oct. II 1916 B. R. Bays, salary as Asst. Exam 62.50 Oct. 31 1916, B. R. Bays, salary as examiner 83.33 Oct. SI 1916, J. Murphy, salary as examiner 166.66 Nov. 1, 1916, B. R. Bays, expense 66.16 Nov. 1, 1916, J. Murphy, expense 79.95 Nov. 7, 1916, H. N. Sprague, expense 45.89 Nov. 29, 1916, H. N. Sprague, salary 166.66 Nov. 29, 1916, B. R. Bays, salary 166.66 Nov. 29, 1916, J. Murphy 166.66 Nov. 29, 1916, J. Murphy, Nov. expense _... 37.71 Nov. 29, 1916, H. N. Sprague, Nov. expense 62.80 Total expended ...._ $ 12,911.99 Receipts for biennium _ _ $ 12,003.31 Total available $ 12,923.37 Present appropriation available ..._ _ $ 11.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT THE INSURANCE CODE No insurance legislation whatever was enacted by the Legisla - ture of 1915, and the whole body of insurance statutes consists of four acts passed at the 1913 session. The principal of these, Senate File 364, was approved by Governor Morehead April 18, 1913. and became effective July 18, 1913. It is usually known as the "New Insurance Code'". (Laws of Nebraska, 1913, pp 393-482). The second in importance is by its terms known as the Ne - braska Workmen's Compensation Law of 1913, and only incident - ally touches the subject of insurance. It was originally Senate File 1, session of 1913 and was approved by the Governor April 21, 1913. Afterward approved by referendum vote of the people Nov. 3. 1914 and became effective December 1. 1914. (Laws of Nebraska, 1913, pp 579-603). The third is an original and independent act (Senate File 273) providing for the incorporation and regulation of employers' mutual liability insurance associations, and was approved April 19, 1913. ( Laws of Nebraska, 1913, pp 513-521). The fourth is an amendatory act (House Roll 276) defining a fraternal beneficiary association and providing for changes in the laws of such societies. It was passed with the emergency clause and was approved by Governor Morehead and became effective April 21, 1913. (Laws of Nebraska, 1913, pp 740-741). Prior to 1913 the insurance laws of Nebraska were adminis - tered by the Auditor of Public Accounts, through an insurance department, and with an insurance deputy in active charge. By the provisions of Senate File 364 (The Insurance Code) the governor, auditor and the attorney general were constituted "a state insurance board" and Section 4 provided that "immediately upon taking effect of this chapter the auditor of public accounts shall surrender to the state insurance board all records," etc. Having been passed without the emergency clause, Senate File 364, did not take effect until July 18, 1913. After the act took </seg>
            <seg id="p055">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 55 eflfect the auditor, VV. B. Howard, "refused to assemble with the other members of the insurance board or take any part in its de - liberations, -and refused to deliver to Lawson G. Brian, the in - surance commissioner appointed by the board, the records, books *•*• held by him by virtue of former statutes." Soon thereafter the Supreme Court of Nebraska granted a peremptory writ of mandamus to compel him and his subordinates to deliver such books and securities to the board ; and in August 1913, an action in quo warranto was begun on relation of Auditor Howard. The mandamus suit is No. 18,175, entitled State ex rel Grant 0. Mar - tin, Attorney General, et al., relators, v. William B. Howard, et al, respondents. The quo warranto proceeding is No. 18,218, en - titled State ex rel William B. Howard, Auditor of Public Ac - counts, relatcr v. Lawson G. Brian, et al., respondents. Auditor Howard filed a motion to vacate the peremptory writ of mandamus, and as the same points were argued in both cases, they were combined in cne opinion written by Associate Justice Letton and decided at the January Term, 1914. The print - ed report may be found in 96 Nebraska Reports, pp 278-298. Mo - tion to recall writ of mandamus was overruled, and quo warranto proceedings dimissed — a substantial victory for those supporting the new code. Section 18 (G. S. 3154) provides that "the board shall trans - mit to the governor ten days prior to the opening of each session of the legislature a report of its official transactions and contain - ing *••* any amendments to this chapter, which in the judgment of the board may be desirable." To quote frcm the language of Justice Letton, in State ex rel Martin v. Howard supra — "It is possible that in an act of this scope and magnitude there may be inconsistent and inharmonious provisions embraced, and that it will take the process of amendment to render the legislation the most valu - able and effective for the purpose for which the code was compiled." (96 Nebr. 297). In the something more than three years this code has been in effect, a number" of "inconsistent and inharmonious provisions" have been noted, but none of such serious character as to inter - fere with the orderly administration of the Department. These are now called to the governor's attention for such recommenda - tion as he shall deem wise to place before the Legislature ; but </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT they are not urged for amendment or repeal measures if it shall be found desirable to allow the present insurance laws to remain as they are. Before taking up seriatim the "inconsistent and inharmon - ious" provisions of the code, it will be well to note here the ef - fect of State ex rel Martin v. Howard thereupon : Section 11 (G. S. 3147) — proceelings in the case of any delin - quent domestic insurance company — held valid. (96 Nebr. 295). Section 27 (G. S. 3163 — permitting existing domestic com - panies to continue under certain conditions— held valid. (96 Xebr. 296). Section 92. (G. S. 3228; — reinsurance or consolidation of companies— held valid. (96 Nebr. 296). Section 101. (G. S. 3237) — contents of fire insurance policies; in lines four and five the words, "or may be hereafter", held to be "surplusage, unconstitutional and void." (96 Nebr. 291). This section is to be read as though the four words first above quoted were erased and stricken out. Section 102. (G. S. 3238) — eighth subdivision — providing for policy loans on life insurance policies and limiting the interest to "not exceeding six per cent per annum" — held valid. (96 Nebr. 295). Sections 148. 149, and 150. (G. S. 3284-6)— empowering the state insurance board to fix a maximum schedule of rates for surety and fidelity companies — held valid. (96 Nebr. 279). Section 158. (G. S. 3294) — defining a fraternal beneficiary as - sociation and providing for changes in its constitution and by - laws; in lines 11 and 12 the words "less than nine-tenths of the vote, nor" are held "not enacted in accordance with the require - ments of the constitution and •• of no effect. " Therefore, in this section the 11th and 12th lines should be read: "Provided, the elected members shall have not less than the votes required to amend its constitution and laws." (96 Nebr. 284). Except for the two provisions named in sections 101 and 158, the entire act of 183 sections is held valid. It will be remembered that in the case of State ex rel Martin v. Howard, supra, the court held void certain words in Section 158 (G. S. 3294) which was a part of Senate File 364. commonly called the "new insurance code". It now appears that the Legis- </seg>
            <seg id="p057">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 57 lature of 1913, by a separate act, in great measure duplicated the provisions of Section 158. This was House Roll 276 and appears in the Revised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913 as Section 159 (G. S. 3295). It would avoid a tedious controversy as to which sec - tion prevails, if the Legislature of 1917 should repeal one or the other, whichever may seem the less desirable. General Section 3294 was enacted as a part of the code ; was approved April 18, 1913 and become effective July 18, 1913. It replaced Section 91, Chapter 43, Cobbey's Statutes 1911, which section was repealed with all others of chapter 43 on April 18, 1913, effective July 18, 1913. General Section 3295 was enacted as a separate amendatory act, with the emergency clause, approved April 21, 1913 and took effect immediately. It replaced Section 91, Chapter 43, Cobbey's Statutes, 1911, which section was repealed. Query: which section, G. S. 3294 or G. S. 3295, is now effective t Apparently G. S. 3295 in tot.o and G. S. 3294 in part. En - actment of G. S. 3295 brought about the immediate and effectual repeal of old section 91, even though effected three days later than G. S. 3294 replaced the same section 91 and placed it in position to become effectively repealed July 18, 1913. When July 18, 1913 arrived there was no old section 91 for G. S. 3294 to replace ; but there was a new section G. S. 3295 which in point of time was the latest expression of the Legislature and had never been amended or repealed. There was nothing for G. S. 3294 to replace, but it did not therefore fail to become effective, except insofar as it conflicts with G. S. 3295. The following paragraphs give in condensed form the prin - cipal "inconsistencies and inharmonious" provisions of the in - surance code and kindred laws which have come to the notice of the insurance board during the present biennium: Impairment of Mutual Company Section 10 (G. S. 3146 R. S. 1913) requires directors and of - ficers of a mutual company, upon notice from the State Insurance Board, "to make good the amount" of any deficiency, within 90 days, but does not indicate in what way this may or shall be done. Possibly an assessment upon the members is the way in - tended. If so the provisions of Section 80 (G. S. 3216) are a bit vague. Beginning at line 8, Section 80, it should read: "The </seg>
            <seg id="p058">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 58 liability of a member of a mutual company shall be limited to an additonal sum equal to one annual premium as shown by his policy." Delinquent Company Subdivision 6, Sec. 11, (G. S. 3147) change word ""annual" to "" biennial". The insurance board issues annual summaries giving condensed reports of business done by all companies in the state, but its biennial report is the proper place for this informa - tion. Service on Foreign Company Amend Section 14 (G. S. 3150) commencing at line 10 as follows : "Service of process against any such company may be had by serving in person or by- registered mail triplicate copies upon the secretary of the board, and upon such service being made ••• he"*** triplicate *** this country ; mail one of such triplicate copies to the clerk of the court wherein such cause is pending, with his admission of service noted thereon ; and retain the third of snch copies in the Insurance Department files." Report of Board Amend line 2, first subdivision, Sec. 18, (G. S. 3154) to read "the year ending the thirtieth day of November next preceding." License Fees. — Disposition Section 19 (G. S. 3155) specifies the fees which shall be re - quired in advance, among others, "for each certificate of author - ity to **• any agent or agents ** two dollars." Prior to July 13, 1915, these two-dollar fees, commonly known as agents' license fees, were covered into the State Treasury and placed in the Gen - eral Fund. On July 13, 1915, State Treasurer Hall began the practice of placing such fees in the Temporary School Fund, justifying his acts by reference to Section 5, Art. VIII of the Constitution. (See special article on this subject.) </seg>
            <seg id="p059">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 59 Fees for Examination Line 16, Section 21 (G. S. 3157) should be amended to read: "the state treasury for use of the Institution Cash Fund, and credit of the Insurance Department;" and in line 21 the words "general fund" should' read "Institution Cash Fund." Authorized Investments. — Domestic Mutual and Assessment Companies. Sec. 39 (G. S. 3175) requires the minimum capital of every domestic stock company to he invested and kept invested in cer - tain securities. No requirement is made of mutual and assess - ment companies. Provision should be made that an amount equal to the legal reserve of every mutual company should be invested according to Sec. 39, and likewise the surplus assets of every assessment company. Deposit of Securities Section 42 (G. S. 3178) requires every domestic company to deposit "all of its investment securities", until they aggre - gate $100,000, with the Insurance Board. This is illogical as the bed of Procrustes. The correct principle is to require a deposit equal to the legal reserve liability of all legal reserve companies, and all of the invested surplus of fraternals and other companies not required to report a reserve liability. Salaries Sec. 46 (G. S. 3182) limits the salaries of domestic insurance companies to $5,000 per year, per officer, unless specially author - ized by vote of two-thirds. A further limit should be made that in no event should the salary of any officer exceed 3 per cent of the annual premium income, except where the same is less than $100,000 per year. Statute of Limitations of Actions Sec. 49 (G. S. 3185) forbids any provision in a policy limiting the time within which an action may be brought to less than the regular period prescribed by the statute of limitations of this state. The Nebraska statute gives 5 years on written contracts, </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT and as the Standard Provisions in most states require only 2 years, most foreign policies must be amended by rider. In some forms of insurance, especially live stock and health, the 5 year limit is too long and causes great difficulties in making proofs where suit is brought 4 or 5 years after the cause accrued. Re - commend amendment to 2 years. Accident Insurance Amend clause Eight, Sec. 104, to provide for return of unearn - ed premium in event of natural death, where insured has paid premiums for more than one year in advance. Pro rata or short rate as seems just. Maximum Risk. — Fire Insurance Sec. 113 Mi. S. 3249) prescribes a maximum single risk manifestly intended only to appy to companies writing fire in - surance and kindred risks — cyclone, tornado, windstorm, hail, etc. It should be amended by inserting the word "fire" between No" and "insurance company," first line. Adjuster — Violations Sec. 115 (G. S. 3251 ) should be amended to read "Every ad - juster of insurance written under the provisions of First sub-divi - sions section 79. of this chapter." etc. As it stands the section is indefinite and might be misconstrued. Additional Requirements for Admission Section 140 (G. S. 3276). This section is intended to safe - guard against mushroom companies, but should be repealed. Some companies one year old are better entitled to admission than others ten or twelve years old. The requirement is purely arbitrary and the board should not be so limited. Prate rnals Sec. 158 (G. S. 3294) and Sec. 159 (G. S. 3295) are to a great extent duplicates. Section 158 was part of the Code which was approved April 18, 1913, and took effect July 18, 1913. Sec. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 61 159 was a separate amending bill, approved with the emergency clause April 21, 1913. It purported to amend and repeal Sec. 91, Ch 43, Cobbeys Statutes, 1911, but the whole of Chapter 43 had been repealed by the Code enactment three days previously. This section has been discussed previously herein. Benefit Funds — How Derived Section 161 (G. S. 3297) should be amended to read '*** or dues collected from its members, together with any accretions thereto from rents or interest on investments or loans of such funds." Fraternals Violating Law •Section 174 (G. S. 3310) lines 11 and 12 seem in error. Sen - tence should read, "Provided, if the court shall find that such society was not in default as charged, thereupon" etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 62 WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION LAW OF 1913 This law, as has been stated heretofore, only incidentally touches the subject of insurance. Section 103 of Part II providing the method of election requires the employer to post and keep continuously posted a written or printed notice of his election not to be bound by Part II, and is required to file a duplicate of such notice with the Insurance Commissioner. The employee is also required to give notice and to file a duplicate with proof of service attached thereto with the Insurance Commissioner. Section 135 requires that report of all settlement and release shall be filed by the employer with the Labor Commissioner within sixty days after such settlements are made. There is a further requirement that when a citizen or subject of a foreign country meets with an injury which results in death, the Labor Commissioner shall, after such death has been reported to him, at once notify the superior consular official of the foreign country of which the employee at the time of his death was a citizen or subject. It will be seen that the administration of this law is divided. Except as a matter of oversight of the business of insurance. the Insurance Department should not be burdened with the ad - ministration of the Workmen's Compensation Law. As it now stands there is a_divided responsibility. The Labor Commissioner has taken upon himself the burden of seeing that the law is en - forced and yet he is obliged to consult with the Insurance De - partment to ascertain whether election has been made in ac - cordance with the law. Section 103 should doubtless be amended to provide for filing the election with the Labor Commissioner. Workmen's Compensation Sec. 137 (G. S. 3687) provides that "an employer ••• may insure the liability***." Section 123 (sic) (138) (G. S. 3688) provides that policy of insurance shall cover the entire liability of the employer. Sec. 103 (G. S. 3653) provides for filing with the insurance </seg>
            <seg id="p063">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 63 commissioner a duplicate of his election, not to come under Part II of the law. Sec. 104 ( G. S. 3654) his waiver of election not to come under. Employers Mutual Liability Insurance Associations General Sections 3322 to 3345, inclusive, were Senate File 273, session 1913 (Session Laws 513-21, approved April 19, 1913) and cover the organization and management of employers mutual liability insurance associations. Only two associations have been organized under this law. One, The Employers Mutual Liability Insurance Company of Nebraska, at Omaha, Nebraska, ceased writing busisess in July, 1915 ; and the other, the Nebraska .Manufacturers Mutual Casualty Association, of Omaha, is still operating. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT AGENTS' LICENSE FEES— DISPOSITION Section 19, Art. 11, Insurance Code, (G. S. 3155, R. S. 1913) provides that — "The insurance board shall require in advance the following fees; ****for each certificate of authority to ***** any agent or agents •* two dollars; for each certificate of authority issued to any domestic company, or any agent or agents of such company, fifty cents." All fees required by Section 19 were, for about two years after the insurance board was created, covered into the State Treasury and placed in the State General Fund as miscellaneous office fees. On or about July 13. 1015, State Treasurer, Geo. E. Hall, held that the fees mentioned in the quotation above are in fact ''license money" and that they come within the scope of Section 5, Art. VIII, Const.; and since July 13, 1915, all fees for so-called "agents licenses" have been placed in the Temporary School Fund and apportioned semi-annually in accordance with the laws governing such fund and its distribution. Up to and including Nov. 30, 1916, the sum of $46,360.86 has been thus charged to and become a part of the Temporary School Fund. Section 5, Article VIII. Constitution of Nebraska is as fol- lows : "Sec. 5. All fines, penalties, and license moneys, arising under the General laws of the state, shall belong and be paid over to the counties respectively, where the same may be levied or imposed, and all fines, penalties and license moneys arising under the rules, by-laws, or ordin - ances of cities, villages, towns, precincts, or other municipal sub-divi - sion less than a county, shall belong and be paid over to the same respectively. All such fines, penalties and license moneys shall be ap - propriated exclusively to the use and support of the common schools in the respective sub-divisions where the same may accrue." Treasurer Hall's act in thus placing in the Temporary School Fund the fees received in payment for agents' certificates or "li - censes" is supported by the decision in State ex rel John Stevens appellant, v. J. T. Nickerson, County Clerk, et al., appellees, (97 Neb. 837). This was an action in the district court for Furnas County, for a peremptory writ of mandamus to compel the county clerk </seg>
            <seg id="p065">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 65 to pay over to the county treasurer the money collected by him for hunting and fishing licenses for the year 1913. The county clerk had been remitting to the state treasurer, as required by the game law of 1901, but Stevens, the relator, contended that because of the constitutional provision above quoted, the license moneys accrued in Furnas County and should go into the school fund of that county and not to the state school fund, as provided by General Section 2702. The district court denied the writ and Stevens appealed to the supreme court. Associate Justice Barnes, in his opinion held that "the con- stitution does not specifically forbid the imposition of a license by the state at large" and that ''the constitutional provision ap - plies only to license money imposed by a county or some minor municipal corporation ••••• It does not forbid the state itself to impose licenses and direct how such money shall be used for the benefit of the schools." It is to be observed that the game and fish law of 1901 pro- vides that "all money derived from licenses and permits issued pursuant to this chapter, shall by the State Treasurer be paid over for the use of the school fund of the state" (G. S. 2702, R. S. 1913). But no such provision is made for disposition of moneys derived from licenses and certificates of authority issued pursuant to the insurance code. And in the absence of statutory direction, Treasurer Hall is, of course, correct in applying the principles laid down in Section 5, Article VIII, of the constitution. The insurance code uses the terms "certificate of author- ity", "certificate of license", and "agents license" inter - changeably. Every insurance company requires a "certificate of authority" before it shall transact any insurance business m this state. (G. S. 3167). If it with other companies shall enter into any contract, understanding, or combination for the purpose of controlling rates "the board shall forthwith revoke its license and those of its agents". (G. S. 3193.) And so on. The fee for "certificate of authority" or license is uniformly two dollars for all foreign and alien companies and their agents, unless by application of the reciprocal law (G. S. 3293) a greater sum shall be charged. And fifty cents for all domestic corpora - tions and their agents, except that fraternal beneficiary societies are forbidden to employ "paid agents in soliciting or procuring </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT members, except in the organization or building up of subordinate bodies or granting members inducements to procure new mem - bers" (G. S. 3307). It would seem therefore that Treasurer Hill might very properly place in the school fund company licenses hs well as agents' licenses. Total Securities on File With American Old Line the State Insurance Board $ 110,045.00 Bankers Life 108,800.00 Bankers Reserve 104,500.00 Columbia Life 56,200.00 Commonwealth Life 104,500.00 Dwelling House Mutual 9,300.00 Elkhorn Life 101,100.00 Federal Insurance 13,400.00 Fidelity Reserve 30,000.00 German American 102,200.00 Guarantee Fund 1,324,890.83 Home Casualty 27,689.00 Lincoln Accident 64,700.00 Lion Bonding _ 148,820.00 Midwest Life 122,100.00 National Accident 102,450.00 National Security Fire Co 101,000.00 Nebraska Lumberman 11,000.00 Nebraska Mutual 10,250.00 Old Line Insurance 150,493.31 Omaha Life 14,000.00 Pioneer Insurance Co., Lincoln...- _ 12,910.45 Prairie Life 101,600.00 Security Mutual Life 101,500.00 Union Accident _. 10,000.00 Universal Protective Ass'n 10.00 Western Indemnity 5,000.00 Woodman Accident 108,200.00 Total $3,156,658.59 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 67 REPORT OF EXAMINERS We herewith present, as a part of. the Second Biennial Re - port, a summary of the work of examinations of insurance com - panies (hiring the biennium of 1914-1916. During this period there have been examined one hundred and sixteen domestic companies and one foreign (Iowa) company, a total of one hundred and seventeen companies. Four of the companies were examined twice, making a total of one hundreil and twenty-one examinations as follows: The examinations in most cases have developed nothing un - usual in the management of the companies. The few exceptional cases where the form and method of accounting were deficient were adjusted at the time of making the examinations, and in one instance where insolvency was threatened, the company was placed in process of liquidation and in another case, license was refused. Aside from the matter of inadequate rates with the frater - nals, a normal and healthy condition and a bright outlook for the future prosperity of all sound business companies appears cer - tain. The farm mutuals as a whole are continuing to operate along very economical management lines. Their per cent of losses in - curred is within the usual average at a normal assessment cost. We wish to emphasize, however, the suggestion made in the last biennial report relative to the insufficiency of assessment income from which source is derived the funds to pay the losses. A slight increase in the levies for assessment should he made in order tn enhance the funds to take care of the excess of life companies 12 'raternal companies 8 'arm mutual, Fire, Lightning, Tornado and Hail companies 75 lealth, Accident, Casualty, Surety and other mis- cellaneous companies 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 68 losses. The yearly custom of resorting to the temporary bor - rowing of money to pay losses occasions an unnecessary expense for the payment of interest charges, and at the close of the year when the business is summed up, the deficiencies, caused by the failure to provide sufficient funds, appearing in the nature of liabilities without any apparent resources to pay them present the companies in an insolvent condition. The credit of the com - panies is pledged to repay the loans, their membership being composed almost entirely of farm land owners. Our examinations further disclose that there exists in cer - tain areas of the state extra hazardous conditions occasioned by the prevalence of very severe and damaging lightning storms resulting in abnormal losses of live stock. In such localities a distinction should be made in classifying risks and rates of as - sessment levies apportioned on property according to the in - crease of the hazard thereon. This (would remedy in those affected districts the gross disparity existing in undercharging extra hazardous risks and establish a fair proportion of the ex - penditures of the companies' funds in the payment. of losses. Claims With all companies we have examined there appears a dis - position to pay promptly all just claims in accordance with the policy provisions. The, limited provisions contained in the policy contracts of Health and Accident Companies apparently will always be attended with some difficulty in harmonizing claimants' expectations; however, these'' companies invariably waive technicalities when the claimants' case appears honest. In every examination that we have made, courteous treat - ment and every facility was afforded us in making the same. All books, records and papers were produced when desired. Respectfully submitted, J. MURPHY, Examiner. H. N. SPRAGUE, Examiner. B. R. BAYS, Examiner. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 69 RECEIPTS FOR BIENNIUM BY MONTHS General &amp; Tem. Scho'l Cash 1914— December $ 1,089.30 $ 164.20 1«15— January 8,939.92 89.50 February 48,794.56 571.80 March 24,013.73 1,171.18 April 18,495.33 88.15 May 14,814.46 1,080.90 June ! 19,243.33 136.26 July _ 15,989.50 804.56 August ' 3,943.15 *863.53 September | 925.50 '168.16 October _ _ | 1,463.79 401.40 November 2,424.32 802.62 December _ 672.10 28.90 1916— January 1,649.06 250.06 February 63,910.98 956.83 March _ I 26,280.51 200.00 April 23,173.80 970.83 May 7,772,72 313.02 June 37,049.51 1,009.75 July 10,741.53 595.75 August 2,199.05 327.50 September _ 2,284.75 1,261.05 October I 808.00 208.20 November i f2,406.88 159.45 Totals $339,085.78 $ 12,623.60 •Less transfer to general fund 620.29 Totals 620.29 Net cash collections * 12,003.31 tLess $159.45 cash fund 159.45 Net collections I $338,926.33 $ 12,003.31 General &amp; Total Tem.ScWoT Cash Year ended Nov. 30, 1915 I $165,858.86 $160,136.89 $ 5,721.97 Year ended Nov. 30, 1916 185,070.78 178,789.44 6,281.34 Total for biennium $350,929.64 $338,926.33 $ 12,003.31 Gain 1916 over 1915 19,211.92 18,652.55 559.37 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 70 Recapitulation: Classes and Total Payments Companies Amount Stock fire and underwriters 118 $109,815.55 Mutual Fire, Tornado and Hail 12 2,692.54 Assessment Hail and Plate Glass 2 217.88 Assessment Fire and Tornado 75 2,814.83 Stock Legal Reserve Life 37 87,774.21 Mutual Legal Reserve Life 27 112,443.79 Assessment Life 5 2,015.45 Casualty, Surety and Miscellaneous 71 52,639.85 Assessment Health and Accident 19 1,408.68 Fraternal Beneficiary 46 3,203.14 Sheriff's and Miscellaneous 381.83 381.83 Totals 412 $375,407.75 Less local taxes paid 24,478.11 Net to State Treasurer _ _ $350,929.64 Less receipts 11-29-16, turned over 12-1-16 . 13.00 Agreeing with State Treasurer $350,916.64 Placed in Funds General $292,552.47 Cash 12,003.31 School _ 46,360.86 Total : : $350,916.64 Admission Fees 7 Stock Fire 350.00 3 Mutual Fire, Tornado and Hail 150.00 2 Assessment Fire and Tornado 20.00 3 Stock Legal Reserve Life 10.00 1 Mutual Legal Reserve Life 50.00 12 Casualty, Surety and Miscellaneous 600.00 600.00 8 Assessment Health and Accident 130.00 6 Fraternal Beneficiary 120.00 42 Companies $1,570.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 71 Filing Annual Statement Statutory Reciprocal Total 23 Mutual Fire, Tornado and Hail 458.00 19.00 477.00 214 Stock Fire 3 Assessment Hail &amp; Plate Glass 214 Stock Fire $ 4,280.00 % 391.00 % 4,671.00 6.00 6.00 299.00 299.00 1,440.00 312.00 1,752.00 1,062.00 84.00 1,146.00 56.00 20.00 76.00 2,409.00 701.00 3,110.00 215.00 27.00 242.00 850.00 350.00 1,200.00 $ 4,280.00 % 391.00 $ 4,671.00 3 Assessment Hail &amp; Plate Glass 6.00 6.00 149 Assessment Fire and Tornado 73 Stock Legal Reserve Life 54 Mutual Legal Reserve Life .... 10 Assessment Life 149 Assessment Fire and Tornado 299.00 299.00 73 Stock Legal Reserve Life... 54 Mutual Legal Reserve Life 10 Assessment Life 1,440.00 312.00 1,752.00 1,062.00 84.00 1,146.00 56.00 20.00 76.00 121 Casualty, Surety and Miscel ... 27 Assessment Health &amp; Accident 85 Fraternal Beneficiary 121 Casualty, Surety and Miscel ... 27 Assessment Health &amp; Accident 2,409.00 701.00 3,110.00 215.00 27.00 242.00 85 Fraternal Beneficiary 850.00 350.00 1,200.00 759 Annual statements 759 Annual statements % 11,075.00 $ 1,904.00 * 12,979.00 $ 11,075.00 $ 1,904.00 $ 12,979.00 Other Fees Statutory Reciprocal Total Stock Fire Stock Fire $ 35.50 % 421.00 $ 456.50 $ 35.50 % 421.00 $ 456.50 Mutual fire, Tornado &amp; Hail Assessment Hail and Plate Glass Assessment Fire and Tornado Stock Legal Reserve Life Mutual fire, Tornado &amp; Hail 650.05 210.00 860.05 55.88 55.88 650.05 210.00 860.05 Assessment Hail and Plate Glass 55.88 55.88 Assessment Fire and Tornado 850.33 850.33 850.33 850.33 Stock Legal Reserve Life 2,963.23 623.00 1 3,586.23 2,963.23 623.00 1 3,586.23 Mutual Legal Reserve Life Assessment Life Mutual Legal Reserve Life 986.37 323.00 1,309.37 986.37 323.00 1 1,309.37 Assessment Life 1,361.95 119.00 1,480.95 1,361.95 119.00 1,480.95 Casualty, Surety &amp; Miscel Assessment Health &amp; Accident. Fraternal Beneficiary Casualty, Surety &amp; Miscel 2,820.13 590.50 3,410.63 2,820.13 590.50 3,410.63 Assessment Health &amp; Accident.... 312.18 214.00 526.18 312.18 214.00 526.18 Fraternal Beneficiary Totals 1383.14 1,883.14 1,883.14 1,883.14 Totals $ 11,918.76 $ 2,500.50 $ 14,419.26 $ 11,918.76 $ 2,500.50 % 14,419.26 Cash fund % 12,003.31 General fund _ 2,415.95 Total _ $ 14,419.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Agents' Licenses Statutory Reciprocal Total 29,812 Foreign Stock Fire. $ 59,623.36 f 59,623.36 696 Domestic Stock Fire 348.00 348.00 M Foreign Mutual Fire, Tor- nado and Hail 108.00 4.00 112.00 1,699 Domestic Mutual Fire, Tor- nado and Hail 849.50 849.50 308 Domestic Assessment Hail and Plate Glass 154.00 154.00 3,276 Domestic Assessment Fire and Tornado 1,638.00 1,638.00 2,200 Foreign Stock Legal Re- serve Life 4,400.46 10.01) 4,410.46 2,693 Domestic Stock Legal Re- serve Life 1,346.50 1,346.50 2,101 Foreign Mut. Legal Re- serve Life 4,202.00 203.00 4,405.00 860 Domestic Mutual Legal Re- serve Life 430 00 430.00 171 Foreign Assessment Life 342.00 342.00 Domestic Assessment Life.. 230 115.00 _• 115.00 3,707 Foreign Casualty, Surety and Miscellaneous 7,415.00 364.00 7,779.00 2,281 Domestic Casualty, Surety &amp; Miscellaneous 1,140.50 1,140.50 132 Foreign Assessment Health and Accident 264.00 264.00 489 Domestic Assessment Health and Accident 244.50 244.50 38.177 12,532 Foreign Agents' Licenses- Domestic Agents' Licenses. $ 76,354.82 $ 581.00 $ 76,935.82 6,266.00 6,266.00 50,709 All Agents' Licenses $ 82,620.82 % 581.00 $ 83,201.82 29,866 Fire, foreign $ 59,731.36 $ 4.00 $ 59,735.36 5,979 Fire, domestic 2,989.50 2,989.50 35,845 Fire, all $ 62,720.86 $ 4.00 $ 62,724.86 4,472 Life, foreign % 8,944.46 % 213.00 $ 9,157.46 3,783 Life, domestic 1,891.50 1,891.50 8,255 Life, all $ 10,835.96 $ 213.00 $ 11,048.96 3,839 Miscellaneous, foreign $ 7,679.00 $ 364.00 $ 8,043.00 2,770 Miscellaneous, domestic 1,385.00 1,385.00 6,609 Miscellaneous, all $ 9,064.00 $ 364.00 $ 9,428.00 35,845 Fire, all * 62,720.86 $ 4.00 $ 62,724.86 8,255 Life, all - 10,835.96 213.00 11,048.96 6,609 Miscellaneous, all 9,064.00 364.00 9,428.00 50,709 Grand total _ $ 82,620.82 $ 581.00 $ 83,201.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 73 Taxes, Statutory and Reciprocal All Foreign Premiums Statutory Reciprocal Total 39 Stock Fire ... $ 2,188,038.00 $ 44,048.69 $ 44,048.69 2 Mutual Fire, Tornado &amp; Hail 8,322.00 243.99 243.99 27 Stock Legal Reserve Life... 3,615,639.00 72,312.78 4,196.24 76,509.02 21 Mutual Legal Reserve Life .. 5,103,676.00 102,073.52 3,026.90 105,100.42 50 Casualty, Sure- ty and Misc 1,794,174.00 35383.48 702.44 36,585.92 139 Companies $12,709,849.00 $210,269.78 $ 52,218.26 $262,488.04 32 Companies, lo- cal taxes 1 24,478.11 24,478.11 Net paid State Treasurer $210,269.78 $ 27,740.15 $238,009.93 Statutory Reciprocal Total 41 Fire, net to State Treasurer $ 19,822.50 $ 19,822.50 48 Life, net to State Treasurer.. $174,386.30 7,223.14 $181,609.44 50 Misc. net to State Treasurer... 35,883.48 694.51 36,577.99 139 Companies _ $210,269.78 $ 27,740.15 $238,009.93 Overpayments Miscellaneous Fees Not Paid by Companies Sheriff's fees, reciprocal $ 199.75 Other fees, statutory 182.08 Total miscellaneous - 1381.83 Recapitulation: Nature of Receipts Statutory Reciprocal Total 42 Admission fees $ 1,570.00; $ 1,570.00 759 Annual statements 11,075.00 $ 1,904.00 , 12,979.00 Other fees - 11,918.76 2,500.50 14,419.26 50,709 Agents' licenses 82,620.82 581.00 83,201.82 139 Companies' taxes, net 210,269.78 27,740.15 238,009.93 Other fees 19 Overpayments _ 367.80 367.80 Miscellaneous 182.08 199.75, 381.83 $318,004.24 $ 32,925.40 $350,929.64 7 1 4 1 1 1 3 1 Stock Fire 318.00 Assessment Hail and Plate Glass 2.00 Assessment Fire and Tornado 7.50 Stock Legal Reserve Life * 20.00 Mutual Legal Reserve Life 3.00 Assessment Life 1.50 Casualty, Surety and Miscellaneous 13.80 Assessment Health and Accident 2.00 9 Companies „ $367.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT STOCK FIRE INSURANCE COMPANIES "/ Admis- Annual! Recip'l sion Statem't Ann. St. Other Fees! Aachen and Munich $ 40 00J$ 2 00 1 Aetna 40 00 2 Agricultural 40 00 2 00 ..._ 3 Alliance Assurance Co., Ltd J _ 20 00 4 Alliance J 50 00 J J 5 American 40 OOl J 6 American Central _.._ 40 00 22 Offl 7 American Druggists' Fire _... 40 00 4 0O ] 8 American Eagle Fire I 50 00 I J. j 9 Anglo-American Re-Insurance CoJ J 40 00J 80 00 ] 10 Atlas Assurance Co., Ltd. Atlas Assurance Co., Ltd 40 00| 2 Offl 11 Boston _ 40 00 12 British American Assurance Co... 40 00 J 18 Buffalo German _ J 40 00 2 00, 14 Caledonian J 40 00 2 00 J IB Camden Fire Insurance Ass'n 40 00( J 16 Citizens 40 00 22 Offl 17 City of New York 40 00| 2 00 18 Columbia 40 00 19 Columbia Fire 40 001 20 ComT Union Assurance Co., LtdJ ~~. 40 00 « M| 21 Commercial Union Fire 40 00 2 00 22 Commonwealth _ _... 40 00 2 00 ~ 28 Concordia Fire J 40 00! 10 00 J 24 Connecticut Fire .1 40 00 J 26 Continental 40 00 2 00 26 Continental County Fire 1 40 00| 4 Offl 27 Dubuque Fire and Marine J 40 00 4 Offl 28 Equitable Fire and Marine 40 00| 29 Farmers j ! 40 00 4 Offl 80 Federal 40 00 81 Fidelity-Phenix Fire J 40 00 2 Offl 32 Fire Association of Philadelphia..! 40 00 4 00 33 33 Firemen's J 40 00 34 Firemen's Fund _J 40 00 20 Offl 86 Franklin Fire 40 00 4 00 86 s* l ti* * rw\ AA t\ /Vrfvl nr+ General Fire Assurance Co 20 00; 2 00 _ 37 German Alliance 40 00 2 00 88 German-American 40 00 2 00 39 Germania Fire 40 00 2 Offl 40 Girard Fire and Marine ! 20 00 2 00 41 Glen Falls 40 00! 2 00, 42 Globe &amp; Rutgers Fire I 40 0O| 2 00 43 Hamburg-Bremen Fire..._ ! 40 OOj 2 00 44 Hanover Fire 40 OOi 2 Od 46 Hartford Fire 40 00, 46 Home 40 00 2 Offl 47 Imperial Assurance Company | | 40 00, 2 00, | 48 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 75 STOCK FIRE INSURANCE COMPANIES Recip'l Jther fees Agents' Licenses Recip'l Agt.Lic Tax Reciproc'l Credit Local Tax Balance TaxRectsj Total Cash 1 80 00 . t 122 00 2 1870 00 ..._ 1910 00 3 262 00 „ 304 00 4 ..._ J 20 00 5 27 001 _ 77 00 6 1526 00 3151 99 2058 77 2659 22 T 10 00 360 00 1157 97 368 95 1221 02 81 4 001 36 06 84 06 9 184 00 234 00 101 32 00 _ _ 152 00 11 102 00 144 00 19 88 00 463 47 187 86 404 11 13, 128 00 168 00 14 80 00 122 00 15i 140 00 ;. 182 00 16 10 00 144 Sfil . 194 35 17 10 00 90 00 253 64 174 49 241 15 18 66 00 _ 108 00 19 14 00 105 44 159 44 SO 40 00 21 ..._ 826 00 868 00 22 56 00 98 00 23 280 00| 322 00 24 90 00) 18182) 113 11 208 71 26 1374 00 1414 00 26 1994 00 2036 00 27 126 001 ; 28 05 _ 198 05 28 10 00 154 00 : 751 11 338 15 620 96 29 108 00 144 44 97 53 194 91 30 10 00 502 00 631 56 225 77 961 78 31 14 00 11 85 65 85 32 2366 001 2408 00 M 824 00 1550 33 1036 07 1182 26 34 408 00 1187 73 808 71 827 02 35 5 001 258 00 696 51 362 37 657 14 36) _ 318 00 465 04 136 15 690 89 37 20 00 _ 42 00 38 230 00 272 00 39 1888 00 _ _ 1930 00 40 522 00 ;; _ 564 00 « 134 00 „... 490 46 186 66 460 80 42 738 00 780 00 *&amp; 560 00 592 00 44 130 00 172 00 46 624 00 666 00 46 1140 00 _ _ ; 1180 00 47 2668 00 . 2610 00 *8 388 0O| 144 OOt 574 00 ,.i </seg>
            <seg id="p076">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 76 Admis sion Annual Statem't RecipT Ann. StJ Other Fee Indemnity Mutual Marine Assur- ance Co., Ltd Insurance Company of No. Amer. Insurance Company of the State of Pennsylvania Law, Union and Rock. Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe, Am. Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe, Eng London Assurance Corporation... London and Lancaster Fire Mannheim Mechanics Mechanics and Traders Mercantile Insur. Co. of America Michigan Commercial Milwaukee Mechanics Minneapolis Fire and Marine National-Ben Franklin Nationale Fire National Fire National Security Fire National Union Fire Netherlands Fire and Life Newark Fire New Brunswick Fire New Hampshire Fire Niagara Fire Nord, Deutsche North British &amp; Mercantile (Am) North British &amp; Mercantile (Eng) Northern Assurance Co., Ltd North River Northwestern Fire and Marine. ... Northwestern National Norwich Union Fire Ins. Society Old Colony Orient Palatine Paternelle Fire Patriotic Assurance Co Pennsylvania Fire - People's National Phenix Fire Phoenix Phoenix Assurance Co., Ltd. Providence Washington Prussian National Queen Insurance Co. of America.. Reliance Rhode Island Royal Royal Exchange Assurance Co Salamandra Scottish Union and National 1 _ I _ ...I I so bbj 40 0O' 40 00 20 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 20 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 20 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 20 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 20 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 20 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 20 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 40 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 4 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 12 00 10 00 2 00 4 00 I N 2 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 2 00 5 00 2 00 I i'ooj _ io ooj .... ... ... 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 98 94 95 96 97 96 99 100 so'bbi so bbj 50 OOJ 2 bbj 2 00; 4 bo 4 00 54 00 2 00 2 Offl I 1 2M 1 *4 .... 2 bbj </seg>
            <seg id="p077">77 Kecip'l Other Agents' Recip'l 1 fees licenses Agt.Lic Tax Reciprocal Credit Tax Balanci Local TaxRectel Total Cash _ 49 24 Ott J 50 1334 W 3083 66 4 Offl 2285 08 66 00 2180 58 51 224 00 573 02 52 8 00| 53 94 00 54 2102 00 „ 55 82 00 56 438 00 57 6 00 58 34 00 _... 123 99 59 300 00 158 00 „ 2 00 60 70 00 '&lt; 61 86 00 : 376 00 62 564 00 :.. 749 56| 63 864 00 486 99J 64 104 OOl ] 277 81 65 12 00 J _ 66 2600 OOl _ 67 348 OOl 68 434 0© _... 1408 57 2 00 69 54 00 70 70 00! _ 296 32 71 22 00 64 40 72 676 00 1083 81 73 272 OOl „ 74 56 00 75 22 001 76 1208 00 _ 77 516 00 _ 78 87 07 2 00 79 10 00) 546 00 1722 72 80 1742 00 1679 89 81 . : 268 00 82 38 00 181 94 83 224 00 84 . . 244 00 ' 85 2 OOl 86 87 524 00 1283 17 88 27 00 214 00 509 64 89 38 00 90 940 00 91 284 00 158 00 92 362 00 249 56 93 136 00 94 960 00 95 338 00 6K 29 96 36 00 220 74 97 1816 00 98 134 00 99 100 326 00 .... 420 55 5337 12 30 mi 457 lOj 27 61 77 03 854 30 40 99 362 1 10 431 00 1142 56 104 66 73179 506 22 398 47 50 00 136 00 2150 00 124 00 480 00 48 00 146 62 499 70 90 00 330 62 906 46 1375 38 348 78 52 00 2640 00 418 00 1034 27 94 00 365 33 126 40 1437 71 314 00 98 00 94 00 1250 00 558 00 131 07 1889 72 2304 33 310 00 155 28 264 00 286 00 94 00 74 00 1119 38 838 64 80 00 980 00 484 00 631 56 176 00 1002 00 526 07 296 74 I860 00 174 00 42 00 366 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Admis-I Annual Recip'l sion Statem't Ann. St. Other Fees Second Russian 40 00 2 Offl 101 Security 40 00 102 Springfield Fire and Marine — . 40 0» 108 Standard Fire 40 00 104 St. Paul Fire and Marine 40 00] 2 Offl 106 Sun Insurance Office I 40 OW 2 00 106 Svea Fire and Life _ J 40 00 2 m 107 Tokio Marine 50 Off 20 00 108 Union Fire 40 001 108 Union Marine 60 00| 110 United States Fire 40 00 2 Ott Ill Western Assurance Co 40 00 112 Westchester Fire 40 00 2 Ott 113 Williamsburg City Fire 40 00 2 Ott 114 Totals 112 Companies | 350 001 4280 00 391 00 18 00 115 Columbia Fire Underwriters 17 50 116 Fidelity Underwriters 1 117 German Fire Underwriters 1 118 New York Underwriters 119 Philadelphia Underwriters 120 Rochester German Underwriter^ 121 Total 118 Companies... I 350 00 1 5280 00 1 391001 35 50 i 122 Recapitulation Admission of 7 companies J 350 00 123 Filing 214 annual statements, statutory fees ] 4280 00124 Filing 74 annual statements, reciprocal fees J 391 00 125 Other fees, statutory I 36 50 126 Other fees, reciprocal J 421 00 127 Agents' licenses, 29, 812 foreign, 696 domestic... 59971 36 128 Reciprocal Tax, 39 companies, $2,188,038 premiums J 44048 69; 129 Overpayments by 7 companies _ J 318 00J130 Total paid in Nebraska. J 109815 55 131 Less local taxes paid counties 24470 18 132 Net amount paid. State Treasurer J 85346 37J133 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Recapitulation 79 Recip'l Other fees Agents' Licenses Recipi Agt.Lic Tax Reciproc'I Tax Credit Local Balance Tax Recto Total Cash 01 05 1522 00 2654 00 236 00 10 001 1898 00 306 00 48 00 4 00 10 00 _ 4 00 ... 29 29 152 00 714 00 695 00 ., ___ 7942 06 _____ 4857 78 .. , ______ 9636 '74 _____ '583» 27 ....... _-___«J - ........ .... .. 42 00 1562 00 5778 28 276 00 5747 47 348 00 90 00 74 00 50 00 64 00 71 29 192 00 756 00 743 00 09 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 .17 18 19 421 00 52977 36 OOOA AAi 2320 0» 646 (X* i ci _s An 52977 36 2320 00 646 00 1616 00 1352 00 888 00 172 00 $44048 69! $318 00 1 $24470 l»j $78333 87 _._ 2337 50 _ „ _ 646 00 . 1616 00 1352 00 888 00 172 00 1616 0fl lOCO AA 1352 0» OOO t\IU 888 0» 1 &lt;7O AA 21 172 00 $421 00 $59971 36j $44048 69| $318 00 $24470 18 $85345 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT MUTUAL FIRE, TORNADO AND HAIL INSURANCE COMPANIES Admis- Annual Recip'l sion Statem't Ann. 40 00 sion | Statem't Ann. St. Other Fees St. Other Fees 70 00 1 Capital Fire Mutual. Capital Fire Mutual 40 00 70 0tt 1 00 20W 2 00 2 Farmers Fire 50 Farmers Fire 50 50 00 20 00 2 00 2 Federated Merchants' Mutual Federated Merchants' Mutual ! 60 00 87 70 3 60 00 87 m 3 Grain Dealers' Nat'l Mutual Fire Grain Dealers' Nat'l Mutual Fire 40 00 15 00 4 40 00 15 00 1 4 Millers Mutual Fire Millers Mutual Fire 40 00 5 40 Od 5 Millers National Fire. Millers National Fire 40 00 6 40 00 6 National Hail National Hail 40 00 70 00 7 40 00 70 00 Nebraska Hardware Mutual Nebraska Hardware Mutual 40 00 _... 166 00 8 40 00 166 Ofl 8 Ohio Fanners 50 Ohio Fanners 50 50 00 20 00 2 00 9 00 20 00 2 OOl 9 Retail Merchants' Mutual Fire Retail Merchants' Mutual Fire i 58 00 32 35 10 58 00! 32 35 10 St. Paul Mutual Hail &amp; Cyclone 50 St. Paul Mutual Hail &amp; Cyclone..! 50 50 00 20 00 11 00 20 Offl 11 40 001 225 00 12 11 Union Fire ' 40 001 225 00 12 Union Fire Totals 12 companies... 150 00 458 00 19 001 650 05l 13 Recapitulation Admission of 3 companies 150 00 14 Filing 23 annual statements, statutory fees 458 00 15 Filing 3 annual statements, reciprocal fees 19 00 16 Other fees, statutory 650 05 17 Other fees, reciprocal 210 00 18 Agents' licenses, 54 foreign, 1699 domestic 957 50 19 Agents' licenses, 4 foreign, reciprocal 4 00 20 Reciprocal tax, 2 companies, $8,322 premiums 243 99 21 Total paid State Treasurer 2692 54 22 Filing 3 annual statements, statutory I 6 00 4 Other fees, statutory . 55 88 5 Agents' licenses, 308 domestic 164 00 6 Overpayment, 1 company 2 00i 7 . Total paid State Treasurer I 217 88 8 ASSESSMENT HAIL AND PLATE GLASS Admis- Annual Recip'l sion j Statem't Ann. St. Other Fees Farmers' Co-operative Hail National Plate Glass 4 00,. 2 00 ! 55 88 1 ■ Totals, 2 companies I 6 00 55 38 Recapitulation </seg>
            <seg id="p081">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 81 MUTUAL FIRE, TORNADO AND HAIL INSURANCE COMPANIES Recapitulation RecipT Other fees Agents' RecipT Licenses Agt.Lic Reciproc'l Credit Tax Balance Local TaxRects Total Cash Tax 1 ■i 3 4 5 H 7 8 y 10 n 12 185 50 2 Offl 50 00 8 00 4 00 80 00 2 00 80 00 4 00 256 50 1 00 4 00 11 60 88 00 396 00 $210 00 $957 50 M 00 295 50 11 33 85 33 147 70 232 66 349 66 _ 122 00 124 00 366 50 206 00 76 00 101 85 158 00 660 00 $ 243 99 $ 2692 54 13 ASSESSMENT HAIL AND PLATE GLASS Recipi Other fees Agents' RecipT Licenses Apt.Lic Tax Reciproc'l Credit Local Tax Balance TaxRects Total Cash I 153 50L. a $154 00 .... 2 001.. 215 38 2 50 3 ' $2 00! . J 217 88 ...I.. _L Recapitulation </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT ASSESSMENT FIRE AND TORNADO Admis- sion i Annual Recipi Statem'1 Vnn. St. Other Feei Antelope Co. Assess. Assn Battle Creek Mutual Boone County Farmers Mutual Boyd County Farmers Mutual Cedar Co. German Farmers Mu- tual Fire _ Clay County Mutual _ Cuming, Burt and Dodge Farm Mutual Dawson County Farmers Mutual Dorchester Farm Mutual Dwelling House Mutual Farm Central Mutual Fire Farmers Mut. Ins. Co. of Hamil- ton Co Farmers Assess. Tornado Ins. Association, Wahoo I Farmers Mutual Assess. Assn. of Nebr. Big Springs 10 00 Farmers Mutual Fire &amp; Light Ins. Co., Burt Co Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Thayer Co Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Fillmore Co _ Fanners Mutual Ins. Assn. of Dodge Co Farmers Mutual Home Farmers Mutual Home Tornado Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Buffalo Co , Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Nebr., Lincoln Farmers F. A. Ins. Assn. of Madison, etc., Cos Farmers Mutual Fire Ins. Co. of Madison, etc Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Plymouth Farmers Mutual Fire &amp; Live Stock - Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Saun- ders Co Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Scott? Bluff Co _ Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of Wausa Farmers Mutual Ins. Co. of York Co - - -- Farmers St. &amp; Tor. Assess. Assn. of Pierce — Farmers Union Mut. Ins. Co. of Saunders Co T5o 4 Off 2 00 _ 4 OOi _ 4 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 76 00 4 00 82 82 4 00 50 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 4 Offl n 2 00 6 00 m M H lfi H IT 4 00 4 00 4 00 u 19 20 4 Ott 21 4 Offl 270 00 22 H 2:', 4 00 24 H = 2:. 4 Offl 2fi H 27 4 00 2H 2H 4 00 4 00 4 Oo) i 30 SI 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD ■ ASSESSMENT FIRE AND TORNADO Recip'l Other Agents' Recip'l Reciproe'l Credit | Local I fees Licenses Agt.Lic Tax Tax Balance Tax Recta ital ash 1 14 Od 18 00 2 18 501 22 50 3 . 2 00 4 4 50 I 8 50 5 10 50 1 14 50 22 00 « 18 00( 7 4 Od 8 00 8 9 5©! _ _ 13 50 9 6 50i _. 10 50 10 195 5ffl _... 275 50 11 68 OOj 154 82 12 ; 4 5tt ...: 9 00 13 23 5tt 27 50 14 19 50| 31 50 15 5 00 _ 1 11 00 16 13 00 17 00 17 1 50 5 50 18 8 50 ..._ J 12 50 19 12 00 16 00 20 4 00 21 i 4 00 22 206 60 — -. 479 50 23 12 00 16 00 34 2 00 _... 6 00 24 L W - u w 25 50 4 50 26 9 50 - 13 50 27 9 00 - 13 00 28 11 50 15 50 29 3 00 7 00 90 2 00 - _ 6 00 31 .._ 12 00 _ - - 16 00 32 4 50 .. _. . ..J _ _ 8 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Admis- sion Annual Statem't Recip'l Ann. St. Other Fee: Franklin County Farm Mutual Furnas County Mutual Gage County German Farmers Mutual Fire German Fanners Mut. Fire Ins. Co. of Sarpy..._ „ German Farmers Mut. Ins. Assn. of Seward Co German Farmers Mut. Fire Ins. Assn. York Co German Mutual Ins. Co. of Dodge Co German Mutual Ins. Assn. of Nebr., Johnson German Mutual Ins. Co. of Saline &amp; Seward Counties Grange Farm Mut. Ins. Co. of Wash, and Burt Counties.... Grange Mutual Ins. Co. of Custer Co Hammond Prect. Mut. Fire Ins. Co. of Nuckolls Co Interstate Automobile Fire Ins. Assn _ _. Jefferson Co. Assessment Assn Kearney County Farm Mutual.... Lancaster County Farm Mutual.. Lancaster &amp; Gage Mut. Fire and Lightning _ Leigh German Farm Mutual Madison County Farm Mutual Mutual Fire Ins. Co. of Ger. Far. Saunders Co _ Mutual Protective Fire Assn Nebr. Lumbermen's Mut. Ins. Assn _ Nebraska Mutual.... Nemaha Co. Farm Mutual Fire &amp; Lightning Nuckolls County Farm Mutual Nysted Farmers Assessment Pawnee County Mutual Phelps County Fire &amp; Lightning Mutual Pierce County Farm Mutual Platte Mutual Polk &amp; Butler Cos. Farm Mutual Richardson Co. Farm Mutual Fire and Lightning Roman Catholic Farm Mutual Fire Scandinavian Mut. Ins. Co. of Axtell State Farmers Mutual Sterling Farm Mutual ..._ I 10 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 H 6 00 • H H H 4 00 H H 2 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 33 34 36 36 „ 37 38 39 40 41 43 45 50 46 47 48 49 4 00 4 00 6 00 50 61 52 53 54 4 8" 47 50 55 121 00 56 4 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 57 58 59 60 4 00 4 00 4 00 4 00 61 62 63 64 4 00 4 MM 66 RR 4 00 4 00 4 00 68 67 108 00 68 ... I 69 _...! </seg>
            <seg id="p085">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 85 Recip'l Other Agents' Recip'l Reciproc'l Credit Local Total fees Licenses Agt.Lic Tax Tax j Balance TaxRects Cash «„.____ 15~00 J ....... WwT 84 4 06 I TT1 8 00 » 14 56 : Z\ ...jl 18 50 36 4 06 I , I::::::::.:;;;::.;: 8 oo 37 : : 4 00 38 ! 4 00 » j : 2 oo: s oo 40 5 56 ' ! I 9 60 41 30 06 ! 34 00 42 3 06 I ! 7 00 43 10 06 14 00 44 1 16 001 1 20 00 45 8 56 12 50 46j 50 56 i J 63 00 47 12 00 16 00 48 26 5ffl J 30 50 49 ! ! 17 56 I 21 50 50 5 50 i I 9 50 •1 1 50 5 50 52 1 50, ! 7 50 53 4 o6 ! 8 00 54 51 50 60 56 00 52 50 371 50 U M 246 50 57 5 Ott ... ; 2 00, J 11 00 J* 8 06 12 00 59 ] 11 56 15 50 60 1 06 5 00 61 7 00 I 11 00 62 16 o6 I J 20 00 68! 4 00 64 10 ©6 I 14 00 65 3 00 3 06 10 00 Ml 5 56 _J ? 50 67 28 06 32 00 « I 185 06 297 40 69 6 06 I 10 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Admis- Annual sion Statem'tj Recipi Ann. St. Other Fees) Svea Fire &amp; Lightning Assess. Assn. of Saunders Co 4 00 -70 Washington Co. Scandinavian Mutual 4 OC 71 Western Union Mutual Ins. Assn. _... 4 Ow 72 Wilcox Fanners Mutual Fire &amp; Lightning 4 00 73 Totals, 73 companies 20 00! 293 m 706 72 74 143 61 75 Nebraska Hail 4 00 Scandinavian Mutual Life Stockl 2 00 76 Totals, 75 companies | 20 00| 299 001 850 33 77 Recapitulation Admission of 2 companies 20 00i 78 Filing 149 annual statements, statutory fees 299 00 79 Other fees, statutory...- 850 33 80 Agents' licenses, 3,276 domestic _ 1638 Offl 81 Overpayment by 4 companies 7 50] 82 Total paid State Treasurer $ 2814 83' 83 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 87 RecipT Other ! Agents' RecipT Reciproc'l Credit Local Total fees Licenses Agt.Lici Tax Tax | Balance Tax Rects Cash 70 9 00 J 13 00 71 3 00 _J 7 00 72 10 00 1 : I 14 00 73 5 00 ' 9 00 74 $1548 HM $7 5tt , $2675 72 75 89 m I 237 11 76 ! ' I 2 00 77 1 $1638 00 1 ' $7 50| $2814 83 Recapitulation </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT STOCK LEGAL RESERVE LIFE Admission of 3 companies 150 0C| 40 Filing of 73 annual statements, statutory fees 1440 00 41 Filing of 35 annual statements, reciprocal fees 312 00 42 Oiner fees, statutory _ 2963 Other fees, reciprocal 623 2963 M 43 44 Agents' licenses, 2,200 foreign, 2,693 domestic _ 5746 45 Agents' licenses, reciprocal _ _ 10 00 Tax, statutory, $3,615,639 premiums 72312 78 Tax, reciprocal...- — _ _ 4196 24 10 00 46 72312 78 47 48 Overpayment by 1 company _ 20 00 49 Total paid State Treasurer 87774 21 50 Admis sion Annual! Recip'l Statem'tl Ann. St. Other Fees! Aetna Life _ American Central Life American Life..._ Bankers' Life Bankers' Reserve Life Capitol Life Central Life Assurance Society.... Central States Life : Commonwealth Life Continental Life Equitable Life Assurance So Equitable Life Ins. Co. of Iowa- Farmers Life _... Franklin Life Germania Life Guaranty Life Home Life Kansas City Life Manhattan Life _ Merchants Life Michigan Mutual Life Midwest Life Missouri State Life National Life Ins. Co. of the U. S. A Old Colony Life Old Lane Pacific Mutual Life People's Life _ Prairie Life..— Protective League Life Provident Life &amp; Trust Co Prudential Ins. Co. of Amer _ Reliance Life Travelers Union Central Life Western Indemnity Co. (Burial) 1 ■• ... _J 50'0&lt;&gt; 60 "obj 50 00 I I 40 00 . . ..... 1 40 00 20 00 2 1 40 00 4 00 3 40 00 629 25 4 40 00 925 42 5 40 00 70 00 6 40 00 4 00 7 20 00 134 46 8 40 00 468 25 9 20 00 11 00 „ 10 40 00 2 00 11 40 00 4 00 12 60 00 105 001 13 40 00 14 40 00 4 00 15 40 00 4 00 16 40 00 2 00 17 40 0» 22 00 ..._ _ 18 40 00 2 00 1» 40 00 4 00 _ 20 40 00 21 40 00* 309 50 22 40 Offl 22 00 23 40 00 _ 24 40 00 25 40 00 244 00 26 40 00 20 00 27 40 00 28 40 00 155 85 29 40 00 „ 30 40 OOl 4 00 81 40 00 32 40 OOj 400 33 60 00 .... 34 40 00 4 00 35 20 00 36 — Totals, 36 companies Central National Life 150 00 1420 20 312 00 2866 73 37 96 50 38 Totals, 37 companies 150 001 1440 312 2963 23 i 39 ....&lt; litulation </seg>
            <seg id="p089">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 89 STOCK LEGAL RESERVE LIFE i RecipT Other Agents' RecipT i fees Licenses Agt.Lic Tax Reciprocal Credit hocal Tax I Balance TaxRects Total Cash 1 2 50 00 3 4 5 &amp; 4 00 7 ft 9 _ 10 11 1* 13 14 105 00 15 lfr 17 18 15 00 19 20 14 00 2l| 22 23 10 00 230 00 | 6074 14 00 7 00i 167 88 54 00 1 496 94 602 00 41 50 92 00 1145 64 78 00 998 72 290 00 118 00 10 00 238 00 11930 96 124 OOl 4583 72 132 00 404 41 84 OOj 391 60 56 00 860 05 32 00 288 61 66 00 552 45 252 001 3930 62 137 001 135 63 4 OOl 559 49 18 001 613 60 168 501 54 00 1453 58 I 6344 26 83 94 382 82 124 24 719 18 1271 25 1006 92 1351 64 249 69 1370 41 494 46 _ 626 25 91 00 12210 96 1145 94 5897 66 701 41 670 60 960 05 72 15 436 76 660 45 4259 62 314 63 139 87 _ 761 36 671 60 518 00 1579 58 24 105 00 25 105 00 26 ! 27 5 00 28 105 00, 29 1 30 105 00 SI 32 33 34 35 M 82 00 2594 74 44 00 61 65 175 50 88 001 3 00 1747 73 124 00 120 83 73 50 64 001 1140 76 162 OOj 2011 50 654 00 14203 71 141 46 922 94 888 00 5399 14 188 00 9521 62 9 00 2821 74 250 65 459 50 __ 1903 73 389 83 : 269 35 20 00 1369 76 2217 50 4897 71 ~~ 1108 40 6347 14 2380 41 1 2134 03 29 00 37 $623 00 $ 5588 46 $10 0&gt;l 38 168 50 $72312 78j $4196 24 $20 00 ;?499 21 275 00 ... 39 $623 00 $5746 96 $10 OS (72312 78l $4196 241 $20 00| .. | S 7 74 21 itulation </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT MUTUAL LEGAL RESERVE LIFE AdmisJ Annual Recip'l sion Statem't Ann. St. Other Feesi Bankers Life Ins. Co. of Des- Moines 40 00J 4 0« 1 Columbia Life 40 Offl 130 57| 2 Connecticut Mutual Life J .... 40 Offl J 3 Elkhorn Life and Accident 40 Offl 109 83 4 Fidelity Mutual Life : 40 Offl 4 001 5 Fidelity Reserve Life 22 Offl J 138 07| 6 German American Life 1 40 Offl 243 40 7 La Fayette Life 40 00 20 00| 8 40 Offl 9 Massachusetts Mutual Life 40 Offl 9 Metropolitan Life 60 Offl 7 Offl 1 50j 10 Minnesota Mutual Life 40 Offl 2 OOi 11 Mutual Benefit Life 40 Offl 1 12 Mutual Life 40 00| 2 OOi 13 National Life 40 00( 10 Offl 14 New England Mutual Life 40 00 15 New York Life 40 Offl 2 00| 16 Northwestern Mutual Life 40 Offl 5 00, 17 Northwestern National Life 40 Offl 2 OOf 18 Omaha Life 50 00 20 00 19 Penn Mutual Life 40 OOi 4 Offl ..'. 20 Phoenix Mutual Life 40 00 21 Scandia Life 40 00 22 Security Mutual Life, Lincoln 40 00! 363 00| 23 Security Mut. Life, Binghampton 40 00 2 00! 24 State Life 40 00 20 OOJ 25 State Mutual Life Assur. Co 40 00 26 Union Mutual Life 40 00 27 Totals, 27 companies | 50 OOJ 1062 00 84 OO! 986 37 28 Recapitulation Admission of 1 company „ 50 00 29 Filing 54 annual statements, statutory fees. 10H2 00 30 Filing 20 annual statements, reciprocal fees 84 00 31 Other fees, statutory 986 37 32 Other fees, reciprocal 323 00 33 Agents' licenses, 2,101 foreign, 860 domestic 4832 00 34 Agents' licenses, reciorocal 203 00 35 Tax, statutory, $5,103,676 premiums 102073 52 36 Tax, reciprocal _ _ 3026 90 37 Overpayment by one company. 3 00 38 Total paid State Treasurer 112443 79 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 91 MUTUAL LEGAL RESERVE LIFE RecipT Other Agents' RecipT Reciproc'l Credit Local Total fees Licenses Agt.Lic Tax Tax Balance TaxRect* Cash Other Agents' Recip'l fees Licenses Agt.LicI Tax Tax Balance Tax Rect; Cash 1 120 00 5425 83 1356 46 6946 29 2 43 50 3 00 217 07 3 106 001 2949 29 3095 29 4.....: 94 501 244 33 5 30 Offl 1180 86 _ 1254 86 6 40 001 200 07 135 50! 418 90 7 8 50 00 258 001 129 Offl 897 40 448 70] 1843 10 I) 92 00 1894 84 202H S-l 11664 69 12071 19 10 338 00 11 50 00 94 00 1018 01 1214 01 12 206 00 6934 24 7180 24 13 890 00 12625 83 13557 83 2015 42 14. 68 OOt 1897 42 IS 138 00 5467 65 5645 65 16 504 00 18441 80 18987 80 17 668 00 16740 92 17453 92 18, 60 00 110 00 499 35 711 35 19 8 50! 78 50 20 148 OOi 4579 01 4771 01 21 42 00 3466 16 3384 16 22i 105 00 52 00 877 25 1074 25 23 108 OOi 511 00 2A 84 00 155 33 281 33 25 48 00 148 00! 74 00 2443 48 1221 74 H995 22 2fi 90 00 2568 26 2698 26 271.. 16 OOi 427 00 483 90 28' $323 00 $4632 00 $203 001102073 52| 3026 90 $3 00 112443 79 Recapi) ulation </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT ASSESSMENT LIFE Admis- Annual Recip'l sion Statem't Ann. St. Other Fees Guarantee Fund Life Asso 4 Offl 886 40 1 Illinois Bankers Life Asso. 4 OOl 16 m 2 National Life Association 40 OOl 4 00 446 40 :...3 Nebraska State Life 4 00J 4 Scandinavian Mutual Aid Asso 4 Offl 29 00 5 Totals, 5 companies I 56 OOl 20 OOi 1361 90 6 Recapitulation Filing 10 annual statements, statutory fees 56 OOi 7 Filing 4 annual statements, reciprocal fees 20 00 8 Other fees, statutory 1361 95 9 Other fees, reciprocal _ 119 OOj 10 Agents' licenses, 171 foreign, 230 domestic 457 Offl 11 AgCUtO 1H.C110CO; A. I i. iUlClgll, SdUTJ UV/IIICOUV. -ft I VV 11 Overpayment by one company 1 60 12 Total paid State Treasurer 2015 45| 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 93 ASSESSMENT LIFE Wh«! Aunts' Recrpl _ I Reciprocal Credit _ Local I Total feST Scenes A^ud Tax i f ax Ba^ TaxR^te _Cash 1 57 50 1 6ri 949 42 i"5Tii 252 ».. "1 ■■■■ I 1 £! 52 9 14 00 90 00 594 46 .1 It V7V i*V W '.I 1 " j A An 3 36 00 - -- 40 00 a I 21 50 54 57 d $119 00! $457 00 1 ' 1 $1 S0| I $2015 45 Recapitulation </seg>
            <seg id="p094">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT 94 Lincoln Accident Lion Bonding and Surety Co Lloyd's Plate Glass London Guaranty &amp; Accident Co London &amp; Lancashire Guar. A Accident Co. London &amp; Lancashire Indemnity Co. of A 50 00 Maryland Casualty Co Maryland Motor Co _... 50 00 Masonic Protective Asso Mass. Bonding and Insur. Co Merchants' Life and Cas. Co 50 00 Metropolitan Casualty Metropolitan Life (See Mutual Legal Reserve Life) ■•- National Accident National Life Ins. Co. of U. S. A. (See Stock Legal Reserve Life) National Surety Co 40 00 40 00 40 00 20 OOi 20 00| 40 00] 40 00 40 00 20 00 40 00 isw uu tia 777 40 c4 2 00 35 33 1 H r 1 50 IS 10 00 2 00 V) v 2 50 4l 2 00 41 2 00 2 00 (-1 i 40 obi I 45 280 50 16 .17 2 00 2 00 18 ■40 obi CASUALTY, SURETY AND MISCELLANEOUS Adrois- Annual; Recip'l sion ! Statem't Ann. St. Other Feed Aetna Accident and Liability Co. i 40 00) 12 00 1 Aetna Life See Stock Life Com- panies) 2 American Causualty Co I 40 OOl 4 OOj 4 00 3 American Credit Indem. Co I 40 0C 4 0* 4 American Fidelity Company 40 00 10 OOr 6 American Indemnity Company... 50 00J 20 00 2 00| 2 00 6 American Mut. Surety Company.. 40 00 ! 7 50 7 American Old Line 24 00 309 69 8 7 50 American Surety Company 1 40 00J 2 00 50| 9 Automobile I I 45 00 126 50i 10 Bankers' Accident I 40 00 4 00 11 Casualty Company of America... .__ 40 00 2 00 2 00 12 Chicago Bonding &amp; Surety Co 40 OOl 3 50 13 Continental Casualty Company 40 001 20 00 14 Employers' Liab. Assur. Cor. Ltd. 50 00 40 00 15 40 00 15 European Accident 50 00 20 0&amp; 2 001 16 Federal ! : ' 20 00| | 50 17 Fidelity &amp; Casual. Co. of N. Y 40 00 2 00: 18 Fidelity and Deposit Co. of Md.. I j 40 Offl 10 00 15 00 19 Frankfort iGeneral I 40 OOl 2 00j 20 Gen. Accident F. &amp; L. Assur. Cor. 40 00 2 001 | 21 Georgia Casualty Co. } -... 20 Offl j 22 Globe Indemnity Co.. Z"""""Z3 "..__ 40 Offl 2 00 2 50 i 23 Great Eastern Casualty Co 40 00J 2 00 J 24 Great Western Accident j ' 40 OOj 4 00 .25 Guardian Casualty and Guaranty 50 00 20 0» 35 00 26 Hartford Accident and Indem. Co. 50 00, 27 Hartford Steam Boiler Inspec. &amp; Insur. Co 40 00 28 Home C— Kjf &lt;X 40 00 ! 220 25 29 Indiana and Ohio Live Stock I 40 0W 20 OOi H Inter Ocean Casualty Co 40 00] 20 OOj 31 Kansas City Casualty Co 40 00; 22 00| 12 40 00 22 00 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 95 28 29 30 50 00 31 50 00 32 20 00 ■13 34 a*&gt; 36 80 00 37 242 00 68 50 28* 00 144 00 2 00 1 00 54 00 243 00 414 50 128 00| 212 00 30 00 472 33 MS T4 1 17 39 ' 226 16 I 110 "27 „.____ _____ 1 3620 64 754 33 328 75 1454 74 130 39 352 16 473 00 1231 90 280 27 3952 64 . ; 264 05 I 316 05 38 89 40 41 42 50 43 44 96 00 122 00 if m 344 00 34 00 144 00 211 09, 1593 00; 143 18, _____ Z. I 1178 09 2 32 _ 302 94 7 93 378 59 1767 00 50 00 195*18 1565 09 108 32 483 01 45 46 125 50 _____ 446 00 47 48 232 00 . 1844 61 , 771 2 00 I -7 2122 61 CASUALTY, SURETY AND MISCELLANEOUS R«^ Other Agents' Recip'l Reciproc'l Credit Local Total fees Licenses AgtXid Tax Tax Balance Tax Rects Cash 1 70 GO 277 02 2 00 40102 2 3 32 00) i 263 46 I 339 46 4 2 00 22 50 1 68 50 5 28 Offl 200 301 278 30 6 74 00 7 2 Off 49 50 8 58 001 391 69 9 580 00J 1135 74 1758 24 10 157 5d 329 00 11 12 00 110 00 1122 17 280 56 ... 1568 72 12 72 OOl 959 39 _... 1075 39 13 80 00 114 «&gt; 89 85 327 35 13 80 00 114 W 89 85 327 35 14 50 00 146 00! 73 0« 1339 17 1668 17 14 50 00 146 OOi 73 0« 1339 17 .... 1668 17 15 208 Offl 545 09 _... 843 09 843 09 16 . 72 00 17 19 00 39 50 17 19 OOl .... : 39 50 18 355 00 3624 48 4021 48 3624 48 ..... 4021 48 19 210 Offl 1292 37 1567 37 20 258 00 936 83 1 _. 1236 83 21 10 00 154 08 206 07 22 11 00| 6 00 179 90 "."""___ 9 8G j 226 70 21 184 00 1190 50 1419 00 24 52 00 328 21 422 21 25 12 00 244 00 1581 83 395 46 2277 29 26 , ... 105 00 27 14 00 64 00 28 242 00 472 33 754 33 29 68 50 328 75 30 50 00 28S 00 144 00 912 74 1. 1454 74 31 50 00 2 00 100 17 39 ' 130 39 32 20 00 54 00 226 16 352 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Admis- Annual/ Recip'l sion Statem't/Ann. St Nebraska Manufacturers Mut. ! Assn 50 0(X 40 Ofl J I 49 New Amsterdam Casualty Co I 50 00 20 00 10 00, '"" 2 "ool 50 New England Equitable ! J 40 00 51 New Jersey Fidel'y &amp; Plate Glass 40 00 1 52 New York Plate Glass ] 40 00 2 Ott 53 3 late Glass 40 OOi _ 52 J 40 OS 2 (id 63 North America Accident _ 40 Offl 54 Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Cor 40 00| ■ Ml 55 Pacific Mutual Life (See Stock Legal Reserve Life) ] J 56 Pioneer J 40 Offl '. 225 Offl 57 Preferred Accident _ i 40 00 2 Ott 58 Red Men's Fraternal Accident Assn. of America ■ 40 0© 2 Ott 59 Reliance Life (See Stock Legal Assn. of America. Reserve Life) _ 60 Southern Surety 40 001 300 Offl 200 50| 61 40 00 :«X&gt; 00 200 50 61 Standard Accident j 40 00 1 62 Standard Live Stock 40 00 20 OOJ '..'.'. 63 Travelers (See Stock Legal Reserve Life) J 64 Travelers Indemnity Co 40 00 66 Union Accident ' 40 00 162 50 66 United States Casualty Co 1 40 00 2 00 67 U. S. Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Co ' | 40 00( 10 OOI 6 50; 68 World Life and Accident 50 00 I 60 Totals, 69-6 (63 companies 50 00 2290 OOi 535 00; 2564 34 70 t •»»._j 1 T •_l_il/i T Employers Mutual Liability Ins. Co. of Nebr 50 00 40 OW 71 Equitable Surety Co 20 00| 10 Ott 6 00 72 Illinois Surety Co 40 00 18 00 73 National Fidelity &amp; Cas. Co 20 00 231 79 74 Northwestern Live Stock 20 00 2 00 75 ilUl Wl ncoici 11 *-«»c fcjiiwaw «#w wi «■ w Southwestern Surety Co 20 Offl 150 00 Southwestern Surety Co 20 00 150 00 76 Union Casualty 40 00 4 00 77 OUUklincakCiu kJUAWj w I «*v ™ iww w ...-, Union Casualty 40 00 4 00 U. S. Health and Accident j 78 Totals, 77-6 (71) companies 600 00 2409 OOi 701 0O| 2820 13 79 Recapitulation Admission of 12 companies .' _ 600 00 80 Filing of 121 annual statements, statutory fees 2409 00 81 Filing of 53 annual statements, reciprocal fees _ 701 00 82 Other fees, statutory 2820 13 83 Other fees, reciprocal 590 50 84 Agents' licenses, 3,707 foreign, 2,281 domestic 8555 50 85 Agents' licenses, reciprocal 364.00 86 Tax, statutory, $1,794,174 premiums 35883 48 87 Tax, reciprocal _ _ 702 44 88 Overpayments by 3 companies ,_ 13 80 89 Totals paid in Nebraska _ 52639 85 90 Less local taxes paid 7 93 91 Total paid State Treasurer 52631 92 92 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 97 RecipT Reciproc'l Credit Local Total Tax Balance TaxRects Cash Reciproc'l Credit Local ' Total Tax Balance TaxRects Cash Other Agents' RecipT fees Licenses Agt.Lid Tax — - 49 ... 4y 90 00 90 00 50 _____ 42 00 _ 50 J 42 00 124 00 488 64 401 79 271 84 821 72 124 00 488 64 51 92 00 354 64 5i 92 00! 364 64 52 174 00 187 79 52 174 00.. 187 79 5S 70 00 159 84 401 79 53 70 00 159 84 159 84 271 84 54 80 00 184 00 517 72 5* 80 0« 184 00 ! 517 72 821 72 _. 2432 40 2432 40 55 116 00 2274 40 55 116 00 ! 2274 40 5« M ," \ 1 420 50 420 50 1047 73 571 ___..__ 155 50 _ 57 155 50 _ 58, 36 (m 969 73 _ 1047 73 58 36 00 969 73 59 - 4 00 1 33 59; 4 0&amp; 1 33 47 83 47 33 60&lt; 6l! ,'"".'" 96 00 "" 48 Ooj 1034 1 07 . _____ ! ' 1718 57 61 96 00 48 00 1034 07 1718 57 1255 69 206 38 62 " 406 00 809 69 63 ""50 00 2000 10 00. 6638 62 406 00 809 69 ... ... 1255 69 63 5000 20 00 10 00 6638 _ 206 38 64 66i ZZZI vrfm ™ 53 _______ _____ ] 338 53 65 178 50 120 53 338 53 396 00 176 06 2542 39 _ 396 00 66 193 50 67 26 00 108 06 66 193 50 _ _ 176 06 _ 2542 39 «7 26 00 108 06 «gj "„'.'."..'. 706 00 1779 89 68, . 706 00 1779 89 69 I 50 00 50 00 m 7ffl$484 50 $8227 00 $282 Offi $34525 76 676 01 $13 80| $7 93 $50059 48 94 00 71 .... 4 00 72 10 00 96 00 192 35 334 35 73 80 00 28 00 _ 890 68 1056 68 74 8 50 76| 16 00 28 00 105 73 260 29 26 43 i 198 16 76j 164 00 82 00 133 40 771 __ I 549 40 44 00 77. iJzzz: 1: :.- 35 56 35 56 79 $590 50l $8555 5ol$364 OOl $35883 48 $702 44 $13 8C $7 93 $52631 92 Recapitulation </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT ASSESSMENT, HEALTH AND ACCIDENT Ad mis- Annual! Recip'l sion Statem'U Ann. St.; Other Feed Brotherhood of all Railway Em- ployees 14 00 8 00 1 Business Men's Accident Assn. of America 50 00 20 00 11 00 Business Men's Protective Asso. I 40 00 4 OOi I I 4 I Central Business Men's Asso. ] 10 00 Central Health Company 10 (K* Conservative Health &amp; Accident Co 10 00 I Fraternal Protective Asso. 40 001 7 Inter-state Business Men's Acci. Association 40 00J 4 00 8 Mutual Benefit Health &amp; Acci. Assn 4 Oft 87 68 9 National Travelers Benefit Asso. 20 00 27 00i 10 Omaha Health &amp; Accident Asso. 10 00| 2 Offl 11 Physicians' Casualty Association 4 Ou 11 Physicians Health Association.... 4 Offl 18 Travelers Health Association 4 00 14 Universal Protective Association 10 00 2 00j us Western Travelers Acci. Assn. 6 00i 9 00 16 Woodmen Accident Company i 4 00| 168 50 17 World Accident Association ,. 4 00 46 50i 18 Totals, 18 companies 120 00 215 OOi 27 001 311 68 19 Columbus Acci. &amp; Health Assn. 10 00 50 20 Totals, 19 companies 130 OOl 215 00, 27 00 312 18l 21 Recapitulation Admission of 8 companies 130 00 22 Filing of 27 annual statements, statutory fees 215 00 23 Filing 7 annual statements, reciprocal fees 27 00 24 Other fees, statutory 312 18 25 Other fees, reciprocal 214 00 26 Agents' licenses, 132 foreign, 489 domestic 508 50 27 Overpayment by 1 company 2 00 28 Total to State Treasurer 1408 68 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 99 ASSESSMENT, HEALTH AND ACCIDENT Recip'l Other Agents' Recip'l fees Licenses Ajjt.Lic Reciproc'l Credit Local Total Cash Tax Tax i Balance Tax Rects 1 160 00 4 00 186 00 2 58 00 139 00 3 12 00 46 OOi 4 30 00 14 00 102 00 54 00 6 1 50l 11 50 • 29 50 39 50 42 00 2 00 8 12 00 132 00 2 00 190 00 9 136 00 227 68 55 00 57 00 10 8 00 11 45 00 12 4 00 4 00 II 1-1 4 00 16 4 :,o 16 50 1H 15 00 17 16 50, 189 00 18 3 Offl 53 50 19; 214 00 500 00 20 8 50 2 OC $1389 68 8 50 19 00 21 | $214 00 $508 50! $2 Ofl $1408 68 Recapitulation </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT FRATERNAL BENEFICIARY Admis- Annual j Recip'l sion Statem'i Ann. St. Other Fees] Aid Association for Lutherans 20 0W J 1 Ancient Order United Workmen 20 m 212 77 2 Ben Hur I 20 Offl J J 3 Brotherhood of Amer. Yeomen ' I 20 00 30 0O 1 00 4 Brotherhood of Locomotive F &amp; E 20 00| 5 Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen 20 001 30 Offl 6 Catholic Knights of America 20 0« J 7 Catholic Mutual Benefit Asso. I 20 00j- 10 Ofl J J 8 Catholic Order of Foresters | 20 Offl 9 Catholic Union Daughters of Co- I lumbus J 20 00 ] 5ffl 10 lumbus Catholic Workman 20 Offl 11 Court of Honor 20 Offl _ 12 Danish Brotherhood in America.... 20 00 J 120 501 13 D. of H., A. O. U. W. of Nebr 20 OOi 20 001 254 75) 14 Fraternal Aid Union 20 OOi 10 00j 10 Oft J IK German Bapt. Life Asso 20 00 1« Independent Order of Foresters 20 Offl 17 Independent Order of Vikings 20 0W I 18 Knights of Columbus — . 20 0« 1» Knights and Ladies of Security 20 Ott 20 OG 20 Knights of Pythias (I. D.) 20 Offl 21 Ladies of the Modern Maccabees.. 20 Offl _... 22 Ladies Auxiliary B. R. T J 20 ON 30 00 2S Loyal Mystic Legion 20 00J 69 821 24 Maccabees I 20 00 26 Modern Brotherhood of America.. 20 0ft _30 Ott 26 Modern Woodmen of America ....: j 20 0W 2 Od 27 Mystic Toilers ! 20 0W 30 00 28 Mystic Workers of the World J 20 0» 29 Nat'l Fraternal So. of the Deafl 20 0W 90 National Union 20 0» 30 00 1 31 Polish National Alliance 20 00 _ 82 Railway Mail Association 20 OW 3S Roman Cath. Mutual Protec. SoJ 20 0d 30 001 2 OOi 34 Royal Arcanum 20 00 20 Ott 35 Royal Highlanders... 20 00 8 00 36 Royal League 20 Ott 87 Royal Neighbors of America 20 0d 38 Sons of Hermann 20 00 39 South Slavonic Catholic Union ...J 20 00| 10 00 40 United Com. Travelers of Amer. 20 00| 30 (MW 41 Western Bohemian Cath. Union.... 20 00! 30 Ott 42 Western Bohemian Frat. Assn 20 00! 30 00 10 00 43 Woman's Benefit Assn. Maccabees 20 00 44 Western Bohemian Frat. Assn. 41 Woodmen Circle 20 00 626 75! 46 Woodmen of the World 20 00 r. 575 05 46 Totals, 46 societies | 120 001 850 001 350 00! 1883 14 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 101 26 _ i 27 ..JZ.~... . "]"" _ _ 28 _ " " 29 . . ' 30 31 32 i S3 . „ " _ ZZ 34 _ I. _ 36 1 _ 38 _ _ _. 37 _ 38 .... __i_™ „ 39 " . . 40 _... 41 _ ... . 42 _ 43 44 _ 45 _ 46 I 50 00 22 00 50 00 20 00 20 00 50 00 20 00 20 00 52 00 40 00 28 00 20 00 20 00 20 00 30 00 50 00 50 00 60 00 20 00 646 75 595 05 47. 3203 14 ,.|.. FRATERNAL BENEFICARY "Recipil " \ Other Agents ;ip'l Reciproc'l Credit Local Total fees License t.Lic Tax Tax Balance Tax Recta Cash l| ! 20 00 2 232 77 8 , 20 00 4 51 00 f v 20 00 9\ 50 00 50 00 8 J _ 30 00 30 00 • ' : 20 00 lq 20 oo lM J 20 00 12; 20 00 20 00 18 — ! 140 50 14 _... .._ _ 294 75 16 1 _J 40 00 40 00 16 -'■- 20 00 17 _ 20 00 18 , ] 20 00 19 - - 20 00 20 i _ I 40 00 21 - ' 1 20 00 22 „ „ „ 20 00 a •'-- I so oo W -4 ', 89 82 25 .... : 20 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Recapitulation Admission, 6 societies 120 00 48, Filing 85 annual statements, statutory fees 850 00 491 Filing 25 annual statements, reciprocal fees 350 00 50| Other fees, statutory 1883 14 511 Filing 25 annual statements, reciprocal fees Other fees, statutory. Total to State Treasurer 3203 14 521 MISCELLANEOUS FEES Sheriff's fees, reciprocal 199 75 53 Miscellaneous fees, statutory 182 08 54 Total to State Treasurer \ 381 83 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 103 Recapitulation </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT INDEX Accident Insurance 60 Additional Requirements for Admission 60 Adjuster — violations 60 Admitted Foreign Companies: Assessment health and accident 37, 38 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 36, 37 Fraternal beneficiary 38 Mutual fire, tornado and hail 34 Stock fire 33, 34 Stock legal reserve life 35 Authorized Companies 11-21 Authorized Investments — domestic, mutual and assessment companies 59 Benefit Funds — how derived _ 61 Change of Classification I companies ) : Assessment fire and tornado 23-26 Assessment health and accident 30 Assessment life 28 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 28-30 Fraternal beneficiary ..._ 30, 31 Mutual fire, tornado and hail 23 Mutual legal reserve life 27 Stock legal reserve life 27 Change of Name (companies): Assessment fire and tornado 23-26 Assessment health and accident 30 Assessment life - 28 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 28-30 Fraternal beneficiary - 30, 31 Mutual fire, tornado and hail 23 Mutual legal reserve life. _ 27 Stock fire - 23 Stock legal reserve life 27 Classification Changed: Assessment fire and tornado 23-26 Assessment health and accident 30 Assessment life — - 28 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous...- 28-30 Fraternal Beneficiary 30, 31 Mutual fire, tornado and hail _ 23 Mutual legal reserve life 27 Stock le*gal reserve life. _ - 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 105 Code, The Insurance: Discussion of _ _ _ 54-66 History of litigation regarding 54, 55 No legislation in 1915 54 Recommendations _ _ _ 57-66 Sections sustained by supreme court 56 Companies: Admitted 32-38 Changed class _ 22-31 Changed name 22-31 Licensed 32-38 Merged 22-31 Withdrawn _ _ 22-31 Companies Authorized Assessment fire and tornado _ 14-16 Assessment hail and plate glass 14 Assessment health and accident _ 19 Assessment life _. 17 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 17-19 Fraternal beneficiary _ 19, 20 Mutual fire, tornado and hail - 13 Mutual legal reserve life 17 Recapitulation 20, 21 Stock fire 11-13 Stock legal reserve life 16, 17 Delinquent Company 58 Department Expenses: Cash fund, examiners'... _ _ 49-53 Office expenses, etc __ 43-49 Deposit of Securities _ - 59 Dissolved Companies: Assessment health and accident _ 30 Domestic Companies Licensed: Assessment fire and tornado...- _ 35 Assessment health and accident _ _ 87, 38 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous _ 36, 37 Fraternal beneficiary _ 38 Mutual legal reserve life 35 Stock fire _.._ _ _ 33, 34 Examiners, Report of 67, 68 Fees: Constitutional provisions discussed 6 For examination _ 59 How handled by department .'. 6 Moore v State cited _ 6 State v Home Insurance Co. cited 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Financial Statement: Expenditures _ 39-53 Receipts _ 69-102 Foreign Companies Admitted: Assessment health and accident _ 37, 38 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 36, 37 Fraternal beneficiary 38 Mutual fire, tornado and hail _ _ 34 Stock fire _ 33, 34 Stock legal reserve life. „ „ 36 Fraternals _ _ 60 Fratemals violating law..._ _ _ 61 Impairment of Mutual Company _ 57 Letter of transmittal _ 5 License Fees — disposition. _ 58, 64-66 License Refused, assesment hail _ 23 Licensed Domestic companies: Assessment fire and tornado „ 35 Assessment health and accident 37, 38 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 36. 37 Fraternal beneficiary _ 38 Mutual legal reserve life 35 Stock fire _ _ _ 33, 34 Maximum Risk — fire insurance _ _ 60 Merged Companies: Assessment fire and tornado 23-26 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 28-30 Fraternal beneficiary _ 30, 31 Mutual legal reserve life.— _ 27 Stock fire _ 23 Stock legal reserve life..._ 27 Moore v State: Cited (53 Nebr. 831) 6 Nebarska State Insurance Board: Department officials...- _ 3 Officers constituting _ „ _ 3 ■i Omission from prior report: Assessment life _ 28 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous .28-30 Recapitulations : Admitted companies 20, 21 Authorized companies 20, 21 Companies admitted..— _ 20, 21 Companies authorized .20, 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">NEBRASKA STATE INSURANCE BOARD 107 Receipts: Assessment fire and tornado 86 Assesment hail and plate glass 80 Assessment health and accident 98 Assessment life _ 92 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 96 Fraternal beneficiary 102 Miscellaneous fees 102 Mutual fire and tornado 80 Mutual legal reserve life 90 *3tock fire _ 78 Stock legal reserve life 88 Receipts: Admission fees 70 Agents' licenses.. ._ _ „ 72 By classes, total payments _ 70 By months _ _ 69 Filing annual statement „ 71 Other fees _ _ 71 Overpayments _ 73 Recapitulation 73 Taxes, statutory and reciprocal 73 Receipts, Companies Classified: Assessment fire and tornado 82-87 Assessment hail and plate glass _ 80, 81 Assessment health and accident. 98, 99 Assessment life _ _ _ 92, 93 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 94-97 Fraternal beneficiary _ 100-103 Miscellaneous fees _ _ 102 Cash fund, examiners'...- _ 49-53 Extra help _ 42, 43 Insurance Commissioner _ 39 Stenographer _ _ _ _ 42, 43 Securities deposited with State Insurance Board 66 Service on Foreign Company _ 58 Mutual fire, tornado and hail..._ 80, 81 Mutual legal reserve life 90, 91 Stock fire..- _ 74-79 Stock legal reserve life.— - _ 88, 89 Receiverships : Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 28-30 leport of Board _ _ x . 58 Salaries _ 50 Salaries Drawn: Actuary _.._ 39, 40 Bookkeeper _ 40, 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT State v Home Insurance Company, cited (59 Nebr. 5?4) 6 State ex rel Howard v Brian, cited (96 Nebr. 278) 56 State ex rel Martin v Howard cited (96 Nebr. 278) 55 State ex rel Stevens v Nickerson, cited (97 Nebr. 837) 64 Statute of Limitations of Actions :. 59 Summary of Insurance Business: Cost to the people. 9 Discussed ..._ - - 6-10 Taxes discussed...- _ 9, 10 Supreme Court Decisions: Sections held valid 56 Taxes: Amendment proposed... _ 10 Income, 1914-15 9 Withdrawn Companies: Assessment hail 23 Casualty, surety and miscellaneous 28-30 Workmen's Compensation Law. 62 </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>