<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home To the Governor and Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OP THE Nebraska Industrial Home MILFORD, NEBRASKA To the Governor and Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION Lena E. Ward Superintendent Wm. Sandusky Physician Sude B. Ward Matron and Head Nurse EMPLOYEES M. Evelyn Meyer Secretary, Stenographer, Steward and Teacher Eva Sharon Domestic Science Teacher Trecia Williams Sewing Teacher R. E. Williams Enfrineer C. L. Shoots Fireman Walter Rifenbok Farmer </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 393 NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Howard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and Silas A. Holcomb: Gentlemen: It is with pleasure that I submit my report for the two years ending November 30, 1916. These have been years of prosperity and advancement and I am pleased to report that conditions at this institution are most gratifying. The purpose of the "Home" is two-fold: First, to give care and training to young girls, who have been unfortunate or who are, for lack of parental care, in danger of going wrong. Perhaps it is not generally known that sixty-five percent of our girls come from broken homes, where it was impossible for them to obtain the schooling and training necessary to develop intelligent, upright and self-sustaining young women. Second, to give the unfortunate child a chance to be born under the best possible conditions so that it will not, through neglect and improper nourishment, be forced to go through this world, blind or otherwise physically disabled. Also to see, that it is placed in a good home, when conditions are such that the mother cannot keep it so that it will have an equal chance in life with children of more fortunate birth. The "Home" has now been in existence almost twenty - eight years — long enough for the results of the work to be beyond question. During this time one thousand fifty-nine girls have been cared for, encouraged and given a new chance in life. Milford, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 394 It has been our privilege, during the time we have been associated with the "Home", to come in close touch with a number of these unfortunate girls or children and to indirectly hear from a great many others who have been out of the institution in the world long enough to prove, beyond doubt, what they are. We find these girls as faithful, loyal mothers and housewives, teachers, seamstresses, nurses, and domestics, living good, upright lives, — some in positions they have held from five to twelve years. Some have not only cared for themselves, but also cared for their unfortunate child. A few of these have been able to lay up a goodly little sum, with which they hope to educate the child, for whose unfortunate birth they are responsible. One girl, who was denied her own home and people, after her misfortune, and who has lived a life above question, has by hard work and self-denial been able to save two thousand dollars in the past eight years. Another, a little cripple girl, without father or mother, has supported herself and child and has a goodly sum in the bank. Just what percent make good, it would be difficult to say, but we know that, by far, the greater percent live upright lives after leaving the "Home". What' of the children who have been born in the "Home"? Of the boys born in this institution, one is a grad - uate of the University of Nebraska ; another of the University of Wisconsin; one, who visited the institution a few months ago, has been in the employ of an eastern railway company and carried an annual pass which is only given to employees after ten years of faithful service and also carried a visiting pass from the Masonic Lodge; others, in this state, are en - gaged in farming, stock-raising and mercantile business. Of the girls born in the "Home" and are now women, one is a principal of a school ; another has charge of the music in one of our large schools; others are bookkeepers, stenographers and housewives. An old gentleman, who, twenty-five years ago, took from this "Home" a baby boy and girl and raised them as his own children, visited the "Home" last summer and told us that these children had never been anything but a pleasure to him ; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">/\ I . '- . . . 1 . i i s I I ►— 1 . i • 4 - . u c 1 - -3 B 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 395 that the boy was married and was an excellent man, living near him on one of his farms, which, at his death, is to be the boy's; the girl was also married and he made his home with her; and no one could be better or \10re thoughtful of him than she ; that he had been paid many times for all he had done for them and he would always have the kindest feeling for the "Home" from which he got these children. The institution has not made an effort to keep in touch with these children as they grow up, but is always glad to hear from them. The homes into which some of our babies have gone the last ten years have been of the very best in the State and it is such a pleasure to see the care and training they are receiv - ing. Before a child is placed in a home, it is carefully investi - gated. Care is also exercised by the institution that the child is suitable for the home. Then it is placed out on four months' trial. At the end of this time, if everything is satisfactory, the adoption is closed. THE WORK OF THE HOME The work of the "Home" is divided into details, through which all must pass, that each may get a general idea how to do the work. There is a school of letters every afternoon. In past years each girl was required to attend this school when not on duty. That made it impossible for her to do so. This we found to be very unsatisfactory, as it was impossible for the teacher to give any one girl or class of girls enough time for them to derive any benefit from their school work. The number in school would average from thirty to forty-five, and from the third grade up to the high school. Some had finished high school. So the past year we have only had the girls in school, who have had but little schooling, or those who are trying to fit themselves for some special line of work, or to keep up with their classes, so that they may go back to school after leaving the institution. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">396 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF There are special classes in sewing, nursing, care of child - ren, and domestic science for those who are not in school. The sewing classes have also been graded and a progressive system worked out. In the first class they do hemming and mending, darning, sewing carpet rags and tying comforters. Advance - ment is made into the second class, where plain sewing such as bed linen, children's skirts and gowns, laundry bags and towels are done on the machine. In the third class are made house dresses, aprons, baby dresses and night gowns. Finally, those who have passed through the other grades satisfactorily are taught to plan and make more difficult dresses, — each one being allowed to select her pattern and to make, under the direction of the teacher, any dress she wishes to undertake. Each afternoon special classes in domestic science are conducted. One day is spent in study and discussing the lesson and the next in demonstrating. The food prepared in class is served at meal time, — each girl preparing enough for a family of six. The following menu, which was prepared for food stuffs, raised at the institution, was served on Pure Food Day, April 6, 1916: BAKED CHICKEN WITH DRESSING MASHED POTATOES GIBLET GRAVY CREAMED CABBAGE SCALLOPED TOMATOES SPICED APPLES PARK PICKLES VEGETABLE SALAD SPRING ONIONS COTTAGE CHEESE HOT ROLLS AND BUTTER CHERRY PIE WITH WHIPPED CREAM SWEET MILK BUTTER MILK No more faithful and interested class of girls could be found than the five, who are taking the training in caring for children and obstetrical cases. These girls are high school graduates, are conscientious and painstaking in all of their work. In this class, they are taught to bathe babies, take temperatures, pulse, care for the eyes, weigh, prepare food, feed babies, keep charts, care for their clothing and so on. They are furnished with plenty of good books on care of </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 397 babies and obstetrics, which they must read and recite upon. Absolute cleanliness is taught them at all times. At this time we do not have a laundry teacher, but hope to have one next year. One is needed, — not only to teach the girls but also from an economical point of view. RELIGIOUS AND MORAL TRAINING Each evening, all assemble in the chapel, where thirty or forty minutes are spent in Bible study, the reading of some good book, or talks along the line of morality and right living. We also have a regularly organized Christian Endeavor Society which meets each evening. This meeting is in charge' of one of the girls, under the supervision of one of the teachers. Each girl is expected to take some part in these meetings aside from singing. This is sometimes, at first, very hard for some, as they have never attempted such a thing before, but it is often times very surprising how well they do it and how much interest they take in it. On Sundays at nine thirty in the morning, the Sunday school meets and the International Sunday school lessons are studied. After Sunday school the girls go to the library, where they are given a book or magazine to read during the after - noon and coming week. Our books and magazines have all been carefully selected by the Librarian of State Institutions and are greatly enjoyed by most of the girls. IMPROVEMENTS Of all improvements ever made at the institution, we feel that the new quarters provided for the babies are the best. Until the last biennium, the babies had been kept in two small rooms, with only one window in each, where the sun could get in during the day and that only for a very short time. The institution now has two large sun nurseries where there is no limit to the sunshine and fresh air. In connection with the one, where the older children are kept, there is a large bath room nicely equipped; a large linen cabinet for the babies clothes; a diet kitchen, where their </seg>
            <seg id="p009">398 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF meals are prepared; and a neat little dining room. With the nursery for the younger children there is a bath, similar to the other, but with the high tub, so that the one bathing the babies can stand upright, which means a great deal where there are from fifteen to twenty babies to be bathed every day. There is also a neat little retiring room for the mothers. A hospital ward, consisting of five small beds has also been provided, but, we are happy to say that we have found but little need of this, since the babies have so much sunshine and fresh air, there has been but very little sickness among them. Not one had to be taken to the hospital during the hot months last summer, when there was so much sickness among babies, and it is now eighteen months since we have lost a baby from the nurseries. LA large new ice box was installed, which made it possible care for their food much better than heretofore. Both main buildings have received a coat of stucco, which has not only improved the appearance of the institution but has made the buildings much warmer and prevented the mois - ture from coming through the walls causing them to mildew. All of the rooms occupied by the girls and employees have been newly painted and papered, — a number receiving new plaster, steel ceiling and hard wood floors. Wardrobes were built in the girls' rooms and new plumbing and fixtures installed in a number of the bath rooms. The kitchen was remodeled with more light and ventila - tion, new cabinet, new range and dish sinks. Much improve - ment was also made in the dining rooms. The porches and all outside wood work received a coat of paint. THE FARM The institution only has about thirty-seven acres of land and some of this is waste land. Several acres are in lots, orchards, pasture and alfalfa, so that there is very little for cultivation. This remaining tract, however, is put into garden and the girls help to care for it, — most of them enjoying the outside work though to many it is entirely new. The girls </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 399 also help in the raising of the poultry and with the milking. The institution has a small dairy herd of grade Holsteins, consisting of eight milk cows, three young heifers and one young bull. The following tables will show the work done in the different departments and produce raised on the farm SEWING ROOM Aprons with sleeves 145 Aprons, bungalow 90 Aprons, kitchen 96 Bags, laundry 12 Bands, hospital 8 Bands, infants _ 96 Belts, sanitary 72 Bibs 25 Blankets, receiving 16 Blankets, pinning 12 Carpet rags, pounds 300 Cases, pillow _ 125 Coats 40 Comforters, tied 28 Corset covers _ 180 Curtain, pairs 8 Dresses, adults 75 Dresses, infants 306 Gowns, adults 150 Gowns, infants 200 Gowns, hospital 12 Hoods, children's 32 Napkins, infants 808 Napkins, sanitary 480 Napkins, table 24 Pads, table 24 Quilts, nursery 22 Rompers, pairs 12 Sheets, bed _ _ 36 Sheets, single bed _ 100 Sheets, ironing 98 Sheets, nursery 98 Table clothes 114 Towels, dish _ 72 Towels, hand 98 Wash rags -... 72 Garments mended ~ - 16,996 A y^yji flprf&gt; niitnKi^f r\f y%| j^|* j^p I oil y\ (\ &amp;f\ v^^i* TTTfi^lf 9RIC </seg>
            <seg id="p011">400 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF KITCHEN Bread, corn 225 Loaves Bread, graham 60 Bread, rye 56 Bread, wheat 8,831 Biscuits 12,572 Buns 1,761 Cakes 399 Cakes, coffee 122 Cookies 6,454 Cream, ice 70 gallons Doughnuts 306 Gems, graham 569 Pies 1,387 Puffs, cream 261 Puddings 375 Rolls, cinnamon 485 Rolls, light 5,025 Rolls, "Parker House" _ 321 Apples, canned 270 quarts Apples, butter 366 gallons Apples, jelly 50 quarts Apples, crab, canned 206 quarts Apples, spiced _ 24 gallons Grapes, canned 80 quarts Grapes, jelly _ 24 gallons Tomatoes, canned 360 quarts Tomates, butter 60 Tomatoes, mangoes _ 20 gallons Pickles, beet 110 quarts Pickles, park 100 quarts Pickles, sweet 40 gallons Piccalilli 232 quarts Sauer kraut 230 gallons Chili sauce 64 gallons PRODUCE RAISED Alfalfa, 50 tons $ 400.00 Apples, 425 bushels 225.00 Beets, 18 bushels 11.00 Beans, string, 13 bushels 10.50 Cabbage, 11,680 pounds _ 273.60 Cherries, 10 bushels 30.00 Corn, 185 bushels _ 108.00 Cucumber, 20 bushels 30.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 401 Peas, 30 bushels 24.00 Potatoes, 375 bushels 300.00 Popcorn, 18 bushels 18.00 Radishes, 20 bushels 12.00 Rhubarb, 8 bushels 5.00 Sweet corn, 300 dozens 30.00 Sweet potatoes, 11 bushels 20.00 Tomatoes, 300 bushels 225.00 Turnips, 80 bushels 40.00 Total farm produce _ $1,812.10 PRODUCE FROM ANIMALS USED Hogs, slaughtered, 7,625 pounds $1,149.25 Chickens, killed, 400. 120.00 Ducks, 24 12.00 Geese, 2 „ _ 2.00 Eggs, 11.507 dozen 376.75 Butter, 750% pounds _ 225.15 Total produce from animals $1,885.15 Year Ending November 30, 1915 Cows milked 6 Gallons of milk, 5,929.41 $1,185.88 Cost of feed _ 360.00 Profit $ 825.88 Calves, sold 60.00 Year Ending November 30, 1*16 Cows milked JJ Gallons of milk, 8,588.24 $1,717.65 Cost of feed 480.00 Profit $1,237.65 Calves sold 77.00 Hogs, sold 203.60 Chickens, sold . _ 16.26 Egrjrs, sold _ 4.11 Grand total from farm $6,121.74 Estimated value of stock on hand $2,534.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">402 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF PHASES OF THE WORK OUTSIDE OF THE INSTITUTION Learning what we can of the homes and environments rom which the girls come; finding homes and employment or those who do not return to their own homes upon leaving le institution ; teaching them the value of money ; advising lem about buying their clothes ; encouraging them to save part of their earnings; advising them about their com - &gt;anions and the many questions which come up which they o not feel able to solve without the counsel and advice of ome one, whom they know is interested in them and under - ands them; investigating homes and placing children in lem ; getting settlements either through marriage or support ' child briefly sets forth our multifarious functions. One of the greatest needs of the institution is that of more help in the institution, so that more time can be given to outside work. Unless this work is done and done well, a great deal of the work that is done on the inside will be lost and the State will in a large measure fail to accomplish the purpose for which the "Home" is maintained. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS NEEDED tNot a great deal of repairing will have to be done on main buildings this biennium, but there is some that must done. There should be fire escapes on both buildings. No fire protection has been provided for outside of the buildings and new fire hose is needed. The two boilers at the plant will hardly last through the winter and a new smoke stack will have to be built There must be a well dug, pump and house provided for the same. The old well now in use will not furnish the institution with water much longer. New electrical machinery is needed. The barns and ice house are badly in need of repairing and rebuilding. It is impossible for us to care for the grain as it should be and each year there is a great waste along this line for this reason. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 403 Much work and improvement is needed around the lots and grounds. More land should be provided so as to enable the institution to keep more cows and to raise such produce as is needed to operate it. ESTIMATED APPROPRIATIONS FOR B1ENNIUM BEGINNING APRIL 1, 1916 Salaries $13,480.00 Repairs and improvements 15,800.00 Maintenance _ 35.000.00 Purchase of land 12,000.00 CONCLUSION To you, Governor, and the members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, I wish to express my sincere appreciation for your hearty co-operation and support, which I have at all times- received. I also wish to thank those who have worked with me here in the "Home". Whatever degree of success has been attained is largely due to their faithfulness. To our physician, Dr. Wm. Sandusky, I, especially, feel indebted. He has not only been faithful and earnest in his professional duties, but has at all times and under all con - ditions rendered every possible assistance. Respectfully submitted Lena E. Ward, Superintendent. Milford, Xebraska, November SO, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">404 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF I'OI'I I.ATION K&lt;w Veiir For Year ending endiliK Total Xnv. .Ml. Xii\ for MOVEMENT f..r 1'iir, l'llc, l-.ivti ii in in M. F. T. M. K. T. M. K. T. ■ 47 ■ 17 Hi m ■ 'x\ 1:&gt; 31 31 :a&gt; :;:&gt; 7o 7" 1 1 I I 7 7 Present nt Ipi^'iiuiiim of iii'riml Admitted : Present nt iM'^in nin^ of iii'rioil 1* 47 I!' 17 Hi m :;"i M !:&gt; Admitted : Aclultx: Kor first time Iti •-nillnittfil* . Transfprrc&lt;l from other Institutions. Infants : Born at institiitinn Returned from trial homes in wliieli plnoes before ■■oiiinn'iiceineiit at |&gt;e riort .. ._ _ F«&gt;r flr»«t time Total under care Adults: Kor first tiiiMv Iti •-mlinirtfd*. l ::i Transferred from other Institution*., Infants: 1 1 ii t; Born at institution.. 17 17 34 H H J".i ■Ml ■■■:•. Ki 1 1 1 1 17 17 34 H H J".i :■.(! :■..'. 63 Returned from trial homes in wliiili places before commencement nf |&gt;e riod ...... 1 1 1 1 For flrM time. 2 3 3 -1 5 Total under care. :s7 w. i.b :n mi 141 us n*\ r,i '.«; M :i1 111) 14) Us -iMi Xti In due course. 'I'ninsfined to other iiiKtitutions Hleil 3 14 :! 3 :) 4 Departed witliout leave... 1 1 1 1 Infants placed in permanent lioinei- 1 ( 1 t Miirricd Infants placed in trial homes and not returned duriiiK perUxl - _ 4 3 7 !&gt; :; 1^ 1.1 6 10 Si ill born 1 Total removals _ 20 SO 70 is 4&lt;t ir7 :!.v w 1::7 Alisent in trial homes at commencement of or during period and later dis- charged witliout returning to instltu- tion » 5 14 !&gt; 7 16 •Includes those who have been previously In this or a similar Institution. TABLE II. \(.K AND COLOR OF MM I I » ADMITTED For Temr For Year ending ending Total Not. SO, Not. SO, for AGE for 1915 1916 I lien ii in in W. C. T. W. C. T. W. C. T. rler 14 years., and nnder V't I I I lfi and under 10 _ 1 1 | 5 3 6 6 1« and under 17 _ « 1 ♦ .1 5 \ S l 9 17 and nnder IS _ 15 5 B 5 : 10 10 1» and under 3» I ft « 8 8 14 14 20 and under 25 12 1 13 IS tt 26 1 2« 25 »nd over 2 1 3 7 7 0 1 10 Total*. 2» 3 32 45 « 74 3 77 I&gt;iM4-har?e&lt;l : 1(1 M&gt; 4!t !l :SI 4S l!l 7&gt;- \&lt;7 1 1 1 1 J 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 405 I I Wll t III. SEX AND COLOR OF INFANTS BORN AND AHMIITHI For Year For Year ending ending Total \. v. .10. Xuv. .»&gt;. for COI.IIK f,.r l!li:&gt; 1916 I Biranluiu M. W. T. I M. F. T. ! M. F. T. torn nt institution White _ IT 14 31 13 1« 3»i 30 SO CO Colored 3 S ' 1 1 . . 4 4 Am It ted : White Colored 1 li 1 1 lit 17 36 14 17 31 St 34 «7 Totals... TABLE IV. EDUCATION OF ADI LTS ADMITTED I _ _ - EDUCATION For Tear I ending Not.», 1915 For Year ending Xot. 30, 1916 Total for Hlfii ilium r^- r. R KHM - "&gt;rd isrinlf anil lielow 4th grade Sth (trade fith jrrade - 7th t* rail ♦■... — vth grade _ High school - — College - _ — Unknown 1 i ii 3 8 I 2 3 6 1 12 11 i i Totals— S2 r.2 m +.-, — w~ 77 TABLE V. NATIVITY OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Tear ending Not. 30. 1913 For Year ending Nov. Ml 1816 Total for Blennlam NATIVITY v F F Nebraska _* - — I'nlteil Stiit&lt;-s other than Nebraska -... ■ 7 ■ •J) it Total natiTe born— .T-' 42 :■» I'mtada Kngl.nrt Scotland — 1 1 1 1 1 1 Total foreign born Total* XI </seg>
            <seg id="p017">406 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI. 1-AKKM'AI. CONDITION OF ADULTS ADMITTED For iear For Year ending ending Tutal PARENTAL CONDITION Not, 30, Not. 30, for I'M.- 1916 [ Biennium F. F. F Both parents dead 6 6 12 Father dead _ — 6 4 10 Mother dead 3 10 13 Parents llTing together-..- J 11 20 SI Parents separated 6 4 ft Has step-father I 4 15 Has step-mother 2 13 S Unknown ..__.««»«—•_...... .- .... 1 ■ Total* 38 il 49 87 TABLE VII. AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS OF ADULTS ADMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Total AGE Not. SO, Not. 30, for 1915 1916 Biennium F. r F Age at death of father: l'nder 10 years _ 7 7 14 10 years and nnder 15 2 1 3 15 years and ni-q* 2 1 J Ace at death of mother: Under 10 years 4 10 14 10 years and under 15— 5 5 10 15 years and &lt;*v«»r — — 2 « Totals 2(1 M 4.i </seg>
            <seg id="p018">J rtj -I l^ ■•If t tarn Q &lt; H Z &lt; D - M &lt; I z'. '— e X S C - ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 407 TABLE VIII. ADMISSION OF ADl'LTH FROM HKIKI IIU. OK III- 1.1 M|t t \ I HOMES For Year For Tear ending ending Tntsti f'l.ASS Xi v. ::n. Not. 30, for 1015 1916 Blennlum r. r. r Feeble-minded : Father i Mother Both parent* 1 _ 1 Brother 1 1 Sister Imm*: Father 1 1 Mother 2 1 J Both parents . _ Brother Sister . Intemperate: Father Mother Both parents . — — 1 1 Brother Sister . Delinquent : Father _ 3 3 Mother 3 3 3 « it Both pnrents Rrothpr ~— _ Sister . ., i 1 — . 1 Inknown Totals 17 18 3S j~n- r fe ..—...— — ......... ' 3 3 Domestic T 11 18 3 Domestic 7 Hotel work 1 T 14 Housekeeper — In school I 5 8 U Musician _ 1 1 Office 1 1 Telephone" — — I 3 Teacher J * ! Unknown Worked at home 1 • 18 I Worked at home- Totals^ i 82 « 17 TABLE IX. PRKY1OI/S OCCUPATION- OF A1HXTN ADMITTED OCCUPATION For Y««r ending Not. 30. 1915 For Year ending Not. 30, 191ft Total for Biennlnm F. F. r </seg>
            <seg id="p020">408 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE X. (Ol STY OF KKSlDhM K OF THOSK AUMITTEO AND OF THOSE RKMAIMNC. AT KM) OK BIBMMIVM ' For Yemr For Year eiiiMiiK ending Total N&gt; v. M, .Nov. 30, for COUNTY fcir 1915 1916 It it'll n in in r. r. F. Box Ilutte.. 1 1 Hnffalu 1 :i BuMer 1 1 Itacrrv 1 1 Cheyi'iine 1 1 CWer 1 1 Law- 1 1 I'»»M1II 1 1 i m 1 1 IkMiKln. •■I 1 1 Fillmore Frmnklln 1 ] Frontier 1 1 Fur.,.. 11.11 1 i Hamilton _ 1 1 Jeffemon .... - - 1 I Jolm»nn 1 1 Kcox 1 I Lancaster Hi IT Lincoln 1 1 Madlaon 1 l MerrWk 1 1 ■ 1 1 Phelp. 1 1 Platle 1 1 Polk 1 1 RootU BlalT _ 1 1 Steward _ _ 1 1 Sioux 1 1 Thaj-or _ _ -... 1 1 1 •&gt; Tota)«... X 4.-. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 409 1 T Wil.r. XI. PBOCEDIRK KOK ADMISMON OK ADILTS ADMITTED Tor Year For Year ending ending Total .Not. 30, Not. 30, for PROCEDI'RK for 1915 ISIS Bieiiuium ending ending Total Nuv. :so. Nor 30, for CAUSE for tna 1910 Biennhim M. r. T. 1L F. T. M. F. T. Acute Kaotrlti* 1 1 1 1 l l l l Acute Indigestion 1 1 1 1 Pneumonia _ — 1 1 1 — ■ 1 Pernicious anemia — 1 1 -- 1 — - Puerpernl eclampsia , -I 1 1 — 1 1 Puerperal eclampsia. Tabes me»entrica_ -... — 1 1 — 1 Tubercular — I 1 — 1 - 1 — 1 Total* S 1 4 3 3 3 4 r. r F Voluntary application Decree of court : Delinquency Dependency 31 37 OR 1 8 '■' Totala. _r :;2 4.". 77 TABI.K XII. CAUSE OF DEATH h-oi </seg>
            <seg id="p022">410 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XIV. lll» I KIHI THIN or I.WiOiC OF M.I. MKMBKKS AT KM) Of Illl NMi M Cooks Dining room Milk room _ 1 Laundry: Wash room Ironing boards Mangle _ _ 4 DriMi \ i) rrwri*** — 4 House work 10 Sp winjj room.—. _.-.. — 11 Totals 47 r.. 1 ~" I _ - f AGE For Y«tr endinit Not, 30, 1915 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1818 'I i&gt;t:ll for Blenntum M. F. T. M. F. T. M F. T Under 1 month m _ , \ to 3 iiiont 1)b ...„.„„ 3 to 6 months 1 6 to 12 months 1 •J(&gt; £(i '2?t V4*fl f*K ..i. — „_ 25 years and over 1 __ 1 1 i l ' l i i l .... l . l l i i i l 1 ! 1 Totals 3 1 4 I :i :t 4 7 .•! 1 4 .. :s I :\ I I 7 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>