<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00042">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00042</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  THE BABCOCK TEST AND ITS USE IN HERD IMPROVEMENT.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 25. The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE BABCOCK TEST AND ITS USE IN HERD IMPROVEMENT. Bt J. H. Fbandsbn. Distributed September 10, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. Itm mni or Twt iimhmitv) RNORABLB CHARLKS B. ANDERSON, Crete. NORABLB GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, Pretident, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITHORE, Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERT, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. E. A. BURNETT, B. 8c., Director. C. W. PUGSLEY, B. 8c, Director of Extension Service. J. 8. DALE8, M. Ph., Financial /Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. »Hui WtLcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. W. Uf6on, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Cham, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. •R. K. Bliss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Feaxmek, M. 8. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Brttneb, B. St., Entomology. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy H. C. Fillet, A. M., Farm Management. W. J. Mobsill, M. Fob., Forestry. • R. A. Emebson, D. 8c., Horticulture. Q. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Shtdek, M. 8., Superintendent of Experimental Substation, North Platte. fB. Lee, A. M., AttodaU in Animal Husbandry. . H. Swenk, A. M., Aiiodate in Entomology. George K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. J. W. Calvin, B. 8c., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Babkeb, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). Etwi.i Hopt, B. Sc., Auistant in Agronomy (Crop*). J. A. Ratclitf, B. Sc., Attittant in Experimental Agronomy. Howard J. Gramlich, B. Sc., Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Hones). L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Anistant in Animal Pathology. E. O. Woodward, A. M., A$$i*tant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Coopeb, B. Sc., Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. Sc., Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. James Cowan. M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. Fritz Knobs, B. Sc., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. *8. W. Peri*. Farm Superintendent. H. L. Kte, Foreman Demonstration Farm, Culbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">INTRODUCTION. As the farmers of Nebraska are realizing the Importance and possibili - ties of systematic improvement of their dairy herds, there is an increasing demand for information in regard to operating the Babcock test. A great deal has been written about testing milk and a large number of Nebraska farmers already use this test, but enough inquiries have come to the writer to warrant the assertion that the subject is not yet fully understood by all. Many seem to think that the Babcock test is a complicated process and at best unreliable. This is an erroneous idea. The test is simple, accurate, and easily mastered by anyone who will give the matter careful study and attention. Fig. 1.— Apparatus needed for weighing, sampling, and testing milk. 1, Milk sheet; 2, Babcock tester with bottles ready for whirling; 3, dividers for measuring the fat column; ). 17.6 c.c. pipette for measur - ing the milk into the test bottles; 5, sulphuric acid; 6, sample Jar; 7. acid measure; 8, test bottle containing milk sample; !&gt;, test bottle containing milk sample to which acid has been added; 10, sample dipper; //. preservative tablets; If, brush for cleaning bottles. EXTENSION BCL. HO. 85, AGE. EXP. STATION OF NEBE. BT J. H. FKANDSE.N. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 The Babcotk Tett and Itt Vie in Herd Improvement Within the past decade there has sprung up in our public schools a tremendous de - mand for more agricultural work, for some - thing that will bring the child into closer touch with nature and in a measure make his education more practical. There is every reason why agriculture should be more ex - tensively taught in our schools. It is here that the boys, and the girls as well, receive their first impressions as to what is to con - stitute their life-work. The study of the fat content of milk Is one of the easiest and at the same time one of the most practical and useful lessons for every one interested in the dairy industry, whether it be from the con - sumer's or the producer's standpoint. Teach - ing the farm boy how to determine the rich - ness of the milk is incidentally educating the future dairyman to a higher standard of quality for the city milk supply. In response to the numerous inquiries that have reached this department from teachers and farmers for Information in re - gard to the Babcock test, and with a desire to aid in every possible way those who are interested in learning how to operate the test, this bulletin has been prepared. THEORY OF THE TEST. The theory of the test is simple. Owing to their lightness, the fat globules of the milk will, upon standing, rise to the surface, forming a layer of cream. They do not all rise, however, owing to the viscosity which the other solids give the milk. It was found that sulphuric acid would dissolve the other milk solids without affecting the fat globules, and would thus permit them to rise to the top more readily. By whirling this mixture at a high rate of speed this process can be much hastened and more effectively per- Fig. 1. — 12, Champion milk pail; IS, spring balances used in weighing milk. of the centrifugal machine. Dr. Babcock of formed; hence, the use Wisconsin, in 1890, was the first to furnish a practical means of using these facts. His method, called the Babcock test, was given to the rid as a free, scientific discovery. This test is now in general use determining the percentage of butter fat In milk. BABCOCK TEST OUTFIT. The apparatus necessary for making the test is as follows : 1. The Babcock tester, or centrifuge, in which the test bottle* are whirled. (Fig. 3.) test bottles in which the sample is 2. Milk, cream, and skim milk tested. (Fig. *, d, /. and e.) K3. A pipette holding 17.6 c.c. for milk and skim milk to be tested. accurately measuring out the sample (Fig. 4, a.) </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Babcock Te$t and It* Vte in Herd Improvement 5 4. Cream scales for accurately weighing out the sample of cream to be tested. (Figs. 12 and 13.) 5. An acid measure holding 17.5 c.c. for measuring the sulphuric acid to be added to the milk or cream sample. (Fig. 4, c.) 6. Sulphuric acid in a glass or earthen container. 7. A small coffeepot, or cup, with a V-shaped spout for adding hot RA pair of dividers for measuring the fat in the ueck of the bottles. .4,0.) 9. A test bottle brush (fig. 4, ft) and washing soda for cleaning the ■■*- test bottles. Fig. 3. — Babcock testers, or centrifuges, in which the test bottles are whirled. (c) Babrock steam tester. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 The Babcock Test and Its Use in Herd Improvement A 4-bottle tester with all necessary glassware for testing milk can be at any creamery supply house for about $5. (Fig. 3, 6.) This is large enough to be used for the ordinary dairy of less than fifteen For larger dairies, and in many smaller ones as well, and in cows. schools, 12-bottle testers costing about $14 are more economical. Fig. 4. — Glassware and other apparatus used in the test. IMPORTANCE OF SAMPLE It must be borne in mind that the accuracy and value of the test de - pends largely upon the care exercised in taking the sample to be tested. If that is improperly done, the results are of little value. For example, the writer has known of cow owners, when desiring to test the milk of an individual cow, to take the sample by milking directly into a sample bottle. When it is known that the first part of the cow's milk is very poor in fat and the last part or strippings very rich in fat, it Is self - evident that such a sample would yield results of little value so far as determining the actual richness of that particular cow's milk. The entire milking should be drawn and a sample taken from the whole after com - plete mixing. A composite sample which consists of a number of small samples from different milkinps gives a more accurate estimate of the cow's test, because the percentage of butter fat frequently is not the same in the morning and night milkines. The several small samples which go to make up a composite sample should be proportional in quantity to the amount of milk given in the different milkings. For example, If a cow gave 20 pounds at the morning milking and 30 pounds at the evening milking, the sample from the evening milking should be one and one-half times as large as the sample taken from the morning milking in making up the composite sample. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">fTi X. D/i Itst/lsil* T 1 jy 4 n ti 14 XT ' J 9 1 n€ DUOLOt K 1 €91 uflfl /•• L/8€ %fl xlCTd IftipTOV€1ft€Ht 7 HOW TO MIX SAMPLES. The milk to be tested should be poured from one pail Into another several times, or carefully stirred with a stirrer until It is of a uniform mixture. The sample is then immediately taken, preferably with a small, long-handled dipper. (Fig 5, c.) If the testing cannot be done soon after the sample is taken, it must be placed in an air-tight Jar (fig. 6) and some preservative added to keep it sweet. Fig. 6.— A good type of sample jar. Pig. 5. — Stlrrers and sample dipper used In takiug samples for test - ing. Corrosive sublimate tablets, which may be secured from a creamery or dairy supply house, are very convenient for this purpose. Other preserva - tives which may be used are a few drops of formalin, or a little potassium bichromate. Care should be taken in using these preservatives, owing to their poisonous character. MEASURING THE SAMPLE. KThe Babcock test bottles are graduated on the supposition that an 18 - m sample is taken. Milk varies very little in its specific gravity, and Ipette graduated to hold 17.6 c.c. will deliver 18 grams of milk. When the sample is ready for testing, it should be at a temperature of about 70* F. If too warm or too cold it may be brought to the required temperature by setting the sample jar in water. Mix the sample well and be sure that any cream which may have gathered on the side of the jar is care - fully mixed with the other part of the sample. The measuring pipette is now filled by sucking the milk up into the pipette above the 17.6 c.c. mark </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 The Babcock Tett and It* Use in Herd Improvement and immediately placing the dry forefinger over the top of the pipette to prevent the milk from escaping. By gently releasing the pressure, the milk is allowed to flow out until level with the mark on the stem of the pipette. The pipette now contains 18 grams. The sample is then emptied into the test bottle. To do this, the test bottle should be held in a slanting position with the tip of the pipette resting lightly in the mouth of the bottle. By releasing the pressure on Pig. 8. — Showing method of holding test bottle and pipette while trans - ferring the sample of milk to the test bottle. Fig. 7.— One of the standard milk test bot- tles. the pipette, the milk is allowed to run slowly into the bottle in such a way as to permit the air to escape from the bottle without causing the milk to bubble out (Pig. 8.) ADDING ACID. The next step is adding the acid, which should be carefully measured in the acid graduate. The exact amount to use will depend largely upon the strength of the acid and the temperature of the sample to be tested, but under ordinary conditions 17.5 c.c. of commercial sulphuric acid will be found approximately correct. The temperature of both the acid and the milk should be about 70* F. If too warm, the add will act too vigorously and some of the solids will </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Bahcock Tett and Itt Die in Herd Improvement 9 be charred, causing a black substance to rise with the fat and obscure the test. If too cold, all the solid* will not be dissolved, some of the butter fat globules will not be freed, and the undissolved curd will cloud the test later. This condition can be partially regulated by adding mo:-e acid when the acid is weak or too cold, and less when the acid is strong or too warm. This additional amount should not exceed 2 to 3 c.c. in extreme cases. With a little individual experimenting, the operator will soon discover the proper amount to use. To prevent the burning or the charring of any part of the milk, the acid is poured slowly down the side of the bottle until all has been added, slowly revolving the test bottle dur - ing the process in order to wash the milk from the neck of the bottle. Mix the acid and the milk by shaking the bottle with a gentle rotary motion so that the acid will act equally on all parts of the milk. The mixture should now be of a dark brown color, with no undissolved par - ticles remaining. It is always best to hold the bottle in such a way that if part of the contents should spurt out it would not strike the operator. The bottles before being allowed to cool are placed in a tester in such a position as to keep the machine bal - anced; that is, the bottles are set exactly opposite each other. In using the small 4-bottle hand tester the samples should be kept warm by the use of hot water in the test bottle containers. The bottles should now be whirled for 5 or 6 minutes at the speed indicated on the machine, usually 60 revolutions of the handle a minute. The machine is then stopped and hot water added to the bottles, either by means of a pipette, a small pitcher, or a cup with a V-shaped spout Soft water is preferable and should have a temperature of at least 120° F. Hard water may be softened by boiling or by adding a few drops of sulphuric acid. Enough water is added to bring the contents up to the lower part of the neck of the bottle, after which the machine is run for two minutes, again stopped, and Fig. 9. — An acid dipper. sufficient hot water added to bring all the fat into the graduated neck of the bottle. After another whirling of one minute the samples are ready HOW TO READ THE TEST. To read the amount of fat, take out one bottle at a time, holding it in an upright position with the graduated part on a level with the eye. (Pig. 10.) The difference between the highest and lowest limits of the butter fat column is the amount of butter fat, expressed in per cent direct. Most milk bottles are graduated up to 8 or 10 per cent, each large division indicating 1 per cent of butter fat. This column may best be read by means of a pair of dividers, placing the points at the extreme top and bottom of the fat column, and then, by transferring one point to the zero mark, the other point will give the correct reading. To illustrate, let us suppose the top of the fat column is at 8.4 and the bottom at 4.4. By put - ting the point of the dividers which was at 4.4 at zero the upper one will </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 The Babcock Tett and Its Ute in Herd Improvement be at 4, which is the percentage of fat in the sample of milk. This means that in each 100 pounds of milk there are 4 pounds of butter fat. Pig. 10. — Showing method of using the dividers In measuring the fat col - umn. Fig. 11.— Showing the points from which cream tests and milk tests are measured. The reading should be taken before the fat is allowed to cool. If the fat column is cooler than 140 degrees the bottle should be placed in water having a temperature of about 140 degrees and allowed to stand 10 minutes. If the reading is taken when much warmer than this, it will be too high, and when cooler, the top and bottom line of the fat column will be somewhat obscure and the reading will be too low. In a small hand tester, placing hot water in the test bottle containers will aid in keeping the fat warm. This should be done in all but the warmest weather. COLOR OF TEST. If the testing has been properly done, the butter fat column should be perfectly clear and of a golden color, the line separating It from the acid being clear and distinct. Too strong acid is apt to cause black or charred particles to appear In the fat; this same result may also be due to too high temperature of either the milk or the acid, too much acid, or allow - ing acid to stand in contact with milk before mixing. An insufficient amount of acid, too weak acid, or too low temperature of the milk or the acid may result in a white or cloudy test, due to the undissolved particles of curd remaining. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Babcock Test and lit Use in Herd Improvement 11 CREAM TESTING. Cream testing is a little more complicated. The varying thickness of cream, viscosity, specific gravity, and amount of air bubbles which it contains would introduce large errors into the test if the cream were measured with a pipette; hence, the sample should be weighed into the cream test bottle. As cream contains less of the solids not fat than does milk, a little less acid is needed in the cream test to get the best results. The other operations of the test are carried out the same as for milk. The reading of the cream test should be from the extreme bottom to the bottom of the upper curve of the fat column. (Fig. 11, ft.) Skim milk may be tested by the use of special skim milk bottles, which are graduated much finer than the ordinary milk bottles. The ordinary milk bottle can be used when extreme accuracy is not desired. If there is enough fat found in an 18-gram sample so that it may be measured in a whole milk bottle, the separator is not doing good work. Fig. 12. — An inexpensive cream scale suitable for cream test- Fig. 14.— The SO per cent 9-gram short neck standard cream Fig. 13. — A very sensitive cream </seg>
            <seg id="p012">The Babcock Tett and Itt Use in Herd Improvement 12 IMPORTANCE OF THE TEST. The principal object of this bulletin is to impress upon farmers and teachers the simplicity of the test and that there is nothing difficult or mysterious about it. It is so simple that anyone with ordinary intelligence and patience who is willing to give it a little time can easily master all its details. The Babcock test enables every purchaser of milk to deter - mine easily and readily its butter fat content. When the farmer fully realizes that it furnishes him a key not only for weeding out his un - profitable cows but also for checking up his creamery, he will not hesitate to make use of the Babcock test. KEEPING RECORDS OF DAIRY COWS. In no other business except farming has general success been attained without the use of business methods, such as keeping records of the various transactions. With the increasing cost of farm operations and keener competition in selling, success under these conditions is becoming less and less certain. Careful attention to details is essential to success in dairying, and as a result the most successful dairy farmers are keeping records of the individual cows. The use of the Babcock test and scales, as explained in the first part of this bulletin, enables the farmer to keep an accurate account of what each cow in his herd is producing, thus making it possible for him to weed out his poor cows intelligently and build up a good producing herd. The following method is simple, easy to understand, and requires but little labor. The use of these records in schools would give the pupils training in practical arith - metic and at the same time teach them something that would be of value to them later as farmers and business men. For keeping these records, the following articles will be needed: 1. Scales 2. Milk sheets. 3. Babcock testing outfit. 4. Blank book for permanent records of each cow. SCALES A good spring balance of the type illustrated (fig. 15), costing from $3 to $4, is the best for ordinary farm use. This balance weighs in pounds and tenths of pounds, and has two hands, one of which is movable and may be set at zero with the empty pail attached. Fig. is.— Type of This allows the weight of milk to be read directly, and it spring Males uied takes but a moment for the milker to weigh the milk in weighint milk. _ nd recor A ( tB weieht on the milk shppt These balances and record its weight on the milk sheet. These balances should be hung near the milk sheet, in milk room, or stable, convenient to the milk can and at such a height that the figures will be opposite the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Babcock Tett and Its V*e in Herd Improvement 13 MILK SHEET. tThe milk sheet, illustrated in figures 16 and 16a, will hold an entire nth's record for 16 cows. At the bottom, each cow's milk can be totaled and the test recorded. By multiplying the two, the pounds of butter fat produced in the month are ascertained. The sheet Is the or - dinary letter size (8% by 11 inches), — hence takes but little room in the barn and can be easily filed away for permanent record. Some means of protection from flies and dirty hands should be used, especially in the summer time, to keep the sheets clean. These sheets may be obtained at the University of Nebraska, Dairy Department, for the cost of printing. Other types of milk sheets, for varying numbers of cows, either weekly or monthly forms, may be obtained for a nominal sum from publishers of dairy papers and dairy supply houses, but the form illustrated on pages 14 and 15 is considered as being especially convenient for farm use. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 The Babcock Test and Its Use in Herd Improvement </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Babcock Tett and IU Vie in Herd Improvement 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 The Babcock Test and Its Use in Herd Improvement BABCOCK TEST. EThe handling of the Babcock test has been fully described in the first t of this bulletin. The monthly test of two days' composite sample la iciently accurate for the farmer's needs. PERMANENT RECORD BIJVNKS. This last record, if kept proierly, requires a little extra time on the part of the iranager, but will be found of sufficient value to make the additional effort worth while. Several record books for this purpose are published which are very convenient, but for the ordinary farmer who does not make pedigreed stock a specialty, the following; system is suffi - cient. Buy an ordinary blank book or a loose leaf book. The latter is a little more expensive but more convenient. On the left-hand page put Fig. 17.— La May, a cow of the special dairy type and a wonderful producer. down the name of the cow, her herd number, and any distinguishing mark of identification; under that, place her date of birth, and name of her sire and dam; under that, any information which may be desired, such as her former owner, when bought and for what price, and when sold. This ought not to take over one-third to one-half of the page. Then rule the lower half of the page as follows for a record of her progeny: </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Jot hcock Tett and (« Pse o€tcL Improvement S - "3. I ? "8 I 1 ...... I". - I:::::: 1 I ■ ! ■ 3 1 MMM § : ! \ \ i i 1 nm i I . 1 . a 3-5 - p S ° a-S • 1 "8 i ft I 1 ::::•: « J3 11 =■53 u i I 1 1 3 I i ■ I J a • • I "5 Q 1 I T i 8 § a 1 1 9 I 8 3 : • . '. : '. \ : : : : • ■5 § 5 : : : : : : fa*' </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 The Babcock Tat and It* Vie in Herd Improvement This gives the totals for the year and may be copied from the milk sheet. The feed should be estimated at the end of each month if a daily rerord is not kept. In a loose leaf book additional sheets may be added as needed for the records of succeeding years. One page of letter size ought to hold two years' records. In an ordinary book a few pages may be left blank after each cow, to use for the following years. Records of this kind require but little time and will prove very valu - able in determining the profitableness of the different cows as well as of the whole herd. When the farmer realizes the difference in income be - tween cows yielding less than 150 pounds of butter fat per year and those yielding over 300 pounds of butter fat as shown by actual figures, he will soon see to it that the unprofitable cow is taken out of the herd. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Fig. 19. — A cow of fair dairy type. Such a cow may cr may not prove profitable. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 The Babcock Tett and It$ D$e in Herd Improvement The average record for two years of the cow illustrated in figure 19 Most people would judge the cow in figure 20 to be a better dairy cow than the one in figure 19, but no one would venture to assert that she would return almost five times the income above cost of feed that t other cow returns. This illustrates the fact that the only accurate of judging such cows is to weigh and test their milk. SUGGESTIONS AND PRECAUTIONS. 1. The accuracy of the Babcock test depends upon the care exercised by the operator. Carelessness at any point in the test may render the final results of little or no value. 2. Sulphuric acid is a strong poison, hence rhould be properly labeled and kept out of the reach of children. Acid also chars or destroys nearly everything with which it comes in contact, hence should always be used with caution and kept in glass or earthen vessels. Should any of the acid be spilled on the clothing or hands, ammonia, washing soda, or some alkali or plenty of cold water should be used to stop its action. 3. A black char below the fat column indicates too hot acid or milk, too strong acid, or too much acid. A white, flocculent substance indi - cates too cold acid or milk, too weak acid, or insufficient acid. A white foam above fat indicates hard water. 4. In cleaning bottles, empty the acid mixture immediately in some safe place, shaking to remove sediment from the bottom, rinse in hot water, and brush out the neck with a dilute solution of sulphuric acid and chromate of potash. 5. By the use of the Babcock test and milk scales, the farmer is able to keep a complete record of each cow and thus determine which are profit makers and which are "star boarders." 6. The size of outfit needed depends upon the size of the herd. A small 4-bottle tester with glassware and full directions can be secured for $5 of any creamery supply company. 7. The farmer should keep records of his individual cows in order to "weed out" the poor producers. 8. The value of the time required while using the scales, milk sheet, Babcock test, and record book will be more than repaid by the elimination of one unprofitable animal from the herd. 9. Monthly milk record blanks, as described in this bulletin, each sheet holding a month's record of 16 cows, can be secured from almost any printer or from the Dairy Department of the University of Nebraska at 10 cents a dozen. 10. This department will gladly give such other information as may be desired on this subject. Is as follows: trage pounds butter fat produced— 249, at 30c $74.1)) rage cort of feed 64.15 Average income above cost of feed $10.55 Pie average record for two years of the cow illustrated in figure 20 follows: Average pounds butter fat produced — 387, at 30c $116.10 Average cost of feed 66.50 Average income above cost of feed $49.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The Babcock Teat and Its V»e in Herd Improvement 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 The Bahcock Tett and lit Vte in Herd Improvement </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Babcock Tett and It* V*e in Herd Improvement 25 ■ &gt;, •a 1 E s J P b 1 § *1 n ,u H -g .9 § o a "o ° o .s &amp; ■ §,1 a * a « o I E F 1 I 1 3 t ! </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>