<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Supplementary Feeds in Fattening Lambs</title>
               <date value="1919-07">1919-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 173 July, 1910 Supplementary Feeds in Fattening Lambs H. J. GRAMLICH AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 173 2 SUMMARY I. The limiting of corn in a corn and alfalfa ration for fat - tening lambs reduced the daily gain slightly, increased the alfalfa hay consumption considerably, and reduced the cost of 100 pounds gain 47 cents and increased the profit per lamb slightly. Lambs fed a medium feed of corn and alfalfa produced the most eco - nomical gain of three lots fed corn and alfalfa in varying &lt;|iian - tities, and cost but $4.90 per 100 pounds gain in comparison ■with $5.53 where the lambs were on a full feed of corn and $4.94 where a light feed of corn was fed. Their profit was $2.27 in comparison with a profit of $2.12 where a light feed of corn was fed and $2.13 where a heavy feed was fed. Lots 1-2-3. II. The addition of 1.53 pounds of corn silage daily to a corn and alfalfa ration increased the daily gain per lamb .051 pound, decreased the cost of 100 pounds gain 58 cents and increased the profit per lamb 39 cents. Lots 1-4. IIT. The addition of .218 pound of oil meal daily to a corn and alfalfa ration increased the daily gain .071, decreased the cost of 100 pounds of gain 10 cents and increased the profit per lamb 35 cents. The oil meal in this test proved to be worth $5:5 per ton, with corn at 60 cents per bushel and alfalfa at $10 per ton. Lots 1-5. IV. The addition of .226 pound of cottonseed meal to a corn and alfalfa ration increased the daily gain .1 pound, decreased the cost of gain 38 cents, and increased the profit 52 cents per head. The pen of lambs receiving cottonseed meal were, furthermore, the most profitable in the entire experiment and carried more - finish at the conclusion. The cottonseed proved to be worth $55 per ton. Lots 1-6. V. The addition of .322 pound of cold pressed cottonseed cake to a corn and alfalfa ration increased the daily gain .093 pound, decreased the cost of 100 pounds gain 35 cents and in creased the profit per head 47 cents. These lambs ranked second in net profit per head in the experiment. The cold pressed cotton - seed cake proved to be worth $41.50 per ton. Lots 1-7. VI. The substitution of hominy feed for corn when fed with alfalfa hay increased the daily gain per lamb .023 pound, in - creased the cost of 100 pounds of gain 25 cents, but increased the </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS profit one cent per head, due to the greater daily gain and the somewhat less food consumption. The daily ration in these two lots was 1.286 pounds of hominy feed and 1.08 pounds of alfalfa in lot 9 in comparison with 1.33 pounds of corn and 1 pound of alfalfa in lot 1. Figuring corn at 60 cents per bushel the hominy feed proved to be worth $25 per ton. Lots 1-9. VII. The addition of sliced sugar beets to a corn and al - falfa ration increased the daily gain slightly, namely, .029 pound, and decreased the cost of 100 pounds gain by the narrow margin of 8 cents, and increased the net profit per head by 14 cents. The beets were valued in this test at $4 per toil. Lots 1-10. VIII. A comparison of the open lot with the open sIhmI showed a considerably greater feed consumption in the open lot. a greater gain by .04 pound per day and a lower cost of 100 pounds gain by 7 cents. The net profit per head shows 21 cents in favor of the lambs fed in the open. Lots 1-11. IX. The use of the self-feeder gave a very heavy daily grain, namely. .501 pound for a 40-day period. The cost of gain was very high, however, being $7.34 per hundred or almost $2 per hundred higher than in any of the other lots. The net profit was consequently cut down to $1.45. This trial seemed to show that the self-feeder method w T as practical but not economical under ordinary conditions. Lots 1-8. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 17S b °°. •. » Unp ■■«■ *■.■»*; « » *" «S 5 l£t 3l 3 ~ I I 2 2 w 2 N ** csicc'^r «| bee "*"*l "* Sl«»l 2 I 2 1 2 S-2 -22 I Ssd SS 222 - 22 I 22 I 2* IS I SI SI S SSS^SES §355 I SS 85S 11 if i Igl 2 2 I » SSS HJS 2SS I S'd 223 £ "S 22 2 W SI S S|Sf:2|S5S S=S SS S£3 „• I 2 I gS g Is I 2 1 2 alssalsas sda gs S22 si gs I 23 2 5 I oi| "| - I IS I22S I 3SS I P25 I S§ 22SI.J I § I SS « -j jj -I a I »' I »'bo I bob I abb | no -j eg » | 2 | « -j | ej~ -j i «| si s sss £§; sel ss sl2 s» i is i s jo -|oo|oo«aeabb ti»a aa jj ■•• | mn | h Si i 3 I |j{i e| o| o|x»a iio| «*a «•« 2 = 2 I S go | 22 5 S"| M -i si si sisss sss sss I ss ses e - 1 1 si i s S'5 »l « «0 loose* &lt;x« x'ccx I ocx °&gt;2d i « •' I = »l a IS I 8 1 SI S 885 1583 1 283 I S2 SWM I 2= | £g g I jo | a&gt; I t- | t- f»i|iai| t^x'x t-^ao «d« t-' ) oc x | oca! a lo I «!| SI §185? SSSI SS5 I !SS SS5 1^ 8 83 1 P |Ji| a I o&gt;| o&gt; | t- x x oc a a I x x a ) x x a b « ] 2 o a a b | a j«~ I -I SI E SJ!2|§22| gS2 I 5§ I SgSS d | SS I S |» - « | t- | t- t-t-oo | t-«JM J t^^oo t^^: ab- 2 ojx oox x I !-^—. = — i , — , ~~ ** " 3 5j i I 5 I 1 ST~£ S SI5S 5£2 2SS £5 S = 2 SS §5 2 jo x I &lt;s • e-r-t- t-t-x r^t-t- t-t: a b - jj aV x'x oc r ~S i?~ j to © I « I oo I t- I © ttU}^&gt; • I • (-r-t- Sl S|2S§ 00 I Ok I t^t-^l&gt; Is! si II !I2^I355i *?53 ~~ ?"-NI *i sai g IJjl • I "I • I »-«•«- 1 00 » 00 I t-xoo I t-x xab|. ox I is I od I i I | ||ei| 3.1 ? £ 3SSI23S SS? I S2 ggS| d SI PS S S *" I " • • • f t- 1- 1- «[-i- «t-' x"ab|jj eit^l t^od © as ao a a &gt;aa« • | • i &lt;e&lt;ef S §1 81 g ISSS |S§5 I SSS I SP I S53 I SS I 2S I 2 jo t- \ &lt;s 1 «l««t. Icc-t-l ((f 1 «&lt;s I xao j^ I od« I t-:^ I r^ Id I 5 1 SI 2ISSS|SSS| SS5 I gj I SSS „• S| SSI S |«J t- I t- I oo |&gt;a»&lt;e I vvf I «d^ | »» | S e&lt;e | t-V | S || w I -I S SI5SS SS3I 2S2 ES I £55 * "a I SSI S 3C o e&gt; 5 N»e t- ao I &lt;e I © a t-\ « &lt;oo&lt;£ i-l oo I ««« I S i — s SI SISSS to ] id I oioia ■a "|| s . I «| SISSSISSSI qgS I 32 I SSSI I g§| SS 5 i •* n n ««s. ■w io O •0 Ok to I lAlOtt J t 3 5 SJ355J 6EE ESS 58 E££ &amp;£ ' — ■ — ' 555 ttt '*"*&gt; 55- I I I I I «• i&lt; "l 1 I. ' I I I &lt;t ri &gt;: Jl i * I! i B I i B i 5 i -ft &gt;il K4i *M &gt;£* * B li XE '" SSS V « V iii M GO OT III] V h I I ■&lt; ! I 888 E E E 555 i guo | 1 I s 1 1 I J X I 13 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 5 i SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS LAMB FEEDING EXPERIMENT December 30, 1915, to March 14, 1916 By H. J. Gramlkh OBJECTS The objects of this experiment were to ascertain the most economical methods of fattening lambs with feeds at prices pre - vailing on Nebraska farms. The basic ration used in practically all lots was corn and alfalfa hay. To this the protein supple - ments, oil meal, cottonseed meal, and cold pressed cottonseed cake, were added to ascertain the efficiency of their use. Silage was added in one lot. In another instance sugar beets were added. !t was likewise desired to ascertain whether it was advisable to limit the coin to fattening lambs when on a corn and alfalfa ration. One lot was fed hominy feed and alfalfa hay. with the object in mind cf ascertaining whether hominy feed could be profitably substituted for corn. Many Nebraska feeders handle iambs without shed protection. One lot of lambs in this experi - ment was fed in the open to ascertain the value of a shed under central Nebraska conditions. The value of self-feeding was tested in another lot. DESCRIPTION OF THE LAMBS The lambs used in this experiment were of Wyoming origin, apparently a cross between one of the long-wooled breeds and :he Rambouillet. They were purchased in Omaha December 20, weighing at the time 59 pounds. The cost per hundred pounds ayed down at the University was $8.56. At the time the experi - ment opened the actual cost was #8.52 per hundred pounds, the ambs having been held one week on alfalfa and prairie hay before starting the experiment. RATIONS USED Lot I: Corn (heavy feed), alfalfa hay. Lot II: Corn (medium feed), alfalfa haw </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 178 Lot III: Corn (light feed), alfalfa hay. Lot IV: Corn, alfalfa hay, silage. Lot V : Corn, oil meal, alfalfa hay. Lot VI : Corn, cottonseed meal, alfalfa hay. Lot VII: Corn, cold pressed cottonseed cake, alfalfa hay. Lot VIII : Corn and oil meal in self-feeder, alfalfa hay. Lot IX : Hominy feed, alfalfa hay. Lot X : Corn, alfalfa hay, sugar beets. Lot XI: Corn, alfalfa hay. Fed in open lot FEED YARDS AND EQUIPMENT An old machine shed had been made over into an experimen - tal sheep feeding shed and was used the first time for this experi - ment. The building is open on the south and contains ten lots. The shed space in each lot amounts to 200 square feet and the EXPERIMENTAL SHED AND LOTS AT THE UNIVERSITY FARM open lot to the south gave an additional 300 square feet. There were 28 lamtis per lot, hence 7 square feet of shed space and W square feet of open space, or a total of 20 square feet for each lamb. The grain was fed in the open and the hay bunks kept under the shed. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 7 DURATION OF THE EXPERIMENT This was a 75-day experiment, commencing December 30, 1915, and continuing until March 14, 1916. Lot 8, the self-feeder group, was marketed at the end of 40 days PRICES OF FEEDS Owing to the tremendous variation in the price of all feeds. it is difficult to use figures which would be satisfactory for com- parison with those prevailing at any future time. The prices below are those actually prevailing at the time this test was made : Shelled corn 60 cents per bushel Hominy feed $25.00 per ton Oil meal 40.00 per ton Cottonseed meal 35.00 per ton Cold pressed cottonseed cake 29.00 per ton Alfalfa hay 8.50 per ton Sugar beets 4.00 per ton Corn silage 4.00 per ton DOES IT PAY TO LIMIT THE CORN IN A CORN AND ALFALFA RATIONI LOTS 1, 2 AND 3 Table 2 — Lots 1, 2 and 3 Lot number 12 3 Number of lambs in lot 28 28 28 Corn Corn Corn Ration (heavy (medium (light feed) feed) feed) Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Average initial weight, lbs 60.33 60.92 60.92 Average final weight, lbs 85.64 85.62 83.30 Average gain 25.31 24.70 22.38 Average daily gain .337 .329 .298 Average daily ration, pounds Corn „ 1.329 .857 .721 Alfalfa 1.007 1.642 1.662 Pounds feed required per pound gain Corn 3.943 2.604 2.419 Alfalfa _ 2.988 4.99 5.577 Dost of 100 pounds gain $5.53 $4.90 $4.94 initial cost per lamb $5.11 $5.16 $5.16 Zoet of feed per lamb 1.40 1.21 1.10 .nterest at 6% for 75 days .06 .06 .06 3oet of marketing .19 .19 .19 Total cost per lamb 6.76 6.62 6.51 Receipts per lamb @ $11.10 per 100 pounds, Omaha $8.89 $8.89 $8.63 &lt;Jet profit per lamb $2.13 $2.27 $2.12 « -Tuitritive ratio 1:6.6 1:5.4 1:5.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 173 8 Owing to the fact that in Nebraska alfalfa is often very cheap and corn relatively high in price, we find many feeders inquiring as Jo the advisability of using a limited ration of corn in fatten - ing lambs. To ascertain. the advisability of this practice lots 1, 2 and 3 were fed as follows: Lot 1, corn (heavy feed), alfalfa hay; lot 2, corn (medium feed), alfalfa hay; lot 3, corn (light feed), alfalfa hay. The lambs in these three lots were all started on a limited quantity of corn, it being increased more rapidly in lot 1 than in lot 2, and again more rapidly in lot 2 than in lot 3. The plan with lot 1 was to have the lambs up to a full feed within 30 days from the time the test started and to allow them all of the corn they wished from then on. In lot 2 the plan was to work the lambs up to .5 pound per day at the end of 30 days and then to increase them gradually to 1 pound per day at the LOT 1— CORN (HEAVY FEED). AND ALFALFA Lambs in this lot made a greater gain than those fed a medium feed of corn (lot 2) or a light feed of corn (lot 8). However, their gains were the most expensive of the three end of 60 days, and to hold them at an amount close to this for the remainder of the test, allowing them practically all of the corn they wished the last week. Lot 3 was started on a light feed of corn, and at the end of two months they were getting .75 pound per day. They were then gradually increased until at the close they were receiving 1 pound per day. In addition all three lots had alfalfa hay before them at will. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SUPPLEMENTARY KEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 9 By referring to the average daily ration consumed we find that lot 1 consumed 1.33 pounds of corn, with lot 2 taking .86 pound and lot 3, .72 pound. As regards alfalfa, we find lot 1 sat - isfied with 1 pound per day, whereas lot 2 took 1.61 pounds, and lot 3, 1.66 pounds, indicating the greater consumption of hay in the lots with the reduced corn ration. By adding together the amounts of corn and alfalfa we find that the total feed consumed per day in lot 1 is 2.33 pounds, in lot 2, 2.5 pounds and in lot 3, 2.4 pounds. Hence we find practically the same total feed consumption in each lot. By referring to the average daily gain, we find that lot 1 gained practically .34 pound per day. lot 2, .33 pound and lot 3, .3 pound. In other words, we get very little dif - ference in the rate of gain between the three lots, altho there is &lt;jmte a difference in the amount of corn consumed especially between lots 1 and 2. The figures that are of most importance in any feeding ex LOT 2— CORN (MEDIUM FEED), AND ALFALFA These lambs returned more profit than those fed a full feed of corn (lot 1) or light feed of corn (lot S). periment and especially in this one are those indicating the amount of feed required per one pound gain. In lot 1 we find the feed consumed per pound gain amounting to 3.94 pounds of corn and 2.988 pounds of alfalfa. In lot 2 the figure is 2.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 178 10 pounds of corn and 4.99 pounds of alfalfa ; and in lot 3, 2.42 pounds of corn and 5.58 pounds of alfalfa. These figures offer consid - erable opportunity for study. We find in comparing lots 1 and 2 that in the feed per 1 pound gain, 2 pounds of alfalfa in lot 2 re  - placed 1.34 pounds of corn in lot 1. By comparing lot 3 with lot 1 we find that 2.59 pounds of alfalfa replaced 1.52 pounds of corn. Judging by these figures it is very easy to see that the justifi - ability of limiting the corn ration depends entirely upon the price of the corn and alfalfa. With corn high and alfalfa cheap without any doubt one would be justified in limiting the corn. In comparing lot 1 with lot 2, we find that one pound of alfalfa saved .66 pound of corn and in comparing lots 1 and 3, we find that 1 pound of alfalfa saved slightly more corn. Hence, from the standpoint of feed per pound gain alone, it would seem that with alfalfa selling comparatively reasonably, there could be no doubt about the advisability of limiting the corn ration. There are times, however, when it is necessary to get a quick gain upon lambs and when the profit is somewhat dependent upon the length of time the lambs are in the feed lot, and under such con - ditions it is possible that the limiting of the corn might not be entirely justifiable. With corn and alfalfa at the prices used in this test, namely, 60 cents per bushel and $8 per ton respectively, we find the cost of putting on 100 pounds of gain to be $5.53 in lot 1, $4.90 in lot 2 and $4.94 in lot 3. This shows a material difference in favor of lots 2 and 3. The lambs were sold at $11.10 per 100 pounds and on this basis the net profit is in favor of lot 2, the actual fig - ures on this being $2.13 for lot 1, $2.27 for lot 2 and $2.12 for lot 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 11 DOES IT PAY TO ADD SILAGE TO A CORN AND ALFALFA RATION? LOTS 1 and 4. Table 3 — Lots 1 and U Lot number 1 4 Number of lambs in lot 28 28 Corn Corn Ration Alfalfa Alfalfa Silage Average initial weight 60.33 60.88 Average final weight 85.64 89.99 Average gain 25.31 29.11 Average daily gain 337 .388 Average daily ration, pcunt : Corn 1.329 1.241 Alfalfa 1.007 .681 Silage 1.525 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn 3.946 3.198 Alfalfa 2.988 1.592 Silage _ 3.93 Cost of 100 pounds gain $5.53 $4.95 Initial cost per lamb $5.11 $4.95 Cost of feed per lamb 1.40 1.44 Interest at 6% for 75 days .06 .06 Cost of marketing .19 .19 3.93 Total cost per lamb 6.76 6.85 Receipts per lamb @ $11.10 per 100 pounds, Omaha $8.89 $9.37 Net profit per lamb $2.13 $2.52 Nutritive ratio 1:6.6 1:7.8 In states where alfalfa grows in abundance we find quite a tendency for stock feeders to resort to this and corn as their sole ration in fattening animals, the contention being that such iVeds as silage require tco much labor to j&gt;ut up and do not show sufficient profit in the ration to justify their use. To secure data covering this lots 1 and 4 were fed, lot 1 receiving a heavy feed of corn with alfalfa hay. lot 4 receiving corn and alfalfa as in lot 1, together with a ration of corn silage which started at 2 pounds per day and was gradually reduced until at the close they were getting but .5 pound per day. The average daily ration was 1.33 pounds of corn in lot 2 in comparison with 1.24 pounds of corn in lot 4; 1 pound of alfalfa in lot 1 and .62 pound in lot 4, plus 1.53 pounds silage. The silage required to produce one pound gain in lot 4 amounted to 3.93 pounds. From the table it will be seen that «&lt;.93 pounds of silage took the place of .74 pounds of corn and </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 178 I I &gt; i 1.39 pounds of alfalfa hay, or a total of 2.13 pounds. Consider - ing that the silage used contained 70 per cent water we find the dry matter in the silage, actually amounting to 1.08 pounds, re - placing 2.13 pounds of corn and alfalfa, the dry matter of which would amount to 1.87 pounds. By referring to the cost of 100 pounds gain we find that with silage charged at $4 per ton, we have the cost in lot 4 $4.95 in comparison with a cost of $5.53 in lot 1. In other words, the gain cost in lot 4 was 58 cents per 100 pounds less than in lot 1. The profit on these two lots shows $2.13 in lot 1, in contrast to $2.52 in lot 4, or a margin in favor of lot 4 of 39 cents. LOT 4— CORN, SILAGE, AND ALFALFA Tho addition of 1.52 pounds of corn silage daily to a corn and alfalfa ration (lots 1 and 4) increased the daily gain, decreased the cost of producing 100 pounds gain and increased the profit per lamb materially. On the basis of this trial it would seem fair to assume that the addition of silage to a corn and alfalfa ration, with prices as they are in this test, is justifiable. If the corn price rises to such a point that the silage must be charged considerably higher and alfalfa hay remains constant in price, the above figures on cost and profit would quickly change. Leaving the price of alfalfa and corn constant, the price of silage could be raised to $8 per ton in this test and the profit in lot 4 would then be the same as that in lot 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 13 By comparing lot 4 with lot 2, which was fed a limited corn ration with alfalfa hay we find that the profit is somewhat less in favor of silage, namely, only 25 cents, altho the cost of 100 pounds gain is practically the same. DOES IT PAY TO ADD A PROTEIN SUPPLEMENT TO A CORN AND ALFALFA RATION I Table 4 — Lots 1, 5, 6 mid 7 Eot number 1 5 6 Number of lambs in lot 28 28 28 28 Corn Corn Corn Corn Ration Alfalfa Oil meal Cotton- Cotton- Alfalfa seed meal seed cake Alfalfa Alfalfa Average initial weight 60.33 61.31 59.73 59.06 Average final weight 85.64 91.86 92.52 91.31 Average gain 25.31 30.55 ' 32.79 32.25 Average daily gain .337 .407 .437 .4:'. Average daily ration, pounds Corn 1.329 1.219 1.293 1.221 Oil meal .218 Cottonseed meal .226 Cottonseed cake Cottonseed cake .322 Alfalfa 1.007 1.078 1.071 Alfalfa - 1.007 1.078 1.071 1.0:55 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn 3.943 2.995 2.958 2.839 junds feed per pound gain Corn 3.943 2.995 2.958 Oil meal .535 Cottonseed meal .517 Cottonseed cake .748 Alfalfa 2.988 2.648 2.45 2.406 Cost of 100 pounds gain $5.53 $5.43 $5.15 $5.18 Initial cost per lamb $5.11 $5.19 $5.06 $5.00 Cost of feed per lamb 1.40 1.66 1.69 1.67 Interest at 6% for 75 days.... .06 .06 .06 .06 Cost of marketing 19 .19 .19 .19 Total cost per lamb 6.76 7.10 7.00 6.92 Receipts per lamb @ $10.10 per 100, Omaha $8.89 $9.58 $9.65 $9.52 Net profit per lamb $2.13 $2.48 $2.65 $2.60 Nut'itive ratio 1:6.6 1:5.3 1:5 1:5.4 With corn very high in price there is considerable question as to whether a corn and alfalfa ration can be improved by the addition of a protein supplement, the thought being that the pro- tein supplement would increase the daily gain, tend to economize the ration and increase the finish carried by the lambs. With the plan in mind of ascertaining the advisability of adding a protein supplement to a corn and alfalfa ration, and at the same time comparing the three most common supplements, namely, oil meal, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 173 cottonseed meal, and cold pressed cottonseed cake, this experi ment was planned. In comparing these four lots the plan was tc keep them all on full feed from the close of the' first month. Tht lots receiving the protein supplement were to receive in additior to their corn approximately .2 pound per day of oil meal anc cottonseed meal and .33 pound per day of the cottonseed cake In addition to the amounts of the protein supplements men tioned, the corn in each instance was to be practically the ful amount which they would clean up. As a result of adding tin LOT 6— CORN, COTTONSEED MEAL. AND ALFALFA The addition of .23 pound of cottonseed meal daily to a corn and alfalfa ration it creased the daily gain .10 pound, reduced the cost of 100 pound* gain by S8 cents ar increased the profit per lamb 52 cents. This lot gained the most and made the great* profit of any in the experiment. concentrates we find the average daily ration in comparison wit; lot 1 which was fed on corn and alfalfa alone to run considei ably higher. For instance, lot 1 consumed daily 1.33 pounds o corn, whereas lot 5, receiving oil meal in addition to corn an - alfalfa, consumed 1.22 pounds of corn and .22 pound of oil mea or a total of 1.44 pounds of concentrated feed. Lot 6, receivin the cottonseed meal, consumed 1.29 pounds of corn and .23 pound, of cottonseed meal, or a total of 1.52 pounds; and lot 7, receivin the cold pressed cottonseed cake, consumed 1.22 pounds of corJ and .32 pound of cottonseed, or 1.54 pounds total. ThereforJ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 15 it will be seen that the addition of the protein supplement in- creased the grain consumption noting the alfalfa hay consumed in lot 1, 1.08 pounds in lot 5, pounds in lot 7. In other words, lots is approximately the same, protein supplements, it may be per day quite materially. In we find it to be an even pound 1.07 pounds in lot 6 and 1.04 the hay consumption in the four Hence, from the standpoint of said that they consistently in- creased the daily feed consumption of the lots in which they were fed. As regards the daily gain, we find it to be, in lot 1, .337 pound ; in lot 5, the oil meal lnnibs. .407 ; in lot 6, the cotton- M'ed meal lambs, .437 pound, and in lot 7, the cold pressed cottonseed cake lambs, .43 pound. In other words, the daily gain in the three lots re - ceiving the protein supplement shows to be markedly higher than that in lot 1. receiving no THE HIGHEST GAINING LAMB OF THE EXPERIMENT This lamb was in lot 6. He sained 49 pounds in 76 days. In the same lot the m lnn ldm0nt low raining lamb added but 21 pounds. supplement As to the feed per hundred pounds of gain which again is the real index of the worth of a ration, we find, in lot 1, 3.94 pounds of corn and 2.99 pounds of alfalfa required per pound of gain, whereas in lot 5, 3 pounds of corn, .535 pound of oil meal, and 2.65 pounds of alfalfa made one pound of gain. In other words, .535 pound of oil meal in lot 5 saved .94 pound of corn and .34 pound of alfalfa, in comparison with lot 1. The net profit per head in these two lots is $2.13 and $2.48 respectively. On the above basis $53 per ton could have been paid for the oil meal and the profit would still be as much per head as it is in lot 1.. By referring to lots 1 and 6, we find under the feed per pound of gain that .517 pound of cottonseed meal in lot 6 saved .98 pound of corn and .54 pound of alfalfa hay. This shows even a more marked saving in feed per pound gain than that secured </seg>
            <seg id="p016">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 17S 16 in lot 5 from the use of oil meal, and as a result we find the profit in lot 6 running higher, in fact the highest of any lot in the : experiment, namely, $2.65 in comparison with $2.13 in lot 1. On f this basis, we could have afforded to have paid $55 per ton for ; the cottonseed meal. ; The total amount of feed consumed per one pound gain ■ amounted to 5.92 pounds in lot 6, in comparison with 6.93 pounds in lot 1. Hence we see quite a marked saving in actual pounds of feed in this instance. The lambs in lot 6 carried a great deal i erf flesh and were the top pen of the experiment. They seemed to relish the cottonseed meal and possessed splendid appetites thruout the entire trial, as indicated by the daily feed con - sumption. The profit is based in lots ."&gt; and 6 on a price of $4(1 for oil meal and $35 for cottonseed. If we raise the price of the cotton - seed meal to $40 and put it on a par with the oil meal, we find the profit in lot 6 is $2.52 in comparison with $2.48 on the oil meal lambs, or there would still be a slight margin in favor of the cottonseed lambs. The meal used in feeding these lanitis was finely ground and of the 41 to 43 per cent protein grade. Cottonseed by-products usually available for stock feeding consist of the higher protein feed sold as meal, or nut cake ; and the so-called cold pressed cake which runs considerably lower in protein, and higher in ciude fiber, due to the presence of more hulls and lint, and somewhat lower in price. In lot 7 we have lambs which were fed upon corn and this so-called cold pressed cottonseed cake. By comparison with lot 1 we find that the addi - tion of .33 pound per day of the cold pressed cake caused the 1 lambs to eat .11 pound less corn per day and a shade more alfalfa, and increased the gain frcm .34 pound to .43 pound, or .09 pound. Tinder the feed per one pound gain, we find that .75 pound of cold pressed cottonseed cake saved 1.10 pounds of corn and .58 [tound of alfalfa hay. With corn and alfalfa at the prices men - tioned this cold pressed cottonseed cake returned a value of $41.50 per ton. By comparing lot 7 with lot 6, fed cottonseed meal, we find ' slightly less daily gain in the cold pressed cake lot, practically , the same daily feed consumption and the total amount of feed per one pound of gain to be 5.99 pounds in comparison with 5.92 1 pounds in lot 6. The profit is 5 cents per head less than in the i cottonseed meal lot. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 17 By referring to the cost of 100 pounds of gain in the 4 lots compared above we find the figures to be $5.53 in lot 1, $5.43 in lot 5, $5.15 in lot 6, and $5.18 in lot 7. In other words, the addition of the protein supplement in each of the three lots de - creased the cost of 100 pounds gain considerably, the most reduc - tion being in lot 6, where the cost of gain was 38 cents less than LOT 7— CORN. COTTONSEED CAKE, AND ALFALFA The addition of cold-pressed cottonseed cake to a corn and alfalfa ration increased the rate of daily Rain rather Uss than where cottonseed meal was added but somewhat jrreat?r than where linseed meal formed the supplement. in lot 1. In summing up from tlu&gt; figures given here it would seem that the addition of any one of the three protein supple - ments mentioned to a corn and alfalfa ration, with prices as they are in this test, would be justifiable as without fail the rate of daily gain was greatly increased and the net profit was in turn considerably greater. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 173 18 CAN HOMINY FEED BE SUBSTITUTED FOR CORN WHEX FED WITH ALFALFA HAY! Table 5 — Lots 1 and 9 Cot number _ — - 1 9 Number of lambs in lot. _ 28 28 Corn Hominy feed 9 Ration Alfalfa Alfalfa Average initial weight - 60.33 59.86 Average final weight 85.64 86.85 Average gain. 25.31 26.99 Averaee daily srain _ .337 .36 26.99 Average daily gain - .337 Average daily ration, pounds _ Corn 1.329 Corn Hominy feed _ 1.286 Alfalfa _ 1.007 1.083 1.286 Alfalfa Pound feed required per pound gain Corn „ _ 3.94 3.57 Hominy feed _ _ _ Alfalfa „ 2.988 3.008 Alfalfa Cost of 100 pounds gain. $5.53 $5.78 Initial cost per lamb $5.11 $5.07 Cost of feed per lamb _ 1.40 1.56 Interest at 6% for 75 days .06 .06 Cost of marketing .19 .19 Total cost per lamb 6.76 6.88 Receipts per lamb at $11.10 per 100, Omaha $8.89 $9.02 Net profit per lamb 2.13 2.14 Nutritive ratio of ration 1:6.6 1:6.9 During recent years there has been an ever increasing de- mand for corn products for human consumption. The milling of corn of necessity leaves considerable by-product which is not used for human food and which is therefore sold for stock feeding purposes. In the milling of corn for human use a by-product re- sults commonly called hominy feed. This consists in the main of the hull, the germ, and various other parts of the kernel. It is usually sold at a price per pound approximating that of corn. With a desire to ascertain whether this hominv feed could be </seg>
            <seg id="p019">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 19 I used as a complete substitute for corn in fattening lambs, lot C was compared with lot 1. The hominy in lot 9 was fed in similar amounts to the corn fed in lot 1. After the lambs were on a full feed, which was at the close of the first four week period, they were allowed all of the grain which they would consume. We tind the daily feed con - sumption to be 1.33 pounds of corn in lot 1 and one pound of alfalfa, and in lot 9. 1.29 pounds of hominy and 1.08 pounds of alfalfa. In other words, slightly less of the hom - iny ami slightly more of the alfalfa was consumed in lot 9. The daily gain was .337 pound in lot 1 and .36 pound in lot 9; hence, a slightly greater gain in lot 9. Under pounds THE HIGHEST GAINING LAMB IN LOT 4 This lamb added 42 pounds during the 75-day trial. His ration consisted of corn, silage and alfalfa. of feed consumed to produce one pound of gain, it will be noted that the lambs on the hominy feed consumed 3.57 pounds of hominy in contrast to 3.94 pounds of corn consumed in lot 1, or .37 pound less. As regards the alfalfa required we find .02 pound more in lot 9 than in lot 1. The price used for this hominy feed, in ascertaining the cost of gain and profit per lamb was $2.") per ton in contrast to a price of 60 cents per bushel, or practically $21 per ton for corn. With these prices we find the cost per 100 pounds of gain in lot 1 to be $5.53 and in lot 9, which was fed the hominy, to be $5.78, and the profit was practically the same, or to be more exact, 1 cent more in the case of the hominy lambs. If the hominy were to be charged at the same price as the corn, which is the market condition usually existing, we would have the net profit in lot 9 at $2.78. From this it may be seen that if the hominy and the corn were to be charged at the same price, there would be quite a difference in favor of the hominy. The lambs in lot 9 seemed to relish their feed and there were no in - stances of sickness of any kind during the trial. They carried considerable flesh at the close of the test. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 178 20 DOES IT PAY TO ADD SLICED SUGAR BEETS TO A CORN AND ALFALFA RATION! Table 6— Lots 1 and 10 Lot number 1 10 Number in lot ! 28 28 Corn Corn Ration Alfalfa Alfalfa Sugar baets Average initial weight ■ 60.33 59.99 59.99 Average final weight 85.64 87.44 Average gain 25.31 27.45 Average daily gain .337 .366 Average daily ration, pounds Corn 1.329 1.261 Alfalfa 1.007 .956 Sugar beets 1 -C91 Pounds feed required per pound gain Corn 3.94 3.445 Alfalfa 2.988 2.61 Sugar beets , 2.08 Cost of 100 pounds gain $5.53 .$5.45 Initial cost per lamb $5.11 S5.08 Cost of feed per lamb 1.40 1.49 Interest at 6% for 75 days .06 .03 Cost of marketing , .19 .19 Total cost per lamb 6.76 fi.82 Receipts per lamb at $11.10 per 100, Omaha 8.89 9.09 Net profit per lamb 2.13 2 27 Nutritive ratio of ration 1:6.6 1:6.8 Most seasons the average farmer has a small patch of root crops which he plans on feeding to live stock. In order to ascer- tain whether the feeding of one of these root crops in eon junction with corn and alfalfa was justifiable, sliced sugar lieets were added to the ration of lot 10. By comparing with lot 1 we find that the addition of 1.09 pounds of sugar beets increased the daily gain .03 pound. The daily corn consumed in making this gain was. in lot 10, .07 pound less than in lot 1 and the alfalfa con- sumed .05 pound less. To produce one pound of gain the addi- tion of 2.98 pounds of beets saved .5 pound of corn and .38 pound of alfalfa hay. Charging the beets at $4 per ton. the cost of 100 pounds gain is 8 cents less where the beets were fed than where not. and the profit per lamb is 14 cents per head more. On the basis of these figures the beets actually returned a value of $4.95 per ton. There is not sufficient margin in these figures to indicate any marked advantage from the feeding of the beets. Owing to the labor involved in the production of beets together with the extra labor in storing and preparing them to feed to </seg>
            <seg id="p021">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS 21 stock, it is doubtful if one would be justified in feeding them on a very extensive scale, judging by results indicated here. DOES A SHED PAY? Table 7 — Lots 1 and 11 Shed Open lx&gt;t Lot number 1 11 Vumber in lot 28 28 Corn Corn Ration Alfalfa Alfalfa Average initial weight 6O.:i:! G1.61 Vverage final weight 85.64 89.91 \verage gain , 25.31 28.30 Vverage daily gain .337 .377 Vverage daily ration, pounds Corn 1.329 1.487 Alfalfa 1.007 1.074 'ounds feed required per pound gain Corn 3.94 3.94 Alfalfa 2.988 2.848 :ost of 100 pounds gain. _ _ $5.53 $5.46 nitial cost per lamb. $5.11 $5.22 lost of feed per lamb _ 1.40 1.55 nterest at 6% for 75 days 06 .06 larketing cost 19 .19 otal cost per lamb 6.76 7.02 leceipts per lamb at $11.10 per 100, Omaha $8.89 $9.36 let profit per lamb 2.13 2.34 futritive ratio of ration 1:6.6 1:6.8 Owing to the fact that in most parts of Nebraska we have datively dry winters and what moisture we get comes in the jrm of dry snows, most sheep feeders feel that it is not neces- iry that a covered shed be provided for fattening lambs, altho iany in the southeastern corner of the state in the territory trib- vtary to Lincoln plan on having an open shed accessible to the imbs. Lot 11 in this trial was fed in an open lot with no shelter Ither than a board windbreak, in comparison to lot 1 which had kcess to 7 square feet of shed space per lamb as well as ample &gt;en lot space. Both lots received shelled corn and alfalfa hay, ie corn being full fed after the close of the first month. Inasmuch as weather conditions naturally affect a test of this ind materially, a brief review of the weather during this 75-day iiriod which extended thruout the winter season would not be £it of place. The second day after the experiment opened we \d a rather unusual winter rain. This extended over a period </seg>
            <seg id="p022">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 173 22 ] I t I [ r s &gt; i 1 f :» a ■ i |: of some 14 hours and amounted in all to one inch of precipiia - tion. Following this a cold spell occurred and thruout the re - mainder of the trial alternating moderate and severe weather, with considerable snow, altho not an excessive amount. Just be - fore the close of the trial a rain of one-half inch occurred. How - ever, it did not turn cold following this and the lambs did not seem to suffer. In comparing these two lots, we find the amount of feed con - sumed to be considerably greater in the case of the lambs fed outdoors, they consuming 1.49 pounds of corn in comparison with 1.33 pounds in lot 1, and at the same time consuming 1.07 pounds of alfalfa in comparison with one pound of alfalfa in lot 1. In other words, these lambs fed outdoors apparently had better appetites and consumed more feed, as indicated by the fact that their total feed consumption amounted to .23 pound per day more than those in lot 1. The rate of daily gain is likewise greater in the lambs fed in the open, it being .377 pound in contrast to .337 pound in lot 1. The feed per one pound of gain is found to be very similar; in fact, the corn requirement is identical, 3,94 pounds, while the alfalfa required is .14 pound less in the case of the lambs outdoors. The cost of gain on the two lots is slightly less in the instance of the lambs in the shed fed lambs. The net profit per lamb is likewise greater in the lambs fed outdoors, being $2.34 in comparison with $2.13 where the lambs were shed fed. These figures seem to indicate that the use of the shed was not entirely justifiable, at least not necessary in such a winter as the one during which this trial was made. I Temperatures were taken regularly and it was found that the temperature in the open shed was practically the same as that out of doors, being in several instances two degrees warmer. On the other hand, on days when the sun was shining it was found that the temperature was generally 2 to 3 degrees higher on the south side of the windbreak in the open lot than it was under the shed where lot 1 was being fed. From this trial it would seem that under conditions such as we have, the shed may not be entirely necessary other than for conscientious reasons. Many feeders prefer to know that in case of a bad storm all of their animals can seek the protection of a shed if they wish. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">SUPPLEMENTARY FEEDS IN FATTENING LAMBS THE SELF-FEEDING OF LAMBS Table 8 — Lots l and 8 Lot number 1 5 8 dumber in lot 28 28 28 Ration Alfalfa Alfalfa Oilmeal ) ., . , Corn Corn Corn I sell-le.l Prairie hay \verage initial weight 60.3:? 61.31 61.61 \verage final weight 85.64 91.86 82.01 Average gain 25.31 30.55 20.05 Average daily gain .337 .407 .50 Average daily ration, pounds Corn 1.329 1.219 1.326 Oil meal 1-047 Alfalfa , 1.007 1.078 Prairie hay .363 Pounds feed required per pound .rain Corn 3.94 2.995 2.645 Oil meal 2.088 Alfalfa 2.988 2.648 Prairie hay .724 Feed cost per 100 pounds gain. $5.53 $5.43 $7.34 Initial cost per lamb $5.11 $5.19 $5,248 lost of feed per lamb 1.40 1.66 1.47 Interest at 6% for 75 days 06 .06 .035 Marketing cost per lamb 6.76 7.10 • Total cost per lamb 6.76 7.10 6.75 ** Receipts per lamb at $11.10 per 100, Omaha $8.89 $9.58 $8.20 Selling price per 100, Omaha $11.10 $11.10 $10.00 Met profit per lamb $2.13 $2.48 $1.45 Nutritive ratio of ration 1:6.6 1: 1: "These lambs were marketed at the end of 40 days. ••These lambs were marketed at home ; hence no charges. Many extensive feeders follow a practice of feeding corn and )il meal mixed in a self-feeder and allowing the lambs prairie lay at will. The advantages of this method of feeding are that he lambs can be quickly put upon a full feed and as a result, ;an be marketed following a very short feeding period. The plan followed in getting the lambs on full feed is out- ined below : The bunks are filled with pea-size oil meal and the ambs allowed free access to them. They will usually consume ' to 2.5 pounds per head the first day. The second day a few rernels of corn are scattered thru the oil meal and each ncceeding day the corn is increased until at the end of 5 to 8 lays the lambs are getting practically all of the corn they wish ogether with considerable oil meal. At the end of two weeks he mixture placed in the bunks consists of four parts of corn </seg>
            <seg id="p024">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 173 24 and one part of oil meal, and the average lamb will take in the neighborhood of 1.75 pounds of corn and about .5 pound of oil meal. The hay consumed is negligible, usually running about .33 pound daily. To ascertain the advisability and economy of the above method of feeding, lot 8 in this trial was fed practically as indicated above. The lambs in this lot were marketed at the end of 40 days, owing to their high degree of condition at that time. By comparing these lambs with those in lot 1, fed on straight corn and alfalfa in the usual manner, and with those in lot 5, fed on corn and oil meal together with alfalfa hay, we find a consider - ably greater daily gain in these self-feeder lambs, their gain being slightly over .5 pound. We find a daily feed consumption of 1.33 jounds of corn. 1.05 pounds of oil meal and .35 pound of prairie hay. showing that the hay consumption is very low in contrast to that consumed in the other two lots and the oil meal con - sumption runs very high. The feed required to produce one pound of gain is shown to be 2.65 pounds of corn, 2.09 pounds of oil meal and .72 pound of prairie hay, a total of 5.46 pounds, which contains a considerably higher percentage of grain con - centrate than was consumed in lot 1 or lot 5. The proportion of grain and concentrate to hay in these three lots is of interest In the self-feeder lot, 6.6 pounds of grain were consumed to each pound of hay. In lot 1, 1.32 pounds of grain to each pound of hay, and in lot 5, 1.33 pounds of grain to one pound of hay. The cost of 100 pounds of gain under this method of feeding was found to be $7.34 which is almost $2 per hundred higher than that of any of the other lots fed in this experiment. The profit is as a result somewhat less, being but $1.45. From this trial it will be seen that while the above method has an advantage in the fattening of the lambs quickly, it is not as economical as the other methods of feeding outlined and it is not to be recommended un - less a man is desirous of putting a high degree of finish upon his lambs in a very short time. Subsequent trials to the one given here and the experience of practical feeders has shown that the lambs fed in this manner for a period exceeding 50 days are subject to sudden death possibly from apoplexy due to the exceed - ingly large amount of protein in their ration. In this trial there was no sickness and no lambs went off feed and the 28 head at the close of the test were carrying a uniformly high degree of finish. [8 M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>