<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00031">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00031</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">&lt; &gt;F T11K rBRABKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE Vi:ar 1OO8 I'KKl'ARED BY S. C. BASSETT, SKcwmin- Nebraska Dairymen's Association YORK BLANK BOOK CO.Primfks </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Governor of Nebraska v in this case made ami provided of the Nebraska Dairymen's Asso- You fully </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">5 r X i I } \ ' I :: K. A. rilmann Production of Sanitary .Milk — Dr. (iti -W. Righter Wood Farm and Winter Dairying — A. E \. Poynter the Further Development of the Dairy hnson Mluction — Prof. W. J. Fraser reiving Station ('. S. B Kay Wm. Thompson I Economic Milk Production — Prof. A. L mmissioner to the Station Operator § Prof. E. M. Little </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">ker. Lincoln A E. T Omaha ( Lincoln O m all a shland Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">- a lit -I </seg>
          
            <seg id="p010">\ 9 i ist or mi:mi!i:i:s. Honorary I i I • ■ MiiiiIhi-. Micnel Micnetka Sew lliimpto New Hampton, i Fort At kin Pint Atkinsu I I .). X« I. hi- Miiuliei-.. I. ilr Mi'inlH'r ibbon \. I k A: Water Sis . Chi. , liibboi . Omaha Gibbon . Yorl Port Dodi Chi A: Cibbon Omaha '.ihhiiii York Sultim Cililxm \ Waterloo, N '.cc Building, Omaha, X Gibbon, N Beaver Crossii Germantown. St:iiioii H. Omaha, Station I&gt;. Omab Vll.ion. Nebr n \. Lincoln l.in.oli: mt Cry. Co., Cnia: Lincoln. N Omaha. N York. N niverslty, Lincoln. Suttoti Omaha Fairmont. Nebi Linioli \- 1 (Jibbon, Nfl&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p011">1( Sutton ■. \V. Stev, . Vaughn . WhiliiK !1. If. WiiiK \.l \i \\ \ Kl. Clin. ; Carte ■ ■ H. Con, nk Col« onley i Cole IN. Conklin Cannelly . ('(M)kSi('V 7. II. Chittenden </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 Holbrook. Nebr . Dunning. Nebr Holdrege, Nebr Superior. Nebr Lincoln Nebr Auburn. Nebr Lincoln. Nebr N :;::r St (ier Tecumseh. NVbr port, Nebr I, Lincoln. NVbr Br ska Dairyn .in. Primrose, NVbr Scribner. NVbr Havelork. Nebr ilavelock, Nfbr -&lt;ip. Crefl liu'iv . i l.imulii. N.-ln Lincoln, Nebr ii ral City. Nfbr ;]&gt;■&gt;■. Nfbr line", N"l uide ltork iiuci Island, Nfht Howella, N Wayne, N Stair Farm, Lincoln. N Hildreth. N th Omaha. Nebr t Ashton. Nflir V.rk. N rossinn. Nfbr IJttU'ton Cry Co., Denver. Colt t. Joseph. Mo lleulah. Wyu. 1'awnee City, NVbr Courtlanl. NVbr Comstock, Nfbr Pawnee &lt; sty. Nfbr N 12 St, Lincoln. N-br Keitublican City, Nfbr I 'aw nee City. Nebr Lincoln, N.-br </seg>
            <seg id="p013">l«l I ■ n / v iry K \ K. k ,. Robt UcRinni 1. \li Kh C. H. Mullii l. Holms I. 1 lolli.ii •". Hansi n Inlhin }' II. Lot) I. &lt;&gt;f!!l T McGrie \ M.M-rill </seg>
            <seg id="p014">NVENTION 1 Xebr Maxwell. Nebr Omaha. [ n I 1! • Creamer Carrol. Nebr Lincoln. Nebr. Kearney. Riverton. Nebr. Masti: Walnut. Nebr mlii Creami n. ( U. F 1». N Bcmot Oxfor &lt; inJ. Xebr Stdnej \rradia Cri-tt Duniphi.n. Omaha Atlanta Omaha, Omaha Cold 8( Powell Carroll Lincoln Terumseh Creami !n Be&amp;tri&lt; Mullen lirmoni Omaha. Nebr Normal, Nebr Beatrice Cry Co.. Lincoln. Nebr Security Mutual Building. Lincoln. Nebr Bos 715, Lincoln. Nebr Stanton. Nebr liolchow. Mo Carroll. Nebr Risins City. ! ran 1 Island. Nebr 7 1 ."&gt; . Lincoln. Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Ralph Saul M. M ateraa Kay Stepbeaaon A s. lilicklieiml &lt;&gt; A S#V( tSrhoberl . Selling A. Studl. Frank 17 O. .! 11 T. w S i ?. ; K. Von oh anakiver I. 1' Vog C. Van Tim I. Weber. anl Witt . IVagnei :. Wood. Wri s t,t Wliitino B. e. w I. \v Weber Otto E. \Vern </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Lincoln, Nebr. Hill, Nebr. Belvideie, Nebr. Lincoln, Nebr. 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">, ,, . riii 2AIV1A ki iltlli How to 1 Ik -n-iisi- Milk Relation of tin- I): \\ IVIY-I Ol KTil l\\l \l MIIIIM. (»| TOI \MW;V-lv\ &gt;\IIC^ M AVs \&gt;«,«»( I \ | |()\ i\ i'&lt;li!4*s&lt;lu) . Jaiwj The ("itv rkalr </seg>
            <seg id="p018">I riiliM . Janaarjr Station Clark S. B ,iry American Assik iation [Ctmubm7 Batter Mi P. M. E W. Frost. Superim- Prof. K. M. Little W. Frost. Superintend**! tin k pavilion, a milking ■nt in the live stock pavilion. ■ milking practical operation by those in attenda*r« rat bv in attendant-* a tii n IDGINO CONTEST Regulations association Mlj it ion onl .ill lie (lividcil anioiif; UMMC sioriii- 1 lie divided nmi &lt;■ Inn points, in proportion to the mini lim poiBta, in proportion to the nuinli*-r n( idfd that of the pro rata fund no contest- led that of tbe pro rata fund no ronteat- o ie sum of $ 1 (i. mi. t ie (.11 Friday, January JJ I 1' M n Friday, ,lannar&gt; 1' M l. ssoi iation is invited to take part in t hi: to take part in K AM) CHEESE EXHIBIT inry 20-22. 1!" ndent, Experiment Station. Lincoln. X&lt; nt. Experlmeal Station. Lincoln. N- R«Kulationa tion only: any one ma nt of am lal nieinbersln • F :r J Prnn Sid Pirn Aih Pmn ■ni £ ) .00 |3.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN Df pro rata premium! n i Whole milk hottlps ;m.: viva . \\ rr N \ A ninl For ureni the liutter. milk or BASS Cre 811 ery exhibit than 20-pound pack. inv M in. (trie of dsi k r1*&gt;:tW&gt;r u- All Davilion at the Ei Krimrnt Station, I.inrolt For programs or nth iutr addrt-ss </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
    
            <seg id="p021">19 IMI VKItltASKA DAIltYMEVS \SS«M IATION A M. by President Wilkinson. follon Or PKKSIDKNT he t-'tutr Dairy Association n of the honor and with pleasure that I inual meeting of this association in Sanitation in developing the dairy with admiration for the members with but one aim — to put Nebraska r fille and I congratulate you on the suc- mery butter manufactured in Nebraska breaks all records as it exceeded thirty - total value to the producer was between ollars. In view of the fact that quite a is only partially settled; that the majority ting dairying as a side line; that a: y a beef strain of cattle; and that our ural advantages in its fertile soil, mild I. it is only reasonable for us to if our state is still in its infancy. tates, has passed through a creamery- untold failures, but has finally adopted a ted to our conditions and most profitable to e hand separator and the centralized cream - umber of local creameries are being operated nislies by far the greater number of corn- ream. I feel justified in saying that the uited to Nebraska's conditions as a he wonderful increase made during the in lpally it has eliminated practically all le other creamery systems that were objectionable which resulted in failures. ■ This system has invited unlimited competition and in many ways shifted the farmers' burden to the creamervmpn whiio ««»,«« of trade, it undoubtedly is responsible for many abuses nto ■amery business, and these should be l\(,&gt;&gt; &lt;&gt;l THK TWKMV-KllliTH AXMAI. MKKTI\&lt;; &lt;&gt;!•' mers' burden to the creamery men. While compe- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">I feel that it is neither advi 20 20 NEBRASKA DA1RY.MK.VS ASSOCIA fn is vitally inn mery work of Nebraska pr of Hip lushest quality, l&gt;r in? the produi er. We dncer or ami eronomii al iiiici Injuring an injur X and il,. and tin and in, pro.li 11 careful, ski 1 If 1 Our interest in tlu milk receiving station, whirl and sanitary place for &lt; man; ream or i i tamina • ■ry. w the importance of good highest standard of that will afford the 1 ! this we have largely disi t I'oiiMiiniption and sat Our interests arc not only In to: industry but in their protection US V I feel that they are inadequate to properly handle the situation of t day. The appropriation the present law provides is inanfficiel port a dairy &lt; ommissiciiier and necessary to give the dairy and deserves, and which is warrrantc the producing people of our state nspei tors creamery Indus :1 by the enormo the iini'ortnn I. thereby ducpr an I secure foi clu&lt; ts iii the markets throuplinu by furnishing pure, wbolesonu is necessary to realize the great&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p023">r one head, handle ukl be divorced from tlK with it an appropriatioi nt. a dairy coniniissione ile duty should be to look lone in other tlize the importance of such ttention to the oleo in r ' nal laws that place a tax upon ill as an imitation of pure butter. If tremendous loss and an tlce in allowing the olet ipon the market in dire t compe- uv material of which does not aid for butter fat. In my margarine to be artificially colored in 1 upon the market and sold for what t the dairy farmers against fraud and tec t the consumer, as oleomargarine could. worth and the consumer would not b r for this art ntion to the im D made by our n our dairy tier's. Some of the nances prohibiting the sale of butter that nty that the cream from which the urized or is the product froir n test. It is gratifying to say that nitter made in Nebraska dur- nanufac tured from pasteurized cream; ssiveness of the creamery and dairy in- itt lutions place this organ- mii encour he pasteurizing of all of (-reamer utter in Nebraska, to con- *ill b tel for the purpose of meet- ment pointment of a Legislative Com- bers. with instructions to wait upon our now in session, urging the necessary re. sent laws, the enactment of n w laws that are reiuired, ppropiiatlon to maintain and support a dairy th Inspectors; that this committee be further instructed jii with the National Dairy Union to combat the lishoiif oleomargarine in competition with pure nder the National Dairy I'nion all possible assistance and mi sec iir.- by voluntary contribution irom our mem- |1 1 1 1 1 Fl i \ f PI li t\ i | \ I g t #■ g\ t\ it 1 I t fll/l ' 1 1 I l t t*^ n 9 s\ i i </seg>
            <seg id="p024">\ n our national le^islatu to protect the in ten ■ dishonest sale of oieomargari It is very important thai our dairy industry. our hearty support. We cannot expert t plish successful found anywhi young men to tin iiiikIi to the futur .1 that ti rid use our hfsi since t he adven reaii) reeeivin territory, have Ik it. To tin addition to other vain of dialing directly with tl right direction and tli the Kim." We hope tin ndan cient to show that they and tin &gt;ur efforts in their helm cation that can be derix 1 hope this meet ins will p rand influence of this orpanizatior meeting, but that the officers and Bter activity in promoting our printi neet in our next annual oonventioi Nebraska will have maintained its i t and that the volume of l!Hi'i u; standard of our creamery batter he r l&gt;artm»'iits. We have cm. -iiized authorities, iiperintendt'iii sut&gt;jf&lt; ts pertaining to feel proud of our achievements arrompl </seg>
            <seg id="p025">read my report as treasurer. As many of he work of the association, the financial Ire from the state each year $U" m iation. anil out of the $H&gt;' tnnoal reports that you see here, shall be printed. I have here the item - the expenditure* of everj item together Nebraska Dairymen's Association 1 ns;i&lt; lions of the association S. C. BA88ETT, T UKCKII'TS $ 6 fee, M. Dab 152.40 ition $10 1 I r.3 x I 4 .21 tel expense annual meeting. 1 expenses as Suj.t an apt. Tow Judging Contest. . . ittle. services in connection with Vanf'elt. expense to deliver an aili I I'oKl &lt;&gt;| SKCKKTAKY \M» TKKASl HKIt. ■tea to the report of our Secretary Itpport &lt;if TrcaMiivi EXPENDITURES </seg>
            <seg id="p026">24 uinary -'■&gt;. ]&gt;aid Adolph Ki .1 \V. Hi iiiary ul'. Win. Kirki anuary 22, K. 1). Reei. staiioj try lanuary 29. laid IJ. A A H\\ uaiy iirv rv 1 ary 29, i January 29, paid Charli 1 uniai January 29, paid John &lt; January 29, paid Mai-tin Hal January -'It. paid L&lt; January -".&lt;. paid I). E. Hanson, prt l January 29, paid Karl Harv January 29, paid H. F. Hammoi January 2'J, paid C. II. Hurt, i .1 inuary 29, paid Hoy llamn i January 29, paid Elmer K. .1 lanuary 29, paid John A. .1 January 29, paid II. C. Jolinsor J inuary l'H, paid And </seg>
            <seg id="p027">I .60 4" 10 1.80 1.20 I u »&lt; 1.20 (« 1.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOC1A Kary 29, paid Ralph Paul, p ary 2t, paid Geo. Thomas Eary l'!i. paid B. IS. TieU, pr ary HO. paid Roy I'hl. pren ary 28, paid K. I) Vanderlj January February February February H A I E February r. nt. si A February K I. it February 1 , . paid ( February 17, paid R. A. St. John, envelopi February 17. paid I A Kirk x May i' , . paid K. II stationc June L'J. paid Ciirnell En raving September 1, paid R. A. St. John. (' M . postage stami Kary 2», p ary S», I January = lary I 7. paid Hem and &lt; o-(i| April is. paid S. C. Ii.-iss.Mt. salary April 18. 8. C. Bassett. exp&lt; .lune K, paid Exprei </seg>
            <seg id="p029">x itampa tar tin in stain i mil move that this report an.l all ac - n auditing committee of three Miuuittee to report during the &gt;tion carrit I'KOKITS OK I \ISM CHKKSi: M.\K1X&lt; a n n K into ■ dairy state, autl it is quite 11 ke anywhere else are anxious to k of their cows. The condition in this ared with conditions that existed yet there is still much room for further f giving the farmers the oppor- mean aoney for their milk, seems to be cheese the possibilities of cheese as a ie are produced in the iint uter (juantities are consumed, because mported from the Old Country. Nebraska among some other states is not a strong cheese producing state. onsumer. We find in the stores ii n. Michigan. New York and other states. And ini • we know. that, for example, the Wisconsin farmer, buys alfalfa and corn from the Nebraska farmer, turns it into milk from which he beese is produced just to be shipped back to Nebraska again, the iiuestion arises — would it not be profitable for the Nebraska farmer o partake in the supplying of cheese for the local market. At present Ik is used for buttermaking purposes, the butter being </seg>
            <seg id="p030">28 \s \ the above question we have to making with the returns from n selling crean am to I'onsirii For our Riving 1,718 II Bes butti e for tl per ci-nt worth for tl that m&lt; Val From tlii and marketing Y ■ that the 10 hoi The churning wi ■ hours what would mom 10 dollar too low. So thai we have n&lt; Separating Churning Marketing Tot a And Valae of butter and skim milk Cost of production and marketing Net Hut if we assume that our f; town and he has to sell his but in such a case he would set for his butter $99.71 nd the net returns would be only 1354.80 From selling his 17 Hi lbs of butter fat to a creamery his net returns would be as follows: In bulletin KM. Pr&lt; the average price of 1 poun 1 of butter fat at .2 cents. At this made either on the fartni </seg>
            <seg id="p031">kt't. we may put the price also would h;&lt; 6 lbs. on at least f and the caring for day would in in the year, at 1 "i cents the larketlng of the cheese would be take In conslderattoa that it making and raring room, and ney invested and the cost of that we would have 121.50 30.00 191.50 v 711.00 •1 of manufacturing </seg>
            <seg id="p032">AT So that we set- that the fan jf milk testing Mit fat po Selling butter for 20 cents Selling rrrwi for 22c ■ pool Making ' \\ Hut we liav sider it a paying for doing ■ Nebraska Dairymen's As be overcome and ho« i braska farmer .lust a few w&lt; Ottage cheese, or to call it. We all k maybe, ther by telling you on the Station As you km separated or skim milk. P sell all superfluous skim mi for LMI cents a hundred But is offset by the remain ing wl up in one pound packages, and these boxi So that the net price for a pound of that would make for 16 pounds milk $1.4 4. instead of 2 0 cents w. ing is there some money in the often neglected cottage cheese or not If now that man whom we supposed iving nearby and selling his butter for 2 5 cents a pound, would make cottage t cheese from his superfluous skim milk and sell it to his custom* together with his butter, what do you think he would be mak his 45,000 lbs. of milk? He was getting net for his butter and skint milk if fed $454.55. Now we will say he would use about half the skim milk on the farm and use some 15000 lbs. for making Selling butter for -' As the figures cheese making, iinl makiiiK OB tin •tare and the lc sonifwliut tlittii u Bing to pay nun hope thai n"xi skim milk 1&lt; pounds of eotta pound. Of course, we add somi cream of medium richness never that we do not lose money by addii </seg>
            <seg id="p033">ANNUAL CONVENTION 31 lbs. of skim milk were worth when This added to the above n more than in the case of making nl market conditions, butter making would bring the most ;res show net returns are from n pound $ 4T.4 und ',4. Ml und, butt ?r fat 11 h cott i heese making H40 ntlemen, this subject of Mr. I'lmann night ut some very good points lid like to ask Mr. I'lmann wo making on the farm? t of irying. and if there are any i rimann »ny questions, or supplement e pleased to hear from them. If there are t on the program. The je&lt; hav tl pleasure of introducing ker. of t Uuited State* Department nsumer K Nl I'IM.Y VM&gt; I'liODKTlON OK SAMTAUV MILK ght to you a very &lt;] ninter- y ke it interesting to you iv mornings ago, my eve rested opposing certain proposed ing for government to take .vr man the control of his business and put it I bacteriol So I will take ning. Is it within the pro- ike from a practical man. the control it amis of "veterinarians" and man? I may not agree with you, but n of the word "practical", and if I id if I have studied it aright, "practical" 1 to an individual, one who has had It does not necessarily imply skill or tiir iii-i v- hafn hail ,,, nrn aviuplam .. rhon nir m&lt;i&gt; n«i\t ii&lt;tu huh t ejL|ieneii&lt; e lildu j on the subject of great im- uers of whole milk. W. \V hi taker </seg>
            <seg id="p034">y. but if you had a i ase of sickness in your fainil von call first, the young man fr&lt; witn no experience, or the qui producing market milk the thri-shold of tl ■ K spell OB tin a dairy ham \ nt. it lint 11 ■II may lie a disag i ■erinarians he i- .lid what pi hai pi ii tlu th.it have follow) Kill thus adding greatly • il many o milk may be a m torch of education, in order to milk business must be conducted und is and veterinarians in ord -ure on the stubborn and us for official milk inspectioi rculosil is caused by specit I through milk from I 1 Koung graduate from an ui patitnt. ;ind thai ex W DM affr. with it t&lt;&gt; mak t Second. \\ •il "prai t Ira frinarians " .' It tells V Ife savinu. i o in fort- ridii tiled by sonie "prarl &lt;lo not realize the situatioi ai&gt;prei iati 1 thai it nit-aiis liglith in detail, has bacteriology showr • ■1] as nu'n. women and rbildrei </seg>
            <seg id="p035"/>
            
            <seg id="p036">the health of the cow and •&lt; ulin test, and that th. ■ in lude that all n test, and that tiV Delude that al: for Unman consumption, should lie nan &lt;i tisuniption. should be hich fail to react should be i h fail to react should be \side from the public health de from the public health e breeder in enabling him t breeder in enabling him ti&gt; i«&lt; losses from those which roni those whicli healthy row conditions for y cow conditions for M lit. well ventilate! ami (inld be light, well ventilate 1 and not c ted that the cows ma te I that the cows mav b^ &gt;f inclement weather H.iin y spell of inclement weather. Bara f cold pure air in curi riology has shown that biinclam e of cold pure air in currents hold fever and diphtheria, may lie upply. Kach of these dise i 1 no crop. This - the utensils, pails, cans, bottle) erms of those cli- ring for a person sic k with any II. handling an Kht tring for a sick p&lt; -on or over the I I kins over a ran or strain. isists in absolutely sterilizing I, cans, strainers and bottles and in keeping all i k persons, entirely away from tho us should keep Hies away fire milk ! One morning he took a disc of absorbent orty cans of the milk, eacl then dried those discs and sent them in graphed those, some of which I now show I'tty clean. That photograph repn presume many of you wilt t careful enough union form of contamination of the seeds of any dangerous .vliich can upset the weak stomach of n« 1 infantum. dysentery anrl other mis are intimately associated with The more dirt and foreign matter. ria. and the mor. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Prof* 'son font single fine hair from a row's fianV out the visible insoluble dirt, will i v from 1 1 1 &lt;&gt;-- • •n I. H. II. Dean Can x j count I a hi from tl a row of of haetei into But 1 1 fully scrubbi City of Par When aninii ■ &lt; ontaiiiinatu n lonlin Ions as itre on all panic Emins or bri:shii milk pail. The s'all- BT stall' hicins in tin- 1! :t will inntain. Profe hay about two I* earr '■(1 eight rather supply tl Pny oil i (LI U. 1 I distan 1 wit an.! the pii Mtltb, I old Ilia aii'l ha as thi-y c ■] ■■■• if anything could aving more i&gt;. i e in the better followed. 'I illustration. Referring graphically tlic de </seg>
            <seg id="p038">I n \ ■ ' -rt 1 i. I • ? i ! v </seg>
           
            <seg id="p039">i l t v 1 I I i i i i 1 \i t 35 lit and simple mangers. The lanure and all of the dirt jshed down The walls and or paint. The milk should lkers with dean, dry hands. dry hands the cow is iarn as soon a tin small Boor, cement preferred, walla ptly cooled to fifty degrees or below t into the milk. t;&gt; some extent at least the natural tempera hi. and desenr antum. dystentery and like it. After making an vitality that would not live me that taking a half of year right here in c to the local milk supply. i Bonn e i n. Tlii 1 Mama and angles ty for harboring bacteria linatlag rontagioM di^- tilth bacteria gettiBg into milk k Citv. 100.006 fe&lt;al bacteria touches them. Eve* if the teria niiiy be on its sn: was not tret- from ban ut s&lt; aid with bolIlBg • If you srald a ian ami then ] the good (lone by sc.i! or.ncl some pails bright anil t quantities of putrefartion 1 lady said that in addition y. she BRUSHED OUT THE ave been offended if I lKht she was doing well Ity, 100.006 fecal baoti und on the tof in manure pile to swill tub nother and in liis walk over i will sec the necessity of i.vthing that concerns it. I oth over bottliBg machines. if MHphasiling these things. &gt;w that about two babies in id that is true right here in </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Kl o the relation between :tnlilo mm n&lt;. ho hrmif mntri rli:n mine ■riiili.l t! i I ». a lot lli.i t i . : in t into wli .,&gt;■,),! I, M for ., Tnnilern i le:ii tor "He nrart ir:i 1 ' ' m:ii vrm :inil in \ iiriwliHt Inn The best results. I tliinl Khmild Te;n h the i (l not enough for cvitv om. A in the srorine of dai la to nif t hat these cards have t impartial and I think, will ho ii&lt; &gt;&lt; ' an m i * ItTWl 111 I : I! V I I »nst tlii- ' pr:i aerce with nointed . bast*:! o help til** ignorai toward the r1air\ the willful or inexcusa card in which a certain nun titial in the prdui tion ol von take these cards. In man ti nothing in the card th </seg>
            <seg id="p041">&gt;nic of the do not which </seg>
            <seg id="p042">NEBRASKA DAIRY. Ml- DETAILED SCORE ■ for equipmem I.— If ;m\ Mln Sc = Final Scor&lt; ■ If th </seg>
            <seg id="p043">on the part melhing like tliis. -if you bring about milk to the rjons n he amicable and ion- 1. utti iiu onneoted to do with the proposition physician with might to be v milk supply County Medical itiiin appointed ■ mi certain i healthy and roducera in that vicinity you a cer- that suggestion and he rtifled niiik. and secure:! 'mi ]\- has since ion under the in. Those mntry. The the Bubject. and thev men under thf u rt ns n that rertiflej oine i he milk &gt;n of nythinK hut milk produced Applaus' i photographs \v Production. Mr Wood was Iture and we will listen WITAItV MII.K I'ISOIII ( I 1&lt;)\ quart </seg>
            <seg id="p044">■ ontan ii ii SlipplM \&gt; II1O1 found out Kit in « inn :ry (ii 1 l)r K &gt;" \ rua the wiiiu ol to the milkman. known to ivnci-i" soim v other mem her: meci to infitnts tl Through ignoram »n indifferem e to the laws ol clean line iropcrly liKhted and ventilate 1. an nust be in striit accord with tbe 1 ■ t appre&lt; lat try tbe milk proi lltS tell 111 !u&gt; niilkin a cow; if MM Ktion &gt;v«»r i neans of DISEAS that pliysu uins jirth of what is called CKRTIK rhe meaning of Orliti. mcier tlif supervision of ;i M )iirity and (onti'in. Ti </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Milk Production— W. Ritfhter Wood-Arwood Dairy w Uarn. cows fe 'ilinjr out of cement mangers. Sanitary Milk Production— W. Rig hter Wood, Arwood Dairy— ■ ilked at or.ce with milking machines </seg>
          
            <seg id="p046">n proven This plan of prodn 1 as Wt mstructio ■imnil a dairy knows thai t away every day ive in its construction is mm h i i 11 f whi t T rthod is tli in I &gt; 111 I t() •", jllc llH: nt niixtui nl remit tin Boor a non- ns the liability f&gt; rheumatism llciors which a h nh nore sanitary and look better. I in t need upon LIGHTING and ventilat is tin' only agency ttiat will dea i 1 ier than iwi hr the this, an 1 if not ntilation. tuberculosis is the result n you entered in the stench would Certified Milk cannot be produced in e nvenience should be install! u in the performance of their duty. Tl t every day and D4 kept in ]ierfei t ordet iv enter without the tear of Boiling 1 not in line wit' rotn the litter of the harn. The build ins </seg>
            <seg id="p047">42 arrangement and apparatus should be conveaient and samtar&gt; \ vessels that contain milk should be thoroughly scalded with liv. they arc used. The buildint; ou ■m all time After &lt; oiiMiui ti&lt; n and equipment, tl herd. Persons that have the means oftea dairy rattle. Inn it is not necessary H ifn railed -Tlit" Deaa of America herd Persons that liave the means nftet dairy &lt; attic but it is not nee . mi of Ai in the OrtiSed Milk baaineM witli a nil ii there is nothing like baring in (he Certified Milk busin. ied In ki mal-Puru. VERY unsat i unsatisfactory in the speaker liis eoniiiiion by using a pure bred dairj The nai do not milk liryraao has to have a bunrti "coi i'iv.-a". T -ted in 01 kell. After i A i i( b the : At An M , ii Ian colored ja&lt; k&gt; white. | method for I". Try ii ! Its ( In Bp an:! pra&lt; I . inner requires no r. The Milk iiii;- I i( ult hi- .■". It may i-ater to I OS'l" ,-tri I lives. Til'' bl this, or i s( -calle I 'Certl In many |&gt;Iarea no mediral boi rd ins| C ii\ In many placi s no «l\n iik tl'is milk, t milk to be healthy an </seg>
            <seg id="p048">■oduction— W. Ri^hter Wood. Arwooil Dfcirj Ik and cream cooler in operation. Sanitary Milk Production— \V. Righter Wood. Arwood Dairy — Bottling milk and cream. </seg>
           
            <seg id="p049">1 t * i i r I FUIKTH ANNUAL CONVEXTICX \ han the ordinary canned stuff measured ; cooled and bottled Immediately after itir ! plant, there to be pasteurized. coole&lt;f imagine the condition this milk will u&lt; h stuff is enough to cause any liaby n Certified .Milk dairy, conducts 1 alo*C se people have been humbugged with teurized milk, and worse that ciialk- ■ 1 rows unl Mlthy surrounding pie imagine your milk is as poor in x. and the press lake-warm for fear of lcsm r the want of some then the education of tli und and mih-11 allon can and shipped or taking, or will soon become so Wlien milk is a slow pro ive liis snlije&lt;t well in hand. Employ he Bar re— or failure of this l&gt;usin&gt;-ss In writing your adver- tnith. Invite the people to call. Hava ■ that visitors will lie attra. Mr. Curler relating liis experiem . m n Chicago's market? What a time ho uairian (limbing the 'ladder of t •cad" rather rough' A •quitter" ii.-^.t mm h less the miik busim- ■n very soothing at th: ;ir whistles blow. or gongs don't sound. around. just the tn linn of li' ■ : over stones e;l ti &gt;r katydid. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">44 XEBRASK \ DAIRY.ME Soraetimea it seems to nte I must •lust (juii the city's din and dust And set out where the sky is Id And say now. how does it seem Peoi iik In is all they should tliink they know how to tn Ims been know n to break mipetitora trying to ■ p ideas &lt;in "i list of pro to !»■ ignorant, us folto </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Milk— W. Rigrhter Wood. Arwood I&gt;:in&gt; anintr the dairy utensils. He henl -Arwood Dair\ —Guernsey bull '■Birthright </seg>
           
            <seg id="p052">I is ignorant in dairy knowledge, or de- norant in dairy knowledge, or de- i jjay the cheaper price. ONLY be obtained from healthy cows; XI, Y be obtained from healthy cows initarv equipment and handling; and an ipment and handling; and an irman. I.a.lies and (ientlemen. I desire rman. Ladtw and (ientlemen. I desire rman. Ladtw aud (ientleiuen. I desire Ima Mater, The- I'niversity of Nebraska \lnia Mater.- -The I'niversitv of Nebraska Ima Mater, The Iniversity of Nebraska \ ben I entered this institution some years know ledge of this subject future will ever attest to the feet ion and I'urity. 1 thank you i We will now- ni which i» Management of y Mr. Andrew Klliott. (lalt. aid interest the &lt; reaniery men 1 be the remarks ind I have the With US til: him in you. if ah I I1AIK1 I.'KAI Wil WI.VTKi; ll.\IKVI\(i dairying it operations man to so bring 1 thert-froin « r«eeivia| a profit gives to thtr ing herself in a - of rare and u the rapid improvement an all other fa&lt; tor., combined ml craze for light colors has seriously w. The fashionable de- icniMiie an I switch i i the doom mil females of the Jersey as well, and nation to proba and prove the useful arts influence! brought to bear upon my form- \KTi:i{\&lt;!&lt;&gt;\ SKSSIO.V </seg>
            <seg id="p053">46 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOOIATIO of the Holstein. to the neglect of point of intrinsi In the breeding, selection and management i f my look for only one thing, namely, the ability to give a supply of milk, rich and pure. Kverything in and around subservient to this all-essential To accomplish this my built around two points, the digestive organs and the in iins anil tl" Er. The one to digest and assimilate the food, anil tl ert the resulting blood into milk, and every distinct tic of my cow must l&gt;e such as will enhance the ahili two. to perform their wort Form." It is worth whil K ledger! dairy conformation haa been obtain no such thing as the dairy type, neither ii ideal of the I started in a ration* heifers from the be from a parent t ■s was what » best b&lt; The dairy type we are justified ii was the result of proof of this also dairy cows, we tin haraeteristic say little, only that it capacity to digest and vigorous heart and lun. •■nough to do this, ati'l conv than beef and sustain the c There are three food 11! solids or products of th ary to life The first tiling a cow n to digest, that after ■ cow ha of food consumed, is to dipest more fi next to ke&lt; a good normal condition, and lastly to put the residue ii ir pail. True. MM cows love their owl 11 that tht their body to keeo up a scanty supply of lacteal Raid, but Kdo for a short time and ■ row Insufficiently fed nk in ler milk and when m do this, ni feeling will brins her back to otherwise have been. me foods are </seg>
            <seg id="p054">47 11X i I 1 n ht ii v tl i V \ x \ ii return. The digestibility of foods ■d ration, coarse Teeis and gr tant. A food that a cow likes will Akfam, a ration that contains all feet nourishment of the body, or a I digestion. Not only is a succulent il so materially assists in dii. in;; tliat no ration is as it ought to succulent natur What month of the year above all every one would reply June oft and succulent and there is 1 water abundant, the cows are liv- ought to aim tc ar rcund. dra tarry June condi- I is the best food rappljr of .adii.I ma eo«ld be forth - ve would desire nothing bettar. We anils, nver pasture, thereby into the roots, in time, destroying mittlng weels in their plai ■»• Close 8 particularly to be condemn*' on our pasture for three uciulence if put in the ment of the protien. the two KK .Milk contaii putting that amount into *Uil&gt;le. Above all. succulei. k and produ* t. In time we will have el op dressing and caring for it. the enough (or live, and then four ■ovisim should be made for feed IrougBl ;uil for the supplying "f a hen fie 1 i&gt; dry. This on In in i . store:l in the siln As rendition the silo has k»| it 1) (din store I in the silo, and hay Nebraska roaM control the i'.sku :is a dairy state aj-e superior nate i&gt; a happy nieliuni br' ■ driving cold of the north — pure I plants of the world. The </seg>
            <seg id="p055">c IBRASKA houhl :&gt; iso be Dure. Germi • 1 water suuiily, that tin t throrsh her bod? to tin lines bi k.Mit i i vinter I have nevi iccounl shrink in their milk. pmne r:i 1 1: i n I h»' a n ii i ii ii ' ■Ivhta nil ■ taint eerm will live for six lii.hl will W To this fin) &lt;t:)hlf shttiili! t» i:,wiiin ■ ;trv to life thai on air and water. Animal: without water, hut without air Ii lunB«. here it rim to the bloo: houses ran t-aler and i up a mouse in a pint by its own exhalatio rows onlv that the Ik In ma 1 i crv hazi saw a co Pll 1* t I \\V lot lu- hi&gt;:i 1 1 «f hnvinir th*» lx I1MII I'Tc- ] i-lH I! ■ I inoi"t abundant. !n carbonic eas. as the DOisom slightly heavier than pi mef»ns is Rdoptd to get confined in small close 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">\N.\TAI CONVEXTK 49 ( n I 1 v. mild \ i Igl Jt III .1 t ii n i ;ik of til building with floor admitting ill tin - eat generate • foul ■ in the snil ! by the i ired from their k to fca for removing building run- Id be made of tad vain omlcnse mon an iron pipe quickly anj or 14 inches air from the ranted u ii in r the ceiling. side of the they i! will partially Hue Of H stable. Pure the base and the room und ■niniis on 1 t trikiiu room. low ii. lis alfalfa anil bis pay in tht There never Ife with al! nan's wonderful ult of who can tell? i sou mon witli that i. u fieri ii- fort lioops and fails ml neivoi nd fearful in weakness^ and la hides and hields it fron nd fearl . and how truly doe from it With what a n You have all seen i s and ventilator nil and sanitary. The\ Straw should be pro* ttrmw cannot !&gt;»• obtain' i corn .stalks that catn- Iding the stables i riner passei i therefrom &gt;th&lt;-r thins: e cow has ! ns and </seg>
            <seg id="p057">50 hear the low .heartbreaking moan thing. How for days will she t time to the object of her hearts gr row is a machine." of agon lie fondle; rcmn t des returning fr Tell nit I It is through this instinct (if rally as soon as the calf is Ma, but ! ng. : of Uu tation i mother! that i t ma n;i i finitt To obtaii the affeclii n she hi Iht of allovii'- jn r oun out to the lit the involi v K. When a drop of milk gets on the hand the mode of milking, do not strip He teat as though you wanted to get udder into milk pa nr the milk, rather lift the hand up, p land int w </seg>
            <seg id="p058">51 K iii£. lie excites the nerves of the ('■et all the milk. A pound of the a nt than three of the first. Cool milk* in a uling, and get milk or cream to con- w, I will repeat, remember that she with the highest attribute of life, motherhood. called the Foster mother of the human race. higher or aesthetic development, it would d perish from off the earth were it not for the \\V now come to a number, the author of which oduction. He has been before the public for a ■Object for this afternoon is Our Conditions," Oil! ( OMIITIONS W. A. Povnter and understanding of conditions is a very &gt; of any business. The ability one has to dittos, and more especially to fit his business to kind of ability which brings the largest returns. that business methods change conditions but If he proved too short to fill it he was red length. If too long then he was chopped sure. Tho king by this drastic rule had all his length, but he had made lots of cripples. some papers seem to think that there is just one the dairy business of the country should be conducted. kind of an Og"s bedstead and compel the dairy &gt; erywhere to conform to this standard. In some places they ff, and in others they would stretch it out, but they conform to their ideals of their methods of We may admit their method is exactly right fectljr as the king's diis change business methods. So it is very ur business methods to suit our conditions than iditicna to comply with our ideas of business ideas of business very much like the fabled self to be the perfect type of physical man- very man in his kingdom must just fill id more, no less. So he had a bedstead built mil required each man in his dominion to lay </seg>
            <seg id="p059">We wild are gtlhered here are all interested in I pint lit years by practical I work 01 been dnin u*rii ulti ii V ■ions u kno« und 1 for agric nltorml i to the in rultlvi is in ■ irn prodt of any of Eorntins air healthful alaria in all its forms Ncrtli nor the i:ls of fuj; ;n ness which make lift' on the I i iinntfnrr ii old shine than can be toand in ;n Pure water is abundant in &lt; r streams, so plentfnl a number of IBM*, ti »»rU i to be tapped to yieid aa 1 sparklinK water, the purest inn] and water are the essentials tor have them combined in such pe ; not be excelled m any kil N - than thf kir longer than h&lt; Kh of a with tt </seg>
            <seg id="p060">&gt;.\VK&gt; 4 pro '■mill u in i :&lt; ii nui vct'ii farm an Tn iVllO m stay. It must be rerkoM (rove N ,ne of </seg>
            <seg id="p061">\ \ population becomes dense enough and knowledge strong enough to make the local 'reamer paper I hat I f butter that tl whiih a in. lined to think merit won sui-li records art kept h determine that they tuiv credit for. We must tin row* he speaks of in the state to begin with, an produced in tl There is another 1 I in the home as they did Ik lo use whole milk in i and fruit in season, now we use. t \\' use it just as freely &lt;!&lt;&gt; not produce. I tliint Boi appear when you are talki we have hand ie|MM </seg>
            <seg id="p062">55 k»* ir n n t r 1 t part w w t ter i :i i x a uni in the state i) consideration It is increasinK hat the law says irteea per cent butter fat . you will realiie » mount of butter ibutins; ■ large .ik* n into consir ■for. I dislik &gt;ve our rows are ration, and th&gt;? to have an prod in ins twiitr hed the milk and save the It would substantiate what I ha«« I 550.000 strictly dairy rows in th together best when you coin &gt;ur cows freshened in the fall We have found a much sweater hen in the tprtng time. When rv business on a :ie of cows Wi ni will better your con t thins for the state of Nebraska, that x years t ere was somewhat at the farmers would be com Ki dairy row* in the to how that statement has come id (leal of guess work con he number from my own county. dairy province of Onlurici. an I as iws of our rtate InimeBM amount pretty well acquainted with the s talking recently with a gentle- of the state, li^ Mid In- had absolutely neiessary fur him to i his herd. He said I am getting illons of milk a day. lie said it he had to do something i cteme nm .it of thtj iot milking their rowi from k I I d abundant credit a matt, i it i.s unfortunately so for the dairy s amon.i; the s7:i.'hi" dairy </seg>
            <seg id="p063">NEBRASKA DAIRY E" would include many wl in milk prodiK tion. It « e«ptBg and (iiiinu 1 its troi </seg>
            <seg id="p064">\ unit' the awe to ih- 1 an mi farm the whole The ilaii more fertile (line to bt ti an is has ■ attention awe a pile of hi the corn an attempt producing nditioiis Inn under ;iy in some phi .t liu- They do not a it it in that • lut'ution. We will be rarkin- new befoi xperimenl stations for if iffoid to try i information ther rieultural coll knows but Ik information lifferent kind not report mnot eve in book farming" so thor- nother part of their \( iHiaintance f friendship, and in' ows all look alike to us leration of cows have h attention to them to </seg>
            <seg id="p065">58 minded me how awkward and em harassing it mav undertook to harness them. Xo out of my line. I never ha nee did not seem pleas und actions. I could not m i man to do it who knew bow. But I knev to the library f knew that if 1 not to take my a cow man witt I ha\ ■ man win H. n ' Differ. with (1 w when her milk* do mut'h fo understanding of r saw a man m being told Cows ki&lt;k because they fear turns to hatred. Then tl ing cows have tried for ag ought not to he in it Cow feeding is a very Imp much easier to find men w ran feed. Co is the hi. from a text book the right proport to use. The balanced ration has b Is an art. Taking adraata] takes long practice and skill Tin in this world, ("olantha 4ths Johanna in a year. That is a great record. Hi famous cow could make a batte buy in Lancaster County have made with Calantha Una Johani up with animals we &lt;!o not unrterstar </seg>
            <seg id="p066">nt counts. We all ire is the differen knowledge and skill bom Bred at what they call the h to pay for her feed. Call the s been all the cry. Well there are a ows never do pay for their k&gt; of the blame in another try to get a little larger )i- the training there is in it. If i better learn to be a row man ile in this part of Nebraska to to consideration the be very good feed. 1 don't members of the auditing neddon and E. T \ I'ovnter, loin ui- dairy l&gt;arn \\&gt; have ml talks in regard to the ideal conditions ere we can see them In pr hrmiKli the barn itil Thursday morning nirn </seg>
            <seg id="p067">60 Meeting Hi- !;' Illl MOST Ml NT I.I THK H\li:\ IM.I law ; Ktrylns to lift the men her itABdard. Wlii'ii. dairyman "You must di mi i;M&gt;\t \ioi:\i\&lt;. — w-.m \. m my perfoi will follow. busii, tt is unsanitary milk lefinert by tin- law li </seg>
            <seg id="p068">61 mventilated an.l filthy cow y to admonish the farmer on ntends to compel him to keep law or l;i;ps out of the dairy i We don't allow yet this filthy milk, reeking with ille:t with ins in the statute hook, will Ig to them bles and let in the lisht The saying to the lean up th ir &gt;w stables prose- time th sine law will be n and savins t him You must nlawful to sell it or to have if the milk dealer of the milk he sells. He must n&lt;ler sanitu n.ler sanitary con lition.s. ition is now now going on bare in LJl 11 1 .1 ii' ■ • I it in- 1 a stream of f Hrty filthy milk irty filthy milk insi ill*, law. S;&gt; OOd lionest IBM who v nebo I 1 firmer? - the law? dean the idly s,&lt; firmer? mil iv In - the law the effect of the tl clean the tuidllcin.-n u ho llelllell tt llO ire de ery milk dealer in to«n to »t thi - the drii- iny co his busira t the liquor man lid he didnt e bought it of a traveling man. The You ha\. and to run a saloon". Yt f it drives every ignorant &lt; tor or druggist who ((impounds ine-lirine n any dru« or article to and whether it was pro- predefine him over and over bould require ■ saloon man business and the liquor he </seg>
            <seg id="p069">62 If Jones, the producer nsamtar I»-ddler. and Smith sells it to Brown ami following the unsanitary milk from n ni: rnissioner at tbe state hous re the court and 1 And why : What is a law for All tin milk. There is ;iu e» us If Brown who k 1 am suggesting some! I..in« oln. and On about milk. Nobod r knows r wh n Iowa, luit tl is whole bum Com If such law v business it wouli milk?" Y sani ta farmer sells n la premisi If Brow i in writing from the milk p from the dairyman that in the law. But .Iciies. tl OBM to lay the blame on and sanitary milk on its way from the row's udder provided her a sanitary st; milk under sanitary conditions When 1 look at this law dncer "Don't hold your rrean 11 it or offer to sell t or t&lt; There is a lot of bad cream bein and it ought to be stopped. You can't mat Bit we make low grade butter i -tern market and that \\ Nebraska market. If tli weet the butter factories could a a million dollars more for it ev This law is also poil to him "Stop you; unsuspecting patrons at his eating </seg>
            <seg id="p070">\L CONVENTION \ IT. I ream receiving roper attention to the ream business and how ami who will be careful and upling and era will have in the business will grow. An as life and development. A dishonest rements. will cause general I : fail for want of an honest dnwn • ■m. it will be largely becaa irar.te&lt; these two y ran Mid of the business, ■inn something into their his c reamery in. let him quit us proposition. I could in this state and revoked w you have power to without pulling the ould have brought latins the law. but I did not want to ok me in the face and say. "You tore i rank: you want. how business." This regulating its effect It is now beginning to people a little tighter all along the rriMin because of other duties, then they might say you have t is quite problematic IV V ry department of the busi - honesty must be more and And this y the enforc ement of this law. The law power It needs more men. It is impossible to pervise the daii of a state as large as this with n. Three times as many men can be profit tor pay and they should be high nt them, and the business tea with another by short e into court and show •reamery business that &gt;f the Incompetent </seg>
            <seg id="p071">111 oniDiti-nl or ■ selling rotten iin (mi Detent \'inir airent nrali mrt ., 1 1 1 1 ik i r :iin: iiriiiinrtioiiat nallv to balai I 1,,'li..' 1 1 r t h? ml u In i I Cow it )):&lt;&gt; ■a nn inn. and t) ■r or MMBDler i With more f aid tl and al e dairy Ini N'ebras Tlir I'r.'siciint : As M </seg>
            <seg id="p072">65 ONVKNTION \ 1 at 1 r i i h i kV i i n doi i IV i nish t di ii on this st rrfKiuorins work Late along • pinion on this subject ol :l\\ IBBd upon nson ought to kn tetter than I le I and what is practical in uld be profitably employed in tlii usht to have twenty he ardon mo if I do so tile same. W law and their duties arc plainly re&lt; five I was never able to under- other food products instead ol I is plain as to what they should do at the dairy interests should li» One of the planks upon which ' at we should have dairy legislation. -Matured enough to permit them to )ins to &lt;all it in my remarks, thf our understanding that we lone because we had four more in trues. It seems in that reaper* «. And 1 have never been able to figure authority, or whether the law i ■ dairy Inspector to inspect gti orn meal and hundreds of i for the nod of th&gt; ] am but I have been asked to Rive my Johnson not his authority for the ting all these other thiii- \v nly one creamery th- work there in an hour the day u ith noth ;tt work en into tl hort ability than I : ••' up &gt;je&lt; t so important tar! that I havt- no vei\\ &lt;lc. M had to say aliuut th&lt; nn lawfully taki 1 ) plainly written into tlit nlain. For instance an in- </seg>
            <seg id="p073">66 get me a sample of meat and send it home, and if it ute that meat dealer. In that way I got a lot rk the dairy inspei tors which did not interfere with their other w I did not have enough food inspectors to il&lt;&gt; it. 1 did not Authority, 1 jui-t did it. I said to then tend to your bu word about a certain drug st&lt; the next time you are in that towr naming it. I simply got the men t not hurt the men It dil not hurt i &gt;k X without any &lt;loubte:lh in It av of tin ' when th&lt; i wan in a town or ins out m; ret Ilii'iu in tl ,1 prai ii&gt; al n to deliver it in prop ■fcortH omlng of tke fi tin- milk is drawn tint try in t that Mr. Re&lt; n thai our Ke inti v. ■ train the i aw, at U in .• ( n the pr is a part cf your to &lt;lu everything you cai tMr. R« tor : wlio ■ make is r», it «( Mr. Ji butter. I v made from that rream so tli I hop&lt; the oe </seg>
            <seg id="p074">V r fni ira i t m would give to it when the law was the dairy industry which we all here tate organization behind which is our of our product and we should formulate tions as this association deems wise and the further advancement of our industry unt, Beatrice or auy particular creamery, ip and discuss all these propositions by ; able to know more than Mr. Johnson I hope if nothing more is acconipluh- ner will see the importance of giving us ir Inspector*, and that be shall instruct duties: and that in addition to examining i&gt;ut into the country to the farmers and 1MPII license fee. $1.00 each is sufficient. thousand operators in the state paying f buying cream and bringing lly one license were i- four and sometime* th ike an examination, so that ther :i station. The law is that Vnd so it runs in my mind state food, dairy and usinesa. Mr. President, that port of that business? That is a principle in govorn- f the public should be taxed especially uld luinK in $.".immi to the state. In in tlic interest of the publi&lt; b that any business that has to be ors. their pails and ians and ascertain irs that we are buying from these farmers. is OM day. one week or two weeks old, le we arc pratically forced to buy ; us it to us. if licensing all cream receiving Kgents. hat |ilan. There is no reason why those ; and not testing should not come under licensed and fai e an examination aa to uni-le cream as well as those who test it manipulation of the testing or the result IttC to the sampling itself. If the sample start no matter how accurate the testing ;-s tliere are issued, it cannot be right I licensing. 1 in not in favor of requiring. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN aublir to supervise tin- buaine - Tom must pay the bill. Um I don't m« why thai is noi a fair proi VI rjr drag store in tin- stale and mak&lt; the exp. use nf supervising the drug Mi-kinz h in I do not i. V till , ■ u .. i llllllll!l, t meniliers of this umilil talk 1 will he nleased to meet von I li • ist;mil there is al 1'nless tilt re is some o this time we will pa:-s on i von meet the commute.- o uir l .Mr. Johnaon : la rm «)Ulsi,ie our state and is t state. 1 would sav that - I; 5= Ire you c the disi usMon tliai lit llHT IKM'i'l's r ■ 1 ) 1 1 •tate, I would mjt ihat j me in Iowa or wli &lt;iuiik a&gt; ii Kd&gt; Inside oil </seg>
            <seg id="p076">\N.\TAI CONVENTION 69 K n the other state. We cannot test ing it here and sell it on that test. n us it comes within our state. It iw. We cannot do anything with k in regard to the extent that this state, whether any provision inner may be reimburse! by the Often fanners would like to know I lint they produce a good product imal that might have to be killed on uld like to know if the: inibursed ferre 1 to a committee who will id have it introduced during the pi Djei t will be taken ii|; separate ssiuii. It will be to the effect that the morning is by I'rof subject of "Some K&lt; i i I.. H ■. I, business to make D Or pleasure. kin a IV oH table dairying as there It is enough to say profitable is to make it •reduction should be in the and for without such we the business We can not average is quite poor r country, but it is high II as her care. The time has t tlie conditioi 1. and the increase 1 &lt; oat w produces about Un lbs. in what 100 lbs of butter will Ib. tor profit KKATl IlKS c»l K(OM»Ji:( MII.K I'liODl ( Tl«)\ u ;:ii&lt;l Slock llli|&gt;li&gt;i iMii'liI ine profit derivej from </seg>
            <seg id="p077">70 NEBRASKA DAIRY.MKNS ASSOI ATIOX need not bother about Improvement, but few would cmre to mill rows with sui h a reward. It always teemed to me it was easier t milk a pood cow than ■ poor one, and I know &gt;od profitable. It lias been said that t at i is more good dai yni n nd tha is a better specimen of b an her k&lt; ;aid that the average row ugh ■lit man is content t&lt; tli for we must ad ml By better methods double the milk yi lairvmen however we should of the common &lt; ow, but blood. Tl in our cnunti will require uiai of our dairies. With the r that we (In ! The | ning 1 Distant markets in ibis country numbers of animals id future In. good pur profitable busii market and at the iami • ost for the high yielding men of Denmark and Hollani a&lt; re land if it were not ■ may be said of the farm and Guernsey (Sood rowi that I : intend to use them are the first of economic milk production both milk and beef, but the said that the average cow is en man and cause him to q«H tr age means relation: to Impr islesl nii'thoil of low ! Japanese merchant big pri&lt; ea for tbi ly populated c ounl • ill t v » f arc «hii h ] to such a funrtio </seg>
            <seg id="p078">71 nniiiK the Derby with draft horses, cutting &gt;r chasing jack rabbits with pug dogs onoinic milk from beefy cattle. The &gt;e found wherever ■ test has been tried. At Buffalo and !rt. Louis it was brought out in janv of cur experiment stations found the r making milk production a small [jrovetuent is not so important, but I have 1 is carried on in this manner there is ■ ying should be made more of a business. ter tion we had better drop it altogether, and lijei ts we rare for and are willing to FKr l!S AND FKKI)IX( upply our animal liuellt they | with cheap food and at 1 tlieir best development to nourishment if they ninial well f tin- ration, but it r Hiires some study u.e milk ei on mtcally we should ins wherever it is pos for by so doing ilinu bulky mat rial, but will also f our land, If we must buy let it be I OS- rial that is high in nitrogen ii ml carbohydrates ughag bay in this k 1 ini sure will sell his ter comment is intended for the man who wishes n. On most of our ■Ids can 1 arrange. 1 to produce Id I ur tirst consideration t ii so much its benefits here infilling it to tht oik- of the best tute pasture in the sun but little grain nee.1 bi list winter we found u&lt; have yet tried I per ton and fitting the f;roiin lit; ;&lt;nd putting it in the silo it would still be a cheap feed n fodder is another stc n and until the silo i a inter flie fodder may </seg>
            <seg id="p079">* ma v 11 mini' til milk in dry iows rlnvpr nr ratios ti „ X III] III -mint t lie mini ■r-fm The inw will prnl. BB in the winter it will I - unit so will need but si? With the war-arum ipiing least niDi tie-lil and tan in th»- fall ■■ iili lit' fed i'liil milke: ' nshf barn, in ventilation. My ei and </seg>
            <seg id="p080">73 riox itnd tu keep them in n IVw more profit to n 1 it i lounct Hi li. int. i U Mains, the law shoal all the tro n 1 hope to lirini: into iik haired t production k. To test the for 1"" pou« I I Kit NOON &gt;! the law there he reniaii .. tv in- I was running a </seg>
            <seg id="p081">an.l it is ;i now in i\( i W. l. Praiier. Chief d( Dairy li After t. ii \ • point. I do not ; ti real profits in dairy I ', Ing upi n this 01 1 ii| n ifsniHii to s.-iii won Id be Um ■ la what i Knnci-iii n wit i \-i Mil k i&gt;i:i:i&gt;in (II Mr President, I spot in the dair The ;n tiiiil relation of </seg>
            <seg id="p082">• HE .MARK El where hi this is true, but the farm, as grain, hay n&lt; y of the row comui dairyman's pi hall' rent a bushe ish eiioui. Yet the dairymen iiyinp them only will pay fifty y ronsume. The differ. -in •• la ii is not ut it is none tli. ndividual i o» the I'niv. Lb., fat M.. (71 t m 474 l!M 'S ■ \ v i'KH REGISTRY IlKrOHD </seg>
            <seg id="p083">nmiml. ■ted T In llu- U 11 1 1 ■ I : i :■ II mm IaIIaw. V. Ill 11. II is 111 j 1 k Bill B iyear in the fc 1 ■ i ■• Tka int. .r.xt t Till T'l ■ )lf)ftf*f1 en u ) red for -At\ mi y (lifTertiit » ■ i han 1 2 pound- i pet i ft 1. 1- i ali'ina K fourth lactation I 111-1 ,1 .. 11.,.!.. T ] I •&gt; KuM I A lirt 1.. &lt; ThfSH \\ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p084">OXVEXTIO ■ 4 1 t 1 the ii x Illinc Lilt' Of ourtii of all ) yield - riag the xnar, ami the duriag tile \Hiir, anil the of ::u l poandi butter fat. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">:.VSKA DAIRYMKN A SIX I A fat in his milk, it &lt; ostin the overrun lo niali per pound for butter fiit. the pi r. of $30.77. At the low imate of y per row to he win make an avers oil !8 per year for U »r profit &gt;w Th. MAKE hi Weak Twen ver Wlllllll 1 would attempt . mlv we of 1 1 1 i n ittered and Xe I herd in the stat and time and effort has pxten tis. Is it any mon inessl to keep live, ti !i or twenty- iv &lt;)\V TO SOLVE THE LABOR I'koliM &gt;s. And certainly it is drudi </seg>
            <seg id="p086">■ following tablf which lifid of tliirty-fom in |lfl il :.i 4 1 4! t 1 1 11 IN&gt; i iai ) l.*i -:; L':i *i' </seg>
            <seg id="p087">and tin- 1' </seg>
            <seg id="p088">in dairy herds as well as ii rly understand that M&gt;mt» li^rds di and to hml out fo tvhat each indiviiiiM </seg>
            <seg id="p089">82 ASSO4 V not pay for the teed uiven then a marfctn of profit to justify the investment in inoi Anil that still other herds are making t When we realize this, it is easy to Bee how the profit Do dairymen in general know that these differen that ma; be readily uadei |M&gt;ur lierrl to the highly profitable h&lt; mutter, within at all mi i viiliui I the writer one-fort h to the own very hare of kn (Unary d; The natural in\ Few rows of the lov everj herd a Is fat. The dairyman si eaeh year, telling all easily done and it re cows than it d&lt; mi dairyman ran affi pounds fat per year W1IOI.K HKKI) BROiriiH •O\V BY TESTINC AND WE To illustrate how t OC may lie increased hy t tine tht poor producers, and pi ttins hettel to &lt; all your attention which was tested to the r &gt;v this Static </seg>
            <seg id="p090">83 !•«« Ml' :j.4 23ii i..il SHI 4.0 ::|t&gt; .",.■• 4;! 4 '■-'■■• 4.1 3m 7.4H.1 4.17 * 4 W 4 I 4..H2 4 .» i.li" U2.NM ER FAT PER COW IN TWO YEARS linii stmi . pounds of milk contain ■ 12 cowi the (econd year averag oundfl of batter fat: ami that 1 pounds of milk two This nifans I the year's production; wlii. amounts 1 •VSH 4.2 1M4 K.2 j + .1' 1^1' si»;ht is as averts ir, and urn w the third &gt;• r hole profil fi </seg>
            <seg id="p091">EBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S 1 t ll 11)11 11 In ill! t 1 1 1 - I 1 In zivp Him It ex L', tin- sii-f may lir much ged by the qaamtlty, sinus Of tin- &lt; haracteristirs he transi may thus, within ■ U&gt;* \ III I ll W ll'IV t ll f S tifn-m-sixU'enths la Tll!l« t II ■ullv "flip Wllfl </seg>
            <seg id="p092">I. !&gt;• iriidut mK mnu unit's -idea • i ii i ■ i.i 1 1 * in. 1 11 M Kr lii'iu i/.ii '" ire in 1 1 K i i&gt;CI JMI or until sn will the u(i(l qualltl nrst laiiaui'i Bight dollars and twent improvement or increase or in sire is purchase* * null •run 11 &lt;l;i after purchasing tn s at nve pe ■ (1 from thi </seg>
            <seg id="p093">ii. ■ daugh III . , ! :i II !■ ) •jt.l.. Jw a:«s liuri i: Tntal i&gt;v V.*vt k'vlr-i . i ■ ( 'i infill, ri n i TS FROM )!i&lt;- daughter &gt;m- daughter i fnr I r. Where «i l-i. f,,r :&gt;: ,li lirntit on </seg>
            <seg id="p094">87 Bto the right kind of ■ dairy sirt within th r&gt; iw t stimates to b« iiiu- nargin left for failures and unfavor- nd pounds of milk per year is a con- ovenient of the daughters production lftails of figuring it may t»e varied to different localities One hun- liber*] allowance for the pur. uills here named are based upon taring lead of I lie herd A herd of only 38 or eud of tile herd A herd of only :; :, or t ration, while I rigor O— sire properly for a herd of I :. to .",11 cows provided lie us sire properly owi iirovided he hem. Then- is another distinct improve- if is another distinct improve Ighter besides her milk production ; it is JKht k prod art Ion; it is her n &lt;l or breeding, as the result of which her the result of which her ilk producers. This blood improvement 1 through a series of years n efficiency of the herd. uulated through a sen , ,s means tt of the her on EXPERIENCE of all dairymen who have mm that the investment has made them airynier who hare used ;t the investment has made them st price looks -too bis' only to the nar - the natural Improvement of the herd only to the nar- ii .■.■ the natural improvement of the herd dairyman Bight have reason to say that lit have reason to say that ! price for a line cow, hut the sain.- argn - pun has,- of an improved boll. because mi h farther and faster than that of to lie raised for dairy (ous. there is ab- irii e for a tine row, hut the sam,- argo- w m proved bail. berau» faster than that of r daily ( ow», th i sim on earth for keeping a scrub hull. lere is. pay a heavy price annually for The scrub bull i&gt; the most expensive annually for most expensive attle flesh on any farm. He does not !'iit will lose the farmer the | v year he is kept. The dairyman scrub bull if the animal were given to m. He does not aimer the prict The dairyman animal were given to &gt;ardt»i tl mil given a premium lardtng the beast and given a preinium llini - T! ■• the scrub sire in ■ uli sire in iiany tunes without a single l( ualiric ation '»&gt;' 'i ■ without a single qualification a - an ml a disgrace to the dairy il u ■ the dairy ■tisemeiit of the dairyman's thoughtless :iirv I ':" I1U II T h'SS Oil ACTUAL RECORDS </seg>
            <seg id="p095">not been Tliis impi Tin- actual relation of il at least solicit thi tlii- anni! ]&gt;rai ti&lt; rt] lakil Eviiliial row &lt;*. the ml profit* &lt;! -i-iv.-.l tram dairy rarmii i/&lt; .1 by il.&lt;- pi . | I,- ,1 , , utUmu np&lt; n HiU &lt;«•&lt; apatiea for a lii :t- &lt;&gt;ii the .nii-.ii;,- dairy fern l&lt;;day ran &lt;-ji&gt;ilv In- duultli and inure money. If the Dairy Commim(oB&lt; interested in daii </seg>
            <seg id="p096">89 (NVEXTICN -tly differ - ■ f the 1 among his s. hic-h dairying i ry or rtorv iiu ■r and xtendi whi i&gt; t (ll!t t isily pi irm outbuilding have no fault n another one of the many I am glad to note, how- nttinils as many times the 1 buyer but ■) ality of and the statt larator companies are trying </seg>
            <seg id="p097">1 is time in selling separators and ha nil li :t ii A I i 11 1- nf m ■ or IK) • •videiit from the filthy places op&lt; undreds of cream buyers in K;uis;i ditions I than in Kansas, and If conditions n chance, Kau^ v lla urhir-ti tun iMtaf fur the business, while at i i *i ..•••!•] in tootino i i . thp irPHIIIfl'V IS lllCft iav &amp;!. This loss is after 1 for butter fat: w tmsiness of our stai i- 1 1 ii i ■ ■ i ■ &gt; w I unt linrit v number of inrreasiim tlierfore found tli Nebraska, it will til </seg>
            <seg id="p098">91 production and unitary manner in and qualified to test and by testing I those who mik lies in must become an »■ u r n'aining Dot onlv t most sanitary keep tlu tubes, bottle and tasty. To ablisb absolute lity to test the urthf mil i ii sting bottles ■ nt of i inch fifty per «ent em e in the small neck it would tend to favor t n The larger the sample 1 n botl neii us i nine inch luoated in tin the proper size absolutely agree with no k for graduation. vt-nient. Kishtncn I forty </seg>
            <seg id="p099">92 \ Mr. Wilsrn: I (annul adopted that law. hut the tempera! If he raises twent) i i ills a hi per acre and sell i! ;U a \ profit still The swine print usiertain and secure tin n single row. The operator ra operator should thoroughly have ins and butter fat can be obiatl butter fat ran be obtained from th from the same labor. A station facts and impress them upon his tarn if rach law v the i oinniissioner' i iple thai it is wli way of feeding cows so tlwt ll </seg>
            <seg id="p100">93 and the proper u or e have in this in trouble must entirely with in the world possible to obtain 1 believe I am Justified •am. That I of the busint of the ladder as inanu- end. The idea in uc h ike drudgery. P.ut n milk twenty-five rows and ne hundred and two must spend our eneriry and and Gentlemen, i Apula tomorrow ( Friday j The ereameric mis upon the manag </seg>
            <seg id="p101">94 A si ATI KAKM. IMIin III II.IHV.. JAM AIM l-J. IIM»ii U is Chairman 1)h pleased to listen m liii RESOLVED. Thai in tl Eiiwn ;i prominent and who. diiriiij: all thoi mnts (ii adrai iation h« Ml Your ( inn the follow ins &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p102">•"ornTn annual convention pat y in this their I nail to them at MM roves much more expensive on uiiouni e further fad the machines for hand- ist about twice as luurli as thi bottle in actual practice does m 11 bottle in actual practice does no- lian the I in . we rwnaiiM that the an the ( In., we recommend tli : nit tlit» use of tlie t; in. bottle as in most all glassware tor the testing oi the hands of the Daily Conili;i- il the &gt;; in. in it He a.s in most all glassware for the testing of mills of the Dairy Com mis- o its accuracy, and all scales I ,111 for t«atiBg of butter fa 1 u curacy, and all scales u-- am for testing of Imtter fat &gt;val of the food, Iliiiry and DrVf the Food Hairy and l&gt;nm Com- the value of proper facility ii ullure. and. Iwe of proper facilities accommodations on our Stat mmodations on our if objective perfection in animals, crops parted to our farmers in a shoi &gt; iked for by the Regents of tin- jiitive perfection in animals, rropi ur farmers in a short for by the Regents of th n. when- our boys and nirls receive the lere our boys and nirls receive tin tils them for successful farm lit. hem for successful farm llfi lature: therefore be it il heartily endorse such improvements as mprovemen ■ ('.rounds and State Farm, and request ind Stale Farm, and e sutlii ient money for such struct' of Nebraska. y for such structun Dairymen's Association hold their annual which for the past tweajt] isl t\vent\ of the lirst week ill September, by the itid Exposition!, therefore be it iiiest the Legislature to k in September, by the .ind Expositions, therefor- the l,eKis!atin la i he third the thirii ilow 1 C'ondU' ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p103">ii . V man himself. In out the (ans: tlie anil drive bark lal in thpir hn JOW I ((IMIKT A CREAM I!K(K1\ l\&lt;; STATK) Pirn: th&lt; til*- OKtmlBg. (I ".(i t;er i &gt;'iit of </seg>
            <seg id="p104">97 XTICN ( butter fat butter fat anil K ill tron mi s an nil in r I VI my and t DC, hi. iiU'ii or re now at this time my iiatrons 1 k*"ci&gt; for Ik \\ i t i , oulile with tlu-ir ative rom- I think it c-ommittee nt (111 the committee, S. C. . B. T. Rector ami Crant if our pro men, norning. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">98 come in line of the work tt ilile paper* already man whom I am si II veil known in if his life in f (wo pocnda •xiellnil work. T! rounds of niiik. ai times this amount, food at one-third the eipenei thai we find tin- densely po] le voting their attention to c! me of the greatest things in the soil of its oatural feti rv Agriculture, in with one of tl rountry. This al attention to o:l;iy than it •■vit » i » , 1 ■ • \**V1j"llltlt } " t ' 1 1 i ' T i </seg>
            <seg id="p106">\I. CONVENTION \.\ 99 e land " Wealth may be define 1 mi- or happiness of man. and be transferred from one lie sun. soil. air. water. ulturi.-it ti lin tlie largest an I out&lt; (ime of true purpose in the activities of life farmer as a man of real cul- s found only in idleness and history of air. ny better than it ivIihii feil t!&gt; dairy lection of better t! t this ezha t ioil. unless rou that should be seriously consid- uil rentra We hav w tint from poor farming in our eastern e tbiim in our southland: and are of dairying that might i». dis. nist always &lt; laim our at- ire and production. During the past few through the press an 1 other anufacturing: some pr ratlve and others &gt;\ mentions have not been They remind nit t religious denominate us You take a the ne. essary Hgenl for salvation. friem's still dins to the doctrine of for. nominations do not thiun either ■iiit denominations kinji fin the same mils ■en committed who thought they lairy &lt; attle furnish anothe r of llol- I from any other and Ayrshires and In fact, 1 have heard some ...linst other I &gt; I qualiti ■ lualiTi </seg>
            <seg id="p107">I E&gt;ns in orded to niak ability to handle and ■ out tke best that is ■ ciualili&lt; at ion of thingi Kit i -\ * Put Mr. G hi make a It he liialiest 2.700 Minn won! ■&lt;l in , | </seg>
            <seg id="p108">\l MENTION 101 n trusted to him. It was students were to work at inst ;ul of &lt; otiiineiK inn at the Bd work lip. This in the creamery tern newspaper was asked ur young men - nic phrase: "Because too many of T y want egin at the top safe in saying us in. - due to lark of It is said that the sn&lt; - n v t ion engines for seve ■t, would rnnsi Bo, in running tioll el I and md sines for t t. would ihl (onsiiiiic or runni: nuery nsiin. runr iimery just be i arefully \va ist lie carefully Fully watched to prw- watched to pi is. tlic batter prodan tlie market. Anotl ■ produced nnisi Another important t butter pi irket. Anotl r important iimr si"i(ls to the be i) the bfsi tl! t ad \ ant a ■ three retinlreiiM nts ret arm for th u tbe country and i pat in charge tbe material in t reBM nis will !»■ in .i for their bun reUM nts will lie in ,i for t ir iir.try and iy and equip it \vit!i -killel it with -killel rial in the right con- The bnaiMM of the that one ( annoi i right con- iss batter. The Im ic in Illlot ]l I to the Bten I'l All 1 n nt nut of Ins my other 1. i ii why mt on ule into tirst i lass butter. Tht makea sue. Dairying is one y mdition of the market The reason why farmer think 1 an n business knows ither liiiiii does, i had many stu- y did not need any instructions in Tlier&gt; rsuit. If a farmer has *1 pain.-; to tit tlieni know The f iii democ </seg>
            <seg id="p109">ASS&lt; [j ondltion is not cob fined to 01 Taking up the questirn of pr lered is the cow \ &lt;iu.i tna mint ma v * Mil II II * i KM whs ni \;ilrc thl 1 1 auMii \s niiotli I til •,vitv t;it mer 1 •Hxing the creamery bu I'l till Ml f i:t kind el •ill II &lt;()« IS proillll !!1£ 1 HIS iyanls and ■ II the stet&gt;l&gt;;ilils. If nilk sampler. | oui itiit-r. so us to prel ;m even niii kly eaovgh to BII ;t bdj with tin- iiiinil i iiimDei </seg>
            <seg id="p110">103 KVEXTION When you pounds of milk l&gt;y the test ami of butter far the cow produce •is per month, you ran ap- ter fat t II t li . you i &gt;f batter fat she prodtmM in ■ (lurillK the &gt;■ 11 should. in lures in a you should ■ profitable and which are un- n her test, a person should ould inn clone their part in farm Ir |m it in turn per material or nourishment in li terial or nourishment in tbi ent weather When ti j nt weath When the I no fruit lie ili:| not inuiit riiit He di:l not inline liat'h meiiatelj 'hence under more favorahl. lice Mil er ire fruit it was to be liewn fruit re liave seen (killed dairyni. av i • low prices, simply bee an- his pearl A man of this arl A man of tlii- e little boy who construe tei i mi hoy w ho ronstrui te 1 a mud xceptins tin* hea:l an 1 one ar Ing the head an 1 one am mother insisted that h ahseiit -■ other insisted that t fellow was absent i&gt;v pond When the lit- I ftul wei i ai ks. It is n id were ,-, few tracks. It In ippointed. Some days aftei it m:l there, to his gnrprtl e arm. He followed thi.i man tve 1 tl nally the man became coii- Turnlng around be sail t li-l to tl )h. nothing much." the little lothin nt the man. At last the \l last ill What do you want?" The little vay before I hail finishe.l j with a good row an I - id finished you - 'Kid cow an I vould feel about like the little results in any business, a man nil have nrnmh to iut like the little noueh to throngs Germany wfe rouuli Germany with one day to (all on an old (lennati trying to make music on an oh! a few minutes, my friend . to ( all on an old (!• ng to make innate on an &lt;&gt;\&lt;&lt; few minutes, nay friend ie took it an 1 tunel it as only an selections, when the old Cerman ex - ill is worth live times as inin </seg>
            <seg id="p111">.1 i hiiilriini ( IK .. . . .. , . , , , • Tlu 1 i;rt':it s;ivi I </seg>
            <seg id="p112">105 w va V 7 average breeder cannot expect to told that the average butter pro- we we per cow. Today, the average is between »e can at I that we are progressing although not as rapidly as we should. I heard iv lately that there had been more advancement ars in dairying than there had been in the pre- I am not sure but what he was about right. ipon the question of feeding, would say that this itiject and one on which authorities do not vernor Hoard who said: 'The inside of a are in the universe." We do not thoroughly of the gastric juice and the digestive juices on •w. All these juices contain enzymes. We scientist, who bases his conclusions largely on and starch may be acted upon by the digestive nto a soluble protein compound. It is also t istrii and digestive juices have the power of nr splitting it up into as many as 18 other id that there is a possible chance of the digest - mie of the proteins into fat. The experiments l t (icneva. bear out this theory. He sent the experiment away to have all the elements produce fat in milk. In the feed that was Kiven period, there was only enough fat left to yet that cow went on and gave 66 pounds of anie time put on extra flesh. This demonstrates .1111 n the feeding question as we might be that the gastric juice, which is in the stomach always act the same on feeds on account of the i fferent cows. The same is true of people; all per- ame food. The successful feeder must neces- vidual cow. We do know that in June and the nr cows produce more than at any other time, t that they have an abundant supply of succulent f this condition could be carried through the entire year we would hear very little about dairying not being a paying business. not understand me as opposing a balanced ration because I at the man who can prepare a balanced ration for every cow e man. There are some practical things in connection with feeding that 1 think are sadly neglected. Take up milk, and what do we find? In a hundred pounds of milk we find 87 V4 per cent of The milk of a cow that produces 10,000 pounds of milk lv land this is possible), contains on an average 8,710 pounds of water. ::nti pounds of fat. 485 pounds of sugar, 340 pounds of proteirs matter and 7 5 pounds of ash To Droduce the above </seg>
            <seg id="p113">during the win 1 hpavv nroflnii'i- </seg>
            <seg id="p114">107 an additional ilk on lanl that is valued ltry; yet the ■aid to the farmers here. great quantitii *' turnips &lt;sfully food lally not far distant when t the pr- ntry have to wake up: the proili tion is little th arc i ■ tt k mi I lire of the .As f Bob Tayk n nioiis to th lually iiu- stine of for tuberculos t n f a few of the iiiu&lt; h higher in the eastern </seg>
            <seg id="p115">108 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION states being about 2 5 per cent. Cr York - are passing ordinances requiring th 5 the marketin and not only in the way of cleanlim fr&lt; a tu of view as well. There is a wav fn n in i \ and justly so. I want to show you where it is nece««ar i regulate the farmer Dr. Thompson spoke of the larg*- number of cattli hoes shipped to market that were foun easarily had to be rejected. He said it was almost ■a corn and time spent in bringm*: such (attl&lt; t to say nothing of 1 which the banket thai tubenulu - and it »,ts necessar&gt; t: iken to or stamp Mm out; that the that tuberculi' 4 and H measures be taker farmers should do th dair farmers should do their part and t hat agricultural - and dairy associations should see thai making it a misdemeanor punishah ■ for shi, k from on&gt;' :&lt;&gt;ther of cattle that had not That tl Elemeanor puni mother of cattle tl lid be prm* i one state ini ier s: inc I should be prosecuted to the limit. That this d ought from one state int&lt; without bein. n its earlier si miM I h - If you don't test \our &lt;att n don't know wh I If you don't test your tt Eit or not. wh&lt; iKe it inijiht easily : if it got into your herd have it or not. wl you learne&lt;i that they had it In &lt; ipient sta^c it minht i eradicated and you herd: if it got into your herd you would not know it for ;i long time time nnd it might then be time and it might then be too late tu eradicate or you might not ki. t until they died. One dairyman I remember li He El they died. One dairyman 1 remen a fine herd of Shorthorn cattle. It no more business and his only re*r test early. Testing for tuberculosi: ing whether it is in your herd and rent it spreading to other herds and milk from a sanitary point of v had a fine herd of Shorthorn cattle. It got in his herd and he could do no more business and his only regret was that he did n&gt;&gt; and test early. Testing for tubercu!&lt; r the purpose of deter- mining whether it is in your herd and eradicating it if it is and to prevent it spreading to other herds and also from injuring the and milk from a sanitary point of view and injuring the public health. If you are trying to build up a permanen aolutely necessary to test, and you must report the health. If you are trying to build up a permanent herd it is ab- solutely necessary to test, and you must report the performan rforn condition of each animal at once. In Denmark they eradicate this condition of each animal at once. In Denmark the radicate t disease promptly and effectively. I am not hf disease promptly and effectively. I am not here advocating a theor- adv- ocating a t etical folly in the eradication of tuberculosis for we have proved that etical folly in the eradication of tuberculosis ft have proved that rk in the vicinity in order to pro- Wfc we ran do it. The Department has taken up this wor of Chicago in conjunction with the Board of Health duoe sanitary condition, and we have cleaned up i dairies. we ran do it. The Department has taken up this work in the vicinity of Chicago in conjunction with the Board of Health in order to pro- dace sanitary condition, and we have cleaned up as many a as many as 1 dairies. Anyone who wants to eradicate this disease from his herd must L Anyone who wants to eradicate this disease fr ly to Dr. Peters, of your experiment station. Question: You spoke of some action being t aken to prevent </seg>
            <seg id="p116">RTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 109 an be done under the Federal law if it jed. The Department has established hicago and some of the other larger cities for the state requires such testing. If Nebraska Nebraskan who went to Chicago to purchase ? tattle tested right there which would attle into Nebraska if it were ascertained son went east to buy thoroughbred cattle he certificate to show that the cattle were all had a man tell me last year in the dairy busi - .lersey bull at a dairymen's show in Chicago, nd he got the veterinary s certificate that ght months the bull died. He had con np taken away. dairy industry and the farmers every- B among themselves in the matter of ght pass between the testing and in animals. Some act in 24 hours rd be i obtain proper mui h disease yi u have in your months 01 II is sufficient. x After the disease an:l infect othe the aninii-1 might year. In three util threw you were to buy an animal and from tubercu- Answer: No. you would not unless you knew the herd or the ■I to man. If I bought an animal • and he passed the test I would n not put the animal in the herd unless he had been on my place three u know, is of </seg>
            <seg id="p117">financially and otherwise. The prod ■tabltahmcal of the health of hi with proper food. Ttie rounD The i nnsunier of milk needs e-lm take milk into the elty a qa </seg>
            <seg id="p118">111 gladly pay milk no. an I &lt;.f the k of k ha ■ wyt ■ we have h an 1 smith with n i have COW II IK.I\&lt;. « -OXTKST st. Superintendent, attracted 1 a lively interest; ten cows were used in the r ive dairy test and coming I» iivilual dairy herds in the state: the cows were placed on an:! l&gt; . ughout the Dr. Whil D and suni- </seg>
            <seg id="p119">it the University of Illinois. One hundred and twenty-six n the contest, four being disqualified und ind were awarded a pro rata share of tl und Cf the -sful conte Cf the &gt;sful (ontestants i :. correctly placed the •ow and 19 the poorest cow: The highest or ! being mac i ii*r "■ students or graduates of th&gt; judge the tows a rope was stretche.l on the campus near the dai building and the rows lied to the rope thus giving abundant oppo Eiation is greatly ind . Frost and others at th operlv arranging an Her. E List of the A I mil' T. B. A I ler n Ake Anthi ■A. Arnistini rles Rerrv IH. Blakt P. Hrin i. H. Pn m now. II. Birman irrett : h Hlechi titon . A. Huehlei On Her I'k. M. Cole . . Dem.c m. Davis. WB. A. Doubt "Woener DeCroi: Wni Dav John Dobson Frank Doub m luded in the list Riven: seventy-li . ontestants scored 7 2 or more |&gt;oints out of tunity to inspect the rows l&gt;y th&lt; II H. Com Cann ■\V I' r.irltor </seg>
            <seg id="p120">N 113 Score F. T. Ryan 79 Willis Rogge 74 8 W. E. Roueche 70 I E. Roberts 71 86 David Rees 66 80 B. B. Rice 70 L. K. Schoenleber 78 W. O. Schoenbeck 72 58 67 John Sneddon 87 68 J. B. Smith 74 .66 Frank Soukup 74 Roy Stephenson 76 6 2 A. Sohlickbernd 75 64 B. Schobert 76 78 Ralph Saul .84 M. M. Sterns 68 58 George J. Thege 66 67 Herman Ullrich 76 74 F. A. Ullrich 86 J. If. Weber ,x4 I. W. Weber 7l' Pernlianl Witt. . .68 • u to B. Werner. . . . 66 7.' R. B. Whitmore Ill: DAI! v i:\hiiut of the association. ;i very credible affair un at ttie statp farm arranged and attracted n-kages were scored en the fol- were scored en the fol- , color 15, salting 10, style of No exhibit was awarded any of olor 1",. salting 10, style of package an.l pac king .", : Total 188. package an.l packing ~&gt;: Tot No exhibit was awarded any of the pro rata premium money which rata premium money which lid not score 85 points out of a lid not score 86 points out of a possible Iimi points. po The following are the scores of the exhibits 70 66 L. B. Taylor 72 64 Roy 1'hl 88 H. C. I'rbauer 64 64 C. Van Tine 82 76 Emil Van Ohler ! i.hn Vanskiver 64 </seg>
            
            <seg id="p121">IWJ.NUMBCR Or HAND SEPARATORS number or aowREMiLEa ,Mur*iatR or mi EACH COUNT ; oun^ No Squor, No MU No Hand Counry Mo Souar, N. IJUW. No Ha d Coon.y No^or, H.J1** £*.£ ETlTH i ! IPs 1 I Coun^ No Squ&amp;rt No Milch No Hand County No 3quar* No Milch No Hand County No Square No Mikh No miles Cows separators miles oowj Separators mi'« Coxvs 3&lt;pai Adam* 3^*■ V +7 **° Cheyenne ifaoi 4.571 lEO Frontier 980 b)=*l 4o Antelope 87* i^fcii ip4o Clay 58fc mill *53O as 715 8.668 86 Banner 744- lol CoHon +O5 8889 +00 Ccq# 6Sb P495+ 5! Cou t3 Cuns 3&lt; FurnOJ 715 8888 Ccq# 85fc 1495+ i»a y Bla.ne Tit 4 + J 3o Ci/minq J80 u'll I J4-0 Cordeld st8 I.7i7 Roon* Mfa ICX8I9 5ZO Cuslcr i,595 U.14t l,2k0 Colpfr +72 4;48* n,e Bo» lioffe i/&gt;78 5117 ISO DaKofa 'tt4 4.H4 to Grant 7b0 4+1 lo Boyd J53 (^71.1 SoO Oawes *»ll 4E93 He Grfflty 58O 0.451 &lt;32O Drown t.tti 1&amp;.1 130 Dowsoo ivui (687 7"C H «"il 51.1 7378 J7o Tnorslon 39k 3411 |O0 Buffalo 983 11,418 S4O D«u«l Zpil J7M ■ 10 Hamilton 550 10.440 J30 ,♦1 50 Uorf «7b *}tt 3.1O Dixon *5O io,4l8 ISO &amp;" 5fct 1«ol *70 Luqan 57I» Butlir J6d u.Z»S 3io Oudqe i i9 I l,o*« fclo 7t5 J.i« Cidar 125 IIJBJT 5oo Dunclv 3Zl MW 170 ISlO 15.7*6 'HO gS? - S2X. s: s izr &amp; vk s Chase 9OI Jfcil 1 80 Fillmor« 5b8 10459 »to K«r 7H i it Cherry i89i *.2«l ISO Franklin 5b8 81-to *^o jrd 514 iji&lt;J JW </seg>
            <seg id="p122"/>
            <seg id="p123">115 tary 131.52S 246.1 512.544 879,000 366,456 71 11.3 1 1 1.7L'6,180 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">116 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Pounds creamery butter manufactured (c) ( l&gt;07 i *27.r 1 74.70O Number hand separators (c) ( 1906 ) 30.690 Average No. hand separators to each 4 farms 1 ( • ) Partly estimated NOTE — In the various tables, the authority for statistics quoted is indicated as follows: (a) U. S. Census (b) Reports V. S. Dept. of Agricult (e\ Reports Nebraska Dairymen's As (v\ Reports Nebraska Dairymen's Assoc iatioi TABLE NO. -2 TAItl E NO WESTERN NEBRA; WES TERN NEI RASKA Area, sq. miles, (being 4 Area, sq. miles. I being 4t; per &lt; ent of total No farms, (a) ( t&gt;«0 » ... . No farms, (a) ( l'jni Dairy cow population lai I Dairy cow population Dairy cow population (litoTi on Dairy cow population ( 1 Average No. Dairy cows to si|. i . Average No. Dairy cowl tt Average No. Dairy cow Average No. Dairy COWS to farm No. hand separators i &lt; ) (19 No. hand separate Average No. hand separator! NOTE — Western Nebraska (Table No. Average No. hand NOTE - West of the state lying west of tin of the state lying west Dawson. Ouster. Blain and Brown i i Dawson. Ouster. Blain an 1 Loup, Garfield. Wheeler and Brown i on Loup, Garfield. Whi with a dairy cow population with a dairy mile, it can I mile, it can be readily seen can (the manufacture of creami manufact a central plant as no where in this terriu a central plant h cow population to warrant the establish] cow population to warrar t there are con there are considerable ship'. state to central plants and in thi^ state to central plan steadily on the increase: as the purpi steadily on the ini tl commercial dairying, the production of mill commercial dairying, the production facture of creamery butter, also the condll facture of creamery butter, also tr n ■ in comparison with like conditions in t in comparison with like conditions in the st ieemed best to consider only dairy con • the dairy industry is more largel} icemed best to consider only dairy con relative importance: hence Western Nebraska will not be im luciett ir making comparisons TA1U.K NO. :i EASTERN NEBRASKA (Being that portion of the state not herein design*) </seg>
            <seg id="p125">IXNUAL CONVENTION f the total area of the 41.630 1 0 a . s 6 4 entire state) (a) (19ii' 246.1 460.7^0 n basis of 7 1 per cent 7N7.S31 ate ■2 27.600 f arm 1- sijiiar a nslii| TAIH.K NO. I low A fi Ml -JX.6HJ i 151.2 00) 1.432.648 1.555.000 Ir ation II! 1.353 dairy cow population ■\ uare mile ( 1907) ri dairy rows to farm (190 ,£ m to 1 dairy cow ■ ■&gt;. farms in township ( 6miles square) Ul A township TAH1.K NO. .-■ \V1S( ONSIN 56.040 169,795 Average No. acres in farms (a) ( 1900) 117 Dairy cow population (a) ( 1900) 998.397 Dairy cow population (b) (1907) 1.392.000 Increase in No. dairy cows 393,603 Per cent of increase in No. of dairy cows 39 Average No. of dairy cows to square mile ( 1907) 24.8 Average No. dairy cows to farm 8.2 Average No. acres in farms to 1 dairy cow 14.4 Average No. farms in a township (6 miles square) 197 Average No. dairy cows in township. . . *t&gt;» </seg>
            <seg id="p126">, rn Nl rVn&gt;») Th of f . .1 rr.i lv V»» ,1 i«P Ni: K'e No ( ftmilo f 'PftT V**l»r«s; iidy of the above tabu regard to certain conditions in each of requires li-ss ac res u i sive fariiiinii profit ■ABLE XO. &lt;t. K(\ote) The nun creamery i ho gvprn **■»&gt; n i t.oH from iv of •(Tl I VliON Averact' No. fan eat of increase in da population 1900 t;&gt; Average No square miles i ROA Hairv i nu-e </seg>
            <seg id="p127">A 119 lairy cow to 21'. 2 acres a farm has 1 dairy cow w population from 1900 to states in Nebraska being 71 per cent, the per cent as great as in Iowa and large per cent of increase f improved conditions, better in previous eration of a local creamery fluient number of dairy cows, the creamery as ;in&lt; e of iver the milk or ■ .mum distance which would )on tl ier of the the dairy herd, that is, a ily afford to deliver of ."&gt; miles while the owner of 6 jperation of local creameries, conditions t Nebraska as in Iowa or Wisconsin is raaka there is an average of 18.8 dairy 7.7. in Wisconsin 24.8, also in a Iowa jf dairy cows -in Nebraska 4 2.5 i : taking the last bat taking the average dis- uch a creamery in each of would be in Nebraska 145 no small item ■ day, 3000 Eastern Ne- vn&lt; mportant in commercial u tant it is in the ■ aery where it includes private test we have trans by rail: before considering transporta ial dairying, let us which has had a </seg>
            <seg id="p128">120 assist in a clearer understanding of the matter, attention vited to a dairy map of the state, published by the Nebraska Dairy men's Association, which is made a part of this bulletin. Nebraska a plain or prairie state, devoid of mountains, extending some miles north and south, having an elevation of about 1000 feet at its eastern border and increasing in elevation at a quite uniform ris of from 8 to 10 feet to the mile reaching 5000 feet at the western border, a distance of about 400 miles. Eastern Nebraska, the dairy section, is about 200 miles from east to west by about the same tance north and south The railroad system of the state consists of three trunk lines ex tending entirely across the state from east an verging at a common center on the eastern border. These rail have, what is termed, river grades and for the delivery of cream t central creameries it is all down grade. In Kastern Nebrask is a complete network of branch lines extending into ev and as trains on branch lines run to connect with through trair the main lines there is the least f cream from branch line station &gt; trains it is delivered speedily and without delay to 1 1 1 ■ creameries situated at convenient ra station' in Eastern Nebraska (of wr there are one or more cream re&lt; ei ceived, weighed, sampled for test ins an capacity shipped to the central factor is a most condensed product averaging that is in 100 pounds of cream ther from which can be manufactured abou "over run" as it is termed being from cream receiving stations are a less average distan than would be local creameries for there we such a creamery at each railroad station. As a stations are open for business, during business hours, da the dairyman is not compelled to deliver his (ream at fixed h&lt; experience and observation shows that a major portion delivered at such stations is delivered by some member of the fam other than the "man of the house" also that in the delivery cream the trip is not always made especially on account of th cream but in connection with a trading trip to the store or a social visit to town acquaintances. There is no question that so far as the dairyman is concerned dairying by hand separator and central creamery system is carried on at the least possible expenditure of time and labor in transporting sale and delivery of the cream product In table No. 1 is given the number of pounds of creamery butter manufactured in the state in the years 1900, 1905 and 1907. the increase from 1900 to 1995 is 85 Der cent and from 1900 to 1907 the </seg>
            <seg id="p129">121 t This great increase is partly due farm butter and the selling of that of the creamery butter nt was by the centralizer system lat of the creamery butter manu- 9 4 per cent was by the centralizer increase both in per cent of :i f the creamery butter manufactured for to be plain indications of a most ipment of the dairy industry of the both on the farm and in the previous years. This satisfactory growth. nditions have not been brought about because of ed sentiment or feeling but are the nd natural conditions surrcv nding and ndustry of the state and of practical xperience nt on the part of both producer and con- KKAMERIES able, there were in operation, in ■ries as follows inc definitely whether some of the as ■central" for the reason lants receive ■ considerable immediate territory, delivered Mice other than the pro lucer of the one creamery operated entirely on v i Co-operative t had in 1907 a t&gt;66 pounds of milk from iouikIs butter. The average price l.nr, «-7 cents per IM pounds k wa The total receipts for butter fat &gt;f .231 cents per pound. The ■ 04. SI being .0253 cents per given as paid shareholders. The poula- pound. A 4 per cent dividend wa amery has been in - opera- the cr </seg>
            <seg id="p130">122 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN I COMPARATIVE EXPENSl DELIVERING .E MILK SEF ARATOR CRY A statement, in detail, of the yearly expel milk at a local creamery r taining tl H farm, also the delivering of hah ream at ; ceiving station DELIVER1NC nee delivered ( mi No. cows in dairy herd Total number pounds of milk Average per rent of butter fat in milk Total pounds butter fat Average No. lbs. milk deliv Total No. trips, delivering k Average time required Id makt Delivery expense. :i 1 '■', tr raated loss in feeding va milk creamery as ramp hand separator on fai 10 lbs. separator milk at Total expense in delivering milk in value of separator milk Expense per pound of butter fat DELIVERING IAN I SEP i ice delivered (miles No. cows in dairy herd Total No. pounds milk -»» per cent of butter at n lbs. butter fat ■ trips. .'! deliveries per v. • for G men th Average time, in h Delivery expense. 180 hours at 30 if separator Kstiniated life of separator 1 US years it on cost of separato Oil and repairs for separate Annual separator expens Expense of separating, unit: </seg>
            <seg id="p131">\L C INVENT! 125 . Pierce </seg>
            <seg id="p132">rock Co-Op. Cry. Co., Cumstcx k Joshua, Hampton u ther, S. R. A: B(MM, Bancroft antown Co-Cp. Crj i Dairy, Grand Island Loup Valley Co-Op. Cry. Assn.. I); MrGinnis Crv Co. Amelia. tow Qn h Crv. Co. Newma Mo !.. O'Neill Red Cloud Cry. ( Riverti;n Crv. ( Schuy. Sergri- SprinK Craeh ILibory Cry ( st f'nint Butt Cox Bros same lfpre In 1 its ::u ter ani to fcrtht'i members of the Nflbni annual rceeliiiK Tie repoii I ducticn c:f the cowi making ui test. Of the ten raws entered t HIS fOR 1 1907. Owner, l"niversir. kis &amp; Golisworthy. Nor is Cry. Co., Lyons. . THE CO-OPERATIVE I Frit&gt;*;;iiis and three Shtrthorm follows 1. Mermaid. Holstein. bon Polo B.. .lev </seg>
            <seg id="p133">125 Freshened Jan 13, 1908. ). Freshened Jan. 13 Nebraska. Lincoln Freshened Jan Freshened Jan. 27, 1908. cows varied remarkably throughout atetl the same and fed according to of days in lactation shows fairly were in their milk Bow- So fat. ll.s 4r,!i.2"&gt; 5*9.25 ll-i 400.64 4tiT41 !"•&gt; 4.4 313.25 .;iw.4ii 7 :&gt;.4 311.23 3H3.W K5] 4 M* i 74 »».«» W3 3W t 4(1 llii.i 13H very good understanding of the butter production mm in the table gives the amount of ilk from each cow. The solids not fat it of butter fat — the richer the milk in fat content and the reverse. By the use skim milk, each cow is given credit for de of the feed eaten by each cow with the was approximated on a basis of the A w x oek, Nebr. n .June 20, 1898. Freshened Jan. 10, aska. Lincoln. n April g, ikland. Neb Lincoln. norn July 10, 1900. Freshened Jan. 23, ■hraska. Freshened Jan. 30, Nebraska, Line oln. liDin Nov. IS, l :•&lt;"&gt;. Freshened Jan. 15 on. Oakland. Nebr. nly necessary to give here the re unds. This makes a very </seg>
            <seg id="p134">r with the ., </seg>
            <seg id="p135">1 I t X Tl 71 7 L 'l Tl / . »- r i &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p136">128 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATIO.N Each weight given here is the av ings made a week apart, so .-*» umue a »eeK apart, so is very correct Tl, -hows that the condition of all the cows was verv uniform (hrn,,»h.,,,. was very uniform th cost of feed and the value of the product are not indu us report because they must necessarily be aDDroxin.ar...! approx are not representative. It is sufficient to know that the largest vield of milk, butter and solids was made by U&gt;« cow which had the long* rtion period ami cOMMMd U* In nthnr « ' </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>