<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00009">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00009</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA</title>
		             <date value="1902">1902</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p002">CATTLfc COMING OLT OK DOTIM TANK </seg>



            <seg id="p003">
By A. T. Peteks. 

HISTORY. 

There have been numerous reports of a skin disease 
among cattle and horses from various parts of the State of 
Nebraska. The first reports received by the department 
were in 1896. Since then the inquiries have become far 
more numerous and upon investigation we find that this disease 
has been prevalent on the ranges of Colorado, Wyoming, 
Montana, and Kansas for a great many years. Dr. M. 
E. Knowles, in a paper read before the American Veterinary 
Medical Association in 1900, stated that cattle men had reported 
this disease as existing to some extent for the last 
twenty years. It was generally regarded by experienced 
cattle men to be of little or no consequence, but they admitted 
that it had increased in the last two or three years. I 
have found the same conditions existing in our own State. 
"A number of reputable cattle men who have been in the 
range cattle business for thirty years or more believe that 
the infection came from the buffalo, and describe the disease 
as having affected the buffalo in the same manner. Old buffalo 
hunters still residing in Montana have described to me such 
a skin affection, claiming to have killed buffalo where the 
hide was worthless from a complete absence 'of hair, and 
covered with ulcers. They also relate that the disease appeared 
to be worse on the neck, withers and the base of the 
tail.'" This disease is also described by Dr. N. S. Mayo in 
his Bulletin No. 69, Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station, 
as early as 1897. He suspects that it was introduced by Texas 
cattle. I am also informed by cattle men that this disease 
exists in certain parts of Canada. In our own State the dis- 

BULL. 74, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR., VOL. XIY., AST. IV. 

'Proceedings of the American Veterinary Medical Association of 1900, 
p. 101. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 

Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs. 

ease in confined largely to the range districts. It has spread 
with remarkable rapidity within the last three years. This 
disease has been described by European authors as early as 

CAUSE. 

Isoroptic Scabies of the. ox is a skin disease affecting catjnly 
and is caused by a minute animal parasite, Psoroptes 
'mail*, var. bovis. This cattle mite is very closely reft 
to the mite that causes scab in sheep. Both belong to 
same genus and species, but are of different varieties. 
( not known that the sheep mite ever infects cattle, nor 
the cattle mite injure sheep. 

The cattle mite is very small, barely visible to the unaided 
eye. of long experience with this disease on Nebraska 
ranges maintain, until shown the little mite, that the 
disease is due either to freezing in hard winters, or to scarcity 
of food, causing derangement of the stomach. The 
mite can very readily be detected by scraping the crust of 
the skin with a sharp instrument and allowing this crust to 
remain from five to ten hours in a clean, wide-mouthed bot- 

tle.^ Some^ white specks 

will appear on the surface 

of the glass, which, when 
examined with a lens, show 

the details of the parasite. 

The accompanying illustra- 

tion, Fig. 1, shows the cattle 
mite, adult, female; Fig. 
2, the first right claw of the 
same specimen, showing 
disc more highly magnified. 
"In young specimens these 
discs appear to have a perfect 
bell form; in other 

Fig. 1 —Texas itch mite, Psoroptes 
communis. var. bovis. Adult 
female, greatly magnified. 1 (After 
Fig. 2. — First right claw of same 
specimen, showing disc; more highly 
magnified. (After Mayo.) 

Bmens it appears to have the form of a lily ; while in 
adult specimens it has the form oi a trident, as shown 
e drawing."* I have kept specimens^of cattle mite 

Bt should be noted that the disc on second left leg was 'cut out' by 
graver." 

•Kansas Bulletin No. 69, by Dr. N. S. Mayo, p. 104. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
Mange in Cattle and Horse*, and Lice on Hog*. 

5 

fin a small glass bottle in the laboratory at ordinary 
temperature from five to eight days. Exposure to 
bright sunlight seems to kill them in a very short 

SYMPTOMS. 

Cattle mange seems to be more troublesome during the 
late fall and winter than at any other time of the year. It 
usually disappears in the springtime when the cattle are 
turned on the pasture. Cattle of all ages may become affected 
but the disease seems to be more pronounced in yearlings 
and especially in bulls, because the bulls come in contact 
with most animals on the range, thus being more liable to 
infection. It has been stated by ranchmen that it is not so 
prevalent after a mild winter, but our experience does not 
verify that statement. It is certainly not due to lack of 
food or to severe climatic conditions, but the true cause is 
the cattle mite. 

The first symptoms noticed are intense itching of the skin, 
usually in the region of the neck and shoulders, and shedding 
of the hair on the neck and withers. The irritation 
may extend to the shoulders, the sides of the chest, and in 
very aggravated cases over the entire body. However, the 
most prominent points where the disease first appears are, 
the base of the tail, the neck, withers, and shoulders. The 
skin becomes thickened and very dry in places. It is not 
uncommon to find the skin becoming wrinkled, and the 
hair dropping off, leaving large bald patches of thickened and 
callous skin. As the disease progresses there is an intense 
itching and the animal will be seen rubbing itself 
against another or on wire fences or posts, sometimes causing 
large, bleeding scratches and sores In the advanced 
stage the animals may be entirely void of hair. This prodaces 
anaemia and if the animals are allowed to remain on 
the range without shelter losses are sure to occur. 

I wording to Dr. Mayo, if the hair comes off, the parasites 
that part, the bald area gets well and the hair starts 
¦ow again. Animals in the advanced stages of the diseat 
very little. They spend most of the time rubbing 
selves on posts or licking each other. 

This diso&amp;SG sDrosds vorv r&amp;T)icll v throusrhout licrcl Our </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 

Mangt in Cattle and Horaes, and Lice on Hog$. 

observation has been that, if animals have been exposed, it 
takes from four to six weeks before the disease makes its appearance 
in the herd. It is natural that thrifty animals 
should resist this disease much longer than cattle in a poor, 
debilitated condition. There is no doubt that this disease 
spreads by direct contact of infected with healthy animals. 
It is also true that railroad cars, stock yards, mangers, 
sheds, posts, chutes, and fences may be sources of infection. 

Gerlach and Mueller have remarked 1 on the modifications 
occurring in this form of scabies by change of season, reciting 
an instance where the disease prevailed among cattle 
every year, commencing towards the end of autumn, when 
the animals began to be housed, reaching its maximum in 
February, and diminishing in the spring, when the oxen 
were employed at labor. The crusts then became detached, 
the hair grew, and there remained only a few patches at the 
root of the tail and on the neck. The train of symptoms 
reappeared each autumn. Neumann observed that these 
parasites {pmroptes) persist during the summer, although the 
cattle appeared to be cured. Gerlach and Mueller found the 
parasites in great numbers on the neck and around the horns. 
The writer has also found a great number of these parasites 
daring the summer months at the base of the horns and on 
the neck, the animals showing no symptoms whatever of inconvenience 
from these parasites. 

Dr. Knowles in the Proceedings of the American Veterinary 
Medical Association of 1900 states that he found the 
parasite in great numbers during the summer months and 
was surprised at the slight amount of skin irritation during 
that time. It must be borne in mind that one must observe 
very closely to discover the parasites. In three herds in 
which the disease had existed during the winter and nothing 
had been done in the line of treatment, the writer found 
during the month of June in every instance the parasites on 
the places named. It may be that these mites seem to disappear 
during the summer months, as the ranchmen have 
discovered, but from our observations they still infest the 

'Neumann's Parasites and Parasitic Diseases of Domesticated Animals, 
p. 150 </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
Mange in Cattle and Horten, and Lice on Hog» 

7 

El, but cause no noticeable inconvenience during this 
hence, it must be that they feed on the surface and 
f the animal ; whereas, during the fall of the year these 
begin to burrow into the skin and produce this intense 
BJ (pruritus). 

TREATMENT. 

The problem of successfully stamping out this disease on 
our ranges is a very serious one. When only a small number 
of animals are to be treated, any efficient liquid remedy 
can be successfully applied by means of a swab, brush, or 
spray pump. This method has been employed in controlling 
this disease on the average ranch for a number of years. It 
lias been found to be both expensive and impracticable. 
When it becomes necessary to eo over a large herd of cattle 
affected with mange, then the above method will be found 
¦wholly inadequate. Therefore I believe there is but one solution 
of this problem, one practical and certain way to wipe out 
this trouble on our ranges, and that is to erect dipping vats 
so that cattle can be thoroughly immersed in a solution that 
will kill these mites and yet be harmless to the animal. Dipping 
is becoming very popular, wholly on account of its practicability. 
Dipping tanks are now a common sight on our 
ranges in the western part of the State. Cattle men are beginning 
to dip, at regular periods, cattle affected with mange, 
the same as sheep affected with scab are dipped. 

There are a number of co-operative dipping tanks in operation 
in different parts of the grazing country in our State 

Fig. 8 - Ground plan of the oattle dipping plant 

I they have proven to be a great benefit to the stock 
rers wherever they have been operated. The operation 
lipping cattle is not a difficult one but is precisely like 
of dipping sheep. All that is necessary is a crowding 
and a corral with a chute leading to the tank, 
he end of the chute is a sloping surface on which the ani- </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs. 

8 

mal slides into the tank, swimming through the preparation. 
See that the head as well as the body is thoroughly immersed. 
A simple plunge in and out of the bath is sufficient for lice 
or ticks, but immersion of from one to three minu'es should 
be given for mange. The process of simply dipping in vats. 
without the previous breaking down of the scales with brush 
or broom, will not allow the liquid to reach and destroy the 
ova and young momri, and their continued presence must inevitably 
cause the itch to reappear after a short time. For 
this reason it is well to insist on the breaking up and removal 
of the scab by means of a scrubbing brush or broom 
before dipping in vats. It is well to leave the animal in the 
tank from a minute to a minute and a half, and in very bad 
cases I would suggest longer On reaching the other end of 
the tank the animal ascends another inclined surface, which 
starts at the bottom of the tank, and which has cross slats 
to help the animal's progress, as he walks into a dripping 
pen. The cattle are allowed to remain in this pen for a few 
minutes for draining off and then they are turned out. The 
superfluous dip is allowed to run back into the tank or vat, as 
the floor of the dripping pen has a slope toward the tank for 
that purpose. 

In order to make this operation a success the dipping 
should be repeated within ten days, to kill the parasites 
hatched out in the meantime before they become old enough 
to lay their eggs. The same process is employed that is 
used in eradicating scab in sheep, regardless of the kind of 
dip used, for the life histories of the parasites are practically 
the same. 

Cows and heifers heavy with calf should not be dipped 
after they are more than three or four months advanced, and 
even previous to that time care should be taken to avoid 
crowding in the chutes. The plunge itself does not seem to 
be of any consequence. 

I; have found that warm solutions are practicable whenthey 
can be employed. The temperature should be from 
to il5 8 Pahr. Of course this depends largely on the 
atmospheric conditions and somewhat on the condition 
e cattle. The cost of dipping has varied from five to 
! cents per head for each dipping and the results have </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogt 

9 

been most gratifying, so that no stockman should allow his 
cattle to go through the winter without dipping them. 

THE BEST TIME TO DIP. 

I is advisable to dip cattle twice in the fall and again 
e in the spring of the year at intervals of ten or twelve 
. Usually we find that it is difficult to persuade owners 
p cattle twice at an interval of ten or twelve days. We 
this to be especially the case when the herd shows no 
ied symptoms of the disease. Experience has taught us 
it is best to dip twice in the fall of the year regardless 
le condition of the cattle. In the spring of the year there 
ot so much necessity of dipping twice, as the animals 
lot then so liable to reinfection as in the fall and winter. 

There are numerous dips on the market at the present 
time, and, no doubt, they all have some merit, but there 
have been a great many failures in dipping, possibly due to 
the fact that the dip was not efficient. We have made extensive 
experiments with the coal tar preparations and have 
found them effectual to cure cattle mange. The dips that 
have been employed by us are chloro-naptholeum and zeno- 

When using coal tar preparations, such as zenoleum or 
chloro-naptholeum, it is well to test the water. Where 
soft water cannot be obtained, add to the hard water sufficient 
washing soda or sal soda to break the water. This is 
best done by taking a small sample of water and determining 
whether it will saponify readily; otherwise these preparations 
will not perfectly mix with the water. 

We have conducted experiments in which we have dipped 
seven thousand head of cattle with chloro-naptholeum that 
were very much affected with cattle mange, and the results 
have been very satisfactory. We have numerous letters on 
file from parties who have dipped with the same preparations 
and have had good results. There have been a few 
complaints made of cattle becoming reinfected in a short 
time after being dipped. Stockmen that have gone to the 
expense of erecting a dipping vat and using dips of various 
kinds on cattle once or twice and then have found that in 
a short time their cattle showed unmistakable symptoms of </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 

Mange in Cattle and Hornet, and Lice on Hogs. 

reinfection have sometimes lost faith in the efficacy of the 
dip and method of dipping. The reason for these reinfections 
may be illustrated thus,— Mr. A has done his part in 
dipping the cattle to eradicate this disease; his neighbor believing 
the disease not a contagious one will not dip but will 
allow his cattle to roam at large, and thus Mr. A's cattle become 
newly infected by his neighbor's cattle. I have had 
my attention called to a number of just such cases. This, of 
course, cannot be the fault of any of the preparations in 
which the cattle were dipped. Failures have also resulted 
in the use of these dips because the solution was not of the 
proper strength and the capacity of the tank not accurately 
estimated. The . parties were under the impression when 
they were dipping their cattle that the solution was of the 
required strength, about 3$ per cent, but upon examination 
I found these solutions were less than 2 per cent and on that 
account no good results were obtained. I further believe 
that, when cattle are in the advanced stages of the disease 
and have large areas of crust, it is advisable, no matter 
what dip is used, to have the fluid in the vat warm. It 
stimulates the penetrating power of the dip and certainly 
- better results. 

The benefits that are received from the use of dips are 
very numerous. One of the old ranchmen in western Nebraska 
slated that since he had dipped his cattle they had 
made larger gains than in any previous year since he had 
been in the stock business. Another ranchmen stated that 
for a number of years since he began dipping cattle he 
found that it is not only beneficial in the destruction of 
mange but that it is also very beneficial in ridding the cattle 
of lice in the summer time, and it lessens the liability of being 
molested by flies and gnats. 

A 4 per cent solution of chloro-naptholeum was used in 
our field experiments and we recommend that these coal tar 
preparations be used at that strength. I have known instances 
where a much stronger solution of these coal tar 
preparations was used by mistake without any injurious effects 
on the animal. There is no danger at all connected 
with the operation of dipping. However, it is not advisable 
to dix) animals that are in the advanced sta£res of Drefirnnnov </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
Mange in Cattle and Hones, and Lice on Hogt. 

11 

After cattle have been dipped they should not be allowed 
to lie down in the old infected corral, nor to mingle with diseased 
cattle. It is better to wait for some time before taking 
them back to the old range to feed. If these precautions 
are not heeded I doubt whether one or two dippings with the 
very best dip that could be secured would assure the owners 
absolute safety from reinfection. For this reason it is of 
great importance to use all necessary precaution against 
the reinfection ; otherwise the procedure of trying to stamp 
out this disease becomes very expensive and discouraging. 

In conclusion I wish to mention a few conditions resulting 
from mange. The writer has seen numerous herds that were 
reported to be dying with some mysterious disease. These 
animals were a pitiful sight to behold. They were thin, 
emaciated, very much debilitated, and hardly able to exist 
under range conditions of the most favorable kind, simply 
because they were one mass of running sores and scabs. 
They were too poor to go over a large territory each day to 
pick up their food, and soon would die. They were also 
bearers of infection to the remainder of the herd and especially 
to the young stock. Animals that have been affected 
with mange need more and better food to carry them through 
the winter months. 

Iimatic conditions are of great importance. Animals 
:ted with a very bad case of mange very often die in sestorms, 
because they have lost the natural protection, 
hair. 

The young calf crop is also an important consideration 
in mangy herds. It stands to reason that cows affected with 
mange and having to endure some of the above-named conditions 
are very apt to abort. The writer has seen a number 
of herds on the range in which abortion occurred on account 
of lack of vitality to carry the young the full time. 
The writer has also observed that when mange existed in 
herds it was not uncommon to find that the young calves were 
born weak and with less vitality. For this reason a large 
number of them would die three or four days after birth with 
what is commonly known as calf cholera or white scours. It 
is also a fact that in herds where mange exists the first animal 
to become infected is the bull. If nothing is done to </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 

Mange in Cattle and Horiet, and Lice on Hog*. 

B r e the bull of this parasite, he will soon run down in 
and, if allowed to remain in the herd, not only will he 
; the whole herd but his get will be of inferior quality. 

Taking economy into consideration, we find it costs considerably 
more per head to winter animals affected with this 
disease. The facts that are in favor of dipping cattle^for 
mange are overwhelming. 

I conclusion, I wish to say that dipping is, on general 
iples, a treatment that is most beneficial to cattle and 
lat will certainly become more fully recognized in the 
3. A ranchman that has seen its effects in the healthy, 
f coat of an animal regularly dipped will not hesitate 
t his herd through the dipping vat. The appearance 
imals that have been dipped speaks for the efficacy of 

this treatment 

LICE ON CATTLE 

K4. — Short nosed ox louse, — Hcematopinu* eurysternus ¦ a, female; 
rum; c, ventral surface of the last segments of male; d, same 'of 
i; e, egg; f, surface of same greatly enlarged. (From Osborn, U. 

S Dept of Asrr ) </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
13 

Fig. 4 is an illustration of the 
short-nosed ox louse found on our 
ranges. Fig. 5 represents the 
long nosed ox louse, which we find 
to be just as numerous. The methods 
employed in eradicating scab 
are just as successfully used in 
destroying lice on cattle, and therefore 
should be used to protect the 
stock against these parasites. 

DESCRIPTION OF A DIPPING VAT. 

Fig. 5. — Long-nosed oxlouse, 
Htzmatopinus vitu 
It; female, under surface 
of last segments of abdonit-n 
of same, showing 
bnish-like organs — enlanred. 
(From Osborn, U. 
S. Dept. of Agr.) 

"We manufacture a dipping vat 
made of 2-inch lumber and dadoed 
and dowel pinned staves, in the 
same manner as a supply tank is 
made, with four girts or ribs on each 

¦Ma. The top rib is a 4x4; the others are 2x6 stuff. Bolts 
pass through the bottom of the vat holding the staves on 
tight. The ladder end is 15 feet long and well cleated, making 
exit for the animal easy. Six bolts pass through the 
vat just under the ladder, making a strong clamp. Three 
bolts pass through the vat at the square end, holding that 
portion firm. The top 2 feet of the staves are tongued and 
grooved, to save the splash in case the staves shrink in that 
part that stands above the ground and above the liquid. 
This vat is 24 feet long at the top, 9 feet high, 18 inches 
wide at the bottom and 46 inches wide at the top. When 
filled to the depth of 6 feet it holds 1520 gallons. The slide 
is made of 2-inch stuff with sides of the same material. The 
bottom of the slide is covered with galvanized iron and 
when kept wet is very slippery. This slide is 24 inches 
wide and 90 inches long, with a lip of iron that fastens on 
the under side of the slide to the vat to prevent a leak. 
This slide enters the vat at the 6-foot or liquid line, thus 
avoiding the splash and danger of the former trip board that 
threw the animal down three feet to the liquid and often out 
into the center of the vat. Now he slides in at the end without 
jar and gets the benefit of its whole length. The top </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hog*. </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hog*. 

15 

edge of this slide should be even with the top of the ground, 
so that the animal walks in on the level from the chute and 
crowding pens, until he touches the iron and slides easily into 
the tank. The draining pen should be made 16 feet 
square, of 2-inch material tongued and grooved. This floor 
or pen should be divided into two parts of equal size, with 
a gate that will swing each way on the center fence, so that 
one pen can be filled while the other is draining. We also 
make seven stringers to go under this floor, which are concave 
so as to cause this floor to dish to the center; then by 
having the outer end of the floor about 6 inches higher than 
at the vat, the liquid will first run to the center, then back to 
the vat. This floor should be so placed that the center 
plank sh;i 11 just rest on and lap over the end of the vat, so 
that there will be no place for the liquid to leak out. Around 
the edge of this floor should be nailed a strip of 2-inch stuff 
to prevent the liquid from running off the floor. Build a 
good high fence around this floor. 

I The chute leading to the vat should be not less than 32 
long besides wings or crowding pen at the outer end. 
last 16 feet of the chute, which contains the slide, 
Id be tight and smooth, so that after the animal begins 
ide nothing in the construction will give him a chance to 
i anywhere and hang with his weight down in the vat. 
chute should be just 2 feet wide at the bottom and wide 
gh at the top to allow a large animal to pass. A chute 
aet long with wings 8 feet long and material to fence a 
as stated above, will require 55 posts 2x6-16, 8 posts 
L2 and 22 good 10-foot posts. 

"DIRECTIONS FOR SETTING UP A DIPPING VAT. 

I Cxcavate a hole 8 feet deep, 24 feet long at the top, 13 
long at the bottom, 3 feet wide at bottom and 5 feet wide 
tie top. Place the bottom of vat within a few feet of 
pit as near level as you can, and block it up from the 
ind three or four inches. Place the square end and stay 
it with a brace ; then, as you stand at the outside looking at 
the square end, on the left side place the staves that are lettered 
and on the right side those that are numbered, beginning 
with the letter A and the figure 1. As you place a </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
Mange in Cattle and Hortes, and Lice on Hogs. 

16 

stave, tack the lower end — after the dowel pin has been 
placed — to the bottom of vat, but leave the nail out far 
enough to be drawn later on. When the long staves have 
been placed and you have reached the other end of the bottom, 
place the ladder with the foot just to a line marked on 
the bottom and raise the outer end up eight feet and prop 
there. Put on staves enough to reach out to where the 
second rib from the bottom will extend, place the 2x4 on 
each side and tack parallel with the ladder. Put the cross 
pieces on and tighten enough to hold the vat in shape. 
Draw the nails in lower end of the staves, place the lower 
rib and the bolts that pass through the vat. Do not tighten 
any of the side bolts until the vat has been completed and 
tightened at the end rods. The other ribs can now be placed 
and the balance of the staves. The cut on lower end of the 
stave will show you as to the height of the ladder, as the 
edge of the ladder and end of staves should be even when 
the staves are all placed and the long bolts all entered and 
drawn up. Go on the inside of vat, and should there be 
any signs of an opening under the foot of the ladder, drive 
in a little oakum (placed in the box of bolts for that purpose), 
then place the block over the foot of ladder and turn 
down the lag screws. Place the slide flush with the inside 
of the vat, nail the iron down on the under side and nail the 
sides to the vat. 

' 'By Forest Lumber Company, Geo. W. Clark, Agent, 

"Alliance, Nebraska." 

Iie material required for the tank proper will amount to 
following: 550 feet of 2x12 tank lumber, 100 feet 2x6 
»w or white pine, 80 feet 4x4 and 64 feet 3x4. Twenty 
ids of 20-penny nails will be required besides the iron 
i purchased of the company. The cost of this material 
be governed by the local market prices. 

I be pig dipping tank shown in accompanying cut may 
constructed similarly to the cattle tank heretofore 
ribed. A galvanized tank can be built by any tinner or 
be purchased on the market from firms handling dips, 
may be used in place of the wooden one, but the setting 
approaches will remain the same. The iron tank is 
ily recommended on account of its cheapness and dura- </seg>


            <seg id="p018">
18 

Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hog*. 

bility in all kinds of weather and climate. A wooden tank 
will require 240 feet 2x12 tank lumber, 12 feet 4x6 white 
pine or tank lumber, 40 feet 4x4, 16 feet 2x6, 16 feet 2x4, 24 
feet 3x4. For the approaches and dripping board will be 
required 10 feet 2x12 tank lumber, 100 feet 4x4 yellow pine, 
60 feet 2x6, 114 feet 2x4, 162 feet fencing, 17 pounds 20-penny 
nails and 7 pounds 10-penny nails, 10 square feet of 
zinc, 4 T hinges 8 inches. A canvas curtain hung at the 
juncture of the crowding pen and the slide will serve as a 
blind and facilitate the driving of the animals. 

K details of construction may be ascertained from the acmying 
cut (page 17.) 

Sarcoptic Scabies in Horse*. 

Krcoptic Scabies in horses is a disease similar to the one 
•ibed in cattle, the difference being in the mite. The 
record that we have of this disease existing in our State 
1895. It has not spread very rapidly in this State and 
jxisted in very few herds. 

SYMPTOMS. 

The animals are found rubbing themselves against fence 
posts, sheds, wire fences, and the like. Upon closer examination 
one will find the skin elevated and somewhat rough. 
A number of elevations and many papules around which the 
hair has matted can be felt. When the crust is removed it 
leaves a moist, red surface. These papules increase in 
number and cause intense itching. With the loss of hair 
large, dry areas are formed covered with debris and thin 
crusts. These patches extend, and finally invade the entire 
surface of the body. I have not seen a case where the disease 
extended to the knees of the animal. The coat of the 
animal is dead and over a large portion of the body aggravating 
ulcers and sores are seen. These ulcers vary in size 
from that of an inch to five inches in diameter. The skin invariably 
becomes thickened, especially in the region of the 
neck, where it is attached by loose connective tissue and 
then appears in very large folds The irritation induced by 
rubbing and scraping is the important factor in extending 
the lesions of the skin. </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
Mange in Cattle and Hone*, and Lie* on Hog*. 

19 

•"The young larvae and the ovigerous females live in the 

intra-epidermic galleries or 
grooves which, in man, are 
indicated by a fine red line, 
from 10 mm. to 20 mm. long. 
These galleries are not vis- 

op 

ible in the horse, because of 

the pigmentation of the 
skin and the thickness of 
the epidermis. They are 

excavated by the female 
a ' immediately after Copula- 

tion; and they are rapidly 
formed, for in from 15 to 
30 minutes the work is completed, 
and all the more 
promptly if the temperature 
be elevated. It is for 

te 

this reason that these par- 

asites have been considered 
as noctambulent ; if they 
torment animals more by 
night than by day, it is be- 

c 

cause then the conditions 

of temperature — warm 
stable, litter, and probably 
clothing — are more favorable. 
At the point where 
the sarcopt penetrates, an 
inflammatory papule forms, 
but the parasite is not to be 
found beneath it, but at the 
other extremity of its gallery. 
' Our experience with 
the disease has taught us 

Fig 8— Saroopt of man A feeumlate'1 
female (#) forming its gallery or burrow A 
¦eml-dtagrammaiic figure, partly after Ger 
1Mb. From before 10 behind are seen the 
eggs Increasingly older, a. on. an. then 
come empty egg cases, c; o. opening for tbe 
escape of tbe larra; e, excrements. (After 
Neumann.) 

that it exists in both warm 
andTcold weather. 

We have employed the same method that Dr. Knowles 

•Neumann's Parasites and Parasitic Diseases of Domesticated Animals, 
p. 188. </seg>


            <seg id="p020">
20 

prescribes in the Proceedings of the American Veterinary 
Medical Association of 1900, namely, that of scraping. 
His method has been very satisfactory and we give it in 
full. "During cold or windy weather it is extremely difficult 
to discover the sarcoptes ; therefore, to not meet with 
disappointment it is advisable to have warm, sunshiny 
weather in which to make the search. It is necessary to 
make skin-scrapings to the blood and through the entire 
thickness of the epidermis with a sharp instrument. When 
the scrapings have been collected, they should be placed in 
a well-heated box, or in a window exposed to a strong sunlight. 
A small quantity of the debris, after it is well 
warmed, can be spread on a slide, and examined with a microscope 
with one-third or two-thirds objective. Should the 
slide and stage be warm, the sarcoptes will disengage themselves 
from the debris, when they may be removed with a 
needle and placed with a drop of glycerine on another 
glass." Fig 6. (page 19) shows how this mite burrows 
under the skin and produces these tunnels mentioned 
above. 

II bare had the very best success by using the coal tar 
arations, either as a wash or as a dip, using 
i at a four per cent solution. In the several hundred 
&gt; treated, we have had success with one application of 
but 1 would recommend two dippings in very severe 
i. The »ame kinds of tanks and dips that are employed 
e eradication of mange in cattle are very successfully 
in the eradication of mange in horses. (See preparaof 
tanks and dips in eradication of mange in cattle. ) 

The Value of Dipping Hogs for Lice. 

It has been known to the intelligent hog breeder that the 
presence of insects on the hog is a very serious matter. It 
is a fact that very few hogs are free from lice, and that 
breeders have been accustomed to use various remedies for 
the destruction of the pest. The favorite seats of lice on the 
hog are back of the ears, along the neck and under the beast. 
These vermin are bloodsuckers, and they produce in a short 
time a very weak, debilitated condition of the animal, mak- </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
Mange in Cattle and Harriet, and Lice on Hogt 

21 

Iiim far more susceptible to other diseases that the anis 
heir to. The louse has not been credited with occang 
serious loss, but of late years more attention has 
given to this little insect by the Department of An- 
Pathology. We have found that the hog louse becomes 
re serious enemy when hogs are out of condition. As 
e stated, it is a bloodsucking insect. If the accoming 
conditions are bad, especially if the pens are exvely 
dusty and through the inhalation of an excessive 
mt of dust there should be a slight pneumonia of the 
s, the animals badly affected with lice will be all the 
! apt to die. 

¦. 7. —Hog louse, — Htmatopinut uriut : a, female; b, ventral view 
terior segments of male; e, leg, showing protractile disk of tibia, 
ed. (From Osborn, U. S. Dept. of Agr.) 

We have also found that where animals affected with 
cholera were free from lice there was a much smaller percentage 
of loss sustained than where the herds were largely 
affected with lice. This has been brought to our attention 
aftpr pit Ami n i act numerous h6rds ill various TD&amp;rts of th© </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
¦ 

Mange in Cattle and Hone; and Lie* on Hogt. 

state during the last five years. The first rule that we now 
insist upon when we visit an outbreak of cholera is to examine 
for lice and, if present, to thoroughly destroy these 
insects. The breeding pens and hog houses are also thoroughly 
disinfected. All the bedding that is found in pens 
and hog houses at time of disinfection is burned. The 
method that we have for disinfecting the hog pens and hog 
houses is as follows: For the stables we prefer to use hot 
water and any of the coal tar preparations, such as zenoleum, 
chloro-naptholeum, and similar preparations. This is 
done by making a 3 per cent solution of either of these preparations 
and using it liberally with broom and brush and 
also with a spray pump. If you have any of the spray 
pumps used for spraying trees they will answer the purpose 

After the stables and pens are thoroughly disinfected the 
animals should be disinfected also. This can be done by 
dipping them, which is a far easier method than any other. 
Of course it necessitates a dipping tank. These dipping 
tanks can be bought on the market very reasonably. If one 
is not in favor of using the dipping tank, or does not feel 
warranted in spending the amount that it would cost to purchase 
one, a spray pump will do the work ; but in spraying 
hogs one should have them on a wooden floor and must have 
quite a large and forcible pump, so that they can be thoroughly 
saturated with the liquid. If sprayed, they should 
also be rubbed with a broom immediately so that the fluid 
will soak well into the skin. The solution that we recommend 
is from 3 to 4 per cent for grown hogs and about 3 per cent 
for small pigs. In our experience we have not found any 
harm resulting from dipping very young pigs. 

Spraying and dipping for lice can be highly recommended, 
as it is the only safe, rational thing to do if hogs are in 
any way infested with lice; and, as stated above, there is 
not a breeder of hogs "who has not been troubled with this 
insect. The remedy is to dip, and dip often. It aids the 
very best balanced ration that can be given to a hog, by enabling 
him to thrive and assimilate the food administered. 
Breeders who have begun to dip their hogs find it very economical 
and a very efficient method of ridding the animals </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
Mangt in Cattle and Hortes, and Lice on Hogs 

23 

Ihese insects. The coal tar preparations which have 
i mentioned — chloro-naptholeum, zenoleum, Lincoln dip, 
Lee's carbolic dip— leave the skin in a very soft, pliable 
lition, and I believe that it is a very economical and sen- 

sible way out of this difficulty. 

In conclusion, I desire to say that I do not wish to convey 

the idea in this article that it is absolutely necessary to procure 
a dipping tank. I have known instances where our 
American farmer, with his genius for making the most of 
his surroundings, has soon improvised a proper dipping 
tank with a very little cost. It is the purpose of the writer 
to urge every grower of swine to dip his hogs at least every 
three to four weeks to have the very best success, and also 
to use liberally any of these dips in his hog pens; and he 
will attain the very best results and in a great measure prevent 
infectious diseases from gaining any foothold on his 

premises. 

We herewith mention some of the well-known sheep dips 

Ii have been tried by the Government and found very 
;tual in the eradication of scab among sheep. However, 
sh to state that the lime-and-sulphur dips are somewhat 
serous. They must be prepared exactly according to 
formula given, for, if not, they are liable to produce bad 
ilts. It is not uncommon to find cattle with eyes swolshut 
after being dipped in'too strong a solution of lime 

and sulphur. 

KEROSENE EMULSION DIP 

Dissolve the soap in boiling water and while still hot add 

the kerosene and agitate thoroughly until cool, when the 
stock emulsion thus obtained should be of the consistency of 
thick cream and without the presence of free kerosene. 
When ready for use, dissolve in about twenty times its vol- 

ume of water. 

"LIME-AND-SULPHUR DIPS. 

"Under the term 'lime-and-sulphur dips' is included a 

¦J. S. Department ol Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bul- 
No. 21. 

lard soap or w. 
fater 

ha 

le oil i pound 
Igmllon 
2 gallons 

kerosene </seg>


            <seg id="p025">
25 

DANGEROUS FORMULAE. 

"7. California lime-and-sulphur dip: 

Flowers of sulphur 100 pounds 

Lime 28 pounds 

Water 100 gallons 

"8. A very dangerous misprinted formula to be found in 

several books and journals, probably due to a typographical 


"In case of fresh scab, formula No. 6 will act as efficacious- 

tthe dips with a greater amount of lime, but in cases of 
hard scab a stronger dip, as the Fort Collins dip, 
d be preferred, or, in unusually severe cases, an ooze 
more lime in proportion to the amount of sulphur, such 
e Victorian (No. 1), the Nevada (No. 4), or the South 

African (No. 3) dip might be used. 

"Many other formulae might be cited, but these are 

enough to show the great variations in the dips which have 
been used ; and to prove that when a party simply states 
that 'lime and sulphur' is an excellent dip, or that it is a 
dangerous dip, or that he has succeeded or failed with it, 
or that the lime-and-sulphur dip is injurious to the wool, his 
statements cannot be taken as definite, unless he also states 
which lime-and-sulphur dip he used and how he used it * 


"If a lime-and-sulphur dip is chosen, it is better for ordinary 
cases to use the solutions containing a small amount 
of lime and three times as much sulphur as lime, as the 
Fort Collins formula (33 pounds of sulphur and 11 pounds of 
lime to every 100 gallons of water) or the Bureau of Animal 
Industry formula (No. 6) (24 pounds of sulphur and 8 pounds 
of lime to 100 gallons of water), rather Jthan the formula 
with a greater proportion of lime. 

Ethe stronger solutions, as the Victorian formula (No. 
the present South African formula (No. 3), or the Neformula 
(No. 4) are used at all, their use should be conto 
unusually severe outbreaks. Under no circuin- 

Flowers of sulphur 100 pounds 
Lime 150 pounds 
Water 100 gallons </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 

Mange in Cattle and Horte*, and Lice on Hogs. 

« 

stances should the California formula (No. 7) or formula 
No. 8 be used. They are too strong, and the latter is especially 
liable to kill the sheep. • * *. 

"PREPARATION OF THE MIXTURE. 

''Almost as many different methods of preparing the liquid 
exist as there are different formulae, some of the methods 
laying great stress upon sifting both the lime and sulphur, 
others laying great stress upon allowing the liquid to settle, 
others leaving out of consideration both of these points. 
The method which has been found in the Bureau to be the 
easiest and most satisfactory is as follows : 

tTake 8 to 11 pounds of unslackud lime, place it in a 
box or a kettle or pail of some kind, and add enough 
to slake the lime and form a 'lime paste' or 'lime 
1 

' 'B. ' Sift into this lime paste three times as many pounds of 
flowers of sulphur as used of lime, and stir the mixture well. 

Ksure to weigh both the lime and the sulphur. Do not 
to measuring them in a bucket or to guessing at the 
t. 

"C. Place the sulphur-lime paste in a kettle or boiler 
with about 25 to 30 gallons of boiling water, and boil the 
mixture for two hours at least, stirring the liquid and sediment. 
The boiling should be continued until the sulphur 
disappears, or almost disappears, from the surface ; the solution 
is then of a chocolate or liver color. The longer the 
solution boils the more the sulphur is dissolved, and the less 
caustic the ooze becomes. Most writers advise boiling from 
thirty to forty minutes, but we obtain a much better ooze by 
boiling from two to three hours, adding water when neces- 

"D. Pour the mixture and sediment into a tub or barrel 

I Many persons prefer to slake the lime to a powder, which is to be 
I and mixed with sifted sulphur. One pint of water will slake three 
ds of lime if the slaking is performed slowly and carefully. As a 
however, it is necessary to use more water. This method takes 
time and requires more work than the one giren above, and does 
ive any better results. If the boiled solution is allowed to settle 
Dze will be equally a* safe." </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
Mange in Cattle and Horses, and Lice on Hogs. 

27 

placed near the dipping vat and provided with a bunghole 
about four inches from the bottom, and allow ample time 
(two to three hours, or more if necessary) to settle. 

' 'The use of some sort of settling tank provided with a 
bunghole is an absolute necessity, unless the boiler is so arranged 
thi.t it may be used both for boiling and settling. 
An ordinary kerosene oil barrel will answer very well as a 
small settling tank. To insert a spigot about three to four 
inches from the bottom is an easy matter. Draining off the 
liquid through a spigot has the great advantage over dipping 
it out in that less commotion occurs in the liquid, which 
therefore remains freer from sediment. 

E. When fully, settled, draw off the clear liquid into the 
ng vat and add enough warm water to make 100 gal- 
The sediment in the barrel may then be mixed with 
1 and used as a disinfectant, M under no circumstance* 
! it be used for dipping pmrpe 

f double precaution against allowing the sediment to 
the vat is to strain the liquid through ordinary bagas 
it is drawn from the barrel. 

11 watching the preparation of lime-and-sulphur dips by 
• parties the Bureau investigators have found some perwho 
laid great stress upon stirring the sediment w«&gt;ll 
the liquid before using the ooze. This custom is untedly 
responsible for a great deal of the prejudice 
h exists at present against lime-and-sulphur dips; and 
dering the preparation of these dips in this way there 
wonder at the immense prejudice against them in cerquarters." 


Accepted for publication April 12, 1902. 

Erratum — Foot note on page 23 refers to the extended 
quotation beginning with headline "Lime and SulpherDips" </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
NABOB. IN MOST ADVANCED STAGE. </seg>



            <seg id="p030">
AVAILABLE BULLETINS. 

The following bulletins of the Station may be bad on request : 
No. 1». Farm Notes for 1»1." 

B Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska." 
"Detasaellng Corn." 

B Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska." 
"Cost of Farm Crops." 

No. 30. "The Influence of Changes of Food and Temperature on the and 
Quality of the Milk or Dairy Cows." 

No. K, "Wheat and Some of 1(8 Products." 
No. S3. "Meteorological Observations for 1883." 
No. M, "Chinch Bogs." 

B. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska." 
. "Nebraska Weather Review for 18M." 

No. 88, "Nebraska and the Beet Sugar Industry. Report of Or. Mai Hollrung. Halle. 
Germany. Translated from 'Zeitschrift des Vereins fuer Ruebenzucker Industrie 
An Deutschen Beichs.' " 

No. K. "Some Obstacles to Successful Fruit Growing." 

No 40. "A Preliminary List of the Honey-Producing Plants of Nebraska." 
No. 41, "Water Supply In Nebraska." 

No. 4*. "Nebraska Weather Review for 1896." 

No. 4S. "The Conservation of Soil Moisture by Means of Subsoil Plowing." 
No. 44. "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet In Nebraska. " 
Mo. 46. "The Rainfall of Nebraska." 

¦ "Nebraska Weather and Climate for ISM." 
"Windbreaks." 

No. 40. "Suggestions for Chioory Culture." 
No. 60, "Notes on Pruning." 

B "Observations on the Codling -Moth." 
"Cornstalk Disease." 

No. 53. "A Preliminary Report on Experiments with Forage Crops." 
No. M, "The Effect of Certain Methods of Soil Treatment Upon the Corn Crop.** 
No. 66. "Ornamental Planting." 

No. 50. 'Method* of Tree Planting." 

B "Proceedings of Agricultural Students' Association, 1868-1886 ' 
"Annual Forage Plants for Summer Pasture." 

No. U. "The Homemade Windmills of Nebraska." 

B Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska." 
"Hungarian Brome Grass (Bromut tiwrmit )." 

No. 85. "Blackleg, Its Nature, Cause and Prevention." 
No. 66, "Sheep Feeding Experiments in Nebraska. 11 

B "Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet tn Nebraska." 
"Feeding Skim-Milk to Calves." 

B'Some Forage Plants for Summer Feed." 
"Locusts or Grasshoppers." 

No. 71, "Sheep Feeding Experiments in Nebraska." 

No. 71, "The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat." 
No. 73, "Experiment* tn the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska." 

Address, AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION, 

UbcoIo, Nebr. </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

or 

NEBRASKA 

THE GOVERNING BOARD 

BFORELL, President, Kearney 
. F. KENOWER, Wisner 

fN C. RICH, Omaha 
L. TEETERS, Lincoln 
CALKINS, Kearney 
ERNST, Lincoln 

THE STATION .OFFICERS 

B BURNETT, B. Sc., Director and Animal Husbandman 
LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist 
DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary 

WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

A. T. Peters, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist 
Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanut 
Hudson H. Nicholson, M. A., Chemist 
A. L. Haeckek, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman 
Lawrence Brcnek, B. Sc., Entomologist 
Ebwin H. B arbour. Ph. D., Otologist 
R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist 
O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer 
U. D. Swezet, M. A., Meteorologist 

A. T. Wiancko, B. S. A., Assistant Agriculturist 
H. R. Smith, B. Sc., Assistant Animal Husbandman 
J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist 
Henrt B. Slade, B. A., Assistant Chemist 
S. W. Pkrin, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm 

(thc maiNTt op thi uwivansmr) </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>