<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  STORING MOISTURE IN THE SOIL.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 114 BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXII, Article IV STORING MOISTURE IN THE SOIL. Rkport of Experimental Substation, North Platte, Nebraska \V. W. Burk. \V. P. Snyder, Superintendent. E. A. Burnett, Director. Distributed May 3, 1910. OVEN, BALANCE, AND SAMPLING TOOLS LINCOLN, NEBRASKA (Substation Bulletin No. 5.) Thk University &lt;&gt;k Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD « (tm« malNTt or ihi univimpv HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN. President. Lincoln HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE. Vnlley HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete HONORABLE GEORGE COIPLAND, Elgin HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER. Oriaha THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., Chancellor, ex officio K A. BURNETT. B. Sc.. Director J. S. DALES, M. P".. Financial Secretary \VM. W. MARSHALL. Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF E. Mf.ad Wii.cox. Ph. D., Agricultural Botany V. I. Ai.way. Pu. P.. Agricultural Chemistry L. W. Chase, B. Sc, M. E., Agricultural Engineering H. R. Smith. B. Sc, Animal Husbandry J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology A. L. Haeckeb, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bbuner, B. Sc, Entomology E. G. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy Frank J. Phillips. M. F.. Forestry Ebwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geology G. R. Chatburn, A. M., Highway Engineering R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulture O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering G. A. Loveland, B. Sc. LL. B., Meteorology C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc. Soil Agronomy W. P. Snydeb, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte Miss Vents W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany G. Herbert Coons, A. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany R. S. Trumbuix, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry P. B. Barker, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils) T. A. KressELBACH. B. Sc. A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops) Ebwin Hopt, B. Sc. Assistant in Agronomy (Crops) L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology M. H. Swexk. A. M., Assistant in Entomology R. F. Howard, B. Sc. in Agr., Assistant in Horticulture r. W. Burr, B. Sc. Assistant in Soils and Crops, North Platte; Assistant Agriculturist, Office Dry Land Agriculture, V. S. Department of Agri - culture rcES Cowan, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine Knobr, B. Sc. , Superintendent Experimental M'.hsfotion. Mitchell W. Perin, Farm Superintendent •Miss Louise M. Allen, A. M., Scientific Assistant, Seed Testing •Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">isA \. \V CANYON PASTURE \j[ \\ 47 \ 44 I42 \ / J \\ 10 ACRES, \ //-y — ~i\ V\ \ \ / EXPERIMENTAd] 1 8UB-8TAT ION \ / \\ NO. PL AT TE NEBR. \l }]\ I) BEMCHy LAND / -sit— '-* 37 36 LAND IS jgsasasiL 25 32 33 31 B B B 13 23 3O -H "2 ~3"~ — 4 -- 2O A A. A 12 1O 22 "- 28 -. IOACR 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">B o * 5 O to .■&gt;•" I *&lt;: °*b • T "Z ? "o7&gt; % &lt; * SJ 2 c Z m \J LJ s K ¥i. &lt; X K X '£; o &gt;K^ z &lt; z rv? o \' &lt;♦&gt; — o A f H . r. ■ •• t^: f^M £&amp; k i 2 j 1? Jl^m* *^il :'.. \z- i ■ 3 v, 3 an X &lt; X K 1 a i &gt;- z o o * E? \3;': •Jfc *§ «•"'&gt;'. '•"•■it I . • X * !■'. - .i I , &lt; n « _ 4 •? - # 1 1 $JSir»'«y^ • • • ■ • •*!• 3( SI mm ■l i 'i I -. a </seg>
            <seg id="p005">STORING MOISTURE IN THK SOIL. By W. W. Burr.* INTRODUCTION BY W. P. SNYDER. The development of the table-lands in western Nebraska de - pends largely on the amount of moisture available for growing the crop. How to make the best use of the precipitation is one of the most important problems before the farmer. The general decrease in precipitation as we go westward leaves a considerable belt of land in which precipitation is sometimes abundant but frequently is too small to insure a crop. When the rainfall of a single season i3 not sufficient to grow a crop that will give a net profit above the cost of production, it may be found profitable to store as much as possible of the rainfall of one season and add it to the rainfall of the next year. In this way we may collect sufficient moisture to insure a crop tho the rainfall of either season alone might not be sufficient. This system is practiced in many regions of limited rainfall and is the common practice in the Great Valley of Cali - fornia, Utah, Northeastern Oregon, Eastern Washington, and Saskatchewan, the chief wheat producing province of Canada. It is believed that some modification of the system of alternate crop - ping and summer tilling will prove the solution of profitable crop production in western Nebraska upon the good, hard, deep, tillable soil, much of which lis now used for range purposes. Where the soil is sandy or where a rock or hard clay formation come3 near the surface and prevents the storing up of surplus water, we do not expect the same degree of success from summer tillage as upon the E 'Assistant In Soils and Crops, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment tion ; Assistant Agriculturist, Office of Dry Land Agriculture, Bureau Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. Bhe work given in this bulletin has been done largely thru the ation of the Substation and the Physical Laboratory, Bureau of Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 deep, hard lands. We do not recommend summer tilling all of the farm land each alternate year, excepting in the driest parts of the state during a series of dry years. It is highly probable that summer tilling once every four or five years, followed by a crop of winter wheat, on the hard land in central and possibly western Nebraska will prove more profitable than to farm without summer tilling. It may prove profitable to summer till more frequently, growing more winter wheat, or to summer till for spring grain crops, but we have not been sufficiently successful with spring grain crops to feel warranted in recommending its extensive prac - tice. Our greatest success with summer tillage has been in the preparation of the land for growing winter wheat. PAji acceptable five-year rotation at the Substation farm which des summer tillage has been worked out as follows : Summer tillage (or summer fallow) from May to September; Winter wheat, sown in September; Corn; Cpring grain upon disked corn land (a light coat of manure ommended) ; E'ane or sorghum upon manured land spring plowed. gives one winter and one spring small grain crop, one for - nd one corn crop, and one year in fallow. All conditions indicate that some summer tillage and thoro cultivation of the soil to retain moisture must enter into the com - mon practice of the farmers of western Nebraska if the country is to develop to the best advantage. The farmer who summer tills occasionally and gives the soil thoro cultivation of the right kind will receive more net profit from his farming operations in a series of years than one who follows old methods. In previous bulletins the yields secured from summer tilled fields are given (see Bulletin 109). Other results of these tests will be published from time to time. In the present bulletin we have presented some of the data which have accumulated regarding the moisture in the soil on the Substation farm at North Platte for the years 1907, 1908, and 1909. We have picked from the large mass of material collected a few </seg>
            <seg id="p007">• gthat the farmer can put into immediate use. We show con - y that moisture can be stored and is stored by summer and that surface evaporation is checked by all thoro culti - that the amount of moisture which can be held in this way ient to assist very greatly during a dry season or during a eriod of drouth. Pie charts regarding rainfall show the extreme variations be - wet and dry years and the rainfall by months for the three under consideration. The natural laws regulating the relations between soil and water hold true the world over, but the application of these laws must be modified somewhat for soils of different types. In some respects the soil in different sections of western Nebraska differs widely, but so far as the storage of moisture is concerned it is probable that the results reported in this bulletin will hold accu - rately enough for all practical purposes when applied to the hard soils specified above. In giving the results of this investigation the aim is to show the effect of tillage on the water in the soil and the use of water by growing plants. From any curve or line on the charts showing the moisture in a field at a given time, one may note an increase in the moisture content of a cultivated field compared with an un - cultivated field. Where tillage is kept up thruout the summer and no crop grown, the moisture is held at a comparatively high point, increasing as the season and the rainfall continues, until it may reach a saturated condition, that is, a condition where the moisture is lost downward by seepage into the lower soils. Where a culti - vated crop like corn is grown, there is ordinarily an increase of moisture in the soil during the heavier rains, and this increased amount of moisture is held until it is used by the growing crop. When rains cease, the growing crop immediately begins to reduce the amount of moisture in the soil. By cultivation, water has been stored for the use of the crop and this may be used at a later time when rains cannot be depended upon to provide the water as needed. Cultivation serves to check surface evaporation and de - stroy weeds, thus holding for the use of the crop the water which </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 would otherwise be wasted. The most effective method of storing water in the soil has been by summer tillage. However, in culti - vated crops, as in corn ar 1 rowed cane, almost as much water has been gotten into the soil during the early part of the season as has been stored by summer tillage. It will be noted from the charts that a small grain crop gen - erally leaves the soil drier than a cultivated crop. This is prob - ably due to two factors: first, the water which goes into the soil is used immediately by the larger number of plants; second, the surface cannot be kept cultivated and loose and the rain cannot so readily penetrate into the soil. The seasonal rainfall, which usually begins in early spring and continues thruout the growing season of spring small grains, furnishes unusually favorable conditions for the growth of crops of this character without the previous storage of additional moisture in the soil. It may be noted from the charts that a soil which has been in alfalfa or grass for several years becomes very dry. It has been found true in every case that the soil on such fields is dry to a considerable depth and on the table-land it has beer dried out to a depth of at least 15 feet. Where alfalfa or grass land is broken, it should be followed by a cultivated crop that has great drouth resisting power, like sorghum or Kafir corn grown in rows. The cultivation of the crop aids materially in getting water into the roil. The cultivated crop also requires less water early in the sea - son. The yield at the Substation farm with either small grain or a cultivated crop has generally been small following either alfalfa or brome grass, due to the fact that the crop was obliged to depend wholly upon the season's rainfall for its moisture supply, there </seg>
            <seg id="p009">By W. W. Ik hr. In the spring of 1907 a laboratory was equipped at the Sub - station to make determinations of the amount of water in the soil. The purpose in starting the work was to determine the effect of various methods of soil tillage on storing water in the soil ; also the Kount of water required by growing plants, and the time such ter is used by the crop. GENERAL CONDITIONS. rPart of the land used in making these studies is bench or sec - bottom land, and part is table-land. The soil on the table - land is very similar to that on the bench. On the bench land, sheet water is only 35 to 40 feet below the surface. It may be that subirrigation takes place with deep-rooted plants like alfalfa. On the table-land the sheet water is from 200 to 250 feet below the surface and crops can not get water by subirrigation. This abso - lute dependence of the crop on surface precipitation gives the best conditions for the study of soil moisture. TYPE OF SOIL. PThe soil on the farm is a silt loam commonly known as loess, native vegetation was mainly buffalo and grama grasses. The soil is free from gravel and is easily tilled. The mechanical char - acter of the soil is quite uniform to a considerable depth, the most noticeable change being less organic matter in the subsoil, indi - cated by a change in the color of the soil. This change in color begins in the third or fourth foot. Mechanical analyses have been made to a depth of three feet. The following tables give the results of eight analyses : </seg>
            <seg id="p010">g «c « rt 2-i m— i© 1-35©' M«SIO boo©' 1-^ as'r^ac m' as'ac MIMfO OS -H« NaO" u; x o at on r-'©'^ 3 I ■ § -H rt O C^ f^ f^ C^ CO M JNon aci-oc esie-iio •r ■* •* ac -h to ict-'o ?c c*^ c^ as •*• co •* — m !* r g 1OIM Oh 388 ©0O 06 ao t- r- H^r* «3S 99S •-H ft- 33S jus as © — -r — • I 30 « 33 t- «O OS I .S Q a a i HiOJl cjeMm ION =■.©•♦ la'ioao icdcc '« i— me dacia ::•: — I I | I ; s p jl •&lt; I « § S I s | — —i— ~i — e -.-.-. coe*ji- Ni-Ci-l w II 6 2 «e«cs rt — &lt; •— ■ i— i »— » »— • *-N -" I . . . „, II ©CO oo© o © o l©c© ©o© ©o© c© © 1 « i "is H O HOOO aa&gt;« t-« © *«3 1 «e usaor- oosoo 5-.-. 8 -^ei« r«NM Uet« ~tc*m »ein «e«n — &lt;N« -nr; </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 From Table I we note that the soil has a low per cent of all material coarser than very fine sand. This, with the low per of organic matter, would indicate that the soil would bake &lt;&gt;r badly. However, the soil is easily tilled, this being due probably to the correspondingly low per cent of elay. Xo trouble has been experienced as yet with the soil baking or running together badly. In considering the work given in this bulletin, it is important that one should not lose sight of the character of the soil on whi -h the work was done. It is not claimed that the same results can be obtained upon soils of widely different character. The results will vary with the character of the soil. It is highly probable, however, that with most soils the results will be similar, tho the per - centages of moisture may vary widely. DEPTH OP SAMPLING. During the season of 1907, most of the samples were taken to a depth of only three feet but some to a depth of six feet. It was found that the moisture was affected below this depth, and beginning with 1908 most of the sampling was carried to at least six feet. We are therefore using only a small part of the Jata obtained in 1907. During the latter part of the season of 1908 a ten- foot tube was' procured and samples were taken to a depth of 10 feet. This year (1909) we have sampled all of our fields to a depth of 15 feet, as we found that the moisture was affected even below 10 feet. The reason for such deep sam - pling is to find the point where the moisture content remains con - stant; that is, the point where the moisture is not affected by the tillage on the surface or by growing crops. We feel that it is nec - essary to do this deeper sampling in order to determine how far moisture may move up from below and supply water to the crop; and, also, to find out if the water that is below the reach of the plant this year may not be drawn upwards during the winter and be used by the crop the following year. We must have these deter - minations before we can ascertain how much water was used by the crop, for altho we know how much water has been used from the upper six feet of the soil we can not say that this represents all the water that was used, unless we know that no water was used from below this depth. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 WATER IN THE SOIL. In order to better understand the work given in this bulletin, a brief discussion is given of the water found in the soil. Water is found in the upper strata of the soil in three con- ditions : 1. That which is absorbed by the soil particles from the water vapor of the air; called hygroscopic water. E2. That which is held by surface tension, as more or less thick - id films around the soil grains, and in the small pore spaces ween the soil particles; called capillary water. L3. That which is being drawn downward thru the soil, by the of gravity; called gravitational water. HYGROSCOPIC WATEiR. Hygroscopic water is that which an absolutely dry soil will absorb when exposed to a saturated atmosphere. The amount of water absorbed depends in part upon the type of soil. The finer the soil particles, the more water they will absorb. This water is held in the soil as thin films around the soril particles. It is of no value in furnishing water to agricultural plants. Hygroscopic water may have beneficial action in bringing into solution some of the plant food held in the soil, on account of its close contact with the soil particles. From determinations that have been made in the laboratory, and from studies made under field conditions, we conclude that plants are not able to use this moisture for growth where less than 7 per cent is present in the SOil- CAPII.J^A'RY WATER. CAPILLARY WATER. Capillary water, or that which is held against gravity in the small pore spaces adhering as thickened films to the soil particles, is the source of supply to growing vegetation. This water is free to move in any direction in the soil. Capillary force can draw the water slowly thru the soil to other portions that may have become dry. Such water always moves from the wetter towards the drier soil. It moves thru the soil in the same manner that oil moves along a lamp wick. As the oil is burned at the top of the wick the films of oil there become thinner and consequently exert a greater force </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Storing Moisture in the Soil 13 and draw oil from the adjoining portion of the wick. This portion of the wick in turn draws oil from the next, and so on down, lifting the oil from the bowl of the lamp to the flame. In the same way water is drawn slowly thru the soil. If the surface soil begins to dry out, the films of water surrounding the soil particles there become thinner and exert a greater pull on the films around the next soil particles, taking away some of the water from these particles. This causes the next film to become thinner and consequently more active and it draws some of the water from the film around the next particle of soil and it in turn from the next. If evaporation is eheeki &lt;1 at the surface the upward n ment of water stops as soon as the soil particles near the surface have as much water as the neighboring particles. If there is no addition or loss of water for some time, the movement of the moisture in the soil stops. Disturb the equilibrium by addition or loss of water and movement starts again. GRAVITATIONAL WATER. As a soil becomes more and more nearly saturated, we reach the point where gravity exerts a stronger pull than surface ten - sion. The water then begins to move downward thru the soil. Gravitational water tends to move downward and connect with the ground water or sheet water below. When the ground water is at a great depth, as it is on most of the table-lands, the gravitational water seldom reaches it. Under such conditions, the downward movement of the water continues until by distributing the water thru a larger body of soil the force of gravity is finally over by the capillary power of the soil. When the water that is moving downward is not carried too far, it is brought back by capillary force to replace the water used above and is in turn used by the growing crop. This is exactly what takes place when a field is given a period of summer tillage to prepare it for growing a crop. While the land is under cultivation and not growing a crop, it accumulates water in the lower soil areas. After the crop is planted and begins to grow, it draws the moisture from the soil nearest to the roots and extends the root-system into the deeper soil in search of moisture and plant food. f &amp; dry period follows </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Storing Moisture in the Soil 14 the water stored in the lower areas of soil rises slowly by capillary action to supply the needs of the crop. The movement of water in soils is slow, however, and the height to which water may rise from lower levels to supply the needs of the crop is unknown. We feel positive from our investigations that the water content of the lower soils is affected bv cultivation and cropping to at least 6 feet, and that all water within the first six feet of the soil is within the reach of small grain crops, while alfalfa doubtless draws its ■ from a depth of fifteen or more feet in dry periods. EXPLANATION* OF CHARTS. EThe per cent of moisture as used thruout this work is 1 he dry weight of the soil. For example, if a chart shows 10 cent, it means that there are 10 grains of water per 100 prams ried soil. The curves shown are made by averaging all the samples taken from a field or plat on the same date and using the average. The number of samples varied from i to 24, according to the size of the field. tThe numbers along the left side of the chart represent the per t of water; or, where a curve showing precipitation is given, h of the larger divisions represents one inch of rainfall. EPhe lower line of the chart represents absolutely dry soil. The er the curve representing the moisture of Ihe soil is from the line, the more water there is in the soil. The vertical lines represent periods of ten days each. To find the per cent of moisture on a certain date, follow the perpendicu - lar line representing that date to the point where it is cut by the moisture curve and read the per cent of moisture indicated by fi&lt;_ r  - ures on the margin of the chart. For example, in Chart No. 1, let us assume that the per cent of moisture in the summer tilled plat is required for August 7. We will note where the curve crosses this date and follow the horizontal line to the margin and find there was 17.4 per cent of moisture in the soil on that date. On the same date the corn plat showed 13.5 per cent and the oat plat 9.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 \\V have drawn a line across all charts at the point I ing 7 per cent, to indicate that the water below this line is prob - ably not available to promote growth. Therefore in studying the ch;irts we should judge the effect of a crop, or a method of til on the soil moisture by the distance of the curve above the line representing 7 per cent. EXPLANATION OF CHAH8 1. 2. AND 3 EThe moisture curves in Charts 1. 2, and 3 show the resul mer tillage, of a cultivated crop, and of a small grain crop, as cated by the storage or loss of moisture in the soil. The curves &lt;riven in Chart 1 represent the moisture content to ■ d.pth of only three feet. It will be noted that the three en start very closely together, having less than one per cent diffe 1 in moisture content. As the season progresses the amount of \ increases, but less rapidly in the oat plat, as this crop is i the water more rapidly than the corn at this time. The curve resenting the corn plat runs up rapidly during May. This i fore the crop requires much water. The cultivation keeps th in a very receptive condition and prevents much loss by era] tion. After the first of June the corn not only uses the rain i that soaks into the soil and is retained, but also begins^drawhi the water stored. The curve reaches its lowest point September 13. about the time the crop is harvested. The summer tilled plat ft! very little increase in moisture content during the summer, but at the close of the season has about 5.5 per cent more water than the eon plat and about 6 per cent more than the oat plat. This amount for the three feet is equal to about three inches of rain. B this there is a difference in the moisture content below, which not be shown where shallow sampling is practiced. Since the sea - son of 1907, deeper sampling has been practiced and it has been found that the difference for the second three feet is as great as that found in the upper three feet. Therefore there were probably more than six inches of available water stored in the upper six feet of soil by summer tilling in 1907. Another thing to be noted is that there was more moisture in the corn plat than there was in the oat plat. The cultivation of the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Storing Moisture in the Soil 16 corn field forms a soil mulch which keeps the water from escaping. This extra amount of water was needed later in the season to ma - ture the crop. If the water had been allowed to escape earlier in t season, there is little doubt but that the corn would have suf - d during August, and that the yield would have been reduced. Charts 2 and 3 show the averages of the moisture percentages in the upper six feet of the soil. They show a continuation thru the years 1908 and 1909, respectively, of the work shown in Chart 1. During both years the results have been very much the same as in 1907. By summer tilling during a season, several inches of rain have been stored in the soil for the use of the succeeding crop. Furthermore, where a cultivated crop is grown, during the early part of the season water is stored for the use of the crop later in the season. The curves also indicate that a small grain crop leaves the soil drier than a cultivated crop. It begins to draw heavily on the soil moisture much earlier in the season and during late June and July makes very heavy demands on the soil for moisture to mature the crop. If rains are abundant and timely the crop is increased. If water has been stored in the soil by a period of till - age before sowing the crop, this water is used to great advantage in developing strong, vigorous plants and bringing them to full maturity, where a lack of water at this time would have dwarfed the plants, shortened their ripening period, and reduced the yield. The corn crop drains but little moisture from the land before the first of June and if spring rains are favorable we find the moisture in the cornfield on the middle of June nearly equal to that in the summer tilled field. About this time, however, the crop begins to draw more heavily on the soil moisture and the moisture content continues to run down, while in the summer tilled field but little moisture is lost and they close the season with a wide variation in </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 » :j$ »*»^«s^gii 5 § o&gt;«n« is O o fe I- bl hi U 5 s8tj (A &lt;« "2 * e *== S 3 si - =« 5-5 Sg S* «C. I o ! S I ;-:! is ►0 i u 3 n a bf \Ss a ' * ? o I .■I 5 "t b "t ~ _L k»- + l Jj § &gt; at2fe«S?5558&gt; *O «M '. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Storing Moisture in the Soil K 8! 5 S g. &lt; K Ml 5 c| 8 §"^° t2 iliiil h h h si H II a J h a y/ \ — h^H- ssa^s 2— t-i^t-itfe- II Si t 3 l_L _S.' «k_ = *=q3zii3:WJ===: k A L &gt; _ 5p X- 42 §^ V t.\ hi -I \ • t5iS J2Jt3^5S'»- o0l&gt; ' N 0«o» w 5 w - 'o </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 .8_ g$ s &gt;e g at s s* =t s&gt;«n« a o i 4 . 113 •5 si S* j ? 11 Is sS Sfe 3| §£ ? a Si NO |« J n I? «i a| " ! : I / 2 3/ 5 o 3 $ fe fe *». U : i N n •« H «' i »' frtttt- 1 KM II II I 11 II II lQ)h *4 N n O ( 00 f^ V 10 •&gt; fO M •«. • </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Babies II, III, and IV give the percentages and data used in ucting Charts 4, 5, and 6. K'hese spring wheat plats are used to show the effect of contin - cropping as compared with alternate cropping and summer Kats A and B are in spring wheat each year. A is spring and harrowed. B is disked after the binder and fall . Plats C and D are alternately cropped and summer tilled. Plat C was summer tilled in 1907, cropped to spring wheat in 1908, and summer tilled again in 1909. Plat D was cropped in 1907, summer tilled in 1908, and cropped in 1909. A study of these tables will show that where a plat is summer tilled there is an increase in the moisture content, and that this in - crease can be held thru the winter to be used by the crop the fol - lowing year. Fig. 3. Winter wheat, bench land, 1908. See Chart IX, page 36. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Storing Moisture in the Soil 21 P Table II. — Soil moisture determination*, W&lt;&gt;7 . A. — Spring plowed. Spring wheat every year. April April May May June August Jf 1 23 e" 21 « Feet Percent Percent Herce-t Pticenl Percent Percent 1 16.4 15.5 Hi 7 lti.O 20.4 I 16.9 16.4 16.1 17.3 I 15.8 16 0 14 7 15.8 14 5 v4 « .... -t ■■ ■ itA Average to 3 16 4 16 0 15 8 15 t 17.4 B.I Average to ti . Flat B. — Disked after binder and fall plowed. Spring wheat every year 1 1G.5 14 1 19.7 IS 7 20. 5 2 16.4 13.9 15.8 IS ti 17 B 3 15.9 15.4 14.7 i:&gt;.7 15 9 • r &gt; IX.I I : :■ ; 12 2 Averageto 3 16.3 14.5 16.7 15 7 18.] Averageto 6 j | 10.0 Plat C— Spring wheat 1906. Summer tilled 1907. 1 15.6 12.3 19.2 ; 17.6 I 21.9 I |f.| 2 | 16.6 12.7 16 5 I 17.1 2o (I j 3 15.5 12.3 15.5 15.9 17. ti 16.8 6 17.0 Averageto 3 15.9 12 4 17.1 16 9 19.8 Averageto 6 17. 9 Plat D.— Summer tilled 190C. Spring wheat 190 1 15 7 15.0 19 ti I 17.4 20 1 I |.| 2 16.9 15 6 17.1 lti'ti 17 8 3 15.9 15.4 15 2 15.9 15 1 7 8 r&gt; 12 a 6 139 K*&gt; W.I verageto I 16.2 15.3 17 3 lti 6 ! 17 7 \ VAratM* to </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 I at A. — Spring plowed. Spring wheat every year. *, I April May June 3 July August T .verage to ■ verage to lat B.-D Feet Percent Percent Percent Percent 1 14.2 17.6 16.9 14.3 2 11.0 8 9 12.8 9 3 3 11.0 8.2 8.7 8.6 4 10.3 9.1 9 5 9 0 5 11.6 10.9 11. 0 10.6 6 12.1 12." 13.2 11.9 J 0 9 10 6 , 11.7 11 2 12.0 10.6 10 I sked after binder and fall plowed. Spring 1 14.0 18.7 17.8 12.1 2 12.1 11 9 14 6 8.7 3 8.7 8.6 10.3 8 8 4 9.3 9.5 9.4 9.6 5 12 1 11.0 12.2 12 9 6 14.3 12.2 15.2 15 4 7 8 9 10 6 11.8 12 0 13.3 11 3 10 mmer tilled 1907. Spring wheat, 1908. 1 15 9 19.4 15.4 12.6 2 15.7 15 6 14.0 9.7 3 15.4 14.1 14.9 10.1 4 14.9 14.5 14 1 10.7 5 18.9 16.4 17.4 15.7 6 18.0 16.2 18.0 16.0 1 8 9 10 6 16 5 16.0 15 6 12.5 10 ring wheat 1907. Summer tilled in 1908. 1 14.6 19.7 21.1 22.5 2 11.8 13.2 18.3 18.4 3 8 8 9 5 13.5 17.5 4 10.7 11 7 12.0 16.2 5 15.5 14.2 16.2 17 8 6 15.0 14.4 15.3 15.7 7 8 iS ::::::::,::::::::::::::::■.:::::::. 6 12 7 13.8 16.1 18.0 I 10 ; Per cent 7.2 8.3 8.1 8 4 10.0 11.8 " 9.0 wheat eve 7.3 7.7 77 8.7 11 3 14 1 ' 9.5 e Percent sry year Average to | 8.1 7.8 7.2 8.0 13 3 15.1 '"9!9* I Average to Average to Plat D.— Si 16 1 10.8 16 3 16.0 18.6 16 9 I 15S5S </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 O * ;c r- x x 3= ~ x f r- :s x x « hr-xxo«^oo';. h x x a r. x f r- s x r ** f r-xxOM^OOa «H ♦3 I '.".!* . '^ * I I SXTf^iOOSr- • • • • «O ; ; • ; ;X 2 Sx^Hioajr- • • • -co • H^ot*^W • • ; • x ■ Is X pic o •••;.., ***M u.. OS OS 3= OS — CD : . IO . OOiAOftHlQ . , . ,O ;i os 05 3: as — ci ! . ;o ; c 3 1 . 3: r: -* o -J — . x 3 3 « r Oi © « r- f i* n x « o x «c«ct-xo:it:)^:i e«t-t-i;Mi«oi no«oi-io:if;i«:i t* rl — 3:0000031 — •* axao^-tw--'^ ®3 Oj &gt;^ 5)CHCrtt"X ; ; : ; «&gt; ; MS M^ OS X O ; ; ; • *3 r-t J[ - -- a 6 c 1 * . . ** I ■— imqooj^* . I ! '. *J • 5 *h : : : : : : : : ■ : a -s : : . : : : : : : : ■ Jhiosoho ::;;«; *ioio*ia3 ; : : !* ' ~ 3 "* i^i-'indn : : . '- : gieeen* ! . tV ■ «&gt; © — s « t- XIS 1 i ; ; . ,n ! — jibs'"* . ; : ,n r- 1 x C — OSOhS ; ; ; ; * ; •* 10 10 ■"*• »O — ; ; ; ;*• -r i-t«HM : : , '-- : * » © © « * : : : -r N-, — -— : . . . « . ~ "* "= : : : : : : : : : : &gt;j S S) 35 00 it! t- ; ; ; ; CJ ; . — " ■««• i- X i US 3&gt; ; ; ; ; C • | *M ; . i"tCIM 3: X IS I— Ui Cl —1 X b I "* . * ■: t r. o r: -r s s — — 1— . . . .-&lt; . 4,——. ,^ rt i-i . . . .-* : ?. «" ■ 5 &amp;t :::::* • : : : : B &gt;&gt; . ■ . . *» — — B i Smmoonoi- • : •' •'© • ®-*^-roo« : : • • t- ■ ~ ° &gt;, giNMooNoi- • • • ;o • • ■ • ;^ • J2 &gt;&gt; * m : ; : ; -j • ) •* *• • • •• *o • • ■ ■' ' I — 1 — - ■..■..■.■ e ■.:::'. ,., a S SsfOSMXN ; ; ; ;« : E "*"" U3 BJ OS r- ; ; ; ;■© • — I o.»" lSCVNhm ; ; I \ta . 5" t— oao'Mu; ! .« • — T v (M 1-* — &lt; r* . . . . I— » .CC'^^^ . # I #^H M &lt; * r 1 a&lt; :::*:, : : : : : c • • • • '--6 • • • • -\ x 1 k ■» ' 3 BS Ssns»i»N • • • •« ■ ■Jf-'iowar- • • • •&gt;O ■ 1 t-s^ ° : ■ .■ - • • •_■ l •■■_■■• : : : ■ • • I x ii-sa*sr-«oex a S •_ » O3 ■* -- 33 -H ©' 3C 30 00 O &gt;M "3. 00 ■* CT © C^ ■* M — t-t © x-*ioui*«-'Mon« ?; •— tit "O i ■ je 1- • • X . • ait) i « « 6£ S£ „• U ■2 » * S * e </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 !, 5 t-lOr-M-^0i©O»!O«5t--0D| ©"©ai©-^&lt;'*"M--i-^ — — — .— ir-1 ii—ii— 1»— iH«f« SwNHooae ; ; ; ; N ; " © t^ &lt;d «c 3J ad '• 'od • i. (M •-! i-l i-i i-i ri ■ ' ;r- . &lt;? \\ ; i i us O © O » ; • • ; M ©as aJoiin'"*' • I • •&lt;-&lt; • w+ Hi-l * • ■ 'rt • 7 I" 5©3&gt;oqi— »■*•— cci-^io^oo *"(X)cc5&gt;/;50o6a64CffC^ccr-tc HhioO»!»rtOl * rt - 1— t "iHi^r-rir"^" ! ■** 1 ! I • • &gt;. S O5 &gt;o o a&gt; * i ao • ; : ; •• : — jj c eo — oo h t-^ io : ; ; ;• ; 2 !. &lt;M im ri r- r-i i-i • ; ; ; •-&gt; . *• » . ■ • • Soo ««t^d»«M • • . -!" : •_ M — -^ r-n-H • * ; '•* . &lt;S : : : ■ ; I— I— OS CO J 30 ; • ; ; -«* (N r- O5 *O ■"* • ' * O £^ eH r-) -^ i— &lt; * * * * ai r- »c -^ r- "^ ■ .* ; &lt;o i — n a I ■ d &gt;, 5 CC U5 «O "&lt;» | &lt;C 1 00 • ; ; ; •♦ • 00-1"'M'O03t-- ; • ; ;CO • j I" ? cc a&gt; cc t— ao ■ ; ; ; i— ' • , ; ; ; ao • * to ■** a&gt; © « eo •' ; . ; Jjj j § Heiho»i-^ j ; ; co . ■s '■ ' '• • '• •£ : : : : : * t^ •* ao as •* &gt;o '. • • •« ■ t» ao to o to © t^ • '. • r- '. -—^^ — -ca* '~ : - : ' "En q.-i &lt; 1. i C | j q»daa ■ • c : : S » c i ??« Ill </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 EXPLANATION OF CHARTS 4, 5, AND 6. Charts 4, 5, and 6 are used to show the effect on the moisture content of the soil of continuous cropping with spring wheat as compared with alternate cropping and summer tillage, for the years 1907, 1908, and 1909. The curves marked "a" represent the moisture in a plat continuously cropped to spring wheat. G and D are alternately cropped and summer tilled. Eirt 4 shows only the amount of water in the upper three soil. The curves for the three plats begin near the same . the spring of 1907. Plat D had been summer tilled the preceding year. The precipitation during the fall and winter had moistened the surface three feet. It is very probable that the mois - ture content of the second three feet was much greater in the plat which had been summer tilled. This shows the desirability of deep sampling in soils of this character. The curves shown in Charts 5 and 6 are made from the aver - age moisture percentage to a depth of six feet. The results are very similar to those obtained in 1907. The plat which was sum - mer tilled the previous year starts in with several inches more water than is found in either of the other plats. This excess of water is used, however, later in the season. The water which had been stored in the soil tends to insure against drouth the following season. When rains come, as they generally do, during the growing season of spring grain, the benefit from the water which has been stored is not so evident as it would be under more unfavorable con - ditions. In case of dry weather the water stored might account for the difference between a failure and a crop. This much the charts show conclusively: that several inches of water can be stored in the soil and held until used by the grow - ing plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 s £g^ggggg = g -I 1 Smtr =f= I!* IS u NO K N* I. * &amp; S | J * • s 8 ! s- *. I r^ I s Si iir § e 3 o o co «M kH '!!», »- 4-« r ? I s £F K i~^ *H S £hH PW rf 1 1 1! S2 — ; ? T^—rv:^" 5 ° ° a O_^ -^ ■ ■ . i i 5 4 » ff\ a * ova 1 fcFf-4d4- 4f*t— Si E I_/ _^L » J_Cft,_^_ .1! 4 V fc &lt;" *F-^r fl- fc I Kfflm^m $ P L I I I I I I I 1 ' ■ ' I 1 ■ 1 1 » ' I - I.. &lt;« • </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 SSSSSSSS^So-aors* s N r Si r i — s &gt;s — ««* Mil vn is 4- 4— M I I—^ 4^ f- « l5 Ai I kZ * \ 1 2 rs 2 II !S 13 ~ s = *S 5 &lt; N A, oj \ Qv a ■i O &gt;K5«(N </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 O Z0TX71Q JjlOXStHTB Xft \H&amp; oOlt tg^^gig^gg^g***^^ 1 § 8 •* I « I (j " -* N«K S g P Ml -*| " s I s 5 I ** s a I s. s . a . 3 . ; \\\ i 5 M U « i.2 &amp; &gt; *. I 5 I. . - L *0 &lt;• • a^S£^!S!9StaSf^5 o ' 0 »N'o*&gt;»in«M^ </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 Table V gives the data from which Charts Nos. 7 and 8 were constructed. It is interesting to note that during the entire season of 1908, the soil in the brome grass field (Field 1) did not become moist below the first foot, or at least was not moist below the first foot at any time when samples were taken. There is a slight increase in the per cent of moisture in the second and third foot samples on July 20, but not enough to make them really moist. On the date of first sampling in the spring of 1909 we find the soil fairly moist to a depth of three feet. This is doubtless due to a heavy rain in the fall of 1908. On October 19, 3.24 inches of rain fell and this field, as well as others on the bench land, was flooded and the moisture in the first three feet was considerably increased. The moisture content of this field is not only maintained, but increases with the rains of June and July, 1909, until on July 17th we find an increase even in the 6th foot. At the close of the season, how - ever, the soil is dry to a depth of at least ten feet. If the table for Field 2 which grew corn in 1908, is compared with that for Field 1 for the year 1908, one can see the difference in moisture content due to tillage and to the fact that the corn in Field 2 was using much less water than the grass in Field 1. There was an increase in moisture content in Field 2 as early as May 11. This increase continues until the latter part of July, when the rain is less and the crop is using more water. The tillage had, however, served the purpose of holding the water until needed by the crop. In 1909, Field 2 was in small grain and there was consequently less difference in tillage and crop growth in the two fields and we find the difference in the moisture content of the two field3 cor - respondingly less. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">A. Alil-fc V . OvlC 77tC/ToCZ*7^o CZcto/ "i TTicJCtOTio. Field 1, 1908. In brome grass three ye a rs. ■5 — (5 March April May 16 18 11 June June July 11 22 20 &lt;* **v I. _ Feet Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 1 12.2 8.0 12.4 14.3 14.1 10 6 2 86 7.3 7.3 8.5 9.7 10.7 3 7.8 78 7.0 6.7 6.8 9.6 4 7.7 7.0 6.8 6.4 6.0 7.1 5 8.2 6.5 6.9 6.7 6.0 6 8 6 8.5 6.7 7.0 6.7 6.7 6.8 7 8 9 10 6 8.8 7.2 7.9 8 2 8.2 8 6 in In brome grass four years. April May June July July 11 8 14 17 26 1 17.5 11.8 17.5 18.8 10.5 2 15.9 14.5 18.2 14.8 10.8 3 12.7 12.0 14.7 11.4 9.6 4 7.1 8.1 10.7 10.7 8.4 5 7.0 »i.8 9.3 10.8 9.4 6 7.0 6.9 7.7 10.4 9.3 7 7.4 6.8 8 7.3 6.1 9 7.7 6.4 10 7.4 7.1 6 11.2 10.0 13.0 12.8 9.7 10 9.7 8.4 , Small grain 1907, corn 1908. March April May June June July 1 18 11 12 22 20 1 13.4 13.1 18.0 22.4 18.2 16.6 2 11.2 11.2 15.1 17.9 18.7 16.0 3 8.3 7.6 11.8 16.3 18.3 17.4 4 7.7 6.9 11.2 14.6 17.2 17.3 5 7.4 6 9 9.9 10.4 12.9 14.5 « 7.6 7.0 9.4 10.3 10.3 13.4 8 9 io ........ ..!.... .....!! ' '".'. " 6 9.3 8.8 12.6 15.3" 15.9 " 15.9 Small' grain 1909. April May June July July 24 8 14 17 26 1 18.6 15.2 22.6 20.1 11.3 2 13.2 13.2 18.5 15.9 11.6 .. 3 9.6 10.1 14.8 12.8 9.4 .. 4 9.2 10.2 12.8 11.6 10.6 5 8.7 9.3 10.0 9.C 10.5 6 9.1 9.1 10.8 10.1 9.4 7 10.6 10.1 .. 8 11.1 11.6 ....... 9 12.8 13.5 10 13.0 15.3 .. 6 11.4 11.2 14.9 13.4 10.5 10 11 fi 11 ! Average to Average to Field 1, 190S I * Average to Average to Field 2, I'M) t I Average to Average to Field 2, 190! T I Average to </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 EXPLANATION OP CHARTS 7 AND 8. The curves in Chart 7 represent the moisture content in a field which has been in brome grass for three years, and also a field which was in corn during the season of 1908. The two curves start very close together in the spring but the cultivated field soon begins to increase in moisture content, reaching its maximum in June, and holding it thru the greater part of July. At the time the crop required most water, the soil was fairly moist. These curves illustrate again the effect of tillage and plant growth on the amount of water in the soil. The two fields are on the bench land and ad - jacent, and the difference shown by the curves is due to the tillage in the cornfield, which permitted the rainfall to enter the soil and prevented it from escaping, and to the growth of the brome grass, which used the water as fast as it was available. The brome grass sod also permitted more run-off than the cornfield. Chart 8 shows a continuation in 1909 of the same fields shown in Chart 7; however, the field which was in corn in 1908 was put into small grain in 1909. Pn 1909 we do not get as great a difference in the amount of in the two fields as we did in 1908. This is probably due to il factors. The rains of 1909 were more continuous than in and more water soaked down into the soil of the grass field during the year previous. Also, the small grain could not be cultivated as was the corn and the surface of the soil could not be kept in as good condition to catch and retain the rain. Again, the larger number of plants in the small grain used more water and used it earlier in the season than did the corn. It is also noted from Chart 8 that very little water was lost from the soil in the small grain field after August 1. This field was fall plowed about that time. This checked evaporation and killed the weeds that had come up, preventing them from drawing moisture out of the soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 t 5 S 4 JtSS^S^-N'* I B o / CM . 3 5 KB k c c t 2 s u 2 &gt; :° i^* • i — l I O qO *; 10 / / -J •&gt;\ h E h -4 .^1 'tJS^U-N^^NN J o </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 gfcgsgigggg?^ I </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Storing Moisture in the Soil 34 EXPLANATION OF CHARTS 9 AND 10. Charts 9 and 10 show the moisture content of the first six feet of the soil in Fields 13 and 17 on the bench land, during the sea - sons of 1907, 1908, and 1909. There are some changes during the winter months that the curves do not show. The curves for 1907 show only the condition of the soil in the spring and in the fall. F During the season of 1907 Field 13 was being summer tilled, moisture content during this time increased from 14 to 16.5 cent in the upper six feet. This field was seeded to winter wheat in the fall of 1907 with the first six feet of soil holding a high per cent of water. During the winter the moisture content decreased until it stood at 12 per cent April 9, 1908. This de - crease continued until harvest notwithstanding the fact that the rainfall between April 1 and harvest time amounted to 12 inches, aa shown by the precipitation curve. In producing the immense growth of wheat, which ave 57 bushels per acre, there was used not only the 12 inches of rain - fall but also about seven or eight inches of water that had been stored in the soil. It is probable, however, that there was some run-off from the surface of the soil during heavy rains, also some evaporation from the surface. But the loss from these factors was slight and a large part of the water was used in producing the crop. During the remainder of the fall after harvest the moisture content increased as rain fell, until when winter set in there was 11 per cent of water in the soil. The first sampling of the spring following (1909) showed about as much water as in the fall. Dur - ing the season of 1909 this field grew a crop of corn. The curve shows that the moisture content of this field increased rapidly un - til the latter part of June, or until the corn had become larjre enough to draw heavily on the moisture Then it decreased dur - ing July and August, tho the precipitation curve shows that the rainfall was about 7 inches during these two months. On Septem - ber 18 the curve shows that the moisture content was down to about 12.5 per cent. If we follow the moisture curve for Field 17 during the same three years, we shall be convinced of the relation of crop growth and tillage to the moisture content of the soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 In the spring of 1907 the moisture in the upper six feet* of soil in Field 17 amounted to 14 per cent dry weight of the soil. In the fall the percentage of moisture had decreased 5 per cent, tho there had been 15 inches of rainfall during this time. The field had produced a heavy crop of cane drilled for forage. During the winter following, the moisture increased to 11 per cent, but fell one per cent before seeding time. The field was planted to cane in rows and cultivated. The moisture curve shows a rise until the crop had developed a large leaf area and would therefore permit a rapid loss of water by transpiration thru the leaves; then the curve shows a rapid decrease until in the fall the moisture avail - able for plant growth is all gone. This field also showed an increase of moisture during the win - ter so that it had 11 per cent in the spring of 1909 when it was seeded to oats. The moisture content increased until in June, at which time the crop had reached sufficient development to use the water very rapidly. At harvest time the moisture content was about the same as it was at the time the oats were planted. The crop seemingly was produced by the rainfall that came between seeding time and harvest. That was about 12 inches. If we compare the moisture curves of these two adjoining fields we shall find that the moisture content of one may decrease rapidly while the other is increasing just a3 rapidly, depending on the tillage given and the crop being grown. In fact, after a little study one can tell by the direction of the moisture curve dur - ing the season what class of crop and tillage was given to the field during the time under consideration. E*On this date the samples were taken in this field to a depth of three feet, but the conditions were bo similar to those of an ad - nt field that the moisture data from the latter were used. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 g. oo g sgggg^g •• m • j^l | • """Hi ? ! « i IS s- kg I i o H ft i &lt; P a o uj-l Ml I Mil </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 EXPLANATION OP CHART 11. Chart No. 11 shows the soil moisture in three fields dur - ing the season of 1908. These fields are on the table-land and entirely dependent on precipitation. During the entire season the moisture content of the alfalfa field remained low. The surface of the soil was so dry and hard that it was difficult for the water to get into the soil. The water which fell was used by the plants, evaporated from the surface, or lost by run-off before it could get very deep into the soil. At no time during the season did the rainfall penetrate the soil to a depth of more than 30 inches. This was soon used and at the close of the season almost all the available water had been drawn from the soil. The curves representing the summer tilled field and corn plat start very close together and follow each other quite closely until the last of June. From the first of April to the last of June about five inches of water was stored in each of these plats. This was about 45 per cent of the precipitation for that time. After the first of July the corn began using more water and not only used the rainfall but began drawing on the water which had been stored in the soil. At the close of the season there was still about three inches of available water left in the upper six feet of soil in the corn plat, but the soil had a little over one per cent less water than it had the first of April. This would indicate that the corn U3ed about one inch more water than fell during the growing season. After July 1st there is a drop of one per cent in the moisture content of the summer tilled plat. This was probably due to some loss by evaporation from the surface and to the fact that water was being carried down below the six feet. At the close of the season this plat had between eight and nine inches of available water, while the cornfield had but three inches, and the alfalfa field had no available water which could be used by the plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 + e • w c ? e u o v 5« 3 ;_■ i ui U, &lt;l; &lt;o -El- h+ S8 V* K M ■K -MS' •"•So 5 / feL U- S: h s-d § S K u \ 2 ==3 T^i E =d?b * cH NJ i h -*hH-F a p il H 2 Sl— • _^A o %'^_ £ 2 if** \ S * K -LL «. 1 t- • \ _^J 1 M I -UI \v B Cl &gt;&lt; u J j 1 A? " e 3 £ i i i i i i i i i i i i i * </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 . e Dables VI, VII, and VIII are used to show the effect on mois - iontent of continuous cropping t# corn as compared with alter - cropping and summer tilling. Plat A is spring plowed and listed to corn every year. Plat B is fall plowed and listed to corn every year. Plat C was summer tilled 1907, cropped to corn 1908, and summer tilled again in 1909. Plat D cropped to corn in 1907, summer tilled in 1908, and cropped to corn in 1909. From a study of these tables it will be noted that at some period during the summer we get about as much water in the soil when corn is grown continuously as there is in the plat which has been summer tilled. However, this is used by the crop before the close of the season. At the close of the season there is always several inches more water in the soil of the summer tilled plat than where a crop is grown. Ee hope the tables will show conclusively that by tillage water , and is, stored in the soil, and that it can be held by culti - until needed by the crop. Fig. 4. Rotation and cultivation plats on high table-land. (In coopera - tion with the United States Department of Agriculture.) </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 I o2 V.N0O0O ■::•*: 3rS ;. — • o&gt; • • • • © ' ■ £~ ; I : i id ac ad ■ ■ • O " r-l - - " »— • a: r i n ; ; ; *• ' *— t * ; \ i— * ; v ! ** e* • • • &lt; »S ; ; ; ; * ,2™ : : •- : «oh : : ■ ao • d»lS! ■ " • ri ' rt r-t ' ; »-;»o : : ;•* ■ — — — | * *-^ * i « 1 I- jeii- ; : ■ ** '. i» Q r^ » ■ " - a6 • * : : : : a ~* us : ; ; &lt;o ; rHOOCO " ' *00 ' I 1. £ rj — ■ • * *** ' n«s : ; : &lt;-&gt; ; O5 ffl • • •» • Nmh ; ; ;i-4 ; m — — . * &lt; w c^4 ■ • • «i • « «5 ■* ■ " " «o " $ ' ! ! i i : : i ! , a* S ■* .... 8 ac is &gt; «* ; ; ; as ; £» -; » •-&lt; '■ '. '. * k V &gt;d W ••*« • « e e u: ; ; ; £ ; i, : : : : « : : : . • • • o ' ■g • • - o g •— i — as ; ; '*» ; yoci-H • ; ;» . k.«»ioi4**"*" « «e •♦ ■ ■ • us ■ : : : "S : : : ■ 3 * qtdaa ~ o S3 5 23 tt « 2£ a) a&gt; 'S » » t» &amp;■ * &gt; &gt; « a* &lt;&lt; 23 &lt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p042">c -/ — i ; : '.'*- x aq ao - 'S .... . . . . \\ ~ 8^°. *! ' • ■ I ~ l • — '•" '" • - ■ 3 : • 3 *• &amp;~~~ : : : 0T3 1_! — Hs S 'i ; *; — aq — M r- 1- i t - o •2 §2 tsi X — ao » • • • ao Tl i-i « • ■ ■ — 2 r~ 5 J_ S t ~ Or- £ -r I S ■— — -— I -„ i22 - S*x P accc -r 01 - — "-&gt; — i 3 i. s •s| -r £-"--' o — . yS qviaa J-«««« —• fe rr s PS I hi 3- c « i. t— r— «2 " • ■ — •g^ sjcos : : :-•= : is «3 ,» HHH ...'-. E LL^^ V !&gt;£■* . iri ce o • • • «5 • &lt; g : : : : I ;: «" t* » goo ox •* &lt;e &lt;o ; ; ; oc 1 — i* s» a ic 10 c« t- -_ -f HedNsntoh S — idi-i n' erioc ci e i- -.c x x =:' x &lt;L I I: • •■£ ;= -* • • "O fa S OS 33 D &gt; &gt; j2 &gt; o\ 22 ti. ti tl &gt; &gt; « </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 **■ «**i*C* » i A. kjiJ I L lit U UtL tlitf- Ctc It: J IH I ll( I [ tO/Jo _/ %J\sQ . Plat A. — Spring plowed. Corn every year. g, April May June July August * 6 6 3 2 3 -J3 Per cent 13.2 14.9 15.8 Hit 16.4 16 1 12.1 J .:.::.::: •::.:::::•::••••::•••:: '2? 8 9 ... «« » 8.6 10 I ,.. 7 a Average to 15 2 Average to iq i i i i...::::. ..::.:. Plat B.— Fall plowed. Corn every 11.8 - n.7 14 .9 16.6 14.4 14.6 7 T". ...... 17 s ,■; 9 "."'."' .'.'..'.'..'.. '.'.'.'.'..'.'..".'.".:. » 9 8 10 i . Average to 14 2 Average to PlatC Summer 12 4 i:5.&lt;» 14. 1! 15 18.5 17.2 Average to 15.3 Average to •Corn 16.3 17 4 16.2 14.5 15.8 16 1 16.1 Feet Percent Percent Percent Percent 1 14. L 21.9 21.1 21.7 2 11.1 12.3 18.4 18.4 3 92 94 13.2 17.2 4 9.9 10.0 9.4 13.4 5 13.4 13 7 12 7 13 4 6 12.8 13.7 13.7 13 2 7 6 11.8 13 5 i 14.8 i 16.2 plowed. Corn every year. 1 14.4 20 9 20.8 21.4 2 10.4 10.1 17.3 18 1 3 9.1 8.9 12.6 17 0 4 9.3 10.3 9.7 12.7 5 13.1 13 3 13 3 14 2 6 14.0 14 8 15.6 15.1 « 6 11.7 13.0 14 a 16.4 14 2 13 fl io i ; mer tilled 1907. Corn 190* 1 15 3 2 15.7 3 14.3 4 14.4 5 116 6 17.2 7 8 9 10 6 15.8 10 i 1907. Sun 21.3 15.8 14 7 14.5 15.9 17.4 20 9 21.3 19.3 18.6 18 1 16.7 ie.3 no 17 9 20.1 18.7 19.9 lti.ti 18.9 i 1907. Summer tilled 1 13.7 20.1 2 10.5 9.2 3 9 6 9.1 4 10.8 10.7 5 14.8 14.5 6 14 9 15 4 7 8 9 10 6 12.4 13.2 10 1&lt;K&gt;8, 20 5 21 9 17.7 18.5 11.6 17.0 11 1 14.8 15 2 15.0 15.1 15.5 15.2 17.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 ON |onoaoxoso»cni;e fc aso»ojoiwj«viasoo't-"t^©os ao i-i as © us cc © us © m ao as «' a ad d ri ■+ ri d d s I c i-H -^ r^ f^ &lt; g « r^ i-&lt; ao r-; os : ". '. ; M | t —■©■ — -«•*« ; ; ; • *i ; "e^NHt- ; ; ; ■ x : -lo'-'tiiso • • • • e-i • W^rl 3« It ■ • • g -^ &gt;o © us co ; ■ ; ; ao ; 1"^ *^2 f* # fc^^j ■ • • C^? * r^ " * " * • § m e « 00 o 1- ; ; ; ■© ; »-J^S2^J2^ • • • 't^ • ftn : • : : : «d ao n oa © to ; ; ; ; © ; t^ ® «i id ■♦ n • ; ; • id ; 1 is |onc&gt;aon : ; ; ;us ; u at^«ujoid • • • "so ■ £ rH »-H »— I rH ?^ ' «— t • &amp; ' : : : : r- e a » © &gt;o : . : • « ; 06 1- 1 sc ej ers ■♦ • • • -us • ' \\\f\ : 1-9 gn4|4|Ncia ; ; ; ; us ; 1. ei ad oi ci e4 • • ••♦ • v m .— 1-^ 1-^ • • • • 1— i ■ ~H ■ • • • j o e^ o o 03 ■* ; ; " ; m ; -■ ad o » ~ •* • • • • •# • 1— ( • * • ' f-H ; i 1. io «* » ao — ' .-&lt; • • • • £ *-* 1— 1 i—i * * * * ** • a* : : : : : ia ; « a&gt; r~ © oo ; ; ; ; t- ; •• « ao oo n &lt;H • • ■ •-- ■ - 1 " w : : : :•■* : cSoo 2- 1 1 a »c c&lt;i oi si ?i «' - 6 © d ci^ M -I is &lt; I ■* • ■ • • g 00 as « -h a&gt; r-; : : : : oq • jjt«n«oe : • ■ ■ ©_ • k5^g»2fl • • : :?i . g22»»2J2 ' : : "2 '■ t, :::::« : : : : : • • • a ■ i ■5. be a I &lt; - J3 2 i s vC'riooseii-IosasaoaofJ — 05 ei » os m •♦ e-i © © =' H ?i * -8 22fc &lt;&lt; a- I «\ </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 |e&gt;O4kiec«i r- x; a o 1- o «( on «e&lt;D ft *4*i — •«4eJ •** .... a g a -/.c t» ao •ri o ; ; ; : m : &lt;j [a, : : : : : ♦ • • — to m : 1 : ■ o : ri ri ri •* x x • ' • • i.t' • [UN 1 £*^^?j= : : : £ : : I : : ■g "5 •- &gt;. t^ r^ » t- r^ t^ ■ • • *r- ■ •5 : : : : : I „ 3 S s. «3 rj O JC r- i~ ; ; ■ ; ■ "^ • • • • t— od » — © »i ; : ; ' m ; ad r^ 1- s o= ■ ' " " ao ; ■^ .... j^minmx ; ; • : 00 : 3 ■"»■ — x fi ri ic »*&gt; ■ • • • ta ■ 1-9 ,« *' ™ " - 1 " - 1 : * : : a : — ■ ..... I* 1-5 in^i-r-i-^ ■ ; ■ ;o ; -^ » s -t !■- 1- " "oo ; %'- » r- * « c k -• : ■ : 'in ; * x m x c »i ; ; ; :&lt;x&gt; ■ •^ •** -&amp; r* ** -t&gt; *r ; • ; &amp;i • o »&lt;i us ■** i~- * * # \ ; o ; h iMNVieipiOMCianAi* io •*•»•••*" p&lt; *™ • ™t *! ■ v o ni r4 -i -!• ■"* c; c c: yi -&gt;i i- « -)■ i" t- o * c-i 1-1 — v£ "SlO — — &lt; = a g e « «•■• • : : ■ : •* : •* •* s « t- ; — : : : :• : k i-(e&gt;aHie^ ■ ■ ■ • -I- • .9 odsci't-i-' • • ■ ■ &lt;s *&gt; '-»- : : .- : w«*»«-^ ::::": I *• ** a I ! I OOCB Eli </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 WEATHER RECORDS. The following weather record charte are used to show the character and amount of rainfall during the time the moisture work was in progress, and to show the average rainfall thru a long period of years. Table IX shows the amount of each rain during the months March to September inclusive. This is shown for the past three years, the time the moisture studies have been in progress. It will be noted that many rains are so small in amount as to be of little value from the standpoint of storing moisture. Other rains are very heavy. If one studies the moisture curves carefully and compares the results with this rainfall chart, a correlation will be found be - tween frequency and amount of rainfall, and an increase of water in the soil. Chart 12 shows the average relative amount of precipitation for each month. These averages are made from the records shown in Table X. It will be noted from Chart 12 that January, February, and March have only a light average precipitation. In fact, the late fall and winter months are all dry. The amount of rainfall in - creases in April and reaches its maximum in June. About 80 per cent of the annual precipitation falls during the period of April to September inclusive. This distribution of precipitation gives as much water during the growing season as have many sections with a much higher annual precipitation, and is favorable for the production of crops. Chart 13 shows the annual fluctuation of the precipitation above or below the normal. Table X gives a record of the rainfall by months, the total pre - cipitation, and the amount above or below normal. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Storing Moisture in the Soil 47 : - I ~ • i ' &lt; ■ ■ r " ' i 3 0 3 i -- &lt; M -* U5 CC t- X P 3£ St, * S S ) 3 7 ? ■M . T X — -f r- 2 •M . .HK — -I — . — . X 1 - SS2 t-— . . X CO •£_, • — h Tl -»• i?i rr ?in . -m *- S ;i '- ti i ?i K - ME | os ! ,'ienMop °«h .'n^ad .' I : .'at- , ; m : .' . S" S I S O t« ej ■ ■•Moo-f -m; • ■-» O ■* ■ • • ■ 3. -z. ■ r •;_,© - ■ ■ S ?El« isnNx . -* ao t t&gt; i- t- IM ?&gt;'f, dQ •i x?i IN ■M - ' — i r- i- £5-1 ; iJJ2 ■» O .' -M -*• u- -f ■- X) .' — X ■ ? £ : : : :rn :©&amp;**« : : : -.- : :tH : :o :St,fH :■- 2 B *i -oc x ■^ tn~. ir. * ©■* i— i « ■ 3 • ;SS * - — i&gt; ri 1} . -j |- _^J • * * * * * : • ■ • • * * ■ &lt;^L Jr ?M '. '. o •&gt;! « !?i .'•»• . ■&gt;»• -r -* ii .'n .' « ti f ri itriric ~- : • : :^ • : • : • : : • :«j ooaos • • • • • • • N49 1. LjCflO • O S § : « - r- =1 c-i : « i : : N : i : i ;? = :: r-i viall I ; I ! i ;h i i ; i i is Ls in i ; :s=^ in : i </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 CilAKT XII. Average Pr*ctpiTa.rion by Memhs tor ZS Yecrs o.t hiorrh Plarre </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 i X d ■*oocortM!oeooNaiaar-ioiot««*'-t-t--5«ot-«g-"»e«|Li 2 «ononOrt^»i'-f-o-Sa«oocn«tli;r-'"Sq*MM»»n- •M — e3 ■ - i S r~* r~ r~ r * t -• ao oc oo QO Q0 00 3C oc QC 3C 3^ s&amp; — - 3^ O^ O^ Ob 3t 35 O O O w w w O O w O &gt; XXXXXXXIXXXXXXXXXrXXXXXXX3i*J*9** 9*3 s|| i i + i + i + i^T+T-t-i+T+f 1 mi i mi 1+1 ++++++ ►&gt;•►—&gt; o o*S«HMfi)o*er-»Hctii'OOHee«j:i«iao«HNo«s«»" :1 '' &lt;*-« . &gt;» . . . . c~ f | S6aaaPaa5?a82as«G»t*t33s»Jis«&lt;t8582*a(2 • — m "~" ' '"— ' " '" » &lt; i ti «o«Neeio(CHnt-s!-ieeNia-Ni-(or-iflp«t-o*ooioi-&lt;c*i-")' r- , a «*o«)H$i'gioH«seso**o»HHOO*»«oi-iONioc'&lt;i.':N m Jfsf -3 53SSS5S8SSSaS8SSaSS2888SaSRaSSSSSSi:r. g •^ p &lt;-t o4 i-H e4 « ad ei « ei i-I ©i « "«ci» *«4»{vJ«i*4t^'M«4«i« WllWlllirfMitfM ~~ wososo — NM*oos*ciir.r»5H«ir»»i*iOMOi«oi«n30st-» — I »S &lt;% i-j i-&lt; ' ei »o « « «c ■* r^ ™ m — ' re ci -^ ■m* r^ '*«'*« — NrtrtrinnVr 1 ' ei K3 •-" i4 I "£ *• »r»Mi»i(;x*it-o-'t&gt;-n-"OOiOios»r--'«aoe«o()^n(criCL &gt; ::i -^ I .« Q^ S -5 *i « « e4 n V m * oi « « ■■*c-i ' — m-.' '■rj-- '■*■«" 'nHdirt^NfiHri -i 11^ £ SSSSSSSSSSS8«SSS3SS3S9S$S3aSSSSSSSSS3f-! 3 [•J*! i •«23=a«*5*B««58C358P8Cf*B»352Saa2«»b fl&gt; "V 1-1 I— — </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Chabt XIII. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 CONCLUSIONS The data in this bulletin show : 1. That land which is under thoro cultivation absorbs water much more freely than land not under cultivation or which is cov - ered with grass or for any reason has a hard surface. 2. That land under thoro cultivation loses but little water from below the first foot by surface evaporation so long as the mulch is kept in good condition. 3. That a growing crop uses water from the land in propor - tion to the growth of dry matter in the crop. 4. That land under summer tillage or thoro cultivation from May 1 to September 1 on the Substation farm has accumulated from 5.5 to 7 inches more water in the first six feet of soil than similar land growing a crop. The water so stored has been equal to from 40 to 50 per cent of the rainfall for the same period. The moisture content on summer tilled land increases below the six - foot area and is apparent to a depth of at least 10 feet. EThat water stored in the subsoil to a depth of at Iea3t six available for the use of farm crops, and that alfalfa is able r water from much deeper areas. r5. That abundance of water in the subsoil is a great protec - to the crop against drouth, and that moisture in the surface soil, while it may favor the immediate growth of the plant, does not protect it against prolonged drouth. The protection of the crop against drouth is in almost exact proportion to the total avail - able soil water within the reach of the crop. 7. That grass crops (alfalfa and brome grass) dry the sub - soil to such an extent on the Substation farm that the first crop following grass is wholly dependent on the season's rainfall for its moisture supply. 8. That a rainfall of from a quarter to a half-inch may have a decidedly beneficial effect upon a growing crop and is of great assistance in securing a good stand at seeding time. Such a rain - fall has little or no effect in increasing the water in the lower soil unless the surface is already moist from previous rains. Less than a half -inch of rain falling on a dry soil mulch does not wet the soil below the mulch and is soon evaporated by the sun and wind. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 AVAILABLE BULLETINS. The following bulletins of the Station may be had on request: No. 25. Det&amp;Bseling Corn. No. 39, Some Obstacles to Successful Fruit Growing. No. 41, Water Supply in Nebraska. No. 48, Windbreaks. No. 49, Suggestions for Chicory Culture. No. 51, Observations on the Codling-Moth, No. 70, Locusts or Grasshoppers. No. 77, Poisoning of Cattle by Common Sorghum and -Kafir Corn. No. 84, Pasture, Meadow, and Forage Crops. No. 85, Feeding Experiments with Cattle. No. 89, Winter Wheat. No. 90, Cattle Feeding Experiment. No. 93, Cattle Feeding Experiments. No. 94, Fattening Pigs on Corn and Tankage. No. 96, The Hessian Fly. No. 99, Growing Hogs in Western Nebraska. No. 100, Economical Rations in Beef Production. No. 101, Dairy Herd Record for Ten Years. Cost of Butter Fat Pro - duction. rl04, Cultivation of Small Grains. The Use of the Fanning Mill for Selecting Seed Wheat and Seed Oats. No. 107, Foods Supplementary to Corn in Fattening Pigs. The Effect of Food on Breaking Strength of Bones. No. 108, Milking Machines. No. 110, Report of the Nebraska Seed Laboratory. No. Ill, Changes in the Composition of the Loess Soils of Nebraska Caused by Cultivation. No. 112, Experiments With Corn No. 113, Oats. No. 114, Storing Moisture in the Soil Press Bulletin No. 6, The Fall Preparation of the Land for Sugar Beets. Press Bulletin No. 19, The Hessian Fly. Press Bulletin No. 20, Fattening Pigs and Wintering Brood Sows on Alfalfa and a Grain Ration. Press Bulletin No. 21, A Good Oat for Nebraska. Press Bulletin No. 23, Ergot and Ergotism. Press Bulletin No. 25, The Seed of Cheat, Meadow Fescue and Brome Grass Press Bulletin No. 29, Pocket Gophers. Press Bulletin No. 30, Rolling Winter Wheat. Press Bulletin No. 31, Production of Hog Cholera Serum Press Bulletin No. 32, Testing Seed Corn. ■Bulletin No. 33, Construction and Use of the Road Drag. (In BBS.) Address, AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION, Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>