<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Spring Grains Time of Seeding and Comparative Yields</title>
               <date value="1926-03">1926-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 213 March, 1926 Spring Grains TIME OF SEEDING AND COMPARATIVE YIELDS L. L. ZOOK Bulletin 25 of the North Platte Experimental Substation W. P. Snydeh, Superintendent Yields in pounds per acre of spring grains seeded on different dates for 17 years at the University of Nebraska Substation, North Platte. Nebraska THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. Burnbtt. Director Muwos ac«e noo &lt;J00 800 700 0AT9 flfl«LEY "•., **". \ \ \ &lt;*0Q ■s x 5 RYE S00 *"y. 400 3WME«T EMMEK 300 *? zs 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">TIME OF SEEDING AND COMPARATIVE YIELDS L. L. ZOOK • This bulletin reports results secured by seeding spring grains at different dates for the 17-year period from 1909 to 1925 inclusive at the North Platte Experimental Substation of the University of Nebraska. 3 The results also furnish infor - mation on the comparative yields of the different grains used. Four spring grains were grown each year. Three of these — barley, oats, and wheat — were grown for the entire period. The fourth grain was either emmer or spring rye. Emmer was grown for the 10-year period from 1909 to 1918 inclusive and rye from 1919 to 1925 inclusive. The grain varieties used were: Kubanka durum wheat, except in 1913, 1914, and 1915, when Marquis was grown; Kherson oats until 1919, when it was replaced by Nebraska 21, White Kherson ; Common Six Row barley except in 1917 and 1918, when White Smyrna was used; White spring emmer; and Commercial spring rye. The tests were located on bench land at the station. In nearly all cases the previous crop was corn. The land was prepared by a thoro double disking, usually immediately pre - ceding each seeding. One plat for each grain for each date of seeding was used. The plats varied in different years from one-fourth to one - half acre in size. With a few exceptions each of the four grains used were seeded on four dates each year. In all of the Great Plains area the time at which field work can be begun in the spring varies greatly from year to year. At North Platte, field work in some years has been carried on during practically the entire month of March. In other years it has not been possible to begin until sometime after the first of April. The terms early and late as applied to time of seeding must therefore be considered in relation to the character of the season rather than in their relation to specific calendar dates. In the tests here reported no attempt was made to seed on definite dates. The first seeding was usually made as soon 1 Agronomist, North Platte Experimental Substation, detailed by Bureau of Plant Industry, Office of Dry Land Agriculture, U. S. Department of Agriculture. 3 A part of the results have been reported previously in Bulletins 172 and 193. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">-1 as possible after frost was out of the ground and a seed-bed could be prepared. It was planned to have the last seeding made late in April or early in May. The second and third seedings were so made that the time between the first and the foarth seeding was divided as nearly as possible into three periods of equal length. The dates of seeding each year and average dates of each seeding are shown in Table 1. In 1912 and 1915 the first seedings were delayed by un - favorable weather conditions until after the usual dates of second seeding. In these cases only three seedings were made; and in arranging the data, yields from the first date of seeding are used under both the first and the second dates. In 1912 the fourth seedings of spring wheat and emmer were omitted and the yields from the third seeding are used under the fourth date. In 1910 the fourth seeding of barley was omitted and the yield was supplied by using that of the third Table 1. — Annual and average dates of seeding spring grains, 1909 to 1925 inclusive Year 1st 2nd 3rd 4th 1909 April 1 April 10 April 20 May 3 1910 1 March 17 ' March 30 | April 8 ' April 20 1911 1 March 18 J March 28 April 7 ' April 17 1912 I April 8 ! April 8 April 19 April 30 1913 | March 31 ' April 14 I April 24 May 5 1914 ! March 18 ' March 28 I April 7 April 17 1915 ! April 12 I April 12 I April 29 May 7 I 916 ! March 21 April 6 ' April 18 April 26 1917 1 March 27 | April 9 ■ April 21 May 5 1918 1 March 12 ' April 2 ! April 16 | May 1 1919 1 March 29 ! April 15 ! April 24 ' May 1 ! March 31 I April 9 | April 27 I May 7 I March 16 I March 29 ' April 14 April 26 1921 1 March 16 1922 j March 16 '• March 31 ! April 15 April 29 1923 ! March 29 ' April 9 ' April 21 April 30 1924 1 April 2 ' April 11 1 April 22 1 April 29 1925 1 March 12 ' March 27 ! April 7 I April 21 Average [ March 25 ! April 5 I April 18 } April 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Spring Grains 5 The earliest seeding in any year was on March 12. The latest date of first seeding was April 12. First seedings were thus distributed over a period of 31 days. Second, third, and fourth seedings were distributed over periods of 19, 22, and 20 days respectively. The average dates of the four seedings were March 25, April 5, April 18, and April 29. The interval between the first and last average dates was 34 days. The average inter - vals between first and second, second and third, and third and fourth seedings were 10, 13, and 11 days respectively. EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS Annual and average yields in bushels per acre from each date of seeding for each crop are shown in Tables 2 to 6 inclusive. The diagram on the front cover page shows graphically the average yields in pounds per acre from each seeding. An examination of the tables shows a considerable varia - tion in the trend of results from year to year. Crop yields are influenced by variations in moisture and temperature in different seasons. In most years, however, conditions were more favorable for early than for late seedings. In the 64 crop years represented, there are 21 cases or 33 per cent in which the yields ranked in the exact order of seeding. That is, the highest yields were secured from the first seeding, and yields from successive seedings decreased with each later date. There are 48 cases, 75 per cent, in which the highest yield was secured from the first or second seeding, and 50 cases or 78 per cent in which the lowest yield was secured from the third or fourth seeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">1 Yield from first seeding used for both first and second seeding, used only once in annual average. s Yield of third seeding used also for fourth seeding, used only once in annual average. Spring Wheat. — For the 16 years in which crops were harvested, spring wheat produced the highest yield from the first seeding 10 times, and from the first or second seeding 14 times. The second highest yield was produced by the second seeding 9 times, the third highest yield from the third seeding 11 times, and the fourth highest yield from the fourth seeding 11 times. The 17-year average yields of spring wheat rank in the order of seeding. The difference between first and second seedings was slight, but a rapid drop in yield occurred after the second seeding. The average difference 'ABLE 2. — 1 seedings 1925 inch ibanka i ch year, ive pnng wheat, yields from successive yearly and 17-year average, 1909 to 1st seeding Bushels 27.9 14.6 0.0 6.1 ' 4.2 2.8 12.2 ' 20.8 15.3 12.6 14.8 22.1 10.7 4.5 16.6 15.5 9.0 2nd seeding Bushels 21.7 12.0 0.0 6.1 ' 3.2 2.8 12.2 ' 17.8 13.4 9.5 18.4 19.8 11.0 4.1 21.6 21.2 9.9 I ! I 3rd 4th Average 4 seeding ' seeding seedings Bushels Bushels Bushels 26.6 24.1 25.1 2.4 2.6 7.9 0.0 0.0 0.0 | 4.3' | 4.3 * 5.2 I 1.1 0.0 2.1 6.7 4.3 4.2 10.2 8.4 10.3 9.8 8.0 14.1 7.8 5.5 10.5 7.0 2.1 7.8 10.7 7.0 12.7 13.9 8.7 16.2 8.0 4.8 8.6 2.3 3.2 3.5 15.9 9.0 15.8 14.8 10.2 15.4 11.7 10.1 10.2 17-yr. average.. 12.3 12.1 I ' 9.0 I 6.6 10.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Spring Grains 7 in time between the second and fourth seedings was 24 days. The average decrease in yield from the second to the fourth seeding was 5.5 bushels. The average rate of decrease in yield for the delayed seeding was .23 bushel or nearly 2 per cent per day. 1 Yield from first seeding used for both first and second dates, used only once in average. Barley in the 16 years made its highest yield from the first seeding 5 times and from the second seeding 9 times. The average yield of the second seeding was 1.4 bushels per acre more than that of the first seeding. The decrease in yield from the second to the fourth seeding was 9.3 bushels, which is 0.39 bushel or 1.6 per cent per day. 'able 'arley yields from fi and 17 -year &gt;ur seedings each y&lt; averages ■ar, yearly 1st 2nd Year seeding seeding 3rd seeding 4th seeding Average 4 seedings 1 j Bushels Bushels 1909 41.0 32.3 18.5 16.2 19.6 ' 19.6 • '.".".""'.'.'.'.".'. ll!2 8^8 30.0 ' 30.0 ' 32.3 31.3 35.7 32.8 14.4 19.3 38.4 32.5 32.8 27.3 15.3 17.8 10.9 10.0 27.3 32.2 38.5 71.7 1925 7.9 13.0 I 17-yr. average..! 22.5 23.9 I I Bushels 44.2 8.9 0.0 19.8 8.3 12.0 26.2 21.9 21.1 19.7 23.3 37.2 14.8 14.1 21.2 18.8 11.0 Bushels 37.4 8.9 ' 0.0 0.0 2.4 10.1 26.5 16.3 15.2 15.2 19.6 17.1 12.8 9.8 16.9 22.7 17.5 ! Bushels s 0.0 13.1 £ 27.6 25.5 26.2 17.2 ll!2 24.4 27.9 12.4 18.9 14.6 20.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Table 4. — Oats, yields from successive seedings each year, yearly and 17-year averages, 1909 to 1925 inclusive 1st 2nd 3rd 4th [ Average 4 seeding seeding | seeding . seeding seedings Bushels . Bushel* Bushels Bushels Bushel* 1909 i 42.3 38.2 59.3 66.0 51.5 1910 1 15.4 11.9 9.3 7.7 11.1 1911 j 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 1912 22.0' 22.0 ' 21.8 15.0 19.6 1913 ! 10.8 5.4 1.6 .9 4.7 1914 j 0.0 0.0 16.0 19.3 8.8 1915 50.0 ' 50.0 ' 40.6 35.7 42.1 1916 57.2 54.2 27.4 22.2 40.3 1917 1 35.1 21.4 21.2 8.2 21.5 1918 26.4 36.0 28.0 14.1 26.1 1919 ! 49.5 48.2 39.0 39.0 43.9 1920 46.6 68.6 45.7 44.0 51.2 1921 20.5 21.1 18.0 12.0 17.9 1922 1 10.1 12.3 12.0 8.7 10.8 1923 1 47.9 53.5 42.6 38.6 45.7 1924 1 50.1 62.4 48.9 34.4 48.9 1925 11.2 20.4 20.0 20.5 18.0 17-yr. average.. 29.1 | 30.9 26.5 22.7 27.J 1 Yield from first seeding used fur both first and second seeding ; used in annual average. 1 Yield supplies by using average of first and third seedinks : not used in anr Oats, in the 16 years, made its highest yield from the first seeding 7 times and from the second seeding 6 times. The highest average yield was from the second seeding, which, however, exceeded the average of the first seeding by only 1.8 bushels per acre. The decrease in yield from the second to the fourth seeding was 8.2 bushels, which is 0.35 bushel cr about 1 per cent per day. The early seedings of oats were injured by freezing in 1914 only. In the other years when better results were secured from late seedings than from early seedings, it was the less favorable moisture conditions that caused lower yields and not freezing injury. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Table h.— Emmer yields from four seeding s each year 1909 to 1919. Yearly and 10-year averages 1st 2nd 3rd 4th i Average 4 seeding ' seeding ! seeding j seeding ! seedings Year Bushel* i Bushels Bushels Bushels I Bushels 1909 1 38.6 40.0 * 41.5 33.1 37.7 1910 1 20.7 7.8 3.8 3.8" 10.8 1911 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 1912 11.0 ' 11.0 ' 7.1 0.0 6.0 1913 ! 4.8 1.0 .8 0.0 1.7 1914 1 .7 1.6 6.0 5.9 3.7 1915 45.3 * 45.3" 26.5 31.7 34.5 1916 1 24.8 11.3 3.3 2.0 10.4 1917 1 10.5 3.4 1.7 1.1 4.2 1918 ! 4.4 5.2 .7 0.0 2.6 10-yr. average..! 16.1 12.7 9.1 7.8 11.4 * Yield from first seeding used for both first and second dates ; ustd only once in inuai average. 2 Yield supplies by using average of first and third settlings ; not used in annual average. 3 Yield supplies by using that of third date ; not used in annual average. Emmer, for the 9 years in which crops were harvested, produced yields that ranked in the order of seeding 6 times. The highest yield was produced by the first seeding 6 times and the lowest yield by the fourth seeding 7 times. Average yields ranked in order of seedings. The average decrease in yield from the first to the second seeding was 3.4 bushels per acre, from the second to the third seeding, 3.6 bushels and from the third to the fourth 1.3 bushels. The total decrease for the 34 days average interval from the first to the last seeding was thus 8.3 bushels, which is a little over 0.24 bushel or 1.5 per cent per day. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION, BULLETIN 213 Spring rye behaved somewhat differently from the other grains used. In the 7-year period during which it was grown, the highest yield was secured from the first seeding 2 times, from the second seeding 2 times, and from the third seeding 3 times. The highest average yield was from the third seed - ing, the next highest from the second seeding, and the third highest from the first seeding. The difference between the three seedings was slight, however, being only 0.4 bushel be - tween the third and first seedings. Average yields dropped off 4.6 bushels between the third and fourth seedings, or at the rate of 0.42 bushels per day. Jpnng rye yields, y year from 1919 t '-Ids from four seedings each 1925 inclusive 1st seeding 2nd seeding 3rd 4th seeding ! seeding Bushels \ Bushels I Average 4 seedings Bushels Bushels Bushels 1919.: 1920 1921 1922 1923 1924 1925 18.9 11.8 12.9 3.4 20.1 29.9 8.8 17.1 8.9 12.1 2.1 24.0 32.8 10.5 14.9 | 10.5 15.0 7.3 9.1 8.3 12.5 5.6 21.7 15.9 23.0 17.3 12.3 11.1 155 10.8 10.6 5.9 20.4 25.5 10.7 7-yr. average.... 15.1 15.4 15.5 10.9 I 14.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 COMPARATIVE YIELDS OF SPRING GRAINS Comparative average yields of five spring grains are shown in Table 7 and the accompanying figure. Oats show the highest yield in bushels per acre. Barley outyields oats in pounds per acre. When compared in pounds per acre with barley as 100, the other grains have values as follows: oats 91, rye 73, wheat 63, and emmer 52. Since some grains Yields of sprint; grains in pounds of grain and pounds of hull-free crain for 17 years at the North Platte Substation thresh free of hull and others have varying amounts of hull, a fairer basis of comparison than either bushels per acre or pounds per acre is pounds of hull-free grain. Compared in this way, barley still occupies first place and oats falls below both rye and wheat. Of hull-free grain, with barley as 100 the other grains have values as follows: rye 89, wheat 76, oats 72, and emmer 48. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Amount j Hull-free of hulls | grain Crop Variety yields Bushels Pounds [ Percent j Pounds 1 Rye and emmer were Brown for 7 and 10 years respectively. Their yields are calculated for the 17-year period on the basis of the ratio of barley for the correspond - ing years to barley for the entire period. CONCLUSIONS Trials of early, medium, and late seedings of spring grains for 17 years at the North Platte Experiment Substation, re - ported in this bulletin, and trials for 7 years at the Nebraska Experiment Station reported in Nebraska Bulletin 201 ' seem to justify the following conclusions: 1. Higher yields usually may be expected from early than from late seedings of spring grains. 2. Seeding time must of necessity be varied considerably from year to year on account of climatic conditions. The best time for seeding in eastern Nebraska is usually between March 15 and April 1, in central Nebraska between March 20 and April 5, and in western Nebraska between March 25 and April 10. In some years, seedings may be made earlier than these dates. Also, a year will occasionally occur when seed - ings cannot be made until after these dates. 3. Seeding may be made with reasonable safety as early in the spring as a seed-bed can be prepared after frost is out of the ground. K4. On the basis of hull-free grain, barley has been the highest yielding spring grain at both North Platte and Lin- coln. Spring rye occupied second place at both stations. Oats occupied third place at Lincoln but was outyielded by spring wheat at North Platte. The poorest yields were made V,., .,-v,™,,.. n 4- M^^+V, Dln+4-.r. n *A K,r V,, ,!!«„„ U n ,.i,,,, „*- T «■■- - » by emmer at North Platte and by hulless barley at Lincoln. 1 Nebraska Bulletin 201. by T. A. Kiesselbach and W. E. Lyness, reports a number 1 Nebraska Bulletin 201. by T. A. Kiesselbach and W. E. Lyness. reports a number of experiments with spring erain. including variety tests, effect of grading, time of ieeding. rate of seeding, seed from different sources, and comparative yields. E Common Six Row.. Common Kubanka J Kherson i Common ! 20.0 12.5 10.0 27.3 12.6 960 702 600 874 504 17.5 35. 25. i ' 792 702 600 568 378 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>