<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00024.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00024.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report OF THE Game and Fish Commission OF THE State of Nebraska For The Two Years Ending December 31, 1910 To The Governor</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BROOK TROUT RAINBOW TROUT SMALL-MOUTH BLACK BASS </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Biennial Report OF THE Game and Fish Commission OF THE State of Nebraska For The Two Years Ending December 31, 1910 To The Governor </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Lincoln, Neb., Dec. 31st, 1910. To His Excellency, Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor of the State of Nebraska. o Dear Sir: — I have the honor to submit herewith a report of the financial condition of the Game and Fish Commission for the biennium, beginning December 1st, 1909, and ending November 30th, 1910. Also a report of the number of arrests and convictions caused; the amount of fines and jail sentences imposed upon offenders against the game and fish laws; the number of illegal fishing devices confiscated and destroyed; the amount of game and fish confiscated and disposed of; the amount of money realized from the sale of fish for stocking pri - vate ponds and from the sale of licenses during the years of 1909 and 1910; also recommendations pertaining to the desired changes of our present game and fish laws; supplemented with a detailed report of the State Fish Hatchery by Deputy Warden W. J. O'Brien. In this, my final report, I wish to express my sincere gratitude to you for the many courtesies shown me and for your sportman-like man - ner in dealing with this department. Respectfully submitted, DAN GEILUS, Chief Deputy Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION' 5 Biennial Report OF THE Game and Fish Commission APPROPRIATIONS AND EXPENDITURES Salary of Chief Warden. Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 625.00 Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 3,000.00 Total $ 3,625 . 00 Amount expended during last biennium 3,125.00 Balance November 30, 1910 $ 500.00 Salary of Deputy Warden at Hatchery. Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 600.00 Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 2,400.00 Total $3,000.00 Amount expended during last biennium 2,400.00 Balance November 30, 1910 $ 600.00 Salary of Three Deputy Wardens. Amount on hand December 1, 1908 /.t 750 M Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 3,600.00 Total $4,350.00 Amount expended during last biennium 4,275.00 Balance November 30, 1910 $ 75.00 Salary of Secretary Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 630.00 Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 1,680.00 Total $2,310.00 Amount expended during last biennium 2,030.00 Balance November 30, 1910 $ 280.00 New Apparatus and Repairs, Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 443 . 70 Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 1,650.00 Total $ 2,093 . 70 Amount expended during last biennium 1,891 .42 Amount reverted to State Treasurer 21 . 00 Balance November 30, 1910 $ 180.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Necessary Labor. Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 225 . 00 Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 2,500. 00 Total $2,725.00 Amount expended during last biennium 2,318.00 Amount reverted to State Treasurer 1.00 Balance November 30, 191» $ 406.00 Procuring and Transplanting Fish, Fish Food and Fuel — South Bend. Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 298.59 Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 3,000.00 Total $ 3,298.59 Amount expended during last biennium 2,870.30 Amount reverted to State Treasurer .54 Balance November 30, 1910 , $ 427.75 Stationery, Telephone, Postage and Office Expenses. Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 235.55 Appropriated, April 2, 1909 1,100.00 Total $ 1,335.55 Amount expended during last biennium 1,197.42 Balance November 30, 1910 $ 136.13 Purchase of Team, Harness, Etc Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 6.14 Amount expended during last biennium 6 . 00 Amount reverted to State Treasurer .14 Balance November 30, 1910 $00,000.00 Constructing Assistant's Cottage, Etc. Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 3.79 Amount expended during last biennium 3 . 05 Amount reverted to State Treasurer .74 Balance November 30, 1910 .' $00,000.00 Traveling Expense Amount on hand December 1, 1908 $ 1,037 . 15 Amount appropriated April 2, 1909 5,000.00 Total •. $ 6,037.15 Amount expended during last biennium 5,226.48 Balance $ 810.67 Cement Works and General Improvements — South Bend Amount appropriated April 2, 1909 $ 1,500 . 00 Amount expended during last biennium 1,498.72 Balance November 30, 1910 $ 1.28 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">ON THE BANKS OF THE PLATTE RIVER. GRAND ISLAND THREE SPORTS FROM O NIKL. HOLT COUNTY </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION" Building Sidetrack, Moving Car House and Painting Fish Car South Bend Amount appropriated April 2, 1909 $ 500.00 Amount expended during last biennium 179.46 Balance on hand November 30, 1910 $ 320.54 Procuring Breeding Stock and Conducting Experiments — South Bend. Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 $ 500.00 Amount expended during last biennium 340.71 Balance on hand November 30, 1910 $ 159.29 Heating and Lighting Plant — South Bend. Amount apropriated April 2, 1909 $ 500.00 Amount expended during last biennium 375.00 Balance on hand November 30, 1910 $ 125.00 Maintenance and Improvements of Sub-hatchery, Cherry County. Balance on hand December 1, 1908 % 533.25 Amount appropriated, April 2, 1909 .,. . 2,000.00 Total , $ 2,533.25 Amount expended during last biennium: 2,167.33 Amount reverted to State Treasurer 33.24 Balance on hand November 30, 1910 $ 332.68 Cash Fund Amount on hand, December 1, 190S $ 225.83 Receipts from fish sales during biennium 598.50 Total $ 824.33 Amount expended during last biennium 714.41 Amount on hand November 30, 1910 * $ 109.92 Summary. Total amount on hand, December 1, 1908 $ 5,614.00 Appropriations, April 2, 1909 28,930.00 Receipts from fieh sales ' . . . . 598 .50 Total receipts $35,142.50 Expenditures during biennium $30,618 . 30 Amount reverted to State Treasurer 57 . 07 — $30,675 . 37 Total balance on hand November 30, 1910 $ 4,467.13 The balances as shown in the forfegfofing report, in my judgment will be ample to properly continue to carry on the work of the de- partment until the new appropriation becomes available. Moneys Paid to State Treasurer for Sale of Licenses and Sale of Fish. For the years of 1909 and 1910— 227 non-resident hunting and fishing licenses at $10.00 $ 2,270.00 414 non-resident (fishing only) licenses at $2.0? each 828.00 213 resident seining licenses, at $2.00 each 426.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 9 13,240 resident hunting and fishing licenses, at $1.00 13,240.00 21 scientific permits, at $1.00 each 21.00 Receipts from sales of fish for stocking private ponds, 1909 and 1910 803.50 Total $17,588.50 ARRESTS, SEIZURES AND CONVICTIONS. During the last biennium the Commission has caused the arrest of 177 persons, charged with the violations of our game and fish laws; 152 of these were convicted; 18 were acquitted and the cases against 6 are still pending. Of those convicted 150 paid fines and 30 were com - pelled to serve jail sentences. The total fines imposed and paid to the various county treasurers amounted to $1,63: Illegal nets numbering 149; and 345 unlawful fishing traps were con - fiscated and destroyed. A great many lines, having more than the legal number of hooks thereon have also been destroyed. In the neigh - borhood of 2,500 live fish were released from the unlawful traps and nets and approximately 2,000 pounds of fish and 100 game birds con - fiscated were disposed of to charitable institutions. In addition to this about 40,000 pounds of carp, buffalo, gars and hickcry shad were taken from the waters of Carter Lake in Douglas County. These fish are detrimental to the propagation of game fish and therefore were re - moved. These fish were disposed of in a manner to reimburse those engaged in the work, and the state, in that instance, was placed to no additional expense. Work of this nature has been dene in a dozen other localities in this state under the same conditions and with gocd results. Justices of the peace before whom nearly all prosecutions were brought seemed to be very lenient in administering punishment. In some instances even going so far as to disregard the law wherein a specific minimum penalty was provided for. Very seldom was a fine in excess of the minimum penalty imposed. The officers of this department have at all times endeavored to do their duty as they deemed proper and have at no time insisted upon severe punishment, but have tried to create respect for our laws by leniency. In many cases where the offense was trivial or of a technical nature the offenders were permitted to go with a warning or reprimand since we believe that more respect for law is to be gained in this man - ner than by the infliction of severe punishment. RECOMMENDATIONS. The result of the past two years' work of this department as a whole has f been very satisfactory, taking into consideration the pres - ent existing conditions. In some counties the law has been very well enforced. This was due largely to the assistance of sportsmen and other public spirited citizens who demanded a strict observance of our game and fish laws. In other counties, wherein public sentiment is contrary, very little could be done to compel due respect for these laws. In several in - stances those who were charged with the enforcement of the laws, In their respective counties, not only failed to do their duty but also assisted offenders in escaping the deserved punishment, thereby encour - aging future violations. To secure better observance of our game and fish laws, in the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">I </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION' future, new legislation is needed. Under our present system we em - ploy on a salary, one chief warden and three deputy wardens. The three deputy wardens each receive compensation for only eight months' service in each year, hence the continued service of only two deputy wardens is really secured. With this limited force, it is impossible to properly cover the entire ninety-two counties of this state. Therefore to attain the desired end a great deal of assistance from special deputy wardens must be relied upon. These special deputy wardens receive no compensation for their services, save one-half of the fines actually collected, in instances where such deputies appear as complaining witnesses. Many times when friends and acquaintances of these deputies are the offenders, they (the deputies) fail to cause prosecution, for the reason that since they draw no salary they do not feel in duty bound to prosecute and cause the enmity of their friends and ' acquaintances. If these special deputies would receive compensation for their services I am satisfied that they would -feel as though they owed something to the state for the moneys received and would then deem it their duty to prosecute offenders regardless as to whether or not such persons were their personal friends. By providing a salary for these special deputy wardens their service could be relied upon «nd of course such deputies would then be on the alert and keep a look-out, not only for offenders but also for the general improvement of conditions pertaining to the preservation of game and fish. In many localities in this state, especially in those counties along the Loups, N'emahas. Blues, Elkhorn, Platte, Republican and Missouri rivers, millions of fish which enter bayous, adjoining these streams during the high water period perish during each fall and winter, on ac - count of insufficient water to sustain fish life. Under our present sys - tem the money appropriated for this department is not sufficient to carry on the work of transferring these fish to waters wherein they will survive and the special deputy wardens do not feel it their duty to do this work unless they receive payment for their services. If these deputies would receive a salary, they, of course, would then deem it part of their duty to attend to such work. These deputies, if paid, would also feel it their duty when hearing of intended violations from among their neighbors and friends to immediately investigate and fore - stall the intended violation or prosecute the offender if necessary. Their assistance could then be depended upon and a great many offenders who violate our laws and who now go unpunished would be apprehended and brought to justice. A deputy warden in his own lo - cality is better acquainted with the conditions pertaining to violations of our game laws than is a stranger who is sent there on short notice. The local deputy warden is also well acquainted with the people of his community and knows those who are in the habit of violating our laws, he knows the persons who deserve to be watched and is fa - miliar with the conditions of the locality wherein poaching is being done, a great deal better than one who has visited that vicinity only once or twice. He is also continually in touch with his neighbors and commands a certain amount of their confidence and respect. Many of his neighbors who hear of intended violations would not then hes - itate to report the same to their local deputy and of course complaints would be made and the necessary information could be more easily obtained. The deputy warden in such instances would be in the im - mediate vicinity about the time the offense is committed and the arrest of the offender could be more easily made and the proper erl- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">- 12 GA.ME AND FISH COiJ. MISSION dence more readily secured. The common knowledge tbat a paid deputy who is willing to act resides in a community is sufficient to forestall many violations. In order to raise sufficient funds for the payment of the services of a force of deputy wardens large enough to cover the entire state, It is necessary to tax those who reap the benefits. By the adoption of a universal license system I believe that this question would be solved. In the state of Iowa, the last legislature passed a bill providing that every resident and non-resident who desired to hunt in that state must procure a license. The fee for a resident amounted to $1.00 and that for a non-resident to $10.00. Such a license permitted the holder to hunt or fish anywhere within that state during the year. Under this law in the year of 19C9 they succeeded in raising a fund amount - ing approximately to $105,000.00. I am satisfied that if this state would adopt a similar measure, in the neighborhood of $50,000.00 per annum would be realized from the sale of hunting and fishing licenses. This would then place the department in a position to pay for the services of not only a large force of deputies but would also permit the depart - ment to save millions of fish which now perish annually. I would recommend that every person over the age of sixteen years, who desires to hunt or fish within this state, be required to procure a license each year. The fee for such license for a resident to be $1.00 and that for a non-resident $10.00. This license to be pro - cured from the county- clerks, authorized to issue same. I would also recommend a provision requiring the applicant for a license, to pay to the county clerk for the service rendered in issuing such license, the sum of ten cents to be retained by the county clerk. Under our present law the county clerks receive no compensation whatever for such services and are put to an expense for which they are in no way reimbursed when issuing these licenses and making returns to the state treasurer. Our present laws require only those who hunt and fish outside of the county in which they actually reside to procure licenses; it seems to me that this provision is not entirely fair. I believe that every person hunting or fishing receives some benefit from the enforcement of our game and fish laws and from the propa - gation and preservation of game and fish and therefore should be re - quired to pay his proportionate share of the moneys necessary to carry on the work. The constitution of this state provides that all moneys realized from the sale of licenses must be deposited with the state treasurer and credited to the school fund and that such moneys can only be ex - pended for school purposes. This constitutional requirement has been met in the past by the legislature making a direct appropriation amounting aproximately to the same as that of moneys realized from the sale of licenses and from fines imposed. I believe that our future legislatures would be willing to appropriate, for the protection and preservation of game and fish an amount equivalent to that collected from the sale of licenses for the preceding biennium. This would place the legislatures in a position where they could say that the state was merely returning to the people the money which they had set aside for the protection, preservation and propagation of game and fish and to which they are justly entitled. Many complaints have been made during the past two years from localities where railroad construction gangs were employed. The </seg>
            <seg id="p013">ONE DAYS KILL IN CHEHRY COCNTY ENDEB9' LAKE BLACK BASS </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION common laborers who compose these gangs are in nearly all in - stances foreigners. These people do not seem to understand the ne - cessity of our game laws or either do not care to respect them. It has been reported in many instances that they go out and wantonly slaugh - ter all kinds of game, song and insectivorous birds and also domestic fowl and animals. If these persons were rejuired to procure licenses, I am satisfied that a very small number of them would be permitted to carry fire arms, and thereby this evil would in a large measure be overcome. Our present law permitting the taking of certain species of fish by the use of a net ought to be amended. The use of nets should only be permitted in waters wherein fish will not survive the summer or winter on account of insufficient water. The permission of the use of nets in streams allows only the few engaged in. fishing in this manner to reap the larger benefits of fish propagation, while the angler who pays his proportionate share must be content with what is left. I wish to also recommend the enactment of a law authorizing the department to issue permits allowing persons to kill beaver upon their own land, in instances where these animals are causing damage to trees. I would not recommend an open season, for the reason that the furs of these animals are very valuable and that if the pub - lic generally would be allowed to kill these animals a great many trappers and persons who engage in no other useful occupation would be constantly pursuing this work thereby causing the farmers and land owners untold annoyance by trespassing and other similar unlawful acts. In many instances the persons owning the land' where beaver abound do not wish these animals to be molested and in such cases permision to kill beaver could not be gained, thus insuring better pro - tection where desired. I wish to recommend a short open season on quail. Many of these birds which are useful as food perish during severe winters. If we had an open season, I am satisfied that the same would insure a bet - ter observance of the law in protecting these birds. Our present law provides for an entire closed season and since the temptation for hunting these birds is very great, I believe that those who now violate the law by killing them wherever and whenever found would confine their hunting to the open season aiyi feel satisfied. I wish to also recommend that the beginning of the open season on prairie chickens be changed to September 1st, instead of October 1st, the present opening date. On several occasions when visiting the re - gion where these birds are hatched and reared, while endeavoring to enforce &lt;jur present prairie chicken law, we have met with nothing but discouragement. We find that the residents of that portion of the state are very much opposed to our present law. They claim, and from observations I believe that they are right, that these birds are about fully grown by the 1st of September and that therefore they are in a condition to be killed. By the 1st of October, our present opening date, most of theee birds have left that section of the country, thus giving the persons who have protected them during the hatching and breeding season no opportunity for enjoying the benefits which really be - long to them. I believe that persons who are instrumental in the protec - tion and presevation of game are entitled to some consideration, but I do not think that they should be allowed to commit wholesale slaughter, but should cnly be permitted to take enough for home consumption. I would therefore recommend that no person be permitted to take more </seg>
            <seg id="p015">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 15 than ten prairie chickens in any one day or to have more than ten of these birds in his possession at any one time. I wish to also recommend a change in the open season on wild ducks and water fowl. Our present law provides for an open season frcm September 15th to April 5th. ! believe that the same should be from September 1st to April 5th. We find that a great many of our native wild ducks and water, fowl, which we have protected during the spring and summer migrate before the present opening date and we thus deny ourselves the sport of hunting the eame and afford the people of Kansas and jOther southern states, whose open season be - gins on September lsf, oenefits to which we are justl&gt; entitled. Turtle Doves. — An open season on these birds is also desirable. Under our present law, they are protected during the entire \ear and cannot lawfully be killed at any time in this state. These birds feed principally on grain and are therefore of no great benefit to the farmer, tut are considered a very dainty morsel of food. In many southern states no limit is placed upon the number of these birds allowed to be killed. and at times in such places they are slaughtered in great num - bers. We deny ourselves the privilege of killing these birds and there - by insure better sport to hunters of other states to which they mi - grate. In anticipate an attempt to change certain provisions oi our now existing laws, by the next legislature, which I think should by all means be prevented. One will be the attempt to change cur laws which make it an offense for persons to pursue same birds out of season. A few persons interested in the training of hunting d understand will introduce and push a bill of this character. These men are not engaged in the training of dogs for sport, but it is their purpose and intent to make money thereby. If a law were ] permitting the pursuit of birds at any time this state would be over - run with dog trainers and dogs sent here to be trained from almost every state in the union. This work usually -goes on during the months of July and August, when birds are small and very eaaj rrey for the dogs which are in training and not yet broken and of course when the time arrives for the sportsmen to lawfully take same, a great many of the birds have already been killed or on account of continual 1 ursuit have been driven out cf the state. Another attempt to change our laws will be, to repeal the sec - tion which not prohibits the sale of game and fish taken from public waters in this state. In nearly every state in the union the sale of game is prohibited. The purpose cf this restriction is to prevent the few market hunters from killing almost all of our game and fish and leaving only a few for the legitimate sportsmen who really are en - titled to the lion's share of the cesult of protection. Some ten years ago when game was permitted to be sold in this state I witnessed conditions in the commission house district in Omaha which were really shameful. I have seen ducks, geese, prairie chick - ens and quail piled up on the side-walk in front of commission houses by the thousands with no immediate means of disposal or ready sale, hence they were left to lie there and spoil and were eventually taken to the city dump and thrown into the Missouri river. I sincerely trust that our future legislatures will see the wisdom in our present law and not change the same. Lastly I wish to recommend the increase of the salary cf the su - perintendent cf the State Fish Hatchery. At the present time he re- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">ELKHORN KIVER SCENE A MORNINGS KILL. PLATTF RIVER </seg>
            <seg id="p017">v GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 17 ceives for bis services the sum of (1,200.00 per annum. This at least should be increased to the same salary as that of the chief warden, which amounts to $1,500.00 per annum. The superintendent at the State Fish Hatchery carries a great deal more of responsibility than does the chief warden and his knowledge of fish culture can only be attained by many years of hard and patient work. The present incum - bent has for the past twenty-two years been engaged in this work for this state and of course the longer so engaged the more valuable his services become and I believe that an increase in his salary should be seriously considered. In conclusion I wish to express my sincere gratitude to the sportsmen of this state for the assistance which they have rendered, and also to the special deputy wardens, whose work, without compen - sation, has been very material in the result attained. I wish to also thank the press for the many courtesies they have shown this depart - ment. Yours respectfully, DAN GEILUS, Chief Deputy Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">TROUT PONDS AND ASSISTANT'S COTTAGE </seg>
            <seg id="p019">O, tingling veins and blood that surges deep; O, royal sport to ardant mortals sent To feel the tremor of the lithe rod creep, To m3et the sullen plunge, the desperate leap. With victory mid waters turbulent. Report of The Superintendent of The State Fish Hatcheries Greta, Neb., Dec. 31, l»10 Hon. A. C. Shallenberger, Governor. I have the honor to submit a report of the number and kinds of fish hatched and planted, from the Hatcherjes, during the past two years, also a detailed statement of the more important improvements made at the Hatcheries during the period covered by this report. The grand total of fish planted includes all fish artificially hatched at the Hatcheries at Gretna, and Valentine, also all fish obtained from over- flow ponds transplanted or purchased for distribution: their ages range from two weeks old fry to mature fish as shown in the tables of distribution. The arrangement of the tables of distribution is some- what abbreviated as compared with the methods used in former reports but is the same as is used by the United States Commission of Fish- eries in their annual reports and will save considerable in the cost of printing, the records at the Hatcheries showing date of planting and names of applicants or employees who performed the work. Summary of Distribution, 1909-10. Wall-eyed Pike 9,1 Brook Trout 617.300 Rainbow Trout 534,600 Large Mouth Black Bass Crappie 54,564 Striped Perch 50,350 Channel Catfish 38,920 Yellow Bullheads 61,175 Sunnsh 13,150 Rock Bass 2,800 Small-mouth Black Bass vim Goldfish 2,398 German Carp 700 Buffalo Fish 2,300 Bull-frogs 2l'.7imi Cray-fish 500 10,863,241 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION With the exception of Pike the distribution has been more than trebled as compared with former biennial periods, this being especially so of the Basses and Catfishes. Fish planted in what is known as the fry stage were from two to twelve weeks old. Fingerlings mean fish from our to eight months old; yearlings about one year old and adults, mature or full grown fish. The adult stock was mainly secured from overflow ponds where there is danger of loss from ponds either drying up during the fall months or freezing to the bottom in winter. IMPROVEMENTS. Thirty-one hundred lineal feet of cement retaining walls along Bass, Crappie, Catfish, Perch and Goldfish ponds. These walls are from tvo to four feet in depth, and average about sixteen inches wide at the bottom and ten inches at top of wal' with sloping front, built of crushed rock, sand and cement. A carpenter shop fourteen by eighteen feet, with cement floor and permanent work bench and vise. Emir., new floor and closets in kitchen at Superintendent's residence; new pressed brick outside chimney, plastering repaired ; newly papered and painted interior and exterior; American Ideal Hot water heating plant installed in residence; gasoline lighting plant installed in hatch - ing house; entire new set of eight, bulk system, open trough, trout troughs; one hundred new trays provided for hatching house; hatchery building painted outside. Three hundred feet of two inch iron pipe laid from second dam to hatchery to supplement water from main spring for hatching purposes*. Cement floor put in tool and feed house, Ice and tool house painted. Necessary repairs made to barn, driving and material sheds, all repainted outside and white-washed inside. Assis - tant's cottage painted and new woodshed buiif for same. Cement floor and iron railing in spring house and house painted; road graded tc grove, and to prevent washing, cement gutter was built along same. Minor repairs to fence surrounding grounds, additional seats and tables, hitching racks and swings placed in grove for visitors. Pond banks above new retaining walls sodded, additional supply and drain pipes put in ponds as needed and a large amount of mud and leaves removed from ponds. Fish car "Antelope" painted, varnished and overhauled at the Burlington shops at Piattsmouth. Car house painted; 200 feet of tiling laid from ponds to river; stumps removed from strip of land between public road and the Plaite river; trees on this plat of ground trimmed, very much improving the appearance of the same. New steel gear lumber wagon ; set of bob-sleds ; ice plow, steel boat; three new seines; sixty additional shipping cans and much ether minor ejuipment purchased. Cherry County Sub-station. Two years ago the Legislature was asked for an appropriation of $5,000.00 to buy land and properly start the sub-fish hatchery in Cherry county. The appropriation of $2,000.00, made two years previous be - ing entirely inadequate for this purpose. But the members of the Leg - islature, in their wisdom, refused this request and made another al - lowance of $2,000.00 to continue the work. This amount being insuf - ficient to to purchase even a suitable site, let alone make improvements and hatch fish, I accepted an offer of the town of Wood Lake, which jiave us the free use of a seven acre lake in the town limits for a bass breeding pond. The state to place a small embankment around the west end of the lake to prevent fish from going out on the hay flat during periods of high "water. The citizens agreed to see that enough water was pumped into the lake to keep up the level, a wind- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 21 mill being put up for this purpose. The lake was stocked with adult Bass, during May, 1909, these spawned and hatched out a fine crop ot young bass, but the extreme dry period that followed in July and August, sapped the water at an alarming extent both by seepage and evaporation and the mill proved entirely inadequate to furnish sufficient water to keep up the level. As the water got low the alkali that is present in most all the sand hill lakes, bwame so strong that the smaller and weaker fish began to die. As soon as the weather was cool enough an effort was made to remove and transplant the fish, this work proved both disa point ing and expensive, as inc low stage of water had caused the moss and other vegetation to become very rank. After three days' work with a crew seining and cleaning out the moss we had only collected about 2.000 bass, and it was decided to discontinue the work. A caretaker was employed and was paid a small sum to keep air holes chopped in the ice during the winter to prevent smothering, but despite of this fact a part of the stock per - ished. A number of brood stock were again added during the past spring, not thinking we would have two dry years in succession, but the dry weather set in earlier than usual and by the middle of Sep - tember there was only about eighteen inches of water left in the deep - est portion of the pond. This enabled us to thoroughly seine it. While the increase was not as large as expected we secured over 2,000 Bass, mostly yearlings and adults, and about 5,000 adult Bullheads, and Sunfish which were in the pond prior to the time it was stocked with Bass. These were planted in the lakes and bayous along the Elkhorn river from Atkinson to Fremont, as shown later in the report. The Truot Hatchery at Valentine, operated out of this appropria - tion has proven a complete success from the start. About seventy - five per cent of all the trout eggs we have hatched for the past two years being furnished at this hatchery, and planted in the streams along the Northwestern railroad from Norfolk to Harrison.. With practically no loss. During the past summer an addition 14 by 20 feet for a bedroom and storeroom has been built, also new hatching troughs and trays and everything put in shape for the winter's work. A small amount of money was also spent of this fund for the purpose of keeping air holes open in the ice on Willow Lake, to prevent the smothering of thousands of Bass. If the present winter should be a severe one this work will be continued. While the law does not specifically provide that this fund shall be used in this kind of work, I think the end justifies the means Our experience of the past three years both as to the artificial ponds at Red Deer Lake and the natural pond at Wood Lake, fully demonstrates that while Bass and Crappie will live and thrive in these shallow sand hill ponds when the rainfall is normal and sufficient to neutralize the alkali, in dry years, the bet - ter class of game fish will perish. Seining the fish out of these shallow lakes is also expensive on account of the rank growth of water vege - tation that flourishes in this part of the state. Brook Trout. 617,500 were planted, nearly all in the fry stage, during the period covered by this report. As usual, the major portion being planted in the tributaries of the Niobrara River and the White River, streams that have proven by experience especially adapted to their culture. The rapid increase in the value of pasture and hay lands during the past few years has caused much of the waste lands bor - dering our best trout streams to be heavily pastured, resulting in the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">FKONT HATCHERY AND MILL PONf&gt; VALENTINE </seg>
            <seg id="p023">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 23 stock tramping in and destroying the banks and hiding places of the trout, thus destroying to a large extent their, feeding pools and leaving them an easy prey both to the poacher ■ and their natural enemies. However, where- they have in this manner been driven out of some streams they have sought refuge in other streams among the network of those emptying into the Niobrara, and as a whole, reports are satis - factory, as some nice catches of Brook Trout are reported from streams in Dundy, Keith, Deuel and Cheyenne counties, portions of the state not heretofore considered favorable to their growth. . Rainbow Trout. The number of Rainbow Trout planted during the past two years is greater than ever before and some nice catches of Rainbows are reported. Among the illustrations shown in this report is one of a two foot Rainbow, taken from Chadron Creek, Dawes county, on the ranch of Hon. Chas. Mann of the State Board of Agriculture, by F. H. DeRhodes of Chadron. This fish weighed four pounds, ten ounces, and while not as large as some specimens taken from Long Pine Creek and the headwaters of the White River, still it shows that even in in - ferior streams this species of fish is a success. They do not seem to increase in a natural way as well as the Brook Trout and continual stocking seems to be necessary to keep up the supply. Large-mouth Black The increased number of Bass planted is largely due to the large number planted in the fry stage which is much greater than in the preceeding periods. While I would like to rear all bass distributed to the fingerling or yearling stage before distributing, it is not practical in small ponds and we find that we can plant from one to two hundred thousand fry yearly and have about as many fingerlings for planting in the fall; this is accounted for from the fact that where the fry are so numerous in the ponds the cannibalism is greater than when they are thinned out so that the natural food afforded by the pond Is sufficient to keep them growing evenly. Bass fishing has been good in all our waters adapted to Bass culture in the past two years. Crappie. 54,734 crappie were planted during the past two years, all of them being from five months old to adult fish, having discontinued the at - tempt to plant a portion of them in the fry stage. The Crappie has proven one of the most successful fish every introduced into the in - terior waters of this state, and are now found in all of our principal streams and lakes. They thrive equally as well in muddy or murky water as they do in clear waters. They are very prolific and are not as destructive to their own kind as other members of the Bass family. A notable example of the enormous natural increase of species of this fish is furnished by the stocking of the mill pond at Valentine. This pond is fished in almost incessantly during the summer months and crappies of all sizes are taken. Yet the pond is still fairly teeming with them. Another pond which is well stocked with them is Swift's Lake, near Ashland. This lake has only been stocked about twelve years. It is a shallow, muddy lake, yet the crappies have multiplied by thousands. The propagation and planting of this fish should be increased. Wal-eyed Pike. A considerable decrease in the number of Pike planted in the past two years, as compared with the former two-year period, is shown in </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION this report. We have always depended on collecting our Pike spawn from fish taken by the commercial fishermen on Saginaw Bay, Lake Huron, but by the last session of the Michigan Legislature an amend - men was attached to their fish laws, which provided that all fish eggs collected from fish taken from public waters should be turned over to the State or the United States Bureau of Fisheries and Hatch - eries, to be planted in Michigan waters, and when I arrived at Bay City last April, I was informed of the provisions of this law. I made a trip to the state capital and Hon. Chas. H. Pierce, the chief warden, gave me permission to collect what eggs we needed, saying that he thought there was enough eggs there for all the hatcheries. I did not meet with such a pleasant reception from the agents of the United States Fish Commission,. Instead of co-operating with us, as the gov - ernment commission is supposed to do, every obstacle was placed in our way*. We only wished to put spawn takers on two boats out of about fifty, but F. N. Clark, the general superintendent of the United States Hatcheries in Michigan, personally came to Bay City, and under cover of this law demanded that his spawn takers be placed on one of the boats I had made arrangements for. Not wishing to engage in a law suit or desiring to embarrass Mr. Pierce, after a few days 1 work in an effort to collect on boats not taking many spawn fish I decided to abandon the work. Nezt sprinp we will either have to go to some other point for tire epgs, or buy the unripe fish from the fisher - men on Saginaw Bay, and hold them in racks until they are ready to Spawn. This will add to the cost of collection, but it is the only way to insure getting a supply. As a result of the large number of Pike planted by this Commission Pike fishing was better the past summer than it has been for many years Striped Perch. Generally speaking the Perch are not holding their own in our waters. This is especially so in the eastern part of the state. Carter Lake in Douglas county and Crystal Lake in Dakota county, the two best lakes bordering the Missouri river a few years ago, afforded splendid Perch fishing, but now these lakes seem almost barren of this gamie little pan fish. I cannot positively account for the changed conditions. Perhaps the Carp, which are numerous in both bodies of water, are eating all of the Perch eggs and thus preventing an in - crease in a natural way. I have come to this conclusion from the fact that Raccoon Lake in Cherry county, »na Adkinson Lake in Dundy county, which fifteen years a^o contained no Perch, are now fairly swarming with them. Neither of these lakes contain Carp. This seems to prove that the Carp are responsible for the disappearance of the Perch. Channel Catfish. The demand for Catfish, both for public and private plants has been greater than ever before as will be noted by the great increased distribution. The lack of rainfall and consequent low waters which, unlike wet years, permitted them to get over and around many of the dams spanning our streams has caused numerous applications to be made for Catfish to stock mill ponds and sluggish streams during the past two seasons. While I have not been able to furnish them in the quantities demanded in many requests, still the distribution has been more than doubled: as they were nearly all yearlings' and eighteen months old fish the good results that will acrue from this distribution can hardly be questioned. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">FOUR PROMINENT NEBEASKANS WITH CATCH OF BASS FROM DEWEY LAKE </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Yellow Bullheads. The ease with which this fish adapts itself to almost any kind of water makes it a valuable fish to stock muddy ponds and sluggish streams. In the eastern and southern part of this state I think no fish will give better returns on the money spent in their propagation and distribution. While they do not appeal to the angler with expen - sive tackle and do not furnish much sport they have gladdened the heart of many a small boy and furnished a nourishing food for many a poor man's table. They also produce results in waters where the planting of the more aristocratic Trout and Bass would bring only disappointment and failure. Sunfish. While we have hatched but few Sunfish at the Hatcheries in the past two years, a large number have been seined from drying up waters and transplanted from lakes that were overstocked with them to other waters that were barren. Some of the lakes in the sand hills are becoming so overstocked with them that they are stunted to such an extent as to be unfit for table. use. These should be trans - planted to barren waters as fast as possible. Under favorable condi - tions they attain a weight of one pound or more and furnish in the stock country a staple article of food for many a ranchman and home - steader, as there is no better pan fish than the sunfish. There are enough sunflsh in the lakes and ponds of Cherry county to stock every barren water in the state if we had sufficient funds to properly trans - plant them. Bull-frogs. As the Bull-frog rejuires five years to mature it is yet too early to tell definitely what the efforts to introduce them into our state will amount to. Those planted in Brown, Chase and Dundy counties seem to be thriving. Reports from other points are not so flattering. How - ever, the outlay on the frog experiment has been so small that the ex - periment will be well worth all it will cost. Smal-mouth Black Bats. An appropriation of $500.00 was granted by the last legislature for the introduction and experiments in hatching new varieties of fish, among them small-mouth Black Bass. After considerable correspon - dence with the officials of other fish commissions, arrangements were finally made with Hon. Chas. H. Pierce, chief game warden of Michigan, for the exchange of Channel Catfish and Crappie, for 200 adult Bass, we to deliver the Catfish and Crapples and collect the Bass. Last April transportation was secured for the fish car and crew to Bay City, the intention being to collect the Bass on Saginaw Bay, Lake Huron, the same point where we collected our annual supply of Pike eggs. Satisfactory terms were made with a number of fishermen to save for us the Bass that were taken in their nets and to furnish dummys or live nets toehold the fish until we secured the required number. We found Bass exceedingly scarce, not more than two or three being taken from a string of pound nets daily. After spending about ten days and having collected only 140 fish we decided it would be impossible to hold what we had secured in the live nets any longer, therefore we col - lected a number of adult Rock Bass and Yellow Perch, and with the Pike eggs we had collected we started home. We suceeded in getting through with the loss of only one Bass. For the first month after they were placed in the spawning pond they seemed to be doing fine, but suddenly about the time they began spawning — about May 15th — fungus </seg>
            <seg id="p027">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 27 began to appear on them and it looked for a time as though we would lose the entire lot. The usual remedy to counteract the fungus was ap - plied and we succeeded in saving about one-half of the number. The females that were left spawned out in due time but only about a dozen of the nests produced healthy fry. Xone were planted in the fry stage, but 800 flngerlings were planted in the mill pond at Valentine and uewey Lake in Cherry county, both of these bodies of water being admirably adapted to their culture and growth. We still have about one thousand of the flngerlings on hand for spring delivery or to in - crease the brood stock. An effort was made in October to securo an additional number of breeders from akher Missouri or Minnesota, but the wardens in these states claim they were getting so scarce that they did not care to allow any of them to be taken out of the state. However, another attempt will be made during the coming spiing a* there is yet about $160.00 available of the appropriation for this pur - pose. Marble Catfish. Among the new varieties of fish contemplated to be introduced un - der the special apropriation was the so-called Marble Catfish. This fish is extensively cultivated by the Ohio Fisn Commission and is rec - ommended for pond culture. We secured 100 of these fish from the hatchery at London, Ohio, and were somewhat disappointed to find that while they belonged to the Catfish family, they were really nothing but the native Bullhead, found in Michigan. Ohio and other states bor - dering the Great Lakes. While they are excellent fish for stocking farm ponds and sluggish streams they are in no way superior to our native yellow Bullhead for this purpose and resemble them in every way, except color, which is a dark marble and very much like the Bullheads found in some of our sand hill lakes. Under the circum - stances we see no advantage to be gained by taking up the propaga - tion of this specie. Rock Bast. While we have been engaged in the culture of the Hock Bass in a email way for several years, the addition of a new stock of brood fish procured while at Bay City last April, has enabled us to greatly in - crease our distribution of these fish as will be noted by referring to the tabulation of distribution. Our Sand Hill Lakes. Our main reliance for good Bass Ashing will in a few years de - pend entirely on the large lakes in Holt, Rock, Brown, Cherry, Itawes, Hooker, Grant and other counties in that part of the state, known aa the sandhill region. A number of these lakes now afford as fine angling as can be found anywhere in the country. Most of these lakes are comparatively shallow and while they are the natural habitation of the Bass family, during severe winters like the winter of 1909 and 1910, unless air holes are opened frequently to allow the air to get to them, large numbers of the fish perish. A paid warden should be stationed in Cherry county to look after this work every winter in Cherry county and the adjoining counties. This warden should be a reliable man, not a politician who would do his fish conservation around some hotel radi - ator, but one who lives in the lake country and is familiar with the surroundings and imbued with a desire to save our game and fish. Part of the time this work of going from one lake to another would have to be done on horseback and a youne;, active man would be needed </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 29 for this position. While few of these lakes have outlets under normal conditions, during periods of continued wet weather they overflow down the valleys and thousands of fish are carried out rn the hay lands or shpllcw swamps 10 perish. Most of these swamps are so densely filled with moss, bullrushes and other water vegetation as&gt; to make success - ful seining impossible. This waste could be prevented by s,creenin? the cutle.s of such lakes as Dewey, Willow and Trcut Lakes in Cherry county and Enders Lake in Brown county, if it has been worth the efforts put forth during the past t«ent\-five years to stock these lakes with edible fish and which makt thousands cf pounds of fish grow where none grew before, it i&amp; surely necessary to protec. them. Conservation of Fish. Within tne last four or five years considerable inkiest ha:; been routed in the question of conservation of our natural resources. The last legislature made an appropriation of $1,000.00 fcr a commission to inquire into the most feasible method cf stopins t lie waste. At a meeting held the past summer I was appointed a member ro report on fish and birds. I hive taken no part in the deliberations of this com - mission ( as 1 think 1 have been doing my part in a practical way to save what I could of our native fish from extermination, and while I have decided views as to what should bo done to conserve our re - maining birds and same, this portion of the work is properly :he field cf my colleague on the Game and Fish Commission, therefore. I shall not attempt to deal with it. Nebraska never has been noted for her fisheries, and after twenty - three years of almost continuous work in the employ of the Commis - sion I am free to admit that so far as the better class cf game fleh, such as the Trout and Bass, is concerned, we will never take high rank, as a large portion of our state is not adapted to their cul - ture, owing to the fact that '.and is increasing in price which is caus - ing the breaking up and tilling of thousands of acres cf land, that has hitherto been devoted exclusively to pasture, thus adding enormously to the soil wash and in many cases entirely filling the streams, lakes and ponds. If they are not entirely filled in they become ?o shallow that they either dry up in the summer or suffocate their finny inhabi.ants in severe winters. Under these cenditions it is certainly folly to con - tinue to plant game fish in these waters where they have no chance to thrive and increase. Twenty years ago it was an easy matter prac - tically all over eastern and southern Nebraska to go to almost any stream, pond or bayou and with a few yards of seine haul out a wagon load of fine Buffalo fish. The same was practically true of the Pickerel, Bull-heads and Sun-fish. Today a five or ten-pound Buffalo fish is extremely rare and over a large part of this territory the Pick - erel, Bull-head and Sun-fish have practically disappeared. At the pres - ent time ninety per cent of all the pickerel left in the state are con - fined to Antelope and Holt counties. This commission has never de - voted any attention_to either the Buffalo Fish or Pickerel, and only in the last few years has any effort been made to propagate cr conserve the Sun-fish or Bull-heads. The older inhabitants will tell you that Catfish, both Channel and Yellow, weighing from fifty to a hundred and fifty pounds were quite common twenty-five years ago. Today it is a rare sight to see one of these fish taken. Fish too small are being taken from the Missouri river and other streams and are being sold by the thousands, which weieh from four to eight ounces and we have no law to prevent it. With fish taken </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION &gt; from the Missouri river and with an inadequate warden service to en - force the law on other streams, what is true of the fish above is also true of other native fish. The striped bass, once abundant in Carter Lake in Douglas county and Crystle Lake in Dakota county are now practically extinct. My remedy for saving those left is to pass a law limiting the size of all kinds of fish that may be taken. To also provide a fund for the commission to seine and transfer all fish which are left in shallow waters, by overflow of streams or by drouth, to flowing water. While we have done considerable seining of overflow ponds we have saved only the Bass and Crappie, leaving the other fish to perish, on account of lack of funds. All fish, with the exception of a gar fish, found in these ponds should be returned to the streams. I know our sportsmen will criticise this statement, but the growing value of even the despised carp must be recognized. Four years ago I called atten - tion in my report to the fact that H. H. Biggerstaff of Ashland had taken 14,000 pounds of Carp and Buffalo fish from Salt Creek for which he received over $600.00. The following hauls of Carp have been made in other states within the past sixty days: J. B. Converse, at Lake Kegonsha, Wisconsin, 50,000 pounds, value $3,000.00; Henry Gatlin, Peoria, Illinois, Illinois River, 200,000 pounds, value $8,000.00; Hardman &amp; Nelson, Spirit Lake, Iowa, from Spirit Lake, 320,000 pounds, value $6,400.00. These figures were taken from the Fishing Gazette, and can be relied upon. From an angler's standpoint the introduction of the Carp into some of our waters was a mistake, but from a commer - cial point of view they are the most profitable fish ever introduced into our waters. Illinois and Ohio now prohibit the taking or sale of Carp under one pound in weight and the catch of Carp in Illinois now amounts to more in value in a commercial way than all other kinds of fish combined. Uuder these circumstances it seems to be the height of folly for ua to allow hundreds of thousands of them to perish in our overflow ponds every year. A law that prevents the taking of these fish from overflows by- our citizens and does not provide funds for the Commission to save these fish meets only with the public derision it deserves. The coming session of our legislature should pass a universal license law, imposing a license on hunters, anglers and commercial fishermen modeled after the Iowa lav which has pro - duced a revenue of $108,000.00 during the first year of its enforce - ment. If this money has to be paid into the School Fund as our pre - sent license money is being disposed of, the Auditor should' be empowered tp draw out of the General Fund an amount equal to that being paid into the School Fund, which is derived from euch licenses, the money to b«&gt; used in supporting this Commission. One-half to be used in providing an efficient warden service, and the propagation and distribution of game. The other half to be used for the propagation, conservation and distribution of fish in our waters. The sale of mature Buffalo Fish, Carp, Sturgeon, Gars, Quill Back and Suckers should be permitted and the sale of all kinds of Bass and Trout, except Lake Trout, wheth - er taken in this or other states should be prohibited. These fish will never become numerous enough in our state, except in a few lakes and streams to allow them to become a commodity of barter and sale. In the lakes and streams adapted to their culture they should be pre - served for the benefit of the whole people, and not used for the profit of a limited few Private Hatcheries. During the past twenty years many attempts have been made to </seg>
            <seg id="p031">CAME AND FISH COMMISSION 31 establish private fish hatcheries, but either from lack of experience or capital, they have in most instances proven a failure. The success of a small hatchery started at Benkelman, Dundy county, about five years ago by Barr &amp; Runion is something worthy of more than passing no - tice. Started originally merely for the personal pleasure of the owners it has become a source of considerable profit. They rear Bass, Crappie. Perch and Sunfish and are now equipped to handle a limited number of Trout. The past two winters they have hatched out several thousand eyed Trout eggs, for this Commission, without expense, and planted them in the creeks in their vicinity. They have found a market for most of their output of Bass and Crappie in Colorado and New Mexico. We have bought a few thousand fingerling fish from them for distri - bution in the southwest part of our State. I regret very much that we have not had ample funds to handle all the Bass and Crappie they have had for delivery. Elsewhere in this report are shown some views of of their plant. Aquarial Exhibits. The usual live fish display was made at the State Fair in the past two years, in an endeavor to educate the people as well as to amuse them. Neat placards were placed above each acquarium giving the habits and relative food value of each kind of fish shown. Also one aquarium containing six months old specimens of the various kinds of fish propagated at the hatcheries. The management of the Land Products Exhibit to be held at Omaha, January 19th to 28th, 1911, have asked for a small exhibit of live fish and a demonstration of trout hatching at their show and their request will be granted, they to pay all expenses. Cash Fund. This fund is derived from the sale of fish for private ponds, and ornamental fish. $803.50 has been derived from this source and paid to the State Treasurer, as provided in Section No. 13 of Article No. 1 of the present Fish and Game Laws. Conclusion. In the estimates made for current expenses, a slight increase is asked for in the items of Necessary Labor, Procuring Fish Eggs, Trans - portation, Etc. While I know it to be a fact that nearly every super - intendent or head of the department, is usually asking for more money, I think the increase in this case is amply justified for the following reasons : We are being allowed practically no greater amount in these funds than we were fifteen or twenty years ago. At that time the railroads, without exception handled the fish car and Commission employees over their lines free of charge. At the present time we pay ten cents per mile for handling the car and regular fare for employees in charge of fish, with one exception, the C. t N. W. Railroad, still handles the car free over their lines. The price of beef livers and other fish food has nearly doubled in the past two years, as well as a big increase iu the cost of all other supplies. Ten years ago we paid our help at the Hatcheries forty dollars per month. We are now paying fifty and six - ty per month. It is difficult to get competent help at that price Since the advent of automobiles our visitors have multiplied by the hundred. They demartd that everything about the hatchery and grounds, espe - cially during the summer months, be kept spink and span. This takes </seg>
            <seg id="p032"/>
            <seg id="p033">33 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION money and labor. In addition to direct appropriations, Iowa and Colora- do have a universal license system, which money they use, while our license moneys are turned into the School Fund. The last session of the Iowa legislature appropriated $13,000.00 and passed a license law which has produced $108,000.00 the first year. Colorado made a direct appropriation of $73,200.00 and collected over $53,000.00 in licenses. All of which is used, in both states, for the suport of their Game and Fish Department. The above sums are small compared to what is be- ing spent in other States. While we need more money and should pay more attention to the conservation of our fish and game, than we have in the past, I think it should come out of the pockets of those who hunt and fish, so that this department could be a revenue producer instead of a tax on the general fund and I hope that legislation to this end will be enacted at the coming session. The State property at the Hatcheries is in first-class condition, as I believe an inspection will prove. There will be no deficiencies to pre- esnt to the coming legislature. I wish to thank Chief Warden Geilus for his co-operation in the work, as well as my assistants at the Hatch- eries, also the County Commissioners of Sarpy county, who have de- cided to spend a large amount of the inheritance tax fund now in their possession in improving the main roads leading north and east from the hatcheries. Aleo the press who have given freely of their space for the benefit of the hatcheries and fish cultural work. Respectfully submitted. W. J. O'BRIEN, Deputy Fish Commissioner. State Property at Fish Hatcheries. Site of 53 acres all fenced $ 5,000. 00 Hatching House 2,500.00 Hatching apparatus, furniture and shipping cans 8( Superintendent's residence 2,800. 00 Assistant's cottage 1,200.00 Ice house 500.00 Tool house and shop - Barn, driving and material sheds 600 . 00 Workshop and tools 200. 00 Spring house and 1,000 feet supply pipe 600.00 Steel windmill, pumps and flume 300.00 Fish distributing car and car house 4,000.00 Twenty-five ponds with stone dams and supply pipe 4,000.00 Estimated value of fish in ponds 2.000 . 00 Team of horses, three wagons, two sets harness 600.00 Row boats, seines and nets 200 . 00 Miscellaneous tools 200 . 00 Hatching house and apparatus at sub-hatchery 800.00 $26,500.00 Wall Eyed Pike Distribution. 1909. Fingerlings, Disposition. Yearlings. Counties. ■ Fry. arid Adults. Antelope — Clearwater. Elkhorn River 100.000 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Butler- Ulysses, Blue River „ 50,000 Cuming — Wiener, Elkhorn River 500,000 Clay— Sutton, Little Blue River 50.000 Colfax — Clarkson, Jonas Pond 120 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 500.000 100 Furnas — Cambridge, Medicine Creek 50,000 Holt— Ewlng. Elkhorn River 500,000 O'Neill. Elkhorn River 150,000 Knox — Niobrara, Niobrara River 500,000 Nance — Genoa, Loup River 500,000 Platte— Columbus, Loup River 1,000,000 Sarpy— Fisheries. Platte River 1,000.000 Fisheries, Elkhorn River 1,000.000 Seward — Milford, Blue River 200,000 Seward, Blue River 200,000 Saline- Crete, Blue River 200,000 (Estimated) 6,500,000 120 Brook Trout Distribution, 1909. Antelope — Clearwater, Pebble Creek 5,000 Orchard, South Verdigre Creek 25,000 Savage, North Verdlgree Creek 16,000 Brown — Long Pine, Pine Creek 10,000 Long Pine, Short Pine Creek 10,000 Cherry — Valentine, Minechaduza Creek 15,000 Valentine, Schlagel Creek 10,500 Valentine, Seven Creeks 12,500 Valentine, Big Cedar Creek 2.500 Cody, Medicine Creek 7,500 Kilgore, Canyon Creek 5,000 Valentine, Berry Creek 7,500 Dawes — Chadron, Big Bordeaux Creek 15.000 Chadron, Beaver Creek 5,000 Dundy — Benkelman, Buffalo Creek 10,000 Benkelman, Rock Creek 10 000 Benkelman, Indian Creek 10,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">GAME AND FISH COM .MISSION 35 Holt- O'Neill, Red Bird Creek 10. O'Neill, Eagle Creek 10,000 Cella. Eagle Creek 5.M6 Stuart, Big Sandy Creek 1 0,000 Stuart. Spring Creek 12.-".'in Dorsey, Steele Creek M Finserlings, Disposition Yearlings. Counties. . Fry. and Adults. Rock— Bassett, Three Creeks 15.000 Sheridan- Gordon. Spring Creek I.6M Rushville. White Clay Creek 12.500 Thomas — Seneca. Big Creek 3.000 Rainbow Trout Distribution 19C9. Antelope — Clearwater, Pebble Creek Royal. North Verdigre Creek 15,000 Brown- Long Pine. Pine Creek 45.000 Johnstown, Plum Creek 2 Cherry- Valentine. Schlagel Creek B.OM Valentine. Minechaduza Creek I Dawes— Chadron. Ch'adron Creek Andrews. White River : Holt- O'Neill, Eagle Creek O'Neill, Red Bird Creek Hainesville. North Verdigre Creek O'Neill, Blue Bird Creek 2 Ml Atkinson, Eagle Creek 7JM Atkinson. Big Sandy Creek Atkinson. Middle Eagle Creek 17.500 Madison — Norfolk. Clear Creek 3.000 Thomas — Seneca, Middle Loup River 12.000 Seneca, Big Creek 1,000 (Estimated) 229 1,000 Lake Trout Distribution, 1909. Brown— Mfdvale. Clear Lake MM Long. Pine Mill Pond 2.500 Cherry — Valentine. Mill Pond 5.000 Washington — </seg>
            <seg id="p036">HATCHING TKOt'GHS SHOWING EUGS IN PROCESS OF INCUBATION </seg>
            <seg id="p037">GAME AM) FISH I'OJIMIr Arlington, Wilson's Lake I.. (Estimated* 14.500 Large Mouth Black Bass Distribution. 1909. Fingerlinga Disposition. linns Counties. Pry. and Adults. Adams — Roseland. Dewltt's Pond \l&lt;t Antelope — Clearwater. Elkhorn Cut-Off Neligh. Mill Pond Clearwater. Huffman Slough Brown — Ainsworth. Spring Lake. Ainsworth, Hofeldt's Lake. gM Long Pine, Berger's Pond. Buffalo— Pleasanton. Pleasanton Lake 10 Ravenna, Beaver Creek Kearney, Grothan's Pond 4"0 Cass- Louis ville, Park Pond Chase- Imperial. Frenchman River Ml Champion, Champion Lake Ml Champion, Moranville Lake Ml Cherry — Cody. Raccoon Lake 42 Valentine, D Bar Lake 12 Wood Lake, Clear Lake ion Wood Lake. Wood Lake Merriman, Spring Lake Clay- Angus. Little Blue River Ml Colfax— Clarkson, Jonas Pond 1 "0 Cuming — West Point. McKirrahan's Lake Custer— Anselmo, Victoria Creek .'..' Arnold, Spring Pond i'"'" Dakota — Dakota City, Crystal Lake 25.000 Dawes — Wayside. Baird's Pond Douglas — Omaha. Carter Lake Omaha. Johnson's Pond 1 .itiin Irvington, Shepard's Pond Frontier — Curtis, Curtis Lake 1.000 May wood, May wood Lake Furnas — Cambridge. Park Lake Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p038">2 z 2 a i Q 5&lt; SI M I' 1 I I as o i a ■ ■m w ■ J" </seg>
            <seg id="p039">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 39 Cambridge, Medicine Creek Grant — 500 Hyannis. Stump Lake. Oi'O Hyannis, Twin Lakes. Harlan — 2.000 Orleans. Mill Pond 400 Oxford, Republican River. Holt- 40i&gt; O'Neill. Elfchorn River 1,000 Atkinson. School Section Lake 400 Amelia. Artesian Lake 500 Jefferson — Fairbury, Little Blue River 2m) Keya Paha — Selden, Selden Lake 300 Selden. Trapper Lake \ y 300 :oln— y. Lincoln — North Platte. Turpie Lake .". l .:,00 North Platte. Neville's Lake Nance — Genoa, McKay's Lake. 300 Genoa, Spring Lake Otoe — 5M Nebraska City. Driving Association Lake 10,000 2.SM I'nadilla. Pickrell's Pond i:,0 Nebraska City, Roddy's Pond Pierce — Pierce, Mill Pond Platte— Columbus, Polander Slough 1.M4 Columbus. Stevens' Lake Cclumbus, Halej 's Lake Red Willow- McCook. Willow Creek Saunders — • Wahoo Nygren's Lake 5.000 500 Scotts Bluff — Gering. Huffman's Lake Gering. Irrigation Lake 500 Sheridan — ■ Gordon, Clear Lake »&gt;u0 Gordon. Carson's Lake 4M Gordon. Hay Creek Ponds Stanton — Stanton, Hagelman's Pond 140 Thomas- Seneca, Swan Lake 20.000 1,040 Wasnington— Blair. Spring Lake 2.000 133,000 37,814 Crappie Distribution, 1909. Fingerlings, Yearlings. and Adults Disposition Countie Fry. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">INTERIOR VIEW MAIN HATCHING^OUS^SOUTH^END. SHOWING METHOD OF </seg>
            <seg id="p041">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 41 Antelope — Clearwater. Elkhorn Cut-Off. 500 KM Clearwater, Huffman Slopgh Oakdale. Elkhorn Cut-Off... Neligh, Mill Pcnd 500 Blaine— Dunning. Middle Loup River Brown — 1.000 200 Ains worth. Spring Lake. Ainsworth. Hofeldfs Lake Buffalo — 300 Pleasanton. Pleasanton I^ake Ravenna. Beaver Creek 500 l.noo Chase — Imperial. Frenchman River Cherry — 500 Cody. Raccoon Lake... Valentine, D Bar Lake. 2n 14 Clay— Angus, Little Blue River Curoing — 1.500 5M West Point. McKirrahan's T^ake Custer — Anselmo. Victoria Creek Dodge — SM Scribner, Elkhorn Cut-Off Douglas — M« Omaha. Carter Lake. Frontier — goo Curtis. Curtis I&lt;ake. 1.000 1.000 Maywood, Maywood Lake Furnas— Cambridge, Park Pond Franklin — 1 000 100 Upland, Roggenkamp's Pond Grant — Hyannis. Stump Lake Hyannis. Twin Lakes. 1.000 1 .000 Hall- Grand Island. Wood River Cairo, St. Michael's Slough Harlan — 500 Orleans. Trestle Pond... Oxford. Republican River Hitchcock- Trenton. Spring River. 4 or, Culbertson, Frenchman River. Holt— Ewing. Elkhorn River Amelia. Artesian Pond Atkinson. School Section Lake Atkinson, Lamb's Lake 300 ?JM Atkinson, Dora Lake. Jefferson — SM Little Blue River. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Johnson — Tecumseh, Dafoe's Pond. Lancaster — 50 Denton. Deitrich's Pond. Lincoln — 200 1,500 1,500 North Platte, Turpie's Lake. North Platte. Neville's Lake. Madison — Norfolk, Mill Pond Nance — 500 500 Genoa. Spring Lake. Pierce — 500 Pierce, Mill Pond. Platte— 200 Columbus. Polander Slough. Columbus. Haley's Lake. Columbus, Guter Slough. 500 500 Columbus, McPherson's Lake. Red Willow — 1.000 McCook. Willow Creek Saunders — 500 Wahoo. Nygren's Lake. Ashland, Wahoo Creek Ashland. Swift's Lake. 500 1000 1.000 Scotts Bluff — Gering. Huffman's Lake. Sarpy— 500 LaPlatte. Trestle Lake. Seward — 500 Milford, Blue River. Thomas — 500 Seneca, Swan Lake. 1,500 32.484 Yellow Bullhead Distribution, 1909. Fingerlings, Yearlings, and Adults. Disposition. Counties. Fry' Antelope — Neligh. Mill Pond 1.000 Clearwater. Huffman Slough Blaine— 500 Dunning. Middle Loup River Brown — 1,000 Ainsworth. Hofeldt's Lake. Buffalo- 300 Ravenna. Beaver Creek. 1.000 Kearney, Grothan's Pond Butler — 300 riysses. Blue River. Cuming — 1.000 West Point, Mill Pond Custer — 500 Broken Bow. Cullen's Pond 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 43 Colfax— Benton, McPherson Lake. Dodge — 1,000 Scribner, Elkhorn Cut-Off. Douglas — 1,000 Omaha, Carter Lake. Furnas — 1,000 Cambridge, Park Lake. Hall— MM Grand Island, Wood River. Holt— 1.000 Ewing, Elkhorn River. O'Neill, Elkhorn River. 1.000 600 Jefferson — Fairbury. Little Blue River Johnson — Ml Tecumseh, Dafoe's Pond. Kearney — 50 Axtell, Nelson's Pond Lancaster — 100 Lincoln, Salt Creek Madison — 2.000 Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn River Otoe— 1.000 Nebraska City, Driving Associatiqp Park Pawnee — Lake 150 Table Rock. Gilpin's Pond Platte — Columbus. Loup River. Saline- 1.000 Crete, Blue River DeWitt, Zagens Pond 500 100 Saunders — Ashland, Wahoo Creek. Scotts Bluff — 1.000 Gering, Huffnian"s I^ake. Seward — 1,000 Milford, Mill Pond Seward. Mill Pond 1,000 1.000 Sheridan — Gordon. Choke Cherry Creek Thomas — 400 Seneca, Stump Lake. Washington — 5M Blair. Anderson's Pond 400 22.700 Channel Catfish Distribution. 1909. Fingerlings, Yearlings, and Adults. Disposition. Counties. Fry. Antelope — Clearwater. Elkhorn Slough Oakdale. Elkhorn Cut-Off.. 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">TWO GOOD ONES AT ENDERS LAKE A MORNING'S CATCH OF BASS BNDER'S LAKE A MORNINGS CATCH OF HOLT COUNTY PICKEREL </seg>
            <seg id="p045">game and fish commission 45 Butler— Ulysses. Blue River Brainard, Horacek's Pond Brown— Mid vale. Clear Lake Cass — Murdock, Klemme's Pond Cherry— Wood I&gt;ake. Leach's I&gt;ake Clay— Suttcn, Little Blue River Dodge — Scribner. Elkhoin Cut-Off Lancaster — Emerald. Sharer's Pond M.iiis.in — Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn Otoe— 1 '"ii Nebraska. Driving Association I I'nadilla, Pickrell's Pond 1. 200 ?oo e Nebraska City. Roddy's Pond Platte Coiurnbus. Loup River. Polk— Hordville, Larson's Pond Saline — Crete. Blue River Sarpy — Papillion. Jaug's Pond Seward — Milford, Mill Pond.. Seward. Blue River. Sheridan — Gordon, Choke Cherry Creek Striped or Ring Perch Distribution, 1909. Antelope — Fingerlina;s. Yearl and Adults. Disposition. Counties. Fry. Neligh. Mill Pond Clearwater. Elkhorn Sloughs. Cuming — Wortman's Lake Cherry — Valentine. Mill Pond Dodge — Fremont. Ice Co. Pond '5.000 Frontier — May wood. May wood Lake. Holt— Ewing. Sanders Lake Pance — Genoa. Loup River </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Pierce — Pierce, Mill Pond. Saunders — 500 Wahoo, Nygren's Lake. 500 (Pry estimated) 10,000 4,500 Sunfish Distribution, 1909. Disposition. Counties. Buffalo — Kearney, Grothan's Pond. Grant— Hyannis, Twin Lake. Kearney — Axtell, Nelson's Pond. Sherman — Asbton, Jamrog's Pond . Rock Bass Distribution, 1909. Fingerlings, Disposition. Yearlings. Counties. Fry. and Adults. Jefferson — Fairbury, Little Blye River. 200 German Carp Distribution, 1909 Adams— Hastings. Weber's Pond. Kearney — 150 Axtell, Nelson's Pond. Saunriers — 100 Weston, Sklenair's Pond l.-.n 450 Bull-Frog Distribution, 1909. Cherry — Wood Lake, Leach's Lake. Wood Lake, Dewey Lake. . . Chase- Champion. Mill Pond. Champion, Moranville Pond. Dundy — Benkelman, Bomberger's Pond. Benkelman, Adkinson's Lake. Lincoln — Dickens, Braugh Lake Sheridan Gordon, Choke Cherry Creek. Thomas — Seneca. Swan Lake. 9. r&gt;on </seg>
            <seg id="p047">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 47 Brook Trout Distribution 1910. Fingerlings, Disposition. Yearlings Counties. - Fry. and Adults. Antelope — Orchard, South Verdigre Creek 50.000 Brown — Johnstown, Plum" Creek Long Pine, Pine Creek 30,000 Long Pine Short Pine 10.00&lt;&gt; Burt— Lyons, Blackbird Creek Cherry- Valentine, Schlagel Creek 15.000 Crookston. Minechaduza Creek 10,000 Wood Lake, Fairfleld Creek 15.000 Kennedy, Boardman Creek 20.000 Chesterfield, Spring Creek Dixon— Coleridge, Spring Creek 2,500 Dundy — Benkelman. Indian Creek Benkelman, Buffalo Creek 5.0M Benkelman, Rock Creek .".hum Dawes— Chadron. Big Bordeaux Creek 2&gt;&gt;.'Mmi Chadron, Little Bordeaux Creek Chadron. Dead Horse Creek 10.000 Holt- Phoenix, Turkey Creek 10.000 Celia. Brush Creek m.noo Atkinson. Eagle Creek 15.000 O'Neill, Red Bird Creek 5,000 O'Neill. Eagle Creek : Dcrsey. Steele Creek 10.000 Morrill— Minatare, Willow Creek 5.006 Minatare. Middle Creek Sheridan — Rushville, White Clay Creek 15,000 Rushville, Larrabee Creek (Fry estimated) P.: Rainbow Trout Distribution 1910. Fingerlings Yearlings. Disposition. Counties. Frv. and Adults Antelope — Orchard, So. Verdigre Creek 20,000 Brown — Long Pine, Pine Creek 50.000 Jchnstown, Plum Creek 10,000 Burt— Lyons. Blackbird Creek 15M </seg>
            <seg id="p048">"TOT" FRANCKE. 13 YRS OLD. WITH A MORNING CATOB OF BLACK BASS FROM HACKBERRY LAKE. CHERRY COUNT* </seg>
            <seg id="p049">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 49 Cherry — Valentine, Schlagel Creek 15,000 Crookston, Minechaduza Creek 10,000 Wood Lake. Fairfield Creek 15.0W Dixon— Coleridge. Spring Creek !£M Dundy — Benkelman, Rock Creek 5.006 Benkelman. Buffalo Creek Dawes — Chadron. Chadron Creek 20,000 1.000 Andrews. White River , 6 Crawford. Spring Creek 20. Fillmore — Grafton. Garbes Pond -t .&lt; ■ 100 Holt- O'Neill. Eagle Creek 10.000 O'Neill. Apple Creek MM Dorsey, Steele Creek 10,00fl Dorsey. Apple Creek MM Dorsey. bouse Creek Middle Branch. Ar. pie Creek Star, North Verdigre !.Mfl Kimball— Kimball. Ix&gt;dge Pole Creek 3 M0 Madison — Norfolk. Willow Creek 5.000 (Fry Estimated) 283 1.100 Distribution Wall-eyed Pike 1910. Cuming — West Point, Elkhorn River 20 Douglas — Waterloo, Elkhorn River 20) Madison — Norfolk, No. Fork Elkhorn River 20 Platte— Columbus, Loup River Saline— Crete. Blue River 250.000 Sarpy — Fisheries, Platte River 750.000 Fisheries, Elkhorn River 500,000 (Frv Estimated) 2.600.000 Large-mouth Black Bass Distribution, 1910. Fingerlings, Disposition. Yearlings. Counties. Fry. and Adults. Cheyenne — Antelope — Clearwater. Elkhorn Sloughs Mi Neligh. Mill Pond Ml Clearwater. Huffman Slough Mt </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Adams — Hastings, Heartwell Lake 500 Burt— "Lyons, Logan Crek lO.onn Butler- Able, Spring Creek B,0M Ulysses, Chermoks Pond 1.500 David City. Abbott's Pond 5.000 Brainard. Horaceks Pond 4 "&gt; Brainard. Sabata Pond 200 Buffalo — Pleasanton. Pleasanton I«ike 500 Ravenna. Beaver Creek ." 500 Blaine— Dunning. Middle Loup River Brewster. Eriokson's Pond Cherry — Cody. Raccoon Lake 1 £99 Wood I^ke. Morris Lake Wood Lake, Marsh Lake 400 Eli, Horseshoe Lake 300 Irwin. So. Irwin Laek Lodge Pole. Oberfelder's I&gt;ake 300 Angora. Johnson's I^ake Cuming — West Point. Mill Pond West Pointc, McKirrahan's Lake 800 West Point. Wortman's I&gt;ake 500 Wisner. Thompson's Lake Col fax— Schuyler, Ellers Pond 200 Dawes — ■ Crawford, Spring Lakes 1.000 Crawford. Swinbank's Lake 50 Wayside. Baird's Pond 100 Deuel — Big Springs. Irrigation Lakes 10.000 Chappell, Ix&gt;dge Pole Creek .".no Douglas — Waterloo. Compton's Lake 10,000 Omaha, Carter Lake 2. into Omaha. Miller Park Lake 300 Omaha. Hanscomb Park Lake 300 Omaha. Riverview Park Lake 300 Dcdge— Vehling, Miller's Lake 500 Furnas — Arapahoe, Debenhani l.::Ve 500 Arapahoe. Chindor Lake 500 Frontier — Maywood. Maywood Lake 10,000 500 Curtis, Curtis Lake 500 Gage- Beatrice. Mill Pond 500 Seneca, Swan Lake 500 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 51 Holt- Atkinson. Dora Lake Ml Chambers. So. Fork, Elkhorn River Ml Hall- Cairo. St. Michael's Sloughs 500 Hooker — Mullen. Cody I^kes Ml Howard— Cotesfield. Nielson's Pond M Harlan — Alma. Methodist Creek Alma. Snyder Creek Orleans. Mill Pond Jefferson — Fairbury. Little Blue River 300 Jansen. Oldwell's Pond i'.dhu Knox— Verdigree. Bartcs Pond Wausa, Johnson's Pond 100 Lincoln — Wellfleet. Burton's Lake Dickens. Brausrh Lake Madison— Tilden. Cut-off Lake Norfolk. No. Fork. Elkhorn River 1 .urtO Norfolk. Bcohf s Pond l'»0 Morrill— Empire. Sheep Creek 10.1 Xance— Fullerton. Mill Pond Nuckolls Superior. Mill Pond Pierce— Pierce. Walker's Lake Pierce. Mill Pcr.d Platte— Columbus. BlauEer's Slough : Columbus. Way's Slough 10.000 Columbus, Guder's Slough 1 1 Ml Columbus, Eteven's Lake Ml Richardson Falls City. Maust Lake ■".." Falls City. Farrington's Lake l.rtOO Red Willow— McCook, Driftwood Creek 500 Sheridan — - Gordon, Horseshoe Lake Gordcn. Clear Lake *&gt;'»o Gordon. Fowler's Pond .'"0 Celek's Pond " 1 *n Sioux — Harrison. Wickersham's I^ake :'.*0 Sherman — Loup City. Ohlsen's Pond 5,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">HATCHING HOUSE AND PONDS. BENKLEMAN FISHERIES BENKLF.MAN FISHERIES. BENKLEMAN. NEB </seg>
            <seg id="p053">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Saline— Tobias, Kuceras Pond 1.000 Sarpy — LaPlatte, Kimball's Pond 100 Saunders — ■ Ashland, Swift's Lake 100 Praguo, Kaspars Pond 200 Prague Wagners Pond Thayer— Alexandria. Big Sandy Creek 10.000 Thomas— Thedford, Spring Lake Seneca, Swan Lake 1 .••• Webster — Blue Hill, Little Blue River 10.000 Washington — Arlington. Wilson's I^ake 10,000 Calhoun, Horseshoe Lake 10,000 Fry estimated) 156,600 34.050 Small-mouth Black Bass Distribution. 1910. Cherry— Wood Lake. Dewey Lake Valentine. Mill Pond Rock Bass Distribution, 1910. Cheyenne Lodge Pole, Oberfelder's Lakes Cherry- Valentine, Mill Pond Grant — Hyannis, Stump Lake Hooker — Mullen, Cody Lake Platte — Columbus. Stevens Lake Columbus, Guders Slough Crappie Distribution, 1910. Finserlings Disposition. Yearlings Counties. Fry. and Adults. Antelope — Xeligh. Mill Pond Ml Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs 4 mi Adams- Hastings Heartwell Lake Buffalo — Ravenna. Beaver Creek 1.0M Pleasantcn. Pleasanton Lake Blaine— Brewster. Erickson's Pond </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Cherry— Wood I^ake, Morris Lake r.nn Wood Lake. Dewey Lake Cody. Raccoon Lake SM 1.000 Eil. Horseshoe Lake Irwin, Twin Lake . . 300 300 Cass — I.ouisville, Park Lake Cumins — West Point, Mill Pond Clay— r.oo Angus. Little Blue River Dawes — 10 Crawford. Spring Lakes Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake Dodge — . . 700 Xickerson. Elkhorn Sloughs Hooper. Elkhorn Cut-off Holt- 500 Atkinson. Dora Lake Hooker — 500 Mullen. Cody Lake Furnas — 200 Arapahoe. Chindor Lake Frontier — 20 Curtis. Curtis Lake Lancaster — 1.000 Princeton, Buhrman's Pond 100 Emerald. Xobbman's Pond Lincoln — 50 Wellfleet. Burton's Lake Marti son — •00 Tilden. Stanton's Lake 200 Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn Nuckolls— 3"n Superior. Mill Pond Richardson — ■ 500 Humboldt. Nemaha River Saunders — 50C Ashland, Wahoo Creek . Ashland. Swift's Lake . Prague, Wagner's Pond Pregue, Kaspar's Pond . 1.000 3.000 800 200 Seward — Milford. Mill Pond . Seward, Blue River 500 MM Saline — Friend. Turkey Creek Sarpy — 500 Chalco. Spring Pond 800 Papillion, Horn's Pond 500 LaPlatte. Hushar's Pond LaPlatte. Kimball's Pond 200 300 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">GAME AND FISH COM. MISSION" Sheridan — Gordon, So. Twin Lake Gordon, Clear Lake . Thomas — Thedford, Spring Lake Seneca, Swan Lake . . Mi Webster — Blue Hill, Little Blue River 4mi Sunfish Distribution, 1910. Adams — ■ Hastings, Heartwell Lake Antelope — IM Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs Buffalo — Kearney, Barney's Pond Dodge — Winslow, Logan Creek Uehling, Miller's Lake l.OIMt Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake j&gt;uel— Chappell, Lodge Pole Ponds Furnas — Anipahoe, Debenham Lake Gage- Beatrice, Mill Pond Beatrice, Senderegger's Pond Harlan— Id!) Orleans, Mill Pond . . . Alma, Methodist Creek Howard— Loup City, Ohlsen's Pond Johnson — - Cook, Livingston's Lake Jefferson — ■ Fairbury. Little Blue River Lancaster — Emerald, Xobman's Pond Morrill— Empire, Sheeop Creek Madison — 1"! Madison, Mill Pond Phelps — Holdrege, Brick Yard Ponds Saline — Friend, Turkey Creek Saunders — Ashland, Swift's Lake Richardson— Falls City, Maust Lake Falls City, Farrington's Lake 1.000 ll.Too </seg>
            <seg id="p056">M o &lt; e 3 / </seg>
            <seg id="p057">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Striped Perch Distribution 1910. Fingerlings. Uisiosition. Yearlings, Counties . Pry. and Adults. Antelope — Neligh, Mill Pond 400 Butler- Ulysses, Chermok's Pond 100 Cheyenne — Angora, Johnson Pond Ml 300 Lodge Pole, Oberfelder Lakes Cherry — Valentine, Mill Pond MM. Wood Lake, Dewey Lake Eli, Horseshoe Lake 700 500 Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake 500 Waterloo, Compton's Lake 2,000 Dawson — Lexington, Uoung's Pond 150 Deuel — Chappell, Lodge Pole Ponds 300 Frontier — ■ Maywood, May-wood Lake 5,000 Grant — Hyannis, Stump Lake BM Hooker- Mullen, Cody Lake 200 Lancaster — Princeton, Buhrman's Pond 200 Morrill— Minatare, Huffman's Lake Ml Platte— Columbus, Blauser's Slough 2.000 300 ■M 3«X» Columbus, Way's Slough 2,000 Columbus, Guder's Slough 2,000 Richardson — Falls City, Maust Lake 500 Ml Falls City, Farrington's Lake Saunders — Ashland, Swift's Lake 5,000 Prague, Kaspar'st Pond Prague, Wagner's Pond 200 ■2M Sarpy— Fisheries, Stone Lake 100 Thomas — Seneca, Swan Lake 300 Thav-er — Alexandria, Big Sandy Creek 2,000 Webster — Blue Hill, Little Blye River 1,000 Washington- Arlington, Wilson's Lake 5,000 Calhoun, Horseshoe. Lake 2,000 28,000 7.SM </seg>
            <seg id="p058">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 58 Channel Catfish Distribution, 1910. Fingerlings, Yearlings, and Adults. Disposition. Counties. Fry. Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs Adams — 500 Hastings, Heartwell Lake Blaine— 50&lt;? Dunning, Middle Loup River Buffalo — 500 Ravenna, Loup River Butler — so© Brainard, Horacek's Pond 100 Brainard, Kavelec's Pond Ulysses, Blue River 50 coo 100 Ulysses, Chermok's Pond Cass — Louisville, Mayfields Pond Clay— 100 Deweese, Little Blue River Custer — 600 Mason, Cler Creek Ansley, Mud Creek 500 300 Dawes — Crawford, Swinbank Lakes 700 Crawford, Spring Lakes Dodge— 800 Nickerson, Elkhorn Cut-off 50.) Hooper, Elkhorn Cut-off r,i)O Scribner, Elkhorn Cut-off Douglas — 500 Omaha, Carter Lake Gage- 300 Wymore, Blue River Beatrice, Mill Pond 500 1,000 Harlan — Orleans, Mill Pond 200 Oxford, Republican River 1,000 Republican City, Mill Creek Alma, Methodist Creek 200 200 Hall— Grand Island, Wood River Hamilton — 1,000 Phillips, Otto's Pond Johnson — 100 Tecumseh, Mill Pond Jefferson — 1,000 Fairbury, Little Blue River Kearney — 300 Minden, Whiskey Slough Knox 500 Wausa, Johnson's Pond Lancaster — 100 Princeton, Buhrman's Pond Hallam, Vratile Pond 200 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 59 Madison — Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn River SM Battle Creek, Elkhorn River Tilden, Elkhorn River iM l,tM Madison, Union Creek 500 Nuckolls — Superior, Mill Pond Ml Platte— Columbus, Loup River 500 Polk— Hordville, Larson's Pond 100 Pawnee — ■ Table Rock, Nemaha River . . . Burchard, Cole's Pond Steinauer, Somerhalder's Pond 1.000 100 Richardson Verdon, Bloom's Pond Verdon, Harden's Pond BM Verdon, Franenfeltey's Pond Verdon, Friedly's Pond Verdon, Gebhard's Pond Salem, Steinbrink's Pond . . . Humboldt, Nemaha River . . Falls City, Maust Lake .... MO Mi 100 BM 1,000 Saunders — Ashland, Swift's Lake . Ashland, Wahoo Creek Prague, Wagners Pond Prague, Kaspar's Pond Wahoo, Luer's Pond . . . Ml Ml Ml Ml Seward ■ Seward, Blue River Milford, Blue River Beaver Crossing, Michael's Pond •200 Saline — Crete, Blue Rivpr . . . Dewitt, Blue River . Friend, Turkey Creek Ml Sarpy — Chalco, Spring Pond Papilion, Horn's Pond ;;:;:; Thayer — Alexandria, Big Sandy Creek Alexandria, Averilla Pond York— Thayer, Lincoln Creek York, Lincoln Creek. 500 29,550 German Carp Distribution, 1910. Fingerlings, Yearlings, and Adults. Disposition Counties Butler— Fry. Brainard, Kavelec's Pond 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p060"/>
            <seg id="p061">►51 GAME AND FISH ("Oil MISSION Jefferson — - 100 Gladstone, Kape's Pond Knox— Verdigree, Barto's Pond 100 Yellow Bullhead Distribution, 1910. Antelope — ■ Elgin, Beaver Creek Clearwater, Elkhcrn Sloughs Burt— l.DOU Lyons, Mill Pond Butler- Ulysses, Little Blue River Ulysses, Chermok's Pond Brainard, Kavelec's Pond Ml IM Brainard, Horacek's Pond Buffalo — Kearney, Barney's Pond Custer— KM Mason, Clear Creek Ansley, Mud Creek KM 500 Cuming — 1,500 West Point, Mill Pond Cherry — Wood Lake, Burley's Pond Cass — Louisville, Park Ponds Murdock, Schewe's Pond Clay- Angus, Little Blye River IM Deweese, Little Blye River Danes — Crawford, Spring Lakes Dawson — Lexington, Young's Pond Douglas — Omaha, Carter Lake Dodge— B, Scribner .Elkhorn Cut-off 500 Winslow, Logan Creek Furnas — 1.IHM) Arapahoe, Debenham Lake 300 IM Arapahoe, Chindor Lake Frontier — Maywocd, Maywood Lake Gage — 1.000 Wymore, Blue River Beatrice, Mill Pond S Harlan — Alma, Methodist Creek . Alma, Snyder Creek Orleans, Mill Pond Oxford, Republican River IM 500 Hall- Grand Island, Wood Fiver </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 GAME AND FISH COMMISSION Hamilton — Phillips, Otto's Pond Howard — 100 Cotesfield, Nielson's Pond Jefferson — ■ 125 Pairbury, Little Blue River Johnson — 5irf» Tecumseh, Mill Pond Knox — 1,000 Wausa, Johnson's Pond Kearney — 100 Minden, Whiskey Slough Lancaster — 51MI Emerald, Nobbmans' Pond Bennett, Finke's Pond 100 100 Madison — Norfolk, North Fork Elkhorn 50" Battle Creek, Cut-off Elkhorn Tilden, Cut-off Elkhorn 500 500 Madison, Mill Pond Pawnee — l.ooi. Table Rock, Nemaha River Burchard, Cole's Pond 1,000 100 Phelps— Holdrege, Brick Yard Ponds Red Willow, Driftwood Creek . Richardson — BOO 5lH» Humboldt, Nemaha River BOO Salem, Steinbrink's Pond Dawson Heim's Pond . . . 100 100 Saline- Crete, Mill Pond 500 Friend, Turkey Creek Dewitt, Mill Pond . . . Me 50(1 Saunders — Ashland, Swift's Lake . Prague, Wagner's Pond Wahoo, Luer's Pond . . 500 200 100 Sarpy— Papillion, Horn's Pond 20m 4..o Fisheries, Proctor's Pond La Platte, Hushar's Pond 1,000 1,000 LaPlatte, Kimball's Pond Chaloo, Spring Pond . . . MO Sherman — Loup City, Ohlsen's Pond Sheridan — inn Gordon, Clear Lake Seward — SlHl Milford, Mill Pond Seward, Mill Pond 500 500 York— Thayer, Lincoln Creek York, Lincoln Creek 5.M - 500 38,475 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">GAME AND FISH COMMISSION 63 Bullfrog Distribution, 1910. Antelope — Clearwater, Elkhorn Sloughs l . 1,000 Brown — Ender's Lake, Ender's Lake 500 Cherry — Wood Lake, Dewey Lake 1,000 Valentine, Mill Pond 1,000 Dawes — Crawford, Swinbank's Lake 1,000 Crawford, Spring Ponds 1,000 Grant — Hyannis, Stump Lake 1,000 Gage- Beatrice, Mill Pond 1,000 Holt- Allison, Dora Lake 1,000 Hooker — Mullen, Cody Lake 1,000 Lincoln — Dickens, Braugh Lake 1,500 Platte— Columbus, Guder's Lake ■ 500 Columbus, Island Pond 500 Sheridan— Gordon, Clear Lake 100 Thomas — Seneca, Swan Lake 1,000 Tadpoles estimated 13,00o 200 Crayfish Distribution, 1910. Brown — Ender's Lake, Ender's Lake 500 Buffalo Fish Distribution, 1910. Cass— Plattsmouth. Missouri River 2.000 Samv — LaPlatte. Allison's Pond SAfl Goldfish Distribution, 1909-1910. 2.W </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>