<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-EIGHTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1, 1935</title>
               <date value="1935-02-01">1935-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-EIGHTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Jl^^^^jk. : -..■'' Presented to the Governor February 1, 1935 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA „ U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, R. L. Cochran, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with thc act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved iuT 3 \ m7 &gt;. «0*hshing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Forty-eighth Annual Report of the Agri - cultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Mr s,T' 7i B "Z' D i rect0 ' K&lt;l»&lt;"K° Agricultural Experiment Station: of the * A Lv.S y f£ n ° W CdgC ° £ *« Fort y^^th Annual Report ot the Agricultural Expenment Station of Nebraska. Lincoln, February 1, 1935. *' U </seg>
            <seg id="p003">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Arthur C. Stokes, Omaha, President .Term expires January, 1937 Earl Cline. Lincoln. . . Term ex^ res January 1937 Stanley D Long. Grand Island . Term expires ,-,„„', 1939 Frank J Taylor. St. Paul Term apirei Januil^ m 9 Marjon A. Shaw, David City. . Term expires January, 1941 Charles Y. Thompson, West Point Term expires January, 1941 E. A. Burnett, D.Sc., Chancellor L. E. Gunderson, 1 Finance Secretary &#132;, ,„ THE STATION OFFICERS W. W. Burr, B.Sc., Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF C. W. Ackerson, PhJ5., Assistant m Agricultural Chemistry M. A. Alexander, M.Sc., Assistant m Animal Husbandry Arthur Anderson, Ph.D., Assistant m Agronomy A. E. Baragar, M.Sc., Assistant m Home Economics Marvel L. Baker, M.Sc., Assistant m Animal Husbandry, North Platte M. J. Blish, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemistry (Chairman) E. E. Brackett, B.Sc. m E.E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) t. M. Brouse, B.Sc., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine L.. X.. Crowe, M.Sc., Assistant m Dairy Husbandry H. P. Davis, M.Sc., Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) P. A. Downs, PhX&gt;., Associate m Dairy Husbandry H. C. Filley, Ph.D., Rural Economics (Chairman) A. L. Frolik,2 M.Sc., Assistant m Agronomy R. W. Goss, Ph.D., Associate m Plant Pathology H. J. Gramlich, B.Sc., Animal Husbandry (Chairman) Lionel Harrb.3 M.Sc., Acting Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell I.L. Hathaway, M.Sc., Assistant m Dairy Husbandry Harold Hedges,* A.M., Assistant m Rural Economics Eleanor Hinman. A.8., Assistant m Rural Economics J. A. Holden 3 4 BSc&gt; Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell X D. Keim, Ph.D., Agronomy (Chairman) T. A. Kiesselbach, PhX&gt;., Agronomy E. B Lewis, B.Sc. m A.E., Assistant m Agricultural Engineering ' W. ]. Loeffel, M.Sc., Assistant m Animal Husbandry W. E. Lyness, M.Sc. m Agr., Assistant m Agronomy H. A. McComb, B.Sc., Assistant m Horticulture, North Platte C. B. McGrath. B.Sc., D.V.M., Assistant m Animal Pathology and Hygiene K. A. \Upes. Manager Union Fruit Farm, Union R. F. Morgan, M.Sc., Assistant m Dairy Husbandry F. E. Mussehl, B.Sc., Poultry Husbandry (Chairman) }. F. Olney, D.VJ4., M.S., Assistant m Animal Pathology and Hygiene G. L. Peltier, Ph.D., Plant Pathology (Chairman) E. L. Reichart, M.Sc., Assistant m Dairy Husbandry Raymond Roberts. M.Sc., Assistant m Entomology J. C. Russel. M.Sc., Associate m Agronomy »On lave. W.!h^j&gt;" D??. 0 *" "* V """ U ''"I"™ Agriculture. United Su.e. Depanmen, of Agriiuhure. 4 Deemed. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">R. M. SandstedT, M.Sc., Assistant m Agricultural Chemistry %Z?l *Jt M V"- 8 "' B ° X BuUe E *P™™»"l Alliance Edna. B. Snyder, M.Sc., Assistant m Home Economics L. B. Snyder, M.Sc, Assistant m Rural Economics C. A SiZlm'Vvft' S l pirime P d " tt . Experimental Substation, North Plane C. A^ Sunesok.b M.Sc., Research Assistant m Agronomy M- H. Swenk, AM., Entomology (Chairman) ft ?; TS" 3 *^.' M - Sc - Aaist &lt;"ft m Animal Husbandry H.M. Ttedai.,B PhX&gt;., Research Associate m Agronomy « p «T' M " D »\Yf •' A "' mai PatAol °ey and Hygiene (Chairman) » w Weakly.* M-Sc-. Assistant Agronomist. North Platte R. M. Weihing, Ph.D., Assistant m Agronomy M. D. Weldon, M.Sc, Assistant m Agronomy H. O. Werner, Ph.D., Associate m Horticulture D. B. Whelan, M^c., Assistant m Entomology C. C. Wiggans, Ph.D., Horticulture (Chairman) W. W. Yocom, AM., Assistant m Horticulture C. L. Zink, B.Sc, Tractor Testing Engineer L. L. Zook 7 B.Sc, Agronomist and Acting Supt. Experimental Substation, North Platte CONTENTS Introduction Agricultural Engineering Animal Diseases Dairy Husbandry..... Field Crops and Soils Fruits and Vegetables .....'...... Home Economics Insects, Rodents, and Birds Livestock Feeding , Milling and Baking ; Plant Diseases ZL Poultry Rural Economics State Serum Plant ' V. North Platte Substation .* . f Scottsbluff Substation ]\ Valentine Substation ........* \_. '* Box Butte Experiment Farm _ „ Additional Land, Buildings, and Equipment . ..:..".' 34 Changes m Staff Publications Since the Last Annual Report ' 35 Fmandal Statement of Money Received from the United' States Government' '" 36 Financial Statement Exclusive of Federal Funds. 38 ;,, .'Deccued! ,!.'.••' • • W«h^.'?D.T ° &amp;CC Ce ~ 1 Cn&gt;P ' a ° d D '" aK '- Uni^ Si «« "^»n»cn, of Agriculture wJh^o? i"c. •° ffiCe ° £ FOriBe propf and Dilcu * s ' United ■»« &lt; D«l«««^.^^rWli«s. W^SSSSfoc 1 . ° ffiCC ° £ Dfy UDd A^™ 1 '«™. «««««l Sutc Dcp, rlment of Apiculfure&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Forty-eighth Annual Report This report differs from previous reports in two respects: it covers experimental work up to January 1, 1935, and it includes brief abstracts of publications since the last report. Previously, most of the report dealt with work done before the end of the fiscal year; that is, work done between June 30 and January 1 was not reported until over a year later, for thc most part. The present report corrects that defect, and in addition the abstracts of publications will make the report more useful as a reference guide to published matter. The financial report at the end covers the fiscal year ending June 30, 1934. The projects are, as heretofore, discussed under subject headings. In addition to the abstracts, brief reports of progress in projects under way are included. Complete data for these projects are, of course, not included; rather an attempt has been made to show how far the work has gone and to indicate some of the directions or trends of the work. The drouth of the past summer reduced yields severely. As a result the collection of significant data on yields was almost impossible. A few of the Experiment Station workers have been loaned to federal projects. Despite these handicaps many projects have been advanced and many have been completed. The bulletins and circulars mentioned throughout this report and brought together in a list at the back are available at the College of Agriculture at Lincoln. ;7 AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING Tractor testing. — Nine tractors were tested during the testing season of 1933 and 11 in the season of 1934. A new record for economy in fuel consumption was established by a crawler-type tractor equipped with a Diesel motor. The first tests of rubber-tired tractors were made this season. Bulletin 292, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-1934, Jan., 1935, 30 pages, summarizes the tests on machines which are now on the market. Pneumatic tires for farm tractors. — This work has been completed and the results have been published: Bulletin 291, A Comparative Study of Pneumatic Tires and Steel Wheels on Farm Tractors, by C. W. Smith and Lloyd W. Hurlbut, Sept., 1934, 38 pages. The study reports the results of 24 tests under actual farming conditions. In addition, inflation-pressure tests were run, the effect of transfer of weight on the reduction of travel of a pneumatic tire was studied, wheel-efficiency tests were run, the effect of adding weight on traction was studied, and the tractor testing course was compared with a stubble field as a place for obtaining test data. One important conclusion is that a saving in time and fuel can be made on most farm operations with pneumatic tires. This saving becomes less significant and may become negative as drawbar pulls increase, necessitating low gear, and it increases with lighter loads which permit the use of higher gears. Most of the results of this study were reported also in an article under the tide above in Agricultural Engineering 15:33-48, February, 1934. T </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Electric power on Nebraska farms.— The Engineering Experiment Station cooperates with the Agricultural Experiment Station in this project. The work includes several subprojects. The following general bulletin has been issued since thc last Annual Report: Bulletin 289, Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms, 1920-1934 bv E E Brackett and E. B. Lewis, June, 1934, 45 pages. This bulletin reports 'the present conditions in rural electric service in Nebraska. It endeavors also to show farmers thc probable benefits and costs to be expected if electrical equipment were used under present conditions and to show distributors of electrical service the possibilities of, and problems involved in, supplying this service to farmers. The sources are widespread surveys of farms, tests under tarm condiUons, and other sorts of investigation. Efficiency of tractor lugs—Work to date has been done with model units ,n the laboratory with soil at practically constant moisture content. 1 he work is being conunued. Methods of cooling milk on farms.-Methods of equalizing tempera - tures in refrigerators, the effect of various temperatures on the rate of yeast and mold growth and bacterial count with reference to cottage cheese, air conditioning for cheddar cheese, cold-air diffusion in cooling crated bottles, and the effect of holding fresh warm milk on thc cream line have been studied. Wind-jdriyen electric plants.— The collection of data has almost been completed. A large proportion of favorable reports from Nebraska owners indicates that the plants meet the needs of many who are remote from central staUons. Pump irrigation.— Work on pump irrigation is carried on at North Watte, in addition to that done at thc experiment station at Lincoln. (See later section on work at North Platte Substation.) Since the last Annual Report the results of a great deal of investigation have been reported in tne following pubheauon: Bulletin 282, Pump Irrigation Investigations in Nebraska, by E. E. Brackett and E. B. Lewis July, 1933, 30 pages. This bulletin attempts to bring together all available information needed by anyone who expects to ungate with a pump. Needs of water for various crops, irrigatio^ns, pumping and yields of wells, pumps, power, and costs are among subjects ANIMAL DISEASES The influence of environment on poultiy morbidity.— This project has two purposes: to test thc efficiency of hygienic measures and to gather information i on the causes of disorders in poultry. Various environments, sanitary and unsanitary, arc used. During the year the following publica - tion was made: e F Bulletin 290, Diseases of Poultry— Their Nature and Control, by L. SSeS l"S? \l' .° lDC V ul y&gt; 1934 &gt; 108 Pag«- Th" bulletin replaces Bulletin 195. Like its predecessor, it deals only with disorders having an </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Forty-eighth Annual Report economic importance. Besides a discussion of diseases it contains chapters on sanitation, hygiene, control of diseases, avitaminoses, and parasites and pests. The results of investigations carried on under the large project on studies of environment are included. A report of the results from this project up to November 1, 1934, was read before the committee on poultry diseases of the United Livestock Sanitary Association in Chicago, December 7, 1934. This report will be printed in the proceedings of that association. The project will be com - pleted during the year 1935. Organizations belonging to the hemorrhagic septicemia group. — The work on this project has been completed and the results will be published later. Erysipelas among Nebraska swine. — This project has consisted largely of survey work. Erysipelas was found in about 20 per cent of the out - breaks of acute swine disease that were investigated. A publication will be made later. Laboratory diagnosis and examination of specimens. — This project requires a great deal of attention and labor. From December 1, 1933, to December 27, 1934, 7,616 examinations and reports were made. DAIRY HUSBANDRY Study of vitamins. — Recent work has had to do with the comparative vitamin A content of sweet-cream butter, sour-cream butter, and oleo - margarine. No significant difference has been found between the two kinds of butter, but the brands of oleomargarine tested thus far have proved to be poor sources of vitamin A. Since the last Annual Report the two following research bulletins have been published: Research Bulletin 69, The Vitamin A Content of Skjmmili\, Standard - ized Mil\, and Cream from Different Breeds of Cows, by I. L. Hathaway and H. P. Davis, December, 1933, 14 pages. Approximately 750 rats were used in nine experiments. Thc conclusions were (1) that the vitamin A content of milk is associated largely with the butterfat and that separated milk containing a small quantity of fat contains only a small amount of vitamin A, (2) that thc standardization of the butterfat content of milk by the addition of separated milk reduces its vitamin A potency, and (3) that under the conditions of the experiments Holstein cream contained more vitamin A than Jersey cream. Research Bulletin 73, The Vitamin E Content of Certain Dairy Feeds, by I. L. Hathaway and H. P. Davis, August, 1934, 8 pages. Female rats that were unable to cast litters when fed a diet deficient in vitamin E were used. Twenty to 25 per cent of the bran, shorts, linseed oil meal, hominy feed, white corn, yellow corn, cottonseed meal, kafir, or alfalfa furnished sufficient vitamin E to allow the rats to cast litters. On the other hand, 40 per cent of the corn gluten meal, the corn gluten feed, or thc beet pulp furnished very litde vitamin E. There 1 was no significant difference be - tween the white and yellow corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Contagious abortion in a dairy herd.-This project is being discon - tinued, because the herd is now apparently free from contagious abortion. An extensive publication (Research Bulletin 46) was made in 1930 Milk qualitv as affected by the individual cow in a herd.-Attempts to control mastitis, wh.ch seems to be correlated with so-called salty flavor in milk, have been ineffective. This flavor seems to be associated also with chlorine content. Feed flavors have been noticeable in milk from cows ZzZr£ Ur l l Wh i le -n * mp0rary P astures of W sudan g«ss, or sweet clover. The study of milk flavor and bacterial flora of the udder is being continued. Growth of dairy catde.— Accumulation of data continues. The aim in general is to find out how growth takes place. Gain in weight of pregnant cows is being studied by breeds and ages in an effort to differentiate the influences of growth and pregnancy. Reproduction in a dairy herd.— The effect of age of bulls and cows on number of services required for conception is being studied. Sprouted oats as a source of vitamin E have been fed to heifers before breeding in an effort to study the effect of such feed on number of services required. Improvement and standardization of butter.— Samples of butter from cooperative creameries were analyzed and considerable variation was found m tat, curd, salt, and moisture. The purpose is to aid the cooperative creameries in improving and standardizing butter. Ice cream making-Samples of vanilla and strawberry ice cream from manufacturers m Nebraska were analyzed and variations were noted, lnis project also looks toward improvement of quality. nle^S^ u cresun n «=hcese.-Work on this project has been com - pleted and a bulletin will be printed within the coming year. It will include directions for making cream cheese on the farm and in the factory. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS Com improvement.— The main purpose of this work is to compare farmers varieties and to develop and test hybrids between selfed lines, btnking differences between varieties and the superiority of good hybrids 7Z W re^ u ! / 33 and L confi ™«l earlier tests. Commercial production of hybrid seed by farmers has been initiated. The better experimental and commercial hybrids and several varieties have also been tested on four eastern-Nebraska farms. Data have been reported in thc 25th Annual Report of the Nebraska Crop Growers Association, "The Latest in Hybrid Corn", by T A S*^.^ PP- 50-65. As an average for 111 tests! standard eastern-Nebraska varieties showed an extreme difference of 15 7 bushels per acre, while the five best hybrids yielded 10.1 bushels (20 per cent) more than the five best varieties. Thc methods and results of hybrid seed-corn production are discussed in the Proceedings of the World's Grain </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Forty-eighth Annual Report Conference, Vol. 2, under the title, "The Possibilities of Modern Corn Breeding", by T. A. Kiesselbach, to be published in February, 1935. Corn production practices. — The effect of variations in seedbed prepara - tion, planting, and cultivating corn have been studied during 1 1 years and the results are reported in Bulletin 293, Cultural Practices in Corn Produc - tion, by T. A. Kiesselbach, Arthur Anderson, and W. E. Lyness, January, 1935, 18 pages. I With surface-planted corn early spring plowing yielded 5 per cent more grain than late spring plowing and 18 per cent more than fall plowing. The best listing and surface-planting practices yielded essentially alike. Disinfecting farmers' seed corn with commercial seed treatments did not prove advantageous. While excessively deep and close cultivation may injure roots enough to reduce yields 20 per cent, tillage not exceeding a depth of 5 and a distance of 9 inches from the plant is likely to do no harm. Cultivation after corn is normally laid by was of no benefit. Studies indicating that considerable irregularity in distribution of corn plants does not materially affect yield of grain although plant variability is increased, are reported by T. A. Kiesselbach and Ralph M. Weihing in the Journal of Agricultural Research, 47:399-416, September, 1933. Small-grain improvement. — This project. involves the testing of varieties and the breeding of winter wheat, oats, arid barley. The wheat improve - ment is cooperative with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Results are summarized in a series of publications. Bulletin 283, Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska, by T. A. Kiessel - bach, Arthur Anderson, and C. A. Suneson, July, 1933, 24 pages. During five years the recently distributed selection, Cheyenne, yielded 14 per cent above standard Turkey and surpassed all the other 65 varieties tested. This variety is characterized by stiff straw, shatter resistance, and Hessian-fly tolerance. Several other Turkey selections from this station have proved extremely resistant to stinking smut, and two of them are also decidedly resistant to Hessian fly. 8 The varietal and breeding results with spring small grains have been summarized by Arthur Anderson under the tide, "What is New in Spring Grains?" 25th Ann. Rep. Nebr. Crop Growers' Assoc., Febr., 1934, pp. 69-72. Iogold oats, Ceres spring wheat, and Glabron and Spartan barley are outstanding new certified varieties in this state. Iogold oats and Ceres spring wheat are especially resistant to stem rust. Three new productive Nebraska selections from Common Burt oats have also shown great resist - ance to stem rust and are being increased for distribution. These have been •Five additional papers dealing with these winter wheat problems are: (1) C A. Suneson, "Cheyenne Winter Wheat", 25th Ann. Rep. of the Nebr. Crop Growers' Assoc., Febr., 1934, pp. 65-69. (2) C. A. Suneson and T. A. Kiesselbach, "Differential Varietal. Responses of Winter Wheat to Time of Planting", Jour, of thc Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:294-96, Apr., 1934. (3) C. A. Suneson and G. L. Peltier, "Cold Resistance Adjustments of Field-Hardened Winter Wheats as Determined by Artificial Freezing", Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:50-59, Jan., 1934. (4) C. A. Suneson and G. L. Peltier, "Effect of Stage of Seedling Development upon the Cold Resistance of Winter Wheats", Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:687-93, Aug., 1934. (5) Arthur Anderson and T. A. Kiesselbach, "Studies on the Technic of Control Hardiness Tests with Winter Wheat", Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:44-50, Jan., 1934. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station reported in the Journal of thc American Society of Agronomy, 25:684-88, October, 1933, by Arthur Anderson and T. A. Kiesselbach, under thc tide, "Selection Within Burt Oats". The Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, 26:681-87, August, 1934, carries an article cntided, "The Comparative Cold Resistance of Spring Small Grains", by G. L. Peltier and T. A. Kiesselbach. The order of cold resistance of the three principal spring small grains as reported here was spring wheat, barley, and oats. Varieties within any of these crops differ materially in this respect. Small-grain production.— Variations in seedbed preparation, seed treat - ment, methods, dates, and rates of seeding, and time of harvest are studied in this project. Yields and crop quality may be greatly influenced by the cultural practices employed. This is shown for winter wheat in the follow - ing two publications: (1) Bulletin 286, Cultural Practices in Winter Wheat Production, by T. A. Kiesselbach, Arthur Anderson, and W. E. Lyness, April, 1934, 28 pages; and (2) "Furrow Versus Surface Planting Winter Wheat", by T. A. Kiesselbach and W. E. Lyness, Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:289-94, April, 1934. Early seedbed preparation for winter wheat accompanied by sufficient tillage between harvest of the previous small grain and seeding to control weeds and volunteer grain has been found profitable. Delay of sowing until the fly-safe date in years of fly prevalence may result in gready increased yields. Seed treatment for stinking smut is important and copper carbonate dust proved the most practical. The use of furrow drills is not advisable in eastern Nebraska because the rows are too far apart to give maximum yields. . 4 seed-activation study to investigate thc possibility of inducing head - ing in winter wheat when sown in the spring showed that this can be accomplished by storing thc germinated seed for a period of 30 days at a temperature barely above freezing, prior to planting. It is, however, con - cluded that such practice has no commercial value. Thc results are pub - lished by G. L. Peltier and T. A. Kiesselbach in Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:503-6, June, 1934, under the tide, "Inducing Early Fruitinjj in Winter Wheat by Seed Activation". Alfalfa improvement— It is the purpose of this project to test varieties and regional strains and to improve the crop by breeding. Thc work is in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Extensive breeding operations have been inaugurated, and promising selections and hybrids have been planted for yield comparisons and seed increase. Many have proved superior to Hardistan and Turkistan in forage and seed yield and in resistance to cold and wilt. The most satisfactory variety now available commercially to plant under conditions of wilt prevalence is Hardistan. This and good strains of Turkistan will maintain a stand several years longer than other varieties where conditions are favorable for wilt, such as the subirrigated alfalfa centers. Under upland conditions Grimm, Cossack, and northern-grown Common alfalfa are the most suitable varieties now available. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Forty-eighth Annual Report The new variety, Ladak, continues to give favorable results. Studies indicate that it should be cut somewhat later than standard varieties for maximum production. Its high first-cutting yield suggests 1 its use where production is confined largely to the first crop. The seed supply is still limited and none is available in Nebraska. Various phases of this work have been summarized in the following publications: (1) Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:773-81, September, 1934, "Improvement of Alfalfa Seed Production by Inbreeding", . by H. M. Tysdal and Ira Clark; (2) Research Bulletin 76, Wilt and Cold Resistance of Self-fertilized Lines of Alfalfa, by G. L. Peltier and H. M. Tysdal, September, 1934 (see under Plant Diseases); and (3) Jour. Agr. Res. (in press), "An Analysis of Soil and Seasonal Effects in Alfalfa Variety Tests", byH. M. Tysdal. The results of alfalfa hay-making studies in the Platte Valley, co - operative with the U. S. Department of Agriculture, were published in February, 1934, by W. H. Hosterman, T. A. Kiesselbach, and Elvin F. Frolik in a 36-page mimeographed circular of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics, entitled Alfalfa Hay Management Studies. The results from various practices in use by farmers are discussed. Legumes following alfalfa. — It has been found that cropping Nebraska uplands to alfalfa for five or more years depletes the subsoil moisture supply to depths of 25 feet or more. Long periods are required with normal cropping for this subsoil moisture to become restored. In thc meantime the yields of alfalfa grown upon such land are greatly reduced. They are, however, approximately as large as those from sweet clover and red clover under the same conditions, and choice among these crops may therefore be based upon other considerations than total yield. The results of these investigations appear in the following publication: "Subsoil Moisture and Crop Sequence in Relation to Alfalfa Production", by T. A. Kiesselbach, Arthur Anderson, and J. C. Russel, Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., 26:422-42, May, 1934. The results of a state-wide survey of alfalfa and subsoil moisture relations, cooperative with the U. S. Department of Agri - culture, is being prepared for publication. Annual and biennial forage crops. — Comparisons are made of various forage crops for their cured forage, silage, and pasture value. During six years, Atlas sorgo has proved superior to all other crops in yield of total dry matter. This is a lodge-resistant, late-maturing variety which can be depended upon to mature seed in only the southern part of the state, and is recommended for forage throughout the southeastern half. Most profit - able results have been secured in southeastern Nebraska from sowing 20 pounds of seed per acre in cultivated rows. The demand for Adas sorgo seed was so great in 1934 that other less productive varieties were sub - stituted and special care will be needed in 1935 to procure seed of correct identity. Orange sorgo has ranked next to Atlas. Sumac and Black Amber are among the best early maturing varieties of sorgo. Seed of the grain - sorghum variety known as Hegari promises to be plentiful in the spring </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station of 1935 and may be sown for forage if seed of the standard forage varieties is unavailable. Sweet clover has proved highly suitable for temporary pastures when second- and first-year crops are used to supplement each other or when second-year sweet clover is pastured in conjunction with sudan grass. The sudan grass failed in 1934, however, as a result of chinch-bug ravages, which suggests that it should not be depended upon when this insect threatens. In a comparison of varieties of lespedeza under controlled conditions the order of cold resistance, from most to least, was as follows: perennial, common sorts, and Korean. Results are reported by H. M. Tysdal and' A. J. Pieters, Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 26:923-28, November, 1934. Weeds.— The identification, growth habits, and modes of eradication of thc worst weeds arc being studied. Information concerning common grass weeds has been reported by F. D. Keim and A. L. Frolik in Bulletin 288, Common Grass Weeds of Nebraska, June, 1934, 40 pages. The general principles of weed control are discussed in the 25th Annual Report of the Nebraska Crop Growers' Association under the tide, "Our Weed Problem —Control Measures", by F. D. Keim, pp. 28-35. Preliminary experiments indicate that there is a differential response of blue grass and crab grass to sodium chlorate when applied to lawns. The proper management of such treatment is being studied. The results of 15 years' investigation of field bindweed and methods for its eradication have been reported in Bulletin 288, Bindweeds and Their ro£ a4 y A- Kiessdbach » N - F - Petersen, and W. W. Burr, May, 1934, 47 pages. Two effective methods of extermination have been found: clean summer fallow and treatment with sodium chlorate. Both involve the disuse of the land for one or two years. The clean-fallow method is recommended for all large areas because the chief expense is labor. Ihorough frequent tillage for one and one-half seasons has , eradicated well-established stands. Sodium chlorate applied cither in dry form or as a water spray has repeatedly been successful. The amount needed has been found to vary with soil fertility (amount of organic matter), soil texture, and vigor of plant development. Average conditions require approximately .^00 pounds per acre, but the amount may vary from 320 to 800 pounds At 8 to 10 cents per pound the cost is prohibitive except for small patches and along fence rows and highways. Because of fire hazards, precautions 'u "li"? arC re&lt; l uired - Mter lal »d has been cleared of bindweed, the field should be so managed as to prevent its rcestablishmcnt from seed, which may remain viable in the soil for several years. Management of permanent pastures and native meadows.— It is esti - mated that the drouth of 1934 has destroyed three-fourths of the permanent pastures of this state that were planted to cultivated species. Owing to scarcity of seed of the most desired species, formulas for pasture mixtures are being prepared which will make the best use of available sorts. A general survey indicates that native pastures and meadows have not been so </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Forty-eighth Annual Report seriously injured and that the native prairie grasses endure heat and drouth far better than bluegrass. Studies concerning the introduction of cultivated forage plants into the subirrigated prairie meadows of the Elkhorn valley and sandhills have given favorable results and are being continued. The restoration of organic matter in Nebraska soils. — The experiments for determining the rate and nature of decomposition of various organic materials when added to soil under field conditions are being continued. The number of soil and plant samples has been increased by 700. With the aid of a grant from CWA, 838 total nitrogen, 150 organic-matter, and 60 volatile-matter determinations have been made. The availability of phosphorus in soils of alkaline reaction as related to usage of phosphate fertilizer. — Laboratory studies of the year have been confined to the Minatare silt loam of Minatare Experimental Field, Scotts Bluff county. Three methods have been employed: displacement of the soil solution of field-moist soil, continuous leaching with C0 2 -free water, and continuous leaching with a dilute alkaline buffer reagent adjusted to the exact pH of the soil. The first method, when applied to samples from untreated plats and from phosphated plats of varied history, has shown no consistent correla - tion with phosphate availability as revealed by crop response. The P 2 0 5 contents of the soil solution have been low. The second method has like - wise shown no consistent relationship to availability. Extractable phos - phorus, however, has been greater. A previous report has emphasized the fact that rate of extraction by pure water declines gradually from the out - set. With the third method the rate of extraction seems to be fairly con - stant over an extended period and is outstandingly higher than with pure water. Furthermore, the quantities extracted are consistently in the same order as phosphorus availability as indicated by growing crops. Field work of the season has again been cooperative with the U. S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Chemistry of Soils. Three phases have occupied attention: intraseasonal variations in soil pH, phosphorus absorption of sugar beets at various stages of growth on phosphate-deficient soil, and response of sugar beets and alfalfa to phosphate fertilizers applied at different times and rates. As a result of weekly tests of soils to a depth of twelve inches in two-inch sections in 16 locations in Scotts Bluff county, the conclusion has been reached that the pH of alkaline soils is not sub - ject to any great variation. Occasional extremes of as much as 0.5 pH could not be correlated with any soil moisture changes or cultural circum - stances. The studies with sugar beets are being continued. The investiga - tions on alfalfa response have been concluded and are being prepared for publication. A paper on "Phosphate Deficiency and Irrigation Agriculture", by J. G. Russel, has been published during the year in Proceedings of the 41st Annual Convention of the Nebraska Irrigation Association, pp. 62-68. In this it is emphasized that not only is phosphate fertilizer necessary in certain irrigation sections, "but it is the inevitable consequence of the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station practice of irrigation in an arid land." The reasons for this are to be found in the profile characteristics of arid-soil groups, particularly in the reaction profile and the position of calcium carbonate relative to incidents of irri - gation culture. The profile characteristics of western-Nebraska soils are explained and correlated with present phosphate fertilizer practice. FRUITS AND VEGETABLES Orchard culture. — This project includes studies of growth of both roots and upper parts, culture, subsoil moisture, and other problems that con - front the fruit grower in Nebraska. Because of the drouth of the past year, Jonathan and Stayman cracked severely before harvest but good Winesap and Delicious were produced. Root excavations indicate that trees use all the space in 30x33 spacings and penetrate to a depth of 30 feet or more. The 17-ycar-old filler block averaged 12-13 per cent in soil moisture down to 30 feet. In thc permanent block the percentage near the tree was approximately 12, midway between trees 15, and in the center of the tree space about 20. An area not in trees averaged about 25. By adding water to a limited area an effort will be made to study the rate of removal by the tree. With grapes the studies of mulch and soil moisture indicate uniformly greater moisture content under mulch than under clean cultivation. Spraying for control of codling moth.— Drouth and extreme heat inter - fered with this work. The materials tested were those which seemed most promising as substitutes for lead arsenate. Nicotine sulphate used with oil gave as good control as lead arsenate, and Kalo, Black Leaf 155, and cal - cium arsenate ranked in the order named and allowed 7 to 13 per cent more worms to enter the fruit. Development of young apple root systems.— Much more marked varia - tions in the development of root systems were evident after the second years growth than after the first. The average extreme depth of rooting after two years under cultivation was 8% feet at Lincoln and 12 feet in loess at Union. The total lateral spread was similarly 15 and 18 feet. Root systems under sod and mulches are also being studied. Pruning.— Jonathan and Winesap trees, heavily pruned at transplanting and In the eighth year thereafter, produced a markedly heavier bloom than lightly pruned trees. The trunks of heavily pruned Winesap were slightly smaller in diameter than those of lightly pruned Winesap, but the opposite was true with Jonathan. Raspberries spaced 6x6 feet and pruned to 6-inch laterals produced larger fruits and better yield than those spaced 5x6 with 5-inch laterals or 4x5 with 4-inch laterals. The dry season prevented heavy yields. Fruit stocks.— The usual measurements have been taken on the top - worked orchard at Lincoln and the scion-rooted orchard at Union and trenches are being used to study root development at Lincoln. The effect of the drouth on trees on various root stocks is being noted. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Forty-eighth Annual Report | Nutritional conditions influencing tuberization of the potato. — This study is concerned with the influences of length of day, nitrogen supply, and temperature upon tuberization. A research bulletin has been published on earlier work and another is being prepared. Research Bulletin 75, The Effect of a Controlled Nitrogen Supply with Different Temperatures and Photoperiods upon the Development of the Potato Plant, by H. O. Werner, September, 1934, 126 pages. This bulletin reports a study of the development of various parts of the potato plant when the external nitrogen supply, length of day, and temperatures were varied. Organic and inorganic nitrogen in various parts of the plant at various stages of development was studied. Among the more important conclusions were the following: A high nitrogen supply, long days, and warm temperatures were most favorable for vegetative growth, whereas short, cool days were most favorable for tuberization. Tuberization was accelerated by withholding nitrogen from vigorously vegetative plants, but not when other conditions were most favorable for tuberization. Tubers were produced at high temperatures by means of short days. Nitrogen was assimilated by tubers extensively after its assimilation had ceased in leaves and stems. Storage of potatoes at Alliance. — The results of this study are reported in the Annual Report of the Nebraska Potato Improvement Association, "Storage Experiments with Seed Potatoes", by H. O. Werner, pp. 28-32, 1934. Six to ten weeks of cold storage in the spring after cellar storage seems the most desirable method. It was almost as effective as continued cold storage in preventing loss of weight and it reduced rotting and ade - quately delayed sprouting. Studies have also been made with injured and cut potatoes. Storage in low temperatures during the first few weeks after harvesting retards healing of wounds and causes increased rotting. Development of tuber-line strains of seed potatoes. — The usual index work with five strains of Triumph is being continued. An effort is being made to determine the differences in these strains in their response to lengths of day, with falling and rising temperatures. Since day lengths in the Gulf Coast states are different from those in Nebraska, this knowledge is important. There arc indications that late strains will not tuberize readily in long days (16 hours). Crop rotations at Alliance. — Satisfactory yields were obtained from potatoes following corn or summer fallow and unsatisfactory yields following small grain during the drouth season of 1934. Asparagus, lettuce, tomatoes, and carrots. — A cutting season of six to eight weeks for asparagus seems better than four weeks or ten weeks. Applications of salt have reduced yields without keeping weeds down. Straw is proving inferior to manure for mulching; the latter reduces yields but causes larger spears than with cultivation. After seven years the plats planted with large crowns are still more productive than those planted with small crowns. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station , n»«l«*»ng again showed promise as a means of growing head ST^t ~ SCaSOn WaS t0 ° hot for thc settin &amp; o£ toma "&gt; fmits. At Nebraska City no tomatoes were produced. Varieties, mulching, and irri - gation with carrots have been studied to determine inBuences on size of core and other characteristics. HOME ECONOMICS Study of gas stoves.— Within the coming year a research bulletin will be published on this project. The work on surface burners has almost been completed and work on ovens is in progress. Burners were tested as built in the stoves and other tests were made to find means of increasing efficiency by modifying some feature of the burner application. Electric stoves.— This work was completed in 1933. A research study and also a popular publication were made as follows: Research Bulletin 68, A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves, by A. E. Baragar and Edna B. Snyder, October, 1933, 60 pages. This is a complete report of thc investigations, including technical details, carried on with five electric stoves having major variations in types of surface units, m the construction, lining, and insulation of the oven, and in retail price. The purpose was to determine the efficiency and speed of surface units and the merits of differendy constructed ovens. Circular 47, Choosing and Operating Electric Stoves, by A. E. Baragar and Edna B. Snyder, March, 1934, 22 pages. This circular discusses ways of judging quality, working convenience, and cost of operation. It is designed to aid the prospective buyer and user of an electric stove. Cooking qualitv of Navy and Great Northern varieties of beans.— The beans were obtained from several bean-producing states and from western Nebraska. A standard procedure was used for cooking the various lots and the resulting products were rated for quality. Variations from tiiis procedure have also been used and the results compared. The effects of various solutions such as acids, hard waters, sodium bicarbonate, and seasonings have been studied. The results show that cooking qualitv is determined largely by the capacity of the skin to soften and permit the entrance of water. The results will be reported in a bulletin during the coming year. ° Comparative costs of certain home and commercially prepared foods — Preliminary work has consisted of a survey of 1,300 homes to learn the common practices in providing bread. More records will be obtained Commercial bakers wUl provide information on prices and ingredients so that comparisons of quality can be made. Actual baking of bread will be done m the laboratory. Records of cost of all materials used and also of fuel will be kept. Stability of lard for cake making.— The preliminary study consisting of 40 methods of mixing cake with lard has been completed. Several methods compare favorably with the use of butter. Temperature, time for combin - ing ingredients, and amount of mixing are being studied. A survey to </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Forty-eighth Annual Report provide information on preferences of shortenings has been begun with the mailing of 2,000 questionnaires. Family history and standards of living of farm families. — This work has been completed and the results await publication. A subproject on food consumption will perhaps be completed within the year. Its aims arc (1) a comparison of account and weekly records as methods of obtaining data for food studies, and (2) nutritive analysis of the food consumed. Laundry equipment and methods. — As a result of a study of home laundry problems which was sponsored by McCall's Magazine and super - vised by the Home Economics Department of the University, informatipn for a popular circular became available and was published as follows: Circular 49, Laundry Equipment and Methods, by Edith Carse and Helen Jeffrycs, April, 1934, 14 pages. This presents practical information on the laundering of clothes, at home. INSECTS, RODENTS, AND BIRDS The chinch bug, Hessian fly, and other injurious pests. — The marked decrease in Hessian fly population in 1933 and 1934, especially in the latter year, practically suspended work on that phase of this project, as in the years 1926 to 1928. No Hessian-fly field-observation stations were main - tained in 1933 or 1934. On the other hand, thc increase in population of the chinch bug during the past two seasons, especially in 1934, made neces - sary some concentrated attention on that pest. Chinch-bug barriers were studied in the emergency chinch-bug-control campaign of 1934, in which 104,950 gallons of creosote were distributed to 1,525 farmers in 14 counties in southeastern Nebraska, resulting in the erection of 332,237 rods of barrier protecting 82,500 acres of corn. Grasshopper control. — Thirteen seasons of work on this project, which was begun in 1922, have resulted in the accumulation of much data. One phase of the project emphasized in 1933-34 was a compilation of all of the available data on thc geographical and seasonal distribution of the 179 kinds of grasshoppers known in the state, and also of the principal food plants of each species. Studies of the composition and distribution of grasshopper baits, looking toward increased economy and efficiency, were likewise continued. This was largely done incidental to the distribution of 2,482 tons of poisoned bait for grasshoppers, furnished by the federal government and distributed in 56 Nebraska counties. The 1933-34 season was a very good one for the furtherance of this project. Distribution, life history, and means of control of the common Nebraska cutworms. — This project, begun in 1916, has as its purpose the ascertaining of the species of cutworms responsible for injury to field crops in this state, their general and local distribution, food habits, methods of attack, number of generations annually and the period of their occurrence, general life history, and natural enemies. Much progress has been made in a study of the cutworms themselves, with a view to identifying species. An important: </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station new line of work, which may eventually form a separate project, is a study of the nocturnal activity of the adult moth stage of species of cutworms. During both the summers of 1933 and 1934 the different species of cut - worm and armyworm moths were collected at light traps throughout the season, along with other species of moths numbering over 100, and their season of flight and relative abundance at different times indicated. Thc very dry and hot summer of 1934 had the effect of gready reducing the late summer flight of many of these species. Likewise over 100 species of beedes, including many common pests, have been collected and their season recorded. For example, over 15,000 seed-corn beedes were taken in the light trap during their season of flight ih 1933, and over 31,000 in 1934. ioj^ bTOOd StUdy ° f thc codlin S moth »n southeastern Nebraska.— Thc 1934 season completed the seventh year of work on this project, which has been designed to cover a ten-year period. The extreme drouth and the heat had marked effects upon both the population and the seasonal history of the codling moth. These effects were significant for that part of this project designed to determine thc effect of seasonally varying meteoro - logical conditions upon the number of generations, and the period of development of the broods of eggs, larvae, pupae, and moths of each of these generations. These data will serve as a basis for recommendations for timing spray applications in both normal and abnormal seasons. Control of rodents and other injurious mammals.— This project was set up in 1912 to study the mammal pests of Nebraska. Work on pocket gophers, prairie dogs and ground squirrels has been most emphasized in the past. The common mole has become so troublesome in recent years that it has commanded considerable attention under this project, and it may be necessary to set up the investigations of it as a separate project. Kangaroo rats have in recent years become more destructive in corn fields than formerly in the sandhills of Nebraska and may require some special Principal biologic factors determining the population level of the Bob - white Quail in Nebraska.— This new project was begun in 1934 with thc purpose of securing data upon which recommendations designed to restore the Bob-white Quail to its former numbers within the state might be based. It includes a study of the former and present distribution and abundance ot thc species, winter survival, food supply, parasites both external and internal, and natural enemies. This project is being carried on with the cooperation of thc Game, Forestation, and Parks Commission. LIVESTOCK FEEDING" Pasture vs. dry-lot feeding for half-fat and feeder steers.— Two lots of yearling steers which had been wintered on silage and alfalfa and two tlJr I Lm£erf^eJ n cii™ &lt; f ! . ,^ k iet £ D '". U "»&gt;°, reference is made to mimeographed circular, by of AgSStSre' ______^___%_??_}* ""*__ ' ,rom * e Department of Anima , Husbandry, CollegJ for cat* "SerUnents _ * f? . T^ a V. ,ho "' unle " » iven «&gt;&gt;«"«*. «= « follows: Alorander *^ Thalman and H. J. Gramlich; for hogs, W. J. Loeffel; for sheep, M. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Forty-eighth Annual Report groups which had received a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa for! 150 days were used to compare dry-lot and pasture feeding. The feeder steers fed on grass gained 59 pounds more in 190 days than those in dry lot,' but shrank twice as much in shipment. In neither series, however, was there any difference in economy of gain between dry-lot and pasture feeding. See Mimeo. Circular 138 (1933); also Circular 148 (1934). Summer-feeding catde wintered on silage and alfalfa. — Yearling steers, steer calves, and heifer calves were placed on a wintering ration (150 days) of silage and alfalfa, and in April, 1933, were started on corn on pasture. During the 190 days of summer-feeding the yearling steers gained 1.97 pounds per day, the younger steers 2.4, and the heifers 2.0 pounds. In economy of gain, the lots ranked in the same order. (Mimeo. Circular 139. See also Mimeo. Circular 147.) Shelled corn, cracked shelled corn, and ground ear corn for fattening steers on pasture. — Three lots of yearling steers were fed corn on pasture as indicated above for a period of 190 days. Within the limits of this trial, there was no advantage for ground shelled or ground ear corn over shelled corn with steers being fattened on pasture. (Mimeo. Circular 140.) Shelled corn vs. cracked shelled corn. — Two groups of yearling steers were fed 130 days. One lot received shelled corn, alfalfa, and cottonseed cake, and the other cracked shelled corn, alfalfa, and cottonseed cake. Cracking the corn did not affect feed consumption, and the rate of daily gain was less than in the lot receiving the unground corn — 2.58 as against 2.77. The amount of corn required to produce 100 pounds of gain was 53 pounds less for the steers receiving the unground corn. Pork produced by the hogs following the steers eating ground corn was 52.5 per cent of that of the steers eating unground corn. (Mimeo. Circular 141.) Grinding shelled, ear, and snapped corn for yearling steers. — Four lots &gt; of steers were fed 180 days. Lots 1, 2, and 3 were fed shelled corn, cracked shelled corn, and ground ear corn respectively. Lot 4 was fed ground snapped corn 80 days, ground ear corn 60 days, and cracked shelled corn for 40 days. All had alfalfa hay. A repetition of this trial in 1932-33 gave somewhat conflicting results. Detailed results are reported in Mimeo. Circular 143. The paired feeding method for nutrition experiments. — This experiment had three objectives: (1) to compare group feeding with the individual feeding method, (2) to secure data upon the relative digestibility of ground and unground corn, and (3) to determine what effect bulkiness of the ration has upon digestibility of the grain. Eight yearling steers were divided into two groups of four head each and full-fed 180 days. One steer in each group was fed corn prepared by the same method as a lot of 10 head which was group-fed. The steers were fed individually in stalls and three different times feces were collected and digestion studies made. Pairs 1 to 4 received the same rations as Lots 1 to 4 of the test reported above. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The group-feeding method was probably more reliable as a measure of the over all effect of the ration. The digestion studies yielded little information regarding die effect of grinding corn upon digestibility. There was Iitde difference within each pair in coefficients of digestibility and per- K^^T S™"/"^ P asscd hy the steers. (Mimeo. Circular 144, by R. R. Thalman and R. B. Cathcart, based on thesis by the latter ) Differences between "red" and "white-faced" steers.-One lot of Iong.yead.ng steers of Shorthorn and one of Hereford breeding were fed shelled corn and alfalfa for a period of 180 days. Both groups were pur - hr "^ 3ha £. arket&gt; the " rcds " COStin g 53.75 and the "whitc - taces J4.50 per ewt. There was no justification for the difference in initial cost when based upon feed-lot performance or market value as fat cattle. (Mimeo. Circular 145.) (1) Atlas sorgo silage vs. corn silage when supplemented with alfalfa, cottonseed cake, or cottonseed cake and limestone for wintering stock calves. (2) Corn silage for wintering yearling steers and steer and heifer calves.— vSr7 a a flir., WCre dC betWCen COfn and Atlas sila &amp; e when supplemented with alfalfa hay, with cottonseed cake, and with both cottonseed cake and ground limestone and also comparisons between alfalfa hay and cottonseed cake as supplements to a silage ration. A mineral supplement of limestone with silage and cake was also considered. rh.Tvn C f WaS n ° a PP arent difference in palatability of the two silages and the gains from Adas were 90 per cent as great as from corn silage, fnd the gain per ton of feed consumed was also 90 per cent as great from Atlas The gain per acre of Adas was 1,449 pounds and for corn 683 pounds. As o A* A substituting cottonseed cake for alfalfa as a Supplement 29 i/Lnr"^ A th , C g T- a PP roximatcl y 21 per cent with corn silage and 29 per cent with Adas. Limestone increased the gains 9.45 per cent with corn silage and 5.28 per cent with Adas silage. (Mimeo. Circular M6) Summer-feeding catde wintered on silage and alfalfa.— Thc obiect was to gather additional data upon the advisability of carrying yearUng steTrT steer calves and heifer calves through the winter on forage DeTorc Scuredln a? dU ," ng thC SUmmCr ; ""* rCSultS WCre compafablf to tho " secured in an earlier experiment (see Mimeo. Circular 139). The main for summ%?feed P,an V^ J"** ■»**»** «* avaS first? a i p 4 r 7 ov ) ,des for the markcting ° f iow *™ d ™* h - Pasture vs dry-lot feeding.-Two lots of yearling steers, one fed shelled corn and alfalfa in dry lot and one fed corn on pasture, were corn! ed r^diffSn 5 rCC dOSC,y WUh th0SC ° f ° ther trials^ There was prSfy ,n rate or economy of gain between lots. (Mimeo Circular Shelled, ground shelled, and ground ear corn for fattening vearlinir steers on pasture.-This is the second trial in which yearHng "L^wSf fed corn on pasture. The grain ration for the three li washed c^rrT, </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Forty-eighth Annual Report ground shelled corn, and ground ear corn. The feeding period was j 196 days. The use of ground ear corn did not result in any saving of alfalfa (used to supplement the pasture, which dried up) while the catde were on pasture or during the last 30 days they were in dry lot. The ground shelled corn showed to better advantage than in the previous test, but when thc cost of grinding was added, there was no advantage. (Mimeo. Circular 149.) Long alfalfa, alfalfa meal, and alfalfa meal and cottonseed cake for fattening yearling steers. — Three lots of yearling steers were fed 196 days. The object was to compare long alfalfa and alfalfa meal for fattening cattle and to determine the advisability of adding a protein supplement to an alfalfa and corn ration. There was 0.03. pound difference (favoring long hay) in daily gain between the steers fed long alfalfa and those fed alfalfa meal. Feeding the meal resulted in a considerable saving of hay, but more corn was required in the lot receiving meal. The addition of one pound per head daily of cottonseed cake increased the daily gain from 2.17 pounds to 2.31 pounds. (Mimeo. Circular 150.) Wheat straw as a roughage for fattening catde. — Two lots of yearling steers were placed on feed July 20, 1934. The experiment is in progress. The object is to determine to what extent straw can be used to replace alfalfa in the fattening ration. (Mimeo. Circular 152.) The seeding and carrying capacity of temporary pastures. — This is the second trial of a series scheduled to continue over a period of years. The tests were planned to secure data on the comparative value of temporary and permanent pastures and to obtain general information regarding their management. Second-year sweet clover gave the most pasturage of any crop during the 1933 season. White sweet clover gave more than yellow. Oats as a nurse crop did not affect the carrying capacity of first-year sweet clover. The pasture season on sudan grass was cut short by chinch bugs. Rye followed by sudan gave the second highest carrying capacity. Blue - grass sod gave slighdy more pasturage than first-year sweet clover. (Mimeo. Circular 142, by R. R. Thalman, H. J. Gramlich, W. E. Lyness, and T. A. Kiesselbach.) The 1934 results were affected by drouth hut records were tabulated (Mimeo. Circular 151). Drouth feeds and rations. — A general circular classifying feeds accord - ing to type and nutrients was prepared to serve as a guide for the farmer faced with maintaining his livestock upon maintenance ration (Mimeo. Circular 173). Tankage as a protein supplement for catde and lambs. — A circular has been prepared summarizing the results obtained by the Ohio and Nebraska stations on the feeding of tankage to catde. Results indicate that tankage is as good as or better than cottonseed or linseed meal. It is not unpalatable and it can also be used for sheep or lamb feeding. (Mimeo. Circular 174.) The use of hull-less oats in hog rations. — In a 100-day trial in which pigs were full-fed corn and tankage on sudan grass pasture, hull-less oats </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station proved to be very palatable Larger gains were made and the oats proved to be equal to corn, pound for pound. (Mimeo. Circular 242.) rhe effect of certain supplementary feeds upon the firmness of pork.— This investigation was undertaken in cooperation with the Cudahy Pack - ing Company to study such supplementary feeds as linseed meal, ground me'aTNone^T 1 F*. -T^ ' meal &gt; «"» gluten meal, S^g meal None of the by-products used or even six per cent of soybeans exerted any serious softening effect upon the lard. Hal and bacons from Srcut W 2430 ' WCre SatiSfaCt0 ' y " tC (^ were fc^ fr ° D ****«»? pasture.-Eight lots of 85-pound pigs were fed on sudan-grass pasture for 110 days. The self-feeding of tankaee with corn greased the daily consumption of corn a pound a dty and almost doubled the daily gain. jWhere self-fed, a ponn/of tankage^ 5 pounds of corn. Where no tankage was fed, depasture was destroyed SLKP./" 1 *"5 ° **_ of a mineral P mixture TneTand feeding of % pound of tankage per day with a self-feeder of corn increased die daily gam more than 50 per cent, and a pound of tankage saved 7 pounds of corn. Cracked barley and tankage proved more palatable than corn and tankage, but the barley was only 81 £r cent as XbiTa^ corn Where ground barey was compared with corn alone, the barley was 97 «&amp;SAiis? a f ,arger gains wcre — ed * tnnW Pa^,° £ ! r ° Und Mts With threc of S round corn by weight plus tankage, produced as large gains as corn and tankage. On a weifht baris ground oats were 50 per cent as valuable as corn. Equal __Z of JcZrl rapSTTthJ?^ three times as rapioiy as those fed only two pounds per head daily of the same ration "e^r^^'w Kq 1\i ° nly *° ? &lt;*" - -ch feeTtoma°ke of rnrn rVA • ° f 10 P" CCM ot with the light ratio,, onlv an H T T? H &amp;»'&gt; ««* P°™* °* tankage repla«d L raSly^ Zs? /^ C ° rn - gfOWn ° n und "«*S B nof^n oer ™L J T- d 3n CqUal amount of corn - Ground barley waf85 per cent asjfficient as corn per u^it of weight. (Mimeo. Circula? 2? 5 !) i/ dd . feed /ng of pigs.- Hundred-pound pigs full-fed ear corn nlus pounds of gain; each pound of linkage, self-fed, replaced 3 £ pounds of </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Forty-eighth Annual Report corn. Where V. pound of tankage was fed per head daily, the gain increased from 1.08 to 1.71 pounds; on this basis, a pound of tankage replaced 8'/ 2 pounds of corn. Alfalfa hay fed to pigs in the cornfield increased the daily gain from 1.08 to 1.57 pounds; each pound of alfalfa hay fed saved 2 pounds of corn. Where both hay and tankage were self - fed to pigs in the cornfield, no increase in gain or saving in tankage was noted, although some corn was saved. Contrary to popular belief, young pigs which had been liberally fed prior to being turned in the cornfield made fully as efficient gains as older pigs which had been grown on a lower grain allowance. Early and late lamb production from western ewes.— Three groups of western ewes were used for a two-year early lamb production study. The group receiving grain before and after lambing gained almost twice as much and sold higher as fat ewes in May than thc group receiving gram after lambing, and gained 3 V_ .times as much, with a higher selling price, than the third group of ewes receiving no grain before or after lambing. The market value of thc lambs varied in proportion to the amount of grain fed the ewes, as did the return per lamb. Feeding grain to late lambs while on pasture was advantageous. (Mimeo. Circular 324.) Linseed meal, cottonseed meal, and corn gluten meal compared in lamb fattening rations of calculated equal digestible crude protein and total digestible nutrients.— Five groups of western feeder lambs were used. Ground shelled corn and whole alfalfa hay were fed in each lot. The same amount of hay was fed in each lot, but the amount of corn varied in accordance with the amount of calculated digestible nutrients added by the inclusion of a protein supplement. Corn starch was used to balance the nutrients after the protein had been balanced. No fattening properties were revealed by the rations containing a rich protein feed that were not also shown by the corn and alfalfa ration. The corn gluten meal, "nseed meal, and cottonseed meal showed similar values and reactions when added to a corn and alfalfa ration. (Mimeo. Circular 325.) Adding various protein supplements to a corn and alfalfa hay lamb - fattening ration.— The average of three years' work comparing cottonseed meal, linseed meal, corn gluten meal, and various combinations of the three supplements as an addition to a basal ration of corn and alfalfa for fattening feeder lambs is reported in Mimeo. Circular 326. The corn gluten meal produced 0.01 of a pound greater daily gain than linseed meal or cottonseed meal. Thc saving in favor of corn gluten meal was 15.43 pounds of shelled corn, 1.79 pounds of supplement, and 30.27 pounds of alfalfa hay for each 100 pounds of gain. Efficient corn and alfalfa hay rations for fattening lambs— Eight groups of western lambs were used, and the rations differed in amounts of corn and alfalfa. Thc results show that thc number of days between the start - ing of feeding and an expected favorable market will be an important </seg>
            <seg id="p024">. Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station factor in making up such a ration. The combination of corn and alfalfa should be determined first and then adjustments made to suit the price relationship between corn and alfalfa. Eight tried combinations, with the number of days required to make a desirable market lamb, are shown in Mimeo. Circular 327. Short-tailed Hampshire sheep.— A Hampshire ram lamb was dropped January 30, 1933, with a tail about half normal length. He has been mated with four ewes, and four ram lambs, one with a 5-inch tail, were obtained. The project is being continued. Expected difference in gain of paired individually fed lambs.— Ten pairs of lambs were used to study the difference in gain that can be expected between paired lambs fed identical rations. Four of the pairs showed a gain difference within the pair of less than one pound for the period of 79 days. The other differences ranged from 2.3 to 11 pounds for the same period. Thc results are not available in published form. Farm flock performance.— Seventy-nine head of western ewes showing a solid mouth and two Southdown rams are being used. The data for the first year will soon be completed. Information on the care, feeding, man - agement, and establishment of a Nebraska farm flock is given in Nebraska Experiment Station Circular 48, Farm Sheep Facts, March, 1934, 18 pages. Fattening Iambs without hay.— Six groups of western feeder lambs are used in the study. The comparisons include Adas silage and wheat straw. The test is now in progress. milling and baking Preparation and study of tie cereal glutelins.— Studies of the character of the cereal proteins and of means for their identification have been con - tinued. New and improved methods of "fractionation" of these proteins have been devised. One of them, which seems to offer an almost ideal starting point for fractionation studies, involves preliminary dispersion in sodium salicylate. Enzymes of wheat flour as related to flour grade and baking character - istics.—-A simple, convenient aluminum manometric apparatus ("Pressure - meter") has been perfected, and its use adapted to a rapid and accurate method for the estimation of diastatic activity, or "gassing power" of wheat flour. Catalase activity in a series of commercial flours of widely different origin was investigated. It was found, as has been noted by others, that for any individual sample of wheat, catalase activity is very definitely correlated with flour grade, being highest in the lower grades and vice versa. However, wheats from different localities vary widely and system - atically in catalase activity. It runs highest in the northern spring wheats of Canada, and lowest in the winter wheats of Kansas and Texas. Wheats from intermediate localities occupy an intermediate position. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Forty-eighth Annual Report The following publications have been made since the last Annual Report: "The Laboratory Baking Test — A Science or a Fine Art?" by M. J. Blish, Cereal Chem., 11:70-73, 1934. A polemical discussion. "Yeast Variability and Its Control in Flour Gassing Power Tests"; by R. M. Sandstedt and M. J. Blish, Cereal Chem., 11:368-83, 1934. Factors causing yeast variability in gassing power tests are identified, and a pro - cedure is described for the reduction of such variability to a negligible quantity. "Report on Diastatic Activity of Flour", by M. ). Blish, Jour. Assoc. Offic. Agr. Chemists, 17:394-99, . 1934. A revised and improved method for the estimation of flour diastatic activity is specified, and recommended as a tentative method of the Association of Official Agricultural Chemists. Collaborative trials are reported. "Diastatic Activity in Suspensions and Doughs", by R. M. Sandstedt, Cereal Chem., 11:532-35, 1934. Data are presented showing that degree of diastatic activity in yeast-fermented dough may be accurately estimated and predicted from estimations of diastasis in flour-water suspensions, under controlled conditions. PLANT DISEASES The pathological and physiological aspects of alfalfa failures in Ne - braska. — This work is cooperative with the U. S. Department of Agricul - ture. Results dealing with the behavior of inbred lines of alfalfa with respect to cold and wilt resistance are reported in the following publication: Research Bulletin 76, Wilt and Cold Resistance of Self-fertilized Lines of Alfalfa, by G. L. Peltier and H. M. Tysdal, September, 1934, 26 pages. The results of subjecting self-fertilized lines to cold and wilt elimination are reported. The study also includes inheritance of wilt resistance in sub - sequent generations and the occurrence of wilt and cold resistance together and separately. High wilt and cold resistance do occur in the same I indi - viduals, but the results point to independent segregation. Preliminary results of compositing seed from desirable plants, or "strain building", indicate promising possibilities by this method. Potato scab and fusarium wilt in relation to infection from the soil. — The results of a preliminary survey have been published in Phytopathology, 24:517-27, May, 1934, "A Survey of Potato Scab and Fusarium Wilt in Western Nebraska", by R. W. Goss. In this publication the effects of the following factors upon the diseases are presented: length of rotation, crop preceding potatoes, type of soil, reaction of soil, and the kind and number of microorganisms present in the soil. The practical application of results obtained from field experiments have been published in the Annual Report of the Nebraska Potato Improvement Association for the year 1933-34, pp. 33-38, "Four Serious Diseases of (Table and Seed Potatoes (Scab, Fusarium Wilt, Rhizoctonia, ahd Early Blight)", by R. W. Goss. The effect of the preceding crop, the interval between </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station potato crops, the effect of time and depth of plowing, time of planting a?itd USC Cm,Cal SOU trCatmCDtS f ° r thc C ° ntro1 ° £ disSes'fe -ff-^f Pr °" Cm ". bein « studicd in the greenhouse to determine the effect of various environmental factors upon the occurrence of these d£ plvsioht, : f tl ,° rat 7' StUdiCS arC *** made 0f thc ™orphoo^ and physiology of the pathogenic strains of Actinomyces, both in pure and mixed cultures. Histological studies of the infection phenomena have bee~n made and are being prepared for publication. nn rh!!^^. if*"?"* diSeaS ? CaUSed by C ««"»K« A/«»«/«.-The work Reotrt SSffih V «° mpl » d the r " ultS P ub,ishcd in Annual 8ETv thc c Neb^ aska St ate Horticultural Society for 1934, pages 93-104 G™ Tm ?Pn 2? ng . Tc8t l f0r C ° ntrol of Chcrf y Leaf-spo P t"f by R. W and the time 5 Ji" "— UP ° n *■ diSCa " ° f ***-" 0i W rdarion t "J application * given, and the prevalence of the disease in relauon to weather conditions during the years 1929 to 1933 is discussed has lv?„ 1 J* °f m fa Ne »&gt;n.ska.-The work on this problem has been completed and the results published fi/ZlT? w^ k lTT m . Wilt and Die - ba * °f the Whit &lt; Elm by R. W. Goss and Paul R. Frink, 22 pages, January, 1934 This *£ StaLS ~ thc ,. rCSU k lts . of a st udy of a nevv disease^in NebraTS a^atoriv morn^ SSCS d,rt T buU ° n and P^valence, symptoms, pathological U_TT!' m ° r P ho . lo gy' and Physiology of the causal organism/results of inoculation experiments, and suggested control methods Diseases of field and garden beans in Nebraska^-An attempt is being made to obtain, by selection and hybridization, varieties of fid Und gaS beans that are resistant to halo blight, common blight, and bacterial wilt. POULTRY Comparative efficiency of various proteins in poultry feeding —Studies d£ of V ft V d Cd h a rt? gr ° Win^ chicks^re fodl^S^qua" S Lfled IK f ° r d f nlt^ ?"**• " CX P iration 5 whic^they are killed, weighed, and analyzed for total N, Ca, and P. This procedure permits an accurate and direct method for estimating the d^tHnich £* iTSLTnT* diffcr u m W" ° f fccd anH different Sta are SST'™?* ST* ° f u, Crr0 f haS b6en found satisfactorily low. L&gt;ata arc being prepared for publication. ine qCSs'of tr^ ° f » nn *W I d ***-A study of the complement - ing qualities of certain protein supplements resulted in evidence that a considerable variety of protein sources does not necessarily g^rantee a h g J SSfLSL* ,n / hC COmbination - In two series of SJSSi t*e u^Tsix fee S ° Ur " S T 11 ' P r ° Vcd ■*» than^he one made sou™ V m „T 1S V u Sg«t.on that the combination made up of four bXthin d m2Ki?* K mCa1 ' d u ied buttCrmilk ' S °y- bcan oil mcal &gt; was hT Po„h™ S? t . h =. 0th f r combinations. The results will be published in Poultry Science within the coming year. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Forty-eighth Annual Report Since earlier work had shown dried buttermilk to be better for growing chicks than dried skimmilk, two series of tests were planned to answer these questions: Does the higher acid level of the former conserve some essential nutritive factor and does thc method of processing these dairy products affect their value as growth-promoting feeds? It is apparent from these tests that skimmilk dried by the roller-drum process is better than that produced by the vacuum-spray process. The difference was especially notable when the basal ration was heated for 96 hours at 100" C. to destroy the vitamin G. More work will be done before final conclusions can be drawn. Nutritive requirements of growing turkeys.— Over 1,100 turkeys have been used in various parts of this work. The conclusions are that growing poults are able to adapt themselves to considerable variation in the Ca:P ratio when the most favorable conditions for assimilation and fixation are provided. Further work will be done in 1935 and a publication of results will be made in the near future in Poultry Science. Incubation of turkey eggs. — A report of progress was made. Further study will be directed toward determining what modifications should be made during the last four days of incubation. Research Bulletin 74, Some Observations on Humidity and Weight Loss in the Incubation of Turkey Eggs, by F. E. Mussehl and G. W. Ackerson, August, 1934, 11 pages. No significant correlation was found between thc loss of weight of eggs during incubation and the growth rate of poults during the first eight weeks. Rate of air movement and humidity in incubators apparently have more influence during the last four days of thc hatching period than during the first twenty-four. Other character - istics of the eggs were noted. RURAL ECONOMICS Studies in prices, volume of production, and purchasing power of farm products.— Work under this project during the past year and a half has been devoted to the publication of the following bulletins: Bulletin 284, Local Prices of Farm Products in Nebraska, 1895-1932, by H. C. Filley and Arthur M. Haukc, July, 1933, 36 pages. This bulletin presents information on prices paid farmers for wheat, corn, oats; hogs, butter, butterfat, eggs, and potatoes during the period covered by thei study. The purchasing power of the same products during these years is also presented. The methods of determining purchasing power are explained fully- , r- s, ■ Research Bulletin 71, The Effects of Inflation and Deflation upon Nebraska Agriculture, 1914-1932, by H. Clyde Filley, June, 1934, 130 pages. This study covers a period of varying prosperity. Among the sub - jects treated arc thc changes in prices of various commodities, changes in purchasing power of farm products, and changes during the period in wages, farm income, types of farming, banking, taxation, land prices, and </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station va^mT condlS 05 ' "^ PUrP ? SC h t0 a PP raise the influ «ces of 3 are thet ZJT*"' " Am ° ng ° thcr inclusions ruonS nf tSn i thC ,nCreaSCS in knd P ficc in 1914 and the early montW 1920 were due to increased farm profits and not to speculation or1nflation\ g *** *""* * m ° rC bcncfidal than ™*« period Mn^ ebK^ ka had P rices — °ne part of this project, on farm mort- S 0? d4 no b U h n r ; on and ; pr vL c f history ' werc «W* -^ pX raroffat^ S m enran°d Ur tn S ° f IT*' *"?*■ ° f f ° recfosur « £ voTunt^' Se Utter Srt?f f „ SUbjCCtS "? Some attenti °n " given to the fatter part to the present situation in farm mortgages. Sui ?? b y .Eleanor H. Hinman, June, 1934, 58 pages. This study deals with the variation in sales activity, changes in price ifvels and se tions o sT 1 '? ° f ,and t0 3Ctivit y and foreclosures Various fSw w C XT? re P rcsented - Among the observations were the SrS SlnN^TH £armSS ° Id "? a "° rC rate ° £ ""« tu - wtVn farms ,n each decade subsequent to 1894 Widun each county studied except Box Butte, the rough? rolling? sandy or clayey land sold at a somewhat more rapid rate than the better land during the boom dod&gt; m^ { J d SSnglsSS were r Jsks*; nas of land which had shown thc ~ - s P^ta^ad^n^-S S? t „1 S5 b £ ~?* **» gators. P The ,„£ products to market has received consideration also. The financial status and operating results of farmers' elevators during the KtiodmLiTlZ being considered, and effort is being made to SSSjlSSLSS u£ of elevators in analyzing their results. UW Fann organization and farm costs.— This project utilizes the farm account book in obtaining information on profifs from virion systems rf oZ^oT^ZZr??**™ ofthe'statc. Many of the S ct ?Sr 19« ,h P A r0dUCt ;°» fCCOrds on onc or two crops. For the EStfllJSr i*™? EC u° n , 0mics "nbKfiwTTTS books. d^t a „Kr " 3 ' 000 ~° k f. we « placed with farmers in 1934. Some of the SbrStlS^ *■ Pr ° JCCt arC Pr^ ntcd in Rcsearch Bu »«?n </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Forty-eighth Annual Report Cost of producing farm crops. — This is a companion project of the! one above. Cost-of-production records completed in 1933 were as follows: potatoes, 22; horses, 14; tractors, 9; corn, 218; and wheat, 128. Cost of baby chick production and custom hatching service. — The field work has been done and the data have been tabulated and analyzed. Farm real estate tax delinquencies and public expenditures in Nebraska. — A large amount of data gathered and compiled under a CWA project is available for use in this project. Complete 'data for the years 1928-33 have been obtained for 12 counties. Farm mortgage foreclosures in Nebraska. — In addition to data obtained by a CWA project on land transfers, other more detailed information on acres transferred, consideration for each transfer, type of deed, and whether mortgage or cash transfer, has been obtained and tabulated. This material will probably be published in a bulletin during the coming year. STATE SERUM PLANT There was very little hog cholera during the year. In addition, the drouth, the hog-reduction program, the declining market, and the rela - tively high price of serum and virus established by the code, all had their effect on the demand for serum and virus. Sales were diminished every - where. The state plant had no difficulty in maintaining supplies and in filling orders. The policy of buying the main supply of serum subject to retest and of making the virus was continued. Considerable repair work was done about the plant. With the present improvements, blood serum can be produced on a reasonably large scale. With the addition of some special equipment, concentrated clear serum can be produced. I. Serum sold throughout the year at the code price of 55 cents for 100 cc., and virus at thc code price of $1.50 for 100 cc. A report of the sales by months follows, together with a financial statement for the year ending January 1, 1935. Scrum and virus sold by months: Serum Virus cc. cc. January 156,875 10,980 February ' 85,625 6,085 March 75,375 5.195 April 79,500 6,920 May 235,975 18,070 June 481,450 37,375 July 457,060 31,400 August 359,250 23,445 September 194.250 11.755 October 56,750 3,865 November 45,750 2,910 December 18,625 1,265 Serum and virus used at plant. 1934... 20,000 4,600 2.266,485 163,865 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Serum on hand January 1, 1934 ,,,„„„ Serum on hand January 1 1935 / ,330,380 cc. Pigs used retesting serum and making 'virus.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.' '338 5 ' 263,895 «■ Total gross sales. .... Money collected and receipted' for * 13,289.09 _.., 15,301.83 StfSS 8 v°re and,anUary '• 193 5, according ,o bursar's report $ 81,714.00 Miscellaneous stock 17,897.24 " • 625.25 Total assets. . . . ■ $100,236.49 NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION e z^___ m T r^, md r* hm •»*** - ■ &lt;&amp;Jo r &gt;A'f_ a b _% 2S£*^» *• 44 "■» •«*-* - and 273 blS^S,^ ""^ "* *"'&gt;' Kal ° «** *"* M w^L"Sl,' , wT 1, LfS ,,i ' &gt; ° Pl "°! "V*™* 1 81 d„, Thc "»d «!4 fakC LIS £ 7 """"f' "Ii 1 " 1 **&amp;&gt;•*«* - *= «a»n </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Forty-eighth Annual Report including electricity, distribution, and fixed costs, was $8.17 per acre on 112 acres. I—,".., r c One field of corn on alfalfa sod received 31.6 inches of water in 5 applications and produced only 8.5 tons of silage per acre; on 37.7 acres of corn the average was 21 inches and the yield 5.6 tons Adas sorgo on alfalfa sod received 40.6 inches and produced 13.2 tons of silage per .acre; another field received 25.2 inches and yielded 16.2 tons. Potatoes on alfalfa sod produced 290 bushels per acre with 33.7 inches in 8 applications. Although the plant operated at a low efficiency level, and the ratio ot water used to yields was unusually high, high market values, low current costs, and wider distribution of field costs contributed to higher net returns than usual. At $6.00 per ton for silage, $10.00 per ton for sorghum hay, $15.00 for alfalfa, and $1.00 per bushel for potatoes, the crop value was $3 687 94 more than the estimated value of crops from a similarly cropped, unirrigated area. With total costs of $915.55 deducted the balance is $2,772.39. This is the second time in ten years that a single year s profits have exceeded the $2,500 original cost of the plant. Beef cattle.— A third year's work on creep feeding has shown results similar to those of the two preceding years. In a test of roughages for fattening calves one ton of silage replaced from 850 to 900 pounds of alfalfa hay and there was some advantage in feeding 0.1 pound of ground limestone per head per day. In a comparison of native grass pasture and dry lot for steer calves, it was concluded that in general the calves grazed, whether fed a full feed (8 pounds of corn per day) or no grain while on grass, made more economical gains than those fed in dry lot. The use ot alfalfa pasture in feeding steers again proved profitable. A project com - paring prairie hay, prairie hay and cottonseed cake, and prairie hay and steamed bone meal as winter rations for breeding catde was begun and will be continued until three crops of calves have been obtained. Swine.— In a cross-breeding test with Duroc gilts and Duroc and Hampshire boars, the purebred pigs made slighdy larger and more eco - nomical gains and sold at a slighdy higher price. I Poultry.— The flock-testing project, in cooperation with thc Extension Service and the Department of Poultry, has revealed differences among flocks in hatchability of eggs, vitality of chicks, and production of pullets. Effort is being directed toward finding the causes. | Dairy.— The present Holstein herd consists of 28 cows and 15 heifers. The heifers are daughters of the senior herd sire, Sir Tnun e Pagsjr 24th and are bred to a Substation bull from a cow with a record of 1,000 pounds of fat. Since the herd was established the Substation has placed more than 200 bulls from high-producing cows, most of them in Nebraska, During the past year, four cows have completed records above 800 pounds of fat, thc highest being 974. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station During the dry weather of the summer the dairy herd was pastured on ungated alfalfa pasture with no cases of bloat a^d favoTable" result's Tn tainedT^T 011 ash block &gt; which **d previously main - tained a high rate of survival, was almost completely killed Hon" - bTmade tIT *"* "T^ mUch Urcd - ° ak *-^«? well (^ t S P ro S/ cs !' L while western yellow pines are in fair condition survtal lixtSd i? pla, " ing ' of "* f» fi ™ f»" *°» P»or SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION The work of the year 1934 was affected by the severe drouth m„,K ST fi^ £ d p ~t d T rm„ „*,..• cen l° elow normal &gt; and ,n some cases even more than 50. _7^_ alfSa and ma^ute C Ts JmY t haS dcmons £ted the value of sweet clover, than to alfalf™ u 'e poS^J^ betta to manure T^™k f_V. . P" 8 *** and oats respond better to alfalfa. valuTS bo^S^S TT" " DOW *&lt;** "W ° n to studv the pulp andX'pufp and^omS XSP* l"^"' l ° COm P arc wct through thiZ y«£. ° mparC barIey and corn - Th * test will run 5 ughage r h a ? d without a g fain -ppi - organizcd. * C ° ntmUed - The dair y work is being replanned and re - begl?^rwt±liltd b t 0f tHC ****? VaricticS ' Which -s condition S^Sd^ 0 £. B,,,t,UB , Sati^ ctoril y because of ad - for the previous Tears Thelt othc " w «&lt;= ■&lt;** than half of the average previous years. The data on yields are available at the station </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Forty-eighth Annual Report VALENTINE SUBSTATION The work with crop varieties at this substation failed because of thc drouth. Fields that were disked early could not be plowed until after the rains in the middle of August. The season turned dry again and fall - seeded grains failed to germinate. Crops. — The yields of spring grains were very low. Kanota, with 11 bushels, was the highest-yielding variety of oats. Spartan barley, with! 6.4, and Garnet wheat with 7 bushels per acre were highest-yielding varieties. Seed corn of the dent varieties from local farmers excelled seed from other sources. In a test of grain sorghum varieties, Tribune, Modoc, and Wheat - land showed promise in their yielding more pounds per acre than corn. Wintering range calves. — This year concluded a series of tests corripar-' ing grain with cottonseed cake as a supplement to prairie hay. The replacing of one pound of grain with one-half pound of cottonseed cake increased the winter gain 59.4 pounds with corn and 44.5 pounds with rye, thus demonstrating the value of protein as a supplement to prairie hay. A complete report can be obtained from the station. Dairy cattle. — The purebred Holstein herd has continued its high pro - duction record. The average feed cost per 100 pounds of milk for the past three years has been 63 cents and the cost per pound of butterfat 16.6 cents. The average price for butterfat during the period has been 17.2 cents. Since 1930 thc herd has been regularly tested for contagious abortion and at present is free of this disease. Reactors were sold immediately after reaction and cows about to calve have been segregated until two or three weeks after calving. Meadow improvement. — Thc seeding of clover on native meadows was unsuccessful this season because of the drouth. The March readings of surface wells in ten meadows showed an average drop of 10 inches in the level of ground water, as compared with the previous year. BOX BUTTE EXPERIMENT FARM The crops, because of the drouth, were the poorest in the history of this experiment farm. In many of the rotations the potato crop was a com - plete failure; the best yields followed summer fallow and corn. Soil mois - ture in plots following small grain was insufficient for plant growth by thc middle of August. All the work mentioned below is directed from the central experiment station at Lincoln, and it is discussed more fully in previous sections of this report. A slight change in the management has been made through the resignation of Bill Allington, whose work has been taken over by George Schmid. Strains of Bliss Triumph with different degrees of maturity and free from disease are being increased for distribution to western-Nebraska growers as foundation stock for certified seed. Work on seed indexing, strain testing, cultural studies, and storage experiments is being con- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station tR^Ztt____t f^^TSd z_ ADDITIONAL LAND, BUILDINGS, AND EQUIPMENT the tT^ h Re^ C N ° rth PkttC Substatio « *• completed since CHANGES IN STAFF JS^&amp;WZ** " H ° mC ***** who bad been on leave, </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Forty-eighth Annual Report PUBLICATIONS SINCE THE LAST ANNUAL REPORT ANNUAL REPORT Forty-seventh Annual Report, presented to the Governor February 1, 1934. 1,500 copies. BULLETINS No. 282, Pump Irrigation Investigations in Nebraska. E. E. Brackett and E. B. Lewis. July, 1933. 5,000 copies. No. 283, Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska. T. A. Kiesselbach, Arthur Anderson, and C. A. Suneson. July, 1933. 5,000 copies. No. 284, Local Prices of Farm Products in Nebraska, 1895-1932. H. C. Filley and Arthur M. Haukc. July, 1933. 3,000 copies. No. 285, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-1933. Board of Tractor Test Engineers. January, 1934. 3,500 copies. No. 286, Cultural Practices in Winter Wheat Production. T. A. Kiesselbach, Arthur Anderson, and W. E. Lyness. April, 1934. 5,000 copies. No. 287, Bindweeds and Their Control. T. A. Kiesselbach, N. F. Petersen, ' and W. W. Burr. May, 1934. 5,000 copies. No. 288, Common Grass Weeds o£ Nebraska. F. D. Keim and A. L. Frolik. June, 1934. 7.500 copies. No. 289, Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms, 1920-1934. E. E. Brackett and E. B. Lewis. June, 1934. 10,000 copies. No. 290, Diseases of Poultry" — Their Nature and Control. L. Van Es and J. F. OIney. July, 1934. 15,000 copies. No. 291, A Comparative Study of Pneumatic Tires and Steel Wheels on Farm Tractors. C. W. Smith and Lloyd W. Hurlbut. September, 1934. 5,000 copies. RESEARCH BULLETINS No. 67, Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Southeastern Nebraska Townships, 1870 - 1932. Eleanor H. Hinman and J. O. Rankin. August, 1933. 3,000 copies. No. 68, A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves. A. E. Baragar and Edna B. Snyder. October, 1933. 2,500 copies. No. 69, The Vitamin A Content of Skimmilk, Standardized Milk, and Cream from Different Breeds of Cows. I. L. Hathaway and H. P. Davis. December, 1933. 1 3,000 copies. No. 70, Cephalosporium Wilt and Die-back of the White Elm. R. W. Goss and Paul Raymond Frink. January, 1934. 3,000 copies. No. 71, The Effects of Inflation and Deflation upon Nebraska Agriculture, 1914 - 1932. H. Clyde Filley. June, 1934. 3,000 copies. No. 72, History of Farm Land Prices in Eleven Nebraska Counties, 1873-1933. Eleanor H. Hinman. June, 1934. 3,000 copies. No. 73, Thc Vitamin E Content of Certain Dairy Feeds. I. L. Hathaway and H. P. Davis. August, 1934. 3,000 copies. No. 74, Some Observations on Humidity and Weight Loss in thc Incubation of Turkey Eggs. F. E. Mussehl and C. W. Ackerson. August, 1934. 3,000 copies.| No. 75, The Effect of a Controlled Nitrogen Supply with Different Temperatures and Photoperiods upon the Development of the Potato Plant. H. O. Werner. Sep - tember, 1934. 2,500 copies. No. 76, Wilt and Cold Resistance of Self-Fertilized Lines of Alfalfa. George L. Peltier and H. M. Tysdal. September, 1934. 3,500 copies. CIRCULARS No. 47, Choosing and Operating Electric Stoves. A. E. Baragar and Edna B. Snyder. March, 1934. 7,500 copies. No. 48, Farm Sheep Facts. M. A. Alexander and W. W. Derrick. March, 1934. 10,000 copies. No. 49, Laundry Equipment and Methods. Edith Carse and Helen Jeffryes: April, 1934. 25,000 copies. technical papers Because the technical papers published by Station workers are mentioned throughout this report, no list of them is included. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station IWANC^ STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVER^ffiNT^ HATCH FUND Receipts act of Congress approved March 2, 1887* Total. ._ . . ...... $15 000 00 For salaries .... Expenditures $15,000.00 Total ' ■ $15,000.00 ADAMS FUND Receipts act of Congress, S^U^S^T^^^^ Wd "^ nnnnn For salaries . . Expenditures $15,000.00 .. , Total Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, .' "IT $15,000.00 January 16, 1935 L - E - GUNDERSON, PURNELL FUND FiMnCC Secretar y- D • . . , Receipts act of Congress approved February 24,' &amp;&amp; tS.^ . 3 °'. .^. SALARIES Expenditures Regular Temporary $35,723.28 ' 3,292.86 Total ~ - SUPPLIES $39,016.14 Office Supplies t Laboratory Supplies . . * - Awll Fuel (Coal). . . 2,450.50 Educational and Recreational 'AAA'""' I?'2S Janitor and Barn Supplies =£2 Feeding Stuff, ,J"J Agncultural Supplies AAA..". AAA.'.'.'.'. 293 98 Total EXPENSE $ 6,667.01 . Office Expense and Postage * , d „ Freight, Express and Drayage * XTg Water, Heat, Light and Power....::: ' Public : Printing and Advertising ,,„„ ■as** 1 — y-AAAAAA ass &amp;£i^ 5J II Total $10309.27 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Forty-eighth Annual Report repairs Building ' $ 314.84 ' Land 15.25 Equipment 39435 Total $ 724.44 EQUIPMENT Furniture and Fixtures $ 283.47 Apparatus (Labor and Equipment) 2310.41 Machinery 22333 Books, Magazines and Maps 13.27 Total $ 2,730.48 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land Improvement $ 12433 Total $ 124.33 FIXED CHARGES Refunds $ 42833 Total $ 428.33 GRAND TOTAL $60;000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, January 16, 1935. Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station FINANCIAL STATEMENT EXCLUSIVE OF FEDERAL FUNDS — SALARIES SUPPLIES TOU ' $64,803.60 Office Supplies $ 90fi Laboratory Supplies • «. xsZJ, Fuel (Coal) «««-£ Foodstuffs "26.85 Educational and Recreational . Ir, W Janitor and Barn Supplies ... B i?'„ Feeding Stuffs "f. 23 ll 1 1? Agricultural Supplies •.!..!."!!!!!.'•! 3,72631 EXPENSE TOta ' $36,071.74 Office Expense and Postage « 1 126 04 Freight, Express and Drayage 79Qtt Water, Heat, Light, Power and Fuel .'.'.'AAA. 5 04708 Public Printing, Advertising and Photography 1,98807 Traveling Expense * ' 1 «Odo Rcnuis ..••.." ::::::::::::: 24405 Special and Temporary Services AA. 21 16234 Miscellaneous \ '_ \ \ '%£% REPAIRS TOta ' $33,189.02 Building - , ,, Land ;;;;;; * 2.47331 ******* ::::::::::::::::::jw3X5 EQUIPMENT Tou1 -- $8,184.78 Furniture and Equipment S 977 gn Apparatus (Labor and Equipment) ...AAA.'.'.'.'.'." 2 485 37 M^inS?::::::::::::: ::: "Hjfg Total $16,775.93 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land , _ n _ Land improvement: 'AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA.'AAAAAA. lolii Total $ 1314.51 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Forty-eighth Annual Report FIXED CHARGES Refunds ' $ 151.47 Total $ 151.47 j GRAND TOTAL $160,391.05 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, January 16, 1935. Finance Secretary. [IMiMI </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>