<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Pine Tipmoth in the Nebraska National Forest</title>
               <date value="1927-04">1927-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 40 The Pine Tipmoth in the Nebraska National Forest M. H. SWENK Department of Entomology LINCOLN, NEBRASKA April, 1927 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Summary 3 Previous history and distribution of the insect -. 5 History of the Nebraska infestation 8 Introduction of the insect .... 13 Manner of attack and injury ..... 14 Seasonal history Number of annual generations. ■ 21 Season of flight of the first brood of moths .„ 21 The depositing and hatching of the eggs of the first brood . .21 Larval development of the first brood ... 23 Pupal development of the first brood &#132; 27 Emergence of the moth* of the second brood 28 Season of flight of the second brood of moths .. &#132;.. 30 The depositing and hatching of the eggs of the second brood .... 31 Larval development of the second brood 31 Emergence and cocooning of the second brood larvae . 36 Hibernation of the insect within the cocoon . 40 Removal of infested tips as a control measure ... 42 Parasites present m Nebraska ... 45 Literature cited ... .. . • 49 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY The pine tipmoth first attracted attention in 1876, when it severely attacked the young pines on Nantucket Island, south of Cape Cod, Massachusetts. Later it was found to have a general distribution in the United States. It was first noted in the Nebraska National' Forest in 1909,- where it had been introduced sometime during the preceding 7 years, probably by being carried in on forest pulled trees, or Dossibly by natural spread from native western yellow pine growth to the north and west. Attack by the pine tipmoth chiefly concerns young and rapidly growing pines. The newly hatched larvae first attack the bases of the needles or needle clusters, then later move to the tip of the growing shoot and start a burrow there, usually in or near the terminal bud. When this- portion of the shoot is consumed the larvae burrow down-' ward within it, usually killing it down as far back from the tip as the burrow extends. When this attack is repeated during successive seasons the tree is forced to make an unsymmetrical, bushy type of growth that largely destroys its value and beauty. The pine tipmoth has 2 complete, but overlapping, generations annually in the Nebraska National Forest. The insect passes the winter in silken cocoons spun during the latter part of August and early September by the second brood of larvae. The moths of the first brood fly about among the trees on warm, still days during May. They deposit their tiny, rounded, flat, yellowish eggs singly or in very small groups on the outside of the leaf bud scales. Oviposition takes place at night. In 6 days or more these eggs hatch into larvae 1 milli - meter or slightly over in length, and pale yellowish with a black head in color. These first attack the needles, then the terminal buds, and finally the interior of the growing shoots, varying their movements somewhat according to the species of pine, upon which they are work - ing. The period of larval development of this brood extends from late May to late July, there having been a seasonal variation of fully 3 weeks between the early season of 1911 and the late season of 1909. Pupation by the first brood takes place invariably in the larval burrow in the pine shoots. The total season during which first brood pupae may be found extends from early June to late July, tho the indi - vidual pupal period is only about 9 to 13 days. When the pupae of the first brood are readv to give forth the moths they force themselves half way or more out of the opening. The pupal skin then splits and allows the moth to escape. Emergence takes place chiefly in the morning hours. The total period of flight of the moths of the second brood extends from the latter part of June to the latter part of July. Ovioosition begins within a few hours after emergence. The eggs are laid chiefly on the contiguous surfaces of 2 pine needles, but also elsewhere on the needles and their sheaths. The hatching period of the eggs of this brood is about 6 to 9 days. The period of larval development of the second brood extends from early Julv to early September, tho most of the larvae have matured and left their burrows by middle August. A very few pupate in the larval burrow, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulleti^ 40 but the vast majority when mature crawl out of their burrow and drop to the ground, where they construct silken cocoons for wintering, and probably winter in the pupa stage. If the first brood of larvae is eliminated, or practically so, dn a given clump of trees, by pruning and destroying the tips containing them,, an influx of moths of the second generation from infested trees 'elsewhere will replenish the infestation by the second brood of larvae to the normal amount. Up to the close of 1912 the pine tipmoth larvae were known to be parasitized by 2 ichneumons, 1 braconid, 4 chalcids, and 1 tachinid parasite, and the eggs of the moth by a minute chalcid parasite. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">" The Pine Tipmoth in the Nebraska National Forest . M. H. SWENK&gt; The introduction of the destructive European pine-shoot moth (Rhyacionia buoliana Schiffermiiller) into the eastern United States about 15 years ago, as fully recorded by Mr. August Busck (12 and 14) shortly thereafter, and the subse - quent prohibition of the. importation of all pines into the United States from Europe after July 1, 1915, under the pro - visions of Federal Quarantine No, 20, has drawn the atten - tion of entomologists very pointedly to the entire, group of injurious pine-boring moth larvae belonging to the Tortricid genus Rhyacionia; and its allies. For, in addition to this re - cently imported species, there are at least 8 indigenous ones (21) occurring in various parts of the United States, prob - ably the most important of which is the one commonly known as the pine tipmoth {Rhyacionia frvstrana Comstock). In Nebraska, the ravages of the pine tipmoth have been increasingly severe, during the past 17 years, among the pine plantations in the Dismal River and Niobrara Divisions of the Nebraska National Forest. As a result of its injurious activities the solution of the most important problem in hand there, namely the determination of the feasibility of attempting forestation in the Nebraska sand - hills and the best methods of accomplishing this end, has been given a material retardation and some otherwise very promis - ing prospects have been seriously vitiated. PREVIOUS HISTORY AND DISTRIBUTION OF THE INSECT References to the pine tipmoth in the entomological litera - ture published prior to its discovery in the Nebraska National •Forest in 1909 are neither numerous nor extensive. On August 26, 1879, Mr. S. H. Scudder (1) gave a short account of the injuries of the insect on Nantucket Island before the entomological club of the A. A. A. S., which was reported in the Canadian Entomologist the following month, but without 1 The writer of this bulletin wishes to acknowledge his great indebtedness to Hr. John T. Zimmer, formerly' an assistant entomologist in the Station, for his painstaking field studies on the life history of the pine tipmoth, carried out on the Dismal River Division of the Nebraska National Forest in 1911 (June 7-10: August 21-September 3 and September 20-24) and 1912 (May IB-June 28 and July 6-September 10). and also to Mr. Roy G. Pierce, formerly Deputy Forest Supervisor of the Nebraska National Forest, for his valuable field observations made in 1910-1912, and to his predecessor, Mr. William H. Mast, for similar observations made in 1909. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 descriptive matter of any sort concerning it. Professor J. H. Comstock (2) in 1880 recorded this species under the name "The Frustrating Retinia (Retinia frustrana Scudder MSS.)" as greatly injuring the scrub pines (Pinus inops) in Virginia, near Washington, D. C, about the middle of May, 1879. Specimens of the reared moths had been sent to Professor Fernald, the Tortricid specialist, who determined them as identical with the species discussed by Mr. Scudder, who had given it the manuscript name Retinia frustrana. Mr. Scudder (3) gave a final report on the insect in 1883 in a 20-page pamphlet entitled "The Pine Moth of Nantucket— Retinia frustrana." In this report he described a severe outbreak of the insect on Nantucket Island in 1876, when it was found to have killed nearly every new shoot on the trees examined. A.s Professor Comstock's description and figures antedate Mr. Scudder's description at least a couple of yearB, and as the description and figure were his and not Scudder's, Com - stock must be regarded as the authority for the name Rhyacionia (=Retinia) frustrana. In 1890 Dr. A. S. Packard (4) quoted both Comstock and Scudder fully, but added no new information about the insect. In 1891 Miss Mary Treat (5) recorded R. frustrana as destructive to hard pines at Vineland, New Jersey. In 1903 and again in 1906 Dr. E. P. Felt (7 and 8) discussed the insect and recorded it from New York State, also quoting Dr. A. D. Hopkins to the effect that the species Was very common at Allegheny Front, Mineral County, West Virginia. Then in 1909 and 1910 the writer (9 and 10) arid Messrs. Bates and Pierce (11) drew attention to the ravages of the pest in the Nebraska National Forest. The early references to the pine tipmoth, and even some of the more recent ones, e.g., Mattoon (16), place it in the genus Retinia Guenee, 1845. In 1902, however, under the impres - sion that this insect and its close relatives were properly to be placed in the genus Evetria Hubner, 1826, which name of course had many years' priority over Retinia Guenee, Fernald (6) placed them in the genus Evetria. For the next 20 years, and in some cases even longer, e.g., Felt (23), they were commonly referred to that genus. Barnes and McDun - nough (17) followed Fernald in their Check List of 1917, but in 1923 Heinrich (21) showed that the type of Evetria was not related to any of the other species that had been cited as Evetria, but was congeneric with Epinotia similana Hubner. Evetria, Hubner thus falling into synonymy under Epinotia, the name Rhyacionia Hubner is the next available </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska generic name for the European pine-shoot moth and its rela - tives, including the subject of the present bulletin, and is now being currently referred to under that name. Cf . Forbes (22), Howard (24), and Essig (25). In 1914 Busck (13) described the insect treated in this bulletin as a new species — Evetria bushnelli^-irom specimens collected by Mr. G. E. Bushnell at Fort Bayard, New Mexico, but stated that it was the same species as had been excessively injurious to the pine plantations on the Nebraska National Forest near Halsey, as described by the writer in 1910 (10). Busck stated that bushnelli was very close to the eastern frustrana Comstock, "but averages considerably larger and differs in the details of ornamentation." He also gave some facts regarding the biology of the insect in New Mexico, on the basis of information furnished him by Mr. Bushnell, including the statements that the larvae worked in the terminal twigs of western yellow pines and other pines, to which trees they appeared to be severely injurious, and that "the moths from overwintering pupae produce an early sum - mer generation, the adults of which issue about July first." In 1915 Rohwer (15) described Scambus evetrivorus n. sp. from specimens reared from material of bushnelli from the type locality (Fort Bayard, N. M.) on September 7, 1913, by Carl Heinrich. Similarly in 1917 Cushman (18) described Cremastus evetriae n. sp. from specimens reared from bush - nelli material from the same locality on January 25, 1914, by Carl Heinrich. In 1919 PearSon (19) referred to the severe injury of "Evetra" bushnelli and E. "neo-mexicana" to western yellow pine in New Mexico and Arizona. In 1923 Heinrich (21) wrote bushnelli as a race of Rhyacionia frustrana, for which he offered the following seemingly adequate explanation: "Busck described this as a separate western species distinct from the eastern frustrana. After several years' rearings of both forms, during which I have succeeded in producing a typical bushnelli artificially by inducing our smaller native frustrana to oviposit on western yellow pine (P. ponderosa) and rearing thru on that tree, and after comparison of the genitalia of several specimens, I am convinced that it is nothing more than a local food plant race. There are, in fact, no consistent characters upon which to separate the two. On account of its great economic im - portance in the section of the West where it occurs, I am retaining Busck's name as a racial designation. I have seen it in the West, only in places where reforestation has been undertaken, and in such places its origin can be traced to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 trees introduced from eastern nurseries. At Halsey, Ne - braska, the infestation is especially severe, nearly every bud of nearly every pine tree containing one or more larvae." In regarding bushnelli as a race of frustrana, Heinrich has been followed by Forbes (22) and Essig (25). The distribution of the two forms, as published in the literature, is as follows : Rhyacionia frustrana frustrana (Comstock) — Massa - chusetts (1, 3, 4, 21, and 22), New York (2, 4, 7, 8, 21, and 22) , Pennsylvania (21), New Jersey (5, 20, and 21), Virginia (2 and 21), West Virginia (8 and 21), District of Columbia (21), South Carolina (21), Georgia (21). Florida (21 and 22), Alabama (21), and Texas (21 and 22). Rhyacionia frustrana bushnelli (Busck) — Nebraska (9, 10 11, 13, 21, 24, and 25), New Mexico (13, 15, 18, 19 21, and 25), and Arizona (19, 21, and 25). HISTORY OF THE NEBRASKA INFESTATION The attack of the pine tipmoth on the pines of the planta - tions of the Nebraska National Forest was first noticed on June 30, 1909, by Mr. William H. Mast, then the Forest Super - visor located at the Nebraska National Forest. The attack seemed to develop quite suddenly, the excessive exudations of resin and the rapidly browning needles of the new shoots becoming sufficiently conspicuous to attract attention, with the resulting examination and inquiry. The affected trees were the largest and oldest ones present, having been planted in 1903. and were mostly located on the east slope of a hill just south of the buildings on the Reserve, within the planta - tion known as Nursery 80. These trees were mostly jack pines (Pinus Banksiana), the largest of them standing from 6 to 8 feet high, while scattered about among them were numerous much smaller Scotch pines (Pinus syliiestris). Some of the larger jack pines had as many as a hundred tips attacked. The attention of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station was first called to the condition of these pines when specimens of both jack and Scotch pine twigs showing tip - moth injury were received from Mr. Mast on July 7, 1909. The Department of Entomology of the Station at once wrote Mr Mast, acknowledging the receipt of the injured pine tips and inquiring concerning the situation. Mr. Mast's reply of July 9 contained substantially the information given in the pre - ceding paragraph. The matter seemed worthy of further in - vestigation, and accordingly the writer started for Halsey on </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska July 10, and began on July 12 the series of investigations that enabled the securing of the body of information concerning the pine tipmoth that is incorporated in this bulletin. The infestation on July 12, 1909, seemed to be confined to Nursery 80. While it is true that neither Mr. Mast nor the writer made a careful examination of the other plantations, from the observations reported by the men employed at the reserve, and who were familiar with the outlying plantations, it is believed that the latter were not attacked by the tipmoth at that time. Within Nursery 80 the jack pines and the Scotch pines seemed to be about equally affected. Mr. Mast and the writer estimated that about 35 per cent of the new tips on the trees in Nursery 80 were affected, and practically all of these had their needles dead and brown and rapidly dropping off. No further increase in injury was noted after July 15, in 1909. In 1910, Mr. Roy G. Pierce became Acting Forest Super - visor at the Nebraska National Forest, with headquarters near Halsey, and actively interested himself in the study of this destructive insect. Convinced that the tipmoth should be kept under close observation, the Department of Ento - mology of the Nebraska Experiment Station kept in contact with Mr. Pierce on the situation all thru 1910, thru correspondence and personal conferences. During that year the injuries noted in 1909 were repeated with even greater severity, and attacks by two distinct broods of tipmoth larvae were involved. The net result of the attacks during 1909 and 1910 was the loss of from 7 to 10 inches of growth in the terminal and lateral jack pine shoots. As the leaders of the jack pines were killed back many laterals shot out to take their place, resulting in a crooked and scrubby growth of the tree, or the formation of a "witches' broom," and a consequent loss of most of the height growth for the two years. In 1910, in conjunction with the tipmoth attack, the cones on the jack pines of Nursery 80, tho very numerous, failed to mature, but shrank in size as autumn approached. Probably this was due to the vitality of the trees being drawn upon too heavily in replacing the dead shoots to enable the production of good seed. On June 16, 1910, Mr. Pierce discovered that the young western yellow pines (Pinus ponderosa scopulorum) in the more outlying plantation adjacent to and just south of Nursery 80 had become infested, larvae being found in 10 trees, varying from 1 to 3 feet in height, out of 100 or more trees examined. This infestation on the western yellow pines, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 however, was not nearly so heavy as on the jack pines in Nursery 80, near the Reserve buildings, and it was evident that the western yellow pine plantation had become infested thru the natural spread of moths originating in the pines of Nursery 80. Mr. Pierce found that on June 16 nearly every jack pine in Nursery 80 that was 3 feet or over in height had from 1 to 10 of its growing tips infested with the larvae of the first generation. The later attack of the larvae of the second generation was also quite general. The tipmoth infestation of 1910 was at first estimated by Mr. Pierce to have increased from the 35 per cent of 1909 to from 50 per cent to 75 per cent of the tips on the jack pines in Nursery 80, and even this estimate was later increased by him to from 60 per cent to 80 per cent. The larger western yellow pines in the outlying plantations were estimated to have from 10 per cent to 20 per cent of the tips attacked by the tipmoth. About 10 per cent of the large transplants were infested and a small per cent of the seedlings. At a conference between the Department of Entomology and Mr. Pierce in September, 1910, the latter formally re - quested the Agricultural Experiment Station to take up the study of the pine tipmoth as a definite project, but lack of available funds prevented that being done at the time. Never - theless, the writer again visited the nursery plantations at Halsey on October 27 and 28, 1910, and made a thoro survey of the situation. In Nursery 80 there was every evidence of a great abundance of tipmoth larvae, during 1910, and the dead tips were not only more abundant but were more gen - erally distributed than they were on the writer's previous visit on July 11 and 12, 1909. The writer determined that Mr. Pierce's estimate of an infestation of 50 per cent of the jack pine tips in Nursery 80 was quite conservative. Some of the trees had nearly every tip showing more or less injury. The infestation on the outlying plantations was also serious. A report of the infestation at that time was made by the writer (10) in the Forestry Quarterly for December, 1910. On May 8, 1911, Mr. Smith Riley, the District Forester, with headquarters at Denver, in a letter to Acting Supervisor Pierce at Halsey, requested that the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station take up energetically the investigation of the pine tipmoth in the Nebraska National Forest. This request being presented to the Department by Mr. Pierce later in the month resulted in the presentation of the problem to the Experiment Station Council as a proposed Station project. The project was approved on May 31, 1911, and </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska the expenses of the investigations of 1911 and 1912 that are reported upon in this bulletin were borne by the Adams Fund of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. In 1911, the evidences of injury by the pine tipmoth were to be found in all of the plantations of the Dismal River Division of the Nebraska National Forest, even the most out - lying clumps of trees showing evidences of attack. Not only that, but in the middle of September (14th) of that year Mr. Pierce found that the western yellow pines on the Niobrara Division of the Forest, which lies between the Niobrara and Snake Rivers, were also attacked by the pine tipmoth, es - pecially the younger trees. When the first attack was ob - served in the Dismal River Division, late in May and early in June, the leaders of the jack pines had made a growth of from 8 to 14 inches, the growth of the other species being less. Mr. Pierce made an examination of the attack in Nursery 80 on June 8, selecting 3 typical scattered jack pine trees and counting and dissecting all of their tips just as they came. The 60, 25, and 20 tips examined on these 3 trees harbored, respectively, 7, 9, and 11 larvae, or a total of 27 larvae on 105 tips, indicating an average infestation of 26 per cent by the first brood of larvae. This infestation was not greatly less than the infestation by the first brood of 1909 (estimated at 35 per cent) , but was decidedly less than the infestation by the first brood of 1910 (estimated at 50 per cent or more), in the same plantation. In 1911 the seedling beds were heavily invaded, and an effort was made to keep the pest out of that part of the nursery by immediately picking off the attacked portions. Jack, western yellow, and Scotch pine trees as small as 4 inches high were observed by Mr. Pierce to be infested on July 9. But, on the whole, the terminal shoots were not killed back as far in 1911 as they were in 1910, by either the first or second brood of larvae, the burrows extending down 3 inches or less following both broods, 1 even on the jack pines, while in 1910 both broods had frequently killed the terminal back from 7 to 10 inches. In brief, the trees made a better growth, in the face of tipmoth attack, in 1911 than they had done in 1910. It seemed in 1910 that the jack pine was the only species that recovered from the attack of the pine tipmoth to the extent of sending out a new growth during the same season. However, in 1911 Mr. Pierce found that the western yellow pines were also sending out new buds from just below the end of the larval burrow, and that the Scotch pines were 1 Ten burrows, taken at random from dillcrent plantations on August 23, 1911, by Mr. Zimmer, measured from 10 to 76 mm. in length. All except one (which had two) had a single larval occupant, these larvae measuring from 4 to 11 mm. in length. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">________&amp;_____. - ' _$__ ____ ■ P_.l^_________________B_________B_________M:i -h__ii i „ ■ " ' !_____ * * •__."" ' S__________P___M-_! -^ " -^yj&gt;PHytf-. yr^-w iL: " - ■ - IA ______ Br ' ' ■' "^_^_a aH Fig. 1.— General view of the headquarters buildings of the Nebraska National Forest near Halsey, as they were in 1912. Note the seed beds in the right foreground, the Middle Loup River in the distance at the right, and the jack and Scotch pines of Nursery 80 on the hill slope at the left. (Photo by R. J. Pool, 1912.) .'.■-■ . • " ■ '. ' ■■-.-: ' ..•■':' ■ : "■ ■ ■ _U ,tffiTw___y^*tt^i_f V '7l h'r , ff^^^M ________ ."4^41 "''''' ■ *'■ A-"/^ EMHii___T*^''^M^a_M R-.*^ ."'jy^V :\__ &gt; "'^*' ff^-^*^fcnHm^^!T.ir^BI _____p_-^r^-?_3 ______ *•» v -^» ' *.'Ji .- __&amp; ' ' _B &amp;Ct?cffm2&amp;3!s^^L^s^L\_K*^*^&amp;^'r^B^ &gt;B FlG Vh_;"^! 1 K a ,_ t t ti0 M ?• y °r_F jaek . an d , Scotch P ine in the sandhills of the Nebraska National Forest, back from the river valley, they were ,n 1912 Note the covering of bunch-grass between the grow* ing trees. (Photo by R. J. Pool, 1912.) </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska doing the same thing. In all three species these buds con - tinued to grow and take the place of the destroyed leader. In .1912, up to the time of the appearance of the first moths on May 7, the jack pines had made a growth of from 5 to 9 inches, the Scotch pines of from 1 to 4 inches, and the western yellow pines of from 1 to 2 inches.. On June 15, of 3,144 growing tips of 9 jack pine trees from 2 to 7*_&gt; feet in height, 283, or 7 per cent, of the tips were infested with tipmoth larvae. But on the western yellow pine on the preceding day, of 334 growing tips on 9 trees from 2 to 6 feet high, 104, or 31.1 per cent, of the tips were infested. It is thus evident that in 1912 the burden of the attack was shifted from the jack pines, which had been the most attacked in 1909-1911, to the western yellow pines, which had become increasingly affected during 1910 and 1911. This shifting was probably due in part to the more favorable conditions presented by the relatively short western yellow pine tips as compared to the mostly quite long jack pine tips, as is discussed in a para - graph farther on. . introduction of the insect It is, of course, quite certain that the pine tipmoth was Introduced in some way into the Dismal River Division of the Nebraska National Forest, where it was first discovered in 1909, since there were no pine trees in that region prior to the establishment of the Dismal River Forest Reserve, as it was then called, in 1902. That introduction must have taken place sometime between the starting of the growing of jack and western yellow pines from seed, in the fall of 1902, followed immediately by the planting of forest-pulled jack and yellow pine seedlings, in the spring of 1903, in the plan - tations along the Middle Loup that later came to be called the Bessey Nursery, and the discovery of the pest 7 years later, in the jack and Scotch pines of Nursery 80. But just when and how it took place has never been definitely ascertained. As to the manner of introduction, two possible theories are tenable: (1) That it flew, or was carried by winds, from the growth of western yellow pines native to northwestern Ne - braska, the nearest ones of which occur along the Niobrara River some 50 miles to the north, or (2) that it was im - ported on young trees as they were originally brought in, and multiplied and spread from these introduced trees. According to Bates and Pierce (11) insects similar to the pine tipmoth were noted in the western yellow pine forests of the Pine Ridge as early as 1901. The species was certainly present in the Pine Ridge near Crawford in June', 1910, for </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebr Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 Professor L. Bruner and the writer saw several of them among the native western yellow pines there at that time, and cap - tured one to make the identification certain. But just how far to the eastward, along the Niobrara River, the pine tip - moth had followed the western yellow pine during those years is not known. The first indication of an infestation in the Niobrara Division of the Nebraska National Forest was dis - covered in 1911, 3 years after the pest had become noticed in the Dismal River Division, and after it had begun to spread. It is mentioned more as a possibility, rather than a prob - ability, that these sedentary moths should have flown or been carried to the young pine plantations across the 50 miles of sandhills lying between them and the native pines. Decidedly more feasible is the theory that the pest was introduced on young trees. In the spring of 1903 some 70,000 forest-pulled seedling jack pine trees from 2 to 5 years old from Minnesota, and some. 30,000 forest-pulled western yellow pine seedlings from the Black Hills, were planted. Either of the§e plantings might have brought in the pest, but the Min - nesota jack pines are particularly open to suspicion because (1) three years later (in 1906) about 15 or 20 per cent of the jack pines had survived while all of the western yellow pines had died, and (2) the infestation was discovered in 1909 in the jack pine plantation. Other pines are said to have been imported from Wisconsin, Michigan, and New York. The Scotch pines were first started from imported stock in 1907, and from locally grown stock in 1908 and 1909, so very probably the infestation of this species that was found in 1909 was derived from the jack pines. Austrian pine (Pinus nigra) and Norway pine (Pinus resinosa) trees were not brought in until 1909, and so can scarcely have had any role in the introduction of the pest. MANNER OF ATTACK AND INJURY Attack by the pine tipmoth is chiefly concerned with young and rapidly growing pine trees. Immediately upon hatching, the young larvae usually enter the base of an adjacent needle or needle cluster, in which they burrow and feed for a time before moving on to the terminal bud of the shoot. This is especially the case when the larvae are attacking western yellow or jack pines. On Scotch pines they usually attack the terminal buds very soon after hatching. On reaching the terminal bud the larva constructs a small, transparent, resinous cell, usually on the outside of the tip, within which it feeds for a time before beginning its longitudinal burrow. Occasionally the excavation starts in the lower part of the </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska terminal bud, or below it, instead of at its tip. Of 27 infested tips examined by the writer on June 8, 1911, the injury had involved the terminal bud first in 24 of them, or 89 per cent of the whole. The burrow in the bud is at first of tiny bore and very short. Usually it is on one side, probably where the larva has entered the bud. When the larvae have reached a length of 4 or 5 mm., and their burrows are of about the same length, they begin to enlarge the burrow and eat out the bud. By the time they are about 7 or 8 mm. long the entire interior of the terminal bud has been consumed, and they have started bur - rowing downward in the shoot. When the bud is hollowed out and the shoot is entered, there begins a very profuse accumulation of resinous matter. When they have attained full size (9 to 12 mm. long) , the larvae have excavated a burrow in the young and succulent shoot of a length varying anywhere from 7 or 8 mm. to as long as 40 or 50 mm. The exact length of the burrow depends largely upon the kind of pine shoot in which the larva is burrowing — tending to be longest in the western yellow pine, nearly as long in the jack pine, and shortest in the Scotch pine — and upon the number of larvae working in an individual shoot, tending to be longer in the shoots harboring more than 1 or 2 larval occupants. The longest shoots may commonly harbor as many. as 5 to 7 larvae, rarely more. However, on August 6, 1912, Mr. Zim - mer found 14 larvae in a single western yellow pine shoot, while 4 days later, in a single leader of the same species, attacked by the first brood and its stools reattacked by the second brood, he found 30 larvae of various sizes. Usually the shoot is killed as far back from the tip as the burrow extends. In some cases where the burrow is made entirely oh one side of the shoot, the uninjured side continues to grow with the result that the tip bends to one side in a characteristic manner. Sometimes the original point of attack of a larva is below the terminal bud ; usually not more than an inch or two, but in some cases, especially on jack pines, 3 to 10 inches, in which event the tip curls up and becomes brown and dead. When a tip has been attacked and destroyed by the tipmoth larvae, a new shoot usually starts growing at once from buds below the injured tip. But the tips originally sent out are the ones placed so as to be the natural leaders of the main stem or side branches of the tree, and when they are attacked and largely destroyed for 2 or 3 successive seasons the tree takes on an unsymmetrical growth, with a bushy top due to the "witches' broom" branches. This prevents the formation of a straight-boled tree and thus largely destroys its value </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Fig. 3. — Pine tips attacked by pine ' tipmoth larvae; above, work in tips of jack pine; middle, work in tips of Scotch pine; below, work in jack pine when the larvae enter below the tip. (Author's illustration.) </seg>
            <seg id="p017">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska and beauty. On August 17, 1912, Mr. Zimmer examined 91 trees taken at random from the whole of the plantations on the Dismal River Division, and found that all but 6 of them had the natural leader attacked and injured. On the Nebraska National Forest most of the injury in 1909 to 1912, inclusive, was on the western yellow, jack, and Scotch pines. However, probably any species of pine would be attacked more or less by the tipmoth, for on August 22, 1911, Mr. Zimmer found what seemed to be the burrows of this pest, apparently those of the first brood of larvae, on several Black Hills Spruce trees on the Reserve grounds, indi - cating that probably Picea, as well as Pinus, may be listed with the genera of conifers subject to attack. On June 20 and 25, 1912, Mr. Zimmer measured a number (93) of typical burrows in infested tips of western yellow and jack pine, to determine the exact depth to which the larval burrows, extended and also to ascertain if there was any cor - relation between the depth and the number of occupants of the burrow. The results of this study may be expressed in the following table, the length of the larval burrow being given in millimeters. From the following data it is obvious that the pine tipmoth attacks the Western yello\# pine shoots the more heavily, and extends its burrows more deeply in them, on the average, than in the jack pine shoots, and also that the burrow tends to be longer in those shoots harboring the larger numbers of larvae: </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 Western yellow pine Jack pine • i il ._. . s. » n Date _N _g |i Date 3|| - :E *s|l 3JI Is J T une 20 8,1 || j une 20 | 7 ~~T~ June 20 10 1 I j une 25 9 1 June 20 111 June 20 I 10 1 June 20 11 | 3 I June 20 I 10 1 June 20 12 1 J une 20 : 10 1 June 20 1)1 June 25 10 I 1 June 20 14 1 June 20 n 1 June 20 14 1 June 20 12 I 1 June 20 11 1 June 20 12 1 June 25 15 1 June 20 12 1 June 20 15 2 June 25 12 _ June 25 15 2 June 25 , 12 _ June 20 If, 1 J une , 25 12 1 June 25 16 1 June 20 13 1 June 25 16 2 i June 25 I 13 1 June 20 10 3 \ June 25 I 13 ! ] June 20 16 fi J une 25 I 13 | 1 June 20 17 1 June 20 14 1 June 20 IT 1 June 25 14 | _ June 20 17 2 June 25 14 I 1 June 20 18 1 June 25 14 j June 20 18 2 June 20 IS 1 June 25 18 2 June 25 "| 15 j j June 20 19 1 June 25 I 15 1 June 25 19 1 June 25 I 15 1 June 20 20 ( 1 , June 20 15 2 June 25 20 1 June 25 15 i 2 June 20 20 2 June 20 1 ( ; 1 June 20 20 2 June 25 " ifi 1 June 25 20 2 I June 25 16 1 June 25 20 2 j June 25. 10 , June 25 20 ! 3 | June 25 , 1G 1 June 25 ... 21 4 1 June 25 17 1 June 20 I 22 2 , June 20 18 1 June 25 22 2 II June 25 20 1 June 20 22 3 1! June 20 | 20 " June 20 23 3 June 20 22 1 June 20 | 21 5 June 25 24 1 June 25 25 3 1 June 25 25 2 June 25 25 3 j Juno 25 "| 26 1 June 25 26 I 2 June 25 .... 26 2 June 25 28 3 jj June 25 27 3 June 25 29 6 ll June 25 28 5 June 25 30 3 ! June 25 ; 30 q June 20 30 1 7 June 20 i^o 1 June 25 32 5 j June 25 1 34 3 / June 20 ... 41 5 I . Average 19.9 2.3; Average | 14.4 us </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska _____ _\ "3k *' m n Kb qk »4i &gt;. J _____■_^*3&amp; t _Wij~T_f P___r ' _BI _____F * &gt; ii fi *V 'S_F Fig. '4. — Pine tip opened to show character of burrowings of the pine tipmoth larvae. (Original.) </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 _\ -&gt;M¥ hjd \\ brood ■ '' ■ ____r ' ' m I BI l____r » v&gt; J I mm. \W W ____ ui m *,V ___v IV. _■ flf a Mf v v _____r-__ ■ elm a ft v Bi p/ % s k*s___t jf Fig. 5. — Large leader of jack pine heavily attacked by pine tipmoth larvae of both broods. (Original.) </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska seasonal history NUMBER OF ANNUAL GENERATIONS The pine tipmoth has two complete, but overlapping, generations a year in the Nebraska National Forest. The overlapping of the two generations occurs mostly in late June and July. For example, on June 25, 1911, Mr. Pierce found larvae of the first brood, pupae of the first brood, and moths of the second brood on the trees at the same time. Again, on July 17, 1912, Mr. Zimmer found larvae of the first brood, pupae of the first brood, moths of the second brood, eggs of the second brood, and larvae of the second brood, all at the same time. The periods of activity of the two broods of moths and the egg period of the two broods are, however, quite dis - tinct. SEASON OF FLIGHT OF THE FIRST BROOD OF MOTHS The first obvious evidence of seasonal activity by the pine tipmoth in the spring is when the adults or moths emerge. The insect has passed the winter, very probably chiefly or entirely as pupae, in silken cocoons that were spun upon or just beneath the surface of the ground by the mature larvae of the second brood of the preceding year. When the trans - formation to the moth stage is completed, these escape from the cocoons thru a rounded emergence hole which they make at one end of the cocoon, and may later be observed flying about among the trees on warm, still days, especially in the evening. ' In 1911, the first moths of the season were observed on May 8 by Mr. Pierce, who collected several of them on that day in the jack pines in the hills. They were still very numerous on May 24 in Nursery 80, according to Mr. Pierce, but none were seen after May 27. In 1912, Mr. Pierce observed the first moths on the evening of May 7, when as many as 25 or 30 of them were seen upon a single jack pine tree 4 feet in height. Mr. Zimmer found them gradually diminishing in numbers from May 16 to 24, 1912, and he did not find any moths of the spring brood that year after the latter date, except for a single moth seen flying on June 1. The spring brood is evi - dently active, therefore, chiefly during early and middle May. THE DEPOSITING AND HATCHING OF THE EGGS OF THE FIRST BROOD The egg of the pine tipmoth was first discovered by the writer on June 29, 1910, when moths of the second brood that had emerged in rearing cages laid their eggs during the night by the hundreds on the pine needles in the cage, and </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 also on its glass walls. The eggs were tiny objects, round in outline, flat in form, and pale yellowish in color. They were first discovered in the field by Mr. Zimmer, who on June 3, 1912, found them placed, usually singly but occasionally in very small groups, on the outside of the terminal leaf bud scales, before the latter burst and the young needles com - menced to grow. Some eggs had hatched on that date, and only the white shell, with an irregular opening thru which the larva had emerged, remained. One was found that con - tained an unhatched larva, curled up and perfectly visible thru the pale, transparent shell of the egg. In addition to the normal, pale, yellowish eggs, some were found that were black and opaque, due to the parasitism of the egg by a very minute species of HymenopterouS egg parasite that will be ... ~'-k FlC. 6. — Adult moth of Rhyacionia frustrana bushnelli, at left above; eggs of same as laid on the glass of a rearing cage, at right above; parasitized eggs of same as laid on pine needles, at right below; injury by young larvae of the pine tipmoth in base of needle cluster, at left below. (Original.) </seg>
            <seg id="p023">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska more fully discussed on a following page. Eggs were dif - ficult to find in the field, especially on the jack pines with their extensive growth, of new tips providing many suitable places for oviposition. The length of the incubation period of the eggs of the first or spring generation of the pine tipmoth was not exactly determined. The egg with the visible unhatched larva, found on June 3, hatched on the following day. An egg collected June 4, 1912, which did not seem to be much incubated, hatched on June 10. This gives at least 6 days for the incuba - tion period of the eggs of this brood, but the total incubation period may well be considerably more, since it was not known how long the egg had been laid when it was discovered. LARVAL DEVELOPMENT OF THE FIRST BROOD The newly hatched larva, as Mr. Zimmer discovered on June 4 to 10, 1912, is of a pale yellowish color, with a black head, and measures 1 to 1.5 mm. in. length. It does not change materially in color during growth, but immediately following a molt the head is pale for a time, soon, however, resuming the black coloration. The number of larval instars was not determined in these Studies. The fully grown larva measures from 9 to 12 mm. in length. The larva is active at all stages, and when it is disturbed by breaking open its burrow it rapidly crawls out, often spinning a thread and dropping like other Tortricid larvae. In 1911, the first young larvae of the season were found by Mr. Pierce on May 24, on some Scotch pine tips. In 1912, Messrs. Pierce and Zimmer found the first young larvae of the season on June 1, working rather commonly on the tips of western yellow pine, less commonly on Scotch pine tips, anu rather sparingly on jack pine^ tips. In both years the presence of the larva on an infested tip was made apparent because of a small, transparent, resinous cell that it had constructed on the outside of the terminal bud, and within which it fed for a time. In some cases the larvae had burrowed into the side of the tips, altho none of these burrows were extended at all longitudinally. These larvae were about 3 mm. long, in the case of those found on May 24, 1911, and 5 or 6 mm. long in the case of those found on June 1, 1912 — therefore in neither case newly hatched larvae. The larvae found on June 1 were obviously in at least the second instar of development, for Mr. Zimmer in two cases found shed larval skins within the cell. As a result of field observations made June 1 to 5, 1912, Mr. Zimmer concluded that, immediately upon hatching, many </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 of the young larvae enter the base of some nearby needle, or needle cluster, and burrow and feed there for some time be - fore continuing their wandering upward to the terminal buds. Larvae which he found on the tips on June 3 varied from 2 5 to 5.5 mm. in length, and all of them, both small and large, whether the burrow on the exterior of the tip was short or long, had been burrowing in the sheath of a nearby needle. If the larva had reached the tip it had begun to burrow there! On June 5, of 38 larvae collected at random, 32 had their burrows in the needles or on the outside of the tips, while only 6 had started burrows in the terminal bud itself. All of these tips examined by Mr. Zimmer had a single larval occu - pant except that two had 2 larvae and two had 3 of them. Later studies, made on June 7 to 15, 191.2, showed that the length of time the larvae will work in the needles is largely dependent upon the species of pine they are attacking. On the Scotch pines, while the young larvae usually preferred to start their feeding by burrowing in the needles, they soon deserted these for the terminal buds. Of 18 larvae collected at random from Scotch pines on June 12, all but one were working in the terminal buds, and that one was on the out - side of a terminal shoot, tho it had formed no burrow These larvae varied from 3 to 10 mm. in length, their re - spective lengths being 3 mm., 1 ; 3.5 mm., 1 ; 4 mm., 3 ; 4.5 mm 1 ; 5 mm., 7 ; 6 mm., 1 ; 7 mm., 2 ; 8.5 mm., 1 ; and 10 mm., 1. ' On the jack pines, on June 7, Mr. Zimmer found that the larvae were still mostly in the needles, altho a few had reached the terminal buds. On June 11 he found a hatched egg of the tipmoth about three-quarters of an inch from the base of a jack pine shoot 4V_ inches long, the larva from which on hatching, had obviously burrowed into and hollowed out a nearby needle and then moved to the tip, altho not as yet to the terminal bud. On the date of its discovery it was 3 ??• on g * x? f 42 larva . e collected from Jack pines on that date, 30 of them were either burrowing in the needles or in the covered resinous burrows on the outside ot the terminal shoot, while only 12 had started to burrow in the tip These 12 varied from 3 to 8 mm. in length, their respective lengths be,ng3 mm 1; 3.5 mm., 1; 4 mm., 2; 5mm., 4; 5.5 mm., 2; and 6 mm. and 8 mm., 1 each. By June 15, of 51 larvae collected from jack pines on that date, 31 were either burrowing in the needles or were on the outside of the shoots, while 20 were burrowing in the terminal buds. The first lot measured as follows: 4 mm., 3- 4.5 mm., 2; 5 mm., 14; 6 mm., 9; and 6 5 mm., 3. The second lot averaged much larger, measuring as </seg>
            <seg id="p025">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska follows: 5 mm., 5; 6 mm., 2; 7 mm., 4; 8 mm., 2; 9 mm., 3; and 10 mm., 4. Evidently the larvae enter the terminal buds on the jack pine chiefly when about 5 to 7 mm. long. On the western yellow pines, as on the jack pines, there is even more disinclination of the larvae to desert the needles early. Moreover, they are inclined to burrow more in the bases of the needles, or where the cluster of young growing needles is bound together. Of 57 larvae collected from western yellow pines on June 14, 47 were either burrowing in the needles or were on the outside of the shoots, while 10 had started burrowing in the terminal buds. The first lot meas - ured as follows: 4 mm., 3; 4.5 mm., 1; 5 mm., 21; 6 mm., 11; 6.5 mm., 1; 7 mm., 6; 7.5 mm., 1; 8 mm., 2; and 8.5 mm., 1. The second lot averaged much larger, measuring as follows: 5.5 mm., 6 mm., and 6.5 mm., 1 each; 7 mm. and 8 mm., 2 each; and 9 mm., 3. The larvae evidently enter the terminal buds on the western yellow pine chiefly when they reach a length of 7 or 8 mm. On June 2, 1912, Mr. Zimmer carefully compared the varying manner of attack of the larvae on the tips of the dif - ferent species of pines. The growing tips of the different species vary considerably in length at that time of the year. The slower-growing western yellow and Scotch pines, which often bear the heavier part of the tipmoth attack early in the season, have grown but little in comparison with the more rapidly growing jack pines, some tips of which may have reached a length of 2 feet by early June. The larvae that were found on the jack pines were on the shorter tips, and, as short tips were fewer on the jack pines than on either the western yellow or Scotch pines, the percentage of infested jack pine tips was less than in the case of the other species. On Scotch pine trees a foot and a half in height, with growing tips from 41/2 to 5 inches long, the larvae were located from 1/2 to % of an inch from the terminal bud; on western yellow pine trees 2 feet in height, with growing tips from 2 to 5V_ inches long, the larvae were located either at the terminal bud or not over an inch from it; while on jack pine trees 2V_ feet in height, on growing tips not over 4 inches long, the larvae were located either at the terminal bud or not over a half inch away from it. However, on longer jack pine tips the larvae would.be found working farther from the tip; for example, on June 7, Mr. Zimmer found two cases where the larvae made their entrance an inch and a half from the tip, another where the entrance was -2 inches, another 3 inches, another 3V*&gt; inches, and a sixth where it was 5 inches, from the tip. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 In 1911, on June 5, Mr. Pierce found larvae varying from 3 mm. long to nearly fully grown working in the terminal and adjacent buds, but as yet not burrowing down in the tip. On June 8, Mr. Zimmer and the writer found larvae of various sizes in the pine tips. Of 29 larvae collected at random and measured on that day, it was found that 2 were 4 mm., 8 were 5 to 5.5 mm., 2 were 6 mm., 5 were 7 to 7.5 mm., 6 were 8 mm., 3 were 9 mm., and 3 were 10 mm., long; and as' the larvae are fully grown when from 9 to 12 mm. long, they may be said to have been at that date from about one-third grown to fully grown. In 1912, Mr. Zimmer made several such larval counts, between the discovery of the first larvae on June 1 and the finding of the first pupa on June 17, which may be summarized in the following table: 1 _ j l.emrth of larvae in^millimeters b _\- | £.*', 2 ,2.5 3 3.5 4 4.5 5 5.5 6 | 6 S 7 7.5 H H.5 9 10 11 12 j _\ [ I _ _ ' _ ' 2 13 16 1 2 1 2 3 2 1 1 5 3K 4 3 4 2 ' 4 11 3 B 1 7 4 2 1 1 10 4 1111 11 42 7 7 12 1 10 3 1 1 12 IK 113 17 1 2 1 1 13 29 3 10 3 8 2 1 1 1 14 57 3 1 !1 1 12 2 » 1 4 1 3 15 51 3 2 '19 113 4 2 3 4 17 43 2 15 0 19 20 1H 22 « 1 3 It will be observed from the preceding data that the degree of larval development on June 5, 1911, corresponded fairly closely with the degree of larval development attained on June 12, 1912, and that, similarly, the larval development on June 8, 1911, paralleled that of June 15, 1912; in other words, that in 1912 larval development was about a week later than in 1911. Very probably there is even greater seasonal varia - tion. In 1909, Mr. Mast found larvae varying from 3 mm. to 9 mm. in the tips on June 30, 1 to 3 larvae to the tip, a degree of larval development corresponding well with that of June 11 and 12, 1912. This seems to indicate that larval de - velopment in 1912 was over 2 weeks earlier than in 1909, making the seasonal variation between 1909 and 1911 a dif - ference of about 3 weeks. From all available data pertaining to the years 1909, 1910, 1911, and 1912, considered in combination, the period of de - velopment of the tipmoth larvae of the first brood is found to extend from May 24 (1911) to July 22 (1912), tho of course it is not likely that this range of dates would be attained in any one calendar season. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">The- Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska PUPAL DEVELOPMENT OF THE FIRST BROOD Pupation by the first brood takes place invariably in the larval burrow in the pine shoots. In 1909, altho examina - tions by Mr. Mast revealed nothing but larvae of various sizes in the tips on June 30, by July 12 the writer found practically all of these larvae had transformed to pupae, and,, in fact; most of them to moths, for an examination of a number of tips on that date disclosed only a few untrans - formed pupae remaining in the larval burrows. In 1910, Mr. Pierce found plenty of larvae, but no pupae, in the tips on June 14, but material collected on that day and forwarded to Dr. A. D. Hopkins at Washington, D. C, contained both larvae and pupae on June 24, tho.no moths had as yet emerged. In 1911, Mr. Pierce found larvae varying from 3 mm. long to nearly fully grown on June 5, and Mr. Zimmer and the writer found larvae varying from 4 mm. long to fully grown on June 8, but no pupae on either date. On June 9, after examining many tips and finding many larvae, Mr. Pierce and the writer found a single freshly formed pupa. By June 22 pupae were quite common, Mr. Pierce finding 8 of them, along with 10 larvae that varied from one-fourth to fully grown, in 8 tips of jack pine and Scotch pine examined by him. By June 25 most of the insects had pupated, altho some larvae were also present in the tips. In 1912, despite almost daily extensive search, Mr. Zimmer did not find any pupae until June 17, 8 days later than their first appearance in 1911. This corroborates the discrepancy in larval development between the two seasons discussed in a previous paragraph. From the data given in the preceding paragraph it is evident that development in the season of 1910 was about a week later than in 1912, while in 1909 it was still later than in 1910, and at least two weeks later than in 1912. Taking 1912 as a typical year, development being later in that year than in 1911 and earlier than in 1909 or 1910, it may be noted that the 3 pupae that were found by Mr. Zimmer on June 17 were all found on a single 2-foot western yellow pine tree. Many of the larvae found that day, both in western yellow pine and jack pine, were rather contracted and inactive as if approaching pupation. The same was true in the examination of about 50 western yellow pine tips on June 18, when only 1 pupa was found, the other tips con - taining anywhere from 1 to 10 larvae. On June 20, out of 18 jack pine and 20 western yellow pine tips examined, all contained from 1 to 5 larvae except 1 western yellow pine tip that contained 2 pupae along with 4 larvae. However, by </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 June 25 pupae were common. Mr. Zimmer found on that day 28 jack pine tips containing pupae, all but 2 of them with a single pupal occupant, these exceptions each containing 2 pupae, and 27 western yellow pine tips containing 50 pupae distributed as follows: One each in 17 tips; 2 each in 5 tips; 3 each in 2 tips; 5 each in 2 tips; and 7 in 1 tip. By July 6 'there were very few larvae that had not transformed remaining in the tips, there being more of them on the jack pines than on the western yellow pines. A number of larvae collected by Mr. Zimmer on July 6 and 10 pupated on July 7, 17, 18, 20, and 21. In the tips a few first brood larvae were found July 17 and the last one on July 22. From the combined data secured in 1909, 1910, 1911, and 1912, it may be stated that pupae of the first brood may be found in the tips from June 9 (1911) to July 22 (1912). The duration of the pupal stage of the individual insect ap - parently varies from about 9 to 13 days. Mature larvae that were noted on June 12, 1911, had pupated and emerged as moths 9 days later, on June 21, and an individual larva that was observed to pupate on June 12, 1911, gave up the moth on June 24, 1911, after a pupal period of 12 days. Another individual that pupated on July 7, 1912, transformed to the moth on July 20, 13 days later. EMERGENCE OF THE MOTHS OF THE SECOND BROOD The pupae of the pine tipmoth have a very considerable power of movement within their burrows. When they are disturbed there they wriggle away with a circular, twisting motion, which, with the assistance of the abdominal spines, enables them to progress in a very efficient manner. When they are ready to give forth the moths they force themselves to the exterior opening of the burrow in the terminal buds, and then half way or more out of the opening, before the pupal skin splits and the moth emerges from it. The wings of the moth expand rapidly after emergence. Emergence seems to take place most frequently in the morning. Of 52 moths that emerged on July 8, 1912, 16 were out early in the morning and 27 more were out by noon, while only 9 emerged during the afternoon. Similarly, of 53 moths that emerged on the following day (July 9), 17 were out early in the morning and 25 more by noon, while only 11 emerged in the afternoon. In the rearing cages the moths began dying rapidly 3 days after their emergence, but probably the lease of life is longer in the field. The moths are inactive during periods of high wind. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">BV \A___ _____ v ___■(_ I ____y__M ______F ___■ ■«_: I _____*_. ______________________________ H ______H ____■ _____r________i Hfl I • vtuI \\\\\\\MM WM 1 dl U \_f______________________________________________________________fl \____i ■ ill ■I ___5-l Fio. 7.— Pine tips attacked by pine tipmoth larvae; at left tip opened to show pupa «JgJj tips showing manner of emergence of the moths. Adult moth at inset above. (Authors illus tration.) . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 SEASON OF FLIGHT OF THE SECOND BROOD OF MOTHS In 1909, the writer found that most of the moths of the second brood had emerged from the pine tips by July 12 and were to be found flying about among the pines in Nursery 80, often several of them near the tips of the branches of a single tree. The opening of a number of the infested tips revealed only a few pupae, and moths that were ready to emerge, re - maining in the larval burrows. From material gathered on that date, 28 moths emerged, as follows: July 13, 11; July 14, 2; July 15, 4; July 16, 9; July 17, 1; and July 21, 1. In 1910, Mr. Pierce collected a number of infested pine tips on June 14, from which 8 moths emerged, as follows: June 28, 1; June 29, 2; July 1, 1; July 2, 3; and July 5, 1. On July 10, Mr. Pierce found that moths had emerged from pupae that had formed a week or two earlier. In 1911, from 367 apparently infested pine tips collected by the writer on June 9, 158 moths emerged, as follows: June 21, 1; June 22, 8; June 23, 17; June 24, 24; June 25-26, 52; June 27, 14; June 28, 15; June 29, 12; June 30, 8; July 1, 6 ; and July 3, 1. On June 25, Mr. Pierce rioted the first moths of the second brood in the field. These were newly emerged, and were noted among the taller pines in Nursery 80. On this same day Mr. Pierce noted other moths in the act of emerging from the pupal skins in the terminal buds. Most of the tips contained pupae at this time, altho some larvae were also present. From jack pine tips collected in Nursery 80 on July 3 by Mr. R. W. Dawson, 62 moths emerged, as follows: July 6, 31; July 7, 12; July 8, 9; July 9, 7; July 10, 2; and July 18, 1. On July 9, Mr. Pierce found the moths fly - ing plentifully and attacking the small trees, even down to those 4 inches in height. In 1912, Mr. Zimmer noted no moths of the second brood up to his departure from the Nebraska National Forest on June 28, but on his return there July 6, he found that a large num - ber of moths had emerged during his absence and were flying among the pines. On that day he collected 205 first genera - tion pupae from the pine tips, and from these 180 moths emerged, as follows: July 7, 2; July 8, 52; July 9, 53; July 10, 15; July 11, 22; July 12, 14; July 13, 13; July 14, 7; July 15, 1; and July 17, 1. From 4 first generation pupae col - lected by Mr. Zimmer on July 17, 2 moths emerged on July 18 and 1 each on July 19 and 22. A single pupa collected July 20 gave forth the moth July 23. By July 22 Mr. Zimmer found the moths to be no longer abundant in the field. From these data it is evident that there is considerable seasonal variation in the period of flight of the second brood </seg>
            <seg id="p031">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska of moths, but that, considering together the 4 seasons on which we have data, the total period of flight extends from June 21 (1911) to July 23 (1912), with the maximum flight occurring between June 23 and July 13. THE DEPOSITING AND HATCHING OF THE EGGS OF THE SECOND BROOD The actual act of oviposition was not observed in the field during the entire progress of these studies, and that in spite of the fact that during July, 1912, when the moths of the second brood were abundant on the trees, Mr. Zimmer spent many hours watching the moths in the hope of finding one depositing an egg. Evidently the depositing of the eggs is done at night, for when the moths are placed in rearing cages with pine twigs they lay their eggs in profusion on the needles, and on the sides of the cages as well. Egg laying by the second brood of moths begins soon after emergence. Some moths that came out on June 29, 1910, and were immediately placed .in a rearing cage by the writer, deposited eggs that same night. Similarly, several newly emerged moths placed in a rearing cage along with some pine tips on July 11, 1912, by Mr. Zimmer, laid eggs on the bases of the needles, on the needle sheaths, and on the outside of the shoots that night. Several more newly emerged moths placed by him in a similar cage the following day (July 12) also laid eggs on the enclosed pine tips during the night fol - lowing. In the field, Mr. Zimmer found eggs commonly July 13 to 16, chiefly on the contiguous surfaces of two needles in - a cluster, but also on the outside of the needles, on the upper surface of the needle sheath, and elsewhere, there being no regularity in the place where the eggs were laid. None were found on the terminal bud, however. Eggs laid on June 29, 1910, hatched on the following July 5, giving an incubation period of 6 days. Five eggs laid on July 12, 1912, hatched on the following July 20, the incubation period being 8 days in this case. Five eggs laid on July 13, 1912, hatched the following July 22, after an incubation period of 9 days. Two eggs of unknown age collected on July 16 also hatched on July 22, 6 days after being collected, while 2 larvae emerged on July 25 from eggs collected July 22 and one larva emerged on July 27 from an egg collected July 25. Apparently the incubation period of the eggs of the second brood is about 6 to 9 days. LARVAL DEVELOPMENT OF THE SECOND BROOD In 1910, on July 30, Mr; Pierce found larvae of the second brood in the tips of the western yellow pine and jack pine </seg>
            <seg id="p032">nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 trees in Nursery 80. These larvae were all very small and in the judgment of Mr. Pierce were not over a week old. A later examination, made on August 4, showed that the larvae were still working in the terminal buds and had not burrowed downward very much as yet. On August 9, 104 pine tips showing dead needles were examined by Mr. Pierce, and all of them were found to be infested with larvae. But when Mr. Pierce next examined a number of injured tips, on September 4, he was unable to find either larvae or pupae in them, al - tho they looked as tho they had only recently been vacated. On October 3, Mr. Pierce examined 75 additional tips of jack and Scotch pine, finding no larvae or pupae in them. Careful examination of a number of tips sent to the writer by Mr. Pierce at the same time showed all of them to be empty, except that 1 contained a single pupa. This con - dition was so unexpected that it was decided that the writer should make a personal investigation. On October 27 and 28 he examined the tips of pines all over Nursery 80, and, after cutting open several hundreds of them with the net result of finding only 1 larva (a fully grown individual on the 27th), he came definitely to the conclusion that sometime between August 9 and September 4 there had been a general emergence of the occupants of the burrows, and that the pine tipmoth larvae of the second brood did not hibernate in their burrows in the tips in Nebraska, as they were reported by Scudder ( 1 and 3 ) to do on Nantucket Island. In 1911, on August 6 Mr. Pierce examined the jack pines in Nursery 80, and in 7 tips that he dissected he found numer - ous larvae, 4 of them in a single tip. These larvae were approaching full growth, measuring 7 to 9 mm. in length The larval burrows in which they were found varied from 63 to 100 mm. in length. Mr. Zimmer, arriving on the scene on August 21, found that by that date the larvae had largely matured and left the burrows. Eleven trees that were care - fully examined by him on that day had a total of 229 empty burrows (this including, of course, the tips burrowed by both broods of larvae) but only 24 larvae, 1 of which was dead. No pupae were found in the many burrows examined Ten occupied tips examined on different parts of the plantation on August 23 had larval burrows varying from 10 to 76 mm long, the average being 27.2 mm., and each contained but a single larva, these varying from 5 to 11 mm. long, except one that contained 2 larvae, 4 mm. and 8 mm. in length, re - spectively. Also, a larva 6 mm. long was found on the' out - side of one of the tips. Mr. Zimmer made prolonged searches for larvae and pupae in the tips on August 22, 26 and 28 with results that may be in part tabulated as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p033">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska Date Height of Total No. No. empty No. larvae No. pupae August tree in feet of tips burrows found found 28 2 13' .... 0 0 26 2.5 185 12 2' 0 28 3 26 * .... 0 0 22 3 121 19 0 0 28 3.5 22 .-.. 1* 0 28 3.5 132 24 0 0 26 3.5 342 23 l 1 0 28 4 22" .... 0 0 22 4.5 321 36 3* 0 28 5 334 55 0 0 22 5 414 71 3* 0 26 5 612 105 1' 2 28 5.5 439 73 0 0 26 7 310' 0 0 26 7- 569' .... 6' 0 26 11 331* .... 2' 0 Total 4,193 . 19 2 From this table it is at once evident that in 1911 the larval emergence from the burrows was practically completed by August 21, since out of nearly 4,200 tips examined during the following week only 19 larvae (and these mostly fully grown or nearly so) and 2 pupae were found. Moreover, in addition to the counts on the 16 trees tabulated above, Mr. Zimmer examined many tips on other trees growing out in the hills on August 22 j and on different parts of the plantation on August 23, 24, and 25, and found only a few larvae and a single pupa (on August 24) in them. On August 30 a larva 7 mm. long was found in a tip by Messrs. Zimmer and Pierce, after con - siderable searching, that being the last one found during that year. In 1912, Mr. Zimmer found the first larva of the second brood for that year on July 15, which was 15 days earlier than the first second brood larva was found by Mr. Pierce in 1910 and 22 days later than the first one was found by him in 1911. The larva found on July 15 was correspondingly small - er, only 1.75 mm. long. It was burrowing in the base of a pine needle and had already eaten a passageway 7 mm. long that resembled the trail of a leaf-miner. The following day, July 16, Mr. Zimmer found 10 additional larvae at work in the needle bases. Two each of these were 1 mm. and 1.5 mm. 1 Only the dead or dying tips counted. 1 Only a part of the tips counted and these taken at random. 3 One living larva 9 mm. long, the other one dead. * One larva 10 mm. long found in the leader. 'Larva 7 mm. long. * Size of larva not recorded. 'Larva 6 mm. long. •One larva each 7, 8. and 9 mm. long and 3 larvae 10 mm. long, respectively. ' One larva each 7 and 9 mm. long, respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 long, 4 were 2 mm. long, and 1 each was 2.5 mm. and 3 mm. long. In several instances he found the shells of the eggs from which these young larvae had evidently recently hatched. These were on the same needles as the ones in which the larvae were found working, or else on nearby needles. In one case a larva 2 mm. long was found burrowing in a needle to which it had evidently moved from an adjacent needle, in which it had previously burrowed. This latter needle was 147 mm. long, the shell of the egg from which the larva had hatched was 61 mm. from the base of the needle, and the opening of the larval burrow was 33 mm. from the base of the needle. In another instance a larva slightly over 1 mm. long was found in the act of burrowing into a needle about an inch below the empty shell from which it had recently emerged. In other cases the empty egg shell was nearer to the base of the needle than was the burrowing larva. Obvi - ously, there being no uniformity in the places where the eggs are deposited, the newly hatched larvae must migrate to a suitable place on the needle for beginning their entrance bur - row, and the direction of that migration may be either toward the base or tip of the needle, as conditions require. Other newly hatched larvae were found in needles on July 17. By July 31 Mr. Zimmer found that the second brood larvae were working on the outside of the tips as well as in the needles, tho none were found actually working within the terminal buds until on the 3 following days, August 1 to 3, when tipmoth larvae of the second brood were found to be beginning their burrows into the terminal buds on a number of pine trees out in the sandhills. They were also starting new burrows into the shoots just below the point where the burrowings of the larvae of the first brood ended. This latter habit, which proved to be a common one, accounts for some of the exceedingly long burrows that are to be found in the tips at the close of the period of activity of the second brood of larvae. By this time (August 1) the majority of the larvae that were to be found on the trees measured from 5 mm. to 8 mm. in length, none being found that exceeded 8 mm. This stage of larval development corresponds closely with the stage of development of the larvae of the second brood when they were first discovered on the tips in 1910 (July 30) and 1911 (August 6), the younger stages when the larvae were at work in the needles having been com - pletely overlooked in those years. By August 6 many of the second brood larvae had attained a length of 10 mm., altho there was still an abundance of them to be found that measured only 4 or 5 mm. in length. In </seg>
            <seg id="p035">j The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska • ■ fact, this plenitude of small larvae proved an embarassment to Mr. Zimmer when attempting to make an accurate count of the infested tips on August 7, it being difficult for him to tell in many cases whether a tip had an occupant at the time or whether it merely showed the effects of attack by the first brood of larvae. Many of the tips killed by larvae of the first brood were still on the trees, and a number of them had not become reinfested, so that it was necessary to dissect all doubtful tips and hunt for possible occupants, many of which were of too small a size to be readily found. For these rea - sons, after counting 1 jack pine on August 7, Mr. Zimmer postponed further counts of this kind for 5 days. On August 12, 13, and 14, however, he carefully counted the tips of 9 jack pines and 7 western yellow pines, noting the total number and the number affected with tipmoth ; larvae of the . second brood. The result of these counts may be summarized in the following table: Date Kind Height of Total No. No. of tips August of pine tree in feet of tips affecte-l 13 jack - 2 117 20 12 jack 3 302 51 14 I jack 3.5 151 6 14 jack 3.5 483 47 7 jack 4 375 41' 13 jack 4 454 26 12 jack 4.5 463 16 13 jack 5 640 24 12 jack 6 845 47 14 jack 8 1,254 103 12 wn. yellow 2.5 ■" 27 27 12 wn. yellow 3 27 18 12' wn. yellow 3 64 19 12 wn. yellow 3.5 59 29 12 wn. yellow 4 143 132 12 wn. yellow 5 154 16' 12 wn. yellow 6 121 27 Analyzing briefly the above data, it is seen that the 10 jack pine trees, varying in height from 2 to 8 feet, had 5,084 tips, of which 381, or 7.4 per cent, were attacked by larvae of the second brood, while the 7 western yellow pine trees, varying in height from 2V_ to 6 feet, had 445 tips, of which 268, or 60.2 per cent, were attacked by larvae of the second brood. And not only was the percentage of tips attacked by tipmoth larvae of the second brood much greater in the case of the western yellow pines than in the case of the jack pines, but the number of larvae per tip was also greater. One 5-inch 1 One to 4 larvae in each tip. 9 The leader of this tree was not affected, hence the relatively small number ot affected tips. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 jack pine leader dissected by Mr. Zimmer on August 7 had 5 second brood larvae working in and on it — an exceptionally heavy infestation for jack pine — and had been entirely killed by this second brood attack. Contrasted with this may be cited a western yellow pine tip dissected by Mr. Zimmer on August 6 that contained 14 second brood larvae, and a leader of the same species of pine dissected on August 10 that had been attacked by the first brood of larvae and reattacked by the second brood and that contained 30 larvae of various sizes. The western yellow pine is more likely to have the same tips attacked by both broods of tipmoth larvae than is the jack pine because there are fewer tips on the former species and also because the tips are larger and can harbor more of the larvae. By August 9 numbers of the second brood larvae were found that were approaching full growth, but none of them as yet showing evidences of the close approach of pupation. By August 16 second brood larvae were collected that were about fully grown. The last larvae taken from the trees were col - lected from seedlings on the seed beds on August 26. These seedlings had come up from seed planted that same spring (1912) , and had such small tips that the maturing larvae could not continue to occupy the burrows they had started in the tips, so had fastened several of the bud needles together with silk and were occupying the covered burrow thus formed. From the combined data secured in 1910, 1911, and 1912, the general statement may be made that the period of de - velopment of tipmoth larvae of the second brood extends from July 5 (1910) to September 1 (1911). EMERGENCE AND COCOON1NG OF THE SECOND BROOD LARVAE It was obvious, from the observations of 1910, that the larvae of the second brood either left their burrows in the tips when they became fully grown, or else pupated in the tip and the pupae immediately wriggled out and dropped to the ground. The evidence was conclusive that, in Nebraska at least, the insect did not normally hibernate in its burrows in the pine tips, as it was reported to do on Nantucket Island by Scudder (1 and 3). The observations of 1911 practically proved that the emergence from the tips was accomplished by the larvae. The very few pupae found in the tips during August, 1911, by Mr. Zimmer (only one on August 24 and two on August 26, out of several hundreds of tips examined, while 53 larvae were found on August 21 to 28, inclusive) seemed to clearly indi - cate that the insects left the tips while in the larval stage, and, after a definite migration, hibernated elsewhere. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">, The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska The beginning of the solution of the problem was when Messrs. Zimmer. and Pierce started digging around in the soil under s.ome pine trees in Nursery 80, on August 29, 1911, and in so doing discovered a single live pupa. Numerous empty pupal cases were also found on that day (possibly left there by the hibernating brood, but also quite possibly dropped pupal cases of the first brood) , but no live larvae were found in or on the soil. Continued search on August 30 and 31, 1911, revealed no more pupae, but on September 1, after much search, Mr. Zimmer found 2 more pupae, evidently freshly formed, on or near the surface of the ground, under some injured tips. Only the 2 could be found. Mr. Zimmer placed some larvae on some empty pine tips with some pupae in a rearing cage on soil, on September 1, and examined them 2 days later. Some of the larvae had spun cocoons on the needles and on the sides and bottom of the rearing cage, but otherwise conditions within the cage were unchanged. Mr. Zimmer carefully sifted every square inch of soil under some of the infested trees, to a depth of 6 or 8 inches, on September 2, without unearthing any pupae, and from this he concluded that pupation did not take place at any great depth in the soil, if in the soil, at all. . From the position of the 3 pupae found he also deduced that probably the larva drops directly from the tip to the ground. While not enough pupae were found on the ground to correspond with the number of larvae that obviously had been present in the pine tips overhead, a painstaking inspection showed- that they were not concealed anywhere on the needles, trunk, or bark, and a wholly inade - quate number was present in the burrows to lend any color to a belief that this brood normally hibernates there. The complete solution of the problem of the hibernation of the pine tipmoth was made by Mr. Zimmer in August, 1912. On August 16 he collected a number of apparently fully grown larvae of the second brood and placed them in a rearing cage over sand. Three days later (August 19) one of them had spun a cocoon on the surface of the sand in the cage. Mr. Zimmer's subsequent studies may well be quoted directly from his own interesting field notes for that day, and for the 3 following days: "The cocoon itself was covered with sand, which stuck to it so that it presented the appearance of a spindle-shaped ball of sand. Had it not been that it was only partially completed and that the rest of the sand in the cage was so free from lumps, I might easily have passed the cocoon over unnoticed. Search in other cages produced more of the cocoons, so I immediately went out into the field and commenced to search </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 I 3 __— -_____-__-___—^— — j Kir,. 8. Cocoons of Rhytirinn'ttt (rtntlmmt Imxhinlli, of grains of sand and © bits of pine needles spun together with silk. (Original.) </seg>
            <seg id="p039">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska under the trees. I found a dozen or more of the cocoons on the surface of the ground, usually immediately under injured tips. "August 20. While sifting sand from under the pines for cocoons I unearthed a larva which had not yet begun to spin. I placed it on a tip of a tree to see how it would descend, and after crawling over the tip a very short while it dropped directly to the ground. Here it wandered over the surface for some little time but finally found a place which apparently suited it, for it began to burrow into the sand and went in probably a half inch. It then appeared to remain quiet for some time, and, in fact, was still inactive when I left. When I returned a few hours later the cocoon was fairly started but not completed. The larva had already constructed a complete shell over itself thru which I could see it working within. The cocoon was just below the surface of the ground, just far enough below that it was entirely encrusted with the sand. This is the same way that the larvae in the breeding cages are constructing their cocoons. "I set some traps for tipmoth larvae to find their mode of descending from the tips when going to the ground for the purpose of pupating. These traps consisted of bands of tar around the trunks, to catch any of the insects attempting to crawl down, and cans partly filled with water and with a film of kerosene on top to catch those dropping from the tips, the cans being placed directly under affected tips. "August 21. I examined my larva traps and found 4 full-grown larvae in the cans under the tips. None were on the tarred bands. Numerous cocoons were found under the trees on the ground. One that I found was attached to an old dead needle cluster, so I examined the rubbish covering the surface of the ground under the affected trees and found cocoons fastened to bits of bark, grass, needles, twigs, etc., but always just beneath the surf ace of the sand. "Several more larvae were unearthed and without exception when these were placed on the trees they almost immediately fell to the ground by the shortest possible route without going through the process of descending by a silken thread. One of them when replaced on a tree, while crawling over the tip just before descending, appeared to slip off unintentionally and it then used the silken line to catch itself and regain the tip; but when it finally descended it tumbled off directly. "A few of the larvae were seen on the surface of the ground in positions where they were evidently getting ready to spin up, and 2 larvae dropped to the ground while I was watching, </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Sebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 altho I did not see them leave the tips. I watched one of these spin its cocoon. After dropping to the ground it crawled about over the surface for some little time, but after a while reached a place which seemed to suit it, for it worked its way into the ground just beneath the surface and there turned on its back and began weaving a mass of silk back and forth across the arch of the burrow, so as to form a sort of covered passageway. It backed out of the hole once and spun the lower end of the structure, and then crawled back under the silken mass again and began to spin the bottom of the cocoon. I was not able to see the completion of the structure, but enough of it was done when I left to show that in this case at least the cocoon was begun as a sort of roof to which the lower part was added later. The whole process Was carried out just below the surface, and of course when com - pleted the cocoon would be entirely encrusted with sand particles, while the surface of the ground remained unbroken. "August 22. I watched another larva build its winter home, but this one went at it in a different way from the one noted yesterday. Instead of crawling beneath the surface of the ground and there spinning, this larva crawled partly beneath a dead needle and bits of weed and then began the construc - tion of a dome of sand over itself. Grain by grain it picked the sand up by its jaws and packed it in a layer above itself, except where it was covered by bits of rubbish, altho these same bits of rubbish entered into the composition and were glued fast to the layer of sand particles in just the same way as the sand particles were fastened to each other, by means of a secretion of the mouth. When the whole larva was thus covered it began to complete the cocoon by the deposition of silk on the bottom of the hollow, and when this was done the cocoon was finished, altho still quite soft." HIBERNATION OF THE INSECT WITHIN THE COCOON It was not definitely determined by direct observation just when the larvae of the second brood pupate, after having spun their cocoons. However, because of the fact that second brood pupae were found in very small numbers in the larval bur - rows during latter August, and on the ground during latter August and early September, and also because Scudder (1 and 3) had shown that on Nantucket Island the species passed the winter as a pupa in the larval burrows, it was assumed that very probably the larvae pupated within their cocoons shortly after spinning them in late August and early Septem - ber. A number of cocoons collected under the trees between August 19 and September 9, 1912, were packed in a tin box </seg>
            <seg id="p041">-» u. Z &lt; Z __&lt; __\ &lt; co o X Q I 15 311 15 281 15 3U 13 301 15 311 13 101 IS 311 IS 311 IS 301 IS 311 15 301 13 31 *"3 OVCRWI NTCRIN6 COCOONS _&gt; .,__£ £___... &gt;3 Mil g LARV AC ''-__! .___-£^_-S _&amp;_-_.•■ PU PAE : ' "__• ______ _l5__£i____.. ■oths. -r-:»2j cass " LARVAE j g - l l l I- l 1 l 1 I 1 l Fig 9. — Diagram of the life cycle of Rhyacionia frustrana bushnelli in the Nebraska National Forest, based on the combined observations of 1909-1912. (Original.) </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 and taken to Lincoln for the purpose of making examinations to determine the time of pupation, but other matters pre - vented giving this question prompt attention, so that, when the cocoons were finally examined early in 1913, it was found that the moths (31) had emerged from them. This prompt emergence of the moths under artificially warm conditions may also be taken as an indication that wintering takes place as a pupa within the cocoons. removal of infested tips as a control measure While it was known early in 1911 that the second genera - tion of the pine tipmoth did not normally hibernate within the larval burrows in the pine tips, it was also known that the larvae of the first generation did pupate within their burrows and that the moths of the second generation later emerged from these infested tips. The practical question arising in this connection was whether the pruning and destroying of the infested tips at a time when the great bulk of the larvae of the first generation were in them would materially reduce the infestation by larvae of the second generation later in the season upon such treated trees. Accordingly, on June 8, 1911, an isolated clump of 11 jack pines was selected in a pocket of the sandhills (of P. No. 2, BI. No. 2), among the Norway pine plantings of 1911, for an experiment on the effect of pruning and destroying the in - fested tips. The selected trees were a considerable distance away from the closest obviously infested pines and were pro - tected by the hills in such a way as to present the maximum difficulties of reinfestation by the blowing in of moths from the infested trees. The selected trees were from 3 to 6 feet tall, on the average about 4 feet, and the total number of tips on them varied from 73 to 995, averaging about 300 tips. AN tips showing the slightest browning of the needles were picked off by the writer on the following day (June 9) . From the 11 trees 367, or about 11 per cent of the total number of tips, were removed, thus averaging about 33 tips per tree. Ail of these tips contained living larvae, practically all of them of obvious size and many of them large enough to com - plete their development in the pruned tips, since later 158 moths emerged from these tips. This same clump of trees was examined again 74 days later, on August 21, 1911. At this time 252 tips were found in - fested, or an average of 23 tips per tree. In spite of the tip - moth attack the trees had increased in height, now varying from 3 to 6'/_ feet, and averaging nearly a half foot taller than on the preceding June 8. On August 21 nearly all of </seg>
            <seg id="p043">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska the larvae had matured and the burrows were mostly de - serted, over 90 per cent of them being empty. The following table contrasts the findings : L I- |- «.' &amp; fi B % - |«- z,- !__! s« s^ I* h £•_. z x - . _. . , 2 _ fc.S S&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; 2~ 1 4' 324 74 23 4.5' 63 62 1 2 5' 294 60 20+ 6'. 43 43 0 3 3 ; 73 9 -12-- 3.5' 11 10 1 4 5' 233 17 7--' 5' 25 23 2 5 3' 206 41 15+ 4' 19 15 4 6 3' 106 7 7—3' 3 2 1 7 5.5' 387 31 8+ 5.5' 17 16 1 8 6' 995 59 6— 6.5' 36 26 10 9 3' 259 14 6— 4' 11 10 1 10 4' 241 32 • 13+ 5' 13 12 1 11 3' 128 23 18- 4' 11 10 1 Average4+' 300+ 33+ 11.1 4.7' 23— 21— 2 + Total 3,306 367 252 229 23 As checks on the above experiment, the following examina - tions of other trees Avere made : — '« o. n _■ ._},_• c. B £ Zl o| _ 1_ -si 9l ifi _»__ a 3 0'3 ou o,_ oO 0_. OC O.'S-.S a&lt; Z-C Zt S"3- HZ Z.5 ZS 8S«c 22 1 ' 1 4.5' 321 39 36 3 larvae 2 3' 121 19 19 0 3 5' 414 74 71 3 larvae 26 2 ' 1 5' 612 108 105 1 larva, 2 pupae 2 3.5' 342 24 23 1 larvae 3 2.5' 185 13 12 1 larvae 28 3' 1 5' 334 55 55 0 2 3.5' 132 24 24 0 3 3.5' 439 73 73 0 Average 4.1+' 367—48— 46+ 1+ Total 2,900 429 418 11 The above observations seem to indicate that the careful pruning and destroying of the infested tips while the first , brood of larvae is in them will not insure protection from a severe attack by the second brood, nor even materially lighten the attack of the second brood.. In fact, if we allow one-half of the infested tips found on August 22, 26, and 28, at the close of the active season of both broods of larvae, as belong - 1 Clump No. 1 was in the immediate vicinity of the experimental clump, on P. No. 2, BI. No. 2; clump No. 2 was immediately south ot the Reserve buildings ; clump No. 3 was xm a plantation south of- Nursery 80. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 ing to the first brood, the infestation in the experiment and the check is seen to be practically identical. Nevertheless, to make quite sure on this point, the experiment was repeated in 1912. On June 26, Mr. Zimmer selected an isolated clump of 26 western yellow pines, located about one-half mile south of the Reserve on the main north-south double guard, and picked . off all of the tips showing infestation. The selected trees were from 1 to 5 feet tall, on the average about 2.4 feet, and the total number of tips on them varied from 10 to 167, averaging about 44 tips. From the 26 trees 180, or about 15.8 per cent of the total number of tips, were removed, thus averaging about 6.9 affected tips per tree. Forty days later, on August 5, 1912, this clump of trees was again surveyed and found to be heavily reinfested with second brood larvae, these averag - ing over 12 to the tree. The following table presents the findings in detail: ■/. Z'~ ■-'— — — C MCi -w 2 to * to 5 _ a Z :■ &amp;% sz -jg fa °.?s - ±3 Oo o _ _*r: sua 1 1.5' 11 0 0 5 2 3- 1G7 27 16 7 3 2' 3'J 4 10 10 4 2.75' 21 4 19 8 5 3.5' 31 4 12- 11 6 5' 53 8 15 10 7 2.5' 54 0 0 11 8 4' 33 7 21 1 9 2' 28 5 17- 24 10 2' 23 11 23- 6 IV 1.75' 16 5 31 9 12 1.5' 38 5 13 - 29 13 1.25' 24 6 25 17 14 V 20 4 20 19 15 1.5' 18 6 33 7 16 3' 55 4 7 21 17 5' 70 14 . 20 14 18 4' 126 22 17 44 19 V 24 4 16- 2 20 5' 107 18 16— 23 21 1' 17 0 0 2 22 2' 49 7 14 - 8 23 3' 62 11 17+ 9 24 1' 18 1 54- 2 25 V 25 0 0 4 26 1' 10 3 30 12 Average 2.4 ' 43.8- 6.9+ 15.8+ 12 1 + Total 1,139 180 315 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska From these experiments of 1911 and 1912, it is obvious that the pine tipmoths fly sufficiently well and far that even when the first brood is eliminated, or practically so, on a given group of trees, the influx of moths of the second generation will replenish the infestation of second brood larvae to the normal amount. To be of any real value as a protective or control measure, the infested tips would evidently need to be removed and destroyed simultaneously over the entire plan - tations — a manifestly impossible or prohibitive task when it is remembered that on a jack pine tree 3 to 6 feet tall there are from 100 to over 900 tips, in round numbers, and the percentage of infestation will run somewhere about as in 1911 and 1912, when it averaged over 13 per cent and nearly 29 per cent, respectively , ( of all of the tips on the trees, after the completion of the attack of both broods of larvae. PARASITES PRESENT IN NEBRASKA One of the early thoughts in the study of this problem was to learn the nature and extent of the parasitism of the pine tipmoth in the Nebraska National Forest, and to ascertain if any practical advantage might come of this knowledge. It was thought that possibly the tipmoth had been, introduced into the plantations without any, or with but very few, of its natural parasitic enemies, and that the lack of these might account for its severe injuries there. The same species, as has already been stated, is known to occur in the western yellow pines of the Pine Ridge region of Nebraska. On July 12, 1909, the writer secured an abundant supply of infested jack pine and Scotch pine tips, from which were reared,. between July 13 and 21, the following 11 parasites: Date Ichneumon : Chalcids : July ltoplcctis connulaitor ' Holtichdla xanticlce 2 Eurytoma sp.' 13 1 15 1 16 5 17 .2 - 1 21 I 1 3 . 1 7 It is thus evident that as early as 1909 there were at least 3 species of Hymenopterous parasites at work on the tipmoth larvae in the Nebraska National Forest, of which a chalcid of the genus Eurytoma was the most numerous, the next most numerous the ichneumon Itoplectis conquisitor (Say), while a single specimen of a chalcid belonging to the genus ■Determined by H. L. Vicreck. * Determined by J. C Crawford. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 Haltichella, and identified by Mr. Crawford as H. xanticles Walsh, was reared. On July 12, when the material from which these parasites were reared was being collected, 3 specimens of the Itoplectis were seen flitting among the trees. No rearing of parasites was done in 1910, but on July 3, 1911, Mr. R. W. Dawson collected a large number of infested jack pine tips in Nursery 80, and the writer reared from them, between July 6 and 21, the following 40 parasites: lehnt- iimitn . l.raconid : ChalciU»: I'teromaliiis : Dan II,,,,!.,,,* M; ,,,l,ra,,,„ ll.itlu l„-U,t t. u r „ I BIM S|&gt;. 1 J Sp. 2 - Sp _S ' Jul) ,;.,„i„,s,l«t ,-|.. ....... •■'.-« - .,,.• C 1 19,2c- 1 7 11' 1 8 i t . l • ;; il 1 3 i , l - 1 1U 1 I 1 1. I i 2 11 11-. 2 1 1 2 '•'&gt; i . 1 ; 13 I / 1 1 14 1 18 1 ■ 21 1* 2 1 1 12 ? . 7 • 7 6 1 These rearings show that in 1911 there were at least 7 species of Hymenopterous parasites of the tipmoth present in the Nebraska National Forest. Of these, the chalcid of the genus Eurytoma continued to be the most numerous form, while the well-known ichneumon Itoplectis conquisitor (Say) was apparently less numerous than in 1909. The Haltichella apparently just about maintained its previous abundance. The 4 species present in 1911 that were not reared in 1909 were a large yellow braconid (Microbracon sp. ) and 3 species of unidentified Pteromalidae. The most numerous species of the latter group was one of minute size and purple in color (sp. 1); another almost equally numerous species was small and of dark shiny green color (sp. 2) ; while the third species (sp. 3), of which but a single specimen was reared, was also of a shiny green color, but was large in size. In addition to these Hymenopterous parasites, on June 27, 1911, il small tachinid fly was reared from a tipmoth burrow. In 1909, along with the 11 parasites there came out 24 moths, thus making about 46 per cent as many parasites as moths. In 1911, along with the 40 parasites there emerged 62 moths, showing about 65 per cent as many parasites as moths. In other words, the parasitism apparently increased about 20 per cent between July, 1909, and July, 1911. 1 Determined by H. I.. Viereck. 1 Determined by J. C. Crawford. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska On August 19, 1911, Mr. Theodore Kruger collected some western yellow and jack pine transplants and some Scotch pine seedlings from the seed beds and sent them to the writer for examination. From them, between August 28 and Sep - tember 6, 11 parasites were reared, as follows: Dute Ichneumons : Chalcids : Pteromalida : AiiK.-Sept. Sp. Eurytoma «p.' Sp. 2' 28 2 (S) 2 30 1 (Y) 31 12 (J) 2 3 (IS, 2 J) ' 4 15 (Y) 6 ' ■ .3&lt;$ (1J.2 Y) 5 12,44 1 The importance of these rearings is the addition of a second species of ichneumon parasite (a short, stout, black, un - identified species), and the demonstration that the Eurytoma continues actively until early fall. At the close of 1911, the pine tipmoth larvae were known to be parasitized by 2 ichneumons, 1 braconid, 5 chalcids, and 1 tachinid parasite, a total of 9 species. During the 1909 and 1911 investigations no egg parasites were noted. But in 1912 Mr. Zimmer discovered the presence in abundance of a most minute chalcid egg parasite, as yet un - identified as to species, attacking the eggs of both generations of the pine tipmoth in the plantations. He first found eggs parasitized by this insect on June 3, 4, and 5, and collected a number of them on each of these days. These parasitized eggs were much easier to find than the unparasitized ones, because they were of an opaque black color in decided contrast to the color of the leaf scales upon which they were deposited, render - ing them conspicuous and easy to see, while the unparasitized eggs harmonized so closely with the color of the leaf scales as to make them difficult of detection. When empty these par - asitized eggs showed a clear-cut, rounded emergence hole, very different from the irregular opening thru which the larva forces its way out of an unparasitized egg. The first adult parasite emerged on June 10 from the eggs collected June 3 to 5, indicating a developmental period of at least 5 days. Mr. Zimmer found parasitized eggs of the second generation on July 13, 16, 22, 25, and 27, and on August 1 and 6. From 2 parasitized eggs collected July 13, adults issued 11 days later, on July 24. From a parasitized egg collected July 16-, along with several others, 2 adults issued 1 Determined by J. C. Crawford. 'The letter J symbolizes jack pine; S, Scotch pine; and Y, western yellow pine. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 8 days later, also on July 24. Of 37 eggs collected as found on July 22, 28 proved to be parasitized and only 9 normal. The adults issued from these parasitized eggs as follows: July 23, 3; July 24, 1; July 25, 2; July 26, 1; July 27, 1; July 28, 6 ; July 29, 9 ; and July 30, 9, after 1 to 8 days, respectively. From eggs collected July 25, 1 adult issued July 30 and 3 issued July 31. An egg collected July 27 gave forth the adult on July 30. Several parasitized eggs from which the adults had not emerged were noted on the trees August 1, and a few as late as August 6, but by that date almost all of the par - asitized eggs had given forth the adults. From the above observations it is probable that the period of development of this egg parasite of the pine tipmoth is about 8 to 11 days. Usually but a single adult emerges from a parasitized egg, but Mr. Zimmer noted some instances where 2, and even 3, adults issued from one parasitized egg. Where there is more than a single occupant, usually each has its own place of emergence, but sometimes a single exit hole is used by all of them. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">The Pine Tipmoth in Nebraska literature ■■• CITED 1. Scudder, S. H. in: Meeting of the Entomological Club of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. Canadian Entomologist, xi, p. 176. (September, 1879). 2. Comstock, J. H. Report of the United States Entomologist for. 1879, pp. 23G-237, pi. v, fig. 2 (June 30, 1880). 3. Scudder, S. H. The Pine Moth of 'J Nantucket — Retinia frustrana. Publications of the Massachusetts 'Society for the Promotion of Agriculture, pp. 1-20 (1883). 4. Packard, A. S. Fifth Report of the' United States Entomological Commission, pp. 745-754 (1890). 1 5. Treat, Mary; The Pines at Christmas Time. Garden and Forest, iv, p.14 (1891). 6. Fernald, C. H. A List of North American Lepidoptera — Bulletin 52, United States National Museum, p. 448, No. 4998 (December 1, 1902). ' if, 7. Felt, E. P. Seventh Report of the Forest, Fish, and Game Commis - sion of New York, pp. 501-503 (1903). 8. Felt, E. P. Insects Affecting Park and Woodland Trees. Memoir 8, New York State Museum, pp. 405-407, Albany (1906). fl. Swenk, M. H. Report of the Entbmologist for 1909. Annual Re - port of the Nebraska Horticultural Society for 1909, il, pp. 112 - 117 (1909). 10. Swenk, M. H. Two New Insect PeSts in Nebraska. The Pine-tip Moth (Retinia frustrana Scudder). Forestry Quarterly, viii, pp. 411-413 (December, 1910). 11. Bates, C. G., and Pierce, R. G. Forestation of the Sandhills of Ne - braska and Kansas. Bulletin 121; Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture, pp. 45-46 (February 3, 1913). 12. Busck, A. A Destructive Pine-moth Introduced from Europe (Evetria buoliana Schiffermii_l$r). Journal of Economic Ento - mology, vii, pp. 340-341, pi; ix (August, 1914). 13. Busck, A. Descriptions of New Microlepidoptera of Forest Trees. Proceedings of the Entomological Society of Washington, xvi, pp. 144-145 (December 30, 1914)-. 14. Busck, A. The European Pine-Shoot Moth; A Serious Menace to Pine Timber in America. Bulletin 170, United States Department of Agriculture, pp; 1-11, pi. i-vi (February 9, 1915). j 15. Rohwer, S. A. Descriptions of New Species of Hymenoptera. Pro - ceedings of the United States'National Museum, xlix, pp. 225-226 (July 16, 1915). 16. Mattoon, W. R. Life History of Shortleaf Pine. Bulletin 244, .United States Department of . Agriculture, p.36, pi. ix, fig. 1 (July 21, 1915). 17. Barnes, W., and McDunnough, J. Check List of tha Lepidoptera of Boreal America, p. 167, Nos. 6760 and 6773 (February, 1917). 18. Cushman, R. A. A. Revision of Hymenopterous Insects of the Tribe Cremastini of America North of Mexico. Proceedings of the United States National Museum, liii, p. 530 (August 22, 1917). 19. Pearson, G. A. Studies of Yield and Reproduction of Western Yel - low Pine in Arizona and New .Mexico. Journal of Forestry, xvi, p. 270 (March, 1918). 20. Weiss, H. B. Nursery Insects. Circular 26, New Jersey Department of Agriculture, p. 31 (1919). 21. Heinrich, C. Revision of the North American Moths of the Sub - family Eucosminae of the Family Olethreutidae. Bulletin 123, </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 40 United States National Museum, pp. 20-21 (January 31, 1923). 22. Forbes, W. T. M. The Lepidoptera of New York and Neighboring States. Memoir 68, Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, p. 438 (June, 1923). 23. Felt, E. P. Manual of Tree and Shrub Insects, p. 285. The Macmil - lan Company, New York (1924). 24. Howard, L. 0. Report of the United States Entomologist for 1926, p. 27 (1926). 25. Essig, E. 0. Insects of Western North America, p. 728. The Mac - millan Company, New York (1926). Edition [3M1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>