<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Farm Cheese-Making</title>
               <date value="1917-11-01">1917-11-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 47 BULLETIN OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE FARM CHEESE-MAKING J. H. Frandsen and T. Thorson Distributed November 1, 1917 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. Distributed in Furtherance of the Purposes of the Cooperative Agricul - tural Extension Work Provided for in the Act of Congress of May 8, 1914. University of Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and the United States Department of Agriculture Cooperating. C. W. PUGSLEY, Director of Extension Service </seg>
            <seg id="p002">University of Nebraska College of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD (The Resents of the University) Hon. Frank L. Haller, President, Hon. John E. Miller, Lincoln Omaha Hon. Philip L. Hall, Lincoln Hon. Victor G. Lyford, Falls City Hon. Harry D. Landis, Seward Hon. Edward P. Brown, Davey THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor E. A. Burnett, D. Sc., Dean, College of Agriculture; Director, Experiment Station J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Director C. E. Gunnels, B. Sc., County Agent Work Lew. T. Skinner, B. Sc., Assistant to the Director Maud Mathes Wilson, B. Sc Home Demonstration Work R. P. Crawford, A. B. Agricultural Editor C. W. Watson, A. M., Junior Extension Work EXTENSION SPECIALISTS I. D. Wood, A. M., Emma Reed Davisson, Women's Clubs Mary A. Rokahr, A. B., Home Economic* Esther Ord, B. Sc, Home En Ada Johnson, B. Sc, •nomun Dairy Husbandry Home Economics R. R. Spafford, B. Sc. Farm Management A. G. George, B. Sc, Junior Extension Work J. F. Hendricks, B. Sc Farm Management Mary-Ellen Brown, B. Sc, Junior Extension Work E. L. Rhoades, B. Sc, Farm Management W. J. Loeffel, B. Sc, Junior Extension Work E. H. Hoppert, B. Sc, Horticulture F. D. Keim, B. Sc, Agronomy R. E. Holland, County Agent Work Alva Wilson, County Agent Work J. H. Claybaugh, B. Sc., Junior Extension Work T. H. Goodding, B. Sc, Junior Extension Work THE EXTENSION COUNCIL (Heads of Departments) E. A. Burnett, D. Sc, Dean C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Director E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D. J. H. FRANDSEN, M. S. A. Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc. Entomology Agricultural Botany F. W. Upson, Ph. D. H. C. Filley, A. M. Farm Management Agricultural Chemistry Alice M. Loomis, A. M. Home Economics L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E. Agricultural Engineering R. F. Howard, A. M. Horticulture W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Agronomy J. H. Gain, M. D. C. G. A. Loveland, A. M. Meteorology Animal Pathology H. E. Bradford, A. M., Principal, School of Agriculture Agricultural Engineering K. F. Warner, M. S., Animal Husbandry D. H. Propps, B. Sc., </seg>
            <seg id="p003">FARM CHEESE-MAKING J. H. Frandsen and T. Thorson A large amount of food material goes to waste every year in skim milk and buttermilk. In making butter all the fat is removed from the milk, leaving the protein or muscle-building substance in the skim milk or buttermilk. From the standpoint of supplying the necessary food to the body, this material is more valuable than the fat alone, since butter contains less than half the food material present in the milk. A great deal of food that is now used for animal feeding could be made into products for human use, by making the milk or milk products into cheese. While a great deal more skim milk could profitably be used both as a beverage and in cooking, a great deal more could be used in making cheese. Several kinds of cheese can be made from skim milk and buttermilk, while others can be made from whole milk. In either case, more of the food value of milk is conserved for human use than when only the fat is used. COMPOSITION AND FOOD VALUE OF CHEESE The materials found in milk are of two classes, those that make up the cheese and those that go into the whey. The cheese - forming materials are fat and casein. The whey-forming materials include the water, milk sugar, albumen, and mineral matter. Some water is retained in the cheese and is therefore one of the cheese-forming materials also. Thus, cheese is composed almost entirely of casein, butter fat, and water. So much importance has been attached to the percentage of butter fat in milk and other dairy products that the real value of the other materials found in milk is usually underestimated and frequently entirely overlooked. This is a mistake, since casein, which is the principal protein compound of milk and also the principal constituent of cheese, is one of the cheapest forms of muscle-building material. In general, foods that are high in protein are high in price. Protein is usually supplied by meat in the diet of most persons. A pound of cheese will supply twice as much protein as a pound of the very best meat. For that reason it can be used as a substitute for meat to a considerable extent. In Farmers' Bulletin No. 487 by the United States Department of Agriculture), "The Economical Use of Cheese in the Diet," the following statement is made: "From the standpoint of the housekeeper cheese is of importance because of its high nutritive value, particularly its high percentage of protein or muscle-forming materials, because of the ease with </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin No. 47, College of Agriculture which it can be kept and prepared for the table and the great variety of ways in which it can be served." As a food, cheese has always stood high in European countries, taking the place of meat to a large extent. Cheese being rich in protein logically replaces such foods as meat and eggs, as is shown by the following table: TABLE 1 — The average composition of cheese and some other common foods as purchased 1 Food Carbo- Mineral Fuel value material Refuse | Water Protein Fat hydrates matter per pound One of the greatest objections to the more general use of cheese is that it gives rise to certain physiological disturbances when it is eaten in very large quantities. The United States Department of Agriculture has investigated this matter. Its findings are summarized in the following statement quoted from Fanners' Bulletin No. 487: "Extensive studies have been carried on as a part of the Department's nutrition investigation of the food value, thoroness of digestibility, ease of digestion, physiolog - ical effect, and special character of cheese as food, as well as methods of preparing it for the table. The conclusion drawn from this extended study is, in brief, that cheese properly pre - pared and used is not generally a cause of physiological disturb - ances and that it may be easily introduced into the bill of fare in such quantities as to serve as the chief source of nitrogenous (muscle-building) food and may be made a substitute of other nitrogenous foods when such a substitution is desired." In Hutchinson's "Food and Dietetics" the following statement is made: "The larger the lumps of cheese that reach the stomach the slower will the digestive juices act upon it. Hence, the im - portance of reducing the cheese to a state of fine division before •From Fanners' Bulletin No. 487, United States Department of Agriculture. Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent :heese 34.2 25.2 33.7 I 2.4 Jeef of av. comp. 18.6 60.5 15.2 15.5 'orter- house.. 12.7 52.4 i 19.1 i Dried beef 53.7 26.4 6.9 Sggs 11.2 65.5 13.1 9.3 Milk 87.0 3.3 4.0 5.0 irt*d 35.3 9.2 1.3 53.1 'otatoea. 20.0 62.6 1.8 .1 14.7 Percent* 3.8 .7 .8 8.9 .9 .7 1.1 .8 Calories 1,950 935 l.lio 790 635 310 1,215 295 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Farm Cheese-Making 5 ii is swallowed. This may be done by careful mastication, but a better plan is to break up the cheese before it is eaten at all. This may be done by grating, but a better way is to dissolve the cheese and then mix it thru some other form of food. If the cheese is first grated or finely chopped and some milk and eggs added, a very savory and exceedingly nutritious pudding or fondu may be prepared at a very small cost. If cheese is ever to take the place it ought to have as a cheap and convenient form of protein food, some such method must be employed, for it is the difficulty with which cheese is digested that renders it impossible food to some persons." So much of the cheese now on the market is made in factories equipped with modern apparatus that many persons are led to believe that cheese is a factory product which can not be made without expensive equipment. As a matter of fact, cheese has been made for some centuries in the farm dairies of the Old World. It is not the purpose of this bulletin to discuss the relative merits of farm and factory dairy systems but to supply information in regard to the manufacture of cheese on the farm. Some of these cheeses are very easily made with utensils found in every home, while others are a little more difficult; but with a little experience, any of the cheeses here described can be made without much difficulty. COTTAGE CHEESE In every pound of cottage cheese there is about one-fifth of a pound of protein, nearly all of which is digestible. A pound of cottage cheese daily would supply all the protein required by the ordinary adult engaged in a sedentary occupation. The United States Department of Agriculture states that cottage cheese is much cheaper than most meats in supplying protein for the diet. For protein, one pound of cottage cheese equals: 1.27 pounds sirloin steak 1.00 pound round steak 1.37 pounds chuck rib beef 1.46 pounds fresh ham 1.44 pounds smoked ham 1.58 pounds loin pork chop 1.31 pounds hind leg of lamb 1.37 pounds breast of veal In addition to protein, energy for performing body work must be supplied by food. Furthermore, as a source of energy, cottage cheese is cheaper than most meats at present prices. On the basis of energy supplied, one pound of cottage cheese equals: 8J ounces sirloin steak 11 J ounces round steak 111 ounces chuck rib beef 10 J ounces fowl 5 ounces smoked ham 6 ounces loin pork chop 7 J ounces hind leg of lamb 12 1 ounces breast of veal 5} ounces fresh ham </seg>
            <seg id="p006">KxtnttioH Hulirtin No, i7. Collrgr of Agricultun 6 The nimplent method of mnnufact urinn cottage cheene in to «h u quantity of frenh skim milk in a moderately warm room and allow it to Hour naturally. I'nlem the milk ha* been contaminated by the introduction of tilth in an unclean barn or an unwashed ■M'piiriiior, the curd will be nmooth and even and free from rum bubble*. The bent temperature to *et milk for cot tape rhctw \n from 70 to 72 dejrree* Fahrenheit, An noon an the milk i* curdled uniformly It *hould be broken up thoroly. Since there i* no fat Ki«. 1— A dairy thMtnnnwtvr riwU only HA iwnU. Dairy M|ul|imMit i« In - iMimiiloIr without It. In thin milk, the curd need not be cut. The UmpMrntttft *hould then be mined utinliiiilly to iilnnil 104 decree* Fahrenheit for at leant fifteen minute*, or until the whey nepamten from tlu&gt; curd The curd In then pnuml Into h immlln bait and htinu up to drain. A limit* nack or n nuwtr nack will nerve I hi* put'po*t&gt; very well, It will take from two In ten iMUfl t » » drain the whpy from the curd. ili'|n'nilinu upnii the nine mid flrmnen* of (Iip curd pHrllclp*, When Him cumin properly drnlned, It I* mn|*t hihI itrHiiulnr bin tint ntlcky. Tu complete Him bftNNNW, the dmlned cui'il I* nnllcd il Hie i m» •■ of line miiii'M uf nail In Mii»lii nr tell pnuitil* nf i'lit&gt;p*p, A hint uf nWPPl I'lMtiiii In mim'Ii It'll |inumU nt I'ltMtW IttH.V ttUn lie ihIiImiI 1 1 » give it Ht'TiPC flnVtir, The i&gt;Iiwm&gt; I* t|ip(i t'PMdy for uw Thin pciH'wn iiih,V I»p nndlflpil In vmi'Iihi* wmv* In IntUtt imii'M imirniiii im«iiIi« IikIi'ih iif nlluwllitt the tnllk in nutic iiiiliiiiilh . the li'iiiiMiilMllnin iiimv ip imiiiIi'iiIImiI Iiv tinlltu H nlHflpfi TftP nlHt'lPt' iiimv Iip pIiIipc h mt'p i'IiIiiiim (Mil'i'lmnpil me Ililn |hiiimi««&lt; ni'M HMltll'Ml nlrtliMMlMVM MlPil Ml Iiiiiiik l''ni Iniuii lit'nm. iiimMmw Him Ittlli'l niMllinil In iii'nliMlilv Him ntnnl |iumUuiI A mhIimmI mIhi'IpI 1 Id i(pvp|n|mii liy Hlliiwilttl m nltmll i|iiMiilllv m IllRi Mf H «KtMl'l itf I'lwiii mill* In «lninl lilllil ■inn ptintiun In nrnkf II ihti'k. A Miit II i|iimiiiii.v nf «Min milk U lltpit IiphUI in I Ml iImmimmh iillli (|p|l Hi lllMl MlllpurMllIlM fill Ml Im»»«I l*Mlih 1 1 1 1 1 1 u I mm MMll HlMll MIHlPlI In 7(1 iImuimpb A RIIIHII ililtUHHv ill III. iil'pviniiMly •imiimiI mill In ihIiImiI In lltp iipw ■•uiiiiIm unil IipM Hi Hini i mill iIiiim null II witil'n. TliU ii|imiiiI|uii iiimv Iim I'MpuHlnd •t« ilflpli ii» iiih'mmuiv Mini Him ■hiii mi i'iiiiImiI iiti'i h Inim |imi|imI VMii-ii it i|ii*nilltv nl rnllitliM i Iimm«m l« In Iim iiiimIm, IhhImhiI tif nl Inwiny Hip milk In wmr nf iiwlf it nrny Iip IipmIwI mihI Hipii iimiIkiT Hip umiiip hm Hip »iiimII »miii|iIm, nr Him ■imiMi limy lit* </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Farm Chreae-M (iking 7 added to the raw milk without heating it and set away in a warm place to sour. From this point, the procew in the name aa that already described. Cottage cheese is sometimes put up in pound prints quite the same as butter. A more common way, however, when put - ting it up for market, in to put it in pasteboard boxes. Oyster pails are also sometimes used. Cottage cheese will sell for from 10 cents to 20 cents a pound, depending upon the quality of the cheese and the market. It can be served in a great variety of ways, Quite often It is eaten without any further preparation. It is delirious served with cream and sugar. It can also be made Into a salad. Farmers' Hulletln No. 4K7 gives a large number of ways In which It can be served. BUTTERMILK CHKMft Ituttermilk cheese Is quite similar In appearance and flavor to cottage cheese. It Is smooth and fine grained. Cream or milk may therefore bp easily mixed with It alt tin this in not sit necessary as with iMitiHuc I'lii'i'sp liiiiii'tnillk riiww Is easier made than ■•id i hup I'lifpw, Iipciiiim" there It nut (Tip danger of making a dry, pimrsp, hard cIippsp fmm healing to tun high a temperature, Tn iiiiiiu' iiuiti'imill* i'Iippup tin' nuliprmllk u IiphIwI In a pan tn alimit 140 dpgrpps Kahfpnliplt ispaldlng hut). In mIhiiii half mi hour It Is iiniiipil Into a pIippsppImiIi Img and Itung uti In drain. In twn iii fmif hunt's liip 1'iird will lip dry pnntigh In salt. Kail Is aililwl al i In' mil' mi min ntitipp tn pvprv fmir nr tlvp timinils nf pIippsp. Afli'i Hip sail ami i'Iippsp hip iIhhmIv mlMtnl, fHP pIipusp IM li'llllv fill IllltltPlllllIP IIUP AMKNirAN NKUKCMAm (MIKifc S'piifi'lintpl i'Iipp«p was Iliii iiuhIp |it I'Vmiii'p as lltM imiin* imlii'iitPK It Is ttiiw ittaijp pulPhslvply lit HtU mumhIpv, bud Ihn nmiiiiftti'ltii'M U i|iiiip illltpipiii rnuii wluii It Is in I'Vttiii'P. |t I'pmpimIiImd imiiimhm i'Iimm«m wiittpwlml in tiiiiiPMiHiii'p, »«»i*&gt;|it. llm&lt; H lo Illll'l MIlllllHil (Hill Ililo it SlttMlllhPt 1 llMily, Mini tllP llt.lP l« MUMP wIlHl iii"iM' llplil'HlP Fill 1 IMP IIIHMIIU • »f tills I'llPPUP, I ttll MHIIM Illllllllty hIiihiI I hlil v iiuiiiuU hi'p iiprltHlm Him immsI sMiisfni'iiiiv 'Dtp iPiiijmrttliiiM i» •ill lllllHM'lUlll, mi' I il HUM llP MUMP rmnlllv inillll'lllln'l III ii i.in . .r this Hlstt iiinl nlui|iti I him |ti itiiy iiilim Cm in lip*imiHP IIipsb mhos i iiii lip |ilui pi I ill u lull nr IiimIi --I k.iIpi lit wllllill Ihn lpiM|iiiiiihiii&gt; -mi lip i|ullP I'tuilv IipIiI I'uiiilMiil TIip milk sliutilii Iip mi| In I ft** uflPiiiiMiii It U hrsl liniiiulil Iii ii iPiiiiipmliii'P nf 71) iIpiuppii I''ih iliirly imiuiiiU ur milk Hhimi iinn-lmU nuliin it«tnliiM#Mir nt </seg>
            <seg id="p008">NMmuHuh HutlrHn No, 4f, CitHpfr nf Afrivuliun 8 iftiliMj 1111111 i'i| In itlimii iwMMly Ilium n« imii'h imiIiI whIh In 'iiI'IliI In ihf m lit, If n'inii'1 ImIiIi&lt;u mi' iinwI, mum HmIiMi itf n NlHall ii'iitii'l IiiiiImI whli'li In iiliutil Him mImp itf m i|lm» nIhiiiIiI lw llllMMll dtlMt [I Ilim llMMM iIImhIvImI III ,| «Mttlll MIIMIIIIll llf I Illll WMll'l II In iImnIihIiIh lit ami Hliiilll iiHM-fnllHlt iMimpiiiinfiil h t&lt;illijt&gt; I't'lllllltl'lMI I llf MhHmI' III IIIM lll.Hk IlI'MHI' |II|IIJHM III Mil' ll'lllll'l If Imp ulttilw In In Iim lutil, bid II |n mil mhI.IipIv hww»nhi'.V&gt; I hi ii'iiiu'l ittit"! Iim Mint nl v MtlUMil with Him milk TIim milk uluiiilil Hill Iim nIIN'mI MtfMlll, lull i'MIm miiinI Iim ItthMlt In *tw ll)«l Mim iMitt|iMt«liiiM In |«m|iI ii|i In 7f) i1m«immh lit twelve lif pI«IiImmii HHMPKi I llf I'Hi'il in I Iim milk will lit* i|iiIIm flfiti, wllli m III lie wltey •i.|ihimI»m| mil riiiiit Him i'IiiiI 'Him hihI In Mimii iinuml nnlii I'llllllll I'lllMlN, I'WI'M llMltIM I«HM(I Hill III lllMrtH MlM •■(1***1 MMK'M I llttll in ni'i i'mmiv tliiii' Mi|« imniiIu lii n Iiinn nf fit I Mill I'liHuegUMHllv •I liiniUM t'llMUMi If |i)tMM*Mli|lllll I* M»Mll II nllMIl i| Iim i|im|[i|iu| Ml iiimvmhI I(im Iiinn iif Inn iimrli ctuil TIim dull! n MmiI im lulu »t IIMH llV llllJIUillM UlM Mllll I'lllllMI* Iliunllll'l Mllll I VjllW MllMII lllUMlllMI wiiii m •ii'Ijik TIim ih'mnniiiu ihhv mm iIuhm liy |iIhii|hi&lt; I im \m mi •i iiililn ni' III it vh! Mini |iIui&lt;Ihm wmjuIiU nil Inii nf il TIim imimmihi will ilrwili NMli»fi4i'ln;'ily, linWMVMi', If Mm Imu In Iiiiiiw u|i uml Mic wIimv mIJuwwI In ilmi nlf 1 1 In iImnIi'mIiIm In miti|in Mm i&lt;nnl n(f l Iim iilnlli imiiimn|iiiimII.v In liruVMllI Mim i'Iipmnm limn lipiininii||( dry uml Imiii|iv VVIipii Mim riiimwi U wi dry Ihul mi innru whey U nililiinu nfi. nmIi In Hililml hi Mim chIm nf Iwn ninn no In Imii |himhhn il rluu'w Tim will In Mmi'iily iiiUml wllli Mim cIikmnm. TIim i&lt;Iimmm&lt; n I'MUily In uwi Ml nlirc 1 1 run ln&gt; liu|il mily u [mw iIhvn Imfnrt' I Will Npllll. Tlltifflll'Ki IIM IIMIIK lIll'IWI' nIiIIIiIiI III' lllll'lt 1 Ml "Ml Mini' I him I'Mll Iim iIIn|iiiniiiI nf III 11 fnw (Im,vn, WIimii II In put up fur iiimi'hmI II U winiMlliiiHN mmli' Inln ipiMi'lMi'-pmiml prlnlN wrMppMll ill | mi i limi'Ml plipi'l uml im dill AiinlhiT wiiy wlilch In mi'i'llnu wllli Mil' iippl'iiviil nf iminv pMl'wiHN In In inil II up In i hi illiniiiil Imim'h hi il&lt; It mm M ipim Iim nf m piniml Hpi'i'liil Imihi'm iiic miii'Ii' fur I hl« | m tr | m »«•*• A Nituill Hit) llhl t» NmiiCi'IihIi'I I'hi'imi' niny Iim iiiihIm hn fnllnWNi A ipmrl nf lull i In IiphIwI In 7ft iImuimiw riIii'miiIimI), Ailn iihm ImiiiMi nf N Jinilu'l IhIiImI iIInmiIvmiI III imiIiI wiiIim Km&lt;p Mlllh Ml 7n iImhiiu'n W imii Mini'iily i'HI'iIImiI, pniii 1 In n I'lnlh lm« mimI Iiniim up III 'li iilii WIipii Nil llti' rri'f mnJNlni'M Iihn iIcmIiimiI nit, nil* I'llMUMh NMll III ttiMHP il iMNlP, TllP I'llMMNM In MlMll I'MWllV fill 1 IIM&gt; pmwro chiih I'lmi'iiiii i'Iippn* In nmilp hy mlilim plim&lt;niiw with Amidi'Mii • Mi' IimIpJ M\mm, Friim "Mi' imir in iihm imiuhiI nf jiIihphUm In •uhVlPiii fiir \m piiumU nf I h« iiht*w* 'I h»&gt; plmi'iiliiN itm tlmi </seg>
            <seg id="p009">t'nim t'hmr-Mtilunt 9 Mhtliml lint' liy iiiiiiilnu Ihi'in Hun m fn.nl . |iu|i|imi I !•••« UN then • hunily hiUi'tl wllli Ilii' &gt; Iimmw. A kiiihII iimiiiiHI nf minimi imiI |II'|I|IMI ID MlltlMl|lllM« MlMl'il. hill mil' llll|«! I *• • lllhl'll mil III Illll •it Inu nun h ll Will IIMH'IIV* I lie iflin.'iilM , Im-&gt;«&gt;&gt; Iii iiiii || id, H ll flNlll l'llll|l|IM|' HflMI HlM |.lllllMlllim ItHVM llMMll l(l|«Mll Wllli I III" I'hlNWf! Ill Hl'lW III till lltlM, IliiWi'U'i, Hit' i iunnn |||||«I Iim wilil MW'iHM 1 II id Illll Mllfl wliMM WHIIII hnii'iilii iluuw U wiimmiI mi In miuI lll.i. (ml I mi 1 1 In H4|i»i&lt;lrtlW DiiM rm limklHN nMllilwli'llwt, VVIii'fi |iii| ii|i nil' initilo'l, Him Mltin Mini llf Mill kilKM* MIM IIMmI m fill 1 NHlfl'MMlPl l'IIW«&lt; Men HI»M Cluli Mltww i« im\* liv inuiiiM Ihii i mi mill wxI!:|||wiimi| " llMl|l|«r I'llWW Mlllll I|(M lilllHWM MMll HlH llllllMl •Illllllll llH llf yiiiiil nHViii 1 , Tilt* uligwf In hr«l Kiiitiiul Hum Iiv miiiiiium II ilun h riiuil liii|iiiiii iiiiMiifili iiiiiiiiiI ut Iiiiiimi In jlu.ii hiUmiI wllli m |nit)in nf ii|imhm&lt; If llin I'fiMMjiw I* iliv, II limy Iim iimmmimmo In m«m •I Illl M IMIHK lll|llMI'. Tll»« I'llMMUM MMll Illlllnl nllHllM |l|i HlHIlllv liilUMi ■ Urn iiiilliii niltimMl* Hum iiutiin i'i|ii Hun Hid fuml i Ihi|i|imi III iinli'i In hmiili }l|i iiliv Illllliw lull iiiiylil Iim |HmhmiiI .iihI In Mini'* lliiirnly mU I Iim liiiiim Mini n immum II I Iim i Iimmwi i* whiImhI urn miiiiIi, lllMl'M i« iUiiuim nf ila iiMiiiiiiny wifl imhI »l|nkv |l «liiiiiM, iliiiiiifnin, Iim wniltMil iiiily miihiiuIi In Iiiuhh ii|i mII Iim Illllliw, i 'lull i'Iimwmi lit VMiy Hum fur »iiiii|wIi|im» Ii him Iim iihmuiI lll«t' lull Iim Nliim II |« iIiIiih 1 1 nrilillMiy I'llMWMi ll "Imiilil nlwiiv» Iim mil mm wllli In mimI m iiiuknr* iiml mil hIiiiim |l mn iimiMlly In' iiiuiIm iiji iIimhiimi ill I limn ll cmm Iim ImiiihIh AMKNIl AN ( MKKMk ininil milk in iim Mini mmmiiIIiiI in M'li'il i Iii'I'mm I'lulmlily im niliMr ilnlcy ih'imIim'I nuiiilrmi u mImhmmi' milk him! ninm iMtfmil«*t k I'liiiinil nf iiMiiii'iiiiiiinii limn ilium i'Ihhimh Tin' ihiiwiii fur HiIn i* HimI iIimihw" iniikliiu Invnlviw m him liw iif fi'iiiu'iiliitlnii« Mini Miiy uihImhIihIiIm Inn ii'iiu, iiiIiih|iiiiimI llii'ii Him urm nf iiiii'Immh milk, will ili'vi'lup mill 1'iiimn 1 1 iiiiIiIh I'Hlii'i iim inn Him iiuiMiiu m Hu&gt; I'Uiliiit iii'iii'MM ThU I* iimllruliuU Hum iif iIimkmi iif Him full ' I "'Mill III' I 'lii'ililill I VI"' wllll'll IIM|lllli"&gt; ll ii'llillll ilt'HI'MM llf I'l IM iimm Iii Him milk liMfiii'M ll I* «m P'ni I Iim imihiIJiIiiiin iiimImc wli t'li Him milk iiiuii Iim wi, h iMiimii mcmIiIm iImkcmm uf Mill iiihI niiIIm iIm ii|i|niiiiiii« mi&gt; uniH IkiI in |iniiliiiiM uiiiiil ('IimiIiImc i'Iimmwi Hiiicm •in Ii it|i|nuHi u» U Imi'Miiu In iihimI fjtnn iIhIHmh, I Iim ( 'Iim»|i|mc i'Iimmmi Hfiii'WMi muni Iim miiiimwIihI MiMilllli'il My Him inmllfiMil (iriHiMM, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 t w.m.iih. /4iW/ri&lt;t&lt; A/11, 4f , (W^p nf A^lvulhrn fi|| ptcnllelll I'llMUMi limy I in produrnd III uny l.tlln .l.iln Wllll mil in no -mi t i.i s tif mhhIi fur Hililiiimml t&gt;i|uipint&lt;m I III' ni|lll|i|ll(HII Hllll MIMillKB Unwind Mil': A ViU ill MIIIM' imn|iuirln in which in »i'i i fin milk urn nnliimry ww«h boilm will wnu llif purpoaui, innilul Iwltlnln, vUww rlulh, H hoop nr mold ill whirl) In |iii'»i lliu (throw, 611111U itiiplluiicn wilh which lii i-iii llu - cllld, iiml 14 llleiiiiiiiunlci &lt;'oiuplelt&lt; iilllllU collluilliliu till (it i limit) uriicltM nitty liu iiliiiiinml from vhHiiuh dairy NUpiily him** fii H wry ruttwiimlilu iiricn. Mm wIiiti- i tin iiinmini ur nwmu U&gt; iv 1 1 mi In is vory biniilf umi iiiii'inii-ii only for humtt KonimmpUiin, ilu&lt; nwuwwry u|i|mruiu» nmy l)t&lt; im|&gt;niviiuNi from .h n&gt; !••« found in uny i i noune. lluvinu pruviilwl Ilin nwuwwry u|i|iuiulu«, Ihn n»Kl »lu|i U th* ■nlniiiiin ui i In' milk to In- uwil. OihhI vhwtm inuy be nuulti from milk i liui Inn- Imfii kn|ii In mi \'2 in 24 hour* In u god plure, but for I In- till m rlll't'Ht'-lllltkl'l' it in Mliilf Ullviwillltl 111 UHt* frwh, «WMt milk. Tin' milk Mhould be muled to N(l deurei-H Kulirenhujl, and eiuumli rellliel Miluliiin uddi'd to iiinlle llie milk in 1H or 2&lt;&gt; iiilliiileH, The reimel Mlluttun Illli.V lie |ile|mred by dlHMdlvinn ■ nit* niiiiiII rcnnel tablet in iine-finirth pint of cold water. Tin* iiuant It v of rennet solution In millleicni for about ei«hi kuIIdiix of milk! Aftvr Ihv rennet Milution him bt'en added lo the milk It nhould be ullrred nenlly for two or three mumuIi'k until the rennet In ilmiiih nnxed with the milk and I hen I'nvered with a eloth lo miilnliiln the temperature of the milk in the vat Tin- milk nhnultl mil be ■IIitihI or dUlurbed tiuitin until the curd in ready to rut. The ea*le*l and nini|ile»l inelhod of dclcrminiuy when the curd U ready for cultliiM, In by Inwrlltm the forellnner into the curd at a hIIkIiI anule until the thumb null louche* the mirfnee of the milk. A kIImIi) Hplll l« made In the curd with lh&lt;&lt; thumb nmi Hipforeflriiipr ft slowly ralnwl up thru It A cunl llmt \n firm eiioui/h for Immedliiie ciitlinK will imrt with a clean break leavimi ho iiiirlicli'n of etird ndlicrlnK to I fie llnuer or In Hie whey. Hi'tflilar curd knives nhould be lined for ciilllnu Him nod d ijlich kttlvMK nii'obtiiliiiible, became liellei h'nullf wlllbe oblnlned HUl niiv Mt her de\ Ice nmy be imed which Will ciil the curd Itito plMcM« of utilform ftlM&gt; wll'lioiii enmhlHit th** p«Hh'lw. I hlf \* n very iniportiini purl of ilu&lt; clte»w-tnMklnii «nd II should !»• icim-iiibeied Umi Hie curd |tni*l be HI I nnd Hill brnkeii, liecai|«c it ciitd I hul HHS imMti cllldliwl Io«mii it IrtfMi' Mltioiltil Of I he fM&lt; •■MMieiil ittaildlHiin lii Hil«, m btokflt eunl In mi i»tM«iiliii ■ llml Hif l)«Hli'iM« Will Hill Mill uniformly WHPH iHf t'Uhl IhIiHHU llHIIwl If mUM t'HWHN) MilVM Hf** Hill Ml HMHfl fllr I Hid Wllrli M Wire </seg>
            <seg id="p011">tm 111 I /inoi Mali my 11 »»w»ier wit It wiim» miih Imlf null H|mii nmy |»&lt; u««l wild Mil* III h m I rwiulU Wliuli'vur lip liinllinil ttf t'tilllllM, P*[e tthuwlil » taken mil Mi jttin ilu&lt; run I liy iwreluwily fnniim the (wife iulu I IIm- imiiixi muilim! itf iiiBiniinu ilin knife i» hi Ihv ii uir»&gt;» Me utluu of (he vul in w liuriimiiiittl |iiwiiiiiii. 1 1 u I hen litwereti into the ntnl tiy &lt;)i|i|iini{ Hie uuler en&lt;l inln the i-unl while reniiny the upper end tin (he wine of the v«i. The knife hImiiiM now h«- L. -t Kit. a Ty(i«i nf ItnlvM Iw t-ut ttn« ciiriln ■»inniliiiu M'liii'iilly In the vmI with the milpr pml r^llitK M (he liiilinm My hulilliiii Him knlff In lltln vwlinil lumllliin M IM« movwi Hip lp»i(t)h tif Ihp vut, thp ctinl In cut Inln Itiypr*. THp I'licil nlmulil lit' cut liuth li'ti«lltwl«c anil criitwwlw nf the vnl wi I hut II will lie cut Intii •mull ctlliffl t»f tinlftiflti *\tv ATii. i tlif i ulllny In ciiih|iIi&lt;IciI, Hit- cilftl miMUliI tM iillim-t.il to icmiilli HI|iI)«IuI'Iii.m| MUlllM fnl' wvctill Ililnulf* llv Hml Hitif Hit Clll-li iMIttlclM Will lie Illlll elinlipll Illitl Hie IIIMM ItlMV lie dllfMNI WllliOUl Ijf-MrtMMM lltHtJ. The IlitjMCl llf nllH-ltltt thl&lt; CIIHl lH In limit e MhlfMttt. HfHtl IhM hh»| Iti |tH»yt*Ml. Ine »'UhJ muti uhiIHiim lintel het In (hf iMiHitttt .m I H»« VKl. An I he ciihI In lieJHi njlitMtl I he leHttiet-Hlut-e mupi b* VImiIiihIIv iiilwtl In 'i« Mi' IIHI ilKMtfM FMliieiihell hhiI Iteiil Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p012">hihifinn Hulli'tm Nu. kf, ('"tiff nJ Aynrulluit 12 i hiii imiiiiI fni Ullm ■ ill! iiitiiiiii&lt;«* iiiiill I hr ninl |h Iliniiul «nl!ii ii'iiiU I'ui I lu&lt; Iiiiiii I'lii'iiMt-nittki'i', lilt 1 liwil iiimIIiimI nf ilcli'i inlnlnw whi'ii ilif niril I* firm pmiutfh U l»v iK'Ufly ih'mmImu n (IhuIiIm Immlful tut ii niiiMii'iil ninl llu'ii n|ii'iiliiw tin' limn I 17 tin' ciil'il iiMrllrlm fill nil) ihIIiiti' ilimi'ly Inil Iimvp n li'inli-iii v III lull ii|miiI. I !»♦• mini Id firm i&gt;iiimihIi miuI Hip whfy hIiuuIiI l»«* iIcmwii hi unw, Afici i lin whi'v Iimn Iimpm remiivfili i lie ciil'il niuiiiM lie hIIiiwhiI In iIimIm fur ii fi'W imiini'iil* mill IIiimi Ih&lt; linti«ri'iii'il In llii' muliU unit iiiiwmhI iImwii iililll I lin muliU me wi'll ftlltxl, A &lt; In iilm '""mil iir fiillnwi'i In |iliiii'il mi ln|i t »r Hie riinl wlilt'li In Hu-ii |ii|l &gt;i in Id mum Ifiii I f iirnMiit'i' fur ii In hi I mi hinii Im mui|illwl liy m liiiiiifiiiMilf Invfr |l y II* M IfM Ii ml 1 1 III I ii I lii'lil |h |I|'IHM, Till* |llim* I'llMdlMl* «lMI|ih •Itti i. liy ii hliiyi' lilt I lin ii|iilultl Ilinlii'i MllMi'hwl III I ll«' Iimmi Hi Iim IlinliMi nmy if I hi ii«i iniili'i it clfNl mi Him wmII In linjil II II IIIMI'f, TIlM HIWNM* Illlllll I* |llll«Ml| Mlllltll' I till HlllllKI Illllltll I Ui'¥¥ tm\ fiuiii Him mI]ni&lt;IiwI kihI hihI m )iliii&lt;h |imi&gt;fil nil ln|i iir I III* fiilliiwi'l, wllll I Iim Imvmc imhIIiim nil I Iim liliii'b TIim liMi'M«Mry iii'Mwiiirii Ip *ii|i|iIImiI liy IihiiuIiih n wmImIiI mi Him nulor fiul nf I Iim Imvw', 'I Illii whImIiI iiihv Iim ii liiii'ltMl nf hIiiiim ur Mliy ul Iimi •iiIImMm wkIiiIiI KiiII ihmmiiik I* mi|i|iliwl liy IihiimImk iim wmImIiI mi I lit* MilimiiM Mini nf In* lnv»r II II *»*v Mia M MtMUMMUlfl tfftUMMft MMMM I In MI'l I-M.1U IHMMIII I' IMMV lit' .IIII|||||m| ll </seg>
            <seg id="p013">t'llnil I 'hum Milk my 13 Wht'ii llif rluww litiM Iiwii ihmmhI fur mm hum. II aliuuM Im ii'iiiovt'il limn l hi' iimlil unit ilri-wM'il Tin 1 liiiiiilntiMH umm| In illimnllitf I'llfWi' riiimlnl lif rllii'xt'iliilll iiluilll I'lylil Ilii'lum wltlw itli'l Inliu I'linliull III tlOHf'IMIMll lilt' I'lll'l'M'llllil lll|l HVI'I' uilllUl IWII Ini'liM, mull Iniilm |ikii'&lt; nf rlii'i'ai'i'lnili Imviiitf ii illnitii'li'r n hilli )m» I him i In' i lii'i'W' Whi'ii I hi' rhiu'w In ii'inmi'il fiuin &lt; hi- \nv** II nliuiilil hf i|||i|n'i| lulu win in wiili'i In Miflfii Ilic mil ff mirfttri' mi Ihitl tin ninl iiiirili'li'K will I'i'iiii'iii iiii/i'ihi'i hihI Iimih h NiniNilh rind whvti Illl' ' ■MMI'W U | It 1 1 Illll It |h I 111' |lll'«« Afll'l lilt' I llt'l'W I III* tlfPM i|||i|it&gt;i| In tlif win mi wiili'i, Ihi' Immliiut' Im WfH|i|itxl miiihuIIiK itMMitiil ii with ilif 1'ilui'M fuMttl itfiiilv iivi'i ilif t'liiU of tin i'Im'I'-I' Mini n i III ||IhI ' ii|i I'llllll |iIih i"l lilt I'M' Ii i nil I In i Ili'i'm l« llit'ii ii'iiiiiit'il lii ilif imhIiI ninl |ini iiinli'i full ihi'ihiiim' fm Illllllll 'J4 llllllI'M I [■flllll KIM 4 Ililllllillll III .Hi ||| |I|M 'III lllHk lit' IK»H|Hlt&lt;l| lit illMMflllM »i|l|i|M« »»|Hl |l MMIIMIlt III t-Mlll* MIIIIIM I ll|..l,l...l WNtHr III llflli Illl «ll«|inili|w| IihIh* Mit'i ilit&lt; 1 lintmt' Iih- liiiiiii iiit'Mi'il fur U4 Iiiiiii'm 11 ■I11111M In 11 mm H limn Illl' Iimlil llllil Mitlltul |i|lllii|' liy lillililliu ill'V *nll nil Illl' hiiImIiIi' ill 1 liv ■"Mililliu III 11 «li miy In Hit' miliilliiii fm I wii Hit v- VMiilf ilif 1 Iihiimii U MmkliiM In iIiIm miIiiiIum II nIhmiIiI I ••■ lurnwl 1 wn \) lii nil ■ mill it III I lii Mtll a|i|liiltlin| nil 1 1111 imiiimiul Hill fin 1 Wlit'ii ilif mmIiIiih ihui'I'mm |m I'Miiijili'ii'i! 1I111 pnim |m cmmiIv lii In H'MiiMfiiri'Mil in 1 1111 1'iirliiM 11 *t it 1 1 I Ih&lt; 1 in imm cm iiii mIhhiIiI Iih Htii'li llutl fulrlv iiHlfniiii Mini mil inn Midi ii'iii|ii'iiiiiii'iw iiimv Iim mihImImIiiwI y\w Mir in iln </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 /mIhmihi) fhilhliii \m H, I nili hi nl \nnnillun 'Hi Him ihhIii ||ill»l. Iim I»m|iI IIIhIjiI In III MV Mill Him i.Iimhh. ill HUM mil I iiIimIiIkiIIIh ill* illlliiijIllMM hI mHllllHlliillM iiiiHmimi ImI|||IN|HIII|M« HMll |HM|ll'l limMlllH III Mil' Mil til Mlillll.lM iMitm - lllH imIIhi |r Him iiilml »iiIImIi|h |iImh Im miliiM Iniiil • Iimmw I'UII.IIH Mil' IM WMMk III' IWll lllH illi"«i&lt; «)|M III lie llili.nl 'I'llU NiMH, MM HlM Illll) to'Ml Mm i III liHMi I Him ii Iiiiiki I t »'i|ilHill&gt; TllI'MN IIIIII'm it WMMk »|ll lllt'l llM Mil lili'lll 'ililll I Mil lin illMMMM |l IIIIIIMll (I «lini||il |m mil nil u II , || M ,,,1! 11 11I I !»&lt; llMllll Hit Illll ll^llIM kHHIl lllH I Illll HjllMlll I Mllll ||l| Illlllll III III mi ilic Hill* ilf iif Him 1 lin»'»f il mIiiiiiM Ii&gt;i whuIihiI nl wild it wurni in mi Hiiliiilnii ii«iim h I'lnlli 111 liiuali In id'iin I it&gt; Him) "(in i|im»w)&gt; iiimiIk Iiv I til* in in i&lt;M 1111111I it'tnulii In Hit' mi Km rnniii Hi IhnmI »U hi i'ImIiI whm!»«, itfit'i mIiIi Ii II U imhiIv Chi huh MIM MMK I MUMH )&lt; IMWM \Mk iiiihIi hIIIIIIhI In ■Sun 1 linn MllMNM "Hi lie inii'li Illllll Mtllll IMIIh II U IIHI'HMHIV III HiMll|iMlilll' II UMMll llt'lll III rt lllt'l IIIMI'M'I, lll'ltlllMI' Wllt'll Mil fit l« |HM«'lll MIIIHImIi IIIHII' WltlKI iniial ) ■ liiiiii|ini|iii'il In IhKi' Him |i mi 1 )' nf Him fill I'iiW HiU l« mmiim 1 im ■Mm milk i'Iimmim will lit* mill iiih till In iiimMmm III* i'Iimmw, Him rMiii milk I* hIIiiwmiI Ii \m\m* iilniiml Mtiiii llt'ni lii nn ilMMit't'M Mini mill i mm imiiiimI Im iImI uIIr •■iilu'il Hi mill WMImI i In I'Hill M Mill nil" H mill' II I IM Il||l||l| |i&lt;IIIIMl In IImmiI, iilin iiiijii i. In HI) Mlllllllllf Milk Will lit' illllli hnl lUlf I'miiiimI mIiiiiiIi Iim llininlv imUmiI willi I im milk mill Hun Ihj lllllk mImimIiI ■IiiiiiI mmiIIhIimIii'iI Ini 11I11111I mil &gt;ni luilll' 111 illllll Hit' mi'l |m him I nl lulu i.iiIiii« wllli 11 1 lii't'w Itiilff, In Him •mint' \H¥ »■ fill' AmimiIi'mm i'Iimmmh HI i II vm»v mmiiIIv hii II v &gt; mliniii'* ImImiih' Him wIimv i|)lli'klv mill |i|Im Him i Iimmkm Hi mm «mih I it |i(Im h« iiihIIiIh nl niic Hill nf Him Mil III Ift Ml MllMf imiI liln litiy&gt;' iImiim* mihI 1(1111 llit'lii iivmi III MlinlliMi I mliuilim iiiiill Him rfi miiI II Hiln ■imhII |iImii'« mIimiiI iiiim Him 1 mhcIi w»k MImmi Wllll Hllll WMlH Mil ■MM III I III' Mill' n nun illlllll' I" (mil |ininiiU nf iIimmrm In tt fVw miIiiiiIm* ml liiln Him mIimmm* Illlllll* MUM |IIMM ■HMIM MM fill AiiHIImiII I'llMMf F MUM Illl* alHlt* mi Him |iihi&lt;m«i Im Him bmiiim hi fm AimmiImhii iIimww 1 MM MVtHtl lliHf I* iiiiimIiImihIiIm fnnil mihIhiIhI Nl IM Hit. wllM&gt; ulit'i I llMMMM HIM llMMM IIIMlll' fllllll Illlll*. Il (■ ('Ml lll|M| Mil llllll *lll'» l|lt« m null im f Him mtiil vmIi/m nf ■Mm Millk Him wIimv inninliH illllllll IIV» |IMI IMIH llf milk ■IIKMI, IIMHllv Mill' |IH "'Ml nl|n if iiiul iimmi y hII Him miImmihI mimiIh nf Him ml k In Nniwu*, •wmiIhi J»'MMiMik Mini In m ■immII mdImm! III iIiIm imiiiiIiv I ltl» </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Mimt'kmt- Mukttiu 15 WllMV l« llMlllM |IIM(Im HfH Hf II IIIHMlltf hllMHVH Iif H }l»n»|l I Him •Hill jnlliH M UIIIU ItMllV III « tllMMDH *H« H)I«|IIHM&gt; HIHlln fl Illll IIHMl • Illlll* WlllMM flVHN II M WWW ' Ihiimi IhUIIi; |i||||UMII| IIhYUI II I III* I-HIIMIIV, llMWNVMI'i II « IMMiIm I'HIIimU flMlll MM* '■ Illllfc I a»| t II llM« UlM mtliiM I ||Hliii I Ml m| }»i limit HUM H|I|IMHI'HH|IN Hill III) iMWjl In milllMWllHl tl IIMIHHI I Iim mm I* iml In mm I»miiIm I Iniinylii in h Imll Wiiliin h fluirl I Hum h W'Iiiii fill fill ill till Him finiMi m Till* |&lt;iiiiI»»Iiim Him iilliiiiiiHii hiiiI iiiiiiI i if Din ml HihI l» In I Iim wIim^ TIim mm \* ii'iniiiiMl nil mill I'tjii In Iim imI*miI *iiIi Him i |immhi. l&gt;|h i mii TIin miIIIiim I* Ilifii iiiniliiHMil null) lliHHiniiniil itf iikiImiImI M\ in Him ■nit' In niiU hIihiI iiiih Ililnl mI Him hiIuIiimI •iiiimiiiii ul »Iim ininti I lil« IIiiim I in mm inil«l Iim hIIiimiI m-nh mII (I m Hiiim It) |»'»»vkiI Him iiihImi hU iiitin liinniiiu mi Him I»mII)h, * ihIi mimlil y VM I IM I'llMMUM H IIIIIIMll ||)l ui| A I I III* HlllM HlM »l|il |I)|||||I» III Iim \/tm rihiIi) w miIiImiI Im Hd &gt; Iimumk hiiiI Him Iim I m WiH | IIIIIU Illllll I IM II IM III III Illicit Illlll || Will Illll IIIIIIIMI 1)1 Hi* IJII III Inn nimi'M nfi iv Hit* 111111111 III «i Iii Him Him i»»-i i » * IIimii Ih|«mii iilr Him Him hihI Him iiIimmnm |h nIIiimiI mill) II Iimmiimn* Iihi Hlil'lt III ■III HIIV IIHIIH II |l HlMIl IIIIIIIMll HiIm H *V Mill HI lm« "i Iihii»»I|. wIihi'm il l« wmkNil liv niMiiiN mI ii IhiIIh iiii I II I - i iiiiImiI nit If Ii I- i niili'il Inn i|illi I'U I IM HIMitl will I'lVfliillUM A rl mi wiiiloiiM nil iilniiil Iml/ mi limn , II h mil In m iiimiiIiI III n \m ilMVM Mm IiiIiimmI In y |||&gt; Him! |l i nil Iim ||nhiI Al I III* Ulllf II i HI) Iim nil illlll uiiv Illlll «lli'M« Kim hiIiii iif iiiliniml vhI'M* fimii N UmIiI \»\\\iw In m iImiI' IlI'MWII, llM|IMllllillM ll|lllll Ilin li'lll|iHiilHIM Ml WMImII lIlM Mlll|Mll|| WHU illllll' If •IMMMI if IIUMM MM I MM NMIIM'M ill Imill, M liulll MIlllllMll 1'llMIHM m\\ IMMII III flllk If I I* llMMlMll * 1 1 1 Ml 1 1 V llllllVM II Illlllll' Him mmmmrm will Iim ilmb In huh II l« immiIv in ij«m mImmhI Iim iii'illiiii'U ulii'i Iii'Iiim iiimiIm, ml II h-ii Hi H liili U ilmii|i iiImi •■ I I'lin Iim (imiiI fni' mmvmimI imiiIiHi* wlHiinil «|ni])int&lt; mi • •IimiimImw i ill HMV WMV II Ml IN Mill MHallv, IlllWMVMI \ uninl |||li|IIU ill M'IiihiiI hIimiiM Iim iimIIIihi iliv |hh i imtflit fl mIiiiii III Iim ilit HIMIIMI Hull II will IiimiiI lulu Illlll mIIi-hn, mill *Ml || dIimhM Illll IMVM MIMM NIIMHI |i||iIhIi) Hllll Illll MM MHIImHiI III MilllllX II Tl m Mull k IMvWmii nf Him |lM|iMilinMi]l iif AmiIi •i/Iimim hiimiiihiIi Him fiHiiwinv imi-I|mw inuilvlnv HIm h*m nf imIImum mIimmm- HIIMIHN NHAMl I | I ..in khlHHjr llNNIII, III MI|MUlllNlll HIIHIlMU Iif HHIlM llMM 1 mm mmt mm Iiim.I Hfiimlii Hull MmmIi Him Iimmiih mi iml Himiii I Inn u immhI m/IihImi AiM Hi. - lUrnm, Mini IiimmiI i&lt;imiiiIi* Miinntili In iiim)*m Him Mil»lnn&lt; -mHIhImhiU </seg>
            <seg id="p016">h.rliit»iutt liulhliti Nil, */, ( 'nlhyr ttl Ayttailliitt 16 ■ult in hit formal lulu m mil. link* In h miHlomio ovwi, Inwiiriy ii«'i&gt;Hiinimlly with Iimiiki 1 nr mliur ftti, timl wuImi Hwve with iiiniwiti NNUcf. Thin 1IUI1 nmy lit* li»tvor«l with rlmiiiiwl union* iiiiikwl iiniil U'liilm In liuiinr or mliw* f«i uml n vwy III tin wnlw FIMKNTO AND COTTAGE CHIMB IIOAfT y MtUful* it( I'liiikcil MniN Iihmii* illllMllll I'tlllMK** I'llWW ■ Miiiiuil iiiiimiiiiw p)iii|i|iwl llrxttil .■rumU Mi I'm Hi** rtr»i ihrnn iimrwliuiiu thru u mwt choputtr. Mu Untruly winl Hiill Itl'BUil rruinlm until it in HtllT uiumuli lit form into k roll, Mrown in ovon, lm»iinu cMrmtionully with huttw nr ulhttr (Hi, mill wulur COTTAOE CHKUK AND NUT ROAST 1 cupful puttan* ohMM I i»lil«i|iiMiii(ul ul imiii-i 1 cupful vhuppwj Knillith wnlnuu Juio* of hull » lamon I uuitful lirend nrumlw Halt »nd pappar •i uitltwpuonfuli uf uhopptid onion* ('ook the onion in the butter or other fat urn I a little water until tender. Mix the other ingredient*, and mointen in the water in which the onion ha* been cooked. Pour into a shallow baking di*h and brown in the oven, IMO-'IT- I0M.I </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>