<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00043.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00043.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Ninth Annual Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission</title>
               <date value="1918-11-30">1918-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 Ninth Annual Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln - Nebraska November 30, 1918 KLINE PUBLISHING COMPANY Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nebraska Public Library Commission M G. WYER, President Librarian of the University of Nebraska S. AVERY Chancellor of the University of Nebraska W. H. CLEMMONS State Superintendent of Public Instruction H. C. LINDSAY State Librarian C A. SOMMER, Lincoln CHARLOTTE TEMPLETON, Secretary JULIET M VORE, Librarian NELLIE WILLIAMS Librarian for State Institutions HELEN G. MATHEWSON, Clerk </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 NEBRASKA LIBRARY COMMISSION Secretary's Report The report which follows covers the biennial period from December 1, 1916, to November 30, 1918. For a year and a half of the two yean, we were at war and libraries have been affected in many ways by war activities. Libraries and the War Public Libraries have served all sorts of patriotic causes. The build - ings have been used by the Food Administration, the Councils of Defense, and the Red Cross, and librarians have assisted in the registration of nurses, the registration of women for service, they have acted as secre - taries for the Red Cross, they have had charge of yarn and hospital gar - ment materials for distribution, they have sold thrift stamps and bare distributed material on gardening, canning and food conservation. A number of libraries report a decrease in circulation, chiefly in fiction, because of their patrons being absorbed in war work; on the other hand they report the use of the library for reference work increased. In many public libraries war records of the community are beinfc kept in scrap books of clippings and card records of the men who have gone from the community into the service. This will be a valuable contribution to local history. As a special library war service, public libraries have collected, sorted, and prepared for circulation many thousand gift books for the camp libraries, and in September, 1917, collected over $11,000.00 as a contribution to the American Library Association War Service Fund. The libraries have also assisted in the United War Work Campaign in November, 1918, in which over $200,000,000 has been raised, 2.56% of which will go to the war fund of the American Library Association. Our library personnel has suffered from the war. Librarians have been drawn into better paying occupations and it is doubtful if we can ever get back librarians of the quality we have had until salaries are substantially increased. Public Libraries In spite of the war. more new libraries have been established in this </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 bienniuin than in any previous two years. Tbe townships at Ansle.», (larks, Orleans and Silver Creek and the towns of Cotad, Guide Rock, Hebron, Lexington, Morrill, Red C'.oud, Scotts Bluff, Table Rock, and \V\ more have established new libraries and voted a tax for their support, while libraries at Creighton, Randolph, Weeping Water and West Point, previously maintained by library associations, have been taken over by the cities. At Wausa, Comstock and Newman Grove library levies have been made, but libraries have not yet been organized. I This gives us 10S tax-supported libraries in the state, 12 of them K township libraries. We now have only one town of a population ,000 which does not tax itself for a library, and eight towns of a ilation of from 1,000 to 2,000. In two of the latter group, however, iries are maintained by c \.bs which will undoubtedly soon become ic libraries. The maximum library levy under the state law is 3 mills and 39 towns make the full levy. The average levy is 23 mills which is i mill higher than the average of the last biennium. A 3 mill levy in a email town is entirely insufficient and the maximum should be raised to 5 mills. The average annual circulation per capita population is 5, while the highest circulation per capita is 13. There has been an unusual number of library gifts. W. T. Auld of Omaha save to Red Cloud $20,000.00 for a library and to Guide Rock, $15,000.00. The library at Guide Rock is a memorial to a friend and busi - ness associate, and is known as the Auld-Doudna Library. J. M. Preston built and equipped a beautiful library at Orleans, as a memorial to his wife. L. O. Stcrest, of Hebron, bequeathed to the city 160 acres of farm land and other property to be convened into a fund to establish a library. From the will of Jacob Kent May, the Fremont Library received $500 00. L. K. Alder, of Ainsworth, presented the Alder Library with a $1,000.00 liberty bond. At Weeping Water the Congregational Church has presented an old stone church to the town for a library, together with 5.000 volumes, largely a reference collection which constituted the Weeping Water Academy Library The church has been remodelled into one of the most charming library buildings in the state. A business lot was presented to the Red Cross at Oakland and its purchasers gave it to the Woman's Club to be held as a site for a future library building. In addition to these gifts, the Carnegie Corporation has made the following donations: Ravenna, $10,000.00; David City, $10,000.00; Stromsburg, $10,000.00; Wymore, $10,000.00; Randolph, $6,000.00; Lexing - ton. $10,000.00; Clarks, $7,600.00. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Traveling Libraries. Study clubs all over the state have given up regular study work and have devoted themselves to Red Cross and war activities, and our special reference work has fallen off greatly as a result. The closing of schools and libraries of from four to six weeks on account of influenza, practically stopped our traveling library work for that period. In the winter of 1917-18 freight shipments were greatly delayed which was another source of loss of circulation. That, with these handicaps, the circulation has held its own with the circulation of last biennium. which was the largest circulation in our history, is a creditable showing. The loans have been more widely distributed geographically than ever before, and there is on'y one county out of ninety-three to which we have sent no loans during 'he biennium. We have added to the traveling library department 4.836 volumes and have withdrawn 1,149, leaving us with 19,719 volumes on December 1. 1918. TRAVELING LIBRARY LOANS FOR 1916-1918 STATE INSTITUTION LIBRARIES Report of the Librarian Incident to frequent changes and retrenchment In number of employees in state institutions, the libraries have suffered, along with all other departments, some lessening of service. However, in every institution there is an acting librarian giving supervision to the work. In some places, notwithstanding present economic conditions, the situation has materially improved. This is particularly true at the Tuber - culous Hospita!, where a change of location in library quarters, installa - tion of a charging system, and a librarian who visits the wards daily, have combined to increase interest and circulation. The work at the schools for the Feeble Minded and for the Deaf has been somewhat stressed during (he past biennium because conditions in iroups of Taxpayer* Other Organization* Requests Filled 262 Requests Filled Volumes Loaned 14,645 Volumes Loaned •ublic Libraries Individual* Requests Filled 244 Requests Filled Volumes Loaned 9,758 Volumes Loaned Ichools Charitable Institutions Requests Filled 390 Requests Filled Volumes Loaned 19,742 Volumes Loaned itudy Clubs Total Requests Filled __ 70 No. of Requests Volumes Loaned 758 No. of Volumes Loaned 4 M» </seg>
            <seg id="p006">t places justified a proportionately larger addition of books. No change acation in any institution has been more appreciated than that at home (or the Feeble Minded from an unattractive, inconvenient room lie beautiful library in the new school building. In the School for Deaf, the placing of groups of books in the school rooms has stimu - i interest In the library on the part of both teachers and pupils. I In the thirteen state institutions to which the Library Commission irnishing books, there is a combined population .of 4,692, exclusive mployees. Based on statistics given by the Superintendents, we find verage of 45% of these physically or mentally unable to read, which ices the number of possible inmate patrons to approximately 2,100. employees of the institutions number 640, thus making the total ing population 2,750. With a record of 44,912 volumes loaned during year, there is a per capita circulation of 16.3. ■There are 13,211 volumes in the thirteen libraries, 2,776 of these i been added during the biennium. There have been 464 books und. RThe Library Commission also subscribes for 241 periodicals for ve of the institutions. The periodical circulation is recorded only le Penitentiary where it was 11,291 during the past year. At the semi-annual conference of Superintendents of State Institu - tions in May, 1917, the librarian read a paper on Libraries in State In - stitutions, bearing upon their inception, their progress, and their prob - lems. Deeming the problems worthy further consideration, a Library Committee was appointed to make recommendations relative to library matters in the various institutions. This committee, with the librarian, met and discussed plans for the increased usefulness of institution libraries. At their request a second paper was presented by the librarian at the next conference in November, 1917 This dealt more specifically with conditions and possibilities in the several institutions. At this time, the Library Committee, consisting of Supt. F. W. Booth, School for the Deaf; Miss Lena E. Ward, Supt. Industrial Home for Women, and Dr. W. S. Fast, Supt. Hospital for Insane, Ingleside, sub - mitted 1 the following resolutions which were unanimously adopted: t "Resolved, That it is the sense of this Conference to recommend to Board of Commissioners of State Institutions that the Library be e a regular department of the institution and as such that a certain ified time be devoted to its concerns; that reports from the acting irian be sent regularly to the Library Commission, and that the srintendents incorporate its workings into their published reports. "It Is also recommended that the librarian of State Institutions be authorised to take up with each Superintendent library problems, as they pertain to the respective institution, and with each head, work out a plan of employing for part or full time, a librarian for each institution. (6) </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 "It is further recommended that considering the necessity of cur- tailing expenses during the unsettled industrial condition, if possible, no plans be made at the present time which would call for any addition to the pay-roll." In July, 1917, the institution libraries were represented upon the program of the Alienists and Neurologists of America, meeting in annual session in Chicago. The Nebraska institution librarian read a paper on the Library from the patient's point of view, dealing with books in the insane hospitals. Expenditure*, Dec 1 1916-Nov. 30, 1918 From appro- From appro- prlation,1915-17 priation, 1917-19 85.05 1.645"0 Extra Help _ -__._Z-_ - . M-JJ . 29? « Books, etc, for State Institutions 1,34695 3,067.13 Secretary 600.00 2.500 .00 Librarian ."." — 300.00 1.489.50 Assistant 'ibrarian - 300.00 1,500.00 Stenographer 1.803.13 $ 3.689.32 $17,950 31 3.689.32 Total $21,«39.«3 Appropriation. 1917-19 _ $21,600.00 Balance 3.549.69 Expended April, 1917-Nov. 1919 $17,960 31 looks _ •rarel finding Tinting &gt;fnce. supplies, etc _ | 114.87 166.68 492.11 224.42 191.53 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 c *-oSo~^ o -■ 5 Mlfili|iii$!{fJijsL ilfl^P^fst^sill Illllllllllllllllllll j r I I 1 o I : O n us : :i«B«e(H°ISS ! S3 S « : 5 ■ O -J rs ■ : K qo~ ao « &lt;D ao o w : t-" o t-" : m i i §r-n :»Mos«iouooaai-i&gt;« :m ! t-w :«"ioovu3vKc«cotaHa -in : Ii 2! ;ooo : p o o o p e p p § o p o o o :o ; w '■•. us . o«iai&lt;NooiaNKHNot :oo 1 , — :^ifi««Hifiaao«««eu3nttioN00ia — xbhhh — ' n" d" a&gt;" m' „" -*" ,H"e«r4,-r I IllllliilllllllJIIH I tiiiiliifiiJilliiiA! H»n«ia»t-aoAeHe«(o«io&lt;sb.«4keH </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 c &gt;» a c 1 I C— © :oe t iO O I *-» 1 i •'I :oo» toxneanti Mavnaoo c E JL! 3 » N :«I*O»» :*iee r- IS 2 n I- as Q- "5 N &lt;C :^ io" us - : t-' O* N« BI«HNf."» £ j &amp; 2 ° oooooooooo :eooooo Q a ! * : P *«®9 «&lt;=&gt;«=&gt;«! :=&gt;opoco Jr. 5 ° o cnooOAianotN o o ob o o o H S • ® :h«om»h»oh« o»S«tSt2S OC - « - - M ei rt" CM rt " «" CM o a. J* M :nmn» |«M ;•«„ f «•«»*«« p X &lt; lililfliliiliiiliifd Nl-lOlOb- cc 10 O o &lt;C O I— Li :— T . w — w. »~- w n w CMWTO)gD« |f — -r— «- ! liilliWllfiiiiili! ooooooQQSCfcCCfcCoeSooo </seg>
            <seg id="p010">! 10 . gg 8 iKIlJJtl Ilir-lh !*-« 11211 !«I i rf l If - I 10 ■«■ &lt;e {us^Tie : ■ t- i- :« cm &lt;o o o&gt; t-«=m joiiaoeo : : e* n : o» : oo m :«n m «-( *-t to f-&lt; &gt;h ct ■ il|i|l|i| 'I'illlll* tlllilil lilif liliitli c I : o» ■* oo '■ ; o : « : '. — e : o m o : oi ~* :t-^rH : :io : o : : o t- : O i-&gt; «d oa : *-&lt; ■* :oo«o : :oo : c^ : : oo »-* :Oi-c9H :o« : co e« : •" : to : : ci : V f-« : w* I I :0»0o : us O O O : : ~ - O : t- t- : o W os ~) o : oo ia o r- : : -. — :O t&gt;eooo :OO 1 s icidec ioNHx ! :r^O : o o © © loco C4OO :ou3Oh : :iav : ~ o o o : © m a t-_ * : o&gt; t- o ■ : w+ eo : &amp;z eq m &lt;c : « 0^*-*'^ ©J »fi f* f-T •&lt; '^T^ I ! H(o o* « r* &amp;$ r* ** r* ■ id" ** I I I I I I I I :••;••:;•••!■ </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 I | §1 IS L I L 2 33bss2ssssus il^SsSs I JSSSSSS : SS5? IS : &lt;: 9 iSS I -H | I :f^t*ie*4fH itoo^nee : : :«o : tar* g : oo m oo o qo :a&gt;o"&lt;ooo : : :S • t- o E ;»Nnnn »hiCi.«m : : : ifi — ac ■JJ | : «#f^i-&lt; '■ ri eiri : : : «-f : I ri 8 : h io h « h n o o eo io o : :oo : «e&gt; *q ' NC4* A N H H(Q N* N*H (DfQ : ' ' « *-■" V g ;§§§§§§§§§§§§ I i jS :SS aioecoooodoiood : : : : ted O :N&lt;sc4oou3OOC4Ok0U3 : : :*&gt; ■. ao o V H»»«NNrtr-iOtfiN» ! O :iAO = &amp; i * i [ i m i I # §uien«Nniee«eHt-er-««MeH« »eat-aaOHe9«xonu«itoas 5 OHt- OOO MH«00«CiNOHM«HCM jS &lt;© i-T V «O* Ol *J *J »«J *H VHHHHWIfl Cs| 3 £ El UN M in ii ill! ill I iffjlllliiililiiiiii 7. 22obooeuB.Sa.a.ft.sJB6«oBxo6oB </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 is .1 fi i i cs Bc|se||£Se|s^£2ga£ as aa's a ow_s 3 s S_a a « a_a 53 a e» r- : : o ai » :^ : t- :ant-n«« : : &lt;o I eo to : t-_ m_ »&lt; j *• : « : ia to o&gt; is c: oo : » t-V : : «i-r*a : t- : «' : Nt&gt;'nt*'oo : : ** I mo : :«»iooo3r»o»HK*»»r ■. so'" ■ oo us inftNNnt-nr^NUSBOOcnHion I I i |g I © o : : n « * « * - o io o « t- n /. » -- « "t 2 8 il I CO O O OO Oi : :OOOOcoo : o o o o o o o :o | o O O O E&gt; o O rooOOOOO : O : : : O © &lt;S r- •-« M : ?; o O &lt;© »o C-J :io ■ jAHtDO^OM : h 00 O O O c: &gt;O CJ at ■*3 e* C* C* Nn«n;iNr-MM | CC H K n H n « I teoo r-mo-«-miaoO'«'i-'&lt;e*'eio&lt;0'«'tot~i£&gt; * &gt;- &lt;e « n t- n [.^ a oo « t- u&gt;« co ■-• o t&gt; « M U 1 i ; h oooo |||t|l:|lll|||lll|l IllliiilliiiiJfilll Jiff IllllilllllillllHJ SS Vt*aodipH7'in^iA«NaoaoHi4N« </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 i j £E L Illl : ih : »- | | mo oo 55 UJ ! i is i» us is O i— i O O 10 a - -* g U NCIItM I J 5 11 &lt;e«o is H SO99TH PS y ""\ i_ [ill ■ 1 * flH till I </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 gill IllllillHI Hi ill i i 3 S"a I MM Mil Mil EL C o O o : o o : © © © O :O : S P *9 *9 :C ? C ! : °. P ** P :i 9 ' m a t-N* : ©i 06 : cc r- &lt;e ! «N : g in * ! OOOU3OU3U3OOO llfiO : Q — OHNUSOOON?^^ ! &lt;T. !£ : C r&gt;ocM*woccft-«u:v : X • ■ ■ &gt; 5 -^ I : i rt" ui — " »■*" •-&lt;" eq .-&lt;" n V i»i «s&gt; : I co i-T ~ en-. ccH^HHt-w : iijlij »]lilJ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 •Chiefly pamphlets and clipping*. SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES School Location VoU. Bellevue College Brownell Hall _ '' Cotner University Creighton University.. Doane College Franklin Academy. Grand Island College* Hastings College Luther College _ Nebraska Wesleyan State Normal School- State Normal School State Normal School .... State Normal School.... Union College Uni. of Nebraska York College Bellevue Omaha ........... Bethany Omaha Crete Franklin Grand Island ... Hastings Wahoo „ Uni. Place Chadron Kearney Peru Wayne College Vtew Lincoln York 6,750 1.200 4,900 46,000 14,015 6,613 «,500 3,000 10,000 4,958 15,000 27.418 6.700 7,000 138,500 2,600 Mrs. Bessie Johnson W. T. Klnsella Nora Hjeln Esther A. Beck Flora Fisher F. A. Linden May Ingles Mabel Harris Ar&gt;na V. Jennings Elva E. Rulon Jessie Jenks O. Q. Andrews Malcolm G. Wyer Mary Cave •Temporarily closed STATE LIBRARIES Department Location VoU. Director I State Library Public Library Com'n Legis'lre Ref. Bureau State Hisfical Society Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln 75,820 19,719 •15,000 66,000 H. C. Lindsay Charlotte Templeton A. B. Sheldon A. E. Sheldon </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>