<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production</title>
               <date value="1927-07">1927-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Eulletin 223 July, 1927 The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production T. A. KIESSELBACH, ARTHUR ANDERSON, AND W. W. BURR DEPARTMENT OF AGRONOMY THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Summary . 3 Experimental procedure . . 5 Relation of wheat yield to seedbed preparation ... . 7 Time of plowing .11 Depth of plowing- .12 Disking before and after plowing 12 Packing soil before seeding . . .14 Favorable mechanical seedbed condition 14 Listing as a means of seedbed preparation 15 Drilling wheat m cornstalks 15 Proportion of grain to straw 16 Effect of seedbed preparation upon the development of the plant 17 Relation of seedbed preparation to quality of grain 17 Effect on the protein.rontent of the grain 17 Effect on the milling and baking value of the grain lit Relation of seedbed preparation to soil nitrate development and moisture accumulation 22 Soil nitrates 22 Soil moisture .... 23 Interrelation of factors influent-inn yield and quality of grain 29 Seedbed preparation for winter wheat under special conditions 30 Test on weed-free new ground m a favorable year 30 Test on weedy old ground m a dry season 31 Results from tests conducted m western Nebraska .31 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY 1. The tin 1 / 1 and manner of seedbed preparation have proved im - portant factors m the yield and quality of winter wheat at the Ne - braska Agricultural Experiment Station. These factors operate largely thru their influence upon the elaboration and accumulation of soil nitrates, soil moisture conservation, and the physical condition of the seedbed at seeding time. The efficiency of weed control thru a suitable combination of tillage operations has an important bearing upon the matter of available nitrates and moisture. Weed control m itself is not, however, the only principle concerned, since different tillage treat - ments that were about equally effective from the weed standpoint differed decidedly m their effect upon the amount of nitrates accum - ulated. The type of tillage supplied by a plow or lister is ordinarily more effective than that of disking. 2. In a comparison of 22 tillage combinations during the 5-year period 1922-1926, early plowing on July 15 at a depth of 7 inches, which was followed by disking on August 15 and again just prior to seeding, resulted m a yield of 28.4 bushels per acre as an average of 4 similarly treated plats. The individual yields of these duplicate plats, which were located m various parts of the field, were 28.4, 27.8, 28.3, and 28.9 bushels per acre, respectively. The omission of the August disking m an otherwise similar seedbed preparation on this date re - duced this yield 6.0 bushels per acre. 3. Plowing 7 inches deep on August 15, accompanied by disking on July 15 and just prior to seeding, yielded 28.9 bushels, whereas omis - sion of the July disking lowered the yield 3.4 bushels per acre. In the absence of supplementary tillage to control weeds, plowing at an inter - mediate date (August 15). has proved advantageous over either earlier or later plowing. 4. Plowing 7 inches deep on September 15, accompanied by diskings on July 15, August 15, and at time of seeding, yielded 20.1 bushels per acre, while omission of the July and August diskings reduced the yield 5.8 bushels. 5. Disking the ground m July, August, September, and just prior to seeding, without plowing, returned a yield of 21.6 bushels compared with 28.4 bushels where 7-inch July plowing replaced the July and September diskings, and 20.1 bushels where 7-inch plowing was sub - stituted for disking on September 15. 6. Listing on July 15 followed by splitting the ridges August 15 and disking m September to level the ground yielded 27.8 bushels compared with 28.9 bushels for the highest-yielding plowed plat. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">i 7. Seeding between the rows of standing corn without special prep - aration yielded 17.1 bushels compared with 15.5 bushels on disked corn stubble ground and 28.9 on the best plowing combination on oats stubble. 8. The influence of plowing depth was far less than that of plowing date. It appears that under the conditions of these tests a gradual in - crease of about 2.5 bushels per acre might be expected as the depth of plowing is increased from 4 to 7 inches during July and August. In the case of late plowing (September) a depth of 4 inches proved sufficiently deep for maximum profit. Plowing to a depth of 10 inches at any date was not advantageous. 9. Variations m depth of plowing had little effect upon the protein content of the grain harvested. Interpreted m terms of similarly treated check plats, there was a slight tendency for early preparation to excel m protein content of grain with a maximum effect of approxi - mately one per cent protein. The increase m soil nitrates thru early preparation went to make a greater yield rather than to markedly affect the composition. 10. The loaf volume was approximately 5 per cent greater for wheat grown on land plowed m July and August than for September plowing. Doubtless the greater quantity of soil nitrates has led to the increased baking strength of the flour. Those seedbed treatments that give highest grain yields thru accel - erated moisture and nitrate accumulation and superior physical con - dition of the soil are satisfactory from the standpoint of crop quality. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Seedbed Factor m Winter. Wheat Production T.- A. KIESSELBACH. ARTHUR ANDERSON, AND W. W. BURR The object of these investigations has been to compare various methods of preparing the seedbed for -winter -wheat m relation to the yield and quality of this crop. Because of . the extensive production of winter wheat m this state and the high expenditure of time and labor ordinarily involved m preparation of the land for seeding, a study of these rela - tionships becomes important. The chief factors of seedbed preparation which are under the control of the farmer are time, manner, and depth of tillage. Plowing is commonly the basic treatment, and sup - plementary treatments such as disking, rolling, and harrow - ing are practiced m varying degrees. Sometimes listing or mere disking or some combination of these is substituted for plowing. Under some conditions, especially m the western part of the state, seeding is done directly into the stubble or corn field without preparation. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE Twenty-two methods of seedbed preparation were under direct comparison on the Experiment Station Farm during the 5-year period, 1922-1926. The arrangement of plats and their respective treatments are shown m Figure 1. The plats comprised one-tenth acre each, being 28 feet wide and sep - arated by 7-foot cropped discard strips. These discard strips serve for making adjustments m the plowing depths and other tillage operations that occur between adjacent plats, and also overcome any border effect that might result. Four similarly treated plats plowed 7 inches deep on July 15 and disked August 15 were located m various parts of the wheat field for comparison of results. Other treatments were unduplicated. The principle of replication was served m part, however, by rotation from field to field and by in - clusion of somewhat similar treatments within any one date of plowing. Twenty of the methods of seedbed preparation under ob - servation were m a 3-year rotation of corn, oats, and wheat. Three fields of medium fertility, lying side by side and sep- Acknowledgment is made to Supt. W. E. Lyncss for assistance m conducting th* field -work since June, 1925; to Professor J. C. Russel under whose direction th* soil nitrate determinations were made (Soils' Laboratory of the Agronomy Depart - ment); and to Dr. M. J. Blish, Station Chemist, who directed the milling and baking tests and protein analyses of the wheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 i i i i i — i i 1 i _S 7r 5,a"-"if «"- without Seedbed Preparation . l i I ' 1 i | I .'•* Dottle a .*«_■ fen STuObte ground __ Dou6/€ c.s.r. Jul. 15. Aug 1 . and 5.pr. 15. ) i J 3 I 1 1 ! , , .2- / t,&gt;4 Jwp^ 15 and Jt'.Q IS, ridges d-shed down Sept. IS. '. . I t , _ I 1 . 1 * 1 I 1 I 1 '.I Plowed lulu IS, 7 mches deep, double disked Aug. IS. i I I I I , , 1 , It Pic ea Seel 15, 10 in dew, double dislrtd JakjlStAifjlS, filed Sept li 19 Plowed 5epi IS, ID m deep, doublr disked July IS and Jlug. 15 , 1 i 1 i 1 )8 flowed Sept :'. 7,n. deep, double dished July I. eAug.tS, rellea Sept IS\ 'J Picked Sep* 15. 7 incites deep ■ 1 | 1 l 1 It pic*te Sip ' 15, 7 inches deep, double dished July 15 and Aug IS. [ 1 f 1 f I IS Plowed h&gt; pr li. -f inch.5 deep, double disked 'July IS cud /__ 15 J* p'ju-ra Juh 15, 7 imbti dap, double disked Aug 15 1 i ' 1 1 13 pto-ea Aug 15, 10 'n,hes deep, edited Sept IS. ... _ . f , /.' Plc&lt;.fd A uu 15, 10 inches Oiep , _ , ( , [ | ,11 Plata Aug 15. 7 riches ar ep, relied Sept 15 ■ 1 i 1 1 1 10 Plowed Auy IS, 7 inches dce/o, double disked JufrJS. 9 plowed Aug. 15, 7 inches deep , J8 Plowed Aug 15. S't inches deep | 7 Plowed Aug 15. . inches deep i ■ j i —l i 1 i 1 6 Plowed July 15, 7 inches deep, double disked Auy IS 1 I 1 1 5 Plowed Julu 15, 10 inches deep, double dished Jiue IS 1 i I r I v 4 Plowed Jul, IS. 7 inches e/eep I I J I ' ' 1 , , , i j 3 Plowed July 15~ } 7 inches deep, double disked Aug. IS , ! ! ! I Plowed July 15, S &gt;) inches deep, double disked Aug IS 1 1 1 1 1 Plowed July IS, 4 inches deep, double disked Auy tS ' Field 1 . ' ' F,.ld 2 ' I Field S . I Fic. 1. — Diagram showing relative location and detailed treatments of plats in seedbed preparation experiments, 1922-1926. In addition to the treatments indicated the plowed plats were harrowed immediately after plowing and Plats 1 to 23 inclusive were disked uniformly prior to seeding. Plats 1 to 23 were in a 3-year rotation of corn, oats, and winter wheat, while Dhe rotation in plats -24 and 25 consisted of one year of corn followed by two years of winter wheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production j arated merely |by 20-foot- brome-grass roadways, were used for this purpose. The fields were seeded respectively to corn, oats, and wheat, and all treatments were uniform within a field except for the wheat. For corn the seedbed was pre - pared by plowing to a depth of 5V_ inches and for oats by double disking the corn land. The basic treatments for wheat in this rotation consisted of plowing at 3 dates, July 15, August 15, and September 15. In July and August, the plowing depths were 4, 5i/o, 7, and 10 inches deep! compared with 4, 7, and 10 inches in Sep - tember. All plats were harrowed after plowing but varied as to disking prior to plowing and as to both disking and rolling thereafter. In addition to the plats that were plowed, one plat was listed July 15, followed by listing out the ridges August 15, and disking down September 15. Another plat was merely double disked on July 15, August 15 and Septem - ber 15. All plats were disked uniformly just prior to seed - ing, in an effort to provide reasonably good seeding condition. All plats were seeded uniformly lengthwise of the field, using normal seeding! practices. Two additional comparisons in a 3-year corn, wheat, and wheat rotation | consisted in seeding wheat in double disked corn stubble ground and in standing corn. The seedbed preparation for) the second year of wheat consisted in plow - ing 7 inches deep July 15 and disking August 15. The effects of variation in seedbed management upon the nitrate and moisture content of the soil have also been studied in connection With these tests. j relation of j wheat yield to seedbed preparation The annual and average grain and straw yields secured from these tests are reported in Tables 1 and 2. The various methods of preparation in which plowing was the basic treat - ment are grouped in the tables according to the time of plow - ing. The depth of plowing and all supplementary treatments are indicated except the harrowing after plowing and the disking just before seeding which were done uniformly on all plats. A separate group of miscellaneous methods of prep - aration is included in the tables. The four duplicate check plats which were distributed in various parts of the field are reported individually to indicate the degree of plat variability. As an average for the 5 years the extreme variation between these duplicate check plats was only 1.1 bushels per acre, which lends considerable con - fidence to the results. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Table 1 -The effect of time and method of seedbed preparation upon the grain yield of winter wheat. iABi^ . // / W22-1926 __ I Yield of grain per acre S plat Seedbed preparation --..--- —-- Relative W No' (Time and depth of plowing and other treatments) 1 . __ _ . 1 5 7922 "iTzTImT 1926 1926 A^ J^_ JK^ J9U_ _^_ JW&gt;_ _*____ &gt; ( PlowedJulylS , , .. - ,„„ ... , 72 193 28.4 100 100 100 100 100 100 R 7 In., disked August 15 (Av. all checks! 46.0 19-2 «•« ™ |»-^ | B 2 79 ,, 6 97 87 81 90 * 1 4 in. disked August 16 35.4 f-\ \\\ \\\ \\\ 27.6 81 126 108 98 79 97 "3 2 6H in., disked August 16 36.6 24.2 44.5 6.8 10 J g _ -g « 4 7 inches 39.1 }f« JJJ |£j l4 .£ 27.4 94 92 112 94 75 96 g 6 10 in., disked August 15 4_:.5 , "■' •"•■" lD -' „ „, g Plowed August 15 - 3g g 13 _ , 30 2 3.0 79 71 97 77 67 81 g 10 7 in., disked July 16 46.9 6.8 42.5 b.| |J.£ » 93 83 j^ gg 11 7 in. rolled September 15... «.G 9.9 38.2 4.Z | 7( . 9g 96 OT 12 10 In "\ \\% Hi 135 216 26.0 93 78 93 78 111 92 H 13 10 in., rolled September 16 41.9 * 4 - 9 J 8 - 2 I3 - 6 g Plowed September 16 „„ , .„„ ,„ , , 38 i 2 a 20.5 74 69 72 80 66 7J 3 15 4 in., disked July 15 and August 16 J3.2 U.J 29.4 3.8 |S i 74 ?g 5- g3 71 g 16 7 in.| disked July 16 and August 16 30-3 14J 32.5 11.6 jjj.l .._ __ __ 35 55 50 g, 18 7 '"".disked July 15 and August lib. rolled Sept.' 15. 2!U ll'jj 33.1 12.8 11.6 20J2 65 76 81 74 9 10 in., disked July 15 and August 15.. 32.4 2.8 33.7 4.6 3.7 |^ 64 _ 3 g4 „ -, g 20 10 in., disked July 16 and August 16, rolled Sept. 15 29.6 1Z_- 30.1 l».« .•-» _ _. t. Miscellaneous treatments ._,_,,____,_ ._ o ,79 38 7 17 4 20.9 27.8 98 93 94 101 108 98 [-. 22 Listed July 15 and August 16 disked Sept. 15 44.2 17.9 38.7 W.4 i g _ gg „ 3 5 87 76 __ 23 Disked July 16. August 16 and September If. 41.0 13.1 J1.4 »• 1 42 _,. „ 52 28 65 24 Disked corn stubble ground !*•» '4.5 *»■' |-» gg „., 46 32 90 72 46 60 - 25 In standing com ZUB o_i 01.. . z 3 C^A,yl5,7 in., disked August .5.. 42.0 21.7 44.6 MJ 17 5 28 4 93 llj 108 g£ g 6 Plowed July 16. 7 In., disked August 16 45.6 18.4 3J.1 0.0 iu.u gg g, , 03 j^ £3 _. IK_i_S;, 1 !:?iS::ffi£_i!5SiS::: *S3 ™ &lt;°° " : « *° :? 28 ' 9 m 89 97 122 102 102 ■In addition ,0 the treatments indicated, Thawed plats wore harrowed immediate after plying and P.ata 1 to 237^1^ ™^^^^ «vora B e yields reported 1„ Co.umn 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Bushels • • per Acre , H ■ m Mm m Fin - - ill 11 ii'iij.i i — ■■ — ■ — %--% ~~°^ Pig. 2.-Comparative yields from various methods of seedbed Preparation for winter -wheat during the 6-year period, 1922-1926. See Table 1 for description of plat treatments. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Table 2.-77..- effect of time and method of seedbed prepumtio,, upon th, yield of tttrair and proportion of grain to straw in winter icheut. l.&gt;~~-M~o _______ ~ I Yield of straw per acre ' Ratio, weight oi grain to weight of straw M Plat Seedbed preparation Yield ol straw per acr. .... gj No. (Time and depth of plowing and other treatments!' , j^. | |a _ ( j |i)2 _ j ( g 26 | Av ,. r _ K . 1 922 j 1923 | 1924 1925 | 1926 Av.'^ » P 7r. d dffid 1 August,6 ( Av. all checks, 3968 1922 2700 ,280 j, 557 |285 .00 | .68 j .60 .« | -74 M 1 4 in., disked August 16 ; 447 26..0 2741 JIM M I 6(J , H g2 .,g .61 .65 X 2 6. . in., disked August 15 _*f \_f f_f \ \*__ &gt;**, , H51 8I .74 .56 .90 .68 .76 .72 g _ .oln.. disked August. 5 366. 2080 3480 ! 1 .81 .209 2382,104 .70 5. -79 ...6 .,2 .69 g Plowed August 1 5 , 2593 1.006 1110 1754 77 .78 .61 .92 .79 .70 .79 _ ,S 7in:,di,kedju,y,5: :: 33,9 .297 ,656 2406 ,05 J, .75 .77 .75 .8 ; Z 11 7 in, rolled September 15 3983 626 2610 056 B4J *1« fiil 7g , 2g 75 g. .82 12 10 in 4'43 16 8.4 1U5 73/ _,, g , . ., gg _„ g7 Cfl 13 10in., rolled September 15.. ... 3476 1108 lhiJ J-i ■ «&lt; g Plowed September 15 , . . &lt;17 ,„., gu0 1372 60 .82 .74 1.0 .80 .96 .JO jr: 15 4 in., disked July 15 and August 15 2418 082 •■$ _" ___ ..g ft8 .,_&gt; .78 1.18 .79 .90 .91 2 16 7 in., disked July 15 and August 15 f|25 1099 647 878 80S !_» g| ,„ „ g .89 g !2 .!n:.diskedJu.yl5andAug.,5.ro.,ed S ep, 1 5 .094 .5.3 860 765 .294 57 78 .80 1.3, .89 .1 . _. _.' ! U !_::__„e_i-!.!Ian__u„^o„cdSept..5 __£ 'Si SSKS SS H82 65 .78 .74 .85 .76 .97 .8 g Miscellaneous treatments _ AQ 97l(ll ..i«a iooc 2310 101 .58 .71 .84 .78 .95 .72 H 22 Listed July 15 and Aug. 15. disked Sept 16 4600 508 2780 13.9 325 4 1U ... g . .. ?( . g 7 2 £ 23 Disked July 15, August .5. and September 15 3783 .16 »» » ■' -J"" 60 71 ., 4 ,., 9 .59 .39 .68 24 Disked corn stubble ground -™6 982 1495 W «•« ||»J ?2 _., 2( . 74 63 68 . 62 25 In standing corn I "" "■* H Check plats .,„„„ „„„ r ,nq i_rb 1650 2376 104 .66 .50 1.09 .72 .64 .Ii _S 3 Plowe. July 15. 7 in., disked August 15 3822 260o 24 19 .186 60O AWg iu ._ 6 Plowed July 16. 7 in., disked August 6 3661 ||64 3 11 58 .w -4 G4 , „ 79 .71 .78 [O It SSgSg^?fc.!SSi3Si5: pi }?« 88 !£ i«3 •» .02 .65 .73 .•» .» .82 .74 » ■In addition to STt^iSSuT^Sud: the plowed pTats SS^^dTn.medi.te.y «ft W Plow.,. end P..t. I to 28 .nc.ua.ve were disked uniformly prior to seedinit. . . 'These ratios are based on the averaue grain and straw yields. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production TIME OF PLOWING The time ofi plowing proved to be an important factor in the yield of -winter wheat. Late plowing, especially, was at a marked disadvantage compared with early and medium late dates. A number of 5-year, average comparisons may be made which are strictly comparable except as to date of plowing (Table 3). 1 Where there was no supplementary disking, plowing at a depth of 7 inches on September 15 yielded 14.3 bushels per acre compared with 25.5 bushels for August 15 and 22.4 bushels for July 15 plowing.- The superior yield of August 15 over July 15 plowing was doubtless due to somewhat more effective weed control in the absence of timely supplementary tillage. . In the case of 7-inch plowing, which was either preceded or followed. with the disk, the September 15, August 15, and July 15 plowihgs yielded respectively 20.1, 28.9, and 28.4 bushels per acre. Averaging the above comparable cases with and without supplementary! tillage, September plowing yielded 17.2 bushels, August plowing 27.2 bushels, and July plowing 25.4 bushels per acre. Tabus 3. — Effect of time of plowing upon the grain yield of winter wheat, 5-year average. 1922-1926 Date of plowing Soil treatment Sept 15 Aug. 15 July 15 Bushels Bushels Bushels I - • Plowing alone 7 indies 14.3 25.5 22.4 Plowing 7 inches and disking 20.1 28.9 28.4 Average....| 17.2 27.2 25.4 It would seem from these results that in a system of good seedbed management, plowing may extend over a period of 5 or 6 weeks after harvest, or until about August 15 under eastern Nebraska conditions, provided the plowing is ac - companied by timely supplementary disking. ' ■' '■'.' </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 DEPTH OF PLOWING The depth of plowing did not prove to be as large a factor in yield per acre as did the date, but a certain degree of consistency is seen in the data favoring a medium depth for farm practice. Comparable data are summarized in Table 4. Land plowed on July 15 at the respective depths of 4, &amp;/%, 7, and 10 inches, followed by disking August 15, yielded 25.7, 27.5, 28.4, and 27.4 bushels per acre, respectively. When plowed on August 15 at the depths of 4, 5V&amp;, 7, and 10 inches, without supplementary treatment except disking at seeding time, the yields were 23.0, 24.8, 25.5, and 27.2 bushels per acre, respectively. Plowed on September 15, and preceded by July and August diskings, the 4, 7, and 10 inch plowing gave the respective yields of 20.5, 20.1, and 21.4 bushels per acre. By averaging these July and August data, the " Law of Diminishing Returns " is fairly well demonstrated. Starting with a basic depth of 4 inches, increasing the depth by 1.5, 3, and 6 inches increased the grain yields 1.8, 2.6, and 2.9 bushels per acre, respectively. One could well afford to in - crease the plowing depth from 4 up to 7 inches to get 2.6 bushels more wheat, but not from 7 up to 10 inches just to get 0.3 bushels more. Table 4. — Effect of depth of plowing upon the grain yield of winter wheat, 5-year average. 1922-1926 Depth of plowing Date of plowing 4 in. 55 in. j 7 in. 10 in. I Bushels Bushels I Bushels Bushels September 15 20.5 | 20.1 21.4 August 15. 23.0 24.8 25.5 27.2 July 15. 25.7 27.5 | 28.4 27.4 Average July and August I 24.4 26.2 27.0 27.3 Average July, August and September. . 23.1 24.7 25.3 DISKING BEFORE AND AFTER PLOWING One of the most striking features of seedbed preparation developed by these investigations is the great value of well timed disking supplementary to the plowing. The objects of such additional tillage are weed control, accumulation of soil </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production moisture and available soil fertility, compacting of the soil, and improvement of the physical condition of the seedbed. These are all conducive to prompt and uniform germination, vigorous seedling growth, abundant stooling, extensive root development, and superior winter endurance. A number of {comparisons (Table 5) are possible in which the methods of j preparation were identical except as to the matter of disking either before or after plowing. Land plowed 7 inches deep July 15 followed by disking August 15 yielded 28.4 bushels compared with 22.4 bushels without the disking. Table 5. — Effect of disking before or after plowing upon the grain yield of winter wheat, 5-year average. 1932-1926 I Depth Date of plowing of Disked ' Yield per plowing acre Inches Bushels September 15 1 Not disked 14.3 September 15 7 July 15 and August 15 20.1 Increase due to disking 5.8 August 15 . . 3 7 Not disked 25.5 August 15 7 July 15 28.9 Increase due to disking 3.4 July 15 | 7 Not disked 22.4 July 15 i .... J 1 August 15 28.4 Increase due to disking ■ 6.0 Plowing 7 inches deep on August 15 preceded by disking July 15 yielded 28.9 bushels as against 25.5 bushels when the disking was omitted. Plowing 7 inches deep on September 15, preceded by disk - ing on both July 15 and August 15, yielded 20.1 bushels i compared with 14.3 bushels without the disking. September 15 disking without plowing yielded 1.5 bushels more (Table 6) than September plowing 7 inches deep, when both were preceded by July and August disking. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 These results indicate that one disking after early plowing and one or two diskings before later plowing are worth from 3.4 to 6 bushels per acre. Tamlk W.—Late plowing vs. disking for winter wheat. 5-year average. 1922-1926 Plowing Disking Yield per acre Bushels Plowed September 15 July and Aug. 20.1 Not plowed July, Aug. and 21.6 September PACKING SOIL BEFORE SEEDING It is the common experience of wheat growers that winter - killing is less likely to occur on a compact than on a loose seedbed. Artificial packing by either disking or rolling in the absence of natural settling by rains is recognized as a good practice. This is especially true of late plowing. Fail - ure to increase yields in these experiments by rolling in Sep - tember is accounted for by the fact that all treatments in - cluded disking just before seeding and this served to settle the ground. FAVORABLE MECHANICAL SEEDBED CONDITION The uniformity of seed germination, thrift of seedling growth, and favorableness of stand may be greatly influenced by the physical condition of the seedbed. Dry, cloddy, loose soil is unfavorable. Such a condition is sometimes unavoid - able but may often result from poor seedbed management; as, late preparation, and failure to work down the ground with suitable tillage implements. Harrowing after the plow before the soil has time to dry out is beneficial under most circumstances. Weed growth, either before or after plowing, tends to dry out the soil and should be prevented. Retarded fall development of the wheat due to a poor physical condi - tion of the seedbed at the time of seeding mav result in a material reduction in yield. As shown in Table 9, September plowing resulted in ap - proximately 10 per cent reduction in stand of plants, and strikingly reduced the number of stools, per plant as compared with July and August plowing. As a result of </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production reduced germination and stooling, the wheat on September plowing averaged only two-thirds as many heads per unit area of land as did the July plowing. LISTING AS A MEANS OF SEEDBED PREPARATION [ In some sections of the Middle West, listing is used as a basic method for preparing wheat land. The plan is to single list as soon as possible after harvest for the purpose of weed control and the conservation of soil moisture and available fertility. Somewhat later these lister ridges are worked down and the land is levelled by means of disk or cultivator. j Occasionally, as was the case in these experimental tests, the procedure followed is to single list in the middle of July, split the ridges with a lister in the middle of August, followed later by disking japd harrowing. It is not known how the particular method employed in these Experiment Station tests would compare in yield with other modifications of the system. Table 7. — Listing as a seedbed preparation for winter wheat, 5-year average, 1922-1926 Listing or plowing Disking Yield per acre Bushels Listed July 15 and August 15 September 15 27.8 Plowed July 15 ■ - August 15 28.4 During the 5-year period 1922-1926 (Table 7), land that was listed on Juiy 15 and had the ridges split with the lister August 15, followed by disking September 15, yielded 27.8 bushels per acre compared with 28.4 bushels for land plowed 7 inches deep July 15 and disked August 15. DRILLING WHEAT IN CORNSTALKS In order to bring about a change from corn to small grain in the rotation, it is rather customary to seed oats on corn ground. The same purpose may be accomplished by seeding winter wheat with a one-horse drill between the rows of standing cornstalks. In case of corn that is cut for silage or fodder, the land may be disked before seeding. As a substitute for bats, winter wheat yields secured in this manner may be compared with those of oats. On the other </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 hand, as an alternative method of growing winter wheat, the yields should be compared with those of wheat produced by standard methods. In these tests (Table 8) which were made in part during a series of unusually dry years, wheat drilled between rows of standing stalks without other preparation yielded 17.1 bushels per acre as compared with 25.9 bushels for oats. In a similar comparison, wheat on disked corn land yielded 15.5 bushels. The standing stalks doubtless resulted in highest yield because of their tendency to catch snow. These yields are comparable with 28.4 bushels for land plowed 7 inches deep in July and disked in August. While wheat seeded on stalk land was far less productive and profitable than wheat on plowed oats stubble, it proved more profitable than oats during these relatively dry seasons. Table S. — ,SVv d'nuj wheat in cornstalks. 5-year average, 1922-1926 St Where seeded Yield per Yield of oats acre in comparison Bushels Bushels e Standing stalks 1 7. 1 Disked stalks 15.5 25.9 Oats stubble plowed 7 inches deep, July 15, disked August 15 2.S.4 PROPORTION OF GRAIN TO STRAW Some interest attaches to the relation of cultural practices to the ratio of grain to straw. Straw yields were determined in connection with all of these seedbed practices, and the results reported in Table 2 indicate these yields as well as the ratio of grain to straw. In connection with the dates of preparation, all of the July-plowed plats averaged 70 per cent as much grain weight as straw weight; all August - plowed plats averaged 80 per cent as much grain as straw weight, while all of the September-plowed plats averaged nearly 90 per cent as much grain as straw. The general in - dication would seem to be that delayed plowing reduces the rankness of vegetative growth, thereby increasing the pro - portion of grain to straw. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">' . ' • The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production effect ofj seedbed preparation upon the development of the plant It is of interest to note the effect of the various seedbed preparation treatments for winter wheat upon the growth of the crop. Such data pertaining to plant development have been summarized jin Table 9. Tho these data do not indicate a marked difference in heading date, date ripe, or plant height, there was a slight indication that conditions which retard fall growth, such as late seedbed preparation, tend to delay the date of j heading and ripening and result in some - what shorter straw. These differences are most apparent ' early in the season and tend to disappear as the season ad - vances and the grain matures. . Stand counts at harvest showed that early plowing and favorable seedbed; conditions resulted in a somewhat thicker stand and more stooling. As a 2-year result, 5 July plowings averaged 9.8 mature plants per foot of drill row compared with 9.5 and 8.6 (plants per foot for 6 August and 3 Sep - tember plowingsj respectively. Stools per plant averaged 2.9, 2.4, and 2.1 for July, August, and September plowings. RELATION OF SEEDBED PREPARATION TO. QUALITY OF GRAIN In order to study the quality of the grain produced by different tillage treatments, annual protein determinations were made for the grain from each plat and the wheat from 8 distinct treatments was subjected to a standard milling and baking test. These data are reported in Tables 9, 10, and 11 for the period 1922 to 1926. EFFECT ON THE PROTEIN CONTENT OF THE GRAIN The 5-year average, 1922-1926, protein content (13.5 per cent moisture basis) of the wheat produced from the plats comparing the various seedbed preparation treatments is re - ported in Table 9.; An average of 5 methods involving July plowing shows a protein content of 12.6 per cent as com - pared with 11.8 per cent for 7 August-plowed plats and 11.0 per cent for the 6 September-plowed plats. Comparing the average of the 6 September plowings with the average of the two check plats located on either side plowed in July, the September group was 0.8 per cent lower in protein than the July. These data j indicate that early plowing as compared with late plowing on soil of medium fertility may be expected to produce wheat j with somewhat higher protein content. Interpreted in terms of the check plats, a maximum difference </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Tahlk 9.-77,, effect of time and method of seedbed prr/mvat; th, ,,l„„t ,U relopment &lt;&gt;f winter wheat. ...... 2 -.- - 2-year average *T ! :,.. , rw - isoa-im*. .i9»i-im)__ g Yield per Weigh! IT.- I'l»m« Stnlka I Stools p Plat Seedbed preparation I '"" ... h , _,. r ,. ,,t tein ' peril. peril. P« CO No (Time and depth ..( plowing and other treatment-! »"« lmsh( .| ,„ row row plant _- h'u.l , ' Straw Cram «™" 1 ' ► .'lowed July IS , ... - , :(,,« -.-is.-, 2S.I n9.n li.l i ... t_ 5 10 in., disked August 15 I , ... a a 2_ n 2 4 Z Plowed August 15 , ! , ; .„, 27 ., , 7 ;,l I 2:1.0 . ». 5 I • • »•» |*° 2.J 7 4 in. 7 h ;„, _«.i iiw 21.8 -&gt;!'. - *■' T,i' i _ :1 8 S!_in Ii ;; : |;; a,., .947 25.5 59.6 2.2 »-» g-J _f Cfl 9 'in. ;| :.(&gt;.« 2406 28. 9 «.• •' -J ,_ o.. V 25 ._ 10 7 in., disked J.ily 15 i : ,' ; „ : „, ,-, _i il 27.7 5».« .9 »--» «- 7 z - 0 &gt; 11 7 in., rolled September 15 ; - , ; ,„ 4 ,.90 27.2 MM &lt;&gt; ., i B , 26 H 12 JOin ...... I , .J T | .iti.o 1796 26.0 60.0 H..1 ■&gt;■■' -■&gt;■■&gt; g 18 10 in., rolled September 15 ,, ' 2 4 12 Plowed September 15 6.71 28.11 1:172 20.5 60.2 11.0 8.4 iO._ *•• .&lt;=. 15 4 in., disked July 15 and August 15 | Jj ■ - 2S , 1:1: |„ | 20.1 Ml. -&gt; . ,^ 16 7 in., disked July 15 and August 15 • i .,,. „ ,„;,; 14.3 60. _■_ \_* fj CO 17 7 in ... !: ! - . ■&gt;« fi 1294 20.2 60.1 11. 1 •*•' i«.i _, 18 7 in* disked July 15 and Aug. 15. rolled Sept. 15 64 , . , - g |r . 7 2| . , 6() 5 1 0.7 P 19 10 in., disked July 15 and August 15 ..,,,, '■ , -, j 29 2 1482 20. 1 ; 60.5 .0.9 _~ 20 10ii.. disked July 1 5 and Aug. 15, r. d Sept. 15 i ; H Miscellaneous treatment, ._.,.,.-.„.,, 6 | 71 '31.8 2.110 ! 27.8 , 60.1 1.4 10.0 2o.8 |.o Q 22 List, d July 15 and August 15. disked Sept 15 J 2 „ , 79s , 2 1.6 | BO.O I 10.8 r.9 U..1 g 23 Disked July 15. August 15. and September I.. i| 27 , 1:16:1 15.5 j 58.6 11.0 24 Disked corn stubble ground ( . . - ., 2N ,j | |655 : 17.1 | 59.7 Il.J 25 In standing corn ... _,.,,. q n 29 n :l.2 £_ Check plat. ,. , . , ,,. (i .;, ti :,„ 30.8 ! 2:176 | 28.4 58.5 2.6 9.0 2J.0 M 3 Plowed July 15, 7 in., disked Augus t 16 '. -, .,, KH 22 50 I 27.8 .ifl.3 20 6 Plowed July 15. 7 in., disked Augus .. 63 7 1 i 30.8 2180 , 28.3 I ;»» 2-2 14 Plowed Julyl5, 7 in., disked August 15 B4 7 1 ! 31.6 , 2334 28.9 i 60.2 HI . 21 Plowed July 15, 7 in., disked August 15 II I _J ' 'Protein calculated on 13.5 per cent moisture basis. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production . - of approximately! 1.0 per cent protein was brought about by the" best compared with the poorest treatments. Variation in the depth of plowing, or in the amount of disking and packing in addition thereto, had no marked effect on the protein content of the grain. Wheat produced on the listed plat had an average protein content of 11.4 per cent compared with that of 10.8; per cent for the disked plat, whereas that from the disked corn and standing corn plats averaged 11.0 and 11.4 per cent; respectively. . EFFECT ON THE MILLING AND BAKING VALUE OF THE GRAIN Milling and baking tests were made during the 5-year period 1922-1926, to determine the effects of the time of plowing upon the milling and baking qualities of the wheat. The milling samples were made up as follows: (1) wheat composited in equal amounts from plats 6 and 14, plowed July 15 and disked August 15; (2) wheat from plat 4, plowed July 15; 1(3) wheat mixed in equal amounts from plats 9 and 11, plowed August 15; (4) wheat composited in equal amounts from plats 16 and 18, plowed September 15 and disked July 15 and August 15; and (5) wheat from plat 17, plowed September 15. These plats were all plowed 7 inches deep and in addition to the treatments above indicated were harrowed immediately after plowing and disked uni - formly just prior to seeding. The annual and average results are reported in Table 10. In addition to 'wheat from these date-of-plowing treat - ments, grain from three other treatments was milled during 4 years as follow^: (1) plat 22, listed July 15, ridges listed out August 15 and disked down September 15, (2) plat 23, double disked July 15, August 15, and September 15, and (3) plat 25, wheat seeded in standing corn, (Table 11). Among the desirable qualities sought in milling and baking are: (1) high percentage of flour, (2) high water require - ment in the dough which reflects economy of flour in bread making, (3) large loaf volume which is an expression of " strength " in the flour, and (4) fine texture and light color of the bread. ; - ■• Aside from the protein content and loaf volume, the milling and baking qualities of the wheat were but little affected by the various seedbed preparation treatments. As a 5-year average, 1922-1926, the plats plowed July 15, August 15, and September 15 produced wheat which, when milled and baked, had a loaf volume of 2,010", 2,014, and 1,916 cubic centi- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 meters, respectively. Corresponding results for the July - plowed plat which was disked in August, and the September - plowed plat disked both in July and August, were 2,044 and 1.924 cubic centimeters, respectively. Tabi.k 10. — The effect of the time of plowing upon the milling and baking value of winter wheat. 1922-1926 j drain i Straight Hour Baking results Year ' ■ - , 1 — : I Yield I Weight I Protein | Ash | Per Dough Loaf Bread per per (13 _ I content I cent ■ i acre ; bushel per cent i Water Volume Color Texture moisture) i ab - i ' sorption IlushiU \ I'ouniU I Per rent 1'er rent I Percent C.c. Percent Percent (1) I i2&gt; I r .-I , I id (5) I (6) I (7) (8) (9) (10) PLOWED JULY 15. 7 INCHES DEEP. DISKED AUGUST 15 (PLATS 6 AND 14) 1922 I I5.fi : 56.(1 I 12.8 .39 \ 61.6 . 64 1,960 96 97 192-.1 18.9 58.0 | 12.4 .40 ! 63.8 68 2,250 98 98 1924 39.9 | 61.0 I 10.2 .39 ' 64.1 67 1,850 97 . 98 1925 I 15.8 60.(1 j 11.9 .44 j 6:1.5 . 66 2,030 98 99 1926 | 20.0 j 62.0 | 13.0 | .40 | 63.2 66 2,130 98 100 Average ] 28.0 I 59.4 | 12.1 1 .40 j 63.2 66 I 2,044 97 93 PLOWED JULY 15, 7 INCHES DEEP (PLAT 4) 1922 39.1 i :,7.o \ 13.0 l .39 I 63.2 I 64 | 1,920 I 98 96 1923 ' 1H.5 ! 57.0 12.1 I .43 I 63.2 | 64 2,000 98 100 1924 30.7 61.0 | 9.8 I .39 ' 66.3 | 66 1,890 98 98 1925 ] 11.9 58.5 13.7 I .42 61.2 65 2,010 98 100 1926 I 9.0 ! 60.0 ■ 14.0 j .44 | 63.2 \ 67 | 2.2:10 I 99 102 Average I 22.4 I 58.7 I 12.5 I .41 I 63.4 i 65 1 2.'O10 I 98 99 PLOWED AUGUST 15. 7 INCHES DEEP (PLATS 9 AND .1) 1922 J5.fi I 57.5 I 13.3 .37 I 63.3 I 65 1,850 I 96 94 1923 16.8 | 58.0 | 12.1 .44 I 63.8 , 66 2,240 i 98 98 1924 37.9 i 61.0 9.9 .37 I 62.6 66 1,800 98 98 1925 14.0 60.5 J 11.7 .15 63.0 65 1,980 98 100 1926 18.8 | 61.0 | 13.2 .37 63.0 65 2,200 98 100 Average | 26.6 I 59.6 I 12.0 .40 I 63.1 I 65 | 2,011 98 98 PLOWED SEPTEMRER 15, 7 INCHES DEEP. DISKED JULY 15 AND AUGUST 15 (PLATS 16 AND 18) 1922 I 29.7 I 58.0 12.1 .36 63.8 | 65 1,810 97 94 1923 I 14.4 \ 58.5 11.7 .39 61.4 66 2.110 97 97 1924 32.8 . 61.0 9.7 .34 62.1 65 1,830 98 98 1925 1 12.2 ! 61.3 11.5 .46 64.9 65 1,920 97 100 1926 j 11.9 I 61.8 11.0 .40 61.8 65 1,950 98 100 Average i 20.2 I 60.1 I 11.2 I .39 63.4 I 65 1.924 97 98 PLOWED SEPTEMBER 15, 7 INCHES DEEP (PLAT 17) 1922 18.6 I 58.0 I 11.2 .38 63.8 64 1,880 97 95 1923 11.9 I 58.6 11.8 .42 64.9 64 1,930 98 97 1924 24.2 ! 61.0 I 10.2 .36 62.3 65 1,800 98 100 1925 6.1 ! 61.5 11.1 .48 63.4 65 1,970 98 100 1926 10.6 | 61.5 I 1 1.0 .42 64.4 65 2.000 98 100 Average 14.3 I 60 1 j 11.1 .41 63.8 65 1,916 98 98 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production As a 4-year average the loaf volumes obtained for the mis - cellaneous treatments were as follows: (1) the July-plowed and disked plats, 2,093 cubic centimeters, (2) the listed plat, 1,875, (3) the disked plat, 1,950, and (4) in standing corn, 2,038 cubic centimeters. I- _ :;■; Tabu. 11. — The effect of miscellaneous seedbed treatments upon the milling an&amp; baking value of winter wheat. 1922, 1923, 1925, and 1926 j * Grain Straight flour Baking results Year 1 : Yield Weight Protein Ash Per Dough Loat Bread per per (13 H content cent 1 • acre bushel per cent Water Volume Color Texture moisture) ab - sorption Bushels Pounds Per cent Per cent Per cent C. c. Per cent Per cent (IV (2) (3) j (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) PLOWED JULY 15, 7 INCHES DEEP, DISKED AUGUST 15 (PLATS 6 AND 14) 1922 .45.6 56.0 12.8 .39 61.6 «! 1,960 96 97 1923 18.9 58.0 12.4 .40 63.8 68 2,250 98 98 1925 15.8 60.0 11.9 .44 63.6 66 2,030 98 99 1926 20.0 62.0 13.0 .40 632 66 2,130 98 100 Average 25.1 59.0 12.6 .41 63.0 66 2,093 98 99 LISTED JULY 16 AND AUGUST 16, DISKED SEPTEMBER 16 (PLAT 22) 1922 44.2 58.5 |' 12.5 .39 65.0 65 1,970 98 96 1923 17.9 58.4 11.2 .42 64.6 65 1,780 98 89 1925 17.4 61.5 1 11.1 .44 63.0 64 1,840 98 100 1926 20.9 62.0 12.2 .41 63.6 64 1,910 98 100 Average! 25.1 60.1 I 11.8 .42 64.0 65 1,876 98 99 DISKED JULYJ15, AUGUST 15, AND SEPTEMBER 16 (PLAT 23) 1922 41.0 58.5 ' 11.6 '.39 62.6 64 1,860 98 99 1923 13.1 57.8 . 10.5 .40 63.9 65 2,030 98 100 1925 6.0 60.0 10.8 .44 64.8 64 1,860 98 95 1926 16.7 62.5 11.8 .38 63.0 64 2,050 98 100 Average 19.2 59.7 11.2 . .40 63.6 64 1,950 98 99 ! IN STANDING CORN (PLAT 26) 1922 20.8 58.0 I 11.1 .39 62.7 64 1,910 98 97 1923 6.2 66.4 . 11.1 . .40 63.9 64 1,950 90 100 1925 12.4 60.5 12.7 .46 63.0 64 2,100 96 100 1926 8.8 58.5 \ 12.7 .42 64.1 64 2,190 98 100 Average 12.1 58.4 ' 11.9 .42 63.4 64 2,036 96 99 j . As a general principle, those practices which lead to highest grain yield are satisfactory from the standpoint of grain quality. . -1 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 relation of seedbed preparation to soil nitrate development and moisture accumulation Soil nitrate development and soil moisture accumulation were studied during the 4-year period 1923-1926, on 15 plats receiving various seedbed treatments for winter wheat. It was hoped that such studies might be of value in interpreting the effects of seedbed preparation upon the yield and quality of grain produced. Nitrate production was measured in parts per million of nitrate nitrogen (Phenoldisulphonic acid method), and the soil moisture content was calculated in per cent (dry basis), from representative samples of soil taken 4 times annually from each plat. As a 4-year average, samples were taken on July 15, October 15, April 28, and July 8 of each crop year. The tirst sampling preceded the first seedbed treatment, the second followed the seeding of the wheat, the third preceded marked spring growth, and the fourth followed harvest. Soil samples were taken in one foot cores to the depth of 2 feet for nitrate determinations and to a depth of 5 feet for determining the moisture content. Samples from the first 2 feet were made up of a composite of 8 cores systematically located in the plat and the samples from the lower 3 feet from 4 such cores. The nitrate data are reported in detail in Table 12 and the moisture data in Table 13. SOIL NITRATES The nitrate content of soil samples taken in July preceding the first seedbed preparation was found to be uniformly low for all treatments with but little variation from year to year. As a 4-year average there was less than 1.5 parts per million of nitrate nitrogen present in the first foot and less than 1.0 part in the second foot. The October sampling, however, shows that the time and method of seedbed preparation have been factors in nitrate development. The first foot in 5 July plowings averaged 8.5 parts per million compared with an average of 5.1 parts for 5 August plowings, 2.2 parts as an average of 4 Sep - tember plowings, and 3.8 parts for the unplp&amp;ec^disked plat. Corresponding nitrate nitrogen contents for The second foot were 2.6, 1.2, 0.7, and 1.1 parts per million, respectively. In no case did variation in the depth of plowing, with other - wise comparable treatments, affect the soil nitrate nitrogen content to exceed 2 parts per million. The 7-inch July plow - ing, which was not subsequently disked in August, contained approximately half the amount of nitrates present in the other July plowings. The September undisked plowed plat </seg>
            <seg id="p023">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production was also materially lower in nitrates than the disked-plowea plat. These data show clearly that uncontrolled weed growth prior to seeding interferes with nitrate accumulation. On the other hand, plowing or some equivalent tillage of the soil seems essential to a liberal nitrate production, since merely disked plats on which weed growth was controlled showed low nitrate development. It may be concluded therefore that early plowing followed by such tillage as is necessary to con - trol weeds is most favorable for continued nitrate production and accumulation. ! Depth of plowing, within a range of 4 to 10 inches, did not appear to be a material factor in nitrate development. Sampling in April before much spring growth occurred showed somewhat lower nitrate content in the first foot than the October sampling but practically the same relation of nitrate content to treatment was maintained. As a 4-year average, the July, August, and September plowed plats and the disked plat averaged 5.0, 3.2, 2.1, and 2.4 parts per million. The July- ■ and September-plowed but undisked plats were still somewhat lower in nitrates than the plowed-disked plats. The nitrates in the second foot did not differ ma - terially from thosej of the October sampling. As a 4-year average, following harvest, the first foot of the July plowings averaged 3.0 parts of nitrate nitrogen per million compared with 2.1 and 1.4 as an average of the August and September plowings and 1.3 parts for the disked plats. The nitrates in the second foot varied but little and averaged less than 1.5 parts per million. SOIL MOISTURE The moisture content of the soil in one-foot sections, to a depth of 5 feet, is reported as a 4-year average in Table 13. The soil moisture samples were taken coincidentally with the nitrate samples. A's a 4-year average of the 5 July plowings, the average increase in percentage of soil moisture from the July to the October sampling was 2.0 per cent per foot from the first to the fifth foot. Corresponding increases as aver - ages of the 5 August and the 4 September plowed plats were 1.5 and 1.1 per cent, respectively, and for the disked plat 0.9 per cent. It is apparent that the method of seedbed prepara - tion did not influence the moisture content of the soil very decidedly. Differences in moisture content due to seedbed preparation are somewhat more marked, however, in the upper two feet. As averages of the various July and August plowings there was an increase in the moisture of the first foot of 3.0 and 1.1; per cent, respectively, between the July and October samplings, whereas there was a decrease of 0.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Table Y2. — The effect of time and method, of seedbed preparation for winter irhcat upon soil nitrate development. 1023-1926 Nitrate nitrogen i parts per million) Plat Seedbed preparation - - - - No. iTime and depth &lt;&gt;I plowing nnd other treatments! First fool I Second foot ►-/ | 192:1 j i 92. j 1 'I25 j FoatT | \v~ | i~923 j 1 924 i 1925 j 1926 j Av! w 111 12) I i3i I f41 I 15) i«l I 1-1 l l8l l9| i 1 10) I (111 I (.2) fa SOIL SAMi'I.Kl) IN JULY, HFI-'tlKF. FIRST SKKIlllKIi TREATMENT &gt; (Plowed July 15 I | II £2 1 4 in., disked August 1 5 0.7 2.7 , 1.1 10 II ' 0.7 i i :i 0.9 0.7 0.9 ps 2 5 '■• in., disked August 15 0.9 2.(1 1.1 1.0 II 0.6 | 1.4 1.(1 0.6 0.9 &gt; 3 7 in., disked August .5 I 0.8 2.3 (1.9 1.0 1.3 (1.5 1.6 0.9 0.6 0.9 4 7 in 0.9 2.3 0.9 0.9 1:1 0.7 1.5 0.8 0.6 0.9 t_ 5 10 in., disked August .5 ' 0.8 2.0 0.8 | 0.9 1.1 0.7 ! 1.7 0.7 0.6 0.9 X Plowed August 16 *B 7 4 in | 0.7 2.8 0.9 II 1.4 i 0.7 1.5 0.8 0.6 0.9 W 8 5.. in.. 1.2 2.8 0.9 1.(1 1.5 , (1.7 1.8 0.7 0.6 1.0 W 9 7 in. (1.8 2 9 0.8 1.0 1.4 0.5 1.9 0.8 0.8 1.0 5 10 7 in., disked July 15 0.8 i 111 0.8 (1.9 I.I 0.6 1.8 0.8 0.8 1.0 g 12 loin , 0.7 [ 2.5 0.9 1.1 1 ... (1.5 1.6 0.8 0.7 0.9 W Plowed September 15 2_ 15 4 in., disked July 15 and August 15 0.8 2 1 0.9 0.9 1 .:l 0.6 I 1.1 0.7 0.6 0.8 ►_ 16 7 in., disked July 15 nnd August .5 0.8 I 2.9 0.8 1.2 I.I 0.6 j 1.8 0.6 0.7 0.9 17 7 in. 0.9 .1.0 0.8 1.1 1.5 0.5 1.5 0.6 0.6 0.8 CO 19 10 in., disked July 15 and August 15 I 0 7 2.1 0.7 (1.8 1.2 0.5 1.5 0.8 0.8 0.9 H Double disked &gt; 23 July 16, August 16. and September 15 0.6 I 2.7 | 0.9 0.9 1 ..1 0.5 j 1.6 0.7 0.7 0.9 3 SOIL SAMPLED IN OCTOBER, AFTER SEEDING OF WHEAT © Plowed July 16 2! 1 tin., disked August 15 4.1 5.2 15.6 16.1 10.3 1.6 3.5 7.4 4.1 4.2 2 5 _ in., disked August 1 6 5.2 6.2 10.8 14.0 9.1 1.7 3.6 3.7 2.2 2.8 ttf 3 7 in., disked August 15 7.1 5.6 11.7 11... 9.8 2.9 3.2 2.4 2.5 2.8 r. .1 7 in 7.8 1.1 6.9 4.0 8.0 1.7 0.9 1.6 0.7 1.2 £3 5 10 in., disked August 15 6.7 6.6 6.6 13.3 8.3 2.3 2.1 1.5 2.5 2:1 _-■ Plowed August 15 t_ 7 4 in 10 5.3 3.3 10.7 5.1 0.6 1.5 1.8 0.9 1.2 &gt;_ 8 5 _ in. . 0.9 5.5 2.9 12.0 5.3 0.8 1.1 1.2 1.0 1.1 H 9 Tin. . 0.8 1.5 4.1 11.9 5.3 1.0 1.2 0.9 1.3 1.1 -3 10 7 in., disked July .5 1.0 5.8 3.5 13.0 5.8 0.9 1.7 0.9 1.8 1J1 _.. 12 10 in 07 2.8 1.1 10.8 3.9 0.9 0.7 0.5 2.5 1.2 £2 Plowed September 15 __ 15 4 in., disked July 15 nnd August 15 0.6 3.1 2.4 2.6 2.2 0.6 0.9 0.5 0.7 0.7 16 7 in„ disked July IS and August 15 0.6 5.8 1.5 2.5 2.6 0.8 0.7 0.4 0.5 0.6 17 7 in 0-7 1.8 2.1 2.0 1.7 0.7 0.6 0.4 0.5 0.6 19 10 in., disked July 15 and August 15 O.fi 2.9 3.3 2.5 2.3 0.9 1.1 0.4 0.7 0.8 Double disked 23 July 15. August 15, and September 15 1.2 4.6 3.1 I 6.1 3.8 1.0 1.9 0.7 0.8 1.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Table 12 (Concluded).— The effect of time and method of seedbed preparation for winter wheat upon soil nitrate development. 1923-1926 ' « Nitrate, nitrogen (parts per million) y_ Plat Seedbed preparation — . , Second foot • S No. (Time and depth of Plowing and other treatments) ____ I 1926 I Av. _J£gg_|_JLgg±__] =^gg^|^i£gg = _]_^_^____ = g "' SOIL SAMPLED IN APRIL, BEFORE MARKED SPRING GROWTH Plowed July 16 _ -. „ K si '_, 4.4 1.6 2.7 1.6 -2.5 2.1 _d 1 4 in., disked August 15 1-6 2.6 8.4 5.1 44 to Plowed August 16 i 6 1 7 23 6.0 2.7 23 1.4 13 2-2 l.| ,_ 7 4in \\ H 33 43 2.8 2.1 1.1 1.1 J-6 J.5 £ 8 6Hin _■* \\ 29 43 2.6 1.7 13 0.9 1.6 1.4 * 9-. 7in :••••! i-2 i-| «0 61 4.2 2.0 23 0.9 1.7 1.7 10 7 in., disked July 16 2.2 2.6 6.0 b.j |-| . g M ., 36 1-9 12 lOin *■" *•' &lt; *-° „ , „ - , S Plowed September 16 .■_•__-__ it in 43 2 0 23 13 0.7 ■ 0.9 13 1.1 Z 16 . 4 in., disked July 16 and August 16 1.7 \_ *■* _» __, 16 i. 0 i.i 1.9 1.4 HJ 16 7 in, disked July 16 and August 16 1-8 '■» »•» _■% {•% 1&gt;8 0 .8 1.0 1.1 1.1 H 17 7in7. :-/•••_;_ .g 11 36 81 2.4 1.7 0.7 0.9 2.1 1.4 &lt;fi 19 10 in., disked July 16 and August 16 1.8 11 »- e °- 1 Double disked _ „ _ . ,. . -■ 19 16 4.3 2.4 ' 1.6 1.4 1.0 1.1 13 ■&lt; 23 July 16, August ,6. and September 16. . . —^^ £ TER RVEST =? 1 - |.j ?r »-j g IS i:? ?: 8 o if if i:| g 2 BMTn.. disked August 16 \_\ \\ £2 6 4 3.4 1.6 0.9 1.8 1.7 1.6 « 3 7 in., disked August 16 2.4 1.0 a.» o» x 1.6 13 M 4 7 In.. M 2-q so 69 33 1.4 0.7 1.9 8.1 1.8 H3 6 10 in., disked August 16 2 -« °- 9 B - 8 °f . .... 8 Plowed August 15 6 „ 9 2il 4 . 8 2 .4 13 0.9 1.6 1.6 13 g 7 4in }-2 „ 9 2.4 43 23 1.1 0.8 1.0 1.8 1-s M 8 6Hln....: J-| gj __ 83 2.0 13 0.7 1.1 1.6 \J_ g 9 7 in J-i Jo 23 2.9 2.0 1.4 0.7 1.2 1.4 13 « 10 7 in., disked July 16 \-\ _% |j" £7 1.6 13 0.6 13 13 1.1 g Plowed' September* .6 _____ 1R 0 h 17 1.9 1.6 1.4 0.7. 1-2 M }3 a 16 4 in., disked July 15 and August 16 1-6 __* _■• } g _ A ia 0 .8 0.9 1.6 1.1 16 7 in. disked July 16 and August 16 \_\ g.8 1.5 18 1 Qg g, ,0 i. 9 17 7 In.. :•.-•••;;•- i_ .8 15 16 1.4 1.4 8.0 0.9 13 1.6 19 10 In., disked July 16 and August 15 1-6 °-» i -° Double disked ________._« 17 10 1.0 1.6 13 1.5 0.7 0.8 13 1.1 _ 23 July IS. August 16, and September 16 1-7 i___ i__ __J : </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 Table 13.— The effect of time and method of needled preparation for winter wheat upon the sod moisture content. Average for 4 years. 192.1-1926 PI. J ,T im .'l''n , '^'"", P i, r TT U '' n , _ Moisture eontent ol I Deviation Plat (Time and depth of plowing and Sam- soil 1 column r i N.i. I other treatments) p|p ... .-.._, i from . _i .depth July | Oct. | April' July j column I . | „ /■'•'"' ' /'. rl. ' /•. r(. P. et. P. et. I Per rTnT '" 2 ' j IS) I Hi 1 IS) i (61 ; i7i . isi [Plowed July IS ; . i 1 4 in., disked August 15 1 20.2 23.1 19.2 16 2 I 4-3 2 2 18.6 22.8 . 22.1 17.4 +42 .1 '• 18.3 20.3 i 20.1 . 17.4 -2 0 I I 18.0 18.7 j 18.7 18.0 -0 7 5 20.0 20.2 j 20.1 19.6 4.0.2 Av. 19.0 21.1 . 20.0 17.7 Deviation from column I -2.1 .1.0 -1.3 2 5 '.in, disked August I.' 1 2u.fi 24.0 192 17(1 .|| 2 19.6 23.3 22.7 18.7 ►.■17 •I 19.1 20.9 20.3 . 18.0 -|'.s 1 19.1 20.1 20.(1 18.2 .1 3 21.1 21.9 21.4 20.1 -o'.8 Av. 19.9 22.1 20.7 ISI Deviation from column 1 -2.2 -0.K l :, 3 | 7 in. disked August I.", | 2(1.7 24.3 19.5 '17.7 -.16 -' 19.5 23.(1 22.7 19.1 -3*5 ' 19.0 211.8 20.4 17 5 . | u I 19.1 21.1 19.8 |8.3 -2*0 I ■'• 21.4 21.0 21.1 20.2 -n. I j \v. 19.9 22.0 20.7 IX fi Deviation lr..m c.-lumn I -2.1 -0.8 1 .3 * i 7in - 1 20.6 22.9 20.5 17.-, . 2 'I 2 19.3 22.5 22.fi 19.3 -:l'.2 :l 18.9 21.1 20.6 1X6 -22 1 I8.H 19.8 19.3 19.4 ■ To | ■'• 20.8 21.5 21.0 20.5 .(|.7 , Vv 19.7 21 .1) 20.8 19 I Deviation from column 1 .] (| . | | _ ,, ,; 5 I 10 in., disked August 15 I 2 0.8 23 2 ■'! ', If, 'I . •&gt; , ' 2 20.2 23.7 23;! 17.8 -3*5 3 18.8 21.5 21.1 18.2 -2 7 i I 19.9 211.2 19.7 IX.fi -o':l •". 20.9 21.4 20.8 20.6 -0.5 „ . Av. 20.1 22.(1 21.3 18.4 I Deviation from column I -I...1 .]_. _,- Plowed August 15 III 4 '" 1 1».1 21.0 20.0 17.9 +1 3 2 18.4 22.3 22.4 19.0 +3.9 3 18.8 21.8 j 20.7 19.6 -.3. 1 19.1 20.6 19.5 18.9 +.'5 5 21.8 21.8 21.3 20.3 0' i ..... Av - 19 -6 21.5 20.8 19.1 I Deviation Irom column 1 .] i| +. | g _Q5 I Plowed August I 5 8 ' 5 ' 2 ' n - i I 20.7 21.6 19.9 17.3 ' +0 9 I , 2 21.2 , 22.2 22.9 j 19.0 +I.'o -I 19.8 21.6 20.9 ' 19.6 ! +1 8 j I 19.2- 20.6 19.9 , 19 5 +1 4 . 5 ; 21.4 22.6 22.0 20.8 I +13 ,, . . , Av. 20.5 21.7 21 1 .' 19 2 ' Deviation from column 4 +1.2 1 +0.6 ! -13 | </seg>
            <seg id="p027">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production Table 13 (Continued).— The effect of time and method of seed - bed preparation for winter wheat upon the soil moisture con - tent. Average for If years, 1923-1926 Seedbed preparation Moisture content ol Deviation Plat (Time and depth of plowing and Sam- 3o.I column 6 No - other treatments) d $„W Oct j April 1 Jul? column 4 I Fool\ P. ct.\ P. c.'..\ P. ct.\ P.ct. Percent (I) (2) j (3) I (4) I (5) I (6) I (7) (8) n 7i „ • 1 21.7 23.1 20.7 17.7 +1.4 J '" \ 2 21.1 23.6 23.9 20.0 +2.5 3 20.6 22.1 20.9 18.4 +1.B 4 21.1 21.3 20.6 18.8 +03 5 21.8 23.1 22.4 21.3 +13 Av. 21.3 22.6 21.7 19.2 Deviation from column 4 +13 +0.4 -2.1 ,0 7 in., disked July 15 1 gj 233 gi 1U +1.0 3 19.9 21.8 .22.0 18.9 +1.9 4 20.7 22.5 21.1 21.5 +1.8 5 22.6 23.4 22.6 21.6 +0.8 Av. 21.5 23.0 22.3 20.0 Deviation trom column 4 +1-5 +03 -1.5 ,_ ,nin ■ j -. . 1 23-7 1-24.4 223 17.0 +0.7 12 IOin 2 22.1 24.3 24.4 19.9 +2.2 3 20.8 22.4 21.8 18.9 +1.6 4 21.7 22.6 20.6 18.9 +0.9 5 22.4 23.6 22.7 21.0 +13 Av. 22.1 '23.5 223 19.1 I Deviation trom column 4 1+1.4 +03 -3.0 1 Plowed September 151 „ _ __„!.«_ _-■ 15 4 in., disked July 15 and August 15 . I 223 22.1 |2.0 19.0 -0J 1 3 20.6 22.6 20.7 19.8 +2.0 4 21.8 233 21.1 20.8 +1.5 6 23.6 243 22.7 22.9 +0.6 Av. 22.1 23.0 22.1 20.6 I Deviation from column 4 +0.9 0 I -1.5 l 16 7 in., disked July 15 and August 15 . 1 22.6 ||3 22.8 17.7 -03 3 20.4 2L7 20*.5 183 +13 4 21.1 22.8 20.8 19.4 +1.7 5 23.0 243 22.7 22.1 +13 . | Av. 21.6 22.7 22.1 19.1 Deviation from column 4 I +1.1 +0.5 - 2.5 I 17 7i n ....' 1 21.4 21.4 21.6 173 1 0 " ' 2 20.3 22.2 23.1 19.6 +1.9 3 19.4 21.5 20.8 19.2 +2.1 4 20.9 223 21.1 20.4 +1.4 5 22.4 24.4 22.8 22.9 \ +2.0 Av. 20.9 22.4 21.9 19.9 Deviation trom column 4] I +1.5 | +1.0 -1.0 | 19 10 in M disked July 15 and August 15 1 23.0 21.7 22.5 183 -13 I 3 19*7 21.4 203 17.7 +1.7 4 20.4 23.0 20.8 19.2 +2.6 5 22.7 23.7 22.6 21.4 +1.0 •Av. 21.4 22.3 22.0 19.1 Deviation from column 4 +0.9 +0.6 -2.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 Table 13 (Concluded).— The effect of time and method of seed - bed preparation for winter wheat upon the soil moisture con - tent. Average for ., years, 1923-1926 Seedb=d preparation Moisture content of Deviation Plat (Time and depth ... plowing and Sam- soil column 5 No- other treatments) pie , . . — f r nm depth July Oct. April July column 4 foot P.ct. [P.ct. P.ct. \ P.ct. Percent 11 &gt; '2' (3) (4) I (5) (6) 1 (7) (8) [Double disked I 23 July 15, August 15. and Sept. 15 . i 1 21.7 23.6 22.4 18 8 +19 2 21.5 22.9 23.6 20.4 +1*4 3 20.5 20.9 21.5 19.4 +0.4 4 21.3 21.8 22.3 19.7 +0.5 \ 5 22.9 23.4 23.6 22.4 +0.5 1 Av. ; 21.6 22.5 22.7 20.1 Deviation from column 4) i ' +0.9 +1.1 -1.5 per cent for the September plowings. Increases in the second foot were 3.6, 2.3, and 1.4 per cent, respectively, for the July, August, and September plowings. It seems probable that the differences in the moisture content of the upper 3 or 6 inches was likewise relatively greater in case of the early plowings. These more favorable moisture conditions in the upper soil at seeding time have usually caused higher and Table 14. — Monthly precipitation dvring the 5 crop years from J nh,. 1922. to July. 192eP Vear [ I [ I I | ending July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Jan. Feb. March April i May June Annual June 30 I ' (" I &lt; 2 &gt; I (3) (4) I 15) I (6) (7) I (8)"|79Ti (10) iTlT. :7T2. Tl_) (14) ' PRECIPITATION (INCHES) 1922 5.64 ] 3.42 4.75 1.1! 0.00 0.05 0.66 0.72 2.14 I 1 .85 1 2.73 1 2.95 26.02 1923 5.14 0.49 1.38 1.37 2.90 0.02 0.50 0.08 2.21 2.66 2.54 5 76 25 05 \lli ?__ ,11 9 _° °- 46 °- 21 °- 68 °- 61 '- 09 1-40 1.53 1.90 4.46 3037 1925 5.46 1.25 1.25 1.62 0.47 1.73 0.60 1.81 1.25 1.48 1.00 1 6.49 24 41 1926 °- 90 __530_ 2 - 59 I- 7 ? 0.10 0.72 1.18 0.76 0.41 033 | 2.43 2.44 18.93 Average 3.97 3.27 3.97 1.27 0.74 0.64 0.71 0.89 1.48 1.57 I TtiT T« 2536 _ Normal 3.85 3.63 3.03 1.92 1.05 0.82 0.64 0.98 1.23 2.49 I 4.12 I 433 28.09 PERCENTAGE OF PRECIPITATION FALLING IN AMOUNTS OF _ INCH OR LESS '2~ 2 4 52 12 15 10 ° 10 ° * 00 24 63 58 40 27 35 '923 30 100 100 21 36 100 100 100 29 46 79 26 43 1924 12 15 12 100 100 100 100 37 100 4f 70 47 33 '™5 13 10 ° * 00 25 10 ° *1 100 20 53 28 100 21 38 1926 100 29 44 68 100 100 44 100 100 100 37 37 60 Average 36 59 54 46 87 88 ~89 5(1 69 56 IT ~32 40~ _ L !____ ____L___J I !__ 'The monthly and annual precipitation records were taken at the Experiment Station Farm wnere the seedbed preparation teats are being made. The normal precipitation data covering more than 40 years were ttksn trom the records of the Lincoln Station of the Nebraska Section. United States Weather Bureau. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">The Seedbed Factor in Winter Wheat Production I - more prompt germination and better established fall growth. Since soil moisture conditions are related to the amount and distribution of precipitation, such data are presented in detail for the 5-year period, 1922-1926, in Table 14. ■ INTERRELATION OF FACTORS INFLUENCING YIELD AND • ! QUALITY OF GRAIN In general it may be concluded that those seedbed treat - ments which result in high yields also produce grain that is Units J : , 1 13 J i : X ~ ] "^X : — ' ________ 5 26 — \ — ;^X z~zzzzzz Z5 X 1 X ~ » X-; s X ~ 23 n^ 1 x — 11 X 10 **-^- \ "ST 19 *-=. -- X l ,l — ; — it. X i- X . 15 A : X 1 w z . *: — . • 3 __^e_e____: - *^~ 11 i± i — ] -^ — _!___C w 9 tCTZIT • I -J , 1 • _ __. ____&gt;o J V) . *". c P _______ » q 5 -^ ■&gt;-_ s*--^ -5 5 2 S_________~__j L —"I : "&gt; I— -~^r^l 0 l u 1 1 1 l_ Cram yield per acre iiunit-l bu.) = Protein yield per acre (1 unit =10 lbs.) = ~ Protein content of grain ( 1 unit = I %)= Loot volume of bread ( 1 unit = ZOO cc.)= ! Nitrate nitrogen in first .foot of soil, in Octoberd unit'J ppmA- Average increase in soil moisture, upper 2 feet, July to Oct. (limit =114)= . Fig. 3.— The relation' of time of plowing, with or without additional tillage, to the yield and quality of grain. In addition to the indi - cated treatments, all plats were harrowed after plowing and disked uniformly prior to| seeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 223 relatively high in protein content and baking strength. Like - wise, those treatments which produced the higher yields showed greatest nitrate development and moisture accum - ulation in the soil from July to October. Data bearing on all of these points were taken for the plats plowed 7 inches deep in July, August, and September to illustrate these rela - tionships as plotted in Figure 3. SEEDBED PREPARATION FOR WINTER WHEAT UNDER SPECIAL CONDITIONS Two earlier tests of various methods of preparing the ground for winter wheat were made at Lincoln in 1916 and 1918. The treatments were the same both years but the sea - sons and soil differed materially as indicated in Table 15. The tests consisted in plowing 3 and 8 inches deep at each of 3 dates, without supplementary disking except just at the time of seeding. Wheat was also sown in comparison in standing and disked cornstalks. Taw..: !*&gt;, S,iill,,d preparation for trhitrr wheat under special , auditions. l'Jld nnd WIS Weed-free Weedy Seedbed preparation" new ground old ground Favorable year Dry year 1916 1918 Bushel* Rnshels Plowed July 20 3 inches 42.1 11.4 8 inches 40.4 • 13.8 Plowed August 20 3 inches 45.1 20.0 8 inches 42.5 20.4 I Plowed September 20 I 3 inches . . 47.0 7.3 8 inches 44.8 | 8.4 Miscellaneous Double disked September 20 43.0 8.6 In standing cornstalks 36.5 10.9 •All plowed plat* disked at time of seeding. Three plats of each treatment were averaged in 191 fi and 4 plats in 1 91 8. TEST ON WEED-FREE NEW GROUND IN A FAVORABLE YEAR In 1916 the comparisons were made on weed-free land which had been broken 2 years previously from the native sod. Highest yields were secured from the September plow- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">The Seedbed! Factor in Winter Wheat Production ing and in all cases a 3-inch depth proved better than 8 inches. The tillage practice which tended to retard rankness of vegetative growth yielded best. It is considered that nitrate development is held in check on very fertile land by late shallow plowing.; In this season, wheat planted in cornstalks averaged nearly 'as good a yield as on July plowing but ma - terially less than September plowing. TEST ON WEEDY OLD GROUND IN A DRY SEASON The test made in 1918 was on weed-infested soil of medium fertility. The results show very decidedly (Table 15) in favor of August plowing. Since there was no supplementary disking, this would seem to have been due in part at least to more effective weed control at this mid-season date. A depth of 8 inches proved slightly better than 3 inches, which just reverses the result on fertile new land in 1916. August plow - ing gave nearly double the yield of July plowing and more than twice that of September plowing and of wheat seeded in cornstalks. RESULTS FROM TESTS CONDUCTED IN WESTERN NEBRASKA Extensive investigations comparing various methods of seedbed preparation for winter wheat have also been tarried on at the North Platte Substation. Results of these tests which have been; published in Bulletin 193 of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station are summarized as follows: (I) As an 11-year average, 1912-1922, early plowing (August 15) yielded 16.2 bushels per acre compared with 13.7 bushels per acre for late plowing (September 15) ; (2) as an 8-year average, 1912-1919, plowings 3, 7, 10, and 14 inches deep yielded 13.2, 15.2,' 15.3, and 14.5 bushels per acre, respectively, compared with 12.0 bushels for mere disking; (3) as an 8 - year average, 1912-1919, the yield secured from packing was 15.4 bushels perl acre compared .with 13.6 bushels for un - packed; and (4) J as an 11-year average, 1912-1922, wheat following small grain yielded at the rate of 15.2 bushels per acre compared with 18.9 and 22.6 bushels, respectively, for wheat following corn and summer fallow. [Edition 8M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>