<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Economic Aspects of the Cattle Industry of the Nebraska Sand Hills</title>
               <date value="1927">1927</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Econoimc Aspects of the Cattle Industry of the Nebraska Sand Hills * ' M ■■"'•• "V • ' '■■'■• " - "^'- ' ' ' ■ ■■■'■■;'jt« " ■ ■'■■■■■ ' nnvuiiunHD&amp;Hra . </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS INTRODUCTION :.„ 3 HISTORY OF SAND HILL REGION 4 DESCRIPTION OP AREA , : 6 Topography and Soil 5 Rainfall and Temperature '. 6 LAND UTILIZATION 8 VEGETATION ! 9 FINANCIAL STATUS OF RANCHES „ 10 Size of Business 10 Financial Results 10 Sources of Income , .-. 12 . Nature of Cash Expenses..... 12 Variations among Ranches „ 14 PROBLEMS OF INVESTMENT AND CREDIT . 14 Distribution of Investment 14 Indebtedness : .-. 15 Variations in Indebtedness per Ranch.- .. 16 Interest Payments 18 Sources of Real Estate Loans '...... 18 Sources of Chattel Loans '. 19 The General Credit Situation 20 MANAGEMENT PROBLEMS 21 Relation of Receipts to Expenses^.. 22 Size of Calf Crop ". 23 Death Loss 25 Management of Pastures and Meadows : 26 Supplemental Feeds;'. ; .-. 27 Ranch Labor „ 28 Rate of Turnover .-.. 29 Control of Land &#132; ..„ 30 Diversity of Enterprise : '.. „. 31 Breeding Herd C05t.....; '.'. ...-. , 32 Size of Business 34 Beef Production &#132;... 35 MARKETING PROBLEMS J 35 Cattle Sales •. 36 Age and Quality of Cattle !.„ 36 Market Outlets , .'_, t 39 Time/'of Marketing.., .-. 40 Cycles of Cattle Production... 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Economic Aspects of the Cattle Industry of the Nebraska Sand Hills ■ . HAROLD HEDGES 1 This bulletin presents an economic analysis of the cattle industry in the Nebraska Sand Hill area based upon a three - year study of 47 ranches. Most of these ranches are located in Cherry county in the heart of that cattle-producing region. The field study was started in the summer of 1925 in co-opera - tion with the Bureaus of Agricultural Economics and Animal Industry of the United States Department of Agriculture. It was continued in the following two years by the Nebraska College of Agriculture alone. The study covered the three years, 1924-25, 1925-26, and 1926-27, each ending March 31. The purposes of the investigation were as follows : 1. To determine the prevailing organization and practices of the Sand Hill ranches. 2. To discover, if possible, some of the factors contribut - ing to success or failure, and to determine their relative importance. 3. To bring out facts or suggestions which may point the . way toward improving the financial standing of ranches m the area and aid in securing greater efficiency in pro - duction. This bulletin is not written simply to give the casual reader a general impression of the Sand Hill area and its agricultural production. Rather it is prepared to give the more discern - ing reader some insight into the financial, managerial, and marketing problems involved in the Sand Hill ranching busi - ness. A word of caution may well be added. The ranches in this study represent the survivors of the severe depression following the World War. For that reason they may not give an entirely true picture of the status of the cattle indus - try of the area during the past decade. It should be added in further explanation that the ranches studied follow the gen - eral practice of keeping a breeding herd and are primarily engaged m raising calves. They are therefore distinct from another type of ranch commonly called the " steer " ranch which follows the practice, of buying young steers and pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 - ■ I during grass beef. The latter type of ranch is not common in the Sand Hill area proper but is found more often in the outlying parts of the area and in the High Plains region to the west of the Sand Hills. HISTORY OF THE SAND HILL, REGION It is approximately a half -century since the cattlemen pene - trated the Sand Hill region and availed themselves of its resources. In -the years immediately following the Civil War, when cattle trails extended across the Great Plains region from Texas to the Dakotas, cattlemen avoided the " Sand Hill Desert." Tradition has it that it was largely by accident in the decade beginning in 1870 that they became aware of the possibilities for cattle production in the Sand Hills. It seems that during a severe blizzard cattle had drifted far into the Sand Hill section. Cowboys, in trying to round up the drifted cattle, were astonished to find among the valleys back in the hills large numbers of wild cattle in much better flesh than were the cattle which had drifted in from ranches located in the plains section bordering the hills. Cattlemen, awakening to the possibilities of the area, soon established ranches thruout the territory that had once been avoided as the " Sand Hill Desert." Undisturbed possession was not long their lot, however, and the days of the free range came to an end in the early years of the twentieth century. Some homesteading of the more fertile valleys had occurred prior to 1904. The passage in that year of the Kinkaid Act, increasing homesteads in the Sand Hill area from 160 to 640 acres, brought a rush of settlers. How - ever, even the increased size of homesteads was not sufficient to insure permanent settlement. Many abandoned their claims before proving up on them: Others were glad to sell their holdings after they realized that crop-farming on the Sand Hill land was out of the question except in limited areas. The Census data for the counties -in the area tell the story of the blasted hopes of many homesteaders. In Cherry county, for example, the number of farms in 1900 was 1,082. By 1910, the number had more than doubled, being 2,187. In 1920 the number had dropped to 1,664 and in 1925 to 1,401 farms. Since the " Kinkaider " days individual holdings of land have been enlarged by purchase and lease and attempts at cropping operations have been abandoned. Fenced pastures have (replaced the open range and private control of the land is the rule. The final result is a cattle industry established on a much sounder basis than in the' days of free grass. </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">7 </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">Cattle Industry op the Nebraska Sand Hills about 80 per cent of the land was used for grazing, 18 per cent for hay, and slightly less than 2 per cent for crops in 1924-25. There was practically no change in the succeeding two years. Care is exercised by the majority of ranch oper - ators to guard against overgrazing. A common rule that is followed in most of the area is to allow 10 to 12 acres of grazing land for each mature animal and to allow about one to two acres of hay land per animal. There is considerable variation m the productive capacity of the hay land. *m» - , ; __^ i.f , — iBiii IIBIIsssslI slslls us FIG - &amp;i8tf*&amp;£ S£ -S5 2?&amp;»£S?8V braska Agricultural Statistics. VEGETATION The vegetation of the area consists mainly of the native grasses. Bunch grass (little bluestem) is the most conspicu - ous type, found scattered over the hills, but other grasses such as the grammas, June-grass, and Panicums, furnish most of the grazing. In the valleys many other grasses, such as the big bluestems, wheat grass, switchgrass, and slough grass 2E?tff O1 !? «, and utilized * or &gt;y- Clovers have become scattered thru many of the valleys and greatly improve the yields and feeding value of the hay. The common native grasses which predominate over most of pvlnw. 8 ? ,? a £wt re b t tt ? r ada P ted for the production of choice feeder cattle than choice grass-fat cattle. The graz - ing land provides the summer feed supply. The meadow land furnishes a dependable supply of winter forage ISSa com - £»?^°?' « u PP leme "ted with a limited amount of concen - br?ed1ng ee h ' ? partlcularly suited for the maintenance of a </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 ■ ■ ■ . ■' FINANCIAL STATUS OF RANCHES .... In the years following the post-war boom the ranch oper - ators passed thru. a most trying period, which was a real test of their managerial ability. Low cattle prices and a heavy load of indebtedness forced many out of the business and impaired the financial standing of practically every ranch-operator. The first year of the survey, 1924-25, marked the turning point toward distinct improvement which was in evidence in the succeeding two years, 1925-26 and 1926-27. Size of Business. — The average Sand Hill ranch is no small business unit. The average investment in the 47 ranches was approximately 70 thousand dollars. The aver - age size of the ranches was 6,681 acres. Average cash re - ceipts per ranch varied from $6,557 in 1924-25 to $11,837 in 1926-27, and current cash expenses (not including interest and livestock purchases) from $3,809 in 1924-25 to $4,328 in 1926-27. There was, however, a wide variation in size of business among the ranches. In acreage they varied frm 1,360 to 29,280 acres. In total investment they ranged from $16,815 to $332,073 (in 1924-25). In number of cattle, yearlings or older, the variation in April, 1924, was from 144 to 1,868 head, and in April, 1927, from 111 to 1,843 head. Measured in size of breeding herd, that is, number of cows, 14 ranches had fewer than 150 cows (average of the three-year period) , 18 had from 150 to 300 cows, 7 had between 300 and 450 cows, 5 had from 450 to 600 cows, and 3 ranches had over 600 cows in the breeding herd. Financial Results. — Table 3 shows the average financial results of the 47 ranches included in the three years' study. In this table, cash and non-cash receipts and expenses are not separated. The rate of return on the operator's equity in his business is one measure of the results of his efforts. The' rate of return for 1924-25 was one-half of one per cent. It hcreased to nearly 9 per cent in 1925-26, then dropped back to about 5% per cent in 1926-27. Increases in the ma ket-cattle inventory were accountable for part of the gain. However, it should be stated here that no increases were made in inventory values of the breeding herd during the three - year period. A mark-up of such inventory values would have added materially to the net results of the ranch business in all ' three years. It was felt that the breeding herd is a part of the ranch equipment which is essential to production and the only way that such inventory increases could be realized would be by liquidating the business. </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 not call for any outlay of cash but in the long run must be provided for from the income of the business. In every year of the three, the average ranch had a balance of cash remain - ing after paying all cash expenses. In the last two years, the balance was sufficient to cover all non-cash items, including a fair rate of interest on the operator's investment. Sources of Income. — The dominance of the cattle enter - prise on Sand Hill ranches is attested by its importance as a source of income. In 1924-25, 88 per cent of the total receipts (including inventory increases) were from cattle, 93 per cent in 1925-26, and 90 per cent in 1926-27. Other livestock, prin - cipally hogs, was next in importance as a source of income, but furnished only 5 or 6 per cent of the total receipts. Of minor importance were sales of livestock products and of crops. Ojf the 47 ranches studied, 32 received more than 90 per cent of their gross income from cattle, 9 ranches received between 75 and 90 per cent from that source, 6 received from 50 to 75 per cent, and only two of the group received less than 50 per cent from cattle. Crop sales were of more than minor importance on only three ranches of the group. Nature of Cash Expenses. — Hired labor was the most important item of expense on the Sand Hill ranches, [aver - aging approximately one-third of all current cash expenses (not including interest). Other cash expense items in order of importance were purchased feed, repairs, taxes, and rentals on leased land. Purchased feed appeared to be the most vari - able item of cash expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014">Nebb. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 Variations among Ranches.— In no year are all ranches equally prosperous. Wide variations occur between the most successful and the least successful ranches. In 1924-25, 20 ranches of the 47 failed to make any return on the operator's equity in the business and only 7 made 5 per cent or more. In 1925-26, only 6 ranches failed to make any return on investment, and 32 ranches made 5 per cent or more. In 1926-27, 8 of the 47 ranches made no return on investment while 26 made 5 per cent or more. These differences in ranch income are partly the result of factors beyond the control of the ranch operators and are partly the result of differences in their ability to meet the financial, managerial, and market - ing problems which always confront them. The past decade has been a period of severe test and those operators who still remain in business have, by so doing, given evidence of their ability to meet situations as they develop. PROBLEMS OF INVESTMENT AND CREDIT The problems of putting capital to best use, of securing credit, and of using it effectively require careful consideration on the part of the ranch operator. The credit situation has been unduly severe in the years since the World War. Prior to 1920 credit had been extended too far in many instances in order to expand operations of a business in which contrac - tion was more warranted. Since the period of overexpansion, debts, when paid, have been paid with goods (cattle) which have a lower debt-reducing power than when the debts were contracted. Interest charges have had to be paid from ranch incomes that were much smaller than in war days. Many ranchers were forced out of business and many others be - came so heavily involved that it will require a long time to work out from under the load of debt. Distribution of Investment. — The cattle ranch, like most other types of agricultural production, calls, for a large fixed investment. On the average about three-fifths of the total capital of the 47 ranches studied was invested in real estate (See Table 5). The investment in land comprised about four - fifths of the total value of real estate. The cattle investment was about one-third of the total and about half of this invest - ment was in breeding stock. Most of the remaining capital, about 6 per cent of the total, was invested in work stock and machinery and equipment. Naturally there was wide variation among the ranches in distribution of the investment. A few rented all or a major part of their real estate, and so paid rent instead of having a large fixed investment. With such a large proportion of the total ranch investment in fixed forms, the ranch oper - </seg>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 indebtedness. Of those ranches having real estate mortgage debts, the indebtedness amounted to nearly one-half the in - vestment in real estate. The same holds for the relation of chattel debt to investment in livestock on the ranches so in - volved- When it is realized that the indebtedness of some of the ranches was small, it is apparent that the burden of others in the group was decidedly heavy. In fact, in a few cases the real estate and chattel indebtedness was approxi - mately equal to the full value of the property used as collat - eral. Interest Payments. — The importance of the interest item is realized from the fact that 59 per cent of the excess of ranch receipts over ranch expenses of the 47 ranches was required in 1924-25 to pay the interest charge. In 1925-26, a favorable year, a fourth of the ranch income was required for interest payments. On several ranches in the three-year period, the ranch income was not sufficient to pay the interest on borrowed capital, particularly in 1924-25. On those ranches having interest payments to make, it took 65, 29, and 37 per cent of the ranch incomes of 1924-25, 1925-26, and 1926-27, respectively, for such payments. By refunding their debts during the three-year period studied, a number of the ranchers were able to secure the new loans at lower interest rates. The average rate paid on real estate loans in 1924-25 was 6.3 per cent, in 1925-26 it was 5.7 per cent, and in 1926-27 it was 5.5 per cent. On chattel loans, the average rates paid were 8.3 per cent, 7.9 per cent, and 7.8 per cent for 1924-25, 1925-26, and 1926-27, respectively. The improvement in the indebtedness situation thru the reductions in amount of outstanding obligations and in the interest rate is shown by the decrease in interest charges per acre of owned land and per head of cattle. Considering only those ranches having borrowed capital, the interest charge per owned acre was reduced from 25 cents in 1924-25 to 21 cents in 1926-27, a decrease of 16 per cent. The interest payments per head of cattle, yearlings or older, showed no reduction, but the productive value of the cattle increased materially. All in all, the credit situation showed distinct improvement during the three-year period under study and has undoubtedly continued to improve since April, 1927. Sources of Real Estate Loans. — At least two factors con - tributed to the improvement in the credit situation of Sand Hill ranch operators during the period studied. The change for the better in the cattle industry gave loaning agencies more confidence so that loans were renewed at lower rates. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Cattle Industry op the Nebraska Sand Hills The extended use of new credit machinery (largely federal agencies) in the Sand Hill area has also resulted in putting funds at the disposal of the ranch operators at lower rates. Particularly does this, hold true for real estate loans. The sources of real estate loans obtained by the 47 ranches are presented in Table 8. Real estate loans from federal farm loan sources (federal and joint stock land banks) in - creased from 19 in 1924-25 to 24 in 1926-27. Real estate loans secured from insurance, trust and investment companies decreased from 10 in 1924-25 to 7 in 1926-27. Private par - ties were specified as the creditors holding real estate mortgages in 8 instances in 1924-25 and in 9 instances in the succeeding two years. In most cases these were relatives of the operator or else previous owners of the land. Real estate loans made by local banks were not numerous and decreased from 4 in 1924-25 to 2 in 1926-27. This is a desirable situation since local banks are in better financial position when their loans are in more liquid forms. In the years following 1920, many banks learned to their sorrow the danger of having a large part of their loans secured by r«al estate and were forced in many cases to take over the land. Table 8.— Sources of real estate loans obtained by ranch operators of Sand Hill area, 1924-25 to 1926-27. 1924-25 1925-26 1926-27 Number reporting real estate mortgages..-. 35 35 35 Sources of real estate loans: Federal agencies 19 22 I 24 Insurance, trust, and investment companies 10 8 7 Private individuals 8 9 9 Local banks :. : 4 3 2 The change to federal agencies when refunding the real estate loans was desirable from two standpoints. First, the new loans were secured at lower interest rates. Second, the amortization plan of retiring the principal of the loan has distinct advantages. It makes unnecessary the periodical renewal (usually every five years) of the loan. The estab - lishment of federal land banks and joint stock land banks has also been a favorable influence in bettering and making more uniform the terms of real estate loans from other sources. Sources of Chattel Loans. — Table 9 indicates that local banks continued as the most important source of loans secured by personal property — mainly cattle. In 1924-25, 23 of the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 36 ranchmen having chattel loans secured them wholly or in part from or thru local banks. Other banks — all located at principal livestock markets — furnished funds to a few ranchmen direct and undoubtedly furnished a large part of the funds loaned through local banks. Private individuals, most of them reported as related to the ranch operator, were second in importance as a source of chattel loans. Table 9. — Sources of chattel loans obtained by Sand Hill ranch operators, 1924-25 to 1926-27. . 1924-25 1925-26 1926-27 Number reporting chattel mortgages 36 I 33 32 Sources of chattel loans: I Local banks 23 I 20 . 21 Other banks 4 5 4 Private individuals 3 6 6 Insurance, trust, or investment companies.. 2 2 2 Federal intermediate credit 2 3 1 Source unspecified .'. 2 11' Federal intermediate credit facilities. were but little utilized by Sand Hill ranchmen in the three-year period studied, in spite of lower interest rates charged. Ranch operators criti - cized the intermediate credit system because of the detailed financial reports required and the delays in securing appraisal of the collateral. Co-operative effort on the part of the ranch - men may aid in more extensive use of the intermediate credit facilities. The extensive use of local banks in obtaining chattel loans is to be expected. Local bank officials are in favorable posi - tion to determine the financial standing of the individual bor - rowers and to keep track of the property used as security. Loans secured by market classes of cattle are preferred to loans on breeding cattle. With the tendency toward produc - tion of feeder calves, some ranchers who are on a cow-and - calf basis reported difficulty in securing loans because such loans must necessarily be obtained with the breeding herd as security. Some change in the attitude of .local bankers may be necessary on this point if they wish to retain the good will of their ranch patrons and hold their business. The General Credit Situation. — Better credit facilities and lower interest rates can be of only limited benefit to the ranch operator who is already so heavily involved that his equity in the business amounts to practically nothing. His is a most difficult task of working out from under the heavy </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Cattle Industry op the Nebraska Sand Hills load of fixed charges — not a fictitious interest charge of 5 or 6 per cent which he may be warranted in figuring on his investment, but actual outlays of cash to pay interest, taxes, and land leases. Two things may work to better his position. Better market prices for his cattle offer relief. More careful management may result in lowering his production costs so as to widen the margin between such costs and the selling prices of his products. MANAGEMENT PROBLEMS Many of the factors which influence the production costs on the cattle ranch are, partially at least, within the control of the operator. His ability as a manager will largely determine whether or not his business is on a profitable basis. In every business " bad luck" is often given as the reason for lack of success. More often than not it is poor management that is accountable for the " bad luck." The various phases of the farming business are no exceptions. Realization that it is poor management rather than " bad luck " is one step toward remedying the situation. In order to bring out some of the factors which influence production costs and the profitableness of the individual ranch business, the device of comparison is utilized in the discussion which follows. The' ten " best " and the ten " poorest " ranches have been selected for the three-year period on the basis of per cent return to the operator on his equity after paying interest charges and allowing for the operator's and unpaid family labor. Other methods of choosing the ten " best " and ten " poor - est might have been used, namely, the percentage earned on the total investment or the labor income of the operator. If these latter methods had been used, the same ranches with only a very few exceptions would have been in the two groups. Table 10 permits a comparison of the average finan - cial standing of all 47 ranches with the ten best and ten poorest as measured by the per cent return on the operator's equity and by the labor income of the operator. Noting the lower part of Table 10, it is evident that the first year of the survey was a poor one from the financial standpoint, the second year was very satisfactory, and the third only a fair year. Even in 1925-26, the operators of the ten poorest ranches would have been ahead by having their capital invested in sound stocks or bonds and working for wages, since their average labor income was only $66 for their year s work. In the other two years they not only failed to make a labor income but paid for the privilege of operating tneir ranches. * </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 Table 10. — Financial standing of Sand Hill ranches during the three years, 192U-25, 1925-26, and 1926-27. 1924-25 1925-26 1926-27 Per cent return on operator's equity: Percent Percent Percent 47 ranches 0.6 8.8 5.4 10 best ranches 5.4 15.4 10.5 10 poorest ranches..... -2.8 4.3 -1.0 Labor income of operator: 1 Dollars Dollars Dollars 47 ranches. ...: -1,312 2,237 867 10 best ranches 757 4,982 3,147 10 poorest ranches -2,862 66 -1,688 1 Labor income is the balance of the ranch income remaining after allowing for unpaid family labor, paying interest on borrowed capital, and allowing a return of 6 per cent on the operator's equity * in the business. It represents the operator's waff* for labor and management. This wide variation in the financial status of individual ranches is due, in part at least, to difference in the managerial ability of the operators. In any period of stress, such as in the years immediately following 1920, increasing effort is made to reduce production costs and thus offset part or all of the disadvantage of low selling prices. Some of the ranch operators were more successful than others in doing so. Some of the factors of management influencing income were brought out in the survey of 47 Sand Hill ranches. The comparisons between the groups of ranches as given in Table 10 and succeeding tables emphasize the influence of these factors in a material way — on the net returns from the ranch business. Relation of Receipts to Expenses. — One measure of the operator's ability as a manager is the relation of ranch receipts to ranch expenses. Spending wisely and well has an important bearing on the ranch income. Table 11 shows the amount of ranch receipts for each dollar of expenses. For every dollar spent on the ten best ranches, there came back into the business $2.15, $3.07, and $2.52 in the three years, 1924-25, 1925-26, and 1926-27, respectively. These receipts per dollar of expense were from 41 to 55 per cent larger than on the ten poorest ranches. The ability to spend wisely and well is only partly account - able for the differences between the groups of ranches shown in Table 11 but is nevertheless an important factor. Choos - ing the more productive of two possible expenditures calls </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 10 best ranches had calf crops varying from 78 per cent in 1924 to about 84 per cent in 1925 and 1926. Without doubt, the larger calf crops of the best ranches were con - tributing factors to their higher net returns during the three - year period. The average calf crop of the ten poorest ranches varied from about 66 per cent in 1924 to 75 per cent in 1926 — very little different from the average of the 47 ranches. It is well to recognize that the percentage calf crop is only one among several factors which have a major influence on the net returns from the ranching business. The second and third parts of Table 12 offer evidence of this. It will be noted that the best calf crop among the 10 poorest ranches for each of the three years was well above the average for all 47 ranches. In 1926, the ranch having the best calf crop was not among the 10 best ranches. In 1925, the ranch having the smallest calf crop was not among the 10 poorest ranches. A number of factors undoubtedly contributed to the wide variations in percentage calf crop among the ranches and from year to year on a single ranch. Condition of the breed - ing herd as influenced by pasture conditions, winter feed supplies, and weather probably cause variation. Methods of handling bulls and breeding herd have their influence on the calf crop. A number of ranch operators reported that they had improved the calf crop by conditioning the bulls before turning into the herd, by separating the breeding herd from other cattle and restricting it to a small pasture during the breeding season, and by close culling of non-producing or irregular-breeding cows. Practically all the ranch operators in this survey reported the practice of having heifers drop their first calves at three years of age rather than when two years old. There seems to be no close relation between the number of cows per bull and the percentage calf crop. The age and vigor of the bulls as well as the method of handling them and the cows will probably determine the ratio of bulls to cows. One bull to 26 cows was the average for the 47 ranches in each of the three years studied. Of great importance in securing a high-percentage calf crop at weaning time is the reduction of death losses among young calves. Care during the calving season is of utmost import - ance in reducing losses of both cows and calves. Lack of sufficient help or inability to get dependable hired help was cited by a few ranchers as a cause of their large calving losses. Another cause for a low-percentage calf crop given ¥ f num *&gt;er of ranch operators was abortion. In fact, several stated that contagious abortion was the most serious problem facing the Sand Hill ranch operator. </seg>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 Among cattle other than cows and young calves, losses were small. Blackleg, lightning, castration, spaying, and dipping were ascribed, in order of importance, as causes. Vaccination for blackleg was practiced on every ranch but even that failed to give full protection. Lightning as a cause of loss is beyond the control of the ranch operators but loss from the other causes listed might be reduced somewhat if more care were taken in the operations. The three years included in the. survey were not years of severe climatic conditions so perhaps winter losses were less than normal. It is in adverse years that managerial ability comes into evidence in keeping losses at a minimum. Such factors as carrying the cattle into the winter in good con - dition, having reserve feed for unusual needs, and providing shelter all help to hold down losses in bad years when they might otherwise be severe. Management of Pastures and Meadows. — Main depend - ence is placed on grass, whether in pasture or on hay land, as the source of the feed supply in the Sand Hill area. Pro - tecting the feed supply is one means of safeguarding the profits in the business. Methods and means of maintaining and improving pastures and meadows require the attention of the ranch operator. Overstocking of pastures has not been a serious problem in recent years because liquidation and reduction of herds have materially reduced the number of cattle in the Sand Hill area. Even so, a few ranches with no additional pasture land close at hand available for purchase or lease reported that they were overstocked. Apparently their only alterna - tive is to further reduce their herds. Overstocking of pas - tures is particularly disastrous in the Sand Hills, '. where a grass covering of the soil is so essential to prevent wind erosion and the development of " blow-outs." A definite policy of management is needed to maintain pasture grasses. Continuous pasturing should be discour - aged, since it prevents the native grasses from re-seeding occasionally. Fences and cross-fences are common on Sand Hill ranches: Thus a plan of changing pastures would not involve much added expense or trouble in substituting it for continuous pasturing where the latter may be practiced. Ex - perience has shown that allowing grasses to reach the seed stage once in five years and deferring grazing the succeeding year to permit the new vegetation opportunity to establish itself are sufficient to maintain pastures satisfactorily. Increasing the hay supply and improving its quality by getting legumes established on the meadow land are proving to be worthwhile practices in the Sand Hills. Twenty-one </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Cattle Industry op the Nebraska Sand Hills of the 47 ranches surveyed reported varying quantities of legume or legume-mixed (largely clover mixed with native grasses) hay in 1926-27. Perhaps others of the 47 also had some of the mixed hay but failed to indicate it. Yields of the clover-mixed hays were much better than of the native hay and the feeding value was far superior. Ranch experience indicates that a water table close to the surf ace. is necessary for successful production of legumes. 3 This being so, it appears to be the problem of the individual ranch operator to determine the possibilities of establishing legumes on his meadow land. Supplemental Feeds. — Recent experiments * have demon - strated the value of protein in the winter ration of calves wintered on the Sand Hill ranches. Keeping the breeding herd in good condition thru the winter has a direct influence on the calf crop. With these facts in mind, to what extent may it be advisable to supplement the ranch-grown feed supply with purchased feed? The conditions on each ranch ■will determine the answer. Some operators may have suffi - cient supplies of legume or legume-mixed hays and thus have already at hand a very satisfactory protein feed. A few pro - duce limited quantities of grain on land suited for crops. The majority of the ranches studied, however, depended wholly or in large part upon native hay. Information furnished by 38 of the 47 ranches permitted a rough approximation of the kinds and quantities of winter feeds fed to cattle. In 1924-25, 18 of the 38 ranches depended entirely on hay for winter feed. In 1925-26, 9 of the group of 38 ranches used hay only and in the following year only 4 used hay exclusively. Table 14 gives some idea of the differences in the winter feed supply situations on the 38 ranches in the three years studied. Improvement in the financial status of the ranches was probably one thing con - tributing to the increased use of concentrates in 1925-26 and 1926-27. The concentrates used were mainly grain (largely corn) and cottonseed cake. Some shortage and poor quality of hay, together with the low price of cottonseed cake accounted for the increased use of concentrates in 1926-27 During that winter cottonseed cake was fed on 31 of the 38 ranches and made up more than four-fifths of the weight of concentrates fed. •The Valentine Substation. Nebraska College of Agriculture has b«?n v &lt;. r Un. «. the problem of relation of the water-table to ?he establishment Colle|ro7TCTic O ult« e e. wlnterln « experiments of the Valentine SubstaUon. Neb?aTa </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 Table 14. — Winter feed supplies on 38 Sand Hill ranches, 1924-25, 1925-26, and 1926-27. 1924-25 1925-26 .1926-27 Tons of hay per head of cattle * (tons). 1.8 1.8 1.6 Pounds of concentrates (pounds) 23 37 71 1 Figured on basis of number of cattle carried thru the winter and on hand April 1. The scarcity of locally produced grains and the long hauls from railroads over unimproved roads limit the possibilities of extensive grain feeding and practically prohibit the pro - duction of grain-fed cattle. The cheapest gains are made on grass. A protein feed, either in the form of legume hay or a commercial product such as cottonseed or linseed cake, is highly desirable in securing good growth on young stock. It would seem a good policy to keep the young cattle in thrifty growing condition during the winter. By so doing they will come off the grass in better condition the following fall and will show a more profitable gain for the winter and summer periods. Ranch Labor. — Wages paid for hired labor were the largest single item of cash expense on the Sand Hill ranches studied. If to the cost of hired labor were added the value of the labor performed by the operator and his family, labor would bulk still larger as an item of cost in producing cattle m the Sand Hills. Difficulty in securing efficient hired help was reported by many of the ranch operators interviewed. Particularly difficult was the task of securing reliable seasonal labor needed at haying time. Ability to use the available labor, of both paid workers and the family, to best advantage is one of the- several factors influencing net returns. It is difficult to measure this abilitv but it may be done roughly by determining the labor cost for each head of cattle handled or the amount of labor utilized for each 100 head of cattle on the ranch. These measures of labor efficiency are used in the comparison of the different groups of ranches presented in Table 15. The group of 10 best ranches apparently made more effec - tive use of labor than did the other groups. The labor cost per head of cattle for this group averaged lower for the three years, and the amount of labor required for each 100 head of cattle was likewise less. It may be well to add that the labor item was for all ranch operations and not just that used m handling cattle. </seg>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032"/>
            <seg id="p033">Cattle Industry op the Nebraska Sand Hills owned land, not including improvements, was $4,130 a sec - tion. Interest on this valuation at only 4 per cent would equal ™f i a s ?S tlo 2j l . or nearly two-fifths more than the average lv S P f £ The avera * e lease c ost for grazing land rented by 22 of the ranches was about $88 per section in 1926-27. liay land rented on the share basis was secured for one-half yearTriod'lJudief 8 *** redUCed ***** **™* the three " Other things than cost need consideration in arriving at tvltHnlf Sr£ he P r ? b i e . m of contr °J of land. The land owner with lull control of his acreage for operation has greater assurance of his future feed supplies and can plan for the future more definitely. The. ranch operator who dVpendl wholly or mainly on a rented acreage has an element of un - certainty with which to contend. Furthermore, land operated Si he owner is less likely to suffer from careless handling. Ihis is a matter of real concern in an area of light soils such as predominate in the Sand Hills. +v,Pi 6Sp i te the * eneral advantage of owner operation of land, Sfnftf ™£ T* at a di8t i- nct dis advantage from the stand! point; of profits from operation during the three-year neriod studied The spread between the cost (taxes, interest eta ?? to °^M &amp;nd S f thG 5^ als On leased land was wiSeenoSgh £ K Sf f rent f r a f Stinct advan *age. It might be will to state that values placed on the land were conservative being much below the high levels of a few years Sore' Even so, fa view of cost of leases, land values were still out of proportion Some of the deeded land was subject to such a load of mortgage debt that the owners so involved mav a^FlivStock CaPP6d in S6CUring Credit f ° r ™™Z**Xl ? iv -1ft-, ty , of En * er Pri»e — The cattle enterprise has been and will likely continue to be the dominant one in the Sand Hffl area. Only two ranches of the 47 studied put material de Th n ese n t C wo O ra O Sh r enter P rises *» supplement Se prStion «S t two . r . anc *}** wer f peculiarly adapted in soils and gen - eral layout to other enterprises than cattle and were exceo - rfS 47 r6SP l Ct - Te ble 3 ' ei ™S the *»S5 sE of recefpts 6S ' WS * he im P° rtance of cattle as a source The survey made no attempt to determine the possibilities of enterprises other than beef production, but some general conclusions, based on natural conditions in the area seem warranted. The light, sandy texture of the sofl which *rT vails in the area limits the possibilities of crop production on the majority of ranches. The tendency of sheep to graze too closely places that enterprise at a disadvantage in^n area </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 where a grass covering of the soil is necessary to prevent wind action. Such factors as scattered vegetation and distance to market deserve attention in considering dairying as a possible supplement to cattle raising. Production of feeder pigs may offer possibilities on many ranches with the increasing acre - age in legumes. Low prices have discouraged horse produc - tion, but a change for the better in market conditions may alter the situation. Each ranch operator needs to consider his own situation as to soil, ranch layout, and similar factors, and also his own inclinations in deciding how far he may wish to go in supple - menting his main enterprise — cattle production. Depend - ence on a single enterprise usually means wide fluctuations in ranch income. Diversity in the sources of receipts tends to reduce the variations. For this and other reasons the matter of diversification deserves the consideration of ranch oper - ators. Breeding Herd Cost. — Maintenance of a breeding herd rather than the handling of steers was the form of the cattle enterprise which predominated in the section of the Sand Hills studied. Questions commonly asked by ranchmen and others were in regard to the cost of carrying a cow thru the year or of raising a calf up to weaning time. Accurate and definite cost data were not obtained in the survey but the figures secured supplemented by estimates from ranchmen made possible an approximation of these costs. The results are given in Table 17. Some of the items of expense such as death loss and depre - ciation of the breeding herd and a large part of the purchased feed were charged directly to the breeding herd. Other expense items such as repairs, land leases, and labor were pro - portioned between breeding herd and other cattle on the basis of number of cattle units ° of each. Some may question this method of prorating expense, but it is well to remember that all divisions of joint cost items must be based on esti - mates. The data in Table 17 are based on the figures and estimates furnished by 38 ranches which secured more than 85 per cent of their total receipts from cattle. The total cow cost varied from $20.04 to $22.10 per head in the three years and- the calf cost from $27.64 to $30.19. Naturally there was wide variation in calf cost among the 38 ranches. For instance in 1926-27 the spread was from $20.09 to $45.53 per calf. The items of costs are grouped in Table 17 to permit separation of cash and non-cash expense items. The total cash cost would include the cash items grouped to - 'The Texas Agricultural Experiment Station has worked out the feed requirements of rang* cattle with the requirements for a cow the basic unit, called cattle-unit or grazing-ratio unit. The grazing requirements of other cattle and other liTestock are - siren as a ratio of the cow as a unit. </seg>
            <seg id="p035"/>
            <seg id="p036"/>
            <seg id="p037"/>
            <seg id="p038">Nebb. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 . all tie in together. The cattle raiser, with the market the outlet for his product, must give full consideration to it in plan - ning his operations. Maintaining efficient, economical produc - tion is highly important, but keeping production in line with market demands contributes to the financial well-being of the ranch operator. In discussing investment problems, the point was made that expansion of the cattle industry when the future market outlook appeared doubtful had resulted in numerous ranch failures. In matters of investment, there - fore, the market, present and prospective, deserves considera - tion. The cattle producer, once his product is ready for market, is seldom in position to dictate the price of his cattle, nor can he influence the sales price in any marked degree. To some extent luck apparently determines whether or not he strikes a favorable market. Nevertheless, he can influence the market prices he receives by the kind and quality of the cattle he sells, by the time and place he sells, and by the sell - ing methods he follows. Furthermore, he may benefit by vary - ing his operations in line with fundamental changes in the cattle industry. These are some of the marketing problems which deserve his attention. Cattle Sales. — Table 20 gives the average number, weight, and value of the cattle sold from the 47 Sand Hill ranches in the 3 years studied. The number of cattle sold in 1924-25 (largely in the fall of 1924) was below normal, perhaps because of poor feeder demand resulting from the small corn crop of 1924. Sales in 1925-26 were much larger, partly because of the cattle, yearling or older, held over from the previous year. Sales in 1926^27 were larger in number sold due to the decided increase in number of calves marketed. Age and Quality of Cattle. — In the three-year period covered by the survey there was a distinct tendency to sell cattle at a younger age. Table 20 shows a sharp increase in number of calves marketed from 1924-25 to 1926-27. Allow - ing for the holding over of cattle from 1924-25, the number of yearlings sold tended to increase while sales of cattle, 2-year - olds and older, tended to decrease. Table 21 gives some idea of the change in operating policies on the 47 ranches in the three-year period between April 1, 1924, and March 31, 1927. The inventories of cattle per ranch as of those dates are given. The average number of cattle per ranch decreased by 20 head. The breeding herd, cows and bulls, showed an increase of 24 head. All other classes showed decreases, with the decreases relatively greater for cattle 2 years old or older than for yearling cattle. This offers further evidence of the tendency to market the cattle at younger ages. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">37 </seg>
            <seg id="p040"/>
            <seg id="p041">Cattle Industry of the Nebraska Sand Hills limited, the majority of Sand Hill ranch operators will prob - ably continue to market the younger animals. Ability to secure high percentage calf crops and to maintain the breed - ing herd economically favors this policy. If production of feeder calves is to be followed, early calves are necessary to secure desirable weight at selling time in the fall. A common practice, and one that seems desirable, is the sale of the larger, early spring calves in the fall and the carrying over of the late calves to sell as yearlings. This reduces the extra trouble, risk, and expense/incurred in having all calves arrive in the early spring: No definite information was available regarding the quality of cattle on Sand Hill ranches. Undoubtedly there has been much improvement in recent years. Of 42 ranches which reported the kind of bulls used in 1924-25, 39 stated that all were purebred and 3 that part were purebred. Only a few of the ranches, however, reported purebred cows. Im - provement of the herd from the maternal side was made by culling and careful selection for type and quality. Practically a third of the ranches studied did some spay - ing of heifers in 1924-25 but only a few did any spaying the third year of the survey. Market Outlets. — The main outlets used by the 47 Sand Hill ranches surveyed in marketing their cattle were thru the terminal markets (principally Omaha), to local buyers and direct to feeders. Naturally, there was a wide difference of opinion as to which constituted the best outlet. Since the younger cattle largely moved to corn-belt feed lots, many felt that they gained some advantage by selling direct to feeders. The bargaining ability of the individual ranch operator and his grasp of the market situation would probably be import - ant-factors determining whether or not a fair price was received by direct selling. Cows and bulls culled from the breeding herd and off - quality cattle which do not meet the needs of feeders may find the best outlet thru terminal markets. Most of such cattle are ordinarily destined for immediate slaughter. Movement to the point where the packing industry is located would be the most direct route to consumptive channels. With the emphasis being given to production of high-quality feeder cattle in the Sand Hill area, thought is being given to co-operative effort in developing a market outlet. In recent years, auction sales have been held at a number of points in or near the Sand Hills as a means of selling both feeding and breeding animals. In time a plan of marketing in use in some other range sections may prove feasible. This involves setting up definite standards of quality which the feeder cattle </seg>
            <seg id="p042"/>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044">Nebr. Experiment Station, Bulletin 231 been 14 to 16 years in length from high point to high point or from low to low. The first of the three years covered in this survey of 47 ranches marked the low point of the price cycle, following which there has been recovery. Based on past experience the next peak in prices seems due sometime between 1929 and 1932. A long period is required to contract or expand the cattle industry. As prices near the low point liquidation of breed - ing herds takes place. This process adds to market receipts and prices are delayed in recovering. This failure to recover discourages breeders still more and herds are reduced more than necessary. When the price improvement starts, memory of the past and the prevailing high prices induce cattlemen to sell more heifers than they intended to sell. As they gain confidence and more female stock is withheld from the market, prices work still higher because of small market sup - plies. Then expansion of herds is carried too far under the stimulus of high prices, market supplies increase, and a new cycle begins. This has been the history of the cattle industry in the past half century. The ranch operator with a good working knowledge of fundamental price-making factors has a distinct advantage over his less-informed neighbor. He will be less likely to expand operations when contraction is suggested by basic conditions in the industry. He will know the classes of cattle the market wants and will produce to fill the needs of that market. Faced with the many problems of investment, man - agement, and marketing, the success of the Sand Hill ranch operator, like that of any other business executive, depends on his ability to meet the situations which arise. [BM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>