<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Dairymen's Association FOR THE YEAR OF 1904</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">(By courtesv of Twentieth Century Farmer.) EX-GOV. HOB'T W. FUHNAS AND EX-GOV. W. D. HOARD In attendance at Annual Meeting, Jan. 19-20, 1905; were also both In attendance •t First Annual Meeting of the Association, December, 1885. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nebraska Dairy - men's Association FOR THE YEAR OF 1904 PREPARED BY S. C. BASSETT Sec'y Nebraska Dairymen's Association JASON L. CLAFLIN. PRINTER University Plaee, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">provided, I fa Associa- ■Excellency, John H. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska: Sin — In compliance with the law in (his case made and Kby transmit the annual report of the Nebraska Dairymen 1 for the year 1904. Respectfully yours, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">• • </seg>
            <seg id="p006">TABLE OF CONTENTS List of int^mlxTH 9 Address M sa of Hon. W. D. Hoard at Annual Meeting 1H _'lits from the Dairy I V] art men t. World ■ L. I&gt; Still 2« ■;il statement of the flii to the St. L&lt;mis Exposition ••Hints on Profitable Dairying. " Henry ('. UUmh Report of Treasurer 9H Report of Auditing Committee "The Necessity for Grading Cream. " C. H. Hinman Committee on Nomination of Officers : ; Committee on Resolution^ • : Cow Judging Contest f Report of Committee on Nomination of Ofti&gt; • ■■- ; T Report of Committee on Resolutions ■ "Alfalfa— Its Importance to the Dairy Industry of the State. " S. C. Bassett ' 51 ' ' The Common Cow, ' ' Prof. T. L. Haecker ]&gt;erative Tests of Dairy Herds," Prof. A. L. Hiwker 63 The Butter Judging Conti-M Address of Hon. W. D. Hoard, at Dm hope! List of Creameries H4 Tftblfi who w i ii ff co\^s iisfid iii Cow *J ncls i us C '• ► 1 1 1 ♦*** t w \ t h rccowJfi ** "• </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">OFFICERS -19044905 Vice- President Hern maha I i ibfxjn Secretary and Treasurer DIRECTORS J. K. Hun- </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">MR, C. A- CLARK President Nebraska Dairymen's Association </seg>
           
            <seg id="p011">■ LIST OF MEMBERS. HONORARY LIFE MEMBERS. 0 L Gabrilson W D Hoard J G Lumbard Minnetka, ill. New Hampton, Iowa Fort Atkinson, Wig. Osage, Iowa Omaha, Nebr. LIFE MEMBERS. Vijah Allen P Ashburn Omaha. Nebr. Gibbon. N Giblmn. J Mrs D P Ashbnrn J Dixon Avery Cor. Clark and Water Sts. . Chicago. 111. fj Babcock CJ Bas~ tin Baumer tf Bayley W T Bemis H Buck Gibbon, Nebr. Gibbon. Nebr. (tjI)1 Sutton, Nebr. (xiblKjn. N I A Carj)enter C Clark York, ( )maha. Nebr. V3 Coflin H Davis Fort Dodgr Gibbon, Nebr. r\ Dinsmore C Drurv Sutton. Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. A L Haecker Lincoln, Nebr. Ermantown i 1 flissniitn r Fisher r utive Creamery Ase'n (iermantown, Nebr. n B, Omaha. Nebr. H F Flint IS Fulmer W Fnmas C (Tlissman Brownville, Nebr. IW (iunther W Harrell J Hainer FHowe Albion. Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Aurora, Nebr. Omaha. &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">10 ANNUAL MEMBERS. &gt;K Honeywell A Clark Lincoln. Nebr. Ravenna, Nebr. W A Apperson Clem Wilcox G W Her G C Noble Tecumseh. Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. Crete, Nebr. Omaha. Nebr ird, Nebr. rj Colvin B Lipton Ijnry Sunderman W Williams Bee, Nebr. Cook, Nebr. Paul Lorenson Oeo Kohler Filley. Nebr. Lawrence. Nebr. F W Edmnnds Central City, Nebr. L D Stills, m York, Nebr. E C Bishop Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebr C E Barber Oxford, Nebr. J S Temple Cheney, Nebr. Mrs S Pierce Woodlawn, Nebr. V H Ijams I B Kelley Itomas Kirk... Omaha, Nebr. Inez. Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Lirachbaam &amp; Sons Omaha, Nebr. " W Lementin Omaha, Nebr. C Merrill Sutton, Nebr. h- George L Miller 1 H Noble Omaha, Nebr. Gibbon. Nebr. H Rushton Fairmont, Nebr. J«orge H Si'vernail \ R Stouffer Gibbon, Nebr. &gt;uth Omaha, Nebr. William Sutton Table Rock. Nebr. ) H Wheeler Omaha. Nebr. ) H Wheeler, Jr Omaha, Nebr. 7 G Whitmore Valley. Xelir. I H Wing Ithaca. N. Y. tG Furgaaon H Vaughan Beaver Crossing, Nebr. Cheyenne. Wyo. West Point. Nebr. J King Iharle* W Stevenson Sioux City, Iowa </seg>
            <seg id="p013">11 D N Syford Lincoln. N Chas P Shu in way A Laverty Care of Merchants' Despatch, Omaha. » Auhland, Nebr. Oeo Tilden Benedict. O P Hendershot ALCoad Hebron, N Omaha, N Smart Fairmont. University Place, N Stanley Howard H C Johnson C C Lavitz Wvand* I \ Place, S rB Caldwell Harnly Kenesaw ! Edgar fS Wilaon L Jameson R H Searle H A DnBois .1 I) Newell E Parmenter i Creek, la. Allia Edgar San Rafat Colomtms Jc. , la. Papillion H E McCartnev Payn North PI;. &gt;i'gerson Wolfe ( ' H Hinman S B Carpenter C R Reese Callaway. ' Ohiowa. N Lincoln. v Creighton Valeii; Hal C Young Milligan. xz ■Smithtiokl Prim i Merle Little A \V Krambeck Bristol Oreaham. ~ RWestover Brazda Nash Dodge Benson. N State Farm, Lincoln, N W A Doubt N E Tyrrell F M Doubt Care of John Deere Plow Co. . Om aha Havelock </seg>
            <seg id="p014">12 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Mart D Cyphers AD Calkins Valentine, Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Xebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Nebr. Lincoln, Lester Harman D B Me Seal Mecham C F ("has. Nebraska City, North Platte, Kenesaw Pawnee City, Pawnee City, 22 St. , Omaha. F D Scott F W Graham EPDill 'MM N Belvidere, Jerry Van Hoeeen W M Buck man J F Tilden Omaha. Omaha. Benenict. O D Garden Scotts Bluffs. West Union, Howard Wallace R W Boon Riverton, IF Mclntosh WEhlera i Varney win Hopt 3 Reed Alda Cheney, Bennett. Cambridge Grafton JGibb Staplehurst Bernhard Witt Welton C Baines Wm A Crabtree Walter Jaeggi C E Laverick Mrs C W Kauffman W D Stelk Scribner South Auburn Bethany Columbus Beaver City Rokeby Grand Island A J Nelson 250 So. 28 St. . Lincoln, Nebr Chas E Gabby L P Mill- Pawnee City, Nebr, Hastings, Nebr. S F Marsh 1210 D St., Lincoln. Nebr. tdell Brinton Rober R F. D. 2. Lincoln, Nebr Normal, Nebr IC Griftis J Moore H Chassot Lincoln, Nebr. Riverton, Nebr Thoa Thompeen W F Hanmont E G Van Siggern CO Hilber Elton, Nebr, Wayne, Nebr. Wisner, Nebr. John H Schwarting Wisner, Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p015">TWENTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 13 Thomas R Noye Wm Rungt- Lincoln S Wood River, Nebr. Haskins. N F C Boyd Exp. Sta. . Lincoln. C B Lazure Lee Young *C Stein J Olson ■M&amp;&gt; R St.. Lincoln Lincoln Wall James E Reed Havelock. Life Members 53 Annual Members Total </seg>
            <seg id="p016">14 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION TWENTIETH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. HELD IN STOCK JUDGING PAVILION. UNIVERSITY FARM, LINCOLN, JANUARY 19-20, 1905. PROGRAM Thursday, January 19 9:30 A. M. E- the President — C. A. Clark, Ravenna. Secretary and Treasurer- S. C. Bassett, Gibbon, snt of Committees. - ■ Dairy Industry at the St. Louis Exposition — L. D. Stilson. York Home Dairy— Henry C. Ulissman, Omaha. 1:30 F. H. Erhe Necessity for Grading Cream at Cream Receiving Stations — C. Hinman, Lincoln. 3:00 P. M Cow Judging Contest. Friday, January 20 9:30 A. M. Report of Committees. Election of Officers. Alfalfa— Its importance to the Dairy Industry of the State— S. C. Bassett, Gibbon. Co-operative Tests of Dairy Herds — Prof. A. L. Haecker, Dairy Husbandry, Nebraska Experiment Station. 1:30 P. M. Sanitary Milk for City Consumers. Judging Butter from a Commercial Standpoint— F. A. Leighton Lincoln. Butter Judging Contest. COW JUDGING CONTEST. t Regulations. t Prize, gold watch, suitably engraved, value $ 15.00 Rata Premium 100.00 Open to members of the Association who are residents of the State In caae of tie for first prize, it will be drawn by lot. The pro rata premium will be divided among those scoring 75 points </seg>
            <seg id="p017">15 It of a possible 100 points, in proportion to the number of points scored )ve 7"&gt; ; provided, that of the pro rata fund no contestant shall receive exceed the sum of $15.00. §The butter fat production of the cows to be judged, for the past two irs, is a matter of record, and the judging will consist in placing the vs in numerical order according to their relative value as producers butter fat. I The judging will be done on Thursday, January 19th, at 3:00 p. m. , the Stock Judging Pavilion at the University Farm. Every member of the Association is invited to take part in this con- BDTTER JUDGING CONTEST. Regulations. Pro Rata Premium Open to members of the Association who are residents of the state. It is provided that no contestant shall receive of the pro rata fund to exceed the sum of $10.00. Three grades of commercial butter will be officially scored on the basis of Flavor 50, Grain M, Color 15, Salt 10. Each contestant will be required to score, on the same basis, each of the three grades of butter. And the award will be made on the score of the three grades as com - pared with the official score. I The maximum and minimum score which will entitle a contestant a pro rata share of the premium fund will be announced in advance the beginning of the contest. REMARKS. Any person may become a member of this Association. Membership fee, $1.00. Theje will be no exhibit of dairy products, All sessions will be held in the Stock Judging Pavilion at the Uni - versity Farm. A free lunch at noon will be provided for those in at - tendance at the meeting. Ample street car facilities between city and University Farm Headquarters of the Association will be at the Lindell Hotel. For programs or other informaion in regard to the meeting, address. (iihbon, Nebraska. RAILROAD RATES. Rate of one fare plus fifty cents, except where open rate of fare and one-third makes less from points in Nebraska to Lincoln and return ; tickets to be sold on January 14-19, inclusive, good to return leaving Lincoln until and including January 25. 1905. except by depositing tickets with Joint Agent at Lincoln on or before January 25 and upon payment of fee of fifty cents at time of deposit, return limit may be extended to leave Lincoln up to and including January 31, 1905. 8. C. BASSETT. Secretary, </seg>
            <seg id="p018">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 16 rEDINGS OF THE TWENTIETH ANNUAL MEETING THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. Ea well rendered selection of music by an orchestra composed of of the Agricultural College, President C. A. Clark called the to order and delivered the annual address. PRESIDENT'S ADDRESS Ladies and Gentlemen of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association This is the time of year when men in all lines of industry are look - ing over and computing the results and achievements of the year that is past, and planning for the year that is before them. And it is well that the dairymen should get together and compare notes and see if the experiences of the year that is closed may not warn us of some mistakes we have made and point the way to better methods for the future. Dairying, with all other branches of farming, has been reasonably successful and profitable during the pi feed has been abundant, cows have milked well, there has been a ready market for all dairy prod - ucts and prices, though slightly lower than tor the previous year, have been fully remunerative. trhe dairy industry of the state of Nebraska stands on a different is from that of almost every other state in the Union. The mer - ntable product put forth by the dairymen of this state is, practically entirely produced by the use of the hand separator ; and the great prob - lem before us, is to produce as good butter by this process as is pro - duced where other and more approved methods prevail. No satis! solution of this problem has yet been proposed, but we would like to offer one or two suggestions which seem to us to be pertinent to this question. May it not be that our creamerymen so solicitous to extend their territory, that they have placed the separator in the hands of so many farmers who are not dairymen, and who by no known law of evolution will ever become dairymen, that we have by far too large a proportion of incompetent and inefficient "'men behind the separator," thus form - ing an element that fosters discontent and brings disrepute upon the dairy business t Again : The hand separator can not of itself be responsible for the inferior grade of so much of our butter, as we shall see if we consider </seg>
            <seg id="p019">17 icase of two dairymen of equal intelligence, both equally careful and rough in their methods, but one selling cream from his handsenara - and the other delivering his whole milk to a creamery, as is largely e in the older daii Should not the cream that is separated m the milk within fifteen to thirty minutes after being drawn from cows udder be as pure and of as tine, or finer, flavor than that ich remains unseparated from n rer m ilk , while the milk is being de If this supposition is correct, then does not this problem in regard to the hand separator resolve itself lai . the cream promptly and in proper condition after it has been separated ! It seems to me that this is up to us as a very vital question just at this I It was never thought, until this centralizing idea took possession of le of the giant intellects in the creamery business, that cream could held f ir many hcurs and transported hundreds of miles on the rail - ds, as is being constantly done at the present time, and still be in a idition to produce fine butter ; and that this can be successfully done ret to be proven. May it not Vie that this problem will yet resolve ;lf into this: That this business does not have to be centralized and ! hand separator cream sent off on a wild scramble aci&lt; tate; : that each considerable community may do its own centralizing, tb its own creamery, and receive the cream direct from the producer ile it is yet fresh and sweet, and thus save the time lost while the am is in transit, save the expense of transportation on the railroad, 1 save the loss by deterioration in quality"; We believe rthv of earnest consideration. EWe would say nothing in i ment of the lary ameries of our state ; they have shown remarkable energy and posh establishing and extending their business; but it is a well established e of economies that the concentration of any line of business in one ce and in few hands: though it may build up a large establishment 1 a large income for the few. does not best conserve the true and ;hest interests of the people and at I It has sometimes been claimed that these association meetings have m run entirely by the creamerymen and in their interest ; if this i ever been true in the past, it is because the creamerymen have been i hand and willing to take hold and keep the meetings going, while private dairyman has .stayed away. But in refutation of such a irge, we are glad to point to the program of our meetings for this ir where it will be seen that the larger part of the topics to be con - ered are subjects that appeal especially to the individual dairyman, i home dairyman, and the milk producer: and we hope they will be ich in evidence in discussing these subjects. Another question we hope to hear discussed by our practical, think - ing dairyman is as to what proportion of our dairies and what propor- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">18 tion of the individual cows in the several dairies are consuming more value in feed and care than thev are paying back in salable products and increase. We predict that if all these unprofitable, or profit con - suming, cows, who like the mortgage keep on eating day and night. were s- e feed yard or the there would be a much mon feeling among tin .maining good cows, a material reduction in the aim unit &lt;&gt;f butter produced, and a correspondingly better market for , net that in put forth from the profit producing dairies. While these and many lore us and demanding solution, we are again threatened by our old enemy "Ole" with an at - tack to he made on the Grout law in Congress. The officers of the Na - tional Dairy Union think we can successfully withstand this attack, but it is not safe, to trust it all to chance in this matter; we should use means within our reach to be ready for the contest, and I hope this meeting will memorialize our members of Congress in both tranches and urge their earnest support for honest butt' The President : — Ladies and gentlemen, it is a great pleasure to announce that we have with us this morning, Ex-Governor Hoard of Wisconsin. He is one of the patriarchs in the dairy industry. I know he can give us some practical pointers, and he has kindly consented to talk to us for a few moments. I now take pleasure in introducing him e.rnor Hoard was received with applause and spoke as follows: Mr. President and Gentlemen of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association: I am pretty nearly talked out. I have been suffering from a bronchial attack. I have been spending a week in To]&gt;eka, Kansas, and working very hard, and last night's talk at the University leaves me with but very little confidence in my oratorical jwwers. But I like to meet my brethren of the same faith, no matter in what state we worship. I For thirty-four years, I have lx»en jxjunding away along these lines, 1 I am pretty nearly through. 1 nes and principles of the iry business a»-e ot universal application and I shall say few words ng general lines this morning. One thing I want to say to yon is ; not get the notion that because you live in Nebraska thnt things are much different, or that principles are so much different. The cow is it the same. Principles of breeding and dairy cows are just the same iskii as they are in Wisconsin or Vermont. The principle of i and caring for a cow. in order that she may do her level i just the same here as in the more eastern states. The principles of ding, feeding for milk, are just the same, also. Wherein is there -imply a little difference in environment. In passing along through Kansas and from Kansas here my heart absolutely ached, as I looked out of the window, and saw the universal and wide spread method of warming and sheltering their cows. The cattle were cattle suffering with the cold. I say to you it is beastly. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">19 The farmers of Kansas and Nebraska have suffered more loss during the last few weeks on account of their cattle bring exposed t 1, than they will make up during the reminder of the winte nelterf Every man I have spoken with said. "We do not need humbug never took possession of a man s mind in the wi a need to shelter your cattle just the same in Nebraska as • It is just the same principle. Forty-seven years ago I built a barn of straw in t sin to convince a cousin of mine that he was wrong. I set up t\\ of crotches, six feet a part. I went into the woods and rut them and built a barn 56 by 30 feet. The center row was higher than the outside row. I took poles and nailed on the inside of the posts which were set 8 feet apart. Then I took straw,— they were going to burn the straw — , and I took the old mare and walked her back a: n this straw, which I used to build the walls which were six feet wid.- and tun feet high. The general plan of the barn was a parallelogram. Then I cut out a place for windows and doors. In that stable I wintered thirty steers. The thennometor went down to 30 degrees below zero but the steers went through and thrived nicely all winter. The roof was made with poles and brush and then covered with a heavy layer of straw. That stable lasted twenty years. It cost me $7. 00 to build that barn, with what little lumber I used for the doors and windows. That amount of money can be secured by the average western man and he need not say that he don't need to build a barn. In regard t same principle applies identically in the promotion of milk and even more so. Gentlemen, I spoke to yon last night about women being so successful in dairying and as managers of herds of cows. Woman in - stinctively shrinks from cold. She knows better, as a mother, than to leave those cows out in the cold. (Tentlemen, my .»&lt;ht me a lesson that I could not have found in all th d. Thirty years ago, when our younger boy was a babe, a lusty younj; fellow. calling for more milk than she could give. riding together on a cold day with the babe in her lap. She suddenly took a seven* chill. She says. "Oh, I am so sorry I have caught this cold. " I said, should you feel sorry'" The far-sighted mother spoke and said : "Why it means so much less for the babe. " My curiosity was aroused ; I said, "Why does it mean so much less for the babe' chill from cold shrinks the milk." Then I said: "What will you do to re - cover from this t" She said: "I will go in and warm myself ami warm drink. ' ' I went home. I had two Jersey cows and I took a record of the milk they were giving. I then turned them out and • them and then brought them in and they were shaking like I eating. ) Then I took a record of that shrink. I gave them warm water and I saw that function come back. Then I repeated the process and chilled the cows again and afterwards wanned them and then saw that function come back again. Then I published, I think it was in the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">20 Prairie Fanner, to the world my experiment of warmth to promote the flow of milk with cows. I thought I was a mighty smart man, when for a thousand years there hasn't been an old woman in the country who had not known the principle. It reminds me of a cantankerous old maid who said that she didn't like children, she hated them ; she could not get along with them. One day she was asked why it was and she said, "I cannot bear children. An old lady said, "Can't yon t Maybe if you could, you would like them better. " (Laughter. ) There was a remark right down on bed rock by the wisdom of woman. The stand point for you young men to study this cow business, is from the stand point of the motherhood of the cow. There is another stand point, I want to use to bring out a few thoughts. In the first place you must breed from the stand point of motherhood. You are making mer - chandise of motherhood. It is to your interest that you increase it and enlarge it, therefore, breeding starts from a different idea than the average man has. It is just as instinctive and practical to breed for milk as it in to breed for draught. Take a race horse; you heard a lecture yesterday about the race horse. Take his formation. What is the requirement of the race horse? The race horse has sloping shoulders. The draught horse has a very different shoulder ; he is built different. These animals should be studied from the stand-point of their function. The race horse has a sloping shoulder in order that he may reach out with his fore feet. The draught horse has a broad shoulder in order that the collar may have a good tit ; he cannot get his feet up ; he can not run. Each machine is built for its specific function. The dairy cow is built on exactly the same principle. She is built for a certain function. She must be bred in the line of that function, and then she must be cared for in the line of that function. Take the steer, if yon pif fi. full of fat and he will go out and lie down on the snow. He is chockfull of carbon; full of heat. It is a matter of relief for him to lie down in the snow. Did you ever see a diary cow do such a thing as that'.' No. She will find the south side of a barn or shed, or seek some shelter where the sun shines. Warmth is essential to the secretion of milk. Would you think the farmers thought so, who leave their cows out without shelter? I have a barn 142 feet long, that will house 50 cows, with the best system of ventilation. The animals' bodies keep that barn at a temperature of from 50 to H degrees, when the thermometer oustside is at 80 or 40 degrees. The air changes in that barn every hour. That barn is just exactly as healthful as it can possibly be made. Do you know that one-half of the bed rooms in Fort Atkinson are not as health - ful a place to sleep in as that barn? Pure air. A cow lives on water, feed and air. Take away the air and she will die the quickest. Breath - ing foul air is on« of the most destructive influences we have to contend with. It is the foundation of this wide-spread tuberculosis and the foundation of many diseases. I spoke to you last night about the economy of expending $890.00 in ventilation for a barn. Now I have a </seg>
            <seg id="p023">TWENTIETH 21 good many contentions with my friends. There are in the neighbor - hood of our creamery about a dozen dual purpose herds of cows, and pretty good ones too. No one of those cows have been bred for a specific purpose. Everything had been done from a dual purpose stand point. In the creamery. I stand on a par, my milk, with the milk of the poorest man. I get no more for my butter or milk that is separated and taken to the creamery than the poorest. That creamery paid me in cash over 170.00 per cow for cream alone last year. Skim milk worth about $20.00 per cow. That herd of cows turning me about $90.00 per cow. If I were going out on the race track, my friends, and betting my money, and all was committed to the proposition of winning that race, do you think I would straddle h draught h&lt; I was in the battle of Cedar Creek. That was the titr.e that Sheridan made hia famous ride. General Early had attacked our forces at 8 o'clock in the morn - ing ; there was a tremendous defeat going on. By 9 o'clock in the morning he had us whipped. Sheridan was away. He started from Winchester to make that ride. He came down the Straasburg pike. He made the ride of SO miles in an hour. It meant the salvation of our army that Sheridan get there and get there quick, too. I never shall forget the occasion. As Sheridan came down the road, he in stragglers all along down the pike. Raising himself in his stirrmm he hollered to them saying: "Get about. About face. We will sock it to them yet. We will twist them out of their boots. Fie inspired those men. They cheered, hurrahed, yelled and whirled about and commenced marching back : as he came up the pike, his horse all covered with foam hut with unquenched ardor as if to say: "Bring on your miles, tor I have in my veins two thousand years of breeding for a special puipose. " Now my friends, we know the result of that battle and I don't know but what the faith of the Union hung upon it. It depended uiton the breeding of a horse, that Sheridan could get there in an hour's time, a distance of twenty miles. What would have been the result if Sheridan had straddled a draught horse? (Laughter. ) I want to tell you, that the dairyman who commits himself to the prop&lt; in all of its logic, must have a special purpose cow, if he wants to make the most money. So much for the cow. We must care for her as a cow. Take the dual purpose cow and she will do positively better if yon will treat her as a cow, rather than as a steer, if you will feed her for the of milk secretion, a ration that will promote the flow of milk and not a ration that will promote flesh. You have in Nebraska one of the finest rations. You are growing it here with increased acreage. You have the two elements that can beat the world, but yton are fighting the prop - osition with teeth and nails. I read your dairymen's report with great interest Brother Bassett sent it to me last year and I find that you are declaring silos are no good. Yon are wasting millions upon millions of dollars of corn feed by not putting it in silos. It will make the finest </seg>
            <seg id="p024">22 n earth. Then you have alfalfa ; that comes right up against it and the two make the balanced ration. With modern ensilage, ears and all, and from 10 to 12 pounds of alfalfa • iu need but very little to balance the ration. I can take these wo together and as I said to you last night make milk from 4 to 8 cents ht hundred lbs. cheaper, and get that much more cash because I have r than my neighbors, who don't believe these things. I come to yon as the exponent of a specialized dairy idea. I tell you what my friends, you should go to Jefferson county. Wisconsin— it may be n came from there. There is a county twenty-four miles I of the best and and she has a cow to every inhabitant. Jefferson county has thirty-six thousand inhabitants and forty thou - ■ hat an exhibition of agricultural wealth that rises to your travel through that connty composed mostly of (rermans. iinan agriculturists came to visit us. A year ago last tary Wilson sent them out to lcxjk at my farm. They had « the continent and back again. They had been sent out by nt. They came there and looked at my en; te all sorts of questions and they looked all over my tarm. I drove tlirm out through the country. I got about fifty of the German farmer* who lived there and who had good carriages and I put on&gt; in » carriage with one of our G-erman fanners. I said: ■ to them. Pump them full. Show them what this country' has n came here poor hired men with only five to fifty dollars each anil today own your fifty thousand dollar farms."' So after - wards these men said to me: '"How do you make money? How can make money, paying such awful prices for labor?" One man said I have two hundred and fifty acres of potatoes. I cannot afford to use machinery. I hire men for twenty-five cents a day and I don't see how we could afford these condit I said to that man : "I thank God that we do not li\ -mil a count i .lauae) Material wealth is not anything along side of a fair show for the manhood and womanhood in my country. " I said to him : '"I would rather pay $25. 00 or $30.00 a month for good men and feel that they were sharing these things with me, and they had some show for the manhood which is in them, the same chances to learn, study ard look into these things, — I would rather pay that much than to make all the money that you could make at 25 cents a day for a man and 10 cents a day for a woman. " He shrugged his shoulder and •it nix au~ plause. ) I am going to tell you some - f&gt;88 in my county. I took hold of it in 1870. It was clear to the bottom, wheat, wheat, wheat, fer - tility all gone, wheated out. Eight bushels to the acre was the average Inction of wheat. Farmers selling their farms for $18.00 per acre. . selling out and going into Minnesota and Nebraska to ruin another </seg>
            <seg id="p025">23 by-way« and hedges, commei cow. (Laughter.) They said : "What d. man know about this?" They didn't know I had been a trained butter and cheese maker and was reared in that business in New York. But I mi them finally, got them organi/.ed and the bnsiness began to grow | grow and has grown, until today the forty thousand I Jefferson county earned two million of dollars a year, an average of $50.00 per cow. Now. my friends, that is ■ it avera;. usand cows. We took the census of all of th&gt; :ity and we find that they are making on an average today '2tio pounds of butter per cow. The agricultural product of that twenty-four mile* square, to the census of 1W0 is about five million of dollars. That is what specialized dairying has dune. I&gt; I&gt;er cent of all the aaeesninent valuation of those fan - under mortgage. If are any mortgages now it is for the [win hai of the farm - those days the mortgage wax to pay a debt ; last year there wa - fi of farm land sold and the average sale of t h&lt; — •- lands, good, poor indifferent was within a - of flOO.OO i**r acre. Now these instructive. I have seen in the past thirty-four years meat )«n with a bump. I have seen all kinds of farm products in m ■■tea, but I have seen the dairy interests steadily, steadily grow- A great many men say. "Wh\ will go to pieces the first thing you know ; the business will bi But, my friends that is not true. I)o you know that icreaae the consumption that is diverted to cities is almost as great . crease in the number of ci '\v&gt; New York reaches out four hundred miles west to get milk. Chicago is reaching out farther and t and there in that city is an enormous consumption of milk. Tl braska farmer does not need to worry for if there is any thin_ earth it is the dairy industry rightly handled. Now these are some Keral thoughts and I thank you for the opportunity ing a reason for the hope and faith that is within me. tan. ) Pinman : — We have some problems confi in your address, I would lik* 1 for butter in Wisconsin for the various ■ thing about the conditions governing -iness ■ »'&gt;rnor Hoard: It is divided l but more largely by proprietors. The milk is all bought I Babcock test. Gradually we are coming, not a* fast aa you are - are coming to use the hand separator. • Economies are vastly greater with the farm separator, but such move slowly. I cannot tell you what the price of butter fat was i various months of the year, but I can tell you it does not all depend upon the amount of money that the patron receives at the creamery. DISCCSSU &gt;N. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">24 nds largely on the way the thing is handled and managed at the farm and not altogether upon the creamer}'. Q. - You ask what does it cost to make milk and how to make cream a better price? Why my friends, a man who has a cow that gives 300 pounds of butter a year and another cow that makes him 150 pounds of butter a year it costs double for the cow that gives 150 {xninds of t to what it does the cow that gives me 300 pounds a year, and mo; I am putting it modestly. He is looking over to the creamery for better things and better prices while he should look into the details end of the business. The way that we do in Wisconsin B the price of milk for the year. We go by the 100 pounds of milk. that ranges over various figures. For instance, my milk returned to me last year about $1.20 a hundred pounds, but ray cows are high grade and registered cows. —high class cows. I cannot afford to keep an\ cow. A man walked into my yard not long ago and offered me a piece for seventeen of these high grade cows. I didn't sell tl. him. I could not afford to sell them to him. As I said my milk re - turned to me about fl.20 a hundred pounds. In the same en there are men whose milk returned them last year s»; cents a hundred. Mr. Hinman : — What does it cost a co-operative creamery inWisc to make a pound of butter r I Governor Hoard: — I cannot tell you because conditions vary. I 10 average i Mr. Hinman: — The reason I asked the question is, I am engaged in traveling over the State of Nebraska and they say they are not getting enough for their butter fat. I am told by the farmers that they are not getting enough for their butter fat. I am told by the factories that the farmers of Nebraska are getting more for their butter fat than they are in any other surrounding state — of course. Wisconsin is not a surround - ing state. Governor Hoard:— I could not tell you in regard to that. Bur this time is worth in Chicago I think about 27 cents. Mr. Hinman :— In this state I think it is about 2H cents, nor Hoard : — There is a variation ; you cannot fix it Klinman : — The average price for the year 1904 tn&gt;: ring , simply taking each one-half month, wa- m pound &gt;r fat. ernor Hoard: — Of course in all this matter it is for the tanner to post himself. Ignorance is everywhere at a discount. Ignorance is weakness and the farmer that is taking milk to the creamery, why don't he read up and know in regard to all these things? I belie only way to test cream is by weight using 17.6 c.c's. But Gentlemen. I moat go home. I wish yon all God's speed in your efforts to bet • tions of the dairymen in Nebraska. The President : — Governor Hoard has given us some gospel truths ning the dairy business and I hope that every dairymen will take some of these figures and facts home with him. Governor Hoard of the old apostles in the dairy industry. What has been done in Wis - consin, can be done in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            
            <seg id="p028">25 The next on our program is an article or paper by L D. Stillaon of York, who will now address yon. Mr Stillson spoke as follows:— Mr. President. Ladies and Gentlemen : You know that Nebraskans, a good many of them, are like a ■iiiwjn Yon all know what a sponge is. It will absorb lota of water and will not give it back, unless you squeeze it. We sent men to St. Lonia World s Fair to look after the Nebraska product. We sent men down there to absorb every thing, and who don't like to give np any thing without being asked in regard to it. so you will feel at liberty to ask questions fl have written a short article relating to the department of which I ad charge, the dairy, and it is something along this line that I will speak to you about. Our exhibit as a whole was fitted up for us. Some of the states paid from two to three thousand dollars for the artistic work done in putting up their dairy exhiit. Minnesota being on one corner of the block or division devoted to dairy exhibits, had a canoe molded in butter and just landing at the foot of St. Anthony falls ; in the canoe was represented Father Hennipen who discovered the falls, his traveling companion and an Indian guide, all life niae. That exhibit cost them something like fcUMtn. iki for the artistic work. Indiana came next with a very fine exhibit, a commercial exhibit of butter, but showing no artistic frills or anything of the kind. The next was Nebraska's dairy exhibit which is thus described in the report of our state" commissioners : "It consisted of the usual space assigned each state in the refrigeration se&lt; ted entirely to the greatest display of butter and cheese ever made in the world Nebraska's dis - play in reality consisted of two exhibits installed at different times during the season. The first was strictly a commercial exhibit wherein was shown the wonderful growth and development of the dairy industry of Nebraska (Turing the last five years. A map showing the position of the 20. (XXi hand separators in the state that made a part of this exhibit. Later in the season a of butter, from which flowed a stream of yellow butter, wassnbst: with the legend •Nebraska's liquid gold. *20,(HN),0OtUJO annualh gie installation of this dairy exhibit the Nebraska commission the payment of $500 on the part of the Beatrice lany of Lincoln, the Hygeia . • mpany of and the Fairmont &lt; Fairmont. This was subscribed with the understanding that it should be used pay the cost of refrigeration during the season. " Lin n iry exhibit Nebraska was arded a Gold Medal. Ne.\ ikota represented by a statue in butter, two-thmls '. mounted on a pony, as a •'Cow boy" as he was while a resident of that sta Adjoining North Dakota was California with their exhibit of batter, representing the Goddess of Liberty, a statue of a woman, a statue of about sevei She was standing between two bears, mod- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">NEBRASKA D AIR YMF \TION 26 •led in butter and of heroic size. Next to California came Oregon and Washington ; their exhibit was practically made together and made by the same party. One represented a picture, that some of you may have seen, of a milkmaid milking a cow and by her side was a cat ; the maid was feeding the cat at the same time : the other one represented a school boy and girl. The school boy was being fed a piece of bread and butter by the girl. These were made to repraseir eight or nine years of age and were very fine indeed. Missouri at the roi the refrigerator case. Their exhibit consisted of two life size cows molded in butter. One modeled after a famous Holstein and the other a fain ous Jersey cow both of the state of Missouri. This exhibit cost Missouri about $25000.00 for the artist's work. Around the corner there was an exhibit of the Blue Valley Creamery Company with a placard which read th%t they were the largest creamery in the world. They represented themselves as the connecting link between the producer miuI tl. tamer; there was a lady standing with her arms tilled with chunks of batter; on one side of the wall was the producer, in relief work, and on the other side was the consumer sitting at the table eating his menl with his family— all this in relief butter work. Then came New with a very fine commercial exhibit, which wa« a representation of the Liberty Bell, exact size, each pound of butter representing ten pounds tthe weight of the original bell. There were several hundred pounds butter in this mold. Then came Kansas with the new and the le churn and the new style hand separator. In connection with this exhibit was an exhibit of the celebrated •• Meadow Gold" brand of butter made by the Beatrice Creamery Company of Lincoln, Nebraska. Iowa had a bust molded in butter of John Stewart, the father of the Creamery system of manufacturing butter : also in miniature a model of the first Creamery built by Mr. Stewart; included in this exhibit was also, modeled in butter, a representation of the dairy building on the campus of Iowa's Celebrated Agricultural College. Next came Illinois with two of her most celebrated sons, Lincoln and Grant, molded in butter. On a corner was Wisconsin with a life size dairymaid and cow made of butter. The entire exhibit, from an artistic standpoint was the finest ever made and while in the great iral building of the expi covering acres of sp; y hand beautiful and • sive exhibits, yet no exhibit in this building was so much admir. visited by so great a number of people as was the great dairy exhibit. from these various states, this meager description of which gives you bat a faint idea of its magnitude aiid beauty. Side Lights From the Dairy Department, Vorld's Fair, at St. Louis. S. D. Stillman. York. Nebr. It is right and proper that I should say something of the dairy ex - hibit at St. Louis, having been recommended by your secretary for the position of assistant superintendent in charge of the Nebraska butter exhibit To Professor Haecker was given the position for the month of </seg>
            <seg id="p030">TWENTIETH ,L CONY 27 June and to him we are indebted for the first installation of the ex - hibit. I reached St. Louis July 5th and relieved Professor Haecker. Oar exhibit, like all others was in a glass case or room, kept cool by refrig - eration by means of the ammonia process. The front was made of glass with 8-foot panes and each state or exhibit could have one or two spaces as they chose to pay $500 fur each 8-foot space. Outside we had same sized space railed off, for table and three chairs, with a six foot space or aisle between case and table. In the refrigerator case there were twenty exhibits ; Minnesota, Missouri, Wisconsin and New York each occupying two windows, the other states one each. On the rear wall of the space occupied by Nebraska, Professor Haecker prepared and put up a map of the state showing where the central creameries were located also skimming stations, and dots showing where the hand separator was doing its work. We also had small placards telling of our output and some of our advantages for dairying. We were restricted in our work for want of funds, however we made some additions from time to time putting in some new feature and a little difference in Ar - rangement each week until about the I tuner when our wKre - tary, who was the superiutei he dairy department, made his first visit to the exposition and by his magnetism secured from the commission sufficient funds to put in an entirely new exhibit using a little of the old material. tl will say in thja connection, as with all the exhibits that went m Nebraska, everything was conducted on the most economical plan possible. Be it said to the credit of the men who had charge of the exhibition that we went there with only $35000.00 to start with, but the Commission was very influential with* the railroad companies and they gave us about $25000 more ; and* in the final report of the Commission, there is money left to turn back into the state treasury. That is ■ome thing that every man in Nebraska should be proud of, whether they had anything to do with the exposition or not, they should be proud of the commission which handled the funds in such shape as to have money left. None of us became millionaires. No man who waa there was paid over $75.00 a month and he had to pay his own board out of For our exhibit we were awarded a gold medal, in this respect rank - ing equal to any of our competitors. I stayed with the exhibit four months, or until November 3rd, when I was ordered to turn over it* care to the general committee after which I returned home, arriving on elec - tion day. What was done with the material of this exhibit I do not know nor do I know its cost and maintenance. As a commercial and instructive exhibit it was the equal of any. We paid less than $100 for labor of artists and decorations while some of our competitors paid thousands of dollars for such laDor and materials. Of one thing I am thoroughly convinced ; if you wish to make an exhibit as an advertise - ment for products or for the state don't smother your exhibit with artistic work ; let the products speak for thorn— I yea. The butter ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">28 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION hibit was one of the most attractive on the exposition grounds. It was viewed by thousands of visitors every day and often a thousand to two thousand — by actual count, paused in one hour between our table and oar exhibit and every day hundreds came inside our railing to ask about Nebraska. Our butter was only bait, as it were, to get people to stop and inquire. and it served its purpose well. Being nearly always there, we could talk Nebraska and her facilities to an appreciative audience. In the butter scoring contest we only had a single trial. The dairy industry, or the butter making part of it, is conducted in such a man - ner that private dairies were not seeking a market for a few pout high scoring butter and so would not have been materially beii' by having butter scored ; neither did our State Commission feel just - ified in expending money for expenses to have a large butter display, so that when the cash premiums were awarded Nebraska was not in it. Our state is making rapid strides in her advancement in the dairy line of work. Located as we are and with onr rich feeds, there is no reason why we should not take the front seat, and keep it too. Last year our dairy product was worth twenty millions, this year lets make it five millions more. In Agricultural hall there was in operation what was termed "The Model Dairy. " Here all the modern machinery and appliances were in active operation and here one of our Neraska boys, Charles Mellick, was chief buttermaker. In the cow barns was the center of attraction ; a battle going on there to which the world was looking and in which •very cow keeper was to some extent interested. There were kept fifty or sixty cows of different breeds, selected as representatives of dairy breeds to fight for 120 days, to decide which was the better breed. These had been selected by experts and on account of their known work. Every device that ingenuity could suggest or money bny for their comfort was obtained. Every feed that the chemist thought might add another ounce to their milk and butter production watt given them. The whole country was scoured to find attendants t . &lt; Every milking was weighed ; all the feed weighed or measured ; each milking tested. Thirty days saw one breed failing ; sixty days, another breed being distanced ; ninety days neck and neck for the other two breeds. Four months the third breed beaten by fractions of a pound of butter. Thousands of dollars were spent in this test and now hundreds of pounds of wind are being used to tell why they were beaten. This test was also a battle of brains : the care given there was all that could be thought of and in no other way could such results have been obtained. The question is often asked "of what use to the farmer has this contest been. ' ' It has demonstrated to every one the fact that to do her best the cow must be given comfort, rest and feed and that such attention pays. That sometimes fairly good cows, by having extra attention and care can be made to pay pretty well ; that the cow that is bred right and fed right will pay a handsome income to her owner. As a matter of interest in connection with Mr. Stillson's paper, </seg>
            <seg id="p032">TWENTIETH 29 herewith ia given the general statenie finances of the Nebraska State Commission to the St. Louis Exposit -TATEM K Appropriation by the state of Nebraska Donation Union Pacific Railway I Donation, Burlington &amp; Missouri River R. R. Co Donation, Chicago &amp; Northwestern Railwa Donation. Beatrice Creamery Co.. Lincoln Donation, Hygeia C r eamery Co. , Omaha Donation, Fairmont Creamery Co. . Fairmont Received from sale of exhibits and installation m w 125 00 $61,090 75 Disbursements. Agricultural exhibit Horticultural exhibit Educational exhibit, including mineral and social sciei hibits m Moving picture exhibit Nebraska pavilion Live stock exhibit Poultry exhibit Dairy exhibit State Historical Society exhibit Employees Advertising Miscellaneous n Entertainment Commissici: 1 traveling exiwnditures Paid commissioner public lands and buildings, receipts from sale of exhibits and installation Balance refunded to state treasurer KH.090 75 DISCUSSION. KThe President : I would like to ask about the two breeds that i at the exposition, which was first and which was second, and how y stood? Mr. Stillson: In the final wind-up there were fifteen Holsteii the Holstein class. The best was beaten by the beat Jersey three tenths of one pound of but! (A voice), You have that wrong. (Laughter). There was one Holstein cow that came out third. (Laught&gt; - saw the record before I left the exposition and I copied it. In the final Rec&lt; •8S.0- i </seg>
            
            <seg id="p033">30 test the beet test of fifteen Jersevs would have beaten the Holsteins, but the average of the twenty -live Jerseys was higher than the average of the fifteen Holsteins. There has been quite a discussion going the rounds since I came home. I have noticed the papers commenting upon the manner in which that was conducted, and the reasons that are be - ing given for beating and all that. 1[ will tell you. however, right now that the final wind up was good ugh for any one. any person who had a cow in either of those herds be proud of the record that cow made. Q. — I would like to ask if they considered the by-pro&lt;l Mr. Stillson : They were all figured in the final test. Q. — Was the latter herd kept account of. Mr. Stillson: Yes sir; the entire test, each cow was kept account of and each marked for butter fat and also tested for fat and also for milk solids not butter fat. The test at St. Louis was educational. The ■agreement at the start was that it should be along the line of economi - cal production. Mr. Glissman : I am a breeder of Holstien cattle and I think that it is only fair to the Holstein interests, since the matter has come up, to say that the Jersey contingent was in the interest of the American Jersey Cattle Club, with unlimited who took their cattle to " Jersey - ville" in Illinois and kept them there preparing them for the test, while the Holstein Breeders Association did not sample beforehand. If I am mistaken there is some one here who can correct me. They didn't enter the test for reasons of their own ; but there were two or three Holstein breeders who in fact used their own private funds to buy cattle and went in single handed with their own selection, against the entire Jersey Breeders of the United States, with only such cattle as they could get bold of, not having the opportunity of previous records and trials. I do not know how many Holstein cows there were at the start but I think they tried upward of twenty-five. They had the re - oonrces of an association of breeders headed by Mr. Moore and I believe they would have won out under more favorable circumstances. I think the showing might have been very much better if the Holstein men had the same opportunities that the Jersey men did have. I think a special honor ought to be given Mr. Moore and the gentlemen associated with him who had the courage to put up the money and make this contest. Incidently I hear that they lost money l&gt;ecause they paid high prices for these cows and because some of them did not sell for any such price as they paid for them at the end of the exposition. t (Voice. ) I am somewhat of a Yankee and I would like to ask a ation. How many states did they scour to get the fifteen Holstein A. — I cannot tell you. Can you tell? Q. — About fourteen states were represented in the herd of fifteen </seg>
            <seg id="p034">T\\ EXTIETH 31 A. Can you tell how many cows dropped 1/ I don't know that because they won't tell it. I Mr. Hinman : Can yon tell me how many of those cows came from state of Missouri? II think three that were put into the first test but I think there I only one that won out from the state of Missouri I won't b« cer - n, however, because those men kept their records to themselves and outsiders could not find out a single thing. One of their own men told that those fift ted fourteen states. They secured closely as the .1 &gt;!id. I will say for the the Hobteina that they labored undi disadvantage and that was that they did not have the silage to feed as some of the others had. It was green feed brought on the wagon ; and one of the Holstein men said that they had to pay too high price for some green feed brought there. It was cut out in the country and brought in on wagons. IMr. Clark: The next paper on the program this morning is Home iry. by Henrv C. (ilissman of Omaha. Mr. (ilissman : Before I start in with my paper I would like to set Mr. Stillson right on on. it he made and that is in regard to the champion cow at St. Louis It was Zaila &lt;Te,rl&gt;en of the Holstein breed and owned by Mr. M. E. Muore of Missouri. She beat the Jersey a trifle over three pounds and three-tenths of butter fat in LSOdaya. The next best cow was Loretta D. Those are the fa The topic assigned me is the Home Dairy, but I found it a pretty narrow subject and for some of narrow. I have therefore widened it out and have entitled my paper Hints on Profitable Dairy - HINTS ON PROFITABLE DAIRYING. Henry C. (-rlissman, Omaha. Dairying in our state, within the last few years, has undergone a great change. The general systei ing has changed from that of home dairying, or the maK r on the farm, to that of commercial dairying, or the shipping of cream to some centrally located creamery or butter factory, and there made into butter. I Taken as a whole this change has no doubt Iwen a change for the d, for in the short hraska has advanced from twentieth to the tenth state in the rank of butter production. Great as this change in the system of dairying has been, I believe that there are still many places where home dairying can be practiced at a greater profit, than can be had hy selling cream. Location as to market and natural surroundings for the proper taking care of cream and butter must be considered; an article equal to, or superior to the best creamery butter must be produced and private customers for oxir </seg>
            <seg id="p035">32 product must be secured, and to make the greatest profit we must sell direct to the consumer. I For over twenty years, at home, have operated a home dairy, and yet have not been able to figure out how we could make more money I of our cows than by making IS cent butter. Being located near a ge city we have no trouble t&lt;i get cnwtooMn lor all the butter we can )duce. and what is more, we do not fear the ootnpetitioa of delwild, " " ' Meadowgola, " or any other brand it make of butter. In the production of our butter we use the following method : Im - iately after each milking, the milk is separated and the cream ed to a temperature of at least B8 degrees Fahr. . skim milk being to calves, pigs and poultry while warm. The cream is ripened in gallon shot gun cans, and is churned in a dasher churn, operated b&gt; e-power. Twenty to thirty pounds of butter are usually churned time. Immediately after churning, the butter is salted and ked. and put up in rolls or crocks. We make delivery every Satur - , and along with the butter sell all the eggs, poultry and vegetables produce, always getting a good margin alwve market prices for the e. This briefly, is the method in vogue at our home dairy, and one . no doubt can be profitably followed by a good many others. tBut how to make the dairy business in Nebraska, as a whole i Stable, is ]&gt;erhaps the burning question of the day. And to thi stion I would answer, educate our people in the principle* of dairy and bring to l&gt;ear on them the necessity of culling their dair ds. For there are too many "star lwarders in the herds of ou :e that must l» replaced by cows that will yield a profit. Or in y we must use the methods of Lord Rivers, the famous Englis eder of greyhounds, who said that the secret to his success in th eding of these animals was the fact that he "bred many, and bun ny. " And it is my conviction that the time has come when w ;ht to have a closer weeding out of the dairy herds of our state. I Another important course that must be followed is the grading up dairy herds. More pure-bred dairy sires must be placed at the head the dairy herds, and the owners must make up their minds whether •y are going to dairy as dairymen or iust milk for pass time. The milk producer must specialize in the selection of his cows an&lt; must not expect to make a very large profit out of the milk produce* from a beef herd. This reminds me of the story of an old Merman farmer, whom a young doctor was trying to impress with the fact tha he knew a great deal more about medicine than the ordinary docto did, because he had studied both Homeopathic and ordinary medicine The farmer looked the young fellow over for a moment and then re marked. "Well, wbat you say may be so. but I had a calf once tha socked two cows and he never made any thing but a common steer afte all." Now, I believe that the mnn who is trying to make his catt both good beef cattle and good dairy cattle will find as a rule that the are just common steers after all. The education of the people in the principles of dairying, is perhaps </seg>
            <seg id="p036">A. L. c:O A D Winner of Gold Watch in Cow Judging Contest </seg>
            
            <seg id="p037">33 imcwt obstinate barrier to profitable dairying. "It is hard to teach old dog new tricks" is an old saying, but it is nevertheless a very e one. It is hard to get the older dairymen interested in anything t tends to the uplifting of the dairy industry, for but comparatively r of the so-called dairymen of at liat an enormous ount of wealth the old cow is bringing to us and it remains for as to ch the younger men who are in the tormative period of . principles of butter making anil thereby hope to get an interest in rying that we cannot get in any other way. We have here in our universitv railing of life, but I would like to see one more added to the list. I would like to see the degree of Bachelor of Scientific Dairying added to the list of degrees which are given by our- university, and every other university that can boast of a dairy school. To qualify for th I do not mean that one must simply be able to make good butter or cheese, but must be able to handle scientifically every branch of dairying, from the feeding and care of the cow in the barn to the proper marketing of the milk and its products. Before closing, I wish to say that the course in dairying as given by our Professor Haecker. in the dairy school here at the university, is nearer the correct one in my opinion than that ot any other school I know of, in as much as the course her. - that of the Hume Dairy system. Every step of dairying from the time the milk • barn, is handled by the students, by them the milk ated. ripened, churned, salted and packed for market. This practice, together with the hours of lectures and talks by the Professor, in which he makes clear the whys and wherefores tending to the making of good butter, cannot help but make not only good butter makers, but good cream shippers as well, which in this age of commercial dairying is of vital interest and I do not doubt but what the dairy the uni of Nebraska here annually turns out a number of graduates that might justly be given the degree of Baclu ntinV Dairyii Q. — You don't need a dasher chum to net Holatein butt. Mr. Glissman.— No: when we first began churning by horse power it was almost impossible to get anything. : a barrel c-hurn. to hold as much cream as we would like. We never were in favor of the barrel churn. We found a dasher churn that was made in v state which we found v&lt; ..to v and we have now a second churn of that make. While it does first class, the dasher churn makes a little bette r grain. I have no special reason for using that kind of a churn. Q. — Did you take a dairy course at this school.' I Mr. Glissman. — Yes, sir; ii _ard to churns, the sher churn is pretty nearly any barrel churn, but you ve to be a little more careful with thi ture Q. — What temperature do you churn at? DISCUSSION. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">34 Mr. Glissinan. — We churn at from 58 to 60 dergees. seldom above 60 Q. — Do you use starter 1 ! Mr. Glissman. — No; we set the cream in a five gallon can and the cream is mixed from can to can. Q. — What kind of a milk house do you have? Mr. Ghssman. — Our milk house is located very nicely for the hand - ling of butter. We have good natural surroundings and a good spring ; the water comes to the surface of the ground and is led to the milk house by a pipe and the water is kept changing and keeps at a tem - perature of 56 degrees winter and summer. As soon as the cream is separated we set it in this water. Q. — How do you work your butter"; E. Glissman. — We have a double butter worker. I cannot tell the of it but it runs with a crank and we can work about thirty s at once. The President. : We cannot all expect to make thirty and thirty-five cent butter unless we live nearer to Omaha or some other good large city. I have traveled through the state and stopped at hotels and I think it would be a good plan for somebody to go to work and make gome good butter and sell it to the hotel men, judging from the quality of the butter on the table. (Applause. ) For myself I am a creamery Ein and from a financial point I would like to see the farmer sell his sum to the creamery. This association is for the best interests of the irymen of the state. Then there is this home dairy question that is very much neglected. I think if you come to the bottom of facts nine out of even- ten who are milking cows neglect them because it is a little easier not to do the thing requisite at the time it should be done. If you don't want to do this you needn't expect to make thirty butter or to get that price for it. For the best interest of the dairymen of the state it is of importance to know how to make good cream and to make good butter and to know how to sell it. Q. — If Mr. Glissman can make butter and sell it for thirty and thirty-five cents a pound, is it not just as important for other fanners to have some good purchasers of butter? I think every farmer ought to know how to make thirty-five cents butter. The President. — Yes, I think so too. Voice). That is true and he can learn if he will come her. s school. (Laughter). </seg>
            <seg id="p039">35 AFTERNOON SESSION. The President. — We will now listen to the report of the treasurer: REPORT OF THE TREASURER. rthe officers and members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association : Herewith is presented the report of the financial transactions of the Association for the year ending Dec. 31. 1904. S. C. Bassett, Dated Dec. 31, 1904. Treasurer. Receipts r 21 Life membership. Henry C. Gliasman i Annual memberships. $1.00 each 16 State appropriation m s*&gt; | Oct. M s a Total *1 Expenditures z 1 Deficiency . $ H&lt;» 16 S. C. Bassett. Salary as secretary to Feb. 1, 1904 W. A. Rodgera, P. If. Postage to Jan. 5, mm Feb. 16 (). Erf, Expenses to deliver address at annual ing L. D. Stillson. Expenses to deliver address at annual meeting meeting The Ivy Press. Printing " Lindell Hotel. Entertainment of officers and guests M '-•"&gt; J. B. Trickey &amp; Co., Watch for Prize J. W. Brewster. Services as stenographer M. Little " Cream t^st Whitehead &amp; Hoag Co. . Badges R. A. St. Jnhn. Stationary &amp; Printing Feb. 16 F. D. Reed, stationary and printing 8 30 J. A. Harris. Expenses to d&lt; Iress at annual </seg>
            <seg id="p040">36 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Febr. 16 Henry C. Glissman, premiums ' H. W. EhlerB, " R. S. Tolles, " J. M. Brown, ' J. N. Ashburn. " W. A. Doubt. Wilson, • Mrs. S. Pierce, ■ J. L. Wheaton, " Art Gentzler, " M. M. Sterns, ' J. F. Scblappi, " C. W. Tolles, ' J. B. Varney, " Max L. Buschaw • B. R. Stouffer, " D. N. Syford, ' W. A. Rodgers. P. M. postage 3 m B22 S. C. Basnett, salary as secretary to March 31, 1904 I. A. Kirk, cashier, exchange on drafts R. A. St. John, printing and stationary F. D. Reed, W. A. Rodgers, P. M. postage 1 tMI I April 7 Express to Ravenna July 8 S. C. Basset t. salary as secretary to June 30. 1904 &gt; W. A. Rodgers. P. M. postag. Bt John, stationary and printing Oct. 2 Hammond Bros., printing 2000 copies of report. 125 pages at |1.M " 11 Copper plates, % tones for report Freight prepaid on reports IS. C. Bassett, salary as secretary to Dec. 31, 1904 W. A. Rodgers, P. M. jmstago L. D. Stillson, expense attending director's meeting J. C. Merrill, expense attending director's meetin_ R. A. St. John, printing and stationary Freight and expense Henry C. Glissman, espense attending director's meeting C. A. Clark, expense attending director's meeting Express Balance, cash on hand 150 00 2 00 8 30 • 9o Total |l,0M 2« State Appropriation 1903 Amount appropriated for biennium Jan. 1, 1904 Amount expended to d'ate Balance in hands of state treasurer On motion the report of the treasurer was referred to an auditing </seg>
            <seg id="p041">TWENTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 37 Ctee consisting of Messrs. Henry C. Glissman, J. K. Honeywell I). Stillson. At a succeeding session of the meeting this corn - submitted the following report: E President : Your committee appointed to audit the report of surer of this association, respectfully report that we have warn- I vouchers accompanying said report and find the same to be and that the expenditures made were proper and for the best "trta of the association. (Signed) Henry C. Gliasman, J. K. Honeywell, Committee. The President : The next topic on the program is a talk by Mr. C. H. Hinimin on the necessity for grading cream at cream receiving sta - .ind 1 take pleasure in introducing to you Mr. Hinman who will uldress you. El r Hinman: Ladies and Gentlemen of the Association : — The point I covered by this talk is the necessity of judging or grading cream rding to the quality. There was some question raised, particularly one this morning, in regard to the grading of cream for butter fat, and I shall speak on that point first : for instance, the charge was made that cream is tested some times incorrectly, and some times not at all and frequently t&gt;\ incompetent men. If this be true, it is a serious charge because it is on the basis of this grading and testing that the butter fat is paid for. Since the first of December I have traveled more or leas over this state and I have made it my business to investigate the condi - tions- at the receiving stations, to talk with the operators of these sta - tions and find out how they are grading cream and to determine if possible the truth of such charges. In almost every place I go, in talk - ing about cream separators and cream production, I bear the charge that the cream is not fairly tested, "that we are furnishing more batter fat than we are getting pay for;" for instance I was told atOconto, in Cus - ter county, that the operator of the cream receiving station took some cream and tested it for acid and then from the mixture of the cream and hat he took a sample and tested it the same as he would for pure cream. I replied that if any operator was putting anything into cream and then testing it the same as he would for Dure cream that he was doing something unfair and should be corrected for it. I went to the cream receiving stations at Oconto and asked how they tested cream. Each one of them volunteered to test some cream for me. I found that there was this basis of truth for the report that they took the sample of cream, one pipette full, tested it for acid by the addition of one pipette full of alkali, and then from the mixture they took one pipette full and tested it for butter fat, multiplying the result by two. It will be readily seen that this should give accurate results if carefully done. I am not a special agent for any creamery company. They are all alike to me, but I will say that I am convinced that in the great ma - jority of cases, probably 97 out of 100, cream is tested fairly at the cream receiving station for batter fat, except that in most cases I observed </seg>
            <seg id="p042">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 38 they tested by quantity and not by weight, and in some cases a 17.6 centimeters pipette is used and in some cases a test bottle is used which does not read closer than two degrees. This last I think should be changed. I think you might expect it to read a one-half or one per cent, cer - tainly one per cent. In talking with these operators I asked them ques - tions. They didn't know who I was or what I was trying to find out and I asked all sorts of foolish questions so that they would not know who I was. In every case as far as I investigated I found out what they were doing so I am convinced that in the majority of cases, the teat for butter fat is being fairly done, except as I have said they did it by quanity and not by weight. Cases have come to my notice where the operator has taken a holiday and has averaged a test of the preceeding day for the test of the particular day that he was absent. One case in particular came to ray attention. It occured on decoration day in the town of Arnold, Custer county, Nebraska. The operator went away on that day and it was found in checking over his test for that day that i r't hold out. Investigation showed that he had not made the test that he had guessed at the whole bunch, and he was discharged. EIr. Bassett : Did you look over the records of these stations from to day with a view to ascertain whether the per cent of fat was same or nearly so. from day to day, or did the records show that i lot of cream received was tested. Mr. Hinman : I have not done that in every case but in some cases I have and the results have been satisfactory- tThe charge is sometimes made that the cream does not run uniform ■ after day, one day the cream will test high, another day it will test ir. There are plenty of reasons for that but I have not time at pres - to go into that branch of the subject. In the matter of grading the quality of cream we are a very con - servative people. We do not like new things. Anything that is new we are likely to question. We are familiar with the grading by quality of cattle, of anything and everything that we sell except cream. We know that butter made from the hand separator is not of good repute in the market. We know that our sister states of Minnesota and Wis - consin produce better butter than does Nebraska, Kansas or even Iowa. In these states of Minnesota and Wisconsin the hand separator is not in as common use as in Nebraska or possibly Iowa. A prominent creamery Epany in this state and in Kansas have always been behind in the iity of a considerable per cent of their product. They have used as an excuse for paying less money for butter fat than is paid in the states of Minnesota and Wisconsin. They say they cannot sell butter for as much owing to the condition under which they are obliged to make it out of that kind of cream and say that they are not warranted t paying as good prices as they would otherwise for butter fat. Within week I asked the manager of one of our large cieamery comuanies why e company did not pay more for butter fat. He said if we got all st quality cream we could pay more for butter fat but we do not get </seg>
            <seg id="p043">39 R first class quality cream. If this he true, and it is true, they could more if they got all first class quality cream. It is a sufficient ex - cuse for the grading of cream as to quality. Let us consider what hapi&gt;ens when we do not grade cream for quality. If there is a person present, a merchant who does a credit business, he knows that the men who buy goods and pay their bills, pay not only their own bills but also the bills of the men who do not pay. If the merchant makes a profit he makes it from the man who pays his bills and he must therefore charg* ha man who pays his bills shall pay for the man who does not pay. The same is true in the case of producers of good an d bad cream. The bad quality of cream lowers the quality of the butter so that it sells for less in the market. If that is true, then it must l&gt;e true that tl ry eom]&gt;any which will make a profit, must pay enough less t it. The man who furnishes cream capable of making better butter, or butter which would sell for more, must take less for his cream than it its worth in order that the man who is furnishing cream which makes poor butter shall get a little more for his cream thau it is worth. B&gt; I maintain that there is just as much justice in the grading of n for quality as there is for grading your cattle in the market, or ere is for grading anything. Ho- work out'.' Since this ing of cream, as it is now practiced in Nebraska, has beer put operation, every creamery company ot those who have adopted this system of grading, have cut down their re&lt; 2nd grade cream from forty per cent to eighteen per cent. The difference in price for creamery butter varies from two to eight cents a i&gt;ound, showing clearly that they are getting more for their butter on the market. The difference of two cents a pound between the first quality and BteoM quality of cream has stimulated producers to produce enough more first class quality so as to cut down second grade butter from forty to eighteen per cent. I was told that the grading of cream was not fair at all. Then I have been told there would not be any objection to grading cream were it not that they do not pay more for first class cream. They simply cut down the price for a low quality of cream and pay two cents a pound less for second grade. The creamery companies who do not care are still paying the first grade price for all sorts and conditions of cream. Still these companies that grade, admit that they hii ( mam id the quality and therefore the selling prices of their product. Eve nothing to say in reply to this argument. As I said I am not apologize for any i puy If tne system of grading , as these men make this argun to take still larger profit out of the man who furnishes first grade cream, then it is an abuse of the system and not a critiscism upon the justice or expediency of that system. By the statement of the creamery representative if the quality of the cream in the state has been rai- grading, then the com - pany can afford to pay more for it. It is being raised on the same authority. It has been raised enough to cut down the production of second grade cream from forty to eighteen per cent. That being true. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">40 it must be true that the creamery company can afford to pay more for it than they did. Whether they are doing this or not I do not know. It is not a part of my topic here today. I am simply speaking about the necessity of grading. The necessity of grading cream can be summed up in three or four points as it is necessary to produce a high quality of butter in order to command the price for it. You cannot get a good price for butter fat unless the butter made from the cream is of good quality. The quality is increased by the system of grading cream. This is a matter of experience. What are the grades of cream? What constitute** first grade cream and second grade cream? The system now in use of using cream which tests thirty or more per cent of butter fat, and which shows less than eighteen cubic centimeters of alkali, by Mann's acid test, or less per cent than thirty-two one- hundredth^ of 1 per cent of lactic acid, which is about the same thing, and which con - tains no bad flavor, they call first grade cream, and they call second grade cream that which tents leas than thirty per cent of butter fat and more than thirty-two one-hundredths per cent of lactic acid and which has no bad flavor which would render it useless for making a good quality butter. One reason for requiring thirty per cent butter fat is that there is no necessity for transporting to the creamery an unnecessary quantity of milk and there is, therefore, no use of taking cream that will not test thirty per cent of butter fat. In the second place butter fat does not sour. Therefore the more skim-milk you get, the less per cent of butter fat in the cream and the quicker that cream will sour and the more susceptible it will be to bad flavor and odor. \cid in cream is deter - mined by the alkaline tablet. This has been tested in our station, and other stations have tested it. I can say that those tablets are all right. They do just what they say they do. They show, perhaps, not in every case to an absolute mathematical certainty, but they show approxi - mately in every case a test of 1 &lt;•. c. or 32-100 of one per cent of lactic acid. That is a are intended to show. I think they are right in saying that. ing all the circumstances that it is not too much to aks that the cream shall not contain more than 32 100 of one per cent of lactic acid in order to make it first grade cream. In support of this I can say that from Purduni. a station about 300 miles distant from Lincoln, during the months of July and August of last year the busi - ness of receiving cream only showed 1 per cent of second grade cream. Some of this cream was hauled eight or nine miles to the receiving station and then hauled 300 miles by rail to Lincoln where it tested only 1 per cent of second grade cream. If this is true, then there is no real reason why the farmers of Nebraska, wherever located, cannot produce first grade cream when they have sufficeient instruction on this point, with th is system of grading. There are people, one man I know who lives less than five miles distant from this city and keeps a herd of cows, sixty I think, who has produced No. 2 cream right straight along, yet No. 1 cream is shipped from way out in the western part of the </seg>
            <seg id="p045">MR. C. H. HIN M AN Instructor in Dairying at Nebr»sk« Experiment Station; Winner of Highest Score in Butter Scoring Contest </seg>
            
            <seg id="p046">TWENTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 41 rk, and it comes over that branch of railroad upon which the train ice is very unsatisfactory. If you have ever ridden over that railroad branch you would wonder that any cream could reach the central station and be sweet. So far aa I am able to state, after an impartial investigation of the butter teat at the cream receiving stations I think they are a.s jnst as the present method of tenting will admit. I do bOt think the method is right. The grading of cream is a necessity in order that hand separated cream of Nebraska shall be a reasonably Rood standard article in the market; and in order tnat this butter made from this cream shall sell in the open market a fair and living price for the butter fat. The present - Eig cream for first and second quality seems to me to be just, so I, and I do not think they are asking a bit too much, except change the method of testing for butter I If there is any question that anyone would like to ask I would lie pleased to answer. Q. — Can you take thick cream running higher than 30 per cent, which you claim is necessary for first grade cream, and t«- irately by the pipette t A. — N E. — Then, it seems to me. until they are willing to change the sys - ing. not only from the stand-point of the fanner, but from who has done tasting. I think it is entirely unfair to demand above ST cent test. I think the thicker you get it, the harder it is to test ith the pi|i&gt; BHinman : Yes, I think I would advocate a change in method, it is necessary to take 30 per cent cream. I would not advocate higher than 40 ]&lt;er cent, as you cannot get a good sample. If you run the separator at over 40 per cent, the separator is less likely to skim clean. I think the creamery company would be justified in demand - ing a heavy cream if they would be willing to test it different. I also think that the present method works just as much of an injustice to the creamery company as it does to the patron. Mr. Hinman : It is to the advantage of the local operators to give just as satisfactory a test to the farmer as he can. He is paid for the butter fat he receives and it is to his interest to keep his patrons satis - fled. I am aware that creamery companies frequently pay for butter fat they never get, just the same as they do not pay for the butter fat they do get. They claim that they pay for so much more butter fat then they get that they frequently do not get over an eighth or a terth of over run. In son I have been told that from some stations they have not made any more butter than they have paid for butter fat. It is certainly to the advantage of the operator to get as satisfactory a teat for his patrons as possible. Q. — Why do they object to the weighing? EL — The only objection I have heard to it was that it was too much k. That the operators in many cases are receiving small amounts ream and do not wish to go to the trouble of weighing the teat </seg>
            <seg id="p047">42 tiplea. Eighteen drama of cream requires quite a little bother and ■y say that is the reason that they object, because it is so expensive time. I Mr. Bassett : Is it not a more delicate matter to use scales and igh a small amount of butter fat? D.n-s it not require more skill to : by weight that it does by the pipette V Mr. Hinman: I do not think it does for the same degree of accu racy providing he had a perfect scale fixed for that pu/pose. If hi ordinary scales, I admit that it would be. There are scales ma* this particular purpose and I think that if he use these that the ordinary operator— they will have had more or less training— but the ordinary operator would be able to get an accurate a t&gt; - t(A Voice) : I would like to have you go out into the country and ■k a week or two on your theory, and see if the results are not much erent. Mr. Hinman : — I cannot go today. 1Q. — What is the difference between 1H c.c. pipette and 18 grams on a per cent cream test? Mr. Hinman: I uon't think there would be very much difference, bat I can tell you this that the 17.6 pipette, which is used by many creamery companies, does not give you 18 grains cream. I know it is used by one of our companies, and it does nut test IN grams of cream when weighed. Therefore, the more butter fat you get in the cream, the less you get in the pipette. I have forgotten now, but if I am wrong Professor Haecker can set me right, that is, that 18c. c. , of 80 per cent cream would weigh about 18 grams. i Professor Haecker : Cream testing 28 per cent butter fat will come le to 18 grams by weight. I Mr. Hinman: Then you would have to have a trifle over 18 per ette. Of course, this is all worked out — the richer the cream, the re bulky it is. the lighter it | If an operator who is receiving cream at the station and is testing right along says that he can test that cream with the pipette and get as fair and as accurate results in every case, as fair ana accurate as can be done by weight or by the weighing system— if he says he can do that, I reply that he is a good deal better gr.ess»-r than I am. Ly. —Is it fair in the grading of cream to take first class and second k cream and mix them in the sains can? Mr. Hinman : No, sir; if you do that you are likely to injure it f &lt;r first grade cream. EMr. Bassett : Let me say a word in regard to the grading of cream, not let us have any heat in the discussion of it. What we want is discuss these matters in such a way that we will get the most benefit t of it. It is only a few years ago that we started into the system of iking commercial butter, that is by the use of the hand separator and 1 centralized creamery. In the introduction of the hand separator and &gt; shipping of cream, the policy to begin with was to pay one price for cream. I do not know, but I presume that if the people who are </seg>
            <seg id="p048">43 now engaged in the creamery business who began in that uld not begin that way now. At that time the hand separator furnished only a small proportion of the cream which was used in the manu - facturer of butter. Today 15-16 of the creamery butter made in state is made out of hand separator cream. It is another i entirely. They soon began to receive large quantities of band separ. cream of not the best quality, the result was that there wa.s pnt onto market a great deal of low grade butter. The fact that one price was paid for cream regardless of quality did not encourage any dairyman to take any particular pains with the cream that he furnished, li paid fo' at one price. Why should any farmer take his cream to the central stations six days in the week when he cor Id take it one day in the week just as well and get the same price for it? All dairyman did not live within a mile or two of the cream receiving station. B the cream was carted in wagons eighteen to twenty miles The result was that a great deal of the cream that was brought to the station was a week old and was of inferior quality. In time the amount of this inferior quality of cream, second grade cream, became the major portion of the cream that the creamery men bought. So as when as in the be - ginning, they started out with the proposition that they would dairymen, or farmer, within four cents of the highest tions of creamery butter, they found that it was an impossible t: to do and live at the business for the major portion of the cream I received would not make first grade butter. These are the facts and there is no use beating about the bush in regard to it. Then came question: "'What can we do in the matter'" Shall we buy cream at one price or not? Any man who will sit down and give five mir honest thought to the question will say that it can not be d rather ought not to be done. No man expect* to sell wheat weighing fifty-six pounds to the bushel at the same price that he would re&lt; • for sixty pound wheat. We have been so educated along I s as regards selling grain and stock, and why should there Ik- any que- - in regard to the justice or right of selling cream according to qnal The first attempts to grade cream created a great deal of opposition and it seemed some times as if a considerable per cent of the men engaged in cream selling would go out of the business. The creamery man wants your cream. He is anxious tor it and he is not going to do any thing, if he can avoid it, that will tend to decrease the quantiu cream that you will bring. He could not do business without the cream. When you talk about this question of grading cream to men, in a reasonable manner, they concede it is the proper thing to do. I want to mention one or two things in this connection, that the dairymen have some reasons for criticism in this matter of grading. It relates to matters connected with the industry in the state which we as a body ought to endeavor to correct, not as individual dairymen, not as in - dividual creamery men. but altogether. I said at home when the ques - tion of grading cream came up, that \\P*will deliver cream at the station every day and there will not be any question about it being first grade </seg>
            <seg id="p049">44 twin. 1 said I would rather throw the cream out doors than to have the operator teil me that the cream brought was second grade cream. Suppose I take my cream each day to the cream receiving station ; suppose the operator is an honest and efficient man and takes pride in hia work and tests my cream as it should lie tested, and puts my cream into a can of first grade cream and ships it to the creamery at Lincoln. Suppose along about three o'clock in the iifternoon of July or August when the sun is hot and shining, the drayman takes it to the station and places it upon the platform to wait for the way freight to start it for Lincoln or Omaha and it stands there hour after hour in the hot sun and the train does not get there until six o'clock or even later; under such conditions strictly first grade cream delivered at the cream receiving station becomes ■ second grade cream long before it reaches the central creamery. If in order to manufacture a first class article of butter the dairyman must deliver first grade cream at the cream receiving station, then it is just as necessary that the transportation company should handle the cream in such manner that the cream does not change from first grade to second grade between the cream receiving stations and the central I urged that Mr. Hinman should discuss this question here today and insist upon the grading of cream because it is just and right. I do not do it for the purpose of developing any heat Ix'tween the creamerymen and the dairymen, but beCMM it is a great big question in this state today, the question of buying cream according to its quality and paying for it accordingly. While as dairymen we should use every effort to deliver first quality of cream we should insist that the facilities of getting it to the creamery are such that it will continue to be sweet cream when it gets there. We can do this by publishing the facts and demanding that the railroads furnish better facilities for the transporta - tion of cream. » The president announced the following committees; Nomination officers: B. R. Stouffer, J. C. Merrill, A. L. Haecker. Resolutions: C. H. Hinman, F. W. Edmunds, H. C. Young. I The president : The hour has arrived for our Cow Judging contest : ill request Prof. Haecker to make the necessary announcement in ard to the same tPro'. Haecker : We are now going to conduct some proceedings e that will be very interesting to you, I trust. We have had some y entertaining remarks on the grading of cream, but you can not ome successful in your business of dairying unless you are using re that will pay for their feed. We have in our state some twenty or rty thousand dairymen. Of course there are a good many of them o ought either to quit the business or improve in their method, are are too many of them not that are not making profit out of their liness. We are going, this afternoon, to place ten cows right along here </seg>
            <seg id="p050">45 I lore yon. Each of these cows has a record. They have been here the station for a number of years and we are going to ask yon to Ige them on the basis of their value as producers of butter fat, aa *r as you can judge by looking at them. We have their records for I past two years and from such records we determine their actual lue. We have some cards here, printed and arranged for your use 18 afternoon, in the grading of th&gt; COW JUDGING CONTEST This contest is proving one of the most interesting and instructive features of the annual meeting. Prof. T. L. Haecker of Minnesota agricultural college, who was present, spoke most highly of its impor - tance as an educator. Jat it creates much intt '1 by the attendance, ich so crowded the pavilion, that the ;int room for the cows for the contestants to study them and record their judgement. In the contest ten cows. l*»lonj;ing to the state experiment station and whose butter production for t wo years was a matter of record, were used. These OOWI were brought into the stock-judging pavilion where the judging was done, and over each cow was placed a placard giving breeding, age. period of lactation also a fictitios number. To each contestant was given a ruled card and the ci&gt;nte&gt;' in placing the cows in numerical order according to their estimated value as producers of butter fat. In the program of the meeting, which may be found in the first pages of tins report, i n full the Miles and regulations governing th- Herewith is given one of the cards used by contestants in placing ivs; under the heading " "Official ' is the order in which the should have been placed in order to make the higl 100; under the heading "'Score" is given li tants credit, in this case 80 points. NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN Twentieth Annual Meeting. • Card for placing Dairy I -t»nt. Official First place 10 •&gt; Second place 7 9 Third 4 ■ i Fourth place !• ti Fifth plac. 1 Sixth plac- 10 Seventh place 1 Eighth place ■"&gt; 4 5 Ninth place 10 Tenth place 3 lo Total Name Add it </seg>
            <seg id="p051">46 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION In the contest 98 persons took part : of this number 38 made a score ■r more points and were therefore entitled to a share of the pro - rata fund ; of the 93 contestants, 33 correctly placed cow No. 1 ; 5 cow No. I ; 7 No. 3. ; 8 No. 4 ; 10 No. 8 ; fi No. 6 ; 5 No. 7 ; 7 No. B; U No. 9; and 83. the poorest cow. No. 10;. A. L. Coad, Omaha, made the hitfhe- 1 ]» lints, and was awarded a gold watch on which was engraved "Presented to A. L. Coad by the Nebraska Dairymen's Association : 1MB. F. Chase . Pawn. ■ lohnson Hastings amett A. Reid, Lincoln E. Reed, Havelock . J. Nelson, Lincoln Sdwin Hopt, Can-fridge . F. Mclntosh. Alda Z. Parmeter, Lincoln M. Doubt. Ha\ flock jee A. Young, Lincoln L. Jones, Lincoln [E. Nash, Benson fold, Lincoln talk, Grand Island A. DuBois, Lincoln H. Bristol, Lincoln C Gkiffla, Lincoln mdell P. Brinton. Lincoln D. Calkins, Lincoln B. R. Stouffer. South Omaha Peter Kasak, Milligan F. \V. Graham. Omaha t.vell. Columbus Junction nrv Luderman, Bee Hal. V. Young. Lincoln J. B. Varney. Bennet C. Laverick. Beaver Cit (ieorge Tilden, Benedict Ernest tiuff, Lincoln Orval D. Jordan, Scotts Bluff Win. Waif, Ofaiowa C. E. (ial)bv. Pawnee City Payne. North Platte Bernhard Witt Scribner O. P. Henderehot, Hebron R. W. Boon, Riverton </seg>
            <seg id="p052">47 FRIDAY MORNING It was a great disappointment to all, that president Clark's health would not permit of his being in attendance at the closing sessions of the annual meeting: in the absence of the vice-president, Mr. J. A. Harris. Mr. J. K. Honeywell, ex-president of the association was re - quested to preside. I Mr. Honeywell: First in order is the report of the committee on nination of officers Report of the committee : Mr. President: Your committee on nom - tion of officers beg to submit the following report : President, L. D. Stillson Vice- President, Henry C. Glissman. Secretary &amp; Treasurer, S. C. Bassett. I Directors: C. A. Clark, J. C. Merrill, H. (.'. Young. J. K. Honey- II. A. L. Haecker; (Signed) B. R. Stouffer. Chairman. tOn motion the report of the coinmitr ioplad and the persons ied in said reix&gt;rt declared duly elected to the office* named, for the jing year. REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON KESOLl'Tl' Report of the committee on resolutions: Mr. President: Your com - mittee on resolution resi ectfully submit the following : I Whereas, An effort is being made to secure a considerable reduction the tax on imitation butter colored yellow : and Whereas, It has been conclusively demonstrated by the operation of the present law, that it was by means of the yellow color that the great fraud was perpetrated on consumers in the sale of such colored imita - tion butter, as genuine butter, therefore be it Resolved, That we most earnestly protest against the repeal or amendment of the present law. relating to the manufacture and sale of imitation butter, and request that our representatives in congress oppose any legislation looking to the repeal or amendment of said law. I Be it Resolved. That we endorse the hill now before the legislature, ividing for an appropriation of 00 for the erection of a ;k judging pavilion and fish building on the State Fair Grounds. Recognizing the valuable work done for the dairy industry by the officers of the National Dairy CJnion, and deeming it of the utmost im - portance that such organization should continue to receive the cordial atfd loyal support ot the dairy industry of the country. Resolved, That the sum of $25.00 of the funds of this association be ■iropriated for the support of said National Dairy Union ; the same lie paid out of the membership fees of this association. Whereas, It is the opinion of the Nebraska State Dairyman's Associa- </seg>
            <seg id="p053">48 tion that the best interests of all connected with the dairy industry of onr state, demand a better quality of product ; and 1 Whereas, It is certain that mutual care on the part of buyer and er can do much to improve this quality, Be it Resolved. That this association earnestly recommends the buy - ing and selling of cream, according to its quality, and such subsequent care as shall be necessary to deliver the cream to the creamery in the best possible condition. § Whereas, The inadequate transportation facilities afforded cream in braska, is a bar to the progress of the movement for a better quality product, and also to an increase in cream production. I Be it Resolved, That we request such action un the part of the rail - ds as shall be necessary to deliver this cream in good condition. Resolved, That we favor the making of actual tests of herds of dairy cowe, and in case any funds of the association are available for the purpose, we recommend the same be used to assist the state experiment station in making co-operative tests of dairy herds. - »" Since it is important to have, and the statutes require, the subject agriculture taugnt in the graded and rural schools of the state, and ce this can only be accomplished by teachers who have had training elementary agriculture and who are interested in the subject "Kesolved, That we earnestly recommend that the board of educa - tion (.f the state normal schools establish a department of elementary agriculture such as will prepare their graduates for the most efficient teaching of this subject in the public schools; that the department of agriculture be placed in the hands of a man in eai-h school thoroughly trained in this subject and a man capable of adapting the work to the needs of teachers of the rural and graded schools ; recommend further that the board increase the amount in their mate for equipment in agriculture for each school to at least $2,500. " Iir. Bassett ; Mr. President; Please allow me to discuss, briefly, the lution which relates to the teaching of agriculture in the rural and led schools. For nearly thirty years many farmers in this - I prayed that there might be a reasonable number of students in ndance at the agriculture college of the university, and for long ■s their prayers remained unanswered and in fact there never was a ectable attendance of such students until there was established, in college, a high school course in argiculture, so arranged that a child l the eighth grade in our rural schools could enter such agricultural i-Bchool course ; it might be mentioned, incidentally, that the great !e*s of the Iowa agricultuial college, is due to the fact that early in history of that college thev established such a high-school course. The true reason why there were so few students in our agricultural college was. that neither in our rural or high schools did we have taught anything relating to agriculture, and it was the most reasonable thing in ihe world that children graduating from our high schools, and enter - ing the state university, should continue their studies along the lines already pursued. In the year 1901, at the request of the members of the state board of </seg>
            <seg id="p054">49 agriculture r state amended the law relating to qualifications of t« - p— in addition to other ■tadiea. "A satisfactory examination in the itary principles of agriculture, including a fair knowledge of the structure and habits of common plants, insects, bird provided that the law should not take effect until At July; this, in order to give teachers an opportunity I themselves in this respect. »Thi&gt; already engaged in teaching, did by reading and I tnres relating to the subject delivered at t. PWhen the amendment quoted, became a law, I .dent public instruction made inquiry I books which could be need ii the elementary principles of agriculture in our rural s. and neither in this state, nor any other, could there l*&gt; found I book which could be need for such purpose. I mention this to show that up to the time tl -ka. that nowhere in any of the states had there 1 ■ effort to tearh the elementary principles of agriculture in the rural schools. At the request of Superintendent Fowler. Professors Beaaej, Brnner and Sweezy. of our state university, prepared an elem&lt; text book, of the class I have mentioned, for DM in our rural 9C and incidentally it might be mentioned, that the book has met with a steadily increasing demand; not long since the publishers wr&lt; • that they had already received orders from more than one tb school districts hi this state, for copies of the book to be used in their schools; in addition to this a large number of order* ha\ from other states: while four years ago there was no such text book published, at this time there are numerous publications, by different authors, on the market At this time the most important teaching of this subject in our school themselves; when this law, to which effect, our state normal school placed matter in connection with the . is the education of the tea I have referred, first u "agriculture" in its course of studies, but no provision had lieen made for the employment of teachers illy prepared to teach this subject and so the ; ployed at the state normal school to each other branches, tanght this new subject, as best they could. t Believing that the teaching of this subject in our i portance.it is desire, 1 that the board of education of our normal &gt;&lt; shall make the teaching of agriculture in such school, a department, thereby showing its importance and giving it the same now given other subjects in the course of stadia a thoroughly competent person be placed in charge of such department, one who lias been especially fitted and trained to teach the subj. tit is further desired that a sufficient sum be appropriated • i a suitable laboratory for the use of the departu It was my good fortune, while in attendance at the St. Louis expoei- </seg>
            <seg id="p055">■ XEBK VIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION stitutf ere delegates in attendance from most of the states and from the pro\ anada as well. On the mil call of states each dele, sted to give a brief statement of the in - work in his state, the number of institutes held, amount of expended, workers employed, etc. and lastly any new f&lt; bearing upon improvement in agriculture, and almost without i ke-r mentioned that in his state or province, an was being made to teach the elementary principles of agriculti the rural schools and that it was bound to lie of great V&gt;enetit to the cause of agriculture iry of Agriculture. Hon. James Wilson, in his last annual report, speaks at length of the subject ; in fact li&lt; and has organized a department. de\ farmers institutes and the teaching of agriculture in the rut and has placed in charge nie Professor Hamilton, who &lt; ration with people in the various - gaged in work of this nature; also President Roosevelt, in h message calls attention to the importance of the work. I m these things to show how wide spread is this new feature in edi. and the hearty endorsement which it is receiving at the hands of those fully qualified t importance and useful: Pthis connection permit me to say. that our own Dr. Be- - happy inspiration than when he worded the amendm&lt; h I have referred, and which is now a part of our laws relat: &gt;ls ; Let me re]&gt;eat it; "A satisfactory examination in the ei - principles of agriculture, including a fair knowledge of tl ture and habits of the common pli birds and quadra] Is there any thing covered by these words, that every teacher ought not to know something alxiut and be able to teach? Is it not important and necessary that onr children l)e taught something about the common plants corn, wheat, grains, . hies, uj&gt;on which they must all their 1 &gt;d and rapport 1 Should they not lie taught the haln &gt;me of which are useful and many of which are annoying and destructive- Can they be taught too much about the common birds, including the "helpful hen" common &lt;iuadruj&gt;eds. including the motherly cow who has been a "wet nurse' to untold millions of the human race? It was I rej&gt;eat a happy inspiration for it is always necessary. ah\ I, always important to know as much as possible about the common every day things, plants and animals, with which we have constantly to do. On motion the resolutio) iopted. E;r. Mclntosh ; Last night the announcement was made that the re of the i _'iven this morning. I know there are many here who would like to hear the repoit if the sec - ■y will announce the san On motion it was decided that only the successful scores be read P'he secretary then announced the successful scorers. (These appear be account of the cow judging contest). Mr. Coad having r&gt; hrst. prize, there were loud calls for him. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">51 Coad said : This seems a great work. It hascertainl a great ( ] ea i o f interest. It is of great value to every man and eapec iallv to every farmer to know how to judge the points of the cow. I think that is all that I have to say (applause). M Chairman : Mr. Coad. would you he kind enough to explar iefly hat you know about judging the cow and 1 gained your knowledn Mr my knowledge in this matter is concerned I gained it under the instruction of Professor Haecker. I am from the city. My training was not of the kind that comes from the farm. All I know about this matter can be attributed to Professor Haecker. I would say to those farmers who h that it will be for their benefit and the benefit of their sons to have them come here and have them attend this school. (Ap) Loud • "What's the matter with Professor Ha&gt; Loud cries of: •'He's all right Professor Haecker, being calleu com - pliment. I think tl ne flattery about it. 1 don't say it is mil, but more or 'ess. In the COW judging contest I shall offer to the Associa - tion a very much better plan next year, provided the Association wants »I shall give two The plan this year has made very hard. I do not think any one can do justice by mixitu classes. Next year I will offer a class of Holstein.s and a class of Jerseys and I think that will make it very much better. The great difh in the type of the Holstein and Jersey makes it dicftiult to place both in one class and to size them up. i . Applau- THE IMPORTANCE OF ALFALFA TO THE DAIRY INDUSTRY OF THE STATE P order to make plain the great imi&gt;ortance of alfalfa to the try of the state I l&gt;est that I compare earlier coin; those of the present tin In the year 1871. I took a homestead in tne central part of thi - and upon which I have continuously resided. We raised in the early days ho little hay upon the ll&gt;0 acres of land, that we ha ■ dis - tance of several miles to the Platte river bottoms, to cat hav and haul it home. We would go down there in the summer and cut the h&gt; then during the winter haul it home, We did not know at that time that there was any plant that we could i Itably as plant. We had not come to understand the imi n plant or that we could cut the corn up and use it. T. in the central and western part of the state are under entirely different conditions from the people who live in the eastern part of tl in Iowa, Wisconsin or farther east. As you go east if they cut up their corn, they must make small shocks of it in order that it may dry oat. &lt; ■ itilu in. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">■ and ii. 1 to spread the husked I or on the scaffold sometimes, to dry it out. We do not have an;. conditions here. Our corn fodder drys out no matter bow large you make and the leaves are all gone by the time you can get th&lt; to where you can feed them. We never have made very much corn fodder localise of the usual dry conditions of the atmospl;. the fall of the year A large portion of shocked corn is wasted n of every effort. For years we were hoping and praying for a plant tli.it ild raise that would produce the necessary and desirable kind of food for the dairy cow. There are do more nutritious grasses th;r than our native grasses, but they are not grasses that produce a larg of milk or a great quantity of butter. From them can be mack firm butter, butter that will stand shipping long distances and favorable conditioi While our native _ rv nutritious and make tin- h. tare in tin in a pasture of native grasses, then sufti : for a dairy cow until al&gt;out the first of June, and su&lt;l&gt; tures begin to fail early in Septemlier • In this paper let it be m that I sjH'ak largely of conditions which prevail in central Nebr;i - more especially in Buffalo county. None of our nati\t are what are termed succulent and therefore, neither as pasture or fbdd&lt; are they so desirable or profitable a food for milk and butter produ. icculent. cultivated grasses and clovers; during all tl years we hav&gt; \ more or less with tame grasses and ck as pasture tot ;it the present time our Ix-st pasture for - purpose is (Hie of natural prairie in which is a considerable ■ o4 blue grass, but during the entire pasture season our milch oowi ning and night, all the alfalfa hay they will eat; alfalfa : - pasture plant, it . ife during the growing season, to attorn] pasture it with either catti p. but there is nothing better than good alfalfa hay to supplement a pasture sivh as I have menti in fact any kind of a pasture found in the state. ppleinented our pasture with sowed coir raised millet and hunargian grass as fodder or hay ; but these pit all annuals, and there w'l the expense of plowing and ritt i ntj year and also the item of seed; they each and all make i for dair&gt; cov P^an raising alfalfa; possilby it might t» or profit to relate some of my experience in this direcion ; 1 &gt;d to raise alfalfa during some very dry seasons and also en ( Mderuble discussion in regard to the great l&gt;e derived from subsoiling; so. in order to do my aa I thought led, in the spring of the year, some ten M harrowed it down BiM and sowed to alfalfa; the season was rather dry and while the alfalfa came up and made a fine stand, it gradually di - appeared, and with good reason, and as I now understand, I don't H it ; the ground l&gt;eing subsoiled was open and porous, the moisture soon evaporated and of course the young plants soon perished ; some of the </seg>
            <seg id="p058">53 ■ I and thrived and that . grow if given a fair chai: The next attempt was on a field that had been in corn the we broke op the stalks, disced the ground ns , both ways, then harrowed thoroughly and sowed vi« &gt; potmda of seed per acre; we mowed it twice daring I to keep down the weeds and secured a most excellent stand; t! ,ir we seeded a field t) been in corn the previous year and secured a good .stand, but on an ad - joining field, which was plowed in the spring alnmt four inches deep and thoroughly harrowed and fitted, the crop w;is a failure; since then we have seeded to alfalfa in the fall of the year and consider that time • by far the Vtest ; when alfalfa is sown in the spring then coiitiuual fight the first season with weeds; it 18 necessary to mow them and mowing Um uts off the alfalfa at the same time, and that weakens the plant so that it makes but little growth the first year; if sown in August or early September on ground thoroughly fitt. up quickly and there l»ing no interfere it grows rap - idly, baeOBM thoroughly established so a,s to live through the and will cut a full crop of hay the ne r winter wheat can be grown I think there will be no difficulty in - nil of alfalfa sown in the earlv fall. If you wish to raise a crop during the summer it i- uable. You might raise a crop of oats or a crop of wheat tad when ripe take off the crop and as soon . e prepare the ground just M I you were going to sow winter wheat. Plow earlv and then d down I like to disc with the disc set straight because it teii' the ground and break up the air chabmers. I disc it three or fou the disc set straight and then harrow so as to retain all the in Then in August or early September I sow the alfalfa seed and rigs right up. There are no weeds, t ; moisture and it will come right up and get to be good height before mies. and the ne.v m will have a crop of hay without any difficulty, and really have lost nothing in the way of receiving returns Ethe field. Or. if you want to do better than that yon might sum - fallow the field and see that no moisture e&gt; "I&gt;ing down the s, that would l&gt;e an excellent way. and then sow in Aug You will doubltess recall that year 1!H)1 was dry and that for nearly a month during the summer season the thermometer ranged daih KM) degrees Fah. ; pastur. try and brown and all vegetation &lt;1 frjm the effects of the extreme heat and drouth, yet alfai: 1 green and fresh, a most enjoyable and i •■ har - vested from the field a b MOoad growth for seed which yielded six bushels of seed per neve; in I lelded a heavy tonage of hay ; on Jnne 5th the first cutting was alfalfa averaging stti inches in heighth ; on July "&gt;th the second hay nt, the average heighth being tl first Hi - a third cutting about 20 inches in heighth. was cut in Septem - ber. The year If a If a being too wet; </seg>
            <seg id="p059">54 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION we made three cuttings from this field, the first and second contained quite a large per cent of water grass, making an inferior quality of hay, the third cutting, while light, was of fine quality; in 1904 this field yielded four cuttings of hay, the laat being cut late in her; when you consider the rapid growth which this plant makes in the months of May. June and July, it can readily be seen that there must not be any delay in cutting when the proper time comes, and that, for hay. is when the first blossoms begin to show ; as soon as the plant is in full bloom the lower leaves begin to drop off, the stem becomes woody, and a second growth starts from the roots, this second growth, grows at the rate of an inch or more each day so it will be seen that the sooner the preceding crop is removed from the field the better. The most valuable part of alfalfa is the leaves, and therefore it should he put in the barn or stack as quickly as possible ana with as little hand - ling as iMJssihle; of course the liest plan is store in a barn, but if there is not barn room, then the stack ; it will not do to stack when w. rain or dew, but if not thus wet. it can be stacked when quit. fact as soon as it can be satisfactorily handled with rakes and stackers . the fact that it turns brown in the stack, when stacked quite gm notjobjectionable as it* feeding value is not thereby necessarily injured; in fact one of our largest and most experienced sheep feeder - more, per ton. for alfalfa hay of a dark brown or quite black than for that which comes out of the stack green and fresh looking. claiming that the dark colored has a higher feeding value and that sheep are much more fond of it; with us, if the stacks are well put up and topped out with quite green hay, the greener the letter, and then Ed for a day or so with a tarpaulin, or stack cover, until the stack es thoroughly settled, there is very little loss from stacks wetting Aa I before stated, the leaves are the most valuable portion of the plant and as, even in stacks or the barn, the hay becomes dry enough for the leaves to crumble to some extent in handling: it follows that alfalfa hay should be fed in tight mangers or feed racks so that the leaves may not be wasted; the most wasteful manner to feed this^hay is to throw it on the ground, for the stock running over it knock off the leaves and they are thus wasted. Aa a fodder for dairy cows there is nothing superior to a good qual - ity of alfalfa hay ; it has a high feeding value, is succulent, therefore produces a large How of milk of good quality, and is most palatable, not only to the dairy cow but to all our domestic animals ; l&gt;eing a perennial plant, when established it becomes a permanent ni&gt; The raising of seed seems most uncertain, as far as my ex|&gt;erience goes, aa we have been able to raise only one profitable seed crop ; the plant fy bloom profusely, but not a seed pod form, and if left to bloom and seed pods to form, it is then worthless for hay. Alfalfa is a plant ich adapts itself to the locality in which grown therefore, it is beet in buying seed to sow. to procure that grown in the immediate locality if possible. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">■ Let me compare briefly the change* ,ave come abont (in my own farm in the keeping ot dui 1 and. if these changed conditions ure for the letter, in that milk and butter can be produced much easier and cheaper than before, the him change can be made on practically any dairy farm in the state, for I see no good nmm why alfalfa can not be successfully and profitably grown on all of our tillable lands. First, in our own case, the making of hay from native grasses many miles distant and .spending much of the winter months in hauling hay home; next the plowing and tilling of the land and raising n hungarian, sowed corn and such annual plants; now the alfalfa | a perennial, which when e*t means a permanent meadow at ura long term of cutting!* of hay of the hnest quality, succulent, palatable and wli. with corn making n perfect or balanced lation. Is it any wonder that those who grow this wonderful plant enthusia ■ dis - cussing its mei The question is sometimes asked whether a plant, which pp annually so large a tonage of hay of high feeding value, will not q impoverish the soil? In reply, it might be said, that alfalfa a leguminous plant, which draws much of its support from the md increases rather than (!■ the fertility of the on thousands of farms in thi&gt; n almost inexhau soil for the support of plants of the nature and habits of growth, of Bi my own farm it is her, and every foot of this en feet is fertile soil, which if brought to -.posed e elements for a few months, will support th ; alfalfa is a plant wl down into the earth, how deep I can not definit 'his I know that in the ai fields we have dug down six and eight feet and found t) appar - ently of as large size as at the surface and there is no doubt, in my mind, that on the farm, plants of full growth extend their r the full si\ teet to water, this hai tiding its roots so deeply in to the earth, not only • nt to wit: rremes of heat and drouth, but on our deep fertil produce annually, and for a long term of \ &gt; of forage for the dairy cow ; Alfalfa, corn and well bred dairy I yon think of. do you desire, any letter combination for i general cultivation of alfalfa on the fai millions of dollars annually to the pnxluetive wealth from the farms and also to tbi Discrssio.s i^. How much curing does it require? It depends largely upon the weather. If the weather is 1 and the sun shines, and it cures n The thing that usually dam- </seg>
            <seg id="p061">56 ■gas alfalfa is the moisture that falls upon it ; I could not say how much curing it would require, but you will 1*&gt; surprised how green you can put it in the stack. It may turn a dark brown but if there is no moisture other than which as in the plant itself, it will be all right, and that which is dark and brown, even black, the c to like best. y. - Did you ever use a tedder 1 ! IN'o : that would be shaking it up too much and there, would be :iger of losing a gcxxl many leaves which are the most valuable part the plant. y. -Would not there be h little waste land where you built so many ■tacks? A. — It dies out where the stack stands bat that is a very small space y. — Would the alfalfa come up the next year where the stack - A.— No. I might add we have a canvass cover we put over the stacks especially when we have not finished one, of a night. Q. — Where do you get them? A. — The first one I bought was made of the heaviest ducking. I think 18 ounce. I do not think I would buy that kind again. It cracks in - stead of wearing out. The first I bought was MxM feet and en You can buy them of any tent and awning company and they will make them of any size you wish and any weight cloth. C^. By building so many stacks on 4&lt;» acres of alfalfa you would ight or ten of than • if I built one or two stacks today I would cover them tonight and when settled take the covers off It is a good plan t out the stack with quite green alfalfa. Let an alfalfa stack thu - ped out stand about 24 hours with cover on and the rain will not penetrate down into the stack. I had a stack that stood about three years l&gt;efore I ted it out, and there was hardly any waste hay in it. I do not a think there was more than four or five inches of the top of the stack that was worthless ; the rest was just as good as the day it was put up. y. — Which kind of a stack do you prefer.a round or a long one? A. —We build ours about 16 feet long and aixjut 12 feet wide. We prefer that shape to a round stack. Q.— Did you evor try' salting it I A. — No. but a neighbor of mine has and tin- --alts all of when he puts it up. Q. — Can you put it up any greener by usii. A. — That I do not know. tA Meml)er: Last season with us was wet. I was anxious to save my r and told the boys I would take my chaii' ilting it, and did The cattle seemed to eat it cleaner than ever before. Mr. Stillson : In regard to feeding alfalfa green have yon ever seen any danger by feeding green alfalfa? I Mr. Basset t : I am glad my friend Stillson has mentioned this because is rather a new feature with us. I supposed there was not a particle danger in feeding alfalfa hay. I though if I cut it and fed it there was </seg>
            <seg id="p062">TWENTIETH K )N" 57 no danger whatever from hoven or bloat. .Just as we think if we cut up cornstalks and fed them that we will never have any trouble with cornstalk disease. A neighbor living in town had been feeding alfalfa hay to his two cows all the while. I M hi* ral grain in the feed box ; when tin .p the rule was to let them drink and then go into the stall: but that night they did not drink When the morning came he turned them out and they drank a great quantity of water and then he gave them a feed of very l ilfa hay; hay that had been cut late in the season, and only wilt. cared, aniLin course of an hours time one of his neight*&gt;rs rushed i saying "your cows are all bloated up. " He ran out but • ■■ was dead. The other was saved by using the trocar. T) but what they had bloated from eating t alfalfa ! cut some alfalfa last fall, late in October; it cured very little and we stacked it in this green st. &lt;1 to the bf are ■ fond of alfalfa hay if it is not i calves running out and one of them bloated up and died from eating much of this green, nncured hay. It w 'Id weather and tallowed to run to the stack anc I si; had waited until it was and ate too much. When we went in to supper it was all right, but aftei supper it was dead. Q. — Don t you think the frost had something to do with it A.— No; I think it was became it 1. is danger in overfeeding green all Q. — 1- bloat from alfalfa what is to be done Bhe trocar, or any sharp ii 1 and let the gas out. EJr. Stouffer : I whs very glad to hear If to conditions A neighbor fiiend of mine I |M0 an land and has seeded it to alfalfa him 10 pa investment. How do j nt for tli Mr Mclntosh : If you will permit me, in regard to this matt. combustion. I will state tor the information of the n that in which was a very a, on Wood river where we wer. ing a Mr. Taylor who owned a well known ranch, he had a large stack of hay destroyed by spoilt n. The foreman of th&gt; told me that the heat generated, i not due to the but was due to weeds that was stacked along with the alfalt principal weed being water grass that hat is true it probably is d fa hay in stack or barn. But there is no weli 1 case, a - pure alfalfa has been stacked green enough to •prodn combustion. Mr. Stillson: I would like to supplement what Mr. Basser in regard to alfalfa in the state of of Nebraska; the &gt;raska today do not realize what they have under thei merl had the privilege of looking around the c </seg>
            <seg id="p063">58 today. I would rather have a farm of Nebraska soil where we can raise alfalfa than to have any farm in Missouri where the clay is up I second rail of the fence. We can raise alfalfa, wheat and corn, all on -.line land, and th&gt; of all is alfalfa. Mr. Glissman : I have been raising it for ten or fifteen years, and I lave never seen any indications ot combustion from it. The first cutting very rank, and it might possibly cause combustion, bat I don't think lere is any great danger of it. I have stored it in the barn the next ay after cutting when it was very rank. I loaded it onto my t lauled it and put it in the barn. It ni warm, apparently. I saw any indications of fire or combustion from it. and I don't hesitate o put it in the barn. I wish to say a word in regard to sowing alfalfa : on can overdo it on a farm like anything else. The first cutting comes ust about the time it is necessary to plow corn. The farmer will have o cut his alfalfa, and unless he can get plenty of help it will be in a I trouble. I rind it difficult to get help at such times. You will ant to get your teams in the corn field and to cut your alfalfa at the gaine time. Alfalfa is too good to waste after being grown. If you lave a cow the best feed is alfalfa ami corn meal. Of course, if you can have silage in the winter time, it is letter. Green feed is better or milch cows but witl. il alfalfa and corn meal. I wan' ng else. My Holsteins thrive on it. Mr. Sypher: I have been raising alfalfa for a number of vears. and I do not think there is a bit more danger of bloat from it than there is from red clover. It is the way yon turn your cattle in to it. If you tarn a herd of cattle from a piece of short grass and when they are hungry into alfalfa, it is natural that they will want to fill up on it in a hurry. It would be just the same as though you were very fond of sauerkraut and had not had any for several vears and being hungry and anting some thing to tickle your palate when you ran up against a atter of sauerkraut yon ate a good deal more than you shonld. I do ot think there is any more danger from bloat from alfalfa than from rod clov.r. Why? Because I turn my cattle in to it gradually while thers turn them in when they are hungry and they fill up and die with oat and gas. I claim you can turn them in gradually when the oisture is all off. bnt if you fill them up quickly with all they « on must expect disastrous results Fill them up with something else »efore turning them on to aJfalfa. Mr. Glissman : I want to raise an objection to what previous speaker said about sauerkraut. We had a German who came to us to work. He had not seen sanerkraut for four months. The first time we had it be ate as much as anyone else— he tilled up on it. . I think be hi little but he never died : Laughter. but if our cattle swell up oa alfalfa thev die. Member I bo statement that vou filled him up on son </seg>
            <seg id="p064">59 FRIDAY AFTERNOON Association reconvened kith Mr. J. K. Honeywell in the chair THE COMMON COW • rentlemen of the Nebraska Dairyman's Association : I devote nearly all my time to the c I am so attached to the dair &gt;t when I am at home and in the office I spend a good deal of my time with her. 1 individual ani- mal closely. I try to get intimately acquainted with her I try to have her like to see me around. I believe that everv cow in mv barn E rather see me come in to see hei man who feeds her. I go by her I - und I give her a touch and she like* it. Tlu farmer would avoid that. We are dealing with animals exceedingly sensitive. We are dealing in her product in a commercial way. I rind if I can draw her attention to me that she will do l&gt;etter for me thai --■. I have have given m&gt; . - thorough bred calves, and incidentally, to make some butter ; and during the last fourteen years I have kept an accurate account of each cow and studied hat I shall h;. u at this time ia simply what the cow says in return to me under the conditions that I have given &gt;f butter a vear. Now. tne average educator berates that common co"w and blames her for all her pbort comii n try- ijet the average f;-. tse a kind of cow that is adapted airying. That farm iich that the dairy cow will do her be*- them. During the Iig to persuade the farme: toy this cow that I fii table. After spending that much time in the - Minnesota looking around and talking about what I had a bed I began to become discouraged, and I stopped advising the farmer— the average farmer, to get this • !■ not because she ■ or would not do exactly what we claim if her conditions were right. With me the conditions are r the dairy cow returns to me 450 pounds of butter per year. Her feed does not cost but very little Prof. T.'L Haeker. of Min: Birs. I been in close t&gt; r of a century . I i froii - that the average - Jiarely 1-M&gt; pounds years of my work in da nuch time in </seg>
            <seg id="p065">60 over the maximum and the net return BMMWheN in the neighl of 960 per year over and above tli&gt; ier feed. Many faiint - said I believe your record! are correct and that this dairy cow is such a maker, that I am going to breed dairy cattle after thin. I have a good many farmers to start a nucleus of a dairy herd, but not one out of ten who make it :• and I ha advocatil tXow.I want to take up and define the average cow as we rind lit • farm, and give you - to how she should be handled, and what we ma&gt; From her under proper treatn • The common cow. we may say. has adjusted herself to farm conditi She is a common cow because she has had good care under conn environment. I have had now over 4o of those cows in my yard that I have kept records of. The average daily yield of milk is tii&gt;&lt;H&gt; ]«i\, has given me on an av&lt; pounds of butter \\ does it mean' It means that if the cow you now have on the tarn, iligent care and is treated properly that you can add. at !• pounds of butter to her annual yield. That is something that is with - in your means. That is something that yon can aim for with the mals that you have, and if you pleat me with the ucconioda' that you have for that animal, verv litle change is needed. imnon cows that have Urn in my yard were not se - • ■d animals : the/ came to me merelv incidentally and probably, possibly and quite likely are fair representatives of the common cow as she is on the average farm. The question arises why docs the common that gives to the average fanner onlv 14(1 pounds of butter yield pounds under the conditions that she n e will say. at '•riment Station, or any institution of this kind'.' There reason for it.. The first point that is generally raised by the farim B have got the state and the general government back of \ou. If 1 could afford to have this thing and that thing to have the things you have, probably. I would get the same results, but I can not afford to bay all these expensive meals and feeds If I did the bills would he as big as my creamery enecks. " Now. I think there was something in it. I did think several \ears ago that the common cows in niv herd i such good returns I fed them what was called a hula' ration. This is the fifth year I have tried to find if the common Id do as well on the ordinary ration- on the farm, that food, solid ha&gt; lantn and roughage, and then a little mi\ of farm grown grains for her meals, and I find she makes just | rna to me as she did when she got this more expensive ration. us a good, deal to the average farmer; it means that he has a OB the farm that can produce about 878 pounds of nutter a year: it means that she can do it with the feeds he has on the farm. Now, why does she not do it": You have the cow and you have the teed \ - can not be that the difficulty is with the cow. it must be with the man Eo handles her. The man who handles the common cow is not Bl airyman as the common cow is a dairy cow. If you want to talk iut breeding, breed up i ; make him a be </seg>
            <seg id="p066">61 dairyn an so that he can cow before we ask him to get a better or a thoroughfare If he does not know how to cure for the common cow anil how I -t out of her, or as 1 should put it. if he is not a cow-man and I the industry ami and painstaking r to take ire of the common cow to get the best out of her. how can we he will do it with a higher bred dai bat reipi care and better accornodations and environment '.' It is natural t man should do his apprentice work in dairying with the common and then, when he gets her up to the greatest maximum yield. time for him to begin t( to their work. So much for the common cow. .Tu*-t a few words now in regard to the profits that we ma&gt; dairying when it is conducted along intelligent and advanced methods. Ymi remember that I told you I wanted you to get the good-will of the hat is one point. Another one is that - be ahs - comfortable; that is another point, because. \\ 1 abe eats, the energy in H 11 driving away the &lt; ting the storm in standing out during the day shivering, th - ug the body warm cannot I I making milk comfortable and al may have a cow perfectly comforalile but not contented. *he is not receiving the same thing that ing, and is m me thing she received yesterday at this t is in ;i today where *!&gt;■ causes ut among They get out of patience and h other and everything must have a system in handling the cow. We must h:i able in every way; and everything we do in connection with the dairy cow must be done with regularity. Under such a rind that the cornmoan cow will return easily from alnnit MO pou - unds of butter on an average during the year; and a m will add about 100 to ISO pounds to that. Of i will see at a glance that it you are going t of butter the better cow the man should understand how to hanc aid the man who is willing to do it can then understand « should use the dairy cow. but the average man will not meet t quirements. ■ as I was summoned to come down here. I had completed my mid winter experiments in my dairy work ; that is. I had taken the last three weeks work, added them together, the amount of feed per cow and the market price of butter for sum . up the pounds of milk and pounds of butter fat yield during tlie thr found the daily average. The herd li I 11 pounds ofbnti day I do not know what the prevailing price of butter is in thK but I presume it is not far fr the feed they consume at these rates (which I think is rather high, for this locality, ) corn 35 cents a leal 928.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">62 per ton, gluten feed *i» 1 . ( H) per ton, hay ftf.OO. silagi per pound. I wisli to mention that the gluten feed here is simply a by product of the corn products factory. One group -of rows are receiving that, while another group is receiving corn meal in place of gluten feed : that is a part of the experiment, so th;it while I am charging these cows up with gluten feed the indications arc that they would do just as well if I were feeding them corn meal. So far the indications have been that they could make hs large a yield without it If my ielding 1.1 pounds of butter daily, the &lt; I at prices stated amounts to VI 1 ., ind if butter is worth ■£'&gt; cents and the daily cost of the feed \%H cents, they are returning me. at ] * worth of butter for a dollar's worth of feed over and above what we could get for that feed at the market pries. That shows that dairying is very -profitable ver it is conducted along the line of advanced methods, and that if the fanner will follow out simple rules in handling his cows general proposition, he can market his feed through them at alx&gt;ut double price that he would get for it in the market ; at the same time he will have considerable skim milk with which to raise young hogs and calves and will increase the fertility of his farm which is getting to be quite an im]&gt;ort!int item in eastern states, and will, in time, be in Nebraska. I thank you, gentlemen, for your attention, i Applause. ) I Chairman: The next addr&lt; operative Duir.&gt; Herds" Prof. A. L. Haecker of our Nebraska University. We are all ac - linted with him and will \«- pleased to hear him. Mr. President. Ladies and Gentlemen : I attended some time ago a meeting of the directors of the Dairyman - ition. and at that meeting the subject of co-operative test for dairy h&gt; discussed. re unanimous in our ideas thart we. in Nebraska, should have some sort of a co-operative test that would give us reliable data and bring out the great differences that exists betwi in our common herds throughout 1 1 1 • ml the direct. about this that they were willing to donate a certain amount of money from the ition funds in support of such a test. I think we gel some of our Tom meetings where men come together from all parts of tte and where, practically, all phases of the industry are repre - sented. I know from an experimenter i standpoint that a man at an Experiment Station ven -. out of the practical line unless he it with the farmers' institutes over the state and rinds what is i and the important lines to work along. It should l&gt;e the aim and object of our Experiment Station and these different associations to do just as much good throughout the state as they can; and the only way we can tell tlxe best line of work is by consulting the men who are the men who are in the field. Our best experimenters today are the men who take up the causes of the farmers, or the problems that are confronting the tanners. I lay no to the credit of ttlis that Board that met at the Lindell hotel some week* -sed the need of some co-operative tests that would &gt;ked me to briefly compile a plan or Scheme for conducting co-operative dairy herd t. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">63 CO'OPERATTVE TESTS OF DIARY HERDS. Prof. A. L. Haecker I The need of knowing more about the annual production of our i id for dairy purposes is increasing each year. The farmers of our te during the past few years have purchased two million dollars rth of hand separators. This nv twenty or thirty thousand our farmers are in the dairy business and whether they stay in or : will depend upon their profits. The profits they receive will nly depend in a great measure upon the production of their i en a better knowledge of their n ''ting their individual ] lie tmm may be. is one of the most important nting the industry? kTo letter the existing conditions, anil show • .&gt;f more eful study of profitable milk production I know of no better plan ,n to conduct a CO operative herd I I The test should be so arranged as to include the varied farming ions of the state. For example, there should be a herd to represent northwest range condition, also the southwest. The central portion, h north and south, and the eastern section, would give a fair repre - tation of the natural conditions which influence the industry. I ieve ten herds would be all that could be successfully tasted. This nld require nearly all the time of one man. The ten herds could be arranged as to make it possible for the man checking up th - it all. spending one or two days with each, at which time he could «k up the weight and tests and make record of the same. Each d should be visited at least once a month during the entire &gt;enr in er to get reliable data from each individual animal. Equipment. I For each herd should be provided spring balance scales weighiii - ponnds; a set of sample hott red preferred, and a small Bab - -ting machine with necessary equipment. Blanks should be ivided also, so arranged that the name of or number of each 001 ■ herd could be written at the top. In the left hand column room ild be left for dating, eight milkings. This woul require VI blanks ■ the year. In each herd the milk from individual -lionld be ighed and recorded one day in the week. Any farmer desiring the vilege of keeping daily records would lw heartily encouraged but it i been found impractical and almost impomoto in other states to re - ire dairymen to keep daily records. By obtaining a one dav n ■ cow of each week in the year, a very accurate record could be com- I The man conducting the test could tnke such not s as would be ne - sary in order to make fair comparisons and by compiling all re, fast as they were made would be able to make a report by the end of yew. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">64 Work Involved by the Farmer k for the herd owner would be slieht and his trouble more iid for by the knowleii. ] in finding his profitable and Ma - le could be hung in a convenient place in tl I and close to them the milk blank could he tacked to a board, de of tin -iielf could contain the sun; P» work of ■ pling requires about one minuto id figuring to ■ lactation, the year's work would re - bat forty mini. m. Kuld make all fat determi - which method would be advisiible in case the owner BO doubt but what some of tJ willing to make jKirt of the tests in which cbm thi nly to check up his work from time to tin THE VALUE OF' SUCH \ I ■t only to the herd owners but I iish and distribute lirymen of the state. What ■fitable to a IB than a knowledge of their If he has animals in his herd which he is actually keeping year a! . inly worth much to him to know which ones they are. If he can keeji rive cowa that will do the \\ I with double the profit he wants to know it. attention to the heav&gt; investment we have ■iry machinery and tin ry business and In iv in ; now 1( I □ hundred re milking and find, if possible, which are paying bicto are not. It is irn]x&gt;rtant work and we can not do anything due to the dairy interest. The time has come. in a large portion of oar ■ when more attention must be paid to economic production. 1 and food prodnd rating higher priced each year and growing more keen. With more intensified methods of ng the Importance and value of dairying inn &gt;i&gt;eculative farming and lottery must give way to knowledge and facts. It is ■ but true that nine out of ten COW-ownen do no appreci;. - &gt; n individual cow - also true • n *e&lt;- the value m ine of the hardest • ms confronting advancement in dairy farming. iuld do more to bring about improve - ck than anything I know of. It cannot be hoped that uld m anyway revolutionize dairy practice, hut it nuch interest and start • gome allying. pledge of two him «&gt;) dollars made so liberally by the i the dair ition could be invested in pun i blanks. There would also perhaps be mple bottles and a few small testing machines. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">PROF. A. L. HAECKER University of Nebraska </seg>
           
            <seg id="p071">65 P Experiment Station with a competent man to do the work. Id be easily made, and the Dairy Association and Experi - r provided with valuable data. The material would make : bulletin for the Experiment Station and could be published edition. This with 2000 Dairy Association reports would 7,000 publications among the most interested farmers of the I There are many more things I might mention for such a tes-t. but &gt;ught it not worth while because if a test is to be made the men who i going to make it will, perhaps, find it necessary to change the plan th the conditions that they need. But I would like to say this that an association I would like to have your endorsement and also a mo - n to send to the board of regents favoring such a cow census in our te, or such a co-operative test, so that we can point to some figures, e world is getting sceptical. The time has come when we don't care hear a man get up andjsay what he thinks or pleases, but we ; want t. figures. It will tend to more good than the mere knowledge that have one or two thousand cows in the state that are being milked, might create result in showing some men that they are engaged in » wrong business. I believe it would be all right. It is not so much increase the number of dairymen in the state as it is to have them :ome better dairymen. I think %ve have some 20,000 or 30,000 men the state who are dairying to some extent, but I think we could cut t many of these and not miss them at all. We cannot all be dairymen: we cannot all be producers of milk and beef, but whatever we are let us go about it in a sensible and logical way, and know what we are doing. I think the moial effect would be pood, only to give us a little money and a little time to test your cows and find out which is luO-lb. cow. which is 2o'i-lb. cow, and which is 0-lb. cow. Too often we hear it said that that is a good cow. She as a good cow in the owner's eyes. When she was fresh and she gave pailful of milk she was the finest cow in the herd, but he did not now what she tested: she gave milk five or six months, perhap en went dry and became a stripper. She was not then a paying cow. n Nebraska so many people do things so different from what they r.ould; they make buttei when it is the cheapest and at the hardest me of the year to take care of the cream and milk, just at the time hen we have no time to attend to it or to be in the dairy business. We re in the corn belt where we are awfully busy in the summer season, aising corn. You ought to be dairying in the winter when you have ts of time to take caie of the business: when cream and butter are high, and when there is money in it. We don't want to be dairying with range cattle. Let us find out where we are at. (Applause.) Mr. Bassett: I would like to offer this resolution: tThat we favor the making of actual tests of dairy herds: that if re are any funds of the Association available for the purpose, that recommend the same to be used to assist the State Experiment </seg>
            <seg id="p072">66 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION Station to make co-operative tests of dairy herds. I move the adoption of the resolution. The motion was seconded and adopted Mr. Doubt: I expect I am the only man in the state who has his cows tested by Professor Haecker. He has sent out three or four par - ties to test my cows. Be it said to the credit of the institution, some of them did remarkably well. I believe they should send out these men to advise us where we are in error in taking care of our cows. I do not think the cows in the west will do muchbetter without better &lt;ar&lt;\ E- a cow to seek shelter behind a fence will never make a profitable cb. cow. Prairie hay and corn stalks are not going to develop the r : the principal thing is to keep them right; is to feed alfalfa hay [ corn meal; that makes the perfect ration. If you have some silage it would be better still. I believe if you could send a reliable man connected with this institution to test the cows of the state, that it would be he grandest thing that ever happened to the farmers of the state. The farmers would find out the errors they are in and find out just the mistakes they are making, therefore I am in favor of the mo - tion and voted for it. LMr. Bassett: We have provided on our programme a number en - ed "Butter Judging Contest." We had in view a judging contest, along the line of what the market requires when it comes to judging butter. To that end we have had purchased in Chicago, by the official inspector of the Government, three grades of butter as it is graded in the market. We had this official, Mr. W. D. Collyer, score the butter, and we have his official scores. It was the intention to have Mr. L-eighton of the Beatrice Creamery Company, who is an expert along this line, to be present and conduct this part of the programme and explain what is meant by flavor in butter, from a commercial stand - point; what is meant by grain and color and salt. It is not a difficult matter to engage in the dairy business and to make butter to suit your fc taste. It Is an entirely different proposition if you are making mercial butter to go on the open market. When the butter goes or. to the markets of the world it is sold according to its g:ade, or ac - cording to recognized standards of excellence. We are unable to have Mr. I,eighton with us today, but we are very fortunate in having with us Professor Haecker of the State University of Minnesota, who has had much experience along this line and who came here at our invitation, and, I might add, came on a moment's notice — a telegraphic invitation. I think he had just time enough to tell his wife he was going, and catch the first train. This is not the first time he has been so kind as to be in attendance upon our Associa- t meetings. Prof. T. L. Haecker has been so kind as to consent to cha:ge of this contest. I might add that the efforts or skill of contestant will be judged on the basis of 100 points for perfection that a contestant must score at least a minimum of 93 points in ' to be entitled to a share in the pro rata fund, which in this case </seg>
            <seg id="p073">x W L-&gt; A xSt* 1 xl A^i LAb L * J2s \ L^ 1 1* J^ 67 is $50.00. In this contest the following is a brief statement of the method used to determine the grade or score of each contestant, viz.: On the return of each score card, under the heading "Official Score" will be written the official score of the package of butter being judged; the difference between the "official score" and "contestant's score" de - termines the number of "contestant's points off. ' Subtract the num - ber of "contestant's points off" from "perfect," or 100 points, gives the grade or score to which the contestant is entitled in judging the specified package of butter. The premium money is pro rated upon the average score of the three packages by each contestant, and then only to those having an average score of 93 or more points. Our principal object in this butter judging is educational, and more especially to benefit the students in attendance at the dairy school. The officers of this asso - ciation feel that when we come here to hold our annual meeting that we should assist this experiment station, the dairy school, by our presence, by our support, by our good will and Dy the use of some of the money which the state appropriates for the support of the associa - tion. We feel that this is for the best interests of the dairy industry of the state, because the students who are here in the attendance are from all portions of our state, and when they return to their homes they will take with them whatever of knowledge or information they have ob - tained here, and disseminate the same among the people of their im - mediate locality; the student who takes a course in tne agricultural college, in any of its departments, will find upon return to his home that in matters pertaining to agriculture he will have much more of responsibility placed upon his shoulders than ever before; he will be expected to assist in such matters; he ought to be willing to render all possible assistance and I have every reason to believe that you will gladly do so. I Chairman Honeywell: Prof. T. L. Haecker will now take charge of butter judging contest. Professor Haecker. There are for use in this contest three grades of commercial butter, which are known to the trade as extras, firsts and seconds. With us in Minnesota, or the students who have attended the dairy school and taken training in judging butter, the difficulty seems to be in discriminating between the different grades of goods. It is important that you become expert butter judges so that you may readily detect the flaws in the make-up of the different grades of bui - ter. It stands quite to reason that the man who manufactures a certain product ought to know what his customers or the market requires, or the kind of an article that will best meet the wishes of the consumer. Now, the first thing which an expert butter judge does when he opens a package of butter is to smell of it, that is, he catches the aroma to see if it has a pleasant smell. Sometimes it is rather of a tame aroma, nothing pronounced one way or the other. He says, "That is very good butter; that is good butter; that will do." Then, when it comes to be placed in the mouth, it is the matter of taste, that is, the flavor. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">68 that is, it is palatable. Even in taste, the taste might seem quite satis - factory and yet there may be an after-taste which begins to be unsatis - factory and, after a while, we will say that that butter is not reall desirable, and it will fall into a second grade. That will depend largel upon the way the milk has been handled. A butter maker cannot mak a gilt-edge article from cream that has not been properly bandied. I should be clean from the cow; the udder should be clean. It shoulc be drawn in a barn or place where the air is reasonably pure and sweet it should be milked into a pail that is absolutely clean— that mean that the pail should be scalded every time after it is used — and in milk must be put into a pan that is clean, and if it is in a barn, i should be removed as quickly as possible so that it does not take on the barn odor, and when taken out of the barn it should go through some process of areation of either running through a separator or setting in a deep pan in water or something of that kind to drive out the animal odor, which, if kept in the milk, will give the butter a peculiar flavor which they call a smothered flavor, that is, the animal flavor smothered in the milk and not allowed to escape and come out. So far, in regard to the quality of the product from the handling of the cream. We also find that if we have a good article of cream or milk that we can, to a considerable extent, control the flavor of the butter by the process of ripening, or by a kind of culture that we use in ripening the cream. Very few barns or barn conditions are such that you can get the very nicest aroma and flavor by allowing the cream to ripen in its natural way; we used to think we could. We used to make an article of butter that we thought was good. It was good because we did not know of any better way. The public is constantly becoming wore and more discriminating in its taste. The public is constantly asking for a finer grade of goods. Half a century ago a farmer's wife was proud of the fine butter she made. She made it in the spring and stored it away and sold it during the winter, and told how fine a grade of butter it was. It would not do today at all. It was good for that time, but would not be good today. It would today at once be thrown into a second or third grade. I don't care how good butter is made, if it is kept six months it has a sort of rank flavor. People that have been eating that kind of butter call it good to this day, and men who have pas&amp;ed over into the shady side of life, like myself, believe that their mother made good or better butter than now, because it kept six months. It kept for the reasons stated, but it would not answer now. In scoring butter, the first thing to determine is the quality of the arouia. Pickiug out a sample of the butter, draw or pass it by close to the nore. I know a good many of you will not be able to tell much dif - ference between the second and the third grades of butter. One has to be trained in detecting the different aromas just as we have to be trained in other things. It takes time to differentiate between the two. You may say this is good butter, or that is; or, this is good and that </seg>
            <seg id="p075">TWENTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION is not, and so on, but to go on and give unqualified expression is a very difficult thing. We have allowed 50 points for flavor. If you cut off 10 or 12 of these points on flavor alone it means that you have a grade of butter that grades as "seconds." If you find that you have to cut off about six points or so on flavor and have butter otherwise nearly perfect, you have the grade called in the market "firsts." Butter scoring 95 or higher is graded as "extras." In scoring for flavor there is no use scoring off -ed 15 points. There is no use of going beyond that; if j you will go that much out of the way. From 1 to 15 will give you plenty of margin in which to score on flavor. LNow for grain, as it is called, we have allowed 25 points. Grain i reference to the texture, the body of the butter; whether it ia greasy butter. In expressing the different grades of butter in regard to grain you may use probably thiee points. For a fine, waxy butter, that is, not greasy, or dry sandy, we give 25 points. A butter that haa a perfect body has considerable moisture, but still it is firm and has nothing like sand in it, and when it is handled it bends to a certain The grain in butter has no reference to the granular condition of butter because some butter may be granular and not have what you would call good grain. Neither should it be a solid mass, so that it would look like grease or greasy butter. You must express these dif - ferent grades in grain, in figures ranging from 1 to about 3. In color we allow 15 points, and the standard butter should be uni - form throughout in color, not mottled or speckled. If butter has too light a shade, mark off according to the degree of allowance; that is something that is very difficult for us to determine, how much to mark off for a certain difference in the shade, but in a general way I might say that for color we sometimes mark off 1 point. For instance, butter that if of a high color, as here in this exhibit, gets a cut of about one - half, and, possibly, three-fourths, for being too high in color. If it is too light in color we also score it off. As to salt, that has very much to do with the judgment or knowl - edge of what the public wants. It has nothing whatever to do with what you want. That is why a large number of butter manufa manufacture an article for the public and they learn what the general concensus of taste is and grade upon that. If a butter is a little too highly salted it gets marked off half a point or one point. If too lightly salted, mark it off in like manner. I think this will give you a general idea of how to judge butter </seg>
            <seg id="p076">70 BUTTER SCORING CONTEST The butter scoring contest took place in the live stock pavillion, each package of butter, in its turn, being placed upon the table; a large number of small tiiers were used and assistants passed a trier of butter to each contestant. When the judging had been completed, Prof. T. L. Haecker placed the three packages on the table together, and ex - plained in detail the official score and the reasons therefor. This was a most interesting and profitable object lesson; abundant time was taken to explain how to machematically express on a score card the varying degrees of flavor, grain, color and salt. This contest completed the work of the annual meeting, which in point of attendance, in paid membership fees, in interest and enthusiasm has not been ex - ceeded in the history of the association. It was particularly gratifying tnat Governor Hoard, the veteran dairyman, who was present at the first annual meeting of the association, was able to favor us with his presence on this, our twentieth anniversary. I The following are the names of the successful contestants in the but - -judging contest, there being 70 who took part, 38 of the number ring above the minimum: Fred Brazda. Dodge A. R. Bigelow. Sniithfield _ Lee Young. Lincoln Geo. E. Payne. North Platte . A. R. Preston. Lincoln M.M E. Parmeter, Lincoln Jas. A. Reid, Lincoln H7. i is Jan. E. Reed, Havelock J. R. Roberts, Normal M.S1 !t4.41 J. D. Newelll, Columbus Junction, Iowa Mrs. C. W. Kauffman, Rokeby E. L. Jameson. Lincoln ■ loimson. li;istinj;s F. M. Doubt. Havelixk F. C Boyd. Lincoln .... E. C. Bristol. Lincoln Ml ■-»."") M. ) l '.Hi. 5X Geo. Tilden, Benedict ill. IIS N. E. Tyrrell. Omaha L. P. Stone, Lincoln SIT. To Frank Soott, Pawnee City M.M Cbaa Lazure, Lincoln C. E. Laverack, Beaver Citv •ft, H </seg>
            <seg id="p077">■1 71 Fred Westover, Lincoln 96.41 M. ;.". Howard Wallace, West Union J. B. Varney. Bennet Floyd Mecbam. Lincoln L. F. Marsh, Lincoln L. J. Moore, Riverton H. W. Ehlers., Cheny Fred B. Caldwell, Kenesaw C. F. Chase, Pawnee City Chas E. Garby, Pawnee City Henry C. Glissman, Omaha J. R. Gearhart, University Place J Gibb, Lincoln M. Little, Silver Creek C. H. Hinman, Lincoln Daniel McNeal. North Platte Stanley Howard, University Place </seg>
            <seg id="p078">72 NEBRASKA DAIRYMF. oCIATIOX LIGHT VERSUS DARKNESS (An address deliveied by ex-Gov. W. D. Hoard, of Wisconsin, before 'ing of Organized Agriculture of Nebraska, held in the chapel of the state university, Wednesday evening, January 18th, 1905. This meeting was held under the auspices of the State Board of Agriculture, the president of the boaid, Mr. W. R. Mellor, presiding. The attendance was all that could be desired, every seat in the large university chapel being occupied.) Gentlemen of the Convention I am glad to greet you once more. It is a very comforting a ance that I am still alive. I am glad to see that you are. We must while the day lasts. What a beautiful thing it is to be able to work, to think, to reason, and by all these aids to better see the truth. other day a woman farmer in Wayne county, New York me the following letter: Ed. Hoard's Dairyman: — A neighbor called at my house the other night and remained until it was very dark. When he came to go away I urged him to take my lantern to show him the road. He refused, saying: "I guess I know 'the road; I've traveled over it for thirty E&gt;re he got home he ran his wagon into a ditch, was overtui i team ran away, killing one horse. A little cheap lantern light have saved all this. Did he really know the way? Did he know as much as he thought he did? And he had traveled over the road, he said, "for thirty years." Some of my neighbors are just like him about taking the Dairyman O! they "know the way." I find the Dairyman lantern very hand) But I am only a woman, you know, carrying on a farm. But my re per cow are the largest of any at this creamery, and that neigh bor who would not take the lantern was at my house borrowing a hun dred dollars to help him out. I was glad my cows were doing enoug lx tter so I could lend it to him. I am sorry for him, but what can yo do with men who are so conceited that they don't know they need ttern? Maybe I shouldn't have written this. But then, he will neve it, for he never reads the Dairyman. ONLY A WOMAN SUBSCRIBER. The central meaning of my topic today will be "Light Versus Dark ■iu see a manufacturer remarkably successful in his business, you ly inquire what were the causes that led up to it. Did you ever n eminent manufacturer in any line who kept himself in ignor- Wayne Co., N. Y. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">73 rof the meaning of his business? Who kept his mind darkened a sick room? Who dieaded the light? I Did you ever know of a successful lawyer who was ignorant of the ? Do such men succeed before the courts? I Did you ever know of a man who was successful as a mechanic who not make a hard study of his business? Who did not understand terms that are used in th€ literature of his trade? Go where you will — in every line of human effort outside of farm - ing—it is universally recognized that to be successful in it the man must be educated to it. This education he may get one way or another, but get it he must or he goes down. tThis thing we call education is nothing more than comprehension — lerstanding. There is not a farmer in Nebraska today who, if he nks of making a lawyer of his son, will not send him to school. He nits that his boy must have a mental training, must be educated to to understand his business. So it is in medicine, theology, engineer - —everything, in fact. No farmer would dare to make himself so iculous as to sneer against book law, book medicine or book en - eering. tWhy is it that the farmer will recognize the value of a trained, in - ligent mind in every profession but his own? I How do we get this mental training, this insight? (1) By studying leading what other men have found out about the facts. (2) By dying them tor ourselves. Both systems are absolutely necessary lo intelligence and profit thave visited nearly every state in the Union and the Provinces of da in an effort to determine why men succeed as dairy farmeis why they fail. tit is not because of a lack of hard work. Indeed, some of the hardest rkeis are the greatest failures. But I do find, without exception, that successful men are the intelligent ones. I find that they spend ney on their own enlightenment. I Now I am going to bring up some individual examples that have sented themselves to me in the forty years I have been working in field. know a man by the name of H. S. Griswold, of West Salem, Wis. i case is worth considering. He owns only fifty acres of land and it possibly worth $50.00 an acre. He is now carrying 25 cows on this farm, and they are cows. I A year ago I addressed the farmers at a fair in La Crosse county, which he resides. His entire herd was brought on to the race track 1 I talked for an hour, taking those cows as my text. tThey were only grade Guernseys — nearly all bred by Mr. Griswold. t they earned him last year over one hundred dollars apiece in the e of their cream alone. His cows earn him in cream and skim-milk nit one hundred and twenty dollars a year per cow. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">74 Mr. Griswold happens to be the sort of a farmer who is bigger than his farm. That is, he has educated himself to that size. He is a con - stant reader and student of what other men are doing. He makes good joints. ■ I once knew an old cooper who had an apprentice. I said to him one day, "Uncle Tom, will Jimmy ever make a cooper?" "Lord, no," wU the reply. "Why?" "Well," said the wise old man, "you see he hain"t got any idea about making jints." Mr. Griswold makes "jints." Consequently good results don't leak out between joints. He made a first-class joint in his calculations by selecting for his dairy machine a breed of cows that are bred to dairy work. He is not a "dual purpose" man. IA railroad man once gave me a good illustration of the way this ual purpose" nonsense plays the mischief witn men who are vainly ing to make a good profit with cows bred to no purpose. He said: "It costs considerable money to run a passenger train to New York or: a fast schedule. We can make a profit if we carry good loads and nmk€ good time. We will never have a profitable load if we make slow time, so we must have engines built for speed. Such engines will make the distance at the lowest consumption of fuel consistent with the time we must make. "It would prove the biggest nonsense in the world for us to under - take to make a freight engine do such work. It is not constructed right. It hasn't the speed form. Everything in this world that has a purpose in life, or a fitness to that purpose, has a form fitted to its purpose an 1 ! the form is the outward indication of its purpose." LHr. Griswold has sought all the light he can get. How is it with tho braska dairy farmers? Are they seeking the light? tXow Mr. Griswold, with his gross revenue of $2,500 from a net revenue of $00.00 apiece above the cost of feed, is but one ons men who are doing nearly, if not quite, as well, by let - light shine into their minds. I Why don't more farmers look at their business from the same stand - int? Speak to them about it and you will hear them ask: "Suppose erybody had such cows, what would butter be worth?" Did you ever hear the sto:y of the old maid? She was found in a ■ f hysterical tears one day. When questioned as to the cause, she replied, "1 was thinking if I got married and should have a baby, and aid crawl into that hot oven and burn to death, O, how I would feel. I am sure I shall never marry." eveiybody had such cows. What then? Well, it would require only one-third the number of cows to make as much butter and give as much milk as three-thirds do now. Take off two-thirds of the expense and keep the product at the same figures, and then reckon what the increase in net profit would be. The gieat tendency of modern dairy thought is to force us to get </seg>
            <seg id="p081">TWENTIETH ANNUAL OONVENTK )N 75 right down to an understanding of dairy economy We must let in all the light we can. That is Mr. Griswold's plan. His ambition is to see how much, in straight dairy work, he can make 50 acres earn. So he makes that little farm carry a tally o: £5 grade Guernsey tows, and they earned him as I said one hundred dollars '.piece in the production of cream alone last year. We know of plenty cf farmers with three hundred acres of lan&lt;l and herds of fifty cows that did not do as well. Mr. Griswold invests, say, $3,000 in land — for land is not high about West Salem — and makes ir earn more than some other men with six times more land and twice as many cows. There must be some reason for this. What is it? Mr. Griswold uses four times as much dairy intelligence; he does four times as much dairy thinking; he reads four times as much on dairy sub - jects. Consequently he can do just as much business on six times less capital in land and one-half as many cows. Light is cheaper than darkness. But that is not all. The expense in hired help, in farm machinery, in fencing, in horses to do the work, in the fret and worry of body and soul, in the risk against losses, in all these things and more, is a great deal less with the Gtiswold class of farmers. But Mr. Griswold made a different man of himself to start with. I the men who don't believe in farming according to plenty of ght, they have been growing smaller all these years. Those are the men who have made the rich old Wisconsin farms grow poorer every yf-ar. They wouldn't study, nor read, nor attend conventions, nor buy papers and books and get at a reason for this constant backward slide in fertility. No man is a good farmer who allows his soil to decline in producing akes knowledge — a certain amount of scientific knowledge — Ught to stop such decline Esa good farmer who has made himself bigger in comprehfi s farm. The other class of men have grown smaller in lion and administrative judgment every year as they added to tbcir acres. Who made these two Y nsible for such widely differing results? Who dairy farmers as they aie? Each man is hU own schoolmaster. He is bound to be. There is no help for it. Why these things in their true light? Can &gt;n't the American far neglect our minds a: we have done? a othei quality of darkness is the notion that the farmer can not afford hired help. I will admit that if he is going to continue in a wasteful method of arming, he can not afford hired help. Neither could the manufacturers if they run their factories on the same ideas that prevailed 50 years ago, or the railroad men if they ran their railroads as it was done 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">76 But many dairy farmers all over the nation are producing milk just as expensively as was done 50 years ago, with no better cows, no better ideas, no better methods of stabling or ideas of feeding. As the father did, so is the son doing here in Nebraska, and to some extent in Wis - consin. Although I assure you that the light has Men shining a little stronger in Wisconsin than in Nebraska. I On this question of hired help. Pardon me if I bring in my own perience. I own a farm of 193 acres, and keep a herd of registered and grade Guernsey cows. The dairy consists of 42 cows. Ine revenue from the farm consists in cream taken to the creamery, sale of registered and grade stock, pork, poultry and barley grown for seed. taim to make everything of such a character .-at it will sell for a price. I keep four men employed by the year, one foreman and i others, and manage the farm myself when at home. I have invested in the plant about $30,000. I paid for labor last year | The gross cash revenue from the farm was $4,760. This gave me $1,800 in interest on the capital at 6 per cent; paid for the labor, ; : $300 for taxes and incidental expenses and left $1,060 to be re - invested in the farm in any way conducive to its best inten I could have done none of these things if I had refused to employ labor. I must not refuse it labor. In my printing business I keep 50 people on the pay-ioll. I am look - ng all the time for a place wherf I can profitably employ another per - •n. That is the only way I make my business earn more. So it ; - &gt;e farm. Crowd it up to its best economic work all you can. But you an not make labor profitable with unwise management. There is here the use of modern methods, modern intelligence, modern thought, ernes in. You can't afford to be ancient, if you expect to earn the odern dollar. There is such a lot of men who seem to be as afraid f progressive ideas as they would be of smallpox. There are two unds of conservatism— that which is born of fear and ignorance, and hat which is born of knowledge and courage. The first dreads the ghts, the second asks for more light, better lignt. In the summer of 1901 occurred the worst drought in the west we ave ever seen. Milk at the creameries shrank 30 to 60 per cent. A reat proportion of farmers let the matter run without any effort to elp it. They said it would not pay to buy feed. They had no summer los and but little in the way of soiling crops, for the drought hurt that as well as the rest. I happened to have 50 tons of old silage left ver. As soon as the cows commenced to shrink this silage was fed to them night and morning, say 15 pounds to a feed. They held right up n their milk to the usual flow for that time of lactation. I made hand - some money on the investment. One experience was enough with me. built the next year a summer silo. I have neighbors who haven't yet been punished enough. They are looking for the saving grace of an- </seg>
            <seg id="p083">TWENTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 77 other drought. Their cows have not yet recovered from the ill effect* of their refusal to feed when they should have fed. An old German friend of mine took a nice heifer to the county fair. He was leading her home when I met him and asked: "Did you get a premium?" He leaned wearily back against the heifer and said: "You know vot I dinks?" "No." "Veil, I dinks dot if a man hafe de besteat heifer in der vorld und he go py der goundy fair und he got not a goot head, den, py shimiuiny, he got not a premium." Sometimes I think I am a good deal of a crank. I seem somehow very much dissatisfied with the way a large proportion of men about me are carrying on this business of dairying. My wife tells me to let them alone. But at 'em I go whenever I get a chance. They seem to measure themselves and the business so much by what I think are false standards. They pride themselves on being practical. They tell me I am theoretical. I take them to my farm, show them my books, tell them all of my mistakes, and then show a good profit. But still they say "that is not practical.' Curious ideas some farmers have as to what is practical. Here is an example. I put King's system of ventilation into my barn. It cost me $350. The stable is 142x36 feet and houses about 50 animals. The air in that stable changes about every hour. The cow stalls are of the Model Stall pattern. The cows look fine. They are in the finest of condition, eyes bright and full of vigor and they average over a pound of butter fat a day per cow after six months of milking with the most of them; and 17 were two- and three-year-old heifers. It is now five &gt;ears since the Model Stall, the ventilation system and that herd of cows were brought together. But one case of sickness, not a case of garget or injured teats has occurred in that herd in those five years. They have made me a handsome profit. Yet my neighbois tell me I am not practical. Here is a conversation between one of them and myself: "Hoard, how much did' this ventilation cost you to put in?" "Three hundred and fifty dollars." "Gracious! you can't afford any such money as that on a herd of cows just for air. It ain't practical." "See here, my neighbor; how much do you figure that this thing of pure air co6t me?" "Why, $350." "Oh, no; it costs me annually the interest on that sum. 1 have loaned $350 to the herd of cows for this one thing. The interest on that at 6 per cent is $21. Look them over; note how bright, healthy and efficient at the pail they are, and then tell me if you don't think it was a good loan?" Still he shook his head and said. "It don't look practical to me." LYou see, my neighbor could not comprehend this idea of loaning ney to the cows or to the farm, even if it paid three times 6 per cent interest. Was he practical? But to skin it out of the farm and loan it to a neighbor, that would be practical. Do such men have the first true idea of the meaning of the word "Practical?" it seems to me that the first thing a farmer ought to do is to </seg>
            <seg id="p084">78 *s EBR ASK. A DAIR \ M EN S ASSOCIATION et to work to obtain a wise, broad judgment of the meaning of this ork. Such a judgment is needed very greatly, for a host of men are isleading themselves with it. They turn their backs on the light and ay that is practical. Is darkness practical? They refuse to exercise ieir own powers of mind; refuse to do what they can to broaden their inds by better study of this thing we call "agriculture," the biggest, eepest thing in the world, and as true as you live they call that con - tion of mind "practical." Is it? Here is the best definition of the ord I have ever seen: "Anything is practical that you can profitably ut in practice." t Science is all the time bringing out new facts and new ideas that of value to farmers if they are prepared to understand them and sive them. Another illustration: About ten years ago I commenced making a tudy of alfalfa on a number of city lots. Every farmer told me I ould fail. They said they had tried it and it wouldn't grow. I was ot satisfied with the way they had tried it. If I could make a success f it, it would be a good thing for Wisconsin dairymen, so I watched lose and studied hard. Every mistake was welcome, for we learn mors y mistakes than anything else if we will but look into them. By and y, after several years, I found that a certain rigid course must be pur - ued which I called the "Wisconsin iule." If these conditions are beyed, alfalfa is more certain than red clover. I succeeded and now elde of alfalfa are all about me. But a host of men complain of failure. ook into their case and you will find that they will not read and study, 'hey run on their own notion. One man, a German, had a beautiful stand of young alfalfa. His astures were sho:t and he turned in his cows. I said to him, "Chris, ou have killed your alfalfa, for it will not stand pasturing in this limate." Then he replied, "O vat does a newspaper man know about arming?" The next spring he found out — when the alfalfa was all illed. That man was a type of thousands of others. He could not earn anything from anybody else. Others have killed their alfalfa by utting the fourth crop, which should never De done in Wisconsin lati - udes. With me, and on my heavy clay farm, it is a Detter success than ed clover. Last spring I plowed up 15 acres of alfalfa sod for com and seeded 21 acres with 30 pounds to the acre and a bushel and a peck of barley. At the same time I seeded 8 acres of red clover, 20 pounds to the acre, and the same amount of barley. The clover nearly all summer killed and the alfalfa lived. But I noticed it looked weak and yellow in places. Science had been telling me about inoculating the soil with the peculiar bacteria that belongs to alfalfa. One of my editorial staff had tried inoculating it by sprinkling it with bacteria water, and the effect ior the better was Ml at once. So I rigged up a street sprinkling wagon and have gone over </seg>
            <seg id="p085">79 all of that portion that showed a lack of iacteria. The effect was seen in a few days. Mind you, that is scientific light. Had I shut it out of ri, or despised it as book farming, would the light ever have shown me? Too great a proportion of our farmers do no oiiginal thinking and t Etion for themselves. They wait until some other man has ated the truth and then take it up. Could they not be readers 3 of the wo:d as well as anybody? On 32 acres of alfalfa last year I harvested 150 tons of beautiful hay Eof it nearly of the value of wheat bran as a feed for my cows, a daily ration of 35 pounds of corn silage and 10 pounds of alfalfa cured, mind you, in the hay cock under hay caps — I made milk v iwest possible cost, from 4 to 8 cents per i ay less than the otce itrons at the Fort Atkinson creamery. BiTiat helped me to do this? Reading up on the feed question. That more light. There are a lot of things to learn concerning this feed tion. Follow this calculation for a moment. We buy and use all these ntrated feeds for the sake of the protein element they contain. Ee have let the light shine in on our minds, we will know that ling value of any kind of feed is in proportion to the amount of it contains. See how this applies to a few of the feeds dairy buy. Bran contains 12 per cent of digestible protein, or 24u pounds of protein to the ton. If you pay {19.00 a ton for it you are paying, say, 8 cents a pound for the protein. Ajax flakes — dried biew - er's grain— contain 30 per cent protein, or 600 pounds of protein to the ton. If you pay $24.00 a ton for the flakes you are paying 4 cents a pound for the protein. E\eiy dairy farmer ought to be smart enough to cultivate an understanding of the chemical analysis of feed and de - termine by their protein content and the price which is the best feed to buy. Did they do this you would not see them buying protein at 8 cents a pound when they can buy it for 4 cents. This is a good illus - tration that often the cheapest in price is the dearest in expense. P'he various cow censuses which have shone in the columns of id's Dairyman throw a strong light. How strong the contrast in Fond du Lac, Wis., census between one creamery patron. No. 4, and No. 17. No. 4 made a profit of {29.18 over and above the cost of feed. No. 17, living right along side of No. 4, taking his milk to the same creamery, did his work so blindly that he lost flO.17 per cow. No. 4 re - 1" received $10.17 less per cow than the feed cost. In that cow census, out of 48 farmers taking milk to that creamery, 10 of them — almost one-fourth — absolutely received less money from the creamery than the ceived from the creamery $29.18 more than the feed cost per co» feed cost. In addition to the 48 there was taken a census of 12 cheese factory patrons, and the result was still worse, for out of the 12, four last money, or 33 per cent were losers. What is the matter with these men? </seg>
            <seg id="p086">80 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION If you study them and the way they live you will see at once. They do not use their brains. They do not read or study enough on this business of keeping cows. Take the measure of their minds and you will take the measure of their profit. I tell you it has a wonderful sight to do with a farmer's profit whether he reads concerning his business or not. Here are some hard facts to prove it W. H. Jenkins took a census in 1901 of 50 farmers who were patrons of the creamery at Montrose, Pa. Twenty-five of them read dairy pa - pers; 25 of them did not The 25 who did read dairy papers averaged $50.23 per cow for the year. The 25 who did not read averaged $32.95. Here is a difference of $17.28 per cow. Did it pay the 25 to read? Did It pay the other 25 not to read? That's not all. Those who did read averaged a profit over the cost of food of $15.06 per cow. Those who did not read averaged a profit of 66 cents. These are hard facts worth thinking of. Here is another: Mr. Jenkins took another census of 45 patrons ol I! Onandaga County (N. Y.) Milk Association. The tabular statemeut 3 printed in Hoard's Dairyman of February 27th, 1902. Here were farmers taking their milk to the association, where the weight of Ik and cash records were kept. What is the record of these men* ?rty-one read agricultural and dairy papers. They averaged a profit $1.35 for every dollar they spent in feed. Fourteen of these patrons not read either agricultural or dairy papers. W nere a farmer does t read such papers you will also find as a rule that he does not read Eks devoted to his business. These 14 averaged $1.20 for every dollar nt in feed, or 15 cents loss on every dollar. Now, the average cost of ping their cows was $42.66. Multiply this sum by 15 cents and you tve as the loss per cow $G.40. Suppose a man had a dairy of 20 cows; i-n there would be a loss of $128 annually. Wnat can we say for a in who will not stop a hundred and twenty-eight dollar leak with ten do'lars worth of good reading information. Let me show you the figures for a moment on the 14 who did not read and what they lost by not leading, as compared with the 31 who did read: No. 3 with 37 cows dropped behind $ 236.80 No. 4 with 2n cows dropped behind 128.00 No. 5 with 22 cows dropped behind 140.80 No. 6 with 13 cows dropped behind 83.20 No. 8 with 22 cows dropped behind 140. 80 No. 12 with 24 cows dropped behind 153.60 No. 17 with 2ii cows dropped behind 128.00 No. 22 with 22 cows dropped behind 140.80 No. 29 with 24 cows dropped behind 153.60 No. 30 with 10 cows dropped behind 64.00 No. 32 with 7 cows d:opped behind 44.80 No. 33 with 12 cows dropped behind 76.80 No. 36 with 14 cows dropped behind 89.60 No. 38 with 22 cows dropped behind 140.80 $1,721.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p087"/>
            
            <seg id="p088">81 PJ6S with 14 dairy farmers of $1,721. fid. When the effect on iy the right kind of reading matter can be had so cheaply. p folly of these 14 farmers losing seventeen hundied and dollars and sixty cents, when $10 apiece, or $140, would have ! study these census returns and what they tell I am amazed be - yond expression. It is not a pleasant prospect. Long before I insti - tuted this cow census work I was convinced that there was a fearful lack somewhere with the aveiage cow farmers. I wanted to dig out tcold frozen facts and put them before the men who keep cows. I 1 printed in Hoard's Dairyman in the last five years census investi - ma of nearly 1,0*6 farmers, their farms and herds of cows, all cov- Beir work for one year at the creamery. Of these, 212 are in in. loo in Iowa. 100 in Ohio, 325 in New York, and SO in Penn - . These cover a wide range of territory. They tell the same the gain in profit by trying to be intelligent and great losses ing to make an effort to be intelligent. Which is pra THE INDIANA COW CENSUS T hose of you who lead Hoard's Dairyman will remember the "Cow ■" report of 5o herds of cows belonging to patrons of creameries in Marshall county, Indiana, for the 12 months ending October 31st. '•nsus " was the accurate record of the earning of 282 iwned by 50 diffeient men, as shown by the creamery books. A* close an estimate as possible was made of the cost of keeping and the question was brought down in each case to amount of cash received by each herd for every dollars worth of feed consumed. Ee facts were sought to be established. &lt; 1 1 The number of cows •ned less than the cost of their keeping; Ci) The number that enough to pay for their keep and from that up to the hi*: t of profit. (3) What was the mental condition of each herd Was he a man who took an intelligent interest in his • so to be a reader of dairy and farm literature? Knave tound that there is a very dose connection between the of profit a herd of cows yield and the amount of reading and le owner gives to this subjt-. Ee average farmer does not think so, but the average farmer has taken a thorough census of over 1,000 dairy farmers and in various states, to know whether this is true or not. Pr. C. P. Goodrich of Wiscon&gt;ii, was commissioned to undertake the of taking this census. The result of this effort was given in a r read by Mr. Goodrich before the Indiana State Dairy Convention published fully in Hoards Dairyman of Decembei 4th, 1903. I need hardly say that the facts disclosed by that census were a great 'eye opener." Every reader of the Dairyman had a chance to read and digest this report. It cieated a profound impression upon all those who tame within the light. CM course nothing could be done for those who stay in the darkness. If they ever know of it, it will be a wonder. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">82 I will simply give the averages. The number of pows kept by these 50 patrons was 282. Average cost of feed per row, $24.%; average re - urns in butter fat per cow, $32.20; average number pounds butter fat XT raw, 1C6; average price of buttei fat, 19.4 rente; average amount or one dollars worth of feed, $1.29; average net profit per cow, $7.24. "here were five patrons having 45 cows who fed silage last winter, and leii average net profit was $16.74 per cow. There were 45 patrons hav - ng 237 cows, who did not feed silage, and their average net profits per ow was $5.57 — $11.17 less. Forty-five out of 50 owners gave their idea of the value of skim-milk nd their valuation ranged from 10 to 25 rents, which is about the range between men who stand in the light and know how to handle skim-milk nd those who are in the dark about it. But one oi two of these men, hough they were dairymen, had never instituted any close experiments o determine the value of skim-milk. Consequently it was all guess - work with the rest of them. A very interesting and instructive feature was the "census" that was taken of the intelligence of the 50 men whose work was thus brought to light. Here it could be seen "as plain as day" whether it made any difference in Indiana with the profits of a dairy armer whether he was a reader or not a reader of the literature of his usiness. Thousands of famers do not believe that it makes a cents orth of difference with their pocket whethei their minds are light or ark on this question, but it does. What say the facts? Mr. Goodrich says: "One other question that I asked each one was, 'Do you take and read a dairy paper? 1 "Nearly all of them take agricultural papeis with a little dairy read - ing in them, but only six of those I asked take any paper especially devoted to dairying. These six take Hoard's Dairyman and some of them the Dairy and Creamery. "I felt curious to know whether those who took dairy papeis made nough more profits out of the business to pay the sul«cription price of tie papers. I figured it up and I find that the six who take Hoard's Dairyman averaged in net profits pei cow, for butter fat, over cost of eed, $11.07, while the 44 who do not take a dairy paper averaged, in net profit per cow, only $5.58 — a difference of $5.49 per cow in favor of the man who tries to inform himself by leading the experience of others who are engaged in the same business as himself, and who reads the investigations of scientists, along dairy lines, in the matter of feeding ows and all the other problems that arise to confront the dairyman." Let us understand this statement. It cost the sum of $5.49 per cow oi the owner not to give himself a dollar's worth of specific dairy read - ng during the year. If he had ten cows it was $54.90 for the luxury of iving in the dark. Can dairy farmers afford this? Believe me when I ell you this is the key that unlocks good fortune. I am not saying this o you because I am an editor of a dairy paper. It will make but little ifference to me whether you read and study or not, but it will make a </seg>
            <seg id="p090">TWENTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION N Rreat difference to you and your boys whether a strong dairy light shines in your household or not. This thing we call dairying is a very large subject, if it is rightly 1 on, the best profits gotten out of it, the largest pride and en - nt taken in its pursuit, it will call for the highest grade of intel - ligfiue you can give to it. It is universal almost that the farming i lass do not give themselves the mental culture they should for their own advantage man can. if he will, enlarge the light that ■ about hi- \ll that is reqired is to pi o vide for it, seek it. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">NEBRASKA DAIKYM1 &lt; &gt;CIATI&lt; &gt;N LIST OF CREAMERIES Name of Cwaun'y M^r. or Eh Butter Maker Poet Office ns Center E. Hansen J. C. McKendry J. A Holmes Archer Lincoln Carleton Neligh Geo. E. Hask.ll \V. W. Lichty Pexton I. E. CahtK»n CarlMon J. L. Burtis T. S. Pexton R. I. Cahoon Elkhorn Valley ■ ■ Fontanelle aitown • Jol.len Rod Hampton (Ten. Petri F. E. Pratt .1. Cox (xermantown Fremont Hampton Handanoa Omaha Henc: HanlinK Clias. Harding m. H. Lyon ■Tohn StU' Lyons Malcomh Martinshnrg MoGinnia Martinshurg Amelia R. W. IfoQinnia C. F. Bush P. E. Fisher Qea Trine 0. Mnckle E. L. Stacy J. Thonijtson J. Anderson Midland Riverton Ravenna (irand Inland Riverton T. \V. Moon J S. Clark r. M. Henry A. J. Wise Merrill .1. A. Pent • Win. Bechter .). H. Rushton .IF. McCnllongh Ravenna Loup City Ord Sutton Schuyler Pierce Fairmont Fairfield .1. Cox \V. A. Matfinnir ('urn ill C. Carroll ("lias. Harding T. G. Hanna . McDonald Ernest Samzelius Herbe rt Craven SrhuyUr </seg>
            <seg id="p092">KAREN Cow taking first place In contest </seg>
           
            <seg id="p093">TWENTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION M ISflllllK 1 ~ t* sef T * I 3 s ' n 1 1 n i if s! tnnn 3 5 5 it ' X I i» 7 ■ v- *s x s K K if a •i t a r MS i. !Jii ; /. i T 5 | | * fi ? | | 5 - UMMfM •^ -i. " liilsjjii i iii&gt;;p;si * FZ a IM i i 1 1 1 i ! II &lt; 3 - 2:5 5 ; : i i i i i! : Ii I | S | II 8 jf ( i I k a i i i ?■' — o S - 5- i i i i n i « 8 S — I 5§ I i 1 1 « X rt ljlj II ; I * iiiiiiiisS^I' ?? -• — ?B ■ ■ a a &gt; i _J| — ?r g e g a a it t S5 / Rank • * *j « u« ** "" for J yr t; a- </seg>
            <seg id="p094">Hfi </seg>
            <seg id="p095"/>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>