<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00040">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00040</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Tenth Annual Report of the State Fire Marshal</title>
               <date value="1919">1919</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATE FIRE MARSHAL. Office of State Fire Marshal, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. To His Excellency, S. R. McKelvie. Governor of the State of Nebraska : Dear Sir: — Complying with the law in this state, I herewith submit to you the tenth annual report of the Division of Fire Preven - tion. In submitting this report, I am fully aware that owing to the immense amount of work that I have been trying to handle in all parts of the state in connection with this office and the limited time at my disposal for the office part of the work, this report will necessarily be somewhat brief and not as complete as I would like to have it. Inspections When I took charge of this office at the beginning of the year I found that no record had been kept of inspection work in the years past. Believing that this branch of our work should be made a matter of record a form was devised in this office and later an inspection record was printed. The inspection record gives the date of the inspection at each town and pro - vides for entering separately each and every oi'der issued in that town, and giving the total number of inspections made. A card index system has also been put into use for the in - spection work. The inspection slips are filed alphabetically by towns and a complete record kept of all orders of every nature and kind. A total of 374 cities and towns have been thoroughly inspected during the year. A small number of these towns have been gone over the second time. If our inspection force had been sufficient each town could have been </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 STATE FIRE COMMISSION inspected at least twice during the year and it is my opinion that the more often inspections are made the greater the good accomplished. During the year 24,497 inspections were made and 13,105 orders issued for the correction of minor defects that appeared necessary to the inspector. Condemnation of Buildings I also found on taking possession of this office that no record of condemnation had been kept. Believing, also, that matters of this kind should be made a matter of record a form was devised and a condemnation register ordered. This book is indexed by towns, the entries made in each case showing the date of complaint, the name of the city or town, the lot and block number, street number or addition, the name and address of the owner, the date the owner was notified, the month, day and hour set for the hearing, and the finding, giving the orders issued in detail. The last entry shows whether the orders that were issued were complied with. The complaint, copy of notice of hearing and all communications having any bearing upon each complaint are filed for future reference. There has been during the year 282 complaints filed in this office. Detailed reports of both the inspection and condemnation work will also appear in this report. 1919 Fires I also wish to call your attention to a table which will ap - pear in this report giving the fire loss in this state since this office was established ten years ago showing that the fire waste this year is lower than any year since a record has been kept, the loss this year being thirty-four per cent less than the loss during 1918. A report of the work in the Division of Fire Prevention is hereby respectfully submitted for your information. E. D. BEACH, State Fire Marshal. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 3 News bulletin At the beginning of the year we decided to issue a News Bulletin giving the items of interest in connection with this work publication and free circulation at the close of each month. There has accordingly been issued such a bulletin every month since February, 1919 which has been mailed to every newspaper in the state and to all other parties interested in the work of this office. While the time has been limited to prepare copy for this purpose we have endeavored to get some tables compiled each month showing the inspections made, the orders issued and totalling the number of fires and the amount of losses, believing that the people had a right to know what was being done and from reports received from numerous sources we are satisfied that our efforts in this line are to some extent at least appreciated. Steel Gasoline Drums The explosion of an empty steel gasoline drum at Bene - dict in January instantly killing a twelve-year-old boy has been made the text for a seraion by this office on more than one occasion during the year. We have continually called the at - tention of the public to the great danger of empty gasoline receptacles of any kind, especially the steel dnim. We have issued warnings on numerous occasions against allowing these drums to stand on the depot platforms or on the sidewalks in front of business houses or on the back of the lots where there is a possibility of great loss of life and property from explosion. In one little town out in the central part of the state we saw a row of these drums setting along the edge of the sidewalk in front of a hardware store with some of the town loafers sitting on nearly every drum, now and then scratching a match on the steel side to light their pipes. The danger of this was ex - plained to the dealer who said they would be at once shipped back to the oil company. Safety First Another great source of danger to both life and property is the persistent practice of having the automobile tank filled </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 STATE FIRE COMMISSION while the engine is running. Numerous cases during the year have been called to our attention where explosions have oc - curred caused by a spark from the exhaust pipe igniting the gasoline. The oil companies are assisting in this work of education and the men in charge of the filling station owned and operated direct by the company is refusing to fill the auto - mobile tank while the engine is running and we hope to enlist their services in educating the small town dealer who while he runs a filling station has other business and only gives the gasoline business part of his time. Some progress at least has been made along this line and during the coming year we hope that it will become impossible anywhere in Nebraska to run the risk to both life and property that such carelessness is liable to bring about. New Law on Condemnation A new law was passed by the last legislature to cover a condition that existed in the condemnation of buildings where the owner was a non-resident of the state. Under the old law where complaint was made of some old dilapidated building asking for condemnation it was possible after giving the owner a notice and having made a personal examination of the pro - perty to condemn the same and have it removed without going into court but in the case of the non-resident there was no way to get service. Quite often the owner could not be located, sometimes the owners would be minor heirs with possibly a guardian in another state and nothing could be done and the menace from fire of the old buildings under such conditions continued to exist. The new law provides for filing a com - plaint in the distnct court and get service on the owner by publication for three weeks as in civil cases. Then the pro - perty can be condemned by order of the court, the buildings torn down and enough of the material sold to pay for the labor in wrecking the same. While this law has not been invoked up to this time it has had a very good effect. In some cases ■where the owners were non-residents of the state their attor - ney has notified us of their willingness to accept service in the ordinary way without taking the matter to court in order to save expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 5 View of 1513 and 1515 Webster St., Omaha, as building was being wrecked by order of the inspector. CONSERVATION AND FIRE PREVENTION AS VIEWED BY AN ADJUSTER The subject of Conservation and Fire Prevention was for years thought of only by the Fire Insurance Companies and naturally supposed by the unthinking public to be from a mercenary standpoint but when the United States got into the world war it became a very impoi'tant thought among our gov - ernment officials at Washington. The great need of the hour was for more production and less waste by fire thereby in - creasing the supply of the much needed food products and es - sential materials. It •was about this time that the National Board of Fire Underwriters stepped into the breach and offered their services to Uncle Sam, which the government very gladly accepted. In July, 1917, Conservation and Fire Prevention Associa- By W. C. Lyle of Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 STATE FIRE COMMISSION tions were organized in each of the grain growing states. Ne - braska was organized early in July and a force of sixty in - spectors started out to save the food of the state. Their duties were to inspect and make recommendations to all Ele - vator and Flour Mill owners as well as other large Food Ware - house owners and instruct them how to prevent fires. How well they did their work is shown by the fact that the state of Nebraska had suffered a loss of at least one elevator or mill for every week in the year and during the eight months fol - lowing this work not a single elevator or mill burned. The question is — How did they accomplish this result? Having been active in examining the work of the inspectors, I believe I am in a position to state that the principal cause of fires is POOR HOUSEKEEPING. What will cause a fire quicker than a pile of rubbish and the careless fellow with his cigarette stub and matches carelessly thrown around. Of course the wooden pulley in head and boot as well as defective A/iring and the careless handling of gasoline are prevalent causes of fires but to my mind the principal cause of fires in elevators is the accumulation of dust and rubbish or in other words, POOR HOUSEKEEPNG. I wish to leave the thought among the people of Nebraska that they must keep their Homes, Stores and Mills free from rubbish and this means the basement and garret as well as the rest of the building. Also it is a safe and sane idea to have an Approved Liquid Fire Extinguisher handy at all times. These extinguishers won't put out a fire after it has gotten well under way but it will do the business at the start. "Every fire is the same at the start" and 80% of them are preventable. I claim that if 1,500 mill and elevator men could put their properties in order and reduce the fire waste as they did dur - ing the war, then every property owner can do the same thing. Please bear in mind that as the fire waste reduces in this state, so will your fire insurance premiums reduce in the same pro - portion and not only will you save your money but the country will be benefitted by the saving in food products and other property. Viewing the subject of Fire Prevention from the stand- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 7 point of an adjuster, I would say that eight times out of ten after looking at the remains, I can readily see that if a little more care had been taken in HOUSEKEEPING the fire would not have occurred. The victim will claim that the fire stalled in a pile of rubbish down near the furnace or in a pile of old boxes in the back room or just outside the back door. This same careless fire probably not only destroyed the building where it occurred but spread to other buildings owned by an innocent party who probably was a GOOD HOUSEKEEPER and not deserving this calamity. It is therefore readily seen that the careless fire not only injures the building where it starts but the adjacent buildings as well and causes the country a great loss in material things, which by a little more care can be avoided. Keep your pre - mises free from rubbish and you will save yourself and your neighbor many of the disastrous losses that so frequently occur. INDIVIDUAL RESPONSIBILITY. I have always con - tended that the United States should enact laws that would make every individual, who has a careless fire which com - municates to other property, liable for the amount of damage sustained to the other property. Such laws are in force in Europe where the loss per capita is only 33 cents whereas in the United States it amounts to $3.00. If such laws were passed here we would have fewer careless fires. FIRE ESCAPE LAW In April, 1911, a fire escape law which had been passed by the previous legislature was signed by the governor. This law required that all school buildings of two or more stories in height should be properly equipped providing for the easy es - cape of children should a fire break out in the building. It is strange that after more than eight years that so many places had continued to violate this law. A special ef - fort has been made during the year to require the school buildings of this state to be safeguarded as the statute re - quires. Notices have been served on the board of education in a large number of cities and towns and we are pleased to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 STATE FIRE COMMISSION report that the following places have contracted for an es&gt; cape as required by law. Ashton Parochial School — Ashton. Burwood Hotel — Beatrice. Farmers &amp; Merchants National Bank — Fremont. Girls' Industrial School — Geneva. Masonic Hall — Geneva. G. A. Herzog (hotel) — Harvard. Kipp Cigar Factory — Hastings. 129 No. 12th Street (rooming house) — Lincoln. Sacred Heart Academy — Papillion. Parochial School — Petersburg. Ashton Alva Deweese Davenport Ohiowa Overton Alliance Dix Oaglalla Amherst Exeter Paxton Anselmo Beaver Crossing Elwood Elm Creek Ra&lt;?an Red Cloud Bristow Butte Franklin Guide Rock Reynolds Rosemont Brady Island Bassett Bartley Burnham Gering Gandy Haigler Hartington Rising City Stapleton Stratton Scottsbluff Broken Bow Huntley Seneca Chapman Jackson Table Rock Cotesfield Comstock Cairo Lexington Milford Madison Ulysses Venango Verdel Crab Orchard Milligan Wallace Ceresco Newman Grove Whitma". Deshler Oak Walthili Other Buildim ga </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 9 In order that moving picture booths might be made safe and at the same time comply with requirements of the In - spection Bureau the following specifications were adopted and published early in the year. Specifications for Moving Picture Machine Booth Frame. To be made of at least 1 1/2-inch by 1 1/2-inch by 14 -inch angle or tee irons, as follows: Four outside horizontal members at top and bottom. Four corner uprights. Intermediate uprights on sides and intermediate members on roofs, spaced at least every two feet. Doorway to be two feet wide by at least five Teet high, with an angle iron framing. All joints in frame to be made with 3-16 inch steel plates, to which each angle iron or tee iron shall be riveted or bolted by the use of at least two VL-in. bolts or rivets. All bolts or rivets to have flat heads, said heads always to be placed on exterior side of booth and properly, countersunk. SIZE. Each room, compartment, booth or enclosure in which a motion picture machine or device is installed, must be not less than seven (7) feet in height, with area of floor space varying in accordance with the number of machines or devices installed in such booths as follows : 1 Picture machine 6 feet x 8 feet 1 Picture machine and 1 stereopticon 9 ft. x 8 ft. 2 Picture machines &amp; 1 stereopticon 12 ft. x 8 ft. COVERING OF BOOTH. Sides and top of booth and main or entrance door shall be covered with hard asbestos boards or asbestos building lumber, of at least Vi-mcn thick - ness, or their equivalent, or with steel or galvanized sheet iron of not less than No. 20 U. S. gage. The asbestos, or its equivalent, shall be so cut and arranged that vertical joints be - tween boards shall always come over an angle or tee iron, to which it shall be securely fastened by means of proper bolts and nuts, spaced not more than six inches apart. The sheet metal shall be so cut and arranged that joints shall always come over a member, be overlapped and bolted or riveted to </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 STATE FIRE COMMISSION such member ; bolts or rivets to be spaced not over three inches on centers. FLOORING. Floor shall be made of two parts, an upper and a lower floor. Lower floor may be made of wood, 7-8-inch minimum thickness, supported on lower leg of horizontal angle irons. Resting on this floor shall be a floor made of hard asbestos board, asbestos building lumber of 3-8-inch minimum thickness, or an equally good non-combustible material. OPENINGS. There shall be not more than two openings in the booth for each machine — one for observation by the operator and one for operation of the machine. Opening for machine shall be not more than six inches high and twelve inches long. Opening for operator shall be not more than four inches wide or more than twelve inches high. The two openings for each machine shall be provided with gravity doors, constructed of metal not less than 3-16-inch in thick - ness ; when closed they shall overlap the openings at least two inches on all sides, and be arranged to slide, without binding, in properly constructed grooves; said doors to be held open normally by use of a fine combustible cord fastened to a fusible link which melts at a temperature of 160 degrees F., the whole so arranged that the door may be easily released and closed by hand. The main or entrance door shall be hung on at least three heavy hinges and arranged to close against a substantial metal rabbet. The door shall also be provided with a substantial spring which will keep it closed tightly. SHELVES. All shelves, furniture and fixtures within the booth shall be constructed of incombustible material. VENTILATION. Booths shall be provided with a venti - lating inlet in each of three sides ; said inlets to be fifteen inches long and three inches high, the lower side of same to be not more than three inches above floor level. Said inlets shall be covered on the outside by a wire netting of not greater than 1-8-inch mesh, to be firmly secured to the asbestos boards or metal by means of iron strips and screws or rivets, and on inside by gravity doors, arranged to slide in properly con - structed grooves, and which, when closed, shall overlap ven- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE FIRE COMMISSION H tilator openings at least two inches on all sides ; said doors to be held open normally by use of a fine combustible cord fasten - ed to a fusible link which melts at a temperature of 160 F., so arranged that the doors may be easily released and closed by hand. Near the center of the top of the booth shall be a circular opening of not less than ten inches in diameter, the upper side of said opening to be provided with an iron flange, same to be securely fastened to the tee irons supporting the roof. Se - curely fastened to this flange shall be a metallic vent pipe of not less than ten inches in diameter, said pipe leading to the outside of the building or to a special incombustible vent flue ; all parts of vent pipe to be at least six inches from any com - bustible material. For the comfort of the operator it is important to provide for a constant current of air to pass outward through the opening or vent flue at the rate of not less than thirty cubic feet per minute when the booth is in use. BRICK, TILE OR CONCRETE BOOTHS. If the room, compartment, booth or enclosure is constructed of brick, tile or concrete, it shall have walls not less in thickness than eight inches, except that if reinforced concrete is used the thickness need be only four inches. The ventilation and general ar - rangement of the booth and the protection of openings shall conform with the requirements of above. PORTABLE BOOTHS. Portable booths shall not be used m any theater or public hall in which a permanent booth has been or is installed, but shall be used only for the temporary one-night exhibition of motion pictures in places of assembl - age, such as halls belonging to commercial organizations, churches, schools, etc., where it is deemed impracticable to in - stall permanent booths made in accordance with the above specifications. MACHINES. The motion picture machines must be se - curely fastened to the floor to prevent accidental overturning or moving of same. A shutter must be placed in front of the condenser, so arranged as to be automatically closed when film is stationery. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 STATE FIRE COMMISSION No artificial light shall be used in any room, compartment or booth in which a motion picture machine is installed ex - cept that produced by electricity. All electric wiring must be brought into the booth in iron conduits. One light will be al - lowed for each machine and one for the rewinding bench, but all such lights shall be provided with wire guards, and rein - forced cord shall be used for pendant purposes. If house lights are controlled from within the booth, an additional emergency control must be provided near the main exit and kept at all times in good condition. No films shall be exposed in the booth at the same time other than the one film in process of transfer to or from the machine or from the upper to lower magazine, or in process of rewinding. A separate metal case, made without solder, shall be provided for each film when the same is not in the magazine or in process of rewinding, said films to be kept in these cases. No material of a combustible nature shall be stored within any booth except the films needed for one day's operation. At least two standard hand chemical fire extinguishers shall be provided, one inside the booth and located in an ac - cessible place within easy reach of the operator, the other located outside of the booth near the door to same. Neither smoking nor the keeping nor use of matches shall be permitted in any booth, room, compartment or enclosure where a motion picture machine is installed. Each machine, while in operation, shall be in charge of an experienced operator. The entrance door to the motion picture machine booth shall be kept closed, but not locked, when an audience is in the building. NOTICE. Doors and exits in every theater, moving pic - ture gallery or other place of amusement where combustible films over ten inches in length are used there shall be not less than one exit 3 feet wide by 6 feet 6 inches high, and where the seating capacity shall be more than 200 there shall be two exits, which shall in all cases be located at the opposite end of </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 13 the room from whence is operated the operating booth. In every theater or other place of amusement above the first floor there shall be at least one outside exit of not less than 3 feet in width and 6 feet and 6 inches in height, and for every 300 persons for which seating capacity is provided, on each floor of said building, there shall be one additional outside exit of above dimensions, all of said doors to open outward and to remain unlocked at all times during a performance or when there are more than twenty persons in said theater or place of amusement. 1316 Pacific St., Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATE FIRE COMMISSION C. R. McCotter of Omaha, member of the Conservation and Fire Prevention Association at our request has prepared the following article on FIRE PREVENTION IN COUNTRY ELEVATORS For a good many years there has been a strong effort on the part of many individuals to bring about better construction in buildings, and more care, that the criminal fire waste of the country could be checked. In some individual lines the work has met with fairly good success, but the carelessness of the great majority has not been brought home to them forcibly enough so that the results are not what could have been wish - ed. At the outbreak of the war it was soon recognized that if this country was to measure up to its full responsibility, and be able to render its best services, that the needless waste caused by our heavy fire losses must be met. If a factory was destroyed by fire it was of as much benefit to the enemy as if they were able to destroy its products on the seas with their submarines ; if a large elevator filled with wheat was destroyed by fire it meant as much to them as winning a battle. There - fore, every man, if through, his thoughtlessness, carelessness o ' shiftlessness was instrumental in destroying property by lire, he became an ally of the enemy. It will readily be seen with this condition that the safeguarding of the country's food products was of most vital concern. It was absolutely neces - sary that this should be brought home to every individual in any way connected with the handling of these products. It was at this state that the government accepted the services of the fire insurance companies that had been tendered to them, and through their efforts Conservation Associations were formed in the different states. The Conservation As - sociation of Nebraska was one of the leaders in this work. Most of the insurance companies operating in the state fur - nished experienced men, and a careful inspection of all food handling properties was made without expense to the govern - ment. It was then that we woke up to the fact that the country elevator was the nation's store house, and the men in charge of the properties began to feel their importance in the great task that was laid out before us. The loss record in the past, on elevators in the state had </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 15 not been good. It was particularly heavy during the first six months of 1917. The Conservation work was gotten under way in July of that year and the fire loss on this class for the balance of the year was practically nothing. Early in 1918 there was evidence that we were getting into our old habits, as fires again became very numerous on this class of property, but not nearly so heavy as in the same period in 1917. Again the Conservation inspectors made a thorough inspection of the elevators, and arousing the men in charge of them to their responsibility, and again the losses for the balance of the year became very nominal. The same condition applies pretty much to the year 1919. While the armistice had been signed the need of food products had never been greater, so it was felt that the work should be continued and a permanent or - ganization known as the "Conservation and Fire Prevention Association of Nebraska" was organized, with the intent of keeping up this work in the future. It is very evident from the above record, that when we were aroused to our duty, and felt that we were serving our country, we were careful to see that no careless act of ours should bring on disaster, but the increase of losses a few months following the inspection in each year, demonstrates the fact that we have not become thoroughly enough imbued with this fire prevention spirit to keep up the good work without some - thing to spur us on to action. During this reconstruction period our duty is just as plain, and it is just as necessary that continued efforts to prevent fire be made now as during the time our boys were fighting in France. It is easier to accom - plish this if we have the experience of the past to go on and know just what the vital points are. Practically one-half of the elevator fires are started on the outside, and a very large proportion of these are due to lightning and railroad sparks and both of these hazards can be practically eliminated by covering the building with iron, connecting the roof with the sides and grounding the sides. In addition to overcoming the railroad spark hazard it gives very good lightning protection. Experience has also shown that buildings properly protected with lightning rods are practically immune. The railroad spark hazard is unusually </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 STATE FIRE COMMISSION "HOME SWEET HOME" 1516-18 Burt St., Omaha. Has been torn down by order since photo was taken. severe at a time like the recent coal strike when anything that will bum is used. Another outside hazard that has caused the destruction of a good many elevators has been due to tramps. Doors are left open or other openings so that the elevator is easy of ac - cess, and due to the location of many elevators it makes a good harboring place. Certainly with a little care this could be overcome by securely locking doors and windows and seeing that other openings are properly protected. Of the fires originating on the inside the large portion are due to friction, which, of course, can come about in numerous ways. Proper oiling and careful inspection of shafting and seeing that all machinery is kept in proper running order will reduce these fires to the minimum. It is not at all un - common in inspecting to find bearings that have not been suf - ficiently oiled, and that others are running warm due to the shaft getting out of alignment. We are usually told that it is the first occurrence of the kind in a dozen years, but, strange </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 17 as it may seem, the losses on elevators where the manager boasts of never having had a hot box, are heavier than on the elevators where the manager reports having had some bearing trouble but it had been given prompt attention. It is the watched hazard that does not cause trouble. In recent years a good many flour mills and large terminal elevators have been equipped with sprinklers, and the large number of fires that have been started in these plants, and held under control by the sprinklers so that the cause of the rire could be absolutely established, have demonstrated the fact that most of these fires originate in the elevator leg. There have always been a good many fires where it was very difficult to trace the exact cause, but suspicion pointed to the leg. With the evidence we now have of these leg fires in the sprinklered properties, it is fair to assume that most of these unknown fires originate here. What is the solution ? There is no question but that the installation of non-chokeable boots and properly constructed heads tend to reduce these fires, but the fact remains that under the most favorable conditions the hazard is a severe one and it is believed that the solution is in installing metal legs. Then in all probability if a fire does get started it will not gain any headway. Without doubt, the elevator leg is the weak point, from the fire prevention standpoint, in a country elevator, and when its hazard is over - come a long step will have been taken in fire prevention. Spontaneous combustion is usually given as the cause when no other can be figured out. There is but little excuse for fires from this cause if accumulation of dirt and rubbish is not allowed and the habit of throwing oily waste in out of way places is stopped. When oily waste is taken to stuff up holes, and then the whole thing covered with paper and other trash, and conditions become ripe so that a fire ensues, cer - tainly the owner is not deserving of sympathy. A hazard along this line that has developed in the last two or three years is in coal. This is something that is a little harder to meet, and when a very large amount is stored up early in the season it should be watched very carefully. A fire was discovered in a Nebraska elevator on Christ - mas Eve and on investigation it was found that this was due </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 STATE FIRE COMMISSION to an exhaust pipe which the elevator owner felt was perfectly safe, but it is very evident that the proper clearance had not been made and fire resulted. It was only by good fortune that the manager made a visit to the elevator after supper and discovered the fire and was able to put it out. Had it not been for this, while the town was having a celebration on Christmas Eve an elevator full of food products would have gone up in flames while children in the near East were on the verge of starvation. Defective electrical installations are next on the list. It would seem that with all the publicity that fires of this nature receive there would be no difficulty in getting electrical in - stallations properly installed, but with few exceptions, the only standard electrical installations in the state are in cities that have strict building codes and see that they are lived up to. The solution for this problem is for all property owners to employ only competent electricians to install all work and make any changes, and get the electricians enlisted in this Fire Prevention work so that they will feel a personal respon - sibility for their work, and that they will realize that when property is destroyed due to their neglect, that they are not measuring up to the responsibility of a citizen. A law mak - ing it necessary for all electricians to pass an examination, showing his fitness for this work, would help. Heating and lighting have always furnished their share of losses. If carefulness were to replace carelessness these fires would be held down to the minimum. Chimneys should be carefully inspected each fall, and if found in poor condition, should be rebuilt. DON'T take chances. An inspector may not be handy to put the fire out as was the case in an elevator in December, when he found that a fire was getting under head - way due to a defective chimney. The hazards that we have enumerated above pretty well cover the common causes of frame elevator fires, and if each individual in charge of property will see that the proper pre - cautions are taken, there is no question as to what the out - come will be. We have gone too long on the theory that the insurance company pays the loss. They simply collect the money from the many, to pay the few, but nothing can restore the burned structure. It is lost. A fire is a drain on our </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 19 i-esources and the sooner we realize this fact the better it will be for us. During the last few years there has been a tendency to use other than wood for building purposes. The trouble, how - ever, is that a false sense of security has prevailed when the structure was built of so-called fireproof material. In many cases no attention is given to the interior, and wood legs and other hazardous features have been added, so that the possi - bility of fire in plants of this construction is always present. Another feature is that this false sense of security has resulted in no fire fighting appliances being supplied. Every elevator should be provided with water barrels on each floor, and chemical extinguishers of the tetra-chloride type should be placed near each motor if electric power and one in the engine room if gasoline power is used. All concrete elevators are now being built, and this is to be commended, but the same conditions as to a false sense of security apply to these plants. A feeling has grown up that a concrete structure is indestruct - ible. I know a firm operating two elevators, one frame and the other concrete. The manager is alive to the fire hazard in the frame plant and sees to it that every precaution is taken to prevent fire, but this same manager feels that his concrete elevator is immune, gives no attention to the fire hazards and backs up his judgment by not carrying a dollar of insurance. This elevator is always dirty and ill kept. No fire protection is provided, or any of the ordinary precautions taken. It is hard to believe that both plants are under the same manage - ment, but it does illustrate the point that when it is felt that the fire hazard has been eliminated that lack of care prevails. What awful consequences follow this line of reasoning was demonstrated in the Murray disaster at Kansas City a few months ago. This elevator was a so-called fireproof plant. No wood was used in its construction and it was thought that no fire could occur. The facts are, however, that a fire did occur. The elevator was practically destroyed by the ex - plosion that ensued, and many lives were lost. The probabil - ities are that had this been a frame elevator that conditions would not have been allowed to become such that this disaster could have taken place. It must not be overlooked that due to the compactness and rigidness of concrete elevators that </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 STATE FIRE COMMISSION the explosion hazard is greater than in frame plants, and that it is even more necessary that they be kept clean, that electri - cal work be as carefully installed and machinery as well cared for. Many times we have to be forced to do things that are for our own good. It is my opinion that when the present agita - tion for making the person responsible that starts a fire, has been written into our laws, we will all be benefitted to such an extent that we will wonder why such action was not taken years ago. If, by throwing a lighted match into some dry grass which is ignited and eventually causes the destruction of an elevator filled with grain, the party is held personally responsible for it. it is very certain that the careless throwing of matches in that vicinity will cease to be a common habit. A few examples of this kind and Fire Prevention would become an established fact. It has been said that if each person keeps his own door yard clean that we will have a clean street. If each individual will see to it that no act of his causes a fire, the $300,000,000 annual fire waste of this country would soon show such a re - duction that a goodly portion of the interest on the Liberty Bonds could be met by the saving that would result. We have made more headway along fire prevention lines during the years of the war than in any like period of time, and the facts are that we were working under handicaps that we do not have in normal times. During this reconstruction period we are in better position to make a fire prevention record after the experience that we have had, and it is hoped that we will measure up to the opportunity. The great war has proven, beyond doubt, that when the United States sets out to do a thing she does it, but at times we seem to be slow in getting started. This is the condition in reference to Fire Prevention. If we can get burned into the mind of each in - dividual, that we burn up in this country $750,000 worth of property a day, and that no country, however rich, can stand a constant drain of such gigantic proportions, we will then take the necessary means to stop this needless waste. The country elevator owners can well be leaders in this work. They have done well in the past. They should do better in the future. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 21 A fire menace in the business part of Seward which \va later removed. AN UNFORTUNATE DECISION Nearly two years ago a fire occurred in this state con - nected with which were many suspicious circumstances, kero - sene was placed in numerous places about the building in pails and cans, and the fire broke out at the usual time for such fires, about two or three o'clock in the morning. It happened that the fire department was on the job and reached the property m time to extinguish the blaze before it reached any great proportions. All of the evidence showing that someone had planned to burn the property was noted by the fire chief. He reported the matter to the gentleman who was state fire mar - shal at that time and an investigation was started. From in - formation they gathered it was learned that while only a limited amount of insurance had been carried up until two days before the fire, an additional amount, nearly three times the amount formerly carried was added to the amount then in force. After having had the property invoiced it was dis - covered that it was insured for more than three times its value. The parties were at once placed under arrest and after a pre - liminary hearing, were bound over to the district court. condemned and </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 STATE FIRE COMMISSION When the case was tried in district court, one of the parties accused was aquitted and the case against the other party dismissed. One of the parties commenced suit against the state fire marshal charging false arrest and slander and a verdict was rendered giving them judgment against the state fire marshal. This court decision came soon after the be - ginning of the year 1919, and has had the effect of discourag - ing prosecutions in cases where suspicions might point to some parties in connection with fires that were at least of question - able origin. The present state fire marshal feels that if this decision is allowed to stand that it will tend to lessen the number of arrests and may possibly be the means of having no arrests made at all as under the circumstances we are not inclined to do any official act that will require the small accumulation of property that we have gathered together after years of labor, to be held liable for doing a public duty. If this is the atti - tude taken by the courts a state fire marshal would hardly feel justified in causing the arrest of anyone and certainly while we hold this position we shall only assist in the prosecution of alleged criminals where interested parties are willing to sign the complaint. THAT OLD LIVERY BARN About the worst fire menace that the officials have to deal with today is the old time livery barn. The general use of automobiles has put the horse livery business off the map. From an insurance standpoint any business which is not pro - fitable is not a good risk to insure. From the standpoint of fire prevention these old livery barns are a menace to the town in which they are situated. They are not built so that they are suitable for any other line of business and soon become badly in need of repair and are usually a rendezvous for tramps and a gathering place for boys with the cigaret habit. Prob - ably the only reason that more of these buildings do not bum down is the fact that most insurance campanies have cancelled off. We have been making a special effort during the entire year to rid the state of this menace and have succeeded in a large number of cases. More, however are marked for the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 23 slaughter and the campaign will go on until such old wrecks are torn down and the possibility of a fire in such worthless property is eliminated. FIRE FIGHTING EQUIPMENT The city officials in far too many towns fail to appreciate the necessity of properly supplying the volunteer fire company with up to date equipment. We are pleased to note there are some exceptions to this rule. Without having had direct re - ports from the fire departments we have learned that Howells, Bethany, College View and David City have purchased good chemical trucks. The department at Hastings put in a new $10,000 fire truck early in the year and it will no doubt prove one of the best investments that the city of Hastings ever made. FIRE LOSSES DURING 1919 The total fire loss for 1919 is as follows : The above table gives the amount of fire loss in this state for each year since the records were kept in this department. Number of Fires Loss Lincoln 136 $ 103,034.23 Omaha 436 243,768.53 Balance of state 387 1,076,140.84 Total 959 $1,422,943.62 Fire Losses for 10 Years 1910 $2,181,058.00 1911 1,788,123.30 1912 _ 2,251,774.33 1913 1,715,676.10 1914 1,873,071.25 1915 1,789,269.00 1916 1,908,297.46 1917 2,895,935.00 1918 2,158,204.81 1919 1,422,943.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 STATE FIRE COMMISSION It will be noticed that the loss for 1919 is the least of any of these years amounting to 34% less than the loss for 1918. CAUSES OF FIRES Number Per Cent Ashes, hot 14 .0145 Bonfires 7 .0073 Boilers, defective 6 .0062 Candles 6 .0062 Chimneys, defective 46 .0479 Cigars or cigarets 46 .0479 Communicated 20 .0208 Electric or gas irons 14 .0145 Electric wiring, defective 49 .0510 Fireworks 2 .002 Fire place, defective 2 .002 Furnace, defective 44 .0458 Gas 9 .0093 Gasoline and Kerosene 101 .1053 Grease 6 .0062 Incendiary, presumably 10 .0104 Lightning 8 .008 Matches 79 .0823 Moving picture machine 4 .0040 Smoking meat 4 .0040 Smoke stack 5 .0052 Sparks from chimney 168 .1751 Sparks from engine 37 .0385 Spontaneous combustion 41 .0427 Stove 50 .0520 Unclassified 14 .0145 Unknown 167 .1741 Total 959 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 25 Inspector Hayduk standing at rear of a dwelling 424 No. 14th St., Omaha. INVESTIGATION OF INCENDIARY FIRES In the same neighborhood in northern Illinois where the present State Fire Marshal of Nebraska lived when a "bare - foot boy with cheeks of tan" there lived another lad whose name was Frank R. Morgaridge. The writer came to Ne - braska so many years ago that it is hard to remember exactly the number. Frank Morgaridge grew up in the old home town, was later for a number of years connected with the Il - linois State Fire Marshal's department and in recent years has been at the head of the arson committee of the National Board of Fire Underwriters in New York City. At our request he has contributed the following article on the subject as indicated in the headline. It lays down the principles to be followed so plainly in making an investigation that it is worth using in our annual report. The article is as follows: Webster defines an incendiary as one who sets fire to a building or property of another. There is a class of fires, and this class of by no means small, which is set by persons who </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 STATE FIRE COMMISSION are mentally unbalanced and known as pyromaniacs. Such persons are not morally responsible and motive cannot be im - puted to their acts. They belong in hospitals or asylums. The records of the National Board of Fire Underwriters show that during the year 1918 there were 510 convictions for arson and burning in this country. This does not include convictions in three or four states from which returns have not been received. The motives which actuated the fires for which these convictions were obtained have been sub-divided as follows: To Conceal Evidence of Another Crime 30 Revenge or Spite 97 97 Pyromania and Other Forms of Insanity 181 To Defraud the Insurer 202 202 This list does not include juvenile court cases covering those fires set by juveniles through a spirit of malicious mis - chief, weak-mindedness or a mania for excitement. There are more fires set to conceal crime than is indicated by the number of convictions showing that as the motive be - cause prosecutors usually prefer to prosecute for the crime the incendiary sought to conceal than to prosecute for arson. Arson has always been considered a most serious crime, classed in the first degree carried with it the death penalty. The man who sets fire to his own or another's property in a thickly conjested district always jeopardizes the life and property of hundreds of people. He is a serious menace to the community and every effort ought to be made to apprehend him and bring him to justice. There appears to be a universal idea that "Arson" and "Burning to Defraud :&gt; are difficult crimes to prosecute suc - cessfully. This is probably due to the fact that arson is a difficult crime to investigate owing to the fact that evidence of the crime itself is frequently destroyed by the fire. To de - velop a case of arson and justify a probability of conviction theie are four things that must be established in order to prove the guilt of the assured beyond a reasonable doubt. 1. THE FIRE. It is necessary to introduce evidence thai the fire actually occurred at a certain time at a place within the jurisdiction of the court. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE FIRE COMMISSION ■27 2. ORIGIN-INCENDIARY. Direct and positive evidence of some kind must be introduced to establish the fact that the fire was of incendiary origin. Every fire is presumed to be of accidental origin and it is necessary for the state to introduce positive evidence, to overcome this presumption. Sometimes the incend ary origin of a fire can be shown by direct evidence such as the saturation of the premises with kerosene, gaso - line or some other inflammable compound. It can be estab - lished by showing that there were two or three fires which were separate and distinct and having no connection with an - other. In the investigation of a fire care should always be taken to ascertain its character, in what part of the building it originated, how it burned, and other facts and circumstances which may be suggestive of its origin. The appearance of the interior of the building is important, as this frequently shows whether the fire was the result of accident or design. If articles of furniture have been so arranged as to retard the work of the firemen, or if evidence is found that a considerable part of the furniture, fixtures or stock had been removed pie - shows whether the fire was the result of accident or design. If the investigation shows that such articles were removed previous to the fire the importance of asceitaining their where - abouts and having them identified and photographed cannot be overestimated. It sometimes happens that the remains of a plant arranged by the incendiary to cause or accelerate the fire is found in the building after it has been extinguished. It is highly important in the event that candles, oily rags or things of that character are discovered, that they be left ex - actly as found until they can be photographed. It is extreme - ly important that great care be exercised in handling 1 such articles as candles, oily bottles or other things of this character, which were evidently handled by the incendiary. Such articles should always be carefully examined for evidence of finger prints. It is frequently important to eliminate insofar as possible, all of the accidental causes which might be put forward by the accused as the probable cause of the fire. It is therefore, highly important as to inspecting the heating and electrical </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 STATE FIRE COMMISSION equipment of the building in order to be able to prove that the fire was not of accidental origin. All accidental causes should be eliminated insofar as possible. This should be done be - cause a fire may be so suspicious as to indicate the act of an incendiary. In the case of State vs. Simonson, 107 Cal. 347, the court said : "It is quite possible, however, to have a build - ing burned under such suspicious circumstances as to exclude the notion of fire being the result of accident or natural causes. A building may be bumed under such suspicious circumstances as to indicate the act of an incendiary and thus the Corpus Delicti established and the door opened for the defendant's ad - missions and confessions." 3. MOTIVE. It is extremely important, although not ab - solutely necessary, to establish a positive motive in the trial of a case of arson. The motive for the crime may be revenge, the desire to destroy evidence of some other crime, or an at - tempt to defraud the insurer. Over-insurance is not always necessary to prompt an attempt at burning to defraud. Straightened financial circumstances or a desire to change location or some other such motive may be sufficient to prompt the man criminally inclined to attempt a quick sale to some insurance company. It is quite important in all cases of arson in which a de - sire to defraud the insurer is the motive, that the value of the property destroyed be determined as accurately as possible, in cases where this property is not burned out of sight an in - ventory of it should be taken in order to fix its value. This inventory should be taken by some person who can qualify before the court as an expert on values. 4. PROOF OP GUILT. It is necessary to show by facts or circumstances or both that the party under suspicion could and actually did set the fire in question. After the "Corpus Delicti" has been established in an arson trial every fact or circumstances tending to show any light on the case is usually admissible as evidence. Do not under-estimate the importance of interviewing the party who is suspected of having caused the fire. In the trial of a criminal case the defendant is always accorded the privi - lege Of being heard and in the investigation of a crime an op- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 29 pdrtunity should be given to the suspected party to give his version of the matter, his theory as to the origin of the file, his whereabouts at the time it occurred, and anything else which is pertinent in your search for the truth in the matter. The demeanor, conduct and acts of the person suspected of the crime, such as attempt flight, a desire to elude discovery, and anxiety to conceal the crime or evidence of it, are always important as indicative of a guilty mind. It is important to investigate every incriminating circumstance tending to show that the fire was of incendiary origin and that the accused was connected therewith, such as his acts, conduct and where - abouts at or near the time of the fire. Any act of preparation, or the possession by the accused of the means or instruments by which the fire was set, or his possession of goods proved to have been in the building im - mediately before the fire, or proof that he removed goods from the building immediately before it was burned is always im - portant and admissible as evidence against him. While it is usually impossible to introduce evidence of other fires on the part of the accused, it is frequently advisable to have this evidence available in order to establish motive, intent, absence of accident, or connected crime, etc., and to establish this such evidence is frequently admissible. FIRES INVESTIGATED We have been called upon during the yea»t^p^ce investi - gations of what were reported to be suspicious^Kfrcurh&amp;tances in connection with 23 &amp;es. In probably the majority of these fires very little evidence^ could be secured and none that would seem to indicate that they were of incendiary origin. In a few cases there would seem to be no question but that the fire was incendiary but insufficient evidence could be secured to iustify the arrest of anyone with the exception of the Neb: aska City hotel fire. FRONTIER HOTEL FIPE At 8:30 a. m. on the morning of July 13, 1919 fire was dis - covered in the Frontier Hotel, Nebraska City, Nebraska. This building is a four story structure owned and operated by </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Frank Popel, Sr., who was out of town at the time the fire oc - curred. The fire was extinguished by the fire department and an investigation followed which resulted in disclosing the fact that it was of incendiary origin. Separate and distinct fires were found in separate rooms, possibly eighteen or more. The carpet and floors had been saturated with kero - sene. Kerosene cans, bottles and pitchers containing the same fluid were found in the various parts of the building. There was about $30,000 insurance on the hotel proper and $4,000 covering contents of the hotel. On the night of the fire ten people had registered at the hotel and were assign - ed to rooms on the second floor. The fires all were found on the third and fourth floors. Immediately after the fire Frank Popel, Jr., who was in active charge in the absence of his father, was placed under arrest for arson, later on the proprietor, Frank Popel, Sr., was also arrested charged with burning to defraud. The cases are still pending. FRONTIER HOTEL ROOM Photo showing room in Frontier Hotel, where fire burned papers back of commode, blackened wall paper up to ceiling. Drawers of dresser and commode are partly open and filled with crumpled newspapers. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 31 John C. Trouton, city fire warden of Omaha, reports that a fire at 4220 South 39th Street, Omaha, August 30, 1919, re - sulted in Joseph Zyck being bound over on September 2nd, 1919. The case is still pending. He also reports at 15161/2 Johns Street, Omaha, that a fire occured on May 2, 1919 in connection with which Arthur Newland was bound over on May 21st, 1919, pleaded guilty on November 6, 1919 and was given 90 days in the county jail. CONDEMNATION REPORT Believing that one of the best ways to prevent a fire is to remove the cause we have had in mind during the year that the dilapidated old fire traps that exist in nearly all towns in the state, should be removed. A great deal of work has been done along this line and during the year 1919, 282 complaints were filed in this office asking for condemnation. In some in - stances the complaints were filed knowing that the repairs were all that was necessary but believing that the only way to accomplish that result would be to ask for condemnation. After cases of this kind had been filed the owner invariably would agree to repair which was the object in having the com - plaint filed. There has, however been 120 buildings actually torn down and removed. This means that if each one of these buildings had been placed on the end of a twenty-five foot lot it would have made a solid row of buildings more than three-fourths of a mile long. One thing is certain there will be no fires start in the 120 buildings that have been removed. 35 buildings have been repaired according to orders issued in this office and 7 complaints were dismissed. There are still pending complaints on 120 buildings, a few of which we have been unable to examine personally but a large number of these have been condemned and the time limit for removal has not yet expired. These buildings were located in all parts of the state, the largest number of buildings wrecked in any one city or town being in Omaha. The city authorities in all cases have given us splendid support in our efforts to clean and make better their town. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 STATE FIRE COMMISSION FIRE PREVENTON BOOKLET About the best material that has come to our attention for use in the schools along the line of fire prevention is a little booklet prepared for the United States Bureau of Education by the National Board of Fire Underwriters. It contains nearly 100 pages and is illustrated on every page giving the students the benefit of the best posted writers in the world on fire prevention. 5,000 of these books were ordered by this department and have been nearly all placed in the hands of teachers in the different schools of the state. The benefits derived from work of this kind may not be in evidence at once but the instruction given the little ones will be of lasting benefit to them both as to prevention of fires and what to do in case of fire. INSURANCE TAX In Nebraska as well as a number of other states, the funds raised for the work in the fire marshal's office has been by tax levied upon each and every insurance company doing business within the state with the exception of farm mutual insurance companies or companies doing an exclusive farm business. The tax in this state varies with the amount of business writ - ten by the different companies. The amount raised in 1919 by the three-eights of one per cent tax, amounted to a little over $18,000. We are strongly opposed to money being collected from the insurance companies for this purpose believing it to be wrong in principle and detrimental to the successful prosecu - tion of arson cases in court. There is in this state what is known as the Railway Commission but the funds to cover the expense of the same are never collected from the railroads. Any system of gathering funds for the conduct of any depart - ment of the state which tends to put that department under obligation to the corporations contributing the same is wrong and the law should be changed arranging for funds to be raised in some other way. If a complaint is made to this office alleging suspicious circumstances in connection with any fire a man connected with the office is at once sent out to make an investigation. After </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 33 carefully gathering all the evidence possible, if it is in such quantity and of sufficient value to warrant an arrest the party suspicioned is brought into court. His lawyers will at once raise the plea that the millionaire insurance companies have paid into the funds for our use a large amount of money for the purpose of railroading the poor fellow accused of this crime to the penitentiary. Human nature is about the same every - where and the sympathy of the jury goes out to the accused and it is mighty hard to get by with a conviction. While the amount of the tax on insurance companies for the benefit of this work has been small raising not nearly as much money as could be profitably spent in this work it ought to be raised in some other manner than a tax upon the insur - ance companies who, by the way, make no objection to its pay - ment, but the fact remains that coming from that source it is an actual handicap in the successful prosecution of cases of this kind. INSPECTION WORK Believing that thorough inspections will tend to reduce the fire waste, we have made a special effort during the year to push this part of the work. More than 24,000 inspections have been made in the 374 towns and cities that have been in - spected. More than 13,000 minor orders have been issued. This number does not include the condemnation orders or re - pair orders issued in connection with the complaints on dilapi - dated buildings. The following table will tell its own story in connection with the inspection work during the year 1919, showing orders issued : Kerosene and gasoline 241 Clean up 5,854 Chimney 816 Electric wiring 2,793 Metal, asbestos and stove 1,435 Red light and fire escape 420 Miscellaneous 1,104 Repair building 260 Recommend condemnation 182 Total orders issued 13,105 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Total inspections made 24,497 Fires investigated 24 Building's condemned and in process of condemnation 282 There were 4704 inspections made in Omaha during the year. A total of 1840 minor orders were issued by the in - spector. Everyone of these orders were absolutely complied with as the inspector made a return trip in every instance and has certified that all orders were complied with. DEATHS CAUSED BY FIRE DURING 1919 On January 3rd, 1919, a two-year-old boy was burned to death at Grand Island. Vernon Coombs, a twelve-year-old boy was killed by an explosion of an empty steel gasoline drum at Benedict in January. Nels Anderson burned to death in an Omaha fire February 28th. Robert Reynolds died from burns received in a rooming house fire on March 30th at Omaha. Elda Milka, 13 and brother Aaron, aged 5, burned to death in a fire at Beatrice, April 27th from starting fire in the kitchen stove with kerosene. William Thavinet died from bums received in a fire at Grand Island on May 8th. Mrs. O. B. Peterson burned to death in a dwelling house fire at Hooper on September 1st. Mrs. Harry Wullbrandt of Exeter burned to death Sep - tember 11th caused by her clothing catching fire from an oil cook stove. Amelia Taute, 17-year-old girl of Hayland burned to death September 15th while pouring kerosene in the kitchen stove, where there was already a fire. Miss Clara Welsh of Horace was burned to death on Sep - tember 8th. She was generating a gasoline flatiron which exploded covering her clothing with oil. Six of these deaths were due to the careless use of gasoline or kerosene. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 35 TOWNS INSPECTED The following is a list of cities and towns that have been inspected this year. Figures following the name of the town indicate the number of times the town was inspected. The following the figure indicates the last inspection was in- complete on January 1st, 1920. Adams Belden Carleton Ainsworth Belgrade Carroll (2) Cedar Blutfs Cedar Rapids Central City Ceresco Bellwood Albion Alexandria Belvidere Alda Benedict (2) Benkelman Allen (2) Bennet Alliance Chadron Chapman Chappell Chester Clarkson Alma Bennington Amherst Anoka Bertram! Bethany Big Springs Anselmo Ansley Bladen Clay Center Cody Arapahoe Bla ; r Bloomfield (2) Coleridge (2) Columbus Arcadia Arlington Arnold Bloom ; ncrton Blue Hill College View Comstock Blue Springs Ashland Concord Cordova Cortland Cotesfield Ashton Boelus Atkinson Arburn Bostwick Bradshaw (2) Brainard Aurora Bridgeport Crab Orchard Craig Avoca Axtell Broken Bow Bancroft Bruning Crawford Creighton Creston Brunswick Barnston Burchard Bartley Bassett Burwell Crete Battle Creek Butte Crofton (2) Culbertson Curtis Byron Bayard Beatrice Cairo Beaver City Callaway Dakota City (2) Danbury Beaver Crossing Cambridge Campbell Davenport Beemer </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Davey Funk Howells David City Dawson Gandy Genoa Gering Gibbon Giltner Goehner Gordon Hubbard (2) Hubbell Deshler Deweese DeWitt Dickens Diller Humboldt Humphrey Huntley Imperial Inavale (2) Indianola Dix Gothenburg (2) Giafton Dixon (2) Dodge Jackson (2) Jansen Grand Island Grant Doniphan (2) Dorchester Eddyville Juniata (2) Kearney Greeley Greenwood Gresham Guide Rock Haigler Kenesaw (2) Kennard Edgar Edison Elba Kimball Laurence Laurel (2) Lebanon Leigh Elgin Hampton Harbine Hardy Elkhom Elm Creek (2) Elmwood Harrison Lexington (2) Liberty Elwood Hartington (2) Harvard (2) Hastings (2) Havelock Lincoln Lindsey Linwood Emerson (2) Endicott Eustis Hay Springs Heartwell Lodge Pole Long Pine Loomis Exeter (2) Fairbury Fairfield Hebron Hemmingford Henderson Louisville Loup City Lynch Fairmont (2) Falls City Famam Farwell Firth Hendley Herman Hershey Hickman Hildreth Holbrook Holdrege Holstein Hooper Lyons Madison Madrid Magnet Marion Fordyce (2) Foster Franklin (2) Fremont Mason City Maywood McCook Friend Fort Calhoun Fullerton Hoskins (2) McCool </seg>
            <seg id="p037">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 37 Meadow Grove Merna Omaha (2)* Page Shelby Shelton Shickley Sidney Merriman Milford Palisade Palmer Papillion Pauline Paxton Miller Silver Creek Snyder Milligan Minatare South Sioux City Spalding Minden (2) Moorefield Morrill Pender Peru Spencer Stamford Stan ton Petersburg Pickerell Naponee (2) Nebraska City (2) Nehawka Pierce (2) Pilger Staplehurst Stapleton St. Edward Stella Nelson Plainview (2) Platte Center Plattsmouth Pleasant Dale Plymouth Newcastle (2) Newman Grove Niobrara Sterling St. Paul Strang Stratton Nora Norfolk (2)* Norman Ponca (2) Potter Stromsburg (2) Stuart North Bend North Loup North Platte Oak Primrose Ragan Sumner Superior Surprise Randolph (2) Ravenna (2) Raymond Oakdale Oakland Obert Sutherland Sutton (2) Swanton Red Cloud (2) Republican City (2) Oconee Oconto Odell Syracuse Reynolds Rising City Riverdale Riverton (2) Roseland Table Rock Tarnov Ogalalla Ohiowa Orchard Ord (2) Orleans Osceola O'Neill Tecumseh Tekamah Tilden Rosemont Rulo Thurston Tobias Rushville Ruskin Trenton Trumbull Ulysses Unadilla Union Scotia Osmond (2) Overton (2) Oxford Scottsbluff Scribner Seward (2) </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 STATE FIRE COMMISSION University Place Wallace Upland Washinj West Point Wilber Washington Utica Waterbury (2) Wilcox Valentine Waterloo Wilsonville Winside (2) Wisner Valley Wauneta Valparaiso Wausa (2) Venango Waverly Wolbach Verdigre Wayne (2) Wood River (2) Wymore Verdon Weeping Water Wellfleet Wynot York Vesta Wahoo Western Wakefield (2) Weston </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>