<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Seventeenth Biennial Report OF THE Agent OF THE Nebraska Home for Dependent Children To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">T - ', .-. M 0 I M X ' ■£ m ■ H G a: I f- t V ■ t ... I " '] \ d ES 5 7&gt;^&gt; / :&gt;* j« / ' X.'' | :n" M 'j | H </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE OF NEBRASKA Seventeenth Biennial Report* OF THK Agent OF THK Nebraska Home for Dependent Children LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioner!* of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916 •Sequence of reports fully explained on pages 478 to 48L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF rE SHOWING THE NAMES THE INSTITUTION HAS HAD AND THE SEQUENCE OF BIENNIAL REPORTS HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS Authorized by Chapter 52, Sections 1, 2, 3 and 4, Session Laws of Nebraska, 1881. Government vested in the Society of Home for the Friendless and in the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Re - spective duties and authority conflicting and not clearly defined. Operated and recognized as a private institution supported by the State. State furnished land and building and financial support for operation. (The Supreme Court of the State of Nebraska, held, April 6, 1899, that the Home for the Friendless was a State institution from its inception and never otherwise.) Opened for the reception of inmates, January 1, 1882. 1st Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1884. (No report available, though reference is made to such a report in the report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings for period ending November 30, 1884.) 2nfl Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1886. On file at State Library. 3rd Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1888. On file at State Library. 4th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1890. (No report available, though reference is made to such a report in the report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings for period ending November 30, 1890.) 5th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1892. On file at State Library. 6th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1894. On file at State Library. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 7th Biennial Report for period ending November 30, 1896. On file at State Library. Chapter 37, Sections 1, 2 and 3, Laws of Nebraska, 1897. Government vested in Board of Public Lands and Build - ings by above act. This act was intended to remedy the joint government of the act of 1881. The Society of Home for the Friendless did not voluntarily relinquish possession. Action was brought in the District Court of Lancaster county by the State for ejectment. Case was appealed to the Supreme Court of the State of Ne - braska, which court affirmed the findings of the lower court, April 6, 1899, holding the Home for the Friend - less to be a State institution by the act of 1881. See "The Society of the Home for the Friendless vs State of Nebraska," 58 Nebraska, 447. 8th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1898. (No report available nor referred to eo far as traceable, due, doubtless, to chaotic conditions prevailing as a re - sult of legal action.) 9th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1900. (Labelled 8th Biennial report. Covers period April 14, 1899, — 8 days after decision of the Supreme Court of April 6, 1899,— to November 30, 1900). On file at State Library. 10th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1902. (Labelled 9th Biennial report.) On file at State Library and Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. 11th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1904. (Referred to as 3rd Biennial report.) On file at State Library. 12th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1906. (Labelled 4th Biennial report.) On file at State Library and Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. 13th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1908. (Labelled 5th Biennial report.) On file at State Library and Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF BOARD OF CONTROL OF THE STATE PUBLIC SCHOOL FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN Chapter 69, Sections 1 to 12 inclusive., Session Laws of Ne - braska, 1909. Government vested by this act in a Board of Control of the State Public School for Dependent Children in lieu of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings as heretofore. This act was made effective July 2, 1909. 14th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1910. (Labelled 1st Biennial report of the Board of Control of the Nebraska State School for Dependent Children.) On file at State Library and Nebraska Home for Depen - dent Children. BOARD OF CONTROL FOR DEPENDENT AND NEGLECTED CHILDREN Chapter 62, Sections 1 to 12 inclusive, Session Laws of Ne - braska, 1911. Government vested in a Board of Control for Dependent and Neglected Children, the same as by act of 1909, the es - sential difference being, pertinent hereto, the change in the name of the institution from Board of Control of the State Public School for Dependent and Neglected Chil - dren to Board of Control for Dependent and Neglected Children. 15th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1912. (Labelled 2nd Biennial report of the Board of Control for Dependent Children.) On file at State Library and Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN Chapter 179, Sections 1 to 30 inclusive, Session Laws of Ne - braska, 1913. Chapter 231, Section 3, Session Laws of Nebraska, 1913. K'rnment vested in Advisory Board, April 23, 1913, to July 1, 1913, in lieu of Board of Control for Dependent </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS and Neglected Children. July 1, 1913, government vested in the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions in lieu of the Advisory Board. The question as to whether the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions legally had charge of the Home for Dependent Children in lieu of the Board of Control for Dependent and Neglected Children arose. This was not determined till April 16, 1914. Meanwhile the provisions of the acts above named were not enforced. By an opinion, (letter) of the Attor- ney General of the State of Nebraska, it was held that the government of the institution is vested in the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions pursuant to act governing, named above. Ste letter to Dr. P. L. Hall, Lincoln, Nebraska, April 16, 1914, by George W. Ayres, Deputy Attorney General, page 351 of the General Let- ters File for period January 17, 1914, to May 27, 1914, office of Attorney General. The Board of Commissioners of State Institutions actually took charge of the Home for Dependent Children on May 1, 1914, the same being voluntarily relinquished to them. 16th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1914. (Labelled 3rd Biennial report of the Agent of the Home for Dependent Children.) On file at State Library and Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN Chapter 132, Section 1, Session Laws of Nebraska, 1915. The name of the institution given as the Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. 17th Biennial report for period ending November 30, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICERS Etta Caton Agent Amy V. Stevens Assistant Agent Mary B. Grice Secretary Lillie McGoogan Matron Mary Hollahan Governess Inez C. Philbrick Physician S. E. COOK Specialist EMPLOYEE Annie Gress _ Laundress </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 483 INTRODUCTION Standing before us is a ragged, barefooted, freckle-faced, blue-eyed boy. Who can tell what latent forces, what slum - bering passions, what genius or native goodness lie hidden in that head and heart'? There may be the elements of the criminal, the orator, the philosopher, the statesman, or the philanthropist, we do not know. But since his inherent ten - dencies are subject to modification, susceptible to influence and capable of endless improvement, let us do all we can to direct his energies, develop his genius and make him a manly man. The thoughts, feelings and desires which dominate a life during its formative period largely determine its future char - acter and possibilities. The child that rocks in the cradle today is the man of tomorrow — the citizen of the future, whose private character and public demeanor are to affect the social, commercial, in - tellectual and moral status of a commonwealth. Newton N. Riddell. LITTLE ORPHAN ANNIE Little Orphan Annie's come to our house to stay, An' wash the cups and saucers up, an' brush the crumbs away. An' shoo the chickens off the porch, an' dust the hearth an' sweep, An' make the fire, an' bake the bread, an' earn her board an' keep; An' aU, us other childem, when the supper things is done. We set around the kitchen fire an' has the mostest fun A list'nin' to the witch-tales 'at Annie tells about. An' the Gobble-ups 'at gits you </seg>
            <seg id="p009">I SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Ef you Don't Watch Out! better mind yer parents, an' teachers fond and dear, churish them 'at loves you, an' dry the orphants tear, he'p the pore an' needy ones 'at clusters all about the Gobble-uns 'dt gits you Ef you Don't Watch Out! </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN Lincoln, Nebraska To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Hoicard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and Silas A. Holcomb: Gentlemen: Herewith, I submit the 17th biennial report of the Ne - braska Home for Dependent Children, for the biennium be - ginning December 1, 1914, and closing November 30, 1916. Owing to the many changes made in the conduct of this work since its inception in 1881, the various names under which the institution has been operated and the several changes of location, much confusion has existed in the minds of the public concerning it. To clarify erroneous impressions and to trace the consecutive sequence of the various biennial reports, I present on preceding pages, in chronological order a resume of the various changes from the beginning of the work to the close of the present biennium, as pre - pared by Mr. George Weidenfeld, Accountant, Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions. The purpose of this institution is to care for such de - pendent children as have been committed to it as permanent wards by any juvenile court, district or county court of the State, or who have been received at the discretion of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions for temporary care only. All permanent wards being subject to adoption, it is the duty of the officers of the "Home" to find suitable family homes for them as soon as practicable. Such is the demand for children that, were all the homeless children normal, and all of the home of applicants acceptable, it would not be </seg>
            <seg id="p011">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF necessary to keep the child in the institution for a longer time than is required to prepare him for transfer to the family home; in fact, the number of applicants for children exceeds the number of children received. Perhaps one-third of the applications are rejected, the home being considered unfit for the child ; a large number of applications are not filled because there is no child acceptable to those applying. The child is as much an individual as is the man and as such must have his rights and his desires respected. A certain child does not fit into every home, even though he be a nor - mal child and the home a good one; he cannot be happy in every home. Johnnie may be perfectly miserable with the estimable Mr. Jones and wife, and he may make life per - fectly miserable for them. Place him in the home of Mr. and Mrs. Brown and life becomes to him the bright heyday of youth ; and the home, before so quiet and still, becomes a place of merriment and happiness. A girl of thirteen years was taken to a home which had been highly recommended ; within an hour she was in tears and repeatedly said she did not want to stay, she did "not like the lady". She was taken to another home where she is now very happy and the family is happy in having her with them. A Bohemian girl of eight years expressed her satisfac - tion with her foster-home by saying she would like to come to Lincoln to see all the "Home" ladies, but not to stay, as she "would bawl good if she had to leave her ma," which leads us to think that we found the right "ma" for her. And herein comes the nice distinction between placing a child in a home and placing the right child in the right home. And in this as well as in other lines of work, expe - rience is a fine teacher and is very helpful. In doing the very best grade of child-placing it is necessary to know per - sonally not only the child to be placed but also the persons talcing the child. But as it is impossible in the majority of placings to have intimate knowledge of the persons taking the child, there must be more or less of an experiment. Suf - fice it to say that no child is forced to stay in a home where </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THE YOUNGEST AND THE OLD EST WARDS OF THE HOME— 2 DAYS AND 80 YEARS OF AGE, NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE EOARD OF COMMISSIONERS he is unhappy. After a number of years spent in the work, we consider the method of having the home hunt the cflild preferable to having the child hunt the home. Public display of children for the purpose of securing homes savors too much of the auction spirit and is particularly embarrassing to older children. Then, too, in this way, one cannot carry out so desirably the sifting process in selecting homes. By this, I do not mean that no effort is made to find homes. On the contrary, we are constantly on the lookout for good homes. A happy, desirable child in a home is the best ad - vertisement our work can have. While, on the other hand, a child of bad habits placed in a home usually loses that home for the child himself and creates a bad impression in regard to institutional children in general. Hence, a strong effort is made to bring every child into moral conditions as nearly as possible before placing. Of the seventy-eight children in the institution at the close of the biennium, classification may be made as follows : Temporary wards (not for placing) t Physically defective 28 Mentally sub-normal 4 Below normal, both physically and mentally 2 Undesirable because of bad habits 12 Eighty years of age 1 Apparently normal 22 Three of the normal children are Mexican. In addition to the seventy-eight children mentioned, the "Home" has supervision of two hundred fifty-three children who are in free family homes, making a total of 331 under State care. In a way the Nebraska Home for Dependent Children is a clearing-house for the unfortunate children of the State. Many times it is a question with the court as to where the child properly belongs ; hence, there is committed to the "Home" not only the homeless child, but the delinquent child, and the feeble-minded child. The delinquent child is fre - quently sent to the "Home" with the hope that under more favorable environment the delinquency may be overcome or removed. And we have found that this hope is often real- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF ized and that in a new home the faults and bad tendencies which hampered the child gradually slip away and entirely disappear. The feeble-minded child is occasionally committed to the "Home" because it is difficult to draw the line between the normal and the sub-normal. After a fair test in the "Home" and in the public school, and a mental examination by competent persons, should it be decided that the child is a subject for custodial care, he is then transferred to the Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth. In sev - eral instances, children who were apparently feeble-minded have responded so quickly to slight surgical operations or medical treatment of some physical ailment that the change wrought mentally is remarkable. Dull, apathetic faces grow - bright, and minds grasp readily what was before difficult for the child to comprehend. But there is a type of child which is neither delinquent nor feeble-minded, and yet who cannot receive the proper training in the ordinary family home. It is the child who lacks a certain moral sense, — who lacks the ability along certain lines to distinguish between right and wrong, or who knowing the difference between right and wrong is unable to withstand the temptation to do the wrong. Such a child should have special training along these lines in which he is deficient. So far there has been no means of providing such training though it might be the saving from the penitentiary of such a child when grown. I During the biennium there have been applications for admission of 456 persons. Of this number 212 were re - ed and the remaining 244 were provided for in other s. Of the 212 admitted almost one-third were of illegiti - e birth. This brings us face to face with the problem (legitimacy which is a most serious one, and one which are inclined to push aside as one of those subjects which t be spoken of in whispers, yet it is a subject which should receive the most careful attention of our legislators, because its results are far reaching. It not only thrusts upon so - ciety each year hundreds of homeless children, but it affects »a cancer the morals of our young men and young women, it brings into the world an innocent child without a </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS home, without the personal care of a mother and without the support of a father, for in 99 cases out of 100 the man aban - dons his unborn child and its mother to the mercy of a coldly critical world. He goes free; no burden of child support rests upon his shoulders, no stigma upon his name. Scot - land has dealt with this problem in a more practical way than any other country by forcing the father to support his off-spring, and this is the surest and speediest way of rem - edying the evil. Sex-education, another subject of taboo in years past, will also be of untold value not only in eliminat - ing to a great extent illegitimacy but also many other evils which tend to produce child-dependency. In the United States each year nearly 300,000 babies under one year of age die. Many of these are babies that have been separated from their mothers. Generally speak - ing every mother should keep her child, and most unmarried mothers would do this were they able to support themselves and their children, and were it not for the double standard which makes of the unmarried mother an object of scorn and contumely but which upholds the unmarried father as a "good sport". Many an unmarried mother, rather than be ostracized by friends and acquaintances will place her baby in the keeping of any one who will take it, will abandon it entirely, or, in extreme cases, will destroy its life. Many of these unfortunate mothers are splendid girls, natural mothers, and under right conditions would develop the very highest traits of motherhood. And no nation, country or state is going to be at its best until it protects motherhood. This may seem a digression from the purpose of this report, but I am leading up to this : Many a young girl comes to the Nebraska Home for De- pendent Children with her baby in her arms, thinking that she can have it cared for and placed in a good family home without her poor, little pitiful story becoming public prop - erty. When informed that the law governing the Nebraska Home for Dependent children provides that her child can be received only by order of the court, she often goes away in despair rather than face such an ordeal, and then in many </seg>
            <seg id="p016">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF cases only God and the mother know what becomes of the little child. If she appears in court to surrender her child, her name goes on the court record and is frequently pub - lished in the newspapers and the story of her disgrace be - comes common property. This is unfair, as she is but one of two responsible for the existence of the child. And if the State, before being willing to help her, requires her to pass through this trying experience, it should require the same of the father of the child. Or, if it is necessary for the mother to remain a year in a home for the purpose of moral training, how much more necessary is it for the father to have similar training. IThe State should be just, and until such time as the lem of illegitimacy shall be nearer a solution than it is , the unmarried mother should be allowed to relinquish child direct to the Nebraska Home for Dependent Chil - , and that provision in the statute governing admission the "Home" should be changed in this respect. This ild be done not only as a matter of justice to the mother but more particularly for the welfare of the child, which E suffer the consequences if the mother finds difficulty in sing of it to the "Home". Moreover, courts are loath ndle cases of illegitimacy, preferring to leave the mat - the hands of the mother of the child. I Shortly after the close of the biennium ending Novem - 30, 1914, we were burned out of the rented home at 1425 reet, Lincoln, Nebraska, the fire being caused by a de - ve gas pipe near the furnace. None of the children were red but much of the furniture was damaged or destroyed, ecame necessary to secure another location at once and best arrangement that could be made was to accept at ntal of $40 per month the vacant house at 1345 G street, oln, Nebraska, a building old and out of repair and too II to accommodate more than four or five chidren at one l Occasionally we have been obliged to make beds on the floor and to have children occupy the same room ard sometimes the same bed with officers of the "Home". The plastering on the walls is cracked and falling, the paper is </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS old and soiled and torn, and it has been difficult to keep the house clean and sanitary. When cases of infectious disease have occurred in our boarding homes and we were called upon to remove the patient at once, our only means of caring for such child was to give up one of our few rooms to its exclusive use and this brought the diseased child and other children who were of necessity in the "Home" at the time into close quarters. At the close of the biennium we are still located in this building, and the work is carried on in the same general way as for the previous seven years, — that is, boarding the wards in family homes in and about the city until permanent free homes can be found for them. Needless to say, this plan naturally appears to become more difficult as the time approaches for the "Home" to be in - stalled in the new institutional building now nearing com - pletion, where we hope to have much better facilities for carrying on our work. During the last biennium three lots were purchased at 10th and South streets, Lincoln, and a new institutional build - ing has been erected. We feel that this will mean much to our work in every way. It will eliminate many unpleasant and annoying features incident to our boarding plan. It will place the children under our immediate supervision, so that we shall know the individual child better; we can do more to eradicate evil habits, can overcome physical ailments more readily, and hence prepare the child more quickly for his permanent home. In a way we shall have to re-adapt ourselves to our work when we transfer to the institutional plan. While this meth - od of caring for the children will bring some problems which do not now confront us, yet it will eliminate more than enough to compensate. If we are allowed plenty of good food to build up the children physically and a sufficient number of helpers to train them socially and morally, we feel that chil - dren can be placed in permanent homes more rapidly than at present. Our work must necessarily be supported almost entirely by the maintenance appropriation made by the State, our </seg>
            <seg id="p018">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF only other source of income being money received for the support of temporary children. During the biennium just closing this amounted to $2180.52. We receive numerous, unsolicited donations of old cloth- ing, sent in from different parts of the State, but are prac- tically valueless, as they are almost invariably unfit for use. A gift of $100 was recently received from a friend in Idaho. During the biennium we have received in cash For boarding and care of children $2180.52 Gifts 111.60 For clothing for certain children 9.75 For telephone calls _ _ .87 Return railway fare 27.84 Return livery fare 3.00 Nipples (sold to ladies taking babies) .85 Rags .25 Dinner .50 Postage stamp .02 Rebate on lamps .09 House Roll No. 640— To reimburse cash fund 25.00 Total _ $2360.29 Owing to the connection to be made between the physical plants of the "Home" and the Orthopedic Hospital, it is somewhat difficult to make a close estimate of needed appro- priations and of additional employees. However, beside the force already employed it will be necessary to have a boys' governess, girls' governess, two nurses (not graduates), seam- stress, housemaid, yardman, two cooks and two laundresses. The institution grounds will require fencing, grading and improving generally and sidewalks must be supplied. The school question must also receive especial consider- ation should the State be required to pay tuition for attend- ance of the "Home" children in the public schools. And it is very desirable that the children attend the city schools, as many advantages thus accrue to them which they would not otherwise receive. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS An estimate of needed appropriation for the biennium beginning April 1, 1917, follows: This does not include school tuition should such be re- quired. The return to the institutional plan of caring for depen- dent children will probably meet with more or less unfavor- able comment. But to those opposed to this method of caring for dependent children I would say that for normal children we do not recommend institution life. But, as Table No. 14 will show that but 42 children of 212 received during the biennium were normal, and as there are more applications for children than there are children received, it is not neces - sary that the normal child remain long in the institution. And since more than three-fourths of the children received are physically, mentally or morally defective or delinquent, the need of temporary institutional care is apparent. As the work for dependent children requires a work-shop or offices, a social center, an information bureau, a training school and a hospital, an institutional building should supply the need admirably. I wish to quote from one who has made a study of the results of institutional care: "Even the most radical opponent of children's institutions, if he has had any opportunity to study the question at close range, will have to admit that there are some exceedingly good institutions working along most progressive lines for the advancement of the temporal and spiritual interests of the dependent children consigned to their care. Speaking for the State of New York, where exceptional opportunities have been afforded me, during the past year, to look closely into things institutional, I can bear cheerful testimony to the fact that we poaaeas I II V r Maintenance H a. Salaries and wages $18660.00 b. General repairs - 2000.00 c. Other maintenance 24340.00 New Equipment and Furniture Permanent Improvements to Buildings and Grounds New Buildings and Lands Miscellaneous n Total ...._ * .47500.00 7500.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF some exceptionally fine children's institutions whose work is of such a high type as to reflect credit not alone upon the institution itself, but likewise, upon the community wherein they operate. The men and women in charge of these orphanages realize fully the responsibilities they have assumed in offering to act in loco parentis to the children entrusted to their care, and are measuring up to them. One has but to visit such institutions, pass judgment upon them and come away fully convinced that any child committed to their care, quite generally, will be turned back upon the community well trained, physically, men - tally and morally, thoroughly equipped to take his place in society, a proper subject for useful and right citizenship. 'V In conclusion I would recommend that the Legislature grant the estimated appropriations needed; that there be a revision of the law governing the Nebraska Home for Depen - dent Children, permitting unmarried mothers to relinquish their babes directly to the "Home" without court procedure; and changing the title of the head-officer of the "Home" from Agent to Superintendent. Respectfully submitted, Etta Caton, Agent. /-.'nco/», Nebraska, November SO, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 495 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPILATION For Year For Year ending e id Ing Total X.it, 30, Xjt. 30, . for MdVKMBNT for 1915 1916 ' Bienuiuui If. r. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T. rrexent ut IwkIihiIiib of |&gt;&lt;-rii&gt;.l 130 '.'-' J22 137 l:»« SB 1*) H2 2B8 Admitted: Fit flrst time.... 41 1:7 ION HI :tN 'M 102 105 307 K.ir tlrsit time... 41 1:7 ION B1 W !» IOC 1115 307 Keiulmiited _ -' 1 :t 2 2 4 1 5 Readmitted _ .' 1 :t -2 2 4 15 Kftiinioi from trial homes in which !&gt;]:■&lt; •-&lt;! l*-fore kagtalac of period... 15 17 32 1H JO as Total under care- . 238 IX 4.M Kftiirnt'ii frnm trial homes In which |il:ii t*«l Itefore beginning of i&gt;erioil 13 17 :(■-• 18 20 ss Total under care- 286 198 4.M DiwlMrged : Ui'turtHMl to parents or friends :i 2 I l.'l 4 17 16 6 22 !&gt;!••■ liur.-.-.l Hi-turned to parents or friends :i 2 I IS 4 17 1 16 6 22 Adopted 11 18 2i&gt; 1* 15 :« J» 30 !W Adopted _.. 11 ■ 2»i 1^ 13 33 29 30 S» Tranferred to other institatiou» 1 15 16 6 17 Trmiferred to other institutions 1 1 5 1 6 6 1 T Hi,., I i ■_&gt; 4 4 6 « l&gt;i^,l 2 t 4 4 6 6 AttMiu«Ml majority 1 1 2 1 .1 4 2 4 8 Married _ - 2 2 1 1 3 3 Attiiined majority 1 1 •-' 1 3 4 2 4 6 13 4 2 4 8 Married _ - S a 1 1 3 3 M:.rri...l Pla&lt;-e&lt;l under contract and not re - turned during period _ P1a&lt;-ed under contract and not re turned during period. IMaced in trial homes and not re I'IikimI in trial homes and not re - turned during lileuuluui ."&gt;! «7 11* .'&gt;!• 4» 101 turned during liieuniuui 31 IT UN 52 4U 101 Total removal* I I M 30 MB Total removal* nil 30 1OI Remaining at end of period. Ifi7 138 3« 1X3 148 331 1X3 14M 3»1 Remaining at end of period. Average numlier under care 140 115 2W» 1M&gt; 142 32B 16(&gt; 12H 388 Ahaeut in trial homes at rommenremem of or durine period and later dix - i-harireil without returning to Home '.&lt; 30 ■_"!) 17 1« 33 M M «2 Absent in trial homes at rommenremem of or during period and later dix- rfcarffed without returning to Home. Total nuiiilier plm-ed in trial liomen til Vrl 153 &lt;W 92 160 r.ii VH 3U Ti'inl uuiiil«*r plnced in trial homefl. TSttal number returned from trial hnmes 'Si 44 ti? 28 50 84 , SI lot) 199 TABLE II. AGES OF THOSE ADMITTED For Ye«r For Year ending ending Total \. v. :io. x.iv. 30, for AGE AT ADMISSION for 1913 191ft Biennium M. F. T. : M. F. T. M. F. T I-n.ler 1 month 3 ■ ■ H 14 ■ , ■ 2K 41 1 to 3 months- _ } 3 1 4 6 3 9 9 4 13 S to fl nionthH. 1 1 3 • • 7 1 8 « to 12 months. _ — ■ 2 2 2 — 2 2 2 4 2 2 1 to 2 years. -. - - - 3 3 _ 3 3 2 to 5 years - 8 H 1« 9 2 11 17 10 27 5 to in vear* 14 IB 33 18 11 20 32 30 «2 10 to 1« year*.. IS 20 S3 9 7 16 22 27 « IS to 18 y««r» 1 2 31 1 22 3 5 Totals. 1 43 68 111 B 38 101 106 1« at </seg>
            <seg id="p022">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 496 TABLE III. EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Ye«r For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Not. 30, for EMCATION for 1915 r.'lf, Bienntom M. K. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. None 18 2ti 42 35 18 S3 51 44 «6 Below 3rd vrntto. 3rd grade _ 12 14 36 15 8 23 27 22 4» 9 14 6 tt 12 11 IB M 4th grade 4 111 4 .'. 8 MM 5th grade - _ 2 7 ll I 1 45 R 13 6th grade. _ 1 • 7 i 2 2 3 • » 7th grade 3 3 1 1 3 I 8th grade | 1 1 1 1 Total* | 43 6K 111 63 38 101 11* 1(« 212 TABLE IV. MX AND Kilt. OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Tear ending ending Total Not. 30. Not. 30, for RACE for 1915 1916 Biennium M F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. White Negro 42 Si 105 59 37 96 101 100 301 • 14 i 5 5 a ii 1 TotnU 43 (is 111 63 .IK 1(11 1 106 106 212 TABLE V. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Total Xrv. 30. Not. 30. for NATIVITY f,.r 1915 1916 Blennlnm M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. :a V. 7S 4S 24 73 I 82 (• Iftl NVIlTHMkA United State*, other than Nehranka ! 4 16 20 9 8 17 ' 13 54 37 Total natiTe born Canada Poland Italy ... Total foreign born.- _ 2 2 4 . — 1 12 * » Unknown. _ 4 5 • 5 5 10 9 10 » Totals 43 «« 111 1 6S W&gt; 101 106 106 SB 37 61 18 1 » ■ :«&gt; ■ I 111 1 1 1 1 i l II l 1 l l j X 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 497 TABLE VI. NATIVITY OF PAKENT8 OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Total Not. 30, Nov. 30, for NATIVITY OF I'ARBXTS fnr r.ii5 1916 i Blenninm M F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. In I led stmes. Loth parents. 27 46 73 37 23 fiO 64 » 133 telifii. doth parents, ed 6 « 12 7 4 11 I 13 10 23 1 4 5 2 2 3 4 7 I'nUnwn » 12 21 17 11 28 26 23 49 Total* j 43 68 111 63 38 101 106 106 212 TABLE VII. PARENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Tear For Year ending ending Total Sot. SO. Nov. 30. for I'AHKXTAL CONDITION fnr 1915 1916 Bienninni M. F. T. M. F. T M. F. T. 11221 3 326 Both parents denri Father dead 1 • 10 l!l I I 7 14 12 26 Mother dead :. 17 14 31 9 7 W 26 21 47 I 't rents living together 14. 114528 10 Parents separated.. 11 Jl 32 14 111 24 2T&gt; 31 56 Parent* divorced 1 I 4 t • 5 S 1 I Hub stepfather. 6 7 13 4 4 10 7 IT Has stepmother- ■ 5 10 Inknown _ - — 2 2 43 35 2 7 Parents living but unmarried « 13 lfl ! 28 13 36 29 26 56 Total* ' 50 75 134 65 41 106 124 116 240 TABLE VIII. AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS For Year For Year ending ending Total Not. 30. Xov. 30, for AGE OF CHILD for 1915 1916 Bienninm M. F. T. If. F. T. 1L F. T. Ag« at death of father Inder 10 year. - »U» 7 2 9 16 13 26 10 to IS year* _ 1 — 1 — 1 — I Am at death of mother: Under 10 years 11 12 28 8 8 16 19 20 SB 10 to 18 yean 8281 — 17 2 » Totals 272562 1«10 2843*T8 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF i TABLE IX. APMI-.MON I KI1M DEFECTIVE OB I&gt;KI.IXQl KN T HOMES For Year For Year ending ending Total Not. 30. Not. 30, . for CLA88 fur 1915 1918 Bltnnlnm M. F. T. | li. F. T. M. F. T Feeble-minded: Father _ _ _ _ 1 4 5 ' 1 4 • Mother 1 1 _. 1 1 Brother __ 1 1 a . 1 ill * » I lisa lit* Father _ -... ' 2 J 4 J 2 2 4 FaUer - 2 3 4 ! J 2 S 4 Mother . 26813^3912 Aim n^r Intemperate: , Father 17 .11 48 20 8 28 ] )7 &gt; Tl Mather - - 2 4 4 2 8 4 Intemperate: Father IT SI 48 20 8 28 37 3» 7* Both parent* _ - 2 4 « 2 1 S ' 4 5 • Delinquent : Father _ 21 M 37 3 3 6 24 1» 4S Mother 5 10 15 3 2 5 s K 3a Both parents _ 10 30 40 44 23 «T M 53 107 Father ._ _ _ _ 21 M 37 3 3 • 24 If 41 Mother 5 10 15 I 3 2 S M 12 SB Both parents _ 10 30 40 j 44 23 «7 .14 33 10T Brother — _ _ 3 2 5 1 ill 2 • Brother — _ 3 2 5 1 14 2 • Sister _ _ 2 2 4 2 2 4 Unknown 2 2 1 112 1 Totals W 111 177 1 77 « IS. 143 104 Wt </seg>
            <seg id="p025">i I 9 I I** I I I * r , i - I I a - B -z S </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS rilAIlAfTEIt OK ADMISSION For V«r ending Xi'v. .10. Mi r'or Year ending Xot. 30. 191A for Biennlum M. F. T. M. F. T. T. M. r. T Permanent— by decree of court Temporary— b.v contract : With parent _ « With county \ By order of conrt _ _____ 37 1 n vn ei 2 4 « 1 3 ... 2 4 1 33 o 3 SB s 4 ■ 2 3 V \ Totalu « ■ OR 111 iVi SX 101 106 10B 21 TABI.K X. fOI-XTY OF RK.S1DE&gt;&lt; K OF THOSF. VI. Mil I K I &gt; AMI III THOME REMAINING AT EMI OF IIIKVMI M For Y**r For Year ending ending Total COI". NT Y Nor. 30, Nor. 30, for rOIWTY 1915 1916 Biennlum ' M. *\ T. ' M. F\ T~ M. F. T. M. K. T. ] M. F. T. M. F. I. AiIhuik ' „ j 3 3 3 3 .Vilnius _ „ j 3 3 3 S Box Butte • 4 10 &lt; 4 10 Box Butt* — 6 4 10 • 4 10 Buffalo _ _ 1 1 _ 1 1 Buffalo _ _ 1 1 _ 1 1 Cedar __ 4 4 i 4 • Cedar 1 4 4 i 2 j 4 • Clay 1 4 5 1 4 i flay 1 4 5 1 4 9 &lt; 'lister 3 5 S -. 3 5 8 &lt; 'lister 3 5 S -. 3 5 8 furter 3 .-, s 3 5 S &lt; 'lister 3 .-, s _.... 3 5 • I&gt;ouirta» : Ill 14 Ji ■ ■ :«» 37 a • Knwes 1 i 1 i Dawni 1 ... 1 1 i (■age _ 1 l'Jl 12224 Kitt't' _ „ 1 121 12224 Oarfleld _ | 1 1 1 1 (Jarfleld _ | 1 1 1 1 &lt;Jrant _ _ I 1 3 4 1 S 4 (traut _ 13 4 13 4 Hall _ 4 " 4~" 8 _ 4 4 1 Hall 14 4 8 - 4 4 1 Hamilton „ j 1 l l i Hamilton _ 1 1 1 J Jefferson Jefferson 1 1 1 1 _ _ 1 i .Tohngon _ 113 1 1 J Johnson _ 113 1 1 J Lancaster __ « 12 IS id" " lit ii 2S 25 44 Lancaster ..._ « 12 IS 1« MM 22 22 44 MadiHOD _ 2 2 1 1 3 3 Mnilixm f 2 1 i s 3 McPhereon _ ft 1 7 „ _... 6 17 Mcl'her«©n _ • 1 7 6 1 Naiu-e 1 .1 4 .T .t 4 3 7 Nance 1 3 4 3 3 4 3 7 Neniaba 4 » 13 J 1 3 6 H&gt; 1« Nuckolls _ II j « Otoe 3 2 S 3 2 S I'ien-e 2 2 Polk 1 1 _ _.. i i Rirbarrigon 2 7 Sew aril 1 1 1 1 Sheridan I WetiKter ' 1 - 1 1 Wheeler 1 1 _.... ! j York 1 1 1 1 Total. 43 OR 111 B3 38 1O1 lf» 1M JM I Mil t XI. CHARACTER OF AltMIHSION </seg>
            <seg id="p027">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLK XII. D1HTK1BITION OF CHILDREN AT END OF MENMl'H, KOVEMBEB M, 1»1« I \IU.K XIII. 11TI.K ATlllN- FOB ADMISSION Applications for admission _ _.. | ' 4S0 Permanent care _ 336 Admitted ' 1U6 Males _ 96 _ Females ..„.. 99 Not admitted..., _ _ .... no Parents persuaded to keep _ _ ....' lfl Family homes secured under parents' supervision ' 8 Referred to court I __ v. Sent to other Institutions 10 PVjMsjd in domes hy court „ 12 Aged people — Information and advice given in w - curing* homes 4 Applications withdrawn after being advised 17 Temporary care _ _ _ _ _i Admitted ..._ 17 Male* ____________ ..Z ~ 10 ! Female* _ _ | _ i 7 Not admitted ot admitted I KM Parents persuaded to keep _ 13 __ _ _ Family homes secured under parents' supervision 2S _ Referred to C. O. 8. Referred to county commissioners . | Referred to court &gt;&lt; Referred to Orthopedic Hospital __ 2 Placed with relatives » Sent to other institutions Pregnant women...- n 1 Family home aecured 1 Applications withdrawn _________ , __.. _ DISTRIBUTION OF CHILDREN 1 Total for Blenulum Dec. 1. 14 to Deo. 1 1« n boarding borne*., n trial home* ♦7 31 78 136 117 253 Totals 1* UK 331 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE XIV. PHYSICAL CONDITION OK &lt; llll IIKKV WHEN ADMITT! I) Normal 42 I*lgeon breasted 2 Adenoids at Psoriasis _ i Adenoids Abdomeu distended J7 Hound «houldere&lt;l__ __ m Abdomeu distended. 17 Hound »houldered_._. .... ai Auaemia Anaemia _ 71 Ruptore I 71 Rupture Anterior fontanelle large Anterior fontanelle larje 10 Scabies 10 Scal.ies _ "__ i Birthmark Birthmark 4 Syphilis w 4 Syphilis _ is 5 Teeth 50 Bow legs _ 5 Teeth go Bow leys Bronchitis Bronchitis — 1 Bad condition: 'mitlei. 1 tf 1 Bad condition; &lt;■ title* tf Catarrh 2 liutrhinson .... .. X Catarrh lliitruinson Cough (chronic) Cough (chronic) ■• Tonsils (enlarged) Tonsils (enlarged i JS Chicken pox Chicken pox _ _ 2 Thrush _ Thrush 4 Defective speech- 4 Tongue tie Defective speech... 4 Tongue tie __ Deformities 4 Tulwnnlosls Arm 1 I'vula (large) Hip 1 Weak lungs ___ Lea* — - ...._ 1 OvcratitM Shoulder _ _... 1 Ailenolds j5 1 leformlties Arm 4 Tuberculosis 1 1 I'vula ilarge) 1 K 1 Weak lungs __. \ 1 Operation. 1 Adenoid* 39 .1 Appendicitis Shoulder „ Eczema - 3 Appendicitis „ j Eczema 2 Erythema — 3 Bow legs Erythema -. 3 Bow less _ ______ E«r - 7 Brace supplied (spii,.i _____ , i Chronic dls'-hnri:»*. '_' Broken arm Fissured 1 Broken lee _ Brace supplied (spinel _ j Broken arm 1 Broken leg Suppuration middle ear 4 Circumcision ..._ _ _ g Eyes 14 Clipped tongue ....'"" 3 Dislocated elbow In cast 1 1 Excision pedunculated polyp rectum 1 Conjunctivltu Ophthalmia - Blepharitis .. It Foot in cast 1 Hernia . Strain 1 Specific keratitis... Trachoma 1 Hypnspadlas _ Inguinal hernia j 18 Lancing abscess. Glasses supplied Furunculosis 2 Lancing glands _ S Lancing Jaw_ _____ . 1 8 Loosening adherent foreskin. M Goiter Gonorrhea ■ 1 Phimogls Hnrelip 1 rnimosis _ 44 Planter parts cast (spinal cnrrattire) Heart 1 organic and weakness) 1 Rectal flsrare 1 1 Removing crochet hook from hand 1 Hernia 1 umbilical) Hydrocepbalic head lntertriKO 11 Removing birthmark Indigestion (acute) Sewing Incised wound . 3 Tapping spinal canml _ 2 Total operations 117 Jaundice Kidney (weakness). Knock kneed 1 Wassermann tests 4« Lateral curTature — 3 Positive _ m I^eucorrhea 1 Negative _____ S Masturbation Doubtful Premature birth.... </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XV. APPLICATIONS TO I IKK CHILDREN M. F. T. Ji. F. T. ! M. F. T. ■ 140 l'«. 90 144 -J-KI Babies • iilitT children Total* I ~ 145 200 435 TABLE XVI. FIELD WORK III RIM. HIENMI M Traveling — NuiutH-r of miles traveled l&gt;y rail and livery. Rail _ _ 61847 r.Tfwii mm Livery m. r. t. Placed io homes for adoption _ 117 ME* 282 Placed in free home* ! 12 ' 1» 31 Returned from homes „ „ _ 51 10(1 lftl Removed from homes 13 4 Transferred from one borne to another 10 lo 2S I&lt;«&lt;t homes in which placed _ 17 1 18 KMnapiied 1 l Visits to children : 807 Homes, etc.— Number visited in which children have been placed &lt;ES Prospective homes visited « 2M Special cases inrestimtted X founty of juvenile court sexsimis attended 71 Schools visited _ m t'ounty officials and Institution* visited in interest of work 128 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>