<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00035.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00035.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1913</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">»i Tilt \ K11R ASK A DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOK Till-. VKAR 19 13 PKKPAKEII HV S. C. BASSKTT. Ski rktakV NEIIKASkt DUKHItVS ASMKlATIilN </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">Gibbon, Nebraska, Feb. 1. 1914. H. Morehead, Governor of Nebraska with the law in this case made and |&gt;ro\ided Annual Report of the Nebraska Dairymen's 191.!. Yours respectfully. </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">OFFICERS OF THE ASSOCIATION 1914-15 FrcMile m Kka\i&gt;sk\, Vice-President l nry-Treasurer Lincoln BOARD OF DIRECTORS f, C. (Al.UWKI.l E. L. Reukkkn II E, W . Kkost </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">\ My I Winter D i i E limiting Cor lion of Orfii ilution- 1H14-HU5 i K. W. MrC.innis 1 ■ i in nil I te« Work and Its Relation to Dairying Kami Drmonst ration Work V. S. Culver ...:(» Milky Way L. S. Herron 42 Nebraska H. M. Rushnell .... 43 \ Delzell M jpplemeni for Nebraska I'astur* I. H. Krandsen Abroad I. H. Kushton (tttter Production at Home and Abroad \ndrea d its Feeding Um on the Dairy Kami N Pood. Drug. Dairy and Oil Commission I Its Relation t he Halx-oik Test H. Morehead amuel Avery Dairy Cow on the Average Farm Building up a Dairy Herd (). A. Sevier id Feeding the Dairy Cow R. W. Welch I Discussion K. K. Udell. Henry C. C.lissman ommittee'i Report Awarded Members of w Testing Association."' &lt; &lt; Demi B. A Burnett Vd&lt; Advantage! of the Dairy Spei-ial Train '■■ Harmaa . \\ R. Mello 1 Hunter Northwestern Nebraska Jmmtm &lt;;. I'helj ■taaec of Raising Dairy Calve: B. (i. Woodward .... </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN CIATION Report of Delegate to Agricultural Council of N Report of Prizes Awarded Silo Discussion C. K. Sehwager. Professor Chase. A M T E. M. Little. H. C. Young The Pit Silo (". H. Jeffords. Geo. C. .lunkin. I. (i Ph. Value of Corn Silage Professor .1. H. Frandsen Circular Letter sent out by R. W. MrGinnis Circular Letter sent out by R. \V \1&lt;( The Log of the Dairy Train Relation of Railroads to the Dairy [ntereati of Nebraski D. Clem Dmvm Judging Con teal E. \\ Krost. Superintendent Relation of Railroads to the Dairy Intrrnti of \' ( List of Licensed Creameries in Nebraska List of Licensed Creameries in S'ebraska Banquet Mi-nu Toast List N'eliraska Association of let- Cream Manilla*-!:. I N'eliraska Association of lee Cream Manufaclu Silo- and Ensilage \\ J. Spillman, IT. S. Dep't ol \ La Ma) Nebrash pion Co« </seg>
            <seg id="p010">w 9 LIST OF MEMBERS of the Honorary and Life memi association. Honorary Life Members H Pi. Atkinson. Wis New Hampton, Iowa 18 Henrv. lMto U Usage. Iowa per. 1*91 1897 N'aerum, Denmark Omaha. Nebr. Life Members 1885 Gibbon. Nebr. Pittsburgh, Pa. Omaha. Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Beatrice. Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Gibbon. Nebr. \ \ 18 \ 1 A 18 Andreas. 1!M1 1 K85 1&gt;M, Sutton, Nebr. Omaha. Nebr. \\ ilrox A; Streeter. 1888 Omaha, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. \\ H. A; Co., 188 &amp; 1 Omaha, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. Gibbon. Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Hebron, Nebr. (iibbon, Nebr. ft. Dodge, Iowa 18 Sutton, Nebr. .Chicago. 111. Omaha, Nebr. Sutton, Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Milford, MM*. Dinsmore. 1&gt; H t; H H Davis, 1 an I) 1H8« W N Da 1888 .Waterloo, Nebr. Waterloo, Nebr. Building, Omaha. Nebr. Madison, Wis. t[)al&gt;.'lstem. l!»07 l.s Diilielslein. 190&gt;v B. B. Davis, IMfl </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 riry Biehc, 1(HM M. Ebey. 1888 Frank T. Emerson, 1888 Wm. Eiche, 1910 (Hi ». O ( •Hon. R. W. Furnas, 1881 F. S. Fulmer. 1886 Hrow Iirles Finrh. 181 F. Flint, 1 J. Fisher. I n. H. Fieldgrove, G. Furtfuson. I f. W. L. French, 191(1 C. Glissman. ) \ Gil.b. Farm. Li I B, On E. W. Gunther. 18M Germantown Creamery &lt; Henry (". Glissman. 1904 Chr. Hansen. 1 All !MI IF. Howe. 1886 W. Hoyt. l-^&lt;. jis Heimrod. 1 H. Hurley. 1- W. Harrel. 1 *■ B. E. .1. Hairier. I &gt;f. A. L. Haeck.T. 1M&gt;' K. Honeywell. 1908 skell &amp; Boaworth, 1H94 H. Ijams. ] - IE. Her. 188 .lones. 18M il. Kintj. 1 H. Knight. |8i schbraum &amp; Sons. I s imas Kirk. 1 1 relle B. Kin K . 19&lt;M nry Krumhaui-r. |9M n. Lew on. 1888 trt'. Lessentin. 1 ■ M. Little, IM8 o Matjenau. 1- C. Merrill, 1HX6 men &amp; Noble. 1888 rkel &amp; Swobe, XHHX rtyn Bros, 1888 \ N N N N (i Max Meyer, 1888 Dr. Geo. L. Miller. 1888 Omar 'Geo. E. Kvans, 1K^ </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 Omaha, Nebr Omaha, Nebr Omaha. Nebr Stromsburg, Nebr Omaha. Nebr Farm, Lincoln, Nebr .He Omaha, Nebr Omaha, Nebr Omaha, Nebr Gibbon, Nebr Omaha, Nebr &amp; Omaha, Nebr Fairmont Fairmont ( ri umery, Omaha. Nebr ( iimi'ry, Omaha. Nebr re Lincoln, Nebr Lincoln. Nebr Omaha, Nebr Bennett. Nebr. Omaha, Nebr Omaha, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. 188 Gibbon, Nebr. &amp; Co., 1889 Omaha. Nebr. V\ l.SMi Table Rock, Nebr. ITer, 1889 Bellevue. Nebr. \\ . Stevenson, 1 Sioux City, Iowa F.aifle. Nebr. 1911 Omaha, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. \\ 188 Omaha, Nebr. Cheyenne, Wyo. \\ Ithaca, New York w. (;. w nore. IN Valley, Nebr. \\\ 1888 Omaha, Nebr. Wheeler. .1 r . IM Omaha, Nebr. &amp; Omaha, Nebr. A &amp; ( Omaha, Nebr. tt Omaha. Nebr. Gibbon, Nebr. Woodruff, 1*8 A Kilter W 1!KMI Station B. Omaha, Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 •&gt; List of Annual Members Andreas, J. P. Armann. M. R. Allen, E. W. Beatr \ Martell \ X Sis., [in Central ( N N N N Allen. F. O. A K er, C. E Anderson. E. S Anderson. A. H Blaikie, H. E Caldwell. F. C. Culv.-r. V. S Carver. Frank Cromwell. (). P .-. Farm Chittenden. V. H Coplen. C. P Clark. C. A Campbell. P. B Camp, R. H Clark, J. S tise Howard stenson, ("has. I pland Geo istick, E. D.. Jr man, H. N., Jr center, R. W K \ N N id? No. H Cullen Ray Ko Collier, Chas. E II. Lii \ Cole, David N N N Es. R. D ey, I). S no, H. C s Elliott ey, R. H omsl Beat Arcadia N N N Elmwood N Elliott, J. D Beach. I. 1 Backer. K. W B.»usku. r. w Bland, A. D Burton, Alva Brookman, K. h Brousr. K. N Bix-kes, (;&gt;■&lt;&gt;. K Bev.r, B. V. C Bull. H. C. State Farm, Lincolr Mi N'». l«th St., Lineolr </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 Hemingford, Nebr. Farmer's Co-operative Crmy, Omaha, Nebr. Farmers Co-operative Crmy, Omaha, Nebr. Route 1, Funk. Nebr. 2970 Holdrege St., Lincoln, Nebr. Stockman, Nebr. Central City, Lincoln, Nebr. Tekamah, Nebr. 700 So. 16th St., Lincoln, Nebr. Page, Nebr. Phillips, Nebr. H N :!21H Holdrege St., Lincoln, Nebr. 2947 Douglas St., Lincoln, Nebr. II Dewitt, Nebr. Lincoln, Nebr. \\ Havelock, Nebr. State Farm, Lincoln. Nebr. Inman, Nebr. Bancroft, Nebr. Alliance, Nebr. K Carroll, Nebr. Platte Center, Nebr. H Clarinda, la. Madison, Nebr. Sioux City, la. Bladen, Nebr. V 2615 C, Lincoln, Nebr. Council Bluffs, la. Crete, Nebr. Seward, Nebr. 2810 Summer St., Lincoln, Nebr. Whitney, Nebr. Ainsworth, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. Raymond, Nebr. «E Verden, Nebr. Beatrice Creamery Co.. Beatrice, Nebr. Hooper, Nebr. ISM I' St., Lincoln, Nebr. 1401 No. 33d St., Lincoln. Nebr. ;:z A. D 1812 Farnam St., Omaha, Nebr. Geo Litchfield, Nebr. Lincoln, Nebr. State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. i()7 No. 24th St., Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Jenkins. C. C Jordan. Guy F .Jensen, R. G :i(»4 (» i St.. L Has Kami. Lin i K \. Knson. R. H fenson Henry North L \ Kinedy. J. R hn. E. W N Kth St.. Li r K Kennedy A; Pan Ha r McGinnis. R. V\ Martin. Kdward Marsh. E. ( tMillan. J. C rquardt Hcnr rshall, Wilber rshall. K. C Cartney. I.. &lt; xtield. Don racy. A. (" rri.-k. H. C Greer. T. .1 ler, Don H. Nelson. Bro: Eger, Oliver trhout, M. D ii, r. (i Farm Magazine, iimuha. Nt Olsen, E. A Ha U \ Atlanta. Nel Frenr Nel bner. N io.'n \ine, Lincoln. Net tnson, J. Alfred i. son, V. .1 Kent. P. H Kuhun Hlui i Kent. Carl. Lalhrop. I LimlKren. |, (. hop. (i. H on, R . -I Have* &lt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 Ainsworth, Nebr. Alliance, Nebr. Schuyler, Nebr. Joy, Nebr- Box ll)H5, Lincoln, Nebr- Arcadia, Nebr. 1.(41 I) St., Lincoln, Nebr. Talmage, Nebr. 1544 Q St., Lincoln, Nebr. State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. Route 5, Lincoln, Nebr. \\ Route 5, Lincoln, Nebr. State House, Lincoln. Nebr. Route 4. Norfolk, Nebr. \\ Stromsburg, Nebr. ■CilO Holdrege. Lincoln. Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. U. \\ Lincoln, Nebr. Lamar, Nebr. 4.(15 Franklin St.. Omaha, Nebr. Talmage, Nebr. State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. H York, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. \\ Palmyra, Nebr. \ Palmyra. Nebr. Frank N Columbus, Nebr. Central City. Nebr. Mynard. Nebr. Sioux City, la. U Route 7. Lincoln, Nebr. H Seward. Nebr. Columbus, Nebr. David Cole Creamery Co., Omaha, Nebr. \ U Benson, Nebr. 1812 Farnham. Omaha, Nebr. K R Fremont, Nebr. :I44II Starr St.. Lincoln, Nebr. :(019 Starr St.. Lincoln, Nebr. \ K 3440 Starr St., Lincoln, Nebr. (). \\ H. ( SOT No. 24th St., Lincoln, Nebr. University Place, Nebr. Falls City. Nebr. K \Y. I 1 No. Platte, Nebr. Decatur, Nebr. 1'row bridge. P. K Templiti. \.\\\ 1601 M. St., Lincoln, Nebr i Carroll. Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION Kiiiiii Lincoln. N r. J. E L. O Frank Norfolk. N Sargent. N S| K Ranch. N Woodruff. W. I) Whisenand. S. H Weber, A. K i-ottsbluff. N Harvard. N deneva. N Wright. F. C Beatrice. N Worthman. A. B Wintermute, H. ( Weinary, John Williams. R. J Wilkenson. A. K White. Jas. A l!i Cirand St., Omaha. N Friend. N K N I. H leal rice Creamery Co.. Li fair Wellensick, O. H ■n. .1. W Bea K. D. S . s. s er. .1. A Ford. ( H. Ho I. ( ■enand. J. « ice. S. M ht. Frank H,. W. Clark Young. H. C Young, C. C Young, E. K Zubrick. W. E Life Member Annual Members Total </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">w 17 TWENTY-NINTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Wednesday, Thursday and Friday, January 21, 22, 23, 1914 H Assembly Room 110 in New Plant Industry Building versity State Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska PROGRAM WEDNESDAY. JANUARY 2\ Morning Session 10:00 A. M. Dean Burnett Address of President Robt. W. McGinnis ecretary and Treasurer S. C. Bassett Demonstration Work and its Relation to Dairying, O. H. Liebers Led V. S. Culver Afternoon Session 1:00 P. M. Milk Cow Train in Nebraska H. M. Bushnell ational Advantages of the Dairy Special Train, Prof. J. E. Delzell ng Crops and Their l'se in Nebraska .Prof. J. H. Frandsen vine Abroad J. H. Rushton Butter Production at Home and Abroad .W. C. Andreas Alfalfa and Its Ises on the Dairy Farm .E. P. Brown THURSDAY. JANl'ARY 22 Morning Session 10:00 A. M Work of the Nebraska Pure Food Commission .C. E. Harman Sampling of Cream and Its Relation to Babcock Test .E. L. Redfern Dairying in Northwestern Nebraska •las. G. Phelps Calf Raising and Its Importance Prof. E. G. Woodward Afternoon Session 1:00 P. M My Experience in Building I'p a Dairy Herd .0. A. Sevier Economy of Milk Production Prof. R. A. Pearson To b«' followed up with tuberculin test, lecture and clinic. Addre&gt;&gt; of Welcome </seg>
            <seg id="p020">18 N FRIDAY. JAM A in Morning Session 10:00 A. M Ks t&gt;f Committees and I discussion of Silos Kit (Ml I Silag \\ Afternoon Session 1:00 P. M Winter Dairying ami Feeding i In- Dairy Chief Rawl, r s. Dairy I) I). \ Discussion led by Prof. A L. Haecki 3 00 P M Cow Demonsuatioi 4:00 P M Cow Judging Com COW JL DC ING CONTEST Open to members of tht ONLY Anyone may becon payment of $l.oo. Pro-rat a premium ( The pro-rat a will b points out of a | number of points scored ab Ten cows will be us mittee appointed for t h placement of the ruv. The judging will anil everyone is invited lake part in this contest T \ T I ; I-' \ « \i The meeting was called duced as the first speaker. Dean Bu Dean Hirnkit. Mr. President glad to be with you again today, and of successful meetings, which the da university farm since I have been in at either the fourteenth or fifteenth meeting. In that time. 1 have st a continual increasing interest in tht A in the dairy business throughout t hi without my telling you that you are v farm, and that we are always glad to hav Last evening I had the pleasure of one of the agriculture association-. ;i </seg>
            <seg id="p021">\ vel ea i I i \ m nilk know 19 \ l hut there was ■ k"" ( I deal of a gap university and the farmer who wan he farm. I hope that is not true. b-gard to any other branch of agricul- tnnected, l&gt;ecause while, it might be true ml all of their time out on the farms through - quainted with the conditions, all of the men Far as I know, who are teaching agricul- her, come right up from the farm they ming business. They have all been inter- &lt;l farm life. They do not lose that in- to the university, or when they become con - mental staff, or with our instructural statf 1 want to assure you that every man university farm, is intensely interested in agri- Kvery man connected wiih the dairy department. tensely interested in problems connected with the i dI our men. I think I am safe in saying I come right up to their present position from in. Now that ought to put us on common i discuss with each other the things that are pment of the dairy business, and where each he sympathetic assistance of all have gone by, the interest in dairying has nmong farmers of finding some source of )duce more dollars per acre than they used to get, or farming nakes it necessary that a man follow some h will produce him larger dividends per acre fifteen or twenty years ago. At the present the question of cheap feed, we discuss the an be utilized so as to make more profit and very few of us at least are confronted today ii» to utilize cheap feed. Everyone is con - em of high priced alfalfa, high priced silage and the necessity in the utilization of these hat the man on the farm knows how to »g n into the dairy business rather than away ht be said that there is no line of farming much interest as has the dairy business, higher than they ought to be it seems to hich once produced milk is a luxury which t is the so-called dairy cow, which once pro- .i imes ne.cessary for the farmer, as well as, the station to know what his cattle will actually whether there is a profit or a loss in the luestion can only be settled by exact methods, </seg>
            <seg id="p022">M NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION which show whether one cow is eating up the profit, w r cow is producing. I quote from memory a report which I cently of the working of cow testing experiments, at the na dairy show, my memory is that the two best cows in the bu ten made more profit than the six poorest cows; they all mad little profit. As the contest was conducted, one man w h I uate of our institution here, went out among the farme and pick out ten cows: took them to the national dairy show at Chicag them under reasonably good conditions, on a good dai kept a week or ten days record on them. At the end of tha the two best cows made more profit than the six poorest, and I not just sure where the other two came in. You will p u report on it if you have not alread I mention this as indica « taking place, or to have taken place alrea where he has not made actual test of the produc Surely we are getting to the place where no man w this herd simply for their company. He better associate wit other 75', for their profit, th W iting up the profit y of the leading quest ii will hear more of cow- Dairy cattle are so much in derr is one of the dangers of the business. When the in demand that everyb to pay more for a cow than she is worth after he gf To profit, they require good judgment and g the part of the buyer, and good manag frequently the difference between liber dairy business is not a question of th but it is a question of the managerr we are all the time learning, and th ered here this week, which is to di which will make it worth while to pu best brains into the business. Now, I want to again assurt a see the dairymen of the state here ;it the K to go out and see you upon your own farms. We «b a lot more milk, because Mr. Frandsen wa dairy business. Not having enough he farther away than he thinks he ought to K understand that he gets some of it as far away as DeWitt and ( mantown. i Applause. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">21 PRESIDENT'S ANNUAL ADDRESS &gt;m that seems to have been in vogue Nebraska Dairymen's Association, this f and place fo/ the president to read his annual intention and bear with me for a brief i-mpt to inflict upon you a great How of oratory o give you ■ synopsis of what has mleiiv •f our last meeting. lairymen of the great state of when vou I upon me the high honor of the election to anon. 1 felt ii incumbent to put forth my great- ike this year worth remembering in the dairy history ons of this naiu.'t' tile enthusiasm is gener- ual meeting, election of officers, etc., and permitted to drift along and the enthusiasm il the next meeting but in this instance we hopes thai with the aid of our dairy friends and Kincr commitiees of the legislature that this might be in a large and commodious dairy than $11)0.01)1) and something adequate for ie growth of our dairy industry in this state. tin- association were of the very best as well committee that was appointed but owing to the with which you are all probably familiar. We were not nble to secure the appropriation I dairy building appropriation fo and equipment but did succeed the development of the dairy e legislature closed and we were able to check up our we had just $1,000 to use in furthering the airy industry a it h our secretary, Mr. Bassett, who has been lustry all these years, it was finally con bservalion- and general information pertaining and from the statistics he had gathered from ying in II ail III II Nebraska, in what is known as the ■am belt, was not increasing and his investigation n for this was on account of the high price for nil as well as hogs, beef cattle, etc., which showed a ere drifting to a point of se'ling their small grain corn to the hogs and cattle, while on the other und western Nebraska, where these conditions did \ist. there seemed to be more interest manifested in dairying areful consideration we concluded that inasmuch as the and a hat part of the state were beginning to take more interest </seg>
            <seg id="p024">22 in dairying, that it would be to the I if we would put forth our efforts to give them I he proper da education and such information as we could might start out in such a manner to wai We found I hut there were so many to warrant financial We found that there wen- many places and tr large that it would not In- possible, on I large that it would not lie possible, on account of the lack ol fund ii »time, to hold a dairy meeting at a luded that the best way to reach through the territory on the railrc various stati&gt; Our secrela.-y is an old and e\perienc with what assistance the write,- could ol small appropraition we had. that in ord* we would have all our money spent h\ -tart and alter carefully ronsiderinK all eluded to |ireM'iii our ran* &gt;&gt;&gt; ihf railr sequence Secretary Hassett. 1'mt I H went to Omaha and I really Wu-h when story we put up to the railroad rompani Hut it seemed to story short will state that ,dcd railroad officials lo |iv&lt; over braska. from that point t" Norfolk station in Northwestern Nebraska, Burlington officials in the good new and compassion upon us and parried &lt; (irand Island. Grand Island to G rege and then into Lincoln. Kven with this free will onVring as - part of the two largest railroads in i he sufficient funds and having been sn succi tion to Omaha, we then went to Dean telling them how we had progressed and which they cheerfully granted and tina ments completed we left Lncoln at 6:31 making a night "un to Niobrara wit ho A. M., this being the starting point of The train equipment consisted ol kinds of dairy utensils, equipment, etc., the dairy department at the ex peri m and time, to hold a dairy meeting at all the tow concluded that the best way to reach them would be trip through the tt the various stalioi Our secretary with what assistance tl small appropraii we would have ;il start and after ca railroad officials braska. from thai station ill Northwestern Nebraska Burlington officials Grand Island, Grand 1 rege and t hen uitu Li Kven wit h t his I part of the two largest railroad sufficient funds and having tion to Omaha, we then went to Dean H telling them how we had prOfT* which they cheerfully granted ments completed we left Lncoln at 6:30 I' making a night "un to Niobrara without w ] A. M., this being the starting p&lt; The train equipment consist* kinds of dairy utensils, equipment with end doors which contained four milk cows and one I car which was used to exhibit tl coaches for holding lectures, and a h officials of the railroad. On leaving Lincoln the train was accompanied by Dean r. \ Burnett of the agricultural college of Nebraska. ('. W. I director of agricultural extension, .]. H. Kr husbandry, O. H. Lathers, farn mi Gage t </seg>
            <seg id="p025">\ 23 Minnesota. Senator K. I'. Brown v. as a ting as secretary tempor- c illness of our secretary. Mr. Bassett. your tficial Itiiun" ■ short horn cow of the beef production being 1M pounds per year. was shown a regular good holstein named unds butter fat. a jersey named "Gold," 4(10 pounds butter fat. A grade holstein oving breed, making a yield of "J2S pounds hs. and a thoroughbred holstein bull named K us for the occasion by Badger &amp; Frost of nplete log :il the dairy train was kept giving information ■ every stop made which will be printed in our year tributed to all members of our association, consequently ke up your time to enumerate the various towns where incidents of the trip etc.. but will merely the report of the first and last stops. ■nd exhibit was made at N'iobrara com A. M. The mayor of N'iobrara, Mr. George (1 he ground to welcome the train and the \ he other tirsi arrivals was Agent Mclntyre of Agency who came fifteen miles to meet the dairy with him his head Indian farmer. Before the hour ere were Til people at the train, very largely jrrounding country. The opening lecture was Mr. E. P. Brown mi alfalfa, followed by Dean Burne rid then Professor .1. H. Krandseu with the cattle on t description of the dairy row*. fessor .1. H. Krandsen with the cattle on the ption of the dairv cow van ke|il up for two weeks stopping at the various tow h;id crowds of from J.'il) to over ■ thousand people an&lt; WO weeks stopping at the various town from 2M to over a thousand people and loldrege of which we have to say as follows: fthirfa we have to say as follow nit ai ii fell on the Mnal act of the continued performan lie Nebraska dairy special at Holdreue, promptly o he final act of the continued performance Nebraska dairy special i Arrival at the cit v it Holdrege, promptly on ■iheduled. Arrival at the city was immediately followe&lt; was immediately followed •lure and demonstration with the live stock as at oth I'rof. Krandseu. before a very large audience of intereste&lt; spite of the brisk downpour of rain. By arrangement o he live stock as at other urge audience of interested rain. By arrangement of I of I he Holdrege commercial club the remainder of t •lub the remainder of the I presented in the Baker auditorium, with an au- opacity. Holdrege had furnished the one thing hat tax he trip of the dairy train memorable, namely ,ik. as great interest and enthusiasm as has marked K progress of the expedition from the beginning I'rof. Frandse n and Pugsley, also Senator Brown and Prof. (iregg and the w Her accompanied the train the full two weeks as r members of the party were compelled to return </seg>
            <seg id="p026">A ( JJ H and during the trip on l lie &lt; distance of Supt. William ui the last three days of t h the assistance of Prof. E. M I cannot be said in commendation of i lie untiring effort competent and thorough da i Bntil late in the evei 'mm the many lei train we are thoroughly deeply interested proficient and do da that it is the m finances woulf this next sprint; sin and have the as and at Krom stati fact u red almos while it might indii as our investigation consumptior facture of i&lt; AuRUSt and Septembt would have shown a I other hand, the da the reason that pri have been from Ih the history of t be ■ All of which Will. M The recent tariff lull the tariff on butter from w i and we believe that it is either K"ir average butter or it is going to wort The large per cent grade creamery butter. We notice a varian the butter market quotations and fact that the extras which are bring very limited supply made in whole mil the high class hotel and irrespective of price. Bn&lt; 'hi Frandsen. Brown and 1'un in this Krt-al and t;N&gt;r k'l high class and eMMequentl) cum </seg>
            <seg id="p027">.irket and which if on a parity with butter »n from six to ten cents lower umeries and all interested begin iliiv of cream which of course means we rr ay anticipate lower price: rios w. i&gt; \im SIOH, WASHINGTON, U. C. send a representative to the t be held at Washington, D. C, i • 1 •!. this being an organization of the allied dairy seel of representatives from the vuriou ntatives from the various it itereet* and prevnM adverse legislation. hape financially to send a delegate Mr. George E. Haskell. who happened to be in the which he did ami represented N't the meeting whatever, as congress was he currency bill and other matters, but there Is now pending favorable to the oleomargarine •h on this matter later on in my addre: kND \VI\TKK DAIBYING been repeatedly called to the fact that over Nel i natural dairy country. These observations ven by dairymen coming here from abroad and have. Such as the best water, the best climate ind for raising corn and alfalfa and every eeded and is necessary to do dairying on a scientific hiained a pretty good idea on our two hat ill our opinion was needed to further the dairy nt lime we are doing our milking hi of the yea;, when cream is poorest quality be nioM work to perform on the farm. onditiona in our sister states such as Wisconsin. we tind that instead of milking for four months eight or nine, but to do this they have their I, put up silos and silage, milk their cows when there is not much work on the farm, when highest, in the spring turn their cows out in hem eight and nine months How of milk and m prove our ci nduions there is no argument t that we musi get ■ better grade of dairy cows. ,ve have, organized cow test ing association ; and test it our herds, sell or give away the cows which are not paying ex- itul go at the milking business such as a dairy- silos and silage for winter feeding. \\. w mmend silos too strongly and believe til who have tried out the silo will voice MM putting them up fast enough. We </seg>
            <seg id="p028">\ see our neighbor get ;i silo and say " Well, lets watch I how he gets aloiiK and il ■acce—ful maybe we will i and in turning hack to the i liscus .^o 1 find the main ullje Station," "The Hand Separator," "The I And we notice that in di liutter lie ma skimmed from Mibmerged milk'.'" \ of ot her such i|iiest ii \\ r have liei-on ■ .day woul hand separato e law. (unseen tinuc and put dmilili- our Bn AuKUst L'l&gt;i . I received a vi Uestionable w tn { just at the t Kork loi ate for • d so far t with the very alii work concludiiiK that sv a failure it would only on the other hand if it and upon taking the matter and offering to perform Mr. Bassi him to keep the office until our I ■ select someone to (ill his placi for him until the end of nil \| HKTTER SI I'I'OKT IHIK1 I&gt;l\ XI'KKIMI- VI conclusion and wilh the ho|i as fault tindint; or eenauring : " the various state leyisal ion Dairymen we urc (Oiaf tkroug Kof I'sinK Starter in Your Cream to Make B K to notice lh* qucsi ion- thai »nr.- naked tion. "Will milk skim ■in November 18, M&gt; and tlMNNf &lt;&gt;f "'" </seg>
            <seg id="p029">NTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 27 i i I ii I i\ low n i ■ig md K *ith such a ma ha -ing men from tr ing men who i nil the members of this aas IT humble opinion has been seemingly ncilities thmi we have at the ex &gt;f the dairy department. When tablished and the instructions in ;ir A led. the present building on the campus I have the record complete we had about ndsen two men at the heads of these depart - linly made |Tef4 advani-ement in the dairy and know of no two men who could have dont a hat they have had to do with. ka and her resources have grow n. so has our great ill your attention to the fact that whil&gt; an agricultural state and the products of the ■ach year than the mining states or the forest- hwest or the fruit of the tropical states in the •looked the fact that conditions and make Ml of neglected that build new buildings en and will ask you me we seem to have ovt money to improve our ■tier dairymen we have si our university money to odors and professional m iv to improve Nebraska? ii as you might term it to the meat of the ppear to you that most every body has been I he dairyman and is it not about time that •ganization of ours, commit from every county I her and take such steps as will enable us to merit, etc., that is somewhat on ■ parity with luiremrnts as we have yrovwi and from four start we have now nearly I ')() and that will ITer belter facilities for their educa leinen. in charge of our dairy division of instruc- ntal farm, a man who was raised on the farm. boy, went to the great agricultural college at luated with honors, and while he came to us • almost a stranger his recommendations were since he has been with us he has proven his convinced us that he is a thorough dairyman with us 1 believe that we should give him a way and by doing so will not only encourage lairying in Nebraska but we will have more of our im the farm taking the dairy course and when we de - ll who arc proficient ill this department to take charge airy farms or our ice cream factories or our creameries mill dairymen the proper rprogni luiry course. We have had in Prof </seg>
            <seg id="p030">28 PI etc.. if you please il will 1101 l&gt;c necessary for II other states as we will have the material right I hi' mat RKKiMMKMiATI" We have a number til &gt;mn will add very material dairy business in Nebraska board of directors take I ht artion and ask necessary raai First. Thai definite an in matter of national the national daJ ■ t hem. Second, I lion with (li are manufacturing ■ butter, etc. Third. Tha ration with the to prevent dair ■ have not |&gt; FolKTH. T with th« dairy breed* and in each their members a FlKTH. Thl be give*. If 1 he year ami I a em and resolutions ami western Railway, Chicago H their officers who assisted out in the interior also, tha material assistance rendered bv l&gt;eun 1 and Frandsen of the ex peri me i ■ and state superintendent. SEVENTH. I'pon our retur wrote a letter to every creamery f K dairy department in our effort dairy interests in this Kof directors take these in with their recommendatioi representative ilair; thai l hey eneourag ad \ i&gt;«*(l from i i m«* ■farmers institute! held. Sixth, We would aim tion. commercial clubs, retailers mo if t hey were agreeable to CO-ODCTBi </seg>
            <seg id="p031">\ 29 t r g this t t- m K 1 n which are certainly most encouraging me action be taken. hth. A&gt; there is more or less controversy in regard to the ual meeting and in order to have aid recommend that this association take lette as a permanent emblem of the the ribbon attached be changed in color g to the association and believe will answer is intended. iddress was referred to a committee consisting Vogel. Redfern. Clark. Osterhout, Little, Wood. KKPOKT OF SECRETARY ticcrs and Members of the Nebraska Dairymen's igned has served as an officer of the association since in February 1885, serving as secretary from 1889 to 1898 to date, a period of twenty-five years, and in nis last and final report as secretary desires to express It thanks for the great kindness and uniform courtesy ceived at all times from the members of the association. 1.H85 the dairy industry of the state has made great n only in an increased amount of dairy products anufactured but in the quality of the product, and ! years, and in all the changes for the better the ciation has kept in close touch with every effort he improvement Of the dairy industry and for the agriculture as well. No state association, allied to kept in closer touch with the continual advancement made in all branches of agriculture, no association •tive in leading the advance from year to year, and Tien have the largest paid membership of any associa - nculture in our state. Pleased and proud that I was 'lp organize the dairymen's association, grateful that rmitted to labor, for so many years for the upbuild - y industry and of the agricultural interests of the -om the burdens of the secretary's office with feeling work which the association has accomplished and for the many kindnesses received. 5. C. Bassett. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">30 \ ( DAIRY CONDITIONS IN NE BR ASKA C. H\ KTT Nehraskans arc a boastful p of the millions of bushels of corn ai ■a ually. but few of us can- to investigate too closely the n yields per acre or I lie actual returns the producer reeeivi ■ When we (peak in our capital &lt; t hat in t he cit v annually t ha merits are believi &lt;lairy com mission creamery batter i gate too closely a what our milk farmer reeeiu The truth. lit In an effort ■ ur farms in the state: w the state advance of taki is locai ed ranked to the square mi returns and also t hat for nearlv thin t han an averag) summary of this draw his own ronriusiom Briefly analyzing t ht iii this township, beef-b for &lt;lairy purposes with either regisU at the head of the herd and of this census represent average per cow. per year, and averag) year, on thousands of farms prevail. It is self evident that dairy is not considered onf r-r that in farm operations dai There can be no question t h ditions and not theories, to be Bhe dairy industry in Nebrusk; g most needed to develop creameries: others that we mu </seg>
            <seg id="p033">31 i 1!U ! I I I while as a matter of fact the Jims dairy-bred cows be used •&lt;l ilairy-hreil males at the head of he farm lie considered as one of the be conilucteii as a business and i) industry, has ever been deve - profi table liasis when conducted In October 191:}. the Nebraska I i Actual dairy conditions on the farms of a o( the returns and statistics of said census Jlated form. In explanation it can be said tOWMkip is located ranks foruth in having milk cows to the square mile in the ineteen to the square mile according I I'nitcd States census, and judged by its might he classed as one of the best dairy township in question had a population, township is a small village a railroad mi population, but as this is a farm census village in taken or included in this cen- a local creamery, established in the continuously operated by the same -nine years: it will he noted that of unship who sell Imtter fat to a creamery, e local creamery, v. hich is strong evidence e local creamery has hail and still retains • of its local patrons. This creamery of its operation, been operated as a the management of the creamery takes he farm, so that its patrons are at no duct and this feature should be taken into i with the average price paid for butter net at l he farm this township is located has a farm-man lias in its employ a farm-demonstrator with the department of agricultural exten - ancl also in co-operation with the United ultuie. a portion of the expense of said the United States department of was laken on the initiative of the n and at its expense, on Itlanks till' I&gt;AIK\ ( KSSI iiuaiv. is considered us a unit in our aken a township dairy census </seg>
            <seg id="p034">32 Ehed by the association, the direct supervision L but the work of taking I of the farm demonstrati The enumerators who took the census w and and were required to visit each f secure the information desired. The er a separate report for each farm, gi\ location and size of the farm and ot h )i statistics in the report have been h! li 1 da o» practically all other milk cows were registered of the grade beef bred type. Th the tabulated stat very closely with the breeding of bull I This is the second milk &gt;\\ S Number of farms Total number kern Average number acr Total number trrcs Average number Total number a I age number acres in til cent of total aero in alfalfa 1 number of cattle age number cattle to Farm age number cattle to square I number milch eOWl age number milch cows to la age number milch cows to si .1 pounds butter fat sold crea age price per pound received .1 pounds butter fat consumer age number pounds butter fa 1 pounds butter sold I age price received for butter so I pounds butter fat produced I value of butter fat at "Jo cenl age yield of butter fat per cow e of butter fat per cow at J"i &lt; ber of farmers who sold butter ber of farmers who sold butter ber of farmers who sold butter at imt fat tralized creameries Number of farmers who sold butt&lt; m in t he town merators returr ig the Hi i • like informaii Only one farm reported regis braska Dairymen's A </seg>
            <seg id="p035">33 t B 1 ord IX, Shorthorn -~ 45 12 64 ws on farm \\ .irni 71 on farm h cows u 1 1 \\ s 7 \ DAIRY COW CENSUS IN NEBRASKA ('. Bassett • square miles and had 61 he !!»!(• 1'nited States Censa North to South through the center of Custer ies of Kpya 1'aha and Boyd. Brown Loup, Dmwaon and Buffalo. Ciosper and Phelps des the stat into approximately two equal Western part having an area of 37,718 square mil&gt; to lire miles: according to the 1910 United Western Nebraska had 112,813 dairy rows gf the square mile and Kastern Nebraska uws or an average of thirteen IS) to the square 1912 a creamery was promoted in a county in ■ at an expense of $111.01)0. In the 1910 Vnited nt\ (•ported as having 7.647 dairy fourteen 14 dairy cows to the square mile; \pril lHltf the Nebraska Dairymen's Association had taken a ttvering an area of six H miles Ins conn which this promoted creamery tow A creamery had been promoted at this point in i later abandoned. The census was taken under the supervision he dairy department of the state university and by a student in bicycle was used and the compensation IB the basis (if four dollar&gt; $4 per day and $1 for making detail. In the report is given the name of every ance from the town where the creamery is located i the number of cows being milked on the farm. Herewith is given ■ summary of said report: </seg>
            <seg id="p036">34 &gt; i \i\i\in m Estimated area Number of farrr Total number of da if* number of Number farm- 1 farm liad 1 purp&lt;i T detail civ milch cow pounds ol I. Th 'iried to i I compared with 31.1:14.11 apparent increase of :SL' (&gt; |H-r cent in 1 1 l»13 seem Iufactured in th* yeai i-i ntrulizei- plan the year I'll.'. Of t cent are listed as ha\ . f&gt; uith L'(l(l.(l(l!l pou one million, two bet 'ix ranging from 'j.tiiK t he food and dai r 1 sties as to I he make . inn 1 farm had m had ii had '- lia&lt; For </seg>
            <seg id="p037">35 WIKKIKS |N NKBK \&gt;K \ H5.77L' pounds 6.07C.7M pounds I1.72C.1M pounds 3.973,1 C2 pounds 5.M6.7M pounds 29,096,982 pounds 31.134.11S pounds 11. mm. nod pounds &lt; Omt !M4 . 104', licatfd increuiM neasur, to th, K atl,,nn K . ,n a mo,,- s\-.tematu- ame.y butter. It h doubtful if tin- actual flit OV« thr yea,- 1912. REPORT OF TREASURfeR berm o| the \.-l,.aska Dwryami'i AmwUtioa: ■nembership f«t \ I Glover to deliver a of •■(:.' |&gt;c," cent hi,- (hi- yea,' I til Barl K I'aid Book Cow ju&lt;ltcin K premium </seg>
            <seg id="p038">(tn m&lt; FARM DEMONSTRATION WORK \Ni) IIS KH \l DAIRYING In this 1 .11' ii i ilt-itio ii&gt;i rat we are itoiwg. and what we I have done, what I am Kto say this morning, that beeatu one phase, it looks like spreading come after me can. no douln. cove i In Gage county, we have 1 monstra hen 1 w in a quiet way. On the first day at last Febrn I was new to the work, and I \\a&gt; ne« to t h&lt; ii CO U I 'If Of IT) OF1 1 \)&lt; t() iri.t Paid J. W. Brewater, stenographer Paid Edward Loveland, taking dairy cenaiu Paid Printing annual reports Paid Poatage Paid Traveling expense* of nili. i Paiil Office supplies Paid CommiHw expel Paid ripen— milk cow train Stationery and printing Paid Ezpi iiial meeting Paid Sal Freight, telephoi : incident By cash iii balance Total The report ol iditim consisting M H K \\ BcroRi &lt;&gt;v II K. Voi \&gt; M initle ■'■ ■■ • ' I 1 1 K citin iinilf tn report as foil* Your committii Treasurer for I he \ , carefully none a and the financial arpnnrtts en </seg>
            <seg id="p039">V 37 A I I A i I low i ■ giving, and wl all kinds of sr jnd out that a | Tl i 1 help the farmers of Gage county. untry, as the conditions there are ideal. eds i hat are first-class for the dairy cow. lance. Then the climate, the water, and nake up absolutely ideal conditions located Very soon we believed that the establish- alion would be one of I he best things to ad- Kor instance a man could spend a good deal hog cholera, and in owner's meetings and in In that part of the country orchard work important part of the work, and a man could ime along that line. I have taken up the lield cops and the reports. Hut I think we me on the subjects of dairying, than any other irk ver the tield, I noticed that there were a good Iked in (iage county. 1 think there is something owi being milked in that territory. 1 found very :il dairy cows were almost entirely absent. There ough-hred dairy cows. There were a number of to just cows. There were more fceef cows than time almost everyone was milking cows. I could &gt;ws being milked in that territory, that were not d. 1 don't think any man should milk the or- i*ar just for the calf he gets, still there were Farmer* should milk cows on a paying proposi- he ought to have something that will give an association to further dairy interests; and nay emphasizing the thorough-bred cow. I think it was mentioned "the community interest," that ing to do down there. We do not advise and gelling thorough-bred animals of all king were doing. The association put out record kc what the university does, and we used them very long until there was not a dozen farmers lid not use those record sheets. They saw he name of the cow, and put down the amount w gave, and there was a column for the testing of nember there were a few farmers who opposed that houghi it was a foolish thing, and did not want do with such foolishness. Then we started a There the farmers found out what their cows hether they were paying. Some of the farmers hapes and sizes, and breeds of cows, and they iirt of their cows were not paying for their feed. ■slid, and learned that dairying could be don e lairying could !&gt;♦■ made a very paying proposi- i to grade up. To lirst liml out what the </seg>
            <seg id="p040">to much profit by having Lh&lt; demand cam country thorough i horuugh-lii-cil e have il one line. About we li.si lirced is th h&lt;- 1 1 idea to il SL* with lh&lt; ti) be n'i Ihund com in or ii\ l&gt;. like i In ■tTH-Ult meeting ire « We I ■ talk ami I fie rfairj i . licMiif milked. I i din I lie hi, me/, in I ; I In- &lt; 1 i ITi ■ . &lt; ■ i i i mw Imm, mu-Ii ;i~ alfalfa iow it grow*, .mil in i and hog cholera. \\ pen. or w here&gt; w we i tion nut of it it and miles away from ih.-i,- plan have become &lt;)uit&lt;- intemtti To show you how da had an attendance of time over three hundred this shows that they arc becoming in \\ shipped in a ear load of HoUteinx 1,0111 \\ enough orders for another par. Ai organisation ol </seg>
            <seg id="p041">39 it- ieet. In that uch dairying, just starting nation, w&lt;&gt; would have to hat whole territory in establish one. \\ an ideal row ucaic the farmer! to der lo make more in do. and ind demonstrate • pie t here w ho have belter than all the others. The farmer demon- way lit in do a (real deal of good proposition. I thank DISCUSSION OF FARM DEMONSTRATION WORK Mr President and Gentlemen of the . and I believe it will lie hut a Holsiein-, Guerneyi and Joi nt ere* ting in its results. We found Be cow as compared oduce. as compared with the brains of ihe man hack herd that produced a profit, business. In the case of (hose tfhtly so. the man' behind that herd as doing. The men that rand good business pay. A- I said &gt;UKh cows to make it lo I he l&gt;est w. and enthusiasm t&lt;&gt; other [uvm who prove I heir cattle, and in all me&lt;'tin|{s He is. or ibottld bt always poslrd on in Merrick county m«*n who are intc I larm demonstration work. Demonstration work .inless the men of tin- county when' the work is linj; to ro-operate. We were fununalc in having r of thai type ol men in our eouMy so as to t;et iniiation started. Tins association closed its year's of the year. We had sixteen men in the associa- A. \ te have now twenty-three. The work has proved irganised praetiemlly as ■ cow taatiag asso.-ia- torkinx along t Ik- line suutrested l,y Dean Hurneii. iinty into communities, where it will he noted for </seg>
            <seg id="p042">40 we had sixteen herds during the past year. Tr of those different herds varied. There were three r ■.•(I six cows in the association. Of that number forty cow before the end of the year, because, the own* cow- were unprofitable. Of two cows that able, one cow was led three hundred and sixty-live milkii und sixt three hundred and thirty-two days of which the owner reach) down in his pocket ami paid out $-.Ul) for his fur paid twenty-nine cents for his fun. and i ho in the herd any more. Many of the cows thai d and pasture, and Kilo, and I will endeavor to make it n cow testing association, ai and also have it in t he form M the result of his past yea to convince every man that he cam of his cow is unless he weighs h It was found out by comp;i in their respective capacities. The dairy cows; the cows that Etood were beef bred cows: in two of the lowe The top cow in the association was a ■uced four hundred and forty-eight pounds of Our cow testing association was organized pi ing of cows, but we will not stop at tha in that community, and we will create dai One of the things we hope to do. in I'stiiiK. and in which il will slinw pla BMC have l&gt;een made in btrome profitable because tl irnlil alili found out how id feed them to produce the milk tha The highi-st earning &lt;•&lt;&gt;« in the aaaociation ea I1S1.M civit. and above ln-r feed. The lowest retun I, the next highest ear* ■&gt; over and above of tbeae herd* was almost identical in manj rettpeftM « ami their ability quite nimil We- had thr&lt;T berda in the aimocialion, fed grain, and one thai waa Fed no frain whatever du They returned a |irotii of $:!viio per cow, on an aver you may feed ■ dairj herd and make thei Krain. provided they have | I Feed. One at the rate o! (90.00 p&lt; iw» had n&lt; Thai proves i hat cows can be kept without pa vsere conducted the s;ui)c a.- all cow tesUiiL' A on. The cow toater went to each : etc. Earn cow was charged with tl her products at the market prhf, which thi of that month, and he linds oul what p»&lt; With mature cows and with iilentv ol i»&lt;ki </seg>
            <seg id="p043">41 ii i Wt hail N.I i i Katie ( Lin be , K \ I 1 1 iinot r Thi K al Kt of agriculture perate with us, We would like to r I foil ! h« cow tesiirig association dfaipo— d of within the will get hack of the alion sale. Each cow arc enough to be association &gt;w testing assot ■ile will have a record for that year. There was inie last month, the owner having his herd •ar, l.ut because of ill-health the sale is held »n their merits. The tester finds out the lie cows in each herd. This year we will racy separator: for each herd he tests, he ticiency. Where i hey market the cream, we in examination so that the test will be official so that we will know all the time the farmei his production. We believe that will •suits. This cow testing association got very st summer, and it was very beneficial to the sort of a central meeting of dairymen on the We secured Professor Krandsen. and had him we had an exhibit very much as it was carried We brought speakers from abroad and had a I place. We also had from the state farm &gt;&gt;f the different dairy breeds; and we had tier." it being the first time that she was ever coin. I feel more good was accomplished, due &gt;eople could have the opportunity of seeing what ked like, than any other one thing. They had i-ii. hut had not realized what a real dairy cow there will never forget what she did look like, vrshire. and a typical Guernsey cow. and also This was an educational meeting along dairy milking machines there l» show the people hmery was done, being a practical demons! ra- lendance of approximately one thousand people O carry on this good work by holding another H I believe we will reap more good from it, ir We also had a farm demonstration to brine „.. „/ f \:e . i alters of farm life so that they could see with i- a big proposition to convince people, and it by practical demonstration. Our cow testing n that fact. It will only be a matter of one we have two or three other associations in the hing that this cow testing association is trying is coming year we will ask the national depart - and our dairy department at the state farm to and to furnish us with a dairy extension man. ive an extension man work in our territory, at Abo is competent to do the same work </seg>
            <seg id="p044">42 IIS Illj!' CIIU I ) ;itlil tell (it hi',-, « h lirinu to the asHoriatiun -onie of Ihi !. MAKING A MILKY WAI can I what a ilaii the muversi (rain pulls up to I Ix forward to open t lie »« "There they v," (l1 up and conies to ■ sto|.. A \' lly thick and fa are first. The cows will lie sho then you can no through the ex I up folk- in the front Ol llCiW i.Sf (|&lt;&gt; trganize t hree &lt;&gt;i I I my desire to (jet more i man u&gt; «ra i grca There what will li:i|&gt;i&gt;&lt; h«rd the youngste they'll slop rijflil over I m retrace t lu'ir iteptt. " \\ t lir&gt;t'.'" " Whrri- can I Then a l&gt;i&gt;j roice ;m </seg>
            <seg id="p045"/>
            <seg id="p046">ide finds him- it form Mc( president of the state owd. H»' is ably with the train. tnd into their passenger roach 1 1 is wiili difficulty i hat they somebody tells them it. and still ur^e- into the at ion of dairy have an overflow ;iin. Someone will Ami all thai ifr left over go troop- fortaMe on had a rhaitce In- I arnished rare. The fireman The ronUuctor lung is heard hut the voices of the speakfi" Then pande- Idren come rushing out of thei. tin. Nnl is the im&gt;» ii -cr. A little lull they arc PUfvr, loo md the demonstra- ind the people tile THF. MILK COW TRAIN IN NEBRASKA H M H\h I.! |M&gt;i*tam steps taken for the advancement \ atiKuruted and carried out Nebraska dairy train. iled so much to the farmers tint; the opportunities for I development in agricultural led by the agricultural extension Nebraska and the state dairymen's iken by I lie dairymen's association </seg>
            <seg id="p047">44 to have taken t thai aci ;i&gt; i In- dairy ir \mri li siimiM hiii Branrhex and hom&lt; reel work, come i Bu\i to ili'\i'!ii|&gt; dairy iuli \i-rpi ions, have niii t hi' i .mil sec I lii' vs &lt; i r k iln pxprrimentx ;it i ln j ak men i n t in- a^riciilt u r </seg>
            <seg id="p048">45 ■d in thi&gt; arms ami &gt;n I h » he rail « a a i irk M h. or the this kind. and Outside of t lie result, nation that the dair\ n that he &gt;. for the if i-ti igrirul he !■• in and iln ; |,,. issililr ;iild I hat &gt;f I lie Kli:: ildren outside </seg>
            <seg id="p049">I I I &gt; I ' \ I R I, </seg>
            <seg id="p050">I .,11 t I I I) A iT i ■ i Ott k nl r »d h II i In </seg>
            <seg id="p051">i E. t \ w Mu turn. TV ins. Like </seg>
            <seg id="p052">ikUmIki imrermte verv lout' i brooch re ho|n- the hope the .-.nil I hi.- hill. ;i ■ It- in ill i ■ demand is \ isiti-rl. I liiiuld imle*' that from f that from do not iloubl do noi doubt liinv;s hrou|(ht hrou|(ht the work hf w«rk are e aliiiulv Our community is rnmmuni' ti'll you they ■pHc of t In- II you they th ibil til »rn- hay ami ■ alt-el hay ;tml t* dairy train Ml Sliolllll over the ran. i mm ■am in \\ i|&gt;li- of N« tlu- n riM otil .&gt;n milk ami not ity. The food &lt;lair\ i From .1 mi\&lt;'"l stuck \\ &lt;• wciii ihroii|(h I he car until wr ui&gt;, Babcoch in .ill windmill, showing th* ind make it SILAGI \s \ MPPLtMtNT FOR NEBRASKA I I \( URES PAST (• C ASIISKS illy furnish enough food for mmer mi&gt;nths. In view of this • nn hi^h </seg>
            <seg id="p053">•■fiill \ \\ z s &lt; No. I m* fed life »a The </seg>
            <seg id="p054">51 \ S i S I&gt;1' T K N VO WS Acres idt Act* Seed |ht Acre Kverg ind from the Mury. l'ride Itly sulisi u uifil in u&gt; place. ThornuKh August sixteenth it »;i^ xt h tci the t went y-sixt h of rut daily. This iik' dry malUT |&gt;er acr led ti) pea- and oat extreme heat many of the The |iea&gt; that survived the heat a ;i&gt; planted t&lt;&gt; iiihIs of Mil l)finn it before they rearhf&lt;l the bottom. Thi» crop vsa- •&gt; t&gt; ton 8 |H*&lt;-k.- I ii ion.- 1&gt; iM&gt;unils 9 torn •&gt; |**&lt;-k !i Ions ti |&gt;»*cks each !• tOtW t&gt; (KTks t-ach 1 ■ ! tuns IN )x&gt;un&lt;ls 10 ton&gt; 1 5 liushels \'2 Ions 1 ."i hushels 9 ions 1 |K'cks - I lolls 1&gt; |MIUM«ls 13 ions 1 ."&gt; liiislnl- l(i ions 1 1 l&gt;u. rarh 111 Ions I '. iiu. tuck i i lie uhovr plant ing ill—. acII lei sow a vimtn; lllK'lil In- M&gt;« li ill I &gt;l :n &lt;• of •Mint: prop 1") T. i 1 was diviili'd inlo iM|iial ml om-i hinl of ai iirpd. harrowed anil .1 II </seg>
            <seg id="p055">tl'lot \ I was 'l&gt;-\ &lt;&gt; so poor t ii.ii ii n trntion \* mad </seg>
            <seg id="p056">53 tILING Alfalfa. Inwi uthtt *upm\ ALFALFA. Some other ex [wri- vork on this subject and i suliject and in . we And lhat |&gt;eas and Ml hem. we tinil lhat peas anil ml ran generally be countei ally lie counted Id generally l&gt;e sown as aooi generally he sow n as soon ling in the spring anil the second 11 t he spring and the MCMM • u.ik- later. Generally the early later. Generally the earl; tic in the tirst soviiriK :»nd ; Inn rid an excellent foragi I rst mi|| and a excellent forage •ry heavily and is palatalili eld- very heavily and is palatable I Iseil for sidlillt; lliree time: il-ed for -oilillt; three times • &lt;l on late in May or earh May or early md peas, and again just hefore tlr. id acain just hefore the emm rd nilling romps on just after the me&gt; l&gt;n just after the oiidensed Form the yield in tons of |T— ■ m the yield m tons ol ureei t lie act ual cost |irr ton m ual cost |ier ton a- I'AHLK II I'M \\&lt;-\d |xr Acn- |mt Ton Vidd Green r Acn- |&gt;er Ton Dry Dry Matter Gram Dry Dry Matter S *I4.W S $M.:«)' .'0 it; i«.5&lt;» 9 ll.:(5- I.M ll..io- o 12.00 .... Z.A Id. imi one nraaon'a ft-t-dinK nptwi- m the |)re\iotisly descrihed the tal&gt;le. the average oostt i lie siiilini; rropa &lt;;» j| .", </seg>
            <seg id="p057">I </seg>
            <seg id="p058">• Iiiik i \|&gt;iri i.ir. •,.■„, llail In In- of the \ alli-d t&lt;&gt; th«- x|&gt;tTim&lt;-Mi&gt; ;mr Npl&gt;ra~k;i s were tfi"&lt;&gt;» n Kami. Thi&gt;. ic e\|i rimeni ditiona </seg>
            <seg id="p059"/>
            <seg id="p060">he use of t he urself whether I lie 1 1 &gt; pasture l* a continuous by drouth. i ,1 itT. I team daily to rut and haul a supply gular farm work th tr ing as mj hurt age of wi k lids .if weather *us \I\IKK s|| \ ( ,h par I in !"•• harvenl MMKK SI I \i,h sity proceed slowly 'In system. There is absolutely ups and keep man mort soiling crops: that is, if her than the use of pasture. it. however, is rightly concerned chierly about I hail in the privilege of handling \ complete soiling system is enlirelv itiryinf and the ;m&lt;l inn' !&gt;&lt;■ uteh us to order lc&gt; 1V11I </seg>
            <seg id="p061">rompre bending •rarceiy r&lt; Km ■ hat he -i'fk t li.it Kovrrn i Ihmh </seg>
            <seg id="p062">59 aptai imi the hiilior America fade with sun :ir«- less ! han a locks ill the worlil. The sold and exchanged. You While here, you first u1c island the center touch wilti </seg>
            <seg id="p063">60 much romi ;il»olutely K«c«'|i dI t li - on t he sen: an \1. M \1 m* \ i. \i from I Kill This is ulii is as much diversity in ( farmers. Cheshire am) th the kingdom in dairy and you will find th two counties. In tin- county &lt;&gt;\ \ predominates. In fhwh rtrar -kir&gt; and mh Mil ■(riruhur ngland, is pr for tale l&gt; anil fiich farmer's maki </seg>
            <seg id="p064">61 renters a ■i itlk around mi no mile: Knglan.i Thames \I r made up h. It K more than 100.000,000 world London, in oicd for its art .mil rommon lie away from it ays with you. You can't w It is a (real magnet, drawing &lt;i lust thoughts of humanity - old and the Derby w.a&gt; killed in i&lt;l est uary a. i* really »it of ulility ;in&lt;i intelliifenre. the energy, rythinu that makes for </seg>
            <seg id="p065">cp I The din Dial, line \\r have in t H Atiot her I'ai-t 1 1 If i hey bad in tbw I hat we aave in i Ins r-ii lie impossible: ami we i iiic marki't conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">63 pend more or Mint htield market he market plan at Munich. Dresden ami and- out .1- MlllI iilielii American ideal goods, I lie uten- I'he conditions At Smithtield's markets will apply more i :. jl feature: Lc .ir the rive activities seven djacent street - inducted in building* and a part on the three or four d a vegetable » stands, hut Tor the most ivement. Kvery i he bare pavemei he llower- otection from dust ,mcv of the streei- arket. Sometime- &gt;« ol the market. These vegetal)!* great many cases, managed by women Inch these vegetables are sold. both. &gt;l the vegetable* themselve- The quality the market d a appetising appearance; meel t h&lt;- lowest grade &lt;&gt;l restaurant i the producer and only an apparent ldint;--. a,-r the booths for meal. Inside, the people doing e rendition* are much superior between .'1.110:1 anil ID. 1)011 people Kadi wnder sells onlj a -mall </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Tl l.b.1 111.- |.n- There i&gt; one t liini; t lily: ;iiul i Ii;ii \» t hal food*, i&gt; very li m 1 1 &lt;-&lt;i . nf perishable goods, i ■ aim hal \w ha\'f in \ 1 1 i — roul </seg>
            <seg id="p068">65 Jile Monday. Th* com tht - wirkt hap Parii in tht l?hm K . &lt;1 I he weight .lot \:i ill) London. S tly different t ra4t We.in in pi v • M ,H. th&lt; uliarili Danish buue.' will keep \\ leaking l&gt;.-\. without sittne.i pdiateiy nld keep lily thai or tm Normandy vaa rhat ii liiiii it had. eiiher I he inH hixl&gt; Danish butler, for I ideal: Inn tin- maiiu- hat may !»■ &lt;-allt*&lt;l </seg>
            <seg id="p069">I'asu \\. U Beriin. \\ ets in ■lumlit Vecki u F I'niled of |&gt; tilled perha country. Meats N meats and tht price </seg>
            <seg id="p070">67 thai they don't &gt;fl iliat we do. nt. food imiii youth between twenty and iiy. withdrawn from production nipt ion. In the middle of last the term of -service three : ■ Fact! I h;il have grt at </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Tl ■ w hole i&gt;l h t here .iiid&gt; of the the land i&gt; lieinn luted of cert; and enforced, prot </seg>
            <seg id="p072">69 \ev lal inu.'e Marly resemhle^ my knowledge K&lt;&gt;e.'. is the Kliitic. we understand that the Ru-uiri fron- </seg>
            <seg id="p073">I for ir i rue in tr in thai ri TIktc ii </seg>
            <seg id="p074">\ 71 isump- supply iiniriK the h:tt .if all n.iri h l.V.H- a.-i.ih iklllK 12 !.. itrritv LTOWth ur i ml u .tin amount mount d! !ir&lt;l m to the tit h (he hiri*. n- t- and settliliK dfst-rl II ' ;ivc more he winter, be ;unl &gt;ee t hi~i soil is t hirst i IOU » A' mill !&gt;«' lo I all of it hut does not </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Tl « 'i tills will prod farmer may If I I i farn nf artivitic* : bill i he problem up i ;ilily raiw i&gt;n I hi I his f I ;inil 1 I </seg>
            <seg id="p076">73 tility that Shmp ■ K .fat el iurcil. 1 1 »• rrop a k on his farm. his const ant iimI romnwrn ill the farm- ones, Inn ;i herd of eows well ■'■»&gt; i he alfalfa tad the lie alfalfa and the \\ hat iloes the man get from his at does the man set from his ■during a 'lillrmi: a exrrrta. Th» rail thai i&gt; pro- luring excreta. Thf calf ihai i* pr cash value The rxrreta it pit n The milk thai is prodlwtd m&gt;he&gt; i lie lieM of food for 1 i- nvwntial pan in butlrrfat. in rain is prod need, hogi may ba '■ animal on tin- farm, when tile hoc Where sou produce iirm. wh«r« \\ hfif you prodvrc "i- il i» I lie ideal place for poiil- ■in t li.ii ,-lean up i |,,. ,,,|,|-. -,,,,1 I \allle lii-lle.- I hail II lei u^ look al il from I he i-asli rank market for -heep and I he -ln-ep and i In- ■an ulwayx lind a cash marki-i an ul way* find a i-ash market Iways lind u placi- lo put to in always i,ml a ru«h marki-l always find a cash mark.-t ilways find a |i|aci- lo |&gt;ut tn i s on the farm. You can easily he farm to restore the fertility from i!. You can alway- n the farm. You can ea.-ily a •ta on the farm to restore the fertility .• taken from ii. You can always eet an aJwa] Hirii 1 hese other |)ro&lt;iucts i turn your hutte.-fat into i h. her product! OTBf is m the year. Now, to this h* year. Now, to t hi ■e and his home, this is the louse and his home, this is the cash Ks that make for happiness in that that make for happiness in that vided for him. in which they're rket is a iii-h market </seg>
            <seg id="p077">II H I \ ■/. •:::, loud- a 1 can on! Btht-ir prol soIv.mI .hi </seg>
            <seg id="p078">riON \l HOMF. AND ABROAD utter pr&lt; thai I should natural Like the Insh- issiiiu (he hat in 1 1 ■ Ireland!" II iiiK of men) ioning I he That- nuhl However, I &gt;hall imparison and 1)111 terfitl high**! II a&gt; trmi Kuroi oil ,, mil buy ms hanl to with urns!.. hat a I the e»w. more than l.'ill way from i&gt;»s are paying a . hird are heinic he avera^f for 1 Ho tka Station b&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p079">411.7 pounds w pounds of butter The result conducted uml [&gt; ears a«o I4&gt;4 |"&gt;u ire.lit. Nei unsocial Kx-(i uveraKt ■ i&gt;." product 1 1 Knuland Tin- co\\&gt; 925 pounds of m of the Scottish milk On the farm o) Mr. \ ■re found 178 Ayrshi Mr. Cross, uveraged ah hulterfat. per day. Over 12 tured on this farm annualh U dairy school that the 40 A\ </seg>
            <seg id="p080">Holland H.i Rhine [is - given \u in. Toil pounds ot have calved omc cowl ha\e given as much it H not mui-h ■-aid id have tited several farms where i- vielding at) high a- To and Ml pounds hern Germany, H'iKieiii Frisian l»**i tits the I A I).-. IK inn \o« somewhat m th • « pi lamed lireed lii ear and 11. iiim in 15.000 cattle. Mr ilion, informed was better thai, it. while some Mr. Alfred La Pateu- land. stated that the tunda of milk or 4iK) averaged better than cow i&gt; t he principal in • hy (iair;. ing dairj mtf Ku.npeaii countries th.. mm countries than at ram. However, t he iw- However, the -icitTed in determining rmining land worth Irom $100 om $100 1 « icing corn yielding ten tons, alfalfa tiding ten ions, alfalfa better. la pa 11,000 is not capable digestible nutrient- Mr Glover, in a very able Milk Production" stated that ■ ntsining 280 pounds of fat in a </seg>
            <seg id="p081">.in.! ab Ac. ii. ; &lt; Bu s furni Holland and ( '■•m|i»i°i our i m| of money ixp difference, and t northern Germai rating ■ threuhi y ti) foriy-tivc by tday and per bo third &lt;-ent* per under similar .1 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">'. ten head ■iual milking and hand- Therefore. *re far ask. 'Ho* can und we li is time for natural all the kill: let us il herds and feed .leaner «&gt;■ will e with i In best of European dairv countries ink as LFALKA AND ITS FEEDING USE ON THE DAIRY F\RM vim-e&lt;i iential home grown frowe upon the farm ■omparati vely shor' ily the great hardiness native sned.lt is also t- purchased from the that seedsmen intention - • vh.v nature of the cmse source from which their h ate the ma be marketing of iviitH,- than here tetter ilairymun. rows; he knows and also under- 'tt'u-ienl manner. h;uu!s be </seg>
            <seg id="p083">I \ N labor « EkiiiR mi ,r. l'.u obsen he present DCI OH I A not her eler generally ;i ntnins, I" nl* </seg>
            <seg id="p084">81 seeding plant lilVOi'ublt vminatinn wil ti Roots will hen riled. The The Man&lt;l ili'ari • lirouth or t.i wturc in I n 1 be given ih.- nb fiu-li t h • I- rn hf Mil)*. &gt;\»i I :;; 13 Ih.- Ill th&lt;- I han onilil utfi. Iiimii ilim I ids o; Himevrr ly when both alfalfa Generally speakinK he plant ling crop, without T by the mower from c-ontact with lit under it. Since </seg>
            <seg id="p085">he Ix Tl \ II ii|ipr&lt;i.\ima »rittV&gt; judgment will it* \ i&gt;f I.eiti-r ™«&gt;. more alfalfa nary t&lt;&gt; make Neb profitable form of agri&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p086">)ND DAYS SESSION KKASKA PI RF. FOOD COMMISSION nuch pleased to xtended by the advance (hat 1 I had the ability Kr;i)!&lt;lsen and some other My part of t be bu*inm he statute !"■• ii in I he dairy bu«iiw wry Iuiik Nebraska'* greatest riaaunin \ at est icsiiu 1 in', ul tier industry III ll|ilillllii than any other industry tu ii|&gt;lniilii eportx oi ilic various Food nniinih fom- liy, recently I ma m u^ loud rommis he tust ic;il food ci&gt;miiH»ioiier I li.lt ommissioner t hat &lt;'. Baavrtt. In I Ji i- rcpinl are &gt;hmi&gt; tementa and I jotted dowa «&gt;ne w ■ in you i In- Morning. 1 I lotted ciniMi mi morning. Thes meenth annual report ol the or the year l!»oj. i had im i&lt;iea oi I a (in dayo ago, that it vu -. ItrovixJORK hi i In- law atoof otka* aw along other &lt;■ in rooking or lieiii){ served mi the ■ Iii rooking or lieing served on t lie ■ )ni&gt;tec| iii I'cinspiruiius place on the hieh inu.-i stale " Imilaliiin Hutter siilliiient to drive liutterine out of I served to some extent p to the require- unre I asked one liiiiements of the law )» there was surh a Ise I would have i drop the liutte.llie hi. I don't da.-e to put up that un my liusini - ore to run il with that 5!l for earh offense «t be cave good intentions of mplished the desired had ar Ig i-oiiltnission today is the • These departments were operated eads. The oil pa.t has </seg>
            <seg id="p087">l mma nan » Hid ( I M Bak&lt; Hoi. Dai, MiscH </seg>
            <seg id="p088">4. -'4 5 inler this has ben Hid with Mi orcement »S4.&lt; Thiaia alloimeni \\&gt;- il^|&gt;arl mt'iit iiu|&gt;&lt;- I'M I. » kliimn as t hn In- food anil sanita- I'nion ami u lien I tinishnil Im-i sanilation law of that law in 1H1 I books coverinit th* inn in have for riismbution somr posted up in quirement* ol thai </seg>
            <seg id="p089">86 M Mk K, to rut Railroai In addii nit; to build up &gt;f the Kniahed dairy produrt. \\ law. We h-.r • ■ kUc tO ilu&lt; Dai «&lt;■ are Mill product*. I attended ■id the niiiji </seg>
            <seg id="p090">87 be daai he ea ixeessfully hen » tte oi N'ci xhihltinn at nil i&gt;w ami we are i;oinK show for menls. We have . . I h. ill t here is to lie ml of it I think Ae have the best agricultural exhibit in the ear alter year. (1 the excellence horticultural illy that loubled the educational exhibition of any « he swine dairy industry when i he dairy end of the I have ii make an ex- ole horticul- xhibition. I am m I ing that lown Kl \\1 AND ITS RELATION TO THE BABCOCK TEST undalion of an liken in securing well hi' discarded, for without K°&gt;nK to ined little if he has not realize the 1 he test and using every tuple represents the material being ti amples from individual 1 t lie physical prop </seg>
            <seg id="p091">HI IlinK I trruratf &gt;;im f»rtor&gt; — . or i vi Keeping with (M-ia&gt; in m </seg>
            <seg id="p092">arv so many able ngugfd in th«- Ilii-es with nu - ll business. I Iili\&lt; iation </seg>
            <seg id="p093">90 B"&gt; a h u i 7 ami : Kuijh (iiir cily (il l.im live (in so little. li inn Hid dairyiiif In !(i the far fellow hifh-pric I rcmcmliiT t h. rnating about fa we do im &gt;t K« j t ■frirult ural n^s </seg>
            <seg id="p094">91 I \ I Kt-ry; I whom I with his studies hii-h I bel ■■eat ■ mittory we are I believe thai Nc llll iral h of farmitiK. here we know Miss ii:" that on nv wife and children. It was hililn-n \\ i were much impressed with ■eturn through Missouri and i made a&gt; ck a Nebi Aupla MMIKI \ \ K K V 1 \KkS in fllANCK.I.I.OK II im abonl mellot A very. l&gt; (iKNTI.KMKN: Vnur UK as a row man lately, but 1 can veral month- of xluction possibly that itizen ol Nebraaka and rests of the univer I rk of dairying and in the w iny ifreat industry of this PF of people can </seg>
            <seg id="p095">. V university. l&lt; Heal inn (il i In- phi I may &gt;a\ Kh have lieen illil men's aaaociatic &gt;ul assuming to ■H I f.-.-l. Ill Tfctl'll OUt I </seg>
            <seg id="p096">on rHE AVERAGE I R&gt; 93 I \R\l I » a&gt; al all n K ht ul 1 1 1 1 ♦* 1 he £&gt;;"'• ■ .rl ( il \1 r I i IIUIIll Ml \ olds. These ll llHtflll lust iif I hex A nd extra feed put into the ro» - k produced. One eow pro.; M. (tighter W.....I. u HiKhi up; hi- man Of l hi heft- we fed lh&gt; (••♦• I Thi** »as </seg>
            <seg id="p097">94 \ iurl any dii (Ml «&lt;i 1 hat I) \IR\ I \&lt; &gt; &gt; V ui'ali Ii "I n« lain ile\ elopn i la &lt; tittii- lie va nun ill I hi- ron\ en( ioi n territory, and 1 am now the |irn&lt;ii ha.- been abundant Nebraska can financial!) i»u&lt; MC nu-ti here ;uul there through i Kheir husineaa since the rounl rows ihi-outjh the -iiinmer them have al some time of finam est mmttff lifter known in farm cow to avert tinuncial tiis;i- panies maintained ikimniaf itati wa- for a few \eai- an immeni wa.&lt; hauled as high as twenty m every man who owned a cow w;&lt; the cominK dairy country of Ni everv man was a ranee cowma </seg>
            <seg id="p098">ON VE NTION 95 omplished the desired i untry after sur. ;i d pioneering troubles ash was a nec« .1 r ihev once more A business for which ume&lt;l in port ant to us, only hing else would do so ry hill, and do jrts as dairy rows las aesiern Nebraska!^ M jllldy companies paid for As in I he creamery companies who iKh daily country, they tin in their judgment lairying was a good thing for northwest ■Hi Nebraska was ■ fair ba.-is for dairying. Nebraska was a fair ha.-is for dairying. lldgmenl of the men. who were nut dairy- the men. who were not dairy- rymen. There is a difference, however, rvmen. There is a difference, however. i of today and of that period. Farmers dav and of that period. Farmers siness is stable; mushroom growths are developments may come now will lie dairying again assumes (treat importance i- stable; mushroom growths are developments may come now will lie lairying again assumes (treat importance rmaiuntly. and it is my judgment that right nently. and it M my judgment that right me dairymen is crystalizing IB the mind* Nebraskans. No men in that section art me dairymen is crystalizing in the minds Nebraskans. N men in that section are ■ sentiment in that regard than the men ll lit regard than the men Ml arm. and we know that dairying must ow that dairying must m. and we k lustration, five years agV dairy cows »ert igo dairy cows were V country, whereas, during December. 1919 s in excess of 34M head. Five yea countrv. whereas during December, 1913, (111 head. Five ye;. XI s In I h&lt; cemetery at birth. Now w - and have ovei- |M liulls heading he^^ it birth. Now we can lit cemet and have over 1 1&gt;0 hulls heading herds ■nd doing a great deal to make it a land of d doing a gl— &lt; deal to make it a land ol change vet is observable in the public Bilge yet is observable in the public I lairyinr A few vears ago I think a dairy •itiK. A few years ago I think a dairy oided by polite society, whereas now, most i-d by polite society, whereas now. most ids of men who frequent the dairy farm: who frequent the dairy farms k and learn dairy wisdom. Being dairymen you •am dairy wisdom. Being dairymen you You wonder if a logical reason exists for niu wonder if a logical reason exists foi -ibed it. Kit northwest Nebraska is a slock countrj - a stock country, but stock must h» \. liraska is a siock country country, but stock must be han was the cise a few years ago. Then i- country, but evolution and Kinca : d put an end to k omesteadc &gt;n every possible pi- hrouga the winter on the native grass -helien-il ihrough i he winter, or the </seg>
            <seg id="p099">» io.i.l,-.- ,:. tl eighteen y* IlilS I 111' 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">\&gt;l&gt;rask \\ l.-.l I' KI\N(l HI RAISING DAIRY CALVES A N N ma i it her.l A </seg>
            <seg id="p101">I, II </seg>
            <seg id="p102">yt'M &lt;liri|{&gt; ill, al that A 111 urmul will it offered I 111' l'M» allowed to milk ounK ewil is Ik. Kiifhl •oiicr amount \ iiuiiiiils or t hrcH </seg>
            <seg id="p103">A \\ i| </seg>
            <seg id="p104">\ </seg>
            <seg id="p105"/>
            <seg id="p106"/>
            <seg id="p107"/>
            <seg id="p108">\ \ \ I I ) I N ( . I &gt; ■ \ DAIRY 1 1 f. R D </seg>
            <seg id="p109"/>
            <seg id="p110">Ml i&gt; \l R Y &lt; ( &lt;\\ </seg>
            <seg id="p111">\ </seg>
            <seg id="p112">1 \ \ ,1 ,1 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">A V II </seg>
            <seg id="p114">111 llpllshe 11. »r « .il i&lt;l 1 • so often, ;i|&gt;p.-&lt;l up iuuiom Kit nun- iiifii- • ( I ;i silujt'' »■' •I nlafc would </seg>
            <seg id="p115">~l </seg>
            <seg id="p116">I \ </seg>
            <seg id="p117">A </seg>
            <seg id="p118">u H \ </seg>
            <seg id="p119">\l </seg>
            <seg id="p120"/>
            <seg id="p121"/>
            <seg id="p122">I. K K </seg>
            <seg id="p123">farmer wrong end to. Of better than lie does. Hi- -av- down there the farmers lui before i h There nave beei ■ in think t h If I should business who imaha, al durers w ho u Kt . Calhoui • •nts per quart. \\ stnctioMs products, as ■cam silo on his far he silo hut a producer of high&lt; nables him to produi and also in the winter time when tl In this connect largf cities today, ;i {real deal of i With the breweries sell it cheap. 1 know been feeding malt rat . 1 1 plished, hut they &lt;1&lt;&gt; not al» ■ in the u»&lt; I am prepa sikiK*- when the (It higher p therefore have milk whe nimm ■ supposed 10 be ;i eh ii has also a very nut </seg>
            <seg id="p124">121 sideboard* 1 U&gt; haul this mal im with two or tl he vear. and the work of tore expense to the ,-enty acre* of corn in the silo. This, it ttrmtion of the value of silos. ting into the different systems or met I iK into I he different systems or methods of losi of y:&gt;u are familiar wiih it, and no will follow me. will bring out this point. losi of v:&gt;u are familiar with it, and no ollow mi j . will bring out this point. recedes) or example. In Europe, we rind example. In Europe, we find i priced land. better dairy products and lairy products and hey can undersell the American fa butter in produced on made land. They marshes and the low-land.s. tilling them. lured on made land. They marshal and the low -lands, tilling them per aive to till. There are other res &gt;ei- ace in till. There are other re.i out. why Kuropean farmers can under- e, letter care of the row-, and better grade of cow a.e of the cows and better grade of ler-sell ua. Here is an illusi ration showing carried on. The Danes buy our corn at under-sell us. Here is an illustration showing n l&gt;e carried on. The Danes buy our corn at •ems a bushel higher than ou.- farmer- Ml a bushel higher than our farmer- .ind enrich their soil with the manure w hich nd enrich their soil with the manure which raise potatoes on this enriched soil and ;iise potatoes on this enriched soil and e ill the United Slates. Two years ago. Kuropean i'nited Slates. Two years ago. Eur&lt; n Omaha. How did they do it'. 1 By constructive (I dairying. This mean.-, succulent feed for their la. How did they do it.' By constructive ing. This mean.-, succulent feed for their McKay points out in one of his bulletins points out in one of his bulletins rip. thai the English farmer is producing oui of a dual purpose or type of animal that the English farmer is producing il purpose or type of animal iu ey on land, on which they pay from six hi land, on which they pay from six I Some tenants make as much as our nanta make as much as ou hey HM rOOtl anil plenty of succulent feed. talking with some of those farmers some nd plenty of succulent feed. H king with ome of those farmers some |O. Their milk and cream prices are just I asked some of these tenants why they Their m Ik and cream prices are just I of these tenants why they I asked son 1 States and buy and have a farm of their ind have a farm of their How much do your farmers make?" 1 lem make $1,000.00, some $500.00, some $ Li • 1. Him. Hi), some IMO.M, some$-Jii lid. " We can average as well i We can average as well here." and 4!i cows. How do these farmer 10 COWS. How do these farmers pay nake money? They have succulent fee r\ .' They have succulent feed. McKay, and other authorities tell us we can- Kay, and oi her authorities tell us we ean- p on we can on corn silage. I lots a we can on corn silage. I len posteri on the milk industry in the Europe, whv the farmers there did not ■n posted on the milk industry in the the farmers there did not II. l there. In Germany, it mnot rai im up was ilest roved by frost •orn. This ai they don't have - </seg>
            <seg id="p125">\ M They do 1 he next I hay. ! bey d&lt; alfalfa hay and I.. Mr. Borma time compel us to necessity. We ibou now hefore us. beet w -ary. we si as the opportui K hi lies. 1 times as wo \\ Bd expo ltina ai Nebraska Ttu ■■product If our to I hat on i into th. the pro, in the state of Ni of one-sixth of i he size ol \&gt; support more eowi than l(i to silage on I he la i today. If we would add the add of producing this eh which is not unreason more to the value saving to the farn liut the cost nl hi one To two cell! H K:i.()no all o only twei farm »hoi Y.TV littli Switzerland. r warranted in i So that »;;■ Bl»v year. The I) tiKuriiiK Nebrask; woulil l&gt;c $500,009,000 0 the farmer in produi </seg>
            <seg id="p126">\ \ 123 wo-rifths of our We will let this m That is not th. arm, dairying followed. products on this land irs. I feel that the products he sells but there mers would be ahead, even His p.-otits would he would raise on his farm from &lt;&gt; land sii rich but what it will become fa/mintf. Some of it may ;i later it will become oiiic necessary. The ques- lised. During the Kaster Omaha, in 1913, a group of farm build- lemolished; I he bottom of a silo was left stand- hai --ilos are about as sub- low Now ihat we have Marled the silo su: on and 1 hope t hat every person will take nil-important subject '"•: klh silos earn if the dairy mem thai "a ton of alfalfa costs nd. $ln. m;" be received his room. I understand. mi^ht have been that the statement was I was anxious to w I liil to ha\. I Washington, I), c. before the corn im- ,is thai three and one-half tons of i one toa of alfalfa, and then said that alfalfa &gt;.■ thereabouts. OS iich a remark had ar t ha tatement as that pted we would me up he.e to speak iih better qualified than answer inquiries of how to them, and such things as much as I would Iih her day which. I believe I xpe.-iment station record that I hat when corn is put in showed from 1 to It </seg>
            <seg id="p127">per cent loss: the Colorado exp corn is cut as stove,- and shock* or piles, that 4:i per cent of dry natter is lot a hen you feed rive ions, one if you follow that corn stover in your barn. Wt Mk. Tempi w h&lt; time be put then ii uild sih and quite a s Illinois. He pin told me that we producing at that ii the proposition. 1 boui in fact 1 bought a w hoi commenced to tared ii fodder than 1 could U! it until the sap i must he careful about my corn is all right no could have been done ii lie left in the tield until w md I Bnjc you can put it il next year. It i In regard to alfalfa. Ki and put up a silo, in dairying i hat yo ving to Ket the besi occasion. I would 1 a in :u rai lu pensive feed. I' noi lieen -dUU ill my own mini • up as I r; alfalfa. [ bave money. 1 can which I consider Mk. SKVIBB a mai </seg>
            <seg id="p128">125 1 'I H. C. Voun ;i .1 toundi nl silage unit ground corn than any lushed. We produce right here at home In my opinion, they are not to be com iiry. You know one is a carbo-hydrate feed oiein; they are supplementary. They are simply her than as a substitute for one another. We I have put up silos every year and am getting We grow lots of alfalfa. We use alfalfa and silagf I one helps the other t hey are nature's I rind with our cattle age to alfalfa when imd for that rea in it is more palatable So when a man comes practical facts and we have no use for his figures stall'. Applause. T h. e ia one point further bring up and that i he use of the silo all the seem to hall or kick ice a good many farm It is quite a pn P« sit ion on our farm to That empty silo gets hing that needs d and he cannot shake off. During tin iiising corn he middle of lun Immediately afterward Tie land, if we do ot use it for soiling, and In that way we have 1 have used the silo he year rcund. Some ce house 1 would rather use &gt;lying feed for my will give bell I think there is one poini that has not been touched lere. this alfalfa and silage question. In the first •nsilage you will save from one-third to one-half you feed the right amount of ensilage the ( eh alfalfa as otherwise, but ii does them more all alfalfa or all ensilage; and a man raising al - lion of his alfalfa and have plenty left. Let me nythinj; myself. I would like to try man's question in regard to the compi xcess iii anything mes to eating it. W* cattle bunks and keep it baton them, but to feed silage they are right t he/e every one alfalfa and go to the silage. Why? Re liKestion of t he ot h&lt; ly lijjures out that silajje ii"es noi pay us, ■ ur farm and putting iilonu with i hi iV*mI (or in y i-aule. That is what silos vc liciier resuhs ui that than anything v.&lt;&gt; cvops a yea.' for your silos. A|&gt;- feed on earth for mi; dairy cows. Alfalfa and revolutionin the dairy proposition altogether. tail known, twenty years ago. when I was rais- . what I do now. 1 would have had I silo and ahead of where I am now. 1 have l&gt;een guile interested in this discu </seg>
            <seg id="p129">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN ASSIH \ repent, that when you feed alfalf I figure that one ton of alfalfa is worth thret by combining t he t w almo on account because sili at the suprenu who ought uiiwillnn lilo manuf vocating tr doing that 10 the nit ■if sill if these things have no dissai the silo will adv natural for us p personal interest, lint of the state at t he san interest. I am not look u slate meetings this week 'X tin there are lots of crank ■■ meetings as well as tl I come from near the I have referred to it as after: those fellows thai I am not talking almut the irrigation fellows becausi- il a class by themselves. I an annual rain fall in Nebrask for themselves and their m it your lilage, an&lt;l w 1C. H .IKKK I) lit I IMM in wh; lively i-fccin ■ not In a man t ha and lei it h m1&lt;&gt;. I think. much inte public throucho I uft ■ leu uf pleasure think many of them eongreg Ve referred to it as the sem K it semiarid region. Tho: </seg>
            <seg id="p130">127 ( ne.it silos, hollow wooilen silos and cement &gt;e a make-shift, but it n of the central and w. ything if he has a few prin- n i eta his association lid •pare ■ paper upon pit hin 1 did not prepare any &gt;f the use of the pit silo up in How I don't want to take any credit down here to the school of agriculture blame, if there is any blame to be attached. him my farm. He said. Dad. I would "You know Dad. you are some relation w. Dad cannot make a barrel stand up during the whole &gt;es not propose to put his money into ■ sta. down down the first season after it had ) nish material to put down a pit silo h the boy will furnish the labor." which h. iierimented on a 1« by 40-foot silo. \\ xperimental basis, however. We put up n pit silo has given us absolute satisfaction poring here at this time and tellini. understood and carried back to the home* ■eople who are here today. I will give you , he experience and our neighbors, because if there is one siln country there are now probably fifty ranging he small farmer who has a little bunch u twenty feet in diameter, and fifty feet unty. and there are some fellows up thert 1 think twenty feet in diameter is about tht build a silo to be successful. The main me to put on your cement on the wall tly Mat surfaces, so cement would not here were something that it could adhere perpendicular wall therefore the larger he thicker you should put on cement plaster. I because by doing so it may give the We simply commenced by making a ring a the ground and several inches abovi nine work. We then made a box stable and we used it to hoist our icie from which place we afterwards eeded. When we got the silo dug. we plast- ume over it. We housed that silo. imental but we were experimenting. \\ &gt;■ n 'tilled three times. The wall of that U e put on rwo coats of cement plaster </seg>
            <seg id="p131">E slushed with pure cement just had very good line sand, and we cemeni to three parti sand. T Id in concrete and I believe the (or the reason that the silaK to the cemeni unless you nut There is an and that is to I settles it drop the freshl tributer, a tr to the distributer. W before anybody noes down in the down we test it with a liar you don't want here is possibly a lit avoid it. Please do pleasant publicity to the i] protil in i h&lt; t ha sihiK«' can l&gt;e i u M in the ecu' Ela.-ly. Wh. ■ spoiled si • that. Tl he.- of mi-i E; it is absolute! ni)t run in. ht step in -P&lt;&gt;il your rilage. A Ely lihed ■ hi till one shore ground; l&gt;ui when « I \m&gt; i&gt;r three years aK" ■ P hut I believe it was throuKh I 1. - e not heard of a earn There is any umnui nder that manufartur </seg>
            <seg id="p132">129 \ sider it :i pleasure to be to- talk ■ few minutes in support i ld outline of my subject and if u tl hai you wish to ask 1 will be pleased to i get the silage out? y that we take it out of a wooden t of getting the silage out? ptting the silage out just about offsets i a cemenl or wooden silo. About half i silage and about the same cost to drop us it is to elevate it :!() or 40 feet out k every man of experience in filling his silo akes almost as much power to elevate it: way with the pit silo. The boys say 1 a hundred cattle out of a silo than to take in the tield and gather the fodder. H ill e\er heard or had experience of there t silo right through the season, to go down liout any precaution? 1 Mated a little while ago that there has been leraonal knowledge there in our section of the mber of silos up there. There are two. merit the I mom? t one l&gt;ut WC did not the second. The nds to cement the next one. building I solid concrete silo above one b ielow ground for the same price? it know. I would not know until I had handled mud sil&lt; i test your silo for gas every time you go that part of the country fire damp instances. My hoys never pay any are inst \\ t have never had an instance of mean 16- fool silo in circumference? in l&lt; Ksrios: It was simply ■ round hole deep \ &gt;st you $150 \ *ith the hoisting apparatus, track and litter .ir labor and everything. I figure it coat ause we did not know a good many things und out iiclude your cutter? </seg>
            <seg id="p133">130 Answer: No, sir. QUWTION: What did your ratter em Answer: I think the cutter cost about $150 QUESTION: Did you have difficulty in makiriK Answer: Yes. the first one we dug. we did we got to the bottom. The consequence was that A ready to plaster or cement the wall had dried out i: The last silo we built, we cemented it as we wetn &lt;1 A it by means of a swinging platform. We wet the wa i on the cement. In the second silo we built we di scaffold. We would dig H or 7 feet and plaster and cement tht again and plaster and so on dow &gt;n QUESTION: 1 wish to ask you for my ow a there are any wooden sik up Answer: Lots of them. I have a neighbor wl^ Band it was blown do again if he had to pa own on the bottom hi ft n last summer. He said he would the full price of a new one. Hut t h» d where he could not make a pit silo QUESTION: Have an m blown dc Answer: Very few buckles through ignoran&lt; Oc&lt; ;i also one thing that should be remembered, w T crop in that locality las na more silos now. I have a neighbor who has ont deep and twenty feet in diameter. H 60. I said. "Ain't you going it a little stror gracious, no. Shall we with 4 of a good year, allow like this one. when w a the ground?' QUESTION: What do you tigure your Mlagt Answer: About $:i a ton but conditions. Our silage, in the silo as I can estimate it without keeping amounts to about $3 per ton. » her QUESTION: Would that be ( K Answer: Yes. There is another thing condition up there this past year. This la us more than it did the year before considering two or three acres to get the same or usual amount of silage. T year I think we only got about 450 ton of silagt ,i estimate it. I A MEMBER: I have a silo west of Lincoln dug t in diameter forty feet deep. Myself and two hii could dig and plaster five feet in two days, tak plastering the walls. We dug this fall at the si rtment or rather Prof. Chase, of Paw net- City. \ this fal red me (ing the dirt out uggestion of this ■7c began during </seg>
            <seg id="p134">A 131 A ■i ir « i the twenty-ninth of October we put the We hud to run in quite a bit of water; we did us we should skis: I don't want to be misunderstood, if I talk subject of pit silos, but I am a man who believes pit silo or a stave silo. Years ago I was ic silo for the reason that I could buy alfalfa :.."&gt;(! a load and all the hay I wanted by the alks at fifty cents an acre. But when alfalfa got ould not afford to buy any more, so I had to cast about aper feed. So I talked the matter over with my boy». jt cement silo and stave silo. We had an old cistern in use for twenty years. It was in perfect order &gt;ut the frost line. So we agreed upon the pit silo if ike the mial stick to the side of the wall, which we could do. Wi had been discouraged about the pit silo. d that if we bi'ilt one and it failed we could still have it a cistern 01 reservoir. So we constructed a pit sdo ell pleased with it that we have put in another one. go ir.io a long detailed account to tell you how we I want to say that the expense of getting the dirt duced to a minimum. They tell us about the time in going up into an elevated silo to get silage as compared ime of going down into a pit silo. My boy timed himself lay. He took out two twenty-seven boxfuls from a depth feet and elevated it himself and emptied it into the om the time of arriving at the silo and driving away was fourteen and one-half minutes. There were about bus bell in each boxful. I think this can be done in time. If you wish you can pull up fifty bushels at a time. this: How about the cost of the silos? kk: 1 think my first silo cost me about $1.'J5, 1M by M \ lude the work of the three of us all the time. at it at different times. I did not keep any accurate xpense. The second silo cost me a little over $100. it was on account partly because we used the same rope, the same other things that were used in the construction of the 1&gt; by :(0 feet. We constructed it by building a brick feet below the surface, in order to get below the probable ..II and from there down we cemented on the dirt wall. There w even a check in that wall. QUESTION: How do you manage about fire damp or gas? Asswkk: The boys have treated that matter as a joke. The two years they put down a couple of rabbits in the pit silo id left them there until springtime. At other times they have ropped in a couple of chickens for that matter. If they die you ptter keep out. In a silo thirty feet I do not think there is any anger. We elevate the silage with a drum eighteen inches in diam- </seg>
            <seg id="p135">M eter. You can make the drum gentleman asked how fast we dug that we had three digging and two h from 4 to 5 feet in a day. H go as fast. We cemented the bottom draw the center, and in t h&lt; we filled the silo it w of water into the silo. TY was pretty dry hut 1 1 After we got below t hi \\ Kwith great as the boi dumps itM'l Question: l~ Answer: It i QmmoN: ii Answer: 1 Ii county. You ea not be troubled i any water ther THE VALUE OF CORN I do not know you already have had. 1 of hearing Prof. Spill ma ever, been told that h pensive feeds used on our as a feed for aoriei something regarding my le dairy cows. I am told that I" silage as compared to alfalfa b of silage with the total nutrients of alfalfa. Now, regard method of comparison will sa\ has found any equitable basis of the feeds rich in protein w The protein and the emrbohydra radically different purposes when taken into the iys1 analysis will determine th P in the feed. It. however B center, and m the &lt;&lt;ntt as to act as a drain nvi You nefd no h«-a\ a yard of din at I wish some </seg>
            <seg id="p136">133 1 I i i \l w I compare the total with any iliigm could arrive at I lie relative valui il simply by eoaipwiag the w &lt;-i^ht &gt; feeds cine with the other and say that ;ind one in protein. The protein is The cow needs protein to restore worn out dition to this she requires protein to supply in elements in milk. No other substances place of protein and without it she cannot if milk. In addition to this protein or tin, i-eds the cow must have each day in her feed she needs to keep up body heat and body feeds supplying these elements is generally ■h in energy or carbohydrate material. Th.-se nutrients then serve radically different pur - xplains why they can not he compared simply ment of one to that of the other. Alfalfa protein. Corn silage owes its particular value T energy producing constituents. Should we ci.ii silage with alfalfa from a protein point irse. would have hut slight value. Hou e made from the energy standpoint the result fferent. KU ».il (IK (OMPAKIM KEEUi il and scientific way of comparing MM iparc the protein content of one feed with that IKAI' sill Hi KS OK PKOTKIN Kid Lbs. Dec. -2\&gt;. Itll) Trotein 10 $rj 50 *.05!»5 16.1 :!L'.-"&gt;n .Mtt 8».« :i2.5d .(t»i91 Z7.5 -(5.5(1 .0845 ■U.dd .0775 1775 12 on 111 19.00 .OiKSl Rergy &lt;-&lt;&gt;nl cril ml mm feed as compared Lbs. DiccMtiMe Prmimi l',-ic«- Cost «&gt;f l i.i&gt; •'■'"'■in per Ton TTifliMl </seg>
            <seg id="p137">134 to t he rim, I her ■&gt;, mention mini value from the teed t hat has n&lt; Km silage, in some way percentage of all her of this kind. In summing up ■Mt kind of a way. 1 corn silage that she \v pound of grain for ■ of whirl ndicated B mellow seems Mi add It is believed i h </seg>
            <seg id="p138">be mixture us long guming in l&gt;ody weight. &lt;&gt;m which the Rood feeder f*e. nothing that will take I.t rTER SENT OUT BY R. W. McGl NNIS. PRESI - NF.BRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. \ Nkhk.. November 1. IMS. tk&gt;n with and the assistance ;irm extension department of at ion. and the Northwestern un a dairy train over Nebraska, taking information homesteaders in thai section out to the meetings early in night anil the interest taken men and everyone, has led ive sti.-red up should in some bankers and merchants in Ne m w inquire if you K that might be called nery men. hankers. ux muuH-iution.s, etc., who ml in hand, with i lie idea of put- I' t lie dairy inter- ids to you and in HKiliK about t he Me replies were re- UK WIKKIKs Central City Lincoln Superior Omaha willitlK I" meet with K. McGinni ka Dairymen'* Amorimtion. </seg>
            <seg id="p139">136 Kotnanelli- Cn Ravenna Crea Golden Rod ( Columbus Cn Alim Fran I 5; 5 M |i\ . I U»n ih-&gt; I*. Shalk-nl K. Ncwtiin M Talmai 1 ) ISitou s '1 MlMti'f P. W. Mil .1. K. O'Donm r. c. n.Im.m \\ II I- I. Hall M. (. n Mil. \l \\ . I- Cl I.. I' Ks. Mil s. c&gt;i ■ S. II </seg>
            <seg id="p140">137 Lnu-oln Unrola Linr«l. Linroln l.l,,r,,|n Lincoln Lincoln Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p141">138 Nun liwc Harris (Jran.l Isimi Trail »n roar I he Ifct un th. A«ri H. r \1 I. II lie \ ion r am Trannn Hushn.- ~ka D liulltr fai liultiT fat A making A H..K at ion Kl in full. a&gt; each stop. &lt; anil I hr l A « ; :;;fE THE LOG Of THE 1&gt;AIR&gt; I RAIN Hurling to her «a t li«- |&gt;ro|x Bl for i be n ■ pu lil H*ri'»ii h is given I h&lt; numlier of people in at ten </seg>
            <seg id="p142">\ 139 Ksti mated Attendance \\ ake \ e Kiln. 7(10 Cody 111(1 7oo Merriam 100 \I ;iln ooo Gordon I, Mi Gord II Jim Kushville 500 Hay Spring! KMt 10 Hay Spring 500 Chadron &lt; hadr Whim Tim Whitney IM 11)11 Harrison IM Utn Harri •J7o Crawford :too 200 nd Week Burlington Route Crawford jrlington Route Crawford nber L"J. i he route of the ilairy tram I he Burlington was taken up. the train At this |ioint I). Clem Deaver, lm- t. September --. the rMltc of the ilairy tram i-i- i hi- Burlington was takes up. t hi- train 11. At this point I). Clem Deaver, lm- BurlinKton, joi ne&lt;i the train, for (he week's B. l.ainson. Agriculturist, of the Burlington infton, joined the train, for (he week's .amsoii. Agriculturist. ( ,f the Burlington ire at Chicago. Superintendent W. H. nt Chicago. Superintendent W. H \lliatne Division joined the train with hi •e Division joined the train with his e train during the time that it moves week's trip started forth under very Hid week's trip started forth under very weather cool and fine and the lecture it her c-ool and fine and the lecture unday in Crawford. the Sterling division of the Burlington jndav in Crawford master of the SterliriK division of the Burlington ■ in charge of the train on that division. as did also Prof. E. M. Little of Silver lecturers and assisted in the demon- htield as did also Prof. E. M. Little of Silver Mated in the demon- T &lt;&gt;!■ Tow \s TOW s Ued Kstimaled lie- Attendance s.") Semra JIKI Kstimatetl Attendanre JIKI 'I'hedford _'!)() Thedford 7(10 Halaey Mai -no Dunning ng Hill Ansel mo IM Ansel n mill Merna 7.1 Broken Bow 1.0(10 Mei t Broken Bow l.')ll Ansley 7011 l.')ll A lisle SM l.itchtield .'&gt;IIO Litrhtield 150 Ravenna TM Cil Nland </seg>
            <seg id="p143">140 \!t i !HI RKI.ATION 1)1 IHh KMLKOADS ill ,1({.mI K 1:111 win) i tied milk rmw niiini liccuusc hi (iiii'il. In .1 liunc-h ol cows must hi' t lo liusini's.s ;in&lt;l tins in sii INTERESTS &lt;&gt;l NKBK-\&gt;k\ I i&gt; I \\. man m ho i&gt; m i hun I n loan it La mei ai'i|ii:iinli'&lt;l « it li. And ro;iM&gt;!is for ils safiM V. ipplicut ion </seg>
            <seg id="p144">141 Another very great will stand shipment to any orld where regular lines onu reason in favor of Us cream from his amount of money in \&gt;i' sold from the farm. he able to bor- engaged in any other business? The 1 I predict that it will come ul growth in the dairy ska. With row testing associations third of the cows now hould In- fattened and sent to mark' icrcased tremend- t lit* n u in Imt of milk it t Ih- amount &gt;f cream from the ilr. Such figures naraenac that they insiderable extent the po.ssibili - 1 BMure von are most wonder- I)W JUDGING CON TEST IM one of Ten cows were used. \ pi,!ici sro.'e. that is placing inti-d 100 points, and in order to se- ■r he premium money us follows hack Ml No. ti G So. 7 1 No. 8 C No. I K l&gt;v making a few cal- placed l&gt;y ■ rom- red it was necessary A tron of 75 points </seg>
            <seg id="p145">142 In the contest 11H took part and J!» more points. The total nun- it- was I'll making t al In this contest « i more points. In th the per rent of t hi 1IKI points is as IMS, H7 per H't per cent : 1 H 1 points th T! vV \ il.iii Anile I I' Atxlr Chester Af&lt; B \l B Kav K. ( 7. H. (hit Kay Can I) L. Kricksi G. I). Fr Rodney ( Paul Hi \ . .1. He, H C. Mi Albert M R. J. l'o»i Henrv I. Pete K. U. Kystrom R. H. Rome .1. H. Rict O. \\ . Sjogrei Eraesl Stenje L 0. \ ose R. C. Wintermute S H. Whisenand I.ii I \V Whisenand Linn NOTE Most of the sueeessfu tendance at the school of agr address instead of their home addn d. ■. Pier </seg>
            <seg id="p146">143 I \sH&gt; CREAMERIES IN NEBRASKA ikii: \\l oil COMMISSION Arcadia Archer Mason City Alliance Haslnns Beatrice Lincoln Pierce Broken Bow Cortland Columbus Chapman Crete ('■rand Island Omaha A; ( Franklin Fremont Wolbach Hemingford ( ( ( Kontanelle (iermantown Fremont North Platte \i-l&gt;raska City Holdrege Superior Fairbury Humbolt Hartington Falls City Louisville Omaha York Kearney Lincoln Dannebrog Milk Producers Association O'Neill Central City York </seg>
            <seg id="p147">144 Bns CrearmT.v ( la C'olii Stor;in Ri vert on (' Rosche Cm Ravenna (' Rawnna (' swift a &lt; , Schneider V Switz. St. Lib Stapleton ( -loo ( k I -loo ( ■ \ Horn ft M Vcrdigree Butte ■A bai Ka Da Her I O AST M AST K K M RESPON ;&lt;i\ kksok -Ions H. Mom i Corn. (.^iK-cn Wheat, - lOMOKABLI B. H. R\\\l 1 Bsion, Depart mi-nt ol Ag IIHAKI.K \\ . &lt;i. WHITMOKE Cow." Hb. A. T. Bokman, Topeka K </seg>
            <seg id="p148">145 Uaniilac! iirfi-s •(Jlimpses of the il andry Department, Univer- B Agent, C. B. &lt;fc Q. Ky. Co Interests." I) asks. "The Cn» in Politics \i Viinutes of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the k \ \smk IATION OF ICE CREAM MANUFACTURERS January 19 and 20, 1914 President, Mr. R. W A I Soul h Omaha. Nebf Hcatricr. Nebr. Wymorc. Nt-br. Omaha. Nebr. uperior, Nebr Sc ward. Nebr Lincoln. Nebr Omaha. Nebr Grand Island. Nebr. Lincoln. Nebr Kranklin, Nebr. Fremont. Nebr Yenlel. Nebr. Omaha, Nebr. Hastings, Nebr Lincoln, Nebr Holdredge. Nebr. West Point. Nebr. Fairbury, Nebr. O'Neill, Nebr. Norfolk, Nebr. tary American General l';i&gt;s. Ajcfiit. Our Methods." l!Uh at I he Kunii- Hold. Omaha. David City, Nebr. \ iiili^ree. Nehr. No. Plane. Nehr. Geneva, Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p149">146 \KHKASKA DAI KYM.W ii H IN ir Petenon, H. o Kveniia Creamery • rides* Bros. Sleifer. IVter I Waterloo CrctMfy ( Wolz Baking C« Acorn KetiniiiK &lt; Eer lee Mac Mini' (' fectionen &amp; Bmke imery Package M is Cooperage Co K&lt; Downey-T Kor.l. Co., Tr Kennedy * I Morion Sail I Nelson Mfg. Sfthness Co \\ entern Kocl. Tli aildrcs Nexl folli accepted I M H ami Lou t.)u The reail i: lasted until The ev K Kome Hot lunch wan m MeetiiiK called § matter of express rate* ■ of Omaha explained in d Hate shippers. The &lt;iues discusseii. althout(li no !■ -ele&lt;-ti«n of a committee eOM K. G. Caldwell. Lincoln; M Fremont; R. \\ . Mc(iinnis. ( shippers operating aleng the bo A committee chosen at t h of Joe Clark. Ravenna: Ler&lt; Omaha, to look after low charges, was held over for anothe Late reports from the con reduction of from in to "&gt;&lt;i i&gt; Kallon of 1 r on the </seg>
            <seg id="p150">147 l a letter of sympathy for epart him for past favors and expressing the Harmon, pure food commissioner, was of He compared ice cream of today a ■(O, commenting on the improvement and ■am manufacturers established a standard vsus demanded by the consuming public: lard is the highest known in the United npita consumption of any state resulted in ihe re-election of old officers O'Neill. Nelir. Superior. Nebr. Lincoln, Nebr. Omaha, Nebr lent K\K« I Tl\ K c iiMMITTKK Lincoln. Nebr. Omaha. Nebr. Beatrice. Nebr. he place for next meeting AFTERNOON SESSION January 20, 1914 Nebraska and Iowa associations with the E. V. Parrish, manager publicity bureau. 'Organization." by K. 1. Ringer, com- nufacturers' association, Lincoln; address by iologiat, Beatrice Creamery Co.." Lincoln: I litigation, by Judge R. I. Parrish. Des Moines </seg>
            <seg id="p151">148 SILOS AND ENSILACt W. I. Sl'II.I.M \ NuTl Ilg the wet nent and - that it win •ssor Spill i book page 408 : " K for dairy rows 10!l |M lull poundx to 150 i'&lt;&gt; ealetilat ions 1 shall aan A .■„,. ton of alfalfa I nf fli^st il&gt;lc earboh ti&gt; these figures jt !&gt;le nutrinu allowance is indie ■ A hay &gt;li.-.l liol.il li should \.i&lt;\ </seg>
            <seg id="p152">\ 149 Estimating the average at half the original wenty years, with ■ nt on i per cent, we of the shed per i iipacit y. 1. holding 100 ions of silage should of silage should ii sume thuc il will last thirty-three issume thai it will last thirty-three ■hairs should not exceed 1 per cent xceed 1 per cent il charge per ton capacity for repairs large per ton capacity for repairs ni . and depreciation -t per cent lation :{ per cen: &gt;ii i lie original rosi. This is eight This is eight ipacii y. an \i&gt;- l&gt;uih for *:l."&gt;o. It &gt;hould hi&gt;t I. Ii should last he repairs should not exceed 1 per lie re pain should OOl exceed 1 per inn 7 per cent for the annual charge he annual charge ttion, we have an annual cost per cannot l&gt;e built for less than In a dry. windy climate like annual cost per ins cannol In- l&gt;uik for less than I deal more. In ;i dry, windy climate like silu will probably not last on the will p not last on the me ol them may last twent) a year. The repairs on such a wHm may last t went y j ear. The repairs on such a mIo • permanent types of silos, and we ilos. and we ol the first cost per year. We have We have mining a one-hundred tow sta i a one-hundred-ton sta per cent repairs, and :i per cent interest int repairs, and :i per cent interest in the average investment . a total vestment . a total i year per ion rapacity. Since it * parity. Since it I one ton of hay. we must multiply we must multiply I lo make the comparison with hay. oring hay is seventy-five cents per ■si of storing an equivalent amount quivalent amount ii. twenty-six and one-quarter cents: i. twenty-six and one-quarter cents: rents; and in a stave silo, $1.20. i stave silo. $1.20 — s I • » i&gt; about one-third that for hay: hird t hat for hay: ml i he same as for hay: and in a &gt;ring hay. &lt;r h»y: and in a vc i \\h mPHKK halt t here is much less |us» i hi- -ilo i han by curing it as fodder, much les- uring it as fodiler i pretty carefully investigated. On Feeds and Feed- point: "The looses of nutriment in i materially different, though ii men sometimes forget that the </seg>
            <seg id="p153">\ ( E'ntation which takes place in merit, and this taken with tr : equals the loss in corn Fodde Ik hki. \T We liave a for each of t ht eel I vi ■ . .'«. $1(1 braska farm I- Kxpe xcellen •imei amount Similar ex| 1 tie ail van! age li t his w ill cause t h hay is at hat rl cost 01 succu There are nun il y. In a region sulijeel to to make a lield of fodder into the silo, when if left to il/v u worthless. There are also sunn localities there is no quest of the stale of Nebraska already seen that a j^ood pi ■ Of growing l'HJ on ■ i KI is ;i lOIDP* Tht' paladin ■be for ift-dii lion hut thai silaiH ■ account of i he wot he i not depeixl upon mak lunutely. this is a region in v. </seg>
            <seg id="p154">i luii lilage ■ not a tt" 1 "' illy in Nebraska to build lint 1 ili&gt; want In makr it p expensive than tin- l&gt;«-si in understanding we arc le&gt;~ who can depend upon mak- i. irmer ar. which is probably .IV fV Nebra (I not feel discouraged be- MAY NEBRASKA'S NEW CHAMPION COW May. a Holstcin rn« owned 1&gt;&gt; the Nebraska lit- year, just clnsi-il. La May produced 49 pound* of butter fat which, ae- Krinian Auociation rules, is estimated to pro - butter. This record ranks her ninth in milk EN, Di'iisii'i tiicnt of Dairy Husbandry mm licr utMKhl in milk is i hr rrmurkahlt [ ht- cows ol I he world. She also holds the dis- nrc milk in a year than any other cow owned hy Collect. ml under official test on Novemlier 1*. 1912 at m. By food care she was induced to (five as d- of milk in one day. This is equal to about the whole year she averaged 7'!. II pounds daily m per day. She i&gt; a splendid representative of i«- excellent dairy I emperament . She weighs and it is ■ striking proof of her efficiency that to go through a year of heavy feeding without </seg>
            <seg id="p155">n together v ui rurrenl M \] 191 191 1- \| M I Nov. 1-1 Totals jii&lt;&gt;im ill. alfal </seg>
            <seg id="p156"/>
            <seg id="p157">y 153 t brae fi't-d- ht'it|&gt;t 20.00 T. 0.42 J Bu :t:i.00 T. M M. 12.00 T u.'.i; |! ii. &gt;.oo T. 1.00 T no T SII.IKI T 23.00 '1 \1 Lu M $] il Mill I.-.I tht- ihl be ■ |,ii- lmi Ills ||«T mude up i pounil XI II I milk produced daily. The and difestion in k 1 " 11 ' made from linn ncoln. In many I ho me high Anted 10 $1 IJ.ii.l. aflc- it had t&gt;t-en . h t hi- sum- dairy K.om I lu&gt;. how ilso i lit- cost ol l;il&gt;«r uiil delivering nuisi liberal allow- mj; into account milk afi.-,- Mag wort li l.v. IlUt NT fill representative ■fe price paid ihs iii which alfalfa, .-ikM tdr up nl wheat, bran, oil m&lt;-al </seg>
            <seg id="p158">154 to time by adding or substituting and sugar beds. It is not to be presumed that al done but rather that it indicate* the productiveness. Ii certainly should that it is not only powtiblp bul his </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>