<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00083.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0083.0004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATEMENT of the AUDITOR of PUBLIC ACCOUNTS of the STATE OF NEBRASKA Showing the Appropriations Made and Moneys Expended BY THE FIFTY-SECOND SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE Known as the "FIRST UNICAMERAL LEGISLATURE" January 1, 1937 to May 15, 1937 LEGISLATIVE EXPENDITURES Shown up to June 30, 1937</title>
               <date value="1937-06-30">1937-06-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATEMENT of the AUDITOR of PUBLIC Accounts of the STATE OF NEBRASKA Showing the Appropriations Made and Moneys Expended BY THE FIFTY-SECOND SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE i Known as the "FIRST UNICAMERAL LEGISLATURE" January 1, 1937 to May 15, 1937 LEGISLATIVE EXPENDITURES Shown up to June 30, 1937 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">TABLE OF CONTENTS ■ State Board of Equalization 4 Statement No. 1 Appropriation Bills 5 1-A Emergency Appropriations available during the Fiscal year ending June 30,1939 6 1-B Biennial Appropriations for the biennium July 1, 1937 to June 30, 1939 8 1-C Nominal Appropriations 30 Recapitulation of Biennial Appropriations 34 Comparison with 1935 Appropriations 37 Statement No.2 Appropriations and Expenditures 38 2iA Salaries and Mileage Members of the Legislature 39 2-B Salaries of Officers and Employees of the Legislature 4 &lt;&gt; 2-C Legislative Expense— Postage 42 2-D Legislative Expense— Telephone and Telegraph. . 43 2-E Legislative Expense— Supplies &amp; Incidentals 43 2-F Legislative Expense— Printing • • *6 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">STATEMENT OF THE AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS William H. Price j Auditor Philip H. Kohl I Deput Auditor Wilbur H. Pansing I. state Accountant James A. Chapman... Bond Examiner AUDITING DIVISION Antone Sagl 1 County Tresasurer Examiner T. O. Merchant J County Treasurer Examiner Elgie Bute. County Treasurer Examiner Lucille Rudder .Appropriation Bookkeeper Margaret McCalpin Fund Bookkee r Eleanor Hansen Warrant Writer Olga Dvoracek PiU Q k May Belle Sohl | Stenographer Herman B. Grabau.. .....j Accountant STATE BOARD OF EQUALIZATION AND ASSESSMENT R. I* Cochran ,.,..; .- Governor " a .^7 R- Swjmson...., Secretary of State WdlfamH. Price State Auditor Walter H Jensen ■ State Treasurer Wm. H. Smith ....State Tax Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I STATEMENT OF AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS STATEMENT No. 1 APPROPRIATIONS MADE BY THE 52nd LEGISLATURE For the Biennium July 1, 1937 to June 30, 1939 A— EMERGENCY APPROPRIATIONS ■ Amount L - R j Purpose of Appropriations Appropriated 26 Salaries of Members $ 75,000.00 10-69 Off icers and Employees Salaries ) 70-552- \ gc ARn no 677-70 Mileage and Legislative Expenses ) ' 220-567 - 571-40-70Miscellaneous Claims and Deficiencies 43,549.86 567 Paving Taxes— State House 27,915.94 667 Refunds to Counties for Maintenance of Patients in State Hospitals 36,282.46 District Court Order— Eradication of Scabies— Reappropriation of balance lapsed June 30, 1935. 5.236.61 70 Lieutenant Governor Salary 3,488.36 Total Emergency Appropriations from Tax Funds. .1 255,923.23 667 Misc'l Claims paid from Cash Funds 6,881.28 70 State Assistance — Special Re-appropriations — Cash Fund 1 860,835.00 169 Lighting State House . Tower 10,000.00 320 Prison Industrial Equipment &amp; Housing Fund. . 57,633.40 191 Legislative Officers &amp; Employees Salaries 11,693.60 Total Emergency Appropriations $ 1,201,966.51 B— BIENNIAL APPROPRIATIONS 69 State Officers Salaries — From General Fund 893,720.00 70 General Maintenance — From General Fund 11,480,117.99 70 General Maintenance— Unexpended Balances 360,127.83 70 Cash Funds J 27,569,625,66 70 Federal Funds 14,910.230.32 Total Biennial Appropriations $ 55,213,821.80 RECAPITULATION TOTAL Emergency Appropriations 261,804.61 TOTAL Emergency Re-appropriations 940,162.00 TOTAL Biennial Appropriations 55,213,821.80 GRAND TOTAL. $ 56.365,788.31 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">STATEMENT OF THE STATEMENT No. 1-A EMERGENCY APPROPRIATIONS Appropriations made by the 52nd Session of the Legislature, passed with the Emergency- Clause and made available immediately. L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Legislative Department $.143,93^.36 26 E-2 Salaries of Members .$ 75,000.00 , 10 E-3 to 5 Officers and Employees Sala - ries, Mileage and Legislative Expense I 10.000.00 552 E-3 to 5 Officers and Employees Sala - ries, Mileage and Legislative Expense 30,000.00 577 E-3 to 5 Officers and Employees Sala - ries, Mileage and Legislative • Expense 25,000.00 69 E-7 Salary of Lieutenant Governor £488.36 70 E-8 C'erk of Legislature - 450.00 (Salary May 15,' 1937 to June 30, 1937) Supreme Court 20.00 567 E-27 Refund Court Fee 20.00 District Court 470.71 567 E-42 Judges Travel Expense — 1924 &amp; 1925 470.71 Law Enforcement t • 463.80 567 E-57 Extradition of Prisoners 463.80 Secretary of State 7,123.27 567 E-63 Election Printing... ..' 568.25 567 E-66 Printing Constitutional Amend-. merits ' 6,498.52 567 E-67 Refund Corporation Permits. . . 56.50 State Treasurer . 8,565.02 567 E-87 Insurance Policies 590.02 40 E-89 Premiums on Treasurer's and Deputy's Bonds. 7,975.00 Attorney General.' 184.32 567 E-92 Maintenance Deficit— 1934 184.32 .. • Commissioner Public Lands &amp; Buildings 2,657.76 567 E-110 Leo Swanson Salary Jan. 1. 1937 to June 30, 1937 2,500.00 567 E-113 Maintenance Deficit — 1933-1934 157.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS j Department of Agriculture &amp; Inspection e 2 g5 si Dist E-152 Eradication of Scabies and Court Swine Diseases (Balance June i 30. 1935 lapsed to General Fund) District Court Manda - mus April 3, 1937..... 5,236.61 667 E-lflS Exterminating Prairie Dogs... 29.20 Department of Labor $575.01 567 E-155 Workmen's Compensation 575.01 Department of Roads and Irri - gation 4,641.49 667 E-188 Refund Excess Licenses 1,881.64 667 E-189 Contractor Compensation, Auto Accidents, Land Damage and / Miscellaneous claims... 2,759.85 / Department of Insurance 192 67 567 E-217 Refund of Excess Taxes 192.57 I Department of National Guard 10.000.00 220 E-233 Airport for Nebr. Nat'L Guard 10,000.00 Capitol Commission 27,915.94 T7 E-270 Paving Taxes— State House 27,915.94 Board of Pardons 250.00 571 E-302 Additional Maintenance 250.00 I Game Forestation &amp; Parks Commission 554 73 567 E-310 Abstract, Medical &amp; Hospital (expense, Miscellaneous Equip - ment 664.78 Electoral College 144.80 7 E-370 Expense attending Electoral College ....■ 144.80 Board of Control 44,826.11 667 E-598 Refunds to Counties for Main- I tenance of Patients in State Hospitals 35,282.46 667 E-599 Board and Care of State Pris - oners 7,901.60 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk 667 E-680 Unpaid Wages 100.00 Nebraska School for the Deaf, Omaha 667 E-640 Premiums on Insurance Policies 1,432.40 State Reformatory for Men, Lincoln 667 E-670 Injury and Killing Sheep 109.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">STATEMENT OF THE • L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose appropriated Amount Total Board of Educational Lands &amp; Funds 3,934.76 567 E-800 Refund of School Land Rentals and Contract Payments 3,904.76 $261,804.51 . Summary of Emergency Appro-' priations .'. J Appropriations from Tax Funds $255,923.23 Appropriations from Cash Funds 5.881.28 r •■ __^ ■ $261804.51 STATEMENT No. 1-B BIENNIAL APPROPRIATIONS .Appropriations mede by the E2nd Session of the Nebraska State Legislature to cover State -Governmental Expenditures for the Biennium July 1. 1937 to June 30, 1939. L. B. Acct. - No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total LEGISLATIVE DEPARTMENT $ 44.9CO.00 70 1 Incidental Expense of the next Legislature 2,000.00 Legislative Council 70 6 Maintenance and Expense L. B. 395 : 15.000.00 70 8 Salary of Clerk of Legislature.. 7,200.00 70 * 9 Maintenance and care of Leg - islative Chambers, including $700.00 for the care and treatment of floor coverings and draperies 10,700.00 70 10 Printing Journals and Session Laws 10,000.00 Total Legislative Department. . 44.900.00 JUDICIARY DEPARTMENTS Supreme Court. 192.200.00 69 20 Salary of 7 Judges 105,000.00 •This Hem is contained in Legislative Bill No. 559 which was vetoed by the Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Supreme Court — Cont. 69 21 Salary of Clerk 10,000.00 69 22 Salary of Deputy Clerk 6,000.00 69 23 Salary of Reporter 8.000X)0 70 24 Salaries of Employees 55,200.00 70 25 Maintenance of Clerk's Office. 7,500.00 70 26 Maintenance of Reporter's Office 500.00 State Library 30,300.00 69 30 Salary of Deputy Librarian 4,800.00 70 31 Maintenance of Library 4,500.00 70 32 Printing Supreme Court Reports 11,000.00 70 33 Purchase of Books for State Library 10.000.00 District Court 555,500.00 69 40 Salary of 35 District Judges.. 350,000.00 69 41 Salary of 35 Court Reporters. . 192500.00 70 42 Travel Expense of Judges 13,000.00 Total Judiciary Departments.. 778,000.00 EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS 1 GOVERNOR $36,780.00 69 50 Salary of Governor 15,000.00 69 51 Salary of Secretary to Gover - nor : 5,280.00 70 52 Salaries and Wages 6,600.00 70 53 Maintenance 4,500.00 70 54 Membership Governors' Con - ference 200.00 70 55 Maintenance Governor's Man - sion ' .4,500.00 70 55-A Re-roofing Governor's Mansion 700.00 State Sheriff . 49,000.00 Under Directon of the Gover - nor 70 56 Rewards (and unexpended bal - ance) 500.00 70 57 State Sheriff— Law Enforcement 35,000.00 70 58 Division of Athletics—Unex - pended balance after trans - fer of 10,000.00 to General Fund — Estimated 13,500jOO </seg>
            <seg id="p010">STATEMENT OF THE Acct. j. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total SECRETARY OF STATE 56,435.00 69 60 Salary of Secretary of State. . 10,000.00 69 61 Salary of Deputy Secretary 5,280.00 70 62 Salaries and Wages 11,450.00 70 63 Maintenance 5,500.00 For Collection Corporation Taxes 5-00.00 70 64 Election Expense Fund....... I.OOOjOO State Real Estate Commissioner Fund 70 65 All collections and unexpended balance — istimated 13,100.00 70 65-A Salaries and Wages including part time " " manager, not to ex - ceed 6,300.00 70 65-B Legal Counsel 1300.00 70 65--C Maintenance — not to exceed.... 5,000.00 • --.... Stock Brand Fund 70 66 Salaries and Wages, including part time salary of manager, not to exceed 5,280.00 70 67 Publication of Brand Book £000.00 70 68 Maintenance — not to exceed. . . 2,825.00 70 69 Collections and unexpended balance, estimated $12,000.00 STATE AUDITOR 116,291.27 69 70 Salary of State Auditor 10,000.00 69 71 Salary of Deputy 5,280-00 70 72 Salaries and Wages of Office 21,000.00 70 73 Maintenance 10.000.00 70 74 All moneys received from the annual audits of the Metro - politan Utilities District of Omaha for defraying the ex - spenses of accountants and ■ ' examiners— Estimated 1,100.00 70 75 Salary State Accountant and Assistants (and unexpended balances from Salaries and Wages,, and Auditing County Treasurers and State Officials) 9,911.27 70 76 Salaries, Eight Accountants (as provided L. B. 310) 32,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">AUDITOR. OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total " State Auditor Cont. 70 77 Traveling Expense- Accoun tan's 24,00000 70 78 Semi-annual Audit State Trers - urer 2,000.00 STATE TREASURER.... 34,530.00 69 80 Salary of State Treasurer 10:000.00 69 El Salary of Deputy Treasurer. . 5,280.00 70 82 Salaries and Wages 14,500.00 70 83 Maintenance 4,000.00 70 84 Eookkeeping Machine and War - rant Register Machine 750.00 ATTORNEY GENERAL. ...... 141,909.05 G9 90 Salary of Attorney General 10,000.00 70 91 SaUries and Wages. . 48,000.00 70 92 Maintenance, Office 4,000.00 70 93 Litigation — (and unexpended balance) 23,158.10 70 94 Costs and Judgments (and un - expended balance) 6,805.71 70 95 Protection of Irrigation Rights. North Platte District (and unexpended balance) 49,945.24 SUPERINTENDENT OF PUB - LIC INSTRUCTION 363,160.00 69 100 Salary of State Superintendent 10,000.00 69 101 Salary of Deputy 5,280.00 70 102 Salaries and Wages 30,880.00 70 103 Readers of Examinations and Extra help from examina - tions and certificate fees — Cash ..'. 15,000.00 70 104 Maintenance 17,000.00 70 105 Fixed Charges— Aid to Schools. 70,000.00 70 105-A Fixed, Charges— Aid to Mallery Act ;.. 30,000.00 70 106 Fixed Charges— Aid to Normal Training 100,000.00 70 107 Inspection Expense ) 70 107-A Inspection of High Schools ) 10,000.00 70 108 Tuition of Children of Enlisted Army and Navy men I* B. 502 15,000.00 70 109 Instruction of Deaf Children.. 9,000.00 70 109-A Adult Immigration Education.. . 3,000.00 70 109-B Relief of School Districts 30,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATEMENT OF THE L. B. Accf. No. No. For What Purpose .Appropriated Amount Total Bureau of Education and Reg - istration of Nurses 70 109-D Administration and Enforce - ment — all fees aud balance. • '.; Estimated 18,000.00 COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. . . $ 181,340.00 69 110 Salary of Lnnd Commissioner (To Jan. 1939) 7,500.00 69 111 Salary of Deputy (to Jan. 1939) 3:960.00 70 112 Salaries and Wages... 14,880.00 70 113 Maintenance 2,000.00 As Custodian of the Capitol 70 115 Wages of Capitol Employee*. . . 75,000.00 70 116 Fuel, light and Power- Capitol 60,000.00 70 117 Maintenance— Capitol 18,000.00 70 119 Wapes, Maintenance and Sup - plies — Capitol Grounds and Governor's Mansion — .All fu - ture collections from Capitol Levy and unexpended bal - ances — no estimate.. Total Executive Departments $978,445.32 ADMINISTRATIVE DEPART - MENTS Department of Agriculture and Inspection 616,639.67 Bureau of Agricultural Statistics 70 120 Salaries and Maintenance 10,000.00 Bureau of Food, Drags and Oil 70 121 All moneys collected by said bureaus, including fees and money collected under Legis - lative Bill No. 499, Fifty - second Session, during the biennium; and unexpended balance of fees, collected in the 1935-1937 biennium; or so ■ much thereof as may be needed for the maintenance and support of said bureaus, Including salary of Director of said Department, and maintaining seed testing de - partment and including not / </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. N«. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Department of Agriculture and Inspection — Cont, more than the sum of $7,000.00 to be expended under the direction of the Attorney General and subject to the approval of the snid Director ' for salaries and assistants and rffice help m the office of the Attorney General, not to exceed; estimated 290,000.00 Bureau of Animal Industry 70 122 Salaries and Wages (and un - expended balance) 20, r &gt;20.40 70 123 Maintenance (and unexpended balance) . . ... ... . . . . . 4.641.B0 70 124-A Fradication of Bovine Tuber - culosis and Glanders 50,000.00 70 124-B Eradication of Anthrax (and unexpended balance) 19.207.04 70 125 Fradication of Scabies, Swine, and Chicken Piseae-ei (and unexpended balance) 15,795.79 70 127 Eradication of Bovine Tubercu - losis Collections — Estlma'ed 7.776.00 Ports of Entry 70 128 Port Inspection, Salaries, Wages and Maintenance Entry Fees, Fstimated EO.OCO.00 70 129 Towing Fees, Salaries. Wages and Maintenance, not to ex - ceed 56,160.00 • Salaries and Wages, including . enforcement and administra - tion of Ports of Entry not to exceed 99,760.00 Maintenance, not to- ■ exceed 6,400.00 Motor Vehicle Fuel Transport Adm. 70 130 Administration and enforcement — Reappropriate all fees and receipts arising under L. B. No. 97. Estimated 10,000.00 Itinerant Merchants 70 131 Administration. and enforcement AH fees and receipts collected under K B. 50. Estimated. . 1,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">STATEMENT OF THE L. B. Acct. No. Na For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Department of Agriculture &amp; Inspection — Cont Bureau of Animal Industry 70 133 Bee Inspection— General Fund — (and unexpended balance) 2,830.22 70 134 Bee Inspection— Cash All collec ions ? nd unexpend - ed balance. Eitimaed 4,800.00 70 135-C Eradication of Insect Pests and Inspection of Nursery Stock — Cash. All receipts and unex - pended balance. Estimated.. 6,025.00 70 13S-G Eradication of Insect Pests. — General Fund (and unex - pended balance 5,706.72 70 136 Potato Inspection. (All Collec - tions and unexpended bal - ance) Estimated ■ 5,650 00 225 137 Eradication of Weeds. L. R 225 — General Fund 50,000.00 70 138 Inspection of Live Stock Sales — Unexpended balance and re - ceipts. Estimated 528.00 70 139 Administration . and- enforce-. • ment Live Stock Sales Ring Fund L. B. 55— All receipts Estimated 7,500.00 DEPARTMENT OF LABOR... 25,796.33 69 IE-t Salary of Director .of Labor... 4,800.00 70 151 Salaries and Wages (and un - expended balance) 15,132.98 70 152 Maintenance (and unexpended balance) 6.S63.35 Nebraska State Employment Service j - 150,000.00 70 1E3 Service 70,000/K) 70 1E3-F Nebr. State Emp. Service.— Fed. Cash and balance on hand. Estimated 70,000.00 70 154 Unemployment Comp. Adm. Fund ...'. ;'. . ' 10,000.00 70 154-F Unemployment Comp.| Adm. Fend. Fed. Cash. No estimate Workmen's Compensation Court 48,000.00 70 155 Salaries and Maintenance — and balance on hand or to be re - ceived, estimafd- funds avail - able not to exceed.' 48,000.00 • </seg>
            <seg id="p015">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH. . 351.253.39 69 160 f alary of Director of Health.. 6,400.00 70 162 Salaries and Wages 29,000.00 70 163 Main'enance (and unexpended balance) 11,837.61 70 164 Bureau of Examining Boards. including Engineering and Architecturpl Examiners L. B. 14, Barber, Cosmetology, Prophylactic Control L. B. 435, Funeral Directing and Undertaking L. B. 300. All i receipts and unexpended bpl - ances—estimated 109,987.75 70 1G4-B For Benefit of Professions 2,447.25 Reappropriate unexpended balances to be refunded ac - coiding to decision: Gibson vp. Cochran. Doc. 133, P. 103 District Court, Lan - caster County, as follows. Veterinary, Medicine &amp; Surgery 377.00 Embalmers 1,681.40 Chiropody 198.36 Chiropractic 190.49 2,447.25 70 165 Public Health Education in tu - berculcis and venereal dis - ease — Reappropriated from Medical Examiner Fund to Department of Health. Estimated 6,000.00 70 166 Maternal and Child Health Ac - tivities (and unexpended bal - ance) 33,478.04 70 167 Public Health Works (and un - expended balance) 20,250.74 70 168 Public Health Works and Per - sonal Training — Fed. Estimated 83,732.00 70 169 Maternal and Child Health Ac - tivities Federal (and unex - pended balance) Estimated 48^20.00 DEPARTMENT OF ROADS AND IRRIGATION $21,989,768.78 70 181 Salaries and Wages, inclrding \ salary of Chief Engineer — </seg>
            <seg id="p016">STATEMENT OF THE L. B. Acct. • No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Dep't. Roads and Irrigation — Com. From Gas Tax, 3% of the total construction and not more than $8,000.00 for legal salaries (and unexpended bal - ance) Estimated 425,000.00 70 182 Maintenance (from Gas Tax) ,9% of total construction and not more than $1,200.00 for legal expense (and unexpend - ed balance). Estimated 125,000.00 70 183 Salaries and Wages. General Fund 34,944.00 ■70 184 Maintenance. General Fund (and unexpended balance)... 29,824.78 70 185 Bureau of Irrigation. Mainten - ance and Support. Cash. All collections (and unexpended balance) Estimated. 2,500.00 70 186 State Highway Administration. From 3^,% of Motor Vehicle Registration Fees, Receipts and unexpended balances. Estimated 140,000.00 70 186-A State Planning Board Adminis - tration not to exceed $7,500.00 each year and un - expended balance 70 186-B Motor Vehicle Operator's Li - cense Fees under old law. Cash 70 187 Road Maintenance— 30% of . Motor Vehicle Registration Fees and all towing permit fees under L. B. 413 not otherwise appropriated (and unexpended balance) Esti - mated 1^00,000.00 70 188 Road Maintenance — From Gas Tax. Estimated 5,200,000.00 70 189 Road Construction — From Gas Tax and unexpended bal - ance. Estimated 7,280,000.00 70 190 Construction of Highways to State Institutions, and Parks not to exceed 20,000.00 70 191 Motor Vehicle Operator's li - cense Fe« Fund — General Ad- . </seg>
            <seg id="p017">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount . Total Dept. Roads and Irrigation ■■•'■■ Cont ministration and balance. Es - timated 250.000.00 70 191-B Highway Safety and Patrol Ad - ministration and enforcement of Traffic Control L. B. 147 200,000.00 i Motor Vehicle Dealers' Admin - istration 70 192 Salaries, Wages and Mainte - nance — Reappropriate all fees collected under L. B. 388. Es - timated 17,500.00 Motor Vehicle Inspection Fund 70 193 Administration Enforcement - all fees collected— L. B. 147. Estimated 40,000.00 Federal Aid Road 70 194 Federal Aid Roads. Cash and unexpended balance 7,000,000.00 70 195 Trust Account. NatfL Ind. Rec H. F. Fed. Cash State Planning: Board 70 197 Institutional and Educational Building Program Survey... 10,000.00 70 198 State Survey of Human Tuber - culosis . 15,000.00 DEPARTMENT OF BANKING $138,590.34 69 200 Salary of Director of Banking. 9,000.00 70 201 Salaries and Wages (and un - expended balance) 26,476.49 70 202 Maintenance (and unexpended balance) 10,605.95 70 203 Premium for Insurance on Se - curities (and unexpended balance) 2,007.90 70 204 Organization and Administra - tion of State Receivership Guaranty Fund. - 500.00 70 205 Assessments of State Banks and Trust Companies, Build - ing &amp; Loan' Associations, "etc., for salaries and expenses with any unexpended balance. Cash. Estimated 90,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">STATEMENT OF THE L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Department of Insurance 146,400.00 69 210 Salary of Director of Insurance 6,400.00 70 212 Salaries, Maintenance and Ex - penses of Insurance Depart - ment and Bureau of Securi - ties, field Investigation and litigation, all filing fees, re - gistration of agents and mis - cellaneous fees and unex - pended balance— Estimated.. 60,000.00 70 213 Salaries and Expense of Ex - aminers, actuaries and ac - countants, all fees collected from .-Insurance Companies and unexpended balance — Estimated 40,000.00 70 215 State Fire Marshall, all fees col - lected and unexpended bal - ance. Estimated. 40,000.00 Tax Commissioner and Budget Control. 46,355.20 69 220 Salary of Tax Commissioner. . 10,000.00 70 221 Salaries and 'Wages (and unex - pended balance) 39,355.20 70 222 Maintenance . .... G.OOOjOO ■ I ____^_^___ Total Administrative Departments 23,512,803.71 miscellaneous depart - :--■■:■ ments Military Department $166,927.92 69 230 Salary of Adjutant General 8,000.00 69 231 Salary of Assistant • Adjutant General 5,400.00 70 232 Support ("and unexpended bal - ance) . . 153,527.92 70 234 Military Cash Railway Commission 129,580.00 69 240 Salary of Three Commissioners 30,000.00 69 241 Salary of Secretary 5,280.00 70 242 Salaries and Wages. 45,000.00 70 243 Maintenance... 9,000.00 70 244 Extra Help, Travel Expense in - cidental to Rate Investigation 10,000.00 70 245 Miscellaneous' Fees — Estimated. 30040 ■ ■ . ■ ■■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p019">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total 70 246 Grain Warehouse Fees—Esti - mated; 5,000.00 70 246-A Grain Stcrage Fees— no esti - : mate 70 247 Motor Carrier Fund—Regula - tion and Supervision from fees collected. Estimated 25,000.00 Board of Educational Lands and Funds 82,476.25 70 .250. Expense serving school land notices. Supplies to County Treasurer and Sta&lt;e Survey - or, advertising of auction sales and forfeited contracts 2,000.00 70 251 Expense of re-appraising school lpnd* (and unexpended bal - ance) 5,071.25 70 252 Salary and Expense of attorney for litigation in the protec - tion of school landi and funds 5,000.00 70 259 Relief of Spanish Wer Veterans and Dependents 45,000.00 70 260 Publishing Reports— Spanish War Veterens 600.00 70 261 World War Veterans State Re - lief Fund. Rehabilitation and Administration 19,805.00 70 263 Spanish War Veteran?—Main - tenance. Clerical Help 5,000.00 Nebraska Liquor Control Com - mission 304,950.00 70 280 Salaries, Wages, Maintenance and expenses — Estimated.... 304,950.00 Board of Vocational Educa - tion $806,511.54 70 290 Salaries and Wages 27,200.00 70 291 Maintenance 8,500.00 70 292 State Aid Vocational Education . 100,000.00 70 293 Federal Voc. Education. Smith- Hughes (and estimated bal - ance) 164,561.08 70 294 Vocational Rehabilitation and balance from Industrial Re - .. education 50J255.76 70 295 Federal Voc. Rehabilitation- - ' Estimated' Cash 46,850.00 ■''}■■' </seg>
            <seg id="p020">STATEMENT OF THE « L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total 70 296 George-Deen, Federal Fund and balance estimated. 394,144.70 70 *297 Blind Rehabilitation Fund Ad - ministration L. B. 279 16,000.00 Board of Pardons and Paroles . . 18,540.00 70 300 Salaries and Wages 11,040.00 70 302 Maintenance 7,500.00 Game, Forestation and Parks Commission 360,700.00 70 310 Administration of Game Laws, State Parks and Forestry. For propagation, pieserva'ion and distribution of game and fish; for salaries and maintenance of office; for necessary equipment for activities of the Commission; purchasing - and improving lakes and swamps; sinking- wells in lakes not owned by the State. Unexpended balance on hand from all appropriations from Game Funds for all activities . and all moneys received from sale of hunting and fishing permit?.- — Estimated. 320,000.00 70 313 Enlargement of Mains land Hy- ' drants for fire protection— Arbor Lodge. Gen. Fund. ... -2,000.00 70 314 For maintenance of all State Parks, General Fund 32,000.00 70 315-19 For each Park respectively, all cash receipts and unexpend - ed balance — Estimated 6,700.00 State Board of Agriculture.... 74,100.00 70 320 Premiums :.,., 4,000.00 70 321 Meetings of Organized Agri - culture.... 2,500.00 70 322 Maintenance.... . 20,000.00 70 323 Promotion of Agricultural Ac - tivities i '-. i , . , i 1 1 15,000.00 70 324 Development of Boys' and Girls' Club Work 10,000.00 •This item is covered in L. B. 279 vetoed by the Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. , vv [ji- No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount ..Total 70 325 Salary of Ground Superintend- «**! ent , '. r 2,600.00 . ,.„. 70 326 Operating Expense. i. . 16,000.00 70 327 Extension of Water System (to match W&lt; P. A. Funds) " 2,500.00 70 328 Repairs and re-roofing build - ings , to match W. P. A. Fund) 2,500.00 State Historical Society 15,600.00 70 335 Salar.'es and ' Wages ' 9,600.00 70 336 Main'enance .;.. 5,000.00 70 337 Historical Society Museum 1,000:00. :;.: Nebraska State Medical Asso- - t ciation . ' .;._ 1,000.00 70 340 Serum for Infantile Paralysis.. 1,000.00 Grand Army of the Republic. . . , ' ; . . 3,200.00 70 345 Maintenance and Clerical Absib- ..... tance . d^Qp.OO Stale Assistance Committee '; .. ; 13,570,000.00 70 Sec. 49 Appropriate from alcoholic ltq- . . uor taxes and collections arising rnder Chapter 116, Session Lnws of Nebraska, 1935, as amended by legisla - tive KM No. 523v Fifty-sec- ! r nd Session and as amended by Section 7, Leg'sla'ive Fill No. 378, Fifty-second Be-sion, and appropriate 8 per cent of gasoline tax fund, arisng' rnder Legislative Bill No. 158, Fifty-secrnd Session and . appropriate the proceeds of excise and estate taxes lev - ied under Legislative Bill No. 374, Fifty-*econd Session and .-.-.- appropriate proceeds of all head taxes collected under Section 6, Legislative. Bill No. 378. Fifty-second Sess'on. to- . • pether with' any' unexpended balances for biennium end - ing June 30, 1937. in said fund or in any other fund inuring to the State Assist - ance Fund, not to exceed 7,500,000.00 70 351 Admin-'straiion expense — 2% not to exceed. 150,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">STATEMENT OF THE L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total 70 352 Assistance Fund— not to exceed 7,350,000.00 70 351-A Administration Expense — Fed - eral (2%) Estimated 121,400.00 70 352-A Assistance Fund— Fe'deral 5,948,600.00 Bureau of Child Welfare 840.00 70 359 Maternity Home Fund, unex - pended balance and all fees collected. Estimated 840.00 Aeronautics Commission 20,000.00 70 361 Fees and Collections— Office Salaries and Maintenance — unexpended balance. Estimat - ed 20,000.00' 70 362 Air Marking Projects—Salaries and wages. Reappropriate balance 70 363 Air Marking Project^ — Expense Reappropriate' balance — .... 70 364 Airport Survey and Develop - ment-^Salaries and Wages — Reappropriate ba'ance 70 365 Airport Survey and Develop - ment — Supplies — r Reappro - r ate balance I 70 366 Airport Survey and Develop - ment — Equipment — Reappro - priate balance 70 367 Airport Survey and Develop - ment — Expense — Reappropri - ate balance..... Total Miscellaneous Depart - ments 15,554,425.71 EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS University of Nebraska . .- $6,773,762.54 70 400 General Appropriations $2,837,440.00 70 401 Agricultural Extension 226,000.00 70 402 Division of Conservation &amp; Soil Survey 60,000.00 70 403 College of Medicine 412,500.00 70 404 Salaries for new faculty and any unexpended balance from General Maintenance Approp - riations 1935-37 180,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total 70 405 Curtis School of Agriculture- New central heating plant and building 25,000.00 Cash and Federal Funds Re - ceipts during the Biennium and Unexpended Balances Estimated 70 407 University Cash Fund. Balance and all Receipts 2,000,000.00 70 408 Bankhead - Jones Agricultural Extension 19,000.00 70 409 Agricultural &amp; Mechanical Arts 168,085.80 70 410 Smith-Lever Fund 155,882.36 70 411 Agricultural Experiment Station 60,000.00 70 412 Purnell Fund. 120,000.00 70 413 Capper-Ketcham Fund 56,506.22 70 414 Additional Federal Co-op Fund 106!400.00 70 414-A Bnnkhead - Jones Agricultural Extension 346,948.16 Legislative Reference Bureau. . 71,500.00 70 415 Salaries, Wages &amp; Maintenance 12,500.00 70 416 Printing &amp; Editing Blue Book, Legislative Manuals and Bul - letins 4,000.00 Soil Conservation 70 417 Administration L. B. 553 15,000.00 Nebraska Public Library Com - mission 70 418 Salaries and Wages 16,000.00 70 419 Maintenance 24,000.00 Normal Schools and Board All expenditures unless oth - erwise herein specified 1,524,428.66 70 420 Normal School Board 5,000.00 70 421 Comptroller Salary and Expense 8,000.00 70 430 Chndron State Normal—Main - tenance 1 272,650.00 70 433 Boys' Dormitory, training school and gymnasium — Re - pairs and replacements 6,000.00 70 434 New Boiler 4,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATEMENT OF THE L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total 70 436 Special Improvements — S i d e - walks, Curbs, Gutters, Tun - nels, etc.; . provided boys' Dormitory is constructed.... 8,658.00 70 440 Kearney State Normal — Main - tenance , 325,670.00 70 443 Change Heating Plant 21,500.00 70 444 New Roofs, administration and gymnasia m buildings. ....... 2,170.00 70 445 Fire escapes and fire, extin - guishers for administration building and auditorium..... 1,407.00 70 446 Repairing Eva J. Case Hall Dormitory. , 2,000.00 70 447 New Boiler ' 4,000.00 70 450 Peru State Normal—Mainten - ance 284,500.00 70 4C3 Repairing floor, manual train ing room 300.00 70 454 Sewer Assessment — 2 years 1,500.00 70 460 Wsyne State Normal — Mainten- 308.216.00 ance 70 463 Power House Pump.... 1,200.00 70 464 Steam Heater &amp; Copper Coils for two boilers — Power House 3,500.00 70 465 Boiler 3,000.00 70 466 New roof and repairs, presi- . dent's residence | 500.00 .'• 70 467 Repairs— Terrace Hall 500.00 70 468 Re-roofing and repairing build - ings 3 ooo.f Cash or other miscellaneous re - ceipts from miscellaneous sources during the biennium, together with any. , unexpend - ed balance on hand for cur - rent expenses of the respect - ive normal schools. 70 431 Chadron Normal Cash Fund — Estimated 40,000.00 70 432 Chadron Normal Library — Estimated 6,000.00 70 441 Kearney Normal Cash Fund — Estimated | 35,108.72 70 442 Kearney Normal Library —Estimated 10,783.12 70 451 Peru Normal Cash Fund I —Estimated 65,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total 70 452 Peru Normal Library —Estimated 5,000X0 70 461 Wayne Normal ■ Cash Fund —Estimated 88,116.32 70 462 Wayne Normal Library — Estimated 7,149.50 Total Educational Institutions $8,369,691.20 BOARD OF CONTROL 5,842,703.12 70 500 General Maintenance Appro - priation, including repairs and replacements 3,816,698.36 Also re-appropriate unexpended balance of ' Education and maintenance of Deaf and Blind persons to General ■ / Maintenance. 329 501 Revolving Fund — Receipts 329 501-G Revolving Fund— L. B. 329 50,000.00 70 502 New building and equipment Fund and unexpended bal ances from: 647,724.76 Gen'l Maint'ncc Appropriation Emergency Revolving Fund Hospital for TB, Kearney Sewage Disposal Plant New Boiler Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln Tear down old hospital State Penitentiary, Lincoln Building equipment and fencing Soldiers &amp; Sailors Home, Mil- ... ford Additional Water Supply Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Education of Dependent Chil - dren Genoa State Hospital, Genoa Kitchen and baking equipment, Supplies for dining room </seg>
            <seg id="p026">STATEMENT OF THE L. B. Acct. No. Na For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Furniture, Cottages and Supt. Quarters Hospital equipment General repairs, replacements.. 69 503 Salary of three Board Members 24,000.00 69 504 Salary of Secretary of Board. . 5,280.00 70 505 Salaries and Wages of 'office hot to exceed 59,130.00 70 506 Office expense not to exceed $23,310.00. Nebraska Institute for Feeble Minded, Beatrice. A $2,000.00 70 510 Maintenance, repairs : and re - placements I No Estimate 70 512 New Building Fund No Estimate 70 518 Investigation and plans for water supply. Re-appropriate unexpended balance..... 2,000.00 Girls Training School, Geneva 4,747.80 70 520 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 522 New Building Fund No Estimate 70 523 Storage tower, tank, well and pump. Reappropriate unex - pended balance 4*747.89 Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Grand Island 70 530 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 532 New Building Fund No Estimate Hastings State Hospital, Ingle - side 11,229.93 70 540 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 D541-EConstruction ward building, etc. Reappropriate unexpended bal - ance . 70 D541-JF 1 Construction wnrd building etc Federal Fund 70 542 New Building Fund No Estimate 70 543 Electric wiring and fire extin - guishers. Reappropriate un - expended balance 3,348.68 70 544 Hydrotherapy Dept, Reappro - priate unexpended balance.. 7,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Acct. No. No, For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total 70 545 New pump for water supply. Reappropriate unexpended balance No balance 70 548 Water mains. Reappropriate unexpended balance 881.40 70 548-F Water mains. Federal cash No Estimate State Industrial School, Kearney 70 550 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements ...No Estimate 70 552 New Building Fund No Estimate Hospital for Tuberculosis. Kear- TO y 51,000.00 70 560 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 562 New Building Fund ...No Estimate 70 564 Field Workers 6,000.00 70 565 Power House and equipment.. 46,000.00 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln 70 570 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements '1 No Estimate 70 572 New Building Fund ....No Estimate Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 70 580 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 582 New Building Fund No Estimate State Penitentiary, Lincoln 12,000.00 70 590 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 692 New building fund No Estimate 70 593 Repairing walls. Reappropriate unexpended balance $5,000.00 70 594 Magnetic metal detector 2,000.00 70 595 Change dairy barn to horse barn, finishing dairy barn, sheds, fences and potato cel - lar 5;000.00 Nebraska Industrial Home, Mil - ford 70 600 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 602 New buUding fund No Estimate </seg>
            <seg id="p028">STATEMENT OF THE &gt;. L. B. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount T o(al Soldiers' &amp; Sailors' Rome, Mil - ford ■:-. . 70 610 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 612 Newbuildingfuhd.V No Estimate School for the Blind, Nebras - ka City 70 620 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estin^te 70 622 New building fund. ...... . . . . . No Estimate 70 625 Education and maintenance for : • Deaf and Blind, not to ex - ceed $5,000.00. No Estimate Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk 23,000.00 70 630 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 632 New building fund - No Estimate 70 633 Additional Water Supply and Irrigation Plant 22,000.00 70 634 Fire. pump. Re-appropriate un - expended balance. . .".' 1,000 00 70 635 Elevator and Hydrotherapy equipment, not to exceed We.MO.00 No Estimate School for the Deaf, Omaha 70 640 Main'enance, repairs and re- l 70 fi49 m pl " em « nts No Estimate to gS ? e iT w g fund No Esfclmate 70 645 School for speech, handicapped children not to exceed $7,000.00...; State Reformatory for Women, 70 fi K n M ' 25,000.00 &lt;u t&gt;50 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements ,N O Estimate S III o^ buUding fund No Estimate 70 653 Sewage Dispcsal Plant. ;...... 25,000X)0 Nebraska Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln 70 660 Maintenance, repairs and re - ™ c *o P lacements ---- • No Estimate 70 662 New building fund. ..;... N o Estimate m£m </seg>
            <seg id="p029">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS i L. B. Acct. No. Nft For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total State Reformatory for Men, Lincoln 3,874^7 70 670 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 672 New building fund No Estimate 70 676 Building and revamping elec - trical equipment. Reappro - priate unexpended balance.. 1,145.46 70 678 Barns, milk house, sheds fence. Reapproprfate unex - pended balance. 1,929.41 70 679 Root cellar. Reappropriate un - expended balance 800.00 Genoa State Hospital, Genoa 70 680 Maintenance, repairs and re - placements No Estimate 70 682 New building fund No Estimate Board of Control 70 511 Appropriate for each institution -681 respectively all institutional or cash receipts, balance and estimated receipts $ 1,299,000.00 Total Penal and Charitable In - •tltuUons $5,975,555.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATEMENT OF THE AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS STATEMENT No. 1-C NOMINAL APPROPRIATIONS Listed in accordance with Article 3, Sections 22 and 9K r&gt;* ♦!,„ L. B. Acct No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Revolving Funds The receipts for the biennium ending June 30,. 1939, together with any unexpended bal - ances on hand June 30, 1937, are hereby appropriated in the following manner: State Tax Commissioner and Budget Control 70 700 Purchasing Department, Re - volving Fund, No Estimate Department of Roads &amp; Irriga - tion 70 715 All moneys donated and reim - bursements. No Estimate Board of Control 327 730 Nebraska State-Use Prison Em - ployment Fund No Estimate Reappropriation of Balances June 30, 1937 From Auto License Plate Fac - tory Fund Handicraft Furniture Factory Fund Road Marker and Sign Fac - tory Fund </seg>
            <seg id="p031">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS NOMINAL APPROPRIATIONS OR EMERGENCY RE-APPROPRIATIONS L. B. Acct No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total ' Legislative Department $11,693.60 191 E-3 to 6Officers and Employees Salaries, Mileage &amp; Misc'L expense. Re - appropriate Balances in 1935 - 1937 appropriations, 60th and 51st Sessions. 11,693.60 E2 Salaries Members &amp; Officers 1,753.50 E 3-5 Miscellaneous Expense 8,028.03 E 6 Printing House &amp; ' Senate Journals 72.58 S 2 Salaries Members &amp; Officers 484.50 S 3-5 Miscellaneous Ex pen.se 1,354.99 Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings 10,000.00 169 E-118 Lighting State House Tower Reappropriated from re - ceipts of the Aeronautics Commission. Balance June 30, 1937 to be reappropriated. 10,000.00 Board of Control 57,633.40 320 E-597 Prison Industry Equipment and Housing Fund. Reappro - priate balance from Prison Industry Equipment Fund. Estimated 57,633i40 State Assistance Fund 860,835.00 70 E-351 State Assistance (Immediately -352 Available) 260,835.00 70 E-351 State Assistance— Net Proceeds -352 of Gas Taxes collected under L. B. 158 from March 24, 1937 to June 30, 1937— Estimated 300,000.00 Net Proceeds of Liquor Taxes collected under L. B. 523 from April 2; 1937 to June 30, 1937— Estimated 300.000.00 $940,162.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">L STATEMENT OF THE EMERGENCY RE-APPROPRIATIONS No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total ! Summary of Emergency Re- I i Appropriations I Reappropriations from Bal - ances 69,327.00 &lt; - ■ Reappropriations from Cash Funds 970,835.00 ' $940,162.00 TRUST FUNDS Department of Insurance 70 820 The receipts during the bien - nmm ending 'June 30, 1939, together with any unexpend - ed balance on hand June 30, 1937 in the State Hail Insur - ance Fund are hereby ap - propriated for expenditure • ; under the provisions .of Chap - ter 44-1401, Compiled Statute? of Nebraska, ,1929... . ...... . . .No Estimate Board of Educational Lands - - &amp; Funds 70 830 The income from the bonds for Soldier's Relief during the biennium ending June 30, 1939, top-ether with my rn - exnended balance on June 30, 1037, is hereby appropriated '-.■- "■ ' for expenditure . under pro - • visions of Chapter 80-401 of the Compiled Statutes of Ne - braska 1929... No Estimate </seg>
            <seg id="p033">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 70 Sec 55. STATE LEVY, DETERMINATION In each of the years 1937 and 1938, the State Board of Equalization and Assessment is hereby directed to determine the state general fund levy, strictly in accordance with Section 77-1007, C S. Supp., 1933 70 Sec. 56. RESTRICTIONS No person receiving compensation from a "Salaries and wages" appropriation shall receive additional compensation from any "maintenance" appropriation, or from any appropriation of fees: Provided, where there is a "salaries and wages" appropriation no office salaries and wages can be paid from "maintenance": and provided further, no appropriation for maintenance, or of un - expended balances or of cash funds shall be used or expended for the payment of premiums on official bonds of state officers or state employees unless specifically authorized by law. 70 Sec 59. EXPENDITURES TO BE PRO RATA No expending agency of the State of Nebraska shall be entitled to spend more than one-eighth of its appropriation during any one quarter of a year: Provided, that where an emergency exists or a special need arises for greater expenditures, the expending agency shall submit to the Auditor of Public Accounts its request fin writing; and said Auditor shall present such request to the Governor, through the Tax Commissioner, and if such request is approved by the Governor, then the Auditor of Public Accounts shall have authority to disregard the within pro rata provision, but in no case shall the amount of warrants issued against any i fund during the biennium exceed the amount of the appropriation made to said fund during said period. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">RECAPITULATION OF BIENNIAL APPROPRIATIONS July I, 1937 to June 30,1939 Amount of I Tax Reappropria-' Cash Federal Appropriation Funds tlon Fund Funds LEGISLATIVE DEPARTMENT $ 44,900.00 $ 44,900.00 . JZZZZZZ JUDICIARY DEPARTMENT Supreme Court $ 192,200.00 $ 192,200.00 State Library 30,300.00 30,300/)0 District Courts 555,500.00 555,500.00 Total Judiciary Depts. $ 778,000.00 $ 778,000.00 ZHZZZH "» EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS £ Governor $ 36,780.00 $ 36,780.00 H Direction of the Governor 49,000.00 35,100.00" 400 00 S 13 500 00 £2 Secretary of State 56,435.00 33,230.00 * ' 23 20500 I State Auditor 115,291.27 113,280.00 911.27 1100 00 § State Treasurer 34,530.00 34,530.00 ' H Attorney General 141,909.05 122,500.00 19 409 05 O State Superintendent 363,160.00 330,160.00 ' ' 33 000 00 "* Land Commissioner 181,340.00 181,340.00 ' ' H Total Executive Depts $ 978,445.32 7 886,920.00 ' ~ 20,720.32 $ 70,805.00 ~ « ADMINISTRATIVE DEPARTMENTS Dept. of Agriculture and Inspection. $ 616,639.67 $ 162.350.00 $ 15,85167 $438,438.00 Department o' Labor.. 25,796.33 24,175.00 162133 Nphrps^a Workmen's Compensation lMJl * ) Court 48,000.00 48,000.00 Department of Health...... 351,253.39 78,400.00 22,566^9 118,435.00 $ 131.852.00 Dept. of Roads and Irrigation 21,989,768.78 64,464.00 304 78 14,925,000.00 7,000,000.00 Department of Banking 138,590.34 44,000.00 4 590 34 90,000.00 Depart ment of Insurance. 146.400XK) 6,400.00 140,000.00 Tax Commiissioner and Budget Control 46,355.20 45,500.00 855.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">RECAPITULATION OF BIENNIAL APPROPRIATIONS— Continued July I, 1937 to June 30,1939 Amount of Tax Reappropria- Cash Funds Appropriation Funds tion Fund Federal Nebr. State Employment Service. . . 150,000.00 80,000.00 70,000.00 Total Administrative Departments. $23-512,803.51 $ 605,289.00 $ 45,789.71 $15,759,873.&lt;)!0 $ 7,201,852.00 MISCELLANEOUS DEPARTMENTS Q Military Department... "i. ..........$ 166,927.92 $ 163,400.00 $ 3,527.92 2 Railway Comml sicn , . . . 129,580.00 99,280.00 $ 30,300.00 £ Board of Educational Lands and 2 Funds 82,476.25 81,405.00 1,071.25 Nebraska Liquor Control Comm 304,950.00 304,950.00 2 Board of Vocational Education 806,511.54 189,550.00 11,405.76 605 55578 Board of Pardons 18,540.00 18,540.00 2 Game, Forestation, and Parks • 2 Commission 360,700.00 34,000.00 326,700.00 r State Board of Agriculture 74,100.00 74,100.00 O State Historical Society.. 15,600.00 15,600.00 . Grand Army of Republic 3,200.00 3,200.00 . .._ _ O State Assistance Committee 13,570,000.00 7,500,000.00 6 070 000.00 ° Bureau of Child Welfare 840.00 840.00 ' 2 Nebraska State Medical Association. 1,000.00 1,000.00 g Aeronautics Commission 20,000.00 20,000.00 *i Total Miscellaneous Departments.. $15,554,425.71 680,075.00 $ 16,004.93 $ 8,182,790.00 $ 6,675.555.78 EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS University of Nebraska $ 6,773,762.54 $ 3,740,940.00 $ 2,000,000.00 $ 1,032,822.54 Legislative Reference Bureau 71,500.00 71,600.00 . , Normal Schools 1,524,428.66 1,267,271.00 257,157.66 Total Educational Institutions '$8,369,691.20 $5,079,711.00 2,257,157.66 $ 1,032,822.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">RECAPITULATION OF BIENNIAL APPROPRIATIONS— Coniinued _ a July I, 1937 to June 30,1939 ■ . ■$ Amount of I Tax Reappropria- Cash Federal " . . . Appropriation Funds tlon . Fond Funds PENAL AND CHARITABLE INSTITUTIONS Board of Control $ 5,842,703.12 4,293,942.99 $ 249,760.13 $ 1,299,000.00 Institution for Feeble Minded .,. 2,000.00 2,000.00 Girls' Training School 4,747.89 4,747.89 Hastings State Hospital ,. 11,229.98 11,229.98 Hospital for Tuberculosis 51,000.00 51,000.00 . co State Penitentiary 12,000.00 7,000.00 6,000.00 ; £ Norfolk State Hospital 23,000.00 22,000.00 1,000.00 £ Reformatory for Women ,. 25,000.00 25,000.00 g Reformatory for Men 3,874.87 3,874.87 S Total Penal and Charitable Institn- _ — I ' Z tlons ...'$5,975,555.86 4,398,942.99 $ 277,612.87 $ 1,299,000.00 H RECAPITULATION '. | ° Legislative Departments ,. $ 44,900.00 44,900.00 Judiciary Departments 778,000.00 778,000.00 X Executive Departments ,,... 978,445.32 886,920-00 20,720.32 70,805.00 W Administrative Departments ,. 23,512,803.71 505,289.00 45,789.71 15,759,873.00 5 7,201,852.00 Miscellaneous Departments ...; 15,554,425.71 680,075.00 16,004.93 8,182,790.00 6,675,555.78 ' Edncattonal Institutions 8,369,691.20 5,079,711.00 2,257,167.66 1,032,822.54 • Penai and Charitable Institutions 5,975,555.86 4,398,942.99 277,612.87 1,299,000.00 _^_ Total Biennial Appropriations.... $55,213,821.80 I 12,373,837.99 ' 360,127 83 27,569,625.66 ' $14,910,230.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS STATEMENT OF COMPARATIVE APPROPRIATIONS 1935 1937 Increase or Appropria- Approprla- Decrease lions tions 1935-1937 1937-1939 ■ SS^SSfrSSrtoS 11 " 311 ' 580 ' 281 - 24 $ 819,556.751 Sesslon 787,686.60 360,127.83 427.558.77D General Fund, 51st | Session, Special 624,706.68 624,706.68 D CASH &amp; FEDERAL FUNDS ' Game^ Parks and 334,200.00 326,700.00 7,500.00 D r orestation Motor Vehicle Fund... 1.400,000.00 1,847,500.00 447.500.001 Gas Tax Fund 10,630,000.00 13,050,000.00 2,420,000.00 1 State Assistance Committee 3,700,000.00 7,500,000.00 3,800,000.00 1 Miscellaneous Cash 689,040.44 984,318.00 295,277.56 1 Federal Cash 5,998,019.72 14,910,230.32 8,912,210.601 University Cash 2,000,000.00 2,000,000.00 Normal School Cash.. 175,886.62 257,157.66 81,271.041 Institution Cash 220,300.00 1,299,000.00 1,078,700.001 Nebraska Liquor Con - trol Commission, Cash 304,950.00 304,950.001 Aeronautics Commission, 51st Session, Special. 35,000,00 35,000.00 D State Assistance Com - mittee, 51st Session, Special 13,000.00 13,000.00 D Real Estate Commission, 51st Session, Special. 1,500.00 1,600.00 D Total Cash and Federal Funds, 50th Session $25,147,446.78 $42,479,855.98 $17,332,409,201 Total Cash and Federal Funds, 51st Session 49,500.00 49,500.00 D ■Grand Total, ~ 50th Session $37,495,414.62 $55,213,82L80 $17,718,407,181 Grand Total, 51st Session, Special 674,206.68 674,206.68 D Increase $18,153,465.95 Decrease 436,058.77 Decrease (51st Spec Ses - sion 1935-1937) .... 674^06.68 Total Increase . . .$17;044,200.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">STATEMENT OF THE STATEMENT NO. 2 £ . APPROPRIATIONS TO COVER EXPENSES OF LEGISLATURE Acct. No. Purpose of Appropriations Amount E-2 Members Salaries [ $ 75,000.00 E-3, 4, 5 Employees Salaries &amp; Legislative Expense 76,693.60 Total Appropriations $151,693.60 I ;. :; ;■";■■ \ .'- • j , , ■ • ■. h- ■ I ■ ■■■ EXPENDITURES OF THE 52nd SESSION OF LEGISLATURE Statement Amount 2-A Members Salaries and Mileage $ 38,064.98 2-B . Officers and Employees Salaries 39,624.61 2-C Fostage 4,300.00 2-D Telephone and Telegraph 388.19 2-E Supplies and Incidentals.. 3*800.47 2-F Printing Journals 15,267.13 Total Expenditures $ 101,445.38 Balances Unexpended Members and Officers Salaries $ 37,500.13 Employees Salaries &amp; Legisla - tive Expense 12,748.09 Total Unexpended 50,248.22 Total Appropriations ! $151,693.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS STATEMENT NO.2-A SAURIES OF MEMBERS OF THE LEGISLATURE No. Allow. _, , .. of for Total To Whom Paid Salaries MJle8 MIet PflJd Adams, Ernest A Omaha $ 872.09 130 $ 6.50 878.59 Adams, John Jr. Omaha 872.09 130 6.50 878.59 Armstrong, R. M Auburn 872.09 150 7.50 879.59 Ashmore, Hugh B. Palisade 872.09 520 26.00 898.09 Brady, Frank J. Atkinson .... 872.09 502 25.10 897.19 Brandt, Henry F. ..Beatrice 872.09 90 4.50 876.59 Brodecky, Emil E. Howells 872.09 160 8.00 880.09 Cady, P. L Fremont .... 872.09 120 6.00 878.09 Carlson Swrn Funk 872.09 324 16.20 888.29 Carpenter, Earl W Guide Rock .. 872.09 300 15.00 887.09 Carsten Fred L Avoca 872.09 62 3.10 875.19 Comstock, John H Lincoln ...... 872.09 872.09 Dafoe, Charles A r«cimseh ... 872.09 120 6.00 878.09 iJiers, W. H. Gresham .... 872.09 104 r.20 877.29 Dunn, Lester L Lincoln 872.09 872,09 Frost, Tracy T St. Paul 872.09 260 13.00 885.09 nil r i7 E ' Alliance 872.09 513 25.65 897.74 Hall, Leland Roseland .... 872.09 232 11.60 883.69 Haycock, W. F. Callaway.... 872.09 446 22.30 894.39 Howard, P. M Flats 872.09 640 32.00 904.09 Johnson, Roy W. Miller 872.09 340 17.00 889.09 Johnson, Walter R. Omaha 87249 110 6.50 87&amp;S9 John Orrnd Island. 872.09 202 10.10 882.19 Miller, L. A Kimball 872.09 830 41.50 913.59 Mirphy, L. B Scottsbluff .. 872.09 908 45.40 917.49 McMahon, P. J. Omaha 872.09 130 6.50 878.59 Neubauer E.M. Orleans ! 872.09 398 16.09 888.18 Nuernberger, L. C Wakefield... 872.09 240 12.00 884.09 Norton* John N Polk 872.09 160 8.00 880.09 Peterson, Carl H Norfolk 872.09 253 12.65 884.74 Peterson, John B. .Ashland 872.09 60 3.00 875.09 Pizer, Harry L. North Platte. . 872.09 520 26.00 898.09 Regan, R.- C Columbus . . . 872.09 136 2.72 874.81 Reynolds/John D Niobrara 872.09 428 21.40 893.49 Schult?, 0. Edwin Elgin 872.09 330 leiso 888.59 Slepicka, Alois Wilber 872.09 74 3.70 875.79 Strong, Allen A Gordon 872.09 820 41.00 313 09 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATEMENT OF THE To Whom Paid No . of for Total Salaries Miles Miles Paid Thomas, Amos.......... Omaha $ 872.09 130 6.50 878.59 Tvrdik, Chas. F. Omaha ...... 872.09 120 6.00 878 09 Von Seggern, E. M West Point. .. 872.09 184 9.20 881.29 Warner Charles J Waverly .... 872.09 20 1.00 873.09 Wells Franks Fairbury .... 872.09 144 7.20 879.29 Worthing, Wm. E, Omaha ...... 872.09 120 6.00 878.09 37,499.87 565.11 38,064.98 STATEMENT NO. 2-B SALARIES OF OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES To Whom Paid HngoF. Srb Chief Clerk... s 113000 Fred A. Muller. .Afsistsnt Clerk ,. 904 00 J. W. Lundy ..Sergeant At Arms ..'. 549.00 George Santo .Assistant Sgt.At Arms. ......... 488.OO W. B. Zimmerman Chaplain 452 . O o Mrs. Marion Cashing Postmistress .' 53750 EMPLOYEES ?? ! ?r } Dinan "- Assistant to Clerk..: 920 00 Lyda Hafer Journal I Clerk. ....'.. 5 7604 Esther Vandeburg Assistant Journal Clerk 45950 Clara C. Turbyfill. . ; . . . .Chief Engrossing Clerk 63520 Agnes Heagney Assistant Engrossing Clerk 336 00 I™?*"!!* ••..... Assistant Engrossing Clerk, 423.50 Araath Strong Assistant- Engrossing Clerk. ....... 492.00 f 106 ?^ an .......Stenographer 285.00 Stenographer 27 O . flo ttarriette Worman Stenographer 266 25 Edna Ke "y • Stenographer ......'. 473'no Dorothy Scott Stenographer 442.50 Leona Pierson.. Stenographer 466.00 Margaret Devers Stenographer 44725 Lucille Zilmer Stenographer 44559 Freda Eckhardt Stenographer 27450 Randolph Stewart Stenographer 444 : 00 Marguerite Price Stenographer 3 17 " O o </seg>
            <seg id="p041">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS To Whom Paid Helen Wylie Stenographer 263.00 Teddy Schleiger .Stenographer • 139.00 Florence Castile. Stenographer 295.60 Bella Schadt .Stenographer 252.00 Ealine Robertson Stenographer 236.00 Helen E. Johnson .Stenographer .244.00 Minniebell Yowell Stenographer 297.00 Marilyn Hanson. Stenographer 264.75 Lorane Fancher Stenographer 120.00 Maxine Gustafson ....... Committee Clerk 500.50 Mae M. Ellingson Committee Clerk 534.00 John Quinn ...Committee Clerk ..495.00 Maud Butler Committee Clerk 517.72 Harvey Galloway Committee Clerk 445.00 I*. T. Fleetwood Committee Clerk 455.00 Fileen Zarnfaller Committee Clerk . . . . 559.00 Jo. M. Lacy Committee Clerk 526.00 Fiank Wood Chief Bill Clerk \ .531.00 Harry Tague Assistant Bill Clerk i. 444.00 Harvey Hillman Assistant Bill Clerk 436.00 Paul Beacom Assistant Bill Clerk 432.00 Carl E. Peterson Assistant Bill Clerk 468.00 Pat Stanton Mimeograph Operator 456.00 Don Gordon Mimeograph Operator 448.00 Byron Cahill Docket Clerk &amp; Bkkr. 570.10 Celestine Short Secy. Lieutenant Gov. 665.00 Dorothy Woodward Messenger Girl . ; ; . .362.75 Butler *B. Miltonburger. .Assistant Postmaster ; 456.00 Eugene Fowler Page 369.25 Richard Krueger Page 369.25 Thomas Luhe Page 369.25 Harry Bradley .Chief Custodian 540.00 Trago Me Williams Cloak Room Custodian 385.00 John Teft Cloak Room Custodian 395.60 Fred Martin Gallery Custodian 392.00 Joe Dargaczewski Janitor 388.50 Stine Whitielaw Janitor 427.00 Charles Taylor Janitor 416.50 Tommy Cameron Janitor 374.50 Arthur McWilliams Janitor 10.50 Joe Pokorny Janitor 10.50 Mike Gergen Janitor 3.50 William Dean Janitor 3 50 Dale A. Phillippi Proof Reader 479.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATEMENT OF THE To Whom Paid W. G. Whitford Proof Reader 4C6.50 J. B. Farres Proof Reader 402.00 Tommy Doran Proof Reader 187.75 Jack Doran Proof Reader 326.25 Ruth Case Bordsen Proof Reader 8.00 Milton C. Murphy Bill Drafter J 3,100.00 Robert Van Pelt Council 1,097.05 Louis Tepoel Council 500.00 L. L. Chambers Door Keeper 329.00 Lucile Ledwith Stenographer 24.00 Alpha Lundy Information Clerk 100.00 Nebr. Legislative Reference Bureau— Services — L. R. No. 1 - 3,000.00 Nebr. Legislative Reference Bureau — Services — L. R. No. 1 1,000.00 39,624.61 Note — Subject to an opinion of the Attorney General, the Lieutenant Governor is a Constitutional Officer and his salary was not paid from Legislative Expense. , STATEMENT NO. 2-C POSTAGE Date Warrant No. To Whom Issued Amount 2-24-37 M90252 Mrs. M. J. Cushing, Postmistress $1,000.00 3-10-37 M90649 Mrs. M. J. Cushing, Postmistress 1,000.00 3-27-37 M91694 Mrs. M. J. Cashing, Postmistress 1,000.00 4-27-37 M92692 Mrs. M. J. Cushing, Postmistress 1,000.00 5-14-37 M93107 Mrs. M. J. Cushing, Postmistress 300.00 4,300.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS STATEMENT NO. 2-D TELEPHONE AND TELEGRAPH Date Warrant No. To Whom Issued Amount ■2- 8-37 M89427 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Tel. Co. Service $ 29.45 3-12-37 M90699 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Tel. Co. Service 39.02 3-12-37 M9O7OO Lincoln Tel. &amp; TeL Co. Service 43.90 3 32-37 M93708 Lincoln Tel. &amp; TeL Co. Service 85.55 4-9-37 M9J744 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Tel. Co. Service 65.07 4- 9-37 M91745 Lincoln Tel. &amp; TeL Co. Service 25.65 4-27 37 M92689 Lincoln .Tel. &amp; Tel. Co. Service 9.85 5-25-37 M93780 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Tel. Co. Service 87.10 H-25 37 M93796 Western Union TeL Co. Service 2.60 $388.19 STATEMENT NO. 2-E SUPPLIES AND INCIDENTALS Date Warrant No. To Whom Issued Amount 2-8-37 MF9426 J. L. Roscow— Sign and Cards 70.75 2- 8-37 M89431 The Marshall Press— Motion Blanks 15.00 2- 8-37 M89432 Durham Prtg. Co.— Roll Call Blanks 17.75 2-8-37 M89433 The 1935 Supplement — 44 Copies 253.00 2- 8-37 M89434 Baer Ptrg. Co. — Letterheads and Envelopes 246.10 2- 8-37 M89435 Tax Commissioner Purchasing Department — Supplies 456.15 2-23-37 M90126 The Loup Valley Queen— Printing Committee Reports 8.00 2-23-37 M90127 Nebr. Typewriter Co.— Rental 69.00 2-23-37 M90128 Boyd Printing Co.— Printing Rosters 28.00 2-23-37 M90129 Remington Rand Inc. — Stencils and Supplies 23.76 2-23-37 M90130 George Bros.— Office Supplies 72.87 2-23-37 M90132 Baer Printing Co. — Letterheads and Cards 6.50 2-23-37 M90133 State Journal Printing Co.— Voucher Books , 83.00 2-23-37 M90134 J. L. Roscow— Signs and Cards 6.00 2-23-37 M90J35 Jay Worley— Envelopes 48.50 3-12-37 M90697 Nebraska Typewriter Co.— Rentals 89.00 3-12-37 M90702 Lincoln Stamp &amp; Seal Co.— Badge and Stamp 3.70 3-12-37 M90703 Lincoln Stamp &amp; Seal Co. — Two Badges 7.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">STATEMENT OF THE Date Warrant No. To Wjhom Issued Amount 3-12-37 M90704 George Bros.— Bill Binders.... ,. nB 3-12-37 M90705 F. S. Stretton &amp; Co.-Fire Extinguisher L50 3-12-37 M90706 Eiche Floral Co.— Flowers-Regan Frost, Howard '-, . 7 k 0 3-12-37 M90707 Purchasing Department Revolving Fund— Office Supplies 109 01 3-12-37 M90709 The Marshall Press-Stationery. . IBoo 3-12-87 M90710 George Bros.— Office Supplies.... """ rob 3-12-37 M90711 Jay Worley— Envelopes ' "' B r^ 3-18-37 M91207 Baer Printing Co.-Stationery. Tfin 3-27-37 M91591 Boomers Advertising Service— '".' Printed Supplies 23 75 4-9-37 M91740 Boomers Advertising Service— " Stationery I 29 50 4-9-37 M91741 Durham Printing Co.-Qffice Supplies"'" ia20 4-9-37 M91742 Baer Printing ... 240 75 4- 9-37 M91743 State Journal Printing Co.— Office Supplies pqn 4-13^37 M91966 J. L. Roscow-Signs and Cards G oo 4-13-37 M91967 Jay Worley— Envelopes .!...'"" 4114 4-13-37 M91971 Purchasing Department Revolving Fund— Office Supplies 383t85 4-13-37 M91972 Sanitary Towel &amp; Laundry Co.-Service. ' 22 80 4-20-37 M92275 Durham Printing Co.— Roll Call Blanks 900 4-27-37 M92684 Henry F. Brandts-Lodging..... 2.50 4-27-37 M92685 Frank J. Brady — Lodging £50 4-27-37 M92686 Carl H. Peterson-i-Telephone Call .'...'. 1.60 4-27-37 M92687 E. E. Brodecky— Lodging 2.50 4-27-37 M92688 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. 1 Co.— Bus Fare Committee on Institutions 169.20 4-27-37 M92691 Charles Tvrdik— Lodging 2.50 5-20-37 M93449 Boyd Printing Co.— Rosters 24.75 5-20-37 M93454 Nebraska Typewriter Co.— Rentals . . 179.00 5-20-37 M93455 Jay Worley— Envelopes 83.41 5-20-37 M93456 Durham Printing Co.— Roll Call Blanks ..... £50 5-20-37 M93457 Allen A. Strong— Inspection, Train Fare 9^16 5-25-37 M93776 Boomers Advertising Co.— Stationery. ...... 55I25 5-25-37 M93777 Eiche Floral Co— Flowers (Regan and Srb) 5.50 5-25-37 M93778 Eiche Floral Co.4-Flowers 26.85 5-25-37 M93779 Nebraska State Board of Agriculture- Rental of Chairs - 8.25 5-25-37 M93782 Nebraska Typewriter Co.— Rental and Service 44.75 5-25-37 M93783 Bloom Typewriter Co.— Rental.. 35.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">-. AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS Date Warrant No. To Whom Issued Aranl „, 5-25-37 M937£5 Purch. Dept. Rev. Fund-Oifice Amount^ 5-25-37 M 93 7S1 A . G . Sit-Reniai; Wa-ttae! \\ ™£ 5-25-37 MP3787 Remingtcn Rand Inc—Office Supplies 105.37 5-25-37 M93788 H. R. Kelso C.-Soap Dispensers. . . . .[ .' "JJJ =-2E-37 M9E789 Lincoln Office Supply Co.-Office Supplies 9T „, 5-2537 M9S79.1 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co—Office Supplies. ago 5-25-37 M93791 Baer Frin.ing Co.-Envelopes and Stationery . &lt;,» 5-25-37 M93.92 Jay Worloy-Envelopes H04 5-25-37 M93793 Lawlor Sporting Goods Co.-Desk Keys 4 50 5-25-37 M93795 J. W. Lundy-Flowers for Chambers. .' S 5-2F-37 M93 03 Bloom Typewriter Co.— Renta's . 6-22-37 M94S27 Purchasing Department Revolving '"" Fund— Office Supplies 3qji 6-23-37 M94723 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.-Furniture Re P ai « 3.75 $3,800.47 STATEMENT NO. 2-F PRINTING JOURNALS, LAWS AND BILLS Date Warrant No. To Whom Issued Amount 2-8 37 M89428 Burr Publishing Co.-BiUs S 767 S 2-8-37 M89429 Commercial Printing Co,-Journals. ..'."" 34920 2-8 -37 MS9430 Commercial Printing Co Journals Wlrr 2-23-37 M90125 Commercial Printing Co.-Journals " .' .' ' " " !«« 2-23-37 M90191 Burr Publishing Co.-Bills . . . . '"" i?fT™ 3-12-37 M90C98 Commercial Printing Co.-Journals. . """ ***&lt;* 3-12-37 M9070! Burr Publishing Co.— Bills. . . "" 211030 3-18-37 M91205 Burr Publishing Co.— BUls .'.'." 3054.U 3-18-37 M91206 Commercial Printing Co.— Journals. . (S'MRa 3-27-37 M91592 Claflin Printing Co.— Laws.. 00 Rn 3-27-37 M91593 Claflin Printing Co.-Printing passed Bills 2fi40 4-9 -37 M91737 Burr Publishing Co.— BUls '.'.'.'.'.'." 38^*50 4-9 -37 M91738 Commercial Printing Co Journals. ... rra'ra 4-9-37 M91739 Claflin Printing Co.— Laws. ..... . 70™ 4-13-37 M91970 Claflin Printing Co.— Laws '.'." 45 60 4-20-37 M92273 Commercial Printing Co.-Joumals..."!. ' B12!l6 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">STATEMENT OP THE Date Warrant Na To Whom Issued Amount 4-20-87 M92274 Claflin Printing Co.— Lswb 79 40 4-27-37 M92690 Claflin Printing Co.— Journals ...'. 2AA0 5-20-87 M93460 Commercial Printing Co.— Journals . ** 628 56 5-20-37 M93452 Burr Publishing Co.r-Bills 547.14 5-20-37 M9S453 Claflin Printing Co.— Laws 7&amp;8O 5-25-37 M98781 Burr Publishing Co.— Bills. 875.72 5-25-37 M93784 Commercial Printing Co.—Journals .... 873!oo 5-25-37 M93794 Claflin Printing Co.— Laws 70 80 6-3-37 M93884 Claflin Printing Co— Laws 14s!80 G-22-37 M94326 Claflin Printing Co. — Laws '..,'. 604.80 15,267.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">BIENNIAL REPORT of the State Treasurer of NEBRASKA to the GOVERNOR WALTER H. JENSEN State Treasurer JULY 1, 1936 to JUNE 30, 1938 V </seg>
            <seg id="p048"/>
            <seg id="p049">STATE TREASURER TERRITORIAL B. P. Rankin Term of office began March 16, 1885 William W. Wyman. Term of office began November 6, 1855 August Kountz Term of office began October 8, 1861 STATE August Kountz From February 21, 1867, to January 11, 1869 James Sweet From January 11, 1869, to January 10, 1871 Henry A. Koenigh From January 10, 1871, to January 11, 1875 J. C. McBride. From January 11, 1875, to January 9, 1879 George M. Bartlett From January 9, 1879, to January 4, 1883 Phelps D. Sturdevant From January 4, 1883, to January 8, 1885 Charles D. Willard From January 8, 1885, to January 3, 1889 John E. Hill From January 3, 1889, to January 13, 1893 Joseph S. Bartley From January 13, 1893, to January 7, 1897 John B. Meserve From January 7, 1897, to January 3, 1901 William Stauffer.... From January 3, 1901, to January 8, 1903 Peter Mortenson From January 8, 1903, to January 3, 1907 Lawson G. Brain !.From January 3, 1907, to January 5, 1911 Walter A. George From January 5, 1911, to January 7, 1915 George E. Hall From January 7, 1915, to January 9, 1919 Daniel B. Cropsey '.From January 9, 1919, to January 4, 1923 Charles D. Robinson From January 4, 1923, to January 6, 1927 Willis M. Stebbins From January 6, 1927, to January 8, 1931 T. W. Bass From January 8, 1931, to January 5, 1933 George E. Hall From January 5, 1933, to January 3, 1935 ♦George E. Hall .From January 3, 1935, to December 21, 1936 •*H. J. Murray From December 21, 1936, to January 7, 1937 Walter H. Jensen From January 7, 1937, to January 'Deceased ♦♦Appointed OFFICE PERSONNEL Martin F. Hannigan. Assistant H. J. Murray Deputy Ed. Westering Bond Clerk Paul Liewer Accountant Ruth Frantz. Secretary Jean Coleman. .Warrant Clerk </seg>
            <seg id="p050">REPORT OF REPQRT OF THE STATE TREASURER State of Nebraska Treasury Department Lincoln July 1, 1938 To His Excellency, Roy L. Cochran, Governor of Nebraska Lincoln, Nebraska Li accordance with the requirement of the Statutes of Nebraska, I have the honor of presenting herewith my report as Treasurer of Nebraska for the biennium beginning July 1, 1936, and ending June 30, 1938. In addition to mak - ing a report of all receipts and disbursements by this office, there is included statement of the investment funds held by the State, which summarized, is as follows: Cash June 30, 1936 | $ 7,874^2458 Total Cash Receipts.. 75,389,810.89 $83,264,735.87 Total Cash Disbursements 76,817,101.25 Cash June 30, 1938. __ $ 6&gt; 447,634.62 * • ♦ ♦Permanent Trust Funds Invested (Bonds) Balance June 30, 1936 1 $13,747,005.70 Total Investment and Adjustments....! . 3,591,227.15 $17,338,232.85 Total Redemption and Adjustments 3,425,950.87 Balance June 30, 1938 . $13,912,281.98 Grand Totals, Cash and Bonds, June* 30, 1938. , 20,359,916.60 Very respectfully, WALTER H. JENSEN State Treasurer. . ■ •The Board of Educational Lands and Funds shall make the necessary orders for the investment of these funds. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">STATE TREASURER i GENERAL STATEMENT It is with considerable pride and satisfaction that I present the biennial re - port of the Treasury Department, reflecting as it does the brightness of the financial picture of the State of Nebraska. There seems to be considerable confusion in the minds of the people because of the overdraft in the state general fund. It should be understood that the deficit was caused, not by any one department or institution overspending its appropriation, but by prevailing conditions which make it impossible for many people to pay their taxes. The proceeds of the liquor tax, under the act of 1935, went into the state general fund, and when the state levy was made in 1936 it was estimated the revenue from this source would amount to $1,138,007.87. The legislature of 1937 however, transferred the liquor tax from the general fund to the state assistance fund. Accordingly, when the state levy was made in 1937, and again in 1938, it was increased to absorb the loss from the liquor tax. Tax collections, however, have fallen off on account of adverse economic conditions. From the state levy made in 1936 there was delinquent on June 30, 1938, 11.67 per cent of the total amount levied, while from the levy of 1930, up to June 30, 1932, there was only 4.2 per cent delinquent of the total tax levied. From the above figures, it is evident that the increased delinquent taxes exceed the overdraft in the general fund. However, there is every reason to believe that these conditions will be vastly improved within the coming year. We are fortunate in having plenty of money in all other funds which enables us to hold these general fund warrants as cash, thus saving the state a large amount of interest, and employees and firms who are paid by the state, are saved from having their warrants discounted at a high rate of interest. At the beginning of this biennium, the statement of the Treasurer of Ne - braska showed the sum of $2,875,482.44 of the cash funds invested in various Government Securities. At that time the state law required the banks to pay interest on public money, and the Treasurer experienced great difficulty in securing depositories, which forced him to invest surplus funds in Government Securities. , During this biennium, all of these bonds have been sold because the funds were needed, showing a profit to the general fund of $112,666.12. It is not ad - visable to re-invest sums of money in U. S. Government Securities at the present time, because of the fact that bonds are high in price, and cash may be needed upon short notice, which would necessitate reselling them at a pos - sible loss. This condition, together with the new federal law prohibiting banks from paying interest, will materially affect the problems confronting those who are responsible for public funds, at least as to the earning capacity of the cash funds. i It is my contention, the real protection to public officials, is the collateral furnished by the banks to secure their accounts. Then if a bank should fail the official has something tangible to dispose of and not a mere claim to involve </seg>
            <seg id="p052">REPORT OF him in legal difficulties. In other words, we need the cooperation of the banks if we are to profitably handle public funds. At the time I took office, there was in unavailable funds $1,112,675.97 known as State Assistance (Old), or money collected on additional one cent (lc) gas tax, which was declared void by the Supreme Court. Many claims were filed' against this account, and much work and pressure brought to bear were re - quired to prove to the courts that these claims were not just. The fund is now closed and the money paid to the recipients of old age assistance, as was intended. It should also be noted, receipts and disbursements show an increase of more than 25% ov,er the last biennium. There has been no increase in the number of employees in this office to carry out the additional work, because the Legislature granted our request for funds with which to install an up-to - date bookkeeping system, new forms, and other equipment to replace an obso - lete system which had been in effect for over fifty years. The treasurer's office is now being operated on a system as near to that used in banking as is possible, and the records will be found in much better condition, being more comprehensive by far, than heretofore. I have had three complete audits of this office and on each occasion, all funds shown by the state auditor, as paid into the state treasury, have been properly accounted fof , and all bank deposits are shown to be fully protected by the necessary collateral. These audits were made under authority of the state auditor, by Frost, Congdon and O*Hara of Omaha, Nebraska, certified public accounts. The state treasurer, as provided by law, receives all money paid into the treasury of the state, pays all warrants prepared by the state auditor, and has custody of all cash and securities belonging to the several trust funds of the state. A monthly statement covering the state treasurer's cash funds, is made up in the form, of a balance sheet, submitted to the auditor for verification, and is available to anyone who may be interested. Three days after I assumed office, January 9, 1937, there was received in this office the sum of $2,118.35 which was the balance of the judgment ren - dered in the District Court of Lancaster County, Nebraska, in the case of State of Nebraska v. T. W. Bass et al., as decided by the Supreme Court after deducting the costs of the suit. This sum was credited to the several accounts which the Supreme Court found had suffered losses. This judgment was rendered by the Supreme Court because the defendants permitted brokerage concerns who sold bonds to the state, to detach from the bonds interest coupons to which these companies were not entitled. This judg - ment was rendered on the basis of 16 counts. On 95 counts remaining, out of the total 111 counts on the basis of which the Lancaster District Court had awarded $56,338.72 judgment for the State of Nebraska, the Supreme Court de- </seg>
            <seg id="p053">STATE TREASURER ■ clared itself hopelessly unable to arrive at any figure, stating as follows in its opinion (131 Nebr. Reports, 604): "The state must act through the agency of its officers, and when they so far fail in their duty that no proper or competent record is left from which the facts may be ascertained, the state is left to suffer the consequences of the delinquency of its officers the same as is the result with any other business institution." With this opinion before me, on coming into the state treasurer's office, I decided to say nothing about this whole matter of losses suffered by the state, until such time as my biennial report would be made, when I would have the utmost facts available and could render an open statement to the very best of my knowledge and on behalf of the true interests of the state, and present it in a cool and dispassionate atmosphere free of politics and political cam - paigning, and which is herewith presented. Shortly after the beginning of my term there became available the Hanson Report, of the Hanson Audit Company, a report of audit and investigation of the state treasurer's office which was asked by the Legislature of 1935, and covering separately the years 1927-1931 (Stebbins' 2 terms), 1931-1933 (Bass' term), and 1933-1937 Hall's 2 terms). This report is the most thorough report ever made in the history of the state treasury. In brief, the Hanson audit sets forth in detail: A. That the state is short considerable sums as a result of various trans - actions, set forth in detail on pages 99 and 100 during Stebbins' term, in ad - dition to losses cited on page 111. B. That during Bass' term, not counting the items involved in the suit in Lancaster County District Court, 317 blocks of bonds were taken up before they were due or optional, as set forth on page 33 of the Hanson report, mostly without approval of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. C. That "soon after Mr. Hall took office the practice of clipping coupons for accrued interest and premium on bond purchases was discontinued," as stated on page 65 of the Hanson report, and losses to the state stopped. Losses were sustained by the state on blocks refunded or redeemed prior to optional or due dates, but as stated on page 66 of the report these were, in the majority of cases, bonds in distress. Of all losses suffered by the state, based upon careful study and analysis of the records in this office, the greatest loss is possibly through the exchange of good bonds for poor bonds, and principally during the Bass term. The total net loss to the state is hard to determine. Sums that could be recovered by the state is also a difficult matter to determine, although some of these bonds gave every evidence at the time of purchase of being bad bonds. Thirty pages of the Hanson report are given to a listing of the bonds in question. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">REPORT OF • The state treasurer cannot himself institute suits at law to recover funds that are lost, but the present state treasurer is of the opinion that he would be delinquent in office, and false to his oath of office, the state constitution, and the laws enacted thereunder, and which he has sworn to uphold, did he not call attention in this report to the losses suffered by the state and suggest suits at law, the state's only recourse. Less than that, I cannot do, and more so when taxes are raised by difficulty through hard work and toil of the people themselves, and furthermore, when the state has gone to the added expense by legislative enactment of authorizing an audit and investigation of the state treasury, made public during my administration, and setting forth losses to the state treasury such as have been above analyzed and summarized. As the Hanson report states, "* ♦ • some state officials when elected, as - sume the attitude they can do no wrong, that they are above the law, and that an investigation into their affairs is an offense." This should not be, and no amount of law can change such an attitude. And no law can prevent deliberate falsification of records, such as a former official during the Bass term testified under oath in court, had been done during that term. There is no proposed law I can suggest; an honest and correct attitude on the part of the state treas - urer and personnel under him is the best safeguard. As for the conduct of this office since the present treasurer has assumed custody thereof, the following measures have been adopted, all carrying out the recommendations of the Hanson investigation and audit report: 1. Approval of Board of Educational Lands and Funds before buying or selling bonds. 2. Co-operation in spirit as well as in law with the said Board of Educational Lands and Funds instead of entering into deals known only to this office. 3. Support of the Hanson report (page 5) in herewith recommending that the legislature reimburse the school fund in the sum of $43,824 which has been lost in the principal by charge-offs, and which principal sum by law must not be impaired. 4. In accord with the spirit and recommendations of the Hanson Audit, it is the recommendation of this office that a sufficient fund be appropriated to provide for frequent audits of all public offices in which state funds are received and handled. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">STATE TREASURER «.« 0 ? 0 ** 1 ?? u**? 116 !? 1 *T om * e general ledger gives the condition of the several State of Nebraska funds as of June 30, 1938: Current State Revenue: General Fund $ 1358553 Aviation 26 422 69 Capitol Fund _ , : ; : . : , ■• ■" ■■ ■■■■_. ' 49*30 Compensation Court 72,43411 Game, Forestation and Parks ■" ■ ■ 33,'60921 Gasoline Highway Fund. 1,727,583.18 Institution Cash . 141050 44 Liquor Control ... "ZZ~ 20,89957 Miscellaneous Cash 529,823.88 Motor Vehicle ......'.'. 432^387^46 Normal Cash and Library ". 44,*684 44 State Assistance 1,025,39959 University Cash 213,921.17 4,282,251.37* Federal Funds: Federal Aid Road. 178,998.70 Federal Assistance 92,073.50 Federal Building 94,034.07 Federal Public Health 58,728.25 Federal University 40,507 38 Federal Voc. Education. 128,864 95 Trust Acct. N. I. R. Highway Fund. 101,364.67 Unemployment Compensation Comm.. 17,312.76 U S. Employment Service 3,649.80 715,534.08* Current Trust Funds: Normal School Income „ 4^78.59 Soldiers Relief Income 18,659.66 State Hail Funds 2,945.38 Temporary School 556,O83!oi University Income 331,308.38 913,575.02* Permanent Trust Funds (For Investments): Agriculture College Endowment 5,027.11 . Bessey Memorial 868.14 Normal School Endowment 54926 Permanent School 265,984.39 Permanent University 5,311.33 Soldiers Relief _ 57,938.49 335,678.72* Unemployment Trust Fund. 200,595.43 200,595.43* Total Cash Funds $ 6,447,634.62s $ 6,447,634.62* Permanent Trust Funds (Bonds): Agriculture College Endowment $ 660,594.22 Bessey Memorial 5,600.00 Normal School Endowment 82,713.88 Permanent School 10,937,13225 Permanent University 284,180.12 Soldiers Relief 1,942,061.51 13,91228158s Grand Totals, Cash and Bonds $20,359,916.60* $20,359,916.60s Cash Account and Bonds: Warrants $ 427,453.41 . Deposited with Various Banks _ 6,020,181.21 Total Cash $ 6,447,634.62 Permanent Trust Funds (Bonds) 1351228158 Total Cash and Bonds $20,359516.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">10 SCHEDULE A . • • ■ — . ' ' . v- Showing the Receipts, Disbursements, and Transfers of the Nebraska State Treasury for the Biennium, July 1, 1936 to June 30,1938. Current Revenue Funds: . Balance Disburse- Balances June 30, 1936 Receipts Credit Tfrs. merits Debit Tfrs. June 30, 1938 1. General Fund. $ 630,724.95 $10,095,318.87 $2,108,954.02 $11,737,035.40 $ 1,083,97651 $ 13,985.53 2. Aviation Fund. 9,328.53 53,603.36 26,509.19 10,000.00 26,422.69 •3, Capitol Fund. 206,706.74 15,862.93 13,915.61 123,681.71 112,754.27 49.30 4. Compensation Court 43,622.25 75,386.44 46,574.58 72,434.11 5. Game, Forestation and Parks 34,225.06 338,123.54 338,736.58 2.81 33,609.21 6. Gasoline Highway Fund 1,588,058.37 23,682,272.85 455,609.61 20,578,931.91 3,419,425.74 1,727,583.18 « 7. Institution Cash 149,396.20 1,229,698.50 98,609.17 1,204,835.93 131,817.50 141,050.44 H 8. Liquor Control Fund 109,214.98 3,516,722.62 690,201.08 2,914,836.55 20,899.97 9. Miscellaneous Cash 386,295.33 1,166,367.90 24,687,90 1,012,675.53 34,851.72 529,823.88 8 10. Motor Vehicle . 141,531.74 1,887,724.12 27,863.68 1,600,291.81 24,440.27 432,387.46 3 11. Normal Cash and Library 34,745.05 260,050.69 250,111.30 .....: 44,684.44 o 12. State Assistance (New).. 922,828.97 1,385,636.91 6,182,312.34 7,465,378.23 1,025,399.99 "d 13. State Assistance (Old) 895,633.19 .OOf 217,042.78 1,112,675.97 14. University Cash 488,260.56 2,700,553.44 2,974,892.83 213,921.17 Total Current State Revenue $ 5,640,571.91* $46,407,322.17* $9,128,995.11* $48,049,856.08* $ 8,844,781.74* $ 4,282,251.37* Federal Funds Received by State: 15. Federal Aid Road $ 52,910.76 $ 4,190.285.37 $ 5,065.28 $ 3,672,277.82 $ 396,984.89 $ 178,998.70 16. Federal Assistance 234,702.27 5,798,751.55 5,941,380.32 92,073.50 17. Federal Building Fund .Out 214,462.52 131,817.50 238,330.34 13,915.61 94,034.07 18. Federal Public Health 33,484.13 146,901.95 121,657.83 58,728.25 19. Federal University „. 54,681.47 1,066,127.10 1,080,301.19 40,507.38 20. Federal Vocational Education 84,357.62 360,365.13 315,857.80 128,864.95 21. Trust Acct. N.I.R. Highway Fund 423,442.92 7,613,275.02 7,930,287.99 5,065.28 101,364.67 22. Unemployment Compensation </seg>
            <seg id="p057">11 \ Balance Disburse- Balances June 30, 1936 Receipts Credit Tfrs. ments Debit Tfrs. June 30, 1938 Division .00f 114,468.51 97,155.75 17,312.76 23. U.S. Employment Service 9,793.75 59,584.64 65,728.59 3,649.80 Total Federal Funds $ 893,372.92 $19,564,221.79 $ 136,882.78 $19,462,977.63 $ 415,965.78 $ 715,534.08" Grand Totals $ 6,533,944.83* $65,971,543.96* $9,265,877.89* $67,512,833.71* $. 9,260,747.52* $ 4,997,785.45 Current Trust Funds: 24. Forest Reserve 4,770.91 4,770.91 .00± 25. Normal School Income 9,848.79 6,254.89 11,525.09 457859 26. Soldiers Relief Income 31,372.10 151,837.56 10,447.73 150,002.27 24,995.46 18659 66 27. State Hail Funds 4,833.70 2,363.16 4,139.36 112.12 2,945 38 m 28. Temporary School 609,865.79 2,002,041.01 12,108.83 2,040,763.57 27,169.05 556,083.01 h 29. University Income 318,041.46 94,666.19 600.00 78,492.21 3,507.06 331,308.38 &gt; Total $ 973,961.84* $ 2,261,933.72* 23,156.56* 2,289,693.41* 55,783.69* 913,575.02s §. Total Warrants Redeemed 69,802,527.12* g Permanent Trust Funds: (For Investment) »&gt; 30. Agriculture College w Endownment $ 25,071.24 $ 140,034.88 156,336.55 3,742 46 5,027.11 S 31. Bessey Memorial 128.14 740.00 868 14 S 32. Normal School Endowment 4,146.46 13,111.43 16,708.63 549 26 " 33. Permanent School 262,112.48 2,707,138.47 83,116.78 2,781,606.75 4,776 59 265 984 39 34. Permanent University 6.654.61 82,304.54 83,546.85 100.97 5,311.33 35. Soldiers Relief 68,905.38 531,015.65 9,997.73 494,982.54 56,997.73 57,938.49 Total $ 367,018.31s $ 3,474,344.97* $ 93,114.51* $ 3,533,181.32s $ 65,617.75s $ 335,678.72s Social Security Account: , 36. Nebraska Unemployment Com - pensation— (Clearing Account)....$ .OOJ $ 3,681,988.24s .00$ $ 3,481,392.81s $ 200,595.43s Grand Total (Cash) $ 7,874,924.98* $75,389,810.89* $9,382,148.96* $76,817,101.25 $ 9,382,148.96s $ 6,447,634.62* </seg>
            <seg id="p058">REPORT OF 12 SCHEDULED Permanent Trust Funds (Invested) Transfersand Transfers and Balances Investments Adjustments Redemption Adjustments Balances Total Bonds $13,747,005.70s $ 3,533,181.32s $ 58,045.83s $ 3,341,696.49s $ 84^4-3fs |13,912,28158s Total CaA ..:.ZZZ:ZI $7,874,924.98 |75,389,810.89 $9,382,148.96 $76,817,10125 $ 9,382,148^6 $ 6,447,634.62 Grand Totals (Cash and Bonds)....$21,621,930.68* $78,922,992.21* $9,440,194.79* $80,158,797.74* $ 9,466,403.34* $20,359,916.60* </seg>
            <seg id="p059">STATE TREASURER GENERAL FUND Schedule A-l Receipts Disbursements Balance June 30, 1936. $ 630,72455 Receipts From: Auditor of Public Accounts $ 111.43 Bank Charter Fees 1444.36 Board of Control. 5,000.00 Car Lane Tax. 92,578.58 Compensation Court 936.30 Corporation Occupation Tax.... 327,074.73 Estate Tax 33,35358 Governor _ 318.17 Insurance Premium Tax. 1,144554.63 Property Tax 8,339,720.01 Public Lands &amp; Buildings Commissioner, Rents., etc 6,339.36 Roads and Irrigation. dealers license 8,742.70 Interest on cash funds, invested in Government bonds 112,666.12 Supreme Court, fees and costs.. 16,136.89 Miscellaneous Receipts, sale of books, refunds, etc 6,241.61 10,095,318.87* Transfers and Adjustments: From State Assistance (Old) as per court order. 1,112,675.97 From Liquor Tax. 975,483.71 From Athletic Division. 10,000.00 From Boards and Bureaus 5,683.48 Adjustments 5,110.86 2,108,954.02s Total Disbursements $11,737,035 40 Total Transfer and Adjustments lio83.976.91 Balance June 30, 1938 ' 13,985.53 ' $12,834,997.84* $12,834,997.84* </seg>
            <seg id="p060">REPORT OF Receipts Disbursements Schedule A-2 AVIATION FUND Balance June 30, 1936 $ 9,328.52 Receipts ., _ . 53.603.36 Disbursements $ 26,509.19 Transfer (for lighting State Capitol Tower).... 10,000.00 Balance June 30, 1938 J 26,422.69 . 62,931.88* $ 62,931.88* Schedule A-3 CAPITOL FUND Balance June 30, 1936 $ 206,706.74 Receipts i 15,86253 Transfers and Adjustments J 13,915.61 Disbursements $ 123,681.71 Transfers and Adjustments 1 112,754.27 Balance June 30, 1938 49.30 $ 236,485.28* $ 236,485.28* Schedule A-4 COMPENSATION COURT Balance June 30, 1936 _ $ 43,622.25 Receipts 1 75,386.44 Disbursements ..: . $ 46 574 58 Balance June 30, 1938 72,434.11 $ 119,008.69* $ 119,008.69* Schedule A-5 GAME, FOREST ATION AND PARKS COMMISSION Balance June 30, 1936 1 $ 34,225.06 Receipts: No. Account: 310 Administration of Game Laws $ 314,234.62 312 Niobrara Island Park 16157 314 Maintenance of State Parks.... 16,494.11 316 Arbor Lodge 212.65 317 Chadron State Park 6,878.14 318 StolleyPark 7.74 • 319 Victoria Springs State Park.... 134.31 338,123.54* Total Disbursements : $ 338,736.58 Total Transfers and Adjustments „ 2.81 , Balance June 30, 1938 33,609.21 $ 372,348.60* $ 372,348.60* </seg>
            <seg id="p061">STATE TREASURER Receipts Disbursements Schedule A-6 GASOLINE HIGHWAY FUND Balance June 30, 1936 $ 1,588,058.37 Receipts From: Gasoline Tax Collections $22,538,824.11s Remittances from R I Dept 1,143,448.74 23,682.272.85s Total Transfers and Adjustments 455,609.61 Disbursements $20,578,931.91 Transfers and Adjustments .... 3,419,425.74 Balance June 30, 1938 1,727,58318 „ , . , $25,725,940.83* $25,725,940.83* Schedule A-7 INSTITUTION CASH Balance June 30, 1936 $ 149 396.20 i Receipts To: No. Account 501 Board of Control Revolving Fund $ 28,602.91 511 Feeble Minded Institute, Beatrice 75,16059 521 Girls Industrial School Geneva 6,076.70 531 Soldiers and Sailors Home, Grand Island .: 28,891.21 541 Hospital for the Insane, Ingleside 223,184.68 551 Boys Industrial School, Kearney 39,237.92 561 Hospital for Tuberculosis, Kearney 3,929.43 571 Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln ..'. 82,842.27 581 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln.. 56,083.48 591 State Penitentiary, Lincoln .... 99,613.22 601 Girls Industrial Home, Milford 2,653.12 611 Soldiers and Sailors Home, Milford 11,274.45 621 School for the Blind, Nebraska City 1,813.88 631 School for the Insane, Norfolk 55,204.11 641 School for the Deaf, Omaha.... 12,175.58 651 Women's Reformatory, York.. 15,768.48 661 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln 1,404.46 671 Men's Reformatory, Lincoln.. 92,559.69 681 Genoa State Farm, Genoa 57,611.25 730 Board of Control, Nebr. State*Use*Prison Emp 335,611.07 1,229,698.50s Transfers and Adjustments 98,609.17 Disbursements 1,204.835.93 Transfers and Adjustments 131,81750 Balance June 30, 1938 141,050.44 $1,477,703.87* $l,477,703.87s </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OP 1 Schedule A-8 Receipts Disbursements LIQUOR FUND CONTROL Balance June 30, 1936 $ 109,21498 Receipts _ 3,516,722.62 Total Disbursements 690 20108 Total Transfers and Adjustments ... 2,914,836.55 Balance June 30, 1938 20,899.97 $3,625,937.60* $3,625,937.60' Schedule A-9 MISCELLANEOUS CASH Balance June 30, 1936. $ 386,295 33 Receipts To: . No. Account 58 Athletic Division $ 13,74718 65 Real Estate Board 22,662.05 69 Stock Brand Fund 19,165.01 74 Metropolitan Utilities 1,442.54 103 Examination and Certificate Fees, State Supt 13,457.50 109 Bureau of Educ. and Reg. of Nurses 17,807.00 119 Refunds to Capitol Fund. 38.10 121 Food, Drugs and Oils..... 402,368.37 127 Eradication of Bovine T.B 5,679.22 128 Port of Entry Inspection Fees 28,103.50 129 Towing Fees 27,329.80 130 Adm. and Enforcement of Port of Entry 5,640.00 131 Itinerant Merchant 3,640.00 134 Bee Inspection 2,155.41 135c Eradication of Insects, Pests and Inspection of Nursery Stock 4,148.20 138 Potato Inspection 9,380.50 139 Live Stock Sales 6,950.00 164 Bureau of Examining Boards 100,944.08 164b For Benefit of Professions. 1,913.00 185 Roads and Irrigation, Misc. Receipts 5,987.02 205 Bank, Bldg. &amp; Loan Assns. &amp; Trust Co.'s Assessments 66,597.97 212 Insurance Fees _ 163,535.71 213 Insurance Examination Exp... 35,867.79 215 State Fire Marshall 33,534.53 245 Railway Commission, Misc. Receipts 497.64 246 Grain Warehouse Fees 4,165.48 246a Grain Storage Fees 16,462.95 247 Motor Carrier Fund 52,090.00 359 Bureau of Child Welfare 1,314.06 700 Purchasing Dept. Revolving Fund 84,824.00 715 Roads &amp; Lrrig. All moneys donated and reimbursements 14,919.29 1,166,367.90s Total Transfers and Adjustments.. 24,687.90 Total Disbursements 1,012,675.53 Total Transfers and Adjustments.. 34,851.72 Balance June 30, 1938 529,823.88 $1,577,351.13* $l,577,35113s </seg>
            <seg id="p063">STATE TREASURER Schedule A-10 Receipts Disbursements MOTOR VEHICLE FUND Balance June 30, 1936 g U1 ™ ,, Receipts To: ? 141,531.74 No. Account iIrk ?^i e 112,935.26 186b Motor Vehicle License Fee, under old law 13,515 11 ?s ffie^affssssi • i * aiB * A License Fee 3941 'Win 192 Motor Vehicle Dealers «M«W0 Administration 15 8G2 21 1««7 70*19. Total Transfers and AdjustmemZ ' '^863 ef Total Disbursements -27,863.68 Total Transfers and 1,600,291.81 Adjustments _ Balance June 30, 1938 A ™'t!&amp;% $2,057,119.54* $2,057,119^4* Schedule A-ll NORMAL CASH AND LIBRARY Balance June 30, 1936 $ &lt;H7*;n=: Receipts To: * 34,745.05 No. Account 431-2 Chadron Normal .'. 49 035 qq 441-2 Kearney Normal !."ZZ" 67*724 61 451-2 Peru Normal 61 14463 safflssr 1^ = «#s- *— , M Balance June 30, 1938 " 2 2? I HH9 44,684.44 $ 294,795.74* $ 294,795.74* Schedule A-12 STATE ASSISTANCE FUND (New) Balance June 30, 1936 s ooospoq? Receipts From: * 922,828.97 Estate Tax 55,182 67 Old Age Pension Tax " 1 947 3S2 ?f5 Board of Control, for crippled a^/^hm.* children 29,189 85 S^^aKSSfife 53&gt;88203 v"**"' Gas Tax for month of June, 1936.... 192,186^3 Gas Tax for the Biennium 2,967,437J21s Liquor Tax for June, 1936. 106,852.39 Liquor Tax for the Biennium 1,832*50045 oeneral Fund, as per court order.. 1,083,000 00 Adjustments man 1 ; riot,,,,. Total Disbursements ZZZZ 33M5 6 . 182 . 312 -34s Balance June 30, 1938 JffiSS $8,490,778^2* $8,490,778^2» </seg>
            <seg id="p064">REPORT OF Receipts Disbursements Schedule A-13 STATE ASSISTANCE (Old) Balance June 30, 1936 $ 895,633.19 Total Transfers 217,042.78 Total Transfers (Court ruled this amt. should no longer be held up, Tfr. to Gen'l Fund) 1,112,675.97 Balance June 30, 1938 None $1,112,675.97* $1,112,67557* Schedule A-14 UNIVERSITY CASH Balance June 30, 1936 $ 488,260.56 Receipts 2,700,553.44 Total Disbursements 1 2,974,892.83 Balance June 30, 1938 : J 213,921.17 $3,188,814.00* $3,188,814.00* Schedule A-15 ■ .1 '-. ■ FEDERAL AID ROAD Balance June 30, 1936 $ 52,910.76 Total Receipts 4,190,285.37 Total Transfers and Adjustments J 5,065.28 Total Disbursements 1 3,672,277.82 Total Transfers (Gasoline Highway Fund) ■'.! 396,984.89 Balance June 30, 1938 178,998.70 $4,248,261.41* $4,248,261.41* Schedule A-16 FEDERAL ASSISTANCE FUND Balance June 30, 1936 $ 234,702.27 Total Receipts 5,798,751.55 Total Disbursements „ 5,941,380.32 Balance June 30. 1938 92,07350 $6,033,453.82* $6,033,453.82* Schedule A-17 . FEDERAL BUILDING FUND Balance June 30, 1936 _ „ $ .OOt Total Receipts 214,46252 Total Transfer and Adjustments 131,817.52 Total Disbursements „ 238,330.34 Total Transfer and Adjustments h 13,915.61 Balance June 30, 1938 - 94,034.07 $ 346,280.02* $ 346,280.02* </seg>
            <seg id="p065">STATE TREASURER Receipts Disbursements Schedule A-18 FEDERAL PUBLIC HEALTH Balance June 30, 1936 $ 33,48413 Total Receipts 146,901.95 Total Disbursements 121,657.83 Balance June 30, 1938 58,72825 $ 180,386.08 $ 180,386.08* Schedule A-19 FEDERAL UNIVERSITY Balance June 30, 1936 $ 54,681.47 Total Receipts 1,066,127.10 Total Disbursements 1,080,30119 Balance June 30, 1938 40,507.38 $1,120,808.57* $1,120,808.57* Schedule A-20 FEDERAL VOCATIONAL EDUCATIONAL Balance June 30, 1936 $ 84,357.62 Total Receipts 360,365.13 Total Disbursements 315,857.80 Balance June 30, 1938 128,86455 | $ 444,722.75* $ 444,722.75 Schedule A-21 TRUST ACCOUNT N.I.R. HIGHWAY FUND Balance June 30, 1936 $ 423,442.92 Receipts 1 7,613,275.02 Total Disbursements 7,930,287.99 Transfers and Adjustments 5,06528 Balance June 30, 1938 101,364.67 $8,036,717.94* $8,036,71754* Schedule A-22 UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION DIVISION ADMINISTRATION ACCOUNT Balance June 30, 1936 $ .00t Receipts 114.468.51 Disbursements 97455.75 Balance June 30, 1938 i 17,312.76 $ 114,468.51* $ 114,468.51* \ </seg>
            <seg id="p066">REPORT OF Schedule A-23 ! ReceiptS Disbursements U. S. EMPLOYMENT SERVICE ADMINISTRATION ACCOUNT Balance June 30, 1936 $ 9 793 75 Receipts 59'584!64 Disbursements „ _ _ _ 65 728 59 Balance June 30, 1938 3*649.80 $ 69,378.39* •$ 69,378.39* CURRENT TRUST FUNDS Schedule A-24 FOREST RESERVE Balance June 30, 1936 j $ .00f Receipts w _ J 4,770.91 Disbursements i J 4 77051 Balance June 30, 1938 i OOt $ 4,770.91* $ 4,770.91s Schedule A-25 NORMAL SCHOOL INCOME Balance June 30, 1936 $ 9,848.79 Receipts From: Interest on bond Investments 5,922.25 Lease on School Land Contract 332.64 6,254.89s Total Disbursements 11,525.09 Balance June 30, 1938 4,578.59 $ 16,103.68* $ 16,103.68* Schedule A-26 . SOLDIERS RELIEF INCOME Balance June 30, 1936 $ 31,372.10 Receipts: Int. on Bond Investments $ 151,837.56 Transfer and Adjustments 1 10,447.73 Transfers and Adjustments J • 24,995.46 Disbursements J 150,00227 Balance June 30, 1938 j : 18,659.66 $ 193,657.39* $ 193,657.39* Schedule A-27 STATE HAIL FUNDS Balance June 30, 1936 1 $ 4,833.70 Receipts _ J 2,363.16 Disbursements '. 4,139.36 Transfers and Adjustments 11212 Balance June 30, 1938 2,945.38 $ 7,196.86* $ 7,196.86* *. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">STATE TREASURER '■ '■ ' Receipts Disbursements Schedule A-28 TEMPORARY SCHOOL. FUND Balance June 30, 1936 $ 609865 79 Receipts From: Interest on Bond Investments.... 850,758.36 Interest on School Land Contract 116,781.71 Lease on School Land Contract.. 756,985.14 Itinerant Merchant 9J.00.00 Liquor Licenses 262,329.00 Warehouse Licenses 72.00 Employment Agents 1,700.00 Miscellaneous Receipts 4,314.80 2,002.041.01* Transfers and Adjustments 12,108.83 Disbursements 2 040 763J57 Transfers and Adjustments ' 27*1 69 05 Balance June 30, 1938 556!o83:oi $2,624,015.63* $2,624,015.63* Schedule A-29 UNIVERSITY INCOME Ealance June 30, 1936 $ 318,041 46 Receipts From: Interest on Bond Investments 74,252.44 University Land Interest 3,831.25 University Land Lease : 6,239.54 Agriculture Land Interest 2,650.45 Agriculture Land Lease 7,692.51 94,66619* Transfers and Adjustments 600.00 Disbursements 78 492.21 Transfers and Adjustments • 3*507 os Balance June 30, 1938 331,308!38 $ 413,307.65* $ 413,307.65* PERMANENT TRUST FUNDS ■^ (For Investment) Schedule A-30 AGRICULTURE COLLEGE ENDOWMENT Balance June 30, 1936 $ 25,071.24 Receipts From: Bonds Redeemed 140,034.88 Disbursements, Bond Purchases 156,336.55 Transfers and Adjustments „ 374246 Balance June 30, 1938 ___ 5!027!u $ 165,106.12* $ 165406.12* </seg>
            <seg id="p068">REPORT OF 1 Receipts Disbursements Schedule A-31 BESSEY MEMORIAL Balance June 30, 1936 $ 128.14 Receipts, Bonds Redeemed - 740.00 Disbursements ; None Balance June 30, 1938 x 868.14* $ 868.14* $ 868.14* Schedule A-32 Balance June 30, 1936 „ 4 4JL46.46 Receipts From: Bonds Redeemed 1 13,111.43 Disbursements, Bonds Purchased J 16,708.63 Balance June 30, 1938 J 549.26 $ 17,257.89* $ 17,257.89* Schedule A-33 PERMANENT SCHOOL FUND Balance June 30, 1936 $ 262,112.48 Receipts From: Bonds Redeemed ,.....-. 2,615,224.86 School Land Principal 91,913.61 2,707,138.47s Transfers and Adjustments 83,116.78 Disbursements, Bonds Purchased.. I . 2,781,606.75 Transfers and Adjustments 4,776.59 Balance June 30, 1938 265,984.39 $3,052,367.73* $3,052,367.73* Schedule A-34 PERMANENT UNIVERSITY Balance June 30, 1936 $ 6,654.61 Receipts From: Bonds Redeemed 81,57154 Agricultural College Land Principal „ 732.60 82,304.54s Disbursements, Bond Purchases .... , 83,546.85 Transfers and Adjustments 100.97 Balance June 30, 1938 5,311.33 I . $ 88,959.15* $ 88,959.15* </seg>
            <seg id="p069">STATE TREASURER Receipts Disbursements Schedule A-35 SOLDIERS RELIEF Balance June 30, 1936 . &lt;t kb one no Receipts, Bonds Redeemed "ZZZZI * 531 015BS Transfers and Adjustments q'oiv™ Disbursements, Bonds Purchased'™.' ».*»/.« MdQm -. Transfers and Adjustments ~™ •Balance June 30, 1938 j^ZZ s. •Note-$50,000.00 of this amount is ear marked, ASS^t'dLSHZ Schedule A-36 SOCIAL SECURITY ACCOUNT NEBRASKA UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION CLEARING ACCOUNT •Receipts * o 681588 24 Disbursements, to Nebraska Unemployment "Trust ' ' Fund with the U. S. Treasury Dept 3 475 , 00 nn Adjustments, checks Returned Ins. Funds, and d,4fi&gt;,dUU.UO Refunds to the employer c no, Q1 State Treasurer's book and bank balance '" b,U9J.81 June 30, 1938 20059543 $3,681,988^4 $3,681,988^4 •Note— Contribution receipts made to the State Treasurer by the Unemploy - ment Division are a tax made against the employer for Unemployment </seg>
            <seg id="p070">REPORT OF SCHEDULE B: I. PERMANENT TRUST FUNDS INVESTED (Bonds) The Board of Educational Lands and Funds, shall make the necessary orders for the investment of these funds. Schedule B-l AGRICULTURE COLLEGE ENDOWMENT Investment Redemption Balance June 30, 1936 $ 644,292.55s Total Investment 156,336.55 Total Redemption 140,034.88 Balance June 30, 1938 1 660,594.22 $ 800,629.10* $ '800,629.10* Schedule B-2 BESSEY MEMORIAL ENDOWMENT Balance June 30, 1936 $ 6,340.00 Total Redemption 740.00 Balance June 30, 1938 5,600.00 $ 6,340.00* $ 6,340.00* Schedule B-3 NORMAL SCHOOL ENDOWMENT Balance June 30, 1936 ; $ 79,116.68 , Total Investment • 16,708.63 \&lt; Total Redemption i I 13,111.43 Balance June 30, 1938 J 82,713.88 $ 95,825.31* $ 95,825.31* Schedule B-4 PERMANENT SCHOOL FUND , Balance June 30, 1936 $10,853,877.44 Total Investment 2,781,606.75 Total Transfers and Adjustments 1 1,048.10 Total Redemption i 2,615,224.86 Total Transfers and Adjustments 1. 84,175.18 Balance June 30, 1938 10,937,132.25 , $13,636,532.29 $13,636,532.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">STATE TREASURER • Schedule B-5 PERMANENT UNIVERSITY FUND Balance June 30, 1936 /"mwSS^i Redemption Total Investment Z " ? kPSbS Total Redemption 83,546.85 Total Adjustments and Transfers ....."Z ' to ™ Balance June 30, 1938 . HZ™ 284A8ol2 $ 365.831.26* $ 365,83126* Schedule B-6 SOLDIERS RELIEF FUND Balance June 30, 1936 « i ooi na* co Total Investment ? 'K»S Total Transfers and AdjustmenteZZZ 56597 73 Total Redemption ao^wf./a 49,--,-- Balance June 30, 1938 ZT~ ufiSS $ 2,433,074.89* $ 2,433,074.89* </seg>
            <seg id="p072">REPORT OF DEPARTMENTAL, EXPENSE Showing unexpended balance of appropriation on July 1, 1936; appropria - tion for biennium beginning July 1, 1937; amount expended during the two years and the balance on hand at the close of business June 30, 1938. / ■ -' Appro - Balance priation Expendi Balance June 30, July 1, tures June 30, 1936 1937 1938 Salary of State Treasurer..' $ 1,800.00 $10,000.00 $10,000.00 $ 5,000.00 Salary of Deputy Treasurer 2,640.00 5,280.00 5,280.00 2,640.00 Salaries and Wages 7,000.04 14,500.00 14,18456 7,315.08 Maintenance : 1,997.61 4,000.00 3,806.11 17.99* 2,173.51 Premium on Treasurer's Surety Bonds 5,000.04 7,975.00 12,298.63 301.41* 375.00 Insurance Policies 590.02 590.02 Bookkeeping Machine 750.00 750.00 Deficiency in Amount Appropri - ated for Salary of State Treas. by Legislature of 1935 (3,200.00) I $21,637.69 $43,095.02 $47,229.12 $17,503.59 * Lapsed Balances remaining in general fund/ Balance June 30, 1936, Appropriation July 1, 1937 and deficit in Treas. Salary Appropriation .: $64,732.71 Expenditures and Closing Balance $64,732.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">STATE TREASURER GASOLINE TAX DISTRIBUTION July 1, 1936 to June 30, 1938 Gasoline Highway Fund Receipts, as shown on the Statement $23,682,272.85 Less: Remittances made by the Dept. of Roads and Irrigation 1,143,448.74 Total Gasoline Tax Collections 22,538,824.11s Less: Refunds made to Gasoline Dealers 472,971.35— Net Gasoline Tax to be Distributed $22,065,852.76* Distributed as follows: To State Assistance Fund $ 2,967,437.21 To the Counties 6,676,679!98 To the Department of Roads and Irrigation, for highway purposes 12,421,735.57 $22,065,852.76* </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>