<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Cultural Practices in Winter Wheat Production</title>
               <date value="1934-04">1934-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 286 April, 1934 Cultural Practices in Winter Wheat Production T. A. KIESSELBACH, ARTHUR ANDERSON. AND W. E. LYNESS Department of Agronomy THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Summary 3 Methods of Testing 5 Seed-bed Preparation 5 Time of plowing 10 Depth of plowing 10 Disking before and after plowing 11 Late plowing vs. disking 12 Packing the soil before seeding. 12 Favorable mechanical seed-bed condition 12 Listing as a means of seed-bed preparation 13 Drilling wheat m cornstalks 13 Proportion of grain to straw. 14 Effect on plant development. 14 Effect on the protein content of the grain 15 Effect on soil nitrate development 15 Effect on soil moisture content 17 Seed Preparation 17 Farming-mill and size-of-seed studies 17 Farming-mill grading 17 Equal numbers vs. equal weights. 18 Effect of size of seed upon size of plant 19 Control of stinking smut 19 Relation of stinking smut to yield and quality. 19 Relation of degree of seed infection to smut control 20 Removal of smut balls. ~ 21 Rate of application of copper carbonate. 21 Manner of Planting. 22 Broadcasting vs. drilling 22 Narrow vs. normal row spacing. 22 Drilling with and without press wheels 23 Depth of drilling. 23 Surface vs. furrow drilling. 23 Rate of Planting 24 Date of Planting 25 Spring Cultivation 27 Harvesting at Different Stages of Maturity 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY In a comparison of 22 seed-bed preparation practices during 1 L years plowing on July 15 at a depth of 7 inches, followed by disking on August 15 and again just prior to seeding, resulted in a yield of 33 9 bushels per acre. The omission of the August disking reduced this yield 6.7 bushels per acre. Plowing 7 inches deep on August 15, with disking on July 15 and just prior to seeding, yielded 31.0 bushels, whereas omission of the July disking lowered the yield 1.4 bushels per acre. In the absence of sup - plementary tillage to control weeds, plowing at an intermediate date (August 15) has proved better than either earlier or later plo\tang. Plowing 7 inches deep on September 15, accompanied by diskings on July 15, August 15, and at time of seeding, yielded 28.9 bushels per acre, while omission of the July and August diskings reduced the yield 8.9 bushels. | The influence of plowing depth was far less than that of plowing date. It appears that under the conditions of these tests a slight in - crease in yield per acre may be expected as the depth of plowing" is in - creased from 4 to 7 inches during July and August. In the case of late plowing (September) a depth of 4 inches proved sufficient for maximum profit. A depth of 10 inches at any date was riot ad - vantageous. Disking in July, August, September, and just prior to seeding, with - out plowing, returned a yield of 26.6 bushels, compared with 33.9 where 7-inch July plowing replaced the July and September diskings, arid 28.9 bushels where 7-inch plowing was substituted for disking on September 15. Listing on July 15 followed by splitting the ridges August 15 and disking in September to level the ground yielded 30.6 bushels, com - pared with 33.9 bushels for the highest-yielding plowed plat. _ Seeding between the rows of standing corn without special prepara - tion yielded 21.2 bushels, compared with 23.5 bushels "on disked corn - stubble ground and 33.9 on the best plowing combination on oats stubble. Fanning-mill tests showed that large and heavy seed were not more productive than the ungraded seed. Extremely small and light seed averaged 3 per cent lower in yield than the ungraded. Grading or fanning, however, may be desirable to remove weed seed, smut balls, and other impurities. A high inverse correlation was found between the percentage of bunt - infected heads in a wheat field and the yield of grain per acre. During nine years, when the percentage of smutted heads ranged from 1 to 43, yields were reduced approximately one per cent for each one per cent of infection. Nearly smut-free, medium-infected, and heavily-infected samples of seed were treated during an eight-year period with formaldehyde applied by sack immersion in a l-pint-to-40-gallon water solution. The treat - ments gave almost perfect control of smut but yields were reduced from 5 to 8 per cent below that from untreated, nearly smut-free seed because </seg>
            <seg id="p004">of lower germination and retarded growth. Similar seed lots treated with 20 per cent copper carbonate applied at the rate of 2 ounces per bushel failed to give perfect control of smut, with the medium and the heavily infected seed resulting m a reduction m yield of 7 and 5 per cent, respectively, below that from untreated, nearly smut-free seed. With average infection, however, copper carbonate should prove a more desirable treatment than formaldehyde. Broadcast winter wheat averaged 17 per cent lower m yield than drilled wheat. Surface drilling m 4-inch rows yielded slightly less than drilling m rows spaced 7 inches apart. As a three-year average, furrow drilling m 14-inch rows yielded 81 and 91 per cent as much as surface drilling m rows spaced 7 and 14 inches apart, respectively. Other factors appear to be involved also m lowering the yields from furrow drilling under eastern Nebraska con - ditions. Wheat planted at the rates of 3, 4, 5, 6, and 8 pecks per acre gave the respective yields of 24.7, 26.2, 26.4, 27.4, and 27.4 bushels per acre. Wheat planted at the rate of 5 pecks per acre on seven dates ex - tending from September 15 to November 26 yielded as follows: Sept. 15, 25.7 bu.; Sept. 23, 30.0 bu.; Oct. 1, 34.9 bu.; Oct. 8, 30.2 bu.; Oct. 16, 26.6 bu.; Nov. 1, 20.7 bu.; and Nov. 26, 16.4 bu. per acre, respectively. Parallel plantings at the rate of 7 pecks per acre resulted m somewhat higher yields at all dates with a slight tendency for a greater increase at later dates. When the nine years included m the date-of-planting test are grouped into five years of heavy Hessian-fly infestation and four nearly fly-free years, it is seen that the plantings on September 15 and September 23 were at a decided disadvantage during the fly years, whereas during the fly-free years the optimum planting period extended from September 15 to October 1. Boiling and harrowing the wheat m early spring had no significant effect on yield. Wheat harvested at stages approximating early dough, late dough, ripe, and dead ripe yielded 20.6, 26.9, 30.6, and 29.1 bushels per acre, respectively. The moisture content of the grain at these four respective stages of maturity, which averaged 6 days apart, -was found to be 50, 43, 25, and 12 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Cultural Practices m Winter Wheat Production T. A. KIESSELBACH. ARTHUR ANDERSON, AND W. E. LYNESS • u.u. Th^ P, vr P° se of the winter-wheat investigations discussed m this bulletin has been to study various methods of seed-bed preparation, tillage, seed preparation, planting, and harvest - i?? # J n J . view of the extensive production of winter wheat m this state and the high expenditure of time and labor ordi - narily involved, a study of these methods is very important. The results herein reported are largely a continuation and summarization to date of those reported m Research Bulletin 31 and Bulletin 223 of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. r i METHODS OF TESTING Turkey wheat has been used throughout all of these experi - ments. Uniform and standard cultural practices, excepting the special treatments under comparison, were maintained m all instances. The seed-bed preparation plats were one-tenth of an acre m size and the methods involved are discussed m connection with the results. All other comparisons, excepting two tests pertaining to seed size which were conducted m small nursery plats, were made m standard field plats approx - imating one-thirtieth of an acre m size and replicated from two to five times annually. SEED-BED PREPARATION Twenty-two methods of seed-bed preparation were under direct comparison on the Experiment Station Farm during the 11-year period, 1922-32. The arrangement of plats and their respective treatments are shown m Figure 1. The plats comprised one-tenth of an acre each, being 28 feet wide and separated by seven-foot cropped discard strips. These discard strips were utilized to make the necessary adjustments]™ the plowing depths and other tillage operations between adjacent plats and to overcome any border effect that might result. Four similarly treated plats plowed 7 inches deep on July 15 and disked August 15 were located m various parts' of the wheat field for comparison of results. Other treatments were unduphcated. The principle of replication was served m part, however, by rotation from field to field and by inclusion of somewhat similar treatments within any one dlate of plowing. Twenty of the methods of seed-bed preparation under ob - servation were m a three-year rotation of corn, oats, and wheat. Three fields of medium fertility, lying side by side and .1. * T sf £ ro i cI S,, a ? d soll -, nitrate analyses reported herein were made under the direc - tion of M. J. BUsh, Station Chemist, and J. C. Rnssel, of the Agronomy Department, Tespecuveiy. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 6 |25 In standinj corn without Seedbed Preparation \Z+ P»i&gt;Mt dim« 4 corn stubble ground. | | ~| \a Double disked jj&lt; a 15, and"^rp [ f. 1». | |22 Listed July 13 and Aug. is, ridges d/iHed down Sept. 15 . \2l Plowed July IS, V i/»e*»» efe«ft rfcutte d/j&gt;r«&lt;J Aug. is. ~[ |Z0 Plowed Sept. IS, 10 '(n. dap, double disked Juft ISKIuf.IS, nlled Stpt li\ |l 9 Plowed Stpt IS, 10 'jn 'dctp, double disked 5,1% IS utd Au}. 15 I \lt Ptotied Stpt 15, r/rf. Jeep, dtuUe diiA'd jjy li tJS^.IS, nllea J*pt.is\ |»7 Plowrd S»/&gt;t IS, \T\ meAes deep \ \ | jl6 PknJ Stpt IS, 7 \*cJks deep, donUt ditKtd \ July 15 and Jtva. IS. [ \IS Ploied Srpt.lS, *\ inches demp, double disked July IS cm/ Jug if] \nPhued Juk/IS, 7/nc/jei deep, double d/sitd Jug, is I ji3 Plo-*d Jluf.lS, 10 Incites detp, rolled sip/fTF. i \l2 Plowed Juj. IS, jp inches derp | | | 111I II Plmred Jf.lS, 7 inches dtmp, rolled Sepf. 15 I \\o Plowed Aug. lS, 7ln'cJl,l detf&gt;j deuiU~~eliilred July IS. | |g Ployed Jiug.lS, r Incites deep. | | | 1 8 Plowed Ja. s . IS, '?&amp; itctes dey&gt;. \ | | 1 7 Plowed Jluf. JS, \ inches deep. [ [ | 1 6 Phued Jut) 15, inches deep, dontle | d},k.d Juy.lS "[ \5 Plowed Jtk) IS, 10 t inches deep, domt/e c/isked Jtiff. JS. [4 PUwttt July IS, 7 inches */—p ] | | 1 3 PltK/td Julf If,, 7 inches detpj doiiVed(sJr{d jtvg. JS \ \Z Plowed Jufy IS, 'stlf ineftetdetp, douifr\d~isted Aug. 15 \ |l. Plowrd Inly 15, f inches deep, douMc di'slred Auf IS \ 1 TieldT. »■} Field 2. ' I Field 3 . I FIG. 1. — Diagram showing relative location and detailed treatments of plats m seed-bed preparation experiments, 1922-32. In addition to the treatments indicated, the plowed plats were harrowed im - mediately after plowing and Plats 1 to 23 inclusive were disked uniformly prior to seeding. Plats 1 to 23 were m a three-year rotation of corn, oats, and winter wheat, while the rotation m Plats 24 and 25 consisted of one year of corn followed by two years of winter wheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 7 separated by 20-foot brome-grass roadways, were used fir this purpose. The fields were planted respectively to cornj oats, and wheat, and all treatments were uniform within a! field except for the wheat. For corn, the seed-bed was prepared by plowing to a depth of sVfc inches and for oats by double 1 disk - ing the corn land. The basic treatments for wheat m this rotation consisted of plowing on three dates, July 15, August 15, and September 15 In July and August, the plowing depths were 4, 5%, 7, and 10 inches deep and m September, 4, 7, and 10 inches. All plats were harrowed after plowing but varied as to disking prior to plowing and as to both disking and rolling thereafter. In addition to the plats that were plowed, one plat was |listed i ul, y. lo» followed by listing out the ridges August 15 and disking down September 15. Another plat was merely double disked on July 15, August 15, and September 15. All plats were disked uniformly just prior to seeding, m an effort to provide reasonably good seeding conditions. All plats were seeded uniformly lengthwise of the field, according to usual seeding practices. Two additional comparisons m a three-year rotation of corn, wheat, and wheat consisted m seeding wheat m double - disked corn-stubble ground and m standing corn. The seed - bed preparation for the second year of wheat consisted m plowing 7 inches deep July 15 and disking August 15. The effects of the various seed-bed preparation treatments upon the yield and growth of winter wheat are reported m Tables 1 and 2 for the 11-year period, 1922-32. The various methods of preparation m which plowing was the basic treat - ment are grouped according to the time of plowing I The depth of plowing and all supplementary treatments are dhown except the uniform harrowing after plowing and disking just before seeding. A separate group of miscellaneous methods of preparation is included m the tables. For convenience m presentation and interpretation, the average-yield results for the individual practices are shown m Tables 3 to 8. The four duplicate check plats which were distributed m various parts of the field are reported individually to indicate the degree of plat variability. As an average for the 11 years the extreme variation between these duplicate check plats was 2.8 bushels per acre. A generalized error calculated for the 11-year period from the check-plat yields by the devia - tion-f rom-the-mean method suggests that a difference of 3 0 bushels per acre is necessary for statistical significance.! </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 8 Table 1. — The effect of time and method of seed-bed preparation upon the grain yield of wittier wheat — 1922-82 Plat Seed-bed preparation Weld of grain per acre No. (Urn« and depth of plowing and other treatment,)' jm im ] Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. P.et. (1) (2) (8) (4) (6) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (18) (14) (16) Plowed July 15 7 m., disked Aug. 15 (ay. all checks) 1 46.0 19.2 41.1 17.2 19.8 43.6 28.6 41.9 44.7 40.8 87.0 88.9 100 1 4 In., disked Aug. 15 „ „.. 85.4 22.2 40.0 16.0 16.7 44.2 21.0 46.6 45.9 48.2 40.6 88.6 99 2 6W m., disked Aug. 15 86.6 24.2 44.6 16.8 16.8 44.8 26.1 47.6 46.2 39.8 46.4 85.2 104 4 7 In „„ _ 89.1 18.6 80.7 14.9 9.0 85.5 18.6 28.1 86.8 81.8 41.4 27.2 80 5 10 m., disked Aub. 16 42.5 17.7 46.0 16.2 14.6 44.6 20.2 41.7 49.1 42.1 80.2 84.0 100 Plowed Aug. 15 7 4 m 85.8 13.7 89.8 18.2 18.0 43.7 18.1 25.9 87.7 82.2 84.0 27.9 82 8 6% m „ _ 89.7 14.4 89.9 14.2 16.0 45.2 16.2 81.6 88.0 88.0 80.6 29.0 86 9 7 m .. „ 45.6 18.7 87.6 18.7 16.9 42.8 16.9 82.4 86.0 42.6 27.4 29.6 87 10 7 m., disked July 16 „ 46.9 15.8 42.5 16.2 28.2 44.1 18.6 81.4 41.4 80.2 80.9 81.0 91 11 7 m., rolled Sept 16 _ 46.6 19.9 88.2 14.2 20.6 46.4 17.7 86.5 86.2 42.6 29.2 81.6 98 12 10 m ~ 47.8 14.6 40.8 14.1 19.6 46.6 17.1 82.6 87.8 44.8 29.5 81.2 92 18 10 m., rolled Sept 16 41.9 14.9 88.2 18.5 21.5 44.2 18.8 82.8 88.9 46.2 28.1 80.7 91 16 ? 4*rL, disked July 15 and Aug. 16 83.2 15.3 29.4 18.8 12.8 44.8 18.8 38.6 88.3 43.5 29.2 28.5 84 16 7 m., disked July 16 and Aug. 15 80.8 14.2 82.6 11.6 12.1 45.9 18.3 87.2 40.6 40.5 84.7 28.9 85 17 7 m „ ._ „ 18.6 11.9 24.2 6.1 10.6 40.9 8.2 26.8 27.1 28.0 19.8 20.0 50 18 7 In., disked July 15 and Aug. 15, rolled Sept 15 29.1 14.6 83.1 12.8 11.6 45.8 18.5 37.6 89.1 38.0 29.4 28.1 83 19 10 m., disked July 16 and Aug. 16 82.4 12.8 38.7 14.6 13.7 41.6 19.4 83.4 89.0 42.0 29.2 28.3 83 20 10 m., disked July 15 and Aug. 16, rolled Sept 15.... 29.6 12.2 80.1 14.4 14.8 48.0 17.6 84.6 87.8 46.0 27.0 27.9 82 Miscellaneous treatments 22 Listed July 16 and Aug. 15, disked Sept 15 44.2 17.9 88.7 17.4 20.9 44.2 20.6 84.5 87.1 85.6 25.7 30.6 90 28 Disked July 15. Aug. 16. and Sept 16 41.0 18.1 31.4 6.0 16.7 40.7 18.8 29.6 85.4 44.0 17.7 26.6 78 24 Disked corn stubble ground 18.9 14.6 29.7 9.0 5.4 88.9 16.0 86.6 26.7 26.1 87.2 23.6 69 26 In standing corn 20.8 6.2 37.1 12.4 8.8 86.4 17.8 16.4 27.2 19.7 SO.O 21.2 63 3 Plowed* July 16. 7 m., disked Aug 16 42.0 21.7 44.5 16.2 17.6 46.8 22.8 48.1 45.6 88.0 45.7 86.3 104 6 Plowed July 16. 7 m., disked Aug. 16 46.5 18.4 39.1 16.0 20.0 30.7 20.9 38.7 43.8 38.8 36.7 82.6 96 14 Plowed July 15. 7 m., disked Aug. 15 45.6 19.4 40.7 16.6 19.9 45.7 25.1 41.6 47.1 41.9 37.9 34.6 102 21 Plowed July 16, 7 m., disked Aug. 15 46.8 17.1 40.0 21.0 19.7 42.5 25.8 39.2 42.8 44.8 27.8 83.8 98 'In addition to the treatments indicated, the plowed plats were harrowed immediately after plowing and Plats 1 to 23 were disked uniformly prior to seeding. • _j ,■_ •A generalized standard error of a difference as calculated from the check-plat yields by the deviation-from-the-mean method ts 1.6 bushela per acre. A difference twice this great would generally be considered necessary for statistical significance. This error may also be applied to the grain yields reported m Tables 2 to 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat ® SS "«"j — *» j? c*" fc rt 1333*1 &lt;»=&gt;&lt;»«&gt;■» :io •» :••,-. : : oo : i o: : : 5&gt; 5 tl ° " i»»°J ooo»o&gt;o:o&gt; 06 1 00 oi ' I ! oi^:j o&gt;::: jS 5 ft ** M Pita ~~^ —^ — __^ __ — _ I •" g n-° &gt;&lt;S ggggg SSSSSgg gggggg gg'sg gg'gjg 1 a^i-., i" •2 s -5 H~ S •?s sssas assssss sssssssa ssss ssss I. S? | g*S SSSSS SSSSSSS 2SS2SS SSsSE SSSS s* &gt; ° |^s sasss sssssss sassss lass §sis §.-» a — • I 1-S a — *" w s "" s " gasaasjs sssaag ass* gagp *n .£• j* 222 ° 0000000 000000 000 00 00 S S -5 -=- «&gt;««?•» £555555 555555 555J^ 5555 V | £| S 555§5 SSSSSSS 555555 5555 5555 •s ~s i!M! iiiiiH n N is 1 1 f i mm O S ::1 : : ::::::: 1.1 I .1 :: : : •: : : § I I!I ! 1 : I* a 1 I i! s «i!J! 1 11 Sii ill 1311 1 S | fas'. *4 I i€l |2|^^ i^j-?;^^^ | (£J —B) 0&lt; .. A. S9Bj2 &lt;S 55 m —Cl-»ia fKtoxNB leut-oor.o oinim «&lt;e«U _ H r 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 10 Time of plowing. — Time of plowing is a very important factor m the yield of winter wheat. As an 11-year average (Table 3), plowing 7 inches deep on the fifteenth of July, August, and September without supplementary disking re - sulted m the respective yields of 27.2, 29.6, and 20.0 bushels per acre. Table 3. — Effect of time of plowing upon the grain yield of winter wheat, 11-year average — 1922-32 _ &#132; Date of plowing Soil treatment Sept. 15 Ante. 15 July 16 Bushel* Bushels Bushels Plowing alone, 7 inche5............... 20.0 29.6 27.2 Plowing 7 inches and disking . 28.9 31.0 33.9 Average— 24^5 SOJS 30.6 In the absence of supplementary disking, the yield from the September plowing was only 74 per cent of that of the July plowing, whereas with supplementary diskings it was 85 per cent. The increased yield of 2.4 bushels per acre resulting from the August plowing compared to the July plowing where disking was not resorted to m either instance may be ex - plained by the more effective weed control on the August plowing. Where perfect weed control was obtained by disk - ing, the yield from the July plowing was 2.9 bushels m excess of that from the August plowing. This would indicate that m the presence of weed control, extremely early plowing is to be preferred to medium-early plowing. This is slightly at variance with the earlier results, which indicated that very little difference may be expected from the time of plowing up to August 15, provided weed growth is effectively controlled. Depth of plowing. — Depth of plowing did not prove to be as important a factor m yield per acre as date of plowing. Comparable data for four depths m July and August and three depths m September are summarized m Table 4. Land plowed on July 15 at the respective depths of 4, 514, 7, and 10 inches, followed by disking August 15, yielded 33.6, 34.7, 33.9, and 34.0 bushels per acre, respectively. These differences m yield do not appear to be significant. Land plowed at the corresponding depths on August 15 but without supplementary disking m July yielded 27,9, 29.0, 29.6, and 31.2 bushels per acre, respectively. These data, though not highly significant, are suggestive of increasing yields with increase m depth of plowing. Land disked m July and August and plowed 4, 7, and 10 inches deep on September 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 11 Table A.— Effect of depth of plowing upon the grain yield of winter wheat, 11-year average — 1922-32 Date of plowing I Depth of plowing I ■ I *m. | 6tt In. | 7ln. 1 110 m. ' I Bushel* | Biuftrila | BuAcU | Bushel, September IB 28-B ___ August IB . _ 2,8 290 M 6 812 July IB 886 m : 7__««Q__^ 11 _ Average July and August. 30 . 8 81.9 81.8 32.6 Average July. August, and September 30.0 30.8 31 2 yielded at the rate of 28.5, 28.9, and 28.3 bushels per acre, respectively. Although not entirely consistent, these data suggest that plowing less than 5V 2 inches m depth may m most instances be expected to result m somewhat lower yields than plowing at somewhat greater depths. Any increase m yield resulting from plowing deeper than 7 inches would probably not offset the greater cost of the plowing. [ Disking before and after plowing. — One of the most striking features of seed-bed preparation developed by these investigations is the great value of well-timed disking sup - plementary to the plowing. The objects of such additional tillage are weed control, accumulation of soil moisture and available soil fertility, compacting of the soil, and improve - ment of the physical condition of the seed-bed. These are all conducive to prompt and uniform germination, vigorous Iseed - ling growth, abundant stooling, extensive root development and superior winter endurance. A number of comparisons (Table 5) are possible m which the methods of preparation were identical except as to the Table s.— Effect of disking before or after plowing upon the gram yield of winter wheat, 11-year average 1 922-&amp;2 Date of plowing ~ jgg_ _D^ed__ _ , . Inches Bushel* September IB 7 Not disked 2 |).0 September IB 7 July IB * Aug. IB 21.8 Increase due to disking— ■ , g August IE 7 Not disked 2! (.6 August IB 7 Julyls , 0 Increase due to di5king......... .._....„.„.._ „ . . July IS 7 Notdiaked 2V.2 July IB 7 Alw 1B S! 9 Increase due to disking I _ |mmi (l 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 12 matter of disking either before or after plowing. Land plowed 7 inches deep July 15, followed by disking August 15, yielded 33.9 bushels compared with 27.2 bushels without the disking. Plowing 7 inches deep on August 15, preceded by disking July 15, yielded 31.0 bushels as against 29.6 bushels when the disking was omitted. Plowing 7 inches deep on September 15, preceded by disking on both July 15 and August 15, yielded 28.9 bushels compared with 20.0 bushels without the disking. The increases resulting from the supplementary diskings were 6.7, 1.4, and 8.9 bushels per acre for the July, August, and September plowings, respectively. The relatively low in - crease resulting from disking the August plowing would appear due to the limited amount of weed growth on land plowed at this time. The undisked plats of the July and Sep - tember plowings, on the other hand, produced considerable weed growth since they were left m an undisturbed state for a longer time. Late plowing vs. disking. — It is of interest to compare a combination of late plowing and disking with mere disking m relation to yield. The data are summarized m Table 6. Disk - ing on July 15 and again on August 15, followed by plowing 7 inches deep on September 15 resulted m a yield of 28.9 bushels per acre m comparison with 26.6 bushels from a plat disked successively on July 15, August 15, and September 15. These results suggest that there may be some advantage m stirring the soil deeper than is done by the disk. Table 6. — Late plowing vs. disking for winter wheat, 11-year average — 1922-82 ~ &#132; Yield Plowing Disking per acre " Bushas Plowed September 18.... July and August 28.9 Not plowed I July. August, and September 26.6 Packing the soil before seeding.— lt is the common ex - perience of wheat growers that winterkilling is less likely to occur on a compact than on a loose seed-bed. Artificial pack - ing by either disking or rolling m the absence of natural settling by rains is recognized as a good practice. 1 his is especially true with late plowing. Failure to increase yields m these experiments by rolling m September is accounted for by the fact that all treatments included disking just before seeding and this served to settle the ground. Favorable mechanical seed-bed condition.— The uni - formity of seed germination, thrift of seedling growth, and surtfvll of stand may be greatly influenced by the physical condition of the seed-bed. Dry, cloddy, loose soil is unf avor- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 13 able. Such a condition is sometimes unavoidable, but may often result from poor seed-bed management, such as late preparation and failure to work down the ground with suit - able implements. Harrowing after the plow before the soil has time to dry out is beneficial under most circumstances. Weed growth, either before or after plowing, not only tends to dry out the soil but also uses plant-food elements which should be held available for the ensuing crop. Retarded de - velopment of the wheat m the fall due to a poor physical con - dition of the seed-bed at the time of seeding may result! m a material reduction m yield. As shown m Table 2, September plowing resulted m ap - proximately 10 per cent reduction m stand of plants) and strikingly reduced the number of stools per plant as compared with July and August plowing. As a result of reduced germination and stooling, the wheat on September plowing averaged only two-thirds as many heads per unit area of land as did the July plowing. Listing as a means of seed-bed preparation. — In some sections of the Middle West, listing is used as a basic method for preparing wheat land. The plan is to single list asl soon as possible after harvest for the purpose of weed control and the conservation of soil moisture and available fertility. Somewhat later these lister ridges are worked down arid the land is leveled by means of disk or cultivator. Occasionally, as was the case m these experimental tests, the procedure followed is to single list m the middle of July, split the ridges with a lister m the middle of August, and to follow this later with disking and harrowing. It is not known how the particular method employed m these tests would com - pare m yield with other modifications of the system. | During the 11-year period, 1922-32 (Table 7), land that was listed on July 15 and had the ridges split with the |lister Table 7. — Listing as a seed-bed preparation for tointer ibheat, 11-year average — 1922-32 | Listing or plowing Disking pSufre ■ Bushels •I Listed July 16 snd August 15 September 15 50. 6 Plowed Jnly IS „ August 15 83.9 August 15, followed by disking September 15, yielded 30.6 bushels per acre, compared with 33.9 bushels for land plowed 7 inches deep July 15 and disked August 15. Drilling wheat m cornstalks. — In order to bring about a change from corn to small grain m the rotation, it is rather </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 14 customary to seed oats on corn ground. The same purpose may be accomplished by seeding winter wheat with a one - horse drill between the rows of standing cornstalks. If the corn is cut for silage or fodder, the land may be disked before seeding. As a substitute for oats, winter wheat yields secured m this manner may be compared with those of oats. On the other hand, as an alternative method of growing winter wheat, the yields should be compared with those of wheat produced by standard methods. In these tests (Table 8) , wheat drilled between rows of standing stalks without other preparation yielded 21.2 bushels per acre as compared with 42.8 bushels of oats. In a similar comparison, wheat on disked corn land yielded 23.5 bushels. These yields are comparable with 33.9 bushels of wheat on land plowed 7 inches deep m July and disked m August. While wheat seeded on stalk land was far less productive and profitable than wheat on plowed oats stubble, its yield com - pares very favorably with that of oats. Table 8. — Seeding wheat m cornstalks, 11-year average — 1922-32 ZT~~~T! ~ Yield Yield of oats wnere seeded per acre m comparison •———-——- _-__ _____ ______ Standing stalks 21.2 ...... Disked 5ta1k5........ 23.5 42.8 Oats stnbble plowed 7 m. deep July IS. disked Aug. IS.- 83.0 Proportion of grain to straw. — Some interest attaches to the relation of cultural practices to the ratio of grain to straw. Straw yields were determined m connection with all of these seed-bed practices, and the results reported m Table 2 indicate these yields as well as the ratio of grain to straw. In connection with the dates of preparation, all of the July - plowed plats averaged 72 per cent as much grain weight as straw weight; all August-plowed plats averaged 76 per cent as much grain as straw weight; and all of the September - plowed plats averaged nearly 77 per cent as much grain as straw. The general indication would seem to be that delayed plowing may tend to reduce the rankness of vegetative growth, thereby increasing the proportion of grain to straw. Effect on plant development. — It is of interest to note the effect of the various seed-bed preparation treatments for winter wheat upon the growth of the crop. Such data per - taining to plant development have been summarized m Table 2. Although these data do not indicate a significant difference m heading date, date ripe, or plant height, there was a slight indication that conditions such as late seed-bed preparation, </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 15 which retard fall growth, tend to delay the date of heading and ripening and result m somewhat shorter straw. These differences are most apparent early m the, season and tend to disappear as the season advances and the grain matures. Stand counts at harvest showed that early plowing and favorable seed-bed conditions resulted m a somewhat thicker stand and more stooling than resulted under less favorable conditions. As a two-year result, five July plowings averaged 9.8 mature plants per foot of drill row, compared with 9.5 and 8.6 plants per foot for six August and three September plow - ings, respectively. Stools per plant averaged 2.9, 2.4, and 2.1 for July, August, and September plowings. Effect on the protein content of the grain. — The protein content (13.5 per cent moisture basis) of the wheat produced from the plats comparing the various seed-bed preparation treatments is reported m Table 2 for the five-year [period, 1922-26. An average of five methods involving July plowing shows a protein content of 12.6 per cent as compared with 11.8 per cent for seven August-plowed plats and 11.0 per cent for the six September-plowed plats. Comparing the average of the six September plowings with the average of the two check plats located on either side plowed m July, the Septem - ber group was 0.8 per cent lower m protein than the July. These data indicate that early plowing as compared with late plowing on soil of medium fertility may be expected to pro - duce wheat with somewhat higher protein content, j Inter - preted m terms of the check plats, a maximum difference of approximately 1.0 per cent protein was brought about Iby the best compared with the poorest treatments. Variation m the depth of plowing, or m the amount of disking and packing m addition thereto, had no marked effect on the protein content of the grain. Wheat produced on the listed ground had an average protein content of 11.4 per cent, compared with 10.8 per cent for the disked ground, whereas that from the I disked corn and standing corn averaged 11.0 and 11.4 per cent, re - spectively. Effect on soil nitrate development.— Soil nitrate develop - ment was studied during the four-year period, 1923-26^ on 15 plats receiving various seed-bed treatments for winter! wheat. It was hoped that such studies might be of value m inter - preting the effects of seed-bed preparation upon the yield and quality of grain produced. Nitrate production was measured m parts per million of nitrate nitrogen (phenoldisulphonic acid method) from representative samples of soil taken four times annually from each plat. As a four-year average, samples were taken on July 15, just prior to the first seed-bed treatment, October 15, soon after seeding, April 28, before </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 16 much spring growth had been made, and on July 8, after harvest. The nitrate content of soil samples taken m July preceding the first seed-bed preparation was found to be uniformly low for all treatments with but little variation from year to year. As a four-year average there was less than 1.5 parts per million of nitrate nitrogen present m the first foot and less than 1.0 part m the second foot. . . The October sampling, however, shows that the time and method of seed-bed preparation have been factors m nitrate development. The first foot m five July plowings averaged 8.5 parts per million, compared with an average of 5.1 parts t for five August plowings, 2.2 parts as an average of four September plowings, and 3.8 parts for the unplowed disked plat. Corresponding nitrate nitrogen contents for the second foot were 2.6, 1.2, 0.7, and 1.1 parts per million, respectively. In no case did variation m the depth of plowing, with other - wise comparable treatments, affect the soil nitrate nitrogen content more than 2 parts per million. The 7-inch July plowing, which was not. subsequently disked m August, con - tained approximately half the amount of nitrates found m the other July plowings. The September undisked plowed plat was also materially lower m nitrates than the disked-plowed plat. These data show clearly that uncontrolled weed growth prior to seeding interferes with nitrate accumulation. On the other hand, plowing or some equivalent tillage of the soil seems essential to a liberal nitrate production, since merely disked plats on which weed growth was controlled showed low nitrate development. It may be concluded therefore that early plowing followed by such tillage as is necessary to con - trol weeds is most favorable for continued nitrate production and accumulation. Depth of plowing, within a range of 4to 10 inches, did not appear to be a material factor m nitrate development. Sampling m April before much spring growth occurred showed somewhat lower nitrate content m the first foot than the October sampling but practically the same relation of nitrate content to treatment was maintained. As a four-year average, the July, August, and September plowings and the disking alone averaged 5.0, 3.2, 2.1, and 2.4 parts per million. The July and September plowings which were not disked were still somewhat lower m nitrates than the disked plow - ings. The nitrates m the second foot did not differ materially from those of the October sampling. As a four-year average, following harvest, the first foot of the July plowings averaged 3.0 parts of nitrate nitrogen per million, compared with 2.1 and 1.4 as an average of the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 17 August and September plowings and 1.3 parts for the disked ground. The nitrates in the second foot varied but little and averaged less than 1.5 parts per million. Effect on soil moisture content. — The soil-moisture samples were taken coincidentally with the nitrate samples but to a depth of five feet. As a four-year average of the five July plowings, the increase in percentage of soil moisture between the July and October samplings was 2.0 per cent. Corres - ponding increases for the five August and the four September plowings were 1.5 and 1.1 per cent, respectively, and j;or the disking 0.9 per cent. It is apparent that the method of seed - bed preparation did not influence the moisture content! of the soil very decidedly. Differences in moisture content due to seed-bed preparation are somewhat more marked, however, in the upper two feet. As averages of the various July and August plowings there were increases of 3.0 and 1.1 per cent, respectively, in the moisture of the first foot between tlie July and October samplings, whereas there was a decrease] of 0.5 per cent for the September plowings. Increases in the sec - ond foot were 3.6, 2.3, and 1.4 per cent, respectively, for the July, August, and September plowings. It seems probable that the increase in the moisture content of the upper 3 to 6 inches was likewise relatively greater with the early plow - ings. These more favorable moisture conditions in the upper soil at seeding time have usually caused higher and more prompt germination and better established fall growth. SEED PREPARATION Preparation of wheat for planting is generally concerned with grading or fanning to increase the seed size and purity or with treatment to control diseases such as the smuts. The results with such tests are reported herewith. FANNING-MILL AND SIZE-OF-SEED STUDIES Fanning-mill grading. — Two types of machines, an ordi - nary screen fanning mill and a wind-blast gravity grader, have been used to prepare four grades of seed. These grades, which approximated the largest and smallest one-fourth and the heaviest and lightest one-fourth of the bulk sample, have been prepared annually during a 13-year period and grjawn in comparison with ungraded seed. Badly shrunken seed ob - tained from immature harvesting was also included. All seed was planted with the grain drill set at five pecks per acre. The results are reported in Table 9. As a 13-year average, the large and the heavy seed grades yielded practically the same as the ungraded seed. The small and the light seed </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 18 Table 9. — Effect of fanning mill grading upon the growth and yield of winter wheat, 18-year average — 1919-31 Character of seed 1 p V»nt Date Date Weight Yield per acre height m head | ripe perbnshel Actual | RelatlTe  - g«i«==: SS ft gg gj g* » Screened small 84.6 6/8 7/1 58.4 27 7 97 WindKast heavy 84.9 6/2 7&gt;l 68 6 28 6 100 Windbtast light.... 84.6 6/2 7/1 68.4 27.6 • 97 Bhrnnken (immature) ...... 34.5 . 6/2 7/1 6JU 20/7 104 1 The drill was set to plant at the rates of 6 pecks per acre for all oeed. yielded 3 per cent less than the ungraded, while the shrunken seed yielded 4 per cent more. It would appear, therefore, that no benefit is to be derived under average conditions from planting large or heavy seed as compared with the ungraded seed. Grading or fanning, however, may be desirable m order to remove weed seed, smut balls, and other impurities. Equal numbers vs. equal weights. — In connection with the farming-mill tests, large, unselected, and small seed were planted on the basis of equal numbers and equal weights. The large seed was planted at approximately six pecks or the normal rate per acre. The unselected and small seed were planted m comparison on the basis of both equal numbers and equal weights per acre. The average results for a 17-year period are reported m Table 10. When planted on the basis of equal numbers, or at rates approximating 95, 76, and 53 pounds per acre for the large, unselected, and small seed, re - spectively, the unselected and small seed yielded 96 and 90 per cent as much as the large seed. When planted uniformly at the rate of 95 pounds per acre, the unselected and small seed yielded 100 and 94 per cent as much as the large. These Table 10. — Yields from large, unselected, and small seed of Turkey wheat when planted m equal numbers and m equal weights per acre, 17-year average — 1911, 191A-16 1918-28, and 1930-31 ' ' Kind of seed and manner Seed planted per acre Yield per acre of comparison Number | Weight Aetna! I Relative ~ ir , wi? 1 — (2) ' P^' ""IF 'ft"* Equal numbers of seed Large — 1,807,668 95 32.7 100 Unselected 1,807,568 76 81.6 96 Small im 1,807,668 68 29.5 90 Equal weights of seed Large 1,807.568 95 82.7 100 Unselected 1,682,662 95 32.8 100 Small _ I 2.873.081 95 80.8 94 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 19 results suggest that small seed may be somewhat inferior to large seed especially when planted on the basis of equal num - bers at a rate optimum for the large seed but that such dif - ferences will tend to disappear when planting is baded on equal weights or volumes as is the common practice. Effect of size of seed upon size of plant. — The effect of size of seed upon the size of plant has been studied [where large and small seed were spaced so as to permit maximum individual plant development. Average results during ten years are reported m Table 11. The large seed, whichj aver- Table 11. — Effect of size of seed, on size of plant when spaced to permit maximum individual development, ten-year aver - age — 1920-26, 1928, and 1930-31 | Seed planted Crop hnrv&amp;jted Grade Weijrht Height Heads Grain per pl&lt;jnt per 100 of plants per plant . . , TT — ; Actual Relative Grama Inches Number Grama Percent (1) (2) (3) (4) (6) (6) Large .„ „. 8.81 81.2 10.8 4.68 • 121 Small, I 1.28 80.4 9.7 3.82 100 aged 2.7 times as heavy as the small seed, produced plants that were slightly taller, that averaged 0.6 head morie per plant, and yielded 21 per cent more grain. General conclusions. — It may be concluded from the farming-mill and size-of-seed studies that small seed is less productive than large seed when planted to permit maximum plant development or at the optimum seeding rate for the large seed. The difference, however, is not decidedly sig - nificant when both seed sizes are planted at their respective optimum seeding rates. In comparison with ungraded seed, the large and heavy grades had little or no advantage. CONTROL, OF STINKING SMUT Material losses m the yield and grade of winter wheat fre - quently result from the presence of bunt or stinking smut. It is hoped by breeding to obtain varieties sufficiently resistant to the prevailing forms of smut to materially reduce 1 such losses. In the absence of resistant varieties, however, stinking smut may and should be effectively controlled by seed treat - ment. Relation of stinking smut to yield and quality. — In order to determine the effect of the degree of seed infection, upon the resulting crop, nearly smut-free seed was mixed m various proportions with heavily smut-infected seed for comparative </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 20 testing. Six seed lots, one each of nearly smut-free and heavily smutted seed and four mixtures containing 2, 10, 20, and 50 per cent of heavily smutted seed, were tested annually during a nine-year period (1924-32). The data are sum - marized m Table 12. With increasing degrees of infection of the seed planted, the percentage of smutted heads m the re - sulting crop ranged from 1 to 43, the weight per bushel of the crop harvested decreased from 58.7 to 55.1 pounds, and Table 12. — Effect of degree of seed infection with stinking smut upon the infection m and yield of the subsequent crop, nine-year average — 1924-32 Crop harvested i Degree of seed „. &#132; Infection' Smntted Welßht Yield per acre hea&lt;te perbnahcl Aetnal Relative Percent Pounds Bushel* Percent (1) (2) (8) C 4) (5) Trace ,„„„„ &#132;.„ &#132;..., 1.1 68.7 26.9 100 Slight ............................. 10.4 58.1 24.4 91 Medium r , , ",, ,„, 17.5 67.5 22.7 84 Severe ........................... 26.7 67.0 21.2 79 Very severe 86.0 66.0 19.6 72 Extreme 43.4 660 VIA 68 1 The respective decrees of seed infection were secured by mixingr nearly smut-free seed and heavily smut-infected seed m the following proportions: 100:0, 98:2, 90:10, 80:20, 50:50, and 0:100. the yields from 26.9 to 17.0 bushels per acre. These results suggest that for 1 per cent of smutted heads m the crop an approximate decrease of 1 per cent m yield may be expected. Relation of degree of seed infection to smut control.— Nearly smut-free seed, medium-infected seed, and heavily in - fected seed have been given standard formaldehyde and copper carbonate treatments during the eight-year period, 1924-31. The formaldehyde was applied by sack immersion m a 1-pint - to-40-gallon water solution and the copper carbonate (20 per cent copper) was applied at the rate of 2 ounces per bushel of grain m a barrel mixer. The data are summarized m Table 13. As an average the crop from the three untreated lots of seed, smut-free, medium, and heavily infected, contained 1, 31, and 42 per cent of smutted heads. The respective yields were 25.9, 20.1, and 18.0 bushels per acre. The standard formaldehyde treatment, which resulted m almost perfect smut control m each instance, appeared to have a slight but consistent depressing effect on yield. The lower yields were probably due to a somewhat lower germination and retarded growth. In contrast the lower yields resulting from the copper carbonate treatment of the medium and heavily in - fected seed were doubtless due to imperfect control of the smut. When smut control is more nearly perfect, as usually </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 21 Table 13. — Effect of standard formaldehyde and copper car - bonate treatments on seed wheat differing m degree of smut infection, eight-year average — 1924-31 Decree of seed infection and Crop harvested I kind of seed treatment Smutted Weight Yield per acre heads per bushel Actual , vt Percent Pound* Bushel* Per ami Nearly .mut-Jri ceed (2&gt; (S&gt; W) » Not treated 1.0 68.4 28.9 100 Formaldehyde 0.8 68.2 24.S 94 Copper carbonate (20%) — 0.2 68.4 26.1 101 Medium infected seed Not treated „ 81.4 66.9 20.1 78 Formaldehyde .... 0.8 68.6 24.6 96 Copper carbonate (20%) 2.0 68.8 24.0 98 Heavily infected seed Not treated .... ................. 42.4 66.8 18.0 69 Formaldehyde 0.8 68.1 23.9 92 Copper carbonate (20%). IMi 68.1 24.6 96 occurs -with seed of low or average infection, copper carbonate is a more desirable treatment than formaldehyde. Removal of smut balls. — In order to determine thi rela - tion of smut balls m the seed to the effectiveness of seed treat - ment, smutty seed was heavily fanned prior to standard formaldehyde and copper carbonate treatments and planted m comparison with similarly treated but unf aimed seed. As a four-year average (Table 14) fanning heavily smutted seed prior to seed treatment gave slightly better control of smut m the subsequent crop and resulted m somewhat greater yields. It would appear that smut balls m treated seed might result m a certain degree of reinfection of sound seed following* treatment. Table 14. — Effect of fanning smut-infected seed preliminary to standard treatments with formaldehyde and Copper carbonate, four-year average — 1929-32 j Crop harvested Seed treatment _ ... Yield per acre omuttcu \ heads Actual Ridative Per cent Bushels Per cent (1) (2) (8) (4) No treatment Not fanned.................................. 34.8 21.9 100 Formaldehyde Not fanned 8.4 29.4 184 Fanned .. , ....-., . .... 1.6 80.4. 139 Copper carbonate (20%) ■ ..■■ Not fanned—.-...... ........................ 6.7 81.6 144 Fanned ...._..... ................. . ............... 0.9 32.8 160 . . [ Rate of application of copper carbonate. — In order to determine the most effective rate of application, copper car - bonate (20 per cent copper) was applied at the rate of 1, 2, </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 22 Table 15. — Effect of 20 per cent copper carbonate applied at the rate of 1 to 4 ounces per bushel on heavily smut in - fected seed of winter wheat, five-year average — 1928-82 Crop harvested Ounces of copper cerbonate Yield per acre applied per bushel of seed Smutted xiem per acre heads Actual Relative Per cent Buthela Per cent (1) (2) (3) (4) 0 „ . 36.7 21.1 100 1 10.6 28.8 188 2 ...... _ 6.0 80.0 142 3_. . 1.7 25.4 135 4 „ 1.1 28.7 136 3, and 4 ounces per bushel to heavily smut-infected seed. The data for a five-year period are summarized m Table 15. The crop from untreated seed contained 36.7 per cent of smutted heads m contrast to 10.6, 5.0, 1.7, and 1.1 per cent, re - spectively, m that from seed treated with 1, 2, 3, and 4 ounces of copper carbonate per bushel. These results suggest that 3 ounces of copper carbonate per bushel are sufficient even with heavily infected seed. It may be assumed that m case of light or moderate infection, the generally recommended rate of 2 ounces would probably be almost as effective as higher rates. MANNER OF PLANTING Winter wheat is commonly planted with press drills m rows spaced 7 inches apart. In order to determine the effectiveness of this standard method of planting, a number of modifica - tions have been introduced and tested comparatively. An additional method, broadcasting, has also been included. The results are reported m Tables 16 and 17. Broadcasting vs. drilling. — As a 14-year average, broad - cast wheat yielded 23.7 bushels per acre m comparison with 28.4 bushels for standard drilling. This reduction of 17 per cent m yield is evidence that broadcasting is clearly inferior to drilling m the case of fall-sown wheat. Narrow vs. normal row-spacing. — Row-spacing approx - imating 4 inches was compared during a 14-year period with the normal 7-inch spacing. During the earlier years of the comparison, the narrow spacing was accomplished by inter - drilling with a standard drill. During the latter part of the period a standard 4-inch alfalfa drill was used for the narrow spacing. The average yield obtained from the narrow spac - ing was 27.2 bushels per acre, or 4 per cent lower than the 7 - inch spacing. These results suggest that no advantage may be expected from row spacings narrower than 7 inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 23 Table 16. — Effect of manner of planting upon growth and yield of winter wheat, average for the periods 191932 and 1926-82 f &#132;..._ „, n1^«M«» plant Date m Date Yield per acre Manner of planting heißht head ripe , . Actual I Relative (1) I (2) I (3) | (4) | (5) ] ! (6) FOURTEEN-YEAR AVERAGE Broadcast 33.1 6/8 7/1 23.7 83 Drilled, medium depth, press wheels on: 4-inch row spacing 38.0 6/2 6/80 27.2 96 7-inch row spacing 82.8 6/1 6/30 28.4 100 SEVEN-YEAR AVERAGE Broadcast 34.1 6/2 | 7/1 26.5 85 Drilled, medium depth, press wheels on : 4-inch row spacing 34.1 6/2 7/1 28.8 92 7-inch row spacing 33.6 6/1 7/1 31.3 100 Drilled, medium depth, press wheels off : 7-inch row spacing 33.8 6/1 7/1 30.6 98 Drilled, deep, press wheels on: 7-inch row spacing 33.4 6/1 7/1 31.0 SO Drilling 'with and without press wheels. — During a 7 - year period drilling without press wheels resulted m a yield of 30.6 bushels per acre or only 2 per cent less than that re - sulting from the standard practice. It is possible that greater differences might result where the seed-bed is loose or other - wise less well prepared than m these tests. Depth of drilling. — So-called deep drilling was compared with normal drilling during a 7-year period with nc sig - nificant difference m yield. It appears that depth of drilling should be largely governed by the condition of the seed-bed. Surface vs. furrow-drilling. — Considerable interest has been shown recently, especially m the western part of the state, m the use of the furrow drill. It was assumed thkt the furrow drill permitted a lower planting rate and provided and maintained a more favorable seed-bed. , Three different types of furrow drills planting at two rates per acre have been com - pared with a standard surface drill planting at comparable rates m both 7- and 14-inch row spacings during the three - year period, 1930-32. As an average, surface drilling lin 7 - inch rows yielded 42.1 bushels per acre for both rates of planting. In comparison, surface drilling m 14-inch | rows when planted at the thinner rate, 49 pounds per acre, yielded only 87 per cent as much as the 7-inch row spacing. Similar planting, at the heavier rate of 75 pounds per acre, resulted m a yield 93 per cent as great as that from the 7-inch spacing. As an average for the three furrow drills, the thin rate of planting (45 pounds per acre) and the heavy rate (79 pbunds </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 24 Table 17. — Effect of surface and furrow drilling upon the growth and yield of winter wheat, three-year average — 195052 ■ Planting practice Crop harvested T S?m &lt; ? betroen Bate of Plant Date In Date Weight Yield per acre driU "mi planting height head ripe perbu. -^ tval | Revive' (1) ft "'• ft (5) (6) *fc W F W E?™° w J* « 88.9 6/81 6/80 67.9 32.6 77 Farrow 14 79 88.0 6/80 6/30 68.4 36.0 86 Average .... „.. 88.6 6/81 6/80 68.1 34.3 81 Surface 14 76 88.8 6/81 6/29 68.6 39.0 93 Average .... _ 38.5 6/81 6/29 68.6 87.8 90 f™*"" I « B§s 6781 6?30 6877 423 100 Surface 7 75 89.0 5/30 6/29 68.6 42.1 100 Average „„ „ 89.0 5/31 6/30 58.6 42.1 100 J -.?, Tbe dM^, 1 . m , *"*«"» dr lllB ■*• averages for two standard makes with the individual drills spaced 14 inches apart and for one type with drills spaced 12 inches apart. per acre) yielded only 77 and 86 per cent as much, re - spectively, as the standard surface drilling. These results show very clearly that under the conditions of these tests a row spacing of 14 inches is too wide for optimum yields and that such reduction m yield can be but partly overcome by thicker planting rates. In addition to row spacing, other factors appear to be involved m lowering the yields from the furrow drilling. Furrow drilling might, however, be better under less favorable seed-bed conditions. RATE OF PLANTING .Winter wheat has been planted during the 14-year period, 1919-32, at five rates per acre ranging from 3to 8 pecks. The average results (Table 18) indicate that there may be a rather wide range m planting rate without materially affect - ing the yield. Wheat planted at the rates of 3, 4, 5, 6, and 8 Table 18. — Effect of the rate of planting upon the growth and yield of winter wheat, IU-year average — 1919-32 "S* °gfr gff Sfiftfr W lt ht Vdd per acre ing ™* y FaU | Spring bushel Actual I Relative Peek* Inches Pounds Bu. P.et. (1) (2) (3) (4) (6) (6) (7) &lt;8) (9) Three 32.8 6/8 7/2 3.8 3.8 67.9 24.7 94 Four 82.4 6/2 7/1 3.4 8.5 58.0 26.2 99 Five 32.4 6/2 7/1 3.2 2.6 58.0 26.4 100 Six 32.4 6/2 6/30 8.0 2.6 68.0 27.4 104 Eight 81.9 6/1 6/30 2.7 1.7 58.1 27.4 104 'Eight-year average. 1919-28 and 1926-28. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 25 pecks per acre gave the respective yields of 24.7, 26.2,1 26.4, 27.4, and 27.4 bushels per acre. Planting thinner than 4 pecks per acre m eastern Nebraska is not recommended and because of the likelihood of uneven stands, 5 pecks per acre would appear to be a more practical rate. Planting more than 5 pecks per acre would not seem justified except under ex - tremely unfavorable planting conditions. Increasing the rate of planting tends toward slightly shorter growth earlier ripening, and fewer stools per plant. DATE OF PLANTING Five dates of planting ranging from September 23 to No - vember 26 have been compared during a 14-year period. An additional earlier date, September 15, and another inter - mediate date have been included during somewhat shorter periods. During the last nine years, planting at the two! rates of 5 and 7 pecks per acre has been done on each of the jseven planting dates. The results are summarized m Table 19. Table 19. — Effect of date of planting upon the growth and. yield, 1919-32 Average yield per acre daring : .„,,„ j, tB 9 years, 1024-82, when «aS? 14yrs.,l 2y rs.. "-"—"■"-«" 5 He9l&lt;ian . 4 n ? r,y 1919-32 1921-32 S pks. per A. 7 pica, per A. fly years &gt; Actual ReL Actual Rel. Ul U) (8) &lt; 4 &gt; &lt;5&gt; (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) $M s SI |1 || g i || 3 Ifell II II 111 I Summary of plant characters (B-peck rate) . 9 years. 1924-32 I 5 years. 1919-23 Plant Date In Date Fruiting Wt Stools per plant Pmtein hßieht he » d ripe " CTlod (1) («") (13) (U) ffiST ("") (17) (18) &amp;f oil t== 5J i;i ?;i I? »• a a &amp; Oct. 16 83 6/8 7/5 27 690 10 2.3 iTS fii= 1 ks % s s ; I : Spring wheat.. 8S 6/11 7/8 27 57.1 .„ .„ jj?^ *The 5 years »veraged for Hessian-fly infestation were 1924, 1928 and 1930-32 whereas the years 1925-27 and 1929 were considered as years nearly^ fly-free. *""' </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 26 As a nine-year average the following acre yields were ob - tained from plantings made at the standard rate of five pecks per acre on the dates indicated: September 15, 25.7 bushels; September 23, 30.0 bushels; October 1, 34.9 bushels; October 8, 30.2 bushels; October 16, 26.6 bushels; November 1, 20.7 bushels ; and November 26, 16.4 bushels. In comparison, spring wheat planted on its normal date yielded 16.1 bushels per acre. The highest yield was also secured from the October 1 planting during both the 12- and 14-year periods. As an average, there is a rather consistent increase m yields from September 15 to October 1 and this m turn is followed by similar decreases. Very different results are obtained, however, when averages are made from the last nine-year period including m one average five years of relatively heavy Hessian-fly infestation and m another average four nearly fly - free years. During the Hessian-fly years, the highest yield was again obtained from the October 1 planting. Planting earlier than this date has resulted m relatively greater de - creases m yields, whereas yields from plantings after this date were relatively higher than for the entire period. In contrast, differences m yield resulting from the first three planting dates during the fly-free years were insignificant. The yields from the later planting dates, however, fell off much more rapidly than for the period as a whole. Counts and observations made during the Hessian-fly years showed very clearly that early dates of planting were accompanied by greater fly infestation. It may be concluded, therefore, that m the absence of Hessian fly, plantings made at any time during the latter half of September m this region should give about, equal yields.; Following October 1, however, yields may be expected to decline as planting is delayed. Unfavorable seed-bed conditions will further tend to increase the adverse effects of delayed planting. Under Hessiari-fly conditions, planting should be delayed until the latter part of this optimum period. Such, delayed planting, even m fly-free years, will tend to avoid recurrerice~6f severe infestation. In normal years, the fly-safe date m extreme southeast Nebraska has been reported as October 1, by M. H. Swenk, m Nebraska Ex - periment Station Press Bulletin 45. West and north within the state, fly-free dates gradually approach September 22, the average safe date for the, furthermost areas commonly in - fested. ' , I , ; ; The decreased yields from late planting are due to the plants becoming less. well established m the fall, which fre - quently results m greater winterkilling and m prolonging the ripening period into more adverse weather conditions. Two rates of planting were included to determine if the decrease </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Cultural Practices With Winter Wheat 27 consequent to late planting might be overcome m part by a thicker planting rate. As a nine-year average, the 7-peck rate yielded from 1 to 2 bushels more at all dates than the s - peck rate. There was a tendency, however, for the increase to become slightly greater with delayed planting. SPRING CULTIVATION Rolling and harrowing during early spring have been com - pared during a 13-year period with normal or no cultivation (Table 20). As an average, yield differences were found to be insignificant. It is possible that such tillage might prove beneficial under certain unfavorable soil and weather con - ditions. Table 20.— Effect of spring cultivation upon the growth and yield — 13 years, 1919-22 and 1924-82 Treatment Plant Date In Date Weight Yield per| acre bei ' ht head ripo Per bushel Actual ReUtive (1) 'Ti^' rs&gt; lAi found* Bu. P.et. 1 ' 1Z) I B ' U&gt; (6) (6) (7) No cultivation.. 86.0 6/1 7/1 69.2 30.8 100 Boiled 86.2 6/1 7/1 69.2 81.2 101 Harrowed „ 85.1 6/2 7/1 58.8 30.3 98 G an? ce 7 d for B a' n iBsea? I per?od to •*" ** ' 9 " yCar Period and *— m c «*^ HARVESTING AT DIFFERENT STAGES OF MATURITY Winter wheat has been harvested during a 14-year period m what was considered early dough, late dough, and ripe stages. A so-called dead-ripe stage was included during the last nine years. The results are summarized m Table 21L Table 21. — Effect of harvesting at various stages of mat'irity — 1U years, 1919-32* T Stage of ? ate Moisture Weight Weight Protein Yield per acre | maturity £&amp; 0 ™ P£™ «Jt»t 1919-82 yum Actual Bel. Actual ' Rei. &#132;. ... •?•«*• Gramt Pound t p. et. HZ P. at. Bu. IP. et. «&gt; &lt;2) (8) (4) (6) &lt;6&gt; (7) (8) (9) (10) Early dough 6/21 60.1 2.21 65.8 12.4 21.7 71 20.6 67 Late dough.. 6/25 48.1 2.76 69.4 12.8 27.0 00 26.9 S8 Ripe 6/80 25.2 8.86 69.6 13.1 30.7 100 30.6 100 Dead ripe.... 7/9 11.8 3.41 58.1 | 29.1 95 an i d Tl° y* 9-year averasres. and those m Columns 7 and 8 are 14-year averaeesl 1 The data m Columns 8, 4, and 6 are averages for 6 years, those m Columns 2, 6, 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 286 28 As a 14-year average, harvesting m the early dough, late dough, and ripe stages resulted m the respective yields of 21.7, 27.6, and 30.7 bushels per acre. These are relative yields of 71, 90, and 100. During the nine-year period m which an additional stage was included, relative yields of 67, 88, 100, and 95 were obtained for the early dough, late dough, ripe, and dead-ripe stages, respectively. The grain from these four stages of maturity, which aver - aged six days apart, was found to be rapidly decreasing m moisture content with maturity. The grain m the early-dough stage contained 50 per cent moisture, whereas that m the late - dough, ripe, and dead-ripe stages contained but 43, 25, and 12 per cent, respectively. Wheat m the so-called ripe stage would be considered sufficiently ripe for binding but not for combining. In order to avoid heat damage m combined grain, it would be necessary to delay harvest until the grain ap - proaches the dead-ripe stage. The results suggest that a slight loss from various causs, such as shattering before and during harvest, may occur between these two stages. ' [6H] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>