<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT Norfolk Hospital for Insane TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT — OP THE — SUPERINTENDENT Norfolk Hospital lor Insane —TO THE— GOVERNOR POR THEOPERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902 —BY - FREDERICK F. TEAL, Superintendent 1908 Thi Fbimoht TmiBUm Frimoht. Nbb. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">V </seg>
            <seg id="p003">155 REPORT. To the Honorable E. P. Savage, Governor of the State of Nebraska: — I herewith submit for your consideration a closing of the condition and management of the Norfolk Hospit - the Insane, during the period commencing December i, and ending December 6, 1901. My appointment took February 1, 1901. There remained on the hospital records December 1, 1900, 174 males and 91 females; total, 265. New cases admitted to December 6, 1901, 60 males and 39 females; total, 99; a total number treated of 237 males and 132 females; total, 369. Transferred to Lincoln Hospital, 59 males, 69 females; total, 128. Transferred to Hastings hospital, 109 males and 27 females; total, 135. Discharged as recovered, 57 males and 27 females; total, 84. Home on parole, 2 males and 1 female; total 3. Died, 13 males and 6 females; total, 19. Remaining on the hospital records December 6, 1901, 3 patients home on DftTOiC« PER CAPITA COST OF MAINTENANCE. Previous to the fire our per capita cost showed a reduction over the same period during the previous biennium, but with the added expense incident to the fire and decrease in the total population of 160 patients, our per capita cost was immediately raised to $236.02 for the period from December 1, 1900, to December 6, 1901, or $4.45 per week. RECOVERIES. There were 84 recoveries during this period, or 22.76 per cent; the percentage would have been much larger but for the fire, which was the occasion for an increase in the disturbed </seg>
            <seg id="p004">156 Kasting asylum to receive in the spring our incurables, of there were a great many on hand. DEATH RATE. The death rate shows a triumph for homoeopathic medication. While the rate from December i, 1900, to December 6, 1901, shows a percentage of 5.14 per cent, the hospital was not under homoeopathic control until February 1, 1901. From that time on until the closing of the hospital the death rate was 3.05 per cent, the lowest in the history of the institution. This includes two deaths from burning at the time of the fire. In recognition of the large number of the homoeopathic physicians in the state, and in justice to the great body of people in the state who favor our system of medicine, I would respectfully urge the contin - uance of the hospital, in the event of its reconstruction, under homoeopathic control. RESTRAINT. During the last ten months restraint was practically abolished — cribs, restraint-chairs, manacles, straight-jackets, etc., being discarded with one exception; we confined our restraint to the mittens and restraint sheets. The result of this was that peace and quietude on the wards was enhanced. SMALLPOX. An epidemic of smallpox threatened us in the spring, but by vigorous quarantine measures, was shortly stamped out, with a total of four cases, one of which was quite severe. CHAPEL SERVICES, AMUSEMENTS, ETC One of the most necessary adjuncts in the treatment of the insane is mental and physical recreation, and plenty of it. This need was supplied by dances every Thursday evening, the music being furnished by an orchestra composed of attendants; by musical programs participated in by employes and officers. In addition outside talent was procured whenever possible. A baseball nine was formed composed mainly of patients, and a </seg>
            <seg id="p005">157 number of match games was played with the young men from town. Chapel services were held by local ministers weekly. THE FIRE. There is nothing to be more feared and dreaded in an insane hospital than the fire demon. On the morning of September 23, at about 3:30, when everyone was sound asleep, the building was discovered to be on fire. It originated under the basement floor of the middle wing on the male side. The alarm was given and immediate attention was directed to getting out the patients. This was a perilous and arduous undertaking, as in a very short time the wards on the male side were filled with smoke from basement to attic. The experience was one never to be forgot - ten; there was no light except that from lanterns, and these fre - quently went out in the thickness of the smoke. There were many instances of heroism on the part of both employes and patients, while more than once employes risked their lives. When the final count was made, there were found to be only two patients missing. One of these, Victor Kaspar, of suicidal tendencies, of Colfax county, was taken from the building a sec - ond time, and, in the confusion, darkness, and smoke, he went back to his room. A third attempt was made to rescue him, but it was too late. The other man to die was Hans Jesperson, of Cheyenne county; he was finally taken out after a half hour's work with a sledge-hammer; the masonry around the window was knocked away, and an opening large enough to drag him through was made. He was so badly burned, however, that he died in a few hours. While the work of rescue was going on, other employes were busy on the outside in an endeavor to put out the fire. There was a period of about half an hour after smoke was first seen to issue from the basement windows, that no flames could be seen or located. It was at this time when an efficient water service would have probably checked the fire. As it was, both capacity and pressure were lamentably weak, and efforts in this direction proved unavailing. In about a half an hour fire broke through the floor on the basement at the point </seg>
            <seg id="p006">158 the lack of water. By eleven a. m., the entire main ward build - ing was consumed. Before daylight, crowds from town were on hand, and many rendered valuable assistance in getting out furni - ture, fixtures, etc.; the result of this effort being that almost everything in the administration portion and on the female side was saved, the total value of which is probably five or six thous - and dollars. ORIGIN OF THE FIRE. Several theories suggest themselves as to the origin of the fire. Indications pointed to incendiarism, and accident. Deductions were made merely from suspicion, and on this account I recom - mended to the Governor and members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings that the affair be investigated. There were a number of valuable points to be gained from the fire in the event that any future public buildings, especially hos - pitals, are to be built. Fire walls should be run up clear to the roof wherever possible. The building here was a fire trap in this respect. The cottage, or pavilion, plan should be used; each separate building being connected with its fellow by a cor - ridor one story in height. Wrought iron bars at the windows are a useless expense, and a great hindrance at the time of fire, as it is impossible to break or tear them out. Heavy wire screens should be used at all of the window?. It is not necessary to urge the importance of supplying all our public hospitals and other institutions with sufficient and efficient fire fighting facilities. Our plant here was lamentably weak, although the legislature of 1901, realizing the necessity of improvement of the water supply, appropriated $3,500.00, for the construction of a stand-pipe. The Board of Public Lands and Buildings let the contract for this, and also for sinking a new well. These improvements were not yet completed at the time of the fire; although thirty feet of the stand-pipe had been erected. At the present time the stand-pipe is full, and supplies us with excellent water pressure. ACCOMMODATIONS AFTER THE FIRE. The fire necessitated the immediate accommodation of patients, as the main ward building was burned; 160 were </seg>
            <seg id="p007">159 transferred to Lincoln and Hastings immediately afterwards. The rest were comfortably accommodated in other buildings. The Board of Public Lands and Buildings finally deemed it wise to move the balance of the patients to Lincoln and Hastings, which was done on December 6th, 1901. The cattle, beds and bedding, some furniture, cooking machinery and miscellaneous articles were moved to other institutions, and will need to be replaced in the event that the hospital is rebuilt. VALUE OF REMAINING PROPERTY. Eitimate the value of the property here, including the sal - from the fire, as $125,000.00, and chiefly on this account 1 recommend that the hospital be rebuilt; which can be for much less than the old building; construction to be on armitory plan, which is the approved hospital of to-day. I would recommend first that a central main building be built of fire-proof construction, to accommodate 250 patients. Bcond, that the new wing, so called, the walls of which are od condition, be rebuilt, and eventually connected to the building by a corridor. Third, I would recommend a separate dwelling for the super - intendent and family. Ethe appropriation is available for construction, and work menced at an early date, the new wing spoken of can be pleted by July 1st, 1903, and relieve the Lincoln hospital jst immediately of 125 patients. In the meantime, construc - of the main building could be going on. NEW WELLS. The new wells are needed, one of which would require a steam pump. I wish to express my appreciation of the loyal support received at all times from the officers. I am happy to state that our social and official relations have been entirely without fric - tion, and the utmost good feeling has continued throughout the institution at all times. The employes who have been so faith - ful in their duties will be remembered in grateful appreciation. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">160 We wish to express our heartfelt thanks to the people of Nor- folk for their many courtesies and acts of kindness, especially at the time of the fire. Many magazines have been supplied, which were greatly enjoyed by the patients. Our thanks are extended to the editors of the state who have kindly kept us supplied with newspapers. 1 have been the recipient of numerous kindly acts and sug- gestions from the members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, and other state officials; for all of which I extend my grateful appreciation. Respectfully submitted, Frederick F. Teal, Superintendent. f*TE OF APPROPRIATIONS NECESSARY FOR CURRENT 'ENSES FOR NORFOLK HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD, COMMENCING APRIL 1, 1903, AND ENDING MARCH 31, 1905. Superintendent's salary $ 5,000.00 Physician's salary 3,000.00 Employes' wages 18,000.00 Superintendent's dwelling 5,000.00 Board and clothing and all expenses not provided for 28,000.00 Repairing the new wing 15,000.00 Main building 100,000.00 Total $174,000.00 TABLE NO. 1 Movement op Population Males. Females. Totals. Remaining on record, beginning of Bien nial, December 1, 1900 177 93 270 Number in hospital at beginning of Bien nial, December i, 1900 174 91 265 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Insane Hospital, Norfolk. 161 Total number treated 237 132 369 Transferred to Hastings, after fire 108 27 135 Transferred to Lincoln, after fire 59 69 128 Discharged as recovered 57 27 84 Home on parole 2 1 3 Died 13 6 19 Remaining on record December 6, 1901 . 2 1 3 Actual number in hospital December 6, 1901 o o o Daily average 153 81 234 Percentage of recoveries, of whole num ber treated 22.76 Percentage of deaths, whole number treated 5.14 TABLE NO. 2. Showing Deaths During Periods by Months. 1900. Males. Females. Totals. December 2 1 3 I QO I • January 1 2 3 February 1 o 1 March 1 1 2 April 3 0 3 May o o o June 1 o 1 July 1 1 2 August o o o September 3 o 3 October o o o November o 1 1 December o o o Totals 13 6 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">162 TABLE NO. 3. Nationality. FOREIGN OR NATIVE BORN Country. Males. Females. Totals. Native 34 25 59 Germany 10 8 18 Ireland 2 o 2 Sweden 6 2 8 Bohemia 2 1 1 Norway 1 o 1 o 3 1 2 1 2 1 1 39 99 Native born 34 25 59 Foreign born 26 14 40 Total 60 39 99 Excess of native over foreign 8 11 19 TABLE NO. 4. Occupation of Those Admitted December 1, 1900, to December 6, 1901. Occupation. Males. Females. Totals. Brick mason 2 o 2 Barber 1 o 1 Clerk 1 o 1 Carpenter 3 o 3 Cook 1 o 1 Civil engineer 1 o 1 Farmer 34 o 34 Housewife o 23 23 Housekeeper o 9 9 Housemaid o 3 3 Laborer 7 o 7 Merchant 1 o 1 Denmark 3 oland 1 'anada 1 lustria o Total 60 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">163 Pharmacist I o i Railroader i o i Ranchman i o i Student i i 2 Shoemaker 1 o 1 School teacher o 1 1 Tailor 1 o 1 Totals 60 39 99 TABLE NO. 5. Ages and Civil, Conditions of Those Admitted. Ages — Males. Married. Single. Total. 15 to 20 years of age 1 1 2 20 to 25 years of age o 7 7 25 to 30 years of age o 4 4 30 to 35 years of age 1 6 7 35 to 40 years of age 3 7 10 40 to 45 years of age 9 3 12 45 to 50 years of age 2 2 4 5° to 55 y ears of age o 3 3 55 to 60 years of age 3 4 7 60 to 65 years of age 1 2 3 65 to 70 years of age 1 1 2 Totals 20 40 61 Ages — Females. Married. Single. Total. 14 to 20 years of age o 4 4 20 to 25 years of age 1 1 2 25 to 30 years of age 4 o 4 30 to 35 years of age 7 1 8 35 to 40 years of age 2 1 3 40 to 45 years of age 3 1 4 45 to 50 years of age 3 1 4 50 to 55 years of age 3 o 3 55 to 60 years of age 3 1 4 6b to 80 years of age 3 o 3 Totals 29 10 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">164 TABLE NO. 6. Alleged Cause of Insanity of those admitted. Cause. Males. Females. Total. Alcohol 7 9 7 Domestic troubles i 2 3 Epilepsy 3 2 5 Fright o 1 1 Family troubles and financial difficulties .1 2 3 Financial difficulties 2 1 3 Grief 1 3 4 Heredity 21 12 33 Trauma 2 1 3 Menstrual derangement o 1 1 Masturbation 3 o 3 Puerperal state o o 2 Religious excitement 2 2 4 Syphilis 2 o 2 Unknown 10 3 13 Worry 1 2 3 Overwork 2 1 3 Sexual excess 1 o 1 Meningitis 1 o 1 Secondary to cardiac disease o 1 1 Malaria o 1 1 Menopause o 1 1 Consanguinity — heredity o 1 1 Totals 60 39 99 TABLE NO. 7. Fokm of Disease of those admitted December 1, 1900, to December 6, 1901. Disease. Males. Females. Totals. Dementia — (a) Senile 1 o 1 (b) Primary 2 1 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">165 Mania, sub-acute 9 2 n (a) Acute 19 9 28 (b) Recurrent 3 6 9 (c) Chronic o 1 1 Melancholia, sub-acute 6 3 9 (a) Acute 5 9 14 (b) Recurrent o 1 1 General paresis 1 o 1 Neurasthenia 1 o 1 Mania with epilepsy 4 o 4 Hystero-mania 1 2 3 Simple mania 5 9 5 Simple melancholia 2 1 3 Paranoia 1 2 3 High-class idiot o 2 2 Totals 60 39 99 TABLE NO. 8. Showing Cause of Death and Ages of Those Who Died Cause Males Age Fem. Age Totals Chronic interstitial nephritis. . . 1 49 o o 1 General paresis .'.... 1 42 o o 1 General paresis 1 49 o o 1 Pneumonia 1 40 o o 1 Surgical shock 1 46 o o 1 Convulsions Epilepsy 1 19 o o 1 Exhaustion, acute mania 1 40 o o 1 Exhaustion, acute mania 1 59 o o 1 Exhaustion, acute mania 1 36 o o 1 Valvular disease of the heart ... 1 55 1 54 2 Valvular disease of the heart ... 00 1 31 1 Burned to death 1 39 o o 1 Burned to death 1 30 o o 1 Exhaustion dementia 1 59 o o 1 Tuberculosis, pulmonary o o 1 23 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">166 Land Commissioner's Report. Semie dementia o o i 05 1 Pneumonia hypostatic o o 1 48 1 Totals 13 o 6 o 19 TABLE NO. 9. Showing Admissions During Periods by Months 1900 Males. Females. Totals. December 6 4 10 1901 January 2 3 5 February 5 4 9 4 I2 5 16 1 7 September 4 5 9 October o o o November o o o Totals 60 39 99 TABLE NO. 10. Showing Number and Condition op Those Discharged From December 1st, 1900, to December 6th, 1901. Males. Females. Totals. Transferred to Hastings 108 27 135 Transferred to Lincoln 59 69 13&amp; Recovered 57 27 84 Died 13 6 19 Totals 239 130 369 March 4 April May 7 8 June ii July 6 August 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">167 TABLE NO. 11. Residence of Those Admitted. Counties. Males. Females. Totals. Antelope 033 Boone 2 3 5 Boyd 1 o 1 Burt 1 o 1 Cedar 3 o 3 Cherry o 2 2 Colfax 8 ' 9 Cuming 3 o 3 Cheyenne 2 1 3 Custer 1 5 6 Dakota 1 o 1 Deuel 1 o 1 Dodge 7 2 9 Dawes 1 3 4 Dawson 3 2 5 Douglas 1 o 1 Dixon o 1 1 Ureeley 1 2 3 Grant 1 o 1 Howard o 3 3 Holt 2 1 3 Knox o 2 2 Keith O I 1 Lincoln 2 o 2 Madison 2 o 2 Nance 3 o 3 Pierce l 3 4 Platte 4 o 4 Rock 1 o 1 Scotts Bluff 2 o 2 Sheridan 2 o 2 Stanton o 2 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">168 Land Commissioner's Report W ashinijton •••••••..•••••••••••••••. i i 2 Wayne 3 i 4 Totals 60 39 99 APPROPRIATION OF 1901. Showing Expenditures from April. 1, 1901, to December 6, 1901 Balance. Expended. Employes' wages $21,531.43 $10,468.57 Superintendent's salary 3,125 01 1,874.99 Physician's salary 1,937.50 1,062.50 Board and clothing 23,587.34 11,412.66 Fuel and lights 9» 2l6 -37 4.783.63 Drugs and instruments 838.80 361.20 Beautifying grounds !75-5o 2 4-5&lt;&gt; Burial expenses 100.00 Books, stationery and printing 238.05 161.95 Carpets and curtains 381.65 J 8-35 Furniture and bedding 640.70 559-3O Freight, express and drayage I 33-6i 16.39 General repairs 2 44- I 9 955-8i Ice 49°- 6 3 9-37 Incidentals 300.00 Kitchen furniture and laundry ma chinery 136.53 563.47 Music and amusements 472.00 28.00 Milk separator and aerator H-4 1 110.59 Paints and oils 324-64 75-3^ Returning and transferring patients. ... 500.00 Stand pipe 100.00 3,400.00 Vehicles, farm implements and harness. 305.68 IO 4-3 2 Telegraph, telephone and postage 37i-6i 128.39 Total $64,665.65 $36,709.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Insane Hospital, Norfolk. 169 Showing Expenditures from December 1, 1900, to April. I, 1901 Balance. Expended. Employes wages if 10,334.79 $ 6,860.54 Superintendent's salary 066.66 666 66 Physician's salary 500.00 500.00 Board and clothing 13,568.70 7,170.60 Fuel and lights (deficiency) 2,199.70 Drugs and instruments 289.17 207.18 Beautifying grounds 24.92 Burial expenses 481 Books, stationery and printing 281.75 119 .50 Carpets and curtains 6.45 Furniture and bedding 1,217.44 435-62 Freight, express and drayage General repairs 78.60 75-95 General repairs (deficiency ) 53-32 Incidentals 75.58 12.35 Music and amusements 266 87 68 25 Paints and oils 52 42 1750 Returning patients 237 95 49 5° Transferring patients Vehicles, farm implements and har ness 143-55 29-05 Telegraph, telephone and postage 56.18 55 99 $27,805 84 $18,521.71 Totals Deficiency 2,253.02 Balance lapsed $",537-15 $30,050.86 Totals $30,058.86 CASH FUND. REPORT OF D. REES, Steward. 1900. Receipts. Dr. Dec. 1, To balance cash on hand, last report $344.69 Dec. 27, To cash for hides, sold Karo Bros 6.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">170 Dec. 28, To cash for 2 calves $ 1 2.00 ■ 31, To cash for hides sold Dobsoti &amp; L.uudgrceu, Dec. 1, 6, 20, 26 and 31 30 95 Jan. 22, To cash, B. Meyers for 1,455 lb. rags 7.25 Jan. 22, Cash, H. E. Glissman, hides sold from Dec. 28, 1900, to Jan. 31, 1901 43 18 Feb. 4, To cash for three calves, $5.00 per Ucad .... 15.00 Total $459-52 Dec. 1, By John Krantz, feed and livery $ .85 Dec. 4, By freight on bath-tub and fixtures, Omaha . 2.97 Dec. 5, By D. Rees, Steward, business trip to Lin - coln, attending board meeting, 1st and 3d. 10.70 ■ 13, By freight on 1 bbl. sal soda and 5 cases toi - let paper 203 ■ 20, By O. L. Stepheuson, superintendent, busi - ness trip to Lincoln, Dec. 4 12.50 Dec. 20, By freight 2.51 Dec. 20, By 5 yards braid, 2 yards gimp, Bcclcr Bros. .30 Dec. 21, By D. Rees, Steward, business trip to Lin- 17 th and 1 8th, hotel expenses, railroad fare 9.50 Dec. 21, By flowers .75 Dec. 22, By freight on blankets 3.99 Dec. 27, By C. W. Braasch, 8210 lbs. R. S. N. coal, $7.25, and 8,360 lbs. Cannon nut coal,$7oo 59. 10 Dec. 28, By freight on brackets, valve and sink .61 Dec. 28, By revenue stamps -50 Dec. 28, By express 1.55 Dec. 29, By freight on vinegar from Lincoln .99 Jan. 2, By P. O. box rent, Jan. 1 to March 31 .75 Jan. 3, By D. Rees, Steward, expense of attending board meeting at Lincoln, Dec. 31, 1900, railroad fare, $6.70; board and room, $4.50 11.20 Jan. 3, By O. L. Stephenson, Supt., business trip to Lincoln, Dec. 29, 1900, to Jan. 2, 1901 . . . 14-5° </seg>
            <seg id="p019">171 Jan. 3, By Van Hory, ice cream, Jan. 25, 1900 $ 1.75 Jan. 3, By D. D. Bronson, livery and feed, December 5.75 Jan. 3, By 2 ribbons for typewriter and exchange on draft 1-57 Jan. 4, By freight on belt from Omaha .25 Jan. 4, By W. H. Rish, 34 feet galv. pipe, . 3.10 Jan. 14, By Tips for billiard cues .25 Jan. 17, By D. Rees, Steward, business trip to Lincoln, Jan. 14 to 16, 1901 11.20 Jan. 18, By Salter Coal &amp; Grain Co., 9,025 lbs. R. S. slack coal at $4.20 per ton 19.18 Jan. 18, By Johnson Dry Goods Co., $o% yards car- pet, at 70c per yard, for matron's room . . . 35.50 r. 18, By C. E. Inman, 12 spokes for phaeton,$3.oo, and 1 tire set, 50c 3.50 Jan. 18, By O. L. Stephenson, Supt., business trip to Lincoln Jan. 15, 1901 10.50 Jan. 18, By livery hire, Geo. Dudley, Jan. 13 1.00 Jan. 22, By H. E. Glissman, oysters, celery, butter, etc 4.20 Jan. 24, By Winter &amp; Shultz, pump leather .90 Jan. 24, By Aug. Pasewalk, shaft shackle on phaeton .50 Jan. 24, By H. C. Sattler, whip, $1.00, shafts, $3.00. . 4.00 Jan. 24, By Peter Duffy, buggy whip, 75c; repair har- ness, 25c; belly band, 10c 1.10 Jan. 24, By Neb. Tel. Co., line messages, Oct. 1, 1900, to Jan. 1, 1901 13.50 Jan. 26, By E. N. Vail, fruit, nuts, etc 3.05 Jan. 26, By C. P. Parish, nuts, fruit, cheese, etc 4.60 Jan. 28, By 3 doz. fruit jars 2.55 Jan. 28, By Gustav Nitz, horseshoeing for January . . 600 Jan. 28, By Rev. Thomas Walsh, burial services .... 2.00 Jan. 30, By R. F. Bruce, 1 gal. cream .50 Jan. 30, By H. C. Sattler, 1 neck yoke 1.00 Jan. 31, By C. P. Parish,oranges, cheese, celery, nuts, etc 1515 Jan. 31, By express .95 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">172 Jan. 31, By C. P. Parish, apples, oranges, bananas, etc. $ 1.10 Jan. 31, By Neb. Tel. Co., toll line messages 2.10 Jan. 31, By D. D. Bronson, livery 1.00 Jan. 31, By (Jhas. H. Johnson, 1 dish 1.60 Feb. 5, By freight on drugs .59 Feb. 6, By check to M. C. Walker, Steward, for bal- ance on hand 162.79 Total $459-52 CASH FUND Report of M. C. Walker, Steward. 1901. Dr. t6, To Cash received from D. Rees, Steward, by M. C. Walker, Steward $162.79 Feb. 23, To H. E. Glissman, hides 6.85 Feb. 25, To Shurtz &amp; Jenkins, 5 bu. onions 3.75 Feb. 26, To B. Meyer, 3340 lbs. old iron 3.40 Mar. 2, To H. E. Glissman, hides I7-I5 Mar. 22, To Karo Bros., hides 19.80 Mar. 30, To A. J. Durland, three calves at $5.00 15.00 April 23, To H. E. Glissman, hides 12 25 April 23, To The Fair store, onions 9.75 April 30, To Edd Pfiel, 2 calves at $5.00 10.00 May 20, To Mr. Rhines, board 1.50 May 20, To Hides "-35 May 20, To Mrs. Huntington, special attendance .... 5.00 May 29, To three cow hides 8.47 June 6, To 119 lbs. hides at 5^c 6.55 June 10, To 184 lbs. hides at 5j4c 10.12 June 19, To 152 lbs. hides at 5#c 8 36 June 29, To 150 lbs. hides at $tfc 8.25 June 29, To One sheep hide .35 July 20, To One bbl. sold G. W. Schwede .50 July 20, To 125 lbs. hides at 6#c 8.15 Aug. 19, To 106 lbs. hides at 7c 7.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Insane Hospital, Norfolk. 173 Aug. 19, To 96 lbs. hides at 6}4c $ 6.24 Aug. 19, To 7 sheep pelts at 5c .33 Aug. 27, To Reimers, contractor, board of six men for one week at $2 50 1500 Aug. 27, To Reimers, 5 meals at 10c .50 Aug. 27, To O.ie load cinders .35 Sept. 9, To 261 pounds hides at 6 J^c 16 96 Sept. 9, To 168 pounds hides at 7c 1 1.06 Oct. 9, To Cinders, 50c; rags, 750 1.25 Oct. 31, To 260 sacks at 3c 7.80 r. 2, To B jard of C. Chilson and men while build - ing stand-pipe 20-95 Nov. 1 1, To 380 lbs hides at 6%c 24.70 Nov. 1 1, To One load cinders .25 Nov. 24, To 106 lbs. hides at 6#c 6.90 Dec. 7, To R. F. Bruce, windmill 45.00 Dec. 7, To 217 lbs popcorn 2.25 Dec. 10, To N ithaway, 150 lbs hides at 6}4c 9.50 Dec. 18, To One roan horse, $5.00; 1 black horse, $6.00 11.00 D_'c. 19, To 1 bay horse, $5.00 5-00 Dec. 19, To One single harness 3.50 Dec. 19, To Five shoats at $300 15.00 Dec. 19, To 19 shoats at $1.00 19.00 Dec. 19, To One bay horse 6.50 Dec. 19, To 5 shoats at $2.75 13.75 Dec. 19, To One bay horse 3.00 Dec. 19, To One set double harness 3.75 Dec. 19, To One black horse 3 25 Dec. 19, To One set double harness 11.50 Dec. 19, To One bay horse 5. 25 Dec. 19, To One set double harness 5.50 Dec. 19, To One pig .50 Dec. 19, To Eight shoats at $6.25 50.00 Dec 19, To Fourteen hogs at $5 50 77-OO Dec. 19, To Two hogs at $6.00 1 2.00 July 20, To cash 175 lbs. hides at 6#c n-37 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">174 July 20, To cash one sheep hide $ .30 Dec. 19, To cash five shoats at $1.60 8 00 Dec. 19, To cash five shoats at $6.25 3i« 2 5 Dec. 19, To cash twelve hogs sold to Karo Bros., 3950 lbs. at $5.75 227.42 Dec. 19, To cash four loads cinders 1.00 Dx. 19, To cash three loads brick-bats 3.00 Dec. 24, To cash 4680 lbs. potatoes at 85c 66.30 Jan. 14, To cash 7525 lbs. potatoes at 85c 1^6.60 Jan. 23, To cash 14 doz. chickens, A. M. Thoma?, at $2.00 per doz 28 00 Jan. 23, To cash A. H. Kiesau, mdse. returned 5 30 Jan. 31, To cash Total .$1,240.46 Feb. 7, By cash 500 2c postage stamps $10.00 Feb. 7, By cash, one steak griddle -SO Feb. 22, By cash, freight on lard, rubber poods and Heinz goods 1.72 Feb. 22, By cash, three feather dusters 1.25 Feb. 22, By cash, John Friday, two boxes glasR, 14x13 and 10x20 10.50 Feb. 24, By cash, five packages shoe nails .30 Feb. 24, By cash, six picture hooks .15 Feb. 27, By cash, freight 1.72 Mar. 12, By cash, Karo Bros., 33 lbs. lard at oc 2.97 Mar. 12, By cash, one load sand .25 Mar. 16, By cash, freight on one bbl. caustic soda .... 2x0 Mar. 16, By cash, freight on one box glass .56 Mar. 22, By cash, three lbs. creamery butter .75 Mar. 22, By cash, freight on oil .25 Mar. 25, By cash, freight 2.28 Mar. 26, By cash, freight .98 Mar. 30, By cash, Louis Cortelyou, repairing type- writer 2.00 April 23, By cash, C. F. W. Marquardt, repairing 2 clocks 2.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">175 April 23, By cash, P. O. box rent, Jan. 1 to Mar. 31, ♦5 7 ~ 870 50 .42 .80 2.00 1.25 • 1 \j Aug. 2, By cash, Norfolk Sugar Co., 1-4 m. iiducci . .40 Aug. 19, By cash one spring for clippers .15 Aug. 19, By cash M. C. Walker, Steward, ImmmmI trip to Lincoln, August 1, 1901 10.70 Aug. 19, By cash M. C. Walker, Stewaru, ttummamt trip to Lincoln, July 1, 1901 10 70 Aug. 27, By cash one china gravy boat 1.60 Aug. 27, By cash Reimers, crushed rock 1 50 Sept. 4, By cash 9J4 lbs. fish 1 05 Sept. 5, By cash 1 dozen machine m iitam .25 Sept. 5, By cash eight machine needles .20 Sept. 9, By cash George B. Christoph, iwu buio 1.50 1901 • B23, By cash, lrcigtu auu cxpivs- 23, By cash, Dr. Teal, Supt, business trip tu Lin- §coln, Feb. 25, 1901 30, By cash, Geo. W. Recoiu, u-n.ug 3, By cash, notarial expenses, M. C. Walker, Steward May 20, By cash, Dr. leal, Supi., bii»im&gt;» 11 ip lu Lui- ■ coln, April 1, 1901 20, By cash, M. C. Walker, Steward, busings Ptrip to Lincoln, April 1, 1901 6, By cash, billiard tips 6, By cash, M. C. Walker, Steward, ouoincss trip to Lincoln, June 3, 1901 June 10, By cash, rope June 10, By cash, P. O. uox reui June 10, By cash, John McCarragan, digging »c*l. . . June 12, By cash, two loads sand July 20, By cash, Omaha Bee, advcri.s&gt;u;g July 20, By cash, pipe fitting, couplings ana uusinng. July 30, By cash, lumber, nails and boxing of urns at EMilford to ship to Norfolk 30, By cash, 30 lbs. of starch at 4 10 30, By cash, cement </seg>
            <seg id="p024">176 Sept. 9, By cash P. O. box rent $ 75 Sept. 9, By cash M. C. Walker, Steward, business trip to Lincoln, September 30, 1901 9 20 Sept. 14, By cash % lb. Dento compound -6o Sept. 31, By cash # doz. reporters' note books .30 Nov. 4, By cash 2 12-inch globe valves 3 75 Nov. 4, By cash 1 2-inch union .25 Nov. 11, By cash W. B. Vail, repairing clock 1 00 Nov. 11, By cash one load sand -io Nov. 20, By cash repairing clock .15 Nov. 20, By cash two loads sand .20 Nov. 20, By cash forge and postage on same .38 Nov. 21, By cash rubber stamp .42 Nov. 29, By cash 49 lbs lard at 9c 441 Nov. 29, By cash freight .56 Nov. 30, By cash returning escaped patient from Stanton, Nebraska 2.10 Nov. 30, By cash M. C. Walker, Steward, business trip to Lincoln 7- 2 ° Dec. 10, By cash one keg cidei 3 5° Dec. 10, By cash 15 lbs. suet 90 Dec. 10, By cash 30 doz. eggs at 22^c per doz 675 Dec. 10, By cash Wm. Seifert, labor, moving windmill 10.00 Dec. 10, By cash 1 lb. binding wire .40 Dec. 10, By cash bolt, 10c. and butts, 65*.: .75 Dec. 10, By cash express .65 Dec. 10, By cash M. E. Spaulding, seeds 3.70 Dec. 10, By cash 100 lbs. No. 12 electric wire 22.50 Dec. 10, By cash 4-inch Galv. ells at 50c 2.00 Dec. 10, By cash one globe valve 1.00 Dec. 10, By cash 3 gal. oyster at $1.30 3.90 Dec. 10, By cash 5 lbs. butter at 20c 1.00 Dec. 10, By cash 3 bunches celery at 5c .15 Dec. 10, By cash 3 quarts oysters at 5 c 1.50 Dec. 10, By cash 5 gal. gasoline .85 Dec. 10, By cash 1 12-inch round file .40 Dec. 10, By cath repairing harness 1.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Insane Hospital, Norfolk. 177 Dec. 10, By cash two ribbons for typewriter $ 1.50 Dec. 10, By cash 12 spokes, $3.00; 6 fellers, $1.50. . 4.50 Dec. 10, By cash 11 lbs. yeast at 36%c 4 03 Dec. 10, By cash repairs for harness 1.35 Dec. 10, By cash two drafts .10 Dec. 10, By cash H. E. Hardy, B. S. coal 1.00 Dec. 10, By cash repairs 1.75 Dec. 10, By cash 76 lb. turkey at 7c 5.32 Dec. 10, By cash 142 lbs. butter 2382 Dec. 10, By cash 7J^ doz. eggs 1.08 Dec. 10, By cash 200 lbs ice, George Schwenk .50 Dec. 12, By cash two buggy whips 2.25 Dec. 12, By cash lariat .25 Dec. 12, By cash pump leather .50 Dec. 12, By cash gig saddle 2.75 Dec. 12, By cash side curtains for surrey 6.50 Dec. 12, By cash two straps on shafts .80 Dec. 12, By cash 12 sheets wadding .30 Dec. 12, By cash freight and express 1.48 Dec. 12, By cash R. R. and cash to return patient Peter Wonderlin to Merna, Neb 10.00 ■ 12, By cash R. R. fare, returning patient, Fred Dunker 2.00 Dec. 1 J, By cash R. R. fare and cash for patient, F. Stahl, to Johnstown, Neb 20.00 Dec. 12, By cash R. R. fare and cash, patient, Lewis Hopton 12.00 ■ 12, By cash R. R. fare, returning patient, Jack Warner, to O'Neill, Neb 2.25 Dec. 12, By cash four red cedar posts 5.00 ■ 12, By cash balance account of Kiesau Bros., drugs 6.20 ■ 1 2, By cash balance account Geo. B. Christoph, glass, bbls. fish food, ink, etc 7.60 Dec. 12, By cash balance account Asa K. Leonard, paints and oils 5.34 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">178 Dec. 12, By cash, 8 joints pipe, 2 elbow joints with cap, 1 damper, 3 joints pipe, 1 elbow $ 4.40 Dec. 18, By cash, Shurtz &amp; Jenkins, butter and eggs. . 8.25 Dec. 18, By cash, P. F. Sprecher, P. M., postage stamps as per voucher (withdrawn) No. 923, dated March 12, 1901 40.00 Dtc. 19, By cash, expense of transferring patients from Norfolk to Lincoln — hacks, dray, hotel bills of Supt. and attendants and coffee for pa- tients 18.00 Dec. 21, By cash, 1 damper .15 Dec. 21, By cash, 2 boxes .25 Dec. ax, By cash, 2 water glasses .40 Dec. 21, By cash, 500 lbs. shorts at 75c 3.75 Dec. II, By cash, 500 lbs. bran at 65c 3.25 Dec. 21, By cash, telegraph messages .83 Dec. 21, By cash, heating stove, $12.00; pipe, 40c. . . . 12.40 Dec. IX, By cash, cranberries 3.00 Dec. 21, By cash, butter 3.20 Oct. 9, By cash, candle wicks .25 Dec. 28, By cash, 2,855 ' DS - hay at $7.00 per ton 9.99 Dec. 21, By cash, lemons, 25c; celery, $1.00 1.25 Dec. IX, By cash, 3,450 lbs. hay at $7.00 per ton 12.07 Dec. II, By cash, Braasch &amp; Zuelow, butter and eggs 8. 11 Dec. 21, By cash, 6,695 lbs. hay at $7.00 per ton 2 3-43 Dec. 21, By cash, Dr. Teal.Supt., business trip to Lincoln 2.00 Dec. XI, By cash, repairing lawn mower twice 2.00 Dec. IX, By cash, Shurtz &amp; Jenkins, butter and eggs. . 5.10 Dec. IX, By cash, exchange on drafts .60 Dec. II, By cash, ribbon for typewriter .75 Dec. IX, By cash, P. O. box rent .75 Dec. IX, By cash, Sunday lectures to patients from March 31 to August 12, 12 at $2.00 per lecture • 24.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">179 Jan. 14, By cash, J. W. Edwards, 4 new shoes $ 300 23, By cash, Standard Oil Co., 50 gal. Perfection Jan 31, By cash, E. G. Hielman, Deputy State Treas., business trip to Norfolk 2.50 31, By cash, Geo. D. Follmer, trip to Norfolk . . I ll [J| V V ~ ** 1 J A * • »^» • »^* • *«■•■•■■■■■■***•• « J • * * »| 1* oil at 12.- '■■ 21, By cash, W. H. Byerly, board during quaran- tine for smallpox ,„ ,... 23, By cash, D. D. Brunson, hauling and special night watch to hospital Dec. 23, 1901 .... ,.. 24, By cash, Shurtz &amp; Jenkins, butter, eggs and bread .„ 25, By cash, Geo. B. Christoph, typewriting paper j. Jan. 25, By cash, Mapes &amp; Hazen, carbon paper .... .„ Jan. 25, By cash, O. A. Ritchey, 'bus for hauling Jan. patients to train, Sept. 24, 1901 27, By cash, Stitt &amp; White, 1 ij£-inch nipple . . . 27, By cash, Millard Green, hauling hook and lad- " der to hospital; also load of men, Sept. 23, 1901 Jan. Edwards &amp; Bradford Lumber Co., lumber and lime ,8 3 ,-. Exchange on drafts * 29, By cash, M. C. Walker, Steward, business trip to Lincoln .o. 7 o g Jan. 31, By cash, grate for stove 31, By cash, stabling and livery 31, By cash, F., E. &amp; M. V. R. R. Co., transfer- - I ring patients 31, By cash, Dr. Teal, Supt., business trip to Lin- coln, Jan. 20, 1902 31, By cash, R. J. Clancey, trip to Norfolk 31, By cash, Dr. Teal, trip to Lincoln, Feb. 3, z 1902 7 .oo </seg>
            <seg id="p028">180 Land Commissioner's Report. Jan. 31, By cash, C. Bick, wood as per voucher with - drawn, deficiency claim $ 47 25 Jan. 31, By cash, Neb. Tel. Co., deficiency claim as per voucher withdrawn 4-1-55 P31, By cash, Western Union Tel. Co., deficiency claim as per voucher withdrawn 2.26 Jan. 31, By cash, services of auctioneer, Dec. 19, 1901 8.96 Jan. 31, By cash, stenographer's fees 3 00 Total $1,209.10 By cash balance on hand 31-36 $1,240.46 Norfolk, Neb., Nov. 25, 1902. To the Hon. State Board of Public Lands and Buildings: As custodian of the Hospital for Insane at Norfolk, Nebraska, I beg leave to submit the following report of my transactions from January 23, 1902, to November 30, 1902, during which period I have received from various sources and placed in cash fund the following amounts Sale of potatoes $325-55 Sale of scrap iron 62.22 Sale of scrap copper • • ■ • 8.40 Sale of rags 2.50 Sale of parsnips 1.50 Sale of salsify .25 Sale of turnips .40 Sale of popcorn 13 .78 For pasturage 6.45 From M. C. Walker, former steward, balance in his hands 31.36 Total receipts $452.41 From which deduct 271.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Insane Hospital, Norfolk. 181 DISBURSEMENTS FROM CASH FUND. Expenses to Lincoln $ 9.00 F., E. &amp; M. V. R. R., transferring patients 229.60 W. N. Huse, printing notice 16.00 Chicago Lumber Co., cement .50 Stitt &amp; White, two pipe nipples .25 Minnie Zutz, 2570 lbs. hay 7.60 Wm. B. Vail, repairing clock 1.00 G. E. Moore, 3 gal. linseed oil 2.25 Winter &amp; Schultz, repair harness 50 C. E. Moore, stove pipe 1.25 H. E. Hardy, 100 lbs. blacksmith coal .60 Postage 2.00 Stenographer's fees, this report .50 Total $271.05 During my term I have transferred to the Lincoln and Hast- ings hospitals the following articles : TO LINCOLN HOSPITAL. K sacks rubbers and overshoes, sun bonnets. o curtains. I white aprons doilies. 5 tidies. 85 ward curtains, short. 74 ward curtains, long. 25 bed spreads. 5 chenille curtains, 1 pair red portieres. 1 sack patients' individual clothing. 7 sacks dried sweet corn. State clothing too numerous to mention. 40 bushels parsnips. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">182 Land Commissioner's Repokt. TO HASTINGS HOSPITAL. 1 1 bed sheets. i bed spread. 20 pillow cases. 5 chair cushions. 33 underskirts. 50 chemises. 36 ladies' night-gowns. 57 ladies' drawers. 1 sack patients' individual clothing. State clothing too numerous to mention. 450 lbs. dried sweet corn. The buildings which were not damaged by the fire, namely, the kitchen, bakery, laundry, storeroom, steam and electric light plant, two barns, cribs, slaughter house, poultry house and ice house, have been kept in a good state of preservation. About 140 square yards of tin roof were painted. The excavation around the new wall was filled and a brick and cement founda - tion was placed under the pump. The water supply in the stand-pipe has been continuously maintained at fire pressure and hydrants, water mains and pipes have been repaired from time to time and are now in good repair. The hose and fire-fighting apparatus have been kept in order and readiness. All furniture, machinery, tools, library and records of the institution are in a good state of preservation. A new eight inch well was put down and equipped with a new pump by the contractor, Joseph Burns, in February, 1902. The walls of the older part of the burned building have fallen considerably, but the stone foundation seems to be good. The walls and foundation of the new west wing-^r^r in good condi - tian, not a single brick having been displaced. E labor above mentioned was performed by myself, with the tion of putting down the new well, and two days of other which was paid by voucher. Respectfully submitted, A. M. Thomas, Custodian. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>