<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Grain and Forage Sorghums in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">April 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">GRAINS and FORAGE SORGHUMS IN NEBRASKA BULLETIN 316 . APRIL, 1935 T. A. KIESSELBACH. R. L. CUSHINC, AND E. F. FROLIK i •r,' ; :'. \ ..\-'-.'¦'/; ¦;• '.-.¦ ¦¦¦ • - -,-; ¦'"¦'. :¦''(/':..^ &gt;--'^.''A.'":^ ¦:*'¦• :'-\::: '.::..'" :'3^ v-'.:, - "-v---_:-V-*"l ¦t'-y\;- ;¦•¦.:..:¦- '"¦ - ¦¦'';._ ¦¦¦.¦;". ,'"; . "¦- :;/.¦;.„: ¦..'..'•.-:'".^ -."A; ..- • ; ;&gt;\ ;;¦.:'.;.' -(.._. jr.; ;:'.:-¦ (..; ;';-;,'• | EARLY KALa FIFTY ACRE FIELD, YIELD 48 BUSHELS PER ACRE J THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Ij EXPERIMENT STATION, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA ! W. W. BURR, DIRECTOR </seg>
         <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page Pl.*X£ Ol- SoRCHI'M IN N'ERR/tSK.*. . . 3 L'lassimcition of Sorriii'ms (Irown in Nebraska 4 SoHGHLM V*ARlfcTlr.s 5 Grain sorghum varieties 6 Forage sorghum varieties 10 Factors to be considered in choosing a variety 12 Yields at Lincoln 13 Yields at North Platte 16 Varieties for different regions of the state 18 Seed Sr.LF.cnoN and Treatmfnt 18 Cvltiral Practices 19 Seedbed preparation anil planting 19 Depth of planting 20 Rate of planting 20 Date of planting 21 Cultivation 21 Irrigation 21 HaRVISTINI., TIIRtSHINI,, AND STORING 22 Harvesting for roughage 22 Harvesting for grain 22 Storing sorghum grain 26 Utilization 27 Sorchi'm Rotations 27 Poisoning ... 28 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Grain and Forage Sorghums in Nebraska T. A. KIESSELBACH, R. L. CUSHING, AND E. F. FROLIKI; A decided increase in acreage planted to sorghums in "Nebraska during recent years reflects an intense and growing interest in this crop. Accord - ing to the State Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Statistics, an average of 530,750 acres were grown during the period from 1934 to 1937 compared with 186,200 acres for the 10-year period 1924-1933. This change has been largely due to the development and distribution of better adapted forage and grain varieties and to a j general recognition of their superiority by farmers in search of a more dependable crop to meet the prevailing conditions of prolonged drouth. That sorghum is more drouth resistant than corn has been repeatedly demonstrated by experiijient station and outlying co-operative tests and by the experience of farmers. This characteristic of sorghum, may be partly accounted for by its more fibrous root system and its ability to enter into a condition of dormancy'during severe drouth, resuming growth when rain comes. • ¦:¦ Sorghum has also proved more resistant than corn to grasshopper attack. In numerous cases during recent years corn has been totally destroyed by this pest, while adjoining sorghum was damaged relatively little. '-' . .[' Y ¦",&gt;-. As an "insurance", crop, sorghum has unquestioned value, and an increased acreage for forage and grain production would seem to be fully justified. This.is especially true in that part of the state south of the Plattte river where corn failures are rather frequent. On those farms where livestock production is a regular part of the farming system, some sorghum should be grown for forage every year. Atlas sorgo, for example, will produce more forage per acre than any other crop in eastern Nebraska. Normally it yields twice as much silage as corn on the Experiment Station farm at Lincoln, and in years of severe drouth the advantage is much greater. In the central and western portions of the state, somewhat earlier ripening, and j locally adapted varieties as Leoti and Early Sumac show a similar superiority. Production! of grain sorghum as a grain crop is sometimes objected to on the grounds that harvesting' is more difficult and expensive than with corn, that there is no ready cash market for the sorghum grain, and that sorghum is "hard" on the land. It is true ; that harvesting is more of a problem with sorghum, but with the adoption of improved varieties and superior methods of handling the crop, most farmers will not find harvest - ing extremely difficult. With respect to marketing, there are now estab - lished cash markets for the grain, notably at Kansas City. Therefore, when produced in large quantities in any area, the grain can be shipped to a ready market in carload lots. Meanwhile, where production in any com - munity is too limited to make such shipments possible, the smaller quanti - -1 Acknowledgment ii made to L. L. Zoole, Superintendent.land Orrin I. Webster,: Field Astiitant, of the North Platte Experimental Substation for the yield data fiom that station; alio to W. E. Xyness, Assistant Agronomist, and Arthur Anderson, Associate Agronomist, who were associated with these investigations at the Experiment Station in the earlier years. </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 4 ties can be used locally. The adverse effect of sorghum on the soil is temporary and not serious if it is properly fitted into the crop management program. Because sorghum does offer some special problems it is advisable for growers to make a thorough study of varieties and production practices, thereby avoiding many of the difficulties which may otherwise be encount - ered. It is the purpose of this bulletin to present information concerning grain and forage production, based on observations at this and other experiment stations and on Nebraska farms. CLASSIFICATION OF SORGHUMS GROWN IN NEBRASKA Since many of the varieties of sorghum now grown in this state have been only recently introduced, most growers have not had opportunity to become acquainted with the different types. A better understanding of the types into which the varieties are grouped will result from a review of the following outline and descriptions. 1. Sorgo (saccharine) Varieties'. Black Amber. Atlas, Early Sumac, Leoti. 2. Grain sorghum (non-saccharine) .1. Milo Varieties: Sooner, Day. Dwarf Yellow. I-. Kafir Varieties: Pink. Western Blackhull, Dawn. c. Feterita Varieties: Standard. d. Hegari Varieties: Hegari. c. Hybrid derivatives Varieties: Kalo, Early Kalo, Club, Wheatland, Greeley, Cheyenne, Improved Coes. f. Miscellaneous groups and varieties: Grohoma, Freed, Durra, Shallu, Darso, etc. 3. Broomcorn 4. Grass sorghum Varieties: Sudan grass. Sorghum is the common name applied to a group of annual plants known botanically as Sorghum vulgare Vers, h is used in the same sense as the words corn, wheat, oats, or alfalfa. Sorgo is the name applied to the class of saccharine or sweet-stemmed varieties which are grown primarily for forage and for syrup. "Cane" is often used instead of "sorgo" but since "cane" is properly applied only to the true sugar-cane, none of which is grown in Nebraska, the term "sorgo" is much preferred. In general, the stalks are filled with sweet juice and dry slowly when cut. The varieties differ considerably in height, maturity, and head character. The seeds, after removal of the hull, are small to medium sized and are either white or various shades of brown in color. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Grain and Forage Sorchums Grain sorghum refers to that class of varieties grown .primarily for grain and is distinguished from sorgo principally by a lower sugar content ot the stalks. Because of this difference the forage dries more rapidly when cut. . Milo is the name of one group of the non-saccharine or grain sorghum class. Addition of the word maize to milo! (milo-maize) is unnecessary and confusing. The stalks are relatively dry and are somewhat shorter and &gt;more slender than those of kafir. The heads are short, compact, oval - shaped, and have dark brown chaff while the seeds are large and yellow or white in color. Milo is commonly grown only for grain and is not suited for forage except in the form of winter pasture after the heads have been harvested. Kafir is another group of the grain sorghum varieties. The word corn is sometimes added to kafir (kafir-corn) butjthe single term kafir is pref - erable. Ordinarily, the kafirs have thick, juicy stalks and grow to a medium height. The heads are cylindrical in shape, varying in compact - ness, and the hull-free seeds are white, pink, or red, and of medium size. Kafir is grown for both grain and forage. Feterita is also a group of the grain sorghum class having only one variety that is grown in Nebraska. Feterita is early maturing, has slender, dry stalks; oval compact heads; and large, soft, chalky white seeds. It is grown for grain only. j Hegari is the name of a grain sorghum group represented by only one variety in Nebraska. It resembles kafir in general appearance, but is much later and suckers more profusely. j Broomcorn is grown for the brush which is used in the manufacture of brooms. Since the production in Nebraska is very limited, and since it is not grown for either grain or forage, it will not be considered further in this bulletin. ... j Sudan grass, since its introduction in 1909, has become very popular in the Great Plains region as an annual pasture crop. It has great value for this purpose but since under certain conditions it causes livestock poison - ing, caution should be exercised in its utilization. Tests at the Agricultural Experiment Station at Lincoln have shown that Sudan grass is inferior to sorgo in cured forage production. During an] 11-year period, when grown in cultivated rows, it has averaged 2.0 tons'per acre, compared with 4.4 tons for Atlas sorgo. : In a 7-year test it yielded 70 per cent as much as Black Amber sorgo when seeded with a grain drill. Since Sudan grass is recommended primarily for pasture and its pro. duction for this purpose is generally understood, it will not be discussed further in this bulletin. I Hybrid derivatives are a group including those varieties that have originated by selection in hybrid material. These differ widely in various characteristics. ¦""••'•'I - SORGHUM VARIETIES ¦.I. ¦ : '¦¦¦ 1 ' Characteristics of the more common varieties of sorghum grown in Nebraska are given in the following brief descriptions and are summarized </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 in Table 1. These descriptions are based on local observations and on information obtained from publications of the United States Department of Agriculture and various state agricultural experiment stations, particu - larly Kansas. Grain Sorghum Varieties Kalo originated as a selection from a natural cross between Pink kafir and Dwarf Yellow milo at the Ft. Hays Experiment Station at Hays, Kansas. The plants grow to a medium height and produce cylindrical heads 9to 12 inches in length. Kalo seeds resemble those of Pink kafir in size and shape but are pale yellow in color. The stalks are only slightly juicy and do not make good fodder. The variety is susceptible to chinch - bug injury and is likely to lodge if left standing after full maturity. Kalo matures about 110 days after planting and gives high yields when chinch - bugs are not numerous. Kalo is best adapted to the south central part of the state. Early Kalo was selected from Kalo at the Ft. Hays Experiment Station. It closely resembles Kalo except that it matures 10 to 15 days earlier and is about a foot shorter. Despite its comparative shortness, Early Kalo usually lodges too badly after maturity to be suitable for combine harvest - ing and is best harvested with a header or binder. While it does not yield as much under favorable conditions as Kalo, Early Kalo has given excellent yields under conditions of severe drouth. It is susceptible to chinch-bug injury. Of all the varieties tested by the Nebraska Experiment Station, Early Kalo seems best adapted for grain production on dry land in most parts of the state. The first large distribution of Early Kalo seed was made in 1937 by the North Platte Substation. At the present time it is the most widely grown grain sorghum in Nebraska. Pink kafir was selected at the Fort Hays Experiment Station from material originally introduced from Africa. The stalks grow from 4 to 6 feet tall, are rather leafy, of medium size, and vary as to juiciness. The heads are 10 to 14 inches long, slender, cylindrical in shape, and bear seeds that are small and pinkish-white. Pink kafir has given good yields of both grain and forage at Lincoln when drouth was not severe. Because of its late maturity it is adapted only to the southeastern part of the state. Western Blackhull kafir is one of the strains selected from Standard Blackhull and is widely grown in Kansas. Probably all of the Blackhull kafir grown in Nebraska is Western Blackhull that was introduced from Kansas. This variety produces excellent yields in the southeastern part of the state, but it will not mature grain consistendy in the western and south - western regions because of the shorter season and lower rainfall in those areas. Western Blackhull grows to a height of 4 to 5 feet, has stout, semi-juicy stalks and broad, stiff leaves. The heads are Bto 12 inches long, quite large in diameter, and square at the tip. The seeds are of medium size and are white with splashes of red or black at the tips. Western Black - hull is resistant to chinch-bugs. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Grain and Forage Sorghums 7 Dawn kafir was selected at the Amarillo, 1 Texas, Cereal Field Station. It is a medium early variety, grows to a height of about 4 feet, and has stalks that are somewhat juicy: but .not sweet, j The heads are fairly similar to those of Western Blackhull but taper more toward the tip and the seeds are smaller. Dawn has yielded more grain at 1 Lincoln than Western Black - hull, primarily because it ripens earlier. "V". Sooner milo (sometimes called Sixty-Day Imilo) is a very early variety developed at the Southern Great Plains Field Station, Woodward, Okla - homa. Sooner is adapted to the same general regions as Early Kalo and has proved very promising, especially during years of extreme drouth. Like the other milos, Sooner adjusts itself rather readily to variations in stand and responds to more favorable moisture conditions. Sooner grows from 3 to V/ z feet tall, hasjfew leaves, and slender, dry stalks. The heads are oval-shaped, compact; of medium size, and have a tendency to "gooseneck" when the stand is; thin or when there is abun - dant moisture. The seeds are large, oval, and lyellow. Sooner is susceptible to chinch-bugs, and tends to lodge too badly when left standing after maturity to be satisfactory for combining. Day milo has the same parentage as Sooner and is similar to it except that it is shorter and about ten days later in maturity. It is sufficiently lodge resistant to permit combining and at 'the present time is the best adapted combine type for Nebraska conditions] Day. has shown a tendency to blast when temperatures are very high at the time of heading. Whcatland milo was developed from a cross between kafir and milo at the Southern Great Plains Field Station,) Woodward, Oklahoma. It produces rather elongated, open heads with yellow milo-typc seed. The stalks are very short and lodge resistant making this variety a good com - bine type. It has given high yields in some places but on the average is too late maturing in central and western Nebraska. , Cheyenne (sometimes called Sweet Stalk) is a variety developed by Albert Weaver of Bird City, Kansas. It has a rather slender stalk with a limited amount of foliage, fairly loose heads, and white seed. This variety frequently lodge's badly soon after ripening. Some of the stalks are juicy while others are dry and the forage is very similar in quality to that of other dry-stalked grain sorghums. Cheyenne is best adapted in the western third of the state where extreme earliness is of considerable importance. .' ' '.]¦..- Feterita has slender dry stalks, is of medium height, has few leaves, and is of low value as forage. The heads are somewhat cone-shaped and compact. The seeds are large, white, and soft and rot quickly in cold wet soil so that field stands are often poor. Feterita was one of the first grain sorghums grown in Nebraska, early introductions having been made in the period between 1905 and 1910. | Hegari came into prominence in Nebraska as an emergency crop in 1935 because of the shortage of other sorghum seed. Very little grain was matured that year, but on many farms it produced considerable forage. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">N'hbraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 8 Ki,s.«. I.— C.recle? (left) and Western Blackhull (right) growing in test plots at Lincoln. 4 ¦ 4; --Y. ---'l(-.C''''!i--:;Y.;' =:- '--Yi/-'-.'.-;.-:,':/---..'..--;.-.-.' 'v Y Y--Y-.- •-¦¦{ *a• l# /a* a*»i I v ' lil. jk&gt; ' 'iK''mi*m%i&amp;mk.tt' sA^/i^M M srSsfifSl EP -^X\2d!^:^L rm a f-' --'¦.- -.-JswW^-*7^ I* ,.**. .-- *2,''i?*\**.- Fie. 2—Atlas (left) antl Kansas Orange (right) growing in plots directly compar - able with those in Figure 1. Most farmers were pleased with the payability of the forage, but com - plained that it was hard to cut. Hegari stalks grow to a height of 4 to 5 feet, are fairly juicy and slightly sweet. The heads are compact, 7 to 8 inches long, cylindrical, and have seeds that are similar to those of Western Blackhull kafir except for the presence of a red-brown subcoat. When </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Grain and Forace Sorghums 9 Fig. 3.—Early Kalo (left of white marker) and Day (right) growing in four-row plats at the North Platte Substation. grown on dry land, Hegari has given very erratic results. In years of plenteous rainfall it has given good grain yields, but during severe drouth it rarely matures grain. It yields well when grown under irrigation, but should not be planted for grain on dry land except when seed of better adapted varieties is not available. Y Grohoma j originated in Oklahoma, its parentage being somewhat in doubt. It grows to a medium height and produces forage of fair value. The heads often fail to emerge completely from the "boot" and as a result spoilage in the heads is likely to occur. It is somewhat lodge susceptible and tillers much. Grain yields are low anid the variety has been over - advertised. .-'•"" .. |" Y i. . Club kafir grows to a medium height and the stalks are leafy but only slightly juicyl The heads are compact and j club-shaped and have white seeds splashed at the tips with red. Because it is late maturing, Club is adapted onlylto the southern and southeastern parts of the state. It yields well and is resistant to chinch bug injury and smut, but is not suited to combine methods of harvesting. Freed is an early maturing variety with white seed. Like Cheyenne, it produces slender, slighdy juicy stalks with a limited number of leaves, and,tends to lodge soon after ripening. The forage, however, is palatable to livestock. In common with Cheyenne it is very susceptible to kernel smut. .-.'.- </seg>
         <seg id="p010">rABLE I.— Some characteristics oj the- more important sorghum varieties grown in Nebraska. Chief use: . .. , Average strain or Sialks dry. number .if Average lltiw . Variety f, or i"icy, or .lays from height, best Y° 10r Tillers Lodging both iuicy-swecc planting lo inches harvested s'"" n . maturity Atlas sorgo Forage luicy-swcel 125 80 Hintlcr White Many Resistant Leoti sorgo 104 72 " Red-brown " Moderate Resistance Black Amber sorgo 90 70 " Brown - Susceptible Red Anibcr sorgo 96 -\\ Early Sumac sorgo " 106 68 " Brown-red Colman sorgo .... ,„„ 7i .. Red-brown Pink kafir Both Semi-juicy 12(1 «"»** Hinder or While Few Moderate Resistance header Western Blackhull kafir " lIS 60 " " " " Resistant Cheyenne kafir ' ')() (,=, ¦¦ - •• s ,„ m . Susceptible Freed " .... ()n fifl .. .. Hegari Semi-juicy. 125 -IS " " " Many Resistant sweet Grohoma Semi-juicv. 1211 52 " " Bull " Moderate Resistance sweet K-alo Grain Scini-iitscv. I OK -18 " " Yellow Some Susceptible Early Kalo Dry n 5 36 Stsoncr milo " 0(1 -|(| .... .. Many Club kafir " Srnii-iuicy 111 51) " " White Few Dawn kafir .... |s ( , . |(i .... .. „ Resistant Feterita " Dry Kill fill " " Many Moderate Resistance Greeley " Semi-juicy 95 50 " " " Some " " Improved Coes " .... or, .... Dwarf Yellow milo Dry 11 ft Vi " " Yellow Many Susceptible Day milo " " 100 28 Combine " Few Resistant Wheatland milo " " 112 30 " " " •* </seg>
         <seg id="p011">I Grain and Forage Sorghums Greeley ]was developed from a cross between Pink kafir and Freed. It is distinctly a grain type, growing to less'than medium height and pro - ducing relatively little forage, although the stalks are fairly juicy and palatable. It is very early maturing and deserves further trial in central and western Nebraska. The chief disadvantage is that the grain does not thresh free from the glumes. . 1 " Improved Coes is a very early variety developed at the U. S. Dry Land Field Station, Akron, Colorado. It grows jto a medium height and the stalks are slender and slightly juicy. It is not suited for forage production because of low yield. This variety shows some promise for those parts of the state where earliness is of prime importance. It is very similar to Coes from which it was selected. Dwarf Yellow milo has rather dry stalks and large, oval or egg-shaped, mostly pendant or "goosenecked" heads. It has been popular in the Southern Great Plains region, but is being replaced by varieties with erect heads and greater lodge resistance that are easier to harvest. It is not adapted to most parts of Nebraska. The milo seeds are all similar, and because Dwarf Yellow milo seed is quite plentiful in the south it is some - times sold as Sooner or Wheatland to unsuspecting farmers in this state. ' Forage Sorghum Varieties Atlas sorgo was selected at the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station at Manhattan from material supplied by j. N. Farr of Stockton, Kansas, who had found a field cross between Sourless sorgo and Blackhull kafir. Atlas grows from 7 to 10 feet toll, has an abundance of leaves, and stalks that are juicy, sweet and very palatable. The heads are compact and cylindrical in shape although they taper somewhat toward the tip; Un - like most sorgos Atlas has white seeds that are similar to those of kafir in size and jshape. It may truly be called a dual-purpose type since both the grain and forage are of excellent quality.; Adas has proved to be the highest forage yielder at Lincoln over a period of years. It is superior to Kansas Orange in quality of seed and lodge resistance, and is the best forage type' for eastern Nebraska. Atlas requires a very long growing season to mature seed. It will ripen under eastern Nebraska conditions if the crop receives sufficient moisture during the growing season so that growth is not retarded. Just how far west - ward Atlas can be expected to mature seed in normal seasons has not yet been determined. However, its superior forage yield has been demon* strated as far west as North Platte and it is likely that it may be grown profitably for forage much farther west in the state than seed can ordinarily be matured. Leoti sorgo is of unknown origin but was grown locally in Kansas for many years before being taken to the Fort Hays Experiment Station for testing. [The stalks arc very sweet and juicy and quite leafy. The heads are open with long upper branches which give them a drooping appearance. 1 The seed is medium-sized and red-brown in color. </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebr.\skv Acßicri.TLiuL Experiment Station Bulletin- 316 Lcoti matures enough earlier than Atlas to make it well suited to t'orage production in the central, southwestern, and western parts of the state. In the two years it has been tested, Leoti has yielded nearly as much forage and more grain than Atlas. The principal faults are that it is susceptible to smut and its grain is low in palatability and feeding value. Black Amber sorgo is the "old stand-by" among the sorghum varieties in this state. It grows fairly tall with rather slender, juicy and sweet stalks, relatively few leaves, and loose, sprangly heads. Seeds are usually inclosed in heavy, black glumes. Stands are more easily secured than with most other sorghum varieties. In general, Black Amber is fairly produc - tive but may now be replaced with superior varieties except where extreme earliness is needed. It may lodge considerably where the growth is heavy. Red Amber sorgo is almost identical with Black Amber except for the I.o'or of the glumes and being slightly later. Early Sumac sorgo was selected from Standard Sumac at the Fort Hays Experiment Station. It grows from 6to 7 feet tall, has juicy, sweet, moder - ately slender stalks, and matures in about 105 days. Early Sumac heads are small, cylindrical, with a flattened tip, and bear very small, dark red seeds. It tends to lodge and is susceptible to head and kernel smut. Early Sumac is adapted to the same regions as Leoti. Colman sorgo commonly goes under the name Honey Drip. It is a mid-season variety having sweet, juicy stalks and brown seed, and is grown in Nebraska only to a very limited extent. Factors to be Considered in Choosing A Variety The varieties of sorghum differ greatly in their regional adaptation, quality of grain and forage, and yield per acre. These factors must be considered when deciding what variety is to be grown. The degree of adaptation or suitability of a variety for the prevailing conditions of climate may determine to a large extent its performance in any given locality. Within this state the gradual northward and west - ward reduction in summer temperatures and length of growing season, and the westward decrease in rainfall require a somewhat corresponding change to smaller and earlier ripening varieties. Furthermore, some of the varieties that mature satisfactorily in Texas, Oklahoma and Kansas are too large and late for Nebraska. It has been recently established at this Station that varieties normally grown under the relatively short days of the south require more time to mature in the north where the days of the growing season arc materially longer. Sorghum is a warm weather crop and does best where summer temperatures are relatively high. In case of serious moisture deficiency, the plants tend to develop more slowly and maturity may thereby be delayed several weeks. This suggests addi - tional care to avoid using types that are too late and may be caught pre - maturely by fall frosts. In general sorghum may be grown successfully on all types of soil where other standard cereal crops thrive. It has some tolerance for alkaline or salty soils. </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Grain and Forage Sorghums 13 Under some conditions varietal resistance to diseases and insect pests means the difference between good yields and complete failure. Ease and economy of Harvesting are influenced by lodge r resistance, height, erectness of head, stem-diameter, and tillering. The quality of grain and forage that is produced by a variety will help to determine its value. There are striking differences in these respects. :. The value of a variety is not measured entirely by its yield. Some varieties ate capable-of high production, but have undesirable characters that make, them unsuitable for the purpose under consideration. However, since-yield over a period of years is to be regarded as the response of a variety to the sum of the factors of the environment, it is an important index to the value of the variety in question. ' Yields at Lincoln. - A number of sorghum varieties have been tested in comparison with corn on the I Experiment Station farm at Lincoln during 11 years, 1925 to 1937, with 1926 and 1933 omitted. The usual care was taken to provide, uniform land and field management and to reduce yield to a comparable moisture content. The tests have been in four-row plots repli - cated two tolfour times, and the acre-yields are based on the two middle rows. With I the exception of 1937 all planting has been done at a single date. In 1937 four plots of each variety were planted on May 25, and four more on June 5. The yields considered for that year are the average for the twoldates of planting. A rather uniform spacing of plants has been maintained by thinning to the desired stand while in the seedling stage. j . '••"'¦.-i-." .''"'.-' ¦¦¦-.'.¦. ¦" The average grain and forage yields obtained from varieties tested the entire 11 years are reported in Figures 4 and 5, while those for the last five years are shown in Table 2. The average annual precipitation at Lin - coln during Ihe 11 years has been 23.4 inches compared with the 59-year average of 27.2 inches reported by the Lincoln Station of the U. S. Weather Bureau. The rainfall ;was above normal during only two years, 1931 and 1932, vj-hich indicates that these tests were made during a rather consistendy.dry period. During the last five years of testing, the average annual precipitation was only 20[6 inches or 6.6 inches below the 59-year average. Three of the years, 1934 with 15.4 inches, 1936 with 14.0 inches, and 1937 with 19.4 inches, |were highly deficient in moisture available for crop growth. lii Figure 4.are given the average grain yields in bushels per acre for corn and five varieties of sorghum. Of the three varieties of grain sorghum tested, Pink kafir and Dawn kafir, both relatively late maturing types, gave the best yields and averaged 30 per cent more than corn. Poor stands in some of the earlier years y/ete responsible in part for the low average yield of Feterita. The yield of Atlas sorgo seed is not significantly diff - erent from that of Black Amber sorgo, but the Atlas grain is far more palatable and has higher feed value. The standard local corn variety known as Hogue Yellow Dent was used every year except 1936 and 1937 </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 14 Table 7..-—Grain and forage yields of 17 sorghum varieties and corn at the ¦ Igricitltural Experiment Station, Lincoln. Averages for five years. I9U, '14, '15, '16. and '17. &#132; ¦ ii l-'orage yield per acre Grain vicltl per lure &#132;,.,' .' , (15% moisture) variety Variety ' „ i Nusht-ls IVr it-ni „ , ... I'cr cent Ra" k (Sft lbs.) &#132;f .-..rn *»&amp; '"" s ufcorn Stsoner milo . ... I 2.' I 171 Alias surjjn I 4.111 25&lt;J Earlv Kalo 2 22.7 Kid K.im.is, Orange siirjju 2 .'.6fi lib Heicrita • 21" IS'* |-..,rl&gt; Sitnsac sorgo 3 3.22 2l)tl Greeley 4 211.1 If Itlac'k Amlitr sorgo -I .'.15 20.1 Day milo 5 I'l.S IM Crohtsina 5 3.13 2U2 Kalo (. I'l.ll 111 Western Itlackliull k.slir I. .'.(lj l'&gt;s Black Amber sorgo 7-8 17.2 127 Hegari 7 2.«'ft I'M Wheatland milo .. . 7-8 17.2 127 Pink kalir H 2."i IBV Dawn kafir V lft.7 12-1 [Jawn kalir '' 2.88 I«(. Club kafir 1(1 I«.. I 11" club kalir 111 2.f.H 173 Grohoma II I =".*J 118 IVlcrita II 2.f.6 172 Western Blackhull kafir 12 H.I I'M Kalo . 12 2.5V 167 Pink kafir 13 13. S 1112 (.reeky 13 2.56 165 Hceari 15 12.1 'ill Sooner milts l-f 2.-I5 ISH Atlas sorgo 16 lift Sf. Early Kalo 15 2.2'J MX Early Sumac sorgo 17 11.4 84 Wheatland milo Ift 2.08 134 Kansas Orange sorgo 18 9.9 73 Day milo 17 1.94 125 Corn H 13.5 100 Corn 18 1.55 100 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">i. Grain and Forage Sorghums variety [o " 5 *"bio' IS' ""Is m\*?°™, ¦ ¦ 38.E 131 H5.37.8 128 Atlns IsisHssHsssVsHsssl LHLssisaflsl 24. amber corgsJsßssssssassssssßaßssssssssssVsass 23.7 109 Feterita |sb*s*sss*ssb*bs*s*ssbsH 23.3 102 IssllllslslslHsssißsslllsHssss^LaH 21.7. Fig. -1. —Comparative grain yields of live sorghum varieties and corn at Lincoln. -¦ Averages for 11 years, 1925-37, with no tests in 1926 and 1933, T Tons per acre (l&amp;jt moisture) percent Variety 0 1 2 31 4 5 of oom Atlas sorgo I sssassssl 4.38 204 Kansas Orange Borgojasi H 3.81 177 ¦ssaaaHsHsßaaßaßsi \ 3.15 147 |Hssss*ssbsb*lbssssssssss*sssbl 3.12 145 JLssHsssßasßssaHssi 3.05 143 Black Arcber sorgo IB 3.02 140 Corn sassVaHalHasl 3.15 100 * ¦' - i • -^^^^^^^^- I ' ' - Flo. s.—Comparative forage yields of six sorghum varieties and corn at Lincoln. Averages for 11. years, 1925-37, with no tests in 1926 and 1933. when Krugjwas substituted. Each of the five varieties of sorghum yielded more grain than did corn. j Average'yields of cured forage from corn arid six varieties of sorghum for this same 11-year period are given in Figure 5. In general it may he concluded that Atlas sorgo will yield approximately twice as much forage per acre as corn. The later varieties of sorgo normally produce more forage in this part of the state than the early ones, tt should be noted that three varieties of grain sorghum, Pink kafir, Dawn kafir, and Hegari, produced as much forage as Black Amber sorgo. Yields of grain and cured forage averaged, over the five-year period for a larger number of varieties are given in Table 2. No test was obtained in 1933, as unfavorable soil conditions at planting time resulted in unsatis - factory stands. In the unfavorable seasons of j1934, 1936, and 1937 the grain sorghums j produced much more grain than did corn. Likewise, under adverse conditions, the early maturing varieties yielded more grain </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebrask* Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 jiiii Sooner larly Feterita Creeley Day average llseatland Darn club Tteatern PinV Average ello rislo alio Tlio kafir Icaflr S'hull kafir illil tarty •'¦"'tf" !,„ 7«rl«le. 100 .l.y. or leas uo dIJ , „ Mre I — li. t.. —l'iiiii|i.ir.ui\t- strain \icltls al early and late grain sorghum varieties at Lin - ciiln. A.erajies tnr five years, 1932, "3-1, '35, 36, and *37. than did the later maturing sorts. In Figure 6 are given the average yields nf fiie early varieties of grain sorghum compared with those of five late \arieties. While these data are insufficient to draw final conclusions, they indicate that the early varieties are better able to produce grain than the later varieties when severe drouth conditions prevail. Atlas sorgo produced the greatest average yield of forage during the live year period and was followed by Kansas Orange. These results are in accord with those obtained during the longer period of testing. The varieties of sorghum differed in yield of forage but all were materially more productive than corn. Yields at North Platte Variety tests at the North Platte Experimental Substation have been conducted during a five-year period, 1933-1937, on upland soil under con - ditions comparable with those found over a large part of western Nebraska. Plots in 1933 followed corn. In 1934 one plot of each variety was planted un land that had been previously cropped to corn and one plot on land that had been summer-tilled. In 1935 the plots followed corn, while in 1936 and 1937 yields were taken on land that had been summer tilled the preceding year. The average annual precipitation for the five years was 15.95 inches, compared with a 31-year average of 18.61 inches. Precipitation in 1936 totaled 12.43 inches, and 12.37 inches in 1937, making a total deficiency for the two years of 12.42 inches. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Grain and Forace Sorghums „ . . ;¦¦ r ¦ -i Bushels (56 lbs.) per acre | Peroent Variety I 3 S 10 15 go' as -go of corn Knlo BIBBI^BB^gHf 3D.9 307 26.3 j 23.2- 156 '¦ W*\ ssßssssassssasaaasMsssasssflH 23.1 155 Com JsasHLsflssHsßßssßH 1-1.0 XOO Fie. 7.—Comparative grain yields of four sorghum varieties and corn at the North Plane Substation, Averages for five; years, 1933-37. Variety Y Tons per acre *~ I Percent —j ° 1 ¦¦- ¦a- - 3I- ¦¦ A B Lof corn sorgo jWsßssßßssssßsa*assßss.ssWi 4.6 V sssl 4,3 - -80rg0s]sa»s! Baal 4,-J 233 !¦»¦¦¦¦¦¦ 3.6 200 sorgo s|ssHs»&gt;Mss**ss*Mss**iaLslsf 3.5 194 jHHHsaHsBB 2.8 jsaßsaWssasaal 1.8 | 100 Fin. S..—Comparative cured forage yields of six sorghum varieties and corn at the ( North Platte Substation. Averages for two years,. 1936-37. - ¦ . I The. average grain yield of Substation White com and four varieties.} of grain sorghum are given for the .five-year Iperiod in Figure 7. Early Kalo yielded slightly more than twice as much grain as corn under these adverse conditions. With the exception of Kalo, which is medium-early, all of these sorghum varieties are very early maturing. They are relatively new varieties and are regarded as superior to those previously available. This introduction of new, improved varieties has been a contributing factor to the high yields of sorghum in comparison with corn. The first year of testing for Early Kalo, Cheyenne, and Greeley was 1933, while Kalo was included in the tests for the first time in 1929. Average forage yields of corn and six varieties of sorghum are given for the years 1936 and 1937 in Figure 8. Here, as at Lincoln, the later varieties of sorgo yielded more forage than the early varieties even though they are not so successful in grain production. These yields were obtained on land that had been fallowed the previous year. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agriovlti ral Experiment Station Bulletin 316 Varieties for Different Regions of the State Since sorghums differ greatly in character and in their response to various factors of the environment, a variety adapted to one part of the state may not be as suitable elsewhere. Therefore, the state has been divided and recommendations are made by regions, keeping in mind the fact that the boundaries of these regions are somewhat arbitrary and flex - ible. For the reason that no one variety has proved consistently best for grain or forage in any region, several are suggested and final choice will rest with the grower. I """ j """IV"! •— 1 -*-l —¦ j STS3SSS3 j *""""\w - | L^ l 1 I seoioh iii|.'"'i\____^--^:a — "NpPrnjj^. i\ I llGsU:;i: Early nolo, Cheyenne, j 1 | r%. — Jrsfftytri\ Greeley, Iroroved Coea, sirsnq-«2r|_l \^&lt;\ Sooner. I |^"«u I c ,¦.„, _V Iromct: Black AssUer, Leoti, =KsjT=rcr- JS*"*" 0-- " L-i 0" 1 toll Surao. I | *ai^xal"lia!o ~«*r-*T*"\ i t —sta* 1 raws* ieg f^^WF^ mJS m HW To^AGe* Atl*a, LeotlX TH f I rT^i -^-f w'^Y^j-y*i ¦ ¦ -it- ! *»=¦=* j~*r*~ipr\ji. I hsssr.-P^-~&gt;_l_-.i 1 **""¦ REGIC-I* Il r-=* Jt I j "-r-l^-i=*=":ißin,it!ii ni I I I L —.4 HM i I I ' I GHAIii: Pin" kafir. || IGRAIH: Early Kalo, Sooner, Halo, Qay,| Seatarn Bine*'J _ Cheyenne, feetern Blwdc-m'-^J — „, I|- -'I Early \\ FoRAGEs Leoti,Ynriy Sutbc. Atlas! I 11°-° .??'"'"; I. V Stbez.J — Leoti,a l-'i... ''.—Rromnicmsctl varieties of sorghum for Nebraska. Recommendation for each of the four regions as shown in Figure 9, are based on varietal performance in station tests at Lincoln, North Platte, and Alliance and in numerous cooperative tests scattered throughout the state. A return of more favorable moisture conditions may justify changes in present recommendations. Because of limited local information as to the adaptation of sorghum lor grain production in comparison with other crops, no very definite recommendations would seem justified for the high - plains region in western Nebraska. It is often advisable to plant two or more varieties of somewhat different type on the same farm as, for example, Early Kalo and Western Blackhull for grain and Atlas for forage in the southern part of Region 11. This lessens the possibility of complete failure due to unfavorable conditions. SEED SELECTION AND TREATMENT Sorghum seed should be kept as free from mixtures as possible. The crop planted from impure seed is variable in height, maturity, head shape and seed color, thus making harvesting more difficult and lowering the quality. All types and varieties ol sorghum hybridize freely with each other, making it difficult to maintain purity when two or more kinds are grown in close proximity. Whenever possible, the seed field should be </seg>
         <seg id="p019">' ¦' ' I Grain and Forage Sorghums -.- - i 19 isolated from other sorghum, and the further precaution taken of selecting well-filled, mature, typical heads from healthy plants of uniform height.] Field selection should be even morej rigidly practiced where isola - tion can not be provided. Removal of hybrid or off-type plants from the fields aids in keeping the seed pure. All sorghum seed should be treated for the control of kernel smut and certain fungi that cause rotting of planted seed. Treatment with copper carbonate dust at the rate of 2 to 3 ounces per bushel of seed or. with New Improved Ceresan at the rate of Vi ounce per bushel will effectively control this smut and often improves the field germination. These dusts may be applied to the seed with a treating machine, barrel churn, or by shaking the seed and dust together in a closed can. Seed treated with copper carbonate may be stored indefinitely j but when treated with New Improved Ceresan it should be planted within four weeks after treating as otherwise the germination may be injured; Caution: Copper carbonate and mercury (New Improved Ceresan) dusts are poisonous to man and to farm animals. | . CULTURAL PRACTICES .' Seedbed Preparation and Planting The principal objectives of seedbed preparation are to kill weeds, con - serve moisture, and to pulverize and warm the soil. Warming is particu - larly essential because sorghum seed germinates poorly when the soil is cold. Any practical procedure of preparing the seedbed that accomplishes these objectives is satisfactory. I The,following method has been found to give the best stands and the highest yields under most conditions: The field is blank listed in the fall or early spring, facilitating moisture accumulation and warming in the bottom of thefurrows. When weed growth starts in the spring the ridges are thrown in with a listed-corn cultivator. Should it be necessary to kill a second crop of weeds before planting, either a disk harrow or a one-way disk can be used effectively. When it is time to plant, the furrows made in the fall or spring are reopened with a. corn planter equipped with disk furrow openers and the seed is dropped at the same time. The furrows can be reopened with a regular hard-ground lister but if done in this way, they are narrow and the sides are apt to wash down and cover the seed too deeply in case of dashing rains. Planting by this method insures placing the.seed in moist, warm, mellow soil. Sometimes, instead of re - opening the same furrows, the ridges are split, but this is not so desirable under ordinary conditions, as the soil is less likely to be thoroughly warmed. Plowing, followed by thorough tillage, is!a satisfactory method so far .as getting stands is concerned. When handled in this way planting is done with a surface planter or with a planter equipped with furrow openers. The principal disadvantages of this method are that it is'more expensive than listing and weed control is usually more difficult where the crop is surface-planted. When sorghums are to be grown for hay they may be </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 planted with a grain drill in soil that has been plowed and worked into good condition. Listing in soil that has been merely disked in the spring is a common practice, but is often responsible for poor stands, due to seed rotting in the cold soil. The best weed control in sorghum fields is done before the crop is planted. The destruction of several crops of weeds by early and thorough tillage in connection with seedbed preparation greatly reduces the likeli - hood of a serious weed problem after the sorghum is up. Sorghum grows slowly at best and cultural practices that control weeds, hasten the early growth of the sorghum plants, and fit in with other farm practices, arc to be recommended. Depth of Planting Sorghum seed should be covered with one to one-and-a-half inches of soil. If the seed is planted shallower the surface soil may dry out before it germinates and if planted deeper the seedlings may fail to emerge. Rate of Planting The question of how much seed should be used per acre in planting sorghums is not as easily answered as for other crops. The reasons for this are extreme differences in germination, varietal differences in size of seed and plants, and differences in manner of planting, i. e. rows and close - drills. The germination of most sorghum seed is commonly not high and no seed should be planted without testing. Ordinarily about 50 per cent less germination may be expected in the field than is obtained in germina - tion tests. The amount of seed to be used will be determined in part by its germination and by seedbed conditions. There may be considerable range in the spacing of plants without materially affecting yields because of adjustments in suckering and plant and head size. The rate of planting recommendations which follow apply most specific - ally to the southern, western, and central parts of the state. In the east, where moisture conditions are more favorable, the rate should be increased about 20 per cent. For grain.—The kafirs and similar varieties, such as Kalo, Early Kalo, and Cheyenne, ordinarily produce the best yields of grain with the plants spaced about six inches apart in the rdw when planted in those regions where they are best adapted. With seed of good quality and good germination, provided seedbed and climatic factors are favorable, 3 to -f pounds per acre should give the desired spacing. Milo usually makes the best yields when the plants are spaced from 1 to 2 feet apart in the row, and 2 to 3 pounds of good seed per acre will be ample under most conditions. Feterita seeds are very large and often germinate poorly, necessitating the use of 4 to 6 pounds per acre. For forage.—A four-inch spacing of sorghum plants in cultivated rows is considered optimum for forage production. Although somewhat higher </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Grain and Forage Sorghums 21 yields may be obtained from closer spacing, the quality is lowered because of lessened grain content. Such types as Amber, Orange, and Atlas sorgo, the kafirs, and Hegari should be planted 'at the rate of 4 to 6 pounds of good seed per acre to get the desired spacing. Because of its very small seeds, Early Sumac should be planted at a lolwer rate. When planted with a grain drill for hay, seeding rates of 40 to 100 pounds per acre, varying with soil, moisture, and location in the state 1, have proved satisfactory. Most implement manufacturers can supply suitable plates for planting sorghum with either the lister or corn planter. Where these are not avail - able, blank plates can be drilled with three-sixteenth-inch holes for kafirs, sorgos, and other small seeds and one-fourth-inch holes for milos and Feterita. The number of holes per plate should be adjusted to provide the proper rate of planting. . !' Date of Planting Sorghum is a hot-weather crop and this, fact should be borne in mind when choosing the time to plant. Planting should be delayed until the soil is warm enough to insure good germination. Early-maturing varieties may be planted later than the late-maturing sorts. Where chinch bugs threaten and the susceptible milo is to be grown, 1 it is advisable to plant as early as permissible so that the plants will be better able to resist the attacks of the chinch bugs because of their larger .size. In general, sorghum should be planted during the latter part of May or early in June, which is about a week later than the normal time for planting corn. Sorghum may be planted earlier in the southern and eastern parts of the state than in the western and more northern parts. Cultivation Sorghums planted in rows are cultivated the same as corn, the amount necessary depending on the growth of weeds. Where the crop is listed, the first one or two cultivations are made with a listed-corn cultivator or go-devi', although one of the cultivations may be replaced by one or two harrowings. Should further cultivation be needed after the ridges have been leveled it can be done with the rcgularj shovel cultivator. If the sorghum is surface-planted the first tillage operation may be a light harrowing just after the plants have emerged. This is followed by two to five cultivations with a shovel!cultivator. Some farmers prefer to omit the harrowing. ! Y Irrigation •¦]-' * -.'• Sorghum may be grown successfully under irrigation and usually pro - duces good yields of grain or forage. The | rate of planting should be increased under irrigation; otherwise cultural practices are similar. Later - maturing varieties may be grown under irrigation than on dry land at the ¦' same location, because the more favorable water supply hastens plant development. .'...¦ ¦{¦:¦ '¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nbbk.sk, Ac ß ,c, lt , ral Expemment Stat.o* B ullet/ , 316 22 HARVESTING, THRESHING, AND STORING Harvesting for Roughage a r^o gtTht JaS^ °r CUred ™«' " harvested. At the Nebraska Exneri™, S t^ StagC *« «°P Black Amber sorghum 7% , ath WW that Wh&lt;=n maturity-first heads appearing, vSeaded *^ T*s "^ *** °£ npe-the relative yieldsTvere fuO 77m' rl H^ d°Ugh ' 3nd Seed chemical tests, it was found that in L ', ***}}* Per cent* Based on corresponded with the acre y S^ of hay ' °f nntrifinß Per acre JHHHH^r '^mmWmXXw II imlaf - ' ' &lt; im i • I Jaii/a.- i^l I *''*av Sl Bjgf B*H sH^IUrsP ¦I'ts'B ¦ -- ¦O-H.vesti. &#132; ±™^&lt; X t, l sid ; nf . mgan anJ well established that ZgLn \"ll I^H ST" * haS f**ir*y turely. Ordinarily, the crojcan he lTft fad, eV? n tf CUt Prema" if that much time ,s needed to aKain n g"^ time °f fir" f-°* whether the crop is CUt ju„ MoTor TZ^T'f *'" im™«»* frost Obviously' leaving'it^ after =3, tl ft" B* fc kmfa« result m considerable loss of leaves y d wcat[ '« will -'"t^h^S/Lirrf»»—¦» »~&lt; «*• ."•fTS^iTSfeXS?'^ 1 '- - ¦*- Ft ssßta iSLTt si-F?" = -"ss*?: </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Grain and Forage Sorghums 23 Silage.—Sorghum should not be cut for Isilage until the grain is fairly mature. Otherwise too much acidity may be formed in the fermentation process. However, if drouth injures the crop before maturity, it can be successfully ensiled. Likewise, if it is frosted before reaching maturity, it will make satisfactory silage if harvested within a few days after the first killing frost. ' i The field ensilage cutter is proving to be a very practical machine for • harvesting sorghum. A great deal of labor is saved where cutting, chop - ping, and loading into wagons are all done in one operation. When the crop is placed in a trench silo, the wagons are driven through the silo, which simplifies unloading and assists in packing the silage in the trench. -" ' i &gt;'"3 .yjyy.tw-1 fi***. sswatl sSB U'Kfc. '¦ *?¦ affl!.' ... ,^££^ mmn^W*%TTWKSK^KEB*WmmmmmW Fio. 11.—Harvesting Atlas sorgo with a binder. Harvesting for Grain ¦ ¦ There is no single standard method of harvesting sorghum for grain that can be recommended as most practical under all conditions in the state. Such factors as acreage to be harvested, equipment available, normal amount of fall precipitation as influenced by location within the state, variety grown, need for getting maximum amount of roughage, and the purpose for which the grain is to be used, all influence to an important degree the manner in which the crop may best be handled. Roughly, the following methods are used in harvesting sorghums for grain: (a) cutting with binder, shocking in field, and threshing, (b) head - ing by hand or with machinery and threshing, and (c) combining. Several modifications of the above arc possible. Cutting with binder.—Perhaps the most widely used method of harvest - ing consists of cutting the crop with a binder, curing in shocks, and later threshing. This gives the farmer the opportunity to save the grain with the highest degree of quality possible arid to save the roughage. Cutting </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 can usually be done well in advance of the first killing frost. This is especially important where the grain is to be used for seed purposes, since it is thus possible to get the moisture content of the grain reduced more rapidly and accordingly minimize danger of frost injury to germination. Ordinarily, the corn binder is used for cutting grain sorghum. If the crop has been stunted by drouth or the variety is normally short, it may be preferable to cut with a grain binder. The bundles are shocked after cutting and left in the field until thoroughly cured. Following this, threshing may be done in any one of several ways. The entire bundles may be run through a threshing ma - chine. More often, however, the heads are cut off the bundle before they are put through the threshing machine. This may be done as follows. A cheese-knife, consisting of a large blade with a long handle is attached to the edge of a rack. The heads are then cut off with the knife The head material is hauled to a central point for threshing. A vertical sickle - bar attachment is now available for some combines that is very convenient in threshing sorghums. The machine is moved from shock to shock, the heads are cut off by holding the bundles over the sickle and are then run through the combine. In growing varieties like Atlas, many farmers have found that it is practical to harvest a seed crop and still utilize the stover for silage This is possible because the heads mature when the leaves and stems are stilt green and succulent. The crop is cut with a binder and hauled to the silo within a short time after cutting. After topping, the stover is run into the silo. The heads, which naturally carry a good deal of moisture at this time, are usually spread out in thin layers in a building or piled in neks in the open for drying. When the moisture content has been suffi - ciently reduced, the head material is threshed. Methods of heading.-Heading may be done in any of the three follow - ing ways-, by hand, with a special row-header or so-called kafir header and with the ordinary grain header. Where the crop is to be headed, one of the most important factors to consider ,s how the head material is to be handled after harvesting. Head - ing ,s usually clone as soon as the grain is reasonably mature, but at a time when the heads are still subject to spoilage due to the high moisture content o the stems and panicle branches, in regions where the humiditv is relatively ow and the amount of precipitation in the fall is rather limited it is practical to rick the head material out in the open for curing Thresh - ing may then be done as soon as the heads are thoroughly dry or else they may later be stacked in larger ricks and threshed when convenient. Ihe tormer method is no doubt preferable under Nebraska conditions It is obvious that ricking the head material out in the open is not practical ,„ regions where humidity is high and where fall rains are likely to continue over prolonged periods. Therefore, this practice is recommended only for western and possibly the drier portions of central Nebraska. When the crop ,s headed under the more humid conditions in eastern Nebraska, the material should be dried out by spreading it in </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Grain and Forage Sorghums thin layers inside of buildings. Since the sorghum crop is normally har - vested well in advance of corn hijsking time, corn cribs provide a very good place for drying the heads. The added aeration under such condi - tions is very helpful. Obviously, only a very limited acreage of sorghum could be handled where the head material is cured within buildings. r --' 7 ; YvY^^B^M m A - \^MmWrsr^w§^mm\mm» a* JBl afj ft.l.^^awJlawawa^aßaaaaswas. swa Fie. 12. —Atlas sorgo in shock. ¦ Y .'. ¦ . ¦ I • One of the principal advantages of harvesting only the heads is that most of the plant is left out in the field. This is very beneficial where wind erosion is a serious factor. The plants not only reduce the danger of soil blowing, but also may be very helpful in holding snow. The value of roughage is by no means lost, since stock can be turned into the field to graze the headed stalks after they have been frosted and thoroughly cured.'.; ¦ . Cutting heads off with a knife and throwing them into a wagon^is one of the simplest methods of harvesting, ilt is relatively slow and is practical only where the acreage to be handled is small. One man can head about 1 to 2 acres a day by this method. | Special row-headers which are attached to the side of the wagon are now available for harvesting sorghums. They are driven by a chain on a sprocket attached to the rear wheel. Some of these row-headers can be lowered and raised to take care of varying heights of plants within the same field. From 4to 5 acres of sorghum can be harvested per day with the rovv-headcr. This method of heading sorghums although very uncommon in.the state at the present time holds considerable promise. Where available the regular small-grain header may be used for topping the crop.' Laude and Swanson of Kansas say that two men can handle about I3: acres a day with a header. Their recommendations in this con - nection are as follows: "It is usually advisable to make the reel solid by bolting extra slats to the reel arms. This reduces the number of heads that are thrown put by the reel. The bottom of the reel slats should just clear the sickle bar. If the platform does not have sufficient adjustment it may be necessary to reverse the supporting arms under the platform in </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Mebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 order to raise the cutting bar high enough to handle a tall crop properly." (Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 265.) The combine method.—When the sorghum crop is to be combined, it must be left standing in the field much later in the season than when it ia harvested by other methods. Unless seed drying equipment is available the crop can not be combined until the plants have been killed by frost and it has had sufficient time following freezing to dry thoroughly. This period of field curing after the first killing frost may require from several days to several weeks. The combine method of harvesting sorghums has very definite limita - tions under Nebraska conditions. In the first place, it can be used only with the shorter varieties that are lodge-resistant. It is best adapted to the drier portions of the state where the moisture content of the grain can be reduced to 14 per cent or less while the crop is still standing in the field. If there is much more moisture than this when the grain is stored, heating and spoilage are almost certain to result. Recommendations made in connection with setting the reel for a header are likewise applicable to the use of the combine. Setting the threshing machine oi combine to avoid cracking.—Many farmers who are inexperienced in the threshing or combining of sorghums have difficulty because of cracking much of the seed, particularly when it is rather dry. The amount of cracking can be minimized by reducing the speed of the cylinder and removing some of the teeth in the concaves. Storing Sorghum Grain Difficulties with heating and spoilage of sorghum grain in storage are common. Such storage problems arc usually traceable directly to high moisture content in the grain at time of threshing. Conditions at time of harvest play a very important part in the quality of grain secured and hence in the keeping qualities. Moisture content of the grain as the crop stands in the field may be raised several per cent by fall rains and high humidity. Therefore, threshing or combining should be done only follow - ing a period of several days of dry weather. A moisture content of 14 per cent or less in the grain at time of storage should be satisfactory. If the moisture content is higher than this, it may be necessary to move the grain in order to prevent heating and possible molding. Moisture contents which may not be too high to cause spoilage under winter conditions may prove to be too high when the weather turns warm the following spring. Methods for minimizing danger of spoilage in storage are: (1) grow short-season varieties that will mature properly before frost; (2) avoid cracking the grain in threshing, as it has been definitely proved that grain with a high percentage of cracked kernels will spoil much more readily than whole grain with an equal moisture content, but with few cracked kernels; (3) avoid getting stalk material into the grain, as this normally carries a relatively high water content, and (4) watch the grain carefully after it is put in the bin and if necessary move it as an aid to drying. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Grain and Forage Sorghums UTILIZATION Various experiments have been conducted at the Nebraska Experiment Station and elsewhere relative to the feeding value- of sorghum roughage and grain. A complete review of this work cannot be attempted in this bulletin. ¦¦;.'..' Generally speaking sorghum silage or fodder is considered about 90 to 95 per cent as valuable, pound for pound, as that of corn. This slight disadvantage in feeding' value is far more than offset by the greater yields. Like corn, sorghum silage and fodder are deficient in protein and minerals and must be properly supplemented. Grain of the grain sorghum varieties corresponds rather closely to shelled corn in feeding qualities. It is generally considered 90 to 95 per cent as valuable as corn for most classes of livestock. Because of the small size and hardness of the grain much of it is passed undigested when fed whole. the sorghum grain should be coarsely ground for all livestock, except sheep, chickens, and hogs when self - fed. Grain of the sorgo varieties that is brown or red in color and rela - tively unpalatable is regarded as having 70 per cent of the feed value of corn. The white seed of Atlas, however, is equal to grain of the grain sorghum varieties in feeding value. SORGHUM ROTATIONS For years it has been the common opinion among many farmers that sorghum is "hard" on the land. It is true that yields of crops following sorghum are usually somewhat lower than those obtained following corn. The principal reason for this is greater soil moisture depletion. Since sorghum yields more tonnage than most crops, and commonly continues growth much later into the fall, it takes more water out of the soil and hence leaves less for the succeeding crop. The effect in a year of inade - quate soil moisture is obvious. ¦.-,..' However, depletion of soil moisture is not the only adverse effect of sorghum on the soil. It has been noted that the yields of following crops are lowered even on irrigated land. The explanation for this is that there is a temporary tie-up of available nitrates in the soil. This is fairly comparable to the effect of putting too much straw on land. The effect can be overcome by adding nitrates to the soil in the form of manure or by growing legume crops. ¦, Still another adverse effect of sorghum on land often experienced by farmers is that it leaves the soil hard and "lumpy" and hence hard to work down into a satisfactory seedbed. Plowing or listing in the fall to facilitate the action of alternate freezing and thawing will help to alleviate this condition. Incorporation of organic matter will also aid in the tilth o£ the soil. At least part of the adverse effects of sorghum on the land are not so serious when the entire farm management program is considered. Sor - ghum usually means livestock farming. Manure is then available to spread on the land, which aids materially in offsetting these unfavorable soil effects </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 316 Rotations with sorghum have not been fully worked out experimentally. However, based on observations, a few suggested practices in growing sorghum follow. Nebraska farmers have had considerable difficulty with corn "burning" following a legume crop. The reason for this is that the nitrate content has been built up to a point where it is too high in com - parison with available moisture. Since sorghum is relatively drouth resistant, and since it tends to "tie-up" available nitrates, it offers one of the best possibilities as a crop to follow alfalfa or sweet clover. One of the things to avoid in rotations is the sowing of winter wheat on land which has been in sorghum during the same year. Since wheat requires considerable quantities of nitrates earlier in the season than any other crop, it suffers the most from the shortage of nitrates. Spring planted small grains yield better than winter wheat following sorghums, but crops which make most of their growth still later in the season do relatively better. Corn or sorghum following sorghum ordinarily does relatively well. In those parts of the state where land is summer-fallowed, a good three year rotation would be summer fallow, wheat, sorghum, and back to summer fallow. LIVESTOCK POISONING All sorghums are capable of causing the death of livestock when pas - tured under certain conditions of growth. When the plants are stunted, wilted, or frosted, they may contain sufficient prussic (hydrocyanic) acid to cause death when eaten by the animal. Grain sorghum and sorgo are both much more dangerous than Sudan grass, which ordinarily causes little trouble. Under no conditions should livestock be pastured on grain sorghum or sorgo except in the winter after the plants have been killed and are completely cured. So far as is known, there is no danger of poisoning from feeding the grain or heads, and there appears to be little or no danger from feeding well made silage or well cured hay. fodder, or stover of any of the sorghums. (ISM) </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>