<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Effect of Cultural Methods and Maturity Upon the Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes</title>
               <date value="1929-12">1929-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 45 Effect of Cultural Methods and Maturity Upon the Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes H. O. WERNER Department of Horticulture Lincoln, Nebraska December, 1929 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS SUMMARY 3 INTRODUCTION 5 THE SEED POTATO PROBLEM IN EASTERN NEBRASKA 5 HISTORICAL REVIEW 5 Relation of cultural conditions to seed value 6 Relation of maturity or immaturity to seed value 7 EXPERIMENTAL METHODS 9 EFFECTS OF SEASON OF GROWTH AND CULTURAL METHODS ON CURRENT CROP , 11 Rate of plant emergence 11 Growth rate of plants 1 12 Time of vine maturity... 13 Yield of tubers 13 Composition of tubers.... 15 Spindle-tuber prevalence in relation to yield and grade 15 EFFECT OF SEASON OF GROWTH AND CULTURAL METHODS UPON SEED VALUE OF POTATOES AS SHOWN BY THE SUCCEEDING CROP '. 18 Seed potatoes produced at Lincoln 19 Seed stocks infected with spindle-tuber. 21 Plantin&lt;y-time effect 22 Harvest-time effect.... 22 Effect of length and season of the crop period 24 Effect of straw mulching 26 Effect of irrigation !..... 28 Relation of cultural practices to spindle-tuber 29 Effect of cultural practices on grade of tubers: 32 Healthy seed stocks produced in isolated plats : 34 Effect of time of planting 34. Effect of culture and caging with insect proof cages 35 Effect of soil nitrates... 38 Accumulative effect of cultural conditions upon healthy seed potatoes ; : 38 Seed potatoes grown at Union with varied culture 40 Accumulative effect of culture and season upon a line of seed infected with spindle-tuber 40 Effect upon healthy seed stock 43 DISCUSSION : &#132;... 43 BIBLIOGRAPHY 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY Seed potatoes of the Early Ohio and Irish Cobbler varieties were produced and tested at Lincoln thruout a period of 7 years under a variety of conditions. Studies were made of time-of-planting and time-of-harvesting, cultivation and straw mulching, irrigation and no irrigation, and growing of plants under insect-proof cages and in the open as well as in isolated and non-isolated plats and rogued plats. The spindle-tuber content varied from practically nothing in some stocks to a high percentage in others. Early planting, straw mulching, and irrigation were all practically certain to increase the current crop yield. During practically any season and with any cultural system, planting in April would permit at least 75 per cent of the crop to be harvested by the middle of August. Spindle-tuber was less apparent in the straw-mulched than in the cultivated plats. Late planting — that is, in late May and June — resulted in such a greatly reduced yield as to render such practice impractical under eastern Nebraska conditions. The yield from late planting was greater with a straw mulch than with ordinary culture. A few data are supplied concerning the composition of potatoes grown under the different conditions. When spindle-tuber was present in the Lincoln plats to the extent of 5 per cent or less, the increase of .the disease varied in the different lots according to the culture. The disease content increased more &gt;n cultivated than in straw-mulched stocks and more in early than in late plantings. .^ When seed lines infected with spindle-tuber were planted in com - parative plats, straw-mulched stocks were more productive than culti - vated stocks, and late-planted or early-harvested stocks were superior to early-planted or late-harvested lines respectively. Late planting produced seed superior to that of approximately the same maturity but secured by early harvesting. Planting and harvesting dates af - fected the seed more when grown with cultivation than when straw mulched. Irrigation was a negligible factor in these experiments in - sofar as seed-potato productivity was concerned. Seed stocks that had "run out" at Lincoln due to spindle-tuber infection were not re - juvenated by straw mulching. When healthy seed stocks were grown in isolated places or main - tained in a healthy condition by growing parent plants under insect - proof cages, the yield differences were much less than when spindle - tuber was present. Late-planted was somewhat more productive than early-planted stock and straw-mulched stock was slightly superior to cultivated stock. The degree of dormancy of the seed tubers at planting time and the occurrence of tuber production at a favorable or unfavorable climatic period in the trial year were factors which </seg>
            <seg id="p004">influenced yield. The former would continue more or less constant; the latter might vary from year to year. The soil nitrate content did not appear to influence seed-potato productivity. When good seed stock — with less than 1 per cent of spindle-tuber — was planted in eastern Nebraska, its product was satisfactory for use as seed stock. After a second year in eastern Nebraska its seed value was small, owing to spindle-tuber increase. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Effect of Cultural Methods and Maturity Upon the Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes H.' O. WERNER Distinct deterioration or degeneration of seed stocks has for some years been considered the inevitable result of grow - ing seed potatoes in the states located south of, or at a lower altitude than that of, the states producing late potato crops. Until comparatively recently this degeneracy was attributed to the unfavorable effects of environmental conditions upon the tubers. Extensive research during the last ten years has shown that generally the presence and rapid spread of one or more virus diseases is the major or possibly sole cause of this deterioration or "running out" of seed stocks. The spread of these virus diseases is undoubtedly quite distinctly influenced by environmental conditions. An important phase of the seed-stock deterioration problem is the determination of the influence of environmental or cultural conditions and maturity upon healthy seed potatoes. THE SEED-POTATO PROBLEM IN EASTERN NEBRASKA For many years the buying of northern-grown seed potatoes has been an established practice in the early-potato regions located in the eastern, central, and southern parts of Ne - braska, as well as in the other corn-belt states and also in the South. Seed potatoes grown in these regions have almost uniformly been found to be less productive than northern - grown seed stocks. In eastern and southern Nebraska at least, this difference has been apparent after only one year of culture and has increased with each additional year. Seed potatoes as good as northern stocks have been pro - duced under a straw mulch in eastern Nebraska by experi - menters and growers. Occasionally reports are heard that a lot of seed potatoes has been grown in eastern Nebraska by ordinary cultural methods for many years, apparently with - out loss of vigor or yielding capacity. In view of this situation it seemed advisable to investigate this problem to determine whether, and to what extent, en - vironment and maturity as such influence the productivity of seed potatoes and also whether it is feasible to produce satis - factory seed potatoes in the southern and eastern portions of Nebraska. HISTORICAL REVIEW The literature dealing with the effect of environmental conditions upon seed potatoes extends back over a period of many years. Much </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 of it has little value here because of the lack of knowledge of potato diseases at the time the earlier work was conducted. The review will therefore be limited to work which is relatively recent and which has a reasonably direct relation to the special phase of the problem which is considered herewith. RELATION OF CULTURAL CONDITIONS TO SEED VALUE Emerson (1914) reported that the original productivity of seed potatoes secured from the north was maintained at Lincoln when the potatoes were grown under a straw mulch. He also reported the re - juvenation of degenerate stocks by means of straw mulches. It should be noted that practically all of this work was conducted before virus diseases were recognized in this country. Wessels and Hartwell (1927) reported increased yields from straw-mulched as compared with culti - vated stock. In some portions of the country growers have a prejudice against irrigated seed potatoes. A number of workers have given, reports on irrigated versus dry-land seed potatoes. Their reports are not dis - cussed here because all these pieces of work dealt with late potatoes in the main crop-potato districts and none was conducted in the warmer areas, where it is practical to grow potatoes only as an early crop. Parker (1922), Appleman (1924), Rosa (1925), and Salaman (192G) suggested or inferred that droughty conditions have injurious effects upon seed potatoes, but none of them supplied any supporting data. During, the last ten years the author several times has planted lots of seed potatoes that had been grown under as droughty conditions as will permit plants to live and produce tubers, yet the- seed value or productiveness of these lots was apparently unimpaired. Wellenseik (1925) reported that dryness during the last week of tuber growth' stimulated early, vigorous germination of the seed potatoes. Tubers thus produced by him were probably ripened prematurely and conse - quently completed their period of dormancy at an earlier date than did the tubers from plants that did not have their growth checked by drought. Emerson (1914) reported higher yields from seed potatoes produced by planting parent seed pieces at a depth of 7 inches than from those whose seed pieces were planted at a depth of 4 inches and 1 inch. Miiller and Molz (1924) reported that shaded plants produced higher - yielding seed tubers than unshaded plants. They suggest that in such tubers certain substances, especially ferments, remain inactive in the tubers after they are lifted and cause an early growth of vigorous and high-yielding plants. They suggest also that possibly close planting will accomplish the same results as shading. These same authors (1924) reported increased yields from seed stocks produced by plants provided with the least area per plant. Under such conditions relatively small seed tubers undoubtedly were </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes produced. Probably the following season many such tubers were planted Whole or if they were cut into uniform seed pieces there were more eyes per seed piece than were found in the seed pieces from the larger potatoes produced by the plants provided with more space. Consequently yield differences may have been due to seed-tuber size differences and not to any change within the tubers. Wessels and Hartwell (1927) reported that when healthfulness was not affected, seed potatoes produced under growth-limiting conditions, such as too acid a soil, a lack of nutrients, etc., gave the larger yields. They called attention to the possibility that part of this increase may have been due to the smaller size of the tubers produced under un - favorable conditions and the consequent larger number of eyes per seed. piece of any given size. Janssen (1929) reports that infection of mosaic and leafroll occurred to a greater extent in lots of seed potatoes grown on sandy than when grown on clay soils. Seed lots produced on these soils became most heavily infected when given either a complete fertilizer or one lacking potash, while the least infection was in the lots produced with a nitro - gen shortage. In controlled greenhouse experiments he found that altho nitrogen-deficient plants were only one-third the size of high - nitrogen plants, the former were less easily infected and more time was required for their tubers to become infected. By means of care - ful counts they found that aphids increased most rapidly on the potash - deficient plants (evidently because of sugar accumulation in the leaves) and least rapidly on nitrogen-deficient plants (probably because of the tough leaf cuticle). Recent research has shown that seed-potato productivity can be maintained in regions where it is commonly supposed that high pro - ductiveness cannot be maintained. Bushnell (1928) has shown that lots of potatoes have been maintained in Ohio for over 90 years with - out any indication of "degeneracy" of any kind. Brown (1928) has shown that in Connecticut seed potatoes kept free from disease by continual production under insect-proof cages retained their original productivity in a region where degeneracy of seed stocks in open fields is very rapid. In these various studies there seems to be no evidence that cultural methods influence seed stocks when disease is not present, except as they may influence the period of tuber dormancy or the number of eyes per seed piece. RELATION OF MATURITY OR IMMATURITY TO SEED VALUE In Europe immature seed has long been considered superior for seed purposes. Knight is credited (Salaman, 1926, p. 41) with being the first to make an authoritative statement (in 1813) that immature seed was a means of combating degeneration. Among the more or less recent reports is that of Munter (1922) who cites London, Low, Aitkms, Nobis, Ramsay, and Hutchinson as having demonstrated the superiority of immature seed for planting. Concerning his own work </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 he reports that immature seed contained less disease and germinated earlier than mature seed. Botjes in two reports (1923), referring not only to his own work but also to that of Munter, of Molz, and of Hilton, shows that the shortened season in the field provides less op - portunity for virus disease infection and therefore is the prime reason for larger yields from unripe seed. Furthermore, the date of harvest - ing is of less significance than whether infection occurred early or late in the season. This latter idea accounts for some discordant re - sults such as those of Profeit (1923) reporting that in his work, in Scotland time of harvesting had no effect on the amount of leaf roll and mosaic. Schultz and Folsom (1923) and Folsom (1924) showed that in Maine late-harvested potatoes acquired more infection than those harvested early and were consequently less productive. Werner (1924, 1925) showed early caging and early harvesting to be of some value in reducing infection and increasing yields in healthy stocks interplanted in fields heavily infected with spindle-tuber. In 1923, however, infection occurred so early as to render these practices valueless. Edmundson (1922, 1924) did not secure any significant differences in yield by harvesting seed at different dates when using a healthy lot of the Rural New Yorker variety at Greeley, Colorado. However, he stated that really fully mature seed is not produced at Greeley because of early frosts. Butler (1926) reported improved yields and decrease in virus diseases by early harvesting in New Hampshire. Werner (1925) showed that at North Platte, Nebraska, immature seed, whether acquired by early harvesting or late planting, was most productive due to a lower percentage of spindle-tuber in - fection. The degree of infection was in direct proportion to the num - ber of days the parent plants were in the field, but a given number of days in the field late in the season were more effective for the production of disease-free seed than the same number early in the season. Knorr, quoting data secured at Bernburg, Germany, reported (1922) that tubers harvested before" the vines were ripe or later, from plants where tops had been cut while green, produced a higher yield the next year than those that were allowed to remain until the vines ripened naturally. Similar results are reported by Muller and Molz (1924). Stuart ct al. (1927) reported slightly greater yields from mature seed at Norfolk, Virginia, and also at Presque Isle, Maine. On the other hand, immature seed was slightly more productive at Greeley, Colorado, and decidedly more productice at Jerome, Idaho. Since they do not supply information concerning virus-dise.ase prevalence, it is impossible to determine to what extent these results may have been due to disease. Appleman and Miller (1926) analyzed potatoes harvested at dif - ferent stages of maturity. These analyses were made at harvest. time </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes and at the end of the rest period. Their conclusion is: "The data in this paper do not reveal any chemical or physiological basis for the superiority of immature potatoes for seed. The cases reported of im - mature seed giving better, results than mature seed may have been due to a greater freedom from degeneration' diseases in the immature seed." They did not report any data to substantiate the latter con - clusion. Rosa (1928) called attention to the fact that "the more nearly mature potato tubers are when harvested, the shorter is the dormant period, as indicated by more rapid sprouting, when they are cut and planted." He also reported that the primordia of vegetative sprouts develop during the later stages of tuber growth as well as during the dormant period. The relation of seed maturity to yield, therefore, may be influenced by the length and condition of storage before the tubers are planted. Immature seed harvested very early or late presents a greater storage problem than mature seed harvested at the time customary for storing potatoes. There is also considerable variation in the length of the storage period after the rest period has been completed. These two factors, which have not received consideration in studies of im - mature seed, might have decidedly practical significance. On the basis of the experiments reported, disease has been such an important factor that it is impossible to distinguish the effect of im - maturity as such. EXPERIMENTAL METHODS Most of the seed-potato production and comparative trial work was conducted at Lincoln. A small amount of seed stock was produced at Union (about 40 miles directly east of Lincoln) and at Bushnell and Alliance in the dry-land areas in western Nebraska. Culture was varied by growing some lots with and some without straw mulching and also with and without overhead irrigation. Straw mulches were generally applied at about the time the plants were ready to emerge from the soil. ■ The straw covering" was applied so as to pro - vide a uniform mulch about 2 inches deep. From 1921 to 1926 experimental lots of seed potatoes were planted and harvested on different dates at Lincoln. Early Ohio potatoes were used from 1921 to 1925. Irish Cobblers were added in 1925 and used afterwards. Each year good seed stocks were procured from the north or west. Potatoes produced by the various treatments previously enumerated were held in the same storage and were planted in comparative plats the following year. These comparative trial plats were used as a means of determining the seed value of the various lots of seed. Growing conditions in the com - parative trial plats were as uniform as possible for all of the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 lots. As the yield of tubers was sometimes very low with some of the treatments, it was not always possible to plant the desired number of replicated plats with each seed lot. Likewise the size of the tubers varied, thus introducing an - other error in the trials. These exceptions are given due consideration at the proper place in the bulletin. Krantz (1922) and some other workers have shown that the mean representing four single-row plats three or four rods long is practically as dependable as the mean from more plats or larger plats and that when a mean is based on fewer plats the probable error increases rapidly, approximately in line with the theoretical application. The trial plats at Lincoln were always planted during the first two weeks of April. At North Platte the comparative plantings were made the latter part of April and at Scotts - bluff during the early part of June. Furrow irrigation was practiced at the two latter places. Prior to 1923 spindle - tuber was present and infected tubers were recognized as "run out" stock. Beginning with 1923, when it was first recognized as a virus disease, more or less isolation, roguing, and seed selection were used to eliminate it as far as possible from the seed lots planted in the seed-producing plats. Later, to prevent some of the spreading among the lots intended for comparative trials, the cutting knife was disinfected (Goss, 1926). In spite of these precautions spindle-tuber continued to be a more or less serious factor. No other disease was ever a factor of any consequence in the experiments reported in this paper. Altho most of the special terms used were described in a previous paper (Werner, 1925), it will be well to consider them briefly in this bulletin. Spindle-tuber coefficient describes both the relative extent and severity of the disease symptoms of the plant. The spindle - tuber symptoms of each plant are evaluated on the basis of 100 for the most severe type of symptoms and symptoms" of lesser severity evaluated accordingly. The mean coefficient for the lot is the sum of these individual plant values divided by the total number of plants. Tuber type index is used to describe the shape, color, num - ber and depth of eyes, etc. The tubers of ideal type were given a value of 10 and. those of most inferior type 1 or less. Generally values between 6 and 10 represent normal or healthy tubers and all values of 5 or less "spindle tubers." Values of 6 or 7 may indicate mild symptoms of spindle-tuber. Maturity notes were taken at regular intervals in several experiments. They are based on observations, the worker assuming dead vines to be 100 per cent mature. Others were rated accordingly. </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes Pc-jv Ce-A/r Sp/nft/e 7t/6e/-a */ ' S/z&lt;r O/Z3+3 6 7 O 9 /o 451——, . . . . . . . ■ +° • i— 1% W25 " T -*- s . .. 20 - - _ 0 _ /s II I I 1 1 I I IT ■ fer/t/ O/r/o -Co/t/Vatecf * " * Slr*\s Mes/c/xn/ •Jr/sh Cohhfa — Cu/t/Va-tacf © ■» ■* Stray Mu/c/iad Fig. 7. — Showing relation between percentage of small tubers and spindle-tuber content. Data based on 1925 trial lots grown at Lin - coln. Culture and variety are indicated by distinctive signs. SEED POTATOES PRODUCED AT LINCOLN • When studying the yield data from the comparative plats 1 During most of the seasons when the Lincoln work was conducted, spindle - tuber was a factor of considerable consequence. The data procured during the earlier and later years are therefore presented separately, because of the difference in spindle-tuber content. </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 original seed stocks were produced in commercial fields of supposedly good, healthy stock, some of these stocks produced distinctly spindle-tuber plants. The presence of this infection was a serious factor thruout the experiment. The increase in spindle-tuber from year to year was distinctly influenced by the different treatments used in producing the seed po - tatoes. K Planting-time effect. — When considering the potatoes harvested on any one date, the least productive lots the fol - lowing year were generally those planted early, that is, in early April. (See Figs. 8, 9, and 10.) This was especially the case with the cultivated lots and the straw-mulched lots of 1922-23. Frequently, however, the seed stocks raised from mid- June plantings were less productive than the May-planted stocks but even so were still more productive than the April - planted lots. This may have been due to more incomplete development of the buds within the eyes (Rosa, 1928) in the tubers from June plantings. With June planting at Lincoln the tuber production was relatively later than with April or May plantings and the tubers produced were very small Frequently it was impossible, even by planting whole tubers, to have seed pieces from the June lots that weighed as much as the standard seed weight for the April and May lots. Hence, with the June lots, allowance must be made for the slightly smaller seed pieces, the greater number of eyes per seed piece, and the relatively more incomplete development of the buds. Since straw mulching delayed early growth all mulched tubers were more immature than the cultivated tubers with the same seasonal dates. Spindle-tuber was responsible for much of the lower yield of the April lots. It was also responsible for the greater variation in the early years. This phase is discussed more completely on pages 16 and 17. The relative productivity of seed potatoes from different planting dates was influenced by the harvesting date. This aspect is dealt with when consideration is given to the length of time parent plants were in the field. (See pages 24 and 25 ) The low yields secured by late planting the year when the seed is produced, raise the question of the practicability of planting late for seed production. (See Fig. 4.) Harvest-time effect. — When considering potatoes planted on any one date, the lots harvested early were generally the most productive the next year. This condition prevailed practically always with April-planted cultivated stocks It was not so generally true with May and June plantings or with the straw-mulched seed stocks. (See Table 4 and Fig 10.) Early harvesting was less effective in increasing yields </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 Altho with the lot planted April 16 and harvested July 11 there were 87 days between planting and harvesting time, there were only 46 days (Table 5, Column 2) during which 50 per cent or more of the plants were above the ground — counting from the time 50 per cent of the plants emerged (Fig. 1) until harvest. In contrast with this was the lot planted June 13 and harvested September 5, thus occupying the land 84 days but with 50 per cent or more of the plants above ground for 62 days. In most of the season length - groups, the plants of the early-planted lots were above the ground between 7 and 21 days less than the late-planted lots of the group. These circumstances should be kept in mind when studying Table 5. As the length of time the actual seed-producing plants were in the field cannot be definitely stated (individual plant records not having been kept) the time between planting and harvesting is considered the most advisable basis for tabulating results. With both cultivated and straw-mulched stocks the seed from the latest planted lot of each length group generally outyielded that from the earliest planted lot of the same group. The several exceptions, wherein the later-planted lots were low yielding, are based on less reliable data due to the smaller number of plats. Untabulated 1923-1924 data do not reveal such distinct differences or tendencies, especially with the shorter length groups. (See Figs. 8, 9, and 10.) In the groups represent - ing 121 days or more the later-planted cultivated lots were commonly the most productive. Apparently when the number of days in the field was ap - proximately the same, seed stocks planted late and harvested late the previous year were more desirable than those planted early and harvested early. These tendencies were less pro - nounced when seed stocks were practically disease free than when spindle-tuber was present. Effect of straiv mulching. — Thruout the 4 years of the comparative trials, the mulched seed stocks outyielded the cultivated seed stocks in practically every instance. These data summarized in Table 6 are graphically presented in Figs 8, 9, and 10. It will be noted that seed potatoes produced under a straw mulch did not profit as much by either late planting or early harvesting as did cultivated stocks. How - ever, with the lots harvested latest there was somewhat more improvement from straw mulching than with the earliest - harvested lots. Straw mulching was much more beneficial to early-planted seed stocks than to late-planted stocks. Straw - mulched stocks produced a lower percentage of tubers show- ™ g , spindle-tuber symptoms than did the cultivated stocls Mulching seemed to be less favorable for disease spread </seg>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030"/>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 In the season of 1925 all tubers were graded at harvesting time and the No. 1 size "spindle tubers" were weighed sep - arately. The data for these weights are shown graphically in Fig. 14. Spindle-tuber was less severe in the lines of seed used that year, than in those of previous seasons. Cultivated seed stock tended to produce more "spindle tubers" than the mulched-seed stock. April-planted seed stock harvested in October produced more "spindle tubers" than that harvested in August or July. The spindle-tuber percentage from stock planted May 26 was not appreciably altered by time of har - vesting. There was no tangible difference between irrigated and non-irrigated seed .stock. Evidence presented elsewhere (page 16) indicates thae these .estimates of spindle-tuber are relatively low (Fig. 7), probably because many tubers were small due to the disease. In any replicated lot, the higher-yielding sets showed only a low percentage of "spindle tubers." These, together with the other data, suggest that low yields as well as poor tuber type were associated with the presence of spindle-tuber. Effect of cultural practices on grade of tubers. — Late - harvested seed stocks from May plantings generally produced a higher percentage of No. 1 prime tubers than the early - harvested stocks, but in the case of April plantings early - harvested stocks gave the more desired results. There was a greater variation with the Irish Cobbler than the Early Ohio. (Fig. 14.) Thruout all the years the mulched stocks produced a decidedly higher percentage of prime tubers than comparable cultivated stocks, altho in 1925 this difference was less marked. Late-planted stocks were slightly superior in the produc - tion of primes to those planted early. Irrigation of seed stocks apparently had even less effect than the other cultural practices upon tuber grade the following year. The correlation between the percentage of "knobby" and "growth cracked" Early Ohio tubers and cultural practices used in seed production is graphically shown in Fig. 14. The lower percentage of No. 1-size "spindle tubers" in these same lots suggests that their plants were better able to withstand the unfavorable summer weather. (Note yields for these lots in Figs. 8, 9, and 10.) This permitted them to renew growth later in the season with consequent production of knobby tubers, whereas plants with considerable spindle - tuber never survived the summer and of course produced fewer or no second-growth tubers. The Early Ohio check lots, planted with new seed from Minnesota, produced more knobby and cracked potatoes than any of the Lincoln-grown </seg>
            <seg id="p033"/>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 The higher percentage of small tubers in cultivated and early - planted stocks may have been due to the tubers having started on and emerged from their rest period at an earlier date and consequently having lost some degree of apical dominance, with a consequent heavier set of tubers which re - mained small due to moisture shortage. Differences in apical dominance at the time of planting the trial plats and spindle - observed" S6ed St0CkS probably ex P lain the differences t • f l e^ t u?, 8eed » tocks Produced in isolated plats.— In 1926 irisn Cobbler potatoes from western Nebraska were planted 1SO i a i ed M e i d A t Lin ??! n at mon thly intervals, from the middle of April to the middle of July, and all were harvested in October In April, 1927, twelve 40-hill, single-row plats from each lot were planted (magic square distribution) on the same farm. At this time the early-planted lots showed the most sprout growth. Minnesota-grown Cobblers were in - serted as checks in every tenth plat. Effect of time of planting.— The early-planted lots showed the earliest signs of maturity, followed in regular order by the lots from the succeeding dates. (Table 8.) 4-u 4.V. A P nl " and May-planted stocks were less productive than the later-planted ones. (Table 9.) The percentage of tl?- J tubers increased with each succeedingly later planted +£ .»•£ dlfferei &gt; c e 1&amp; Probably of more significance than the differences in total yield. June- and July-planted stocks were as productive as the checks. These differences in favor of the earlier-planted stocks are believed to be due to their earlier arrival at the tuber-pro - duction stage because of their greater advancement at plant - ing time in 1927. Because of the tubers from the early-planted seed lines being; less dormant at planting time, apical dominance was less pronounced (Appleman, 1924) and consequently more stems were produced per seed-piece with a consequent reduc - tion in the size of the individual tubers. In 1927 very hot weather prevailed during the last week n June and early July. Plants from the early-planted seed lots suffered severely and their tubers did not develop to full size. The less-advanced, later-planted stocks survived the period and profited by the cooler weather in late July This would also aid in accounting for the differences in percent - fJniY °- k 8 !* 6 * *,!? be / S - If supposition is correct it will be seen that results from year to year are likely to vary, because the time, duration, and severity of adverse weather conditions will vary from year to year. Spindle-tuber was probably present but to the extent of </seg>
            <seg id="p035"/>
            <seg id="p036"/>
            <seg id="p037"/>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 caged, mulched lots having produced 3.2 per cent (irrigated stock) and 4.9 per cent (non-irrigated stock) of No. 1 size spindle tubers as compared with 8.2 per cent and 11 per cent respectively from the uncaged, cultivated stocks (Fig 15). Likewise in the case of the caged cultivated lots the irrigated stock produced one per cent of No. 1 size (doubtful) spindle tubers" and the non-irrigated produced no "spindle tubers, whereas the uncaged lots produced respectively 8 2 per cent and 11 per cent of "spindle tubers" as previously noted. This experiment was repeated in 1925-26. As the results were practically the same as in 1924-25, no further report will be made. ■ With these relatively healthy stocks it appears that cultural conditions were minor factors, if factors at all, in directly affecting seed quality of tubers produced. Effect of soil nitrates, — Data on hand show that in 1926 the soil nitrate content in the Lincoln plats was higher than usual and that it generally decreased from late May to the end of the season. Both mulching with straw and irrigation reduced the nitrate content with regularity, the lowest con - tent m September being in the irrigated mulched soil. 3 These same treatments increased the soil moisture content and de - creased the soil temperature. The addition of nitrate of soda at the rate of 600 pounds per acre increased the nitrate con - tent of the cultivated and straw-mulched soils. Nitrate addi - tion increased the nitrate content of straw-mulched soils to about that of the untreated cultivated soils. In the 1927 comparative plats, there was no evident cor - relation between soil nitrate content the previous year and the productivity of the seed stock thus produced. (Table 11 ) In this series of plats early harvesting seemed to be the only treatment that was associated with increased seed produc - tivity. There was no spindle-tubef in evidence in any of the lots in the comparative plats. Accumulative effect of cultural conditions upon healthy seed potatoes.— In the spring of 1926 seed pieces from 16 healthy Irish Cobbler tubers were planted by groups of three. One of each of these three hills was cultivated, one. was straw mulched, and one was straw mulched and covered with an insect-proof cage. At Lincoln these groups of three plants from each tuber were planted close together in a corn field and these were isolated from the plants growing from other a^a?,- y P 1 ?"* 11^ the groups 50 feet apart in a corn field. At Alliance the individual hills were also isolated in a corn held. of n d t e^Sr a on O o^y WeI ' e ~ &lt;ta U " der th * dirMti ° n of Pr ° f - J - &amp; Ru».el </seg>
            <seg id="p039"/>
            <seg id="p040"/>
            <seg id="p041"/>
            <seg id="p042"/>
            <seg id="p043">Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes prime tubers they could hardly be considered desirable. They would undoubtedly have been very unsatisfactory had they been carried over for a third year. Apparently a lot of seed which contains only a small per - centage of spindle-tuber may be used fairly advantageously after one year at Union. Roguing is not an adequate means of maintaining such a lot of seed for more than one year. Effect upon healthy seed stock. — In 1925, Wyoming - grown Irish Cobblers were planted in isolated plats at Union, Lincoln, and Bushnell under the conditions specified in Table 14. When planted at North Platte for comparative trials in 1926 these stocks actually yielded more than either the check from seed from the original Wyoming source, or the western Nebraska-grown lots. August-harvested stocks were some - what more productive than the October stocks, the early- August-planted lot was slightly superior to the April-planted lot, and the straw-mulched seed was slightly superior to culti - vated stocks. The percentage of spindle-tuber was very low but increased as productivity decreased. It was also most prevalent in the stocks that had been in the field the longest time the pre - vious year. The spindle-tuber content increased less at Union than at Lincoln or Bushnell, in fact was no greater than in the original Wyoming stock. DISCUSSION Good seed potatoes can be produced in eastern Nebraska if disease-free seed stock is used and seed fields are isolated from other potato fields or from plants that might serve as sources of infection. Such seed stocks should remain pro - ductive for a considerable length of time. Culture, time of planting, etc., will cause variation in the maturity of seed potatoes, which influences the period of dormancy. This in turn alters the degree of apical dominance manifested by seed tubers at planting time — thus affecting the number of stems and tubers per plant. The degree of dormancy also affects the emergence rate and probably the time of tuber setting. These environmental effects are evident only in the next crop and at the present time there is no evidence indi - cating that cultural conditions exert a permanent change in healthy potato-seed stocks. When spindle-tuber is present, however, cultural conditions are of more far-reaching im - portance. Production of seed potatoes for one year in isolated, rogued seed plats is probably a safe procedure in eastern Ne - braska if seed stocks free from spindle-tuber are used. Whether it will be practical to grow such seed will depend upon the yield of seed potatoes secur.ed and also the annual price fluctuations. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Expt. Station Research Bulletin 45 bibliography Appleman, C. O. 1924. Potato sprouts as an index of seed value. Maryland Act Exp. Sta. Bui. 265. *" and E. V. Miller 1926. A chemical and physiological study of maturity in pota - toes. Jour. Agr. Research, Vol. 33, No. 6, pp. 569-577. Botjes, J. O. 1923. Die verwendung unreifer kartoffeln als saatgut. Deut Landw. Presse, 50:118-119. 1923. Experiments regarding the use of immature seed seen at Oostavold during conference. Report of International Con - ference of Phytopathology and Economic Entomology, Hol - land, pp. 143-147. Brown, B. A. 1928. Report of the director for 1927. Conn. (Storrs) Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 149. ■ Bushnell, John 1923. Effect of temperature on the potato plant. Amer. Soc. Hort. Sci. Proc, p. 307. 1928. Do potato varieties degenerate in warm climates? Jour. Heredity, Vol. 19, No. 3. Butler, O. 1926. Field crops experiments in New Hampshire in 1925 X H Exp. Sta. Bui. 221, pp. 13-19. ' Clark, Charles F. 1921. Development of tubers in the potato. U. S. Dept. Agr. -tJ Ul. I) J) n ■ Edmundson, W. C. 1922. Report of experiments at Colorado Potato Experiment Station. Nebr. Potato Impr. Assoc., 4th Ann. Rpt.. pp. 40-44. 1924. Work of the Colorado Potato Experiment Station. Xebr. Potato Impr. Assoc, Gth Ann. Rpt., pp. 49-56 Elmer, O. H. 1922. Mosaic cross-inoculation and insect transmission studies Science, Vol. 56, No. 1448, pp. 370-372. Emerson, R. A. 19 xt 4 V H ? me mulched vs. northern seed potatoes for eastern Nebraska. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 146. Folsom, Donald 1924. The importance and natural spread of potato degenera - tion diseases. Maine Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 316 Goss, R. W. 1926. Transmission of potato spindle-tuber disease bv cutting ?, n \ ve f^ and seed "Piece contact. Phytopathology (Abstracts), Vol. 16, p. 6. Janssen, J. j. 1929. Invloed der bemesting op de gezondheid van de aardappel. (Institute voor phytopathologie, Laboratorium voor bycol - ogie en aardappelonderzoek mededeeling 43.) "Tijdschrift over plantenziekten," 35e Jaargang, 1929. pp. 119-151. 9, b Ma y e i, mfpp" JShg"**™* te ™»™&gt; 25 ' X °' </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes Knorr, P. 1922. Versuchsergebnisse auf dem gesamtgebiete des kartof - felbaues im jahre 1919 und 1920. Arb. Forschungsinst. Kartoffelbau, Heftc 5 und 6. Berlin. Krantz, Fred A. 1922. A preliminary study of field plot technic in potato yield tests. Potato Assoc. Amer. Proc, p. 42. Mttller, H. C, and Molz, E. 1924. Effects of stimulation and depression on productivity in potato culture. (Title translated.) Deut. Landw. Presse, 51, No. 9, p. 91. Mttnter, R. 1922. Unreife oder reife kartoffeln als saatgut. (Immature or mature potatoes for seed.) Deut. Landw. Presse, 49:9-10. Parker, W. H. 1922. Potatoes — maturity and yield trials. Jour. Natl. Inst. Agr. Bot., Vol. 1, No. 5, p. 19. Profeit, W. J., and Findlay, W. M. 1923. Some factors affecting the value of potatoes for seed purposes. Scot. Jour. Agr., Vol. 6, No. 1, pp. 54-G3. Rosa, J. T. 1925. Potato production in California. Cal. Agr. Exp. Sta. Cir. 287, p. 15. 1928. Relation of tuber maturity and of storage factors to potato dormancy. Hilgardia, Vol. 3, No. 4, pp. 100-124. Salaman, Radcliffe N. 1926. Potato varieties. Cambridge University Press. (The Macmillan Company, American representatives.) Schultz, E. S., and Folsom, Donald ' 1923. Transmission, variation, and control of certain degenera - tion diseases of Irish potatoes. Jour. Agr. Research, Vol. 25, No. 2, pp. 43-117. Stuart, Wm., Edmundson, W. C, Lombard, P. M., and Dewey, G. W. 1927. Source, character, and treatment of potato sets. U. S. Dept. of Agr. Tech. Bui. No. 5. Wellenseik, S. J. 1925. Potato storage and blind tubers. (Title and article trans - lated by W. A. McCubbin.) Original article: Die kartoffel. No. 16. Translation in Potato News Bui. 2, No. 10, p. 396. Werner, H. O. 1924. Spindle-tubei, the cause of "run out" potatoes. 6th Ann. Rpt. Nebr. Potato Impr. Assoc, pp. 57-80. 1924. Relation of environment to spindle-tuber symptoms. Po - tato Assoc. Amer. Proc, pp. 102-106. 1925, a. The spindle-tuber disease, one cause of "run out" seed potatoes. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 207. 1925, b. Relation of environmental factors to productiveness of seed potatoes. Potato Assoc. Amer. Proc, pp. 10-22. Paper No. 20, Jour. Series, Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Wessel, Philip H., and Hartwell, Burt L. 1927. Viability and composition of "seed" potatoes as affected by climatic conditions and by various other factors. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 19, No. 9, p. 761, p. 780. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>