<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0075.0025</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>HATCHING TURKEY EGGS</title>
               <date value="1932-04">1932-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">ATCHING TURKEY EGGS * *_____ &lt; -"S ' _■:____&amp;! JJ_ ________B__________^_____l ____»- :^_H_H__f I Ull K__&gt; l KitJ ■»»' \ ill ■Pf^&gt;;&gt; &gt; v • TT^_^^mM_________\ ________________H r ___________P&amp;^ ___________ _&lt;r j?- . IP k_L '*'• &gt; , V U '•T* ' v ii Tamil ■&amp;*____,' &gt;l V V, &lt; _L*__£a9 _t__f T'T^fc, *■* V </seg>
            <seg id="p002">summary of incubation essentials 1. Temperature — Cabinet incubators — 99.75° to 100° F. Sectional or non-forced-draft incubators — 102° F. at top of egg first week; 102.5° second and third weeks; 1(1°' fourth week. ] 03 ■&gt; 2. Humidity — 60 per cent relative — range 40 —70 per cent. 3. Ventilation — requirements increase as in - cubation progresses. 4. Turning — twice daily from second to twenty-fourth day. Gentle rotation of the egg is essential. . . </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hatching: Turkey Eggs F. E. MUSSEHL Department of Poultry Husbandry The use of incubators instead of hens m hatching poults is gaining favor. There are two advantages for the former method; first, a hen will lay more eggs during the breeding season if she is not permitted to "go broody"; second, the use ot incubators is the first step m the very essential sanitation program. In general, the requirements are the same as those tor hen eggs. The fact that turkey eggs can be hatched successfully under chicken hens and that hen eggs can be hatched with turkey hens indicates clearly that the require - ments for hatching chicken and turkey eggs are much the same, except for the difference m the incubation period, which is twenty-eight days. Four conditions must be provided by the incubator and ,the operator m order to get satisfactory hatches. These con - ditions are proper temperature, proper humidity, ventilation, and the turning of the eggs. temperature requirements ™r? at( &amp; ing any ccc is fundamentally a nutritional problem. When the egg is laid it contains the proteins, minerals, fats, and vitamins essential for the nutrition of the embryo Be - sides these, eggs, m common with most other food materials, contain enzymes which, under certain conditions, break down the nutrient material m the egg and make it available for the embryo. Enzyme action is retarded at low temperatures and accelerated as temperatures increase. The optimum tem - perature condition for embryonic development must be close to 100° F., since eggs which are kept m cabinets maintained at that mean temperature usually hatch at about the same time as do eggs which are incubated under hens. In incubators heated by radiation from water pipes a differ - ence of from five to six degrees is often observed between tem - £^ tv . res of the e BS chamber at the top and bottom of the egg. With incubators of this type best results are obtained when ,V&gt;oo x pe , r ,? ture at the to P of the e SS is maintained at from 102 to 103° F., which insures an average of the tem - peratures at the top and bottom of the eggs of about 100° F or slightly below. When the optimum temperature has been provided, along with the proper balance of humidity and ventilation, the hatch should be well finished at the end of the twenty-eighth day. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 269 humidity Moisture is as essential to. the embryo as it is for the hatched poult. The egg is about 66 per cent moisture at the time it is laid, and if this supply is conserved there is suffi - cient for normal development of the embryo. Some of the moisture is lost during incubation, the amount being governed by the relative humidity of the egg chamber. Relative humidity is the ratio of water vapor actually con - tained m a given unit of air to the amount that it would cmu - tain at the observed temperature if the air taere completely saturated. The relative humidity of an environment is de - termined by noting the depression produced on a ther - mometer, the bulb of which is covered with a piece of cloth saturated with distilled water. In order that the moisture-holding capacity of the air may be accurately registered on the wet-bulb thermometer, the air must be m rapid motion over the wet bulb, or, what amounts to the same thing, the thermometer must be revolved rapidly m the egg chamber. The extent of the depression produced, as compared with the dry-bulb reading, can readily be translated into relative humidity by the use of Table 1. Table 1. — Relative humidity at dry-bulb temperature 100° F., pressure 29.0 inches D 2" w^'Jr, 0 De P res - R«latjye Depres- Relative Depres- Relative aion humidity sion humidity | aion humidity sion humidity K . Ptr _fS^ , no Percent Percent Percent 5° 83 12° 62 19° 44 26° *&gt;9 6° 80 13° 59 20° 42 27° 27 I' 77 14° 57 21» 40 28° 25 8* 74 15° 54 22° 37 29° 23 ___' 71 16° 52 23° . 35 30° 21 10° 68 17° 49 24° 33 31° 19 11° 65 18° 47 25° 31 32° 18 The optimum humidity for incubation of hen eggs is taken by Romanoff » to be about 60 per cent relative. This investi - gator states also that "Whether or not this humidity should be uniform throughout the incubation period has not been adequately determined." When a relative humidity of 60 per cent was maintained, however, Romanoff observed that the daily weight loss m hen eggs was quite uniform, with a slight increase toward the end of the incubation period. The weight losses of turkey eggs incubated by chicken hens and m several types of incubators have been observed Co'r^n^ Biophysics ot the Developing Hen'a E„. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Hatching Turkey Eggs 5 at this station. For the first observation, carefully selected eggs of normal shape and shell texture were weighed every four days until the twenty-fourth day. During this period the hen-incubated eggs lost 12.15 per cent of the original weight, while the eggs artificially incubated m a sectional machine with a water pan under the egg tray lost 13.77 per cent. Eighty-nine per cent of the fertile hen-incubated eggs hatched and the poults were all alive, and vigorous at the end of three weeks. They were artificially brooded. Sixty-seven per cent of the fertile eggs m the incubator group hatched, and the poults likewise appeared to be normal, though three poults had died at the end of three weeks. This observation indicates that the weight loss must have been optimum or nearly so m the hen-incubated lot. The weight loss for 100 normal eggs for each of six four-day periods is given m Table 2. The eggs averaged 79.5 grams (2.8 ounces) each at the time incubation started. Table 2.— Weight loss of 100 fertile eggs lst-4th sth-Bth 9th-12th I 13th-16th 17th-20th 21 B t-24th day day . day day day day Ounces Ounces Ounces Ounces Ounces Ounces Hen hatched.. 4.39 5.57 6.00 6*21 6.14 6.86 Sectional incubator with moisture pan under egg tray 5.50 6.78 6.00 6.00 6.68 7.70 The eggs used for the observation reported m Table 2 were weighed individually. A considerable variation m the weight losses of eggs which appeared to hatch equally well was observed. This variation ranged from nine to twenty-one per cent of the original egg weight. It seemed that poults hatching from eggs which experienced a weight loss near the average of the group might have an advantage which would be reflected m a more rapid growth rate. To check this hypothesis 150 normal turkey eggs all within the weight limits of 80 to 90 grams were selected and incubated m a cabinet incubator with excellent mechanical equipment for stirring up the air so that temperature and humidity were the same m all parts of the cabinet. The eggs were numbered and weighed individually at the beginning of the observation, and on the eighth, sixteenth, and twenty-fourth days of in - cubation. The average weight loss of 115 fertile eggs was 14.39 per cent. On the twenty-fourth day each fertile egg </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 269 was put into a wire pedigree basket, and the identity of the poult was established at hatching time with a sealed wing band. The poults were all brooded for the first four weeks m a specially built battery brooder, each unit of which was 3xlo feet m size with a sun porch of the same dimensions. From the beginning of the fifth until the end of the eighth week the poults were all brooded m one 12x16 foot brooder house with the range of a' gravel yard for exercise. There was no observable difference m the growth rate of the poults, thus indicating an adaptability to rather wide extremes of weight loss without a serious retardation of the growth im - pulse during the first eight weeks. Since the hen-incubated turkey eggs referred to m Table 2 hatched well and pro - duced strong poults, the environment which will result m a weight loss of from 12 to 13 per cent from the first to the twenty-fourth day of incubation may be considered optimum. ventilation No investigator has made a detailed study of the ventilation requirements for the optimum incubation of turkey eggs, but rather thorough studies have been made of the influence of variations m this condition on the growth of the chicken embryo. 2 If the hypothesis that turkey and chicken embryos have essentially the same, requirements for optimum develop - ment is accepted, it is possible to outline a satisfactory ventila - tion policy for the incubation of turkey eggs. Lamson and Edmond have shown that with chicken eggs, hatchability is not reduced until the carbon-dioxide level of the environment is raised above 50 parts m 10,000 of air or 0.5 per cent. Atwood and Weakley have observed that car - bon-dioxide production increases as the embryo develops. To maintain a satisfactory carbon-dioxide dilution, the air move - ment through the incubator should therefore be greater dur - ing the latter part of the hatch than during the first part. It is doubtful whether any of the standard incubators pro - vide less than the minimum amount of air movement for the first two weeks, but under certain conditions incubators with non-mechanical ventilation devices may operate near the marginal line of ventilating efficiency for the latter part of the hatch. The developing embryo is fortunately able to adapt itself to rather wide extremes with respect to ventila - tion, and most incubators can be adjusted to provide at least 'Atwood. H., and Weakley, C. E. Jr. West Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin No. 185. 1924. Lamson, G. H. Jr., and Edmond, H. D. (Storrs) Connecticut Agricultural Ex - periment Station Bulletin No. 76. pp. 219-258. 1914. Romanoff, A. L. Journal of Morphology and Physiology, 50:517-525. 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">; ' . Hatching Turkey Eggs 7 the minimal requirements. For incubators that are likely to be deficient m provision for ventilation, airing the eggs thoroughly at least once a day is recommended. The eggs should remain outside the egg chamber until they feel cool when placed m contact with the eyelid. Ventilation adjustments must be considered m connection with humidity. Rapid movement of air low m humidity will cause too great a loss of moisture from the egg. Weighing the eggs at definite periods and inspecting the size of the air cell will help m developing the proper ventilation policy for any particular incubator. The data m Table 2, showing the weight loss of hen-incubated eggs which produced poults of excellent vigor, may be taken as a guide. turning the eggs Turning turkey eggs during incubation is recommended for several reasons. A smooth movement of the egg contents stimulates cell activity and probably makes it easier for the embryo to assimilate nutritive material. Turning the eggs also prevents the embryo from drying and sticking to the shell membrane. Eggs may be turned by hand or with the turning devices that now constitute a part of modern incubator equipment. The ideal turning device rotates the egg gently without shock or jar. Turning twice a day, m the morning and evening, is recommended. Turning should stop on the twenty-fourth day of incubation. [BMI </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>