<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>CONTRACT FEEDING of LIVESTOCK</title>
               <date value="1932-07">1932-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">CONTRACT PEEPING of LIVESTOCK -J - ' ..jBEil/JBsisA- _#"*£UnB____ir^ lll 'w_K_-_-_-^_^_-_-__H_-l ir-i i§2§iii ittl^^ H_^l_^ay.^n_P - )■ i Cl^.i i y_P?P-Ka-P-iA--B&gt;^--- W__T__M -aa\^__rn___^l_T_\___W__^_m__ r ~ l___5H»r^ M S^___Z * J_B__^*&amp;^^ *^^E|^&amp;!4. -4,r- '^^jiS^- f^&lt;^jF^ :^ y,^^]!_fj^^ i i 'y K_nn_H N RSin?lffl_f! \\_\n____wu K^W^jHP-i j?*f* _w\\\___\\\\\\\\\r*wL^^^J»"- iMJpipP^»^P ET^^S^E* J™p5i^ &gt;■ L --crt ■ _■-__-_! -W/-T"* ' T'* - m'p^m&gt;? TB^Ammi aY l^fl _-_■_■ K£^^?W-H__B ! _:i_.S" * &amp;&amp;.r» mir *&amp;^^Z/e&amp;^''zZ i ii^^^^^F _B_t'| &lt;X; 'P- 1 't^^B^' ■-._■- fc - ' j , ■■■fay, jPMrllfrr.-J'-fcfiiJ^ |r _\w*w_\mWi __**£ _h_&gt;* i *-r___¥*--T j h4^«R;.~k . " iy EE^a -. s-LT^l ILL_m_-_I __f 2 9-L^^k -L-ki . ,. mj£ Bfe_^^_^9ll_l &lt;^__M_____m_________\\_Wtt___mL "&lt;■ «__?&lt;_ir"S«W_i^B_3l_Rf^__iEV_^^_rl^_^W_^^ffiWSi^_! _H« </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Abnormal financial conditions existent throughout the nation during recent months have caused some livestock feed - era and growers to enter into contracts whereby the feeding enterprise was carried .on as a joint venture. Contract feed - ing ia largely a result of a severe shortage of livestock credits brought on by falling prices and wide market fluctuations. Thia bulletin U presented, not with the thought of promoting or discouraging contract feeding. Neither is it the thought to discuss the merits of buying and selling direct on the 5 market. It is the object of tbis bulletin, however, to present data that will aid those interested in contract feeding and answer numerous inquiries regarding it. It is also the aim of this bulletin to show the cost, involved in cattle and lamb feed - ing operations. TABLE OF contents Page Introduction „ When and Where Began t An Equitable Contract .„"„„„„"„„ 4 How Growers and Feeders Meet K Who Should Contract and When 5 Shrink ZZZZZZZ 7 Death Loss g Overhead Costs ii Bonus for Good Feeding ' 19 Livestock ii Feedlots ii Cattle 1J Quality 1 o Age z::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::;;:i4 Daily ration and feed requirements 15 Feed cost of gain for steers .... 7.„„!!„!„" 16 Length of feeding period ..".'.'.'.".'."."" 20 Heifers vs. steers '"" 21 Cost of gains for heifers ....ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZAZZZ 21 Effect of sex upon length of feeding period """ 21 Sheep Quality 23 Age and sex. —...„.„„„„;_„!!„!!„ 23 Cost of producing 100 pounds of gain on lambs "!"!„"„ 23 Length of feeding period " 23 Pork Credit from Feeding 26 Total Costs ..„ ZZZ 26 Contracts .....;.."_„!„„!„„„!„!„ 27 Types of Contracts , ...!....„"...!."""".!! 27 The gain-basis plan 28 The gain-at-market-price feeding contract 31 The investment-basis plan 32 The straight inventory contract ,. 34 The custom feeding plan _ 35 Feeds — Most Common Feeds and Types of Feeding. .".. 36 Feeds for Cattle. 36 Feeds for Sheep ........." 39 Experimental Data on Gains Made by Steers 43 Literature Cited " 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Contract Feeding of Livestock It. R. THALMAN 1 During the past few years, growers and feeders of live - stock have shown an increasing interest m what is known as a "share" or "contract" feeding plan. It has been utilized m an effort to minimize the financial hazards which have I re - sulted from violent fluctuations m livestock prices. As is customary with most unfamiliar practices, many expensive mistakes have been made and numerous lop-sided plans of share feeding have resulted. In an effort to cralify this situa - tion and point out the simplicity of making a contract which is equitable to both the feeder and the grower, this bulletin is presented. No attempt is made m this bulletin to advise the feeder or the grower as to whether he should feed on contract or buy and sell on the market, nor is any attempt made to dictate the type of contract which should be used if contract feeding is decided upon. A discussion of the important fac - tors m contract feeding is presented m the following order: an equitable contract, shrink, death loss, overhead costs, bonuses and deductoins, feed costs and feeding methods, pork credit, total cost, types of contracts, and a brief discussion of- feeds. The data presented m this bulletin on feeds, feed requirements, daily gains, cost of gains, age, and sex are based upon weighted averages of numerous trials conducted at the Nebraska Experiment Station during the last 17 years. A summary of these data on the feeding of steers is presented m Table 11 m the back of this bulletin. WHEN AND WHERE BEGUN There is nothing particularly new about contract feeding. In reality it is nothing more than an advanced form of tirade or barter, the like' of which our ancestors practiced for hun - dreds of years before there was such a thing as money,! and which they have practiced during every period of financial stress ever since. Just when farmers began trading eggs for groceries is not recorded, but the practice has for years jbeen so common that it stimulates no particular thought. In a like manner, stockmen of the older school will recall that during the depressions of the 70s and 80s the practice of trading a portion of their herd for feed enough to carry the remainder through the winter was common. From this stage to that of virtually trading a portion of a herd of their cattle for enough corn and alfalfa to fatten the remainder of the herd 1 Credit it due Protestor H. J. Gramlich for helpful luEEestions m preparing thii manuscript and for the me of much of the experimental feeding data. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 is only a short step, and that, in its final analysis, is what contract feeding really is. A few of the larger Corn Belt feeders began the practice with varied success in the late 90s and again in 1920. In 1930, because of the recurrence of violent fluctuations in livestock prices and a shortage of cheap livestock credits, interest in the practice was revived. As credits continued to tighten and prices of livestock to fall, interest has increased until many experienced growers and feeders in all parts of the range country and the Corn Belt are now practicing it. There is now much evidence that, if satisfactory and equitable agreements can be developed the practice may become widespread among livestock men! A little study on the subject, coupled with his present experience, should enable any feeder or grower to prepare such a con - tract. AN EQUITABLE CONTRACT In the formation of a contract for the share feeding of the one's feed to the other's livestock, the feeder and grower must not forget that they are about to enter into a mutual agree - ment. The peculiar nature of this agreement makes its fair - ness to each of them paramount to all other considerations. Any contract that favors the one at the expense of the other is certain, in the long run, to prove unsatisfactory. This is true because as soon as one of the participants sees that he is paying for the other's profit, he immediately becomes dis - satisfied and, therefore, lax or vindictive in the fulfillment of his obligations, and the situation results in a direct loss to both. This was demonstrated in a number of cases in the fall of 1931 where Wyoming-grown lambs were contracted to feeders in the North Platte valley, eastern Colorado, and western Kansas. The feeders, finding themselves suffering severe losses to the benefit of the grower, fed the livestock in such an unsatisfactory manner that the weight of the lambs after feeding was not as great as it was before the feeding period began and heavy losses were incurred by both parties. Likewise, growers have been led into bad bargains. Charges of misrepresentation have been made, and requests for ex - cessive fattening or early sale and other disagreements re - sulted. This, in the end, so disgusted both parties with the practice that neither would try it again. Several types of available contracts may be varied to fit specific feed, farm, or financial conditions. These make it possible for either party to bear the burden of falling prices and excessive death losses, or for these risks to be divided equally. It is evident that where the burden of risks is borne solely by one party, he is entitled to receive all the benefits </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Contract Feeding of Livestock which might accrue from rising prices, good feeding, or less - than-normal death losses. For either party to assume! all the risks and still divide the profits is obviously so unfair as to need no discussion, yet this is exactly what many contracts now in use call upon one of the parties to do. The results in such cases have been so disastrous that even the supposed beneficiary has suffered. On the other hand, much more numerous are the equitable contracts, between responsible parties, which have been carried out to the mutual satisfac - tion of both. HOW GROWERS AND FEEDERS MEET Both the feeder and the grower should be financially able to carry out their respective portions of the contract, and both should seek to enter into the agreement in good faith. To determine the financial standing of a prospective Icon - tractor is, in these days of credit associations, a simple matter; but for a man in position to feed to locate a grower who can supply desirable livestock is quite another problem, even though there may be legion of both. Generally speak - ing, feeders and growers are hundreds of miles apart. They seldom meet except at the central market through the medium of commission men and traders. The service that these slgen - cies perform in this respect is not fully appreciated until the Ak__1. — .^h^^^saw.^Bsva^s^nss^HBsspjVBPsavi — 1*a^v^v^0NVsit__uasBB*"" _mWA_m\ { rCi-i**""-.^'*'' •'■:- ■'• .._■■-■. -&gt;a» .-. ..:..'. a.'.-. . ■'•-■V's? i -■" • - ■-..■ . ';7^7'7""- ; 7 : ;.'' -' .■■■■■■-J i T:..^ / .: : ''f-" '" ' ' -' ,j I - '^S-bs-LssMbb-B*! B^fssi Lb-sb-AP _BB_af~ V ' ""' _ S&amp;_: UsT^ tJ^BBbU, POhj SgPh- __\_\ "-t. • ■ ' '•'■ _^7Hb_K ru ' ' _i i _____"' \\r-~ ' ______ SugHlM l^gLaj|Jh|£9 _|M__S High-grade yearling steers on the range. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 seller attempts to find his own buyer, or vice versa. The im - portance of the responsibility of both parties is even greater in a contract-feeding operation than in a direct sale. Some progress may be made in bringing grower and feeder to - gether through the various agricultural colleges, county agents, railroad agents, livestock associations, banks, etc. Many large growers are already acquainted with feeders to whom each year they contract their output. However, it is evident that the public livestock market men who know both growers and feeders as well as the kinds and grades of animals each produces, will probably continue to be the prin - cipal go-betweens for the rank and file. WHO SHOULD CONTRACT AND WHEN One of the chief virtues of contract feeding lies in the fact that it divides and thereby reduces risks. It also extends existing credits instead of retiring some and increasing others. Yet the very feeders and growers who are most capable of assuming risks and obtaining credits are the ones who to date have made the greatest use of contract feeding. Their reasoning in adopting the practice is that whatever benefits the small operator benefits the large in proportion. Perhaps additional reasons why they have adopted it more universally are grounded fa the fact that the large operators, generally speaking, are the leaders of the industry, who dis - cern beneficial practices more readily. They are afforded more opportunities to become acquainted with the growers. Knowing the ins and outs of the entire industry better, the large operator is naturally more capable of drawing an equi - table contract than is his less fortunate brother. For these same reasons, he is less wary of using such a method. There is no reason, however, why the small operator should not, through study and contact, avail himself of these same oppor - tunities. Contract feeding should not be engaged in by the unin - formed. To employ it properly, the grower must have some knowledge of the feeder's costs and expenses and the feeder in turn must be able to estimate accurately the value of the grower's livestock. Beyond this, and more important, is the fact that both feeder and grower must acquaint themselves intimately with their own risks, costs, and requirements in the fulfillment of the contract they are about to enter. Of prime importance are such factors as shrink, transportation, marketing costs, overhead expenses, and the feed cost of gains to be produced. While knowledge of these factors is highly important in any feeding operation, it becomes doubly so in contract feeding if the proceeds are to be divided in accord- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Contract Feeding of Livestock ance with the risks involved. Without some knowledge of these things, no farmer should attempt to feed, much less to contract feed. With them, he may enter into a contract in confidence and safety. The information needed on these sub - jects is given later in this bul.etin. When market fluctuations are slight, feed prices stable, credit easy, and financial risks therefore, at a minimum, con - tract feeding has its fewest advantages. When the opposite is true, its advantages increase. It is doubtful whether there has ever been a time when risks were so slight that it would not have been desirable to have further reduced them through the use of equitable contracts. SHRINK Even the most casual observer knows that livestock cannot undergo the excitement, lack of feed, and other hardships in - cident to transportation without some shrink. On all range livestock fattened for market, this loss in weight, or shrink, must be endured twice — once when the animals are shipped from range to feed lot and again when they are shipped from feed lot to market. It is important to remember these! two shrinks when the making of a contract is being contemplated. Where a feeder contracts to receive his compensation for the fattening of livestock wholly on a basis of the gain Ipro- bb_ b_W' 'UI ii ~" I -LJ. wrg— ttt— T^^^SS"^^ J BBBBBBBBBBBBTOBBBBBBBBBBBBBB— I I BBe9—BBBsI ~I _^_____\ W-W ' &amp; - I " • BI t^'TtiU, feiljS.-BBT -^aSBBB-L 'i _M_V ' V '_BBt 9 ■ 7 '-"''- '•'^'"^ rr i_BB' I . 51 ~*E£\^5 si J&amp;________a_C^~~ r^ \z=-lr ___________~T_-' I 1 BBMMa_ A,X__mUL.__. J^^'._W^-^l^^^^teL__.--m t '--'-'■~-^'-c^S^^^~"^^^t^'^^^_S__Wsm_^_S____rA m BifefS __\sse 'xsCii: ■? "!"-' m_ fc-.. jC^idJ^tl^TX j 7' -4k48BwHMB--HB-l-BB-BBT '&gt; * : : _____sZ^-- 7 " ' ;"bb# e'l V*^z—_^AXsfa&amp;^Z3t9_vrn 1S.M W____W_1_%$~lifflB___tm__W—- •**' BB_ A.AiL B__ T __\ * A good set of scales will pay for itself many times over. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 duced (see types of contracts, page 28), shrink becomes a tre mendously important factor and it should either TbeKiSatS from consideration by the use of in-and-out wefghts at the , SSiif* °* anient a m o U „t should be added 1 to the cost of feedlot gain to offset its effect. Where feeding is done on the investment or custom plans, this factor will fa most Lset automatically take care of itself. es A feeder without scales has on method wherebv he cm ' arrive accurately at normal shrinks, and, SSuently IS n' cannot guard against them adequately. A good St of sc^le_ can soon pay their cost many times over in making this and ! other necessary calculations. To the regular contractfeeder S7f^ e +^ St For those nSrSequipId and for the benefit of those others whose experience vSth shrinks is limited, the following figures for cattle a?e me - sgaa ass?** these **» -i, teS^ , Hours in transit "S&amp;S^S'' 24 to 06.:::::::::::::::::::::::::::: • !•?„ *° _-u ae to 72 .::::::::::::::: g^ *e m five- 19 a ' B ° "&gt; "-40 uver 7- ..„ 3 96 JJ)Q fsJ^LKi 5 Pf e 1 se ° t . ed to an effort to aid the feeder who is forced to accept loading-point weights and final weights at the market. It will be noted that the data given show the per - centages that feed costs are increased by shrinks. These fig - ures should not be taken to be exact, but they approximate those that feeders not too far from market normally receive Table 1. — The effect of shrink on costs of feed-lot gains I Cattle Sheep Two- I 1 I year- Year - s . olds lings Calves Lambs Range weight (pounds) — 900 I 690 - j 400 I 65~ Inbound shrink (pounds) 45 30 22 5 Feed-lot gain /pound*; 306 358 442 SO Outbound shrink (pounds) ... 40 38 24 8 Market weight (pounds) ■. 1,121 980 796 87 Credit gam (pounds) 221 290 396 22 Increased Feed Cost (per cent) 88.5 | 22.7 11.6 36.8 a Figures in parentheses are references to bulletins on pace 44. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Contract Feeding of Livestock Table 1 shows how much the feeder who is paid solely up - on a basis of the difference between range and market weights must add to the fed cost of gain in order to offset the effect of shrinks. The feed cost of gain can be computed from JFig - ures 2, 3, 4, 5, or 6. The amount that must be added is given in percentages in the last line headed "Increased feed cost". | For example, the feed cost given in Figure 3 (page 18) for year - ling steers (corn at 35 cents, alfalfa at $8.00) is $5.60 per hundred pounds of gain. From Table 1, the increased jfeed cost is shown as 22.7 per cent. Twenty-two and seven-tenths per cent of $5.60 is $1.27, the extra cost that must be added to the cost of 100 pounds of gain. Adding the two ($5160+ $1;27) gives $6.87, the total cost of producing 100 pounds of gain when shrink is considered with feed cost. Common practice is to allow a shrink of 3 per cent on weights of lambs or cattle weighed direct off pasture where water is available. The correctness of this figure, however, is much disputed. A twelve-hour stand without feed and water is more generally used and believed by many to be more satis - factory. Two or three per cent is often added to livestock weighed off the cars in lieu of a hay and water fill at istock yards. Exact data as to the advisability of these practices are not available. DEATH LOSS Experience indicates that a normal death loss on feed-lot lambs will be about 3 per cent. With calves about 2 per cent is to be expected, while with yearlings and older cattle about 1 per cent is considered average. If the death loss is assumed by the feeder he must make up the weight lost on account of death by additional gains on the livestock. Because of the small initial weight and the proportionately greater and! more efficient gains made by calves, the loss of 2 per cent through death does not increase the cost of gain as much as a loss of 1 per cent of older cattle. An equitable contract should (make provision for this fact as well as for the fact that under un - usual conditions much greater losses are possible. Some Colo - rado feeders of contract lambs prefer to accept the risk of any death loss greater than 3 per cent provided they may, in return, receive credit for any death loss of less thani 3 per cent that occurs. By far the greater number of feeders, however, prefer to accept responsibility for any death loss that may result from their own negligence or bad manage - ment, but to divide with the grower the death loss resulting from storms, lightning, disease, or other so-called "acts of God". This division would be made on a basis of what each has invested in the animal. When divided in this way, the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 \_tZ-_^^___^k'_rt'-_\ :: -.' - ■ : _L1$£_I "I ifsf _T _T_\ III' . X M \iM- '_m9-^__\_\-_\^M~''~ '-^5fe*_f « \i_awwma_-_\t\r A. ill ■ «•'-__» ■' -_■?,! _r i _*. ■'•• • - ■XJF Hs-i^rirlliia Jr kii _Ti \|J ■ [.«T_:fl^ ■ .-_ «BBB__i1ii &lt;r ',■■• nf sTF-lsilrrtBrs __m _rl flti ll __ - J^Pa _L^ ' **£ —————^ ?S_isbbb_ _F^j(HP bbb__i *Qbb_ bb_ l\ —W ■ • _ s^^^^sa sbK* "* *^T^*3B 1 -^yfe*'i ! n^'"'-' ; 'Jia»&amp;''^^^TBBBB^^^^^^^***^ ' j I _9____ifc** .' '^K___^^- -^Ch 51 L^^BBB«F^7 '' * '"• - *-———_*** ■ *'sE*____\_^l BBBBBBBB_?&amp;X&lt;. ■ «* C*3 - .-* ' j -^—tS—\ Death loss is important in contract feeding. feeder loses the feed the animal has consumed, while the grower loses whatever the dead animal was worth into the feed lot. If the feeder accepts a normal death loss of 3 per cent on a 65-pound lamb upon which he expects to put a 25-pound feed-lot gain, it will increase his feed cost per hun - dred pounds of gain by approximately 10.43 per cent. For convenience in making computations, the costs of death loss for lambs and cattle are presented in Tables 2 and 3. These show percentages by which feed costs will have to be increased to cover varying death losses. Table 2. — Effect of death loss on cost of feed lot gains (lambs) Death Increased feed cost Increased feed cost loss 55-lb. lambs into feed lot 65-lb. lambs into feed lot Per cent Per cent Per cent 1 2.13 3.22 2 4.37 6.68 3 6.73 10.43 4 9.24 14.49 5 11.89 18.90 Note: Data based on 35 pounds of gain for 55-pound lamb and 25 pounds of gain for 65-pound lamb. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Contract Feeding of Livestock Table 3. — Effect of death loss on cost of feed-lot gains (cattle) 1 Death Two-year-olds Yearlings Calves ! loss | Increased feed cost Increased feed cost Increased feed cost Percent Percent Percent Percent 1 3.50 2.59 1.38 2 7.34 5.33 2.81 3 11.44 {^2(5 4J29 Note: Data based on initial weights and gains as follows: Initial weight Gain Two-year-olds 878 306 Yearlings 708 353 Calves 376 . 442 For example, the feed cost per 100 pounds of gain on a yearling steer (corn at 35 cents per bushel, alfalfa at j$8.00 per ton) is $5.60 as shown in Figure 3. Table 3, for a death loss of 1 per cent on yearlings, shows that the feed cost js in - creased 2.59 per cent. Therefore, 2.59 per cent of $5.60 equals 15 cents, which, when added to $5.60, gives $5.75 as the cost of producing 100 pounds of gain when death loss is considered in the feed cost. OVERHEAD costs In addition to shrink and death loss, certain overhead costs enter into every contract feeding operation. From the grow - er's standpoint, these include the interest on the investment he has in his livestock, plus any supervisory expenses that may be involved in looking after his interests while thp live - stock are in the feeder's lots, plus his share of rail and marketing expenses. Because of fluctuating prices, 'jvages, Table 4. — Feeder's overhead costs per ewt. of gain " Cattle Sheep Two-year- olds Yearlings Calves Lambs Interest on feed at 8% $0.19 $0.22 $0.20 $0.12 Man labor (at $2.50 per day) .77 .74 .53 .55 Horse (at $0.08 per hour).. .29 .28 .20 .23 Building and equipment (upkeep, rent, etc.) 35 .32 .25 .40 Miscellaneous (water, salt, etc.) . .17 .16 .12 .15 Totals $1.77 $1.72 $1.30 $1.45 Note: No charge made for bedding and no credit given for mknure. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 wh™™^ rates .', these are all highly variable factors, but each may be easily computed for the particular operation under consideration. Customarily, interest is charged at 8 per cent for the length of the feeding period and supervision F^iX^JL^ for lambs a ° d 50 cents a head for™£?e Freight rates, of course, vary from different range shipping Points, while marketing costs are standard. *JSL «*&amp;£* °^ erhead cost s toclude a number of variable amtuSs^ven fa'TabllT^ C ° nditi ° n8 ' "*" *™*™™** the BONUS FOR GOOD FEEDING rewiTfor^nri 0 ? 6^ P remiu m for the gain produced as a ni-w * *? od f^ m « or for exceptionally high gains. Others prefer to make a deduction if a specified daily gain £ white* reSUltS haVe Pr ° ved the Practice to L g worth livestock .,p onsi £ er ation must be -**** to the livestock upon which the contract is based. The feeder cannot enter intelligently £ oSitfwlS UDtil he haS fi 5 st such thfagj ?!~4^ J 7 ' age, sex, and condition. Upon these factorsjiepend the feed cost of producing a pound of gain auil^thi T &amp;£ e S B,r P r° d '. and Possiblf the kind g and quality of the feed to be used. The grower in turn must also have a working knowledge of these factors to protect his in - terests and to avoid making unreasonable demands of the \^ er - these factors will affect feeding operations differently m different localities and under varying conditions they can be reckoned with fairly satisfactorily. ' FEED LOTS Every experienced feeder knows that dry, well-drained feed lots are important to the production of good gains on cattle Wet weather often causes excessively muddy lots, which make for unsastisfactory and expensive gains. The grower should consider this factor before criticizing the feeder or the ration and the feeder should do all in his power to keep the lots as dry as_ possible. In some instances, it may be desirable to market the cattle somewhat sooner than expected if the lots become too muddy. Where posible, it is best to let the cattle nave the run of a pasture or field under such conditions. The harm done by the increased exercise will be much less than that done by the mud if the cattle are forced to stay in such lots. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Contract Feeding of Livestock CATTLE I Quality. — From the standpoint of the feeder, it is gen - erally conceded that the better-quality animals are somewhat more efficient in their feed utilization than those of poorer quality. This is no doubt an important feature where!dis - tinctly "off-type" animals are concerned. However, j the difference in daily gain and the economy of that gain between the animals of relatively similar grades does not affect the feed bill as much as is generally supposed. This fact is illus - trated by the feeding tests conducted at the Wisconsin! Ex - periment Station (2) from 1926 to 1929, at Ohio (3) ,! and . I [-— » ■*-" " ' ■ ■■■»■" '■; -— •^g^m ■*"? _ "^^^^7 ' ZIZ: ,m l___na____V_ w __Z____^B_a___^~Z?__7T~.W_______ w^ m^ E -_ :■'.'!. m __We__wax___*______)_*_K 1 r~~-'^AAmM M| K^JrftSSfmSx. " "&lt;^P^^ •^_W ' AbbT^ "* •'--*"' "K!^?^_b»^ I Wf M.- ; ~-B-r^S^-7 . A. ■ ■ B-W ofe^BBBT^I^-^B^V Buyers on public markets appreciate quality and condition. at the Nebraska Station. 8 The importance of quality also varies with the age of the animal, being less of a factor with the older cattle. Because of the longer feeding period re - quired to fatten calves, quality is of great importance. In - ferior calves do not grow and develop uniformly. This, of course, affects the price received for the finished product. Furthermore, calves are frequently marketed as yearlings from September to November, at which time the market is glutted with grass-fat steers and heifers. At such times, only 'Based on unpublished records, Nebr. Exp. Sta., 1925-1982. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 KSS 08 "' 6 0f - high qualit y are considered good enough £n iR d 1&gt; W Bnt Furthermore, good-quality calVes will be finished much quicker than the less desirabS . n „%A!Z Per haps no one factor has a more- important bear- Si U and M bje^i contr a«t Reding of cattle than tnefr age (4 and 5). While age of the animal affects both it i« TL^S&amp;^tStiifls Ite * to the * ro * er SS_&amp;£ ~5 ■?/* quality, the feed required to produce a pound of c-ain S-wdSE^^fi aS the age ° f the animal increases. Age also determines, in a general wav th* man agement of the animal in the feed lot* Twolandtet JeS-~ old steers should usually be placed on full feed and finS be marketed 8 Trafe -J^^^mOy finished.The/shouW . m arKetea, as rate of gain will drop materiallv and ™.f JESTS* P r °Portionately thereafter. ySSLTJvII make efficient gams over much longer periods and tWfm-!. are not so expensive to hold. Furthermore thS e is a ™n,r,' greater and more flexible demand to the KrSht SS d&amp;° h rGSU ts in a more 8table market f £ them * The difference in economy of gain as affected hv »"■* ,•_ perhapsbest illustrated by Figure^ l^wlng'the JSrffi of 1 gain produced from POUNDS GAIN °° e hushel of corn PER BUSHEL CORN FED $____**_*%'-&amp; .. s be noted that the calf ■' ' produces 2.7 pounds more gain than year - lings and 3.1 pounds more gain than two - year-olds from one bushel of corn. At 7 cents per pound for the gain, the calf would return, therefore, ap - proximately 20 cents more for every bushel of corn fed. It also should be noted that the feeding period re - quired to finish the animals is longer for the younger cattle. - io. ..-.Based on a weighted average of i sh °rter the feed - numerous trials conducted at the Ne- mg Period, the more rSoT* E *P erin »ent Station, 1915 to efficient the gains. 18SZ ' Should two-year-old </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Contract Feeding op Livestock steers be fed longer than the time given in the chartj the efficiency will decrease rapidly with each succeeding month's feeding. While this is true to a degree with calves or year - lings, an extra 30 to 60 days' feeding does not affect theirj feed costs nearly so much. The result is that the difference in economy of production becomes greater as the feeding period for the various ages increases, being proportionately greater for the older cattle. Considering the difference in economy of producing a pound of gain between cattle of different ages, the feeder can finish calves for less money per pound of gain than yearlings or two-year-olds. The reason for the similarity in feed require - ments of yearlings and two-year-olds is accounted for by the difference in length of the feeding period. In addition to more economical gains with younger cattle, the percentage of final weight that represents gain decreases as the age of the animal increases. This is illustrated by the fact thatj with a calf approximately 50 per cent of the selling weight isjgain ; with a wearling, 35 per cent ; and with a two-year-old, 25 per cent. This fact is particularly important in determining the relative income of the feeder and grower at the market. It also has a direct bearing upon the feed costs as affected by shrink, death loss, and overhead. Daily Ration and Feed Requirements. — The amount of feed that a steer will consume each day is, of course, variable. Nevertheless, it is possible to approximate the daily ration with a fair degree of accuracy under average conditions. The figures given below represent an average of a number of feeding trials conducted at the Nebraska Station in which shelled corn and alfalfa hay were used. The amounts eaten daily by steers on full feed in actual feed-lot practice should not differ materially from the amounts given. The feeding periods indicated below in Table 5 are ordinarily sufficient to finish cattle of the ages given. Table 5. 4 — Feeding period and daily ration for steers of different ages Two-year-olds Yearlings Calves Length of feeding period (days).. 126 150 200 Average daily ration SheUed corn (pounds) 18.4 16.6 11.7 Alfalfa hay (pounds) 8JS 6.9 4.3 •Tables 6, 6, and 7 were taken from Table 11 which represents a summary of numerous feeding- trials conducted at the Nebraska Station during the last 17 years. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 With the above figures on daily ration as a basis, the num - ber of bushels of corn and the pounds of alfalfa hay required to finish steers of various ages are presented fa Table 6. The amount of gain is also included. Table 6. — Total feed required and gain for average feeding period — steers of different ages Two-year-olds Yearlings Calves Length of feeding period (days).. 125 150 200 Gain (pounds) 306 353 442 Shelled corn consumed (bushels).. 41 44.8 41.6 Alfalfa hay consumed (pounds).... 1,060 1,030 860 Feeders and growers interested in handling steers on con - tract should study Table 6, since it forms the basis for determining the approximate amount of feed that will be needed to finish the cattle. A close estimate of feed cost can also be obtained from this table, together with the gain to be expected. Cost of Gain on Steers. — Since the major expense in cattle feeding is the feed cost, it is necessary that this item be given serious consideration before entering into a con - tract. This applies to the grower as well as to the feeder. Since feed prices vary widely in different localities, Figures 2, 3, 4, and 5 are presented (6)." From these charts the feed cost of producing 100 pounds of gain can easily be determined by the aid of a straight edge. Note that each (Figs. 2, 3, and 4) gives the feed cost for a steer of a given age. Figure 5, given later in the discussion on heifers vs. steers, gives the feed cost of gain for yearling heifers and heifer calves. When using these charts, note the length of the feeding period. If it is desirable to feed for a shorter or longer time, read the discussion on length of feeding period. To use this chart, first place one end of the ruler on the price of corn, on the left-hand scale. Second, place the other end on the price of alfalfa, on right-hand scale. The point where the line crosses the intermediate scale indi - cates the cost of producing 100 pounds of gain at those feed prices. Note the example fa Figure 3 for yearling steers (corn at 35 cents per bushel, and alfalfa at $8.00 per ton, feed cost at $5.60 per 100 pounds of gain) . * Figures 2, S, 4. and 5 are based on a weighted average of numerous trials carried en at the Nebraska Station from 1915 to 1933 to determine the feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain. The data are represented under "Feeds". </seg>
            <seg id="p017">The Contract Feeding op Livestock TWO-YEAR-OLD STEERS PRICE PRICE OF CORN FEED COST ALFALFA PER BUSHEL 100 LBS. GAIN PER TON A F~* I 1 * * • -15 -BS .80 r - - | -14 -?6 •75 r : - | -13 " 24 .70 - - - | Mil r* ' If 2 .ss r r 10 : : - 16 .50 j- r 9 : : -14 .45 r r 8 : - 12 .40 r - 7 : - l0 .35 j- 1_6 •-.•.•• - : I - 8 .30 r -s - : - 6 "r -4 : - 4 •20 r - .I5E E J Fig. 2. — To find feed cost of 100 pounds of gain, lay a straight edge from price of corn per bushel to price of alfalfa per ton. The feed cost of 100 pounds of gain will be found at the point where the straight edge crosses the line marked "cost of 100 pounds of [gain". The figures in this chart are based on a 125-day feeding period. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 YEARLING STEER$ price price of of corn feed cost alfalfa per bushel too lbs. gain per ton ♦J F 1$ * : _ a -28 •80 r 1,* : -26 75 f -13 : -24 70 - -22 .65 - : • : H' -20 ,60- " - = Ho -is 55 r ; : r 9 - 16 50 r : - -8 - 14 45 '- : 1-7 - 12 .40 r : - . : Ir - 10 .35 r -J E Lr; -8 .30 - 5 - : a - 6 .25 r " 4 : : I - 4 .20- -3 i 1 r Pig: 3. — To find feed cost of 100 pounds of gain, lay a straight edge from price of corn per bushel to price of alfalfa per ton. The feed cost of 100 pounds of gain will be found at the point where the straight edge crosses the line marked "cost of 100 pounds of gain". The figures in this chart are based on a 150-day feeding period. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">The Contract Feeding of Livestock STEER CALVES PRICE PRICE OF OF CORN FEED COST ALFALFA PER BUSHEL 100 LBS. GAIN ; PER TON . 1 . $ - - - 28 $.80- - : * l0 &gt; -26 .75 - - - | : 9- "f 4 •70 - 9 . - | -22 : 8 . - 20 .60 - : 7 _ . "'8 .55 i- \ - : - - 16 so '- ft- ~ .: ' -14 .45 7 : «:- J ,2 .40 s . 4 .35 - 4 : 4- 8 •30 r - • 4 .25- 3^ T 6 : - - 4 .20- I5C J 1 Fig. 4. — To find feed cost of 100 pounds of gain, lay a straight edge from price of corn per bushel to price of alfalfa per ton. The feed cost of 100 pounds of gain will be found at the point where the straight edge crosses the line marked "cost of 100 pounds of gain". a The figures in this chart are based on a 200-day feeding period. &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 longe? rferi_d 7^ Paction for the ""f»«f penoa. ine feed required to produce a nminri nf gysaa. spa M^s£| vided the cattle are held a inno-o,. «,*,« ™L- £ am ' pro ' Tn iiwL? +t 1 *. are fed an additional 50 or 100 davs To illustrate, the feed cost on a two-year-old steer fpriiPK fe^f ?5 ' 9 ° P er h«°dred pounds of gifa (Fig 2 corn at $__*&amp;* P er - bu8 i iel and alfalfa at ?8.00 per ton) b^t If tr^^&amp;SSJ^cS 9 £*£ P rod^iaiSwil[ duced from one bushel of e^.JffJK«XB_^ TA^Zr""?^ fe ? / cor T' and Pounds of alfalfa reauired for vanous total gains with different feeding JJSSS7SJ&amp; Pay-xeq , 100 , m , ggg | „===^ Two-year-olds 1SS_^ 349 386 448- Yearlings ~ ' Calves SSS I 2 f« -••• 338 | 883 442" </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The Contract Feeding of Livestock Daily alfalfa consumptoin and the amount required to pro - duce a pound of gain decreases as the feeding period in - creases. Table 7 should be used as a guide in determining the advisability of extending the feeding period. Heifers vs. Steers. — Age (or size) is a far more import - ant factor with heifer than with steer feeding, because' of the usual price discrimination against heavy heifers. For the most part, heifer feeding should be confined to calves and yearlings. At weights not in excess of 750 pounds, fat heiferfi sell well in line with fat steers. With a few exceptions, suph as a very limited number of prime 1000 - pound heifers that are suitable for the Kosher trade, heifers from 800 pounds up sell only slightly above choice coWs. With the exception of the yearling class, steers make slightly greater and more efficient gains than heifers 1(5). However, heifers make less skeletal growth and, therefore, fatten faster, resulting in less time being required to finish them. Under ordinary conditions, the following feeding periods will be sufficient to finish heifers of the yearling and calf classes: yearlings, 80 to 120 days; calves, 150 to 175 days. Cost of Gains for Heifers. — Though identical prices are used, the feed cost for heifers is not the same as for steers of similar weights and ages. Therefore, Figure 5 is ! pre - sented, which gives the feed cost of producing 100 pounds of gain on heifers of the yearling and calf classes. JThis chart should be used in the same way as those for steers. Effect of Sex Upon Length of Feeding Period. — When heifers are fed longer than the time given in the preceding discussion, the cost of gain increases in about the some! pro - portion as for steers. Since the daily feed consumption for heifers is practically the same as for steers of the same weight and age, Table 7 can be used in determining the total feed required for longer periods. Table 8. — Pounds gain for heifers — different feeding periods 1 Days fed 75 | 100 125 150 175 Yearlings (pounds) 173 205 249 300 854 Calves (pounds) 197 257 298 328 1 Based on a weighted average ot 6 trials conducted at the Nebraska Station. 1924 to 1931. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 HEIFERS PRICE OF CORN PRICE OF PER BUSHEL CALVES VFab, ,k,^ PERSON : - — 26 75 — " : II- -13 .70^- : : ~ 24 : 10- H2 *f.. 9 :IL - 20 .55 — 8— J o : _ : 7 ~§? L * :.4 4*r : o : F 6 " 2 r? _ l2 .40- . * - - - ui L — . 3J L s-.*F z'° - o - -_*'• " ° -5 - 8 .30 - 4- o • . UI ■ — - u - • -. : 3 - .20^- : i~3 -« .Ksl H E-2 - 2 1(3Si^ffia_»&amp;^3£'a </seg>
            <seg id="p023">The Contract Feeding of Livestock SHEEP Quality.— Some consideration of quality should be given to sheep, though the variations in the quality of different groups of western feeder lambs is much less marked than with cattle. The percentage of culls should, however, be considered a factor which will tend to increase the dfeath loss and the cost of producing a pound of gain. "Native" Corn Belt lambs should seldom be considered in a contract feeding plan. They are often too badly in - fested with stomach worms ahd other parasites peculiar to sheep to give a satisfactory account of themselves in the feed lot. They are also too growthy to finish at popular weights. Closely allied to quality is health of the animal. ! No feeder can afford to feed unhealthy or unthrifty animals. Neither can the grower afford to put such livestock out on contract. Sick, unthrifty, or "poor doing" lambs should not be offered to the feeder or accepted by him. Some feeders also prefer to reject lambs that are excessively wrinkled. j Age and Sex. — While age is a very important considera - tion in the feeding of cattle, it is relatively unimportant from the standpoint of the sheep feeder. Practically all sheep that reach the feed lots, and certainly all those that are suitable for contract feeding, are lambs. The age factor is, therefore, eliminated and any variation that occurs in the economy of gains in lamb feeding is traceable to factors other than age. Sex, like age, to the lamb feeder is not of great moment and thus will not affect the grower's or feed - er's contract. Cost of Producing 100 Pounds of Gain on Lambs.—Be - cause of the variation in feed costs in different localities, Figure 6 is given, which shows at a glance the cost of pro - ducing 10O pounds of gain for corn and alfalfa at different prices. Note that one of the center scales in the! chart gives the feed cost of 100 pounds of gain for Corn Belt conditions where alfalfa is limited and corn is full-fed. The other intermediate scale is for the western feeder who limits the daily corn to one pound or less and full-feeds alfalfa. Length of Feeding Period. — Most of the lambs that enter the lots for fattening weigh from 55 to 65 pounds. To bring the largest returns to both grower and feeder, these lambs should not weigh much over 90 pounds at the niarket. The sheep feeder is thus limited to putting on a gain of 25 to 35 pounds. This is especially true in eastern Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 LAMBS Sfc c o e r N sets? 1 ™ 5^;^ pR,ctoF PER BUSHEL EASTEP^^o gg^^, .80 E- ii- - l4 28 7cL I L I3 -26 ■ : io- : .70^ : ? 2 ~ 24 .60 t- 8- V -10 _ ° •_s7 7 i I U : 18 - _ 2 I •40|- 5-5 i-e ~ 12 h : -io 4— o . ° — : ° -- p. : g -4 .25^ 3 ~ " : ~ 6 : - -3 - 50=- 2 - I I 4 15IL _ 1 F 2 j 2 Pig. 6.— To find feed cost of 100 pounds of gain, lay a straight ed«» from price of corn per bushel to price of alfalfa per ton f he fefd SSi^ 1^? P ° Und8 of . gain wm be found »t the point' where the SffikV&amp;S "? S8es 2 16 Iine marked " cost of 10 ° Pounds of gain" ™^^ tW °- ,n^ rmediate 8cale8 ' Each represents feed cost of 100 pounds of gain for a certain method of feeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">The Contract Feeding of Livestock and throughout the Corn Belt where the general practice is to feed a heavy grain allowance from the start. The (re - sult is a comparatively short feed and the difference in cost of gain as affected by feeding period is not of practical importance. In the irrigated sections of western Nebraska, Colorado, Wyoming, and Montana, the feeding period is somewhat longer than for the Corn Belt. Because of the relatively high price of grain and cheapness of hay, most lamb feed - ers limit the grain consumption and feed more hay. [By - products of sugar beet factories, which are discussed under feeds, page 40, are also used quite extensively by western lamb feeders. Under these conditions, the feed require - ments differ quite widely from those existing in the Corn Belt. As a result the cost of gain for each method must be calculated from a different set of figures. Table 9 gives the daily ration, the feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain, and the daily gain secured under the two common methods of feeding. Table 9. — Daily ration, feed required, and daily gain (two common lamb-feeding practices) | Corn belt practice— Western feed r lot f_5-feedbie practice— corn lun-ieeaing limited, alfalfa corn -f- alfalfa i fuU-fedT Pounds Pounds Daily ration: SheUed corn 1.21 0.96 Alfalfa 1.10 1.93 Feed for 100 pounds gain: Shelled corn •' 405 325 Alfalfa 371 1 658 Daily gain (UK) 0.30 | 1 Based on weighted average of 10 trials at Nebraska Experiment Station. 1 Based on weighted average of 10 trials, one at the Nebraska Station and nine by Holden at the Scottsbluff Substation (7 and 8). It is believed that these figures are fairly representative of what can be expected in actual feed-lot practice. I The data given on feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain under western Nebraska conditions check fairly closely with those obtained by the Colorado Experiment Station at Fort Collins, Colorado. The practice in Colorado is to feed slightly more hay and less grain. A summary of 10 trials conducted at the Colorado Station (9) shows the following feed requirements for 100 pounds gain : shelled corn, 267 pounds; alfalfa, 741 pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 PORK CREDIT FROM FEEDING __5s_3_p5_rHS_fi Under ordinary conditions in relatively drv feed lof« i i in price the carcasses resShW from H^ &lt; 1 nka ? e is hi * h value as a supplemlnte^fe^I lotho^ l0 " W S ° me TOTAL COSTS aft^he^e^ $• TT 113 factors w *&lt;* feeder and thrower are^!^SSf°^ ° n contrac *, the nnleTJd™ marlS TornU'T (U T&lt; 0ek Wei » hed ™ alfalfa oT$ZmpZrttk) "* ** CenU per bmhel an * -,,, CattJe ' Two-year- — Feed cost (Figs. 2 to 6) ifji ' 88 Calves T "'^°_ Overhead Table 4)„.. . ? l'?S % **** $*™~ Shrink (Table 1).... HZ Hf L80 l-« Death loss (Tables 2 ,„„••„) _\ X *\ . -48 1.45 •*•*• l -J" I .12 5 0tal "•" * 10 ' 15 SR - 74 $6.05 S7 -._ '^ "*""' 6S »— * '°to feed lot J SS; 25 £^~ Sl§___ </seg>
            <seg id="p027">The Contract Feeding of Livestock a— I _ _j^~^7^^* : — vct: .' is— fl_a_— ( T_^j: W ~. — aT— -i' ■- — JF aaas_a_a»ll^^BB_Btiaj^t".^'_ (^' 7_^^BJl ■ rS-S-fift-J^^ " ft_S K _____%- ■-' x v^_r^Wal^8?~- ;^r^_f\ —_—_a MS i _——\ w \AA£r^^____A .^£-^_\ \ ▼iw- ■ __... n-'._ fffc«i * wdi._ —-.'——._—_——— \ —e——\ _——\ _—*—T^_wS' 2ufll A fc — S_ 1 — r~i i hi i. re -sm^ umm - - . - ij . • a^^3c— 39F. av w •. _-————_W—_rt^^ls^i^ 15^jr ij^AJ__v_—w/ 9 z :m^^^_\_'.^^___. i'\ *-,.. xjBaaw_i w ___\——^——*r _———W A__^srr^^a__T___-^.- . ?^_. . \__________\ \ i*^Z_w——_r _^^^^9_—_r^^__^^_^AW^^^' !^^'.'k^^^^__\_^___ ' '■ W -'• The last phase of a contract feeding operation. CONTRACTS A written memorandum of any agreement decided upon should be made in order to avoid disputes, and as a legal instrument in case they should arise. The simpler such a memorandum is, the more understandable and usable it becomes. To aid in the writing of this agreement it is best that all the "wherefores" and "whereases" in so far as possible be eliminated, and that only those things pertinent to the agreement at hand be recorded. Unless the parties to the agreement are accustomed to the making of Icon - tracts, legal advice should be obtained. No attempt is made in this bulletin to advise the grower or feeder as to what contract he should or should not use. However, a few sample contracts are given which may aid in the selection and formation of a feeding agreement. types of contracts Fundamentally there are three kinds of contracts. Each of these has numerous variations, and many of these varia - tions employ some of the features of two or more types. For the convenience of prospective contract feeders each of these three types is discussed separately and specimens are given. Perhaps the most popular contract is one in which the feeder is reimbursed on a basis of the gain he puts oh the ■.-.'"■■. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 JWffJ- Th l second I ? ost Popular type is one in which the feeder and grower jointly inventory the value of thi grower's livestock and the value of the Seder's feed labor SSSb8Br1 ,-ld - profit or l0M * SS operltionsis then SSJfijft accordance with the investment of each S the third type of agreement the grower contracts i Srti thi feeder to fatten his cattle or l8 m Kra 8 pe£2 o fLS f,? e S lfi^ Tl eht : He then Pays the feeder fw the feed used, the labor involved, and other overhead I «2L Each of these plans is being used with SS, rocceS ?v fr,S r !^ nUmber ° f &amp; ed , ers ' An y &lt;»• of the^fan be made SSViff 6 ? a 5 6 agreement or a dangerous W v»4if? a + lr Ji de P endmg on the consideration given to the various details of expense previously discussed. THE GAIN-BASIS PLAN This type reimburses the feeder on a basis of th* _- a . n he puts on the livestock. It is being used lq§U TgeSerflh? £,!? S?P eciall 7 PoP^ar among sheep feeders hi thfolkotes and Minnesota and is being used ii Illinois, Iowa, NeW ka, Colorado, and other states. It usually calls f nr fv,_ grower to deliver to the feeder a specified I number ot '«_£ livestock of stipulated age, quality weifht TJ SlJw? point or at his feed yard. However, range weights with "SfS US ? d V The f ? eder a « rees to put on a denote amount of gam for a price per pound that varies with The SS*!fv- 0£ * feed » i 08 *^ labor, overhead, deaSi iS and shrinks involved. The approximate length of fledlne period w usually stated. The livestock is weijrhed out 3 the feeders yard, his loading point, or at th? market with f* d X ate pr °1? on mad e for shrinks. When thf livestock a sold, marketing and transportation costs are paid the grower 18 ThTtitfe^f Sf I^T^* ™o™*A the £_™ _ « fatle of the livestock remains in the grower's name and if separated by great distance from the feSer he often provides a supervisor to look after his intereste' Before the actual feeding operation bee-ins sati^t™; S?S«ta are always made wtth hofdels oMfa_?S V f e^°- k i, 0 !; fee + d 5° b _ used ' Provision must also be made for risks due to death loss A popular variation of this plan, and one which divid** 3?- Stf S f ? arket fluctuations more equaUy fa. Zfa which the feeder accepts his compensation on a basis of tS gains produced at the market price of the nnishedlnimJl </seg>
            <seg id="p029">The Contract Feeding of Livestock I Usually the feeder is given an additional sum based on the original or in-bound weight of the livestock. This amount ordinarily equals $1.00 per 100 pounds, or half the spread between the price of unfinished and fat animals of the class being fed. His share of this spread ordinarily ranges from 50 cents to $1.50 per hundredweight. Sometimes a small bonus is also offered the feeder for very good gains or a penalty designated for very poor gains. This customarily amounts to around 25 to 50 cents per hundred pounds of gain. For the convenience of feeders and growers a speci - men of this contract follows : feeding contract This contract is entered into this day of , 193 by and between of I , , hereinafter called the "grower", and hereinafter called the "feeder". The grower agrees: 1. To deliver to the feeder f. o. b. at stock yards about head of feeder , branded or/and ear marked , free of "culls", "bums", "dogs", "locos", or otherwise objectionable feeding animals, between the day of , 193 , and the day of ,' , 193 , at the grower's option. All animals are to weigh between pounds and.... pounds, the average weight being not less than pounds or more than pounds per head. 2. To guarantee the said animals to have been off feed and water for a period of at least twelve hours immediately prior to weighing and that these animals shall be dry when weighed. 3. To bill said animals to the market F.I.T. , the bill of lading to be attached to the feeder's copy of the contract and to become a part of it except as hereinafter provided under paragraph 2 of the joint agreement. 4. To secure the consent of the mortgagee to this contract if the said animals are mortgaged and to attach such consent hereto. 6. To have payment made, on the basis provided in paragraph 8 of the joint agreement mentioned below, direct to the feeder by the com - mission agency handling the sale of these said animals at the market. '•' I f 'ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ.'. '. Lj..! The feeder agrees: 1. To take possession of said animals at , stock yards and to accept weights of said animals at 2. To feed and/or pasture said animals at feeder's farm located miles from J </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 s_LF* ~ ss__*__a_i _*£&amp;» airss 4. To sort out and deliver said animals to ST Sit: &amp; iD the °^ iS tnecommi=-nrmhandHng is moSgSVn'd 6 Xl n \am^heS gagee *° "* C °" tract if the « It is jointly agreed that: shall be P »^_H ° ri^ nal u eights of said animals at shall be attached to and become a part of this contract. " -. Freight charges shall be advanced by to be later deducted with interest at "Mr"cent"frn^"+'C sale proceeds of said animals at market before plthprnf tl *% g T- 0SS parties participates in the returns/ T ° f the cont ™cting 3.. Said animals are to be marketed through commission firm at „ n i„~ n „.v '•' a w__ •_ • ,""" unless otherwise mutually aereed 4. The said animals shall be fed and/or pastured for. ._!„_ «fw2 &amp; mann f r *? propria *° otherwise agreed. If said animals gain on the average more rfll pounds per head per day a bonus of „_„♦ r. _ , of gain shall be p_Jd theVeder by fcower" hundred wei_ht __!!!? Charg6S 8nd death l0SS Shail be borne b y /or divided and the feeder shall SmSIIS^ " ! !.._. 8 ..r DCe " hlde Sha " then beCOme th « Property of _._ 6. The feeding in transit tax (a'any7'shali"be"borne "by otherwise agreed. day(s&gt; unless erlsa^iSLSt S'S'* 1 ''? "f ?J d *"«&gt;' -"» •»«■ deducted from the paid direct to the ?JS» 1» «?_ e • 3 °^ nt ¥"«-«-* above, shaU be animals at. .'.".'" " ° n **&gt;**-*&amp; weight of said </seg>
            <seg id="p031">The Contract Feeding of Livestock C After the feeder's deductions have been made, all remaining pro - ceeds from the sale of said animals, except as modified by paragraphs 4, 5, and A above, shall be paid to the grower. 9. In the event that the feeder materially fails at any time to carry out his obligations under this contract, the grower shall be entitled to resume possession of said animals without accountability to the feeder for the feed and labor used or gain produced, except as follows: The grower shall also be entitled to assert all other contract and prop - erty rights otherwise available to him by law. 10. Nothing in this contract shall ever be construed as creating a partnership between the feeder and grower and, likewise, nothing in this contract shall ever be construed as vesting in the feeder the ownership in the above-mentioned animals. Witness Grower Witness — Feeder CONSENT OF MORTGAGEE Of The undersigned moragagee, under the mortgage (s) by the grower referred to in the above contract, consents to the foregoing contract conditioned upon the payment of all sums which shall accrue to said grower under the contract to....^. for account of said grower. Date Mortgagee CONSENT OF MORTGAGEE (grain and feed of feeder) The undersigned mortgagee, under the mortgage(s) by the feeder referred to in the above contract, consents to the foregoing contract conditioned upon the payment of all sums which shall accrue to said feeder under the contract to for account of said feeder. Date Mortgagee GAIN-AT-MARKET-PRICE FEEDING CONTRACT A contract for this popular and equitable plan, as discussed under "The Gain-basis Plan", can be written by substituting the following paragraph in place of paragraph 8 on page 30 under the joint agreement in the feeding contract: </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 It is jointly agreed that: from the finished weights of said animals at..... "j" addition, the feeder shall receive. : dou'ars"iw'e'a'ch"hundred - weight or fraction thereof of the original, or.. «~«™1 THE INVESTMENT-BASIS PLAN This type of contract, though not so simple as the irain-basis mSeS 8 to e^ir° Und Uvest0ck , ?«**&lt;*-* to divide riskl incident to falling prices, as well as the profits to be gained by rising prices, on a more equitable basis than any other &amp;_&amp;K?T^h The **** is that regardSs of wheth-r SL?!iSr g i flP H^ P^ 3 or loses mon ey, the profits or losses will be divided between the feeder and grower on a basis of whafr each has invested. With certain it has been used extensively in northern Colorado^JJSSSLi This contract calls for the feeder and grower to jointtyi£ ventory the grower's livestock (using a disinterested Tarty tf Hwith added interest charges during the feeding period, equals the grower's invest - ment. In a like rnan - and other overhead' costs of the feeder are inventoried. The sum of these equals the feeder's investment, transferred from the grower's ranch to the Is he fat? Sorting should be done by an feeder's lots where experienced man. " they are fattened. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">The Contract Feeding of Livestock When the finished livestock is sold the income, after freight and marketing charges have been deducted, is divided be- ' tween the grower and feeder on a basis of the amount that each has invested in the operation. Here again it is import - ant that adequate provision be made for shrinks, death loss, and overhead costs, as well as feed costs. The chief disadvantages of this' plan lie in the fact that [the feeder may through negligence or mismanagement obtain a very inefficient gain or suffer an extremely heavy death loss. Unless provision is made against this the grower suffers from this error of the feeder. In order to avoid such an injustice two plans have been devised. The one suggested by the Colo - rado Agricultural College stipulates that the feeder's invjest - ment shall be based on the net gain he puts on the animals at the average cost per pound of gain, with feed prices, death loss, and various overhead costs considered. This appears to be a very logical solution. The other plan requires that the grower employ a representative who through constant con - tact with the feeding operation looks after his (the grower's) interests. Both plans have worked well in actual practice!. Colorado and Wyoming bankers have worked out a contract based on the last named of these two plans which provides for an advance by the financing bank to the grower, or the mortgagee of his livestock, as well as an arrangement for; the additional financing of the feeder. It also provides that from the net proceeds of the sale of the livestock the feeder's ex - penses are first paid and then the grower is reimbursed for the inventoried price of his livestock. Any remaining sum is then divided equally between them. The disadvantage of this arrangement lies in the fact that should the price of the finished livestock go down considerably during the feeding operation, the burden of this reduction would have to be borne, in the main, by the grower. A contract for feeding in accordance with the Colorado in - ventory plan can be written by substituting the following paragraph in the place of paragraph 8 (on page 30) of the feeding contract. It is jointly agreed that: 8. After the marketing costs and freight have been deducted from the gross proceeds of the sale of said animals, the remaining sum shall be divided between the contracting parties according to the percentage of their respective investments in the finished animals, to-wit: A. Mortgagees whose consents are attached to this contract shall be paid according to the terms, expressed in such consents. -B. The feeder's investment shall be calculated when the animals are sold on the basis of. dollars for each one hundred pounds of gain or fraction thereof that he adds to the weight of the animals </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 wp1t d 1 + C °«!?f'ii 8^ rin^\.- death loss ' and overhead considered). The gain in weSJ or 6 "2 C ° , ? ,PUted by deducti^ theo^na" weignt or. on the said animals at yards from the finished weight of the said animals at.Z " S deli^ryT 1^ fSd^ufuf WAftaSBW ffuo^r tHe dUrati^ S ffi VaJue of - «*• of at $ per ewt. or ? Interest on $ for days at % o _ % ' Grower's investment .... * be mJd&amp;^S 8^ »*^1fl^ X ° f tbe t otal jnvestments shown above'shall The bonus feature contained in paragraph 4 and the death S Jtt tUIe c ° nteined in Paragraph 5*sh?ul2 be eliminated since they are taken care of under the investment plan! THE STRAIGHT INVENTORY CONTRACT (Inv.stm.ut) To prepare a contract for feeding on an out-and-out in ventory basis the following paragraph should be substituted -S?S a Ss?fct: Under the j ° int a * reement &lt; PaSsO) ofS It is jointly agreed that: a ___rs_i^F^^ hss JS'a MoTt gageea whose consents are attached to this contract shall be paid according to the terms .expressed in such consents ' . /,, * eeder s investment shall be a sum equal to the invent™-..*! £*?** hay tons at $ per ton or $ Shelled corn bushels at $ per bushel or ? ~ ab ? r days at $ per day or ? ..ZZ' Equipment and rental charges of « Interest on all feed value for days at....' '....% per' annum! Feeder's total investment " ""'"% Jintu ♦S_ B i t 5? t *" 0f . the abo _ e f^ eds are not » 8ed to 'fatten the said \^.^'J^ P( i^ lm L n0t s 0 ™ 3^ shall be deducted from the feeder's £S3 ?«._* the prices, and if additional feeds are h?S^25'F aa J!? U *J_ e S™.*. a . 4 market P rfce and their cost shall n mF a part of the feeder's investment. „„i„r'JFlf- ero^ er ' 8 investment shall be a sum equal to the inventoried value of kii said animals at the time of delivery to the feeder plus Tl^^^^ at T in w , l*i 0ried 7S lue for the Nation of the feeding period. This sum is calculated as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p035">The Contract Feeding of Livestock Value of ewt. of. at $ per ewt. or $ I Interest on $ for days at % or $ j...... Grower's investment $ 1 D. Reimbursements on the basis of the total investments shown above shall be made, except as modified by paragraphs 5 and A above, direct to the feeder and the grower respectively by the commission firm selling the livestock. E. The grower hereby designates J....... as his representative to look after his interests in this operation and it is mutually agreed that he shall have the privilege of inspecting the said animals and consulting with the feeder on methods of feeding to be employed. " The bonus feature in paragraph 4 should be eliminated 'and it should be designated that veterinary and death losses should be divided between the feeder and the grower on the same basis as the net proceeds. THE CUSTOM FEEDING PLAN This plan is particularly suitable for a grower who desires to have his livestock fattened for market at his own risk] It is also applicable to a feeder who is hesitant about feeding because of thtf' financial risks involved but who has sufficient feed to fatten some livestock and desires to feed on his own premises in order to obtain the manure. When fed on this basis, the livestock is shipped by, the grower to the feeder's lots where they are fattened for market. This is done under the grower's direction and the feeder is paid an agreed price for all feeds used as well as for his labor and other overhead expenses. When the livestock is marketed, the feeder's compensation comes ahead of all other obligations except freight and marketing "expenses. As is customary in the other types of contracts, the title of the livestock remains in the name of the grower. Death loss is usually borne by the grower, except for such loss as may result directly from the negligence or mismanagement of the feeder. Often the grower purchases the feed outright and pays the feeder a stipulated price per head per day for feeding the livestock. Or the feeder may be paid each month for all or a part of the feed and labor used in feeding the livestock during that period. In this event the feeder is practically ah em - ployee of the grower and the obligations of the contract ap - proach those of an employer and his employee. Or the arrangement may approach that used under the gainfbasis agreement in which the feeder is regulalry paid for the gain he adds to the livestock at a specified price. The same contract form as that employed under the gain - basis plan (page 29) may be used except that paragraph 8 under the joint agreement (page 30) should be changed </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 so as to designate the manner in which payment will be made the amounts and time of such payments" and who if anybody is to be appointed as the grower's representative. anyD0(ly ' feeds fn?n^ U it .,T er t IK !5 8ible ._ 0 discuss a * reat many rations for cattle and lambs, it would not be desirable in a discussion fee / in *&gt; 2* f ° ll0Win * discussion is! l££££. confined to a few of the very common feeds and feedine methods. The data presented are based upon trials conducted at various experiment stations during the last fifteen years jjj6jfrfrv&gt;. ' -^ . ' z.^. : T% &gt;„ • J ■ Ks___SaiWs_is_BW"»aBMi^5Bw^* ( * ivrcJjv*:" ■* *&gt; v^tk - ) ■'^-»aM-s»rS&amp;[s»»»»s»»»^^ V . 1 __| Icr^^K s»_aW^^ass^asssssssssssss—aaa—B~^ . . - J^^^M^tfflliBBffltffr' _■ * * Contract feeding on an extensive scale. The purpose is to bring out only those factors that have a direct bearing upon contract feeding. In the preceding dis - cussion all data have been based upon the standard Corn Belt ration, shelled corn and alfalfa. If additional data on a par - ticular ration are desired, the reader should write to his ex - periment station. FEEDS FOR CATTLE Corn. — In the United States, corn is the principal grain crop used in the fattening ration of livestock. It is therefore used in the following discussion as a standard with which to compare the value of other feeds. Grinding or cracking corn. — The cracking of corn is or - dinarily not advisable unless it is very dry and hard, or there </seg>
            <seg id="p037">The Contract Feeding of Livestock are no hogs following the cattle. Where grinding is resorted to, the cost, which amounts to approximately 3 cents per bushel, should be added to the price. Coarse grinding, or cracking, costs much less and gives better results than fine grinding. The cost of fine grinding is almost double that of cracking. Ground ear corn. — Some alfalfa hay is saved by the sub - stitution of ground ear corn for shelled corn. The daily gain made by the cattle is slightly less but the cost of gain is not materially changed because of the saving of hay. When cotton - seed cake is used to supplement ground ear corn and no hay is fed, one ton of cottonseed cake is equal to three tons of alfalfa. Danger of overfeeding, or founder, is reduced by the feeding of ground ear corn. To finish the animal it is desirable to add shelled corn and to decrease the allowance of ground ear corn. Ground snapped corn. — Ground snapped corn is more valuable for fattening two-year-olds and yearlings than calves or lambs. Most feeders prefer to start on ground snapped corn, gradually changing to ground ear corn and then to shelled corn. Fed in this manner, 1.15 pounds of ground snapped corn are equal to approximately 1 pound of shelled corn. Some alfalfa is saved by feeding ground snapped corn, but the gains made by the cattle are slightly less and the feed - ing period is increased. Wheat. — Wheat should be cracked for cattle. The cost of cracking is approximately 3 cents per bushel. Wheat has proved equal to corn, pound for pound, in feeding value where one-third or one-half of the grain ration consisted of lyheat and the rest corn. The extra weight in a bushel of wheat under most conditions pays for the cost of grinding and, as a result, the feed cost can be figured the same as though corn were used. Barley. — Although investigators are not in agreement as to the feeding value of barley, due undoubtedly to the differ - ence in test weight in different localities, evidence points to the fact that it is approximately 90 per cent as valuable, pound for pound, as corn for fattening cattle. Barley should always be fed rolled or coarsely ground. . Molasses. — The feeding value of molasses is generally regarded as being equal to that of corn, pound for pound. One of the main values of molasses lies in its palatability and that it induces a slightly heavier consumption of feed. Dried beet pulp. — Osland • gives dried beet pulp when fed as part of the grain ration, the same replacement value * Osland, H. B., Information to the author. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 as No. 2 shelled corn for fattening cattle. On this basis, the feeding of dried pulp would not affect the cost of gain as given in this bulletin. Wet beet pulp. — The use of wet beet pulp with a grain (barley or corn) and alfalfa ration is generally recommended in the sugar beet growing districts. 6 Where the hauling dis - tance is not too great, wet pulp decreases slightly the cost of feed-lot gains over a straight grain and alfalfa ration. It is estimated that one ton of wet pulp is worth approximately 70 pounds of corn and 575 pounds of alfalfa. Beet tops.- — Few data are available on the feeding value of beet tops as compared to shelled corn. It is believed, how - ever, that an acre of tops is worth slightly more than a ton of corn silage. Silage. — Corn or cane silage is more useful in the fatten - ing ration for calves than for older cattle that are fed for relatively short periods. Where a light feed of silage is given, some hay is saved. One ton of silage is equal to approximately one-third ton of alfalfa when fed with shelled corn to fatten - ing cattle. Where calves are being wintered on silage plus one pound of cottonseed cake or 2.5 pounds of alfalfa per head daily, they will require approximately one ton of silage and 53 pounds of cake or one ton of silage and 160 pounds of alfalfa to produce 100 pounds of gain. Calves so handled can be finished for market in from 100 to 125 days following the winter period. Corn fodder. — Corn or cane fodder should seldom be used in the fattening ration unless alfalfa is scarce and high in price, and then a protein supplement is necessary. Where calves are wintered on ground corn fodder supplemented by one pound of cottonseed cake per head daily or 2.5 pounds of alfalfa, they will require approximately 850 pounds of fodder and 60 pounds of cake or 165 pounds of alfalfa to produce 100 pounds of gain. Clover hay. — Good red-clover hay is practically equal, pound for pound, to alfalfa hay. It should be figured at the same price as alfalfa in calculating the cost of gain. Prairie hay. — Where prairie hay and shelled corn are fed, 40 per cent more corn is required than where corn is fed with alfalfa. If a protein supplement is added to a ration of shelled corn and prairie hay, 5 per cent more corn is needed to produce 100 pounds of gain than with shelled corn and alfalfa, or 35 per cent less corn than where corn and prairie hay are fed. From 1_ to 2 pounds of linseed or cottonseed per head daily should be fed with a ration of shelled corn and prairie hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">The Contract Feeding of Livestock Protein supplements (cottonseed and linseed meal or cake).— Linseed meal is generally considered somewhat more valuable per ton than cottonseed meal. The difference, however, is slight and it is doubtful that linseed meal or cake is worth more than three to five dollars more per ton than cottonseed meal or cake. Because of a greater daily gain and increased efficiency of feed utilization, the addition of 1 to 1% pounds of linseed meal or cottonseed meal to a ration I ot shelled corn and alfalfa does not increase the cost of gain materially if the supplement is worth not more than twice the price of corn per ton. The market value of the cattle is usually increased by the feeding of a protein concentrate. FEEDS FOR SHEEP The two most common methods of fattening lambs have been discussed and the feed required for 100 pounds of gain given for each of these methods. Space does not permit a discussion of all types of lamb feeding and, as a result, only a few of the more important feeds are mentioned. Corn.— As previously stated, corn is the principal grain used in the fattening ration and ranks at the top of the | list of feeds for sheep. The cost data have, therefore, been based upon corn, and other feeds are compared to it in later dis - cussions. 1_W i ?' A ~ :: '" i *r^~? T 3r£, _[ __f\ J ~" '—'" *—!* J. I J__Vm_m. _ A . . . _^_Sjmgt^fff^ | ■\^'^^^^^^^'2Av Z" Ssss__Bs_S^ r "«7«^ i r /P^^-^rfes-* - '•'—'* T?ZZ*tf&amp;$ '"^*^mP?* L" 'VasSS-aVi. J___^^_[_\_\_\_\_\_\_i \r^t_U_ ■ '..' _w^ _'%r__*__\ ______\_\mll__\ fesftaMF ' ■ f ~\A$Sr^_\^^^ '-^a\_W B-T^^^^^^a-L^TlS '*^_^____f_Z^^tr^.fff' l\__^__\_\\w_ __t.___t ' r -*a\ '^ia_\\ _t__\ i ' Jf \^^_(yL____^' *• B_-j_BTS*^_BY _. \faBBBSlSa_BB__a_B_-l _\*^4. ■ ■• u^AasW bVVWIbb_I_I ll [7 ■7..1k_,. -WllM-s^ Ma-a-T ' . W»'^»Sb^bb^bbb»_b__b_I Contract lambs in feed lots. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 feedS? t?^ r £?* n -* bu * _ large Percentage of the lamb gSSsSSSSs sStton?Mfl_ton^S.2 "f Wor !&lt; at thc of corn andlw plS, o?Sa "^iSffS 114 f P"-* 1 v^s^di?aW^! fieW fed in dry lot ' which in - nSf^T" 1 v numerous trials at the Scottsbluff Substarim, PHSSS33_ftS_gS ' Lascelles. H. R.. Information to the author. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">The Contract Feeding of Livestock tana, Wyoming, and Colorado where barley has a heavier test weight than in Nebraska, the feeding value, pound for pound, approaches 93 per cent that of corn. In numreous trials con - ducted at the Colorado Station, 7 100 pounds of shelled corn was equal to 108 pounds of barley (trebi) and saved 19 pounds of alfalfa. Wheat. — In two trials conducted at the Nebraska Station (11), whole wheat was 85 to 88 per cent as efficient in pro - ducing gain as shelled corn. A mixture of one-fourth wheat and three-fourths corn is equal to shelled corn. Molasses. — Cane molasses and beet molasses are of equal value, pound for pound, when mixed with alfalfa meal (12). Protein supplements (linseed oil meal and cottonseed meal). — Protein supplements are worth less for lambs than for cattle. This is particularly true in western lamb-feeding practices. Under these practices, it is doubtful if supple - ments are worth any more per ton than corn. Under Corn Belt conditions where not more than 50 per cent of the ration is alfalfa or clover, the value of a ton of protein supplement is not greater than 1V_ tons of corn. Averaging 14 trials, Weber (12) gives the replacement value of one ton of linseed meal as equal to 40 bushels of shelled corn and one ton of alfalfa hay. Daily gain was increased 0.05 pound. The feeding period was short, however, averaging 76 days. On the basis of the comparisons made above, the cost of gain is not materially changed by the addition of a supple - ment to corn and alfalfa. With a greater spread between supplements and corn, the cost of gain is increased. !The daily gain and the sale value of the lamb are increased slightly by the addition of a protein supplement to corn and alfalfa. Silage. — Silage (10) shows no marked effect on the daily gains or selling price of lambs, but reduces the amount of alfalfa required to produce 100 pounds of gain. One ton of silage is equal to approximately one-half ton of alfalfa, j Clover. — Good quality clover is equal to alfalfa for fat - tening lambs. Alfalfa meal. — In three trials at the Nebraska Station (12), one ton of alfalfa meal fed with shelled corn was worth more than one ton of alfalfa hay. The difference in feeding value was due in part to the fact that no waste occurred! with the meal, while approximately 10 per cent of the hayj was refused. The use of alfalfa meal lowered the death loss. Alfalfa molasses meal. — Alfalfa meal and alfalfa molas - ses meal (12) had approximately the same feeding value when fed to lambs that were crowded to the limit on corjn. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 of three i _____U ■ ___\t &lt;^^Z.l____________m ' _aa_a_ - -bbbb-T 'IBr -P^:WBs __%_¥ '*W ' ' ' ' -a____»_r^ ■ • -asm _! ■ '■' - ia • -J_WJ_W'. - '4-^m _af </seg>
            <seg id="p043">The Contract Feeding of Livestock experimental data on gains made by steers TABLE 11 Two-year-old Steers i ■ ~~ 50 715 100 I 125 1150 175 200" days days days days days days days Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. ) Lbs. Lbs. | Lbs. Lbs. Average daily ration Shelled corn 13.05 16.08 16.67 18.37 17.28 17.53 17.77 Alfalfa hay 10.11 8.51 8.07 8.51 8.49 7.32 7.00 Feed per 100 lbs. gain - - Shelled corn 508 614 662 750 742 808 1793 Alfalfa hay 393 325 320 347 364 837 313 Average daily gain 2.57 2.62 2.52 2.45 2.33 I 2.17 2.24 Average initial weight.... 847 873 847 878 828 845 867 Number of cattle. 63 75 63 113 127 73 i 30 Number of trials 6 7 6 11 14 7 I 3 Yearling Steers 75 100 126 150 175 |200 t days days days days days days Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Average daily ration Shelled corn 13.38 15.11 14.92 16.55 14.88 15.46 Alfalfa hay 8.11 7.83 7.48 6.87 6.67 1 5.88 Feed per 100 lbs. gain Shelled corn 646 609 654 704 689 '■ 700 Alfalfa hay 331 316 328 292 309 266 Average daily gain 2^45 2.48 I 2.28 JT35 2.16 2.21 Average initial weight. 659 665 648 665 648 | 659 Number of cattle _ 79 79 69 79 58 30 Number of trials 7 7 6 7 1 5 I 3 Steer Calves I 100 I 150 I 175 I; 200 &gt;1 days days days 1 days Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Average daily ration Shelled born 9.15 10.64 10.95 ; 11.66 Alfalfa hay 5.59 5.08 4.80 4.30 Feed per 100 lbs. gain Shelled corn 410 479 500 528 Alfalfa hay 251 229 219 195 Average daily gain 2.23 2/22" 2.19 I 2.21 Average initial weight .'. 371 371 369 376 Number of cattle 164 164 121 50 Number of trials 11 11 8 4 i </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 274 The date presented in Table 11 are based on a weighted SOS. °L nu 5 ierou . 8 steer-feeding experimnts conducted at the Nebraska Experiment Station. All trials included tetwl twSSL 1 ** 8 *£* cond V«ted since m^Tte^Stfm^t in^ TSf^w« t8 iT ere 2? 0f *°° d ualit y an d of belf Seed" ing. This table shows the source of material for the data on grains and feed costs presented earlier in this TbuUetin literature cited 1. U. S. Department of Agriculture, Bui. 25, pp. 73.74 2 - Fuller. J- G., and Roche, B. H. fiS 11^, Crossbred versus Purebred Calves for Baby Beeves Wis. Agr. Exp. Sta. Mimeo. Circular. 3. Gerlaugh, Paul, and Gay, C. W. 1931. Ohio Bimonthly Bui. 152, Sept.-Oct.. p. 179 4. Gramlich, H.J. . ' F 1928. Fattening Steers op Various Ages. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. B ' G _?, ml L ch ' H - J " and Thalman, R. R. 15. Sta. But 25 8 2 FACTORS m CAT ™ FEEDING - Nebr - Agr. 6. Mitchell, H. H. 1921 * &amp; Gra pbicju- Presentation of the J^jxajvcjaz. Pita*™* »* - x. ,_ T T Exn_u KEmS . KL Asc, Ex,. dZ^Tz&amp; T 7. Holden, J. A. ms. Emam_NT._ ™ W*™ t^*^. k*_. 8. Holden, J. A. 1928 * n^Sr^-^S 1 k E F Bra X HNTS IN THB Sugar Beet Growing Districts. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bah 216. G .. Co\o. T_xp. Sta. _ttmeo. Circular 1981. A^RsraED Contact Plan for Lamb Feeding on Shares. 10. Holden, J. A. 1982. Lamb g-g£jg--«Mm« Graxns and Dried P UtPS . "* «^Tr A - D - and Loeffel, Wm. J. „ " 8 i; W f B * T *° B Fattening Lambs. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 257. 12. Weber, A. D., and Fox, H. D. 1931. Alfalta Mo^bse, Meal for Fattening Lambs. Nebr. Agr. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>