<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00020.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00020.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Sixteenth Annual Report of the Secretary of the State Banking Board Showing the Condition of the BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF NEBRASKA For the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1908.  Submitted to the Governor and the State Banking Board September 1, 1908.</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">of the St&lt;vte Banking Boa.rd Showing the Condi- tion of the BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF NEBRASKA For the Fiscal Year Ending June 30. 1908. Submitted to the Governor and the State Banking Board September I. 1908 By E. ROYSE. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">DEPARTMENT OP BANKING OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA BOARD K. M. SEARLE, JI L. G. BRIAN Auditor of Public Accounts and President HON HON State Treasurer W. T. THOMPSON Attorney General E. R( N. R MAU )YS1- Secretary PERSINGKR Chief Clerk DE HOOK EXAMINERS E. E. EMMETT C. H. BEAUMONT W. ERVV1N E. S. MICKEY ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p004">State of Nebraska, Department of Banking, ) T :__„!_ C5 i. 1 1 iiiau I Lincoln, September 1, 1906. ) To His Excellency, George L. Sheldon, Governor of Nebraska, and the Honorables E. M. Searle, Jr., L. G. Brian and W. T. Thompson, the State Banking Board of the State of Nebraska: Gentlemen:— In compliance with section 3a of Chapter 8 of the Compiled Statutes of the State of Nebraska for 1903 re - quiring the Secretary of the State Banking Board to make to the Governor and State Banking Board annual reports. I have the honor to submit herewith the sixteenth annual report of the department of banking for the period beginning July 1, 1 !♦•'", and ending June 30, 1908, showing the condition of the building and loan associations of the State of Nebraska at the close of business June 30, 1908, compiled from annual reports of the several building and loan associations submitted to the State Banking Board, in accordance with the provisions of the building and loan act, approved April 4, 1899. Tabulated state - ments, detailed reports, and such information and comments touching this report as is deemed beneficial will be found on the following pages. Very respectfully, E. ROYSE, secretary State Banking Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Compiled from the Annual Reports of the Building and Loan Associations for the years from 1892, the first year re - ports were received, to 1908 inclusive, showing the totals of all Building and Loan associations in the state for the years above </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 31st day of December. ASSETS. First Mortgage Loans $2,235,1 Loans secured by stock of association •■ 175,160.37 Real estate 50,141 .73 Expenses and taxes paid 75,632.66 Cash with treasurer 69.'.' All other assets 296,523 . 96 Total $2,902,557 . 67 LIABILITIES. Capital stock pail, up $1,924,784.12 Premiums paid 393,103 . IS Interest received 434,859 . 82 Fines collected 33,797 . 48 Other liabilities 116,013.09 Total $2,902,557.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1892. RKlKIPTS. Balance on hand December 31, 1891 i 61,250.27 Dues 515,492.54 Interest 176.50S.51 Fines 10,999.81 Loans repaid 197,409.15 Other receipts 62,945.58 Total 11,024,600.81 EXPENDI1 URES. Loans »641,548.63 Other expenses 10,769 . 46 Withdrawals 199,864.38 Other expenditures 84,478.95 Cash on hand 70.38J.J3 Total Jl.024.600.81 RECAPITULATION. Number of shares in force at last report 41.1* Number of shares issued during year i« .«• Number of shares matured, withdrawn and cancelled 10.553V4 Vumber of shares in force at this date 4&amp;.umi </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THI BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th day of December, 1893. ASSETS ■s secured oy stock of associations estate n»es and taxes paid. Other assets not enumerated above Total LIABILITIES Capital stock paid up Premiums paid Interest received. Fines collected. . . Other liabilities. . Total </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 30, 1893. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand December 31, 1892 $ 79.059.69 Dues 683,746.81 Interest 213,170 . 25 Fines 8.342 . 15 Loans repaid 817,377. 6« Other receipts 87,613 . 70 $1,289,310.26 Total EXPENDITURES. Loans $741,692.54 Salaries 22.141 .11 Other expenses 16. Withdrawals 317,610.88 &lt; a-li on hand 73,576.93 ilaneous expenditures 117,973.84 Total $1,289,310.26 RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR 1893. Number of shares in force at last report MJKt Number of shares issued during current year Number of shares matured, withdrawn and cancelled .... 11.027 Number of shares in force at this date 61.964 RECAPITULATION Number of associations in force December 31, 1892 71 Number of associations discontinued during year 3 Number of new associations during year 16 Number of associations in force December 31, 1893 84 </seg>
            
            <seg id="p010">10 SUMMARY OK THE CONDITION' OF THK BttlLDINC; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATE OF NEBRASKA On the :tl&gt;t day of December, 1SSI4 ASSETS mortgage loans $2,835,105.62 iired by stock of association 27l!o58!59 estate and taxes paid 130 4gg 15 with treasurer 70130 82 Other assets 463,605.00 Total $3,888,001.31 LIABILITIES. Capital stock paid up J2 694 342 84 Premiums paid "'411 'ns9 in T__* . . •■••.•.....,, tll,Ufl4, l\t Interest received .....' 601 163 24. Fines collected .......'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 36.258 .13 All other liabilities ......'..'..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 145;i54:40 Total $3,888,001.31 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 SUMMARY OP SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND KXl'KNIMTl'RKS FOR THK FISCAL YKAR KNDING DECEMBER 31, 1894. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand December 31, 1893 $ 69,115.94 Dues 775.7*3. «4 Int.r-st 225,288. M 8,812.80 Loans repaid L'4:S.632.18 Other receipts 122,357 . 61 Total $1,444,910.9* EXPENDITURES. Loans $671,S96.81 Salaries 27.- Other expenses 22,495.44 Withdrawals 421.833.51 Other expenditures 72." Cash on hand 229.418.87 Total $1,444,910.99 RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR EXDING DECEMRER 31, 1894. Number of shares in force at last report 61,059 1-10 Number of shares issued during year 26.712^4 Number of shares matured, withdrawn and cancelled .... 16,540 1-10 Number of shares in force at this date RECAPITULATION Number of associations in force December 31, 1893 84 Number of associations discontinued during year 3 Number of new associations during year 5 Number of associations in force December 31, 1894 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 SUMMARY OE THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 31st day of December, 1895 ASSETS. First mortgage loans $2,818,386.84 Loans secured by stock of associations 267.543 . 48 Real estate 150.245.20 Expenses and taxes paid 139,043 . 38 Cash with treasurer 62.889 . 84 All other assets 486,669 . 53 Total $3,929,778.2 LIABILITIES Capital stock paid up $2,744,413.83 Premiums paid 338,048 . 53 Interest received 505,182.46 Pines collected 37,098.26 All other liabilities 300,035 . 19 Total $3,929,778.27 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 rMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1895. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand December 31, 1894 $ 63,484.94 Dues 775,161 .51 Fines 7.454.8* Loans repaid 250 Other receipts 132.526 . 45 Total $1,445.M».» EXPENDITURES. Loans $678,602.11 salaries Jo,.' Other expenses Withdrawals 447 Other expenditures 62.^ Cash on hand 203.764.7* $1.445,2«0.» Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1895. Number of shares in force it last report 70 Number of shares issued during year 22.034 % Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and cancelled .... 21.676 Number of shares in force at this date 7n.fil5 RECAPITULATION. Number of associations in force December 31, 1894 S6 Number of associations discontinued during the year .... 8 Number of new associations during the year S Number of associations in force December 31, 1895 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE Hl'ILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OK NEBRASKA On the 31st day of December, ISM ASSETS First mortgage loans $2,832,071.61 First mortgage loans in proo&lt; Real estate for closur 117,368.24 177,492.84 Furniture and fixtures 2,175.84 56.891.46 Due from shareholders Expenses and taxes paid Other assets 98.763.82 169.497.26 317,572.46 Total 71,833.53 LIABILITIES Dues paid $2.582,078 . 82 Premiums unearned 100,537.55 Profits undivided including reserve fund 382.320.47 Profits apportioned to shares i n force 42H.408.76 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 10,572.08 Other liabilities 266,915 85 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE DECEMBER 31. 1896. RECEIPTS AND KAPEN'DITURES FOR THE TEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1896. RECEIPTS. KAPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1896. RECEIPTS. RECEIPTS Balance on hand December 31,1895 , it''.'.'.'.'.'.''.'.*.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.''.'.".'."''.'.'.'.".'.*'.'.'." repaid Balance on hand Dec 3mber 31,1895 » 88,470.44 mber 31,1895 * 88,470.44 778,083.64 778,083.64 216.J 7,021.04 216.: 7,011. M » repaid receipt ti.JSX.97 Other receipts 1 otal 117.: 117.340.73 Total $1,463,502.36 $1,463. EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURES. EX PEN DIT URES 1650. 26." I 114.4 Salaries .'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 26.:'. ; 114,447.29 370,924.08 Other expenses Other exper Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues . Withdrawals, earnini Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earni Cash on hand 370,9 58 102.7 Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings ngs Cash on hand Total 54 ■ ■ $1,461! Total $1,463 RECAPITULATION RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1896. OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1896. END1NT, DECEMBER 31, 189 Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares in Number of shares n force at last report 64/ force at last report 64.62 Number of shares matured during current year . . latured .luring current year atured during current year Number of shares in force at this date force at this date 64,891% force at this date 64.891% Number of shares in Number of loans n ■ Number of loans made for the payment of hom mortgages during current year ade for the payment of home tead ade for the payment of hon ■ ng current year teases dur ng current year Nunil*r of shares issued .liirins; current year uied dartag current year current year Xumlier Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled durin rent year withdrawn and cancelled during cur- Number of shar hdrawn and cancelled during cur 16. • nt year Number of loans made for building purposes durin rent year de for building purposes during cur- for building purposes during cur- us t year lers ".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. issued since organization .... 114.116 Number of shareholders SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Number of shart 1 3UPPLEMEN TAL REPORT Number of share? &gt;f «trwk issued since organizatic since organization Number of sharf ued Number of series of stock issued sine,, organization XiimlxT stock issued sine,, organization stock withdrawn and cancelled tock Issued sine,, organization stock withdrawn and cancelled NumMer of shares of stock withdrawn and cancelled NumlVr of share Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure . . . s in process of foreclosure of foreclosure Number of mortf II Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure . . appraised value of real estate and improvi ■ curity s in process of foreclosure * 111 in process of foreclosure •♦ 111" ie of real estate and improvements at and improvements 4.40fi.9«9.10 Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the ation- as collateral security &gt; in force and assigned to the associ- md igned to the associ x pral security 2.44 1 at ion- as collateral Value of other real estate he'd by the association- r real estate he'd by estate he'd by the association - SHARES STATEMENT. ■uied r thf issociation SHARES STATEMENT. HARES STATEMENT Total number of series issued Total n led res issued 77.371 %i Total number of shares issued Total number of shares issue tres withdrawn 41.850^4 Tota 1 nrniber of shares withdrawn tbdrawn ires lonned on lfi.BfiC 1^ Total number of shares loaned on number of shares outstanding if sharps loaned on ires ont-taniling 30,528% RECAPITULATION. To'al number of shares outstanding RECAPITULATION. LATTON RECAPITI Numb, r of associations in force December 31, 1895 &gt;ns in force December 31, 1895 81 mber 31, 189 Number rce Dec in; discontinued during year ... 1J Namber of association-; discontinued during year . Number of association* discontinued during year Numi.er of new associations during year iriat i &gt;ns during year in&lt;! in force December 31. 1896 73 -1 Number of associations in force December 31, 1896 </seg>
            
            <seg id="p016">16 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 31st day of December, 1k&lt;)7 ASSETS First mortgage loans $2,672,466.66 mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 60,948.60 Real estate 209,682.96 Furniture and fixtures 2,265.34 Cash 81,177 72 Expenses and taxes paid 69&gt; Due from shareholders 75,927 . 49 a»M-i&gt; 3NS.443 "Jo Total $3,554,788.08 LIABILITIES Dues paid $2,368,117.05 Premiums unearned 52.003 . 58 Profit s undivided, including reserve fund 296,690.38 Profits apportioned to shares in force 366,921.84 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 7,854 .74 Other liabilities 463.200.49 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR DECEMBER 31, 1897 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1897. RECEIPTS. XPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS. Balance on hand .*&gt;cembtr 31, lv Dues Balance on ham Dues «Dber 31. KS9« j 53,717. 16 Interest Intt 23ii Fin*'* Loans repaid 427 I Other receipts '.'.'.'.'. Total Total $1,631,105.03 EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURES. EXPEN Loans Loans Salari Salaries Other expenses Withdawals, dues 406 I Withdrawals, earning: Matured stock, dues . Matured stock, earnin Cash on hand Withdrawals, earnings 1 H7.157.12 Matured stock, dues 102,914.4a Matured stock, earnings 5s Cash on hand ......'. Total :;»9.69 11,(31406.01 RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACT ENDING DECEMBER SI, 'F SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR NDING DECEMBER 31. I DING DECEMBER 31 Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares in nice at last report last report • _ ■ Number of shares matured during Ue current ired during tue current year 1 during t.ie current year Number of slime, in force at this date srce at this date at this date Number of loans made for payment of home Rages during fiscal year Number of loans ma e for payment of homestead mort - al year payment of homestead mort- Number of shares issued during current year d during; current year 21 Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled dur »r drawn and cancelled during current wn and cancelled during current year , Number of loans made for building purposes current year Number of loans mad i for building purposes during the for building purposes during th current Number of shareholders SUPPLEMENTAL REPO Number of sharehold UPPLKMBNTAL REPORT. PPLEMENTAL REPORT Number of shares of stock issued since organi: Number of share Number of series lock issued since organization i.v. &gt;ck issued since organization 155 k issued since organization Number of series of stcck issued since organiza ek issued since organization Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled drawn and cancelled Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure n process of foreclosure M l&gt;r Amount of mortgages in process of f r, -closure Amount of mortgages in process of f clllSlll Fmuiiiii m mortgages in process of foreclosure .. | - otal appraised value of real estate and Imnrovemei and lmprovenit as sepurit I Anmunt of insurance in force and x igned to the as iilHin as collateral security Value of other real estate held h real estate held by associations n 183.114.24 SHARKS S T ATEMENT Total number of series issued Total numb lares issued Toal number of shares withdrawn ATION Number of associations in fore- I)e&lt; nilier II, I8M Number ions discontinued during year w associations during rear Number utions in force December 31, Is 47,120 % Total number of sharps loaned on Total number of shares outstan ; in ■ RECAPIT </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NKBKASKA On the .{1st day of December, 1898 ASSKTS ■ mortgage loans $2,821,703.11 mortgage loans in process of foreclosure :.17.89 B"*«te 19z!450.98 Furniture and fixture 2.091.34 146.254.88 uses and taxes paid Due from shareholders 47.464.38 Other assets IH.047^04 Total $3,428,728.11 LIABILITIES il stock paid u| $2,906.86 Profits undivided, including reserve fund 0.247. SI Premiums unearned 47,517.51 Dm shareholders on incomplete loans 476.18 Advance payments 44 Matured stock unpaid 110 120^64 110.12H. 66 Other liabilities Total </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1898 RECE IF TS Balance on hand ijecember 31, 18 t -.- Loans repaid Other receipts 417.7S7.59 188,624.15 Total *1,846,8«6.74 HI TURES. EX PEN »757,1 Salaries 29.4S1.43 191.fi: Other expense Withdrawals, du Withdrawals, earnings Matured stork, dues ■ Matured stock, earnings Cash on hand 14fi.254.85 Total THE YEAR RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR ENDING DECEMBER :S1 Number of shares in force at last re|&gt;ort N'umber of shares matured during current year Numl&gt;er of shares issued during current year 26 Numl&gt;er of shares issued during current year Numlier of shares withdrawn and cancelled during current Number of shares in force at this datf Number of loans for payment of homes tead mortgages dur- ing current year Nuniher of loans made for building r rent year turposes during cur- Number of sharehold PPLEMEN TAL REPORT foreclosure Number of WMTtgMtM in prao Amount of mortgages in proc Total appraised fmtaa of real Ml foreclosure ♦ 61,461 84 ate and improvements held as securit ■nt of insurance in force and assigned to the Associ ntwip- as collateral seeuritv of other real estate held by the associations RECAPITULATION Number of associations in force December 31, 1897 fi( * Number of associations discontinued during year 4 Number of associations in force December 31. 1898 M </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OF THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK THE STATK OF NEBRASKA On the 3(&gt;th day of June. I8»H ASSETS. ASSETS First mortgage loans $2,858,910 72 mortgage loans $2,858,910 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 37,253 50 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 37,253 Real estate 165.O94 Real estate W6.9M Furnture and Fixtures Funrture and Fixtures Cash 146.099 Cash H6.I : .mil taxes paid 11,586 : and taxes paid 41 Due from shareholders 42,838 nsstts 38.477 Due from shareholders 42.838 . 86 asset* 38.477.17 Total $3,332,781 Total *::,n::2.7si . kt LIABILITIES. LIAUILITIJ Capital stock paid up $2,sr,s.:no ■ : , I stock paid up $2,868,310.44 Profits undivided, including reserve fund 2,0,1:',:! Profits undivided, including reserve fund 270,1 Premium* unearned 4"&gt;.::!if&gt; Due shareholders on incomplete loans 31,7 Advance payments 24.8X1 .18 Matured stock unpaid Tt,9( Bills payable Of. er labilities 4,61 1. 59 Total I </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE SIX MONTHS ENDING JUNE 30, 1899. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand December 31, 1898 $135,212.83 573.816.56 lnt* re^t Loans repaid Other receipts 169.994.74 Total $1,294 EXPENDITURES. $546.4 87,794.33 Other expenses . Withdrawals, dues 95,." 43.113.55 Rirawals, earnings . red stock, dues . . . Matured stock, earnings Cash on hand 144.76C.2S $1,294 Total RECAPITULATION. Number of associations in force at this date 60 Number of shares in force at this date 89.492 T1 \ rl D^^r I 8 n jt ««•*•*••«•*••**■•■••••*••*&gt;•*••* * ** t *- * ** </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 SUM MARY OK THK CONDITION OF THE HriLIHNc; AND 1j(&gt;AN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE &lt;&gt;F NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1900 ASSETS First mortgage loans $3,135,360.93 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 28.41fi.36 Stock loana Real estate 130- Furniture and fixtures 2,708.01 Cash 105.^ Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 31,&lt;i Expenses and taxes paid 20,879 . 59 Insurance paid 1 ,553 . 70 Other assets 116,519 . 33 Total $3,697,356.06 LIABILITIES Capital stock running $2,717,380.04 Full paid stock 664,048.92 Reserve fund 46,340 . 69 Undivided profits 159,841.57 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 41,080.61 Premiums unearned 35,630 .05 Advance dues 15,970 . 32 Advance interest and premium 5,548.36 Bills payable 1,050.00 All other liabilities 30,465.50 Total $3,697,356.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING Balance on hand July 1, 1899 Dues (full paid Interest Premiums Fines Membership and transf* Loans rt paid Real estate salf Rents Other Loans Salarit Commission Other expei Undraw als. d &gt; il clrauals, earnings 4- Matured !-tock, dues 1,,- in?.: Aiatured stock, earnin Full paid stock, di Full pad stock, earni Cash on hand Bills payable Total , $^ HARES STATEMENT Number of shares in force at this date Number of shares issued Blnce organization Number of shares issued durin.? fiscal year Number of shares matured during fiscal year Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year Number of shares of running stock in force at this date.. Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this date . . 4 441 Number of shares loaned on Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 SIW1MARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE (IF NEBRASKA ()n the Sith day of June. 19ol ASSETS First mortgage loan B mortgage loans in process of foreclosure loans •■state Furniture and fixtures Delinquent interest, premiums and fines uid taxes paid Insurance paid Other assets . Total LIABILITIES Capital stock running $3,391,920.99 Full paid stock '522V Reserve fund 5?\ Undivided profits Vi'iaed pronts 134&gt; shareholders on incomplete loans 48,0 ■ Premiums unearned ' ' 37,21 4 '. 60 Advance dues 20872 &gt;;7 20.87 Advance interest and premiums 5^825 Bills payable 5235 39 Other liabilities qi'242'qfi 91,242 96 TotaI $4,314,744.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL TEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1901. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1900 ♦ 106,871.60 Dues, (running stock I 1,309,039.13 Ones, (full paid stock) 230. v 280,928.33 Premium;- 36, v 4.*' Membership and transfer fe t s 4,500.14 Loans repaid 680,98*. 08 Real estate sales ■ 16,197.53 6.s- Otli. r receipts 274,034.83 Total $2,951,823.89 EXPENDITURES. Loans 11,3 Salaries 33. &gt;'• ■ Commissions Othi-r expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Matured stoc.k duos Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock. du«'S 57. v Full paid stock earnings 8,160 . 34 on hand 192,256 93 Other liabilities 307" Total $2,951 SHARES STATEMENT. Number of shares in force at this date 119,985 Number of shares issued since orfranizstion .. 248,198 Number of shares issued during fiscal year Number of shares matured during fiscal year 3.280 Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year ttJM Number of shares running stock in force at this date .... Number of shares full paid stock in force at this date Number of shares loaned on Number of shares On which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OK THE miLUIN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS &lt; &gt;K THK STATE oF NEBRASKA STATK OF NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1808. On the 30th day of June. 1902. ASSETS. ASSETS. mortgage loans $4,090,595 . 56 mortgage loans $4,090,595.56 mortgage loans in process of foreclosure ' 2o!t76.17 mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 20,776.17 Stock loans 141,870.96 " sti «&lt;? 111,208 .82 Furniture and fixtures ;; 4 177,668.51 Delinquent interest, premiums, and fines 30,691 .45 ises ana taxt-s paid 23,059.31 Other assets 158,999 . 82 Total $4,758,293 LIABILITIES Kal stock running $3,820,900 . 57 paid stock 544,300.50 ve fund 7S son s« $3,820,900.57 320.36 Undivided profits 169!36o!63 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 48^041 .75 Premiums unearned Advance dues 17 0 7s::. 4? 17.032.44 Advance interest and premiums 1,761 .89 Other liabilities 47/792! 20 Total $4,758,293.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1902 RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1901 running stock) Dues (full paid stock &lt;t Other receipt Total \\ ilmltawals. due Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues . Manned stock, earnings Full pah' stock, dues . Full paiil stork, earning Cash on hand Other liabilitie Total Number of shares in force at this date Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares issued during fiscal year Number of shares matured during fiscal year Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year Kr of shares of Running stock in force at this date . . r of shares of full paid stock in force at this date 6.308 Number of shares loaned on 36,79« Number of shires on which dues are delinquent 4.218 Nun ber of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of du unis Membership and transfer ropaid Other txiKM </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the IWth day of June, 1!H)3. ASSETS. First mortgage loans $4,690.659 . 86 First mortgage loans in process of foreclof-ure 24,154 Stock loiMis 156.066.10 Real tstate 102,153.89 Furniture and station. t\ 3,304.01 216,946.26 IXliiiquent interest premiums and fines 32,352.58 Expense! and taxes paid 18,594 . 24 Other assets 99,197.82 Total $5,343,429.38 LIABILITIES Capital stock running, (Dues and dividends) $4,204,171.68 Full paid stock 760,202 . 26 Reserve fund 102,470 . 31 Undivided profits 158,759 . 44 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 39,271 . 81 Premiums unearned 26,136 . 49 Advance dues 14,050.90 Advance interest and premiums 3,176.40 m.r liabilities 35,190.09 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL TEAR ENDING 30, 1903. JUNE REC EIPTS. Balance on hand June 1, 1902 ... &gt; ,-, . - Dues, (running stock Dues, (full ])aid stock Interest Premium Fines Membership and transfer f Loans repaid v. ', r. . &gt;&gt;)• Real estate sales Real estate sale Ronts Ront.s Other receipt! Other receipts Total EXPENDITURES. EX PEN Salari ri^e " « 4l&gt;.Mh.n2 Commission* Other I ommisMons Otiier expenses Withdrawals, lues 1 1 'ii Withdrawals, due Withdrawals, earnings .1 40 : Withdrawals, earning Matured .-lock, due;, Matured .-lock, due;, 144 • Matured stock, earning Full paid siock. dues . Matured -tick, earnings 49' Fun paid siork. dues .!.!!!!!!!!!!!! 120 ~ Full paid stock, earnings ■&gt;! V 21.17 Ciish on hand 219S Other expenditures SrPrl.KMENTAJ. STATEMENT Number of shares in force at this da . Numb rganizatton Number of ih&amp;riaa issued during fiscal Numb: r of shares matured during fiscal year r^umber of shares withdrawn duripe fiscal year Nun fcer of sharrs of running stock in force at this date Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this dat :. umber of shares loaned c Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues of dues m Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the ag- ount if sanrv Number 208 Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. !■ $24.' Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders Number of minors holding stock in the Associations .... Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dur- n.g fi I Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal vear Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 NUMMARY OE THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA t &gt;n the 30th day of June. U«&gt;4 ASSETS. mortgage loan mortgage loans $5,493,718.87 First mortgag? loan;; in process of foreclosure 27,908.74 Stock loans 709.02 Real es in u 92.664.95 Furniture and »iatini,eri 11 Cash 2(10,2X6.02 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 28,321 expenses and taxes paid 24!ti&gt;6 .48 Other assets 116,122.47 TolaI $6,217,350.40 LIABILITIES Capital stock lunning, (Dues ami dividends ) $4,851,576.89 fuii t aid stock ::::::::::: Wssi.'h e fund 144 Undivided profits 191 ,i Due shareholders on incomplete loans 85J Premiums unearned Advance dues 10 6''7 1 Advance interest and premiums ] 457 70 Other liabilities ........'...." 39,'592i66 Tot&amp;J . . . jc ni i"n i(\ </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 RECEIPTS AND EXPEND] i I RES FOR THE YEAR ENDING 30, 1904. JUNE REC E IPTS. Kce on hand July 1, 190 (running stock) * 217. 2,030.63*. 83 i full paid stock) st 447,128.78 Premiums ■ MMH r&amp;hip and transfer ft Loans repaid I ■ Real estate salt 24,117.39 Other receipts *4,469 Touil EXPEN DITIRES is J2.16X :.4.i&gt;;i 47 tVmml—loM Oth.-r expen: Withdrawals, ilu Iirawals, earning! red stock, fact red stork, tarn in paid stock, dues paid stock, earnir on hand ■ Other rxpenditui Tota 14,469 SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT Number of (baron in force at this date Number ol sli.n : sfnce organization Number of sliares issued during fiscal year Number of shares, mature*! during: fiscal yar Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year Number of shares running stock in force at this ('ate .... Number of sliares of full paid stork in foi&lt;e rt this date Number of shares loaned c Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-paynunt jf dues Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the ag - gregate amount of same. No. 224 $147 1 Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 39 t 36. v - Number of borrowing stockholder)) Nun h&lt; r of non-borrowing stockholders Number of minors holding stock in the associations .... Ml Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dur ing fiscal y Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal I year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year. 106 months Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1.061 Number of leans made for the ;i.iym"nt ' f homestead </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OK THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th dav of .June. IMS. ASSETS. ASSETS. loan* $6,303,316.65 mortgage loans in process of forackKOn Sim k loans ... mortgage loans in process of toreciooure sto&lt; k loam [9o t i Real Futnkure and stationery 18.283.21 4 quent interest, premiums and fine Exi&gt;enses and taxes paid 1.425.6* Other 1 Total $7,269,297.48 LIABILITIES Capital stock running, (Dues and dividends) $5,f&gt;22&gt;7'.i Full paid stock 1,K!4," l:;.14 &gt;e fund 1 72^44. 90 I'ndivided profits 199.771!. 1 Due shareholders (n incomplete loans 148.991.79 Premiums unearned _'44.06 Advance dues 7!&gt; Advance interest and premiums 23.31 Other liabilities 4:;. 929. 09 Total $7 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 JUNE 30, 1905. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1 Dues, (running stock) Jues (full paid stock) . Interest 1904 * 198,718 43i,y 506,1 499,4; Premiums Fines . . . Membership and transft Loans repaid fees Real estate sal Rents Other receipt Total EXPENDITURES Loans Salarie: Commission Other expei Withdrawal Withdrawals, e .rnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earni: Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earni Casl Other expenditu '[.EMENTAL REPORT at this dat" Avera.c rate !»t cent of dividends declared during fiscal Average running li »ck matured during fiscal Numb Numb Numb Numb N'unibi Numb </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 SUMMARY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS or the STATE OF NEBRASKA • A8SI First mortgage loans First mortgage loans in proce Stork loans . . Furniture and Cash Delinquent interest premiums and Expenses and taxes paid . . Other Total LIABILITIES Capital stock running, (Dues and dividends Full paid stock ■ 1,466.516.21 Reserve fund 1'n.livided profits 246,865.01 21fi.S44.27 Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned 1 6 82 Advance dues 14.nfi5.50 Advance interest and premiums Other liabilities 1 44.4S3.31 Total OF THE CONDITION OF THK On the :tmli da; of .Inn Real f state </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 RECEIPTS AND HXPE..DITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1906. RECEIPTS. Balance on har 1 July 1. IU06 * 404,023.50 Dues, (running stock 3,110.336.98 Dues, (full paid stock Interest t-remium Fines Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid Loans repaid Real estate sales Real estate sal Rents ...!!.!!!!!! Rents Other receipts Total Otht EXPENDITURES. XPEXniTl'RES Loans | Salaries Commissions Other expenses 11 Withdrawals, dues Withdra Withdra Matured Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues 1 Matured stock, earnings Matur Full I) Full paid stock, du s tock. du Full paiil stock, earnings Ful Cas Oth Cash on hand 17 Other expenditures Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Number of shares in force at this date Nur Number of (ha I since organization Ni 1 Number of shares issued iluring fiscal year Nil Number of shares matured during fiscal year Number of shares matured during fi Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal jri Nu fi ,vi Number of shares of running stock in force at this dal Number of shares of running stock in force at thi Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this dal Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this date. . . Number of shares loaned on Nun Numb-.T of shares on which dues are delinquent Nunib'-r of shares on which dues are delinquent ares on w Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Nun iii Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the ag - gregate amount of same. No. 176 Numt lo: i the ag X 1 Numb' r of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 66 Numtx r of mortgages in proo lcsure. and Ihf aggregate amou X Number of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year Nutnt i i ir Number of loans made for the payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Number of loans made for the r ayn: homestead :ir Number of borrowing ntockholi1»&gt;r» Number of non-borrowing stockholders Number of nc winK stock N'umber of minors holding stock in the Associations N'umber of minors holdi Average rate !&gt;er cent of interest charged borrowers dur - in.g fiscal year Avera Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THF STATKoF NEBRASK ASSETS iaa.5i I). i ill ta ne« pa LIABILITIES !) K ii unit piviniiiii iiiil. r&lt;iu &lt; &gt;n the :toth day of June, I'M mortgage loans in proo Furniture and fixtures </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR EM»IN&lt;; Balance on hand July 1. 1! running stock) Dues (full paid stock Interest Premi Fines Membership and transfer fi Loans repaid Other reecii '1 Withdraw a Matured stock, du (ash on h{ Mi -eel lane 1'la f Fo&lt; Nui N ;iw of Tota A mo Amou Numb 1 Real "state sa Rents Loans Salai &lt; !omn &lt; &gt;ther expel Witlulrawa Maturec Full pa Full pai Numi Numl Numt N'umt Nur Nur Nui Nui Nui Nui '■■•irate </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have be~n made 16,998, 633.00 Appraised value of improvements WO. 786.00 26,025.00 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 51,425.00 Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the associ ations as collateral security 14,3H4,KO8.O0 Number of loans made for building purposes during fiscal vear 1 921 Number of loans made for payment of homestead mort - gages during fiscal year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year Number of borrowing stockholders. Number of non-borrowing stockholders Number of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent, of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate ]&gt;er cent, of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal vear Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year I Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal vear Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal vear I Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal vear 114.(HiS.tj3 Average rate percent, of dividends declared during fiscal vear •&gt; Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 1O'_&gt; months </seg>
            <seg id="p039"/>
            <seg id="p040">40 SUMMARY OE THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THF STATE OF NKBKASKA On the 3&lt;ah day of June. 1908 ASSETS First mortgage loan lure ami (ixtup terest.prem and taxes paid ■ Tota IJABIUTIKS Capital stock runninyr. (Dues and div Full paid itock Reserve fund Undivided pr Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance due Advance interest and premiums other liabil ti( - Total Kmort}?&amp;£e loans in proo loans estate . </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISC :al YEAR KN DI N( J JUNE 30. 1908. KEl KI PTS Balance on hand July 1! Dues (running stock). . . Dues (full paid stock '.to * "&gt;41.787.e» 4.1M7.LNI1 1.525,430.29 Interest U38.04M Premiums Fines 124..M3.25 Membership and transfer Loans repaid ee* l« Real estate sa 1,315.00 14,211. M Other i S13.T54.42 Tot a 1O,J»7.784.71 KXI'KNDITUKKS I 5,14»,765.3» !Nt.:si;:{. 4« K),3«3.48 issions ... 21,341 o| 1.347.01 expenses '4 Irawal rawals. dues rawals. earnings .{:i. r &gt;.21!i 2H ;i i Matured stock, duet nti - Mat Rured stock, earning) ;;n paid stoi-k. dues iirji.:,in 47 Mati pai&lt;l stock earnings 37,554. nil t ( i on hand other Expenditures 4:iO,t&gt;X4 41; Total $ Iu..")!i7,7-i4 7 1 * 4 71 Sl'IM'I.KMKNTAI, REPORT OKI 1'lan of associations: L".i Serial. W Permanent, 1 com - bination. Total Par value of each share of stock. 44 associations tlOQ, each: 24 associations t^iKl each ;ic Number of series issued since organization. ga Number of shares issued since organization !»7iM 170,* Number of shares in force at date of last report 32K, 101 u Number of shares issued during tiscal year ... 115,836.03 111 V. Footing of two preceding items 44] Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during tiscal year 18,530.45 N Ui -t Number of shares matured during fiscal year. . 4,883.50 Nmnl)ei' of shares matured durintr fiscal year. . 4 Number of shares cancelled during tiscal year but not withdrawn 15,602.00 Footing of three preceding items.. 89.115. Un Fo( Nui i».ll", Number of shares in force at this date 372,1" I Number of shares of running stock in force at this date . . . 344,527.92 force at U Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this date . . N rc-H at this date . . 28.2 Number of shares loaned on 121, 325.il Number of shares loaned or Number of shares on which dues are delinquent '_'.4ik! Nu i II me ation for nc l»av 'otal amount of dues lielin.i u^nt at this dat 10.44 sharel \v « Amount of inter - :ns and tines due and unpaid </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate .-MiMiuiu oi loans upon unimproved real estate $ 4'j u,;-, -; ( Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made * i (k | nin mi * KNI.010.00 Amount of insurance in force and assigned to th.» Associations as collateral security «.]i; 94., 57] 41 Number of loans made for building purposes during fiscal vear Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount 01 losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year $ 7 :- Amount of dividends declared on running stock dur- ing fiscal year « 5:C' Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year t 134,736.95 Average rate per cent, of dividends declared during fiscal vear 8.14 per cent Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 105.3 months Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 211 Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 7(1 Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improvements . .. $ i«K,itt.sa . .. $ 56,934.37 . .. *12.l &gt; ii1.l &gt; 74 .(&gt;■&lt; . . 117,191,023.00 . .. *».7Ko.ln.UHt Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders Number of minors holding stock in the associations. Average rate per cent, of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent, of premiums charged borrow- ers during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal vear I.li4*i 2,39« 9 316,557.56 14,8 ■&gt;l.*-2:&gt; 1,131 8 13 per c«nt 2 per cent $ 51,565.31 rfi </seg>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044">a the 1 1 I r ta to Of total number of associations, number of shares in force, and to ets. from 1X!»2. the first year that authentic reports were made, dowr present time. Year No. of Associations No. of Shares in Force Total Assets 71 *4 tu.m.i -1 f.4 1. 428.728.11 t v.c 1 I l."l IT. .!•")»). Ui 4.:{14.744.hi l*t.iw 4 !•"&gt;.!. 4L'4 4:!. 41". Two associations were organized during the year as follows [••n-on. State Building and Loan Association. nil City. Some Building and Loan Associate! 4.').ulL' tif&gt;; M8.IIO1.3] 70,615 ii4.*'.'l J4.788.08 174,022 ti.217.35O.-W l'.i'i.u.in 7.2«H.2!»7.4H 220,648 8,961,788.11 315,372 ll.422.H9it.8H 372.821.. 7" 13.415.822.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 ) List showing gains and losses of the Building and Loan Association of Nebraska, during the year ending June IVKh., V.xH*. LOCATION ASSETS l»* A9SKTS 19U7 (JAIN Alhion Allianr Aubun Aurora II. tar 8B.6O7 35 151.537 43 51.537 43 -, ti! «. ... ll.r:!. He»trii'. Beatrice IUL Benson XV Ut* CHI ! !(!K 70. W J07 m Blair um Cambridt I'entral C Chappell *' I7« SB 2.H71 411 ■ 17 Columbus- K I" J31 tr 11 r« H Kairtleld Falls iv Fremont St» Freumnt tJtu 4 H;l HastiDsa Him Hll l.au Lin I. ii Li r Lincoln s [jncoln L Mu(lis&lt;iii I Mini -Mil .' McCnok ■ Norfolk h Norfolk I North Lou Norlh Plat Ol Pin Pll 1'iu Tr«- Val Wo Yoi Vor </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 STATEMENT Showing- the Increases and Decreases in the assets and liabiliti the Building and Loan Associations of Nebraska during- the fiscal ending June .Jot.i. 1908. Showing- the Increases and Decreases in the assets and liabilitie: f the Building and Loan Associations of Nebraska during the fiscal ; yea ending June .Jot.i. 1!HP«. ASS1 rs Incn Decreases Ir Decrea rv;i~f First mortgage limns $ 2,100,750.(15 in foreclosure 22,301.83 First mortgage loan i!.H "&gt;ii. i foreclosure T2.'i Stock ; $ 34,033.2f Stock loans Keal estate 4. Keal estate !!"'.i!|L &gt; ..:T Furniture and tixtui &lt;ash Furniture and tixtm «', L &gt;44 •&lt;:&gt; !i.L&gt;4 4.4(1 'a^l' 4,407.74 4 Delinquent interest etc., Expenses ami taxes paid Delinquent interest etc-.. 2.B87.82 lizpenses ami taxes paid 14.'i."&gt;ii §32/74^58 5K.63O.37 * l65,tt»&lt;.:H l,9U2.iKi2.H3 ts in I'.kis 1:!.41"».si'l &gt; .sii " l' MI " IMi'L'.sihi.sc; O»*n l.lf.rJ.iiiiL'.ii.t LIABILIT1 (,;i I.I A I S &lt;'a]iital stcck. ninnir Capital stock, runnii * 7ii:i.lT().41 41 Pull paid slock 1,227.810.55 Full pai Reserve fund 43.OH5.84 I Undivided pr&gt; led )&gt;rotits 21,3»7 51 shareholders on incomplete loans 41.9, Due shareholders on incomplete loan- 41,937.5" Premiums unearned Preraimns unearned 4,170.3(1 Advai 5 ]. Advance due 5.4H.1 Advance interest anrl premiums K»2.O3 Other liabil 1 !4-&lt; 14 I.H No. of loans made for building pu «o. oi loans maue tor Duiluing purposes during war " payment of homestead mortgajri Tiortgajr* during the vear ill 4.i 1 Total number of borrowing stock holt Total lieal Kstate loans in force 14 $1'* *'44 Total appraised value of the •• !at nl Total amount of Insurance assigned </seg>
            <seg id="p047">business June 30th, l ( .)0«. an increase of -J over the number re porting last year, showing an increase of assets during the y s l.w_\'.i:; First mortgage loans have been increased 2,100,7; while items of other resources have been reduced as follows Capital stock (running) has been increased 76a, 176.41 No II Tot SIJ.^44.: t in otal appraised value of the real estate and s liav ot led to til hav lfi.!»4!&gt;,57l.41 The Assc \ i'ii untintr t&lt; at Full paid stock increased .... 1,227610 purposes during year, ■stead mortgag &lt;&gt;\vin&lt;r stiK'klioltlt nun wli u rin if tlit </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 I am pleased to state since the last annual report, no failure of associations has occurred in this state. Wlienth&gt; Cent financial convulsion is taken into consideration, it certain - ly speaks well for the associations of Nebraska to be able to make the above statement. However, there has been no great decline of real estate values as a consequence of the panic. So far its the security of the associations is concerned there has been no real impairment of value. Nevertheless ■ financial shock as re as we have passed through must of necessity affect any kind of financial institutions, so that it is gratifying indeed I able to make the above statement. The real test of the mat nent of a building and loan association conies during a period of falling prices and declining real estate values, and these con - ditions have not held in this state. i While 1 have none bat the kindest words for the pronn I organisers of building and loan associations win re the cient field for their successful operation, I regret to occasionally this Department is compelled to charier insti - tns located in places t'lat sound judgment indicates either Id already occupied or i field without promise of sue&lt; I law leaves no discretionary power with this Department ich matters, sn that the stern school of experience mu« o demonstrate the error of the proposition. Not many instances come to us. but some do. K)n the whole I have nothing but words of commendation le building and loan associations of this State. As a role are officered by men with s dear knowledge of the pur - i and the objects of the institutions under their charge. ne can doubt or question the value of these institut builders, and the succt ►btained by some of them II d he a matter of state prid e originator of an institute eld. however, do not fully ; that is required ordinarily to the point where some it ) the management. There B. It is a laudable ambition to n of this kind. All who ■ will be many disappointments 1 this line, for a building and loan association is a pe proposition, differing materially from most financial venti This Department expect i to com ppreciate the time and tlie &gt;■ to bring one of tlteae instil turns or recompense is )&gt;(»• </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 building and loan associations play an important part in the ti - nancial life in the state. They have no^et rich quick attrib and none but men of high ideals and strict integrity will find reward in this Held of operation. il su^irestions to offer as Ear as the pres ent law ned. It seems to be working out its pur ictory way. and the supervision is proving no in a fairlv nitric consider too large a reserve fund. I am willing to admit that there are t vo good sides to this question, but the mutuality of t ns s holder unnecessarily in order to protect the persistent or future shareholder. It fut ly the intent of the building and loan law, as it now exists, for these institutions to nay such dividends e;irh vtnar =is tl v it of the law to defer t lging the dividends ex year to year, and pena lU- ii r \ Iv. K. IMVSK. ldency toward the creation of what I tin « lost si«jht nf. I do not think it </seg>
            <seg id="p050"/>
            <seg id="p051">ohowing the condition of the sixty-eight Building and Loan Associations in the State of Nebraska at the close of Business June 30th, 1908. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION &lt; &gt;n the 30th 1 1 a y of .June. 1!H y i \ Itl I 1 E STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THE ALBION. NKISKASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p053">_ RECEIPTS Balance on hand July I, 19117 IH Dues, (full paid Interest Me, Loa Real ax \V I: f. A A vi An Kill" nil 1 &lt; I riiimi ii • I r-.T-l \ T- (TUMI I [ 1 1 r I Tl K IlSfni VMT . . L ■ mount of losses cliarEPd to reserve fund during fiscal year Ar e stork durinsr fiscal year d stock during fiscal year ire rate per &lt;*ent of dividends declared rltirinR fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 OF THE CONDITION OF TH» ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION' ALLIANCE. NEBRASKA On the :t(itli day of June. 1IH i I KK A. It. Roduvrs . Vice-Presiden* DlliKCTURS ■ M Hampton U h A. D. Uodtfrrs H E. MoCray K. U Iris I John M F. B. Dinner [(UIVUD AS&gt;K % f and Hxtures N .lt-rt-&gt;t. prei LIABILITIES -tm-k running (l)u»s anrt divide I I st.ick cl iirntils arebolders hq incomplete ■r du ■ ■ inlt-re^t and prern STATEMENT Rilman . Samptoi Oilman . Secretary Attorney I "oil. I. (I </seg>
            <seg id="p055">I KECK1P Du L&gt;u In r Pr. H( II. L, Wit Wit Mat Mai Full Full PU l'a No No .No No. No No No No No No No No N.. ie&gt; suiijeii to cancellation ror non-payment jnt of dues delinquent at this date A N N. An Ap] Ann App wl Ait iat No No A l ■ar N No No ;.&gt; into per rent of in t.-t-.-wt .-liarcpd horrowen d Av -•i luirniwpn nnnnff fiscal year ■d borrowers during flscal year 10 Pin Amount credited to reserye fund during flsral year ' A An An Amnnnr &lt;.f dividends declared on full paid stnrk during flsf-al ri Average rate per rent of dividends declared durfnjr flsral year Averad S^:';,™' :F1S '' AI - Y ™ lurinR fiscal year . d mortcaees during 'lurine fisral year . . strv-k rtitringr ftsral year 1 during fl^al vpar </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION ' i SOUTHEASTERN NEBRASKA WILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AIBIKN. NKUKASKA &lt; t * Tot t </seg>
            <seg id="p057">- ITS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JINK 30, 19(17. RECEIPTS. » tuid di f running: stork during flsral yea r k during flsral year i red during fiscal yea- ■i ti u 1'iliGT fi 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">STATKMKNT AURORA BUILDING AND IjOAN ASSOCIATION Al'RORA, NEBRASKA On the 3nth day of June, 1!" OFFICERS V'it-e l'i s, xttorncv HKKCTOK H A Mun^in J. B. Hunter IT. K Li N J Jo-.. JotlDaon \v K. lirter .1 \ I, \ A Hi ASSKTS V : &gt;■ and tlx iv I f axes | T.it I ABILITIES ■k rimniriK- i l&gt;ut*s antl «J .«-h * ded i»roi »rchold- nun unearneil AtU a: Advance interest and premium Tota DFTHK CONDITION' OF THf R. MuiiMin ... Hunt.-r Sehoonover . •'.. Ijoiiii-.liur\ J. H. Grosvenor . I 5. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Tl-RKS FOR THK Flsi \|. YK\K i junk a&gt;, mm I) Nl It'T Hit 1&gt;U In! Fine Men Loai Ren ENDITUR] XI 1 tO W w Mat Mat &gt; MENTAL REPORT. ■ it) MENTAL REPORT ition. (if ieriai) '".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. ! .... ear 1 year NO ■ iate .... ■ this date No N " m for non-navment of dues To it this date No. mortgages lubjart to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same e. and aggregate amount of same. . ■ A estate * Mat stiite upon which I : A I A M f e ii(H»n Amt. inmiranea in lor.-a aiul assigned to the association as collateral ed to the association as collateral « No pose? during fiscal year luring fiscal year N, nestead mortgages during year . . stead mortgages during Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year ans during fiscal year N No. of No. of minors holding stock in the association i association ! arged borrowers during fiscal year A Aye arged borrowers during fiscal year PI. Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year ■ of dividends declared on full paid stock during flscal year '.'. ue rate per cent of dividends declared during flscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 STATEMENT OK THK CONIMTIUN" OF THE STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION RK'K. NKHKASKA To </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 NDITl'RKS DING JCN &gt;K THE FISCAL YKA1 t B D I&gt; ■» Y * A A « A </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 M STATEMKNT THE CONDITII IN &lt; &gt;F Tin BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BKATRICK, NEBRASKA On tli ny of June. 1!* KilllMIt K. 15. Sheldo S, F. B. Sh 1)1Ri:cti)rs A. .lai \SSh R jrc and rut mil hn 'l taxes paid (1 laxes p;i Tut a LIABILITIES Ntock runn I . d stock . e fund ded profits *rf holders on incomplete loans rns unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p063">B 63 ■i S KKCIili Ba Du Im Pr. Kin Me No purposes during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal vear f*T*t Ami Ammint or ii»»i»i»s chareen to reserve fund durinff flxcal Tear Amount of dividends declared on runninr stock dtirtnir fiscal year -:&lt; n-, u&gt; Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal vear SI -« m Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal vear ' "" a] tf, Average running tlrre of stock matured during fiscal year XPEXDITTRES F( &gt;K THE FISCAL VEA1 ENDING JUNK :!iitl. l!«is Plan of premium Vk n s 8a Wit lii] i a wuls. (lu. - Matured stuc-k due* Miiliii-t-il St... k. Full paid st. Full paid stock, earnii - - t'ush mi hand Other Kx|&gt;end V- Total SUPPLEMENTAL, HEl'UKT Plan of Association, J'ar VBlU( organization. (If serial) .. so. or ahari linca organization No or shares in f,, r ve at date .if last repui So. hi ,1 year . footing nf two prei ■ No uf shares witbi .r • niaturiM i durlnc i ■ an. .ll.-l illll iiii •ootine .,f three pn ■hares in force at this .late &gt;Jo. of running stock li *&lt;&gt; &lt;"■ lock in r.. *o. nt HhareH liuined ■ Jo. of shares on which dui Inquent ... Jo. of shares sulijert to cancellation fur non-payment of dues Total amount of ilues delimiuent at this .lai- Amount of .lues owing liv borrowing storkholders Lnioiint of Interest, premiuma and tines due and unps i Mo. mortgaces subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. '"• ""■' foreclosnre and aggregate amount nt same imount of loans on Improved real estate . jys Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hav&lt; been made Appraised value of improvements ....\ ....... \..\[... Amount (»f loajis upon unimproved real estate Amt. insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral seeuritv j,,, No. loans made for payment of homestead morteraees during year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal vear No. of horrowinp stockholders , No. of non-horrowinp: stockholders No. of minors holding stock In the association ... Average, rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during flsc'-il vear Averaee rate per cent premiums oharped borrowers during fiscal year n&lt; « * </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THE STATE BUILDING AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION BKNSoX, Nf B. VV. ( K &lt;T&gt; !. i&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 RECEIPT8 AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YKAK ENDING JINK .(nth, Unix ECEIPTS Ha l'u ■o 1 hi ft, M&lt; t t A A </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 STATEMENT Or THE CONMTION OF THE BLAIR BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HI.A1K. NEBRASKA Ki-nn Haii kVlh H </seg>
            <seg id="p067">:i n RECEIPTS AM) EXPKNDITURE8 FoU THE FISCAL VK\K ENDING JUNE, *ith IWW. receipts liaiK] July s, ( running stuck ) . . ■unninjf stnrk dm dpflarprt during </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 STATKMKNT OF THh &lt; ONDITION OF THh ENTERPRISE LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION CAMBRIDGE. NEBRASKA ( Hi th FIV I if .i \V. II. Y t t C </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 KIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FoK THE KI8CAJL VE\I ENDING JUNE 30, IWW. r B. H I) &lt; Pi Fi M r * A </seg>
            <seg id="p070">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OP THE 70 STATKMKNT OFTHK lONUITlON OF THE CENTRAL CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION I'.i </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 r RECKIPTS AND KXPKNDlTrKKS FOK THE FISCAL YEAR EM DING JTNK 30, 1808 Ar A. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 STATKMK.V1 K THK CONDITION OF THh CHAPPELL m"IU)IN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION \l'l </seg>
            <seg id="p073">4 ITS AND EXPENDITURES V&gt; &gt;K THE FISCAL YEAR KM) INC JINK 30, 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF TIIK STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THK CLAY CENTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION (LAY CENTER, NEBRASKA On the 3&lt;lth day of June. UK i IFFK'RRS Vio-IV. J. I.. L'ampb) .1. L. ( mmpbe Secretary lilKKi'TuKS \ Wmwi h B. CamplM I k h in Ix, X. I A HI 1. 1 TIKS urned AC To </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES F( &gt;K THE FISCAL VKAR ENDING JUNK 30th, lflOH RECEIPTS E- Intere Prerni Ki 161 TIKES LO, -u s M K N £ is a f .» N No. of minors hold in e 1 stork In the nMorfatfo Average rntp per rent of interest rhar*e*1 borrowers during ffs A ■d hoi-rowers during flBf-at vear Plan Amount of &gt;.i^--&gt;- i- l &gt;:i''.'.'(i to pi Amount of dividends deriarM on ninnlne stor* rturinr flara! v*»«r Amount nf i1Ivid*»ndp dprlnr^d on full nafrt xtonk- rturlner fl^oni v»»r Amount nf iUvMends df»r!arp&lt;1 on full pafri !«tonk flurlne fl)«^al ym Av»racp rate per '■pnt nf divlrtpnils derlarert dnrtntr fl«ral vear Average running tirre of sto^k maturpd dtjrlner fisra! v*» </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 V STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OP THE 0OLUMBU8LAND, LOAM AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION COLl'MBl'S, NKKRASKA &lt; &gt;u th I'll! a \ (IKI-lih I Si-&lt; &gt; Hoc I. Keel </seg>
            <seg id="p077">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 77 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 3&lt;), I ■d d </seg>
            <seg id="p078">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 78 STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OK THR EQUITABLE BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL REI ORT OF THI STATEMKN THK ClIMDITIHN OK THI CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION &lt; KIl'K. NEBRASKA M. K. I la M H. l-l, f. B. Ar &lt; . B. Ai ii. ri \ &gt;■ y t E I </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDIT 'RES KOR THK FI8CAI M'NK 30, Unix YEAR KNDING .1 Balance on hand July 1, ishi,- . REC | E1PTS Dues, (running stock) ' * i8l3.7H Dues, (full paid stock) 17.444.00 Interest I 5 813.7* Premiums .'.'.'.' 3,Wi.t! Fines J^U* '"inster 't*tm and loan' fees ' ."/.'. ' " " ' '. \7. '.'. '. 7.7. ! .7.7.1.7. ££ Real estate sales . IT. 1 11.18 Rents Dues- Loans Bills payable Total a &gt;w m EXPENDIT I RES Loans Loa Salaries SaUirn Com mi Other % Muse no Commlulom K5.U0 Other expt-i Withdrawals, diu Withdrawals, ear «.So».5U Pull paid stoik. d M ■ d Full paid stock. arning 3.8K) Intere Bills p: Total 43.OM.ie SUPPLKMENTAL RKPORT. Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) Par value of each share of stock Sena ,ar ' No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) No. of shares issued since organization 3.647 No list reimrt No. of shares issued during fiscal year .!....!... Fo. S.WS No. of atuntv during flacal year :«.. No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. No. of shares cancelled during tiscal year, hut not withdrawn Footing of three preceding items w No. of shares in forte at this date » :«. No. of shares In force at this date No. of shares of running stock in fo No. of shares of running stock in force at this date ...."......! LM No. of shares loaned on , . 'g,4l No. of shares on which dues are delinouent ' tw No No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount Total amount of dues delinquent at this date t Amount of tlues owing by borrowing stockholders ........[.... * \mount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same' Amount of loans on improved real estate ......................... | eii improved real estate Appraised value uf Improved real estate upon which 'loans'have' been t MJMM Appraised value of Improvements | .. mm Amount t&gt;f Inana upon unlmpmved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Amt. insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security W\ re 1T7 (0" .« Tornnno Ws.oso in $ No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year I it. Ill IV No. of borrowing stockholders .*.*.*.'.'.'.'' No. of non-borrowing stockholders .!z2 No. of minors HnMine utnrL- In th* a»/^i*tt~ n lw No. of minors holding stock In the association Average rat t of Interest charged borrowers tiurlng fiscal vrar Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year • iiu -o Amount of losses chareed to reserve fund during fiscal v'ear Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year ♦ :t OS:, »• Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year 5 4-1 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 STATEMENT PAIRBURY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIKUrKY. NKRRASKA on the 30th da v of June. 1!H A V. Pea V. L Simpkin: J ii Kvan ohn Hond Re»i estate Furniture and nxtup last l&gt;elin«iuent interest, premiums and rtt Kijienses anil lan-s imiu Oilier assets T&gt; i.i a mum I'apital stock running. &lt; Dues and dividend Full paid stock .... Reserve Fund Undivided profits, less ei|*nses and taxes pa l reholders on incomplete loai;s I'remiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiun Overdraft Total * OF THK CONDITION of THE A. V. Pmi K. L. Simpkini ■I. C. Hartijran •I. &lt;). Krans. . J. &lt; . Hartijran First moriiraire loans First iiy •nuiktf loans in pr loans </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 ICEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES K&lt; &gt;K TH VKAK ENDING JUNE 30, IMW. RECEIPTS. Balar Dues. id July ? (i ( Dues Inter « stcv Me. Loa Keal •■ I-JS ( 3XPEN1 URES . I ie.s«i.» Sal 160 k Wit Wit M;it Full K x si PPL.EMEN AL REPORT Plai Par No. No. A -lizat nizal •&lt;1 No. of shares issued during fiscal year Jjj i Po Mo. of shares withdrawn before maturity durin* Use No. of shares matured during fiscal year .. No. No. ot chares cancelled during n.- but riot un FoutiiiK "f three preceding items No No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No force at this date . . . . . . . . . . No No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. sh:ircs subject to cancellation for nonpa.v menc of aur Total amount of dues delinquent at this &lt;1ure Amount of dues owing by borrowing Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpsiul No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same j No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate a ]4 , ., Appraised value of Improi tate upon which loans hav ■«*■•*. App] Appraised value of improvements *.'.*.'.'.'.'.$ Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate st Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have ( Amt. insurance In force and assigned to the association as "collateral * security i No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year . No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year . . No ments of loans during fiscal year kholders No No. of non-borrowing stockholder No. of minors holding stork in the association Average rate per rent of interest charged borrowers during ' 'fiscal 'year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during: fiscal year I( Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year i ia td Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year '. Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year U Amount r1i\ Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE OF THE CONDITION OK THK PAIRPIELD BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRFIELD. NEBRASKA On the »&gt;th day of June. lHOX. OFFK KKS \V. Kmrich President \V. L. Bayly Yice-1'resident F. Anawalt Secretary T. F. Shively Treasurer DIRKl T &gt;KS C L. Lewis ('has. L'rawfi Win. Hoeve B. Hryant ASSETS F'injt mortiratre loam t \:&lt;AM First moriKUKv loans in process of torecl- Stock loans ■ urtf Real estate aioc Furniture and fixtures Cash Delinquent interest premiums ami tine: Kxi&gt;enses and taxes paid 01 Other assets Total MW I.I AHII .IT1ES Capital stock runninif. IDues and dividends Full paid stock Reserve fund Undivided profits Q».« Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Bills Payable Miscellaneous Total STATEMENT L'rawford 1). N. Williun. J. K. Spat </seg>
            <seg id="p085">RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FoK THE FI8CA1 ENDING JUNK 30, 1 VK AK RECEIPTS, RECEIPTS Balai ince on hand July 1, 190; Dues, (running s, (running stock) .......' ■ 1 Full paid (tuck ' Interest Premiur rest mums .. ."!"!! Fines Mem) in « lbership and transfer' fees ". .oai is repaid pa Miscella Horn . m t ftllaneotiH ' '.'. . ■ t*ii Total ...'.".. EXPENDITURES. T a EXPENDITURES U&gt;a IS Salari ries ....'!.'""".'"! missions [**] Con Other exf ;r expenses '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. idrawals, dues '.'.......'. Withdrs Wl Wit idrawals, earnings- '..'..'.'.'... ithdrawals, ea Matured red stock, due-. Mat trad stock, earnings paid stock, dues paid stock, earnings Full paid st Full pa on hand ... Mis ?lluneous. . . Total . . . SCl'I'LKMEXTAL UKI'ORT. of Association. (Serial 01 Permanent) „, . . SUPPLEMENTAL UEI'OHT Plan of Association. (Serial or Parnumonti Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) Tar value of each share of stock . No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) Tar val value of each share of stock of series issued since organization, (if serial) No of shares issued since organization izatk N f shares in force at date or lust report rt No. of shares issued during fiscal year J-outinir of two preceding items &gt;f shares issued during fiscal year J 'ooting of two preceding iu Inc &lt;&gt;f two preceding items No f shares withdrawn before maturity, uunn* rtseal vear N« of shares ma u red during fiscal year Nil '"■'' " f , - ■ ' durin, ir, but'noi Foo bm( of three prcreding items No. of shares in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this d of shares In force at this date of shares of running stock in force at this 1! i No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this 'dat of shares of full paid stock in force at this No. or shares loaned on of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares on which dues are delinquent w 1 No. at shares subject to cancellation for non-pavment of ' dues " t tt Ml for non-payment of d Tota 1 amount of dues delinquent at this date' Amount of di unt of dues owing hy borrowing stockholders iW « At unt of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid line and unpaid I.1I.IM No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of sa mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of sai N'.) nortgaces In process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of a a r,o. menaces in process or rnreclnsnre and agBregate amount of Amount of loans on improved rear estate I I3.IM.M Appraised value of Improved real estate upon 'which' loan's ' hav« unt of loans on improved rear estate alS hten a 'made f lmprove&lt;1 real estat « upon 'which' loan's ' hav« havj Appraised value of improvements aised value of improvements An int of loans upon unimproved real estate In force and assigned to the association as collate ins upon unimproved real estate e in force and assigned to the association as collateral Amt. Ir surance in No. of loans made for "building" purpose* during fiscal "ywmr".'.'.".'.'. if loans made for building purposes during fiscal vear No. loans made for payment of homestead mortpaires during year Amount or advance payment of loans during fiscal ves.r No. of borrowing stockholders ' loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during "year unt of advance payment of loans during fiscal vear of borrowing stockholders . . " No. of non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock In th» jmiii toll/.'" &gt;f non-borrowing stockholders f)f minors holding stock In the association ."!!.!! Average ate per cent of Interest charged borrowers 'during fl'sV-i'l' 'vViir lZ m K m l?t^™^Z? m %r rm dUri "5 "»-. year Avera !«• Plan of pre Amount credited to reserve fund durlnr fl&gt;rr' Amount credited to reserve fund durlnr fi&lt;=rri! $ Amount of losses cha»-firerl ro reserve fund durin" twcnl rpir Amount of dividends rieclnred on nmnlne- stork rturinr- fl«c«1 »«•■- Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during Ssca veSr " . ""•■ Averaee rate per cent nf rllvirtenri. a^i,,^ j,,.iJ_ UL..7 .... v . r ■• Amount .03 Averaee e per cent of dividend., deVJared during fiscal vea/T, Annual with :i Sneci»l :i per cent e-: &lt; Avera rre of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 OP THE CONDITION OF THE HOME BUILDING AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION FALLS CITY NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1901 OFFICERS S. L. Davies. \V. H. Schmelxd SeeroUr? \V. A. (ireenwaltl Trea H. ('. James Att&lt; DIRECTORS H. Ka.isirad Dav W. H. Suljn W A. 'ire [.. C. Kd« A SETS First morttraire Kirsi Htoriiraife loans in proeeNS of t Slock loans He; K'urniture and tixtur IK-hiMiiient interest premiums a;,d tl Expenses and taxes paid . Other Tot * LI AM! ITIKS Capital stock running. I Dues and dividends Pull paid stock Reserve fund Undmded profits Ihie shareholders on inc- Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest arid premiuti: Membership fee Tota STATEMENT &lt;;. H. Kallstead 1 Yesulent V ice-President </seg>
            <seg id="p087">I- 1 T 87 rK( KIPTS AM) EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL VK\R ENDING JINK 30, |M«. Ell ss IS R ?! ii II I MENTAL Kt zat S i s A N t of S v A t v KXPENDITUKKS fund dnriner flncal vp.tt . ' » reserve fund durinp fiscal venr ...,...'. K stork during- fisml year nn full red during f sral ■, . . , - , k maturfnl riurinE* fiucil « </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 STATEMENT OK THK c ONIMTIoN OF THE EQUITABLE Hl'ILDIXt; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEHUASKA on tlu' .'tilth day of June. l!Nis 0FFICBK8 OKFH'KKS C. H. Ma; President Frank Hammond Frank Hammond Vice-1 'resident Arthur TriH-sdell Arthur Truesdell Secretary C. B. Yeazie Treasurer George L. Looaaii lieorpe L. Loomil Attorney Dili DIRKi l ' H M ' lv Frank Haniiiiund Arlhur Truesdell ' B Vm Qae. U LoMrii Frank Fowler B Vea 1 ' '- ee Fred Under Jav A Uonahu ASSETS - uf forclosure • ari?. Kealr Furniture and Fin lent interest premiums ;iml K 3 Tota LIABILITIES stiiok runninir. ( [)ue&gt; and dividends Ke-srrve tund ed protlts Due sharetxilder. plele loans ereM ;nui in . </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 S AND EXPKNDITURKS KOR THE FISCAL YEAR KNDING JINK </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 STATEMENT OPTHE CONDITION ol NEBRASKA STATE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION &lt;». li (lav of .1 T. LIABILITII Undivided pro« - iftreholders on ini Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance Intel i FKKMOXT. NKBKASK .•■ru interest pcnui ■ I tuxes paid Keal eslate sold un contra K stock running 1 slock or paid lip m.i. fund I &gt;■! H. L. Hammond ... V- ,, I'aul Colson. ... r ,„ _. Sc J. T. May ,,, . , I it W . J. Courtright. . . I'IKKCTOHS h 1 T - M;iT •' T M;.v ILK Sato Wr " Frk-d * U. I.. Hum 1&gt;: " J1&lt; 8. IMiurney W .1 lourlriuht ASSETS 'iiit a " e '" an * '" '' r f ''"' ire anil Istati </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 N " K |!nS 1 '™.:x ! |^ H W8CAL yhak Balance on hand July 1 MR RECEIPTS. RECEIPT Balance on hand July Dues, (running stock) Dues, (full paid sto - lntere-.t 1'reiiin. ■ Fines Membership and transfer Loans repaid Dues, (running stock) .. • »■*•■ f .' -1(179 Dues, (full paid stock) W.M Interest 4LJM). Premiun ••. IT.*I. Hum 17.UW1. ■■rship and transfer Loans repaid I.1J1 Keal estate sales Keats ■■«" Miscellaneous Reeeipts. * 7 Total M Loans EXI'ENIMTil. Loa Salaries ".'.'.'.'.'.I'.'.'.'.'.'. Commissions .'. ....'....'. '/.'. :t«i. Other expenses '.'.'.'.'. I. in. Withdrawals, duos ..I!!!!!!! '™'- Withdrawals, earnings ....[.[[[[,' Matured stock, dues . Matured stock, due Main : ■ Matured linings . ' "'•' Full paid stoek. dues r'uil pa i 'ash on hand "* ' ■s I'aid Uy Stock redeemed . " rJ Paid Up - menus expeudiiun '**' -&gt; J* Total Miv SUPPLJDfBNTAL RJ5POBT. Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) p.™ s Far value of each share of stock ..'.'.'.'..' ■ ermanei No. (if MTif;, issued since organization " No. of shai • No. No. No No. of shares in I •*• No of shares issued during fiscal year L \M»tinK uf two preceding Items ,1_ V.. go. of shares withdrawn l&gt;ef.&gt;re mauirity during No. No. of shares matured during fiscal year . No v.i ..r ibarea canceled durinu ■ .: not »ith&lt;li F, -ootins of i' No. No. of shares In force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No No. of shares of paid up stock in force at this date shares loaned on No. of shares of paid u No. »'f shares |&lt; Amount of dues owinpr by horrowine shareholders A Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid * and unpaid No No. mortgaRes subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. ate amount of same. \ No No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same gate amount of same No * &lt; I IMC S Imount of loans on improved re Lppralsed value of improve.! real :i which loans' le Iniouni of loans upon unimproved re Am ■Ymt. insurance in foix-e and assigned to the association as collateral aecariiy £ 3j^ mq^ to the as: as collateral No Mo. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year during fiscal year No *Jo. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year 10 Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year No. of borrow No. of non-borrowing stockholder No t Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers du borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year 1OI Premium .. Mxed lount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount stock during fiscal year . . i SI Amount jring fiscal year Average rate pe dividends d [ared during fiscal year KunniDir per cent y Av«ra# nat id during fiscal year B (■&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 STATKM KNT GERING BUILDING AND LOAN- ASSOCIATION On the 30th day of June, 1!m OFFK RS Si-iTfta IlIKh W. K M A. A M A. H Wo. H. Ha- j. \v. Kinnamoi a s ETS First mortvmcc 1 I ire and rtxu Delinquent intere--t. preiimiHis and Expenses and taxe^ paid other Tut I.IABII 1T1 C»piUl stock runnine. (Dues and divideiul aid stock t Rest* r\ e fui Undivided profits I»ue shareholders iuun: Premiu Advan&lt;*f d Advance interest and p Interest and Fines 1 OK THK CtiXOITIoX OF Tl» GKRING, NEBRASKA E. \V. Honlium . W. Bonbam </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES POR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, I90K. PT Ra I'L Pre Fin Jin Loa Rer Loa \v U M No. z N No No No No T this date No M i Amt. insurance in for e and assigned to the association as collateral ing fiscal year An No. assoclatlc arKed borrowers during fiscal year »i |&gt;er c arged borrowers during fiscal year IM fiscal year ■ I A full paid stock during flscal year ggregate mort^a^es durlnpr year r\g fiscal year nd during fiscal year iK stock during fiscal year lared during fiscal year 3 during fiscal year . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 STATEMENT or the NDITION OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION GRAND ISLAND. NEBRASKA On the .'iotli day of June. l'Mi OFFICERS - Veit Uyan V. \\~. Hrininjrer • '. K. lientlev H. Woollej I l'C^KIt'Ilt V ice I 'resident Seeraterj 'lfe:i- Attorney IMUKcTOISS tnnafcrliu i-.T. i;eer I! I! Hortta i a Xorris ~'nke H. c. Miller K. .1. Hair -ETS ■'irusre lciun^ lortiraire louns. in process ,,1 toreclusure -' ute m)!&lt;1 on contract itv unit Hxuirt-s iiluiii^ and in e« " s &gt;ind lanes paid. ( tax sale certil Aiweu. i.Mti loiin •etUement balaaeea) ] Total I.I AHIMTI: I ] IKS Pininir. I Due-. :ind d Matured uml kerned In I s - cm Incomplete lowii Led included in eapital stueli ahuve) I and premiums. I II </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL VEAK NK 30, 190 „ . . RECEIPT Balance on hand Julv ! Dues. ( &gt; Dues, ( Inter Prer ' Fine Mei i.&lt; p di&gt; i so. si Loar T LKMENTAL REPORT Plan Par No. of No No No. of shares issued during fiscal year .... No. of shares withdrawn before maturity d No. of shares matured during fiscal year No No nning stock in force at this date .................. N, at s No t No Total amount of dues delinquent at this Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders .. '. .......... 47».S) aggregate amount of same, (*«. : • No. mortg ;ate amount of same a No Amount Appraise Ap A.T Appraised value ol unm p&lt;iai&gt;- mum ivhii' Amt. Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral No. of No. of loans made far building purposes during fiscal vear No. loans made for payment of homestead mortcaees dnrinir "™/" No. loans* made for payment of homestead mortgage t of homestead mortgages during year ". . ■ Tieste No. of horrowinp stockholders &lt;iPrs olders ....lilllli No. of non-borrowing stockholders No N'o. of minors holding stock in the association .... No c in the association the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers . A erest charged borrowers during fiscal year fund riuririL , r "*""'.'." .'.'.'.'.''. $ 1.3SCI7 Plan of premium Pla Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal yeai Air Amo'TU of lo-i**-*; chartreil to rvs*»rve fuud (luring M«r:\! year Ani&lt;»"ni of lo.-w»* chartreil xo reserve fuurt dnrin ••rvf f uurt during H**&lt;*a! v«ar Amount of dividends declared on running stock duri A ?d on runniner stock during fiscal year "." ?d on runniner stock during fiscal year ".'J •d on full paid stork during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stork duri Arr •d on full paid stork during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared durine- Average Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year red during fiscal year KNDING .1 XPENDITUREi Withdraw zation, (if serial) ization m *um i.ar \ Amount o No. mortg </seg>
            <seg id="p096">STATKMKN'l I THE CONDITION OF THF W. S W First - and tax ■ nt dues Full p Advance d A i)v;itict' ir f&lt; i HARTINGTON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA John Sohwabland f. M. Kimball... ¥. &lt;&gt;. Etobiaaon. . \V. 8. Wcston... </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">STATEMEX'J HASTINGS BriU)IN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION Icmani W. K. Buchanan I I ' Kohrer.. .1. o Rofarer .1. H. Fleming </seg>
            <seg id="p099">HI A I f RECEIPTS AND KNDITURE8 FOR THE FISCAL VK \R DING Jl'NE .in. iik.s </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 STATKMK.Vl OKTHKCIIMIITION OK THf HAVELOCK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION IIAVKb &gt;&lt; K. NEBRASKA )n tin- :!Otl l'.m Hint ■i. Adams. . Hofmani . Vouiur. . Vin-I' Secretary G. W. Has Alt \V. F. Aekennao &lt;■. W. A H F. Hoi; h'red K i oehlc E M&lt; F li v ASSt It i.iAHir.n i i.i i </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 ENDITURES For THE FISCAL VEA1 dim; junk :«&gt;, iww full paid stnok rturlnir flarnl i ids rlpolared durlnir fiscal vear •natured during fiscal year A\er.TKP r t i norrowers during fiscal year fisrai | ,:,,■, - inning ntnrh rturinR- flsrnl v^x- 11 paid stork durlne flarnl '• - </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION IIOOI'KI Jacob K Vice-] ■ \V. H.ii Sanders. I. Howard Heii ,v A M T ll Kii D, T i.i Aun.nih ' ■ led pr&lt; 1 ■ iuteresi and ( </seg>
            <seg id="p103">\ 103 </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 STATF.MKNT OF TDK CONDITION c &gt;V HUMBOLDT BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION HIWIHoLDT. NEBRASK Ob the 30th day of .lune. \'.x I. F. WaKh Stramei E. !!. BuUerfield . A. 'J'ari i.- DIRHX'TO J F. W H. K. llovd I. S ||;, I! K W»l AS in KI,« To Alill.lTIt K rif 1 1, ("ndivid^il t&gt;r&lt; ld&lt; IT, Advance du . ce hit er*?&gt;t and pr </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 EIPTS AND EXPENDITl S.IPT8 AND EXPENDITURES F(&gt;K THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, IM&amp; REOFIPT^! Balance on hand July 1 190T . , _ Dues. ( running str»olr\ * ■*=- RECEIPTS. on hand July 1 190T « -«» Dues, ( running stock) .. '"• ,. ""*■ Dues, ( [full paid stock) ■••'■'■ •'.'•' •'.'.".'.'.' .'.'i .'.'.'.'.'.'.'.' I fines Meml hip and transfer fee- 1J epaid 7r ,te siilfi ■ EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURE » ;ions .'..'..'.' ot xpenses . 4) Wlthd Withd wall, dues ...... "III. IIIIIIIIIII! « wals, earnings '......'. M itoek. dues stock, earnings ...... J! Ma stock, dues y ttoek. earnin_ - anil ' . a~ iai :::...:.....: SlI'PLKMEXTAL REPORT. Association, (Serial or Permanent) ITPLKMENTAL REPORT Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) le of each share of stock 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 -ii since organization &lt; 3 f serial • izatioi 1 . 1 .late of hist rei Par value of each share of stock So. of series issued since organization (if serial) No. NO No of shares issued during fiscal yea [ares issued during fiscal year F. &gt;f two preceding items So ares withdrawn before maturity during five No. of shares matured during fiscal year hares matured during fiscal year '. . . . No ires canceled dunns.' fiscal \ear but not withdra - Foot of three nrei-edins items ., No. of shares in force at this da hares in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at tins dat lares of running stock In force at this date . . ... No. of shares of hares of full t&gt;aid stock in force at this date loaned on |i No. of shares of full t.aiil stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on • No. of shares on which dues are delinquent hares on which dues are delinquent No dares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues in -payment of du Total amount of dues delinquent at this date ' 1 •« lount of dues delinquent at this date Amoi of dues owing by borrowing shareholders I. III! of interest, premiums nnd fines due and unpaid Amount of interest, premiums nnd fines due and unpaid No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amo gages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. No pages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same of f, i aggregate amount of same I a • r loans an imnroveJreal &lt;■»' ' ■ ' 4 C'"0 1 Am. API IW.020.1 1 value of improved real estate upon which loans have 'b. ■ V Appraised value of improvements 1 value of improvements i c. 1 Amo 1 loans unon unimprored n urance In force and assigned to the association as collateral Amt. insurance in force and assigned to the association as collatera umy security ;;, « v ■ No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year ' No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year 11 Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal vear » - ians made for building purposes during fiscal year ; made for payment of homestead mortgages during year I ad mortgages during year of advance payment of loans during fiscal year i Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal No. of horrowing stockholders of loar borrowing stockholders w No. of non-borrow m-borrowing stockholders ..II No. of minors holding stock in tr linors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during flacal year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year emintn Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year '!!"" Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year * • IM.9 Amount of dividends declared on »:iirt m&gt; stock during flscnl venr credited to reserve fund during fiscal year . i mi of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year .... I ! of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal, year I of dividends declared on »&gt;aid an stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year 1 Average running time of k matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OFTH1 LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LACRKL. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1!K OFFICERS •I. H. Felbtr \V. T. (Jrahara y P. Voter . . . Guv Wilson V. 1'. Voter. DIRECTORS J. B. Felber W. T. Graham C. K. Nevin ASSETS &gt;rtgiiife loan -nifaue loans in process ..f roreelosure Furniture and Hxtun ■-nt interest premiums and tines ~es and tui Other assets lnt pftid LIABILITIES ■ stock running. |L&gt;uesandd i Full u»id stock or paid up stock Keserve fund Undivided prottts Uue shareholders on incomiilete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues. Advance interest and premium' ; ay.ble Total « (' IT. Furle </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 RECEII s S'D EXPENDITURES KoR THE FISC ENDING JUNE :J0, 190s. AL YEAR RECEIPTS Balance Uues, (r Dues, ( hand » Interc Premi Fine Men u.io a u Loar Real 4*6.57 II EXPENDITURE Loan Salar I i Otl Withdraw Withdraws Ri Ha Full i.» Tax aa Intere: dS ital 1'1'LKIIENTAL REPORT. Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) No. of shares issued since organisation at $100 par value Mo. of shares in force at date of hist report 334 No. of shares issued during fiscal year 53 No. of shares withdrawn (Wore maturity during fiscal year No. of shares matured (luring fiscal yea No. of sharps cancelled during fiscal year, but not withdra wr Footing of three preceding items No, No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date N No. of shares on which dues are delinquent a No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment Total amount of dues delinquent at this date } jig. Amount of dues owing by horrowing stockholders $ T»7 SS ■s An Amount or interest premiums anil tfntsiiup and unpan! * Ji- 75 No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. No • | I.7O0.OO irirrpentp flmnunt nt earn* No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same No Amount of loans on Improved real estate t i * 1 1 * '* i &lt; Appraised value of improved real estate uim&gt;q which loans have heen made Appraised value of improvements &lt; l.i Amount or loanH upon uiiimprox ed re a', estate upon which loans have been made! Amt. insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral No. of loans made for huiicMng purposes during fiscal vear No. loans made for pavment of homest mortgages during year . . j No II No No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 6 Av ;ed borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium ., Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal vear I :l Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year .. $ aja. neciarea on running STOCK during nscal year .. | a|ft.O? declared on full paid stock during fiscal year .. t of dividends declared during fiscal vear .. «7io Amount Ke rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year 8 710 e running time of stock matured during fiscal year Average running t </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 "7^- Hurket President .John Gibson ,•• ,, Vice President f. w -.E=- ::."::-jz=; T. N. Hurket K. P. Leonard ..Manager of Ape MBC1OM •o ■ •*■ John Uibson K. P. Leonard Homer K. Burkei 4SSRS 'irtiraue loans ■■rtifiiire loans in process of foreclosure &gt;ans -tale sold on contract &lt;t. premiums and tines ■ 1 taifs |,;,id. lui sale certificate* - (MlK loan settlement balauc - eefvable .. Oftlcc iiuildinjt and furniture V ....... i 1 I Tota; i 1 : ■:s 1-1 AM1L.1 1 lt.&gt; I stock runninir. [ Dues and dividends! 1 stock (Matured and accrued Interest) ■ fund ed proflu ... I!'..'."!.'.".'.'!'..'.. rehulders on incomplete loans us unearned e dues (included in capital stuck above) ".'.' e interest and premiums. 1 l-.:i:l7.iio ao.aM.ai Total </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 KK( r ii rs AND XPENDITURE8 FOR THE ENDING JUNK :$o. IMS. FISC \L V KAK RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1807 j .,, Du Dues Men Kiue- ai Tales Loar, Real esla Home Borrowed money Reser H; Tc (1 .354 EXPENDITURES EXPENDITURE; Loans T7i:W Salaries Commis II m Und HilN ited .... Reser Bills F 51 UH'I.KMEXTAL REPORT. Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) Permar.et Par value of each share of stock 1 iim.i I No. of shares issued since organization No. or force at date of last report Nn of shares issued during fiscal year Footing of two preceding items ai year ,r fiscal year ,.1 r No. of shares in force at this dat No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date ................ Wo No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. ur No. ii No. of mortirutfe&amp; in process of foreclosure, and a»r No. 9 Amount of loans on improved real estate IUK which loar 4.WU m Amount of loans upon unimproved real estale Apnraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare been made Amt. Insurance in lor.-e :&gt;nd assigned to the association as collateral 1 security fejg No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year 2» No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year . . t No f homestead mortgages during yea ii Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year S No. of borrowing s look holders J. 170 No. of non-borrowing stockholders in No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during, fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year * i Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year full paid stock during fiscal running *tt\i*1r dni-lncr fl«/*al Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fls.\ Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year IK mi </seg>
            <seg id="p110">I" THE CONDITION OK THf AMERICAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION loan . il tin erest prtmiams lines Bxtienses itnd iuxpv paid \5^ Tol I irs a Resenrr fu I .ireh.i &gt;n c&lt;l Tola STATEMENT VV. A. S«lleek .. John T. Dorjjan I. H. Hatfirld. . . .1. H. UVstoott. . I. H. HatfU-ld... w a s*nc Advance duet Ailvui.ee interest and iiren Other liabilities </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 BCKIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOK THK FISCAL VF.AR KNDING JUNE .!'&gt;, 1SW* </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THI SECURITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. NEBRASKA On (be 38th day of Ju OFFU'KRS President Vice President I H HatHeld UC.Ota W. A IVnnter W. K. JU W A Selleok j H WMteotl J. H M.m j dc , T t)(&gt;ri{iln tin r I.I A I I d div Kuil paid &gt;ti Reserve fund I'ndirided pruBui eh.ilder^ Premjt Advance du&gt; Advance interest and premiui Interest and Mm-s Other liabi % W. A Poynter L. «'. Oberlies. !. H. Hatfield. . Secretary \V. K. .lakway I. H Ilatlield. . Delinquent interest, premium* i * ■-. ;in&lt;l taxes paid </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 I RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOR TQF PI8C YEAR ENDING JUNE .in. IMS. HE KUT.S AN TQK FIS Ills. yy RECEIPTS, REC EIPTS nee on hand July 1, 11*17 1 hand July 1 ning stuck) . , (running stock) ... " . (full paid stock) paid k est [UIIIS . bership and transfer fees .1 t s repaid ■state sales (lues MIS Tctal ... Mi* Tr.t * II • ,„,„„. EXPENDITURES. EXPEND! URES f Salaries Sala Ml CommtotiuoH other expenses Wit Wit Mat Full Withdrawal*, dues Withdrawals, earnings .'. Manned stock, dues ... Full paid stock, dues .... Kull paid Mock, earnings &lt; 'ash on hand . , • KurniLijit* iiu.t supplies MittceUiiDeoiin Total MlM nr Plan of Association. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. I I'l'LEMENTAL REPORT Plan Par value of each share of stock' * £ a ' l tt.li share of' stock No. of series issued since organizati t No. of series issued since organization " No. of shares issued since organization No no. ..I m,:ii.-s in force ;it date of last report No. No. of shares issued during fiscal 'year*"!" 0 ' rooting of two preceding iimis . No. of shares issued during fiscal year hooting of two preceding items s-,, No •al year No. y~. '•■"■« n.twu^rawn 7 ' No. of sliares in force at this date No. of shares in force at this date No. of shares of runnins; stock in force at this' date 1^^^:^;:"'-":::::::::::: no: of 1 ,.^ stock in force at th '» •:::::::::::::::: full paid stock in force at this daU '.'.'."."."""" No So ■Mlbject Ux-am-ellation for mmpavnieni of c »int of dues ilclimiuf nt »t this date Mntcri- &lt; :inil «n,.. ,1..- ,«J '_■".:: t A-nount of lnt&lt;Te«1 , n .l flnn due and ! .vwgniorinmoi n ,t,ims ami ilnM due and unpaid No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of «ame No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same """■. ','', ;; n " lu^ rral estat « "P^n wtak* "kmns' i,ave".\;.en * ount of. «am AtL^r^^^^Jt^TSSLS^ a^^ a '« **** of i^ e * ' No. v) { al estate A|. iip&lt;m which loan Appraised value of improvements * Appraised value of improvement «' ;eer; n L.e f ""l-^-ed rea^sta-ie'-u^n'-h'i^ loans hav.' Amt Jecur?,v Ce '" f ° rCe 8ml assi^^'toVh«a SS - laiionascollateral * Amt - J"curT,v Ce .'" .'° rCe ' an ''' assi^^' to theaisociaiion- aW Voliaierai liomestead mortgages durinc'Vear" " * loans during fiscal year ..?.......$ Nn wl No. of Hi No. of No. of minors holding stork in the' 'association plX oY !W^ a&amp;3S3 S£S S —• : :, JZ Average rat A m fiscal year Average running time of .tori maVured during n«-,l yMr </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION Ob' THE LINCOLN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. NKBRASKA K Brown Wilson Snavely Parks DIRECTORS ilrown «' I. Olson ASSETS h'r^t morttrutre loans Tlnaur loans in pn &gt;took louns 'oreclosurc Keai estate Kurniture and nx\un I M*.ihiueiii interest, preniiuins and tine; -i-s and taie&gt; |.aio other asset: Total LIABILITIES i aiiital muck running, i Oues and dividends Full paid stock * M.3ai.M fcUMhim e Kund .led protlts ireholders on incomplete iosns Premiums unearned Advance duev included in tirM u^m AdTance interest and premltu Total on the .ioth day of -June. I9M llurkett. Wilson and llruwn K. i I&gt;'(inartl </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 RF.CEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR KNDINC ,11 NK 30. 1908 RECEIPT Balance on hand Dues, (running s * Dues, (full paid st Interest Premiu Fines Membership and transfer fe&lt; Loans repaid KXPENIUTURK I.'.ar ex vv Wit Matin ed Matured Pali pud st 1 :.. Total I 50.HV.I 8UPPLEMENTAI REPORT ent) Pll Perma Permanent | &gt; No. of nee organization. (if serial No. of sliai. -uue organization No. of 8 laics ill force ill liuli' of last I t No of shares issued during tis&lt; al yea K No. of shares wi ;il year No No t nut withdraw No No No l at this date e at this dat stork in f( No No nt ion f layment of due r lat t at tl ing t kholders &gt;reclosure, and aggregate amount of san \o No mortgage* in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same Amount «,f loans on improved real estat real estate $ 4; eal estate upon which loans have M i Appraise. 1 value of improvements f 83.350 Atnouft of loans unon unimpro\ ed real estat Xtnout-t of loans ii'ion unrnlo-ox ed real estate * 700 Oi Apprnise! value nf unimproved real estate upon which loans have* SHI! A:nt. Insurance in forre and assigned to the association as collateral fi3.l-.IO ■ &gt; \-,i Iransniurte for huiM'ni? nuryvises d N'o. loan* made for pavment of homestead mortgages during year . . Amount nf advance payment of loans during fiscal year ..... a No of borrowing stockholders \ No. of non-horrowing storkholdc No. of minors holdinc stock in the association Averape rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durinsr fiscal year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of p Amonn credited to reserve fund during fiscal year .. $ •ve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . . % 5C&amp;.af Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal vear . . Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Ing time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE UNION LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA on the 30th day of June, 190K oi- ■FICERS I. If. Stewart .{'resident A. L. Johnson Yice-President A. W. Miller Secretary I.. J. Dunn Treasurer .1. M. Stewart Attorney DIRECTORS J. M. Stewart H. J. Winnelt A. 1- Johnson L. J. Dunn A. W. Miller ASSETS ortiraire loan ■ &gt;rtt(as;e loans in process of forclosure stock loans furniture and Futures lent interest premiums and fine Krp-nses and taxes paid Ulher asset Total ♦ 41 LIABILITIES Capital stock mnninir I Dues and dividendii Full paid Mook. •m - e fund I'ndtvided proflu Uue shareholder* on incomplete loan* Premiums unearned 4.7: Advance due;* Advance interest and premium: Total </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 RKCKIPTS AND KXPKNDITl'l KS FOR THK FISCAL YKAB ENDING .11 NE 30, UXti RECEIPTS Balance on hand J 1JL Dues, (lull paid »t Interest 1'r Klne M« U,a Keal Be T. EXI'ENDITL'HE! I..,. « Matured Mi' urt*U r Ku I.M hi SUPPLl .M ISN'T AL. KEPOKT nanciiij ...... l'lan of Ass. I'eruiunenl 1 I'ai No Zi n (if serial) No zati No. No :d dur ul ar FtHitlnK of Iwq ii ei edinig Uenia No. of shares withdrawn before uiuiii.it v during naru. withdrav No wit dat N&lt; at this date . i at this date N . No No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of du Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owinp by borrowing stm-kholde Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1 aggregate amount of san- ar N.i Amount of loans on improved real estate t\ i Apr proverr ents I \. praised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans ha Appra the association as collateral Amt. Insu and a igned t I of loans made for hnildine purposes during fiscal year No. of ■ad mortea^es during yea No for payment omest yt loans during fiscal year ■ Am No of No. of non -borrowing stockholders * No. of minors holding stock in the association I. Averaee rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal vear Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year I 1M l« Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year mount of losses charered to reserve fund during fiscal vear . . . mount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . * Ifl3.74 An 1 on full mid stock during fiscal vear * ends declared during fiscal year arc rate per cent of d Running Stock, B per cent: Full raid. 7 per c </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 OF THK CONDITION OK TH1- FIDKLITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION \V. A. KorsjUi W. K. Sharp W. .1. Hill . vv a I'or-wh 1-1 .1 Huilirr l-"ir^( iititrt il Slulinner IK*lui.men ■ - .Hid t;ix«'^ | T • i stork ■ rund i.-«i |.r..fi Artvunrt- inier*"'! jinrt premiunix To! STATEMENT II. II. Treat K. .1. Hhiiiit rrnni ibm lintiflld Advance Out**. </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 I ECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES F()K THK r is AI. Yr AK Balance on hand July 1, 100? Dues, (ruiuiiiii; stuck) I'ucv &lt;Kuu |imu suck Iiue frem Ki Mei liWiQ I' Bills 1'i T( EX I Loan Ot Wit Will Mature Man,, I .1 r; To 1'1'L R I No. of series issued aim e or^amza S*"*o. of shaies issued since organ izy l pea lu (nire at d.u *■ of luii rt£|H o. of shares issued during fiscal y No. of shares vitbdntWR be'ore uiii'unrv &lt;iur No. of shares ma uretl during tisi-al yea Nurnlier of shares &lt; an&lt; el led during N, No t No at t No upnt No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of til S amount of dues delinquent at thii nt of dues owinp bv borrow ins s nt of interest, premiums find fines No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and No. mortffajrM in process of foreclosure ar &gt;winff stockholders ... tock If d fines due and unpaid An d fines due and unpaid No t.c t ure, and aggreprate nmount of same i -•ate in \,, \, Ni opure and aggregate amount of panic ml a te a Amount of loans on improved rear estate Amount of loans on improved rent estate t of loans on improved rent estate i sed value of improved real estate upon which loans liav« Appraised vahie of improved real estate Appra 5eri « Apr if improv ents •» tn Ami. insurance in force and ass-iemed to the association as collateral rturlnp fiscal yen No. loans made for pavment of homestead mortcri of ad\ d fiscal vea A rln N. No No. of minors holrlin^ stock in the a latlon Avern«re mte per cent of Interest ■nl year ■al year Av it premiums charg Plan of premium ... . Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year « Anr a^qred und d fl«cnl re»r Amount of fllrMp ends declared on nmnlne stoclc duHne fl •n! vear vear A of di 1 a vai i s. auu "1 borrowers during d borrowers during •nds dprlarwi on ftiTl paid "trwlc dnrfne fls^ni y </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 STATEMKNT OF THE CONDITION' OK THE McCOOK COOPERATIVE BUILDING AND SAVINGS ■«- imere^l ;md preiuinin </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES F( )K THE FISCAL, YE \K ENDING JUNE 30, 1908. „ , RECEIPTS. IU: Balance on lianel July 1, 1997 . • Dues, (running stock) . * % Dues, (full paid stock) Interest Premiums Fines Fine Men Loai Membership and trail ..'.'. Loans repaid Real estate sales Real Rent Rents Total EXPENDITURES. Xl'l T Loans .... Loar Salaries . . ......'.'.'.'. Commission! &lt;•. Other expenses Withdrawal*, dues Wit Witl &lt; Withdrawals earnings. Matured stuck. does Mat Mil. Matured stuck, earninro Full paid stock, dun y ( 'ash on h;ind ... BIBs payable Total SUPPLEMENTAL KEI'ORT. Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) Pla Par No. Par value of each share of stock No. of series issued since organisation, (if serial) .... la IZ No. of shares issued since organization .■»-._ No. of shares m force at date oi Wo Mo. No. of snares issued during fiscal year Foot In if of 1 v No No No No. of shares withdrawn before maturity during n No. of shares matured during fiscal &gt;ear No. of wharftM cancelled durioic nscal j ear. hut not witbdra « n rooting of three preceding items ■ f No Na No. of shares in force at this date .'.'. No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of "ull paid stock in force at this date: Mutun No ot share-, loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of d Total amount of dues delinquent n' Amount of dues owing by borrowing st - '.'.'.'..... A A &gt;W Amount of Interest premiums and u ,\ No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. ate amount of same No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same No amount of same N Amount of loans on Improved real estate * 1 Amount of Appraised v; Appra AlllDIMIt .&gt;f h 1 esta Appraised value of Improved Appraised value of improvements Amount .»f loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate* upon whir Amt. insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral Amt nt. insurance in force and assigned to ttie association as collate No. of loans made for building: purposes during fiscal vear No. of loans made f:&gt;r building: purposes during- fiscal vear No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages duri Amount 'if advance payments of loans during fiscal year ir.sna '.»i Amount of advance payments of loans durii .. No. of borrowing stockholders .. No No. of non-borrowing stockholders N,, No. of minor* holding stock in the association No. nf minors holding stock In the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year ' Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during- fiscal year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year'!'! Amount of looses charged to reserve fun«1 n - Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stork during fiscal year .. Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal &gt;^ear Amount </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 STATEMENT CK THE CONDITION OF THK MADISON COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAM ASSOCIATION MADISON'. NEBRASKA ■) Henderson H. Davis ... .1. I. Grant Ml HI TORS A-~ • rtitaire Iduiin ■ ■rttf^i:e loans in pr oana Real estate Furniture ;md Hxture C»sh Delimiuent interest, pretniu Kxi&gt;enses and lues paid t&gt;ther Assets Tota I.I.VH1I. !:&gt;• Capital stock running (Dues and d Full paid stock Keserve fund Undivided profits. Due shareholder, on incomplete Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiun Tota t On the :tutli day of June. 1» ~-nvder President Vice-President tary Treasurer Attorney r Richardson R. Q. MaMBM .1 L.i.raiii .lacoh Menders. C. S. Snyder Fred H. n. </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 RECEIPTS AND KXPKNDLTl/l KS FOK THK FISCAL VKAK NE 30, l'.kis KNDING JUNE 3tt, IMW RECEIPTS. 4ECEIPTS Bah Due Due Inte Prei Kir { : M &gt;■ 41 fees Real Rent; Tax m *:tt EXPENDITURES. u» w Wit Wit Matu Matu Full F ■PI .b'.MMMTA |, HKPCJ - L KE1 No rial or Permanent of stock I s organization, (if serial) zation .... ■ i eiMirt .... . ! year No! hefure maturity dui rinK li irinis i. ut not withdrawn K items this ilnte «to&lt; k in fon-e at this d stock in ferca at thi.-^ No No. lies :i : ancellatlon for non-payment of d I linqnent at this date ind tines due and unpaid •sure, anil agKieKate amount of same. All Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid N &lt;&gt;- «'" Lire, ami agKret,-ate amount of same. No So. | VO i . I 500.00 No if foreclosure and aRRregate amount of same No. mortgages in | :md aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on Improved real estate « ;b have been. A,., A m« Apr oveiru'nts n proved real estate upon which loans have i to the association as collateral At I :*&gt;;«» No of loans made for building purposes durlnir flseal year ldinR purposes durlnc fiscal year No. loans mnde for payment of homestead moTttrnires during vear J nt of homestead moftcnces during year . . A pnt of loans during fiscal year ing fiscal yea older* No [] No. of niinots holding stork in the assocfatt « k in the association Av. iniums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium . Monthly Amount credited to teserye fund during fiscal vear * I IT 77 Amount of losses chareeil to reserve fund during fiscal vear J 1.10 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year ". '. I I it of dividends deHared on fun iiafd stork durinc Psrnl vear Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year . IIJ A, Av6r&amp;ff6 ninninc* t f me or s 1 1 m ■ W m&amp; tnrrd rl 1 1 ri n z a q^oi vpaf </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 i STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OPTHK MADISON BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION MADISON. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1906 §Kubrndall Hendersc I)o» iinjr Pirns.. I t&lt; sidei Vice-Presidei Seeretai Trvasun Attorney Andrt Jami-s M Boy Ha W C ll» .lat-ob K ASSETS I- A tixt .1 Total I.I A HI MTI i'.&gt; z ■ iled i&gt;n •-I - uui^ unearn Advanced Advance interest and prei . lota; </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 IIKIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FIS( IPTS V N AL V E AH ENDING JUNE 30, i RECEIPTS, RECEII Td Balance on ha ce on hand July 1, in; (running *t., (full paid stock) s urns V w Krahlp and transfer fees i repaid Total EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURES I Ful Pul &lt; as lissiuns Other expenses Irawals. dues H Matured stock, dues Matured slink, earnings . Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings .'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Rhand Tola; . , SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. f Association. (Serial or Permanent) lue of each share of stock series issued si: nation, (if serial) shares issued since organization &lt; ■ - , SUPPLEMENTAL, REPORT of Association. (Serial or Permanent » No. i wo. of series issued since organization, (if serial No. of shares issued since organization z No. of shares In force ;it date ..f last report ' '".'.'.'" shares issued during fiscal year e of hvu preceding Items ...'.'.'..."...' &gt;liares vltMrmvn before inarurit v. during fiscal year ' shares matured during fiscal year led during nscal year, hut not withdrawn _' of three preceding items No vi.ircs wiinnniwn oernre iiiarunt v. during rtsoa '. shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares in force at this date No. of shares in force at this dat No. of shares of running stock In force at this date No. of shares of running stock In force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock In force at this date" N t this date Vo. of shares loaned rat No. of shares on which dues are delinquent ........[... .. No dellr ml No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date " No Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders ...... iwing t ile \moimt of interest premium* and lines due No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same, s, N So. of mortgage* in process of foreclosure, and s#trrcirate amouo Amount of loans on improved real estate * . alue of improved real estate ujmi which loans made N t r d renl estat ar A, Appraised value of Improvements ements \mount uf loans u|H&gt;n unimproved real estmle An real estm Vpnraised value of unimproved real estate upon . have tiem i Aim a nf which loans have &gt;f Amt. insurance in forje mid assigned to the association as collateral Amt. Insurance In forje and assigned to the association as colli security No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages durln No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during* "ye -a e Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year '. . ...i •&lt; v *, Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year *?;&gt;. of tiormu intr stockholders No. of non-borrowing stockholders Nfo. of non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the association ............. No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal t of year Pla An, Am Plan of premium. Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year t fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal ye ve fund during fiscal yea Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal ve An d on full paid stock during fiscal v ■d on running stock during fiscal . r e Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal . ei t dl 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 STATEMENT Of' THE CONDITION OF Till- NEBRASKA CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA On the .'iutli iluv of .1 OFFICERS K' Fastenau law II Vice I K. Pitzer Meyer. Pitzer Sccrt-tur.v Treasurer M W \V H V. M W. W. Me ASSET id lixt aXt To LIABILITIES n« i Bii iucuin]ilet&lt; [1 - : uod t Tol « </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 ) EXPENDITURES Fill! THE FISCAL YEA1 ENDING JINK 30, 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION' Or THE NELSON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION NELSON. NEBRASKA On the Mth day of June, llios ■FFICKI. Secretary Treasurer r\ttornev I &gt;I BETTORS ■•■odrieh Henry Fox. .Ir. E. I). Brown C P. Stoner W W Ha " W - Huui E Shelton A. W. McResni.lds ft W. Wrirh- ETS A t z '■ loans in process of for. » luxes imid A T..t t MA HI TIES Ones and divide M led pro Advance interest and premiums. Total II. E. Goodrich Henry Fox. Jr. Adah V. Stoner A. .1. Stoner. . . Brown. . . I 'resident Vice President Krehulders on incomplete loans us unearned e dues . </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES F(&gt;K '1 VKAK ENDING .) INK 30, lixi BK K SCAT „ , RECEIPTS. RECEIPT Balance on hand July 1, imc Balance on hand Dues, (running s y Dues, (running stock) ' * L&gt;ues, (running si Dues, (full paid Interest Dues, (full paid stock) . Interest Premiums 1" • Fines Membership and transfer Men Loa Loans repaid Real estate ulng 5 Rents Ke &lt; &gt;n accounts Tax sale certifies Total Tax sa T t; f , EXPENDITURES XPENDITURI Titans. . r,«»;in Saku | Salaries . CominigMlum other expenses er Withdrawals, dues Witl Witl Mati Mati w Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues . Mature] stock, earning* .... ... &lt;t Full paid stock, dues '..'..'.'.'. Full J Full paid stock, earning 1- Cash mi hand Tax Mile eertiOoab Total P.an or Association. SnrLKMEXTAL KEPORT. LK.M1 PORT Plan As Par value of esu h sliare of stock Par v No. o No. of series issued since organization, !No. of shares issued since organization O. of shares in force ;it date .if ; o. of shares issued during fiscal year mtiiiK of two preceding items ....'......'.'.'..." &gt;. of shares withdrawn iierore maturity durinir Aural vear o. of shares ci &gt;lled during fiscal year, but not KitnJrn lOtinR nf three yrec e.liriK items o. of shares in force at this date '.'...' o. of shares of runningr stock in force at this date o. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date ' X or s 1 d on o. of shares on which dues are delinquent ".'.'.'.'. ...'.'..'. [ (.shares suhiccr tt&gt; cancellation for nonnavmem rkfhn»fl No. No. xa Foot N(&gt;. I No. \\ No. of shares in force at this date No. of No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date . '. '. '. '. '. '. No d 10 Tota Amount of dues owing by borrowing \r, nouwii in iniri«-&gt;L jirt-iiiiiiMi- :tn*l nnes flue .tnnnniiu'n No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same • No and aggregate amount of sail Amount Amount of loans on improved real estate &gt; Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which luaniiiave'nien Appraised value of Improvement* ".'.".".'.'.".".'.*.".".'.'.".".".".".' &lt; Amount of loans upon uniiTn.nivfil reiil csiaie ? . iiiu.H' App I pon which loans have 1 r Amt. Insurance in force an.1 assigned to the association as collateral No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. loans made for payment of homestead mortpages durintr vear Amount of advance payments of loans rinrlnir flocnl t Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year t No. ot borrowing stockholders . " ■ t No. of w No. of IP stork in the association .......!!...!!"...'".' t of Interest charged borrowers during n.cni Jioi Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers 'during fiscal year a Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal vear ' . _,J Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal vear Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year' Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal vear " Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal vear 11 Average running time of stock matured during fiscal Amount of year rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal vear running time of stock matured during fiscal year matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 STATKMKNT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NUCKOLLS COUNTY HriIJ)IN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NKLSON. NKBRASKA on the .ioth day of .lune. 1908 OFFH'KRS Geo. Lyon Ji C. I). Peebler ( . K Iraler. . Henry Fox Ji- K. D. Brown President Secretary Treasurer Attorney DIUEc T ■ I ■m.lr K D Brown II KUoodricb F. E. HuitenHeld W \\ Hawle W A M. \V Carter Thus Grahan ASSET irtKaice loans i Titrate loans in proeesi of fore stock loans ure Reai eslalr Furniture and fixtures Delin&lt;iuent interest, premiuins and tine* Kxpeoftes and taxt*v paid , Other asset* Total I.IAUII.ITIH S . slock running. ( Dues and diviilead^ Full paid stock e Fund UndiTided protus Due fihareholders on incomplete l.iai, Premiums unearned Advance dues. Advance interest and ih i President </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 RrXl IPTS AND KAPKNDITrRr :.S FOR THK FISCAL E 30. 1908. VK AR NDING JUM in liHIS RECKIPT Due: Interest »nd tines Premiums Fines Membership and transfer fees I-oans repaid Real estate sales . Kents Total T Bxranimnra F.XPENDITl UK: Loans I»a ■ Salaries &lt; !ommiSHiotiM other e Withdr other expetnea Hi Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals earnings W l&gt; ar Matured slock, dues Matu Matu Matured stucK. earnings Full pa Full pa Cash ot Full paid stock, dues ill Kull paid stock, earnings Cash on hand tTnla. sri&gt;l'[,EMKNTAI. REPORT * "-ianon &lt; serial or permanent) PORT Plmn of association (serial or permane Par value or each share of stock 1'e Far value or each share o( stock ■rm. Par value of each share of stock Number of series issued since on Number or series issued since organization &lt;i( s,- , e orga; Number of shares issued since organization Num Number of shares in force at date of last rei&gt;ort Number of shares in force at da last rei Number of shares issued during tlseal year Footing of two preceding itcma Number of shares issued d .ir Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, dining fiscal \ ear Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, 'duii'nit fiscal year Number of shares matured during fiscal tear' Nunil matured during Number or shares canceled during fiscal year, but not withdrawn rooting of three preceding items Number ol shares canceled during Hsc»l year, but not withdrawn rooting "f three preceding items. . Number or shares in force at this date N a Number of shares of running stock in force at this dat • NumL II stock in force al this da Number ol shares of full paid stocn in force at this date Nun Number of shares loaned on Nun Number of shares on which dues are delinquent ....... Number of shares on which dues are delin w Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-pui ,.ieui ' l\ uui cellation lor 10 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date .. dues delinquent at ibis date Amount ol dues owing by borrowing shareholders .*. Amount ol dues owing by borrowing shareholders .', Amount of interest, premiums anu tint's due and unpaid ' All n iiniuiii in nii-ercsi. preiiimnis iinu nnes due ana unpaid * ] _ Number of ratMtvurm xuli •■ unit torretfate amount of sume Number of mortgages subject to foreclosure and aggregate aw N •cr*ss .»[ fureclOMbre. and ai/K rebate amount of si Numb -r of unmcairea in prueevi &gt;&gt;r forecknare. and aggregate an N f sam No Amoui.t o[ loans on iui|&gt;rovfii re;il estate An &lt; IM« Appraised va:ue or improved real estate upon winch loans have b AP Appraised va:ue of impmt ,-d real estate upon winch loans have been made * 9 2K.MI Appraised value of improvements Appraised value of improvements Amount or loans upon unimproved rt\ Amount of loans upon unimproved r- Appraised value or unimproved real estate upon which loans have Appraised value of unimproved r«»l estate u|H&gt;n which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association security Amount of insurance in force and assumed to the association as collateral security * MJSOIt Number of loans made for building pun»oses during fiscal year Number of loans made for building puri»oses during fiscal year. .iuuii^-1 «m iiittun mittir i&lt;»r uuimimf puriM)ses nunntf nscal year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortiratres during ttsral \ car Amount of advance payment of loans durinif fiscal year j 4bttMi Number of borrowm* stockholders Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages duri a.! Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year Number of borrowing stockholders Sumber of non-borrowing stockholders Num Number of miners holding stock in the association Nuir ie ass&lt; Average rate percent of interest charged borrowers during rtsca Aver ■d borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during ris&lt;' Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year t*lan of premium .Amount credited to reserve fund dur .Amour Kid . Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during tlscal year Amount of dividends declared on running ■■ vear nt of dividends declared on full paid stock during ilscal year AH Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during - Averatfe rur Nu ml </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OK THE NEWMAN GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA OFFICERS A. T. Rodman ChM. Lethebv Randall. K. H. Gt-rhart C. A. Randall .Attorney DIRECTORS A T Rodman V Randall Chas. Letheby K H Gerhart Kobert P. Pearson M. Jei ASSETS Tiifaife irtu'ajfe loans la prt t:, • Furniture and Fixtures Oash Delinquent interest pnmiumi ., Kx\&lt;vnse^ and taxes paid Other a Total LIAHII.ITIKS Capital stock running. (Hues and divid Full paid stuck Reserve fund Undivided profits Ihie sharelioidiTs on incomplete Premijms unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiurr Balance due on outstanding I'ertitica Total On the Itoth day of June. IMG • ... x i*f*sitipnt V ice-President Seeretarj Treasurer </seg>
            <seg id="p133">133 KKCKIPTS AND KXl'KNDIT URES FOR THK FISl JUNK M. 1908 AL YEAR KNI)IN«; RECEIF T:- Balance on hand July 1. liXtr . Dues, (running stuck; Due*. (Fun i&gt;ui&gt;i ikx .. Interest Interest Premiums Premiums Fines Fines : Membership and transfer fees Me Loans repaid Loans repa Delinquent* i Delinquents repaid- . l.edircr lls Earning ac Ledger Halance* Karnintf account . . Outstanding Certificates Total Tot a EXPSN1 HTUIUCfc EXPEN1 UTURi l.oai Commissions :iwals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Outstanding Certifies i Charged lu Ke^erve r'uiw U banted Delimiue Delin'iuent Matured stock, earning* Mat Full paid stock Full paid stock Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, — milts,! Cash on hand Total SUPPLEMENTAL RKPORT. Tota SUITLKUENTAL KEl'OUT Plan of Association, (Serial or I'erinanent) Plan of Ass nt Tar value of each share of stock 1'a No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) . . No, zatio if serial No. of shares issued since organization iharea in force at date of ia-»t report No. of ed izat No No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of shares issued during tiscal year ■ Footing of two preceding items Konti No. of shares withdrawn before maturity, during riscai year No rity. du No. of shares ma ured during fiscal year No Number of shares camelled during fiscal year, but not writ lid Xu wit Footing of t hrce preceding itemi No. of shares in force at this date late No. of shares of running stock in force at this date at this d No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent whi uent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues . . . No. of shar t to non-payment Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders . Amount wii kl Amount of interest, premiums and tines cine and unpaid Amount of interest, premiums and tines due nnd unpaid No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of sai No. mortgf id aggregate umo t a No No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate ft mo* ml of sa Amount of loans on improved rear estate Amount of loans Appraised value i Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans havi heen made Appraised value of improvements Appraised value of improvements - Amount of loans upon unimproved r^ni estate An Amt. insurance in force and ass-lgned to the association as collate ■Morlty Amt. Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral - ■poses during fiscal vear No. of loans made for building purpose? during fiscal venr No. of loans made No. loans made for payment of homestead mortcaees during year No. loans made for payment of homestead mortcaees during year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year No. of borrowing stockholders No. of non-borrowing" stockholders No. of minors holding stock In the association Averapre rate T Interest charged borrowers during ft il year Avera per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium S Amount credited to reserve fund du fiscal A mo ar Amount of dividends declared on running stork during flsrat year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal vear Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during flsr-al year </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION H. A Pasewalk President Ilr. A. Bear Vic-President &lt; 15. Druland Secretary W. J. Stafford Treasurer Mapes A Hazen Attorney DIREC T )i: H A. I'.. Dr A. Bea John Wels: IV- Anton Bucbhol/. Ueo li hristopl I M Ma Peter Stafford Onu ri A I- TS First mnrtuaue loan: f I ■ rltraite loans in process of fore oans r ,0 Furniture und Mxtun -ent interest, premiums and tin ses and taxes paid B Assets Heal estate sold on eontrac nee Profit and Loss and Interest on u dv Ace pu Tot I.I AMI I ,ITIE stock running. I Dues and dividends .d stock •• fund llndi»ided profits Premium Tils unearned Advance dm- t on I,oans Items and Initiation fee </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 RKCKIPTS AND EXPENDITURES V Ol THK K A I VI- AR S( N )ING .JINK "HI* :ceip * Dues, (r stock I.. Interest Premiur m Fines Meml fcS pa T. \ I&gt;I cm Loan Salai :« ex Withd Advan Mulur. Taxes Insura Sundri pa id Heal B Bilis Pn T ta SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT p, Ass na t ) Par v No. o rial) izat lizat No No. No Fix No N,&gt; \v t V sliares of runnins: stock in force at this dat No. of shares on which dues are delir No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of OM1 !-• Total amount of dues delinquent at this date t Total amount An w A'tiount of inrere-t. urcnunin* :inri Hnes &lt;t\ie »nd onn»*«1 No morteaees suhioc t to foreclosure, and aggrregate amount or same No. mortR N, A A PI * Apr ation as collateral Arr Kins made for liuilrtint' inirmwc-i rturin ,ians made for payment of homestead mortgages during year . . Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year } No Nr No t Vf A &gt;w V A, Amount of losses charee&lt;l to reserve fund during flp"al venr • Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year .li id stock dnrine fiscal vear An Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year a „(„„ ♦;„,« n r c t,i..v mohird finHnr fl«cii! vear . ... li d during fiscal A Average running </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 OF THK CONDITION OF THE NORFOLK, NEBRASKA (in tlieifiith day of June. IMS OFFI( KRS Dr. H. .1. c, Attorne DIRK TORS Ilr H J. ( A Dei^ner T E Odiu W A W.l Olamma H. C Mmtrmo t. K. Davenport ASSK1 'S Furniture iind Kii El t pretmunis and tint Tot l.IAHII.ITIKS * .ireholder., on incomplete loans frrmiums unearned Advance du I STATEMENT ELKEORN BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION A. I leaner Vice-President I K. ( kliurne Secretary W.A. Wiui^raan V.V. Treasure ■ si,.ck runninir. ( Hue* and dividend* - I unit I'ntlivided pronts </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 Balance c Dues, (11 Dues, (f Interest Premium Fines . . . Memljers Loans r&lt; Real est Rents . On other i Tol i a C Ot Wit Withd Matured M;iuirt*&lt;l I x Pl« No. No. No No. N N N N N it • An, API Apr Ami AP s N N No. of Averae Av Amount Amount J ickholders took in the association 1 interest charped borrowers durine •'••■■•I vear remiums charged borrowers durinc fls'-al vear erve fund durine fiscal venr f *1 to reserve fund durinp fiscal venr rlareii on runnirir stork rturine flsral yea -lnrert on full pi id stock &lt;&lt; if dividends declared during; fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 STATKMKNT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NORTH LOUP BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH LOU1". NKBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1906 OFFICERS KK. Johnson Hutchins. Habcock. S. Mayo Habcock Vice-President .Secretary Treasurer .Attorney DIRECTORS Geo E Johnson E A. Hutcbins ieo. s. Mayo A C. A Thornitate S. L. Clemen E. J. Babcock ASSETS Firm mortratfe loans t 11 01 5.0 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans c Real Estate Furniture and fixtures Delinquent interest, premiums and lines. Never entered till paid. De linquent earned interest is however about tlfC.Stf Expenses and taxes paid. Account balanced and chirrired off Other assets Total » LIABILITIES Capital stock running. I Due* and dividends] Full paid stock t KM I-'SO Reserve fund 4148 Undivided profits (In ad Jim. m there is about IISiSH Delinquent intere: earned) Dae shareholder* on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues. AH carried in Capital Stock, item I ... Advance interest and premiums. AH carried in item 4 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p139">RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE IK), 1908. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 11807 ♦ tU» Dues, (running stock) MM.M Due«. (full paid itock) iuoou Kl Absts '. —jo Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid \MBM Real estate sal Total l~ 8.HB.74 EXPENDITURES Loans • 4.«so.oo Commissions Other expenses TVW Withdrawals, dues I , Tn Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, dues Full i&gt;aid stock earnings HIM (To correct error &gt;.. It.tt .a band Mg.it Total t S.MI?« SUPPLEMENTAL, REPORT Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) Permanent Par value of each share of stock I luu M ' series issued since organization (if serial) No. of shares issued since organizattoi MN No. of shares in force at date of last report Ml No of shares Issued during fiscal year 1 19 Footing of two preceding items Ml No. of shares withdrawn before maturity during fiscal year 17 No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares canceled durintc fiscal year but not withdrawn Footing of three preceding items 17 No. of shares In force at this date s«s.&lt; No. of shares of running stock in force at this date Ma IHO. Ut »II»I ITS Ul 1 UlllllllB ai"i ■* »•» »ui&lt;_*j «v utia ua»»vi .rw No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date IT No. of shares loaned on 40 No! of shares on which dues are delinquent M No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues W Total amount of diias delinquent at this date (no anrr. kept, about) $ 130.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders I KM. 90 im« and tin*** due and unn:i'«l (nt&gt; fteel. kept ahout)9 IQS.M No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. Vo I.I 1.M0.00 No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same No. I Amount of loans on improveJ real estate .. # 11.91500 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been » n.uo.,. Appraised value of improvements t I7.7SS.* Amoum of lo'in&lt; upon un'mnroT&lt;-&lt;1 r&gt;-^i esiv Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made • ■ ♦ Amt. Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral i tumjm No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year 4 l^O. Ol IO»I1» IIIUUC IUI IU1IUIIIH &lt; I &lt; • I , I &gt; ■, ••.-.•&gt;. ..... No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year I 1 NO. 00 No. of borrowing stockholders tt No! of non-borrowing stockholders *&gt; No! of minors Holding stock In the association * Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year t » Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year I *7 M Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year I Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . j §tt H4 Amount of dividends declared on full paid sto«»k durintr fiscal yea r . Ht.tO Average rat* per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 CF THE CONDITION OF THE MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION Thomas « ' Patter Victor Van Goet? Samuel Goi Frank E. Bui lard Wilt-ox &amp; Halliyu 1 'resident Vice-Pi Secretary Treasurer \ MM i Ira I., liar W. M f*iiiinlii|fc»«i Qeo. W. I M. I P. T. I ■di \Vaik&lt; Patt AN ET Kir&gt;t Ke a . h Kuniit r\ lixmr. Deli Kilrenses und tax otlirr As^-U •I t.IABH.ITIKS apita anrt dividends Kull paid SU rve fun . peholders on ii I*reii)iums unearned - . Advance dues A Advance interest and prem Tot STATEMENT NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA i &gt;n tin' 30th day of June. l!»i ed pmtiis </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL VKAI ENDING JUNK 30, I'.hi- RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1. I'.K'T B. Due Dues, (running stock) Dues, (full paid stock) Dues, (f Interest Preniiuins Interest n Premiums . K Membeiship and transfer fees Mem Loans repaid -' Real estate sales Total To EXPEND1TUMH Loans «■ Lo. Salaries UommigsioDx . Other expenses oil Wl Withdrawals, duea Withdrawals, earnings Matured stuck, .1..- Matured stock. Mining* ■ Full paid stock. dues ... Full p run i Cssb 01 Pull paid stock, earning! ra^h on hand Total ... SI riM-KMKNTAL REPORT. 1 Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) lormri ri 1 ■•: | Far value ot each share of stuck • No of series issued lince organization, (if serial) . iza No of Bliarea Issued sine- organization No No No oi »hare» in force »t rt»te of i»hi report No. of shares issvn-d during fiscal year FoOtillK "1 two prci.dnm Hilt:s No of shares withdrawn before maturity during fiscal year ■hares matured during fiscal &gt;. No No So ..! shai.s . an. elled during fiscal year, but not withdrawn Footing "f three pi edinu Itenw No. of shares in force at this date ■ No of sliaios of I'linniiiR stock in force at this date date No No! of shares of full paid stork in force at this date ■ shares Inane. 1 on at this date No No No of shares on which dues are delinquent No' of shares on which dues are delinquent ■■• No of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues P M 1 . . J ■ If ■■ ■■■■ mm* # nf tliio .In til No of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date t at this &lt;1at Amount of .lues owing by borrowing stockholders . - A wl and unpaid ■• Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid . » st An No. morteaKes subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount nf ■■"»*■ N. No mnUam in process of foreclosure and aKBreKate amount of same „.,.„ Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraiser] value of improved reel esutc upon wmen * nts Appraised value of improvements • A Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have -nt insurance In force and assi'sned "to the association as collateral - - - --*— f *»*.s. Amt No of loans made for luilidinp purposes during fiscal year No. loans made for payment of homestead mnrtfeae" during year . Nf during fiscal yea Atnr No of horrowintr stockholders No. of non-horrowinp stockholders No of minor* holding stock in the association Avernire rate per centof Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year latlon No Average rate per cent" of Interest charg Plan ■■ Amount credited to reserve fund durlnR fiscal year Amount of losses chanted to reserve fund during fiscal year !,.-... Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year full |.-&gt;'d stock duripir I Amount Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 OF THE CONDITION OF THE MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1908. OFFICERS ( has. P. Southard President Chas. E. Reynolds Vice President (i. M. Nattingfer Secretary O. If. Nattinjjer Treasurer Attorney DIRECTORS Chas P. Southard G M. Naltinner T. L. Ringwalt C. E. Reynolds H. P. Ryner ASSETS First morttr age loans t 1.J7S76 First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure Stuck loans Delinquent interest, premiums and Ones Expenses and taxes paid Otber assets. Total • 1.M4.W LIABILITIES Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends! . Full paid stock « as si Reserve fund . Undivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums . Omaha Loan and Building Association Mortgage covered by Sale Contract to Q. L Swartz 16 li) Total S 1 :KI n- Note— In process of voluntary liquidation STATEMENT </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 RKCKIPTS AND KXl'KNDITl'RKS FOR THK FISCAL YKAR NDING .TUN K 30. lMtix RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1. in; I 9OS. SB Dues, (running stock ) 13.00 Full paid stock. contracts . M3.90 Membership and lr» Loans repaid Keal estate ha Due Treasurer 1« '• Total ♦ EXPENDITURES Loam I Commissions MM Other expenses MM Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earning Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earning Total .* I.4MSI SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) Seria' Par value of each share of stock I too (H No. of series Issued since organization. (If serial) M No of shares issued since organization .■ M No &lt;»f shares in force at date of last report shares Issued during fiscal year Footing of two preceding items *l Glares withdrawn before maturity, during fiscal year • No nf shares matured during fiscal year - ares cancelled during fiscal Tear, but not withdrawn Footing of three preceding Items 9 No. of shares In force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No of shares of full paid stock In force at this date No of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are dellnouent su No! of shares subject to cancellation for non-pavment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date * *_ A ., n » nt ,lnoa nwlnv hv hrtrrftwfnff stockholders . ■ Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders Amount of interest nremiums and nn&lt;"« due anil nnnairt No mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. No. of mortgages In process of foreclosure, and agtrreira'e amount of same No Amount oif loans on improved real estate I l.W TO Appraised value of Improved real estate upon whlrh loans have been made • . ■»-•» • of Improvements * 1 (M» .»&gt; Appraised value of Improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Apnraised value of unimproved real estate upon which 'o«n« hnve hetn made Ami. Insurance in for-e and assigned to the association as collateral security i • .^W-0* No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year ■loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year . unt of advance payment of loans during fiscal year I «f hoTowinir «toekho!der« * No. of non-borrowing stockholders No of minors holding stock In the association Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 7 8- 10 Kof premium nt credited to reserve fund during fiscal year t Jl nt of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year I68.S" i rrsi </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF' THE NEBRASKA SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th dav of .June. l!ti KK1C KK Thos. A. Krv President Wilcox Vice President D. H. (ristie Seen Lk M. Talroage John L. Kennedy IHKKl TORS A ET nurtirn lop lire Furniture nod hxlure it-tit interest. pretniu:ni and tir ses and taxes p;nd i«fi&gt; ire»l e-t»te euntr; T..t ■ I.I A HI T1KS Cmintnl stock runniiitf. {Unesand tlividends Ke^rve fund I'ndiTided profits on incom|&gt;le1 Frennunis unearned Adr^noe dues :e loan f Attom.-y ■ A Fry K. S . Wilcux I. . M. Talmaife 1 lav id Onia John "". Hrandt \V It T Belt Thos V. (indfrey Byron K Hutinci TVw I nililllta </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 RECEIPT8 AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAK ENDING JUNE 38, 190*. REC EIPTS Balance on hand July 1 Dues, (running stock) . Dues, (full paid stock I :U13.:17 I 1S4.K5J.I* Premii Fines Memb. Loans j:i M B Real estate Rents Sundry ai Tota f IMJM.M 3XPENI 1 TURES Loans Salarle Kent . . . tSI 4nrui i :«ii. M 1*10.011 I ... ,i;{ ■ eipen* L Withdrawals, d Withdrawals earn Matured stock, di^ Matured stock, ear] Full paid stock, due Full paid stock. Cash on hand Advance pajn I :»TI» Secretary of Stat Total SUPPLEMB ;ntal report onnerly serial Plan or Assoctat Permanent Par value of each share of stock * 100.00 No. of series issued since organization. if serial) No. of shares issued since organization No. of shar No. of shares issued during fiscal year Footing of two r No. of shares withdrawn before maturity during fiscal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year N'o. of shares cancelled during tiscai year, but not withdra wn Footing of three preceding items No. of shares in force at this date tv:tt7 No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of "ull paid stock in force at this date No. ol shares loaned oa 1.943 No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date • Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders Amount of interest premiums and tin* s&lt;lu*» an*) unpaid t No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same, No. S No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same No Amount of loans on improved real estate S IIM.Ma.0* Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hare been made I 3x- Appraised value of improvements I 1M.M6.M - Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real rotate upon which loans ne**n rrnrt •$ Amt. insurance in force and assigned to the association aa collateral security * lSM.t4«.or&gt; No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal vear M * No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year Amount ayments of loans during fiscal year No. of borrowing stockholders lft* No. of non-borrowing stockholders Mi No. of minors holding stock in the association 1- Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 7 8-10 Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year I S.6U.U Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged To reserve fund during nseal v#ar Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year .. i Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running ttm« of »tock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NKBRASKA on the .filth day of June .1908 • i. \V. Loomi E. Brjtoo (i. M. Nattinjrer W. U. Adair Henry W. Yate. Frank H. Gaine- John H. But E A. Panue Millard M Rohert 'irttraice loan: Ttiraife luting in prtx Rcfti ' Furniture and tiitun .ent interest i&gt;remiums and Hn m 1 * and uic- puitl I.IAHII.ITIKS stock runninK ( Dues and diviilend^) Full |»id stock e Fund led i.rolits Due shareholders ih Premiums unearneil Advance dues Advance interest ;ind premiun Kuildinif Earniiiirs and K Total </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 RECK 11 rs AN ) XFENDITURES FOR THr ENDING JUNK 30, 1U08 FISCAL YE AK !• RECEIPTS. Balar J uid 1 Dues, (rumi liuev (Full i Interest . . . Premiums Fines Membership and transfer fees and miscellaneous unei Loans repaid .... Keal estiile Kents Building . tf.3IT.t Kent!. H Bill Pay; Koreclo? Bill Payable. Foreclosures ... Total Tota EXPENDITURES. XI KN1HT i:hes. t Loans Salarie Conimi L,oans * SII.JS4.H * lll.i«W 11 win Salaries 1 1 «S3. - Commissions Other expenses Otlier expi Withdrawals, dues Withdraw ,K Heal estate improvements . **o.n Keal estai Building Expenses Building Kxi I Furniture and Fixtures Kurniture ai i Foreclosure Foreclosure Mil's Payable.. Bills t rash on hand 1VS7U.3 ,sh on ha Total S U 1 "P L, K.MEXTA L, REPORT. Tot PPLENENTAL KEPOKT Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) Permanec Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) Permanent Par value of each share of stock I 20U.I Par value of each share of stock I 20U.UO No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) tl4 No. of shares issued since organization No. of shares issued since organ izut No ot shares m force at date of last ra|MH1 No ot share* m force at date of ia&gt;t ra|MH1 No. of shares issued during liscal year No. of shares issued during liscal year Pooling of two preceding items Kooting of two preceding items No. of shares withdrawn before maturity, during tiscal year t No of *hare-* withdrawn before maturity, during tist'al yea No. of shares ma.ured during fiscal year No. of shares ma.ured during fiscal year RUI'i Number of shares cancelled durini ar. l&gt;ut ii"i • &lt; N Footing of three preceding items 6441 1 Footing of three preceding items 6441^ No. of shares In force at this date «.*17' No. of shares in force at this date «.5I7 No. of shares of running stock in force at this dat« M.axi' No. of shares of running stock in force at t; No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at tl No. of shan "ii No No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of Total amount of dues delinquent at this date ai No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of duel Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders Amou Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of sar N o. V No No. roorUraie* in process of foreclosure and amount of same No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of sa i No it » MM.! » IW. Si Amount of loans on Improved real estate i • Ar Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hav« heen made Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hav« lippn made *' - ii Appraised value of Improvements Appraised value of Improvements M Amount of loans upon unimproved real est:i r * upraised value unimproved re:i ■■ no en ii'irte prawen value unimproved real est»te imon rteen mine nt. insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral Amt. Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral ■eenrlti • " Amt No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year ile for building purposes during fiscal yea No loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year *■ Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year di No. of borrowing stockholders No. of borrow No. of non-borrowing stockholders ■ No. of non-borrowing stc ii No of minors holding stock in the association No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fls&lt;"il year Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during flscil year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year • * Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal yenr » ",'■'■ A-n.Mint of los«e« cha'eed to reserve fund durinc flscM rear Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal yea Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during flscul year I Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year « Average running time of stock matured during fl»cal year </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 STATEMENT CF THE CONDITION OF THE OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. IM0 OFFICERS BF. Flack President . McEachron \ ice-1'n-.ident E. N. Bovell. J. A. Sundtrland Treasure Win. Baird A Sons Attorney DIKKL TUKS John F. Flack R. A. McEachr. K. N. Bovf J. A. Sunderland Robert Dempster ASSE TS First mortgage loans idem ■mortgage loans in process of foreclosure c loans Real Estate sales on contract Furniture and fixtures '-nt interest and premiums Certificate of Depn-it &lt;J Total LI ABU .ITIES Capital stock running. (Dues and dividend: Full paid stock ) ~£» Reserre fund Undivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total I i.ant </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 KKl KIFTS AND KXl'KNDITCRKS FOR THK FISCAL YKAK ENDING JINK 30, 11M»8 RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, liwT $ 107 Dues, (running stock) S&amp;g ■ i .,-- f.- i Duel, (full paid stock) I* lntere»t M.Ms W Membership and tiansfer fees . IwB Loans repaid Real estate sales ou contract i.autt.J3 Certificate of deposit and interest. Keal Instate and Foreclosure U'.dyj j6 Loan Fees und Klpenses ;l.'.«*.M Sub-rent M7.SU Insurance oimmssn »n .. IU4.3U Dividends Total ll.l- KXPEN1 )I TURK* H % *i4r — ( f" 11.1ua.iu j HI 1 Other eiix Withdraw Brawals. earnings ilate and Foreoiust und I'reiuiiK ate of Deposit and I-oan Fees and Kxpensc* Pront and Luaa Insurance prein Casb un band ■ Total SUPPLKME N TAL, REPORT. Plan of Association, Permanent Par value of each share of stock . I No. of share* in forte at date of last iei*m U.*:v No. of shares issued during fiscal year Footing of two preceding items 3I.W7 »-S No. or shares withdrawn before maturity during nscal year No. of shares matuwi during fiscal year Footing of three iirereding items S. r No. of shares in force at this date M ' S.IT8 l-l« No. of shares of running stock in force at tills date S3. 4' : No. of shares of full paid stock In force at this date w.utt 1-40 Amount of interest premiums due and unpaid $ 7.87V.13 No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggiegale nmount nt same, No 3M s.juo.1 No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same so. wl u.uese Amount of loans on improved real estate 41.4*2.uw.tii Ised value of improved leal estate upon wlii tumjm.m i MM Appraised value of Improvements Appraised vaiue of unimproved real estate upon which loans hav •■ Amt. insurance in force anil to the association as collateral rity s during fiscal year a payment of homestead mort- No. of loans m 1' No. loans made for par gages during year Amount of advance payments of loans during: fiscal year $ 37t «o No. ot borrowing stockholders l. in No. of non-borrowing stockholders rs Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year 2 7-1 0 Pl»n of Premium. P; Amount credited to reserve fund during: fiscal year $ i Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year # 1 238. Amount of dividends declared on running stock during flscal year ..&lt; 73 Amount of dividends declared on .full paid stock during fiscal year .. &gt; 0 per cent on j»aid up Stock 10 per cent on Running KtneH Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year It* mo </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION OK THK OK THK CONDITION OK THK CONSERVATIVE SAVINGS AND LOA: CONSERVATIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA OMAHA, NEBRASKA on the. 'loth day of June. 190* OFFICER OFFICERS Oeorg* F. &lt; iilmore F. Flack ........... George F. (iilmore Preside K Flack 1st. Yice-President '/ ( . (^'"" f ' L'nd Vice-president P. \\ . Kulins n»i ■■■.■ . an A T»noo, P. \V. Kuhns m e Secretary and Treasurer Wru. Uaird Wru. Uaird Couns Attornev IMRKCTOKS IMRKCTOK Baitd E. A Hen Baird E. A Benson Randall K. Brown R,&gt;t&gt;ert 1 lull K. Brown Robert Kern Howman OkC.Umh Ueo. F.Uilmora I'Tnm R H»«il»i J.C.I Bowman C'lias (Mieorite Hun r llll»llll» Hymn &amp; I • &gt;underland H. A. Ita|W a P. Tul nderland H. A. ThOMfon a P. Take] C K. asskts , t ris M \V ASSETS irifu^'^ loan~ in process of foreclosure ■ Mhs t: -late ale Sold on Contract. •■rest ...........'. .... '.'.".' .&lt;! taxes paid ... - Certificates ..I Dep. in Bunks &gt;n Contra tes lit l)ep. in H; KuiHlimt ;.n&lt;l 1.. •.uildin* and Lot . ( Total 1.1 AH1UTIKS slock runninif. (Uue&gt; and dividend^ i . 'I ind led prontts '•holder* on incomplete loans :in&gt; un»*ar:ied . U LIABIMTIES ■ ' "■!&lt; runninif . ( Dues and di ridend d e fund I* </seg>
            <seg id="p151">Dues, (running stock I •• ■ 1*4 •* Dues (full paid stock) Interest W.irru Aocri Ai Members Loans i Rents T Loan ei\ m A i tt 'ertiticates of dt liBcc H . Total Amoti No. of No No. of A v^rAjff* Plan of premlur Amoun- credited Amount of losses charced to reserve fund during fls -«l vmr . Amount of dividends declared on runnine stnrk durine fiscal y* Amount of dividends de&lt; Average rate per cent of dividend iurin^ P« Average running time of stock n KNOINO Jl'NK 30. IW». RECEIPTS. BUPPLEMENTAI (Serial or Perm* </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE BANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NEBRASKA On the 3&lt;&gt;th day of June. 190K. Geo. P. Oronk W. D. Lincoln A. D. Touzalin U H. Kortv . . President V ice-President .Secretary Treasurer Thos. D. Crane Attorney IJIKKC A. D. Touzalin .1 S. Sykes J. P. Lenry Jas. Ainscow Thomas D. Crane First niorttcai;e loan: First murticaire loans in process of forecY Stock loans Real estate Furniture and Fixtures &gt;-nt interest premiunu and tine fs and taxes paid Other assets Total LIABII FUn'p^w 'stock"'" 1 ''"' ' Dues " nd dividends Rewrre fun'd ' * o.!.;-| Undivided profits I)ue shareholders on incomplete loans Prerai jms unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total I </seg>
            <seg id="p153">153 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KoK THK FISCAL YEAI KNDING JUNE 30. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 STATKMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE PAWNEE CITY SAVINGS AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PAWNEE CITY. NEBRASKA On the .{nth day of June, 1!his. OFKI F.RS President \ "ii-e-l'resident Treasurer Attorney DIRKl TOKS •I- r i;rimth F. H. Barclay R Other Assets. I-IABILITIE Capital stock running iinr. :md dividends Full paid stock umaenus Reserve fund I) Dividends soci.tk.. ,.| Undivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loai » Premiums unearned ... Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Interest earned on advance payment of duei and intere: Total J. K. Griffith. .1. F. Wilson. R. W. Story. &lt;i. K. Becker. Secretary 7 -. »■;,; -Ts .„,„■•■ « •« „.,„ • ' 5- « « «. </seg>
            <seg id="p155">155 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date • » \mount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 1 agnate amount of sam.^ ■to, i ? 1.810 No. of morliraires in process 'of "foreclosure, and airtfret'ste amoun' ■e N Amount of loans on improved real estate ■••••• ••••;• Vll,, f Appraised value of improved real estate upon wliirh kWH liave heci.^ mane Appraised value of Improvements &lt; Amount &gt;n which loans have been made Apnraised value of unimproved real estate Amt. Insurance in forje and assigned the association as collateral to Ami. iiioumiim "• •"* — — *- ....» No. of e ioans y made for buiiding' purposes during ' fiscal year . .... . . . . No. of non-borrowing stockholders Mn nt minors holding stock In th« association •••••; \?eraee rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during flsca year Averafl rati per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premiurr *,m»mt of dividenrts declared on running itock durimt Msoal year now n force Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during nsca! v«r Averaire rate i*r cent of divide n&lt;1s declared durinj fiscal year unimproved r So! S-ST"^.' fSrTay-»t of h™«Tea&lt;, m o?&lt; R a*« dur.ne yea Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal &gt;ear No. of borrow inif stockholder* RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISI.V ENDING JUNE 30, 1 AL YEAR RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, lsw; Dues, (running stock) &gt;ues. &lt; full raid merest 'remiums Fines emberahip and irannler fees .oans repaid eal estate sale^ Rent* Total EXPENDITURES. Loans Salaries Commissions Other expenses Withdraw ills dues, retired Withdrawals, earnings. Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings Cash on band Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) Par value of each share of stock No. of series Issued since organization, (if serial) No. of shares issued since organization No of shares in fnr.e at date of last report So of shares Issued during fiscal year Footing of two preceding items So of shares withdrawn before maturity, durinif fiscal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. shares cancelled durintr fiscal year, but not wittauraun Footing of three preceding items No. of shares in force at this date • ■ • No of shares of running stock In force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent : - li"i No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues </seg>
            <seg id="p156">156 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OFTHt OFFICERS DIKKCTlt -.1. White W. Smith T. M. Pattenoa J. K. llarwick H h met D h J. H. H ASSETS ure un«l flxl lent interest premiums .. taltv, |iuiil To l LIAUJI.1T1KN .. . led prof l'LATTSMOUTH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA Ob the ;(Otli day of June, LMM Ilter .1. Wl.it. Smith I. l'attfl&gt;t .1: '.. Barwick. i. Windhaiu ■ mortgage mortgage k loan-. running. [ Dues and divid ■ ilens on incomplete lo»ns ■I unearned ee Interesl and premlun i Ida Declared </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOK THK FISCAL YKAK -:M)1NG JUNE 30, 1908 RECEIPTS. ENDING Jl RECEIPT Bala { i Dues, (rL Dues, (f Interest Premiums &amp;ti&gt; h Mem lo.ai h Rents Taxes at.i Tut UU*J£NDiTUIUM. KXfKNDlTUUl: Loan ■ Ot Wi Witlidraw Matured Matured Full paid Full pa axt Tot Pi*t£MKNTAL KJCPOU Pta .No No. No! iul or Permanent) &gt;f itock organization, (if serial) . , i organization ■ e of las g fiscal year [((MIS •efore maturity during fiscal - • w ring, fiscal year Ni ring iis&lt; al year, imt not wiUtdrawu iz items this date took in force at this date stock in force at this date N'. this data ues are delinquent a ancellation for non-payment of due payment of du Total amount of dues delinquent at tliis date ilnquent at this date nt of dues owlnR liv borrowing V borrowing Amount of interest, premiums and fin. I unpaid I urns and fin ( unpaid . . . ggrcgata amount * ►f foreclosure nnd a^re^ate amount M A ved real estate . M am 3\ementa V mproved r«il upraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have iroved real estate upon whlrh loa Apt nil assigned to the association as c Amt. lr a the association as collateral ty No of loans' made for building purpose" during fiscal year Idlnp purpose? durintr fiscal year . . t, i*nt of homestead vn or fences during No Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal yes No nt borrowing stockholders pnt of loans during fiscal year . . A 1 olders kholders No irk in the association No I ■aee rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year nterest charged borrowers during' n&gt; Average Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund d ve fund during- fiscal year to reserve fund durinp fiscal venr Amount Amount of dividends d ired on running stock during fiscal full i'.m.I stuck durii &gt;n running stock during fiscal year . . I 1 Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during; fiscal year z;i </seg>
            <seg id="p158">158 t r STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OK THE THE LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOITH. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1908 OFFICERS D. B. Smith President Marshall Vice I'' Henry K. Get-ing Bten Carl G. Frieke Treasurer Thomas Walling \ttornf v DIRECTORS D B. Smith C. A. Marshall H M. Soennichsen Win A While Win. Haw, Wni. Holly J. Henry Herald F. U. Eifenbenter Henry R. Lierinir irtifaife loans in procma o( for • ians Real estate Furniture and fixtures '■m interest, tine. taxes paid kveu Insurance and taxes \v&amp;\ Re»l estate contracts Total Cai&gt;ita) stock running [Due Full paid stock Reserve fund ted profits.. Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total First mortgage loans </seg>
            <seg id="p159">159 I JUNE :so, HMW. ENDING .1 RECE REC EIPT Balance on hand July 1 1* alance on hand July 1 1007 ues, (running stock) 2; m n Dues, (running stock) Dues, (full paid stock) ues, (full paid stock) Intere terest IT, •emiums ship and transfer ft*^ 11 P2tvi*i Loans repaid oans repaid sal estate sales ft ents i isurance and taxes i«i. and adv Insun Kealt ic ■&gt; JVJLJ i|9 eal rotate contracts state contxac 11 y able "^ 4i 1 iy ills payable Total Hills 1 Tota KXPKN1 KS EXPENDITUI * Loan Salar ,oans alaries c. ommissions ither expenses Ot withdrawals, dues Withdraw Withdraw Withdrawals, earnings Mat [atured Stock, due^ Matured stock, earning latured stock, earnings ee and tuxes i«l. and adv Insurant'* 1 und * ull paid stock, dues ull paid stock, earnings Hon hand contracts payable ,-...■ Total :i n To SUPI'l.K.MK PPL.EMI N 1 a A I ent REPORT of Association. (Serial or Pern !• Plan of Ass. -&gt;ar value of each share of stock . . . stock Par value of each sha .!» .'.1 or series issued since organization I if » V.I To &gt;&gt;f shares tanied linca orBanliatioi No &gt;&gt;f shares Issued since organtiauoi . . . . No. "f shares in force at dale of last repi nr iz &gt;Jo of shares in force at date of last t No of shares issued during fiscal yeai No of shares issued during fiscal yea [] •'...iitiik of two preceding items tinK of two preceding items or shares withdrawn tiefurf maturity during n- ■ two «&lt;&gt; of shares withdrawn before maturity 1 N'o. of shares matured during fiscal y No. of siiares matured during fiscal yea »Jo of shares canceled during nscal year In e of three preceding items . . . No y kof shares in force at this date nt shares of running stock in fore of shares of full paid stock in rot of shares loaned on of shares on which dues are del; of shares subject to cancellation amount of due*d»"n«|ii&lt;Mlt :it this da t No of shares in force at this date . ... _ . . . . •■ No. of shares of running stock in force at tins .late 1 No! of shares of full paid stock in force at this dat ,f 67 ■ of shares loaned on of shares on which dues are delinquent M w No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of il T Amount of dues owins by borrowim Amount of (lues owinir by borrowing era i m .,, m i o f jnfprp^t nr^'Ti''im« and »1n*»s nil' - i-7?" 1 "«r.Li»r= r ...i.wt to foreclosure, and aesrecate aninunt of sa * mount of interest w»Tiiiim« anil Hn»sdu No. mortgages subject to foreclosure. ni of loam on lmpro»e J real estate.. value nf i: '1 &lt;" st! maiie No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and X... ..» Appraised value of improvements .. Appraised value of improvement Iidi of loans unon uninmroied re»l est . insurance in force and assigned security of loans made for 1-ulldinK purpo loans made for payment of liomi nt borrowinc stockholders of non-borrowing stockholders . . . of minors holding stock in the Average rate per cent of interest cha Plan of Premium Amount credited to reserve fund di Amount of losses charged to reserve Amount of dividends declared on rui Amount of dividends declared on fu \ni.iuin t&gt;f loans unon unimproTed n-:i! estate Amt. insurance in force and assigned to th&lt; durinc fiscal ■ of loans made fur ruildinK purposes durinc flscnl year fliflfl .for navment of liomestead mort K a K es dunne yea nr if r non-borrowing stockholders • . ■ ■ ■ • n n r,f minors holdlne stock in the association • No e verage rate per cent of interest charged borrowers d»rln R fteral year Amo°Jnt re c I red"ted- to reserve fund during^ fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal \enr •••••••■ Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal ieai . - credited t A tn. .'in 1 Average rate per' cent of dividends declared during Average running time of stock matured during fls&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p160">160 STATK.MKNT SCHUYLER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION Total OF THK CONDITION OK THK </seg>
            <seg id="p161">161 KKCKI ND EXPENDITURES KoK THE FISCAL VKA1 ENDING JINK 30, 1 KCKIFT R£ g; I l T 1 L 0 ». 8 a I I « I X 1 t mo: i r SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT (.Serial of 1'eimaneiii I m -payment of du&lt; ■ I iid ...... ■ ■mildinff purposes during fisral year .... merit of hon es during ye ments of loans durinK fiscal year winp stockholders ol.iinp stork in the a ,if interest din:. wers dnrinK flsr-nl ver\r r cent premiums chanted borrowers durine I to reserve fund durlner fiscal year a charcPd to reserve fund during fiscal venr lends declared on running stock durlnp fiscal year . . ends declared on full paid stock durine fiscal vear .. t cent of dividends declared durlnir fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p162">162 BZimtnerer . F. Diekman Graff I 'resident Langworthy J. J. Thomas DIKr TOKS J. F. Ueesen O H Franklin J M Oulder P. \V. Coehnt M C. Miller W. H. Smith Hoy It Schlc AS ETS Fin»t murtiratre low • rticaffe luuns in pi Slock Idj! ,&gt; Reai K»taie Furniture and fixture enl interest, premiums and Expenses and tuxes paul nee :;n I Tola MA HI ITIES Capital stock running i stock d dividends Reserve fund Undivided protlts Due shareholders on int- I*remiums unearned ... Advance dues AdTkoce interest and premiun Total V ice-President Secret;! v\ Trvasurt r . Attorney </seg>
            <seg id="p163">163 RECEIPTS AND KXl'KNDITURES FOR THK FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1908 RECEIPTS. NE 30, 1!*W BaUi ■1 07 t MMT &lt; wji Dues, (running Interes Premii. Fines Membe fee's !........ . I'M ■ Kei Tux ee it- i '.'.'.'.".. t 4-.tm.«i To a EXPENDITURES EXPENDITURES. { M.:iw.Y* L*ar Salari C'omm 505.00 Utl Wit Mat Mat Full I T.x Insu Ti g 47.783.43 47.783. 12 SUPP1 'PLEMENTAL REPORT. MENTAL REPORT ent) Plan of Association. (Serial or 1'ermaiient) rial or Permanent) p. n Par value of each share of stock $ 100.60 of stock $ tOO.OO No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) 15 : organization, (if serial) 15 No. of shares issued since organization ' e organization of last report N No. of share* issued during fiscal year ig fiscal year Z- * Footing of two preceding items 1*»1H items l*tlH &gt;re maturity, tlunn* liseai year I No ring fiscal year - »I5H No Number of shares cancelled during Msial year, hut not withdrawn .... I 1 tltirini? fiscal year, hut not withdrawn .... I Footing of I edlng items t!2S g items this date 1 3&amp;* No. of shares in force at this date I-S30 No. of shares of running stock in force at this date . . . 1.35© stock in force at this date .. 1 3S« stock in force at this date - No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this dat «"H 441S No No. of shares on which dues are delinquent ? " i '' lues are delinquent ? " i '' No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment cancellation for non-payment of dues H H linquent at this date * 6 • t this date )y borrowing stockholders . f -■'* -*\ Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockr Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid .... No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same lums and fines due and unpaid » 16o l» 165 1« foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same n in No. 4 * iMXlM No. mortgages in process nf foreclosure and aggregate amount of same I 6U.W7.64 Arm Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans havf hun mnrie UiTSMI 1 v nd Appraised value of improvements , imnimt rtf la^ns iiitnn imimnrnvPil f*~" :» T ostn Tp . * l.rt*. A Appraised value unimproved !■■- iton which loan* nave been mule . ■ il - w ' w Amt. insurance in force and asf-lgned to the association as collateral^ been m No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal yea ri mortgages during year .. No. loans made for payment of 1'omestead tnortcaees Amount of advance payment of loans during fiRcal &gt; al vear i N&lt; No rVO. Ol IMMl-IMM I !»*&gt; ll'li BIV rvi iimwi-i .-i No. of minors holding stock in the association _•" wem during flscnl year ""* Avpra Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund durine fiscal vear t 21S.8S Amount Amount of tos^^ r*ha"ffed to reserve fund d'irnB nscnl vear Amount of dividends declared on mnnlne stock during fiscal year ..* l.lW.tl Hi rear id stock during fiscal year Kt of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year . .* e rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year e running time of stock matured during; fiscal year syrs. llmo </seg>
            <seg id="p164">164 STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION UK THt SIDNKV LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION SIDNEY, NKBRASKA OFFICERS IIIUBt I' H. T.ihm L. J«»ct J.C. Hmls.m M. II Tciliin W. J. Shoemaker c W H..n,.ui;n a Grtwiwin H. BadolIB Cbul'allstaan on the :;&lt;ith dmj of .Junt' .1908 rannanitfr 11. EUdelif. . . • • Newbau - Callahan Vice Seen </seg>
            <seg id="p165">( T 165 r M'lTKKS F()K THE FISCAL YEA1 ITS AND G .1 INK I 1 1 I L ■ a w f Full t .MENTAL KEI i- 1 ■ f t t t I tv t ft te amount of N ,1 f N a s Amount of I A a to the association as collatera A during fiscal vea s t t. j: if IV 1 yea Plan of Amount i 1 year ..« i i Amount ing f a Average r il y nscal year Average running t </seg>
            <seg id="p166">166 OF THE CONDITION OF THE SOUTH OMAHA. NEBRASKA On the *&gt;th day of June. II •FFI ER Patrick J. Bbeebjr J. H. Loechner. . . ■ J. Fitzgerald \V Hastings Murdock Jt Pancuast Dili I'd LIAUir.lTIK and dividends 1 1 Total STATEMENT TO OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION .... President Viee-Pmsident \V P. Ailkin- .( E O Hern S K. Cox Frank Koutsky P. .1 C. M. Sehindel F. M. Smitli J. H LoeetuMr K r. How &lt;ter-. on inc&lt; fiirned Advance tin. - Advftace interest and premiun. </seg>
            <seg id="p167">KK( IPTS AND XPKNDITl RES FOR THE FISCAL YKAR ENDING JUNE 1 RECEIP Balance Dues, (i 1 1tw.5ae.44 Dues. ( Interest Kxiienne. :»* 1.M..1 H Loan Mone Rent Tol Xl'KNDlTI'R Salar X) w s: X|&gt;( Money H&lt; Full paid ! 4 lit M il b To IT PPLEMENT AL ma REPC ent) RT Plan A Per Mi rui ■»■&lt;■! Par No. of series issued since organization, (if seria No zatic No st • s ar y No. of shares withdrawn before maturity during f \v No t not withdraw No it Ar An 3 t of sa :a Nr t a» sar A f App A Appraised value of unimproved real eh^ate upon which loans ha Amt. Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collate Mo. loans t U Amour N'o. o No. of i . A \ 1 w Plan of premlurr 1 Amount of dividends ii on running: stock during fiscal year Amount d stock d AveraRe rate per cent Average running time dividends declared durln* fl» 1 v«,r if stock matured during flacal year </seg>
            <seg id="p168">168 PRUDENTIAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION W a. Mor First Hi • trlftaxe lu^riN Delimiuertt Kxpenses and taxes | Other ussf :^ Total LIABILITIES : ruimintr. ( Dues and dividend - ■; stock ■ ■ Tund «'e interest and iiremiuir uent ■ok and Knu STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION OF THE W. G. Morten . W. K. HaU-liff. H. M. Sanlx rr, &lt; • &lt; '. Vennum.. . Ked proflu ... ......'.""..."."II."" reh.ilder.i on incomplete loans ins unearned I- (llli-s </seg>
            <seg id="p169">169 rECEIPTS AND EXPENDITl'RKS FOR THK FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE W, 1 RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1907 | Duel, (running stock) Balance cm hand July 1, 19 Dues, (full paid stock Interest Membership and transfer fee; Loans repaid Real estate u Total f i M EXPEN1 1 T URES I Com:; - expen irawals, d 1 Withdrawals, earning Matured stock, dues Matured stc Full paid stock Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand Total Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. UPPLK1IEN TAL REPORT Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) Plan of Association, (Serial or Per mar lent) Par value of each share of stock . sued since organization, (if serial) Par value of each share of stock (if serial) Euilsatlon No. of shares issued sinct* ovgastaatfton. No. of shares in force ;it date of last rejNUt f shares issued during fiscal year No. of t date of last r IN No of shares issued during fiscal year Footing of two preceding items Footing of two preceding it No. of shares withdrawn before maturity during ttseal year -hares withdra maturity durin No. of shares matured during fiscal year ncelled during fiscal year. l&gt;ut nut wlihjrawn .. No. of shares matured during fiscal year t UHli.l Footing of three preceding itetns Footing of three No. of shares in force at this date No. of in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in for No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in fore e at this date No. of shares loaned on ... No. of sha 1 No. of shares on which dues are delimiuent No. of shares on which dues are delimiuent Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders nt of interest, premiums :ind fines due .md unpaid No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount ol «nm« » No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of sam No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate a it of sari \ . p i Amount of loans on Improved real estate ,ised value of Impnn ipon which made ' Amount of loans on improved r iis**d value of improve tate made Appraised value of Improvements i Appraised value of improvements Amount or loans upon unimproved re.u i Amount of loans upon unimproved re.n .■-.•»■&gt;. Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hav been made estate upon which loans have Appraised value of unimproved re been made Ami insurance in force and assigned to the association as collaters security the association as collateral Amt. Insurance in force and a security 1 tr » No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. of loans made for building purp les during fiscal year No. loans made for payment of homestead n No. loans made for payment of homestead rr.ort:,ii;t"» dun year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year « No. of borrowing stockholders No. of non-borrowing stockholders 1» Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal yen Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of Premium, monthly nav"ent&lt;* for VI month* Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . . i Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured, during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p170">170 OF THE CONDITION OF THE CITIZENS BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION Sl'PERIOR. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, lints. OK ICEKS \V. S. Younjr President W. 1". Long Vice President K. H. Stubbs Secretary \V. A. Myers Treasurer F. U. Stubbs Attorney 1HKECTOKS W J. Elliott J. H. Kesterson T. Nelson J K. Eyre J. M. Silver AS ETS ■&gt;rtrfatfe loan: I 45 ■ ritate loans m process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and fixtures. Delinquent iDterest. premiums and tine! En&gt;enses and taxes paid Assets Total I.I A HI I. Capital stock running [Dues and dividends Full paid stock Reserve fund tied profits. . Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned AdT»nce dues Advance interest arid premiums Total STATEMENT </seg>
            <seg id="p171">171 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL YF.AR ENDING JUNK ;i(), 19ox. RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 1, l»or i 5, mere Dues, (running slocKf. pass hookn n 006- W Dues, (full paid stock) . . Membership and transfer fees Loan* repaid Real estate ft Total ( EXPENDITURES Loan? I ix.WO.uo Commission Other expenses Withdrawals, dues . 3.HU3.3&amp; Withdrawals, earnings. Matured stock, dues WBLU1CU DIUVK, UUCB . . . Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, dues l.auo.00 Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand . . . . . _|^^B Total., i H. i»5«S SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) Permanent Par value of each share of stock !.'.'."'• IW.M No. of series Issued since organization, (if serial) No. of shares Issued since organisation No of shares In force at date of last report. 879 No of shares Issued during fiscal year ;&gt;_. Footing of two preceding items i jgi So. of shares withdrawn before maturity, during fiscal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. shares cancelled during fiscal year, but not withdrawn Footing of three preceding Items No. of shares In force at this date No. of shares of running stock In force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock In force at this date Nh of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders i tiuo Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid No. mortgages^ubject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. No No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and aggregate amount t Amount of loans on improved real estate .!...... f ij.Hni.n Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been mad e f 75.000 n» Appraised value of Improvements I Amount of loans uj-on unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare been made Amt. Insurance in ror.-e mid assigned to the association as collateral B security { 45 qqo 90 F loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year f No. of borrowing stockholders •- No. of non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year » Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year $ 17iM« Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year I t Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year .. 8 Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 6 s rs t mo'* </seg>
            <seg id="p172">172 STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION OK THE TECUMSEH BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION TECUMSEH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, IMS OKKI EKS KBrundajji Shaw.... I iciujrlas anon... Al N. Dafue.. Secretary Treasurer Attorney DIKK :ctor: r. A. Urundate C. J. Canon L. M J. C. McDermott Harry Phelp Davis J. B Douiflas P. H. Hopkin: i John R. Merson A O. Skiw TS A &gt;h ■ rtgaiff loan $ W.785.00 ■nortc*tf6 luans in process of Tor i loans ur Furniture and fixture «). Other ass Total I IliW'.M LI A III I 1 TIKS (.'ap'.tai stock running. [ Dues and dividends . .1 st.n'k . e fund Undivided protn areboldera on incomplete loans nns unearned Advance due: Advance interest and premiums lent interest, premiums fln ■ji ari'l tuxes paid </seg>
            <seg id="p173">173 ENDING JUNE 30, 1908. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 11 Due*, (running stock) . . Dues, (full paid stock) Interest 3.331 53 18.210. UO 4.i'i3 :fj Premiums Fines Membership and (n Loans repaid . . 12.101 uu Real estate sal Total EXPEN I T URES I ■■■ Salar". Commissions Other expen Withdrawals Withdrawals, earnings Matured Stock, dues ...... Matured stock. Full paid stock, d Full paid stock e i&gt;S M.0H.I1 Casb on band 5 Tota A.L, REPORT snt) SUPPLEMEN T Plan of Association. (Serial or Perma • Par value of each share of stock B series issued since organization (if serial) . shares Issued siiu-e organisatl shares In force at date of last report No of shares issued during llseal year Footing of two preceding K shares withdrawn before maturity dun shares matured during fiscal year . L No. of shares canceled d ithurawn Footing of three preceding 111 I :«&gt; No. of shares In force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this date l :em tto. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on No of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date .... Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premiums and tin's aue ana uniwa No mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on improve*! real estate •••• * KJPAss i™S v»l ul . of Improved real estate upon which loans have be«n al estate upon which loa Inline Appraised value of improvements A Ap P U raSsea 1O varuro n f "SS^.TUS'.Sut. upon which loan, have* hopn mflrie " : * Amt insuranc^m" force and 'assigned' to 'the association as collateral _. . .. " uy No of for building purpose: No. of e ioans y made'for"buliding purpose: during fiscal year during fiscal year ■ad mortgages during year ... It No loans made for payment of homest No. loans made for payment of homest ■ad mortgages during year ... II No. of borrowing stockholders No of non-borrowing stockholders «„' r.t minors holding stock In the association No. of minors holding stock In the ass 1 borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of interest charge Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Amrnin^eredi'ted to reserve fund during fiscal year Ammint of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Knt of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year i lit of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . . i 3.004.11 Eof dividends declared on full ,. aid slock durum tiscai \ear. e rat. p«r cent of dividends declared during fiscal year e running time of «tock matured during fiscal year ... »■ and rtn*s due and unpaid Appraised </seg>
            <seg id="p174">SIXTEENTH ANNTAL REPORT OP THE 174 1 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE TRENTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION TRENTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, MM. OFFICERS S. Hill Vice President J. R. Greenhaltrh Been A. E. Reynolds Treasurer DIKEC ITORS O. W DeWald C. 1 Allen I. E. Thomas I,. R. Coufal Dr. &lt;) B Hunt ASSETS First mortgage loan: t ».aou. urt^'iijte loan* in process of foreck Stock loans ■re Real estate Furniture and Fixtures * Delinquent interest, premiums and tines Expenses and taxes paid Other asst- ts. hills receivable Total LI A BIT 1TIES I 11.131 Capital atoek running. (Dues and dividends! .1 siock e fund Undivided profits jrebnlders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned. . Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total Ol E. Reynolds President </seg>
            <seg id="p175">175 SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISC AL YEAR ENDING Jt NE 30, 190K RECEIPT Halanee on hand July Dues, (running stock). Dues, (full paid stock) Interest Premiums Fines Membership and transfer Loans repaid fee Real estate sales Kents Total ( TB54W EXPEN'DITt RES * Salarie: Commission: Other expenses . Withdrawals. du&lt; Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues... Matured stock, earning Full paid stock, dues . . . Full paid stock, earnini Cash on hand Tota * Number of mortga, and aggregate amount of same asure No. I Number • ret and aggregate amount of same No. Amount of loans on improved real estate. Appraised value of improved real estate 1 Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real eai Appraised value of unimproved real estat which loans hare been made I * ■ 1 n which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 13.800.00 Number of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year Number of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year Number of borrowing stockholde Number of non-borrowing stockhoid w Number of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 10 Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premi Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during ttncal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year. Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal &gt;ear Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year i'PLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Par value of each share of stock $ Number of series issued since organization (if serial) Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares in force at date of last report Number of shares issued during fiscal year Footing of two preceding itmns Number of shares withdrawn before maturity, during fiscal year Number of shares matured during fiscal year Number of shares canceled during fiscal year, but not withdrawn Footing of three preceding items Number of shares in force at this d:ite Number of shares of running stock in force at this date Number of shares of full paid stocK in force at this date Number of shares loaned on Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date $ Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders $ Amount of interest, premium* and tines due and unpaid t i nc it </seg>
            <seg id="p176">176 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION VALENTINE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1908 OFr It KK J. H. Yeast. 1 'resident W. T. Kincaid *:, eel 7 Secretary f. A.Cumbow Treasurer Attornej DIREC T 5KS J. H. Yeast (ieo Elliott J. VV tmmt W. T. Kincaid J. T. Keeley F. A Uumbuw H. Hoenii: H. Dailey K. H. Watson Vice-President AB^ft 13 First rijorlt'inre loans First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Furniture and fixtures lent interest, premiums and lines .'.' d taxes paid Assets Premiums paid on Insurance Pjlicies mscount on Advance Payments f Total f LIABILITIES Capital stock running. [Dues and dividendsl Full paid stock ■ fund Undivided prollts Due shareholders on incomplete loans '." ' Premiums unearned Advance dues ' ' ■ •e interest and premiums Due First Nat 1 Bank of Valentine Nebr .'.'.'.' ....'. I LJU.M Total t 4O.075.tiC </seg>
            <seg id="p177">177 RKCKIPTS AND I- ■:xPKNi&gt;n LI ;es for thk NE 30, 1UU* FISC AL V KAK KNDING J Jl RECEIF TS Balance on hand July 1, IW • Dues, (running Dues, (full paid stock) Interest Pn bines Membei ship and transfer fees i&lt; &gt;*i .i Loans repaid '■&gt;*&gt; 25 Real estate sales Real Rents policy, premium repaid . . irrowed 1st National Hum Total . * ia.wa.uo Rents Insurance policy, premium r Borrowed 1st National Hi Tot£ ♦ W.SW EXPENDITURES. iXPENDIT LI t Loans * 1 ! Loar Sala Salaries S43.UO Conuniasiooa Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Withdraw Matured stock, dues I.SW.utt Matured Matured stock, earnings BB1.U0 Matured st Disc. Adv. paym*Nis Hisc Adv. |pa Paid 1st. Wuioaa. Bank Paid 1st N Cash on hand S*J " rash Taxes pan! cm T. S. Certificate ■ "- 1 ■ Taxes pan! ipn T S. Certificate Premium p. lid on Insurance pottey Total i 18.«3.i»&gt; SUl'l'LBMENTAL REPORT. Premium p.iid on I Tota PLEMEXT Al. na REPORT SI I Plan of Association, (Serial or Permanent) t) a Far value of each share of stock I Far value of each share of stock No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) No. of series issued since organization, (if serial No. of Shares issued since organization No No. or shares in force at date of last reixirt No. ol shares in force at date of !a: No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of shares issued during fiscal yea Footing of two preceding items Foot No. of shares withdrawn before maturity during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn before maturity during fiscal No. of shares matured during fiscal year ■ No. of shares matured during fiscal yea No of shai ! during Dbc&amp;I year, but not withdrawn No hut not w :iwi Footing of three preceding Item* K. No. of shares in force at this date ■""' No. of shares In force at this da No. of shares of running stock in force at this date '•«" No. of shares of running stock in force at this dat No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No! of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Tnml amount of dues delinonent at this date » «LW Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 1 it at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders &lt; 3BU» Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid $ M8.96 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid i 1W No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. No \" NO No. mortgages in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same No. mortgagei in process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of sarr Amount of loans on improved real estate » :t ' Amount (pf loans on improved real estat Appraised value of Improvi lie upon which loans have been •«.«. made Appraised value of Improvi ite upon which loans have been . «j«» Appraised value of Improvement* Appraised value of Improvement* Amount of lnnns upon unimproved real pst. .... Amount of lonns upon unimproved real pst Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hav Amt. Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral Amt and assigned t the association a ollateral Becurity * ■■ loans mnile for building purposes during fiscal year 1 1 600 W ms made for payment of homestead mortgages during year .. t of advance payment of loans during fiscal year I ' borrowing stockholders non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year ■"*• ! during fiscal year . ?ad moTtgaeres during during fiscal year . . . No 101 !."' ig purpo: horn it year if loans :1 St NV k in the as* loclatlon of terest charged borrowers during fit ■Wf Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year t Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . . I - Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p178">178 WAHOO MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDIXC ID. Rupp... Lyle . Strattoi;. st Hanson. '. Simpson J. J. Johnson L. .1 Kudr as. OD, i orttraire loan oriitiiRe loans in pr loans Real Estate Furniture and fixture Delinquent interest, premiums and nr Taxes paid Tola Capital stock running. (Dues and div Full paid stock Reserre fund Undivided profits Due shareholders on iaeompiet* Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest anrt iireiinums Tota! </seg>
            <seg id="p179">179 ECEIPTS AND EXPKNDITURES K&lt; &gt;K THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE #'. I KKCKII-IS. VK AR NDING .11 XK *•. 1 KECKII-I ce on li/ind *uis i. IWS (runiiniK stock I (full paid stock) DueVTr I ret. st ums (Loud ducal I ei-ship and tniiisft-r fees repaid estate s.. Total T KXFKMUTfK TTRr i i W n T i PPLEUENTAL ElEl'OKT Permanent) ii.it ion. (if serit ial N -« -hares of running stock in force at this date ■barea ot full paid stock in foi N ■ f shares on which d t this da Amount of dues owing by borrowing -.■ of interest, prfiniunis ;ind nnesd-ie and un*&gt;i4i&lt;1 irtgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same, N No. mortgages In process of foreclosure and aggregate a N f £ t sed value of unimproved real estate upon Which loans have ussociat as collate al In n» made for huildin? pun -:ir u us made for payment of homestead mortgages during year .. Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year 4 IMP** • borrowing stockholders if No of non-borrowing sto *re rate per cent of interest wen during fiscal year we rate per cent premiums chart wen during fiscal year t of ied in above Plan of premium 15 els per shire Lour. Amoun. credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during; fiscal year ..I 7 **&gt; 21 luring fiscal year .. I Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year .. I Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year . * Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year a </seg>
            <seg id="p180">180 STATEMENT SALINE COUNTY BUILDING ASSOCIATH &gt;N WILHKR, NEBRASKA on the :$tlth day of June. 1006 OFFICERS Joseph ( Yrm President J. A. Hospodskv J. K. Mallat .... Nice 1'resiilent ~ K. V. Shobata J. K. Spirk... OIliBCToU J. Novak P. S SaTarik V. B. Aloi.- Borecky ]•'. -:isek I 'r: afea .1. L. H.ireckv H. Hinder H W;icker J J. Meleer J J. Meleer ASSET •rtifjitre loans BmnrtWKe loans in process of fore i loans . . Kea; pslalp ure and nxtures aent ioterest. premiums and H . ;il taxes paid Total I.IAHILITII- S capital stock runninir. (Dues and dividend- 1 Full paid Koek. .. c Fund ded iirotits ireholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues. Advance intecest and premiums Total . OF THK CONDITION OF THE </seg>
            <seg id="p181">181 gEIPTS AND EXPENDITCRi RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITl RES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR RES FOR THE FISCAL YEAH LTNE SB, 1 ENDING .UN RECEIP' NDING -UN l'.Mr RECf :ipts. IPTS t Balance on hand July 1, I »&gt;; e on hand July 1, ! &lt; )r ' (running stock) (full paid stock) Premiu ims Membership and t Real est Total SXPENI ■rum I i Withdrawa Witliii 4 Matured Matured Full paid Tu SUPPLEMENTAL, ItKPOl 1'ian »&gt;' Asm Par value of each share of stock No. of series issued since organization, (If serial No No. of shares issued since organiz. N f snares issued during fiscal yea nl i\v No. or shares cancelled tooting of three preceding items No. of shares in force at this date No of shares of running stock In force at this date . No. of shares of "ull paid stock in force at this date Nn (it shares loaned on No of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for nor No! of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date * \uiount of dues owinir by borrow iiiir shareholders Amount of interest premiums and Hoes due and unpaid * li No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. ■&gt; « : No. mortgages In process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same No Amount of loans on Improved real estate J Appraised value of in Amount of loans nf Appraised va al esta Ami. insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral ■• No of loans made for building purposes during fiscal vear No loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year .. imnnnr of advance payments of loans during fiscal year ■ ■ad mortgages during year INO. loans maue iui iwviuciu ui nuiin.o..*-»*« ...«. »o~n — — « Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year No. of borrowing stock! No! of non-borrowing stockholders ,,1 No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fis Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fis Plan of premium . t'remiun ihu. p»v»ul ai ■ Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year f i.d K n i ,,f i ,,«.-s .'Mar 'im) i &gt; i/vrve fund i! • int of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . ■ Amount of dividend Amount of dividend d stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Of Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year Footing &lt;&gt;r two p No. of shares wi No. of shares ms Apprmiaed ans have be^n matief </seg>
            <seg id="p182">182 OF THE CONDITION I WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION Wool) RIVKU. NEBRASKA Total STATEMENT On the 3&lt;ith (lav of .Tune. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p183">183 RECEIPTS AND KXl'KNDITIKI.S KOK THE FISCAL YEAR SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan (if Association. (Serial or l'ermanent) lua of each share of stock .... ued since organization, (if serial) ■sued since organization za No. of shares issued during fiscal year j, of two preceding 11 ■ -&gt;s withdrawn tWnre I during fls al year »l will i- of three e at this date shares of running: stock in force at thifl date . . fork in force at this date on - N Total amount of dues I &lt;&gt;f Interi I unr« inject to foreclosure, and nirirresrnte n vment amount of dues i of Inten ibject to f - A i i of loans on Improved real estate . ements £ menis In »bt ments In »bt ed real estate upon which loans have -♦'it valup of unimproved real estate upon win ed real estate upon which loans have icnts of loans during fiscal year ....." $ the as "&gt;wers A\ vpir _e rate per cent premiums charged borrowers d 1 stork dtlri* d« declared during fls^ Average running iime of stock matured during fiscal year in force and assigned to the association as collateral 1e for linildlnp pui :\g fiscal year for payment of homp- --aces during year 1 during fiscal year &lt; ,* prve fund during: fiscal vwr i mnnine stock dnrinir fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p184">184 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE YORK MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK. NEBRASKA on the 30th da] of June. 1!MI* OFFH Ere \V. Shr&lt;vk . es A. Met loud «e R. Reed . . . Vice-President Mtcrcty r v ge W. 1'ost Trea- William W. Wyckoff Attornev H;irr:s M Alfred B. Christian Nathaniel A- De w l'o^t Qaonre B Ueed WTaltcrF. He ;c&lt;.ri.'e W. Sbreck William W. \V ASSETS Tlj-Mft 'JUS re »nd Flxtur Bueru irnetv»i premiunu and •es and t»ies paid 1 I-IAHll.niKS ~-.ick rutinini:. Dues ?;.(» re Tund mil I'renmin MttKITOKS • niplete Advar. </seg>
            <seg id="p185">185 AND KXl'KNDITrRKS K()R THK FISCAL YEAR KECKIPTS KNDINC JUNK 30, 1908 RECEIP 1 TS Balance on hand July 1 * Stf Dues, (run Dues. &lt; Full paid stnc Interest Premiums Fine; Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid Her Total * 75.HW.M EXPENDITURES ix&gt;ans Salaries &gt;" ■»» Corr Oil Withdraw! Withdrawal*, earning Mat ■to Matured ste Full r Full paid stock, earning* T SUPPi. MENTAL, REPORT Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) Comb- ; Par value of each share of stock $ MWW No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) *J No. of Khm «-s issue. 1 since organization No. of shares issued since organization li Vn nf bIium ir fiinw Kt da t* nf us[ relNtit .. .t «.U N No. of shared issued duiing fiscal year Footing of two preceding items No. of shares withdrawn be tore maturity, during nscul year No t tint withdraw N Footing of three preceding Item* No. of shares in force at this date No at this date . e at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in for No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delir nquent for nun -payment of dues ' shares subject to cancellation f&lt; this date * Total amount of dues delinquent at r stockholders Amount of dues owing by borrowing Amount of interest, premiums and due and unpaid cl aggregate amount of same,? No. mortgages subject t a No I 1 aggregate amount of same I Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loana hav« I Appraised value of Improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estat A l rl value unimproved real estate ur&gt;on which loans have hern made ...J l.wom Appraise Appraised value unmiproven real esiair umin nmcri i..,ins .,„&gt;*- ..»-.-„ "....r- - Amt. Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral* No. of^loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No! loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during year . . Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year i J No. of borrowing stockholders No. of non-borrowing stockholders khold No. of No. of minors holding stock In the association Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during flscil year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year i CTt.tS Amount of losses charred to reserve fund durinc flsc»l vemr Amount of dividends declared on ninntnr stork during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of .took matured during flur-al year »b.u!7&lt;rs </seg>
            <seg id="p186">186 STATKMKXT OKTHK CONDITION OF THE WORKINGMENS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK. NEBRASKA (in the .'iotli day of June, ISM OK* ■ McCloud Woods. . . K. Wyckoll Holdeman . Wyckoff 1)1 K I- • iriifatfe loai rlKiifcCe loans in process ul foret ■ ;ins Kr.i : ■ re and Hxture Delimiuenl interest, premiums tines and di Expenses and tuxes paid Other assets Total MABH Capital stock running. 1 Dues and dividends Full paidttocl e fund iled profits .ireholderx on incomplete loans. Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Totul A Mcrinuil K. B. Wo.k1» \V. W. WrttuM G. H. Holdeman N. A. Dean A. 13 rhristiun </seg>
            <seg id="p187">187 It F.I "KILTS AND KXI'KNDnVRKS FOR THK FISCAL VKAI ND1NG JUNE 30, I'.mw RECEIPT Balance on hand July 1, MR Dues, (running stock) Dues, (full paid stc Interest Fines Membership and trnnsfer fees Loans re| Keal estat i 1 xrt Nl r iiu Salarl her Withdraw! Withdraw: Matured ■ 1 .* mi ■ Matw Full paid st Full paid si Total BUPPL.RMBNTAL. REPORT. Total Plan of Association. (Serial 01 l'ermanenl) l'eimment Par value of each share of stork . * ■ " 1 No of series issued since orKaniza i&gt; N.i of shares issued during fiscal year Footing of twf N No. of shares matured during fiscal year No of ..fl Kniit FootinK of three preceding items .»o No. of shares in force at this date t»« No. of shares of running stock in force at this date i-^ No! of shares of full paid stock in force at this date f shares on which dues are delinquent . . T-&gt;tM amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders \Tiounf of interest, premiums :ind fine* due md untied f No mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate annum I of same. No I No mortgages In process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of same .. No. * Amount of loans on improved real estate t 7.MUM Appraised value of improved real estate upmi which Iumm have I n maile ■ * l1-'» Appraised value of improvements * M.4M.I fkmoum of loans upon unimproveu r ..,u t -^ h ■■ I Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon wlilch loans have Appr mad the association as collat nl Amt. lnsura force a .1 g eil t n X t during fiscal year • I' ade fc tead n".ort/iii;es during pa if IT during fiscal year } Amount of advance payments No. ot borrowing stockholder No. of non-borrowing stockhold 'I Average rate per cent of interest cha Average rate per cent premiums cha K ed ged borrowers during fiscal year borrowers during fiscal year 1'liin of Pretr Amount credited to" reserve fund during fiscal year ♦ »«l Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount ot dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year .. * «l.o Amount of dividends def paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of is declared during fiscal yea Average running time of stock matured during fiscal ye Tctal </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>