<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION.  LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A.  THE HESSIAN FLY.</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA. Agricultural Experiment Station. LINCOLN, NEBR., U.S. A. PRESS BULLETIN No. 19. {Distributed September 12, 1904.) THE HESSIAN FLY. Wheat Plant Showing Injuries by Hessian Fly: a, Eoo; b, Larva c, Flaxseed; d. Pupa;/, Female; g, Male; A, Points op Attack; », Parasite— all Enlarqed. (AttbrRilxt.) </seg>
            <seg id="p002">though tlie Hessian fly has been known for a number of i occur within the unparati little damage in the past. During recent however, it \ n more of'a tendency towards multiplying in dan - numbers. Especially lias this been true in south - iii Nebraska where considerable injury has already der that the wheat growers of this and adjoining sections may not lie taken entirely unau lid the insect spread and continue to in Station authorities have thought best to distribute brief circular treating on the subject The pap i compilation from recent Ohio and Minnesota bul - - on tin subject. This insect is a diminutive, dark colored fly, much smaller d a little mosquito, to which latter it bears ;i general re - •lance. Its habit &lt;;f laying n young plant - wheat, barley, and rye renders it a dangerous farm | lv is this true of it in regions where winter grains grow*. It may also become a pest at times even wi spring wheat alone is I imt there is little danger that this last will occur. NATURAL HISTORY. The fly appears chiefly during spring and fall, but a few of the mature insects may be seen throughout the Bummer as well. Here in Nebraska the spring brood may be found in April, during May, and the first part of June. The autumn flies issue late in August, throughout September, and the first part of October — appearing later in spring and earlier in fall northward. The eggs are deposited both in spring and fall on the upper side of the leaves, and the young. as soon as hatched, make their way down the plant to near (Cecidomyia destructor Say) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">j ii in* . jn lii^ second j iiinl b* times even the third joint above tin' roots; but in the fall, when the plant nailer, they &lt;j;o down to a point above the roots, as shown in the illustration at h. T\, on the plant! in the fall is to prevent them from sendiiiL hat would bear heads the following year, and !■ dii. e the growth to a mere hunch of rank growing lea 1 kill out during the winter. In the spring the mag young become imbedded in the straw, thus weakening and when the graii akened straws and break down. The in- the winter Ian in the "Haxsee. '■ about the growing young plai above the roots. It also passes the Bummer, in the sani . but in the stubble fields. The adults d chiefly in spring and fall, at dates varying with the latitude. They live but a few days and die laying their The individuals which come to maturity either in advance or after the normal dates mentioned a - usually found attacking the volunt. d or abnormal planting! and have led to the supposition there may be even three or more broods of the Hies du ear. K sickly appearance of the grain late in fall and failure ■pond to the first warm weather of spring may inn nee of the inset XATIKAL ENEMIKS AND UKMKDIKS OR PUKVKXT1VES. Eie Hessian fly is attacked by a number of different p. Insects which in ordinary years tend to keep it in eht ever, during us when the climatic conditions are •ially favorable to the increase of the |&gt;est. social pre - ons are necessary. These may be summed up bri&gt; Hows: EBurn the stubble when possible. This is particularly ble when, from any reason, shallow plowing is un - ible. If the stubble is left long it will burn more eaa- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">ing straw from threshing over the stubble, thus insuring the burning and at the same time getting rid of some 'flaxseeds' which may have lodged on the suiface of the straw pile at the time of threshing. K"Fall plowing of the stubble in such a way that the ' is completely turned under. 3. "All screenings and litter about the threshing machine should be cleaned up and either fed immediately or burned, leaving no litter from the threshing on the field. There is no absolute need of burning the straw pile. The flies emerging from the 'flaxseeds' in the center of the pile will never reach the surface. 4. "Since the fly lays its eggs, as a rule, near the locality where it emerges from the 'flaxseed,' it is best not to plant wheat on the same ground two years in succession where rotation is possible. Varieties of wheat that produce a stout stalk are the least affected by this pest. 5. "Cooperation is absolutely necessary, for, however care - ful one may be, if his neighbor is not so, the latter's fields will afford a supply of this pest for the former. Since this pest issues from the 'flaxseed' early in May [or even in April], a stubble field left for corn land and not plowed up to the 10th of May or later has probably discharged its quota of flies ready for mischief before plowing." EThe practice of sowing narrow strips of grain across field early in the fall to act as decoys, and later plowing q under, has at times proved beneficial. The decoy plant - should be done late in August or in early September, turing early sown fields with sheep has also been fol - id with beneficial results. Lawrence Bbuner. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>