<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT, NEBRASKA State Board of Agriculture FOR THE YEAR 1905.</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA State Board of Agriculture FOR THE YEAR 190^. Prepared by W. R. MELLOR, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">s \TE BOARD UICULTURE, OFFICE OF SECRET VRY, • m&gt; I Lincoln, $ebr. January 31st, 1905. . John H. Mickey, Governor of ebraska: impliance with the law in this case made and provided, "nansihit the annual report of the Nebraska State Board of </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">SEMI-ANNUAL MEETING Lincoln, Nebr., Sept. 6th, 1905. tinnual meeting of the Nebraska State Hoard of Agriculture lent. ' Mellor: Quorum pr- Eilellor was appointed as delegate to attend National Association of Fairs and Expositions to be in Chicago in November, 1 I ndi'ishot was appointed delegate to the -hort-horn Breeders Association. instructed to appoint a delegate to ting of organ! Mr. Hendershot was ap- Km appropriation for matured corn exhibit and for I the Annual Meeting was left with the Board of Managers </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Tuesday, Januu Meeting called to The Prc Meeting. Seen followii. Dear Sir Official notice if Nebraska State Board of At ■ .: officers, and for tl will be held in tbi third Tuesday in Jatrn 4:00 o'clock P. M. No L Presidents of , in active workiii. their rejM members of the Board. In cases whi reason, attend, the Society must el' reset authenticated cred&gt; RA failure on the part of ■ i mak t and file with the Secretary of tl. required report forfeits the right of r&lt; Mee" inc Yours </seg>
            <seg id="p007">- I All: l',o.\KI&gt; OF A(iRICl T LTrRE .\ .N .N ' - AND REGULATIONS. F I'KKMIIM Morse [1KNTIALS AND RETl'UNS I 'aimer. &lt; c (MM IT \V. K. Melloi muary 1A&lt; \rni &lt;&gt;. H. It. M MKMBKUS &lt;&gt;K THK STATK BOARD. \ HV 1906. \V. ) : iaii ■ DtX . \V. I ... I.am-a- K. M. Wolcott. . . . Merrii-k K. /.. Kussell. . Washington \V. i K: </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 .Lftncaa I. \V. Ha«- ■ - \V It. Mh lard to fill OFFK ■ U &lt;&gt;nard son. &lt;! W H iahit : Ii Saliill.. K M W f Dick! i ill . I N'. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">lentials re - ■ UK DEN I : from and the farther </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">l ,V n N whi ho firm r Your PETER YolNGERS, Jr is a Christmas present to his parents Mllford, 1'ike county, Penn., on December 25th. mily moved to New York City where he received a ■ an office boy &gt;d in Fillmore county, May t Mr. Yi&gt; &gt;k a homestead south of K 'arted th Nursery in I Etth 1ST9 he was married to Miss Murilla Nicholson, of ?h union I born three girls. In 1886 he locat - nd in 188S formed a partnership with Mr. A. J. Brown name of Youngers &amp; Co., which firm is now the largest nd constantly employs from 40 to 120 men. 1 a member of the Nebraska State Board erred on the Board of Managers from mil ident. He is also 'ion of Wholesale Nurserymen, and .■ Horticultural -inoe 1888. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">I IE BOARD OF A.I : kind Provid. nicest blessing fricalturi luring th&gt; nhabitants are well dressed and well f- Kits and ?d forms i of born &gt;i - nds with whi&lt; attained ROBERT \V and will alw. :ii lies in the t reaper has been in. memberr-hii'. one who has lieen recognized ;i&gt; i eat Ben, one » I Board of Ac of whom K words could committee on resolution- von in n h you can ever refer with pride, and your hearts with nobler ideals and purposes; and «• the beneficent remembrance of the great work of • (1 to the pres&lt; tion, but will possibilities of to future untold milliu: The beauty of thought therein expressed remembrance of our worth* anful pn an that n Dg of June 1st, and witness his peaceful number i members of this Boar.: </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 EDMUND McINTYRE. t&lt;)n li' 24th, Father Time, with his sickle keen, made us a lied Edmund Mclntyre, our Treasurer for the from labor to rest. In response to telegrams an - i dozen members of our Board gathered at ;ird to pay our last tribute of respect to a man who was endowed r, as to command the respect of He was ever faithful in the perform - cheerfully performed. No responsi - ■ •■fling qualities exhibited by such lives as that Edmund Mclntyre furnish examples for our admiration and APPOINTMENTS h of our Secretary. I made an order that the sec - removed to Lincoln, and we secured a room in which said office is now located. I also appoint - '. of Gibbon, to fill out the unexpired year as our : Mr W liton. to fill the vacaii' rd. To fill the varan I by the death of Mr. oint.d Mr Geo. F Dickman. of Seward. -LAT1VE APPROPRIATION it our last annual meeting, at the beginning of ill to be prepared asking for an appropriation ure for the building of a Live Stock Pavilion and a This bill was introduced in the House of Representa- Monorable William Ernst, of Johnson county, and finally (Torts of the friends of agriculture, we secured nation of $10,00 1 for the erection of a Live Stock IMPROVEMENTS undoubtedly unnecessary to describe this Live Stock Pavilion. which you are all familiar, but you will pardon us in saying. building for the amount of money expended, to be it ground in the West. We all enjoyed its during the rainy days of the past Fair, and thousands of a better knowledge of the desirable in horv. tttle by being able to comfortably watch the ;&gt;iirements for excellence ••■ individual animal POILTRY BUILDING BThe new Poultry building has been erected with a view to ac - unoda M Industries in suitable quarters for -■i-ment thought the building </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Eh larger than would be required for some time to coom bit in this class was such a record breaker that it ually elled such idea*. ADMINISTRATION BUILDING The Administration building was enjoyed by the general public nearly as much as by the officers, and it is really a convi able to do business with tl officials u tins with the of the office of the Mas - for want of s] niil. ■.! H A grand year, added t&lt; to hold from 1600 to ] ■ thrown oji - to reach one half ii to fill it for th. SWIN the number ot and for iable fact that und. ■ ■&lt;?, as all tl SPEED BARN. I The old sheds in which the speed departs a number of years, spread out over amount o und, and are becoming inadequate as MCMunod dern speed barn demands. We have realized this condition for a nber of years, but our efforts have ba ,1 in other inr ots that were absolutely necessary, hi lepartmei wait. We have now attained a point when we thought it po make a beginning toward modern s|» • nd on the rth side of the track h;. barn or traim locating this barn we h </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 front this Board of the space now occupied by the -. our grounds are rapld - &lt;&gt;om for attractive displ i RETCH. Ert from the inside of the r to make ■ f the track, left the quarter stretch irly in the season a great amount Bd i he nice field in front of the grand stand molding &lt;&gt; of baseball games ions. Tli ■ experiment, think it should be embodied as one of our WALKS. I fort ruude toward walks on the grounds waa lght-foot walk was cut along in avenue, which walk, for about the distance filled with cinders and Sherman Hill north end. in front of Administration and Fish build - mce of 216 feet. V COLLECTIVE EXHIBITS tfind a number of exhibitors who are ira distribution. This has been a with the mai If it is possible to provide : and equitable, we should give it ser - therefore in order to bring this mat - 1 would make the following recommendation; ato four districts, and that the counties following number of points iremlum mone is than I population ov . score not I population o\ score not 0 points. 14th: population under 8,000, score not than BOO poii That in • or district a premium of $200.00 be given to first, and $125.00 I. That all other exhibits scoring above the required number be entitled to t That further, a Sweep - to first; $50 ond; $30.00 to third; and on. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 r careful deltberal 1. To pass offlc .In Tii .valks imj&gt; To crw! a swine judg T&lt;i To uniform E'. T. sinking fund. of neoess. Bn 1 &gt;• EX HI HI!' ment on I to assure ■■ concessional res at our 1905 Fair clo -atisfaction This ass&gt; more money from nt than • concessionaires on earth, for t)&gt;&lt; day* which resulted in great losses to n. murmur, and at the end of the Fair 1 with ' feeling, and we wish to extend to them our . tlnued loyalty and assi MEMBERS It is now two of author me by your suffrage, and 1 wish to say - </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Ill the great success which may have attended ua In iod of ntirely due to the (act that each one has been lbility of his position. I wish to specifically thank B6 of you for your loyalty and displayed industry, ie that you will accord the incoming administration, as you sure of your good will and honest effort. Respectfully submitted, W. R. MELLOR, President. will now listen to the reading of the </seg>
            <seg id="p018">— ■ Re : ■ Paid I </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 I.' 1,169.90 t».M 1 . 1 - 149.91 Buildings 1 Kibbon 1 l 1,1 I I 1ARY. DR. I :til the number and hi whom drawn ;ind for what pui THE FAIR. ement in </seg>
            <seg id="p020">of premiums paid and • is the ti full in the annual report of I mary is herewith ; — </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 trr.-2.00 - ■ 11 *1I2.."^ 1 4 ■ - t \2. (Mi 12 5&gt;&gt; • 4« ii". ~.~. 4n:: i ~ ■+, ■ 10 2 - </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 • ■ - - - and I)ui-k- 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 ■ 1J .".II - 4J I.") Ill 15.50 -14 mi ■ IT </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 1 IJ I &gt; - </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 1 All. $ I'' 47 11,.. IND APIAin An </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">27 ■ Hideration ithout m ibitor of &gt;f far less ■ on so i many sweep- ihe most ibitor at our fair, ibitor the irable hibitor, unequal divi - !ie profes- I has &gt;f the money offered to the i premium list in 10 in thr- $50.00 of the of professional exhibi - ■. ho niak' it of fairs: his i individual antma which he can well afford mimal or herd. The non-profes- ti bitors mltry, $ ! i for - 11 r money, ;ind our premium in their h I premium I d&lt;&gt; hibitor the nirit; the amount of money most liberality in premt - tbe really valuab! ration &gt;nium and rin viinnr H with the ! ium goes &gt; lrag- tial t'xhibi- re by &lt;&gt; whom I the premium bitors who ■ niinm money. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">I ■ ■• ■ tl </seg>
            <seg id="p029">\ 1 1 on a : 11 i ivhich VI Pi i H FILLEV d in many during the sum - nine for the Rock Dl ti) Livingston county, then was employed by e of 1 1 of Illinois, which niaii On Noven mily J. Bind of Pie itling - still living. In on the farm on lected Electe.! of the S 1901 and ■ I nf Managers in 1901 and and 1906. : Molds, Jeff Ing. hi, Nov. _ hool in winter and working on to Joliet, </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 in i u in list iind in th&lt; In i ftlWfl ■ an i at a the seeds will I pupil </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 i germiii., a insight in to fa] ion into if knowledge. Tl • -^ would li. ; with th. -» • d&gt; in the Kl </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 I ■ Normal school courses of study. tThe Annual Meeting of tl Board of Agi Jan. 16th next and it is desired to present at that meeting irt or summary of what is being done in this n all Norn pols and colleges, to tkl m it a treat fuvt&gt;: furnish such informa oik in youi suggestions as regar teaching or facl I tak- mint o the information truly, Sixth Eighth: Plai from ' THK CNIVERSITY montt The nature of class work experimental work, judging perimenting in soi The number of hours of i Labor. All graduates of eli to take this course in the school of agri&lt; The number &lt; r 904-5, 332; in 1*1 four year It • </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 1 1 n re for the firs- a ork of t: ad •■ will off. irthcomlng cat - oth. Tip r Normal Ind Interest, nffordin. e it suffici- 10 undei in arithn rammar i nis. Olive I^vin, "-• </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Delia illips, M I. Ulliai, Marth Arthii" Ruth Row Ethel Wri- Molli. Carrie Erisman. Erne Bewell. John I Hyde, Gladys Corhatn, STATE Ni »OL AT KEARNEY E"l ha\ Information iooI, and will ■ring i up till labor. i BProf SUfflil take the work \\ NEBRASKA NORM \l Xaturt gardening rT»C! stock All prad ork. Number of </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 ■ lie Instruction would be helpfui i;E, FREMONT, NEBR 11 work, recitations and laboratory work Five hours per » ired of each student :u'd for this study, ill udvun&gt; --s are re- ing the work, froi! \I&gt; COLLEGE, GRAND ISLAND. 'New Elementary Agriculture,' Bessey-Bruner - are required of each student in this Iaentary and adv;n re required ing the work in ' in 190 1 YORK C'OLLECE, YORK, NEBR -Brunei nd Bailey rm required of each student. Ipment is l science work. ■ rk in 1!" work in I HASTINGS, NEBR. Iork along this line. In chemistry, 1 rhanges a ill fertilit i thy with an; idies in our course ideration." CRETE, NEBR. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 r and ai iiat of Hon. .1 quiri: ■ • nd. It ii past t ind run.' In addition to and the variou normal sc I and ' junior n&lt; elementary agrkul securing the use of a plot teachers and would-be </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 n up with id the resulting benefits I - manned with greater facll - r numbei ipportunity for preparing I uly norn. ilture ill be pn (culture of the ten plan pi pi!|iils in the public school .mil stud \hibits ■:&lt;t by while no II and </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">I rn in four- i m in rm flv : In the irrt. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 ka G. he managemii or lines o: ing d and bill i I shall in ■ truly. J. L. McBRIK </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 ii each would or at such coll&gt; e word in - iork of our Agricultural or In - ii in agri - of our p ige of r one ■ lik' of this irith is i i ty for the 1;n the md, the : in Industrial Co tiding June :!0th, I I of the | &gt;d in idy in the imi </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 If all students who have been registered in ind and residents of 01 - of our ; tion less than four (4) in m nd of oui would h;r celred instruction d Itural or industrial col; Importance of teaching • ■ what has been ai. ation of o and graded schools Permit me to call tree of t); on by Congress to promote agricultural ii&gt; ormal schools of the United Bl Under certain conditions it seems to me such ion would in this d be taught </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 d it is suggested that no appro - able for purchase of grounds or tiould a state be required to furnish il buildlngi, but in addition should have estab - nhers along agricultural inimum standard and that no part of any "ii Id be used other ea or for apparatus </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 \ i: IN MEMORIAM record d and Hon 1 ■ with hi i ■ [rating in was edit"' Hoard of ~ons wht. \V Furn and John M. Thaj Bnorial Fair v - 23ni ulture w In hi- ion with tho T.Tr: ire. dating f 1 . of a Departnn bfst possible tlal in the administration of </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 * l ars in the last published volume. o 1906 a of the board, died on Decemb. taking an My in the . which he contributed and his i 'iinection with the Board uiiiial meeting as a Itural So ■ oard in inuously since: he has : of the Board of Managers and for the mention that to Robert W. Furn retary and ■ minuted the care and safe that to oth. '■nimiued the task (1 furnishing a report for the : that wi&gt; i nd fidelity had each performed hi&gt; eh agreed lv. one with the other. be truly said his work was well done. worth and work we honor ourselves ird of Agriculture. EXPENDITURES, WARRANTS ISSUED ied No For Wl - Ed Mi 1 Hotel bills H. 1 • in H. C. Yo 3 Hotel bills 4 Ex, imaha Corn Exhibit \. annual ii Bro; D Bro: 8 Printing Ai | 9 Printing Journal I 11 I - I.indell H </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 February E. Witherow . :&gt;t. W. Furnas 18 Robt. W. Furnas 18 Minor S. Bacon E. Cola 13 Printing 14 Allowai :iry, Jan. 19' no annual ni&gt; innual H. Rudge 21 Lincoln Transit 2 7 John B. Lewis . aud K I -»l .i PC *i H. Knight 11 C. H. Rudge 11 Robt. W. Furnas 11 Robt. W. Furnas 11 Chas. Scull 11 E. E. Cole 11 M. B. Holland FBenton 1! John B. Lewis 21 J. R. Sutherland . W. I ell Ho 8 John 13. 39 1 12 Bern on Bros. ■. Hadkinson . Hadkinson . Hadkinson 40 T 41 Labor 43 Tiv - 9.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 H idktnson 46 Incidentals 4" Salary, April 16.66 April, 1 50.00 166.66 toll No. 3 3. W 51 Hay Roll No. 4 ■ications ioard mil nian 54 Road Vpril, 19m; r.C Ft. Tel. &amp; Ex., April. ■ 1.1 H. Had .1 H. Madkinson 12.00 I H. Hadl. 61 Salary. Ma 166.65 R. W. Fur I H lladkinson 64 V. . Roll No. 7 21.00 6 7 Rubber Stamp 71 Mowii 11.7." 7 5 S i 7 7 Pay Roll No 9 : 4 Incubator BIiIk .! II for June Loll No. 11 Q Q </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 l - Bassi ■ ■ la ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 For What Issued Prem. Misc. ll !'•■ 1.98 or July 1 11 us. Tick. . Roll No. 1 .11 Poultrj Bid 11 : 13] Painting Amphitheater Koll Tkt- Movln Bal. on Contract for Aclinn. lildK. 13) Roll No. 2 Roll No. 1 14 t 14J Hill I 144 147 - I ■ I. \\ ICSt 48.05 I.. M Koll. 1.' Supt. &amp; Class H M. Hall Supt. Class H. A. Wol worth Clerk to Supt. Class H 16.00 rt Hall </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 September ,or Fuuk v H I in , </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 Prem. Misc. Date To No. . hat Issued September : . I ! ■ ; :n Sin ed : : I . ■ ! I ; ! ! : ■I ■ I 1 : ; ■ 11.25 100.00 ; 14 II </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Date To Whom Issued No. For What Issued I September IH. Kud- I niugers K. v : I ■ 14 T ]4 H 35.00 14 Western 1 i 14 T 1 KA K nton I ■ ■ellie M. Whit. II 65 2000 3 Jacob North &amp; Co. .. 3 K I ' i : - - • ■ 46 25 435 B. H. R 500 284 Printing anting lealljr [&lt;.«&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 No. For What Issued Prem. ■ Cindert Oil Supt. Amphitbeatei •r August 1.62 1.99 I. E .v Ptng. Premium in in Premium linn 1 u in nun mm i ii in iiiin&gt; mm i ii in mm ; inn mill I ■ 1 Hill Painti Premium alum Premium iiium Premium iiium 311 Premium liUBQ • nun : ill, IT Ex. I IT Bx. ImO.OO l'i'i.OO Hall Hi? El 9 W </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Date To Whom Issued No. For What Issued Prem 11 L. R. Fletcher 11 V. T 111 ■ 1 Is. .). i. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 3.00 1.00 , • \ 3.00 1 04.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">n. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Z. K( - n Do » i he first • I) family moved to Omaha wh&lt; .1 Washington i Mil i of farm Industr i ilar mty in 1 f </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 H. R«4 -peed 40.25 9 J Turn. ■ H \V. N k Hoi • </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 ing in Entry B ing in En 10.50 Printing Printing 9.00 9.00 Brock I.aboi I.aboi ;iper Work dr grnds Ktc. - ;iper Work dr grnds Ktc. — - _ ITS I. umber. Fair I. umber. Fair Oilin- Oilin- Boarding Ace. Fair Boarding Ace. Fair I ustruction i instruction Hal. Police Pay Roll Hal. Police Pay Roll Bdnc'Di Exh. 58. C9 Bduc'ni Exh. oS.69 Suppll Suppli n'l Exh. 40.00 40.00 Void 14 T 4 9 2 4 9 2 30.00 Lumber Lumber Lumber Lumber DM Emp. at State Fair Emp. at State Fair ims 14.50 14.50 12.50 12.50 ims ;.oo 50 Premiums .50 Premiums 8.50 8.50 1.50 1.50 5.00 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 } .". 1 1 Fren. i'lant rehm H. Bowman .\ hlvk in tin H I! I's Dan i ,i ■ :■• nti-i f&gt;4 7 I ■ llinpton libfll </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 I ied No. For What Issued Prem. Misc Premiumi remiums lghton Premiums -'.00 K Knt Yemiumi remiums .61 Premiums 14.90 remiums 'i63 Premiums 100 364 Premiums 365 Premiums 1-M ,66 Premiums 3.00 367 Premiums 3.00 &lt; 56S Premiums I'remiums :.7(i Premiums l.M A D 571 Premiums I Sons 57 2 Premiums Premlnmi Premiums •». H. B. Doolltl • Premiums 1.M ."74 Premiums 2. on M 575 Premiums 2.40 75 Premiums Premiums 576 Premiums 577 Premiums 578 I'remiums MAW 1 1.IHI remiums 79 Premiums remiums : remiums 1 Drain 581 Premiums \ H. Drain I'remiums Premiums 583 I'remiums ll«.M iTemiums 116.00 "n4 Premiums 584 Premiums I'remiums remiums 6.00 remiums 3.50 i&gt;s Eli Premiums Premiums 12.00 •remiums 2.00 ■remiums 2.00 ovan remiums 43.50 ■remiums 16.50 remiums 118.00 Musi 'remiums "-50 I H Ed» E. I- EUworth 1) Erford Blanche Bdmln remiums 8.00 remiums -50 ■remiums 2.00 'remiums 3.75 lemiums 2.00 ami </seg>
            <seg id="p062">XEBI To Whom Issued No. For Wr inber or Roller Mills P uplre Roller Mills Premi rge Ennis 29 A. L. E F" v Hrson 9 III ■ Eddv !» Ullia Fe R. Fl. ok P C. H c e. l. a A Win tin G Gran » 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Datt- To Whon; Seiitenib* J U. Hunga 2* Henning Hiltnt M. I.. Hiltner 21 H. II A: I J H. Hamilton &amp; J H. Hamilloi \V. .1 J O H H Carl Ht 1) Hin Lue Hot Horn iz h h- H Clara M Hervt Libb Florence E. Hilt n V Hindn Lydia H. ! 1 Ha 29 Miss Emil&gt; E. Ha Hindma Harr Eliza 1mm h F Heffl« 1mm 1» Irvin Kurp Jew I'r unson 1 1 Clara I'. .J&lt; Charles .Johnson I'r (I Frank Ja Johnson tl Pt 21 Charles S. Jones 21 ■ hnson 21 J. F. Johnson I&gt; Jennings </seg>
            <seg id="p065">.1 1 0 00 12.0 0 4.00 4.50 3 9.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Prem. Mlsc 1 00 Premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p068">n I I \\" 1 I H. I M O. II I ( </seg>
            <seg id="p069">4 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 September Premi 29 W. H. Hei Premium 29 Willa Spauldir Premii Pi 29 Ruth Sheldon 29 Mrs. J. D .gh Sutti. 29 Scotts Bluffs Co. Ag Paul Mil 29 H&gt; : 29 Sadie 29 A. E. Shall Soddt 29 Mr 29 Mi- 29 Lo 29 Mamii- lie \V Sli 9* 993 P 994 P P R. Tomson I 29 Frank Temple I 29 Mrs. G. B. Simpkins 29 Delmer 29 J. \V. She 2» A 2f L. D. Shave iza Schiff : Safford Smishad K. 1! B. Knerr L. Houck bert Taylor </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 Prem. Misc What Issued 1.50 Premiums 10.00 Premiums Premiums 4.00 I'remiums 13.50 Premiums 006 Premiums mson Premiums Premiums I'remiums Premiums 8.00 Premiums Premiums 1.00 Premiums Premiums I'remiums 1.00 I'remiums iunis 1.00 Valentine 101* Premiums ii 1H Premiums 10.00 -limits miums Premiums ,ums 00 4 Premiums 4.62 mms iums I'remiums Premiurr 30 V( Void Premiums 00 1.00 iums 1.00 Premiums 19.00 iums Premiums Premiums 8.00 50 I'remiums 25.00 Premiums I'remiums Premiums Premiums Premiums Premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p072">M \ M Kobbii Wo] </seg>
            <seg id="p073">I </seg>
            <seg id="p074"/>
            <seg id="p075">MAM R. MELLOR n in a log cabin on a farm in Porter of Michigan City, where he re v vil war. After his father returned from moved to Lowell, Massachusetts, ret urn - n ( ana in April 1867. Her. ■ hool he became a clerk In ition he held for ten years. In 188 2 he &gt;n he held for ten estnan. October 16, 1SS3 he was mar- iober 16, 1883 he was mar- Ammie Fyke and in 1885 they moved to Nebraska ie and in 1885 they moved to Nebraska ee months then located at Loup City in June They homesteaded on a ntheast from the court house at i homestead for five years. In 1889 he ip with J. H. Scott in the n and loan busi- ! to the bar. V member of e Board of Agriculture in 1898. Early in the spring ir was In .incoln was appointed a m&gt; : riagers to fill the aused by the death of which capacity he served said Board during 2 and 1903. At the January meeting 1904 was ie Board and re-elected in 1905. At the win- ted its Secretary, which position </seg>
            <seg id="p076">i .i n • n Hr \V R </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Prem \Y \\ \Y Wi \Y \Y \V 1 w ■ \R RANTS. SKI </seg>
            <seg id="p078">,nt No A 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p079"/>
            <seg id="p080">\TK.\U IF TMI 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">An 362 8061 S6 Admission Tickets ;S1E I'AID BY E. McIXTYRE, TREAS - \RD OF AGRICULTURE. nt No Amount !J:S </seg>
            <seg id="p082">nt No Amo 1 t 1 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Amount Warrant No. Amount 11 4 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 Warrant No ,\ : : i 4 s i i i ; </seg>
            <seg id="p085">rant No Amount 1 l if, !&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 Warrant No. Amoun an 4(H 104.0 15 4&lt;i 474 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">Amount \IZ I ::X Void 41 0 567 IZ </seg>
            <seg id="p088">X f ( :;::; </seg>
            <seg id="p089">&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p090"/>
            <seg id="p091">*■ H RUDGI ES Boardman, Ohio, on the fourth !en years of his life was spent jol during the winter months for he reached the age of fourteen his iwn, Ohio and he attended the ward schools August 1S76 when not quite seventeen of a small retail hardware store as y boy. After ten years service he succeeded in ad- an and a small stockholder in the mployed. Not being satisfied by work- n the spring of 1886 to take "He ad shortly after located in the d go west, and shortly after located in the City rdware business. His business has in - now he is at the head of one of the busint His business has in- w he is at he head of one of the given much of his time to the public in many mch of his time to the public in n director and one year serv&lt; Club of Lincoln. He is also a very en- director and one year servi mmercial Club of Lincoln. He is also a very en- ;n much of his time to the work in the g given much of his time to the work in tlu nd for hi&gt; has been honored by being r his has been honored by b much interested in church h interested in church verv mu tryman and senior warden in Holy Trin - • ars. member of the Nebraska S and senior warden in Holy Trin to fill a vacancy and in 1901 was appoint - nagers and one year later was i ion he has held to date, iioline Stewart of Parnass', a vacancy and in 1901 was appoint- ioard of M ind one year later was ition he has held to date edit for leaving his old home state in the union. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">\ 4 1 n </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Amount 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">■4 . nt Nc </seg>
            <seg id="p095"/>
            <seg id="p096">* 1 4 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p097"/>
            <seg id="p098">98 V a ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 «ond and columns to ad- . mlan The doub- ; and form tniiini No : The i uring both men fniilifiil our !'r H Rl tirman </seg>
            <seg id="p100">.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 $1 I."- ■ E M SEARL1 .1.. \ APPERSON Commit ti will «i\ n which to finish their i ti n Your $11.1 with lino to have furtl it the pri part of I </seg>
            
            <seg id="p102">102 I ; 1 ■ 1 F. H. Yo ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p103">1 Mr. .irdin- Mr. d upon ! ■ied or f Mr. lams b&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 </seg>
           <seg id="p105"/>
            <seg id="p106">105 in (loins itu ■ land rtment as llltv. »hr: l 1Y Hid adjoining - rlcultural prod I 1 !() I if \nni, 1 noi ■ (1 Into the conduct of the y from his The I'.' nd this Hoard under his hat lasted until ls'(::. In whit he held continue (Bee he handled hun- i his I </seg>
            <seg id="p107">106 ■ Mr. 1. members for 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">•d in nomination: — ( \V. Hervey, M. B. Atkins. K. M J. A Ollis, W. A. Apperson, L. i members Mr. llclntyre and Mr. Furnas </seg>
            <seg id="p109"/>
            <seg id="p110">I with hi II in th : n Lii </seg>
            <seg id="p111">110 Y of these worn . but theii and v ;uhi in </seg>
            <seg id="p112">111 w w M. MAYS : hich I; roblem of ii into • 1 larg </seg>
            <seg id="p113">112 h </seg>
            <seg id="p114">11(1 pu nil bn n of i n in i .11 be ■ - ul animal Impn n our knowledge of what mundinns. mpiilse nj; wrought out. The slow re- </seg>
            <seg id="p115">114 mmted wing that tlM peculUr breed b. irtunity to work Both in individual with exc anim idividual mutut w rod v n gold min- nr pure bred anin ■■1 I ■tonal individuals with I ling I&gt;o». j n the analyzed ■ trical dam with aomic I In is of dent; ms b mak- Natur- Two Fid | try in producil a glamour to keep us from - our harsh clln practically f id too much weight If Britain The world « and Ki </seg>
            <seg id="p116">115 • ed more attention gh 1 and perfected her numerous pure d position along this line of i and farming production. With our most exu uient of breeding schools and laboratories velopment of public interest, and with o-operative enterprises, it would tstrip all other countries in the pro- ring the forn: on a small island is her most important e have been too much spread out by our va national herd book. We may need for a time to xisting breeds as new bases to start a breed or or in each group of counties d&gt; inblic money may be needed rs that new and improv •odu&lt; ln'Kun by the Vilmorins in Franc. as already taken hold on American soil. The row ■ duplicated in our row n nting in corn breeding and in the centgener system of il and other &lt;■■ - the breeding of sugar beets is world tens of millions of dollars, so the breeding of ce- . nd fruit crops will be worth many billions. S i more technical, and a ) han anywhere else in the world i in other count a new leredity in producing plants and animals * d in both the pi ■ production; and ing of public and which benefits all and which benefits all ovided for the improvement of ma- : provided for the improvement of ma- ?m o: so the nation and the in of improving our plants and Dg with public money. so the nation and the ming ian of improving our plant izing breeding with public money .sly interfere with patent rights, and it is : can aid in devising lotie plans may be adopted for public p md aid. This assocla - il for the public money and for the with patent rights, and it is A n on can aid in d&lt;\ d and patriotic may be adopted fm w h*&gt;ln and aid. This associa- il for the public money and for the Be and practical plans. This associa- nd me • ■mil &gt;\ plans. This associa- important function than the insurance through com- unction than the insurance through com - ! all public mone&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p117">116 / I f T </seg>
            <seg id="p118">117 nds of d improvement, yet the I out ue of the occasional im - that we may have all forth improved \iiimal liitriMlui lion st riving to irigi- Isdom \! imal hybrids. The effort of the De- ira and ss — is nd Brahma llllff;! Mr. .Jones, of Mon- .ernnif on foot for producing ;iml wild animals. He wolf and the rom- fur. Another basis for hybrids inction of this - notli. idizin^ in the pro- only of impo &gt; reduction of t illustration differ- I'. Uorden, ibility amendable. Ight thing in as lieep. i rope and al unimal and our - irrow eady long-tin). m for found- o </seg>
            <seg id="p119">118 was in tic ;. Th&lt; plant breedinR. Th( ly in tli. Agricultural college, and tlM Col&lt; horticultural had doi,. ring, and tic w The tendency, how. le thf •heep. He b«-; t&gt; mink and tl is no doubt that and while Dr \\ fully producing ;ind t cro»s-bred phi i ' ■ and nev iomelos will add ie as these ai The woi • and hybr; </seg>
            <seg id="p120">119 entering this field ystematic and de a beginning, and nd ables and sow- ially vp.rieties of corn 1 of work done on corn ,ide in the yield and 3 the experiment st f corn brought into so that the i-nsio forms d side by « ould &gt;f breeding to give profound lesson for us in nd ex t. The f he viod.ui orough s&gt;j Weld ;iih1 . ould nn' il somewhat similar in tki with corn, we should hav much Wh hods be ng in A n ons h whollv w nith selling purebred animals. In ca Hols' . the herd boc ion of tho animals. Slate ail matter of co-operative animal f th 1 are too narrow. fundamentally wrong. Each breeder has Etoc! id too few numbers very effe w h;.s there been d one, or Mr. N </seg>
            <seg id="p121">flux 1 i lid for ii K plan I in </seg>
            <seg id="p122">121 and like plant and there must uneration new available Bur- blic insti- ling favor anization One of district of ows wenty ■nalt 1 &gt; IMPART* ion :tni ords. ti K WII ■st on i he il many other onomy </seg>
            <seg id="p123"/>
            <seg id="p124">ad rai - '1 in t H 1 l When quit* mil at the age of 16 w nt Was a men when i lumbus Delent 1 ing associatio Tt became winj Merin ring ;:- man of the Ohio pi ummit 1 joined with 5 other prominet Colun n r : at this m h newly organized newl )n and served in 1 - wool sheep bi and a member of K caving the state, and a memb i countv fair association. W ounty fail ep enterprise intro.: with the first sheep enterprise introd ska in IS S3 and located a was of the Knox and lo Knox countv, was seeretarv of the Knox i loan operations; n loan operations; wa union and Kno- n an l tarv during his connection with th iring his connection with th&gt; - naha in 1887. Eng the "Household, Homi 1 to Omaha in 1887. E i iht the "Household, Home.- I in 1888, changed it ii Stockman and Culti- Ith Q. M. Hi' ,Iy World Herald.' rn Stockman and i 1 with 0. M. Hitch World Herald P^ditor of ' kly World 1901, when he ac&lt; ska Farmer," then rmb- it 1 , 1901, when he aci X l Heath Bros, and Mclntosh: on the retirement of Mr. Mi - i management of the Neb: ;ust 1, 1905, when he resign- Edi i the "Twentieth C n 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">ft iivid 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">A </seg>
            <seg id="p127">and of pure-bred anim;U VRCH, HEREDI Wit i d \ ■nt wilh v. \\ HI) The follow- any del. ' vl ing will arou- . blic as inv which the public : d ii </seg>
            <seg id="p128">127 amount as is h county del- M who were called \iiense of each who reside in )X RECOMMENDATIONS Board of Committee who were appointed .1 &gt;on the report of our if the Sec walks as matter of zz q year miums in heartily R WILL1 \V COLE. SVNKORD RICHARDS Conimi Committee on made the </seg>
            <seg id="p129">■ 1- I ::', </seg>
            <seg id="p130">1 ..ii Polled $s %f, $5 $4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p131"/>
            <seg id="p132">; dos rrci XI </seg>
            <seg id="p133">N N N No No. 78 No. 78 </seg>
            <seg id="p134">■ : f al I </seg>
            <seg id="p135">ton and nature to better adv may see fit to make, o t Friday. Saturday and However, if the Judg an added inducement for r bo a person ai have q </seg>
            <seg id="p136">jple of the adiness lor of the way rions MRS. C. F. LADD, IK VI EXTILE DEPARTMENT i half wards son fo ssion; PRO- !ied in \v w professionals. M )R one premium, ibits nd Quilts 1st Pretn. Prem. $3.00 f </seg>
            <seg id="p137">136 I V Wool W ■ ■ Wool. I </seg>
            <seg id="p138">Pren $3.00 ! $1 &lt;ni 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p139"/>
            <seg id="p140">Y \ I n </seg>
            <seg id="p141">140 I Tra </seg>
            <seg id="p142">141 I 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">142 Kni Knl </seg>
            <seg id="p144">143 " Prem. l 1.00 i. oo d Prem. Preir $1.0 $1 </seg>
            <seg id="p145">iropri ! in 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p146">145 I the Managers be d rt- ling and ml whiit is ii - to offer ier and lai . w </seg>
            <seg id="p147">146 1 A I Mr I 1 all II </seg>
            <seg id="p148">147 udation of this &lt;1 what the premium the motion is tb he words "at a words "he shall a; u and dec tion of the Commit ■ tided that th Any remar </seg>
            <seg id="p149">148 Mr all CO!: Mr 1 of w « Mr. I ILVEI To tt i i n ion and 1 nt. who r 1 of tr </seg>
            <seg id="p150">149 forwai' nations in thli 3Ute Bo;i full and d- ! any. own A sample o! office of the S orthci submit the Board of Agricultu i legislation by the National mmend an appropriation by nd equipment in 1 and have main- ,1 minimum aska quest the ml the high iculture. ward- No ward i with th« the lines iOltlti ntlemen' CREDENTIALS Board of Agriculture </seg>
            <seg id="p151">150 followj r ( 1 hav </seg>
            <seg id="p152">\ </seg>
            <seg id="p153">152 \ ■ V M ■\ </seg>
            <seg id="p154">153 ind this honor ■rything in my ilture for Mr. I iluly 1 1 for I for (1 tin ; f my suffrage Applau iiiiiininious choice </seg>
            <seg id="p155"/>
            <seg id="p156">Y V 1 X A A M Y \ </seg>
            <seg id="p157">Mr. I I f Mr. \V A </seg>
            <seg id="p158">ii n n :1 I wish to ni. reports of mbers and rei&gt;: an reouest. Motion iirman, Mr. H Elijah Fill It d who wi I ha\&lt; and from ■ill wil n the nded on the farm I ;on is land is advancing in *ml pursuit! is much gi </seg>
            <seg id="p159">• : </seg>
            <seg id="p160">159 onei will hat knowl- ind for on &lt; will t of All w Elk wn ' How known soil and nown ■ Wins in f 1 m&lt;&gt;. he month; fficit'nt abandai </seg>
            <seg id="p161">t 1 I K V </seg>
            <seg id="p162">I 1 1 *ith I </seg>
            <seg id="p163">162 I ! </seg>
            <seg id="p164">ii f : ■ r\ in ar K 1 w 1 hand in hand v livid </seg>
            <seg id="p165">TV </seg>
            <seg id="p166">t man t ■i i 1 1. N I nlir i made for them in 1 ;ind wet. and from filth }f til' </seg>
            <seg id="p167">166 nd in w nt which n ■ I tl w d. « t. d a high This -Midied of th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p168">167 11 id h»&gt; one I k much lied » rid ;i d </seg>
            <seg id="p169">wi it in il' ultini w hi ind trial turf n en th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p170">of it 1 lople cm more domestic idy of he ildin of which will food is ive how hing which A ■vith those who what disease most ini to call help in time ■d to our stock- </seg>
            <seg id="p171"/>
            <seg id="p172">.1 4:!. Wh 1 when IV 1 X </seg>
            <seg id="p173">II II • and othi </seg>
            <seg id="p174">field th mind of him who m lildt humanity. All All tha \v ivill t'n rt liiion ' of I to do if farm life, and now fa ieh they own for tl li a small' ry. Wli. </seg>
            <seg id="p175">lessening the amount of I onsen and I running a farm wll nt upon the depend ihe natui which he owns. Here apain ii will be I not only of practical value but o! 1 within not only of practii but of a their fields for I w&gt;rk. !)■ 1 ■i has v Thl: f ■ ■ classes T professions. Tl and insisting upon it for their children ■ which | nd in- filled with thought and d their mental pabulum demand. Let the walls of the farm In 11s of the farm hon Let there be nn. Dthe and &lt; everything which provides for mi mental m und in that with wind </seg>
            <seg id="p176">175 Women will (Idly ! of it will be . nd datiKht (1: in. . will con ilth of our SSH &gt;N I \. p. &lt;;. Ul'AUTY IX LIVE S IV ion tli. lien upon pool have not full&gt; a|&gt; :ii ion to i d into d par wonderful im ; &gt; !!d that th </seg>
            <seg id="p177">rowli portuii: in tin would </seg>
            <seg id="p178">177 rial used in the process nd the quality of the of whatever kind desired rod &gt;ur and expense ow the same amount of ■ or and liels of corn per of produc- and. The in- acre, therefore is !, therefore is t animal thut the has ll for of animal w thut tli' en expense has i for one cow or &gt;r one cou ng such anini i pt on one pt on one r acre, wil of i by all stock- on of kno on of kno jrder thai material ier tha at will permit of a profit. lit of a profit. en qualit lualit ti the gru Ith the growing ,nimal re;! an impo: em to think, when the animal re stablished shed f-ic he crops I nssible be d yield, the crops i f live stock, and the well conducted farm If the busi- of any kind, he first in- icturir n, not alone the source and cost ;il methods to be adopted, but hi- important questions is that of the latest and most hine with the latest improve- n ted, and proved to be the best He adopts the one that can do the time, and produce a finished prod - nomically. He is compelled to do \\t </seg>
            <seg id="p179">178 . of 1 In otf Tht ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p180">179 in the quality of the machine an t </seg>
            <seg id="p181">180 adaptability to milk production. Th will produce a varying quantity as well as qu diff&lt;- • , periods of inu, anc 1 thus \f with a ii t.lity and be sure of a low or po&lt; from disaster, in the lati • I'nlike the manu both for the economy teachings and </seg>
            <seg id="p182">181 Ding so far as to attempt profit with dairy bred steer bred cows in the dairy, ar« m ood reason and just wi V link of using the ancient he modern gang. The one im- he other has been improv- d to a special purpose needs to keep constantly imals, not only the prod- hem for pay for the labor nd for tli. on his investment i more than all that it is an hing for future determination tin for these thinu Of co 1 ally hi n price or the low. he rent h n 1 mil ii hi that upon h, • me desire to get all there is In It heard much of late vator nd of th. for of the farm and es- It is nil, no doubt, most commendable and o doubt, most commendable and will n. 'ion of m products and THAT it itally concerned al for legislation In be- 1 y lead him to think that his at it m ion. and not through his per business judgment f pr »ho some years ago was engaged ■med to be possessed of from what he </seg>
            <seg id="p183">182 » The farmer who Emiliar do with t)i M, from th&lt; harrows Kuld kin </seg>
            <seg id="p184">183 their milk pro.; liilk from bet-! inquired if he would lii. ollow- f How and im ■ \v •u mor ■Hint; which Inaproi which Impi nd will bring it if offered fo bound I' by their ■ including improved live stock, to not ial value of his farm. i or add to the value of his ■ his hind" As we look around I will bring it if offered for sal that valu; I by their earn i, includr ■d live stork, to not add to th value of his farm ■r add to the value of his i round lways found on the and with the most moi d th. found on •id with the most mon- &gt;uld '1 Inquire int* cl </seg>
            <seg id="p185">nt fan N and the most money, or Is it the intelli £ proved stock and better methods, hat stimulated the most mon- t I shall hope that something I ma arouse sufficient interest among the fs them to think seriously and lead thei achieve the best res methods. The first Nt in tli - school bo bras; Corn Th&lt; five hundri Class ners of wr test v *&gt;d hibition from th count Kind 4. How Planting — date, der. rt of hill igth ol «J. Cultivation — tools oi macr how i w of husked ind r quired in rais 1 tie iur hour :t. Total n limber o: h. \al'je uf-r hour c. Total number of ;e of m of oth </seg>
            <seg id="p186">185 gain been stant in juntered with A other ddress, age and school district of contestant held at Lincoln, December 14, 15 and 16, among the school boys created among the ate in the cont&gt; ordingly a corn ed. &lt; &gt;nflned to corn product made in whole or in part from ny product made in whole or in part from Agriculture started a prize list by offering iculture started a prize list by offering retail firms in Nebraska and in other worth of pri» etail firms in Nebraska and in other worth of n cooking exhibits were shown in the ooking exhibits were shown in the hool of Agriculture. Dr. T. Lytle Lyon H i bits. Miss Rosa Bou- --&lt; ience in the University nd graded the corn were 35 8 entries, which Included n buted J200 toward the local ive its full co- Prof. John hout the meeting. The lead- ■urage the work and and girls. The following program Nebraska Corn Growing and Corn Cooking Contest. Outline of Program. I III RSDA1 , I»K&lt; ■KMIIKK 11 Kill i Lincoln hotel &gt;wing and Corn Cooking Con- I ( C Farm niv 1 Nebraska, and Manual apartments of Lincoln ( Afternoon inuation of (a), (b) and (c), of forenoon program incoln Cit </seg>
            <seg id="p187"/>
            <seg id="p188">' \ ii ( Id IV 1 ii </seg>
            <seg id="p189">Drill i I MOW 1&gt;I&lt; I Mill I Address: Addrt Afternoon GENERA! 1 !()( </seg>
            <seg id="p190">ion" and *g S \ I I Kl&gt; \^ . l»l( KMI1KR Hi .incoln incoln holt and girls h m M m of Corn n Corn ( Dr. L. P. Liiildi-n. Toastmastn Hoy J. H. Mickey A. O. Thomas Where the Bo&gt; [ W. Crab Mxb E p Harrison Our Boys. Miss l.\da McMahon Professor John Hamilton striction of detailed report to the n »i Pridaj K\iiiin»j. I orenooa. Pop Corn F Richard Oglesbee Things That Ar Stephens. Farming," Will M. Maupin </seg>
            <seg id="p191">o &gt;dad - Wit) </seg>
            <seg id="p192">191 old King ' \ mil took The Bridal of «'&gt;•• KU»g- buddii noiklii ml v in mil ■ hrkf </seg>
            <seg id="p193">192 : in suit of U 1. • d in rob€ A K&lt; Hid I ( But the glowing Past Orion and t Ere the throne Plump and round and ild fai Tresses touched with </seg>
            <seg id="p194">193 KBRASKA l i are n vania ompleti il ir Beet in white KK.MS To .MK d mini hoii^ht tion ought offi ed, none of which mbar your . tions and industrk mid very appropriately have :ie here to stay.' I am tte in which to live and work and true American, political re- o be in the far West, and yet as longer remote. Governor Curtin, once in a speech before a company - all railroad in his native ed and wa i with Mr. Ludden anno:, ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p195">county related an ineic; ired in h living sold ( and had concludec sold his home, and had that the famil that the family »■« each r. of tli, For insl would t of a Inn of a I Urn m •tate ture of buffalo. "Tli. ,me out M wond buffal gent and progress. go to make up a | has not been in a; has not been i the development of this lai a expanse at will. "What has wrought this gr the development ot I What has wrought thi You have had the m&lt;» nave had the r has had to occupy your lands, tc has had to occu these resources. Your dtiti these reso the eastern states have pro: A in th&gt; he re! w ho M up from your far who I. up from your f app. &gt;' our intel n your experiment station, ul or people; that they are int i your experiment station ri perior people; that they are inte and that makes for pn "Every speech made by and that makes for prc Every speech made by X has been of high order, ad* to live for noble ends Tfci that has not tended toward tr that has not dren, that has not directed then "II 1 K pervaded by rig ■•ntiment and rrounded m wonderful n </seg>
            <seg id="p196">195 the subject. on I n of the director with, and ad- ■ u of you: )U n or at most twenty of your young people )ung people wenty c tural department of your university i: uion room for a brief conf&gt; life which it I. It was ou call it here :!ion that hail that the first. Imagine mj niversity in the It was i call it here, and :iion that hail octed, and t night for the first. Imagine in 3 the building filled with 4 00 of Nebraska's h 4 (mi of Nebraska's building filled wi d with the agricultural department of down from the farms i grad- ith the agricultural department of your wn from the farms of y&lt; grad- his institution home to their farms ami institution home to their farms an.: ing. I was never more astonished in my eeting. I f more astonished in my ch a gathering of young men interested in a gathering of young men interested in ate, and I " io st of the agricul- and I have visited most of the agricul- aental stations of this country. The little his country. The littl statior d for the club that I had expected to meet for the club that I had expected to i pressed me was this — that Nebraska is giv- i me was this — that Nebraska is giv ;r young men that they may not go off intc ng men that they may not go oB into •ned professions outside of agriculture, bul d professions outside of agriculture, but i lean he land and go to work to develop tha- land and go to work to develop that s: n which all others riculture. monstration of the fact that such an edu J iven in Nebraska. That is the kind of i very state of this union. Most of th&lt;- en away from agriculture. Nebraska has is re that they educate can and do go back to n livelihood in this calling, but have as i lomes as exist anywhere in the world, to which I have referred that impressed r ised at the St. Louis Exposition. While ntleman in charge of the Nebraska ex- Nebraska could produce. He took me ,v iious room fitted up after the fashion of mfortable chair started a machine led off Nebraska with all of her great crops of corn and alfalfa and all id nets that grow so luxuriantly upon your her glory, the agriculture of ion, and I was impressed with this id magnificence of production there was ied her. That was number two </seg>
            <seg id="p197">i 196 "The other thing that has Impressed me t Ing just closing. By the way, Mr. Toastma night and these young people ought tending this banquet until some her the soldier who went with Sherni ing that march the.y had to go through a great ma got down toward wi i, ■ Of i called to thinking that Y ■ rid. "Th: I v from V n the yea Ky from wnai we ao 1101 n to come of fa1 _ r ress •jublii partment of publii ,1 their h farm life wkii ml lonelin* lightful o have all of U th of you x ilth of your Ian is n&lt; -impl at work and keep work, doing signed. If t fully and admirably d agricultural education in every publi&lt; college and university will wing w who are anxious tc r trsuit of this great indu "In many states they K falfa, about » I </seg>
            <seg id="p198">197 has departed from (1 of her boys and girls and has them that they shall not only produce corn lion, bui me time insure to the ! ime insure to the nd the best citizenship •ihip I." I ApplMM r 19' &gt; Mended to include 1 n extended to include I i an is number of county contests. The increased number of coun The I and su- th« a addition to corn prod i and bn and rocoanut ud idnse; nd brown igar and glngi Dg and preserving of fruits and needle wo at provides for exhibits ind girls or ornamentation in the hou organization- ne iind preserving of fruits and needle work nine department provides for exhlbltl and girls rnamentation in the nous \ gricultura A Moon Hickt Itii-'h fiar k V. Hi. \Y Aldrich. ( Vldrich. Old. lloulton, G hompson, THE \Kl;i; \sK.\ STATE BOARD HE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD ►F AGBICULTT'RE torial Council on Fiirt;i li day ot ,1 ,h e bill rttortal Hoard lish a Territorial Board 1 time miin »« ()f - Nli; McDonald, who on Tu&lt; Mills S \ i. who on Tuesday tht Do bill On Thur- 'h It ni to the I te on Wednesday, October irdBOn, Territorial I rhunda} 'h It Oi he House of H&gt; ■ l. Territorial Co his Private Secretary John HcConhic follow </seg>
            <seg id="p199">198 AN ACT TO ESTABLISH A. TERRITOI AGRK ULTURI - persons, residents of any county of this T Society for the improvemen \ t.nall have ado and regulations Agricu; and proper office paid to tb upon its mem ■ the amo fore a mj an ord. IDED coun,, allowing five ■the imp ks. artic ind iir the agrk ciry. And it sf ers of small their awards sp&lt; • or be lik« or of improving the soil c thus offered with the inter most economical mode of impro compete for premiums or imp v tion of any crops or other articl miums are adjudged to deliver to the aw correct statement of the process of and the expense and value of tt rately the profits derived or expected to be d&lt; Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of e;. nually a list of the awards and ai. a newspaper in the county, if tt nearest newspaper to said county, and tc </seg>
            <seg id="p200">her with an abstract of county, which report shall th the rules and regulations of the T warded to the Territorial nless a certificate is pre ident of the Territorial Board showing made. son, Harrison Johnson. A. D. Joi hristian Bobst, Robert W. Fur Hoover, Mills S. Reeves, Broad Cole. J H. Chaplin, be and tbey ii ■accession in the he duty of said Board or a majority of them ;oon after the passage of this rnajor- nize I Presi offii hey m time th h member shall half members shall expire e annual meeting. And the President shall henever he may deem it ntral point in the Terri- d at tr nual meet- the Preside i, who shall for the time being b al Board of Agricul mts. prospects and y hout the Territory; and I !) ) the President of the Territorial Board, and elegates shall at this meetin litable ies in the Territorial Board of Agriculture he dutv c I Board to make an an- 1 Assembly of Territory, embracing the Board nd an abstract of the pa irdinate Ies, so as to give a general lture hout the Territory, accom- r nied by such recommendations as they may deem important and county agricultural I which may be or - be and the same are h.rpby declared bodies cor- nder nd polit h shall be capable of suing and being to make a re- d no subsequei. Joel T. Griffin and I f corporate with pe Jed under the name Board w </seg>
            <seg id="p201">200 sued, and capable of holding in fee simple The election of perm Eaas, President; A. D. Jone following Board of Manap* glas: H. Baird, of Dakota: i; and C. Bobst, of Pawne At this first meeting it w for a period of three menrii ber, A. D. 1859. The President was itions from the different ooui ry was ordered to - an address at the first Territorial Fa lipointed as :i Conn list. The foil. purchase or receive by donation, not to ex jy c buildings thereon. Sec. 9. That all deeds, conveyances Band by such county agricultural socie ate, shall be good and valid in law an title in fee simple in such societies to sa Sec. 10. In all cases when such c ■hall purchase ■ here com: nay, if th the counties and societies, pay out of tl couc- line amount of money for tl of such sites as shall I . or shal agricultural si individuals for si solved or cease in an or made for real e improv use of : ounty Ar&gt;; The proceedings Agriculture which was h- was ] Omaha, with A. D. Jones, of O mination as to the length of tern Bhould iie allotment re Thomn brook; S. Reeves; Broad Cole and H. A. D. Jones; R. W. Furnas: J. ( T. Griffin; and E. H. Chaplain. </seg>
            <seg id="p202">201 \TIONS FOR THE FAIR d on the books in the enclosure. On w i animals, cards will be furnished with ed at the office, which are to be , xhibited. No article exhibited shall hibition. without the permi- Every exhibitor should mn nd. if possible, and if do r nnot come in competition for it ion to the re - butter, cheese, liar attention to the re p, plows, butter, cheese ow &gt;s and cattle, open to all. as different breeds of of r with each other. The awards nipetition w mals which h approach the nearest to the the business office imnn io office immediate )air tions and enter upon th o make their reports to Ihe reports nd enter upon tht make their reports to nstru )I1S ■d equ icticable. The reports DGES.- The judges i judges on animals will have id general characte on animals will have maturi ttd general characti They will make proper allowances for ill make proper allowances for f the character and condition ! not to to be awarded to Bulls character and condition No premiums been fattened for the ription -.'iilarity of the j the Secretary for in- doubt, after examination, of their f any animal is of such a charac- ihibition in competition, they will report Commit' »J be adopted &gt;n Fat Cattle will give parti o examination. It is believed, that he best cattle that have the ill require </seg>
            <seg id="p203">i </seg>
            <seg id="p204">R. WILLIAMS Root Adams; in New York, February 11th, 1868 and to them ue to Illinois and remained there dairv and cheese manufacturing Nebraska, took up the dairy and ie up to the year 1902 Republican Party In it was nd 19" rved a and 190 at Collinsville, Lewis count; eat on hool in winter until .rms under ams: in 1868 was married to Miss ssioner ol " the i such capacity until 1906. He uer of Public Lands Nebra &gt;'d of Agri </seg>
            <seg id="p205">Kie cattle in this class to b€ weighed !i, and publish the r also &lt; before awarding any pren: to the manner ar i ■ QBNERAL RULES APPLICABLE xhibitor, although he may s! w urn v ierits of the ai led wt mpetit KEPOK xpi-cted nd desi miums X 1 fu Badd The first annual T lowing tween "d Improv V rs Milch Cows and Foreign C Horses: — Blood Horses; Ho and Foreign Horse Fat Sheep; Foreign Sheep: Middle W lations of the premium li I list provid' a modern premium Cati : '1; G Matched Horses and Geldii^ Sheep: — Of any breed excep Saxons and their grad* </seg>
            <seg id="p206">205 ntered under one classification match, open to all, and for boys bread, butter, hams. in manufactures; needle, An ngs and drawings: designs; liscel- ial; mechanical; chemical; hard- ■emaker's ultural; vegetable nd dr: HONORABLE J. STERLING MORTON. id Gentlemen: Called upon to address you, the you, whose calling I so much honor and love, to address you, the ou, whoso calling I so much honor and love w a a momen' ■ eliant enthusiasm, I a&gt; iertaken the duty which it imposes, which it imp' intention at first thought to gather together ac- tention at first thought to gather together at :atistics concerning I i Rural u. ■ Rural interests and ing itory; '1 at fo11 ' made a trial at coll i icable from tli nt J d of various counl nt up no well iny informa 1 igricul ng from what limited • e to draw information i i figures farm- ii wit h mha and Oto .vhich compris u ri River, north of the ntioned s1 tl iring of 1854, and the Kansas- ■presontatives until the 24th I -on was too far advanced for ierants of that slimmer to put in cro] I in a very few nrt T think it safe to say that not more than a single sec- i in the whole Territory of Nebraska in e only considerable patches of corn that I remember see - ill were raised by the Mission at Bellevue, and by the town &gt;n the town site. I remember that we little colony of hopeful boarders braska ( i the wint and even feed for our horses and vthing t&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p207">had very little to spare s inter was exceedingly i •he farmers with the sturdy hand of indu ,,do» of the rich soils of thi and Tin the I - when the a ment had been settled u; tus field efully b abundanc The glad ed far and nea impetus wa lowing springs. But h&gt; of reckless speculation, anc wealth, sc The legislative Assembly in Jar to have more money in the count the creation of bar that much desired obje&lt; for every five hundred men to issue be Kividua) stock es or ambitions. And w secure discoun </seg>
            <seg id="p208">Nemaha Valley, and case In commercial ml the plentier want iwn lots, and conse- phistlcated and enthu- making money without either men- n invented, and patented far did this idea diffuse it- ka. So ached and took entire pos- he Territory, in so much, that in a Territory, Governor Izard 1 rosperity, the fact that town n a few months, from $300.00 to $3,000.00 nstructors of those patent mills for iliiy nor soundness in the prosperity wealth and true capital must arise -osperity which underlies and su[ Id, and is called agricultural development, w rently satisfied, and lulled itself into arts of industry and economy belonged to a hat here indeed, they were certainly use! would bend the back, nerve the arm to labor il, when by the aid of a lithographer me ephemeral newspaper a half sec ield three thousand town lots at an $100.00 each? Whom could we ex- ecomplished avocation of city founder arduous and homely duties of the ocity and speed, in fact, became a surpass ■d at once to all the luxuries and reflne- gulated communities in the east. We w rough hewn squatters arrayed in buck- ing nation of exquisite land sharks and icloth hi ol imer of 1S56 was consumed in he pn value of city property. Young Chicagos, increscent New Yorks, precocious Philadelphias and d out, lithographed, divided into shares, w nd puffed with becoming unction and complaisance. The mere men- A he purpose of agriculture was nsidered an ei if verdancy wholly unpardonable and entirely of old fogyisni in the first degree. i in tt jmmer of 1856 and there in proportion to the popu- d tha hut the crop of town plats, town </seg>
            <seg id="p209">urnoi more in a. ft* lin ui t hin n ■ f . A grand rally was had for nd more mom orated, and new shares with nothing to insure, and nothing est of wildcat banh for h ecided that th shares, town lots and Nebraska ban abundant. Jinoni unheeded and inii: through and ushered in the will never be forgotten b LTh.- the wisdom in </seg>
            <seg id="p210">209 ing evidence of ars, and a con- uoney IV I ion foi umber, De Soto iw tli- the country by incy. tailed vvorth- nia bank, and have ■ I far re buying anxiously • ■ un- own public nmng finan- i only id one \VI1 hompson . Trust The and proups of d thoroughly sh of ti jnal Treasury, the quaking of the rnments them- sv world, demonstrated beyond a id furthermore, that It was idden storm of rain, ky, almost all sunshine. liles and the poultry h and bellow in the stampede ?culators, bank dir» </seg>
            <seg id="p211">210 nado of 1 ist da had ' warn gont Wlllbi in i rid ill had ii' aloud o a* a .loublful had ii t) pawn for th&lt; and the iudividi I thin. ever looked down upo ■ parallel for our utter and a I believe, on the I an average, *2 50 in cash failures and loss&lt; ! There was one small ave been sadly pin in their ranks, and who wh. Court times were the then h and partments of industry. Merchants. era were continually lanientin </seg>
            <seg id="p212">211 through the year of hereof. They who had fol- I1H sd their crops carefully, they and ■i&gt;le of Nebraska, could board themselves induces thought. It may paralyze will induce reason and reflec- igraent and discretion in the reckless. e failed. I believe that owing to our ex- ere to do more thinking and reasoning during the time had ever been accomplished a en your grandfathers during the long \ iown by the large fireplace where the huge black htly, away back east somewhere. i omesteads. as when the old man after reading his news- I wipe his at them up by the clock on the mself there in the genial firelight, place and his elbows on his knees, and have a h us all in Nebraska that winter. \V n, gloomy "think;" and among us all we tw way of making money by char- pioved a most unprofitable delusion and an humbug. We thought that building large cities without arly crack-brained species of ini v body could not live in town I lie towns were laid off in eighty iction lots We thought, to sum up all hurriedly. it tempt to legislate prosperity into the wealth into our laps by legal kless, very that while we had as- lie had in fact been \ lT«d people; ;t&gt; the part of Dives, we were really better fitted for the r of Lazarus, leme for obtaining wealth without labor, prosperity with - and growing into a community of opulence and ease with- without labor, prosperity with- unity of opulence and ease with- jn ii ad been a complete failure. ail ing of wned upon us and the icy hand of winter and the icy hand of winter u hold upon the e*rth, and the prairies were once more th, an i he prairies were once more inshine and emerald. The result of all our thinking dur - and dreary winter was now about to be embodied in act- erald. Th« ■suit of all our thinking dur- ng and dreary winter was now about to be embodied in act- j enhance our real prosperity and substantial wealth. It and substantial wealth. It ir illy and justly determined that the true grandeur and pros- ly and justly determined that the true grandeur and pros- eople was roncealed in their capacity for industry, honesty capacity for industry, honesty w nt endu endure were fortunes to be made in Nebraska, they were to be in Nebraska, they were to be W€ frugality and persevering exertion alone. The soil was to nd persevering exertion alone. The soil was to i and taxed t of the dwellers thereon; and out of alone, was all true and substantial independence to be de- g our political existence, we re. For • </seg>
            <seg id="p213">ondilic ating and iin] A i md starvation. W&lt; Kl ransformed fit ts of the old M ■ hundred- eastern 11 i hJch at th- </seg>
            <seg id="p214">n months, or will in tli h of land culti in ■d : if m re mpt to por- rivers and ountr and will unil&gt; id independent opul Idden in the fertility of our sprii on » Miod of b* lling for in it he i hand of I dominioi :ind 11 led for He ■ and . "ill be ird«d by the Anglo- n in his onward trail living here mi richness of whic </seg>
            <seg id="p215">and furnishes i &gt;w is an arduous and h Tin- ides .mds is as sr ind r and t Be before i and we vast and beautiful domain. And w prepared for the so-called It ■. icine, let us be content ti ists. Men sturdy in mind and t and active in all that pertains of the physical system of mank lightened and well directed tra d r Klevate and improve 01 i physical and intellec nake &lt; &gt; i'h Bi n and ■ oftly descending d&gt; and co-workers; the tt Th mue ihought and eff and stronger ti </seg>
            <seg id="p216">build. th i \Y nd 1 1.. nd h \ IV M \ k to Him </seg>
            <seg id="p217">• llowir • 1 i fron </seg>
            <seg id="p218">217 iunual collection most benefl- ities of Ne- d which have nd that there ex - v and agriculture. ltural sur- acter and differe 2ntion of u with th ill othe nd art anc iragenient i per - repor jmb i pic Mr. Peleg Red and ne- proof of viden Nebraska lor butt jach bu The material within six n Bolt, was the fastest in a pros- saha — has with found. ons, Call- &gt;d by Mr. Georgt Dg great powers of II Rasin. It attr:. </seg>
            <seg id="p219"/>
            <seg id="p220">E\V ELLIN tiorn of Quake Iowa, 1 da of fourteen t Whittier 7 he moved to Nebraska and d ngled wellinc li of farm- ;il hir of 1 nov. Association &gt;utation. Board of Rhyno lera, Iowa, married </seg>
            <seg id="p221">IV i K John I H. M. I H </seg>
            <seg id="p222">Presidents BRASKA STATE BOARD OF n'RE. Brownvil H Hrownvil Brownvill </seg>
            <seg id="p223">222 Yea J. 1 in Dunham, oniana in Dunham. Oniaht in Dunh;i: in Dunhu In Clar Edmund Melnt Edmund Mclnt » 4 J. B. D M B; M K R R. R y V E ■ tVICE PRESI1 ff, Omi ff. Or Alvin 8 Omal) Morton, Nebrask lorton, N ,rtin Dunham, Omal Fact - Morton, Nebraska j s Morton, Nebrasl 1ST4 Martin Dunham, ■ Martin Dunham, Omar J. F Kinii' liewson, Norfoll Mathewson, J T. Clarkson. </seg>
            <seg id="p224">223 Y I Franklir HE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD LTl/RE Xel nil Mr. !■ n ward </seg>
            <seg id="p225">224 V TREASUREF « K. 7. I Y H. \\ H. V 1 J. C. M&lt; i </seg>
            <seg id="p226">KA STATE BOARD OF Kennedy iilmore, O Jennings )n, J. \V. Hollingshead &gt;od, C. H. Walker king ■olidge, J C. H low, H C. Addis "eking &gt;olidge, J Ulen, C. H Addis ntyre, ntyr© M. Dunhal M . Dunham. \ R. Daniels, G. W. E. Dorsey, E. N iels, G. W. E. Dorsev, E. N W. Furnas, G. H. Walker Me Bride, E. N. Grennell, L rker, E. X. Grennell. L White, J. Jensen, L. A. Kent E Mclntyre, E. N. Grennell nsmore. M. Dunham, H. B. Nicodemus B. Dinsmore, M. Dunham, H. B. Nicodemus J. Mil ninsmore. M. Dunham, R. H. Henry, R. R B. Dinsmore, M. Dunham, E. Mclntyre, B. A rnf H. Henry, J. B. Dinsmore, E. A. Barnes, M. Dunham, J Jens H. Dunham, L. A. Kent, M H. Henrv, J. B. Dinsmore </seg>
            <seg id="p227">1! K H K&lt; \V. Kti r.ldlin ! II. Wl I) H H P </seg>
            <seg id="p228">Wi low, ( Walker, .1 T Thomas, Dr. F. Thomas, Dr. li Q. Stuver, J. H or, J. H. H 1 Dinnin Dinnin, .lidge, J. •olidge, J brisli Vdclis, .1 H. Ely, ( 1 Ely, George P. Eaton, J. D. Barton. J S. Morton, ge P. Eaton, J. D. sor Uarto arton, J. S. Morton, iliell, Willian - Potwin, Willian Potwin, ■ ' H. J. 1 F. K W E. D ke, C. W. Lyman, N. 8. Belden, J. c. w n, X S. Belden, J Hastings, J stings, J. en, H. ■ H. I A , J. D. H. Wheeler. M. 1) H. Who n R. V. \V. Mathewson, J. R. V. W. Mathewson, J. nnell. Mo :ng. H. A. Bruno, king, H. A. Bruno, nr M Walker, C. Hartman, M. Gilben. H Wi H; tniiin. M. Gilbi.'i Ha arbltv I)r \V. Lyman man, Bdmund Mclntyre, C. H \\ \ G. Has- [clntyre, (' H Winslow. A. G. Has- Holi Laws, Horace Holi Laws, Horace M K Dunh iinell. umU, R. Dani&gt; Stoll, J. J. H. Dinsmore, S. Barnard, C. J. B. Dinsmore, S. Barnard, C. A. H. Bartow, E. Mclntyre, Bartow, E. Mclntyre, H. D Wh; Kent, J. F John R. Craig, Royal j, J. C. McBride, E. X. Grennell, J. K Daniels, H. C. Stoll, J. T. Clark- Dinsmore, S. Barnard, C. H. Walker, V. H. Barstow, Ed Mclntyre, Alltt Harker, I.. A. Kent, W- W. T. Dodge, fn </seg>
            <seg id="p229">Jensen, E. A. Barnes, R. Da R. W. Furnas, J. B. Din Ba P. Sava B. McDowell, S. M. Barker, L. A. Ker M. Dr Wr H He M K 1890 L. A. Kent, J. I Barker, J ■•m\ W Cowan, 1 Dinsmore, M. Du Barstow, A. Hurr Judd Richardson, H 1892 L. A. Kent, J. D. McF; E W. D. Wl 1893 R. W. Furnas, R. H. H snry, M. Dui B. Dinsmo ner, E. A. Barnes, J phrey, J. Holcomb, I A W. Bennett, E \ 1883 D. H. Wheeler, M. Dunham, O. M. Dr 1884 C. Hartma 1891 R. W. Furnas, E N A. Kent, J. D. McFar Intyre, J. B. McDowe Hayward, P. H. Barr: Bowen, J. R Cantlin, </seg>
            <seg id="p230">229 ■ E. Mclntji. Do well. S M I her, 8. C . E. L. Vance, M. Doo- P. H To fill vacancies for one M Irian Bruner, W. H. Bar- &gt;am i. Henry, M. Dunham, E. A. Barnes, J. B. mphr&gt; Stuart, J. C. Warner, B. M. W. II der, F. H F. B. Sheldoi Farland, E. Mclni Mclns Do well, S. Dowell, S. iowen, J. M. I. her, M L • &gt;r. M. L. R. CanUii nee, M. Doolittle, S. C. Bas- Mann, L. Morse. K. I. Vance, M. Doolittle, S. C. Bas M( \V. i BM, J. B. Dinsmore, M. Dunham, R. rues, J. U. Dinsmore, M. Dunham, R H. H Humphrey, J. N. Van Duyn, E. M. Searle, W H. D. Kelley, lover, H. D. K- liter. Don: . W. li. Mellor, W. R. ii. X. Withrow. I. I) I !. I.. Morse, ML L W. K. Mellor, W. R I). McFarlabd, L. Morse, M U • in. P. Younger*, Jr., E. L. P. Youngers, Jr., E. L her. M. \V. Chappell. I B. Dinsmore, \V. A Poynter, L. K. McGaw, Poynter, L. K. McGaw ;, F. H. Young, A. Humphrey m D Duyn, W. E. Ewing, F. H. Young, A. Humphrey, B. Ewir Lrte, A C. .lones, G. R G. R II, 0. W. Hervey. W. Herv G rl cFarland, J. R. Cantlin, E Mann, L I Mclntyre, W. R Withrow, L. Mor- &lt;ter Youngera i son. kobt. W. Furnas, C. H. Rudge, L. D. Stl !.. R. Fletcher, C. M. Lewelling, E. Filley, W W. Furnas, C. H. Rudge, L. D. Stilson Fletcher, C. M. Lewelling, E. Fille/, W A. P. &lt;trand, G. R. Williams, H. L. Cook, \ R. Williams, H. L. Cook, W. i A Ewtng. W. H. Barger, H. C. Lydlck. Arnold, S. C. Bassett, J. R. Cantlin, E. L. Vance, Ohailef lick Mann, E. Mclntyre. W. R. Mellor, N. Withrow, L. Morse, T inure. \V. R. Mellor, N. Wlthrow, L. Morse, T A. McKa&gt; Jr., G. W. Hervey, W. Vi . Cole McKa Voungers, Jr., G. W. Hervey, W. W. Cole W. Foster. B. Dinsmore, R. W. Furnas, C. H. Rudge, E. M. Searle, Jr. E. Filley, G. R. Williams, H. L. Cook, W. E. Ewiu,;, W C David Hanna, O. P. Hendershot. T ( Cyrus Horton, R. M. Wolcott, E k. Minier Z. Russel </seg>
            <seg id="p231">1904 V. Arnold, B Mclntyre, W. 1 Young i&lt; H. K NEBH state, and on tions the blending ditions of which car: one neighborho which are of a hay purpn of western Net numerabl' t from llvii through tt, the&gt; the most healthful and anywhere. The high alti ities found in t and j'l human </seg>
            <seg id="p232">k Ruinj: // // /A Br Twist .» I»ursa </seg>
            <seg id="p233">ska though comparath • t agricultural and live stock k Th ii ■us of farm prod full THE TH1 ATE 1 ' Kriod o In 1 E7 it j Iilfnc ri gro census p&lt;- Wher cally all the 1 much crop v In wl until It was at D. &lt;""., was forced r whe wheat slat bnsbe!&amp;, placing of winter wheat, v\ date, being ex In gtneral wheat prod f |.ring v I 4th, 1903 was production of wheat credited bushels. In general whe the following states: K &gt;rth D vu the tenth state in wheat prod shown in ten year periods i a bushel els: 1 MOVING TO THE FRONT Pin oats production Nebraska of the </seg>
            <seg id="p234">SHEEP f Puint* uf tta* iheep, «ut« view Brisket, or breast. M. Hind fl»n lti 5 17. Top line ». Underliu. Kwk vpin. o» nhoni rops 86 Hip 1» Bibe. • f Bun r V* Bibs Kump. t\ Fr&gt;r»-n»nk » Thigh.ortegotmu Rump. U».-k t-.n « k L..H •&gt; * \ V aep, front ami raai .rUiL f - </seg>
            <seg id="p235">234 y cattle in Nebraska. This showing an increase of crease for the forty-fivt handling cattle in Nebra ly Increased number ab&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p236">Y K 8fi Tai •ay Beiiy Fore rta Thifrt 1 S H &lt;A U f * \ \ W 1 h r- H </seg>
            <seg id="p237"/>
            <seg id="p238">ENT AI U M d nt Ver w 1 about n NOLD jncie, Indiana, Feb. 16th, 1861, Ellen Arnold to Shell Rock, la., .•■br. In the year 1874 set - don, where he grew to manhood married to Dora A. Kinney of lildren were born, one boy and and has been Congregational church of Verdon for Board of Richardson Ext fifteen years. During this time !.;nt. Was i twc Board of Agriculture in January 1902 iblican in </seg>
            <seg id="p239">A LENCE AND SUPERIORITY tpast. The r 443; b In 190 increased nuini world in I specimens of tl The ■ In Milk c&lt; P. *4 </seg>
            <seg id="p240">* &gt;3* 37 ,. m \ / \\ / n i i </seg>
            <seg id="p241">U r; &gt;n ami ful o u &gt; ond sequent r com, 1 1 timau confined each com muni bushels over the crop of 1904. 1 1 acre as compared with 7 bushels. The in is 1 : he average yield t as compared with 31.12 bushels in 1904. B t606 bushels over 1904, and Rye, 4 The table on Alfalfa is the result tailed enumeration made of that crop in the yean, the total crop has been estimated the growth and extent of ths NEBRASKA &gt;i and The i ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p242">241 -H Ji'T.-l*, 4tMi. ,. +. -^ 1 1 1 A 4. 444,- 1,777 * 124 in) Ji r &gt;.440 l^.-M 4 14&lt;i 4 I.HH4 i,714,3«] 1,085,744 4u HH 1.2T 1 ' a 4" </seg>
            <seg id="p243">COUNTS ♦ +&lt; I 91.-. : Value of (. orn. V </seg>
            <seg id="p244">243 I HEAT, 1- Av V Pruduc Farm Value Farm Value «3O,31W I25,t&gt;41,: -. ■ 17.4 Mil .-„] 180 52,628 (HJ 17.4 75,180 52,628 oo 2J.4 23.4 i,*&lt;r, H -O.l» 2«0 l!Hi INI H 20.0 --(I l'.Hi ini 10.414 19.6 204.114 14J - 30 25.0 750 414 19.6 204.114 142- 1 .",2.". in) 1.572 12. o 13,2 i 13,2 2.245 lti.T 37,491 2»&gt;.24:t 70 224.-. lti.T :r.,VM 2»i.24:t 70 - 213 - 213 4o:! 403 15,371 1,062,607 4"&gt;.:t7i i.osimio: l".74ii 253,605 177. 0,74« 2:i.ii 253,605 177 50ti 21.5 10.- 21.5 10.- 2.121 22. s 15.0 1.47(1 l.ir 354 K.212 ". 74s 40 l"&gt;.n 1.470 1,02 (51 H.^H' .-,74s 4,i 20.2 1.7'.«. 1,257 ■*.S44 2O.« 1&gt;J. is,; i- T 1 . '. 27 J4.ll 27.u4^ 1M.H 21.-*) 15.0 1J.4H:! -2\.-~&gt; 019 ;wi 15.0 1,431 914 S.i : 22.7 1,061,81a 74:; 24.0 I3.( «,122 40 911 23.1 4«,776 ; L'2.7 1.061,81a 743.270 50 -4.0 |;j,( «,122 40 11.5 »,27."i li 4 l'::.7 233 ltttj 2:i:: ltw.i 22.2 11.077 7.7 i;2.2 11.077 7 7 17.1 47,760 :;:!.) 17.1 47.7.^) 1'i.ii 1,125,504 16.0 1,125,504 20.3 1.11' 20.3 1,110 74" 21..". 21.5 &gt;i.*41 I 20.2 20.0 920 25 144 00 920 25, 144 i«) 210 ..!12 118 40 0 .!12 113,129 7!U:m'3O 113,129 79,190 :J0 744.7l':i 521,3 1.2 44.72!) 1,233. !&gt;S7.: '14.42:! 4.-..0 '14.42:! 20.0 572 4iki •".72. 7xo 4o*.. 17.5 :i4.47". 24,1 SO] 374,9; H.47.". 24.U2 "K} '■^)1 :i74 1*-1 ■".'•':. 417.'.C7 40 Is. 1 5»7, 417. ■ 417,!' 24.3 4'.'7 34«. t 24 21. :? 1,593,367 1,115 :&gt;.' &lt; 21.(1 11.7s! 21.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p245">1 WINTER WHK.V: STY ami thervii|xji 000 ai </seg>
            <seg id="p246">245 I Farm Value 10,510 744 11.1 M.630 60 24o 15.5 14.(i l.T- t 2.721 18.0 10.4 101. l-l 51,101 13.2 14.1 114.. 7.1 1H.4 -UH4 15.8 t&gt;:i,421 44. 7'.'. 140 13.2 ■ I 1,409 14.0 til. - O44 14.5 lie 4.74H U8 Oo 41.H74 lo 224.' !■"»"- 117.' 14.". . 142 171,228 lit*. ~ i:i.~ li.4 15," 4'i.!»21 00 1.7U2 14.:'&gt; 19« ''■' 42.HC. 30 127 Tee io 29,209 W) 244 110 80 15 16 13 19.543 13,880 lo ll.olo 7.707 (HI 12.2 12,822 ~~&gt; 40 171 15.0 Vi 17!i 2o MM) 210 ot) 095 00 13 4,842 20 6M.5O4 20 13 oor. 542 11 |«.2 :!24 22ii 80 1.770 13.4 23,718 !"■' 16.6 Mil 14.571 20 74 16.0 106,184 10, </seg>
            <seg id="p247">246 NI'KP \ I ■ In . . I&gt; &gt;tran Hi.4 ~ - - </seg>
            <seg id="p248">247 « Farm Value rarm &gt; »iw 45 ■ 219 5&lt;) • 155.:' 1,915,170 47-.; i :..-,-&gt;! T.i Till i"&gt; 1O1,23T, 2,766 31,490 "&gt;.4!'!' I.O8I U.O 1.444.44:1 361,11 14 it 13.4 154,110 4 n l.i.JT.tili' ;&lt;■.+ 1.970,76" II 1411.14- 4J i4:; l.Vi. I 1 t;4ti K5.411 50 11,874 V.I-2.-.-.4 !!«.! 2d! 1. 1 HIT 251 4;&gt;.li 45. 1 Ji"&gt;. i*ii -•"&gt; :\&gt; 1 ui.i 14. ti 11.- l,l(&gt;6,2»5 2Tt..:.T:i l.iii.- :«»".« .MO.^iwi 19.731 50 4 4.4WI i;ilS tx&gt; 1»U 41 217. W :i2.4 30.1 151,* _4 th *\ </seg>
            <seg id="p249">- - 14 42.4T-' </seg>
            <seg id="p250">249 Farm Value 742 4T 151 in ■47 ol 9,762 Mil 'M 6,540 2,4 40. &lt;" M.422 2:i,l!Mi 22.1 IX I 1'i-Uxe.i l'.U&gt;41 15 I" ...&gt;.&gt; 200 4,440 156.1 4.440 1.- I Io4.7.'&gt;o *24 1,71" 54,2 20.0' .')4.2.'.T I 20.0" 1 'i;4 11.92 H2.2:s2 1 11.9 2i&gt;4 1 l.Vi 11.1 30,261 ll.lWi :,!.» 551, -«■',. 12.' 4.W loi-fli :::. .551,136 12,«15 101,00c 43. 1, 1,21« *■»•• H14 Ti 0 24.' ». 1 :i:i.44o 27.5 lii.(HHi 23.3 ■';( :&gt; 242,:iii-". ijt l.i 3,175 l.r 2 - ■•I '.i l.i&gt;4 152 2 111. •'•'4 800 2,0" 447 13, •"&gt;. 1 12,627 22.'. 4. ."i!hi 1.' 12. tKK) 4.:;47 i.' 1-7.4NI 713 :!2. 57.1 157 2!t7 39,360 14."' 1,930 2.'&gt;. KC) 4.7M 1,77 260 I."- 24.5 21.- 31 = 11.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p251">1 </seg>
            <seg id="p252">a WILLIS WOODINGTOX COLE. Woodington Cole, was born in Bradford county, Pa., Sept. His father was an extensive farmer and owned a large 1 along the Susquehanna river. Here he attended the h&gt;1 in his youth, finishing his early education at the ma Collegiate Institute at Towanda, Pa. He was a member te Militia for seven years, rising from a private to first lieu- in lch organization was celebrated for his marksmanship, nt of the state medal. In 1885 he came to Nebraska, nch two miles from Oakdale where he remained a purchased a drug store in Oakdale. In 1888 he was Miss Charlotte Shenefelt, to which union has been born n, three boys and one girl, three of whom are living. i ful years at Oakdale, he moved to Pawnee I his present home at Xeligh continuing in the i eh he was the prime mover in locating the xchange, and has been prominently connected with I town, and its public enterprises. He was elected a ate Board of Agriculture in 1902 and again in 1905, ndent of Agricultural Hall during the years •ne position for the year 1906. </seg>
            <seg id="p253">252 HAUL STY 14] - niltou </seg>
            <seg id="p254">- +*4,7n: ao 17.4 -^l "•&gt; 12,217 72," I* ■ 22. • 4mi .'A. - i:5,«i V2.-.2-. lo. 1-.4 14.- 11.0 I."' IT. 4 4.T^ ■:».&lt; 12. ■■ 14." IDT. 'U. " 19.0 1.1- 22.2 '■'-- K0 101,241 00 4."..' 14., lit. i- 1, V 22.' 4.21 * 12,; li.. 18,7Ti 11.- 20, 2.- 73, S) 4) i »l,028 1K.5 4."..- 27.2&gt; 741 17.il 114. 14.4 17.5 117,512 7n." 16.8 7.121 4,27 21.0 1..V 4.- lit.- 11,921 4&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p255">4 1'iwnee - - - </seg>
            <seg id="p256">4 4 Farm Va SOI, 760 111,715 • f3O1.527 in) U,25» 12*.:SU on 13,554 oo 4«2 4. 1 .Yl'.K 4 l.llti 10.1 •22 2«&gt;. . ll.lHil OO •*4.11li 7"&gt;7.O44 in) 4.H24 4:t.4ni oo 4 :,.i)44 45,: 4.QUH 081 On ti,O42 4 24.4 219. 4.1 4,321 37.240 12." 4 47,8: •1.913 o»i liil.ti . 4.".4«i 40." i:;. 124. 7.19« 84, "»M !•&lt;• 10.404 93,i 4W&gt; - 842 214 •MM, . 4 547 13,'tJ 4.1W 17« 1H.1 IB, 126 145, 4.87H :&gt;• 2ii:; 4 12-'. 73. . - </seg>
            <seg id="p257">- \LFAL* &lt; &lt;HN'n \LF\I.KA I'lloli \ til 114* ot &lt;Ti&gt;p« 1 *. M l."i </seg>
            <seg id="p258">iitiou and pn conditions as this time. In Bulletin atement giving t showed there to be 1903, or a growth since r from 1905. i ■ ling A 1905 l $134,991,^11.04 onths of $16,113,483.89 tter date ■f t deposits ANK DEPOS $) 34,991 \ </seg>
            <seg id="p259">«■ oK WESTE1 venti' » T « Tl ■« da while I WOUl'l </seg>
            <seg id="p260">259 of many ago held their posts Tumble-down houses -. clothing, ool. Local alone the I arm to skimming skimmed milk is ound equally nu- n ■t f Now nd. with a hit of bi mid region, ar w nt to w jui d will )n tli and llion n field to I hat of power, Th&gt; ITorestation. •Campbell ilk. the \ the ir &gt;d other low if Ne jundary which d, out of the urnish of land. ■iiount. po admittedly extrav.,- ir million acre*. would be the approximate e ■r. Klmball, Cheyennt; and ! Ighborhood, a eight i ill be appro. i almost completely in i ilily the Loui until the effort al mil clearl) east of the - toward the establisl </seg>
            <seg id="p261">260 souri i that by means of tion, pi ifuial lakes ing irrigation possibilities can !•■ Consider, third our sand bank- lot* lie mainly in the following coun Nothing li of w been made. It probat'i far from 1 bank, for a oon&gt; As in ' 'f m Ofit with wind mil moistened trw the ground » , cult to find ■ time a la r . will have plai will farmer will ii and the ordiii Sugar be&lt; I rule. Bi of gardeii piemen t I dry faru. ence of aid to dr&lt; dry farming ' Thi words, the views of n recognized authority on tl that his f" 11 which w much nic of water to a great deal better. 1 cause we have pi' where. Ind&lt; ; lture a little water will go a great wi is not, I think, v. </seg>
            <seg id="p262">261 erson, Blaine, Loup, Cheyenne, Hooker, areas of valley &gt;( the hills are growing ies in May and June I am told that 1 iindiest spots top. No doubt t i acres will be iw more about ii 1 lo it I plane! soil of &gt;w and is at points here the water table is from six to nstit\ most produc- n acres or so, ural land by U into ngri ht : s remote. i in andhills proper. wt re the precipi- :ind\ ultural &lt; ifter years of ( I the thought dot f pine had be iere, showing 3ur hundred m of humus had fi '1 the soil was a has had a similar production in nited Forest Service h and hilly ever to be it in the soil. h at will for the ither than through af- he whole. fc&gt; fertility through would farm pt in the ;it the abund- ltory must forever w that such part of lsewhere pointed out now distinctly nd this is likely to 9 and the nat- </seg>
            <seg id="p263">m </seg>
            <seg id="p264">&gt; ■ X 1 whirl- I on wl « I) w I M </seg>
            <seg id="p265">tdian can be dry farmed wit ; but this should include a to maintain fertil Mo movin Band ure i in humid ■ lnp I. . command and retain fir Founl. The p Eo as tc n, inc ace becomini ow or agitat You thus ent Ine time, b: from all, i what I land west of the &gt;8tb inei growth of ile fro </seg>
            <seg id="p266">is by no grow. Grazing Is will be found of cl. ly the chief productive as the Conditions ny of our fel - i low rainfall, they are not lightily aid in meet- being con- ichness. and much of msed more by In prot&gt; That is caprt </seg>
            <seg id="p267">s i I - A J !— , » &amp; — \- ! I; M &gt; o • </seg>
            <seg id="p268">&gt;\ FOR ALL STATIONS HE TEN TEARS 18 T 3 « T I 49 * ■ 1 T 11 Ten nioi rainfall record for the if rainfall in the - nd compl- </seg>
            <seg id="p269">268 « A Y Ar </seg>
            <seg id="p270">* «' T * « •■ ( i I • I • </seg>
            <seg id="p271">&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p272">271 I" T U t t ■ T « r </seg>
            <seg id="p273">T ■ A i Arerat ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p274">A ■■ » I I t l&lt; 1 4' ■ -■ </seg>
            <seg id="p275">274 MONTHLY PRECIPITATK &gt;N TOWN Eit&gt;J» How.nl Co A y </seg>
            <seg id="p276">275 Annl Z •■ ■ t T </seg>
            <seg id="p277">TUWW Hrrk </seg>
            <seg id="p278">\T1&lt; &gt;N ■ • M I T I </seg>
            <seg id="p279">\ STATE BOARU OI 278 TOWN M Itod*-t i'luk^ta ( I K ■ : ma i </seg>
            <seg id="p280">279 as 11 X I •4 t 41 M I s 1 * 4 * N 4 » K » ■ 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p281">280 MONTHLY Pi: tlhui-d A I M T A </seg>
            <seg id="p282">281 • 1 3. I &gt; &gt;! T </seg>
            <seg id="p283">■ month l A * ■ A I </seg>
            <seg id="p284">■ ■ I &lt; 4 T </seg>
            <seg id="p285">284 NTHLY I 1 M I h K </seg>
            <seg id="p286">/ 1 » 4 9 *■ I </seg>
            <seg id="p287">286 M&lt; &gt;NTHI.' ■s </seg>
            <seg id="p288">i.S » 4" « </seg>
            <seg id="p289">w </seg>
            <seg id="p290">An * T f 1» </seg>
            <seg id="p291">290 </seg>
            <seg id="p292">291 \i.K (( ►XDITIONS IX XEBE l Agricu. 1906. in Nebraska. This interest imong which may be mentioned j, whi and pur- i of low The h' fall of thi t :. had nn tion. We of the country generall which until lately would have 1 ion with farming hat in addition to making which have on thi itig it pn- ier in t land tought !■• nditioi it in </seg>
            <seg id="p293"/>
            <seg id="p294">Y roduct, being born at His early public school and iiport Business Ogalalla, then ssition he served Keith county for two minted him w of Agri ition he Auditor </seg>
            <seg id="p295">294 '^ f&gt;. Y *— ft T — t hw*H — I &gt;*i^ ♦ *^=- OfrAJNA&amp;E S&gt;YST£M NEAR BURT COUNTY. HeBGWSHA Of ab( of these gi Bwhlcl he dr;i s </seg>
            <seg id="p296">295 and the total little less than two ntinually increasing 't, bottom width uid dimensions as I to perform as the nount of excavation in- ibic yard, Two floating if the is iinil iinliination While this is a u drain a vent all overflow or instance, it is w the land lying on ut of the eive from the drainage &gt;f this overflow water d drains to the Combination tion will approximate $ 10 the land range ubic yards antities and the nt of water equ. </seg>
            <seg id="p297">296 from a merely nominal sum per Ion on the Combination is n&gt; icbing the point w son 11 river. As soon . kind ha: farm- signet at the which ! to to waters which run do creek which enters thp PI 1.1.!.' CUT-OFT C*?*i^- dot&gt;~ ry nc • • living which flows froe cept t i for « </seg>
            <seg id="p298">me of the in July, ■rving the full agri- j or depended o state, is a Je and around many bends, through ing to the fact off the wa- isult that n the hind I: impi i t ral channels 1 the construction of I n f w 1 mu )urinn recent of Offlcci ier k king towards \v th flowing of t Nemah ■ntially similar proj- - under consideration on this ands beit- ime down out of the hills f mm flowing : .: veral the nt of the channel of the &gt; might pass off more i binding channel has been discussed i extensive su veys were made itation having accentu- i he agitation the interested ks being pecially active jrains an a ■a of about 92 ill, the government </seg>
            <seg id="p299">nile ol ,f land »■ i ich w i nit h f Th.' 1 on the aff) </seg>
            <seg id="p300">299 iri with ir i but thu nui which wil narp Id w fflrior ■d ssion Laws for bills. All of them un - nt. the right to iv or con&gt; d in the fore- rovided for the </seg>
            <seg id="p301"/>
            <seg id="p302">f six \\ A the death of ved as </seg>
            <seg id="p303">f 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p304"/>
            <seg id="p305">304 i ability to do sum tlitions the farmer with for such a ki. ■ animal, as shall en </seg>
            <seg id="p306">HI domestic It ha it ome of ather with the deplet- different problem ntain himself upon the 1 maintain its which confronts the present ■ • 1 1 1 .- 1 1 importance to I food supply of the pon this mine of i how to ilopment. ■ centuries od. They k deposit. It required </seg>
            <seg id="p307">306 f </seg>
            <seg id="p308">Id indi i mind </seg>
            <seg id="p309">I The conn; of names. The to tim the coi more than * has been attempts of hygiene. It is dries, into an inc part of its his </seg>
            <seg id="p310">of book- however, a Essentials Hierarchy &gt;oint of de- that prog- has been 1 out if, in the fu- Of is indus- w </seg>
            <seg id="p311"/>
            <seg id="p312"/>
            <seg id="p313">can Ml pupi It * is said is tauj; &lt; * definite a s, or burr him more effi </seg>
            <seg id="p314">eta well intuition. ion brings before i doi machines used in od This much- was not memo- mind tha' im m in the in by the sometimes spoken m of the imaging act he clouds, or to think lations, as when the centaur, or h the ndividual from i is and ins more than a </seg>
            <seg id="p315">314 hu imbii f 1 lie down with tl </seg>
            <seg id="p316">J inu- or indred ■ il A child uneull iiik for th&lt;? </seg>
            <seg id="p317">was in ani » c » 1 ir ord ■n </seg>
            <seg id="p318">X * it k do w 1* w laws of boy. In follow- We find ing intlut in born as far as possible or amidst the solitude he torch from it, and rung ity boy ndeur for his own, )f his high ambitions. He. . ilization, is heir to </seg>
            <seg id="p319"/>
            <seg id="p320"/>
            <seg id="p321">i f ni|'U ■ om th farm-born </seg>
            <seg id="p322">conclude Agriculture Yes; in reply ing cul- •xcepting lRMERS. insist mis 1 ard of and now the plant ... note . ear those which are •1 dispute of all agri- much experimental the necessity Billings was secured to other experl- the extent of these of the Legis- </seg>
            <seg id="p323">» 1 n «• of this institution own Dean Bt fled to done so m on the life of his trespass upon the times and leaving him to tal- and of Al Thursti Moon Dr. B« Kfor a while, i . Here upon this be </seg>
            <seg id="p324">jr w&gt; dedicate, a ind suitable- inspira- :d in the hool of Agri- of Agri- bler things ir things ultation. isonie a i V .idling of skill, of speaks not Dured out to jn n J which later antique li. ,e sons and daughters wi;l j wn i am glad to be here and to be C ate he antly and everlastingly i 00, more or on. "V .1 measure it of time to come. You ere — to be richer In their ure C iden mysteries of animal eating new varieties and new tables, two plants, two did not exist before, produced. If, says the knew it, this is a real illus - id of creation by which this </seg>
            <seg id="p325">'en try, when and collet- brains of the farmers themselves to a higher and broad. ■ and such posslbili Eres health, energy, knowle And if any voung fellow ocation, I ask him, "Are : id be a lawyer or a docto MA A business </seg>
            <seg id="p326">;oly be called he highway has no into play his in the mills i narrowest ruts around in the commer from two student a and that the marvel- rom 111(1 SO ession, but the accumulated he ch« ■tory w;is built in Ne- pUbiltty of our of thi </seg>
            <seg id="p327">Kin this T ■ About w r o XI tmaint;' ■d prod Pis and one of the i Of &gt;( in mi Kni.rs about $ ■ for O </seg>
            <seg id="p328">inc .ontinu- But time entiflc and ud « than equ ion at North forms, fe d under diffen 1 limited fa- nore marked th when the Ird student d that regis Wednesday a 1 id per cent." H of "The Firs nocked about </seg>
            <seg id="p329"/>
            <seg id="p330">1 </seg>
            <seg id="p331">Y A Agr th that from A theory Dl during already in at ill cor vided for them What are yo going home from the r before resolved that, *■ and deeper and \ tlon here o </seg>
            <seg id="p332">3 X lit j profound ;o comprehend of the laws of nature interpret. It is a hop ion, that d the highest talerr ■ time to investigations to Nebraska School of Agrl - lally fortunate. Fortunate lid heredity, the added ote specific o hold his rank </seg>
            <seg id="p333">» </seg>
            <seg id="p334">ther to aid in ■ I CO! K of hi • he I&gt; 1 to see of tiling of a &gt;nntrv life before the truth th where but one had grown Ah, he i which could be na: i of rreatio! of food for « </seg>
            <seg id="p335">&amp; state and a Of wt A drea Divin lolvlne the prot Ring;, t The joy of unt * </seg>
            <seg id="p336">i, of the Rhode Island agricul- f the college of ag The power idy waxes enthusi Goliath. The boy shows his admira- late. Sometimes on the farm the of knightly strength — and sad in- jnworthy. Usually there Is a imagination for the very acme Etd whse confidence and ideal- Sometimes nge forms .1 bird, is entranced Wallace, or by the reckle xploits appeal particularly to ith avidity on stories of courag i! the call to surrender, when he bold t: tt Hazard Perr }f a w able in war, c-1 n the bov thai i led to 1&gt; missionaries, by their wisdom or wisdom or •ouse "iing man. d in nds of young men. iig man, with all Its strength of the moral lead- &amp; in ils but the ideal on of ands of voting men. rt of the n, with all Its strength h I miration for the leader is earnest iesirable ambition. 1 mbition as a foundation. EA DERSHIP trongly the need of And yet we sometimes forget. lion is intelligent, quickly re- public opinion? Is it one dividual? Whatever theoretical have we will all agree that it y ink. and act, and help make pub- </seg>
            <seg id="p337"/>
            <seg id="p338">\. AI *.■ j A PERSON arn in Virginia in 1855, coming to Johnson ked in a Tecumseh dry goods store der the firm name of Warren t he purchased the store at Te- which firm is now running under : part of his atten - hogs, and is a firm believer in the m, the conserving of its fertility. ■asses and road improvement. He wife and child living but a short nna LeMaster, to which union has he Nebraska State Board of Agrl - 906. He filled the office of Super- Fair and is appointed artnership with Geo. Warren and </seg>
            <seg id="p339">* w id </seg>
            <seg id="p340">I f V tvinnin V </seg>
            <seg id="p341">340 to be owners of the land they till, or tenan they to be an intelligent, educated, independe to become peasants — a caste of bard workii promising men with tbe hoe? Are u with American civilization, with all that implit social privileges, political stamina? Or are the&gt; to lag b&lt; Lance, with some futun .h to bews Do you say is to succeed in farn you will have say this you ha •i in will not ••Ires and farmers i belief that the g farn very pr Is ••vid'-i. utur« I think of four w And the first is in good mental need of An: have depended on For the future we must rely on best farmer in your neighborhood, no the best. This is your first for leadership. I assume that this to prepare yourself for les. M is wasted. I have practiced altogeth of preserving i soil fe learn to farm and : opportunities of this sdiool : palgn for better farming. You h </seg>
            <seg id="p342">341 lersonal success that this education the opportunity it affords you to demonstrate new methods, to be hood in raising the quality of its jur neighbors. You ought to make your own farm the beat ke your neighborhood the best Nebraska. If you do the first in help accomplish both results, is the future. No man liveth has a right to live to itself. Pos- \'e have no right to transmit to our Kills, a depleted soil, a decadent agri well expressed in a recent editorial in juote: "Much American farm- which ignores the future welfare Many of the systems employed in wresting wealth morrow, even though they make a makeshifts which no farmer and a respectable under- tion to unborn generations. Land owners are un n to leave the soil as fat as they found it. Cer j) ob it, but those with an md a proper consideration for their defense- to that form of grand larceny on of farming. ROBBERS ml and the south have been blighted by e voracious horde is displaying ominous Here the pilfering of fertility will last is better equipped for &gt;r • n in the heart endure abuse. Land al substances which r 1 constantly engaged in itabl a degree Soils that are required ii to-morrow for some- n not be his posterity. nous as to soil wealth hat are to com- bust ndry and the judicious nan in he farmer's means Id both profit and happiness. Fall- country it will be for n 1 i v with that su- </seg>
            <seg id="p343">342 -• Y l&gt;. v </seg>
            <seg id="p344">343 </seg>
            <seg id="p345">344 in tt tdo tfa&gt; drif n </seg>
            <seg id="p346">what .&lt;: the find ample op- »1 ons keep forcit They will if our national life .mil half our finally oung men, (u move the right outcome ZATI ship. Not onl on, fo •OB </seg>
            <seg id="p347"/>
            <seg id="p348"/>
            <seg id="p349">348 n t </seg>
            <seg id="p350">349 the » however, several leader. The have no desire i opment of perity of your neigh- in men istic needed - self forv igher position by seem- real, sincere, hea: a self-re- self be so sure of his own of others; yet on the the opinions of others; yet on the st have belief in hlm- v &amp; for methods of work - will- :id fo: S along with pe. wlth . m's point of view, and ;ind mo if character rather ider Is a e other man's ind motiv han &gt;f his in- qualities needed, and, blems in hand h e a permanent leader, must know what he is t have a limited point of view. He n it row. He must make which he is dealing. Fins i lader. Real 1&lt; Iwaj left hand an who ilists others. de. When you ride on the hands Th eneral of the ctful then and DEM rd to the duty of leadership. The tuit I want to suggest that. out to yc ur careers on eadership, and the fa fact of this Nebraska ha iven you this ike as for her sake. You have ades on the farm have You have had the cour - me here, whereas the ma- </seg>
            <seg id="p351"/>
            <seg id="p352">I A </seg>
            <seg id="p353"/>
            <seg id="p354">nufacturlng al . will be jdgery nd » d pi ;, aught the ar, and on iced a little only half third Wishing to get fourth The ig. The plowing arrowed, disked and he corn was planted in listed (60) bushels per acre, the most FALFA SOD acre. The i reir in and secured a ount of a poor </seg>
            <seg id="p355"/>
            <seg id="p356">11 A DO unt "■ now the S af th. </seg>
            <seg id="p357">re do» </seg>
            <seg id="p358">mowed, the plants owed to remain long, and just the The roots of the in diameter Turkestan alfalfa nt at but they Turk owi lir ■h of the fol- had prospered, and iots at several een in contrast ill sid. ■ dark decided the Tur- d the seed. ot w&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p359"/>
            <seg id="p360">ought to western eat) has £ in durunc O WHEAT MARKET ' o your ad this • nt. W&lt; i when he was :it th. </seg>
            <seg id="p361"/>
            <seg id="p362">we are proba- ind will b man in v- ado pro\ in doing &gt;on receipt of • 1. If ■ intie I i in introduction 1&gt; follows dmit an error and ioloei' i rinting the me it for \\V </seg>
            <seg id="p363">; </seg>
            <seg id="p364">(1 </seg>
            <seg id="p365"/>
            <seg id="p366">Drug F ( Merchan i f ( IV \ H </seg>
            <seg id="p367">hall v Eo maintain 1 on to her i fifteen </seg>
            <seg id="p368">m nd it is out of her mother - ion of motherhood merchandise. It is to our feed and water and </seg>
            <seg id="p369">1 t PRA&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p370">or wm into well fixed I should st gain on e spring. Then after isturbed and ind al- rzi r vo if these lasture of than if I had After I put cattle in yard. I have fed it dually, gaining n head, and if n in it. I also feed a pound of T for an appetizer, th m h, uttle off feed. I think v hness we have. I like to feed al - he feeding season. Alfal Fat, and I think that fed it long enough to make man should feed his cat- iw of. I think as soon ion't </seg>
            <seg id="p371">able c tal hernin i hand </seg>
            <seg id="p372">371 whereas bag bag aad losiu. 1 d and • lling The anini nd bre visible mei of the d hot to the I s. The animal </seg>
            <seg id="p373"/>
            <seg id="p374">-achusett- eived a public school education. His Boston. On the 19th Miss Flo- ed in Nebraska and settled Babson-Dickman Imple- ted with this or Dickman acted in d the appreciation of his filled that position in Board of m (ii i Mclntyre on Dec </seg>
            <seg id="p375">374 ?, </seg>
            <seg id="p376">t </seg>
            <seg id="p377">smeared on the not v.i pir Bof them use a mixtu and sulphur 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p378">)m the mature embryo passes kept in a moist con- food, such as s as supposed, tion ing lambs also i the los^ e. They have lirough the grass and nd tail of the ewes become no doubt to the animal in to take up ing ted in this manner. This seems ome infested with these para- ietermined by the symptoms t ites or not. This can be ef til post mortem examination, al- epeatedly seen animals affected can ortem. The n old. This no doubt is iwer of r. The symptoms re- affected with w nd they have i ■ 1 ■d api ength of d atment m ex- EC'TIO&gt; hrough inf&lt; April. if&lt; lambs — 14 Dne Oxford mini I juall] ■nbs were nearly all left wi their rom morning until </seg>
            <seg id="p379"/>
            <seg id="p380">V </seg>
            <seg id="p381">t f unknown w that the matur ch in a si some mam ■ »hen already I. tesiim cominp death &lt; ;r nt tensiv r.; confined "Ab stated E bowel and tx tion produced nd in the sut 2= </seg>
            <seg id="p382">381 [Id 3O Y n howeve r iifflculty aot b« \ i i i hold du r nount of mon- </seg>
            <seg id="p383"/>
            <seg id="p384"/>
            <seg id="p385">384 ve stock his lessor a T </seg>
            <seg id="p386">idee w of warded </seg>
            <seg id="p387">brain and mu Kls of the busii ners, retu- Ethout dedut ' are purch; Thes E prove de tt hate In action £ » i i i breed, n Kin at dev prices of thoroughbr </seg>
            <seg id="p388">iv the farms of the state nd quantity of poultry n to imagine. RETH&lt; Experiment deed great. develop tent be nd E b€ hi &gt;ven in e 3n to place &gt;-day the average This very poor showing is neubation of the eggs. If the rt which owing very prac- pecial course in te University, for the icks hatched are. on </seg>
            <seg id="p389">.uderlie these n twill be enabled of the present produ. Th . ■ Ing season E; are readily r the i ished products are di various m;n Kny over s et is «en separ </seg>
            <seg id="p390">\ ■mat if and effective combina- wbich when it on a level with the undertakings of the VCTICE lere are some -irU-uliure and Uer of pure-bred fowls i high plane of i ne who would fellow p n in any way. Let a hi t [ ould ■il to give ir profttablent^ )uld iie local situation and jbk : lOuld i vailable or obtainab wl drinki . keep pros [ to the best fting re from the free "Fa Ins name placed on publications of the De- ined from the Agricultural ronn </seg>
            <seg id="p391">Nebr. V advar : In pc T f I not found » April </seg>
            <seg id="p392">, who n 14 on a w natural ounded by hasp of nd belongs leson, who were had been </seg>
            <seg id="p393"/>
            <seg id="p394">OLLIS, J I i ide of "Enter]&gt; Farm . 1900 and If oup Vail- iltural So 0 he was mar ree boys and I in married to Knott. He d of Sup* in Hancock county, Illn ■ ption of ■ which he an the farm. which has now </seg>
            <seg id="p395">394 D from li across Um another v MM ■ about ■ gi Earl saw U count of t! ■ ory from found ii. id in tin a dii </seg>
            <seg id="p396">395 raens of S His pottei and pots: iland, Ireland, Greenland, md in 1 imen of who! The find is important in i ore link to a loi g us . : ily or totem. It ; hunt ! im- i) hundred I, but r. Joseph the matter. let me M </seg>
            <seg id="p397">396 it is difficult to say which of the two tribes madt convinced that it was Iowa or Omaha; 1 am inclined work of &lt; find rack ii. the mode of burial and it On Friday, J uue Z, 1905, 1 visited Blat d &lt; \V of the gu link gre. Hi A nun ing i. lived i I it and a roof of shinglt-s made over i .oritu ict when Lewis and Clark vis is more like a depression than a me ago a nt nains of "Chaza-Ninga" (John C. F the Black Bird gr. i« m&lt; IThe stream now known as abaa li-Peeche" (The Gr tmany lit can (i write comi </seg>
            <seg id="p398">I t c he ice Herald, who n i \ i r into the going 1 ream where the On. ■ &gt;und, but none of these i The rocky bluff near • iction 13, Town 10 north, Range 18 A. F. Schaffer of Kennard called my •k on this farm, which h- il from de- Mr. D. C. Van I i the Blair on this trip. When we saw the rock we 1 marks which might be taken for charac- lese marks however, by a hard age. n Blair to Omaha, I met Mr. R. F. i was anxious that I ;ht or ten miles up the Missouri river from 11 coated with short grass nd on the highest point and count two hun- Indians. I ot true, 1 but the red men were not slow to avail of burial here nd found nd unique were burned until I'he skull was near bones of the There was not a single imple - und. It is evident the flesh had nd (H spth of two or three feet in the sum- hill ■ fire was kindled and les of the pit were very hot and ottom of the pit; then the bones -ed with earth. The bones were thus consumed. There is no reason ot remain in this state for a thou north an ■&gt;d thereon. Some of these and trip from Blair to . nuated miles up trie Missouri river irom bluffs il of light, jruiii pinnacles, which a s oing 01 a firm hold limself ti I sea work and upon invest ic it ion it v . II placed in a </seg>
            <seg id="p399">l r o ment:- </seg>
            <seg id="p400">399 he practice of pulling ezers; th- lis work and were doubt- found fifty-three of these im- ( has collected a large nsisting of polished stone aver be able to make, although A ound tht v collection is the "G i on this trip. The heirs did not t of their possession, but iphed; they also allowed n !&gt;tO from which I hav. ■ it in the museum This iman face. It is cut from bas-relie: found od 1 sv rods east of The It doei mined Mrs. i be fi •d and nortl to h tv Morr ■ mounds opening two of we ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p401">400 shallow and being in point in q grounc r«arnu of the librarj Ktnd they r not impossible t :iis Ion Kboij' »vho rch we hav rs. The </seg>
            <seg id="p402">NDEX • 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p403">H I An Kill.'. . Wll I \V Hend&lt; - W ■ id, L. W. Mann \V. \i Mi Int x re. Ed i </seg>
            <seg id="p404">4 1 • ,V. H Olli 1 \ lor 1H ti.ld O. W. H \ nd !&lt;■ w \. A. Brlghi </seg>
            <seg id="p405"/>
            <seg id="p406">\ ■ 1 </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>