<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00007">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00007</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>REPORT OF THE Seventh Annual Meeting OF THE Nebraska Conference OF Charities and Corrections FOR 1903.</title>
		             <date value="1903">1903</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-16</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-07</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">REPORT OF 

Seventh Annual Meeting 

OF THE 

Nebraska Conference 

OF 

Charities and Corrections 

FOR 1903. </seg>


            <seg id="p002">
NEBRASKA 

STATE BOARD 

OF 

CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 

GOVERNOR J. H. MICKEY Chairman 

WM. K. FOWLER State Superintendent 

G. D. FOLLMER I and Commissioner 

JOHN DAVIS Clerk 

Advisory Secretaries 

A. \V. CLARK Omaha 

ESEABROOKE 
PH RUESING 

University Place 

West Point 

MRS E. C. JOHNSTON Lincoln 

FOR INFORMATION, ADDRESS 

JOHN DAVIS, State House, 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
3 

OFFICERS OF 

STATE CONFERENCE 

OF 

CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 

(Convention of 1904, Lincoln.) 

President, H. V. Hoagland Lincoln 

Vice President, Mrs. Zara Wilson Lincoln 

Secretary, John Davis Lincoln 

Enrolling Secretary, Mrs. E. C. Johnston Lincoln 

Treasurer, C. E. Prevey Lincoln 

Executive Committee 

Chancellor E. Benjamin Andrews 

Governor 'J. H. Mickey 

Dr. A. W. Clark 

Local Committee. 

(Convention of 1903, Lincoln.) 
Mayor H. J. Winnett, Chairman. 

Chancellor E. B. Andrew 
Dr. H. O. Rowlands 

Dr. J. L. Greene 
Rev. L. P. Ludden 
J. H. Humpe 

Dr. P. L, Hall 
H. V. Hoagland 
M. J. Waugh 
S. H. Burnham 
J. H. Ager 

J. E. Miller 

J. \V. Seabrooke 
G. W. Rhodes 
Henry Mayer 

Mrs. John Davis 

Mrs. A. J. Sawyer 
Mrs. E. C. Johnston 
Mrs. S. B. Sohus 
C. E. Prevey, Secretary 

Mrs. Callen Thompson 
Mrs. H. M. Bushnell 
Mrs. H. J. W. Seamark </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
REPORT OF SEVENTH ANNUAL MKKTING 

NAME AND LOCATION OF 

STATE INSTITUTIONS, 

AND SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE. 

NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE— LINCOLN 

Dr. J. L. Green 

INSANE ASYLUM AT NORFOLK 

ASYLUM FOR THE INCURABLE INSANE— HASTINGS 

Dr. W. B. Kern 

NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME— GRAND ISLAND 

Colonel A. V. Cole. 

SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME— MILFORD 

Colonel Charles Penn. 

HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS— LINCOLN 

Sarah B. Sohu 

STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL— KEARNEY 

B. D. Hayward. 

GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL— GEVENA 
H. M. Clark. 

NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME— MILFORD 

Margaret Kealy 

STATE PENITENTIARY— LINCOLN 

A. D. Beemer 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH— BEA- 

TRICE. 

Dr. A. Johnson 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB— OHAHA 

R. E. Stewart 

INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND— NEBRASKA CITY 

J. F. Morey. </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
5 

REPORT OF THE SEVENTH ANNUAL MEETING 

-I &gt;F THE 

NEBRASKA CONFERENCE 

OF 

CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS 

Held at Lincoln, Nebraska, February 5 and 6, 1903. 

The Conference met in the Epworth League room of St. Paul's 
church, at 10:30 a. m., the president, A. W. Clark, of Omaha, presiding. 

After the opening services, consisting of song and the opening 
prayer by Rev. Byron Beals. a cordial address of welcome on behalf 
of the city was given by Mayor H. J. Winnett. 

Following the address by the mayor was one by Governor J. H. 
Mickey, on behalf of the state. "The way to do the most good in 
this line," said the governor, " is to begin with training the children. 
Train the child in the way he should go and he will never see the 
inside of a prison. The average criminal can trace his wrong-doings 
back to the poor training of his youth. I believe that cards 
and dancing are wrong, and for that reason I refused to give an 
inaugural ball. I had told my children not to do these things because 
they were wrong, and if I had turned against my own teachings 
they would have lost confidence in me and all I have told them." 

JThe governor's address caused a great many comments on acnt 
of its earnest Christian tone and deep interest in all classes 
state work along the lines in which the conference is working, 
tecially did he lay emphasis on the influence of the home in charer 
building. If children were properly trained from their very 
liest years there would be much less danger of the state having 
care for so many helpless and criminal classes. 

The response on behalf of the Conference, which was to have </seg>


            <seg id="p006">
6 

been delivered by Chancellor Andrews, was omitted, as the chancellor 
was out in the state, and was delayed in getting in on account 
of the storm. 

»The president's address was an able one, and well received by the 
ference. It is published in full in this report, and should be read 
every one interested in the management of our state institutions. 

IRev. Marsh moved that it be published in the city papers, which 
done. 

I The afternoon session was opened by John L. Marshall leading 
prayer. This was followed by the appointment of committees, 
committee on nominations consisted of Dr. J. L. Greene, Profeo- 
Pope, Mr. Crawford, C. E. Prevey and Mrs. Z. A. Wilson. The 
on resolutions was composed of Dr. H. 0. Rowlands, F. E. 9ala 
Mrs. Emma C. Johnston. 

The first paper presented at this session was by Dr. J. L. Greene. 
It was very scholarly, and could not fail to carry conviction tnat 
the indeterminate sentence was the only proper and humane way 
to deal with the criminal, both for his own sake and for the protection 
of society. 

Eev. E. A. Fredenhagen presented the subject. "Redemption o( 
Criminal." The subject awakened thought, and a lively discuswas 
participated in. Some of those who entered into the dision 
of the above-mentioned papers were: Dr. H. O. Rowlands, 
J. L. Marsh, Dr. F. S. Stein and Chief-of-Police Hoagland. 

Ilt was the opinion of Rev. Marsh that society was perhaps more 
ponsible than the criminal for the conditions which we are trying 
reform. Dr. Stein thought this would be a dangerous doctrine to 
ih. Children should be taught to respect the law. This would 
far toward preventing crime. 

§To a listener it seemed that both were right. Society should 
h the young to have respect for law. which could be taught in 
home, the schools and all state institutions. 

I A nurse from Chicago was asked to take part in the discussion 
redemption of criminals, and spoke on the subject as related to 
men, saying it was much harder, as society was organized, to help 
se fallen ones than to help men. Mr. Sala, of Omaha, said that 
ras often a fact in his experience that of those who had been brought 
Christ through the efforts of those doing work among prisoners 
jails, especially, many when released went at once to the work 
seeking to convert someone else. 

tDr. Martin, chaplain of the penitentiary, spoke of the object of 
prison association, and of the work they were planning to do. 

LThe afternoon session was brought to a close, with a feeling that it 
been profitable to be there. 

¦ The evening session opened with song, and a prayer by Dr. J. 
Tuttle. 

Judge Lindsey was then introduced, and delivered an address </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
N fc-BR A&amp;K.A CH ARITI ES AND CORRECTIONS 

7 

I must have left an impression, even on the most careless, that 
» was great need to (eel that the boys of the nation, as well as 
ur state, need looking after in an especial manner it we would 
1 a good citizenship to depend on in the next generation. The 
of control by the parents of this generation is responsible tor 
h of the wrong-doing of the children. When a parent fails in 
duty, it becomes the duty of the state to Btep in and train for 
ill lives. Much had been hoped for from Judge Lindsey's lecture, 
the Conference was not disappointed. 

The Conference adjourned to meet at 9 o'clock Friday morning 
Instead of 9:30 as advertised. 

Friday morning's session was called to order oy the president 
Clark. Rev. Quivey led in prayer. 

The subject of City Charities was postponed till another time. 

A communication was read from Chief-of-Police Donahue, of Omaha, 
regretting that he could not be at the Conference. The president 
and several members entered somewhat into the discussion of his 
subject, which was "The Punishment of Husoamls Who Desert Their 
Families." 

Kwas moved and carried that a bill be drawn relating to the 
t, to be presented to the legislature. H. V. Hoagland and John 
were appointed to look after the bill. 

I Rev. L. P. Ludden was next on the program. His subject, "Delent 
Children," was thoroughly discussed. Rev. D. S. Leavitt, 
)maha, was not present, but Rev. Quivey. Rev. Swan, Mrs. Spur, 
and others, entered into the subject with enthusiasm. It was 
general opinion that the state should care especially for those 
iren for whom it is almost impossible to find homes. These are 
crippled and deformed ones. Mrs. Spurlock said it was easy to 
e a child from one to five years of age in a home. From that age 
t becomes more difficult, and the danger of placing a child where 
wanted for the work it may be able to do becomes greater. 

KMr. Sala said that in his work he sought the home rather than 
ting for the home to seek the child. In this way he thought there 
less danger of an undesirable home being recommended. 

Dr. R. C. Moore of Omaha, presented a strong paper on 'The 
Sanatorium Care of Tuberculosis." (See paper on page 39.) 

tThe hour of noon having come, the Conference adjourned to the 
&gt;ital for the insane, where the members of the Conference had 
i invited to luncheon by Dr. Greene. Forty-three persons aced 
the invitation, and took the car at Tenth and M streets. When 
end of the car-line was reached, the teams from the hospital 
; waiting and all were conveyed to that place, where a lunch, 
tily prepared and served in abundance, waited them. After the 
neon, the members repaired to the chapel, where the program for 
afternoon was carried out. </seg>



            <seg id="p008">
I Six young ladies from the institute for the deaf at Omaha, favored 
Conference with two hymns sung in their beautiful and imjn 
language. As they follow their leader, who sings in a sweet 
e the tones they never hear, and yrt which they follow in such 
ect time with rapt expression of countenance, one can but feel 
music is an experience of the soul that has more than one mode 
-ion. 

KDr. Moore, at this point, finished the reading of his paper, which 
interrupted in the forenoon. 

&gt;As the time was so short, at the request of Prof. Prevey it was 
td and seconded that his paper should be omitted from the pro- 
B for the afternoon, but that it be made a part of the minutes of 
meeting and be published in the report. The motion carried. 

KDr. Greene made some remarks on the conduct of the hospital in 
¦ral. and made a statement in regard to the proposed visit to the 
rent parts of the institution. 

Dr. Young followed with an interesting and scientific paper on 
The Care of the Insane." (See page L':;. i 

KProf. Bolton's practical talk was much appreciated and is a part of 
report. 

I The remainder of the session was devoted to the examination 
the institution. The officers and employes taking especial pains 
make the visit pleasant as well as profitable. As there were a 
;e number who had never been through the institution, it must 
e enlarged the knowledge of what the state is doing, in at least 
branch, to care for the dependent ones. 

At the evening session the committee on resolutions reported 
as follows: 

tl. Recognizing the devastation wrought by that dread disease. 
nulosis: that it is contagious, and that it is also curable if 
ly and rightly treated; recognizing also that in some other states 
ial sanitoriums are provided to treat those suffering with the 
isc . we ask the legislature to take measures to investigate the 
tion of providing a tuberculosis sanitorium for tne state of Neka 
by instructing the board of health to consider the question, 
report to ue legislature two years hence. 

2. Resolved. That we commend to the legislature that provision 
k* made for crippled and disabled children where parents or guardians 
are not able to supply shelter and proper care. We urge that the 
doors of that state instituion— the home for the friendless — be immediately 
opened to rece.ve such children until the state provides 
some other sheltering and nurturing protection for this helpless and 
pitiable class of our population. 

Rt solved. That we commend to the legislature that a law be 
•ted that shall in some way restrict the license and lawlessness 
unfaithful husbands and wives, who abandon their companions </seg>



            <seg id="p009">
and helpless children, or fail to support them in the measure of their 

ability and these become pitiable charges on the communities wh 

they live, besides undergoing untold suffering, all on account of tr 

dissipation or depravity of the husband and father, or wife and mother. 

who have cruelly deserted their homes. We recommend that 

desertion tie made a felony ar.d punished accordingly with adequate 

penalties. Moreover, that a system be derlacd bj which such hus 

bands may be paroled and be comp&lt; 

lied to labor for the support of 

their fa 

We call the a 

in of the honorable legislators 

t 

to a law in the state of Ohio, whit 

h compels unfaithful parents to 

rly. me Onio law is proving an 

reti 

mes prop* 

ffective deterrent against this cowardly and cruel evil. (See last pt 

4. Resolved. That we commend to the legislature that a law be 

enacted that any officer, or employe of a hospital for the insane, or 

jf a home or asylum for the helpless, who shall strike or commit 

physical assault, or intentionally injure a ward or patient, shall be 

with felony, and if proven guilty, shall be punished accord- 


Whereas, We. the members of the Nebraska Conference of 

Charities and Corrections, have been 

favored with an address by his 


Gov. J. H. Mickey, of such 

a practical and Christian nature; 

Therefore, be it. Resolved. That we 

most heartily thank him for the 

practical suggestions given us and tr 

¦u we assure him of earnest sup 

al and dependent classes in the 

The members and delegates to the Conference beg to expre 

their appreciation to the good people of Lincoln for their generous en 

tertainment during the sessions of the Conference. Especially do 

they realize their obligations to Dr. Greene, superintendent of the 

r the interesting and instructive visit they were permitted 


to make to that institution. They bear witness to the efficiency and ex- 

ncy of the management therein, and the intelligent and effective 

Kngements for the care and tn 
the state on the humanenes: 

atment of the sufferers. We felici- 

and protection bestowed on those 

who are unfortunate and helpless ,and find a home in this nob 

hospital. 

Kinne's address on the management of state institutions 

proved what all had expected it would, the discussion of the subject 

¦ one who understands all about it. (See paper on page 
Chancellor Andrews had the closing words of the Conference and 

xplained that his not appearing on the program at its first session 

was caused by a broken engine. He warmly commended the addres: 

of Judge Kinne. He also emphasized the importance of the work 

of the Conference of Charities and Corrections; — They help to arouse 

the public sentiment in the care of the unfortunRte. The school for 

the deaf was especially mentioned, and their work commended. This 

port in the betterment of the rrimin </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 


was especially brought out by the presence of the girls throughout 
the day. Much credit and the thanks of the Conference were due to 
Prof. Pope, of St. Louis, who had been one of their instructors, but 
is now working in the interests of the blind and deaf by preparing an 
exhibition of the work and the methods by which they are taught, to 
be demonstrated at the St. Louis exposition. There will be students 
there from all parts of the United States, but it is expected that Nebraska 
will lead them all in the work shown. Prof. Pope kindly 
explained his work by wax figures and photographs. 

The officers for the next Conference are as follows 

H. V. Hoagland, President. 

Mrs. Zara Wilson, Vice-President. 

John Davis, Secretary. 

C. E. Prevey, Treasurer. 

Emma C. Johnston, Enrolling Clerl 

E. B. Andrews, A. W. Clark and J. H. Mickey. Executive Com 

mitte 

Conference adjourned to meet in Lincoln the first week in Fel 
mary. 1M4. JOHN DAVIS. 

Secretary. </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
11 

NEBRASKA CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS 

PRESIDENTS ADDRESS. 

REV. A. W. CLARK. 

' The Management of State Institutions.' 

Be state has very properly undertaken the care of the destitute 
epileptics, idiots, feeble-minded, crippled and dependent childlso 
to do reformatory work for the delinquent and criminal 
and to assist the old soldier as well as the destitute blind 
af. The state has no higher duty and responsibility than this, 
under obligation also to protect her citizens against the evils 
imingling with many of these elan 

I The management of state institutions has engaged the thoughtful 
ention of the best statesmen, scholars and philanthropists ever 
re the first State Board of Charities was established in Massachuts 
in 1863. The discussion has lasted thirty years. On one side 
those who advocate a State Board of Charities with advisory and 
lervisory powers to co-operate with local boards for the various inutions. 
On the other side are those who advocate a Central Board 
Control with full executive authority of management, thus doing 
ay with local boards. I can not bring to you anything new in this 
L-ussion. Neither is it my purpose to consider the general argunts 
on one side or the other. I simply propose in the first place 
mention some things which are especially needed in Nebraska, and 
the second place to show what kind of a board, in my judgment, 
1 meet these necessities. 

1. NEBRASKA'S NEEDS. 

I You may not be aware of the anomalous condition of things ia 
raska. The situation is peculiar and differs from all other states. 
t of the other states have local boards of trustees for the various 
; institutions. We have no such boards in Nebraska, unless we 
e an exception of the two educational institutions for the blind, 
the deaf and dumb. For both these institutions there is a small 
¦d of three members, one residing at Nebraska City, one at Omaha, 
the other at Papillion. Two other institutions have advisory 
mittees of women, but no local boards. Kansas, Iowa, Wisconsin, 
nesota, Rhode Island and a few other states, are without these 
1 boards, but in place of them they have strong central boards of 
rol, with full executive power of management. Here is a notable 
iliarity in our situation. Nebraska does not have local boards, 
is without a central board of control in the proper sense of that </seg>


            <seg id="p012">
Article V. mk Mil 19. of the Constitution of Nebraska, reads: 
"Tlic commissioner of public lands and buildings, the secretary of 

lary of treasury and attorney general shall form a board 
which shall have general supervision and control of all buildings, 
grounds, and lands of the state, the state prison, asylums and all 
other institutions thereof, except those for educational purposes." 
This would scorn to be a board of control, but these men have other 
duties and do not have time to give necessary consideration to financial 
and social problems involved with the state institutions. It was 
nearly ten years ago when some of these state officials first appealed 
to me and to others to use personal influence to bring about a change 
in our system, for the reason that it was impossible for them to protect 
the tax-payers against the dangers of financial losses and to protect 
ihe inmates of institutions against the dangers of unnecessary 
suffering and abuse. If you question these men today they will tell 
you that their regular duties as state officers are such as to demand 
their whole time. They are also members of several other state 
boards and it is an imposition upon them to ask them to do what is 
impossible. Nebraska made a long step in the right direction when 
the advisory Board of State Charities was created two years ago, but 
additional legislation is required. Having stated briefly the situation 
allow me to mention some specfic needs of our state. 

PUBLICITY 

1. The people of Nebraska need information concerning the 
state institutions. Not having local boards and not having a State 
Board of Charities until two years ago, the people have been out 
of touch with these institutions. Since their relatives and friends are 
in them the people have a right to know of their conditions, management, 
etc. It is necessary that they should know in order to progress 
in the direction of properly handling the inmates. Legislation 
can not go in advance of enlightened public opinion and with our 
Nebraska conditions as they have been in the past, the people could 
not be informed, and therefore progress in legislation, in economy and 
in improving conditions has been very slow. 

POLITICAL CORRUPTION 

2. Our state institutions have been in politics from the beginning. 
Politicians without natural or acquired fitness have many times become 
superintendents of state institutions and have squandered the 
people's money and sunk the inmates to lower levels by neglect and 
incomi etency. The anomalous situation in Nebraska makes it impossible 
to take the state institutions out of politics and impossible to 
avoid the dangers of political corruption when the repeated changes in 
administration come. In many of the states, and also in England, requirement 
is made that a man shall have special training, careful 
Ftudy and experience in filling lower positions in a public institution </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
WASTE OF PIBLIC FUNDS. 

3. In addition to the money squandered by politicians who from 
time to time have become superintendents of state institutions for 
which they were unfit, still larger sums of money have been lost to the 
state in purchasing supplies. Nebraska has paid out from fifty to a 
hundred thousand dollars annually for ten years more than was necessary. 
This is a waste of public funds. Large quantities of goods have 
been purchased of the local merchants where the various institutions 
are situated. By going into the open market the state can save at 
least 33 per cent upon these purchases. Contracts have recently been 
let to the lowest bidders. Local freight has been charged on all these 
purchases and commissions of the merchants and jobbers have also 
been added, making it necessary for the state to pay prices far in 
excess of manufacturers' terms. The board of public lands and buildings 
is of the opinion that by going into the open market there would 
be a saving to the state of at least 25 per cent. When you take into 
account that a half million dollars are expended annually upon our 
state institutions, the matter of purchasing supplies is an important 
economic problem. Other states have been saving $100,000.00 and 
more, according to population, annually by purchasing direct from 
manufacturers. Why should not Nebraska? 

BETTER TREATMENT OF INMATES. 

4. The inmates of most of our state institutions need better care 
and treatment than is possible for them under conditions as they now 
exist. To illustrate my thought and make dear my meaning permit 
me to mention 

a. — The Insane Asylums. — We are behind the age in the care and 
treatment of the insane. The cottage system for the insane has been 
tested and its superior value demonstrated. The large prison-house 
structures for these unfortunates have been condemned, and homelike 
cottages have taken their place. These cottages represent the 
best scientific thoughts and methods of the present day. Dr. Kern, 

superintendent of the Hastings Asylum, and myself visited the Hospital 
for the Insane at Toledo, Ohio, last spring, and found a welltned 
village of 1.700 insane people. The superintendent. Dr. Tobey, 
is at the head of this well-regulated community, told us he found 
treatment of the insane to be largely a sociological problem and 
so much a medical one. The beautiful cottages are free from iron 

and after showing special adaptability for the work h&gt; eligi- 

ble to the position of superintendent. Governor Yatfs. in his 

message to the Illinois legislature, referring to former disgraceful con- 

ditions of their state institutions, brought about by the "spoils sys- 
tem," recommended that the "merit system" be compelled by law. 
This is what is needed in Nebraska; a system that will take the state 

institutions out of politics. </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 


bars and the inmates — except the disturbed classes, which are less 
than 10 per cent of the entire population — are given freedom to go 
and come. We found many of them in the parks about artificial lakes 
and places of amusement, enjoying themselves. Others were found 
at work upon the farm, in the garden and in other kinds of labor, and 
we were informed that they were paid wages according to earning 
capacity. The village chapel, amusement hall, reading room, library. 
etc., are near the center of this large group of cottages. A recent 
author announced as his subject, "The Restraining Influences of Liberty." 
This subjfct is illustrated at Toledo. The effects of such surroundings 
and such methods of treatment are marvelous in the number 
of patients restored to health. In Nebraska we are now considering 
the problem of rebuilding the Hospital for Insane at Norfolk, 
which was recently destroyed by fire. We know the time will soon 
come when the asylums at Lincoln and Hastings must be enlarged, 
and I appeal to the members of this conference to use your influence 
to secure the introduction of the cottage system at the earliest date 
possible. I beg of you also to use your influence in favor of a classification 
of inmates that will remove epileptics from the other patients. 

b.— The Penitentiary.— Important changes in the administration of 
the penitentiary are greatly needed. Some of you may not realize the 
conditions prevailing in that institution, which tend to harden the 
criminals and to make young men confirmed criminals. I refer to the 
contract system. The contract system in the penitentiary eliminates 
all thought and effort in the direction of reformatory work and simply 
emphasizes the making of money for the state. Some have advocated 
that the penitentiary could be made self-supporting. If the handling 
of prisoners is nothing more than an economic problem, then the contract 
system is a good one. All that the state has to do is to sell the 
prisoners as slaves to the highest contract bidder and then help him 
apply the lash and thumb-screw. The penologists of this country and 
of the world are agreed that this contract system should be forever 
abolished, and that the state itself should have immediate control and 
management of all prison labor. It is not suggested that prison labor 
should be done away with. This cry of free labor against prison labor 
is without foundation. Prison labor has come to stay, because it is 
necessary, not only economically, but what is of far more importance. 
It is necessary to reformatory work. I do not advocate that our penitentiary 
should be changed at once into an Elmira reformatory, but 
something in that direction should be done by changing present conditions. 
Most of our prisoners are young men and 79 per cent of them 
saved to good citizenship by adopting right methods of treatment. 
The state owes this as a duty to her citizens. 

e. — Home for the Friendless.— This institution is so constituted 
that it scarcely touches the problems of child dependency. It has not 
been the fault of the management nor the superintendents, that so </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
N fc*Urt AbK.A CHAKIII t*S AN I) C UKRt*LXION S 

15 

little has been accomplished in the past, but the home is without official 
touch with county judges and county commissioners and other 
agencies throughout the state in order to do efficient work. It Is 
largely unknown to them and to the people of the state generally. In 
the nature of its organization it has been little more than a local 
boarding school for children. The leading private societies of the 
state have handled and procured the adoption of more than four times 
as many children annually, at less than half the annual cost of the 
home. The placing out system, which is upon a scientific basis in 
most of the states and which has engaged the best thought of philanthropists 
and experts for years, is little known in the work of the 
home. No attempt has been made to study social conditions and to 
co-operate with existing authority for the enforcement of law relating 
to compulsory education, child labor and child dependency. The 
greatest work of an institution of this kind is to prevent children from 
becoming public charges. It is also important to rescue children from 
cruel treatment and vicious and immoral surroundings, by process of 
law. which the home does not undertake to do. The only solution of 
this matter as it seems to me is to pass the bill now before the legislature, 
to abolish the Home for the Friendless and in its place create a 
State Parental School upon a broad scientific basis, to do efficient work 
in every county in Nebraska. 

Radical changes are needed in some of the other state institutions 
and great improvements are possible, but time is not allotted me to 
mention them in this connection, neither is there time to mention the 
bright and encouraging features of work in Nebraska, which are 

II. WHAT WILL MEET THE NEEDS OF OUR STATE? 

Having mentioned some of Nebraska's needs, the question remains 
what kind of a system of management or state board is required to 
meet these- necessities. Governor Savage recommended to the present 
legislature the abolishment of our State Board of Charities and that 
the work of this board be referred to churches and people who are 
charitably inclined. In this is shown that he did not understand the 
purposes and functions of a State Board of Public Charities. The 
nature of the work' renders what he recommended impossible. He also 
recommended that a board of control be established, but did not 
recommend that the work of the State Board of Charities be trans{d 
to such board of control. All leading states men and philanpists 
throughout the country are agreed that state boards are 
ssary for the good of the state institution.-; and most of the 
s have them. The only difficult question remaining not yet dei 
is whether there should be a strong State Board o; Public Chariof 
non-paid members with simply advisory a il supervisory 
ers, or a small board of control, of salaried men, with full execupower 
of control and management. 

The history of state boards for thirty years past indicates a </seg>


            <seg id="p016">
endency in legislation to strengthen these boards, and from time to 

tin 

ommit executive powers to them. This has been especially 

rue of Massachusetts. New York, Pennsylvania. Illinois. Michigan, 
ml Wisconsin. The Massachusetts board is now said to be one of the 

ist important branches of the state government. New York ha 

three boards, one on lunacy, one on prisons, and one for the oth 

state institutions. Wisconsin in 1881 established a board of control 

and iiad also a State Board of Public Charities. The two boards 

worked together for nearly ten years. This was found unsatisfactory 

and now Wisconsin has only one board, the lioard of control. Some of 

the leaders of the National Conference of Charities and Corrections, 
however, believe in two boards and are of the opinion that the states 

will yet adopt that plan. A board of control is important on the eco- 

nomic side, to look after purchasing supplies., financial details and the 

business end of these great departments of the state's work, but there 

is danger of such a board getting under political control as the history 

in Wisconsin, and especially in Kansas, shows. In Iowa the board of 

control is composed of excellent men and has done a magnificent work 

for the state. The first year of its existence it saved the state over 
fliNi.iKKi.iHi and provided better supplies and better service for the inmates 
of all the institutions. I do not believe, however, that a small 

paid board of control like this is in close touch with the people, like a 

State Board of Charities and local boards of trustees, and cannot. 

therefore, do as much to enlighten and influence public opinion. 

Neither do I believe that a small board of control is in a position to 

study the social conditions of the community, to determine the couses 
of poverty and distress, and to suggest remedies in the way of prevention. 
A State Board of Public Charities does this and we know that 
such work has great economic as well as social value. To illustrate 

this, Amos W. Butler, of Indiana, made the following statement at the 
Detroit National Conference of Charities last spring: "Six years ago," 
he said, "the annual cost of official outdoor relief and medical assis- 

tance in Indiana was $630,000.00. As a result of study of conditions 

the Board of State Charities recommended a change in the law. One 
law after another bearing on the administration of outdoor relief 
was successively passed to secure by progressive stages the desired results. 
After six years the amount given was reduced to $210,000.00 a 
year, and the testimony of all was that the poor were never so well 
cared tor as they were under the new laws. Many were fearful that 
the poor asylum population would increase as a consequence. The 
result is that each year the number of inmates has been continually 
decreasing in the poor asylums of the state. The proportionate reduction 
of poor asylum inmates in ten years has been about seven hundred. 
In other words, had we as many persons in the poor asylums in 
proportion to the population' as ten years ago we should be supporting 

;even hundred more than we are at a cost of $7i&gt;."imi.(mi. So the net 

results of the study of conditions and the enactment of laws to meet </seg>


            <seg id="p017">
17 

Ei conditions, together with proper supervision, have resulted in an 
lal reduction of about ISOO.OeO-M just in this one phase of public 
iti&lt;s. The reduction in pauperism and misery no one can meas- 

ure." This is what advisory boards do. What Mr. Butler says of 

Indiana is true also of other states. Rather than put everything per- 

taining to the charities and corrections of the state into the hands of 

three men as a board of control. I think it would be better to form 
lo&lt;-al boards of trustees for the various institutions and then 

strengthen the present State Board of Charities. There are objections 

to this plan as conditions now exist in our state, and I therefore, in 

view of our peculiar situation and in view of the special needs ¦ 

braska. would recommend the union of the two systems of a 

Board of Public Charities anil board of control in one board. This 
cannot be done without an amendement to the constitution, which we 

hope will soon be made possible by the legislature passing a bill call 

r.g a constitutional convention. The kind of state board which I have 

suggested should be composed of nine members, three of whom shall 

»paid officers of the board and who shall perform the functiens and 
ies of a board of control. Six of the members shall be non-paid 

advisory members who shall be the representatives of the people and 

thus keep the public in close touch with the state institutions. In this 
way. I believe, we would gain the advantages of both boards. The 

tk of visitation, inspection, advising, supervision, etc., done by the 
non-paid members would be given without bias to the public. The 

results of their study of social conditions and needs would enlighten 

public sentiment. The people would be constantly informed as to the 

Ernal affairs of the institutions and the non-paid members would 
e as a check on the paid officials. The paid members would handle 
economic problems, would purchase supplies, look after improvets 
of buildings and grounds and give attention to financial details. 

They would do all this in conference with the non-paid members. 

Thus it seems to me that the broad problems relative to the good of 

the wards of the state, the social conditions and problems of poverty 

and prevention throughout our commonwealth would have due consideration, 
and the dangers attending a small board of control would 

be avert* (1. I would not recommend the above system for other states 
of the Union, but conditions being what they are in Nebraska, I am led 

The Redemption of the Criminal 

Addrcn by Rev. Edw. A. Fredcnhig. 

The earlier prison associations were founded with a view to giving 
aid to the prisoner on the expiration of his sentence. "Prison gate 
work" was the common term. To see that the men coming forth to 
begin life anew had sufficient clothing and money to start again was 
their chief aim. This has gradually developed until the society labor- 

to the con&lt;lusions above stattd </seg>


            <seg id="p018">
REPORT OF SEVENTH ANNUAL MEETING 

ng for the redemption of the criminal seeks also to mold environment 
urrounding the prisoner, the law which sentences him. and even 

reaches back into the sources from which crime springs. Time has 
softened the terms used until the word "ex-convict" has disappeared 
from the vocabulary of the workers and newer societies are avoiding 
the word "prison" in their choice of names for their movements. It is 
also recognized that to redeem the individual criminal it is necessary 

to reclaim not only the man and his environment, but also to fashion 
his heredity as well. As much of the crime grows out of dependency. 
iso must be taken into account. The Society for the Friendless 
endeavors to cover the whole field of crime and its sources, lest disregard 
of one portion open the way to failure in another. Consequently 
the work is divided into departments which, though distinct, 
are closely related. I will Fpeak of them in order, as this is the best 
way to treat the subject assigned me. 

I The ex-prisoner, upon his release, needs immfdiate care. A man 
&lt;1 on the steps of a state prison, looked abroad over the lanu 

re down and cried like a child. When asked why he cried he sa 
ave not a friend in all this world. I don't know where to go n 

what to do." This man needed, above all else, a friend: one who 
would receive him. care for him and stand true to him until he 
If-support, The Society for the Friendless is this "first 
friend." In the states where it operates no man is left friendless. If. 

»is sometimes the case, employment cannot immediately be found, 
is cared for in the temporary home until such time as he is either 
Hi for employment or the employment is secured for him. Many of 
men are unfitted to battle with the world. Through long terms 

fhave lost their touch with mer 
and utterly discouraged. This 
pen the prison and the people, 
is the residence of the general 

; or they may be sick, or simply 
necessitates an intermediate place 
This is called the temporary home 
superintendent. The homes of the 
devoted to this work. 

iperintendents are in part 

Ilt is well known that the envir 
conducive to reform. This was 
ly fitted morally and spiritually 

jnment of most of our prisons is 
so evident and the men were so 
for upright lives that the society 

Ier'cl the prisons and organized leagues. These are under the care 
the chaplain, while the superintendent of the society acts as evanist. 
The men are won to Christ and nurtured up in Him. Those 
o do not enter the league feel its influence, for it does for the popuion 
of the prison what the church does for the community outside. 
t- percentage of the prisoners in the leagues is as large as that of 
citizens in the church. Considering the class of men whom we 
essarily find within the prison walls, the results are as satisfactory 

as in the churches. The promoters of the league claim that the religious 
motive is one of the strongest with which to persuade the men </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
NEBRASKA CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS 

19 

to bear upon as large a number of the prisoners as possible and unite 
it with other reformatory forces. The results have justified the movement. 


It is well known that in the prisons where the reformatory system 
prevails a very much larger number of men are reclaimed than in the 
older ones where punishment is the ruling principle of government. 
The best reformatories report about 80 per cent of their men reformed. 
The worst of the older prisons are compelled to admit that "5 per cent 
of their men return to crime. In view of this it is wise, both economically 
and morally, to secure, as far as possible, reform in criminal 
law and prison management. In one state the lockstep has been abolished 
and military double file has been substituted. Grades are soon 
to take the place of the indiscriminate treatment. Laws establishing 
the indeterminate sentence and parole and the suspended sentence are 
passing the legislature and movements to gradually recast the whole 
criminal code are under way. In other states such legislation is being 
encouraged and the people as a whole, through the field superintendents, 
are being educated to demand needed reforms and. above all, 
civil service. 

An inductive study of the inmates of prisons shows that only about 
ten per cent are incorrigible. Many more of these will return to crim&lt;&gt;. 
hot it does not follow that they need to. Ninety per cent of crime is 
environmental ir. its sources. It comes through the failuie of the 
fundamental instill tions of society — the home, the neighborhood, the 
ch'irch. the f&lt; hcol — to develop the individual so that he will Maintain 
himself above the crime-line. Ninety per cent of our prisoners are 
morally, iultlieci-.ially. socially and industrially below normal. Thit 
is. they come frra either poor homes or are homeless, from ba'i nf &gt;gh- 
Lorhooris. are not educated, have learned no occupation or skilloi 
trade, and telonp to the ignorant, vicious, thriftless, and wandering 
&lt; lasses. There are several mistaken ideas concerning criminals. One 

Itliat they are "smart." As a rule they are very ignorant, as any 
r who handles them will tell you. In one reformatory of three 
ndred inmates, ranging from sixteen to thirty years, eight per cent 
re illiterate, forty per cent were in the first grade, twenty per cent 
the second grade, twenty per cent in the third grade. Of the relining 
twelve per cent only three were above the fifth grade, and 
ly one had completed the high school. A leading official, who has 
•ved twenty years in one of our largest penitentiaries, said to me 
it he had found criminals very ignorant as a class. 

Another mistaken idea is that they are mostly born criminals. This 
is true of only a very small percentage. As a class they are more weak 
than mean, and mean because of weakness . In maintaining themselves in 
the struggle for life they have resorted to expedients to satisfy those desiras 
common to us all. Environment furnishes most of them. One 
of the greatest factors is the liquor traffic. From sixty per cent in </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
REPORT OF SEVENTH ANNUAL .MEETING 

prohibition states (part of these prosecutions for liquor selling) to 
ninety per cent in license states confess to drink as the determining 
factor. Child saving societies tell us that over fifty per cent of homeless 
children in prohibition, and about seventy per cent in license 
states, are made so through drink. The drink cursed homes furnish 
many of our child criminals. A neighborhood corrupted by the saloon 
furnishes many juvenile offenders. The crowded tenement districts. 
through which the red line of rum can be so clearly traced are, to a 
large extent, below the crime line. The country villages where the 
saloon and the cigarette hold sway are fields where crime is sporadic 
M of the failure of the vital forces of society to develop its members 
above the crime-line. Where the Sunday school fails to hold the 
and the community is not sufficiently awake to conditions to substitute 
something else, such as the boys' club, the Y. M. C. A., or 
kindred movements, crime breeds. Many of the worst toughs in the 
were tired in country villages. Where the Sunday school grip 
upon the boy is slight the same may be said of the day school. The 
boyish brain, poisoned by tobacco and drink, is a poor subject for the 
teac her. Some communities, or parts of communities, are entirely below 
the crime-line. From these we may expect many criminals until 
ave re-established their fundamental institutions, the home, the 
i hurch and school, and have driven out the dens of vice. The Society 
for the Friendless seeks to redeem these communities through its 
bureau of personal service. This means that pure and cultured men 
and women, for Chrisfs sake, establish their homes in these centers 
in order to re-establish these institutions which ha-ve been broken 
down. They teach the peopde how to do for themselves what the 
community above the crime line do for themselves. They establish 
social settlements, with classes in cooking, sewing, music and art, 
Eall lines of training which prevail in better communities. They 
the streets and the houses, enforce the law, furnish wholesome 
iements and by personal contact advise and lead the people to 
r things. 

In the department of preventive law, efforts are made to establish 
the juvenile court, which has done more to save juvenile delinquents 
than any other known institution. In cities better tenement house 
management is secured and city ordinances are so shaped as to improve 
the moral and environmental conditions of the lowly poor. 
clubs and similar movements as substitutes for the saloon are 
encouraged and fostered. The inductive study of the sources of crime 
continues and wherever these are found effort is made to stop them. 

In closing, permit me to state that the Society for the Friendless 
movement takes the point of view of the church missionary society, 
reinforced by all the findings of scientific charity. We believe in helping 
the whole man, body, soul, and spirit, and in redeeming the man 
below the crime-line industrially, socially, intellectually, and spiritu- </seg>


            <seg id="p021">
21 

ally. We encourage and strengthen all those fundamental institutions 
on which society is based. To the ex-prisoner we give aid; to the 
dependent personal help to self-help. We co-operate with every existing 
agency for the betterment of men and conflict with none which 
does constructive work, no matter how divergent our views may be. 
We believe the time for division is past; that the war of creeds should 
end; that men should stand shoulder to shoulder for each other's 
help; that those who are strong should bear the infirmities of the 
weak ; that all who have power should exercise it for the redemption 
of those less fortunate than themselves. Beginning with the problem 
of crime as we find it expressed in the prison, we trace it out to its 
sources, endeavoring to make an ounce of prevention prove better than 
many pounds of cure. We now operate in three states, having eleven 
workers. Our ranks are rapidly" increasing. Following in the steps 
of Him who said: "The Son of Man came not to be ministered unto, 
but to minister and give His life a ransom for many." we endeavor 

to do as He did — go about doing good. 

" Punishment of Husbands Who Desert Families." 

Ltmrfrom Chief J. J. Donah 

Omaha. Neb.. February 4. IMt. 

Rev. A. W. Clark. President Nebraska State Conference of Charities 

and Corrections. Lincoln. Neb 

My Dear Mr. Clark — Owing to the press of important business. I 
find it will be impossible for me to attend the annual meeting of the 
Nebraska State Conference of Charities and Corrections and discuss 
the punishment of husbands who abandon their families, which I very 
much regret. I wish to state, however, that during my term as chief 
of police the desertion by husbands of their families has given me a 
great deal of annoyance, and in several cases has appealed very much 
to my sympathy. At the present time there are several pitiable cases 
where husbands have abandoned their wives, leaving on an average 
from two to six children depending entirely upon a poor, delicate 
woman for suppport. and in several cases boys from nine to twelve 
years of age have been taken from school and placed on the streets 
to sell papers or as messenger boys, and girls of the same age hare 
been forced to take positions as cash girls in our stores. This necessarily 
deprives both of the opportunity of securing an education. I 
have, therefore, requested some of our representatives from Douglas 
county to draft a bill to reach this class of heartless men with the 
hopes that it will have a tendency to discourage the growing practice </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 


of abandoning families and leaving them at the mercy of the citizens 
of the city, county or state. I have been informed that a bill looking 
to this end has been drafted, and I should like to have the co-operation 
of the Nebraska State Conference of Charities and Corrections in seeing 
that it becomes a law. A few cases have come under my notice 
where wives have deserted their husbands and children, but they are 
so rare I have not felt it important to include women in this law. 
However, it might be well to have the law apply to both husband and 
wife, especially where the wife deserts children. 

Again regretting thaf I am unable to be with you, and with kindest 
regards and best wishes for the success of your meeting. I remain, 

Yours respectfully. 

J. J. DONAHUE. 

Chief of Police. 

' Placing Out Children 

The advantage of placing children in good homes has long since 
become a settled fact, and anyone who has taken the trouble to post 
themselves either by reading or in attendance at the Wational Conference 
of Charities and Corrections must be convinced that the concensusof opinion 
at the present time, both in the United States and Canada and in many 
foreign countries, is to place children in homes rather than in an institution. 
But the very important question is how to secure good homes, 
which is the vital and undelieing principle of all child-placing societies. 
I received a letter from Dr. Prevey requesting me to write an 
artii le on the placing out of cMldren, for he was convinced that there 
was very much poor work being done in that line. Basing my opinion 
on nearly fourteen years of experience. I am compelled to say that 
very many children are placed in poor homes by societies and institutions 
simply because they do not have the proper method of doing the 
work, and not because they do not desire or intend to place the children 
in good homes. • 

The old method of placing out children, which is known as the 
citizens' recommendation, is not satisfactory and is very unsafe, and 
in many cases does an injustice to children by placing them in very 
poor homes. This comes very largely from the fact that the average 
petition as presented is very weak; and second, until individuals who 
sign the citizens' recommendation are protected in some way, you 
cannot get at the true conditions' of the home, for no one is very 
anxious to make enemies or lose customers, which would be the case 
if they were informed that their home was not the proper home for a 
child. And giving references is no better, so far as this work is con- 

Remarks by Rev. E. P. Quivey. </seg>


            <seg id="p023">
23 

cerned, from the fact that no one would give a reference unless they 
were very certain that they would be recommended. — in many cases 
have had a talk with them before giving the name as a reference, — 
and in my mind such recommendations have no value. When we consider 
how many people wish to take children just for the benefit they 
will be to them, we can realize the importance of having some method 
to secure good homes. I remember, in Iowa, receiving a very pathetic 
letter from a gentleman in that state asking for a boy. and assuring 
us of his interest and sympathy with homeless children, which ended 
by saying: "Send us a boy large enough to plow." I do not know as 
to whether he ever got the plowing done or not, but I do know that he 
did not get the boy from our society. Many cases of a like nature 
might be given to show the importance of having the correct method 
of securing good homes and with a well organized, well instructed local 
board, who are protected and in a condition to render a just opinion 
of any home making application for children, there is little danger of 
making a mistake. 

"The Hospital Idea in the Treatment of the Insane." 

Addrea by Dr. G. A. Young 

In making these remarks, on account of the short time at my disposal, 
nothing more can be attempted than a mere outline of the sub- 

* 

I need but briefly call your attention to the exceptional progress 
that has taken place in the treatment for the insane during the past 
twenty-five to fifty years. Hair mattresses and white sheets and the 
watchful care of the uniformed nurse have replaced the rags, straw 
heaps, clanging chains and brutal guards of fifty and even twenty-five 
years ago. Spotlessly clean infirmaries in well-equipped sanitary hospitals 
have taken the place of the filthy rooms which were constant 
breeding places of typhoid and spotted fever. The change has been 
complete. The one condition the very antithesis of the other. 

Can we say that the people of today are more Christianlike. more 
benevolent, than they were fifty years ago? Not at all. The evils of 
those times, remedied now. arose as many, if not all other, do — from 
ignorance. Ignorance as to the nature of insanity, around which has 
been wrapped the darkness of mystery and superstition, befogging the 
perceptions of those" who came into close contact with it and stultifying 
the efforts of those who would see aright. 

We can trace the advent of better conditions to the gradual recognition 
of the main principle of the treatment of insanity, to-wit: that 
insanity is a physical disease, dependent upon physical causes, and 
amenable to treatment by what, in a broad sense, may be termed </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 


Eysical measures. Upon the full recognition of this principle deids 
the present treatment of insanity, and also what is more imporlt. 
the prophylaxis of insanity. 

is this conception tnat I wish to present to your attention. Inity 
is a physical disease, and the victim of it deserving of all the 

careful attention that an appendicitis patient would receive. 1 
conception that has an accepted place in the minds of the world"s foremost 
alienists, but one that the general public far from realizes. The 
c\iiy-day person considers a disease of the mind, so-called, as being 
wholly in a different category from the typhoid fever or pneumonia, 
but it is not. They should be considered side by side. 

When we contemplate the vast complexity of our intricate nn 
i. and glance over the marvelous progress of the past ten 
n our knowledge of its finer anatomy and physiology, which has 
&gt;ened up undreamed of vistas of thought to the student of mental 
It we can no longer afford to ignore even the influence which a 
ight lesion of a single nerve terminal in a remote part of the body 
ay have upon our consciousness. The incalculable number of nerve 
irrents which pass, in health, entirely unknown to the individual, to 
nd between the greater and lesser nerve centers and various parts of 
le body; the immense amount of vital processes dependent upon 
erve stimulus, constantly taking place without obtruding themver 
the threshold of consciousness, have but of late been fully appreated. 
We live our lives, knowing but very little of ourselves. Not a 
hought passes through our minds but what, side by side, in proportion 
o its intensity, a physical process occurs. A nerve impulse has left 
he brain or cord and a set of vessels have been dilated and the supply 
f blood changed; certain cells have been ordered to proceed more 
ctively with their metabolism, secretion here is accelerated, there 
iminished; the heart beats more rapidly or slowly; not a cell in the 
lody but what is liable to undergo a change, coincidentally with the 
passing of some mental state. And all this without our being aware 
[ it. True enough, we possess a certain amount of what may be 
ailed organic sensation, a sense of well being, but how ill defined, how 
ague it is. Pawlow, a Russian physiologist, has, of late, given to the 
orld^n instance of just such an activity. He has found that the sight 
f a certain class of food, or even the thought of it, will cause an outow 
into the digestive canal of the precise kind of digestive agent 
-ary for its absorption, and that no other kind is secreted. 
Other physiologists have come to doubt, and upon good grounds, 
hether the brain is the sole throne of independent, intelligent action, 
nd give to the spinal cord, and even lesser centers, a certain amount 
f initiative power. The most recent advances in the pathology of insanity 
find nerve lesions, in parts, outside of the brain and cord, which 
ndoubtedly have a definite causative relation to the mental sympoms 
present. We are truly composite in our nature. The different </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
N EjoKASivA CHARITIE 

AND CORRECTIONS 

functional symptoms of our econ' 
mutually dependent. Disease of 01 
ment of the others. The problem 
physique is a very broad one and in 
the province of sociology. The crim 
which is linked very closely with that 
iife is indisseverably connected in it 

)my are intimately blended and 

e is followed closely by derangeof 
mental reflex from a diseased 
volves many a difficult question in 
inal is but one aspect of the problem, 
of the insane. The mind in normal 

manifestations with the pi 

es I have tried to emphasize the 
from a physical standpoint. Fun 
psychology, chemistry, into the 
hysiology and anatomy may 

ture advance in scientific research 

mor 

ate myste 

finer 

li i pt. but at present 

prov 

one. Without it. progress could n&lt; 
Now that we have defined this 
a way that will bring forth the bes 

principle, how shall we apply it in 
t results to those most concerned — 

the insane, both those with us ¦ 
herittd predisposition will sooner ( 
come inmates of this or other ini 

w. and those who with their ii 
later, under the stress of life. b. 

titu 

tin the following remarks I s 
lical aspect, leaving alone the ; 
The hospital should, primarily 
lace for custodial care. It sh 
» of scientific research into th( 
wealth of chemical material, h 
(i. nt the most distressing affli&lt; 
human family. 

shall confine myself strictly to the 
administrative department. 

be a place of healing; secondarily, 
juld also be employed for the purtrue 
nature of mental disease, and 

herto wasted, serve to render lew 

that can befall any member of 

t 

Let us take up these th 

tments. consecutively 

¦ 

Considering the institution ai 

imarily an hospital, the patient. 

in all general hospitals, when received, is subjected to a thorough 

»sical examination and the result is that he or she is either sent to 
infirmary ward, in case the physical symptoms are those of an acute 

illnesb. or else is placed upon what may be called an observation ward 

when evidences of disease are not of a character that need immediat 

medical attention. Violent and noisy cases are the ones that, in my 

opinion, need, more than any others, the special care of an infirmary 

the closest medical attention, and the most watchful and gentle super 

vision possible. For these, a small ward should be set apart, and a 

goodly number of sk 

it nurses in proportion to number of 
ases for whom an adequate cause for 

Eents. employed. They are the 
disease will soonest be found, 
to the acute toxic diseases a 
&gt;ital. 

They present the more striking ana 

ommonly witnessed in the general 

hi violent patient is the on 

most amenable to gentle treatment 

importance of considering insan 

physiology and anatomy ma&gt; 
the hypothesis is a most necessary 
Dt be made. 

:onditions of the body by means of myriads of constantly active nerv 

Blaments, and it in turn confesses by its own pnenomena its subjec- 

tion to the influences which come to it from the body it inhabits. 

In these few scattering sentences I have tried to emshasize th 

ri </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
Misunderstood and treated harshly, he becomes dangerous, understood 
and handled with gentleness, he rapidly becomes quiet and tractable. 
The intelligent nurse is the one that can identify the strings that 
are out of tune and leave them alone, touching those only that respond 
truly, and leaving the others to the care of kindly nature. Our aim 
with the noisy, excitable, sleepless, violent, and physically sick patients 
is to meet the conditions as they come, always gently doing our 
best to sooth the anguished mind, restore sleep to the sleepless, quiet 
to the restless, and strength and health to those who are emaciated, 
feeble or otherwise afflicted with bodily disease. To accomplish this, 
measures from the armamentarium of the skilled physician should be 
taken, drugs, hydrotherapy, massage, electricity, anything that will 
help to bring about the desired end. Once the worst of the storm over, 
they are placed upon the observation ward, and a careful invoicing is 
commenced to determine how much wreckage has been done, what has 
been irretrievably ruined, what damaged and what escaped. Here the 
patients are on a par with those who have primarily been placed upon 
the observation ward. Upon this ward it is that a slow and often 
laborious psychological examination must be made, and to do this the 
confidence of the patient, where possible, must be obtained. The patient 
should be made to feel that he is regarded as a sick man, and cot 
as an outcast or a mental wreck. His surroundings should be such as 
would naturally induce confidence and trust. Oftentimes he has been 
brought to the hospital by deception. He has been lied to, virtually 
trapped, and his distorted imagination, when he finds himself practically 
a prisoner, pictures everyone around him as an enemy, only to 
oe mistrusted and feared. To gain his confidence then is a matter of 
much difliculty, only to be accomplished by infinite patience and care. 
The practice, often employed by our sheriffs., of bringing patients 
here by means of false pretense cannot be too strongly condemned. 
Methods of mechanical restraint, though necessary at rare intervals, 
should be discarded as an unnecessary evil. Once his confidence acquired, 
the physician's task is easier. 

I The psychological examination completed, it remains for us to 
1 it to the physical, compare and analyze the two, and decide as to 
at. can be done to restore the normal mental equilibrium. This, 
ortunately, at the present day, is a task barren of results in a large 
centage of the cases. Improvement may result up to a certain 
nt, but beyond that there is no further advance to a state of health, 
lether certain cells have been destroyed, or well worn association 
hways have been torn up, we cannot now tell; we know too little 
the vital processes of the nerve cell to answer the question. 

I Some things we can do. We can often correct physical condim, 
which, by means of what may be called the mental reflex, have 
disturbed the patient's consciousness as to produce the distorted 
cept, the erring judgment which form the delusion, or the false </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
NEBRASKA CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS 

27 

sense impression which produces 
treatment is the one which prom 
psychiatry advances. 

rh 

hallucination. This method of 
the most hope as the science of 

Iln other cases, by means of 
s influence the patient's stre 

pii 

;gestive conversation, we can at 
of thought. 

mam 

The employment of rational 

inv 

rsation as a therapeutic measure 

I been recently employed with 
hie stimulant in a way that is 
especially useful in such case 
:ia. the faculties not destroy 
I possess the qualifications of 
etect tne irritable, bare places 
Hard them from all irritation 
nature, left alone, will often 

suits. It seems to act as a 

i 

t clear to us except by its results. 

&gt; as have sunk into a state of mental 
¦d. but passive. Also the physician 
a good nurse, and that is to be able 
in the patient's mind, and endeavor 

Rest and quiet is what they need. 
accomplish wonders. 

Mental activity must 

zed in other channels, and here is 
ice another point which seems of the 
&gt;ccupat:on of the insane as a method 

Kp I wish to bring to your not 
est importance. This is the i 

of treatment in those curable, and as a source of happiness, or at least 

content, to those incurable. Where the hands have work to do. the 

mind cannot go far astray. To go into a ward in an insane hospital 
and see able bodied patients sitting idle in their chairs with their hands 
listlessly folded in their laps, to me it seems a veritable crime. I can 
see the melancholiac, wrapped in her ideas of self-abasement, going 

over her delusions again and again, and with each time, the nerve 

pathway of her thoughts is made smoother and more easy to travel 

and the delusion is fixed more firmly; the maniac, who has passed 
through an exhausting seige of excitement, has sunk into a stage of 

inertia, and is passing into a state of incuraki- dementia, because the 

moderate, psychic stimulus which would come from employment, is 

lacking, the homicide, brooding over his fancied wrongs, nurses and 

fosters nis plans of revenge until some harmless patient or unsuspect- 

ing attendant is made a victim. All of these cases would be taken out 
of themselves, and their thoughts directed into more natural channels 

by the manual, or even mental labor which would occupy their time 

during the day and leave them healthily tired by night. These meth 

ods have been tried and found successful. I recollect one authority 
speaking of suicidal patients employed in a carpenter shop with edged 

tools, and three homicides working 
sythes, all forgetful of the morbid 

ide by side in a the hayfleld with 
deas that troubled them in their 

I hours. In this hospital, as far as the facilities allow, this method 
Mowed, and with very good results, but many, for the very lack 
&gt;portunity, are forced to remain idle. 

Eto the management of the chronic, able bodied cases who need 
ial care alone. I think the principle of cottages, open wards, and 
r employment with as much liberty as possible, will be the fii'l </seg>


            <seg id="p028">
Coming to the final consideration, that of the hospital as a station 
for research, I can simply refer your attention to the example of the 
wealthier eastern states, that are placing in their hospitals a trained 
corps of able men, devoted and enthusiastic to their work, and actuated 
solely by a desire for the advancement of knowledge in this 
hitherto most neglected branch of medicine. I^ast summer I had the 
pleasure of a couple of hours' conversation with Dr. Adolf Meyer. 
director of the New York State Pathological Institute, which is devoted 
entirely to the study of insanity. I was shown through the different 
laboratories, then not quite completed. It is there intended to 
make a study of insanity from every scientific point of view. There 
were four distinct laboratories, the chemical, bacteriological, anatomical, 
and psychological, each with its chief, and all acting under the 
direction of Dr. Meyer. While not able to support such a magnificent 
pathological research department as New York, each state should do 
-i. according to its means, to promote in every way the advancement 
of such knowledge as will be a help to those unfortunate intrusted 
to its care. Each hospital of any size should have one of its 
staff a complete pathologist, and an adequate laboratory, for it is only 
l&gt;\ careful work along this line that advance- can be promised. It 
would be well for these laboratories to be organised, and a co-ordinate, 
systematized plan of work be carried out. JJy this means, advance 
would be more rapid and the work more reliable. 

To sum up. briefly, we have considered insanity as a physical 
disease, not a disfase of the brain alone, but an affection of the whole 
organism. Working along the line of this conception, we feel that 
there is more hope of obtaining light as to its nature, causes, and prevention 
than by any other. We believe that the hospital treatment, in 
its most approved methods, to be the ideal treatment. In examining 
the medical management of the hospital, we find three departments, 
the hospital department, the custodial department, and the research 
department, all three equally important. For especial mention, I wish 
to call your attention especially to the hospital employment of the 
Insane. 

Three points seem to me worth bringing before you today. The 
first relates to the lack of a theoretical basis for our practical work 
in the care and treatment of the dependent classes. The people who 
are engaged practically in teaching the blind, the mute, and the feebleminded 
are certainly acting contrary to the general foundations of </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
NEBRASKA CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 

29 

education as they are laid down in the books upon psychology, and yet 
they are accomplishing great and good results which no one can deny. 
The blind and mute are being made self-respecting and self-supporting 
and the feeble-minded are surely improved in most cases and many of 
them are brought to a fairly high level of intelligence and practical 
efficiency. The results are being accomplished upon theoretical 
grounds that are not clearly understood and taught. The teachers 
make their appeals to muscles and brains and rely chiefly upon proper 
feeding, fresh air, appropriate exercises and work, and a thorough 
hygienic regimen. Nowhere are minds trainfd directly. It seems to 
appear that where bodies are well cared for, minds take care of themselves 
and develop fairly well. We need just now a practicable psychology 
defining clearly the functional relations in which our minds 

Kto our bodies. The practica 
their theoretical foundations 

methods are right and we need to 

to become more conscious of the 
ications may become possible. As 
has outrun in advancement our 

methods employed that wider app 
often happens, our practice here 
theories. 

The second point concerns the relations that obtain between 

t various charitable institutions of tne state. The laws fix by deflnithe 
classes of our wards, and yet the distinctions that the laws 

prescribe can scarcely be found among the classes as they are pre- 

sented to us. There is a need of a closer interdigitation between the 

state institutions, some unity and centralization in the oversight of 
(hem all. That would mean a more or less elastic system by which the 

wards or patients could be easily transferred and their needs better 
supplied. The practical value of such a scheme lies in the fact that in 

the penitentiary the inmates are forced to work as a mark of disobedienc 
— as a matter of retribution— while jail-birds and orphans cannot 

be made to work because work passes as an evidence of sin and crime 

of which they have not been convicted. The one may be forced to 

work, and perhaps overwork, in a spirit of revengeful retribution, and 

§ other deprived of the most wholesome hygienic regimen in the 
Is of the management. First the public has a right to demand proon 
through its charitable institutions against the depredations of 
anti-social classes and the enormous burden of caring individually 

for the dependent. Second the public has a right to expect that its 

wards shall be cared for at the least MM consistent with the treatment 
that shall improve rather than aggravate their conditions. As 
our institutions are now run they represent rather the force of tradi- 

tion than the highest practicable efficiency that has already beem 
proved and the advancement in the theoretical knowledge of the 
cause and treatment of the delinquent and dependent classes. 

I The third point concerns the attempts that are being made to advance 
knowledge and understanding of dependency and crime. Several of 

ites have already founded institutes for the investigation of in- </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 


{ty and criminality. These are enormously expensive and for 
11 states like Nebraska, Colorado and Wyoming to enter into comtion 
with the richer and more densely populated states of the 
would be assuming too great a burden of taxation. The several 
es of the union do not maintain colonies of lepers, but where 
e unfortunates are found in states that do not have colonies, they 
are sent away to states that have them. In he establishment of institutes 
for investigation, several states like Kansas. Nebraska and 
South Dakota, where the climatic, general geographical and industrial 
Iditions are much the same, might pool their interests, break down 
artificial boundaries of states and found institutes together to 
ly the forms of dependency that are peculiar to the geographical 
industrial conditions of these states. Other states may be left to 
k after the forms that are peculiar to themselves. This has alfly 
been done in the care of criminals. The citizens have a right 
onijilain against the increasing burden of taxation and yet to deid 
that their higher interests in a richer and freer life dependent 
n the best hygienic conditions shall be looked after. 

"The Humane, Efficient, and Economical Manage- 

ment of State 

Institutions." 

Address by Jul| 

LC.Kr 

It is not my purpose to attempt to force upon the people of the 
State of Nebraska any particular system of government for her state 
Institutions, but to present, as best I can. an impartial view of existing 
methods in force in the several states and to briefly consider 
the merits of each. 

In this age of rapid development and advancement in every department 
of human endeavor, it be hooves us to avail ourselves of 
all knowledge and experience of those engaged in like labor to the 
ecd that we may accomplish the best results. \\ nen one speaks with 
•ome degree of positiveness as to facts,, conditions and effects, the 
bearer has a right to know upon what knowledge or experience his 
•tatements are bottomed. The statements in this paper are founded 
upon an experience of almost five years as a member of the board of 
control of state institutions of Iowa; upon personal observation and 
investigation of the methods in force in nearly seventy different 
public institutions situated in many states of this union and upon 
diligent inquiry and study of all existing means of conducting state 
institutions and the results obtained. 

tThe institutions referred to in this paper as public institutions or 
e institutions are those designed and operated for the defective, 
nquent and criminal classes, viz.: colleges for the blind, schools 
the deaf, institutions for the education and care of the feeble- </seg>


            <seg id="p031">
31 

minded, soldeirs' homes, industrial or reform schools for boys and 
girls, reformatories for young men and women, penitentiaries, state 
hospitals for the insane, and the like. The system of management of 
state institutions most general is what I shall call the 

TRUSTEE SYSTEM 

Until very recent years no other system of managing state institutions 
was in operation. Usually each institution was under the 
immediate control of a board of trustees or directors consisting of 
for more members, one or more of whom resided in the town or 
in which the institution was situated. Someit.nes two or more 
utions of the same kind were grouped under one board of trus- 

APPOINTMENT OF TRUSTEES 

I'sually the members of these boards were appointed by the govr 
or elected by the legislature, or by some other outside body. 
etimes this board was composed of persons holding different politconvictions. 
but generally the members were appointed exclusively 
i the dominent political party. Usually these trustees were paid 
¦ expenses and sometimes allowed a small per diem in addition. 

TRUSTEES' MEETING 

Sometimes the trustees were required to meet at the institution 
once a month, though generally they were expected to meet once each 
quarter. 

TRANSACTION OF BUSINESS 

K Often one or more trustees would be absent attending to their 
ate business, and not infrequently a meeting would pass without 
jorum being present. 

I These trustees were expected to examine and audit all bills against 
institution, act upon the recommendations of the superintendent, 
&gt;ect the various parts of the institution, examine into the dietary, 
? and clothing of the inmates, etc. As in most cases all bills had 
n paid prior to the meetings of the trustees, the auditing of bills 
i a post mortem matter, and as the trustees usually came in the 
¦noon and left on the afternon train their time was so limited 
to prevent anything like a thorough investigation of the affairs 
conditions of the institution, and such investigations were usually 
«ly formal. The superintendent if a wise man (and he generally 
0 spread an elaborate meal for the trustees and in other ways 
de their brief stay pleasant, and they left having little more knowl;e 
or information than when they came. 

• «»•••• 

OBJECTIONS TO THE SYSTEM 

11. Its tendency was usually to make the institution an asylum for 
ticians. The fact that many good and capable men secured places in </seg>


            <seg id="p032">
I institutions under this system and in spite of it does not recommend 
As a matter of fact no institution the term of office of whose officers 
&gt;nds upon the political complexion of the state, governor or legisla, 
ever can attain its best development or do the best work. The 
lagement of such institutions must be ploced above and beyond all 
tical considerations if they are to accomplish what they should, 
it can a supeiintendent accomplish whose term of office is likely to 
with any change in the administration, regardless of his fitness and 
ity? What inducement is there in such a situation for good and 
ible men to fit themselves for such special work? How can disine 
be maintained with one or two hundred employees owing allegi- 

iiit to the head of the institution, but to outside parties who dictated 
his appointment and may keep him in office no matter how incomhe 
may be? What sound reason has ever been adduced to show 
that the governing board of such institutions should be made up of men 
whose energies and time are absorbed in carrying on their own private 
¦ &gt;s? It is reasonable to expect that in such cases the trustee will 
permit the interests of the institution to suffer from inattention or 
otherwise on his part rather than to neglect his own affairs. How can 
it be expected that busy men who see the institution for a few hours 
four timts a year can have any real, valuable knowledge as to the situation, 
its condition, and its needs, and how can they have actual knowledge 
as to the conditions and care of the inmates? What a farce it is to 
have a body of men meet to audit bills, to approve or disapprove them, 
and solemnly proceed to 0. K. them after all of them have long since 

12. A great element of safety and protection to the public and intes 
in the management of such institutions is publicity. Publicity 
to the management, if it is bad, speedily results in a change for the 
ter. If the management is good it is a source of great support that 
1 public has confidence in those having charge of the institutions, 
e more the public can know about our institutions and the manner 
i methods of their work, the better it is. There is at best quite too 
ich distrust and ungrounded suspicion on the part of the public genlly 
as to the management of our state institutions and especially 

state hospitals for the insane. The trustee system does not tend to the 
publicity which is desirable. 

t3. The Lobby. The third house, as it has been called, is entirely 
much in evidence at the sessions of our legislatures. The spectacle 
those in charge of the state charitable or penal institutions buttoning 
members of the legislature for proper appropriations for the 
&gt;port of such institutions is not pleasant, nor should it be necessary, 
seems to be inevitable in practice under this system. It is reprehensifrom 
any point of view. 

4. I know some persons have undertaken the defense of a system of 
purchasing in private or public for such institutions without regard to </seg>


            <seg id="p033">
33 

competition. Years of experience has confirmed me in the opinion that 
so far as it is possible to do so all supplies for institutions should be 
purchased on competitive bids. It insures publicity, which always tends 
to safety. It affords an opportunity for all dealers to compete, which 
is only fair to them. It results in securing the article wanted on the 
most advantageous terms, which means a saving to the state and the 
taxpayers. It goes far towards insuring honesty and fair dealing in 
obtaining supplies for the institutions. It tends to disarm public criticism, 
which is apt to follow such purchases when they are made in 
private or when there is no open competition. It is a great protection to 
the institution and especially to the officer charged with the duty of 
making purchases. 

5. It may be well said that the train of evils I have mentioned, as 
well as many others I have not time to consider, does not necessarily 
pertain to the trustee system. As to some of them that is true, but they 
in practice are found to exist much more frequently in connection with 
that system than with another to be hereafter mentioned. Most of them 
If not inseparable from the system, are the natural fruits of it. and difficult 
of separation from it. Occasionally toere is a state where the 
political power in making appointments in state institutions has risen 
above political considerations, but where there is one case of this kind 
there are a dozen where the institutions have been made political asylums 
for politicians utterly incompetent to properly fill the positions to 
which they have been appointed. Though not defined by law as a crime, 
yet it is none the less so from a moral standpoint, for any man or set of 
men. be they governors, members of the legislatures, or others, to use 
the public institutions of the state as a political dumping ground, to 
place political considerations above humane care of inmates, to reduce 
the management of great insane hospitals and other public institutions 
to the level of the political caucus, to place the care of inmates who 
need the tenderest ministrations of those peculiarly skilled in the hands 
of those absolutely unskilled, incapable and negligent in order that a 
political obligation may be discharged. 

THE SUPERVISORY SYSTEM. 

In many of the states where the trustee system is in operation there 
has been created by law a board of state charities and corrections. 
which is clothed with power to inspect and investigate such institutions 
as are considered in this paper and whose duty it is to make report to 
proper authority of their findings and recommendations. In some states 
plans for buildings must be presented to and approved by this board 
before the buildings can be erected; in other states they are clothed 
with more extended powers. In all cases, however, it is merely a supervisory 
board, with no power to enforce its recommendations. It is. as a 
rule, composed of excellent persons, who work without compensation, 
and no doubt accomplish much good. Experience hrs shown., however. </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
34 


that a board without power to enforce its recommendations must fail 
of attaining the success it should and would achieve had it power to 
¦ the evils it finds. Only a year since such a board in Illinois 
mended the establishment of a central board of control in its 
stead and a like recommendation was made in the last report of the 
same kind of a board in South Dakota. The reasons given by these two 
boards for the changes are cogent and unanswerable. 

THE BOARD OF CONTROL SYSTEM 

II come now to a consideration of what 1 believe to be the most 
ern as well as the most perfect system yet devised for controlling 
state institutions. The board of control system is of recent origin. 
•onsin was one of the first states to adopt it. though under their 
?m the board appoints certain officers in institutions in addition to 
chief executive officers. This feature is very objectionable, as the 
pction of the system and its proper working requires that the power 
ppoint all subordinate officers and employees shall rest with the 
I executive officer. Kansas had a system embracing some features 
lat in Iowa. The system is in operation in Minnesota and. as I am 
sed, in the state of Washington. It was inaugurated in Iowa in 

I consider the system as it is found in Iowa because, with the exception 
of Minnesota, which is modeled after Iowa, the Iowa system is the 
most complete and perfect in its details of any in existence. That you 
may fully understand it. I shall give an outline of its main features as 
provided in the low creating our board. 

tThr board consists of three members, who are appointed by the 
¦rnor, and must be confirmed by a two-thirds vote of the senate, 
term of office is six years ad the salary of the members is three 
isand dollars a year and expenses. The board is subject to investigaby 
a joint committee of the legislature; its finances and accounts, 
as well as those of every institution under its control, are yearly investigated 
and checked by experts employed by the executive council of the 
state. It is made a crime for any member of the board to accept gifts 
from any one dealing with any institution under its control. If a member 
of the board or any officer or employee of it, or any officer or employee 
of an institution under its control, exercises political influence on 
another, or contributes money or other thing of value for political purposes, 
he must be removed from office. It is made a crime for any member 
of the board to suggest the appointment of any person to a place 
under any executive officer of an institution. The design of the law is to 
hold the chief executive officer of each institution responsible to the 
board. Said chief executive officer appoints and removes at pleasure 
all officers and employees under him. The board appoints and removes 
all chief executive officers. This is in effect civil service, for every subordinate 
officer and employee of an institution knows that he holds his 
place at the will of the chief executive officer of such institution. A»- </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
N hi'KASK A (. H AKI X 1 t«S AN I) CORK ACTIONS. 

35 

Bon to duty, ability and efficiency in service are the only tests; no 
intment is influenced by any political consideration whatever. 

POWERS. 

The board has power to manage, 
tions under Its charge; to investigate 
condition; to investigate questions of 
pital; to determine when insane pe 
hospitals to be charged to the state; 
and penitentiary districts. 

control, and govern the institutheir 
management and financial 
insanity of patients in state ho«-rsons 
shall be admitted to the 
to divide the state into hospital 

DUTIES. 

The board is required to prepare annually a statement showing the 
cost of operating the institutions the preceding year; to make biennial 
reports to the governor and legislature: to visit all institutions every 
six months and hospitals by some of its members or its secretar&gt; 
a month; to meet superintendents in quarterly conference; to gather 
statistics; to publish a bulletin; to compel all employees handling 
money or property of the state to give bond; to require annual inventories 
of all tne state property, and quarterly of all supplies and stores; 
to annually fix the salaries of all officers and employees of tne institutions 
except the chief executive officers; to inspect or cause to be 
inspected twice a year all county and private institutions where insane 
persons are kept; to inspect private institutions where children are 
kept to be bound out. 

• 

* 

* 

• 

* * • 

ESTIMATES. 

t Everything purchased and paid for must be credited to the institui 
under some one of the classifications heretofore named. Nothing 
be purchased for an institution unless it has been first estimated 
and the estimate approved by this board and the purchase ordered, 
only exception to the above is that we keep in the hands of the 
i of each institution a fund not exceeding $250.no. which may be 
1 by him in emergencifs spccMH in the statute, and for which no 
mate nted be made, but a rf ;:ort of tne expenditures out of such fund 
it be made every month with reasons for such expenditures. 

I These estimates are arranged in accordance with the classification 
of. accounts. They show an item number running consecutively 
ugh that particular classification of the estimate. Each item shows 
what Is wanted, the amount, kind, value per yard, or pound, or as the 
fe may be, and the aggregate amount. These items are arranged also 
ler sub-divisions of the classification. After the estimates are fined 
(they are made in duplicate), they are sent to this board and may 
be approved, rejected or modified, as the board may deem proper. 
When they reach the office of the board they are passed by its secretary </seg>


            <seg id="p036">
36 

to the estimate clerk, and she examines them carefully, notes whether 
the descriptions are correct and definite, corrects errors in the extensions, 
footings and clarification, and attaches a memoranda slip with 
notes for the information of the board. They are then examined by 
the secretary and passed to the board, where they are examined, modined. 
disallowed or approved, as the case may be. A memorandum of 
its action is made on a sheet attached to the estimate, and it is returned 
to the secretary, who puts the notes of the board in formal 
shape and returns one copy to the institution, retaining one copy in 
our office. 

Supplemental estimates are sent up when articles have been overlooked, 
or where the supply is insufficient. Re-estimates are required 
when the article estimated for costs more than the amount originally 
estimated. 

E.-timate blanks for purchases to be paid for from the general 
support fund are print* d in black ink: those for special appropriations 
in red ink. and those for contingent (support) fund on blue paper. 
These are thus printed to facilitate the work and prevent errors in booking. 


KThe estimates are sent in as a rule quarterly, and about two months 
re the beginning of the quarter for which they apply. 

SCHEDULES FOR BIDS 

After the Kith day of November. February. May and August, rei 
ly. when the estimates are all in. schedules are made up for 
each institution of all articles estimated for. These schedules embrace 
about one hundred different headings, and the articles are placed under 
oper headings. The schedules are so arranged as to show the 
general item number, the estimate number and the item number in 
the estimate, the article, quality and measure. Places are left for 
the bidders to fill in the amount of after each item. These schedule 
footed for each institution. There is. for instance, one schedule 
for groceries, but all items for groceries for a single institution are 
under its heading. Bidders are thus enabled to bid on all articles 
in their line for one or more institutions, as they see fit. Attached to 
these schedules are printed specifications, and dealers, wherever located, 
who have made known their desire to bid are furnished schedules. 

SCHEDULES OF BIDS 

IWhn these bids have been received at the board's office, they are 
•fully gone over for the correction of errors or mistakes in extents 
or footings, and if such errors are found the bidder is notified, 
n the bids are put on a schedule, showing the name of all bidders 
groceries, for instance, the name of the article, the amount bid on 
ml the aggregate amount of the bid on groceries for that instituis. 
Samples are required of hats and caps, findings, dry goods. </seg>


            <seg id="p037">
37 

clothing, groceries, salt fish, smoked meats, and many other articles. 
These are properly arranged in rooms for examination. 

rMINATION OF SCHEDULES AND SAMPLES BY THE CHIEF 
EXECUTIVE OFFICERS. 

When the quarterly meeting with the superintendents is held and 
after it is over, the several superintendents take the schedules and examine 
the prices and the samples and make a memoranda of who in 
their judgment should be awarded the contract. 

AWARDS 

Some superintendent and one or more members of the board then 
make the awards. The successful bidder is notified, and the chief executive 
officer of the institution is furnished a list of the goods and the 
price bid on each item. The board fixes a maximum price on tea and 
coffee and awards on them are made after a test is made of the goods. 
The board also fixes the character and quality of certain goods, such as 
curled hair. rice, prunes, etc.. for all institutions. No goods are shipped 
except on the order of the superintendent, and then direct to the institution. 


• * * 

* * 

THE GATHERING AND PRESERVATION OF STATISTICAL INFOR- 

MATION. 

At each institution is kept a statistical record which contains the 
name of every inmate, the date of their admission, their residence, and 
a multitude of facts relating to their history and that of their family. 
This book is so arranged as to show the subsequent history of the per- 

I while in the institution and his death, parole, release, discharge, as 
case may be. Appropriate blanks corresponding to these books are 
lished the institution and upon these all the information is coned 
to the board when it is from time to time entered in a like 
jrd book kept in the office of the board. These statistical books and 
nks are alike for the same kind of institutions. We thus have a 
Ml— Mj full history in our office of every inmate in a state institu-1 
under the control of this board. 


• • • 

* * 

NEW BUILDINGS. 

No new building or improvement can be erected or made which is 
to cost over $300.00, except on competitive bids. 

The board appoints an architect who receives a salary of $3,000.00 
and railroad fare, and who is required to prepare plans and estimates 
for all new buildings and improvements and look after the construction 
»the work. Plans are prepared by him fcr all proposed new buildings 
which appropriations are to be asked from the legislature, also estl- </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
38 


mates for their cost. These are laid before the proper committees for 
consideration. Formerly the legislature was besieged by all the superintendents, 
and many of the trustees of the institutions, who formed a 
formidable lobby for appropriations. Now the needs of the institution 
are presented by the board and the superintendents devote their time to 
attending to their respective institution duties. 

• • • 

* * • » 

• 

mi-annual visits are made by the entire board to all institution 

and some member of the board visit 
by visitation, by reports, by checks, 
board keep in touch with the affair 
the policy of the board to promote 
positions of chief executive officers a 

the hospitals every month. Thus 
by daily correspondence does the 
at the several institutions. It is 
apable and efficient officers to the 
vacancies may occur. 

RESULTS. 

This system of control has now been in operation for more than four 
and a half years and has proven very satisfactory. It has resulted in 
paying women nurses and attendants the same wages as men receive 
for like service: in improving the character of the service; in bettering 
the condition of the institutions: in elevating the standard of care 
afforded to inmates. All this has been accomplished notwithstanding 
the fact that the legislature, just before we took up the work, reduced 
the per capita allowances for support of inmates in the aggregate sum 
of JKHi.iMin per year, and the further fact that nearly all of the time 
since the law has been in operation the market price of many commodities 
has been steadily advancing. Over $80,000.00 which the board 
might have drawn for support of inmates remains in the state treasury 
tided. 

In his last report, the treasurer of state computes the decrease in 
cost of operating the institutions under the control of this board during 
the first year, as compared with the cost of the previous year "under 
the trustee system at $379.49(1.73. or 26.9 per cent." * * * "This saving, 
it is fair to presume, was not the result of unwise economics that 
were detrimental to the institutions. The character of the members of 
the board of control is a sufficient guaranty that such was not the case. 
They have been the fruits of the application of business principles and 
methods in the conduct of the fourtee ninstitutions under the board." 

In the last sentence the treasurer has struck the key-note as to how 
this board has been able to make such a large saving to the state, and 
at the same time improve the conditions at the institutions. </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
N EBRASK.A CHARITIES AND CORRECTION S. 

M 

"Sanatorium for the Treatment of Pulmonary 
Tuberculosis." 

Address by Dr. R 

liird C. Moore 

Pulmonary tuberculosis, commonly termed consumption, has be«n 

from the early ages the most destructive disease with which the humar 

family has had to contend. 

LThe savage in his native state is exempt, but with the advent of 
ization he is compelled to bow in submission to the irresistible 

power, and in his filth and unsanitary surroundings he becomes an easy 

prey. Newly settled countries are for a period free from its ravages 

but sooner or later the disease germs are introduced. Hence it has 

been termed the disease of civilization, and from its destructiveness, the 

white plagut 

In the year 1881, Dr. Robert Koch, a world-renowned bacteriologist 

Krlin, Germany, made the important discovery that pulmonary tuberis 
was dependent for a cause upon a micro-organism, which he 

Ee&lt;i Bacillus Tuberculosis. Upon this scientific achievement have 
established three factors upon which are based the diagnosis, 
hylaxis. and treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis. These factors 

are as follows 

First — Pulmonary tuberculosis is a specific disease 
Second — Pulmonary tuberculosis is communicable. 
Third — Pulmonary tuberculosis is not self-limited. 

1. Pulmonary tuberculosis is a specific disease for the reason that it 

E holly dependent upon the presence of this germ for its existence, 
ral diseases at the onset clinically resemble tuberculosis, but if. 
repeated bacteriological examinations, the germ is not found, then 
disease can be excluded. But if, on the other hand, this germ is 

found, the diagnosis is then positive. 

Tuberculosis is communicable. This fact has been demonstrated 

I the inoculation of lower animals with the specific germ, and in them 
e tuberculosis has been established. Also it has been observed that 
en the germs have been received in an individual, in a condition faable 
for their propagation, such individual will contract the disease. 
I in turn becomes a starting point for a further scattering of the 
ms. Every human being is not at all times susceptible to the de- 

K)pment of the germ. If he were, from the innumerable sources of 
tagion with which we are constantly surrounded, the human race 

would long before this have been exterminated. 

It has been demonstrated that the tubercle bacilli exists in vast 

tbers in the sputum of persons infected with this disease, and when 
matter is cast forth upon our streets, public halls, etc., dried and 

scattered with dust in the air, we daily breathe them in our lungs; and </seg>


            <seg id="p040">
40 

when they are taken in by an individual, who may be temporarily in a 
¦ ondition favorable for their growth, they will rapidly increase in number. 
With this knowledge of the manner of their dissemination, it beihe 
duty of our law-makers to adopt stringent measures against 
the spitting habit, and the duty of the police to see that these laws are 
rigidly enforced. Furthermore, it is incumbent upon the health authori- 
I our municipalities, to issue instructions, plainly worded, setting 
forth the danger to the community from this promiscuous spitting, and 
see that this information is impressed as its importance deserves, upon 
the minds of every man. woman, and child in the community. It is also 
incumbent upon every physician, when treating a case of pulmonary 
nlosis. to eternally ding into the ears of his patient the necessity 
of destroying every particle of sputum. 

I If this principle were carried out as thoroughly in every community 
is in our hospitals and sanitoria. it would not be long before this 
ructive disease would become exterminated for want of seed. To 
hlish sanitoria for consumptives and maintain them at great ex¦ 
to the state, and still permit the promiscuous scattering of the 
is. will no more accomplish the prevention of the disease than the 
itaining of inebriate asylums and still permit the promiscuous sale 
Icoholira will do away with drunkenness. 

kTo accomplish the grrat object of such institutions the isolation and 
mpted cure of the individual must go hand in hand with proper 
&gt;hylactic measures. 

1 Tuberculosis is not self limited. By this statement it is understood 
that when once the tubercular process has been started, it goes 
on increasing in severity until death. Many of the infectuous diseases 
lf-Mmited. the germs have a certain cycle of growth, maturity 
and decline, and if the vitality of the individual is sufficient to withstand 
the attack, recovery takes place. This is true of the eruptive 
smallpox, scarlet fever and measles; also of yellow fever, cholera, 
typhoid fever, etc. Another class is not self limited, but the germs, ins-tead 
of passing through the cycle of growth, maturity and decline, constantly 
increase in number and virulence, invading new tissues until 
I nsues through exhaustion. This class includes leprosy, tubercuand 
probably cancer and syphilis. This statement is true only 
when the case is left to the unaided powers of natural resistance, which 
to a certain extent is inherent in all tissues; but with the great strides 
made during late years in therapeutics at least one of these diseases can 
now bp classed among the curables. and this disease is the one which we 
now have under consideration — tuberculosis. 

The indications for the successful management of pulmonary tuberculosis 
are three in number, surveilliani e, disinfection and by appropriate 
means increase the natural power of resistance: and these indications 
can be followed out most satisfactorily by the establishing and 
maintaining sanitoria. Several of the states have established such </seg>


            <seg id="p041">
41 

institutions, and the subject is now under consideration by several other 
states with the probability thai within the next few years the maintain- 
Kby the state of sanitoria for the treatment of consumption will be 
iidered as necessary for the safety of the people as is the building 
maintaining of hospitals for the insane and asylums for the feeble 
Jed. 

IThe sanitorium for the treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis should 
i state institution, maintained by the state and free to all suitable 
hants. and its management should be completely under the control 
of men who by their educations, executive ability and professional attainments 
are qualified to successfully manage in detail an institution of 
ti intricate requirements. They should depend for their appointment 
rely upon their special qualifications to perform the required duties, 
and be free from political machinations, their tenure of office depending 
upon their wise, conscientious and honest work. Such men can be found 
in every state, and only under such management can the greatest good 
to both state and the inmates be achieved. 

The most complete institution of this character in the United States 
is located in Rutland. Mass. The buildings were planned and I 
especially for the purpose for whic - they are used, and after a careful 
personal inspection I cannot see where any improvement can be made: 
and it will be well worth the time ana expense of a committee appointed 
by any state contemplating the erection of a sanitorium to visit and 
study this completed hospital in every detail. The arrangement is upon 
the plan which is termed the pavilion hospital, which was adopted in 
several instances by the U. S. government during the civil war. A long 
enclosed corridor in the form of a semicircle is the base. From this 
corridor the wards project like spokes of a wheel from the hub. The 
heating plant, kitchen, social hall and dining-room are located at the 
center of a cirde. of which the corridor is the arc. and in a straight line 
extending well to the front are the administration buUdings. By this 
arrangement the wards are ventilated on both sides and one end. which 
an uninterrupted circulation of fresh air — the sine qua non of 
modern treatment of consumption. The cost of such an establishment 
is large, the one at Rutland costing, with the additions made in the 
past year, about $3nn.ciiii. but all who are connected with th« sanitorium 
and those who have made a study of pulmonary tuberculosis as it is 
found in Massacnusetts are of the opinion that it is worth to the 3tate 
every dollar which has been expended. Other states have under consideration 
the establishing of sanitoria. New Jersey at the last session 
of the legislature appropriated $aiUHM&gt; for this purpose, and last fall a 
site was selected and an appropriation of $300.&lt;XiO is asked of the present 
legislature. Illinois has now under consideration an appropriation 
of |2i v fl.H(»i for this purpose. New York has established one and has commenced 
its construction. Nfinnesota. Texas and several other states 
have established special hospitals for consumptive inmates of their </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
42 


penitentiaries. Also arrangements have been made by several stat« s 
arate the consumptive insane from the other inmates of their asy- 
The California legislature appointed a committee to investigate 
the demands in that state for a sanatorium. This committee last month 
• (1 adversely to erecting such an institution, setting forth as a 
for this opinion that the state was being overrun by 'lungers." 
and a sanatorium supported by the state would be but another inducement 
for a still larger immigration of these undesirable citizens. Furthermore, 
this committee suggested that stringent laws should be en• 
stablishing a quarantine against consumptives. This course may 
who are citizens of the most healthful state in the Union, seem 
iiiel and selfish. But when I call your attention to the statistics 
on this subject, we must admit that they are doing this simply in selfw. 
A similar course has been suggested in Colorado, but I believe 
no action has ben taken by that state. 

tYe now will consider the question of practical importance to us as 
¦ns of Nebraska, namely: Is there an urgent demand in Nebraska 
he establishment of a sanatorium for the treatment of pulmonary 
¦culosis? But before answering this question. I will call your attento 
statistics of the deaths from consumption in several states taken 
the report of the census of 1900. The statistics from several of the 

are not accurate, there being no laws relating to registration of 
deaths the figures there published being derived from the reports of the 
- enumerators, and as a consequence are incomplete. But such as 
they are. I will give them to you. with the statement that for scientific 
purposes they are practically worthless, being not exact, but only approximate. 
The population of the I'nited States in 1!»im&gt; was 76.303.387. 


imber of deaths from consumption was 10t,760, being 143 for every 
0 inhabitants. 

This table shows a range of 55 per 100.000 in Nebraska to 186 per 
I) in Massachusetts and 168 in Connecticut. There must be a cause 
for this great approximate difference, which I think can be explained, 
when we consider, first, Nebraska is an agricultural state, which requires 
a constant outdoor life in a rigorous, active employment, while 
Massachusetts and Connecticut are manufacturing states, which compels 
its workers to live their entire life within doors and subject to the 

Deaths Proportion 

.teg. 

Population. 

from per 100,000 
Consumption. Population. 

Ncfcnata 

l.m;i;.3iMi 

m 

Massai-hii.-. ; 

2.8i 13.341; 

BJBM 186 

Minnesota 

1.751.394 

1.S44 

2.231.853 

i.Mi? M 

Colorado 

IM.1M 

ST4 

Connecticut 

Mt,4M 

1.529 168 

California 

1.485.053 

3.48U 234 </seg>


            <seg id="p043">
43 

constant breathing of vitiated air. Furthermore, let there be but one 
consumptive employed in each room of a factory, he or she may be the 
starting point for infection of all of his or her fellow-workers. 

Another cause for the low death-rate from consumption in Nebraska 
E absence of large cities. All our statistics show that the mortality 
this disease is far greater in the large cities than in the rural dis- 
Again. we have no tenement houses, and but few alley dwellers 
large numbers of the poor and filthy are crowded into unsanitary 
apartments. Again, we have in Nebraska no industrifs which employ 

child labor. The working of little 

;irls and boys under fourteen years 
state permitting it. This is a cause 
ieracy. and the universal law of the 
of such communities, brings to an 

of age is a burning disgrace to any &gt;. 
of physical, mental, and moral deget 
survival of the fittest, for the good 

early death the degenerate victims 
Omaha is the only city in Nebraska 
taring establishments, and I do not 

; of such inhuman avarii iousness. 
in which there are large manufai - 
know of a single one in which child 

labor has a place. But on the contrary, only youths and adults are em 
i: and in establishments which I have visited the managers dis 
play a very commendable interest in the physical welfare of their em 
ployi ¦ 

t Colorado, with MS, and California, with 234 per MMM population, 
i the disastrous story of unreasonable flocking of the unfortunate 
ims of consumption to these much vaunted climatic resorts. Many 
are no doubt benefited by the change to these beautiful climates, but 
only when the change is made in the early stage of the disease. Very 
many more are lured to a miserable life among strangers and a death, 
to say the least, not retarded by the change. Colorado and California, 
with such a showing, would be justified in making laws restraining the 
immigration of this large class of not only undesirable, but really dangerous 
unfortunates. 

»The following table of deaths from consumption in the censu 
with per cent of deaths from this cause of all deaths in the followregistered 
cities, is probably accurate: 

Denver 2.4o4 M 17 

Los Angele; 

;eles 1.837 480 M 

I.* 

all causes. 993: from consumption. 
Deaths from all causes. 1.050; from 

¦ Omaha in 1901: Deaths from 
per cent, 8.1. Omaha. IMS: 

Deaths 

Deaths 

from 

trom 

Cities. 

All Causes. 

Consumption. 

Per Cent. 

1.382 

Hi' 

' 

St. Paul 

1.574 

13 

St. Joseph 

933 

»1 

• • 

New Haven 

1.862 

« 

Worcester 

1.838 

218 </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
44 


Bumption. 92; per cent, 8.7. Omaha for the three years: Deaths 
all causes. 3.325: from consumption. 283; per cent. 8.5. 

From this table we learn that Omaha has a comparatively low death 
rate from consumption, and could reliable statistics be obtained of the 
state of Nebraska, the showing would be still better than would be inferred 
from computing from the Omaha reports. 

Nebraska has never been considered a desirable resort for "lungers," 
and therefore probably only few of the consumptives who have dUd in 
this state were imported, but the disease was contracted within the 
state. According to the statistics of ISM, Nebraska had 592 deaths from 
consumption, which was proportionally far less than that of any state 
to which I have referred. And Omaha has. as reported by the board of 
health, an average death-rate of 94 from this cause. From this showing 
I i an not state that there is an immediate and urgent demand for a 
sanatorium in this state. You must bear in mind that a small proportion 
of the cases of consumption are suitable for sanatorium treatment 
with a prospect of being greatly benefited. It is only in the early or 
incipient stage of the disease that we can reasonably expect satisfactory 
results to follow any treatment. And it is far beyond the means of any 
state, or even a justifiable use of the public money, for the state to furnish 
a home for every case of phthisis pulmonaris; therefore, in estimating 
the capacity of a sanatorium that would be required in Nebraska 
1 have considered only the probable number of these incipient cases — 
there being no statistics to go by I must admit that this is mostly 
guess work. But I think I can safely state that Omaha would probably 
furnish twenty-five suitable applicants for admission to a sanatorium, 
and the state fully twice as many. Therefore, for a starter, an institution 
with accommodations for from seventy-five to one hundred patients 
would be ample for the present, and as there became demand for more 
room the facilities for meeting it could be increased. 

A sanatorium in Nebraska would be the means of saving many 
and also would be a center from which information could be promulgated 
for the early management of such cases, and would thus, in 
time, by instructing the people in prophylaxis and in the home treatment 
of consumption, greatly reduce the mortality from this cause. 

tThe expense of building such a hospital and maintaining it will be 
great, and should not be undertaken until first fully investigating 
subject. I therefore suggest that this association petition the legisre 
now in session to appoint a committee for this purpose, or, what 
Id be better, that the legislature instruct the board of health tj 
Bughly investigate the sanatorium matter, and report its findings to 
next legislature two years from this winter. I also suggest that you 
tion the legislature to enact a statute relating to the registration of 
bs and deaths. With the board of health as a central body, and the 
istics collected by the county clerks of the several counties, the exse 
will be very small. </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
NEBRASKA CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 

45 

The good resulting from a registration of deaths will be two-fold: 
First, by knowing the principal causes of death, we will be able to 
carry out suitable prophylactic measures. Second, by showing the general 
healthfulness of our state, the inducement will be held out to all 
who may be seeking homes to come to us. 

Since it has been demonstrated beyond a doubt that the indiscriminate 
casting out of tubercle laden sputum is the means by which pulmonary 
tuberculosis is disseminated. I would suggest thai you petition 
the legislature to enact a most stringent law against spitting on the 
streets, on the floors of offices, stores, and public buildings, in street 
cars and other places which we are compelled to visit or patronize. 
Also making obligatory upon owner or lessees of office buildings to conveniently 
place cuspidors in which shall be placed some efficient disinfectant, 
and that these cuspidors shall be kept clean. 

tThe treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis in properly constructed 
itoria has been quite successful. In fact, the cures in many cases, 
greatly improved conditions in others, have been far greater than 
could reasonably have expected. 

This treatment is very simple, and if we could impress upon the 
minds of the people the importance of following it out in detail it could 
be carried out at home successfully. 

The plan adopted is founded on three essential principles: fresh 
air, generous feeding, and cold bathing. To meet the first principle, 
the patient must live in the fresh air night and day. By day he is outside, 
protected from the heat of the sun and rain by a simple roof, and 
by night his room is open to an unobstructed circulation of the air. summer 
and winter. 

? In Brockton. Mass.. Dr. Millette has had constructed platforms on 
roofs, or so that they could be reached from a second story window 
or door, and on these improvised platforms his patients pass the nights, 
and also the days when the presence of fever demands rest in the recumbent 
position. At Rutland the large windows of the wards are 
always open, so that the air breathed by the patients is as pure as if he 
were actually out of doors. In winter hot air is forced by means of fans 
into the wards to the extent that the temperature is but seldom below 
freezing. The occupants are kept comfortably warm by sufficient cloth- 

IThe expense of heating under these circumstances is very great, and 
cut this down, and at the same time keep the wards comfortable and 
II give the patient fresh air, a novel plan has been tried by placing 
I patient with his head out of a window and his body inside the ward, 
is is accomplished by projecting about one-quarter of the cot out of 
• window and arranging with a canvas flap extending iiom the lower 
;h and fastened to the cot to keep out the cold air and still allow the 
tient to change his position. When I was in Rutland I was told that 
s plan was being tried on a doctor, who was then an inmate. I have 
»rd nothing since as to the practicability of this arrangement. </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
46 


Patients who are continually in the open air have most voracious 
appetites, and to keep them satisfied they are fed six comfortably square 
meals per day. the first at 7 a. m., second 10 a. m., third noon, fourth 3 
p. m.. fifth i&gt;:3ii p. m.. sixth 9 p. m. At each meal milk, eggs, meat, 
bread and butter, coffee and tea are furnished. No alcoholics are given, 
but are considered by the visiting physicians as harmful. But little 
medicine is used, occasionally a little cod liver oil, creosote, and heroin 
for cough. 

Once a day, or as often as the attending physician may think advisable, 
the patient is given a cold shower bath and well rubbed down. 
This may seem rather severe treatment, but when once the patients 
have become accustomed to the slight shock which is caused by the first 
dash of water, they look forward to the time to take the bath with 
pleasure. The effect of this plan of treatment, the combinations of 
living in the open air. eating large quantities of easily digested and 
nourishing food, and the cold bathing, has been found to increase the 
powers of resistance and recuperative functions to the extent that after 
following it up for six or eight months many patients gain in weight, 
the physical signs of the disease disappear, and the tubercle bacilli can 
no longer be found in the sputum. These patients are cured ami the 
reports of the "graduates" of the sanatoria show that they remain 
cored, even after returning to a life of hard indoor work in unsanitary 
environments. The few reported relapses, instead of being true backsliders, 
are probably reinfections. 

" Organization of City Charities. 

The consideration of the subject of charity organization here undertaken 
is meant to apply especially to conditions existing in Nebraska 
at the present time. This is a state with but one large city. Lincoln, 
the second city in size, has a population of 48.000 and is the only city 
which has a charity organization society. The purpose of this paper 
is to show the advantages which a further extension of these organizations 
might bring to the people of Nebraska. It is necessary to explain, 
therefore, briefly, what is meant by charity organization. 

The Telief of destitution is so universally recognized as a duty that 
there is no civilized community that does not provide for it in some 
form. The most primitive and most common form is that of personal 
almsgiving. Alongside of this there exists in every community in 
Anglo Saxon countries the public provision for poor relief through 
taxation, including the distribution of relief to the poor in their homes 
by local overseers of the poor and a long list of public institutions from 
the almshouse to the great asylums for the insane and defective classes. 

Abstract of Paper by C. E. Prcvey </seg>


            <seg id="p047">
47 

Finally there are a multitude of private organizations for the relief of 
every form of distress in every conceivable way. These include all 
church charity societies and local relief societies for aiding the poor in 
their own homes and the variety of hospitals, homes, and other institutions 
in the cities, maintained by private philanthropy for the relief 
or reformation of the unfortunate and erring. 

k There are thus a multitude of agencies working for the relief of 
poor in every large city. Experience everywhere shows that this 
tits in overlapping of work. The same person may obtain alms from 
umber of private almoners and also from a number of relief so• 
ieties or institutions. The most persistent beggar and the most skillful 
ifier gets the most. Again, with such a multitude of agencies to 
the poor, one in need of the special kind of relief that one of these 
cies could supply may suffer in want of it, not knowing of its 
ence. Another evil arises in this state of affairs and that is the 
ace of expert knowledge in dealing with distress. It is found that 
ur modern complex society to efficiently help those in need of 
ity requires knowled'ge of the causes of pauperism and the means 
¦lief, as well as judgment in reading human nature which are only 
ired by long study and experience. Now every individual almoner 
not this knowledge or experience, neither has any ordinary relief 
ty. 

To me?', these two evils then is the purpose of charity organization. 
The evil of overlapping in relief work and the evil of giving 
without adequate knowledege. The first evil is overcome by making 
the charity organization a federation of all the existing charities. Its 
board of directors should include representatives of every church and 
every charity in the city. An office is kept open where all applicants 
may be referred and where any one may report any case of distress. 
All societies acd alms-givers are asked to co-operate by reporting to 
the Charity Organization office the names of those whom they aid 
and by consulting the records at the office before aiding unknown 
persons. There can be but one charity organization society in any 
city and tnat is non-sectarian. The evil of giving without adequate 
knowledge is nut by making careful investigation of the fa. 
every case and by recording these facts for future reference. Adequate 
knowledge and judgment is further secured by employing an expert 
in charge of the office and by making this office a center for the 
study of the problems of charity. 

That the charities of a great city like Omaha could be operated 
much more efficiently if thus organized needs no argument to prove. 
The need of such organizations in the smaller towns is not so commonly 
recognized. Let us point out some of the needs of charity 
organization in the smaller cities and towns of the state. 

1. Even in small cities there is a sufficiently large number of 
charities to require a central bureau for co-operation. There are at </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
48 


t several churches which do some relief work; the county comioners; 
the G. A. R. ; perhaps an aid society; many individuals 
give money to tramps; and then there are all over our state inticns 
and organizations like the child saving societies which do 
ate work. A local organization including representatives of all 
churches, the commissioners, the G. A. R.. etc.. would lead to a 
¦r distribution of relief. Regular conferences of such workers to 
Ider the best way to meet the needs of special cases would reoften 
in making use of some state institution, child saving soor 
other charity outside the community where, as it is now. 
y are neglected who could be helped by these institutions. 

12. If there were a local charity organization in every city it would 
&gt;k- us to deal intelligently with the tramp problem, including under 
head those who are sent from town to town on transportation 
ished by county commissioners, and others, as well as the large 
ibei of families who travel about in covered wagons. As it is, 
oroftssional mendicant, {specially if sick or disabled, can travel 
over the state on transportation which "is readily furnished in 
t towns to (i i sons simply to get rid of them. This should 
¦r be done without first investigating to ascertain where the peril 
ally belongs. If there were charity organizations throughout 
state with whom we could correspond it would make this investian 
easier. These organizations could also come in touch with 
other in the state conference and arrive at some agreement as to 
t to do with those who esk to be sent from one town to another. 

13. Aside from these benefits of co-operation it would be possible 
nany of the large towns of the state to open an office and employ 
aid secretary to take charge of the work. This would greatly imfe 
the quality of work done by all local charities. It would cause 
e attention to be paid to the causes of pauperism and more would 
done to prevent the increase of paupersim while not neglecting 
-elieve that which exists. 

• * • 

In Lincoln the Charity Organization society has been in existence 
for ten years and has become indispensible. It receives a good 
of co-operation among the churches, county commissioners, 
other charities and private citizens. It is so well known that no pro- 

Iional beggar can go far in the city without being referred to it. 
the other hand, its patrons are so numerous in the city that any 
thy person in need of aid is almost sure to be quietly reported to 
office. In either case the society guarantees to avert actual sufng. 
to investigate thoroughly and use such measures as numanity 
ates in the case. 

• • 

• • 

* * 

All the features of charity organization cannot be inaugurated in </seg>


            <seg id="p049">
49 

the smaller towns of the state, but there are many benefits which 
could be derived from a simple organization which could be maintained 
at slight expense. There are cities of only 3.000 which have 
organized charities. We hope to see this work extended in Nebraska 
and urge upon the members of this conference to use their influence 
in their own communities toward this end. We will gladly furnish 
reports of our society and other information to any who can make 
use of the same. </seg>



            <seg id="p050">
Punishment for Abandonment of Families. 

Law Enacted by the Nebraska Legislature, 1903. 

I Section 1. That every person who shall, without good cause, 
idon his wife and wilfully neglect or refuse to maintain or profor 
her, or who shall abandon his or her legitimate or illegite 
child or children under the age of sixteen years, and wilfully 
ect or refuse to provide for such child or children, shall, upon 
iction, be deemed guilty of a felony and be punished by imprisont 
in the penitentiary for not more than one year, or by imprisont 
in the county jail for not more than six (6) months. No other 
ence shall be required to prove that such husband was married 
¦eh wife, or that such person is the parent of such child or chili. 
than would be necessary to prove such fact or facts in a civil 
:&gt;n. 

Sec. 2. Provided, however, if after conviction and before sentence 
such husband or parent shall appear before the court In which 
Ivictlon shall have taken place, and enter into bond, to the state 
Nebraska, in the penal sum of two hundred dollars, to the approval 
the court as to surety, conditioned that such husband will furnish 
i wife with necessary and proper home, food, care and clothing, 
that such parent will furnish said child or children with necessary 
and proper home, food, care and clothing, then said court may suspend 
sentence therein. 

Sec. 3. And provided further, that upon the failure of said husband 
or parent to comply with said undertaking, he or she may be 
arrested by the sheriff or other officer on a warrant issued on the 
precipe of the prosecuting attorney, and brought before the court for 
sentence, whereupon the court may pass sentence, or for good cause 
shown, may modify the order and take a new undertaking and further 
suspend sentence as may be just and proper. 

tSec. 4. Whereas an emergency exists therefor, this act shall be 
arce and effect from and after its passage and approval. </seg>



         </p>

		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>