<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ALFALFA INVESTIGATIONS</title>
               <date value="1926-12">1926-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN NO. 36 ALFALFA INVESTIGATIONS T. A. KIESSELBACH AND ARTHUR ANDERSON DEPARTMENT OF AGRONOMY LINCOLN. NEBRASKA ACCEPTED FOR PUBLICATION JUNE, 1926 DECEMBER, 1926 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS • Page Summary 5 Importance of alfalfa m Nebraska.... .■ 11 Introduction of alfalfa 12 Early history 12 Classification of varieties 13 The Common group 13 The Variegated group 13 ■ . ' The Turkestan group 13 The Non-hardy group , .'. 14 Field plat technique of these experiments.... 14 Plat size.. 14 Duration of tests i 14 Replication and check plats 15 Yields on uniform moisture and weed-free basis 16. Varieties and regional strains 16 Comparative variety tests..... 16 • Yield of hay per acre.....; 16 Physical characteristics 21 Flower color 21 Proportion of leaves 22 Coarseness and length of stem 22 Chemical composition 23 - Comparative crown and root development 23 Comparative test of regional strains of Common alfalfa 26 Yield of hay per acre 29 Yields from irrigated and non-irrigated seed 31 Physical characteristics . 31 Variation m winter hardiness 31 ' Summary of varietal and strain differences 35 Historical review— varieties and regional strains 36 . Comparative yields and hardiness 36 Plant characteristics..... 49 " Cultivation of alfalfa , 52 Yield of hay per acre.: ■. .'. 52 . Effect on plant development 52 Effect of the time of cutting upon the yield and quality of alfalfa hay 54 First experiment, 1915-1918...., „ 54 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">CONTENTS— (Continued) Page Second experiment, 1921-1925 54 Cutting stages 54 Yield of hay per acre 55 Proportion of leaves 57 Yield of seed per acre 57 Effect on plant development 57 Chemical composition of hay 58 Yield of feed constituents 63 Historical review — maturity stages 65 Effect of time of cutting upon yield 65 Relation of time of cutting to physical composition 66 Relation of time of cutting to chemical composition and digestibility 67 Kelation of time of cutting to plant development 68 The use of top dressing on alfalfa 69 Alfalfa-timothy mixture 71 Seeding practices , 71 General observations and recommendations 71 Experiment Station seeding tests during 1922-1925 74 Inoculation tests 75 Maintenance of alfalfa stands 76 Alfalfa m the rotation 77 Principles and practices involved m the curing of alfalfa hay 82 Variation m the moisture content of alfalfa at time of cutting.... 82 Moisture content of field-cured and air-dry alfalfa 84 Field curing tests 84 Experimental procedure 84 Results as to rate of curing 102 Results concerning transpiration as a factor m curing 104 Laboratory tests 109 Relation of the rate of curing to the weather 110 Curing practices m relation to quality of hay produced 110 Application of curing principles 11l Historical review — curing practices 112 Variation of moisture m growing alfalfa 112 Moisture content of field-cured and air-dry alfalfa 113 Relation of curing practice to curing rate 114 Curing practice m relation to quality of hay 114 Literature cited 117 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SUMMARY &gt; 1. Alfalfa appears. to have been introduced into Nebraska m 1875. Over 200,000 acres were reported as having been grown within the State m 1902. There has been a rather gradual increase m acreage since then to over 1,300,000 acres m 1925. 2. As a 3-year average, 1923-1925, Cossack, Baltic, Grimm, and Canadian Variegated yielded 13, 10, 5, and 3 per cent, respectively, more hay per acre than Nebraska-grown Common alfalfa, whereas Sand Lucern and Turkestan yielded 8 and 7 per cent less. Peruvian alfalfa, winterkilled practically 100 per cent during its third winter, and during the time that stands were comparable, it gave no indication of being superior to Common. In a parallel test including 20 regional strains of Common alfalfa, Spanish, yielding 29 per cent less than the Nebraska-grown Common used as check, and West Nebraska dry land, producing 7 per cent more than check, were the extreme yielding strains. Aside from the low yielding Spanish, differences m yield were not significant as long as stands were, comparable. 3. The use of a hardy and otherwise well adapted variety is a very important factor m the maintenance of an alfalfa stand under Nebraska conditions. Wide variation exists between the various varieties and strains m ability to withstand severe winter conditions. During the winter of 1924-1925 Peruvian winter killed almost com - pletely. Sand Lucern and Turkestan were slightly injured, while decided thinning occurred with the Argentine, Italian, and Spanish alfalfas. This winterkilling occurred m the established stands m field plats and m new seedings m the nursery. Some winterkilling was apparent with all the strains and varieties during the winter of 1925-1926, but was especially marked m the case of Sand Lucern. Nebraska-grown Common appeared to show a little more thinning than Cossack, Grimm, and Baltic. Southern-grown domestic strains showed measurably more thinning than the northern-grown domestic strains of Common alfalfa. 4. The variation m flower color of the variegated sorts was the most striking physical .difference observed between varieties. As a 3-year average for all cuttings, the proportion of leaves ranged from 44.9 per cent for the Common, to 47.9 per cent for the Turkestan. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 As a 3-year average for all cuttings, Common alfalfa was 23.4 inches high per cutting as compared with Turkestan with a height of 21.9 inches as the other extreme. Coarseness of stem as measured in 1925 ranged from 2.27 millimeters for Cossack to 2.49 millimeters for Sand Lucern. Detailed root and crown measurements of the Common, Cossack, and Grimm varieties did not show differences sufficient to permit of varietal classification. 5. Variations between cuttings were more striking than varietal or strain differences. As an average for the 7 varieties the yield of the first, second, third, and fourth cuttings was 43, 32, 19, and 6 per cent of the total annual yield. As an average for the same varieties the first, second, and third cuttings consisted of 39.7, 43.7, and 54.9 per cent leaves. Average stem diameters by cuttings were 2.97, 2.38, and 1.89 millimeters, respectively, for the first, second, and third cuttings. Corresponding plant heights were 27.0, 24.8, and 17.6 inches per cutting. The average protein content for the first, second, and third cuttings was found to be 16.84, 18.58, and 19.99 per cent, respectively. 6. Tillage of established stands of alfalfa with disk harrow, spring tooth harrow (alfalfa renovator), and ordinary harrow failed to in - crease yields. The most intensive treatment, that of the spring tooth harrow, after each cutting, reduced the yield 7 per cent as a 4-year average. When all plats were harvested uniformly without tillage treatment in the fifth year, those having had this treatment yielded but 81 per cent of the unfilled plats. 7. During the 5-year period there was a 30 per cent reduction in the number of plants per square foot on the unfilled plats as com - pared with 43 per cent reduction on the plats- receiving disk and spring tooth harrow treatments. There appeared to be no relation between tillage and plant development as measured by root diameters. 8. As a 4-year average alfalfa harvested at the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, half-bloom, full bloom, seed, and new growth stages yielded 3.00, 3.03, 3.35, 3.42, 3.19, 2.82, and 3.51 tons per acre, respectively. The proportion of leaves at time of harvest for these respective stages was 57.3, 56.6, 55.8, 53.2, 49.4, 33.3, and 52.8 per cent. There was measurable seed production from the seed plats in only one year out of four. 9. Harvesting alfalfa in relatively immature stages tended to thin the stand and retard root development. 10. As a 4-year average there was a rather gradual decrease in the protein content of the hay from 21.98 per cent in the pre-bloom stage to 18.13 per cent in the full bloom stage. This decrease in pro - tein was accompanied by an increase in crude, fiber from 25.13 per </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Alfalfa Investigations cent to 30.82 per cent. The ash content decreased from 11.24 to 9.36 per cent as maturity increased, whereas the slight variations in the nitrogen-free extract and fat contents did not appear to be associated with maturity. 11.- Averaging the composition of alfalfa hay harvested at 6 stages of maturity during a 4-year period, it is found that the stems con - tained 75, 43, 249, 91, and 46 per cent as much ash, protein, crude fiber, nitrogett-free extract, and fat respectively, as the leaves. The ratio of the protein content of the stems to that of the leaves remained prac - tically constant regardless of the stage of maturity. 12. The annual acre yields of protein as a 4-year average for the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, half-bloom, full bloom, and new growth stages were 0.552, 0.515, 0.541, 0.535, 0.482, and 0.546 tons per acre, respectively. Of the total protein in the hay, that con - tained in the leaves ranged from 75 per cent in the least mature to 70 per cent in the most mature stages. 13. The first, second, and third cuttings of the 6 maturity stages consisted of 48.7, 56:4, and 58.1 per cent leaves during the 4-year period. The respective protein contents of these cuttings were 18.96, 19.83, and 20.03 per cent. The protein percentage of the leaves of the first, second, and third cuttings was 27.80, 26.82, and 26.44 per cent as compared with 10.62, 11.29, and 11.73 per cent for that of the stems. 14. From the combined standpoints of acre yield of hay and feed constituents, quality of hay, and permanency of stand, it would seem that harvesting alfalfa approximately at the new growth stage should prove the most desirable practice. Under normal blooming conditions this. commonly falls between the tenth and half-bloom stages and the time to .cut may be judged by either the new growth or bloom. Frequent cutting in more immature stages is inadvisable. 15.. The application of either gypsum, sulphur, lime and sulphur, or lime as top dressings to an established stand of alfalfa failed to increase the yield. The application of barnyard manure at the Tate of 8 tons per acre each 4 years increased the yield 13 per cent As a 4-year average the following yields were secured; no treatment 3.64 tons per acre, gypsum 3.58, sulphur 3.53, lime and sulphur 3.73, lime 3.68, and barnyard manure 4.11 tons. 16. The yield of alfalfa and timothy seeded in combination was not materially more than that of alfalfa seeded alone. The first cutting of the season was the only one to contain a measurable amount of timothy. This practice is not recommended unless the mixed hay is considered especially valuable. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 17. Seeding practices should be adapted to local conditions. Favor - able seed bed and moisture conditions at seeding time and timely seed - ing will greatly enhance the likelihood of securing a stand. 18. Experiment Station and cooperative tests indicate that inocu - lation is seldom necessary in Nebraska. Its trial is recommended, however, where repeated failures to secure a stand have been ex - perienced. 19. Partial or complete crop failure frequently experienced fol - lowing the breaking up of alfalfa is primarily due to overstimulation. Crops in semi-arid or subhuniid regions commonly deplete the soil of its available moisture within the working depths of their root systems. For the common cereal crops this seldom exceeds the fourth or fifth foot, whereas with alfalfa it may be 15 feet or even deeper. 20. Under conditions where the subsoil moisture has been depleted, alfalfa should not follow alfalfa for a period of years or until a new reserve of moisture can be accumulated. It would seem, however, that alfalfa could advantageously be left growing under these con - ditions as long as it remains productive. Wherever corn or small grain follows alfalfa, in regions of moisture shortage, the use of practices which counteract the tendency for too large vegetative development are desirable. These may consist in the use of somewhat smaller varieties, thinner seeding, and listing rather than surface planting corn. The use of an intertilled crop seems more desirable since it permits control of the vegetative growth to a greater extent and is less subject to lodging. 21. Clean, fine-stemmed, leafy, sweet, and green-colored hay has superior market and feeding value. The last 3 of these qualities are closely related to curing practices. The rate of hay curing is con - trolled by the moisture content and character of the forage, the weather conditions prevailing during the curing period, and the method of handling. 22. As a 3-day average, the moisture content of growing alfalfa was found to be 2.7 per cent lower at 5 P. M. than at 8 A. M. The moisture content at time of cutting for alfalfa harvested in the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, half bloom, full bloom, seed, and new growth stages was 76,5, 74.3, 72.8, 71.8, 70.5, 60.0, and 72.8 per cent, respectively. 23. The moisture content of thoroly air-dry hay depends pri - marily upon the nature of the crop and the weather conditions. It will average about 11.4 per cent for alfalfa. The moisture content of field-cured hay is more variable. Hay containing 25 per cent moisture is considered sufficiently dry for placing in the stack or mow. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Alfalfa Investigations 24. Windrowing or cocking of relatively green or partially cured hay will materially prolong the curing period, and the time required to reduce the hay to a field-cured or air-dry condition is shortened as the period of swath curing is extended. As an average of 4 field-curing tests, 27 hours were required to reduce the moisture, content of hay curing in the swath to 30 per cent. Where hay was cured in the windrow and cock thruout, 65 and 102 hours were required to reach the same moisture content, respectively. Where swath curing to the " beginning to wilt ", " well - wilted ", and " two-thirds cured " stages preceded either windrowing or cocking, 50 and 53, 44 and 45, and 29 and 29 hours were required, respectively, to reduce the hay to a 30 per cent moisture content. 25. There, was no indication in tests covering a period of 5 years that the leaves functioned materially in the withdrawal of moisture from the stems during the curing period. In 487 comparisons of comparable samples of hay curing in the field with leaves intact and detached, it was found that the moisture content of the two kinds of samples differed one per cent or less 253 times, or in 52 per cent of the comparisons. In the remaining comparisons or those wherein the difference in moisture content was greater than 1 per cent, the samples with leaves intact had a somewhat lower moisture content than the corresponding samples with leaves detached in 117 cases, and a somewhat higher moisture content in an equal number of in - stances. The fact that alfalfa windrowed or cocked in a green or partially cured condition lost moisture more slowly than when cured entirely in the swath, is further evidence of the fallacy of a rather common opinion that such conditions prolong the normal transpiratory functioning of the leaves in the cut forage, thereby accelerating the rate of moisture loss from the stems. 26. Laboratory curing tests of normal hay and of hay with leaves detached indicated that the normal hay dried somewhat faster than the bare stemSj but when the curing of the stems and leaves are aver - aged the rate is almost identical with that of normal hay. 27. A very close relation was observed between weather conditions and rate of curing. Frequently, correlated weather conditions such as high temperature, sunshine, and wind, and low humidity are very conducive to rapid curing . 28. Drying of external moisture bears,, in general, the same rela - tion to weather conditions and method of curing as that of internal moisture, but usually takes place more rapidly. 29. Prolonged curing of hay beyond the field-cured condition resulted in increased loss of dry matter. As an average of 2 tests, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 90.7 per cent of the hay curing in the swath until field cured was recovered. That recovered when cured in the windrow and cock ranged from 99.9 to 94.5 and from 96.3 to 95.0 per cent, respectively depending upon the period of swath curing preceding windrowing and cocking. If swath cured hay were properly handled from the time it became about " two-thirds cured ", it would seem that the loss should not exceed 5 per cent as measured by these tests. 30. In regions where damage from rains may be expected, the best practice would seem to be to reduce the moisture content of the hay to a field-cured condition as rapidly as possible, without undue loss in quality and dry matter. In no case, however, should swath curing continue after the hay approaches a field-cured condition. Partial swath curing followed by windrowing before the leaves shatter may be regarded as the most effective and desirable procedure in gen - eral farm practice. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">ALFALFA INVESTIGATIONS T. A. KIESSELBACH AND ARTHUR ANDERSON The purpose of these alfalfa investigations has been to determine the relation of variety, source of seed, and cul - tural practice to the yield and quality of hay produced. Due to the high initial cost of seeding, the inconvenience and wastefulness of losing a stand prematurely, and the super - iority of properly-made hay, an understanding of these rela - tionships is very important. IMPORTANCE OF ALFALFA IN NEBRASKA Nebraska ranks first among all states m the acreage grown to alfalfa as reported m the 1924 Agricultural Yearbook of the United States Department of Agriculture. 1 The annual crop m this State during the 5-year period 1920-1924 has aver - aged 1,193,000 acres as compared with 9,599,000 acres for the entire United States. The production of alfalfa within the State has had a rather gradual growth during the last 25 years. In 1902, 207,000 acres were' reported m the Annual Report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture. The " average annual acreages for 5-year periods since then as compiled from similar reports m 1905 and 1908, and from Bulletin 123 of the Nebraska Department of Agriculture, have been 322,000 for 1903-1907, 687,000 for 1908-1912, 1,043,000 for 1913-1917, and 1,188,000 acres for 1918-1922. The great economic importance of alfalfa m regions where it is adapted lies m its large and unequaled yield of palatable, high-protein forage, and m its soil-building qualities. No com - bination of crops could be better suited for the extensive pro - duction of livestock than alfalfa, sweet clover, and corn, where these can be grown successfully. It is generally considered that alfalfa is better adapted to irrigated districts and to subhumid regions than to the more humid or arid localities. Thus m Nebraska approximately three-fourths of the acreage is found m the eastern one-half of the State. Nevertheless, the subirrigated valleys and irrigated districts m western Nebraska where the rainfall is relatively low are well suited to the growing of alfalfa. Without question the conditions m regions of relatively low rainfall are most favorable for the handling and curing of the hay crop. &gt; Complete reference to all papers cited may be found on pp. 117-125. ' . . ■ . ; v; : ■ . . </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 introduction of alfalfa According to Bassett (1916), alfalfa was first introduced into Nebraska in 1875 from Utah and during the early eighties it was being grown in several counties in the south - western part of the State. Bessey (1886) stated that " It has been sown repeatedly in many parts of the country east of the Rocky Mountains, but for some reason it has not come into general use even in those portions where the winters are not too severe for it." Bessey further stated at that time, before Nebraska conditions were fully understood, that much of Nebraska might be irrigated and that then red ciover, allalla, and the grasses would flourish as in the irrigated dis - tricts of Colorado Smith (1888) concludes from field tests by the Nebraska Experiment Station that " It is the best of the clovers ' tried by us." Bessey (1890) lists it as one of ■ .lL most P romine nt grasses and clovers for Nebraska and ... I? 6 , qu . otes ?• P- Baker of Curtis, Nebraska, who stated that he had received his first seed directly from San Francisco 17 years previous and that the field seeded at that time was still in vigorous condition. From a review of the literature it is apparent that alfalfa spread m this country from the West to the East. Altho it had been introduced into the Atlantic Coast States in earlier days, it did not maintain a recognized foothold in the United States until about 1850, when it was brought into California from South America. Early History.— According to Hendry, (1923), alfalfa is native to Mesopotamia. From there it was taken south into Arabia during the remote epochs of antiquity The first written reference to alfalfa was found in a Babylonian text of about 700 B. C. In the fourth century B. C, it was found in Greece. From there it was carried to Italy in about the second century B. C At the same time it was taken from that part of Asia which has since become Russian Turkes - tan, into northern China. In the meantime it was being carried out from the Roman Empire into southern Spain and to the Lucerne Lake region of Switzerland. In its subsequent dispersion thru Europe it was known as 'Lucern.' Accord - ll g £fl 0me a " thoritl J M it entirely disappeared from Italy in the fifth century and was reintroduced from Spain in the sixteenth century from where it spread to France and to </seg>
            <seg id="p013">I Alfalfa Investigations Germany in about 1573 and soon thereafter to England. Alfalfa was carried to South America during the fifteenth century, whence it was introduced to the United States. classification of varieties The commercially grown alfalfas are commonly classified in four groups. In case of the Common and Turkestan al - falfa, the group and variety names are synonymous, while in the variegated and non-hardy groups several rather widely recognized varieties are found. The Common Group includes the ordinary purple-flowered nonpubescent sorts. The alfalfa first brought under cultivation was probably of this type. Much of the alfalfa in the United States is of the Common variety, having spread from the Western States after its introduction into California from South America. According to Oakley and Westover (1916) " the term ' Common Alfalfa ' has been used to include all of the alfalfas that are not clearly of hybrid origin or that do not have fairly distinct and uniform varietal character - istics, even though within this group, what are known as ■ regional strains are coming to be recognized." The Variegated Group includes the alfalfas that are com - monly believed to have originated from a natural cross be - tween common alfalfa (Medicago sativa) and the yellow - flowered alfalfa (Medicago falcata). They are considered intermediate in form between these two varieties and they may always be distinguished by more or less variegation in the blossom. They are generally regarded as more resistant to low temperatures than Common alfalfa due to their in - heritance from the yellow-flowered parent. Grimm, Cossack, Baltic, Canadian Variegated, and Sand Lucern are repre - sentatives of this group. The Turkestan Group includes all the alfalfa of Turkestan origin. The original importations were thought to be hardy, due to the adverse conditions under which they had been grown for many seed generations. Within recent years, how - ever, the importations have included miscellaneous lots of seed, much of which has been produced under relatively favor - able conditions, so that now Turkestan seed is generally con - sidered inferior. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 The Non-Hardy Group includes alfalfas of southern origin, generally believed to be more susceptible to low temperatures than any of the other sorts. In the more temperate climates they may be characterized by long periods of growth and quick recovery after cutting. Peruvian and Arabian are the only two varieties of this group grown commercially to any great extent in this country. field plat technique of these. experiments Plat Size. — All yields determined in connection with these investigations are from one-twentieth acre field plats, being either 14 or 28 feet in width. For certain cultural studies, related only to the question of securing a stand and for which yield determinations were not desired, the plats were in a few instances reduced to a single drill swath, 7 feet wide. Fallow strips 1 foot wide have been maintained between plats, and the roadways at the ends of the plats were seeded to alfalfa or brome grass. Duration of Tests. — The plats dealing with tillage, top dressing, and stages of maturity were laid out in the spring of 1921 in a field of alfalfa which had been seeded in the fall of 1918. The plats comparing varieties and regional strains were seeded in the spring of 1922 (Fig. 1). Seedings for the miscellaneous cultural studies were first made in 1922 and continued since then according to the plan of the test. _____ " V*M ■ '-7.y. * " '._.- -./ '■ ■■^■; ,; &gt;;*_X.' ■"- - ..*.'■-■ "fV*'\- '__■__'____ r^F^sr v*a^______l____*f^^iiiSto_______t_t__H__K^ ■yL«*_ii ... - -^^^_^_^_^_mi^jg^MSL___1SZr^f._^m Fig. 1. — General view of field containing the varieties and regional strains of Common alfalfa seeded in the spring of 1922. Photo - graphed May 25, 1925. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Alfalfa Investigations Replication and Check Plats. — In tests where yield determ - inations were desired, the plats have always been in dupli - cate. In the variety tests, three of the more common sorts were replicated five times and the other varieties, excepting Peruvian, three times. Every fifth plat was used as a check, being seeded to Common alfalfa the seed of which was produced in west central Nebraska under dry-land conditions. Seedings were usually made in the spring of the year with - out nurse crops. Except in the method-of-seeding test, an ordinary press wheel grain drill with an alfalfa seeder attach - ment was used and seeding was at the rate of 20 pounds per acre, unless otherwise specified. Clippings were made as found necessary but yields were not determined during the first season. Except where otherwise required by the nature of the experiment, the alfalfa plats were ordinarily harvested at the new growth stage. This stage was determined by the rather definite appearance of new growth or shoots at the crown and usually occurred between one-tenth and one-half bloom. — ■ 7- ; : — 7-t- - -. : A _ j#i ________ Fig. 2. — Field weighings are made with a spring dial scale. As soon after weighing as possible a composite sample of hay is taken for moisture determination. Field weights are converted on the basis of this sample to hay containing 15 per cent moisture. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Yields on Uniform Moisture and Weed-Free Basis— All yields reported are on an equal moisture content basis. ' Plat weights were taken in the field with a spring dial scale (Fig. I t\u time of w^ hin ». a composite sample, of hay (a 2-bushel bag was usually filled) was taken from each variety iA Z treatment - Th ?se samples were run thru a small hand feed cutter, were well mixed, and then reduced in quan - tity (usually to 500 grams). These samples were placed in small cotton bags and dried in an electric oven to a moisture free basis The plat yields have been converted to JJ i per cent moisture content on the basis of these samples In those cases where the forage contained any consider - able amount of weed growth due to thinning as a result of winterkilling or other causes, the percentage of weeds was determined by weight and indicated as in Table 3. VARIETIES AND REGIONAL STRAINS COMPARATIVE VARIETY TESTS Eight varieties, representing the four commercial groups, were seeded at the Nebraska Experiment Station under conV parable conditions in the spring of 1922 in order to measure their relative hardiness, productiveness, and the quality of forage produced. The seed of Common alfalfa had been pro - duced in west central Nebraska under dry land conditions, and was seeded in every fifth plat as a check. The seed of the other seven varieties was secured thru the Office of Forage Sj?S_i nV Tft &amp; n ° nS ? .h United sta tes Department of Agri - culture The Cossack, Grimm, and Turkestan varieties were replicated five times; the Baltic, Canadian Variegated and Sand Lucern were seeded in triplicate, and the Peruvian in YIELD OF HAY PER ACRE The yields reported in Table 1 are weighted on a percent - che'ckf Thr^ -ir With th u e average of the cnecKs. Ihree cuttings were harvested in 1923 and 1924 and four cuttings in 1925. As a 3-year average, 1923-1925! the following yields of hay in tons per acre were secured • Common, 5 36; Cossack, 6.08; Baltic, 5.9 2 ! Grimm 5 62 •' Canadian Variegated, 5.53; Sand Lucern, 4.94 ranT Turkes' So' l°3° So 8 1 P 05 fo^QP^Tor^ - la tive a yTelds were iuu, na no, 105, 103, 92, and 93 per cent. With the excen tion of the Canadian Variegated in 1923, the yields have been </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Alfalfa Investigations Table 1.— Comparative yields, physical characteristics, and chemical composition of alfalfa varieties, 1923-1925 Com- Canadian Sand Turk- Peru - mon Cossack Baltic Grimm Var. Lucern estan vian YIELD OF HAY PER ACRE WITH 15 PER CENT MOISTURE CONTENT Annual yields Actual (tons per acre) 1923 4.33 4.83 4.76 4.37 4.08 8.94 4.24 4.45 1924 6.83 7.77 7.49 7.44 7.09 6.48 6.41 6.11 1926 4.92 6.64- 6.61 6.05 5.42 4.41 4.'5 ' Average 6.36 6.08 5.92 6.62 6.53 4.94 5.00 Relative (Pct.) - 1923 100 112 110 101 94 91 98 103 1924 100 114 110 109 104 95 94 89 1925 100 115 112 103 110 90 88 Average 100 113 110 105 103 92 93 Yield by cuttings, 3-yr.av. Actual (tons per acre) 1st cutting,..: 2.16 2.72 2.60 2.37 2.37 2.05 2.14 2nd cutting 1.13 1.95 1.92 1.83 1.75 1.60 1.55 3rd cutting 1.11 1.05 1.04 1.05 1.08 0.96 1.00 4th cutting 0.37 0.36 0.36 0.37 0.33 0.33 0.31 Relative, inter-var. 1st cutting 100 127 121 110 110 96 100 2nd cutting 100 113 111 106 101 92 90 3rd cutting 100 95 94 96 97 86 90 4th cutting 100 97 97 100 89 89 84 Relative, inter-crop All cuttings 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 1st cutting 40 45 44 42 43 42 41 ... 2nd cutting 32 32 32 32 32 32 SI 3rdcutting... 21 17 . 18 19 19 19 20 4thcutting ....I 7 I 6 I .6 7 6 7 6 ... PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS Per cent leaves, 3-year av. 1st cutting 39.6 40.6 37.6 40.2 38.1 41.0 40.9 2nd cutting 42.8 43.2 43.2 44.9 43.6 43.3 44.1 3rd cutting 51.7 56.5 51.6 56.0 51.8 54.0 57.6 Allcutttnga 44.9 46.6 45.3 47.2 46.0 46.1 47.9 Stem diam., 1925 (mm.) lBt cutting 2.67. 2.81 S.17 3.13 2.90 3.12 3.00 2nd cutting. ... .: 2.22 2.29 2.54 2.38 2.39 2.46 2.18 3rd cutting 1.86 1.71 1.87 1.92 1.90 2.03 1.9. All cuttings 2.29 2.27 2.47 2.45 2.40 2.49 2.40 Plant height, 3-yr.av. (in.) 1st cutting 27.5 27.0 27.1 26.8 27.3 26.7 26.9 2nd cutting 25.4 24.5 24.8 24.8 21.7 25.5 2 1.2 3rd cutting 18.6 17.1 17.5 17.3 18.0 18.2 16.3 AH cuttings 21.4 22.4 22.7 22.5 22.8 23.1 21.9 Variegated Mowers (Pet.) 0 55.3 50.4 48.0 41.7 35.0 0 0 CHEMICAL COMPOSITION (MOISTURE-FREE BASIS)i Crude protein conte_t(Pct ) Annual 1923 15.60 17.16 17.60 17.95 17.60 17.60 18.16 15.80 1924 17.10 17.70 17.60 17.37 17.90 17.93 18.53 18.77 1925 19.10 19.93 19.27 20.20 20.00 19.00 19.30 Average 17.27 18.26 18.12 18.51 18.60 18.18 18.66 By cuttings, 3-yr. av. lstcutting 16.03 16.47 16.30 17.6T 17.43 17.27 16.81 2nd cutting 17.60 18.18 18.43 18.55 19.57 18.83 18.93 3rd cutting 18.67 20.90 20.47 19.83 19.93 19.00 21.18 Fodder analyses, 3-year average (Pet.) Ash 10.16 9.86 10.21 10.39; 10.48 10.02 10.15 Crude protein 17.27 18.26 18.12 18.61 18.50 18.18 18.66 Crude fiber 33.68 32.49 32.87 31.91 32.00 3257 3157 Nitrogen-free extract... 36.36 36.76 36.22 36.64 36.41 36.72 36 62 Fat 2.53 2.64 2.68 2.65 2.61 2.81 3 00 ... 'AH chemical analyses reported in these investigations were made for the Agronomy- Department under the direction of Dr. M. J. Blish, Station Chemist. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebk. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 fairly consistent thruout the period. Further confidence is had in these results when the actual average yields during the 3-year period are compared with the corrected yields as presented in Table 1. The greatest variation of the actual from the corrected yield was 3.8 per cent, while the average variation for the 7 varieties was found to be 1.8 per cent. P0UQQ_{ 1ZO0C _^M — — — - — H im LEAVES = BBS STEMS = Chart 1. — Comparative hay yields of alfalfa varieties together with their proportionate yields of leaves and stems, 3-year average, 1923 - 1925. (Table 1.) It should be borne in mind, however, that in this experi - ment only one strain of each variety was grown; and even tho care was taken to use alfalfa typical of the variety, these results should not be considered as an absolute measure of varietal differences. Attention is called to Table 3, where an extreme variation of 11 per cent in yield was found between domestic strains of Common alfalfa. As a group </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Alfalfa Investigations t ■. the 5 variegated varieties averaged 5 per cent more in yield than Common. With the exception of three varieties Sand Lucern, Turk - estan, and Peruvian, the stands have been quite comparable during the period for which yields have been reported. Peruvian was entirely winterkilled during the winter of 1924 - 1925 (Fig. 3) ; but during the preceding 2-year period when stands ' were comparable, it gave no indication of being superior to Common. Sand Lucern and Turkestan were lUlii ■___!__•' fltt___ jrW w'^tM JK Fig. 3.— Nebraska-grown Common alfalfa at left and Peruvian alfalfa at right, seeded May 16, 1922. Both varieties seemed equally good during 1923 and 1924, but the Peruvian winterkilled almost com - pletely in the winter of 1924 to 1925, while the Nebraska Common ' was uninjured. Photographed May 25, 1925. slightly thinner at the outset, but the difference was not con - sidered great enough to affect the yield. The stand of Turk - estan was slightly reduced and that of Sand Lucern was materially reduced, however, during the winter of 1924-25, and in 1925 the stand of the latter was only 73 per cent of the average for the other six varieties. Again during the winter of 1925-26 the stand of Sand Lucern was further re- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 duced and in 1926 averaged less than one-third of that of the other varieties (Fig. 4). Some winterkilling during the winter of 1925-26 was also observed on all other plats but appeared somewhat more marked with the Common and Canadian Variegated than with the other varieties. Good stands remain, however, and differences in yield due to this thinning are not anticipated except in the case of Sand Lucern. ta^_ _________^ '.___• _______-_______-__* -___-ft-7 _____ _Ki_*______ ._________________$____ Fig. 4. — Canadian Variegated alfalfa on the left, Sand Lucern in the center, and Common alfalfa on the right. Seeded May 16, 1922, and photographed September 2, 1926. The stand of Sand Lucern was - materially thinned during the winter of 1924-1925 and again during 1925-1926. The weeds in the foreground of the Sand Lucern plat have been pulled in order to show the actual stand of alfalfa in con - trast with the adjacent plats. A further comparison of Common and the 4 variegated varieties, Cossack, Baltic, Grimm, and Canadian Variegated, which averaged 8 per cent more than the Common, show their average yield by cuttings to be 117, 108, 95, and 96 per cent of the Common for the first, second, third; and fourth cut - tings, respectively. When the yield of the different cuttings is compared with the total yield, it is found in the case of the </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Alfalfa Investigations Common that the first, second, third, and fourth cuttings have produced 40, 32, 21, and 7 per cent, respectively, of the total yield, whereas with the 4 variegated varieties the first; second, third, and fourth cuttings have yielded 44, 32, 18, and 6 per cent of the total. This would suggest that since there was no apparent varietal difference in time of maturity the variegated sorts are slightly better adapted to and make more of their growth during the early part of the growing season. physical characteristics Flower Color. — No very striking individuality in appear - ance or physical characteristics was observed among the 8 varieties studied. The most pronounced difference between groups was the limited fall growth of Turkestan (Fig. 5) and the variation in flower color of the variegated sorts. ,.„__. _SP__ -_ v ______ r i____r__r V W .__!_____ _________________ ______ _M _F_J__r_H-___-___ '____ Fig. 5. — Cossack alfalfa on the extreme left, Turkestan in center, and Common on right. Turkestan, is slower to recover and makes much less growth after the removal of the last cutting in the fall. Photo - graphed October 23, 1924. Altho the purple flower is the predominating type in varie - gated alfalfa, light colors including greenish or yellowish tints and even pure white or yellow make up a considerable </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 per cent of the total. The amount of variegation varies with the variety, the cutting, and weather conditions. Ordinarily it is much more apparent with second and third cuttings. Counts made from these two cuttings of the variega - ted sorts showed Sand Lucern to have 35 per cent variega - tion and Cossack 55 per cent as the two extremes. Proportion of Leaves. — The proportion of leaves by weight was determined on a moisture-free basis for all cuttings of each of the varieties. As a 3-year average, it was found at time of harvest that Common had 44.9 ; Cossack, 46.6 . Baltic, 45.3; Grimm, 47.2; Canadian Variegated, 46.0; Sand Lucern, 46.1 ; and Turkestan, 47.9 per cent leaves, respectively. These varieties were always harvested and sampled on the same day. With the exception of Turkestan, which was a number of days later blossoming, they usually appeared to be in com - parable stages of maturity when harvested. The difference in maturity will account in part at least for the higher pro - portion of leaves in the Turkestan. As an average of all varieties the first, second, and third cuttings consisted of 39.7, 43.7, and 54.9 per cent of leaves, respectively. Coarseness arid Length of Stem. — Measurement of stem diameters was made for the 7 varieties in 1925. One hundred random selected stems from which the leaves had been stripped in the above test were used. The extreme difference in the average stem diameters between the varieties was 0.22 millimeters or approximately 10 per cent. As an average of all cuttings for the 7 varieties, the uncured forage had an average stem diameter of 2.40 millimeters. Average stem diameter by cuttings for all varieties was 2.97, 2.38, and 1.89 millimeters for the first, second, and third crops, respectively. The extreme difference in average plant height per cutting between the varieties at the time of harvesting was 1.5 inches as a 3-year average. The average plant height for all cuttings and varieties was 22.7 inches. Average plant height for all varieties by cuttings was 27.0. 24.8, and 17.6 inches for the first, second, and third cutting, respectively. Tendency to lodge in the case of heavy first cuttings was more apparent with the variegated varieties than with the other sorts. Altho these data fail to show any marked or consistent varietal differences with respect to leafiness, coarseness of stem, and plant height, they do show an increase in the leaf - iness and a decrease in coarseness and length of stem with successive cuttings. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Alfalfa Investigations chemical composition Complete fodder analyses of the hay were made during the three-year period, 1923 to 1925, for each cutting of all vari - eties. A summary of these determinations on a moisture - free basis is included in Table 1. No very striking varietal differences were found. The 5 variegated sorts averaged 18.31 per cent protein compared with 17.27 per cent for Common and 18.66 per cent for Turkestan. As an average of all varieties, the protein of the first, second, and third cuttings was 16.84, 18.58, and 19.99 per cent, respectively. These variations in protein percentage are in the main asso - ciated with differences in the proportion of leaves. As a 3-year average for all varieties and cuttings the hay contained 10.18 per cent ash, 18.21 per cent protein, 32.40 per cent fiber, 36.52 per cent nitrogen-free extract, and 2.69 per cent fat. comparative crown and root development A comparative study was made of the crown and roots of Common, Grimm, and Cossack alfalfa. Approximately 300 3-year-old plants of each variety taken from 4 replicate plats of the foregoing variety tests were measured in each case. Most excavations and measurements were made to a depth of 1 foot below the crown. In one case, however, a trench 42 feet long and 5 feet deep, across 3 adjacent plats . seeded to these varieties, was opened for measuring and photographing to a greater depth (Figs. 6, 7, 8, and 9). Typical roots of plants one year old and of seedling plants are shown in Figs. 10 and 11 for Common, Grimm, and Cossack alfalfa. In a number of instances, the root systems were very care - fully worked out to a depth of 18 inches in order to show the great abundance of small fibrous roots. (Fig. 12). The measurements and observations reported in Table 2 fail to show any very striking differences in the character of the crowns or root systems. The Cossack variety made the greatest departure from the Common, which it exceeded 22 per cent in number of crown branches, 13 per cent in width of crown, 5 per cent in depth of crown, and 12 per cent in the number of forage stems per crown. The Grimm variety surpassed the Common 9 per cent in the number of crown branches and 8 per cent in width of crown; but did not exceed it in crown depth or number of stems produced. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 _____________^_ ... '_ -— w—a^— — imbkiI __t ___. »___M __^__i ______ ___. '■FT -^'■►Si-S Fig. 6— The trench which was opened across adjacent plats of Common, Grimm, and Cossack alfalfa for measuring and photographing their roots to a depth of 5 feet as shown in Figs. 7, 8, and 9. Photo - graphed October 23, 1924. \m _■■ wMi __________ '■_§? I Fig. 7. — Exposed roots in a trench 5 feet deep within a plat of Common alfalfa seeded May 16, 1922. Photographed November 11,' 1924. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Alfalfa Investigations Fig. 8. — Exposed roots in a trench 5 feet deep within a plat of Grimm alfalfa seeded May 16, 1922. Photographed November 11, 1924. __3___E.'v__l _____ bCti __(___ __P£_r_rM reS____iL___: '_-I^W^ ____! __■ lv_____B______i___ SmK_2 H BfX_______. __S____cS^^'.'jMlSinT8__B -__r_-W_B IIIIB Fig. 9. — Exposed roots in a trench 5 feet deep within a plat of Cossack alfalfa seeded May 16, 1922. Photographed November 11, 1924. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 These 2 variegated varieties had slightly finer tap and branch roots and about 8 per cent more of the roots were branched than with the Common. In the case of the Grimm and Cossack, however, the roots that were branched had measurably more branches per root. Very few of the tap - roots of any variety were forked, and it is doubtful if the small differences in favor of the Common is very significant. Tabu: 2.— Comparative crown and root development of Common, Grimm, and Cossack alfalfa} Variety and average number o! plants Measurement measured Common-316 Grimm-33. Cossack-294 Relatite Relative Relalixe Crown Number o/ crown branches 2.46 100 2.69 109 3 01 122 Depth of crown (inches) . 1.34 100 1.32 99 141 105 Width of crown (inches) 1.57 loo 1.70 108 177 113 Stems per crown' 3.72 100 3.59 97 4.16 112 Root* Diameter (inches) At base of crown- . 0.343 100 0.320 93 0.337 98 1 foot below crown . 0.165 100 0.151 92 0.152 92 2 leet below crown&lt; 0.123 100 0.114 93 0.118 96 3 feet below crown. 0.101 100 0.096 95 0.090 89 4 leet bei iw crown 0.080 100 0.074 93 0.071 89 Depth to first fork or root branch (inches) 2.83 100 2.27 80 2.11 75 Forked roots per 100 plants 9.29 ... 3.36 6 21 Maximum diameter of forked roots (inches) 0.367 100 0.355 97 0.330 90 Maximum diameter of root forks (inches) 0.186 100 0.189 102 0 177 95 Branched roots per 100 plants 20.59 ... 27.49 28.85 Root branches per plant 0.32 100 0.48 150 0^52 16. Diameter of root branches (inches) 0.105 100 0.094 90 0.088 81 Relative flbrousness of roots' 'S-year-old plants. Seeded in Bpring of 1922. 'Stems per plant produced during last crop of season. ■Unless otherwise stated, root measurements are for the upper 12 inches. In case of root branches, only those .05 inch or over in diameter were counted. Roots approxi - mately equally divided were classed aa forked. 'Root diameters taken below 1 foot in depth are for fewer numbers. Accurate measurements and counts of the smaller and more fibrous root branches was not undertaken because of the difficulty in extracting the root system in its en - tirety. Close observation, however, of the above roots as excavated and of a few care - fully worked out root systems failed to show, a measurable varietal difference in relative root nbrouBness. While the fibrousness of the various root systems was strik - ing, there was no apparent difference in this regard for the various varieties. An abundance of nodules were found on the roots of all sorts. COMPARATIVE TEST OF REGIONAL STRAINS OF COMMON ALFALFA A test including Common alfalfa from 20 different sources * was run parallel with the preceding variety test for com - parison as to growth characteristics and possible differences </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Alfalfa Investigations i ■ ■• Fig. 10. — Typical plants of Common alfalfa (left), Grimm (center), and Cossack (right). Seeded September 6, 1924, and photographed November 30, 1925. in hardiness and productiveness. The same strain of Com- - mon alfalfa as used in the variety tests was seeded every fifth plat for checking results. The other nineteen strains were grown in duplicate plats. Five of these strains were of foreign origin. The domestic strains included local seed from each of the series of states extending from North Dakota to Texas and from Montana to New Mexico inclusive. Four of the strains in addition to the check were from Nebraska. Two of these were from Dawson County where they were thought locally to have special merit, while the other two were produced respectively under dry land and irri - gated conditions of extreme western Nebraska. Both dry land and irrigated seed was' included from Wyoming and the one strain from New Mexico had been produced under irri - gation. Otherwise the domestic strains were all of dry land origin. Seed of these regional strains of alfalfa was secured either from the Office of Forage Crops Investigations of the United States Department of Agriculture or thru Experi - ment Stations in the states concerned. Effort was made to </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Fig. 11. — Typical seedling plants of Common alfalfa (left), Grimm (center), and Cossack (right). The plants above were from seed - ings made August 24, 1925, and those below from seedings made September 15, 1925. Photographed November 30, 1925. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Alfalfa Investigations secure seed of known origin and which had been grown for a number of seed generations under the specified environmental conditions. The yields, weighted by check plats, are shown in Table 3. Table 3. — Comparative yields of regional strains of Common . alfalfa, 1923-1925 Average Yield ot hay per acre with 15 per cent moisture content Source of Seed height , 1 1 per 1923 1924 1925 Average cutting Inches Tons Rela- Tans Rela- Tons Rela- Tom Rela - ' lire tile tite lite Nebraska (Lincoln Co.) 23.7 4.76 100 7.18 100 4.90 100 5.61 100 Russia 23.1 6.14 108 7.31 102 6.32 109 5.92 106 Italy' 24.1 5.80 111 7.80 102 3.76 77 6.45 97 France (Provence) 22.0 4.71 99 6.67 93 4.83 99 5.40 96 Spain' 22.2 3.46 72 4.87 68 8.72 76 4.01 71 Argentina' 233 6.02 105 7-36 103 3.37 69 535 94 North Dakota 23.8 4.69 99 7.33 102 4.84 99 6.62 100 South Dakota 23.5 4.90 108 7.28 101 4.98 102 5.72 102 Nebraska (Dawson Co.) 23.6 4.76 100 6.90 96 4.73 97 5.46 97 - Nebraska (Dawson Co.)&lt; 23.4 5.04 106 6.98 97 5.09 104 5.70 102 West Nebr. Dry Land.. 23.7 6.19 109 7.69 106 6.15 105 5.98 107 West Nebr. Irrigated... 23.9 5.21 109 7.56 105 5.02 102 5.93 106 Kansas .23.6 5.34 112 7.63 105 4.87 99 5.91 106 Oklahoma 23.8 4.27 90 7.15 100 6.61 114 6.68 101 Texaa 23.5 4.29 90 7.17 100 6.69 114 6.68 101 Montana 23.5 4.83 101 7.12 99 5.13 105 5.69 101 Wyoming, Dry Land... 23.5 4.73 -99 7.38 103 6.12 104 6.74 102 Wyoming, Irrigated.... 23.6 5.02 105 6.65 93 5.07 103 5.58 99 Colorado 23.0 4.65 98 6.87 96 4.72 96 6.41 96 New Mexico, Irrigated . 23.4 5.30 111 7.53 105 4.86 99 5.90 105 ■Due to considerable thinning thru winterkilling (1924-1926), the fourth crap of the Italian. Spanish, and Argentine alfalfas contained a high percentage ot weeds in 1925. This cutting comprised 29, 28, and 80 per cent respectively of the season's yield for these 3 strains and consisted of 40, 87, and 68 per cent weeds. Stand counts made In the fall of 1925 showed the Italian, Spanish, and Argentine alfalfa* to have but 48, 70, and 61 per cent as many plants per square foot as the adjacent check Plata of Nebraska Common. There waa no apparent winterkilling with the other -trains. 'Grown in Dawson County as Turkestan. In these tests it could not be distinguished from Common Alfalfa. YIELD OF HAY PER ACRE The comparable forage yields of these regional strains as reported in Table .3 are on a basis of 15 per cent moisture content. As an average of the 3-year period 1923-1925, the yields ranged from approximately 4 tons per acre for Spanish to 6 tons for Western Nebraska seed. If we allow 5 per cent deviation from the check for the experimental error of the test, little dependable difference in productivity of the strains has yet been indicated by these' experiments aside from the inferior production of Spanish/ Italian, and Argentine seed. Even these strains, except the Spanish, yielded satisfactorily </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Fig 12.— Extreme types of alfalfa roots. It was found that 21, 28, and 29 per cent, respectively, of the Common, Grimm, and Cossack plants had branched roots. Note the large numbers of finer branches and nodules obtained by careful excavation. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Alfalfa Investigations until the last year, when thinning out by winterkilling re - sulted in a material reduction in their yield and in rather weedy hay during the latter part of the season (Figs. 13, 14, and 15). During the winter of 1925-26 further winterkilling occurred in these 3 strains as well as in all others. This thinning of stand was sufficiently greater on the plats seeded to alfalfa from Colorado, New Mexico, Oklahoma, and Texas, that a reduction in their yield is expected in 1926 as well as a further reduction in yield for that from Argentina, Spain, and Italy. Based on the results of this test to date and on experiences in more northern states, it is to be ex - pected that winterkilling in these southern and less hardy strains will increase and that they will lower relatively in yield as time goes on or as more severe winter conditions arise. It appears from the data at hand that, aside from the factor of winterkilling, all of these strains, except Span - ish, possess nearly equal producing capacity. Yields from Irrigated and Non-Irrigated Seed. — Compar - able samples of seed grown under dry land and irrigated conditions in Nebraska and Wyoming were tested. There was practically no difference between the seed from either State and as an average for both States the dry land seed yielded 2 per cent more hay than the irrigated seed. PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS There were no striking differences in the appearance of these 20 strains of Common alfalfa. Those from Italy, Spain, Argentina, and France usually appeared somewhat lighter green in color. The strains from Russia, Argentina, Italy, and France made a somewhat slower and shorter growth after the last cutting of the season was removed. This differ - ence was not so apparent at other times of the season. On the other hand, the strain from Spain was quicker to start after each cutting and usually made more late fall growth. There was no material difference in average height per cutting except in the case of the French and Spanish alfalfas, which averaged 1.7 and 1.5 inches shorter per cutting than checks. ■ VARIATION IN WINTER HARDINESS Winter killing in these tests has ranged from a very slight to a complete loss of stand. Where winter injury has occurred, some of the affected plants may start growing in the spring but show weakness and continue to die thruout </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 the season. Such results may sometimes be confused with the effects of drought and disease. That there is a difference between varieties and regional strains of Common alfalfa in winter hardiness has been borne out by the results from the field plats previously dis - cussed, and by similar results from comparable seedings of the same alfalfas in nursery plats in the fall of 1924 and again in 1925 (Fig. 16). In 1925 these nursery seedings were made at 2 dates — normal and later than normal. In comparison with the more hardy sorts, the less hardy winter - killed relatively much more at the later seeding date. 1 _____\__M.'^ ji— , VB^^^^nUs^BUmUUtSitrj&amp;ti^yEfsmKsi W*_ _•■• ll&gt;. i-'&lt;MfflKMM__r Fig. 13. — Left to right: (1) Spanish-grown, (2) French-grown (Prov - ence), and (3) Italian-grown seed of Common alfalfa; seeded May 16, 1922. The Spanish and Italian strains winterkilled severely in the winter of 1924 to 1925. Photographed May 25, 1925. Since the same 4 alfalfas winterkilled severely during the winter of 1924-25 and again in 1925-26, whether in new seedings or established two-year and three-year old stands, and since a number of other sorts winterkilled materially in 1925-26, it would appear that more severe conditions in the future may indicate a further difference in the relative winter hardiness of the varieties and strains. All of these estab- </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Alfalfa Investigations lished plats as well as new duplicate seedings of the same seed are being continued in a further effort to measure inher - ent differences in hardiness as well as in production. A new series of field plats has also been seeded to Grimm alfalfa obtained from various sources for similar observation. Waldron (1919) has shown that natural cross-fertilization in alfalfa is rather frequent. This fact suggests that a variety or strain will not remain constant for any great number of seed generations. Thus alfalfa of the same origin, when sub - jected for a number of generations to two widely different environments, may develop into two distinct regional strains thru the principle of survival of the fittest. There are no data available to show the occurrence of such changes but it is probable that natural as well as control selection following hybridization have been very potent fac - tors in variety and strain differentiation. Such differences are largely a matter of degree. '_(__ '■; . ■" ___ At^ t ■ ,-. . _. ._. aa, *__■- i_i_. 1 *i^ _t_4\. ___ _________ -*"&gt;,»" .... ______ •- ___________ JHHk^^.d^A^ v \__^__i _____^^_jH_ _____t&gt;V' ' -__-__* ■%__'' *_Wiri _u ___t. ■•JE. HI _^_a B____'_a_l __■ Fig. 14. — Argentine seed of Common alfalfa at left and Nebraska Common at right, seeded May 16, 1922. The Argentine seed has proved unhardy for Nebraska conditions, winterkilling severely in the winter of 1924 to 1925. Photographed May 25, 1925. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Just to what extent and how rapidly such natural selection may effect the hardiness of a strain of alfalfa has not been determined. In view of all available information, it would seem advisable to use seed that has been grown for at least several seed generations under climatic conditions fully as severe as where it is to be planted. r ________ ilt__i *— iii'i Fig. 15. — Argentine seed of Common alfalfa at left and Nebraska-grown Common at right, seeded May 16, 1922. The same plats as shown in Fig. 14. Photographed September 21, 1925, to show the weed growth in the fourth cutting of the Argentine. Since the better established variegated varieties such as Grimm and Cossack have originated and passed thru the natural selection of climatic conditions more severe than those obtaining in Nebraska, it seems reasonable that they should be among the hardiest alfalfas suitable for our conditions. They have been unsurpassed in hardiness and yield in these tests, and general observations point to some superiority under the more severe winter conditions. On the other hand, the data available indicate that the local and more northern strains of Common alfalfa are also relatively hardy and pro - ductive for average Nebraska conditions, and it may be ques- </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Alfalfa Investigations tioned whether one would be. justified in paying a large premium for seed of the variegated sorts when seed of the former is available. Since an extensive demand exists for recognized hardy alfalfa seed, especially of several variegated varieties such as Grimm and .Cossack, and since their seed yield is satisfactory, more extensive use of these sorts seems advisable where seed is grown. Fig. 16. — Nursery test of alfalfa varieties and regional strains showing winterkilling in winter of 1924 to 1925. . Seeded September 6, 1924. Extreme left to right: (1) North Dakota-grown Common, (2) Argentine, (3) Spanish, (4) Nebraska-grown Common, (5) French (Provence), (6) Italian, (7) Russian, and (8) extreme right, Peruvian. The winterkilling results in this nursery test were identical with those of the field plats seeded in 1922. Photographed May 25, 1925. - SUMMARY OF VARIETAL AND STRAIN DIFFERENCES The results obtained at this station are in the main in accord with those reported elsewhere. Based on all infor - mation, the following broad conclusions seem justified. Alfalfa is being grown in large areas where severe winter - killing is frequently experienced. Wide variation exists in the ability of the various groups, varieties, and regional strains to survive these adverse environmental conditions. The inherent physiological differences associated with this varietal variation in winter resistance have not been estab - lished. . It has been shown conclusively that alfalfas of the non - hardy group are unadapted to regions having severe winters. On the other hand, these non-hardy sorts can be expected </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 to yield most wherever they are adapted. It is also apparent that there is a wide range in the hardiness of regional strains of Common alfalfa which becomes progressively more hardy thru acclimatization as conditions become more severe. The exact comparative winter resistance of the various h\rdy strains has not been fully determined. There seems to be no question but that the most hardy alfalfas available com - mercially are found within the variegated group. All varie - gated alfalfas, however, cannot be considered hardier than some strains of the Common. Grimm and Cossack appear to be among the hardiest commercially available. Indications are that there may be some slight difference in the plant characteristics and hardiness between strains of these vari - eties It is also apparent that yellow-flowered alfalfa (Medicago falcata) is able to survive even more severe win - ters than the hardiest variegated sorts. Such varieties as Grimm and Cossack will produce as much or more hay per acre than most strains of Common alfalfa. Whenever winterkilling becomes a serious factor the varieties or strains best able to survive such conditions will prove most productive. • Dat m„ as to P h y sical characteristics are somewhat conflict - ing, l he variegated alfalfas, however, can be readily reco_ nized by the variation in their flower color. Varieties and strains may also differ somewhat in the amount of earlv spring and late fall growth and in their renewal of growth after cutting. The differences in crown and root develop - ment of the various commercial varieties is too small to ner - mit classification in this respect. HISTORICAL REVIEW '-VARIETIES AND REGIONAL STRAINS COMPARATIVE YIELDS AND HARDINESS r a Hforn^ d rn. itch r k v (1904) ?? eded alfa,fa from A "^na, California, Colorado, Kansas, Utah, and Nebraska nt tho Nebraska Experiment Station in 1898. Th Alfalfa frlm Arizona and California killed out almost entirely during S_ winter of 1898-1899, that from Colorado was severely .njured whereas that from Utah and Kansas suffered more loss £ tha from Nebraska-grown seed. There was no f Srther S until 1902-1903, when that from Arizona aJd CalifoiS regional .train*, (2) maturity _ta„e_ and 111 , !_SlJ " ame1 .. (1) Varieties and review, immediate,. rO.ow the related*' »b_Ut"i.^"„ K__^;JM..' tm </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Alfalfa Investigations entirely disappeared and the Colorado, Utah, and Kansas alfalfa suffered further injury. Conclusions drawn were " not to bring alfalfa seed from a southern to a more north - ern region or from an irrigated to a non-irrigated soil." Wheeler and Balz (1907) report that seedings made at Highmore, South Dakota, in 1905 of Montana, Oasis, Arabian, Turkestan, and Tripoli alfalfas winterkilled during the fol - lowing winter 5, 100, 75, 5, and 100 per cent, respectively. The Montana, Arabian, and Turkestan yielded 2960, 2560, and 3060 pounds per acre, respectively, in 1906. Mackay (1909) reports yields secured at Indian Head, Saskatchewan, Canada, in 1905 as follows: Turkestan 8,840 pounds, Utah 8,080, and Common 7,122 pounds per acre. During the following winter the Utah alfalfa was entirely killed out and the other two were considerably thinned. Six crops were harvested from 1906 to 1909 from these latter two, the Turkestan yielding 2,895 pounds per cutting and the Common 2,508 pounds. A seeding was made in May, 1905, of Utah, Southern Mon - tana, Commercial, Grimm, Peru, New York, Turkestan, Ne - braska, and Northern Montana seed. The Utah, Southern Montana, Commercial, Peru, and Northern Montana alfalfas were entirely killed out in the spring of 1906. The New York, Turkestan, and Nebraska alfalfas were greatly injured, whereas the Grimm came thru perfectly. A third seeding was made in the spring of 1908 of Grimm, Idaho, Montana, dry land, French, and Turkestan alfalfas. The following respective yields were reported for 1909: 5,308, 5,400, 5,830, 7,303, 5,480, and 7,388 pounds per acre. Westgate (1909) reports acre yields for 1907 and 1908 at Pullman, Washington, as follows : Sand Lucern 6,163 pounds, Turkestan 5,358 pounds, and ordinary 5,783 pounds. The following yields produced without irrigation are also reported for 1908 at Great Falls, Montana: Canadian 7,505 pounds, Sand Lucern 6,425 pounds, Turkestan 5,490 pounds, Kansas Variegated 5,430 pounds, and Nebraska dry land 4,700 pounds. At Dickinson, North Dakota, in 1909 the first cutting of Sand Lucern yielded 1,826 pounds as compared with 1,411 for Grimm, 1,179 for Turkestan, and 1,173 pounds for Utah. Brand and Waldron (1910) concluded from a series of tests begun at Dickinson, North Dakota in 1906 "that em - ployment of good tillage, the use of a suitable strain of seed, </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 and the character of the winter weather are the controlling factors in successful alfalfa production in the Northwest." Early dormancy in the fall, deeply set crowns, and the ability to put out new roots and reestablish after breaking of the taproot seemed correlated with winter hardiness. Westgate (1910) in summarization of all available infor - mation to date, with reference to variegated alfalfas con - cludes : " The studies of the somewhat isolated instances of especially hardy alfalfa fields have shown that these relatively hardy strains agree quite closely among themselves in their botanical characters and differ noticeably in a number of characters from the ordinary western grown alfalfa. The investigations recorded in this bulletin have indicated that the primary explanation of the hardiness of these strains is that they possess a small percentage of the blood of Medi - cago falcata in their ancestry. " The preliminary comparative field tests of the different variegated alfalfas are of too short a duration to make definite conclusions possible as to their relative value. The tests in - dicate, however, that under very severe conditions the Sand Lucern, while much hardier than ordinary alfalfa, is some - what less hardy than Grimm alfalfa which has been success - fully produced in Minnesota for fifty years." Brand (1911) found a marked difference in winterkilling between Grimm and Commercial or ordinary alfalfa from seedings made in 1901, 1902, 1905, 1906, and 1907 at St Anthony Park, Minnesota. When these results are averaged for the 5 seedings, it is found that the winter loss in the Grimm during the 2 following winters was 13.9 per cent whereas that for the commercial and ordinary alfalfa was 69.3 per cent. iq^ xte i n f tl rai T W T.-? ee 2l d , at Tappen - North Dakot *» 1905. At the close of the fifth season, in 1909, the per cent of stand as estimated for Montana, Nebraska, Kansas, Colo - rado, Utah, Texas, and Grimm seed was 90, 85, 85, 60 20 5 and 90 per cent respectively. Many of the same strains were also seeded at Dickinson, North Dakota, where the same jren - eral results were obtained. Snyder and Burr (1911) concluded from a series of tests S r "}* 18 strains and varieties of alfalfa at the North Flatte, Nebraska, Substation during the period 1906 to 1910 that under conditions that have prevailed during the past </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Alfalfa Investigations six seasons no one regional variety has shown any great superiority over others. Nebraska-grown seed has produced the most alfalfa. The varieties behave differently as regards freezing and recovery after cutting, but, as noted, the yields thus far have been quite uniform." Hume and Garver (1912) concluded from 3 series of tests conducted at Brookings, South Dakota, in 1908-1911, 1909 - . 1911, and 1910-1911 : " For the conditions of this test, Turk - estan, Utah, French, Montana, Texas, Nebraska, New York, (Non-irrigated) , Grimm, or Sand Lucern proved equally pro - ductive of hay." At the Highmore, South Dakota, Substation during the 6 - year period 1905-1911, two strains of Turkestan averaged 2,684 pounds per acre as compared with 1,938 pounds for Arabian. Oasis and Tripoli winterkilled in 1905-1906. Dur - ing a 4-year period, 1908-1911, at the same station, Turk - estan averaged 1,910 pounds per acre as compared with 1,472 pounds for an average from 3 plats of Baltic. During a 3 - year period, 1909-1911, Kansas alfalfa averaged 1,460 pounds per acre as compared with 1,017 for Turkestan, 1,220 for German, and 960 pounds for Grimm. Cook (1916) states that in West Virginia "the Grimm, Baltic, and other hardy strains of alfalfa have not proved superior to the Common northern-grown seed except in re - spect to seed production." Hume and Champlin (1916) obtained the following acre yields as a 3-year average, 1913-1915, for the 4 South Dakota Stations: Vale (S. D. 22) 2565 pounds, Grimm 2532 pounds, and Turkestan 2527 pounds. Kansas Non-irrigated, Turkestan, Vale, Montana, and Nebraska proved to be the most productive varieties as deter - mined in several variety tests at Brookings. Turk - estan, Kansas, and Grimm each ranked first in hay production in a series of 3 tests at the Highmore Substation, whereas at the Eureka Substation Vale was the most productive of hay, from 1913-1915, and Turkestan at the Cottonwood Sub - station during the same period. Parsons (1916) reports average yields (1911-1915), for alfalfa grown under irrigation in Wyoming as follows: Turk - estan 3.90 tons per acre; Sand Lucern 3.67; Grimm 5.25; Provence, France, 3.31; Utah seed 3.10; German seed 3.90; Dry-grown seed 3.53; Montana seed 4.56; and Native seed 4.38 tons per acre. . It will be noticed that the Turkestan, </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Sand Lucern, Grimm, and Montana varieties stood nearly the same for the first two years. The winter of 1912-1913 was very severe on alfalfa,, and all of the varieties except the Grimm were winterkilled in varying degrees." Voelcker (1916) found at the Woburn (England) Experi - ment Station that as a 4-year average (1912-1916) Russian (Europe) alfalfa gave the highest yield of hay followed in order by Provence, Canadian, North American, Russian (Asia), American (Arizona), and Turkestan. Brooks and Gaskill (1917) (Massachusetts) state, "It has not been our experience that the Grimm variety is any more hardy than the common alfalfa produced from good northern - grown seed." Hughes (1917) states for Iowa conditions that "there is practically no difference in the yield of hay secured from Dakota, Nebraska, and Kansas seed. The Oklahoma seed did not yield quite so well as that produced farther north while the irrigated seed from Utah made a considerably lower yield." Dakota and Montana alfalfas have withstood severe winters better than Nebraska and Kansas grown, whereas under these more severe conditions alfalfas from Oklahoma and Utah have almost entirely killed out. The Grimm and Baltic varieties, while not appearing superior to the imported alfalfas in hardiness, are deemed superior to them because of their high-yielding qualities. Jenkins (1917) reported 4-year average yields (1913-1916) in Connecticut of 4.39, 3.76, 3.92, 3.84, 3.65, and 3.40 tons per acre respectively, for Grimm, Sand Lucern, Kansas, Provence, Utah, and Turkestan alfalfas. Miller (1917) at the Morris (Minnesota) Station reports the following average yields during a period of 4-years: Kansas 2.89 tons per acre, Baltic 3.10, Grimm 3.35, Nebraska 2.57, Dakota 2.40, and Improved Turkestan 2.78. Winter - killing as an average of 3 seasons was reported as 15.9, 3.04, 1.66, 30.97, 26.39, ahd 0 per cent, respectively. It is stated in the Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Sta - tion Report (1917) that during the winter of 1915-1916 nine plats of different strains of northern-grown alfalfa showed on the average 55 per cent winterkilling and yielded 3,840 pounds of cured hay per acre in 2 cuttings in 1916, as com - pared with 2 southern-grown strains which winterkilled 52 per cent and yielded 4,470 pounds; one Turkestan winter - killed 31 per cent and yielded 5,540 pounds, while 4 varie- </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Alfalfa Investigations gated strains (Grimm and Baltic) winterkilled 27 per cent and- yielded 6.Q45 pounds. It is further reported; "The so - called ' hardy alfalfas,' the seed of which was derived from 25 to 35 year old fields in Montana and Dakota, did not show any more resistance toward winterkilling or superiority in yields to the common strains from these states." Blair (1918) reports hay yields (when averaged for 1915 - 1917) for the Yuma Experiment Farm as follows: Peruvian, 3.70; Chilian (Common), 3.14; Arabian, 2.17; and Grimm, 2.12 tons per acre. Holden (1918) at the Scottsbluff (Nebraska) Recla - mation Project Experiment Farm obtained total yields under irrigation during the 2-year period 1916-1917 of 9.39, 9.07, 8.92,. 8.71, 8.45, 8.08, and 6.93 tons per acre, respectively, for Baltic, Grimm, Kansas, Black Hills, Can - adian, Turkestan, and Native alfalfa. "All seemed to with - stand the winters equally well." Kiesselbach (1918) reports 2-year average yields at the Nebraska Experiment Station of 5.4, 5.5, and 5.5 tons per acre, respectively, for Nebraska Common, Grimm, and Turk - estan alfalfa. Boss (1919) in Minnesota stated that "Plats sown to Grimm alfalfa in 1914 yielded three crops during the season of 1918. Common alfalfa sown on adjacent plats was entirely killed out." Knight (1919) as an average for 1917-1918 in Nevada obtained yields of 5.99, 5.85, 5.07, 4.99, 4.88, 4.87, and 4.86 tons per acre, respectively, for North Dakota, Australian, Baltic, Nevada 38, France, Grimm, and Nevada (check) alfalfas. Moore and Graber (1919) conducted tests in Wisconsin with 16 samples of common seed from growers in New Mexico, Arizona, and California and showed that Common .seed produced in these states was less hardy and more sub - ject to winterkilling when grown in Wisconsin than Kansas seed or Common seed produced farther north. On the other hand, trials made. with 40 samples of Kansas and Nebraska - grown Common, in comparison with 20 samples of Montana and South Dakota-grown seed, showed practically no differ - ence in hardiness. It was evident, however, that variations in hardiness of different alfalfas from the same region are to be expected. The most winter resistant alfalfas thus far </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 found for Wisconsin conditions are the Grimm, Baltic, and Cossack. The Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station Annual Report (1920) states that the total yields secured during the 6-year period, 1915-1920, from Grimm alfalfa were 20.8 to 22.5 tons per acre, and the yields from Montana Common were 13.1 to 18.7 tons. Miller (1920) reports from the Morris (Minnesota) Sta - tion : " There was no winterkilling in any of the varieties of alfalfa in the winter of 1919-1920. * * * In 1917 and 1918, winterkilling was very severe with most varieties, Minne - sota Grimm, Baltic, and Turkestan coming thru with the best records. Grimm alfalfa and Turkestan also showed highest yields for 1920. The results of these tests tend to show that permanent fields of alfalfa, even with hardiest varieties, are not yet a reality." Zavitz (1920) of Ontario reports average acre 'yields in tons for a ten-year period (1910-1919) as follows: 3 Grimms, 3.60; 2 Ontario Variegateds, 3.20; 1 Baltic, 3.12; 9 European Variegateds, 3.11; 1 Mongolian (violet-flowered) 3.04; 1 Turkestan, 2.97; 10 Sand (Variegated) 2.87; 1 Ontario Com - mon, 1.81; 1 Montana Common, 1.68; 4 Commons (Utah, Colorado, Nebraska, and Kansas) 1.11; and 1 Texas Com - mon, 1.00. These same alfalfas were space-planted at the time they were seeded in field plats and the following . counts made: Per cent of plants living in 1914 (5 years after seeding) was found to be 68, 82, 72, 42, 92, 39, 42, and 22 per cent respec - tively for the Grimm, Ontario Variegated, Baltic, European Variegated, Mongolian, Turkestan, Sand, and Cornmon as compared with 25, 16, 11, 4, 64, 10, 3, and 0 per cent in 1919 or 10 years after seeding. In another test (1911-1918) Grimm, Sand, and Common averaged 4.3, 4.1, and 1.4 tons per acre. During the first year of the test Grimm yielded 5.3 tons per acre as com - pared with 4.1 for the Common whereas during the last year the respective yields were 2.9 and .03 tons per acre. In still another seeding made in 1912 and replicated 7 times, average yields (1913-1919) for Sand (Germany), Ontario Variegated (Ontario) , and Grimm (Minnesota) were re - ported as 3.27, 3.46, and 3.68 tons per acre, respectively. Damon (1921) obtained yields of 3.05, 3.55, and 3.49 tons per acre for Grimm, Canadian, and Montana Dryland alfalfa as a 2-year average, 1914-1915, in Rhode Island. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Alfalfa Investigations Getty (1921) reports yields as a 4-year average (1916 - 1919) for western Kansas as follows: Canadian Variegated, 1.12; Kansas Common (3 plats averaged), 1.06; Baltic, 1.19; Grimm, 1.08; Utah non-irrigated, .97; Utah irrigated, .92; and Black Hills (South Dakota), 1.01 tons per acre. "The stands of all varieties were excellent and remained so during the tests." In the Iowa Agricultural Experiment Station Report (1921) , it is stated that " A large number of varieties and strains have been compared. Turkestan alfalfa has been found to be as hardy as Grimm, but gives much lower yields. It has been found possible to make four cuttings of Grimm alfalfa in an average season, while not more than three can be made safely with Common varieties, because of the greater winter hardiness of the Grimm. There seems to be little difference in the value of alfalfa strains from the Dakotas, Nebraska, and Kansas. Seed from Utah, Mexico, and Okla - homa is of much lower value than that from the Dakotas, Nebraska, and Kansas." The Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station (1921) reports that "In the fall' of 1920, a number of strains of varieties of alfalfa were sown in order to determine their relative value for Kentucky. The hardy strains, Grimm, Dakota, etc., yielded much more heavily than the common strains in 1921. This was due to the severe freezes in late March and early April, which injured the Common alfalfa very greatly but scarcely injured the hardy strains. As such freezes as this do not often occur, it is not safe, of course, to conclude that the hardy strains are decidedly superior for Kentucky." Miller (1921) states that at the Morris (Minnesota) Sta - tion "Twenty-three varieties have now been growing con - tinuously for seven years in the trial grounds. * * * Dur - ing the seven years these varieties and strains have shown a wide variation in hardiness. Not a single strain has been immune from winterkilling in severe seasons." Bean (1922) obtained the following yields of hay per acre in 3 cuttings from a 1-year-old stand produced under irrigation in Washington: Kansas Common 7.6 tons, Dakota Common 7.2 tons, Canadian Variegated 6.6 tons, Peruvian 6.6 tons, Baltic 6.5 tons, Grimm 6.2 tons, and Turkestan 4.2 tons. In a 2-year comparison Dakota Common yielded 7.1 and Turkestan 5.3 tons per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Forbell (1922) found as an average of counts made in October, 1916, on 20 newly seeded fields of Grimm alfalfa and 21 of Common alfalfa in northern Minnesota, 91.8 plants per square yard for the former and 111.6 for the latter. Counts made in May, 1917, showed 91.6 plants per square yard for the Grimm, as compared with 69.0 for the Common, j Megee (1922) found in Michigan that "Plats seeded to Arizona grown Common alfalfa and Hairy Peruvian alfalfa also winterkilled badly and the yield was much lowjer than that secured from Hardigan, Grimm, and the Common from Idaho, Montana, and Dakota." Noble (1922) states that during 1919 and 1920 a number of varieties tested at the Yuma Reclamation Project ranked approximately in the following order as to yield per acre and adaptability. Hairy Peruvian, Smooth Peruvian, India, Arizona Common, Kansas Common, Turkestan, Grimm, and Baltic. The last four failed to make satisfactory growth during the hot summer months and the plats soon became infested with Bermuda grass and sand burs. The Oregon Agricultural Experiment Station (Umatilla Branch Station) (1922) reports that " Grimm, which yielded 6.66 tons, was the highest yielding variety. Common-grown from local seed producing 6.49 tons, was next." The grow - ing of Grimm, except for seed production, was not advised. The Pennsylvania Agricultural Experiment Station (1922) reports that " The stands on many of the plats of alfalfa varieties seeded in June, 1918, are becoming quite thin and blue-grass is rapidly crowding out the alfalfa. The strains of the hardy group have maintained their stands better than the common alfalfas with the exception of the common strains from Kansas and California. " All of the hardy strains have yielded better than the common strain used for check, while only the California - and Kansas-grown strains of Common have yielded better than check." During 1919-1921, Baltic, Cossack, Grimm, and C_ilifornia - grown Common averaged annually about 1,000, 800, 600, and 500 pounds more hay per acre than the check. j Anderson (1923) obtained the following average acre yields in Virginia during the period of 1917-1919: Common alfalfa, 4,267 pounds; Grimm, 4,540 pounds; Turkestan, 3,500 pounds; and Baltic, 4,417 pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Alfalfa Investigations The Turkestan plats soon became infested with weeds and grass. The other varieties remained comparatively free from foreign material until the end of the third season. King (1923) states that at Sacaton, Arizona, " Over 100 varieties from all parts of the world have been tested and repeated experiments have demonstrated the superiority of the Hairy Peruvian for hay production." Quesenberry (1923) reports average yields of 6.541, 4.918, 5.091, and 4.429 tons per acre, respectively, for Hairy Peru - vian, Native, Grimm, and Turkestan alfalfa grown under irrigation in New Mexico during 1921 and 1922. The Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station (1923) reports tests by Graber and Nelson indicating significant differences in the killing of greenhouse alfalfa plants of the Grimm, Turkestan, and Common varieties, when exposed to a -4° F. temperature in December and January. Common winterkilled to a much greater extent than either Grimm or Turkestan, 84 per cent of the Common being killed as com - pared with 18 per cent for the Grimm. Winterkilling in the field was very severe for all strains, being 100 per cent for the Common and 84 per cent for the Grimm. Numerous tests have shown that new seedings of alfalfa are much hardier than old stands and that late fall cutting under adverse conditions increases winterkilling. Woodward (1923) reports the following 9-year average acre yields obtained at the Judith Basin, Montana, Substation during 1913-1921: Northern-grown 2,228 pounds, Grimm 2,099 pounds, Kansas Irrigated 2,050 pounds, Utah Irri - gated 2,028 pounds, Turkestan 2,002 pounds, and Sand Lucerne 1,857 pounds. Results for the 4-year period, 1918 - 1921 were as follows: Grimm 2,110 pounds, Montana Com - mon, 2,092 pounds, Canadian Variegated 2,011 pounds, Lis - comb 1,960 pounds, Baltic 1,944 pounds, Black Hills 1,937 pounds, Utah non-irrigated 1,839 pounds, Utah Irrigated 1,781 pounds, and Kansas 1,772 pounds per acre. He con - cludes: "Results obtained * * * indicate that there is not sufficient difference in yield between the variegated alfalfa and the hardier strains of the common group to make this a factor of any considerable importance in selecting alfalfa for thisregion. " In localities where alfalfa is subject to winterkilling, preference should be given to variegated alfalfas such as </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Grimm. As a rule alfalfas belonging to the variegated group are more resistant to cold and drought than the common alfalfas." Dalton (1924) states for New York conditions that: " Not until the Grimm variety was produced was there any sort of alfalfa known that was not greatly affected by the cold and unfavorable winters of this state. * * * There are other in - troduced and selected varieties, such as Baltic, Cossack, and Ontario variegated, that are hardy but in tests nif&gt;ne have proved superior to Grimm for the cold humid climate of New York State." The Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station (1J924) re - ports that " Eighteen varieties and regional strains were sown in duplicate in one-twentieth acre plats on the Agron - omy Farm. Good stands were secured in most cases and no winter injury occurred. In 1923 Grimm produced 3.95 tons per acre, the highest yield of any variety. Cossack produced 3.80 tons per acre, Italian 3.69 and Kansas Common 3.27." Kirk (1924) reports the following average yields (1916 - 1924) for alfalfa grown in cultivated rows in Saskatchewan, Canada: Grimm 5643 pounds per acre; Baltic 5892, Cossack 4885, Canadian Variegated 3247, Turkestan (5 strains) 4923, and Falcate (8 strains) 4494 pounds per acre. Oakley and Westover (1924) have reported average yields as follows: 1913 to 1922 at Moccasin, Montana, Grimm 2,132 pounds per acre; Northern-grown Common 2,249, Kansas 2,070, and Turkestan 2,035; 1917 to 1922 at Havre, Montana, Grimm 426 pounds per acre, Northern-grown Common 327, Kansas 285, and Turkestan 304; 1918 to 1922 at Sheridan, Wyoming, Grimm 2.274 pounds per acre, Northern-grown Common 1,948, and Kansas 2,044; and 1916 to 1922 at Red - field, South Dakota, Grimm 3,685 pounds per acre, Northern - grown Common 3,101, Kansas 2,993, and Turkestan 3,187. Piper (1924) compares the yields of 2 variegated alfalfas, 1 Turkestan and 4 common alfalfas when grown from 4 to 9 years in from 2 to 6 locations. When the results from 5 sta - tions (Redfield, South Dakota; Moccasin, Montana; Sheridan, Wyoming; Hays, Kansas; Connecticut Experiment Station or Wyoming Experiment Station) averaging 5 years per sta - tion are averaged together it is found that Grimm yielded 4379 pounds per acre compared with 4017 for Northern Com - mon ; 3924 pounds per acre as compared with 3540 for Kansas Common, and 5680 pounds per acre as compared with 4169 for Utah alfalfa. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Alfalfa Investigations Piper also reports the reduction in stand from 1916 to 1920 at Redfield, South Dakota, as follows: Grimm 21.1 per cent, Baltic 34.9, Kansas 83.6, Utah Irrigated 95.3, Utah non - irrigated 95.2, Dakota 66.9, Dakota 49.3, and Canadian Variegated 52.6. Reduction in stand by years ranged as fol - lows: 1916-17, from 0 to 5 per cent; 1917-18, 1.2 to 27.5 per cent; 1918-19, none; 1919-20, 19.0 to 94.2 per cent. Aune (1925) compared 3 strains of common alfalfa, 4 variegated sorts, and a selection of Turkestan, when grown under irrigation during 1916-1918 at Belle Fourche, South Dakota. No obvious difference occurred in winterkilling and there was no material difference in yield. The 3 strains of common averaged 3.62 tons per acre, whereas the 4 varie - gated varieties averaged 3.80 tons. The 3 strains of common alfalfa seemed a little later in starting in the spring and the yield of the first cutting was somewhat less. Georgeson (1925) states for Alaska conditions that: "The yellow-flowered sOrt (Medicago falcata) is the only hardy alfalfa that so far has been found." " In 1919 for example, the varieties Grimm, Cherno, North Swedish, and Semipalatinsk were tried at the Fairbanks Sta - tion, but either died or so deteriorated in vigor as no longer to justify their occupation of the ground. M. falcata, on the other hand, has maintained itself, and is ripening seed." " The stations have repeatedly experimented with com - mon alfalfa but since it invariably winterkills, no further trials will be made, with it." Kiesselbach and Anderson (1925) found Peruvian, Argen - tine, Italian, and Spanish alfalfa to be especially unhardy under Nebraska conditions. Miller (1925) at the Morris Substation (Minnesota) obtained the following yields in 1925 from a series of seedings made in 1924: Grimm, 3.77 tons per acre; Cossack, 3.65; Hardigan, 3.25; Ontario Variegated, 3.05; Baltic, 3.46; and Northern-grown Common, 3.07 tons. Even, uniform stands were secured in all cases.- Tinline (1925) in Canada reports the results of 3 separate tests as follows: (1) Average yields for 1924 and 1925, as obtained from 1923 seedings, were, — Canadian Variegated, 5.23 tons per acre; Cossack, 5.23; Macsel, 4.85; Grimms, 4.65; Liscomb, 4.79; Turkestan, 4.35; Common, 4.79; Can - adian Variegated, 4.51; and Baltic, 4.49. Per cent stands in 3925 were 87, 88, 70, 80, 93, 75, 90, 85, and 77 per </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 cent, respectively. (2) Results for 1925 secured from 1924 seedings were: Canadian Variegated, 3.28 tons per acre; Cossack 3.50; Macsel, 3.65; Grimms, 3.72; Grimms, 3.55; Liscomb, 2.69; Turkestan, 3.47; Canadian Variegated, 3.62; Baltic, 3.55; and Montana, 3.10. Per cent stands in 1925 were 90, 90, 83, 98, 88, 90, 95, 97, 99, and 92 per cent, respec - tively. (3) The following yields were reported as a 4-year average: Baltic, 5.06 tons per acre; Grimms, 4.85; Macsel, 4.80; Montana, 4.53; Liscomb, 4.51; Turkestan, 4.43; Cos - sack, 3.50 ; and Canadian Variegated, 3.32. Towle (1925) reports the following 6-year average (1918 - 1923) acre yields at the Sheridan (Wyoming) Field Station: Grimm, 2,386 pounds; locally-grown seed, 1,972 pounds; and Kansas-grown seed, 2,122 pounds. There was no material difference in winterkilling or drought resistance. Sylven (1925) states that in Sweden, Ultuna, a selection of a blue and yellow alfalfa cross, has shown itself to be the most winter-resistant of several varieties in different local - ities. In central Sweden it compares favorably in produc - tion with Grimm, but in southern Sweden it cannot compete with French Blue (common), Grimm, Cossack, and other varieties. Grimm alfalfa obtained from various sources showed wide variations in yield. Amy (1926) reports average yields in tons per acre for 5 separate tests in Minnesota as follows: 1913-1916, Minnesota Grimm, 5.42 tons; Montana Grimm, 5.19; and Turkestan Common, 4.74 ; 1914-1917, Minnesota Grimm, 4.77 tons; Montana Grimm, 4.52; Turkestan Common, 3.76; Kan - sas Common, 3.90; and Nebraska Common, 4.17; 1915-1919, Minnesota Grimm, 4.03 tons; Montana Grimm, 3.90; Turkes - tan Common, 2.14; Kansas Common, 2.38; and Nebraska Common, 2.76; 1923-1925 (tests conducted at University Farm, Waseca, and Crookston averaged), — Grimm 3.74 tons; Cossack, 3.82 ; and Northern Grown Common, 3.80 ; and total yields for 1924 and 1925 as follows: Grimm, 7.60; and Com - mon alfalfas as follows: Idaho, 7.28; New Mexico, 7.64; Kansas, 5.93; and Argentine (S. A.), 6.26. Cox and Megee (1926) report as a 4-year average (1922 - 1925) the following yields in Michigan: Hardigan (Michi - gan), 5.95 tons; Grimm (Idaho), 5.75; Grimm (South Dakota), 5.53; and Common alfalfas from Montana, Kansas, North California, Utah, and Idaho, 5.34, 5.29, 5.23, 5.05, and </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Alfalfa Investigations 4.69 tons per acre respectively, and Spanish (Spain), 3.55, Hairy Peruvian (Arizona), 1.75, and Common (Arizona), 1.69 tons per acre. About the same results are reported for somewhat similar tests for the years 1923-1925 and 1924-1925. The variegated sorts in still another seeding in 1924 with - stood the winter in excellent condition with stands of 95 to 100 per cent whereas the South American alfalfas suffered so heavily from winterkilling that they were not worth leav - ing. Overpeck and Conway (1926) report relative yields of 100, 71, 70, and 60 per cent, respectively, for Hairy Peruvian, Common, Grimm, and Turkestan alfalfa tested during the period 1921 to 1925 in New Mexico. PLANT CHARACTERISTICS Blinn (1911) of Colorado observed differences in root, crown, and stooling habits of hardy and non-hardy strains. He concludes: " The fact is the hardy strains of alfalfa have spreading crowns with underground root stocks and shoots with buds which are protected by soil from winter freezing. " The non-hardy strains of alfalfa have more upright stool - ing crowns with the bud areas very near the surface exposed to winter freezing, thawing and drying out." The Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station (1917) states: "The common strains of alfalfa usually make a succulent fall growth, whereas the variegated strains become dormant earlier in the fall after the third cutting. The im - ported Turkestan also possess this characteristic even to a more marked extent. " Comparative tests of 34 different strains have been made on two and three year old growths, and it does not seem possible to connect any very direct relation between the hardi - ness of the branched root plants in comparison with those which possess a taproot system. The observations made show that all of the principal varieties or strains of American grown alfalfa have both types of root systems." Cox (1919) (Michigan) states that "The variegated strains such as Grimm, Baltic, and Cossack are character - ized by closely set and branching crowns, and by greater development of roots with a tendency toward branching. This type of crown and root does not heave or winterkill as badly as the straighter rooted and higher crowned common alfalfa." </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Knight (1919) found that North Dakota, Australian, Bal - tic, Nevada 38, France, Grimm, and Nevada (check) strains of alfalfa consisted of 38.0, 32.2, 39.9, 37.4, 40.6, 40.0, and 38.8 per cent leaves, respectively. Zavitz (1920) compared Grimm, Ontario Variegated, Bal - tic, European Variegated, Mongolian, Turkestan, Sand, and Common alfalfa grown in Ontario. As a 6-year average 34, 19, 36, 29, 3, 1, 29, and 1 per cent variegation was observed for these varieties, respectively. The respective comparative early spring growth during 7 years was as follows: 96, 94, 91, 93, 48, 84, 100, and 64 per cent. Southworth (1921) concluded from observations and in - vestigations that the capacity of alfalfa to withstand severe winter conditions depends very largely on its root system. Plants possessing a branched root withstand winter heaving much better than those having only single taproots of what - ever length. Garver (1922) conducted field studies at various times between 1914 and 1920 of the root systems of Peruvian, Poona, southern- and northern-grown Common, Turkestan, Grimm, and yellow-flowered alfalfas when grown in rows at Redfield, South Dakota. Difficulty was found in obtaining comparable data in the older fields whenever there was a marked difference in hardiness, since it is believed that the more susceptible plants were winterkilled and those remain - ing were unduly favored. Factors tending to produce modi - fications of taproots in alfalfa are soil, climate, cultural treat - ments, and injuries. The root systems of the Peruvian and Poona of one season's growth are characterized by small, upright crowns and dis - tinct taproots with few branches and fibrous roots. All common alfalfas have distinct taproots. The northern grown strains have somewhat broader crowns and exhibit more of a tendency to throw out branches and fibrous roots but in both instances this difference is more pronounced than in the Peruvian and Poona varieties. Grimm alfalfa is characterized by broad, deep set crowns and numerous branch and fibrous roots. Rooting rhizomes are well-developed. Turkestan alfalfa has a root system very similar to that of Grimm. The yellow alfalfas exceed all others in having a broad, deep-set crown and an abundance of branch and fibrous roots. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Alfalfa Investigations Dalton (1924) states that " Common alfalfa has a long tap root from which the lateral roots branch out, while Grimm alfalfa has a more spreading root system, similar to that of an elm tree, which helps to prevent heaving." The Iowa Agricultural Experiment Station (1924) states that " During the past year extensive studies were made on alfalfa roots, giving special attention to comparisons of differ - ent varieties * *' * Our studies indicate that under Iowa con - ditions there is very little difference in the character of the root of the common alfalfa as compared with Grimm, Baltic, and Cossack. The hardy varieties" showed a slightly greater percentage of plants with divided taproots, but the difference was not sufficient to be used in variety identification." Carlson (1925) in New York, studied the effect of soil structure on the development of alfalfa root systems. Grimm, South Dakota and Kansas Common, Siberian, and Baltic were compared. The field plat experiments were of 29 months' duration, the tank experiment 12 months' and water cul - ture 6 weeks'. " The results show that in compact soil all varieties and strains developed branch roots, while in open soil the tap roots predominate; that Grimm alfalfa is characterized by broad deep-set crowns, and numerous fibrous roots; that the northern and southern grown common alfalfas have similar root features, small high set crowns and few fibrous roots; that the Baltic and Siberian compare favorably with the characteristics of the Grimm alfalfa; that the distinctive characteristics of alfalfa roots do not develop until after three to four months of normal growth; and that the results of water culture experiment substantiate those obtained under field conditions. " This would seem to indicate that Grimm and common as representatives of the hardy and non-hardy alfalfas, respec - tively, have inherent root characteristics and that the nature of the soil structure determines the degree of root branch - ing." McCool (Michigan) (1926) as an average of 7 determin - ations in 1924 and 1925 found the tops of Grimm, Cossack, and Common alfalfa to contain 4.23, 3.99, and 3.86 per cent nitrogen, respectively, as compared with 2.38, 2.10, and 2.03 per cent nitrogen in the roots (average of 9 determinations). </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 cultivation of alfalfa Tillage of an established stand of alfalfa has been fre - quently advocated as a means to stimulate growth of the crop and to destroy weeds. A series of comparative tests was started in 1921 to determine the effects, upon stand and yield from cultivation by means of a disk harrow, a spring tooth harrow (alfalfa renovator), and an ordinary smoothing harrow. The details of treatment and the results for the 5 - year period, 1921 to 1925, are shown in Tables 4 and 5. All treatments were in duplicate on twentieth-acre plats in a field of well-established alfalfa seeded in 1918 and having an almost perfect and uniform stand. Production from 1922 to 1925 was relatively low, due to moisture shortage. This condition was intensified by the rainfall being below normal much of the time, by considerable run-off due to the gently sloping character of the field, and by the heavy production of hay during 1919-1921. Yield of Hay per Acre. — As a 4-year average, 1921-1924, the plats receiving no cultivation averaged 3.39 tons per acre. In comparison, 3 different disk harrow treatments averaged 3.22 tons, the 3 spring tooth harrow treatments averaged 3.31 tons, and the ordinary harrow treatment 3.37 tons. No manner of tillage increased the production. Different results might, perhaps, be secured in an old field where the stand has become thinned and where weeds are a factor. When all the plats were harvested uniformly in 1925 without further treatment, there was no marked difference in yield excepting that where the spring tooth harrow had been used after each crop the yield was but 81 per cent of the untilled plats. Effect on Plant Development. — It is of interest to note the. effect of disk and spring tooth harrow cultivation upon the stand and root development of the alfalfa (Table 5) . Quadrat counts and measurements were made in 1925 for 12 repre - sentative locations within each plot. Comparable observa - tions had been made in 1921. The plants were counted after being cut off just below the crown, and the root diameters were measured at the point of severance. The number of plants per square foot has been calculated and they have been classified into several groups according to their root diam - eters. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Alfalfa Investigations Table 4. — The effect of tillage treatments upon the yield of alfalfa hay, 1921-1925 Yield ol hay per acre with 16 per cent moisture content Treatment r 1 1 1 i 1921 1922 1923 1924 Average 19251 1921-1924 Tons Tom Tons Tom Tom Relaliie Tom No treatment 6.23 2.69 2.71 3.02 3.39 100 2.23 Disk barrow In spring and ordinary harrow alter 2nd crop 6.00 2.26 2.63 2.48 3.09 91 2.16 In spring 6.26 2.38 2.79 2.55 356 96 2.16 After 2nd crop 6.67 2.36 2.66 2.78. 3.32 98 2.10 Average....: 558 2.33 2.66 2.60 352 95 2.14 Spring tooth harrow Inspring 6.39 2.47 2.85 2.69 3.SB 99 2.11 Alter 2nd crop 659 2.68 2.81 2.99 8.44 101 250 After each crop 5.19 2.34 2.63 2.48 8.14 93 1.80 Average 652 2.46 2.73 2.72 8M 98 2.04 Ordinary harrow. i In spring 654 2.64 2.85 2.85 3.87 99 2.30 'Harvested uniformly and without tillage treatments in 1925. The number of plants per square foot in the no treatment plats was reduced about 30 per cent during the 5-year period, ' whereas there was about 43 per cent reduction in the plats where the disk and spring tooth harrow were used. It seems probable that if the tests were continued the difference in stand resulting from such practices would become more marked. Table 5. — Stand and root development of alfalfa in relation to tillage practices, 1921-1925 Plants Plants grouped according to diameter per of roots (inches) 1 Year square 1 . 1 • . foot 0-1 1-1 _-_ frl 1-1 . Per eent\Per cent Per centlPcr cent Per cent . NO TREATMENT 1921 I 11.4 I 225 I 69.4 I 8.4 I ... I ... 1925 I 7.9 I 14.0 | 605 | 23.4 | 95 | 35 DISK HARROW IN SPRING AND ORDINARY HARROW AFTER SECOND CROP 1921.......' »....! 11.0 I 16.6 I 79.2 I 4.3 I ... I ... 1925 I 6.3 | 16_t | 44.0 I 32.9 | 5.8 | 1.0 SPRING TOOTH HARROW IN SPRING AND AFTER EACH CROP 1921 I 11.9 1 13.7 1 76.8 I 9.5 1 ... I ... 1925 6.8 14.5 34.1 32.6 15.6 35 1 Root diameters measured just below, the crown.. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Root measurements in 1921, when 3 years old, showed about three-fourths of the plants to have taproots ranging from one-fourth to one-half inch in diameter. Of the remaining one - fourth, about two-thirds of the plants measured one-fourth inch or less in root diameter. Measurements in 1925 still showed about the same relative number of plants falling in the group of the smaller root size but with a much reduced percentage in the one-fourth to one-half inch group while the groups of still larger size had increasingly larger num - bers of plants. There appeared to be no relation between tillage treatment and plant development as measured by root diameters. effect of the time of cutting upon the yield and quality of alfalfa hay Knowledge as to the relation of the time of cutting to stand survival, yield, and quality of hay produced is of material importance. The results and recommendations of different investigators are not all in agreement. It is possible that climatic effects have been largely responsible for these differ - ences. FIRST EXPERIMENT, 1915-1918 Two separate experiments pertaining to the time of har - vesting alfalfa have been conducted at the Nebraska Experi - ment Station. The first experiment 1915-1918 (Table 6) has been previously reported in Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 169. The results of the second test, 1921-1925, are reported in Tables 7 to 12. SECOND EXPERIMENT, 1921-1925 This latter test was run parallel with the tillage experi - ments just reported and the yields were likewise affected to some extent by the abnormal growth conditions resulting from a moisture shortage during the period 1922 to 1925. Continuous harvesting of alfalfa at 7 stages of maturity was practiced. The tests were made in duplicate field plats dur - ing 1921 to 1924. In 1925 all plats were harvested uniformly at the " new growth " stage to determine the carry-over effects of previous treatments. Cutting Stages. — Five of these cutting stages were deter - mined by the state of bloom as follows: (1) pre-bloom, (2) </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Alfalfa Investigations Table (!.— Effect of time of cutting upon the yield of alfalfa hay, 1915-19W Av. no. Number Yield of hay per acre with 15 per cent moisture Stage times of content of cut plats 1 maturity 3 1915- averaged Average 1917 1916 1916 1917 1916-1917 1918' Tom Tom Tom Tom Relative Tom Before normal 5 3 ' 3.72 4.17 - 3.61 3.83 100 254 Normal....: 3 '3 5.01 6.42 5.86 6.76 160 3.62 Later, than norma] 2 3 3.49 8.78 3.66 3.69 94 352 'Recalculated from Table 6, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin No. 169. : Each frequency of cutting was made on the same plats during the three consecu - tive years 1916-1917, in order to determine the accumulative effect. The stage of ma - turity when cut was arbitrary and not determined by the bloom or new growth at the crown except in case ot the normal cutting. In 1918 all plats which had been previ - ously cut at different stages were cut at the same time at normal maturity to determine the effect of the previous differences in treatment. 'Only three cuttings were made in 1918. A light fourth cutting was lost by the erection of buildings upon the land. There was a very marked weakening of plants and thinning of stand where alfalfa was cut too frequently. initial bloom, (3) one-tenth bloom, (4) one-half bloom and (5) full bloom. In a sixth practice the second cutting was left each year to mature a seed crop while the other cuttings were made at the normal or new growth stage. The yields as reported are inclusive of all cuttings. The seventh or new growth stage, also designated as normal or check in these tests, was determined by the rather definite appearance of new growth or shoots at the crown. Ordinarily this stage fell between the tenth and half bloom stages, but several times it preceded or followed them. A modified new growth stage was included, comparable to the other except that the second cutting was harvested each year in the initial bloom stage. Quite frequently under Nebraska conditions the second cutting of alfalfa and the small grain crop are ready for har - vest at the same time and this test was planned to indicate the effect of cutting the second crop early so as not to inter - fere with the small grain harvest. All of these specified maturity stages were adhered to as nearly as conditions per - mitted. Owing to irregularity in blooming and growth asso - ciated with season and weather, some of the cuttings were at times more or less arbitrary. Any appreciable growth at the end of the season was harvested regardless of matur - ity and included in the yield. Yield of Hay per Acre. — The acre yield of hay and the pro - portion of leaves for these various stages of maturity are </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 recorded in Table 7. As an average for the 4-year period 1921-1924, these yields were as follows: pre-bloom, 3.00 tons; initial bloom, 3.04 tons; one-tenth bloom; 3.35 tons; one-half bloom, 3.43 tons; full bloom, 3.19 tons; and the new growth stage, 3.51 tons per acre. Corresponding relative yields were 100, 101, 112, 114, 106, and 117 per cent. The relatively unfavorable soil moisture conditions during the greater part of the period have doubtless caused the an - nual results to be somewhat inconsistent but it is believed that the yields as a 4-year average are fairly indicative of the normal tendency. The one-tenth and one-half bloom and new growth stages averaged 14 per cent higher yield than the pre-bloom and initial bloom stages. The full bloom stage yielded 6 per cent more than pre-bloom, whereas the seed stage yielded 6 per cent less. These data indicate that the .annual yield per acre can be expected to increase until the half bloom stage or slightly past, and then decrease somewhat with further matur - ity. These differences in yield are in the main consistent with those of the earlier test reported in Table 6, tho the effects Table 7. —Effect of time of cutting upon the yield of alfalfa hav. 1921-1925 'lis, Average 1921-1924 Yield of hay per acre with 15 per cant _. ,___ "7. Tr_ moisture content Stage of maturity Date of Propor- cutting tion of Average first crop l-aves 1921 1922 1923 1924 1921-1924 1925' Per cent Tons Tons Tons Tons Tons \ Relatite ."on, CUTTING DETERMINED BY STAGE OF BLOOM f t r, b ' 0 ° m May 231 57-3 13.90 2.87 2.88)2.35 3.00 100 12.47 Initial bloom May 29 56.6 4.34 2.62 2.60 2.59 3 04 101 2 21 One-tenth bloom . . June 2 65.8 4.51 2.76 2.71 3.43 3.35 112 2 09 One-half bloom June 6 53.2 4.58 3.02 2.90 3.20 3.43 114 2 20 Pull bloom June 13 49.4 3.96 3.41 2.96 2.44 3.19 106 272 Seed stage' 33.3 3.54 2 .56 2.57 2.61 2.82 94 2°.57 CUTTING DETERMINED BV APPEARANCE OP NEW GROWTH AT CROWN New growth June 3 52.8 4.67 3-34 2.86 3.15 3.51 117 2 36 New growth' 8.97 3.37 2.67 3.33 8.34 111 2.37 Average 4.18 2.99 2.71 2.89 351 2.88 'All Btages harvested uniformly at the new growth stage in 1926. —. _V n . e , p r &gt;I f r _ ion _' leavea ' mciuan PO* and blossoms and is for the seed crop only, ine yields include a first crop cut at the new growth stage, the seed crop and usually a light, third crop. *AH crops cut at new growth stage excepting the second which was cut _n initial bloom stage. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Alfalfa Investigations are not so marked. No marked decrease in yield may be expected when only one cutting per year is harvested earlier than normal. No other differences were observed to result from such a practice. Proportion of Leaves. — The proportion of leaves at harvest was found to be very closely correlated with maturity. As a 4-year average for all cuttings the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, one-half bloom, full bloom, seed and new. growth stages consisted of 57.3, 56.6, 55.8, 53.2, 49.4, 33.3, and 52.8 per cent leaves respectively. This was an extreme difference of 24.0 per cent, and a variation of 7.9 per cent among the stages ordinarily harvested for hay. Yield of Seed per Acre. — Under Nebraska conditions the _econd cutting is usually considered the most desirable to leave for seed production. It will ordinarily blossom and set seed pods more freely than the first cutting, whereas later cuttings seldom mature seed. Leaving the second cutting for seed in these tests has reduced the yield of forage materially as well as resulting in feed of lower quality. There was measurable seed production during this test in only one year out of four, the seed plats yielding at the rate of 1.2 bushels per acre in 1921. It is recognized that seed produc - tion in eastern Nebraska is uncertain and seldom profitable. Effect ori Plant Development. — Stand and root measure - ments comparable to those in Table 5 were made for the pre - bloom, new growth and full bloom stages of harvest. The data are recorded in Table 8. In 1925, 58. 78, and 64 per cent as many plants survived per square foot for the pre-bloom, new growth, and full bloom stages, respectively, as in 1921. There was a tendency for more rapid thinning out of the stand in the case of the most frequent cutting, tho even here a satis - factory stand still remained after 4 years of continuous pre - bloom cutting. This difference in thinning out was not as marked as that indicated in the earlier test, 1915-1918, which is reported in Table 6. The incoming of blue-grass, the an - nual grasses, and other weeds was not noticeable in this last experiment, whereas in the earlier experiment this condition was very marked. The difference in location of the plats may have been a factor in the relative amounts of weed growth. In the first test the plats, tho protected by a narrow border of alfalfa, were located adjacent to a roadway and </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 the College campus where the conditions were rather favor - able for the ingress of blue-grass, dandelions and other weeds. The second test was located in the center of a larger field of alfalfa which in turn was surrounded by cultivated fields. It is probable that when such weeds once obtain a foothold they will compete with the alfalfa. When the roots of these 3 maturity stages are classified according to their diameters, a slight tendency is apparent for the most frequent cutting to retard root development somewhat. Table 8. — Stand and roof development of alfalfa in relation to time of tutting. 1921-1925 Plants per Plants grouped according to diameter of Year square roots (inches) 1 foot . I _____ 0-1 H --j M Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent pre-bloom 1921 i 11.3 | 11.4 1 77.2 I 11.4 I 1925 | 6.6 ! 9.7 | 45.2 | 43.5 [ 1.6 NEW GROWTH 1921 I 11.3 | 18.9 , 75.7 1 5.4 I .... 1925 | 8.8 | 4.2 ] 50.0 ] 45.1 | 2.5 FULL BLOOM 1921 10.6 16.7 71.4 11.9 1925 6.8 4.8 38.1 52.4 4.7 'Root diameters measured just below the crown. Chemical Composition of Hay. — Fodder analyses were made of the leaves and stems from all cuttings of each matur - ity stage during the 4-year period, 1921-1924. In case of the seed stage, the second or seed cutting only was analyzed. The composition of the whole hay has been calculated from that of the leaves and stems on the basis of their constituent proportion. The ash, protein, fiber, nitrogen-free extract, and fat contents are reported in Table 9 for 1921 to 1924. As a 4-year average, there is a rather gradual reduction in the ash content from 11.24 per cent in the pre-bloom stage to 9.36 per cent in the full bloom stage. The protein con - tent for the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, one-half bloom, full bloom, and new growth stages was 21.98, 20.03, </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Alfalfa Investigations 19.24, 18.84, 18.13, and 18.38 per cent, respectively. This decrease in protein content of 3.85 per cent between extremes was rather parallel with increase in maturity of the plant and was accompanied by an increase of crude fiber content of 5.69 per cent from the pre-bloom to the full bloom stage. - No consistent variation was found in the percentage of nitro - gen-free extract. Of the 6 stages harvested for hay, the initial bloom stage contained ,40.67 per cent nitrogen-free extract and the full bloom 38.70 per cent, as the two extremes. The average fat content for the 6 stages was 2.93 per cent, with an extreme variation of 0.34 per cent. The crop har- . vested for seed as compared with the new growth stage was Table -9. — Effect of the time of cutting upon the chemical com - position of alfalfa hay, 1921-192J, Stage of maturity Constituents 1 1 1 1 1 , Pre- Initial One-tenth One-half Full Seed New bloom bloom- bloom .bloom bloom stage growth Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent | Per cent 1921 Ash 10.35 9.74 9.83 10.33 8.64 6.59 9.78 Protein 20.11 19.24 18.19 18.53 16.41 13.11 18.25 Fiber 25.29 25.25 28.97 30.22 31.99 41.97 29.13 Nitrogen-free extract 40.68 41.87 39.49 37.54 39.69 35.51 39.57 Fat 3.57 8.90 3.62 3.88 8.27 2.82 357 1922 Ash.." 11.61 10.66 . 10.61 11.18 9.89 756 9.60 Protein 2253 20.77 20.68 20.61 1955 18.51 20.13 Fiber 24.84 24.53 24.71 23.01 27.69 33.93 26.42 Nitrogen-free extract 38.49 40.74 40.80 41.75 39.57 42.36 41.05 Fat 2.83 3.30 3.40. 3.45 3.70 2.94 2.90 1923 Ash 11.45 10.84 956 9.71 8.85 6.41 8.99 Protein: 21.47 19.06 18.61 18.08 16.81 13.65 1751 Fiber 26.85 2759 28.69 30.77 3457 39.54 8056 Nitrogen-free extract 37.93 41.17 41.3G 3959 87.80 39.13 4157 Fat 250 2.15 2.18 2.15 257 157 2.17 1924 Ash 11.53 11.32 11.49 11.54 1 10.06 9.04 10.66 Protein 24.12 21.05 19.67 18.18 20.06 16.07 17.93 Fiber 23.65 25.94 25.99 28.50 29.41 30.99 30.49 Nitrogen-free extract 37.77 38.92 89.88 89.22 37.76 41.46 38.60 ' Fat I 8.03 2.77 2.97 2.61 2.71 2.44 2.42 . AVERAGE 1921-1924 Ash..„ 1154 10.62 1057 10.69 9.36 753 9.71 Protein 21.98 20.03 1954 18.84 18.18 14.06 1858 Fiber 25.13 26.75 27.09 28.12 30.82 36.61 29.08 Nitrogen-free extract 38.72 40.67 4058 39.45 38.70 39.61 40.14 Fat 2.93 8.03 8.02 2.90 2.99 259 2.69 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 2.38 per cent lower in percentage of ash, 4.32 per cent lower in protein, 7.53 per cent higher in fiber, 0.53 per cent lower in nitrogen-free extract, and 0.30 per cent lower in fat con - tent. The average physical and chemical composition of the whole hay, leaves, and stems, during the 4-year period, 1921 - 1924, is recorded in Table 10 and Chart 2 for each of the 7 stages of maturity. As an average of the 6 stages of matur- Tai-i.f. 10. — Effect of the time of cutting upon the chemical com - position of alfalfa hay, 1 leaves, and stems. Average for J, years. 1921-1924 r== : z^^~: = Constituents Stage of maturity Propor- , 1 . and portion of hay tion of Nitro - parts Ash Protein Fiber gen-free Fat extract j Per cenl Per cent Per cenl Per cenl Per cent Per cent Pre-bloom j Hay... 100 j 11.24 21.98 25.13 38.72 2.93 Leaves i 57.3 &gt; 12.16 29.04 14.97 40.05 3.78 Stems... | 42.7 ' 10.10 12.90 I 37.11 38.07 1.82 Initial bloom I Hay I 100 10.52 20.03 25.75 40.67 3.03 Leaves. 56.6 11.70 26.82 14.95 42.66 3.87 Stems 43.4 9.09 11.56 -39.38 38.02 ■ 1.95 One-tenth bloom Hay 100 10.27 19.24 27.09 40.38 3.02 Leaves 55.8 i 11.59 26.02 15.91 42.48 4.00 Stems 44.2 8.73 11.31 39.37 38.75 1.84 One-half bloom Hay 100 10.69 18.84 ,28.12 39.45 2.90 Leaves 53.2 12.29 25.74 16.30 41.78 3.89 Stems. I 46.8 8.98 11.33 40.99 36.88 1.82 Full bloom Hay ! 100 9.36 18.13 30.82 38.70 2.99 Leaves 49.4 11.24 25.92 18.00 40.55 4.29 Stems. 50.6 7.71 10.79 42.75 36.95 1.80 Seed stage 1 Hay . . 100 7.33 14.06 36.61 39.61 2.39 Leaves . 33.3 9.00 22.20 22.10 43.53 3.17 Stems 66.7 6.53 10.19 43.59 37.71 1.98 New growth Hay 100 9.71 18.38 29.08 40.14 2.69 Leaves 52.8 11.14 25.45 .16.86 42.89 3.66 Stems I 47.2 8.19 10.87 42.12 37.18 1.64 [ . 'The composition of the hay for each crop calculated from that of the leaves and stems on a percentage basis. The four-year average obtained from the seasonal averages. 'Analyses from the second or seed crop only. The pods and blossoms were included with the leaves. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Alfalfa Investigations Per ce.ni ■' \ ; my i in I _ J * 5 - 12 3 4 5.6 12.450 125 + 56 1 - 3 ♦ 5 6 JTsh Profe/n Titer W-/re_ Er.t fat * ZfifWp — ■ ' Ijjj jlWiti-BiHi-IlM / _ 3 4 5 5 1 2 5 4 S I 1 I 3 4 5 6 113*16 I 25450 ./.sh Protein fiber N-free Ent fat « , As srms __\\_\\_\mma :_________SI^__^______= !__.__ . J 2 3 4 5 _ .2345»'- 23450 1 t 3 * S 6 Jsh Protein fiber N-free. Ext. fat Chart 2. — Effect of the time of cutting upon the composition of alfalfa hay (above), leaves (center), and stems (below). The stages of maturity are designated as follows: (1) pre-bloom, (2) initial bloom, (3) one-tenth bloom, (4) new growth, (5) one-half bloom, and (6) full bloom. Average for 4 years, 1921-1924. (Table 10.) </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 ity harvested solely for hay, the stems comprised 45.8 per cent of the total crop. There was an increase of 7.9 per cent in proportion of stems from the least mature stage to the most mature stage. When the analyses of hay harvested at these 6 stages are averaged for the 4-year period it is found that the stems contained 75, 43, 249, 90, and 46 per cent as much ash, protein, fiber, nitrogen-free extract, and fat, respec - tively, as the leaves. The ratio of the protein percentage of the stems to that of the leaves remained practically constant regardless of the stage of maturity. The gradual decrease in the protein of the leaves and stems, accompanied by a decrease in the proportion of leaves, results in hay of lower protein content as the crop becomes more mature. It is of further interest to compare the physical and chem - ical composition of the whole hay, leaves, and stems, by cuttings. Such data have been averaged for the first, sec - ond, and third cuttings of the above 6 stages of maturity for the 4-year period, 1921-1924, and recorded in Table 11. The first, second, and third cuttings consisted respectively of 48.7, 56.4, and 58.1 per cent leaves. There was a slight increase, Table 11. — Relative chemical composition .of firxt. second, and third cuttings of alfalfa hay as obtained from an average of (1 stages of maturity. .1 verage for 4 years, 1921-1924 1 Pro- i Constituents Cutting portion) , , I of I | Nitro - i leaves , Ash Protein j Fiber | gen-free Fat I I I | ' extract Per cent i Per cent Per cent [ Per cent \ Per cent Per cent hay First ' 48.7 ' 10.29 i 18.96 ' 29.35 I 38.55 2.85 Second ; 56.4 j 10.35 19.83 27.31 I 39.62 2:89 Third 58.1 \ 10.12 \ 20.03 | 27.06 , 39.84 2.95 LEAVES First j . I 12.24 I 27.80 | 15.82 I 40.03 I 4.11 Second ! . ... 11.52 26.82 ; 15.98 41.85 I 3.83 Third ; 11.13 i 26.44 I 16.21 | 42.41 | 3.81 STEMS First | . ... 8.51 10.62 41.97 37.25 1.65 Second 8.98 11.29 40.95 37.04 1.74 Third 8.89 11.73 41.10 36.49. 1.79 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Alfalfa Investigations 1.07 per cent, in the protein content of the whole hay from the first to the third cutting. The leaves decreased 1.36 per cent in protein content from the first to the third cuttings, whereas the stems increased 1.11 per cent. Since the leaves contain a much higher per cent of protein than the stems, these changes would result in lower protein content for the whole hay in the second and third cuttings if it were not for their respective increases of 7.7 and 9.4 per cent in the proportion of leaves. Yield of Feed Constituents. — The '4-year average annual ■ acre yields of moisture-free hay, leaves, and stems together with their yields of feed constituents are given in Table 12 Table 12. — Effect of the time of cutting upon the yield of mois - ture-free alfalfa hay, and of its principal food elements. Av - erage for 4 years, 1921-1924 1 Acre yield on a moisture-free basis Stage of maturity f • 1 1 and portion of hay Nitro- Hay Ash Protein Fiber gen-free Fat extract . Tons Tons Tons Tons Tons Tons Pre-bToom Hay 2.548 0.287 0.552 0.648 0.987 0.074 Leaves. 1.430 0.174 0.414 0.214 0.574 0.054 Stems 1.118 0.113 0.138 0.434 0.413 0.020 Initial bloom Hay.. 2.578 0.267 0.515 0.680 1.036 0.080 Leaves. '. . 1.428 0.166 0.386 0.214 0.604 0.058 Stems 1.150 0.101 0.129 0.466 0.432 0.022 One-tenth bloom Hay -2.848 0.287 0.541 0.797 1,132 0.091 Leaves. 1.534 0.176 0.404 0.243 0.644 0.067 Stems 1.314 0.111 0.137 0.564 0.488 0.024 One-half bloom Hay :.. 2.909 0.304 0.535 0.847 1.138 0.085 Leaves 1.493 0.180 0.387 0.240 0.625 0.061 Stems 1.416 0.124 0.148 0.607 0.613 0.024 Full bloom Hay 2.712 0.262 0.482 0.854 1.042 0.082 Leaves 1.295 0.145 0.337 0.227 0.528 0.068 Stems L417 0.107 0.145 0.627 0.514 0.024 New growth Hay 2.978 0.289 0.546 0.885 1.175 0.083 Leaves 1.518 0.170 0.395 0.262 0.642 0.059 Stems 1.460 0.119 0.151 0.633 0.633 0.024 "The annual yields of the various food elements were calculated from the composi - tion and yield of each cutting. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Pounds . . \ eooc — S5J ' — " 1 1 i - Pre- Initial Uo New Vz Full bloom bloom bloom growth bloom bloom Jtsh=m Protein=M Fiber=M&amp; N-free Extern tat=l^ Chart 3. — Moisture free acre yields of hay (left), leaves (center), and stems (right), for each of the stages of maturity designated at the base of the chart, together with their proportionate content of ash, protein, fiber, nitrogen-free extract and fat. Average for 4 years, 1921-1924. (Table 12.) </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Alfalfa Investigations and Chart 3 for each of the 6 maturity stages. The average annual acre yields of protein for the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, one-half bloom, full bloom, and new growth stages were 0.552, 0.515, 0.541, 0.535, 0.482, and 0.546 tons, respectively. The proportion of this total protein that was borne in the leaves ranged from 75 per cent in the least ma - ture stages to 70 per cent in the full bloom stage. Due to the higher percentage of protein in the hay from the more im - mature stages, there was no marked difference in the acre yield of protein until the stage of maturity producing the highest acre yield of hay had been passed. The full bloom stage, due to its lower acre yield of hay and lower percent - age of protein, yielded decidedly less protein per acre than the new growth stage. From the combined standpoints of acre yields of hay and feed constituents, quality of nay, and permanency of stand, it would seem that harvesting alfalfa at approximately the new growth stage should prove the most desirable practice. This stage usually occurs under average Nebraska conditions during the period from one-tenth to one - half bloom, and for practical purposes harvesting may ordin - arily extend over this period without materially affecting results, using either the new growth or bloom development as an index. A modification of this practice to fit local con - ditions may often prove desirable, but frequent cutting of alfalfa in more immature stages should be avoided. historical review— maturity stages effect of time of cutting upon yield Sanborn (1893) reports one year's results from Utah with harvesting alfalfa at different stages of maturity as follows: early cutting (before coming into bloom) 7182 pounds per acre, medium cutting (early bloom) 7158 pounds, and late cutting (out of bloom) 7122 pounds per acre. Mills (1896), in continuation of the work reported by San - born (1893) , reports yields for 3 years (1893-1895) on a 12 per cent moisture basis, for early, medium, and late cutting, of 9,061, 8,396. and 8,166 pounds per acre respectively. Foster and Merrill (1899), in continuation of the work re - ported by Sanborn (1893) and Mills (1896) reports a 5-year average (1893-1895 and 1897-1898) of early (first bloom), medium (full bloom) , and late (half of bloom gone) cutting of 10,719, 9,829, and 9,100 pounds per acre, respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Harcourt (1900) reports yields of 2,714, 3,525, and 3,142 pounds of dry matter per acre as an average of 3 cuttings in 1897 and 1898 made in Ontario in bud, one-third bloom, and little past full bloom stages. In tests at Ottawa, Canada, Shutt (1904) in 1901 obtained 8742 pounds dry matter and 1411 pounds crude protein per acre for alfalfa cut twice as compared with 8545 pounds dry matter and 1658 pounds protein for alfalfa cut 4 times. Ten Eyck (1908) reports yields for a 1-year period in Kansas of 4.69, 5.35, 4.52, and 5.99 tons per acre, respectively, when harvested in first bloom, one-tenth bloom, one-half bloom and full bloom. As an average for 1903-1907, Hansen (1909) in Denmark reports yields of 7,720, 8,897, and 8,456 pounds per acre from cuttings made 4, 3, and 2 times annually. Hansen (1914, 1915, and 1916), at the Huntley (Montana) Reclamation Project Farm, harvested alfalfa at the appear - ance of the first basal shoots and at 4 successive 5-day inter - vals, the last harvest of each cutting being made 20 days after the first harvest of that cutting. When the yields for 1913, 1914, and 1915 are averaged the following results are obtained — 5.87, 5.81, 5.64, 5.29, and 5.72 tons per acre respectively from the least to the most mature stage. Bean (1922) reports yields from the Washington Agricul - tural Experiment Station (Irrigation Branch Station), of 6.7, 7.8, and 8.1 tons per acre as a 2-year average when harvested just before bloom, one-half bloom, and three-fourths tull bloom stages. Moore and Graber (1925) obtained 1.9, 2.7, and 3 4 tons per acre in Wisconsin for bud, one-tenth bloom, and full bloom stages. Salmon, Swanson, and McCampbell (1925) of Kansas re - port 8-year average yields, 1914-1921, (10 per cent moisture basis) of 3.24 3.41, 3.51, and 2.93 tons per acre for the bud, tenth bloom, full bloom, and seed stages, respectively When harvested uniformly in 1923, yields of 2.47, 2.61, 3 11 and 2.99 tons per acre were obtained from the plats which had previously received these respective cutting treatments. RELATION OF TIME OF CUTTING TO PHYSICAL COMPOSITION Foster and Merrill (1899) of Utah, as an average of first and second crops, found early cutting (first bloom) to con - sist of 41.07 per cent leaves, medium cutting (full bloom) </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Alfalfa Investigations 37.07 per cent, and late cutting (half bloom gone) 30.21 per cent. . Salmon, Swanson, and McCampbell (1925) found in Kan - sas as an 8-year average (1914-1921) that alfalfa harvested in the bud, one-tenth blpom, full bloom, and seed stages con- . sisted of 53.4, 51.1, 48.4, and 41.6 per cent leaves, respectively. During this same period the weight of grasses within the hay averaged 18.2, 5.9, 2.3, and 0.8 per cent, respectively, of the total yield. RELATION OF TIME OF CUTTING TO CHEMICAL COMPOSITION AND DIGESTIBILITY The Colorado Agricultural Experiment Station (1889) reports a decrease of albuminoid nitrogen from 18.19 per cent from the bud stage to 11.67 per cent when seed was fully ripened. Headden (1896) found that, as an average for all stages of development in Colorado, the first, second, and third cuttings consisted of 14.85, 14.43, and 13.05 per cent protein, respectively. Mills (1896) reports from Utah that, as an average of 2 crops during 1 year, early, medium, and late cuttings con - sisted of 14.80, 12.47, and 13.41 per cent protein respectively. The leaves contained 11.92, 18.42, 20.42, 44.57, and 4.66 per cent ash, protein, fiber, nitrogen-free extract, and fat, respec - tively, as compared with 6.82, 7.38, 42.43, 41.33, and 2.04 per cent for the stems. As an average for 3 crops grown' in Colorado in 1896, Headden (1897) reports that the protein content in the be - ginning to bloom, half bloom, and full bloom stages aver - aged 17.69, 17.13, and 17.25 per cent, respectively, and the average protein content for the first, second, and third cuttings of all stages was 16.32, 18.46, and 17.29 per cent. Widtsoe and Stewart (1898) for Utah conditions con - clude that " The digestibility of lucern remains practically constant from budding time to the period of full bloom." Foster and Merrill (1899) report from Utah that the an - nual yield of digestible matter per acre during 5 years, 1893 - 1895 and 1897-1898, averaged 6,413, 5.912, and 5,309 pounds for early, medium, and late cutting. The protein content for the same stages for 3 years, 1895-1897, was 14.26, 12.77, and 12.92 per cent, respectively. " The average composition of all cuttings and crops shows the leaves to contain 150 per </seg>
            <seg id="p068">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 cent more protein than the steffis, 300 per cent more fats cr 5 uae r fi C be n r t » m0re nitrogen " free e *~ct, -d 25o percent fess coSen^ii 9 ?^ I 2K_ B from Ontario ths * the protein 14 ? . nJ g f d ST ?- 5 - 3S P er cent when 6 inches high to Hi J* , 2f t at - the time the bl0 °m « filing. As an ave™ age of 3 cuttings in 1897 and 1898, the protein content aUhe fidTo'W °ri5 a K n ? a W.tf fuU S-rstegefwS xt * _.•_• 18,11 &gt; 1553 &gt; and 13.89 per cent resneotivplv ErtrfS. e ? erime 5 tS ? h0Wed that 58 P 6^l.?and P 513 S Sta wherA T™-- ln St? A r6Spective ste * es ™s dUt digesS?e ' ' and 64,4 per cent of the Protein was Cottrell (1902) reports a protein content of 18 fi 179 ■_„, - from 4, 3. and 2 cutti„|, piA *so„ 6 P * r ""'• ""I**"*. JSaj-i__T__A .stea a re *r « respectively. The litter _ ? LK '"''.J 7 - 7 per cent P rotei " matorit. test contataed 19 9^|| ',. ?_ r ?. ?' "W ° f pounds of hay harvested S TJ'S ' 86 1 2 ' 163 ' and 3 ' 910 bloom, and bLS^^^^'^^^K^^, full duce 100 pounds gain res P ectlvel y&gt; were required to pro- RELATION OF TIME OF CUTTING TO PLANT DEVELOpMENT </seg>
            <seg id="p069">Alfalfa Investigations diameters averaged 6.45 mm. as compared with 6.92 mm. for the undipped. Garver (1922) found at Redfield, South Dakota, that alfalfa clipped 3, 7, and 18 times the second season resulted in a mortality of 17, 92 and 98 per cent, respectively. The plants harvested but! 3 times showed a much larger and stronger root growth.' The Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station (1923) found that late fall cutting or the removal of 3 crops as com - pared with 2 increased winterkilling from 26 to 62 per cent (average of 4 tests). ) Nelson (1925) concluded from a series of cutting experi - ments in Wisconsin extending from 1921 to 1923 that, " fre - quent cutting of alfalfa, in premature stages results in de - pleted root reserves. This causes slow recovery and rate of ' growth after cutting, low yields of hay, increased weed infes - tation, and retarded root growth. An increase in the num - ber of crown buds, shoots, and main stems occurs as an im - mediate effect with frequent and early cutting, but the aver - age height and total yields of these top growths is much less than with less frequent cuttings at a more mature stage. " Chemical analysis of alfalfa roots and physiological obser - vations show that stored organic foods in the roots of certain plants such as alfalfa have an important influence on their productivity. Both the nitrogen and carbohydrate reserves of the root are decreased by cutting the crop too early." Salmon, Swanson, and McCampbell (1925) of Kansas, cutting at 4 stages of maturity, i.e.', bud, tenth bloom, full bloom, and seed stage, found that the respective losses in number of plants per acre from 1914 to 1922 were 77.1, 84.1, 64.4, and 53.9 per cent of the original number; that similar losses in number of stems produced per acre were 50.8, 63.8, 46.5, and 13.0 per cent. The number of stems produced per plant from 1915 to 1921 was practically constant for the various cutting stages, but on the average increased from 3.7 to 7.0 stems per plant. Root diameters measured 3 inches below the crown in 1923 were 241, 206, 233, and 242 per cent as large as the diameters in 1915 for the bud, one-tenth bloom, full bloom, and seed stages, respectively. THE USE OF TOP DRESSING ON ALFALFA It is generally recognized that profitable production of alfalfa hay may be limited on soils low in their lime and sul- </seg>
            <seg id="p070">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 phur content and in general fertility. Alfalfa will not thrive on very strongly acid soils. Sulphur is a necessary plant food element and alfalfa has a high sulphur requirement. Table 13 contains the results of a 4-year test during 1921 - 1924, wherein gypsum (calcium sulphate), sulphur (flowers of sulphur), lime and sulphur in combination, lime, and barn - yard manure were applied as top dressings in commonly recommended amounts to alfalfa growing on the Experiment Station Farm. The applications were made in duplicate in the spring of 1921 on a well-established stand of alfalfa. Gypsum was applied at the rate of 400 pounds per acre. Sulphur alone as well as in conjunction with lime was applied at the rate of 200 pounds per acre, while 2 tons of crushed limestone and 8 tons of barnyard manure were used. Table 1%.—The effect of top dressings upon the yield of alfalfa hay, 1921-1924 ' i Amount Yield of hay per acre with 15 per cent Treatment of moisture content applied in 1921 appli- ,— , — cation . per acre; 1921 j 1922 1923 1924 Average Pounds Tons I Tons Tons Tons Tons Relative No treatment . . . 5.22 2.97 I 3.00 3.38 3.64 100 Gypsum 400 5.29 2.77 2.90 3.34 3.58 98 Sulphur 200 4.98 2.63 2.95 3.54 3.53 97 Lime and. 4000 535 2 g4 3 u 3 4g 3 73 102 sulphur. 200 Lime 4000 5.59 2.89 2.92 3.30 3.68 101 Manure 1 16000 5.89 3.88 3.13 3.54 4.11 113 Average 5.39 3.01 3.01 3.43 3.71 1 ... i ' I "The yields for the manure treatment are calculated from manurial effects in an adjacent alfalfa field. The 4-year averages show practically no difference in the yields from either the no treatment, the gypsum, the sulphur, the lime, or the sulphur-and-lime treated plats. These results indicate that there is sufficient lime and sulphur in this soil for successful alfalfa production. The application of barn - yard manure increased the yield of alfalfa hay 13 per cent over the plats receiving no treatment. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Alfalfa Investigations alfalfa-timothy mixture The growing of alfalfa and timothy in combination has been occasionally advocated. Seedings were made in dupli - cate in 1922, comparing alfalfa seeded alone at the rate of 20 pounds per acre with an alfalfa and timothy mixture seed - ed at the same rate. The mixture consisted of 7 parts alfalfa and 13 parts of timothy by weight. Good uniform stands were secured on the 4 plats. The results are recorded in Table 14. The field in which these plats were located pro - duced a heavy crop of silage corn in 1921 and was in alfalfa during the 4-year period preceding 1921. The dry condition of the subsoil due to the previous cropping, together with a rather dry series of years, resulted in relatively low yields on these plats from 1923 to 1925. As a 3-year average alfalfa alone yielded at the rate of 2.21 tons per acre, where - as alfalfa and timothy in combination yielded 2.35 tons of ■ cured forage. This difference in yield is not considered significant. The first cutting each year was the only one to contain a measurable amount of timothy. As a 3-year aver - age of alfalfa alone the first, second, and third cuttings com - prised 54, 32, and 14 per cent of the total yield and these re - spective cuttings in the alfalfa-timothy mixture formed 58, 28, and 14 per cent of the total yield. The growing of such a mixture is not recommended unless the mixed hay is especially desired for feeding purposes. Table 14. — Comparative yields of alfalfa alone and alfalfa and timothy in combination, 1923-1925 Yield of hay per acre with 15 per cent Crop moisture content ' ■ 1923 1924 1925 Average Tons Tons Tons Tons Alfalfa 2.20 2.51 1.91 ' 2.21 Alfalfa and timothy 2.59 2.76 1.69 2.35 seeding practices GENERAL OBSERVATIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS The relation of various seeding practices to the likelihood of securing satisfactory stands of alfalfa has long been under </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 observation in this State and certain conclusions seem justi - fied. A high state of soil fertility aids in establishing a stand of ~ alfalfa as w°ll as resulting in increased production. Thoroly prepared, finely pulverized, compact, moist seed beds are most conducive to securing a stand. Tillage opera - tions and crop sequences should be planned with this in mind. Almost any seeding or cultural practice will prove success - ful when weather and soil conditions are favorable. The hazards connected with seeding increase as these conditions become less favorable. The most intensive and careful methods often fail when the weather is unfavorable. On the other hand, much can be done thru proper methods to reduce losses and to insure the likelihood of success. Seeding should only be done when weather and soil con - ditions are favorable. It may preferably be either in the spring or the early fall in eastern Nebraska and in the spring or the early summer in central and western Nebraska. If fall seeding following small grain is planned, the land should be plowed as soon as possible after harvest in order to con - serve moisture by reducing run-off and weed growth. Fol - lowing this the land should be sufficiently disked and har - rowed to prevent weed growth and to insure a compact seed bed by seeding time. Fall seeding in eastern Nebraska can be advantageously done between August 10 arid September 1. If conditions are favorable for prompt germination and continued fall growth, there is seldom danger of winterkilling, provided seed of a hardy strain or variety is planted. Chances of winterkilling are increased with more delayed seeding, altho successful stands are sometimes secured as late as September 15 in the southeastern portion of the State. If seeding is to be done in the spring, April and May are considered good months in eastern Nebraska, the exact time depending upon the favorableness of conditions. Seeding seems most successful during May and early June in central and western Nebraska, preceded by tillage planned to con - serve moisture, kill weeds, and compact the seed bed. In those regions where seeding following a small grain crop is successful it will produce almost as much hay the following year as spring seeding. Spring seeded alfalfa sel - dom proves a profitable crop during the first year and must usually be clipped several times the first season to check weed growth. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Alfalfa Investigations Under exceptionally favorable moisture and weed-free con - ditions, alfalfa may be seeded directly into small grain stubble with mere disking or without any treatment. This is regarded as one of the desirable methods on sandy soils which are inclined to blow. Except under extremely favorable conditions, drilling is more successful than broadcasting. It insures more uniform covering in moist soil and more prompt and uniform germina - tion. The drilling should be very shallow. Broadcast seed is usually covered by a harrow. The number of alfalfa plants necessary per acre for maximum production and the rate of seeding required to secure this stand Vary with conditions. There are enough seeds in the average pound of alfalfa to average about five plants per square foot if all the seeds would grow when planted. Five and possibly 3 or 4 well established and evenly distributed plants per square foot may be as productive of forage as a much thicker stand. A thin stand which yields less the first year or two than a thicker stand will ordinarily do relatively better when it becomes well established. Thin stands, however, are invariably more or less uneven, more subject to the ingress of weeds, and usually produce a hay of lower quality. Ten pounds or even less per acre may produce good, even stands of alfalfa when conditions are extremely favorable. The use of a somewhat larger amount of seed per acre will usually increase the chances of securing a good stand. The seeding of more than 15 pounds per acre, however, seems in - advisable and unnecessary. The use of a small grain nurse crop is fairly successful in some localities and especially in the extreme eastern counties. Thin stands of winter wheat often prove to be good nurse crops. Short-strawed, early-maturing varieties of oats and barley, seeded at half the normal rate, make good modified nurse crops. Mowing the small grain early for hay is desirable if the season becomes very dry, or the nurse crop becomes too rank. It is only under exceptional conditions that spring-seeded alfalfa will produce much hay the first year. If conditions are favorable and if there is but little competition from weed growth, one or two light cuttings of fair quality hay may be had the first season. Cutting in this case, however, should he delayed until the crop is fairly mature. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Ordinarily the weed growth proves a very serious factor the first season following spring seeding and the question arises as to how best to handle the situation. If the weed growth becomes quite heavy the most feasible plan appears to be clipping in order to avoid the loss of the alfalfa seed - lings, due to weed competition. Under exceptional conditions 2 or 3 or even more clippings may be necessary the first seas - on. These clippings should be made rather high and if possible during cool, damp weather. Whenever the clipped growth is very heavy, it should be removed. It has sometimes been recommended that the growth be undipped thruout the first season, to be followed by burning over or raking off the following spring. This practice should be governed largely by local conditions. Whenever the weed growth becomes sufficiently heavy so that there is danger of smothering out the less vigorous alfalfa plants, it should be clipped. In the Nebraska Experiment Station tests, the weed growth has been such in two years out of four as to kill out alfalfa when left undipped during the season. Late summer or early fall seeding seldom needs further attention and fair yields of relatively weed-free hay may be expected the fol - lowing season. Seed inoculation has seldom been found necessary in this State. The proper bacteria are present in most of our soils. It has been concluded from various cooperative tests with farmers as well as by Experiment Station tests that in gen - eral inoculation is essential only in the restricted regions of r f) V .S r a u cid soil and P erha P s in a few isolated localities where alfalfa has not been previously grown. Its trial is recom - mended, however, for localities where failures to secure a productive stand cannot be otherwise accounted for. It is evident that the most desirable seeding practice must be decided locally to fit the immediate conditions. EXPERIMENT STATION SEEDING TESTS DURING 1922-1925 A number of seeding and cultural practices such as time and rate of seeding, drilling vs. broadcasting, and the use of nurse crops have been systematically investigataed on the Experiment Station Farm since 1922 in order to observe their relation to securing a stand of alfalfa. These results are summarized in Table 15. Aside from the question of secur - ing a stand, the particular methods employed doubtless bear little relation to the productivity or longevity of the crop </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Alfalfa Investigations after it has become well established. In- these tests a pre - scribed program has been followed regardless of weather conditions. This will partially account for the high percent - age of failures. Table 15. — The securing of a stand of alfalfa in relation to various seeding practices, 1922-1925 1922 1923 1924 1925 Date, rate, or method Stand secured (Stand secured Stand secured Stand secured DATE OP SEEDING! April Good Good Good Good May Good Good Fair Good June Pair to poor Good Fair to Rood July Failure Poor Gocd August Failure Fair to good Good Good September Failure Failure Poor Good Early spring and late fall Failure Failure Failure RATES OF SEEDING' 5 lbs. per acre Failure' Poor, thin, Very, thin, un- Thin, little uneven little uneven even 10 lbs. per acre Failure Poor, thin, Fair to good Fair to good, little little uneven uneven. 15 lbs. per acre Failure Fair, tairiy uniform Good Good, little uneven 20 lbs. per acre Failure Good Good Good NURSE CR0P3 AND MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICES Spring seeded Normal clipping Good Good Good Good Undipped-weeds burned off.... Good Failure Failure Good Undipped-weeds raked oB... Good Failure Failure Good Two bushels of oats.. Good Failure Good Good One bushel of oata. . . Good Failure Good Good Fall seeded Following small grain Failure Failure Failure Good Summer fallow....... Failure Failure Good Good Standing corn Failure Failure Failure Fair 'Drilling and broadcasting was practiced on all seeding dates from April to Septem - ber. On the average, drilling resulted in securing a somewhat larger per cent and more uniform stands. Since seedings were made at prescribed times regardless of con - ditions, the percentage of failures was quite large in both cases. All seedings marked good considered generally satisfactory. *Fall seeded in 1922 and spring seeded 1923-1925. INOCULATION TESTS Inoculation of the soil or seed before sowing alfalfa has been widely advocated. If the inoculating bacteria essential to alfalfa are not naturally present in the soil, they must be supplied before alfalfa will thrive. These bacteria may be supplied by scattering spil from a field known to be inoculated or by artificial cultures applied to the seed- Frequent soil and artificial culture inoculation tests have been made at the Nebraska Experiment Station. No dif- </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 f erences have been observed in any of these tests. The results of one test seeded in duplicate twentieth-acre plats in 1922 are shown in Table 16. There was no apparent difference in stand, vigor of growth, or yield, between the uninoculated and the soil and culture inoculated plats at any time during the 4-year period. Table 1( &gt;. — The effect of inoculation upon the yield of alfalfa hay, 1923-1925 Yield of hay per acre with 15 per cent Treatment 1 moisture content 1923 1924 1925 Average Tons Tons Tons Tons Uninoculated 4.96 6.90 5.16 5.6? Soil inoculated 5.06 7.01 5.00 5.69 Culture inoculated 5.25 6.89 5.05 5.73 'Inoculations made at time of seeding in 1922. No differences in growth observed during the first year. MAINTENANCE OF ALFALFA STANDS Maintaining an alfalfa stand for a period of several years is very desirable because of the expense and time ordinarily involved in securing a stand. The premature thinning out of alfalfa may be due to a number of causes. Some of these may be controlled in a large measure by proper cultural prac - tices. The avoidance of (1) seed of an unhardy sort, (2) cutting too late and too close in the fall, and (3) frequent cutting in very immature stages, will prolong the life of the alfalfa and aid in maintaining effective stands. Unavoidable losses are frequently due to drought and cold, and other adverse climatic conditions beyond the endurance of the crop. Bac - terial wilt ( Aplanobacter insidiosum McCulloch) has recently come to be regarded as a factor in the premature thinning of stands and merits further investigation. Experiment Sta - tion tests have indicated the symptoms of this disease to be most prevalent in those plats seeded to non-hardy sorts in which winter injury has been severe. Disking or otherwise cultivating an alfalfa field in an effort to thicken the stand seldom proves effective. When fields have become so badly thinned as to be unprofitable they should be plowed up rather than attempting to rehabilitate them thru tillage practices or reseeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Alfalfa Investigations alfalfa in the rotation Partial or complete crop failures following the growing of alfalfa are of sufficient frequency and importance to merit consideration in planning an alfalfa rotation and in giving careful study to the crops best suited to follow alfalfa. A better understanding of the situation may be had after comparing alfalfa with the common cereal crops — corn, oats, and winter wheat — in respect to the normal working depth of their root systems, their water reauirement ner unit of dry matter, and their total production of dry matter. It is generally recognized that the root systems of the cereal crops seldom extend below the fifth foot and that their nor - mal working level is somewhat less than this. Alfalfa, on the other hand, has a root system extending much deeper and from the standpoint of moisture, at least, may have a working depth of 15 feet or more. Weaver (1926) states that under normal eastern Nebraska conditions the maximum penetration of the roots of oats and winter wheat will aver - age about 4.4 and 5.4 feet, respectively, and that their normal working level is about 3.4 and 3.8 feet. A depth of penetra - tion of 5 to 6 feet for corn is not unusual. Alfalfa roots, on the other hand, penetrate much, deeper and ultimately may extend to depths of 20 feet or even more. A further contrast of the working depth of alfalfa as com - pared with brome grass and winter wheat is shown by the moisture data in Table 17 and Chart 4. These moisture data were secured from soil samples taken June 24, 1926, as fol - lows: (1) from the alfalfa check plats for which yields are reported in Table 3; (2) from adjacent land which had been seeded to brome grass in 1922 at the time the alfalfa was seeded ; and (3) from an adjacent wheat field which had been cropped to corn, oats, and wheat during the same period. Previous to 1922 these fields had been treated alike, and present differences may thus be attributed to the cropping system. Very little difference was found in the moisture content of the soil in the upper 4 feet from the alfalfa, brome grass, or wheat ground. The soil from the sixth to fifteenth foot of the alfalfa field had been depleted of moisture content practically to the point of non-availability and averaged 7 and 8 per cent lower in moisture than that from the brome grass and wheat fields. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Table IT. — Comparative moisture content of soils from alfalfa, brome grass, and winter wheat fields, 1 June 24, 1926 Moisture content ol soil Depth ,— Alfalfa Brome grass Winter wheat field field field Feet Per cenl Per cent . Per cent 1 15.3 17.3 17.2 2 16.7 16.7 16.4 3 15.4 15.4 15.5 4 14.4 15.1 15.4 5 13.8 16.9 17.6 Average 1-5 15.1 16.3 j 16.4 6 13.5 18.3 18.3 7 13.1 19.1 19.8 8 13.1 19.1 20.7 9 13.5 20.3 20.7 10 13.0 20.4 I 21.2 Average 6-10 13.2 19.4 20.1 11 13.0 21.8 20.8 12 12.9 , 19.6 i 21.6 13 13.5 20.1 21.6 14 13.7 20.7 22.3 15 13.2 18.7 j 22.1 Average 11-15 13.3 20.2 21.7 'The moisture content was determined on dry basis from composite of 3 one-foot cores in each case. The alfalfa and wheat fields sampled are those for which yields are reported in Table 18, while the brome grass field was adjacent. Comparable yields (total air-dry matter) of alfalfa, corn, oats, and winter wheat for the period 1923 to 1925 are re - ported in Table 18 and Chart 5. In total production alfalfa has yielded 239, 515, and 334 per cent as much respectively, as corn, oats, and wheat. The water requirements per unit of dry matter for alfalfa, corn, oats, and wheat as determined in 1916 from potometers situated in the field are presented in Table 19 and Chart 5. The water consumption per unit of dry matter for alfalfa was 3.2, 2.1, and 2.7 times that of corn, oats, and wheat. Due to the high water requirement of alfalfa, its high yield, and the nature of its root system, the depletion of the subsoil moisture to a much lower depth than that of brome grass or </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Alfalfa Investigation's Per cent mnnture .. .,.&lt;-." "&gt;-•• "" 4 —^rfiF^— — —^N feei it 3 -r s e t a s 10 n u 11 tt is Alfalfa field'- Brome grass field' Winter wheat f\e\A- — Chart 4. — Comparative moisture content of successive one-foot soil sections to a depth of 15 feet in alfalfa, brome grass, and -winter wheat fields, June 24, 1926. (Table 17.) wheat is readily understood. Because of this reduction in available soil moisture there was a marked decrease in the yield of alfalfa in 1925 as compared with that of the pre - vious year and in 1926 the yield was only 30 per cent 1 of the 3-year average, 1923-1925. It is thus evident that the period of maximum yield in this field is past and the yields must now depend primarily on the seasonal rainfall. It is likely that the yield of alfalfa in the future will drop down to or below that of the cereals, due to its higher water require - ment. Taiile 18. — Comparative yields of alfalfa, corn, oats, and winter wheat. 1923-1925 ' Yield per acre' Crop 1923 1924 1925 Aveiage Total Grain Total Grain Total Grain Total Grain Pounds Bushels Pounds Bushels Pounds Bushels Pounds Bushels Altalta(Common) . 9520 14360 9800 11227 .... Corn (Hogue) 5370 43.6 - 3600 25.1 5100 21.5 4690 30.1 Oats (Kherson).... 3380 50.4. 1890 33.7 1270 19.3 2180 84.5 Wheat (Turkey) .. . 2810 18.6 5860 45.1 1410 10.0 3360 24.6 [ 'The alfalfa yields are those of the check alfalfa as reported In Table 8 and are for hay containing? 15 per cent moisture. The yields of corn, oats, and wheat were secured from adjacent fields and are based on air-dry material. 'This, relative yield for 1926 has been supplied Bince the acceptance of this manuscript for publication. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Table 10. — Comparative witter requirement of alfalfa* corn, oats, and winter wheat when grown in potometers under nor - mal exposure in fields of their own respective crops. 191(1 I Total Dry Transpiration per Crop and variety , number matter 1 I of per j Gram pots 1 pot Pot dry | j matter i Grams Kgms. j Grams Alfalfa (Common) 6 201 172.4 858 Corn ;Hogue) 1 8 513 137.0 i 267 Oats (Kherson) 6 , 188 I 77.9 I 414 Wheat (Turkey) 6 251 71.0 j 323 'Second year alfalfa. 3 Pots 16 inche_ in diameter by 36 inches deep. A discussion of methods employed may be found in Research Bulletin No. 6, Nebraska A,T ■nltural Experiment Station. Since it is generally recognized that the common cereal crops in semi-arid or subhumid regions ordinarily use all of the available water in the upper 4 or 5 feet, it would seem that the disastrous results frequently experienced in crops following alfalfa cannot be due directly to alfalfa having left the ground in a much drier condition, as is generally thought. In common practice, however, alfalfa is usually plowed up in late fall or early spring and the time for storing moisture for the following crop is somewhat shorter than between cereal crops. It would seem that the crop failures following alfalfa are in the main due to overstimulation. Frequently as in the case of corn there is insufficient moisture to carry the crop with its increased vegetative growth thru to normal maturity. Under similar conditions the small grain crops may lodge and the grain fill imperfectly due to the increased vegetative growth. From local experience and from a review of the literature, more especially the work of Swanson (1917) in Kansas under conditions comparable with those in Nebraska, it may be con - cluded that this overstimulation following alfalfa is due to a marked increase in the amount of available nitrogen. The growing of alfalfa as is ordinarily practiced does not materially increase the total nitrogen content of the soil but does tend to maintain the nitrogen content rather than deplete it as do non-legumes. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Alfalfa. Investigations r&gt;ui____ . Pouad* 1 Ip JJ- m ~m : — 45fl ~p: j ii ill ill jyiiiii TffrALJUOML YIEU&gt; PER ACRE TRANSPIRATION PER POUND jtVEMOE FOR i9Z5-WZ4-ms DRY MATTER Chart 5. — Comparative acre yields (3-year average, 1923-1925) and water requirement (1916) of alfalfa, corn, oats, and winter wheat. (Tables 18 and 19.) Whenever corn or small grain follows alfalfa, a relatively small early maturing variety should be selected and plant - ing should be at somewhat less than the normal rate. The increased vegetative growth due to overstimulation can be overcome in part by such procedure. The use of an inter- , tilled crop seems more desirable since it is better adapted to . the storing of soil moisture and is less subject to lodging than small grain. Listing corn on such land also tends to hold the excessive vegetative growth in check. Alfalfa should not follow alfalfa under the conditions just . described, for a period of years. Whenever the available sub - soil moisture has been depleted as shown in Table 17, alfalfa will not prove a productive crop, even tho good stands may be secured, until a new reserve of sub-soil moisture has been accumulated. The time required for this will of course de - pend on the amount and nature of the seasonal rainfall, the nature of the soil, and the system of cropping. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 principles and practices involved in the curing of alfalfa hay The comparative market value of alfalfa hay depends more upon the curing and proper handling of this product than upon any other factor. The trade demands a clean, fine - stemmed, leafy, sweet, and green-colored hay. The last three qualities are closely related to successful curing practices. By curing of hay is meant those practices involved in handling the forage during the time its moisture content is being reduced to a point where it will not heat, mold, or deteriorate in quality when placed in the stack or mow. Alfalfa is a very succulent plant, usually containing 70 per cent or more of moisture at the time it is harvested. Before such forage can be safely stored in bulk its moisture content must be materially reduced. The producer is interested in lowering the moisture content as rapidly as possible after cutting without undue loss of leaves, color, and other desir - able qualities ordinarily associated with good hay. The rate of drying or curing and the length of time required for hay to become sufficiently dry to stack or mow are con - trolled by its moisture content at time of cutting and by the character of the forage, the weather conditions prevailing during the curing period, and the method of handling. This latter factor especially can be controlled in an important degree by cultural practices. The purpose of these investigations has been to compare the effectiveness of various curing practices, and to establish the extent to which transpiration from the leaves may be made to serve in the withdrawal of moisture from the forage during the curing process. The problem has important prac - tical significance because of the extensive production of this crop and its high market and feeding value. Since the moisture content of alfalfa at time of cutting under various conditions, as well as the moisture content of field-cured and air-dry hay are associated with the reduction of moisture in curing, a study of these factors is of interest in connection with these curing investigations. VARIATION IN THE MOISTURE CONTENT OF ALFALFA AT TIME OF CUTTING In order to determine the variation in the moisture con - tent of growing alfalfa thruout the day, composite samples were cut at hourly intervals from 8 A. M. to 5 P. M. during the 3 days, August 5, 6, and 8, 1921. The moisture contents </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Alfalfa Investigations as calculated from the green and moisture-free weights of samples taken at specified intervals, are recorded in Table 20. The composite samples of green material, ranging in weight from 300 to 500 grams, were cut from a vigorous growing third cutting which was coming well into bloom. The weather during this period was dry, mostly clear, and some - what windy. Average maximum and minimum temperatures were 82° and 58° F, respectively. As a 3-day average there was a decrease of 2.7 per cent in moisture content from 8 A. M. to 5 P.M. Table 20. — Hourly variation in the moisture content of growing alfalfa. August, 1921 . Moisture content of alfalfa Time of sampling : 1 1 : Aug. 5 Aug. 6 Aug. 8 Average Per cenl Per cenl Per cenl Per cent 8 A. M 74.0 71.7 72.4 72.7 9 A. M 73.6 72.7 71.9 72.7 10 A. M 72.1 72.0 70.6 71.6 11 A. M 72.3 70.6 70.2 71.0 12M 72.2 70.9 68.5 70.5 IP. M 73.6 70.7 67.9 70.7 2 P.M... 71.8 70.9 69.5 70.7 3P.M 70.1 70.1 69.9 70.0 4P.M 70.7 69.8 68.0 69.5 5 P. M 71.0 70.0 69.1 70.0 Average 72.1 70.9 69.8 70.9 The results of this test further show a decrease in moisture content from day to day as the alfalfa increases in maturity. This decrease amounted to 2.3 per cent over the 4-day period. The 4-year average moisture content at the time of cutting was 76.5, 74.3, 72.8, 71.8, 70.5, 60.0, and 72.8 per cent, respec - tively, for alfalfa harvested in the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, one-half bloom, full bloom, seed, and new growth stages which have been reported in Table 7. Tho these data show a measurable decrease in the mois - ture content of growing alfalfa during the course of the day and from day to day as maturity increases, the changes are probably not of sufficient importance to be considered a very material factor in curing practices. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 MOISTURE CONTENT OF FIELD-CURED AND AIR-DRY ALFALFA The moisture content of thoroly air-dry hay depends pri - marily on the nature of the crop and the weather conditions. As an average of a large number of air-dry samples of alfalfa hay the moisture content was found to be 11.4 per cent. Under ordinary storage conditions hay will contain a somewhat higher moisture content than this, whereas under extremely favorable drying conditions in the field, such as result from a relatively high temperature, high wind velocity, and low humidity, it may contain less. Moisture contents as low as 5.0 per cent were obtained in field tests under prolonged curing (Table 22). The moisture content of field-cured hay or of hay at the stage it is considered sufficiently dry for storage is less con - stant. There are but few data available showing the maxi - mum amount of moisture that alfalfa may contain when placed in storage without subsequent injury. In method-of - curing studies herein reported notation was made of the time that the hay in each plat was considered sufficiently dry for stacking. As an average of 54 observations in 1922 the moisture content of the hay at this stage was found to be 23.4 per cent. In several cases the hay in. this condition con - tained as high as 33 per cent moisture. In 1924, as an aver - age of 48 observations, the moisture content was 23.3 per cent at the time it was considered dry enough to stack. Extremes were 30.8 and 19.1 per cent moisture content. It is believed that when the moisture content of alfalfa has been reduced to 25 per cent, it is ordinarily dry enough to stack or mow. FIELD CURING TESTS Experimental Procedure. — In view of the conflicting opin - ions and lack of experimental evidence bearing on curing practices, investigations have been made to determine the relative rates of curing, and the functioning of transpiration in reducing the moisture content of hay when cured in the swath, windrow, or cock, and when partially swath cured preceding the windrowing and cocking. The rate of curing was determined by the moisture content of samples of hay taken at stated intervals from the time it was cut until it was either field-cured or air-dry. In all tests except that beginning June 7, 1922, two parallel methods of sampling were employed and served as a check upon each other. In one case composite samples were taken </seg>
            <seg id="p085">Alfalfa Investigations at specified intervals from forage curing under each con - dition. These samples approximated 225 grams of moisture - free hay. In the second method representative samples were selected at the outset of the curing test and were retained thruout in small gauze bags made from thin, white, loosely - woven material known as tarlatan. These samples were re - tained continuously in exposures typical of the particular curing practice which they represented. At each successive interval they were removed for weighing and were immedi - ately returned to their normal exposure. These samples aver - aged approximately 75 grams of moisture-free material. These continuous samples were of two kinds. In one case they consisted of normal hay with the leaves intact while in the other case the leaves were stripped from a comparable sample of forage. In this latter instance the detached leaves and Stems were mixed and included in the same sample, so as to resemble normal hay in texture as closely as possible. It was believed that the relative curing rates of similarly exposed samples having leaves either intact or detached respectively would indicate approximately the extent to which transpiration from the leaves aids in drying the stems. Examination of the data show that the curing rate as measured by these two methods of sampling exhibit the same tendency and in most cases practically the same results. This would suggest that no marked systematic error had been in - troduced by curing the continuous samples in the thin, gauze containers. Four tests of 6-days each were conducted during 1922 and 1924 under relatively favorable weather conditions. Two of these tests, starting respectively on June 7, 1922, and July 30, 1924, were somewhat affected by rain, and are not so repre - sentative of normal curing conditions as are the two tests beginning on August 22, 1922, and August 18, 1924. . In each test, starting at 10 A. M., 24 plats one-fortieth acre in size were harvested. There was usually sufficient hay on each plat to make two average windrows about two rods in length or two cocks of normal size. In 1922 the first 12 plats were cut in the morning and the second 12 plats beginning at 1 P. M., whereas in 1924 all plats were cut in the morning. In the 1924 tests the acre yield of dry matter was determined in both the green and cured condition in order to measure the relation of the curing method to the loss of hay resulting </seg>
            <seg id="p086">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 from the shattering of leaves. As soon as the green hay weights were secured at the beginning of the test, the hay was again spread out in the swath and normal procedure fol - lowed. These 24 plats were divided into 4 groups with 6 adjacent plats in each. The first and fourth plats in each group, or eight plats in all, were cured in the swath thruout the period. The second and fifth plats in each group were windrowed and the third and sixth were placed in the cock. The wind - rowed and cocked plats in the first group were cured in that condition thruout the test ; whereas in the other three groups curing in the swath for various lengths of time preceded the windrowing and the cocking in which condition curing was completed. Swath curing before windrowing or cocking ranged in the second group from 3 to 6 hours; in the third group from 6 to 21 hours, and in the fourth group from 24 to 27 hours. The length of time for swath curing in each of these tests was determined by the degree of wilting or curing, which had taken place, i.e., (1) beginning to wilt, (2) well-wilted to one-half cured, and (3) about two-thirds cured to field-cured. In the 1924 tests the first plat in each treatment was weighed out as soon as the hay was considered sufficiently dry for stacking. The second or duplicate plat was con - tinued in the test until the hay was approximately air-dry or until the end of the curing period. Plats in the first group, however, were continued until the end of the 6-day period, since hay curing in the cock thruout seldom reached a field - cured, condition before this time. Samples were selected and first weights taken by 10 A. M. of the first day of the test for each one of the plats in the first group. Similar samples were selected from the plats in the other three groups after they had cured the designated length of time in the swath. Thereafter moisture determinations were made daily at 7 and 10 A. M. and 1 and 4 P. M. Since all weighings could not be made at the same instant, the same sequence of sampling was followed thruout so as to provide intervals of comparable length. In order to facilitate weigh - ing without undue delay, balances were set up in a protected shelter located near the center of the plats. The results re - ported in Tables 21 to 24 for the four tests are averages of the duplicate treatments. The two 1924 tests which are strictly comparable in procedure are summarized in Table 25. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 Table 21. — Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. Alfalfa cut June 7, 1922 [ ' Moisture content of alfalfa aa determined by composite samples of normal hay taken at each weighing Hay cut at 10 A. M. Hay cut at 1 P. M. Day Hourly — ; and atraom- Windrowed and cocked im- Windrowed and cocked 6 Windrowed and cocked 18 Windrowed and cocked 24 hour eter ' mediately after cutting hours after cutting ■ ■ hours after cutting hours after cutting of - evapo- — : ' : — ■ ■ — j L_j test ration Swath Windrow Cock Swath Windrow Cock Swath Windrow Cock Swath Windrow Cock eq Cc. Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per. cent C (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) (14) !i_ 1- 10 68.0 68.0 68.0 68.0 .... 1 6.08 60.7 63.5 66.9 60.7 67.5 67.5 ►-. 4 6.62 67.6 61.4 62.6 67.6 57.6 67.6 68.7 .... 58.7 _S 2- 7 1.40 46.7 57.4 60.1 46.7 . 49.7 55.2 60.4 50.4 60.4 60.4 &lt; 10 3.08 33.3 65.4 66.7 33.3 48.9 63.9 37.4 45.0 47.6 37.4 __ 1 5.33 27.6 49.5 54.6 27.5 48.1 - 51.1 35.8 41.6 42.8 36.8 36.8 35.8 V_ 4 6.08 22.2 51.1 56.7 22.2 41.2 49.3 24.5 40.1 41.9 24.5 31.7 31.4 __\ 3- 7 1.62 52.6 58.4 67.8 . 62.6 62.6 63.1 47.0 50.8 48.1 47.0 50.4 48.7 S 10 2.17 45.1 52.6 55.8 46.1 44.3 47.0 37.7 48.9 44.4 37.7 43.3 44.3 &gt; 1 4.67 26.0 62.8 61.1 26.0 42.5 44.9 31.0 41.7 40.5 81.0 39.4 89.3 _j 4 6.08 22.9 48.2 49.7 22.9 42.9 44.6 27.0 41.9 88.8 27.0 3G.2 36.5 g 4- 7 2.88 22.5 43.7 49.7 22.5 40.2 41.8 26.2 82.3 31.2 26.2 28.8 31.1 __ 10 8.75 21.7 44.0 60.6 21.7 39.3 39.0 22.1 82.3 29.2 22.1 28.8 26.5 -25 1 6.17 20.8 38.4 47.2 20.8 85.4 89.6 18.4 29.8 27.9 18.4 27.0 24.4 t/_ 4 4.83 14.9 88.3 41.0 14.9 38.0 40.6 16.9 28.6 26.6 16.9 28.8 26.0 6- 7 1.22 84.3 82.9 37.5 34.8 30.6 38.8 27.0 88.0 26.2 27.0 23.7 24.8 10 1.67 20.7 29.9 37.7 20.7 27.9 28.7 17.4 24.2 23.9 17.4 22-2 22.1 1 8.68 11.6 29.6 88.3 11.6 27.2 26.8 13.0 26.8 22.7 13.0 22.2 19.7 4 4.25 11.4 29.6 28.6 11.4 26.5 28.6 12.3 24.2 21.6 12.3 22.9 18.9 6- 7 1.77 17.7 31.9 80.7 17.7 27.6 26.7 16.7 20.4 20.6 15.7 19-2 23.1 10 3.33 15.6 22.4 30.2 15.6 24.6 22.8 16.6 20.1 22.0 16.6 18.6 17.6 1 5.00 13.6 23.4 29.8 13.6 21.7 18.7 16.2 17.0 22.7 16.2 17.7 17.7 4 5.33 11.7 19.8 24.7 11.7 21.3 22.5 13.8 17.6 16.8 13.8 16.9 16.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 Table 22. — Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cork. Alfalfa cut w August 22, 1922 * Moisture content of alfalfa as dotermined by: Day Hours Hourly ; — — — . ; — ™ and after atmom- Composite samples of Continuous composite samples retained at normal hour cutting eter normal hay taken at exposure to show function of leaves in curing pj ol evapo- each weighing — - — — ■ ■ — - - — " X test ration Swath Windrow t-ock _-, Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Swath Windrow Cock detached intact detached intact detached intact t/ J Cc. Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent __\ (1) (2) (3) (4) (6) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (II) (12) 2 WINDROWED AND COCKED IMMEDIATELY AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) _g i_ in 68 4 68.4 68.4 68.4 68.4 68.4 68.4 68.4 68.4 i ""_' '217 64.6 66.1 65.9 66.0 65.9 67.3 66.5 67.7 67.3 _-_ 4 6 3.33 69.9 62.2 66.0 62.2 61.8 63.4 64.1 66.0 66.4 jg 2- 7 21 0 77 67.3 61.0 60.6 59.5 69.1 62.8 63.5 66.0 65.5 __ 10 24 4.12 39.6 53.9 60.1 61.4 61.8 60.7 61.2 61.6 62.9 __ 1 27 3 83 26.8 54.3 61.4 41.1 42.9 56.0 57.2 65.9 59.8 4 80 9 67 14.6 53.9 60.0 31.4 30.2 44.1 46.3 45.6 48.9 M 3- 7 45 1.33 21.8 39.8 55.9 29.0 28.1 35.3 38.5 37.4 37.4 n 10 48 2.67 11.3 40.2 50.0 22.4 22.5 30.O 34.4 33.6 32.6 jj. 1 61 7.17 6.7 34.4 48.6 13.4 13.6 16.4 21.0 24.0 27.5 « 4 54 4.68 8.6 29.8 47.8 11.3 11.0 12.6 14.5 18.8 26.0 w 4- 7 69 1.36 16.8 34.7 41.3 16.4 16.2 16.8 20.1 21.2 20.1 J_? 10 72 2.33 10.7 31.8 41.0 .13.0 11.8 14.6 13.6 21.0 20.4 g 1 76 6.00 6.3 28.9 40.8 9.9 8.9 10.0 10.1 20.6 20.0 __\ 4 78 4.00 9.8 28.7 38.5 8.5 8.3 8.5 9.0 16.7 15.8 £ 5- 7 93 1.97 15.7 28.5 32.1 13.0 13.1 13.2 13.7 19.0 18.1 S 10 96 1.33 13.3 18.0 30.7 12.1 12.6 13.1 13.5 17.7 18.1 3 1 99 2.00 8.3 11.4 26.5 11.4 11.3 12.6 12.7 16.6 16.8 __\ 4 102 3.00 11.2 13.0 21.5 9.8 9.8 10.6 9.9 13.5 14.3 6- 4 126 1.66 10.7 16.0 20.0 7/7 __7 9.7 9.5 SA 9- 6 W . ■ ■ ■ ey. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">Table 22 (Continued).— Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. Al - falfa cut August 22, 1922 Moisture content of alfalfa as determined by: ; D, _ r H /J2_* _£______ ____________ _________ of Continuous composite samples retained at normal __&amp; c_{«_g "eteT exposure to ikr function of leave, in curing A ISFon _«"h weighing Swath ~ Windrow Cock V g Leaves I Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves &gt; Swath Windrow Cock detached Intact detached detached_ intact t« WINDROWED AND COCKED 6 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) 5j , • ,- 68.4 68.4 68.4 __ : . 1 1 nil 1 1 it 1 1 : i I 1 I I 1 g i 1 I 1 i </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 Taiii.k. 22 (Colli inilfil).— Relative rates of ruling alfalfa hug in the swath, windrow, and cock. AI- g fulfil cut August 22. 1.022 . w — — — = -—■■■--- - o Moisture content of ulfalfs as determined by: W anl after itmo'm- " Composite samples ol Continuous composite samples retained at normal M hour cutting oter normal hay taken at exposure to show function of leaves in curing L. J of evapo- each weighing — 1 ' ' , "_ . _~ test - ration , -- Swath | Windrow Cock y Leaves Leaves Leaves I_.qv._ I Leaves Leaven r_r_ Swath Windrow Cock detached intact | detached intact [ detached intact H = ~ = ' ==^Trr" ZeZln~l l^TcTnT "Prrrent ~Perc,„l Per cent Pet cenl l""cenl I V.Tce',1 P'rcs'st H ,,, (2) 13) (4) (5) (6. (7) (8) (91 (10) I (11) (12) 3 WINDROWED AND COCKED 21 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 1 P. M.I 2 ,11 . 68.0 I 68.0 I 68.0 ; ' .8 3.33 64.2 65.4 65.3 . W - _ I ,0 0 77 59 5 i 63.7 63.4 . ... I K 2 ~ ,0 2- 4 12 566 56 6 5B.6 59.3 58.9 66.6 Sfi.B 56.6 56.6 g , 5_ .B. 4?'. 54 . 54 1 45 0 12.7 47.7 46.7 49.4 50.3 W i I. 967 3 "3 493 49! 38 40.3 36.4 36.6 38.4 ! 38.6 &gt; 3 7 42 li3 II 39:_ 38.8 29.6 31.9 31.1 32.4 28.8 29.7 W ,„ it iis. 142 34 8 36 1 23.7 23.2 26.5 27.5 25.8 26.3 y '? if 7 - .7 6 3 2-6 34.6 15:4 15.0 17.3 18.2 19.6 18.1 » i 61 458 8.0 203 28.1 13.3 11.7 13.6 15.9 15.6 4.5 . _K I Sfi ill 192 34 1 16.7 16.9 15.1 17.8 19.1 17.8 CO 4_ ,„ g| 233 9. 20.8 32.- 8.8 ! 2 .4 12.3 15.1 18.1 14.6 g 1 72 BOO 60 20 2 29.2 11.6 9.9 8.9 11.8 16.6 13.1 _- I ?_ .'nn 5. 19 8 24 7 10.4 8.0 8.8 9.9 14.7 11.5 _- . 7-0 l'97 140 210 250 4.4 13.6 12.7 13.9 14.7 14.1 M 5 " 10 93 133 3.0 202 20.5 14.0 13.2 12.2 13.7 14.1 3.9 H 1 9G 200 7 1.10 18.0 12.0 10.8 9.4 10.9 12.6 13.5 B 4 99 §Io° llJ I-..0 16.7 11.6 10.4 8.2 10.1 113 12.2 * 6_ 4 123 1.55 13.9 14.3 15.0 8.8 8.5 6.9 8.9 7.7 8.3 w _ _ _______ , . . — O- </seg>
            <seg id="p091">Alfalfa Investigations **** 11 *• g** c^ &gt;Mllue. ;nto«ioo)t-«one.MHiDeOH C «___ i- : K _________ 1 f t_ el O — „ . *S» ' fen H _ It b V °T. i&gt; _. II 8-fc - * e s « JS2 __ C ::: •' •»S2SS22'^'2■2'2d-i ,,, ' I is PT" • __ C Z_ Srt "° • : e . t . e . e .ca— eic-.-t---__._o 'I _? II § &lt;-T -? Mi: ;SSS22SS° ;a '2222' ,,i _! pS __ Is -_ B* -a " .• ■» ■_ j_i it 8_S If S 1 •« II 31 _? _3 : : : :SS8SS2S32352S 0&gt; ' _«;■ ||| *» A 1 1 «v - 2 !*■• ° ■_, _' » _ 5_S 'Si e 8 2 1 B R *+*-- P &gt;"§ 8C S 9"**. 'S*- 'I® *_&lt;«:»*- W»-«"*OO(D00 rs * "___&gt; ° fl 9 I _C&gt; IT W^^OiioeoO-Mioeotfieo^oW — »»___•_ $-. | ZJ — _, ; __ *- o "05 _. — * g ?p .§ ' S S_. 2 : : c . u . e . &lt; .'. , .&lt;'-««&gt;»e&gt;t-«-- H "§ . s» 6 h sw : : : : :SSSS2S25 , °2!-i222 u 5 «e- II "*_ _ °_i B • _ II Q " i^I 111 § •••■• « «k. sjs* I U s o : : : : :SS2S3S 0&gt;,o ' o 2dSS'S . f is n — Q ■ _- o o -a . jw y g _ _____ 'Ii II P5 _ * II ■ 'S • n — -— B M W 5S.5 •raoo-&lt;Tft-egioo.-«too&gt;e.u-o-._)-i-. O a"5s . B ; . • L. " O 6 . • ,. 1 ! —^ __________ _______________ cm -, a ™ "a ** S _ll*I S M a a j_ *&gt; w &lt; •. E -1 &gt; it t i i i </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 a I I II 5 ! S-lll a . £ S ".-.". , -.'- , . , .'-«?»'»ot ; «&gt;«&gt;_-eit-- 1 eiojooq ess *f v— ffl 10 N © © CI 00 1- .- io u_ a. ___S__-_a__I __0*-(0_. v_. J- __ »S&lt;_&lt;Cl.i.«M_i_«ii.__°,nN«NMN-H ** T_ 1 O an ' 2s- Ijr l#s s ! *; _ 25 fcw S_9» _»»w^««ciioV'«^ci-oe_e»o»«*«id * -. _J_ _T &lt;0 ** (O W IO IO U3 US IO W5 lOKSlO US -foaMC) —!-*«•-«-* C ( e S , — ! _jg Its t . • • • "*S _."o i. Se fcC- *» 2y_.°___:*NNN«O«V-000»T.H ' . '«' T_ E « ™ ' ■g go CI I o ■ — ' S l _ 52 * I 8 * I * ••• O I F &gt;"S {__I to . , . c ". t . ao . t ~.1* 0 .- - owes MCoefV tow M ■ Tf "I » If r § ■ •" *5 § 3 &gt; a ii -jj £ »ow-«q;o«io«iONCftwo©eiiqto&lt;ooq n "^ ' I — __i S g^lli.SE:eioat^No«ie»«N_-()0^o««_i'*-No6t* ■!"•-• a ; _ 1 8 S J [«- o ~ | - - 8 ; (S ■ *-&gt; g o H _ J-i ... -\T o &gt;- § |[ £c H **'^«J l oo«^;««»Oe5-_;eq^o«.-HO ■ © fi "1 1 1 ' Zll 5 ' ' ' * s _ i i nrr n : § ?. I I o u£ 2 .o^iomb ,&gt;oe&gt;5r_N_.t-o_e.^NN-. S I o- I u If 3 --»&lt;o_._&gt;_&gt;_._^-»&lt;_ io-. -.T.-.^c.eo»..N «2.*» |i-J ■ g ~ I a 8 b i ii 3 i«vi j I S &gt;,■£ ± g—. 9 (ooitDw-ctooo^-ioosf-^oiteteooooo ■ ■ « ° i s£ * I u s 8 ssss_.s_s.siss. sjsigsjaaa^ • • -s | lis 1—8 !___§ * ii * _S&gt; &gt;. o i e O ■ - 5 _ _. O 1 .'— . Q_ t-OC-t- OOt-Nt-OO NOOOOOOOOONM-SOO MOO ? 2bS«_ l_S S : -o&lt;.&lt;.o'.&lt;=.-;'.«NoioS?oS.o.ei.o-.S a5"^2 IS • l0 '* oo NNOO--oo_.-f--e.c-i_e-^ — _:_. § U^ L_?_ "w* It "** » J »S 9 ■_£ -^ WW.-^ft-©»Oa0*iTfOiN»OC0«tO0_Mt-©»» I L 2J; j o--ft»©-H^t-o--^t*©-H^ft"©^^t»©^(^ V,---, *• ._, 1 •__■ _yO 3^.15 I -— ■ g Q«_ « || - c__ H I J. _ „ * _ i </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Table 23 (Continued).— Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. Alfalfa cut July SO, 1924 Moiature content of alfalfa aa determined by: 'A • SXT- pw^hln, Swath Windrow Cod. £ Leavea I Leavea Leaves I/savea Ifaves e ? v _* 2 Swath Windrow Cock detached Intact detached _&amp;**&amp;*&amp;_. »"*»» g WINDROWED AND COCKED 3 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) g &lt; * i i 1 1 if 1 II II I T S i:°e? ii:i 8S S3 SB: || : | : If § - . I I I I I I 1 111 1 1 '" i I I 111 111 6- 7 »3 2- 4 » 15 - 6 1B -2 ?_? .§_ .? _ ill ii! 159 142 J ig _:i_ i 2 7 :. J- iil iS ili g g jg ""» </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 Tahi.e 23 (Continued). — Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. 5. Alfalfa cut July JO, 1924 | Moisture content of alfalfa as determined by: ~T Day Hours Hourly — ■ . pg and after atmom- Composite samples of Continuous composite samples retained at normal hour cutting eter normal hay taken at exposure to show function of leaves in curing of evapo- each weighing — • , - 1 Py teat rat/on ■ Swath Windrow Cock X Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leavea Leaves Swath Windrow Cock detached intact detached intact detached intact r/_, &lt; V. Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cenl Per cent Per rent Per cent Per cent ;&gt; (I) (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (8) (10) (11) (12) ►_ WINDROWED AND COCKED G HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) 3 1- 10 69.6 69.6 69.6 ? 1 _ 5.1 7 53.7 60.6 59.0 4 6 4.00 43.7 43.7 43.7 49.4 47.5 43.7 43.7 43.7 43.7 SO 2- 7 21 0.63 41.6 38.0 39.4 43.6 42.4 40.1 41.4 40.4 39.9 M 10 24 0.67 37.9 35.3 36.8 41.5 40.0 89.2 39.5 39.1 39.2 CQ 1 27 2.08 36.5 31.4 34.3 36.0 36.3 36.8 37.6 37.0 38.0 M 4 30 2.67 25.6 25.6 32.0 29.3 29.5 33.3 34.0 34.7 36.7 &gt; 3- 7 46 0.62 40.0 35.6 38.6 33.7 33.3 33.6 33.6 34.3 35.3 JO 10 48 0.17 36.6 32.8 35.0 32.3 32.5 34.0 33.4 34.2 35.2 O 1 51 1.58 28.6 29.3 34.3 28.3 29.2 32.1 32.1 32.7 33.7 X 4 ' 54 0.92 29.7 30.1 32.0 28.5 28.9 33.0 31.8 32.0 33.4 4- 7 69 0.28 59.8 67.6 58.3 64.3 51.6 50.3 61.0 40.6 41.6 M 10 72 2.00 46.9 47.9 46.2 40.4 40.0 41.6 42.5 36.8 39.4 __ 1 75 4.58 27.7 29.3 32.2 22.3 23.0 25.3 28.4 27.5 24.5 S 4 78 4.60 18.6 18.8 26.7 16.1 16.2 19.2 19.3 26.4 22.6 _-, 6- 7 93 2.40 15.6 15.2 19.5 15.0 14.6 17.6 15.4 16.7 17.4 __ 10 96 3.08 14.3 13.6 17.0 12.6 11.6 13.5 13.3 16.3 12.7 H 1 99 6.42 10.1 10.0 13.5 9.1 8.6 10.6 8.1 8.8 9.9 fj 4 102 3.83 7.9 8.5 8.3 8.0 7.8 8.3 7.6 8.5 9.4 Z 6- 4 126 1.78 12.7 14.6 16.7 12.0 11.3 13.5 12.6 13.4 13.4 . -J ■ 05 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">Tabif 23 (Concluded). -Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. Alfalfa cut July 30, 1924 _____ '; Moisture content of alfalfa aa determined by: Day Hours Hourly . ,.„„,„„.!.. umt-lea of Continuous composite samples retained at normal Si cSttinV "StST SSBStwtStt? exposure to show function of leaves _ cur/ng_ hour . cutting ««* each weighing — .' Windrow Cock \_ teat ration _____ . i— — -— — ___ '"" Windrow _Co ± _^ = S=^^l=^=^= 6" ( " WINDROWED AND COCKED 27 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) | bob 69,6 69.6 B l- io •••••• -v,v b_7 •■•■ 6 »- 6 B9 -° ES 1 3 5.17 OS. i ._ . . 7 5 H_ '. . 6 4.00 43.7 \%\ JH " ,_ 7 21 0.63 41.6 .«•• 3J-J g 2 ,0 24 0.67 37.9 ••■•• \\l IM _.__■ 35.5 35.5 35.5 &gt; ■ 1 27 2.08 36.5 35.5 35.5 36.0 35.3 35 5 j . g 4 30 • 2.67 25.6 30.0 31.3 29.3 __■£ . 36 30 „ 330 Q 3- 7 46 0.62 40.0 37.6 37.7 33.7 33.3 31^ J - 33 g 10 48 0.17 36.6 34.9 33.2 32.3 32-5 31 J a g g 1 61 1.58 28.6 32-2 33.6 28.3 |»^ « __ __ 0 32- 2 4 54 0.92 29.7 32.4 32.4 28.5 28.9 *_■* g - 43 6 42 . 8 _ 7 69 0.28 59.8 56.8 60.4 64.3 51.6 4D.1 j 3g^ 10 72 2-DO 46.9 47.7 41.3 40.4 40.0 33 3 39 i £ 1 76 4.68 27.7 26.8 36.4 22.3 2^.0 M-i J 6 24 4 4 78 4.60 18.6 20.7 24.4 16.1 }»•£ }° _ J 6 7 16r3 17.8 - __ 7 93 240 15.6 14.8 21.5 15.0 14.5 14..S to-' 3 16 7 *~ 10 96 3.08 145 13.8 21.0 12.6 1|.| I" »|J }H !2.0 1 99 6.42 10.1 9.9 18.9 9.1 »•» M M 10-4 9.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 Table 24.— Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. Alfalfa cut g August IS, 1924 g. Moisture content of alfalfa as determined by: Day Hours o I j£" r 'j' rnmnoslte sample- of Continuous composite samples retained at normal n h'our c_it?_g «".«"" SThTtaK «£««» sh^Junction_one^^uring „ A ' °r V a?C !__**S — Swath Windrow Cock Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leavea X Swath Windrow Cock detached intact detached intact detached^ intact _ T&gt; WINDROWED AND COCKED IMMEDIATELY AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) H «R7 66 7 66 7 66.7 66.7 66.7 66.7 66.7 66.7 _\ - i i 1 : nil £ Hi Hi S3 S3 S3 : g *? .. KB. 1H8 32 5 44 9 23.7 22.6 61.6 61.3 68.6 66.8 m _ .0 M_ Hi 304 43_! 24.7 24.3 48.1 47.2 65.4 54.8 w ._ - __ 078 397 371 46„ 36.0 33.9 46.8 46.1 63.4 52.5 fc. *" , 4_ ?flf 223 314 43 3 28.1 26.7 44.6 44.1 52.7 51.7 » - i 1 I ?3 la 9 :? S3 83 S3 S3 S3 | « I : 13 It! S3 S3 io 3 :? S3 | S3 g .• 8? ?MS 236 20 4 28 6 21.6 18.9 26.6 25- 32.2 33.0 £-, ' I 1 I ill III fi ft II B B I I i !S tfi Si !« S3 SI K IB is ■_ a, -&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 Table 24 (Continued). — Relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. . • Alfalfa cut August IS, 1924 ' Moisture content of alfalfa aa determined by: Day Hours Hourly , ' ' .1 . . and after atmom- Composite samples of Continuous composite samples retained at normal hour cutting eter normal hay taken at exposure to show function of leaves in curing ' £&gt; of evapo- each weighing ! 1 1 C, test ration - : — Swath Windrow ' Cock __ 1 _. p. Leavea Leavea Leaves * Leaves Leaves Leaves _h ■ Swath ' Windrow Cock detached intact detached intact detached Intact n_ Cc. Percent' Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent (1) (2) . (S) (4) (6) (6) . , (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) g WINDROWED AND COCKED 8 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) &lt;■ 1- 10 . ...... • 66.7 '66.7 66.7 '. .... . GO 1 8 9.00 62.3 . 62.3 62.3 ' 57.3 68.0 52.3 52.3 52.3 52.3 _3 4 6 6.76 41.9 43.8 48.1 47.8 47.6 47.9 47.1 47.8 49.0 3 2- 7 .21 1.86 32.6 35.2 88.0 87.7 87.1 88.9 88.7 42.8 42.4 &gt; .10 24 4.67 27.4 81.4 37.3 30.8 30.5 36.2 ' 35.9 41.4 40.4 l_ 1 27 5.67 18.8 . 26.6 35.5 23.7 22.6 81.0 31.8 88.6 37.5 K 4 SO 4.33 16.2 22.6 28.6 24.7 24.3 27.7 28.9 37.5 36.0 2 3- 7 45 0.78 39.7 31.1 86.7 86.0 33.9 32.2 31.2 36.3 36.5 Z 10 48 1.33 22.3 26.0 29.6 28.1 26.7 30.1 80.3 36.0 84.4 m 1 61 4.67 11.1 20.0 23.2 17.9 16.7 22.7 23.9 34.8 83.8 4 64 9.33 10.2 12.3 22.3 16.0 14.3 19.6 21.1 28.8 28.5 4- 7 69 8.60 14.9 16.7 22.8 18.9 17__ 17.1 16.8 24.9 23.2 10 72 333 12.9 14.6 28.0 15.9 16.1 15.7 16.1 18.9 22.0 1 75 6.83 9.9 11.9 19.8 12.6 12.6 11.9 11.8 16.9 17.0 4 78 6.83 9.1 9.0 14.6 10.7 10.2 9.7 9.4 11.9 10.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">Table 24 (Conchuletl).— Relative votes of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock. Alfalfa cut August IS. 1924 . .. Moisture content of alfalfa as determined by: __ an- after™ .Mm- Composite sTn^Tc. Continuous composite samples retained at normal W hour cutting eter normal hay taken at exposure to ahow funct.'on of leaves in curing ___, B ra V ?i P on • -i Wlndrow Cock &gt; Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves W Swath Windrow Cock deUched Intact detached intact detached^ intact "" _ "^^ = " ====i== "" ==== Percen( "TZcTZ ~ Per cent Per cent ~PerlcnT "^T^T /V«»l Prr cenl Pel j|e_l £ (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (II) (12) y WINDROWED AND COCKED 6 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) I- 10 66.7 66.7 66.7 CO i _ .:?_ S3 -ii*- 4,: 9 - 83 3 i..y .,:»' «*• «&gt;" &gt; ,. S i3? S3 U3 S3 52 | | g || ■ g 1 27 5.67 18.8 22.5 26.8 23.7 22.6 25.0 24.1 29.7 29.1 .g 4 30 4.33 16.2 20.8 25.3 24.7 24.3 23.3 22.7 27.9 26.9 3- 7 45 0 78 39.7 32.2 31.1 36.0 33.9 29.6 28.1 28.3 28.9 10 48 138 25!3 23.1 26.9 28.1 26.7 26.6 26.8 26.9 27.6 g) 1 51 4 67 111 17 5 21.2 17.9 16.7 19.0 17.6 22.J £*■£ M 4 54 933 ii lie 223 16.0 143 13.4 12.9 20.7 20.7 W i- 7 « 9 s -«° I4 - 9 ,M l9 - 2 Ml _•? l-i i.? i«o i?3 " •? ?l ill 'I-. J?3 £_ S3 13 'S3 o.l S3 I?:! S 4 78- i-li S3 83 93 10.7 }o.2 8.4 8.1 9.6 11.0 g WINDROWED AND COCKED 24 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) 1- 10 66.7 66.7 66.7 W 1 3 9 00 52.3 57.3 68.0 C _ 6 B-75 4.3 47.8 47.6 g o 7 oi 1 oe 32 6 ... 37.7 37.1 ■_.'■;• _^ 10 24 467 274 27 4 27.4 30.8 30.5 27.4 27.4 27.4 27.4 M 1 27 53. 183 20 7 20.8 23.7 22.6 2-3 24.9 223 23.6 H 4 30 433 162 19.7 21.8 24.7 21.3 22.0 21.7 22.2 22.2 H 3- 7 45 0 .8 397 33.9 26.8 363 33.9 30.2 30.5 24.4 25.2 in 4« 1 .. 22 3 23 3 23 1 28.1 26.7 29.1 28.6 22.4 24.6 1 5_ \fl II "I 18.1 185 T7.9 16.7 21.2 20.3 17.7 20.1 g 4 64 9 33 103 12 2 16.6 16.0 14.3 13.4 15.3 15.3 173 OT 4 7 69 360 149 15 7 14.9 18.9 17.2 16.3 16.6 12.7 13.9 11 72 333 23 4 6 3 6 15.9 16.1 13.8 13.5 12.0 13.9 1 75 5 83 9 9 12.8 11.4 12.5 12.6 11.1 12.3 10.9 10.4 I 78 683 9.1 03 0.7 10.7 10.2 8.6 8.5 73 . 8.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">Table' 25. — Summary 1 of relative rates of curing alfalfa liay in the swath, windrow, and code. Moisture content of alfalfa as determined by: ; * Da _" «, Hourly Comnoslto samolea of Continuous composite samples retained at normal hour 5tS* e"tc°r m " S5Slfi r , fffl_ , «t expoaure to show function of leave. In curing of cSttlng evapo- each weighing Swath Windrow Cock test . ration Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Leaves Swath Windrow Cock detached Intact detached Intact detached intact Cc. ' Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent (I) (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) WINDROWED AND COCKED IMMEDIATELY AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) , 1- 10 68.2 68.2 683 68.2 68.2 683 683 68.2 683 1 8 7.09 63.0 60.9 633 69.0 58.6 63.8 63.1 65.8 64.5 4 . 6 4.88 42.8 66.6 59.5 48.6 47.6 69.1 58.7 62.8 62.1 &gt;■ 2- 7 21 134 37.1 60.4 57.0 40.7 89.8 68.8 633 69.6 59.7 C&lt; 10 24 2.67 82.7 45.6 64.1 863 85.3 61.9 61.6 68.8 69.1 •_ 1 27 3.88 273 40.1 60.0 29.9 29.0 493 49.4 S7.6 68.3 &gt; 4 SO 3.60 20.9 39.1 47.5 27.0 26.9 46.1 .45.8 65.6 66.7 t* 8- 7 45 0.70 39.9 46.1 62.8 84.9 33.6 463 43.8 63.7 65.0 3 10 48 0.76 29.6 89.0 51.8 803 29.6 44.4 433 533 64.5 &gt; 1 61 8.13 19.9 34.9 433 23.1 23.0 423 40.5 . 623 61.7 4 64 6.13 20.0 82.1 43.1 223 21.6 363 35.1 613 61.1 _T 4- 7 69 1.94 87.4 87.8 61.6 86.6 84.4 41.4 38.7 50.7 61.7 "5 10 72 2.67 29.9 883 473 283 27.6 383 343 46.9 49.6 S 1 76 531 .18.8 803 40.6 17.4 17.8 273 27.7 43.9 44.0 F2 4 78 6.17 13.9 21.6 883 12.9 . 183 20.7 223 39.4 39.1 zi 5- 7 93 1.96 19.6 21.7 84.9 183 16.7 21.0 21.8 823 32.4 S 10 96 2.58 14.6 17.1 83.6 18.9 18.0 18.7 20.7 29.7 80.0 G 1 99 4.88 103 14.4 83.1 10.6 10.1 ' 16.6 163 28.9 263 &gt; 4 102 4.13 8.4 9.9 80.0 93 8.9 133 143 20.6 23.6 __\ 6- 4 126 1.88 11.9 163 22.4 11.1 10.0 13.6 13.0 17.8 19.4 © WINDROWED AND COCKED 8 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) _g 1- 10 683 68.2 683 » 1 8 7.09 63.0 63.0 68.0 69.0 68.6 68.0 63.0 63.0 63.0 4 6 4.88 42.8 433 46.0 48.6 47.6 45.4 45.0 45.9 45.6 2- 7 21 134 87.1 86.6 89.1 40.7 39.8 87.7 37.6 413 41.6 10 24 2.67 82.7 88.6 87.0 863 353 85.9 86.5 403 403 1 27 8.88 273 29.1 86.7 29.9 29.0 82.4 823 88.4 87.5 4 80 8.60 20.9 26.0 803 27.0 26.9 29.6 29.1 863 84.9 8- 7 46 0.70 39.9 293 87.8 84.9 38.6 81.7 80.6 86.7 843 10 48 0.76 29.6 29.6 88.0 803 29.6 80.6 803 86.5 33.8 1 61 8.18 19.9 243 28.6 23.1 28.0 26.8 26.8 34.6 83.0 4 64 5.18 20.0 203 26.6 223 21.6 24.8 24.8 81.6 80.0 4- 7 69 1.94 87.4 88.0 88.8 86.6 84.4 38.6 82.6 88.0 823 10 72 2.67 29.9 81.0 82.9 283 27.6 26.7 26.6 27.8 30.8 1 76 631 18.8 19.9 26.6 17.4 17.8 17.7 17.8 22.0 23.1 4 78 6.17 18.9 14.1 18.9 12.9 183 13.6 14.0 16.6 17.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">Table 25 (Concluded) .Summary ' of relative rates of curing alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock ~~ Moisture c intent of alfalfa as determined by: _ _ _ . _ _ - ------- co Day Hours Hourly r&gt;„" m „„«ite samoles of Continuous composite samples retained at normal -0 r d .Stun* "e^r "oXT hay" SSesfnl exposure t„ show function of leave, ,„ curing hour cuttmg __t weighing - _^_T~ " Windrow Cock &gt; tcgt ration _ ___,... — ;•* Sw sth Windrow Cock de= « _S3=, « j&amp; J^= « ( " WINDROWED AND COCKED 6 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) 68 2 68.2 6«-2 j . .... I ... • J§ ' ""s a sis .... j.. Ii II a. 'si s s _ WINDROWED AND COCKED 27 HOURS AFTER CUTTING (CUT 10 A. M.) B o 2 , . 68.2 68.2 ! CO '" '? "*' 'to*' "" m ffi :::::: S 4 6 4.oo *£.o 40 7 39 8 C 1 7! 1 1 1 1 § 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 - lIllPIEi.biBi iAverage'of 1924 data reported in Tables 23 and 24. </seg>
            <seg id="p101">Table 26. — Recorded weather observations for the curing periods beginning June 7 and August 22, 1922, and July 30 and August IS, 1924 . _____ . Temperature Wind Velocity Per Solar Relative Humidity Rain- Dew . _ -• cent inten- — fall Year Month Day 24-hr. 11-hr. Max- Mini- 24-hr. 12-hr. of . sity 7 A. M 1 P. M. 7 P. M. Aver - raean mean imum mum mean mean pos- . age (7 A.M. (7 A. M. sible . 7 P.M.) 7 P. M.) sun - shine ' —^— — =-"-= ~d7oTf~. Den. F. Dcg.F. Deg. T. Miles' Miles Per cent Oram. Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent In. cnlor. (1) (2) (3) (4) (6) . (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) (14) (15) (16) (17) 1922 June 7 77 83 88 66 10.3 12.2 93 ... 80 39 43 54 8 80 86 90 67 9.7 10.6 87 ... 81 36 39 62 ... ... £" 9 78 84 89 64 16.6 17.8 51 ... 89 61 50 63 35 ... £j 10 80 86 92 68 163 15.9 86 ... 73 48 66 62 ... ... 11 76 81 87 61 6.2 5.7 53 ... 87 45 35 66 ... Heavy £ 12 83 92 98 65 10.8 11.9 70 ... 52 40 42 45 \__ " " AV. 79 85~ 91 65 11.6 12.4 73 ... 77 43 46 65 ....... 1922 Aug. 22 76 79 84' 69 7.8 ' 8.2 48 ... 88 72 63 71 ... ... £ isr__ Aug. jg g . 6S 7g 9g gj 33 34 5, __ ight 24 87 97 104 66 7.0 3.7 77 ... 70 20 33 41 c_ 26 72 80 85 56 73 7.8 92 ... 77 21 32 43 ... ... __ 26 70 74 78 62 7.2 7.7 47 ... 64 21 47 44 T ... H 27 76 83 90 69 7.9 9.5 100 ... 79 30 26 . 45 __ | "07. 78 85 63 ~73 7.5 77 ... 77 33 38 49 g 1994 J11W 30 78 85 89 67 7.6 11.0 99 687.6 93 65 60 69 ... Heavy g 1924 July 30 78 »» » o 1. 1 6g LI ght _, . a i 7, 73 77 64 8.1 9.0 1 165.6 90 75 94 86 .10 Heavy W AUg - 2 83 88 94 70 15.9 18.4 89 683.6 74 45 60 66 .17 ... 3 89 94 101 78 143 14.0 99 684.6 54 37 38 43 ... ■ ... 4 83 85 88 78 7.5 .7.0 45 3733 91 65 63 73 T Light Av! 80 84 88~ : 70 93 10.8 67 604.7 81 59 60 66 1924 Aug. 18 80 86 94 67 12.9 183 80 686.1 88 47 56 64 T '" * 19 83 87 92 76 10.0 9.9 90 565.5 70 49 72 64 ...... 20 86 93 101 72 11.4 11.4 71 683.9 99 38 41 69 Heavy 21 85 90 96 74 14.2 14.8 . 85 480.7 67 42 60 53 ...... 22 73 78 84 60 5.8 6.1 81 664.6 79 38 47 65 Heav. 23 * 79 85 93 71 8.1 9.0 68 601.8 83 55 70 69 T ... JU 81 87 93 70 10A 10.9 79 617.1 79 45 58 61 Data" in columns 4 to 16 were compiled from the records of a nearby station of the Nebraaka Section, U. S. Weather Bureau and those in columns 16 and 17 were taken adjacent to the curing test. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station. Research Bulletin 36 The average hourly evaporation data from two Livingston atmometers situated in the alfalfa field have been included in the tables to show the correlation between the rate of curing and the weather conditions as expressed by the rate of water loss from the clay cups. The daily maximum and minimum temperatures, wind velocity, relative humidity, per cent sun - shine, and other weather observations for each one of the curing tests are reported in Table 26. Results as to Rate of Curing. — The data recorded in Table 27 show the number of hours required for hay curing in the swath, windrow, or cock to reach 30 per cent moisture con - tent. These results are based on the moisture contents of the composite samples as presented in Tables 1 21 to 24. Table 27. — Number of hours 1 required for hay curing in swath, windrow, and cock to reach 30 per cent m.oisture Content as determined by composite samples taken periodically. From Tables 21 to 24 Curing thruout Partial swath curing preceding wind - the test in ing and cocking for 1 Test Beginning 1 1 ' 10A.M. 3-6 hours 6-21 hours 24-27 hours Swath [windrow Cock Windrow Cock Windrow Cock Windrow Cock TOTAL NUMBER OF HOURS FROM TIME OF HARVESTING June 7, 1922 27 96 102 96 96 72 I 69 I 30 30 August 22, 1922.. 27 54 99 48 51 48 51 30 30 July 30, 1924 30 78 126 30 33 30 33 1 30 33 August 18, 1924 .24 33 81 27 30 24 2? 24 24 Average . . . 27 I 65 1 102 50 53 44 | 46 | 29 ( 29 NUMBER OF HOURS FROM 7 A. M. TO 7 P. M. DURING TEST July 7, 1922 I 15 1 48 54 48 48 36 33 18 18 August 22, 1922 . 15 30 51 24 27 24 27 18 18 July 30, 1924 18 42 66 18 21 18 21 18 21 August 18, 1924 . 12 21 45. 15 18 12 15 12 12 Average... 15 35 54 26 29 23 24 17 17 1 Hay with 30.1 to 32.0 per cent moisture content at 4 P. M. waa considered as having 30 per cent or less by 7 P. M. -These periods represent the approximate statres : beginning to wilt, well wilted, and about two-thirds cured. As an average of the 4 curing tests wherein alfalfa was cut at 10 A. M. or 1 P. M., it was found in the case of swath curing that 27 hours were required to reduce its moisture con - tent to 30 per cent. Where hay was cured thruout in the windrow or cock, 65 and 102 hours were required respectively for hay to reach this same degree of moisture content. Where </seg>
            <seg id="p103">Alfalfa Investigations swath curing to the "beginning to wilt ", " well-wilted ", and " two-thirds cured " stages preceded windrowing or cocking, 50 and 53, 44 and 45, and 29 and 29 hours were required, respectively, to reduce the hay to a. 30 per cent moisture content. Relative curing rates of hay by these various meth - ods as averaged for the two 1924 tests (Table 25) are shown graphically in Chart 6. ■AWift-TIiiiiiiiiMiiiiii'iiii MII| iiiim i-~-::::~~:~::~:~~~::~~:::::~~ SM,Ws _."_.:: _ :_:_:i:i_i_i . After 3 ha? — «:5:_:._j , r eh*?- - *":__i":"_""'::"_:":::":::::::44- i27 ' / "' i - = " mmmmimmm ii _H~i._\~-' _ — 4:::::::::::::::::::::::::-:: 1111111 Etffp rt ::_:_:=_:::::::::::3::::::::::::awa3): fl _ j._ --;--] At once= «:\:::::::_;__::A:::;-^::::::^rj^- ; - :: ...__._ J -7&lt;= \--- r oft/3? -4i _ _ s i, h ,. ::~ _ :: _ __L. 1^ -E::::::z:::-:e:--i:U^:is-^::S^::-::-::^ _ ______._______________V,-.---.--;5j 6 7 4 jj _ i * jl-m^iFFH^ 1 1 BimnJir _toi_55 9isair35i9-KssrawT5ia.Brs3siism m i» Chart 6. — Comparative curing of alfalfa hay in the swath, windrow, and cock as determined from composite samples of normal hay taken at stated intervals from time of cutting. (Table 25.) </seg>
            <seg id="p104">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 These data show very clearly that windrowing and cocking of relatively green or slightly cured hay will materially pro - long the curing period. It is further shown that the time required to reduce hay to a field-cured or air-dry condition is shortened as the period of swath-curing is extended. Results Concerning Transpiration as a Factor in Curing. — A study of the rate of curing, as measured by the continu - ous samples having their leaves either intact or detached, respectively, indicates that the normal functioning of the leaves is not significantly instrumental in the withdrawal of moisture from the stems. Of the 487 comparative moisture determinations bearing on this problem (Tables 22 to 24) it was found that the 2 kinds of samples differed as much as 1 per cent or less in moisture 253 times, or in 52 per cent of the comparisons. In the remaining comparisons or those differing more than 1 per cent in moisture content, the sample with the leaves intact had a somewhat lower moisture content than the corresponding sample with leaves detached in 117 cases, and a somewhat higher moisture content in an equal number of instances. The two comparative 1924 tests of the parallel curing rates of alfalfa with leaves intact and those with leaves detached are shown graphically in Chart 7. The fact that alfalfa windrowed or cocked in a green or partially cured condition lost moisture more slowly than when cured entirely in the swath, is further evidence of the fallacy of a rather common opinion that such conditions prolong the normal transpiratory functioning of the leaves in the cut forage, thereby accelerating the rate of moisture from the stems. The histological views of a typical alfalfa stem and leaf shown in Figs. 17, 18, and 19 are of some interest in this connection by way of illustrating the character of the material from which water must be evaporated in the curing process. Fig. 18 shows cross- and longi-sections of the stem with its peripheral distribution of the vascular system. The epidermis of the alfalfa stem is generally supplied with stomata as may be seen in the lower view of Fig. 19, except in the regions of collenchymatous tissue which may comprise one-fourth of the stem surface. A comparison of Fig. 17 (center) with Fig. 18 (above) which are low power cross sections, is suggestive of the marked difference in mass of material between leaves and stems which must be dried during curing. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">Alfalfa Investigations Percent Mqafner '.....■ '. ?TmT n |M " _ffj:::::::::::::::::::::::::swB" ' I Mil II: . Leaves Intact* - i::::i:iiiiiiii::i::i::zi Leaves Detached' — . : wj I V. 1 ..... i .. i . I I i- _ «:::_^_;::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: SliilliplllI ■:___________-_________-_____!_______-___-i_ _! C „ - - - - m m - 12~ 2--\\'_\_\-- ------ ----- -' WINDROWED, tat once, ~t I a :___^::i:ii:ii::i:ii::i::zi i«_v« infect 1 . z m _: _, _ Leaves Detached* - «Z\ZZZZZZZ^ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ WlMMn),lafter 3 hrs) Z as" -I ___! = = H:: :_ S Leaves Intact- v !_ r I ______£__;:_;____. Leaves Detached*- : : :;;===:;: h:l==!hi!jjj S I^Kee;; -EEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEE^=_E_!==_!i=EE=-EEE= - 6::.^::::::::__::_:::_::_:_:___::::::_____ __;;:::::::::::::::::::::::: cocked, (at once) -Lfcf - *IIIII-!_!_:S^~IIIIIIIIIIIi;iII Leaves Intact= ' Z st- :-._!s^ , Zea.es Detached* - «Z\ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZzZZZ\ZZ COCKED.Cafter 3 hrs) _I -_»«__ n Leaves Intact- :::::__ s ;::::::::::: zzzzz^zzeaves Detochetfr—-z ":::::::::::::::::::::::::_:::::::::::::::: n _ _. Jt-H+Ha 1 1 1 1 1 I la 1 1 1 1 1 1 la- 1 1 II 1 1 la-t-1 1 1 II |§±b Hour) s- 9 IS U _7 33 39 45 Si- ST 63 69 TS B BT 93 99 KS m UTSS Chart 7. — Function of leaves in the field-curing of alfalfa hay. Com - parative curing in the swath, windrow, and cock of hay with leaves intact and detached. (Table 25.) </seg>
            <seg id="p106">Nebr. -Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 : __________________________ ■ Mm Mm ______% v t-_i___i _■ --"•';M____ ■ -________________''-__!__________■'' _1 ■_ V _r _______________ ______ __r _______ ___. *--S_____________________l _______ _______ ____&gt;T^ ___h * r_._T .. '■ - ("______ B_p&amp;_f_ _____ f^_^^^^^^^^^^^-«-'-" ■- -■' - -'••'-'■ :;j -- •^■■ : - 1 Fig. 17— Above, photograph of alfalfa leaf (x 1.5) ; center, photo - micrograph of a median cross-section of leaflet (x 20) ; and below, a portion of cross-section (x!75). </seg>
            <seg id="p107">\__. Alfalfa Investigations ________ _______ _____P_______^..-f5Pv3«__l __________ ,^B ______Bto&amp;^ v / ' "• s~^—.' KjQy ____b&amp;!m . '.'&gt;vt__a Bf ■ il _____ ______ _______ Fig 18.— Photomicrographs of a typical alfalfa stem. Above, cross - section, and below, longi-section. (x30). </seg>
            <seg id="p108">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Fig. 19.— Photomicrographs of the epidermis of alfalfa leaf and stem showing the distribution of stomata. Above, upper epidermis, and center, lower epidermis of leaf. Below, stem epidermis. (xl20). </seg>
            <seg id="p109">Alfalfa Investigations A cross section of the leaf is shown in higher magnification in Fig. 17 (below). The upper and lower epidermises with their distribution of stomata which have often been erron - eously said to "pump water" from the stems under proper curing conditions, are shown in Fig. 19 (above and center). The alfalfa examined averaged 220 stomata per square millimeter for the upper leaf epidermis and 215 for the lower. The stomatal apertures averaged 11 millimeters in length and when open comprised 0.4 per cent of the area of the leaf epidermis. LABORATORY TESTS A number of simple tests extending from 1921 to 1925 were conducted in the laboratory wherein the loss of moisture from the normal hay with leaves intact was compared with that from the bare stems. The samples were scattered thinly on sheets of paper and placed in a well exposed posi - tion for curing (but not in direct sunlight). The results of a typical test are shown graphically in Chart 8. These tests indicated that the normal hay dried somewhat faster than the Per ff/rf Nnnture ; ; »|^ ; : Hff °° vV\ : owes* \\\ AVERtGE St erm-Leattsi'- " \\ ■ \X N^ * : x —^_ : **=- : &gt; \ X — ___^ \ V VX * v^ -^ " — : ~ '-&gt;» "— """"-^ . ,_ _^_ ;--■- •• - 5 ■ *" - J I I I I Hours it .a is et Chart 8. — Comparative drying of alfalfa hay, leaves, and stems under laboratory conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 stems alone, but that when the curing rates of the stems alone and leaves alone were averaged, the rates were almost identical with that of the whole hay. RELATION OF THE RATE OF CURING TO THE WEATHER A very striking relation was observed between weather conditions and rate of curing. Frequently, correlated weather conditions such as high temperature, sunshine, low humid - ity, and high wind, are very conducive to rapid drvinir During such a period differences in the curing rate resulting trom the method of handling are ordinarily less marked In attempting to correlate the rate of curing with weather con - ditions (Table 26) it should be borne in mind that the cur - ing rate ordinarily becomes slower as the hay dries even tho weather conditions may become more conducive to hiirh evaporation. K . V? dryi 5? 0f ex J t . ei : nal moisture bears the same relation to the weather conditions and method of curing as that of interna moisture but usually, especially in swath curing it takes place more rapidly. Hay in the swath is more subject to increase in moisture content from humid weather, dews or light rains than is hay in the windrow or cock. Heavier rains, however, can be expected to effect hay curing under all methods to practically the same extent. In the case of wind - row and cock curing, danger of heating and molding from ex - terna moisture is as great, or greater, than that from in - ternal moisture. CURING PRACTICES IN RELATION TO QUALITY OF HAY PRODUCED Curing practices should also be considered in relation tn he quality of the resultant forage. Color and retention of leaves in alfalfa hay are of prime consideration. The drv matter yield of hay was determined in 1924 at the beginning and end of the curing period. The differences obtained were assumed to be due primarily to the curing method Snph data for 1924 indicating the" per cent of d^mSter recovered are shown in Table 28. In view of the fact that the dry matter contained in the stems would be largely recovered regardless of the curing method, such losses as were found must have consisted largely of shattered leaves. Prolonged curing of hay beyond the field cured condition resulted in an increased loss of dry matter. As was to be expected \-hl greatest loss was in the case of swath curing This loss ___! came greater as the air-dry condition was approached The </seg>
            <seg id="p111">:'• Alfalfa Investigations . raking and proper handling of swath cured hay at the right time materially reduces such loss. The data in Table 28 in - dicate that hay should not remain in the swath after it has become about two-thirds cured. If properly handled at this time the loss should not exceed 5 per cent as measured by these tests. Table 28. — The amount of hay (per cent dry matter) recovered from the various curing methods as an average of the curing tests beginning July 30 and August 18, 1924. Hay (dry matter) 30 per cent recovered when moisture 1 , Method ot curing content Field Test All plats reached in' cured ended' averaged Hours Per cent Per cent Per cent Swath 1 27 90.7 81.6 86.1 Windrow, thruout ...' 66 99.9 95.3 97.6 Windrow, preceded by 3 hours swath curing 29 97.8 98.3 9S.1 Windrow, preceded by 6 hours swath curing 27 99.1 94.4 96.8 Windrow, preceded by 24-27 hours swath curing. 27 . 94.5 91.4 93.0 Average 36 97.8 94.9 96.4 Cock, thruout 104 96.3 96.3 96.3 Cock, preceded by 3 hours swath curing 32 98.4 98.0 98.2 Cock, preceded by 6 hours swath curing SO 96.3 96.5 96.4 Cock, preceded by 24-27 hours swath curing 29 95.0 91.5 93.3 Average 49 96.5 95.6 96.1 'Number of hours required for hay to Teach 30 per cent moisture content. From Table 27. : When the hay became air dry or at the end of the six-day curing period. An exact measurement, of color retention in relation to curing method was not undertaken. Close observations, how - ever, indicated that it bore practically the same relation to curing method as retention of leaves. Exposure to external moisture followed by bright sunlight was found very destruc - tive of good color. Hay that was curing in the windrow or cock was more or less protected from moisture in the form of dew. Repeated rains, however, which necessitated the turning and opening of the windrows and cocks resulted in serious color damage, as well as loss in dry matter. APPLICATION OF CURING PRINCIPLES These tests have indicated that under favorable weather conditions the best quality of hay and the largest per cent recovery of dry matter is obtained where most of the curing is done in the windrow or cock. By such practice, however, </seg>
            <seg id="p112">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 tne curing period is materially prolonged and thus the like - lihood of serious deterioration due to unfavorable weather conditions arising is increased. In regions of frequent rains the best practice would seem to be to reduce the moisture content of the hay to a field-cured condition as rapidly as possible without undue loss of quality and dry matter. In no case, however, should swath curing continue so long that material bleaching and shattering of leaves may result. Curing practice must also be considered from an economic standpoint and from that of the individual producer. The more extensive type of hay making as is practiced on most Nebraska farms involves partial curing in the swath followed by windrowing and stacking or mowing as soon as the hay reaches a field-cured condition. Tho this method often results in a little lower quality of hay, it has a lower labor require - ment, permits of the handling of a larger acreage, and is less subject to unfavorable weather conditions, due to its more rapid curing. A definite period for swath curing cannot be assigned, due to many variable factors. Under favorable cur - ing conditions, hay cut in the morning should prohably be raked in the afternoon or early the following morning, where - as under unfavorable conditions it may be advisable to extend the swath curing over a two-day period or even longer. In case swath curing has proceeded too far, undue loss of leaves may be partially overcome by delaying raking until late evening or early morning, in expectation of more humid conditions. Where a rather large acreage has been cut, raking should be started somewhat earlier. This will slow up the curing of the hay first raked, with the result that the period during which the hay reaches a field-cured condition will be extended. Where the acreage is small and maximum quality of hay is essential, the more intensive curing practices may be followed Such practices would involve the careful cocking of the hay soon after it is well wilted and possibly one or more recock - ings if the curing is very slow. Canvas shock covers may be used for covering the shocks during unfavorable weather. Such practice, tho usually resulting in hay of a very good quality, is slow and involves a high labor requirement. HISTORICAL REVIEW — CURING PRACTICES VARIATION OF MOISTURE IN GROWING ALFALFA The Colorado Experiment Station (1889) reports moisture contents varying from 77.7 to 49.3 per cent for hay cut at 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">Alfalfa Investigations stages of maturity ranging from "beginning to bud" to " seed fully ripened." McKee (1914) found in California that the moisture con - tent of alfalfa just preceding the pre-bloom stage was 85.8 per cent. Hansen (1916) reported from the Huntley (Montana) Re - clamation Project that the shrinkage of all cuttings in 1915, 1914, and 1913, was 76.2, 76.3, and 76.7 per cent, respectively. The shrinkage in the first, second, and third cuttings in 1915 was found to be 75.4, 75.4, and 77.4 per cent. Vinall and McKee (1916) found that alfalfa growing at Chico, California, contained 1 per cent more moisture at 8 A. M. than at 3 P. M., and further reported a variation in moisture content of 78.9 to 73.4 per cent for alfalfa varying in maturity from very young (12 inches high) to past full bloom. They conclude that " The moisture content of any crop at a given stage of maturity is not constant, but may vary with the conditions under which the crop is grown." Salmon, Swanson, and McCampbell (1925) report mois - ture contents ranging from 71.7 to 63.8 per cent from bud to seed stages at the Kansas Experiment Station. MOISTURE CONTENT OF FIELD-CURED AND AIR-DRY ALFALFA Cooke (1900) found in Colorado that the moisture content in 35 samples of field-cured alfalfa ranged from 9.3 to 30.0 per cent. Hay containing from 22.0 to 24.0 per cent mois - ture heated somewhat when stored in bulk whereas that aver - aging 26.5 per cent moisture heated quite badly. Arny (1916) found in Minnesota that the dry matter con - tent of field-cured alfalfa in 1914 ranged from 55.0 to 96.0 per cent. . Vinall and McKee (1916) found that field-cured alfalfa at Chico, California, contained 22.3 per cent moisture, and 9.7 per cent when air-dry. They conclude " That the amount of moisture in air-dry material depends not only upon the humidity of the atmosphere but also upon the nature of the material in the sample." Salmon, Swanson, and McCampbell (1925) (Kansas) re - port that the moisture content of field-cured hay varied from 20.8 per cent when cut in the bud stage to 14.0 per cent for hay harvested, in the seed stage. Corresponding air-dry mois - ture contents ranged from 7.5 to 7.6 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p114">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 RELATION OF CURING PRACTICE TO CURING RATE Data bearing on various curing practices are very meagre. Statements and recommendations as reviewed were found somewhat conflicting and have been grouped in Table 29 under several rather general headings. Vinall and McKee (1916) working with sorghum at Hays, Kansas, found that it lost 11.1 per cent of its weight during the first 4 hours after cutting when curing in the swath where - as in the windrow, it lost 6.6 per cent. Piper et al (1924) state that "there is serious doubt as to the accuracy of the theory that the leaves of the cut plants act as pumps. Nevertheless the secret of making good, bright green hay is to reduce the water content in the plants from an average of about 70 per cent to about 15 per cent and do this fairly rapidly and without allowing any of the leaves to be - come brittle dry." Willard (1926) concludes from a series of laboratory tests: " Experiments to determine whether the leaves of plants drew water from the stems in the process of curing into hay indicate that this occurs with some plants and not with others. Alfalfa stems dried at the same rate whether the leaves were attached or not." In a paper appearing since the acceptance of this manu - script for publication, Westover (1926) concludes from a series of laboratory tests " that alfalfa in the quantities here used cures at least as rapidly with the leaves removed as with them attached." CURING PRACTICE IN RELATION TO QUALITY OF HAY Headden (1896) found in Colorado that hay exposed in the field to 1.76 inches of rain during a 14-day period, increased 12.37 per cent in relative amount of crude fiber, whereas the protein and nitrogen-free extract content decreased 7.70 and 5.07 per cent respectively. Cooke (1900) found as an average of 8 tests in Colorado that the loss in dry matter under ordinary methods of field handling varied from 5.1 per cent to 26.1. The extreme repre - sented differences in weather conditions. Kenney (1916) states that the average loss in harvesting 41 lots of alfalfa in Kansas in 1914 was 12.43 per cent of the entire crop. The loss in leaves varied from 6 to 48 per cent. Swanson and Latshaw (1916) found in Kansas that alfalfa </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 Table 29.— Historical summary of statements reviewed bearing on curing practices Mechanical loss re- _., , ,_ „i,i„„ „j„;„„d When properly handled Windrowing and dueed and quality • Windrowing or cocking advised cocking before improved by wind- — -_, «,„„ i. =r.u »_. when falrlv well cured ation and aid materially hay is dry will s&gt; Cooke (1900) FairfleW j* Button Holden(1902) ggj* «J» ■ . Jta^ONQ g £» 4 &lt;fen AtlgaWHson |SS W^W H-V^W) S^fever j-, Moo£*_n_ber Cox (1926) Moore AGraber SSU^flMfi) 2 Stewart (1926) Bee_on. iauie 4 £*%_$_?*&gt;. S bSSr&amp;fiR S C £»26? McCIura (1921) Oakley &amp; Westover (1921) Rather (1924) </seg>
            <seg id="p116">, Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 cured in the sun had a higher pure protein content as deter - mined by Stutzer's method than that cured in the shade. This difference is so great as to more than offset the influence of the loss of leaves. Salmon, Swanson, and McCampbell (1925) found in Kan - sas that as an average of 4 maturity stages, 1914-1920, 19.0 per cent of the leaves or 9.2 per cent of the dry matter was lost in harvesting. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">Alfalfa Investigations j literature cited Cited in this . bulletin on page Adams, J. L. 1 1925. Hay curing methods. Wallaces' Farmer, June 19, p. 853 115 Ahart, J. Lee 1925. Modern methods of hay making. The Field, June, p. 22 115 Ames, J. W., and Boltz, G. E. 1917. Handling alfalfa hay. Ohio Agr. Exp. Sta., Monthly Bui. Vol. 2, No. 6, pp. 178-180 .'. 115 Anderson, B. G. 1923. Experiments with dark tobacco and other crops. Va. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 231, pp. 1-19 44 Amy, A. C. 1916. The dry-matter content of field-cured and green forage. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 8, No. 6, pp. 358-364 113 1926. Alfalfa aids progress in .Minnesota. Minn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Spec. Bui. 104, pp. 1-31..... 48 Atkinson, Alfred, and Wilson, M. L. 1915. Suggestions to alfalfa growers. Mont. Agr. Exp. Sta. Cir. 149, pp. 1-42 i . 115 Aune, Beyer 1925. Work of the Belle Fourche Reclamation Project Experi - ment Farm from 1919 to 1922, inclusive. U. S. Dept.Agr. Cir. 339, pp. 1-48..:. 47 Bassett, S. C. 1916. History of Buffalo County, Nebraska, Vol. 1, S. J. Clarke Publishing Co., p. 392 12 Bean, R. P. 1922. Thirty-second Ann. Rpt., Wash. Agr. Exp. Sta. (Wash. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 175) pp. 50-59 43, 66 &lt;* . Beeson, M. A., Daane, Adrian, and Johnson, D. R. 1921. Alfalfa experiment. Okla. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 138, pp. 1-18 115 '•'■- Bessey, C. E. f, 1886. Nebr. State Bd. Agr., Ann. Rpt., p. 127 and p. 222 12 &lt;- \ 1890. Nebr. State Bd. Agr., Ann. Rpt., pp. 100-108 12 &gt;i 1896. Nebr. State Bd. Agr., Ann. Rpt, p. 91 12 Blair, R. E. iv£ 1918. The work of the Yuma Reclamation Project Experiment v • Farm in 1917. U. S. Dept. Agr., Bur. Plant Indus., West. &gt;V ; Agr. Cir; 25, pp. 1-45 ,... 41 CBlinn, Philo K. 1911. Alfalfa: The relation of type to hardiness. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 181, pp. 1-16 49 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Cited in this bulletin on page Boss, Andrew 1919. Minn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Twenty-seventh Ann. Rpt., pp. 38-43.. 41 Brand, C. J. 1911. Grimm alfalfa and its utilization in the northwest. U. S. Dept. Agr., Bur. Plant Indus. Bui. 209, pp. 1-66 38 Brand, C. J., and Waldron, L. R. 1910. Cold resistance of alfalfa and some factors influencing it. U. S. Dept. Agr., Bur. Plant Indus. Bui. 185, pp. 1-80..... 37 Brooks, William P. 1914. Alfalfa. Mass. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bul.154, pp. 148-171 115 Brooks, William P., and Gaskill, E. F. 1917. Mass. Agr. Exp. Sta. Twenty-ninth Ann. Rpt., pp. 57a-58a 40 Burger, A. A. 1925. Handling clover and alfalfa hay. Wallaces' Farmer, May 22, p. 732 115 Carlson, F. A. 1925. The effect of soil structure on the character of alfalfa root systems. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 17, No. 6, pp. 336-345 51 Colorado Agr. Exp. Sta. 1889. Alfalfa: Its growth, composition and digestibility, etc. Bui. 8, pp. 1-24 67,112 Connor, A. B. 1911. Alfalfa in northwest Texas. Tex. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 137, pp. 1-16 115 Cook, I. S. 1916. W. Va. Agr. Exp. Sta. Rpts. 1914-1916, pp. 13-17 .'. 39 Cook, W. M. 1911. Alfalfa in Ohio— A field study. Ohio Agr. Exp. Sta. Cir. 113, pp. 1-55 115 Cooke, W. W. 1900. Farm Notes. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 57, pp. 1-39..113, 114, 115 Cottrell, H. M. 1902. Growing alfalfa in Kansas. Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 114, pp. 51-95 '.. 68 Cox, J. F. 1919. Alfalfa in Michigan. Mich. Agr. Exp. Sta. Spec. Bui. 97, pp. 1-14 49,115 1925. Crop production and soil management. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., pp. 1-516 115 Cox, J. F., and Megee, C. R. 1926. Hardy alfalfa varieties best for Michigan. Mich. Agr. Exp. Sta. Quart. Bui., Vol. 8, No. 3, pp. 107-110 48 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">Alfalfa Investigations Cited in this bulletin on page Dalton, L. A. 1924. Alfalfa production in New York. N. Y. Agr. Col. (Cornell) Ext. Bui. 84, pp. 1-21 46, 51 Damon, S. C. 1921. Experiences with alfalfa. R. I. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 184, pp. 1-26 42, 115 Doyle, H. W. . 1916. Alfalfa in Kansas. Kans. State Bd. Agr. (Quart.) Rpt., June, pp. 11-171 115 Fairfield, W. H., and Hutton, G. H. 1912. Alfalfa growing in Alberta. Canada Dept. Agr. Exp. Farms Bui. No. 8, 2 ser., pp. 1-14... 115 Forbell, B. " 1922. Starting a field of alfalfa in Minnesota. Minn. Farmers' Inst. Ann. No. 35, pp. 37-52 44 Foster, Luther, and Merrill, Lewis A. 1899. Alfalfa or Lucern: The cutting time, its feeding value. Utah Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 61, pp. 153-214 65, 66, 67 Gardner, F. D. 1916. Alfalfa. Penn. Agr. Ext. Cir. 46, pp. 1-8 115 Garver, Samuel 1922. Alf alf a root studies. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 1087, pp. 1-28....50, 69 Georgeson, C. C. 1925. Alaska Agr. Exp. Sta. Rpt., 1923, pp. 10-13 47 Getty, R. E. 1921. Forage crops in western Kansas. Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 225, pp. 1-54 43 Hansen, Dan 1914. The work of the Huntley Reclamation Project Farm in 1913. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bur. Plant Indus. West. Irrig. Agr., pp. 8-10 66 1915. The work of the Huntley Reclamation Project Farm in 1914. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bur. Plant. Indus. West. Irrig. Agr. Cir. 2, pp. 9-15 66 1916. The work of the Huntley Reclamation Project Farm in 1915. . U. S. Dept. Agr. Bur. Plant Indus. West. Irrig. Agr. Cir. 8, pp. 11-12..., 66,113 Hansen, P. . 1909. On the yields of alfalfa with varying number of cuttings during the season. Tidsskr. Landbr. Planteavl, Vol. 16, pp. 413-429 (E. S. R. Vol. 22, No. 5, p. 443) 66,68 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Cited in this bulletin on page Harcourt, R. 1900. Lucerne or alfalfa; composition and ' digestibility. Ontario Dept. Agr. Bui. Ill, pp. 1-16 66,68 Headden, William P. 1896. Alfalfa. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 35, pp. 1-92 67, 114 1897. A study of alfalfa and some other hays. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 39, pp. 1-34 67 Hendry, Geo. W. 1923. Alfalfa in history. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. Vol. 15, No. 5, pp. 171-176 12 Hitchcock, A. S. 1905. Alfalfa growing. U. S. Dept. Agr. Farmers' Bui. 215, pp. 1-39 115 Holden, James A. 1918. The work of the Scottsbluff Reclamation Project Experi - ment Farm in 1917. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bur. Plant Indus. West. Irrig. Agr. Cir. 27, pp. 1-28 41 Holden, P. C. 1902. Alfalfa. Iowa Agr. Exp. Sta. Cir. I, pp. 1-4 115 Hughes, H. D. 1917. Varieties of alfalfa seed. la. Agr. Vol. 18, No. 4, pp. 163-165 40 Hume, A. N., and Champlin, Manley 1916. Comparative yields of hay from several varieties and strains of alfalfa, at Brookings, Highmore, Cottonwood, and Eureka. S. Dak. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 163, pp. 280-343 39 Hume, A. N., and Garver, Samuel 1912. Alfalfa as a field crop in South Dakota. S. Dak. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 133, pp. 253-281 39 Iowa Agr. Exp. Sta. 1921. Ann. Rpt., pp. 11-12 43 1924. Ann. Rpt., p. 10 51 Jardine, W. M., and Call, L. E. 1914. Alfalfa in Kansas. Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 197, pp. 575-610 115 Jenkins, E. H. 1917. Observations on alfalfa. Conn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 192, pp. 1-12 40 Kansas Agr. Exp. Sta. 1924. Bien. Rpt., pp. 50-51 46 Kenney, R. 1916. Scientific hay making and storage. Kans. State Bd. Agr. (Quart.) Rpt., June, pp. 241-247 114,115 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">__ Alfalfa Investigations Cited in this bulletin on page Kentucky Agr. Exp. Sta. 1921. Thirty-fourth Ann. Rpt., p. 42 43 Kezer, Alyin 1915. Forage crops for the Colorado plains. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 214, pp. 1-25 11.5 Kiesselbach, T. A. 1918. Forage crops. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 169, pp. 1-36 41 Kiesselbach, T. A., and Anderson, A. 1925. Hardy alfalfa for Nebraska. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Cir. 32, pp. 1-8... 47 King, C. J. 1923. Crop tests at the co-operative testing station, Sacaton, Ariz. U. S. Dept. Agr. Cir.- 277, pp. 1-40 46 Kirk, L. E. 1924. Alfalfa production in Saskatchewan. Saskatchewan Univ. Col. Agr. Ext. Bui. 26, pp. 1-30 46 Knight, C. S. 1919. Nev. Agr. Exp. Sta. Ann. Rpt., pp. 17-26 41, 50 Lyon, T. L., and Hitchcock, A. S. 1904. Pasture, meadow, and forage crops. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 84, pp. 1-66 36 McClure, H. B. 1918. Hay making. U. S. Dept. Agr. Farmers' Bui. 943, pp. 1-30 115 1921. Marketing hay at country points". U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 977, pp. 1-27 115 McCool, M. M. 1926. The nitrogen content of alfalfa. Mich. Agr. Exp. Sta. Quart. Bui., Vol. 8, No. 3, pp. 133-224 51 McKee, Roland 1914. Moisture as a factor in determining forage yields. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 6, No. 3, pp. 113-117 113 1916. The effect of clipping upon the root development of alfalfa. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 8, No. 5, pp. 329-332 68 Mackay, Angus 1909. Experiments in growing alfalfa from seed secured from different sources. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 1, pp. 149-150 37 Megee, G. R. 1922. Hardy alfalfa and clover seed. Mich. Agr. Exp. Sta. Quart. Bui., Vol. 5, No. 1, p. 16 : 44 Miller, P. E. 1917. West Cent. Exp. Sta., Morris, Minn., Rpt., pp. 28-29 40 1920. West Cent. Exp. Sta., Morris, Minn., Rpt., pp. 29-30 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Cited in this bulletin on page 1921. West Cent. Exp. Sta., Morris, Minn., Rpt., pp. 30-31 43 1925. West Cent. Exp. Sta., Morris, Minn., Rpt., p. 37 47 Mills, A. A. 1896. Alfalfa or lucern. Utah Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 44, pp. 1-33....65, 67 Moore, R. A., and Graber, L. F. 1915. Alfalfa growing in Wisconsin. Wis. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 259, pp. 1-32 115 1919. Alfalfa in Wisconsin. Wis. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 308, pp. 1-34 41,115 1925. Wisconsin's opportunity with alfalfa. Wis. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 374, pp. 1-31 66 Nebraska State Bd. Agr. 1902. Ann. Rpt, p. 113 11 1905. Ann. Rpt., p. 256 11 1908. Ann. Rpt., p. 382 11 Nebraska Dept. Agr. 1922. Agricultural Statistics. Bui. 123, p. 115 11 Nelson, N. T. 1925. The effects of frequent cutting on the production, root re - serves, and behavior of alfalfa. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 17, No. 2, pp. 100-113 69 Noble, E. G. 1922. The work of the Yuma Reclamation Project Experiment Farm in 1919 and 1920. U. S. Dept. Agr. Cir. 221, pp. 1-37 44 Oakley, R. A., and Westover, H. L. 1916. Commercial varieties of alfalfa. U. S. Dept. Agr. Farmers' Bui. 757, pp. 1-24 13 1921. Utilization of alfalfa. U. S. Dept. Agr. Farmers' Bui. 1229, pp. 1-44 115 1924. Forage crops in relation to the agriculture of the semi-arid portion of the Northern Great Plains. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 1244, pp. 1-53 46 Oregon Agr. Exp. Sta. 1922. Bien. Rpt. (Umatilla Branch Sta.), pp. 83-87 44 Overpeck, J. C, and Conway, W. T. 1926. Alfalfa variety tests. New Mexico Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 152, PP. 1-11 49 Parsons, T. S. 1916. Alfalfa in Wyoming. Wyo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. Ill, pp. 17-55 39' Pennsylvania Agr. Exp. Sta. 1922. Ann. Rpt. (Penn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 176), pp. 8-9 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">Alfalfa Investigations Citedinthis bulletin on page Piper, Charles V. 1924. Forage plants and their culture. The MacMillan Co., pp. 1-671 46 Piper, Charles V., et al. 1924. Hay. U. S. Dept. Agr. Yearbook, pp. 285-376 114 Quesenberry, George R. 1923. Alfalfa. N. Mex. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 139, pp. 1-19 45 Rather, H. C. ' 1924. Curing alfalfa. Mich. Agr. Col. Ext. Bui. 35, pp. 1-3 115 Salmon, S. C, Swanson, C. 0., and McCampbell, C. W. 1925. Experiments relating to the time of cutting alfalfa. Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. Tech. Bui. 15, pp. 1-50 66,67,68,69,113,116 Sanborn, J. W. j.;- 1 1893. Time of harvesting lucern. Utah Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 31, pp. 1-7 , .. 65 Schmitz, Nicholas 1919. Growing alfalfa in Maryland. Md. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 228, pp. 1-24 115 Shutt, Frank T. 1904. Alfalfa or lucern: Its culture, use, and value. Canada Cent. Expl Farm Bui. 46, Part 2, pp. 8-12 66 Smith, Jared G. 1888. Field experiments and observations. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 6, pp. 31-84 12 Snyder, Harry, and Hummel, J. A. 1903. Alfalfa: Its chemical development, feeding value, and di - gestibility. Minn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 80, pp. 149-180 68 Snyder, W. P., and Burr, W. W. 1911. Growing crops in western Nebraska. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 118, pp. 1-69 38 Southworth, W. 1921. A study of the influence of the root system in promoting - hardiness in alfalfa. Sci. Agr., Vol. 1, No. 1, pp. 5-9 50 Stewart, George 1921. Alfalfa production, under irrigation. Utah Agr. Exp. Sta. Cir. 45, pp. 1-48 115 1926. Alfalfa growing in the United States and Canada. The Mac- I Millan Co., pp. 1-517 115 Swanson, CO.. I 1917. The effect of prolonged growing of alfalfa on the nitrogen | content of the soil. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 9, No. 7, .','. pp. 305-314 .80 1 '..'" 1 '■.'.'' </seg>
            <seg id="p124">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 36 Cited in this bulletin on page Swanson, C 0., and Latshaw, W. L. 1916. Chemical composition of alfalfa as affected by stage of ma - turity, mechanical losses, and conditions of drying. Jour. Indus, and Engin. Chem., Vol. 3, No. 8, pp. 726-729 114 Sylven, N. 1925. Comparative tests of alfalfa varieties. K. Landtb. Akad. Handl. och Tidskr. 64, No. 2, pp. 133-135 48 Taylor, W. E. 1924. Soil culture and modern farm methods. Deere &amp; Company, pp. 1-651 115 ! Ten Eyck, A. M. 1908. Alfalfa hay: Its making, handling, and marketing. Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 155, pp. 238-260 66, 115 Tinline, M. J. 1925. Canada Dept. Agr., Rpt. of Supt., Brandon, Man., Exp. Farm, pp. 59-70 47 Towle, R. S. 1925. Work of the Sheridan Field Station for the seven years from 1917 to 1923, inclusive. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 1306, pp. 22-24 48 United States Dept. Agr. 1924. Agricultural Yearbook, p. 773 11 Vinall, H. M., and McKee, Roland 1916. Moisture content and shrinkage of forage. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 353, pp. 1-37 113, 114 Voelcker, J. Augustus 1916. Field experiments. Jour. Roy. Agr. Soc. England, Vol. 77, pp. 235-251 40 Waldron, L. R. 1911. Alfalfa. N. Dak. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 95, pp. 357-424 115 1919. Cross- fertilization in alfalfa. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 11, No. 6, pp. 259-266 33 Weaver, John E. 1926. Root development of field crops. McGraw-Hill Book Co., pp. 1-291 77 Westgate, J. M. 1908. Alfalfa. U. S. Dept. Agr. Farmers' Bui. 339, pp. 1-48 115 1909. Experiments in growing alfalfa from seed secured from different sources. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 1, pp. 145 - 148 37 1910. Variegated alfalfa. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bur. Plant Indus. Bui. 169, pp. 1-63 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">Alfalfa Investigations Cited in this bulletin on page Westover, H. L. 1926. Comparative shrinkage in weight of alfalfa cured with leaves attached and removed. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 1424, pp. 1-10 114 Wheeler, W. A., and Balz, Sylvester 1907. Forage plants at the Highmore Substation. S. Dak. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 101, pp. 130-153 37 Widtsoe, John A., and Stewart, John 1898. The chemical life history of lucern. Utah Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 58, pp. 1-90 67 Willard, G. J. 1926. Do legumes hasten the curing process by pumping moisture from the stems? Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol, 18, No, 5, pp. 369-375 114 Wisconsin Agr. Exp. Sta. 1917. Ann. Rpt. (Wis. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 275), pp. 25-28 40,49 1920. Ann. Rpt. (Wis. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 323), pp. 77-80 42 1923. Ann. Rpt. (Wis. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 352), pp. 29-40 45,69 Woodward, N. F. 1923. Experiments with alfalfa and grasses at the Judith Basin Substation. Mont. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 152, pp. 1-24 45 Zavitz, C. A. • 1920. Alfalfa. Ontario Dept. Agr. Bui. 280, pp. 1-32 42, 50 [4M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>