<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>An Inquiry into the Influence of Environment on the Incidence of Poultry Diseases</title>
               <date value="18??">March 1940</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 118 An Inquiry into the Influence of Environment on the Incidence of Poultry Diseases L. Van Es and J. F. Olney Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MARCH 1940 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Pace Bacillary White Diarrhea 4 Fowl Typhus 13 Fowl Cholera 17 Tuberculosis Coccidiosis 26 Blackhead 41 Miscellaneous Observations 55 General Conclusions 56 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">An Inquiry into the influence of Environment on the Incidence of Poultry Diseases ¦:. ¦.',' .; L. VAN ES and J. F. OLNEY* The principal.purpose of the investigation reported here was to evaluate, if possible, hygienic measures, and in addition to gather whatever informa - tion might become available pertaining to the relation of certain disorders to a given population after its exposure to their specific etiologic factors. The experiments were conducted on a piece of ground upon which poultry had not been maintained for many years, if ever. The area was enclosed by a high fence and the whole subdivided into twelve separate lots. Each lot constituted a unit to itself, separated from, the outside fence by a,space eight feet in width. An aisle, ten feet wide, was established between the two rows of six lots each. Each lot was enclosed by means of one-inch - mesh wire netting, above as well as on the sides. AH were of identical size, .30 by 60 feet, including a housing space 18. by 20 feet. : As illustrated by Figure 1, the arrangement provided two lots, both of which were populated by fowls exposed to one and the same disease. The two lots faced one another across the center aisle. Although identical in character and number, the lots differed in their appointments. In the ones designated by even numbers, general conditions such as commonly prevail in farm, poultry yards were maintained. In these the inhabitants . were in immediate contact with the soil, and food and water were supplied in open troughs. A shallow, open drain ran diagonally through each lot and the birds: had access to it at all times. In the corresponding lots, designated by odd numbers, sanitary measures, reasonable and not be - yond economic possibility, were taken. They were covered by a twelve-inch layer of coarse gravel in order to exclude the possibility of surface-water accumulation. The floors of the shelter houses were covered by heavy, one-inch-mesh wire netting stretched on wooden frames. Later these were replaced by the more substantial and effective hardware-cloth panels. The food was provided in self-feeders so constructed that the possibility of fecal contamination was practically eliminated. Drinking water was made available in self-cleaning fountains, devised by the Nebraska Station some years before. As the investigation progressed and results became available, certain changes in the sanitary equipment in the odd-numbered lots were.made. These will be described at their proper places. In this type of environment all contact with the soil was avoided and fecal con - tamination reduced to a minimum. . All other details of .management etc. were the same for both- types of environment. The fowls received identical rations, were housed in the ¦Dr. H. M. Martin, now with the University of Pennsylvania, participated in the earlier phatei of this investigation. . ¦ ¦ ... -,' . - </seg>
         <seg id="p004">AORICI LTLRAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 118 same manner, and had about the same area per bird at their disposal. Whatever cleaning was done was always identical for both corresponding shelter houses and the open lots were not cleaned at all. On the whole, cleaning was never overdone so that the tests applied to the sanitary meas - ures taken could be reasonably severe. 12 1 I II 10 I I » 8 v~ —I 7 6 5 4I 1 3 2I J I HB'N ;— Fig. J.—Arrangement and designation of experimental lots. BACILLARY WHITE DIARRHEA (Lots I and 2) This disease was included in the experimental scries in order to determine: (1) the possibility that fowls, either carrying the infection or merely sensitized as revealed by positive agglutination tests, might trans - mit the disease to normal hens occupying the same poultry yards, and (I) the influence of environment on the incidence of such transmissions m the two populations in the event that such transmissions took place. Apparently the spread of bacillary white diarrhea from the infected to noninfected adult fowls does not take place with any degree of regular- </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases —itf^HS^^K-— ~si~" y-sS Fig. 2.—View of sanitary lots. Fig. 3.—View of insalubrious lots. ity. Rettger and associates (1-2) - were the first to call attention to such a possilibity. Edwards and Hull (3), Kernkamp (4) and Dearstyne et al. (5) submitted evidence that adult, healthy fowls in contact with positively reacting ones may become infected. On the other hand, Dalling et al. (6) and Brunet (7) obtained negative results in their experiments. 8 See pace 9. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">AciRII'A LTVRAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 118 Although the contradictory results obtained by other workers were given consideration, the experiment was undertaken because in the case of the transmission from infected to noninfected adult hens, profitable in - formation may be derived from a comparison of the developments under farmyard conditions with those in a flock maintained in a more sanitary environment. For the purpose of this inquiry, the two experimental lots were each populated with a number of chickens in which a negative blood titer had recently been demonstrated. It was intended to introduce among them a number ol positively reacting fowls after the former had shown freedom of bacillary white diarrhea infection by one or more subsequent agglutina - tion tests. WWW'' ¦ IB E#r7 U PI I l-'tc. I. —View of houses and center aisle of the experimental compound. In the course of the experiment each of the two lots was occupied by two distinct populations of hens. The first ones inhabited the lots from July 29, 1929, to April 4, 1932, and the second ones from May 7, 1932, to Januarv 11, 1934. FIRST POPULATIONS The selection of the fowls composing the first two populations did not prove to be a fortunate one. These birds, two or three years old, were pro - cured from a commercial flock of known freedom from transmissible diseases and under good sanitary control. Shortly before purchase the fowls had shown negative reactions to the agglutination test. It should be stated, however, that about three years before some cases of bacillary white diarrhea had come to light among young adult birds belonging to the flock con - cerned. Because of this finding the flock was tested prior to the 1927 hatch and severely culled although not many positive reactors were revealed. From then on no chick losses from the malady were sustained. For several years all deaths among brooder chicks were bacteriologically challenged without bacillary white diarrhea infection being brought to light. On the other hand, it should be noted in connection with further developments, </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases that in the subsequent agglutination tests of this flock a few positive re - actors were found and that these were always promptly eliminated. Between July 29 and September 21, 1929, 108 fowls, in four install - ments, were placed in each of the two lots. The monthly agglutination tests were commenced on October 10, 1929, and continued until the last fowls were disposed of in the spring of 1932. It was disappointing as well as perplexing that from the very first positive reactions to the tests were observed in each of the two populations in all but three of the 30 tests made in each of the two lots. As indicated by the graphs exhibited by Tables 1 and 2 the occurrence of the reactions was quite erratic and no hen reacted with any degree of constancy. Although from a statistical point of view the gradual decline of population density and the elimination of reacting units constitute a disturbing fac - tor, the data compiled in Table 3 may serve as an indication of the re - action behaviors among the inhabitants of the lots. The reactions shown by individual fowls were, on the whole, quite intermittent, the intervals between positive reactions tanging between one and 26 months. Consecutive reactions, however, were observed and their numbers varied in the two lots. Among the inhabitants of Lot 1, one hen reacted positively four times, 8 fowls three times, and 12 birds twice in succession. The flock in Lot 2 showed a smaller number of consecutive positive reactions. Three birds reacted positively three times in succession and 5 hens did so twice in the course of the monthly tests. Although it was quite apparent that from the very beginning the pri - mary objective of the experiment was already defeated by the presence of manifestly, infected fowls, it seemed expedient to adhere to the experi - mental program. Hence, on October 27,1930, a number of hens (Table 4) obtained from a badly infected flock were placed in each lot and kept there until all positively reacting birds were removed between April 14 and November 20, 1931. The elimination of the reacting fowls resulted in some decrease of the incidence of positive reactions although not a very conspicuous one. That the infection source was not removed was indicated by the fact that although no positive reactions were revealed by the test of December 15, 1931, the one applied one month later, when the flocks had dwindled to only 36 and 38 hens respectively, showed that the percentage of positively reacting fowls was the highest yet encountered. The testing of the original populations was discontinued after March 19, 1932, and on.April 4 following the lots were vacated and the fowls de - voted to other purposes. In the course of the experiment several deaths from various causes occurred in the lots. In only a part of those was it possible to examine the ovaries bacteriologically. Thirty-three of the birds examined originated in Lot 1 and 25 in Lot 2. From none of these birds could Salmonella pullorum be recovered. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 Of the positively reacting fowls killed from Lot 1, 20 were examined pathologically and bacteriologically. Of these II hens showed ovarian lesions but in only 3 of them could the bacillus of bacillary white diarrhea be demonstrated. Twenty-one of the killed, positively reacting fowls of Lot 2 were examined in a similar manner. Twelve of these had diseased ovaries and from 6 of the group Salmonella pullorum could be isolated. Although the experiment failed in its primary objective, the observations made during its progress tend to show that it was a tactical mistake to select mature fowls from a flock in which, a year or two before, positively reacting birds were demonstrated to be present. The fact that the birds at the time of purchase had revealed no positive blood titers and that for several years not a single chick hatched from eggs produced by the flock of origin had developed bacillary white diarrhea, proved to be no war - rant that the hens were suitable for experimental purposes. It further appeared that inasmuch as there was no conspicuous differ - ence between lots in the incidence of the positive reactions, a purely en - vironmental factor could be safely ruled out. On the other hand it is quite probable that the habit, early acquired, of devouring practically every egg laid in both lots may have been the factor responsible for the peculiar reaction behavior revealed in the course of the experiments. SECOND POPULATIONS In view of the defeat sustained in connection with the first populations, the birds selected lor the second attempt were chicks four weeks old. They had been brooded under strict sanitary control and no case of bacillary white diarrhea had developed among them. These birds were placed in the lots on May 7, 1932, 150 chicks in each lot. There they were left undisturbed until September 13, when the first agglutination tests were applied. These monthly tests were continued until December 21, 1933, when the experiment was concluded. On February 21, 1933, positively reacting fowls (Tables 5 and 6) were introduced into each of the two lots. In the course of the experiment, egg eating was prevented by the use of trap-nests. During the entire period, in the course of which 15 agglutination tests were made, only one positive reaction was obtained (May 19, 1933), the bird concerned being an occupant of Lot 1. After subsequent tests this pullet consistently showed a negative blood titer. None of the other fowls in either lot reacted positively for the duration of the experiment. Although the one positively reacting bird may have become infected by the two months' contact with the positively reacting fowls in the lot con - cerned, it does not appear that environmental infection played a part in the transmission of bacillary white diarrhea. This conclusion derives further support from the fact that there was only one month between the occupancies of the two lots previously occupied by many infected birds. The results of the consistent agglutination tests of the hens compos - ing the two first populations revealed a manifest inconstancy in the posi- </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases. tive reactions of the individual birds. The same phenomenon was also observed in the six tests applied to the infected fowls which were added to the lots (Table 4). Only two of the 23 birds showed consistently posi - tive blood titers. The reaction inconstancy was less manifest among the in - fected hens composing the second populations (Tables 5 and 6). Yet half of these birds consistently failed to react positively throughout the period when the tests were applied. .'"¦'.'•".. For some years the writers had been aware of the fact that the elimi - nation of bacillary white diarrhea on the basis of only one test does not regularly succeed. Hence, in 1934 (8) they recommended repetition of the tests. : ''. Failure of the primary purpose of the experiment recorded in connection with the first two populations, as well as the occasional occurrence of bacillary white diarrhea in chicks hatched from eggs produced in flocks culled on the basis of only one test can, without doubt, be attributed to the intermittency of positive reactions in infected chickens. .¦'. .•'. ¦'Z-s. .-•. -."..'.'¦ .'.'¦ REFERENCES 1. Rcttgcr, Kirkpatrick,,and Stoncburn: Storrs Agr. Exp. Sta. Bu). 74, 1912. 2. Rcttger, Kirkpatrick, and Card: Storrs Agr. Exp. Sta.'Bui. 101, 1919. 3. Edwards and Hull: J. A. V. M. A. 75: 333, 1929. ' 4. Kernkamp: J. A. V. M. A. 77: 280, 1930. 5. Dearstyne, Greaves, and Gaugcr: N. C. Agr. Exp. Sta. Tech. Bui. 40, 1931. 6. Dalling, Mason, and Gordon: Vet. J. 83: 555, 1927. '''•"¦: 7. Brunct: Cornell VeL 18: 135, 1928. 8. Van Es and Olney: Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 290, p. 51, 1934. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 TABLE I PERCENTAGE OF POSITIVE REACTORS TO B . W . D . ANTIGEN AMONG FOWLS MAINTAINED UNDER SANITARY RESTRICTIONS. MONTHLY TESTS.I929-32. ¦r»ro«ulicnlioo|t&gt;lt&gt;|ft| hlm I m/mlt fit .*i Utht |t« |ti|ti|t«|to;«i fit (m|m j»i j«o;n jit 111I II jit.it oiTii of ttt CmSsc iul. ru, kjul ummu iul aw* xt'.g. utiu riiVjjLUFmV-^-^uWjiiwlwfcitfcoc^ ww iifaerie ¦»»»»¦ ii H ii li » «Ti ¦ » 10 i i*T&gt;' » ' ; J* *I * l'*.»»r"|"&gt;»;'» Qet.it--»o- f Latvia (m) at4CT)M« ro«U&gt; puciliiUT. ttiviii in. it •&gt;¦• iei.ie-ii.tn ¦ !»«?,¦» ro*Lt *ui ¦taovio moh Lot TABLE 2 PERCENTAGE OF POSITIVE REACTORS TO B. W . D . ANTIGEN AMONG FOWLS MAINTAINED WITHOUT SANITARY RESTRICTIONS. MONTHLY TESTS. 1928-32. .^..n &#132;.,., ,»¦ .. &#132; .. ..'tt'it'ti ..... | 1,.1,.1,.;»|,i|»1»1»1 &gt;1 |.,|..|4,1»|i. 1i.1,. |..|W OCT. IT-*&gt;o-I*lt,*l |11l auCTia* ro»i« PLACI* !¦ kOT - •livili am.u lie Mf.te-*li.j.u iuctibii revit mi iimsvir ttom ut. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases TABLE 3 NUMtIROF MRIODtWHtrr*"! 'OSITIYE REACTIONS WIRE SHOWN I or powti m mcw lot. I HO.OP 1.0T1W.1. JOTWOJ. reaction M&lt;or „„ period*, rowie. foui. ¦ * " T~~ t ~ T 0 Q ¦ __• e » .': ¦'¦¦"'¦'¦ ' • ».-"" ;¦"¦ 4 e » ¦' •¦¦¦ ¦• •-«¦¦-. ¦-• o r~iT~~ " » !• IT » 1» II I 'o- I-.- »e j 4» .. TABLE 4 'Z^Z ,Z ¦&#132;¦-.¦"' ¦¦'. ' _ INFECTED FOWLS ADDEDTOLOTNO.t. INFECTED FOWLS ADDED TO LOT NO.E, YARD UNOER SANITARY RESTRICTIONS. YARD WITHOUT SANITARY RESTRICTIONS. 0CT.27.-JO. 0CT.27-'«0. W.OF PATES ANDRESULTSOFTESTS. &#132;o s or I DATESAND RESULTSOFTESTsT "&gt;»«, - JK i jM -JO.] Jl I'll| !•« FOW - IS# T|Ol'lO|;iO|'ll|.J||.j| —— s*±! !!=•_ ±m j-s_ a-7 *-i4 . ku4 u-r mi r^s a.7 Ij* —L— JL_°_JLJL JL J?_ __LL_±±_°lJL_?_±±_°_ _li__+__?__ JL_o_ 4+__o_ __jia__ ++ _o__o__o_ 0 ~0~ ___£_;_ JUL. ** JL.JL.JL. __!»_ *+ ++ +¦• + ++ ~ -1-5——-5-— ii —JL _ii_ JL ZZ jl IF JL ~°~ — ±— JL .?+ J±__?_+? ±+_ __L?_ Jl_± ±t±±++++ ' -°_-*--g,-°__g_ -e i&gt; + +"0 0 0 0 __i_*±±ij±_*_j±-«"»- .7 3HZEIF±*"°~* y __•__ JL _*__*_ JL _*_ _£_ 11 tt + o" + DEAD _ XJZL ±t'**+*.*+l*? * it 0 ++ 0 ~o"~» o~ 10 ++ JL ° ° .'+. JL. ao ++" o _+_ _+ _oJ ++^ — »i tt 0 0 +~+ +++ • . __ ___ a» ?? ++ _+_ ++^ +_+ +£ I I I I: I I a» * o 00 00 «++"«A«ttLUTINATION IN SERUM DILUTIONS UF TO AS HIBW AS l-SO. .+ ¦ACSLUTINATION IN SERUM DILUTIONS UF TO AS HIGH AS 1-1%. »0-»AOOLUTINATION - NISATIVf. j^mMRLUTINATION-DOURTTUL. </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Ac.'Rici'LTi'RAL Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 j I TABLE 5 _j INFECTED FOWLS ADDED TO LOT HO.I. YARD UNDER SANITARY RESTRICTIONS. FEB.ai-'SS. HOS . O F DATES AND RESULTS OF TESTS. _^ FOWLS. "32 I *32 I '32 1 '32 I •33T rJ3T TJjT~,jJTTjrr, JJ I '31 I '33 I 'S3 I 'S3 I 'IS 9.13 10.15 11.15|12.13 J.l* 3.21 J.IB S.IRi 4.27 ».4 J.23 10.14 11.1812.2 ZTI -|--|- *++ 0 +_"_+ + + +_ + + _+J_L Z '¦ - - - - ++ -M- ++++++++ ++ ++ " + ++ + + 3 - - - -++++++++ ++++++ ++ + + j ±± 4 1 _ —T— — + ++ + ++ q + __+ + +__+_j;+ 5 I—l—~~ — I — ++ ¦*¦"+ o ++ ,0 -M- + + + 0 0_ 6 |++ ++ ++ ++ ++ +li+±_+±++ ++ ++ ++ ++ beadl_ _ 1 I + ±__+ ¦*•"" t ±± ++ ¦»•+ PEAD _ _ _ _ _" Z 8 ++ ++ ++ ++ ++ + + + + ++DEAP ______ „++•"¦ AGGLUTINATION IH SERUM DILUTIONS UP TO AS HIGH AS 1-50. ..-(-"¦AGGLUTINATION IN SERUM DILUTIONS UP TO AS HIGH AS 1-25. 1 „0"« AGGLUTINATION- NEGATIVE. I ..+"¦ AGGLUTINATION- DOUBTFUL. TABLE 6 INFECTED FOWLS ADDED TO LOT N0.2. YARD WITHOUT SANITARY RESTRICTIONS. FE».2t-'33. __ NOS.OF DATES AND RESULTS OF TESTS. rnwLS '32 ] '32 1 '32 1 '32 I '33 I '13 1 'II I '31 I '31 I *ll 1 '111 "IS I '13 1 *J3 I '33 ' 9.13 10.15 11.15 12.13 1.14 2.17 3.21 4.U »¦!» 4—7 1.4 »_l 10.14 lI.U 12.21 9 |_ - - _++++++ O ++ + ++++++++ 0 10 j _ — _ — 0 + + ++ W + DEAD — — — _ 11 — — _ _ 4 ¦*•¦*• o o ++ o o o o o o ¦2____o + 0 0»0 + + 0 04' 13 - - _ _ ++ ++ ++ ++ ++ ++ ++ ++ ++ ++ + + 14 I++ -H- ++ ++ 4-+ +4- ++ ++ + ++ DEAD — — - __. , 15 ++ ++ +* ++ ++ ++ jft + +++++ + + + + ~±± it l++|++l-r +| + + |+-r 1+ +I+ + 1 0 |++I++ldead| —1 — 1 —~T— l! „-H?-AGGLUTINATION IN SERUM DILUTIONS UP TO AS HIGH AS l-SO. &#132;+"mAGGLUTINATION IN SERUM DILUTIONS UP TO AS HIGH AS 1-2S. .0"- AGGLUTINATION -NEGATIVE. I I i </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases FOWL TYPHUS (Lots 11 and 12) The inquiry pertaining to fowl typhus was conducted in accordance with the general plan followed in the project as a whole. The lots were populated with identical numbers of fowls of comparable age and quality. They were procured from sources known to be free from any communicable diseases. . Three distinct populations were maintained in the course of the experi - ment and the two environments were of a nature so as to correspond to the ones in which similar experiments. were being conducted. The periods of occupancy of the two lots were the following: October 15, 1929—February 17, 1931 June B,l93l—April 4,1932 May 20,1932—October 9, 1933 For the duration of that part .of the experiment for which they were originally designed, the first two populations were maintained without any changes caused by replacements or the removal of living fowls. In the case of the third populations some birds were added to replace fowls which had died or the young cockerels which had to be eliminated because of their disorderly behavior. When making these changes both populations were kept in numerical balance as much as possible; Fowl typhus infection was introduced into each lot in identical man - ner. In addition to the contamination of the lots by sprinkling their sur - faces with a 48-hour broth culture of the fowl typhus bacillus (June 8, 1931) the usual method of introducing the infection was by means of artificially infected fowls. For this purpose the latter were infected either by intravenous inoculations or by the ingestion^ or both, of organs or culture material containing the microbic cause of the malady. The introduction of the fowls infected by the means mentioned above did not regularly induce manifest outbreaks of the disease among the populations concerned or even cause a significant number of cases. These more or less negative results suggest that a substantial proportion of fowls may be quite resistant to direct or indirect contact infection, at least in so far as conclusions may be based on mortality alone. Evidence of such a resistance could be observed not only among the exposed birds in the two lots but also among the artificially infected ones. As revealed by the summarized data shown in Tables 7 and 8, 52 artificially infected fowls were introduced in each of the two lots, of which 19 birds in each lot (36.5 per cent) died of fowl typhus. The artificially infected fowls which contracted typhus showed a con - siderable degree of variation in the length of their,survival periods after the : initial introduction of the typhus bacilli. This phenomenon may pos - sibly also be attributed to individual variances in susceptibility, either of a transitory or a permanent nature. </seg>
         <seg id="p014">AcRICLLTCRAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 118 All fowls dying in the two lots were bacteriologically examined, unless the cause of death could be accurately determined from gross lesions or as a result of trauma. No cases were recorded as fowl typhus unless the microbic cause of the disease could be demonstrated in the organs. It is possible that a few cases may have been missed although adequate pre - cautions were always taken for the sake of accuracy. Tables 9 and 10 present the summaries pertaining to the mortality and the epizootologic behavior of the disease in the two different environments. From the data thus recorded it appears that in the more sanitary environ - ment nothing like a sustained outbreak of fowl typhus developed in any of three populations inhabiting the lot in which a total of 10 birds suc - cumbed to the disease. In the less salubrious environment the exposure to infection of the in - habiting fowls, constituting three distinct populations, brought about a death loss by typhus of 70 fowls. Of the first population only 6 birds died from the disease. On the other hand the second population sustained a regular outbreak extending over seven 30-day periods which resulted in the death of 42 fowls. A less severe outbreak was induced among the fowls constituting the third population. In this case the outbreak showed an intermission of three 30-day periods with a total typhus mortality of 22 fowls. Throughout the entire experiment a total of 80 exposed fowls succumbed to the disease under consideration. Of these deaths, 10 occurred in the more sanitary and 70 in the less salubrious environment. The conclusion is therefore warranted that the sanitary measures taken in one of the two lots had a very favorable influence on the prophylaxis of fowl typhus. On the other hand it cannot be denied that the more or less faulty environ - mental qualities of Lot 12 were responsible for the occurrence of outbreaks of the disease of a nature comparable to the ones observed on farms. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases TABLET rOWLS INTRODUCED INTO LOT NO.II, AFTER ARTIFICIAL INFECTION WITH FOWL TYPHUS. 8*5 INDUCTION OF INFECTION.! NO.OFI NO.DEAD I SURVIVAL PERIODS.DAYS. BATES. METHOD. FOWLS OF TYPHUS. MINIMUM. I MAX/MUM." IQ.lT^ai INTRA V. • 2 20 12 e.ia.'lO INGESTION 10 2 25 34 4.20.-H INTRA*. 1 2 3 I «.aO.'H INGESTION I 2 4 2iO***&gt; p.a.'ii intra v. i a ¦ a t 5.2.'31 INGESTION 1 1 II _n 4.21.12 INCESTION « 0 _ _ 7.».'12 INTRA V. 4 3 4 IS '•"-'» "^Ht^N~ ¦¦¦:«¦- * + 204^ ».2«.'12 INTRAV. 3 0 _ ¦ ¦_ - ».21.'12 | INGESTION I 3 I I ( __S_ I iZ_—— - CO.-OH JUNE e-'II.THE YARD WAS SPRINKLED WITH 500.CC. OF A 41HRS. ¦ ROTH CULTURE OF SH.GALLINARUM. ••' C++3.-THE POSSIBILITY OF POST-INOCULATION CONTACT INFECTION CANNOT RE EXCLUDED. TABLE 8 rZzZ^-y/-. . y - fowls introduced into lot no.i2. after artificial infection with fowl typhus.*?. induction of;nfectionJno.of( wo.dead (survival perioos.oaysT DATES. I METHOD. ~_ FOWLS. OF TYPHUS. ""MINIMUM. I MAXIMUM.. 1Q.17.'2» INTRAV. 8 3 13 17 e.12,'30 INCESTION 10 4 S 27 4.20/31 INTRAV. I - 2 ,- 5 ¦ 6 4.20.'31 INGESTION 3 0 _ _ D.a.'H INTRA V. 1 I B7&lt;wa Vl&amp;* ».2.'31 INGESTION 3 I 22 82 4.21.'32 INGESTION 4 0 _ _ 7.».'ia INTRAV. • 12 4 B ll'l2 INTRAV. ¦ A • i*7«»*&gt; 8.31.iz mG£ST|ON ¦ ' - + ' l4y^ ».ae.'ia intra v. » i 7 &gt; »_»¦•» | INGESTION 1 I j O I' _ I _ «»-0N JUNE 8.-3I.THE YARD WAS SPRINKLED WITH SOO.CC. OFA 44 HRS. ¦ROTH CULTURE OF SH.GALLINARUM. «*»)..THE POSSIBILITY Of POST-INOCULATION CONTACT INFECTION - CANNOT BE EXCLUDED. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 TABLE 9 results of exposure to fowl typhus infection unit* sanitary restrictions. lot no. ii-iii».i»i»_it piniobs of 10 bats. AVERAOE DAILY POPULATION.— 10 day periods. &#132;„...,. FUST POPULATION-410 BAYS. \ ¦oalioi lotH7H«in in!»»)»»In It»ltiltsltolul«t| tt | - iitom population.hopays. INDUCED SY! lU|loS||os|»7|H|77H7|E7|Sl|4»|4S|—l_ I— |_|_ I _T~~ FOWL TYPHUS ~~~ ™~ """ -——— — — "————. —. ———— — __ .=_ IHOCULATION. ' ' 000000001 I 0 0 0 0 0 g FOWL TYPHUS £_ EXPo'sURE 01010000000000000-S = »._ OTHER CAUSES. 11211011141121211 O FOWL TYPHUS "~ ~"" ~~ ——— — —¦ ———- — — — —_—_. inoculation. 'OOEOOOOIOO a - FOWI TYPHUS «£ exposure. ° " 'J ________ ° ° ° ° 8 3 OTHER CAUSES. 14 4 4 1 || II SI •»_._,____ O -fswrrvrtmi —» —— == IHOCULATIOH. OII*OIOOOOIIOOOOO g FOWL TYPHUS Of EXPOSURE. ° ' *000000000»0000__ 1-3 OTHER CAUSES. 2 I 4 I I I I 4 t 4 S 7 If l» IT 1 0 | aos.OF ~T~~~ ~ ~~~~~~~~ ~~r^TTZ"^ PERIODS. J 3 L_ __ -*. JL _7_ _•__*_ JO Jl_ _i J_ J4_ JS. J_ J7. — 1 1 —I—I—I—I—I— I—l , - I I I I I I I I I TABLE 10 RESULTS OF EXPOSURE TO FOWI. TYPHUS INFECTION WITHOUT SANITARY NI4TRKTIONS, LOT NO. II - Itli. Illl.ir PERIODS OF SO BAYS. __^ AYERAOE DAILY POPULATION. 1Y 10 DAY PERIODS. FIRST POPULATION.4»O BAYS. "0""'" l04ll0ll.Tl.«llsll»l.llssl»llT t H»| t Tl4S|«»|4l| t l|l0| — SECOND POPULATION-HODAYI. IRDUCEO RY: 115H011101H7177141 144 111 111 111 111 |_|_|_| _ | _ \ _ | _ THIRD POPULATION - SO4 BAYS. ¦ , I»4|I»I1I44| 14411411115111711141 151 &gt;» I»S I H 111 | |Ql| »|»7| »1 | _ FOWI TYPHUS | | =— ""T •Y 10000000004000000 « INOCULATION. o FOWL TYPNUS Sh EXPOSURE. ° ' J ° ° 0 0 0 00 I 0 0 0 0 0 0 __ OTHER CAUSES. OIOIOIIIISSOI2IIOO FOWL TYPHUS "—"""" — "~" ~~ —— — -——. ' I __. NY 20020000000 — INOCULATION. _____________ .—.-.— _ FOWL TYPHUS ¦ £ EXpßurE. 0 10 11. II 7 I O ¦ O S_ 13 OTHER CAUSES. 2 44 • 1 10 1 S S 4 o____,__'"g FOWL TYPHUS 1 \ \ 1 I 1 1 I 1 1 1 1 I | ~™" "^T ¦T 01021001100000000 s INOCULATION. | wi»»i/wi»»u _ FOWL TYPNUS _»• EXPOSURE. " " __f '______ *000I'0000__ H_ OTHER CAUSES. 7114051410 47517 IISSS _ hos.of — ~^""t" - ~ 7~r~r — __ _r ~r _r ~r _t — PERIODS. _.J_ii_._._______Ol__l_J4||.|ll_T. _ </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases FOWLCHOLERA (Lots 7 and 8) In order to ascertain the possible influence of different environments on the morbidity or mortality of fowl cholera, two populations of fowls were exposed to the infection. These were separated from one another by an interval of two weeks, in the course of which lots and houses were left undisturbed, aside from the removal of the litter and food remnants and some minor repairs of the equipment. On July 5, 1929, 120 fowls were introduced into the reasonably, sanitary Lot 7 and 79 additional birds were placed in the lot on April 17, 1930, in order to restore a certain level of population density. The second population of Lot 7 was more slowly assembled, 145 fowls being added between October 28, 1930, and April 29, 1932. While this population was being assembled and before it was de - liberately exposed to experimental infection, three cases of fowl cholera developed in the lot, apparently due to environmental exposure. The possibility of the introduction of an infection carrier, however, also may be given consideration, v The first population of the less salubrious Lot 8 consisted of 120 fowls introduced on July 5, 1929, to which 73 replacement birds were added on April 17, 1930; The second population of Lot 8 was composed of a total of 147 fowls. They were slowly assembled between October 28, 1930, and April 29, 1932. Before the infection could be introduced into Lot 8, one of the occupying birds developed fowl cholera, probably as a result of environmental contact. Exposure of the occupants of the lots to fowl cholera was brought about by the artificial infection of a number'of fowls. This was accom - plished by the intravenous injection of broth culture of the fowl cholera bacillus or virulent rabbit blood, sometimes also by the feeding of the organs of rabbits which had died of the infection. The details pertaining to these inoculations are set forth as follows: Inocula- Number No. (owls No. fowls No. fowls lion fowls in- dead with- dead after not exposure Popula-. dates oculatcd in&lt;rBhrs. , &lt;fBhrs: dying rcsults '"&lt;&gt;•» '...'¦'.¦':'• ¦'¦•. '.':" ¦ Typical ¦ ¦ 8, 16, -20 6 .6,0 ¦¦¦;,. 0: outbreak lst,Lot7 ¦'¦'.-'-. -| ¦'-'...''.= Typical 8, 16, '29 6 .6 ¦¦: 0 0 outbreak . lst,LotB 6, 2-1, -31' 6- '¦. 3 2 li) 10. 2,'i\. 6 6 0 &#132;'!-., 0 -;•-. 0 '"'."¦ -¦.. Mild out - -10, 8, *31 6 2 ¦¦¦¦:•. '3 1 : break 2nd,Xot7 6,24,'31 6 2 3 1 0 10, 2, '31 6 ' "¦% 6 7 |0 ¦...'• 0 0 Mild 'our,-' i___g__j 6 l--- 3 ' 2 break 2nd.LotB </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 The results of the experiments with fowl cholera are summarized in Tables 11 and 12. They include data pertaining to population density and to mortality induced either by artificial infection or exposure. Deaths from other causes are likewise recorded. It will be observed that in each of the two first populations outbreaks of fowl cholera immediately followed the introduction and the deaths of the artificially infected birds. Although varying somewhat in intensity in the two separate populations, they showed all the characteristics of typical farm outbreaks. A marked mortality was sustained for a period of 12 to 14 days. After this period cases continued to occur in a more or less sporadic manner and at a declining rate during the course of approxi - mately eight months. However, when the original population density was restored by the in - troduction of replacement fowls, the disease flared up again. It was of in - terest to observe that not only the newcomers but also the original inhab - itants of the lots became involved in these secondary outbreaks, which ran their course with considerable intensity. The results obtained in the second populations differed from those of the first. The introduction of infection succeeded only after the third at - tempt, and the outbreaks thus induced were characterized by a less ex - plosive nature and by a shorter duration. The cause or causes of this phenomenon could not be ascertained. Similar observations have been occasionally made in connection with the disease as it occurs in farm flocks. In order to determine the infectivity of the two lots a number of geese were introduced into each lot two weeks after the close of the experiment.. These birds were selected because of their marked susceptibility to fowl cholera. They occupied the lots during a period of six weeks without con - tracting the disease. In the course of the experiment, the first population of Lot 7 sus - tained a cholera mortality of 99 exposed fowls. During the same period 94 died of the same cause in Lot 8. Of the second populations 23 exposed birds died of the disease in Lot 7, and in Lot 8 the exposed fowls sus - tained a death loss of 34 individuals from the same cause. Thus in both populations the fowls exposed to the infection showed a total mortality of 122 and 128 birds in Lots 7 and 8 respectively. Therefore, although some evidence of environmental infection was en - countered, there is warrant lor the conclusion that if the character of en - vironment exercises an influence at all it is greatly overshadowed by the virulence and intensity of direct-contact exposure. The comparatively small difference in the fowl-cholera mortality in the more and in the less salubrious environments certainly cannot be interpreted otherwise. additional experiments In the course of the experiments reported above it became apparent that factors other than purely environmental ones also deserved consideration. The rather explosive outbreak which almost immediately followed the </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases ... - ..." ¦ i '- introduction of infection indicated a direct contact of great virulence, while the cases of cholera occurring at more or less prolonged intervals after the primary severe outbreak served to warrant the belief that these later cases might be evidence of the presence of virus carriers. In order to throw light on this phase of the problem certain subsidiary experiments were made which are here related. On August 7, 1930, 29 fowls were removed from each of Lots 7 and 8 and each bird placed in a cage by itself. Some of these birds died of cholera in the cages between August 7 and 21. Between the latter date and August 28, no further cases developed and to each of the 25 fowls from Lot 7 and the 28 from Lot 8 in their individual cages, two healthy fowls originating from a flock in which no cholera had developed since its establishment about nine years before, were added. These contacts were maintained until about October 8,1930, after which the birds were killed and examined. During the experiment eight fowls originating in Lot 7 died and were carefully examined. No evidence of B. bipolaris could be discovered in six of'these subjects, but in one the organism was present in a necrotic area in the abdominal fat and in another one the bipolar bacillus could be demonstrated in a caseous plug in one of the ceca. Four of the fifty contact fowls exposed to the caged birds from Lot 7 died during the experiment from causes other than cholera. Of the caged fowls taken from.Lot 8, two died in the course of the experiment from intercurrent causes. Of the 56 contact birds in cages with the fowls fromlLot 8, three died during the experiment from causes other than cholera. A fourth was killed because of a respiratory infection, the B. bipolaris being identified in the bronchial mucus. On October 15, 1930, the fowls still remaining were removed, 21 froni Lot 7 and 28 froni Lot 8 and each fowl placed in a separate cage for contemplated contact experiments. On October 25, 1930, 20 of the caged birds from Lot 7 and 19 of those originating in Lot 8 were each given two healthy, unexposed birds as cage mates. These contacts were maintained until January 2, 1931, when all the birds were killed and examined. Of the fowls taken from Lot 7, eight died during the period of the experi - ment; six had died of causes other than cholera; one succumbed from cholera about a month after the experiment began, and another died in consequence of an infection of the oviduct, in the exudate of which the B. bipolaris could be demonstrated. Of the 40 contact birds in the cages with those originating in Lot 7, six died from intercurrent causes while a seventh subject, exposed to an apparently normal fowl from Lot 7, died of cholera. The latter subject, examined 27 days after'being placed in the cage, showed that its nasal mucus contained the B. bipolaris. It died in an emaciated state eight days later/ ' Three of the nineteen fowls originating in Lot 8 died in the course of the experiment. One showed the presence of B. bipolaris in the oviduct and the other two were found to have died of causes other than cholera. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 Of the 38 fowls exposed to the 19 from Lot 8, five died in the course of the experiment. In three of them death was not due to B. bipolaris infec - tion; the other two, however, had succumbed to fowl cholera. The interesting contributions by Webster, Hughes, Pritchett, and Hcaudette (1). in connection with the epizootology of fowl cholera, sug - gested that ihc opportunities offered by the fowls from the exposure yards (Lots 7 and 8) should not be neglected. Hence, the following attempts were made: On Nov ember 21, 1930, swabs were made from the palatine cleft of each ol the 18 fowls from Lot 7 placed in cages on October 15, 1930. The swabs were rinsed in a small quantity of physiologic salt solution and the latter then intravenously injected into rabbits, one for each bird. This re - sulted in the death of two of the 18 rabbits from acute B. bipolaris infec - tion within 24 hours after the inoculation. On December 4, 1930, 17 fowls originating from Lot 8 were subjected to a similar experiment, with the result that the material obtained from one of these birds caused the death of the rabbit injected with it by an acute B. bipolaris septicemia within 24 hours after the intravenous inoculation. On December 23, 1930, swabs were again taken from one of the fowls from Lot 7 and from one originating in Lot 8, which in the previous at - tempts had been shown to harbor the cholera bacilli in their nasal mucus. Only the rabbit injected with the material of the fowl taken from yard No. 7 died of acute fowl cholera, whereas the rabbit injected with the inoculum obtained from the bird originating in No. 8 survived in good health. Apparently, thus, the presence of B. bipolaris in the nasal mucus of virus-carrying birds is not always a constant one. Attention is called to the fact that the fowl from Lot 7 had failed to infect its healthy cage mates and that one of the two fowls exposed to the bird from Lot 8 had succumbed to fowl cholera in the course of the experiment. Between June 3 and 23, 1932, the fowls from Lots 7 and 8 were re - moved and their palatine clefts swabbed as indicated above. The material thus obtained was injected into rabbits in a similar manner with the follow - ing results: One rabbit of the 48, each injected with the material from one ol the 48 fowls from Lot 7, and three rabbits of the 40 injected with the material from each of the 40 fowls originating in Lot 8, died of acute B. bipolaris infection within 24 hours after the intravenous injections. No contact infection experiments were made with the birds belonging to these groups. __.¦&gt;• As additional evidence of the tendency on the part of B. bipolaris to localize in the nasal mucus of exposed or non-fata\\y infected fowls, the re - sults of similar tests made in a similar manner with birds belonging in an - other experimental project are submitted. The fowls used were nine sub - jects which had survived in a hemorrhagic septicemia aggressin experi - ment. The nine were challenged as to their virus-carrier status and the rabbits 'injected with material obtained from the nasaV passages of three fowls belonging to this group promptly died of an actute B. bipolaris septicemia. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases j TABLE 11 RESULTS OF EXPOSURI TO FOWL CHOLERA INFECTION UNDER SANITARY RESTRICTIOHS.LOTNO.T-I»I»..»M.IYPERIOPSOF4OPAYS. AWARE DAILY POPULATION- NY 40 PATS PERIODS. MORTALITY ¦ ' FIRST POPULATION_4IS DOTS. INDUetPPYi WIWIMIHJWHI HHIIOTH4 llSllH -I- I - I _____ SECOND POPUtATIQN.SSQ DATS. ITl44lStl4T 14414S lIOOIRI |TI I4« |»t ISSIM UIUOI _ FOWL CHOLERA \~~~\ 111 \~T I '.' | [~ Z~\ —1 r ¦Y &lt; 00000 0 0 0 00 — —_.— _ INOCULATION. | _2 FOWL CHOLERA " ¦ ~ ~HS _ _!_________________!________________ __,____|__ OTHER CAUSES. 2 I I I I I » ¦ II 0 2 _ _ _ — o ¦ ¦ : . | I | 111 111 I | | | •. FOWL CHOLERA . ¦Nocuglrioi., ° ° ° ° ___ ° • ° ,0 '00000 _| ' FOWL CHOLERA "&lt;__ .»££..» * ' °' ¦¦' ° ° ° ° ' ' ¦¦ ' ' ' '..S3 EXPOSURE. ; _. g_ OTHER CAUSES. 0 Of O • 2 IS TO 12 &lt; 2 2 2 I I _ periods. ~T"T"~~~~^~~~T»ir~~is _ TABLE 12 ZZZ- 'ZZ ___ ,yv RESULTS Or EXPOSURE TO FOWL CHOLERA INFECTION WITHOUT SANITARY »ISTRICTIONS.LOTNO.S-tt»».IMl-NY PERIODS OF 40 DAYS. ATERASE PAILY POPULATION_»Y 40 PAYS PERIOPS. MORTALITY FIRST POPULATION-41S DAYS. _^ INDUCED HYI »»l«OI&gt;«IM|yOI«»l»2»IIOO|«t|»0|24|-.|,|-|_|_.- SECOND POPULAT OH-.SSO PAYS. FOWL CHOURA "~" ~" —~ ""— ~"" """" ""™ """ "~" "~"~ —" ~" """ ~— ~~ "^T .noculltion. « o 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0- _ - _ « FOWLCHOLHA _P EXPOYURE. " •••'¦ ° ° ° »• ,0 t0 » • - -.'- - S3 , . ___ _ . __ . _3 OTHER CAUSES. 1 I 1 t 4 1 « 4 • O O — — —• — J fowlchOLlra 7 ~ --=¦ - — =---- = ==¦ •Y 0 000 00 t 0 t I O 0 O 0 0 -5 INOCULATION. y . " .. " " ° u " O FOWL CHOURA " ! "" ' : M_ •Y 0 00 0 10 102 T • • O 2 i O* EXPOSURE. ____________________ ___ g_ OTHER CAUSES. 1 0 1 » • ' « • * 4 V &gt; 2 2 4 "| PERIODS. Z-~tL!____;^__;___Z_l_[_l_C_£_JL_L "" ".. REFERENCES .-¦ 1. Webster, Hughes, Pritchctt and Bcaudette: J. Exp. Med. 51: 1930. </seg>
         <seg id="p022">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 118 TUBERCULOSIS (Lots 5 and 6) In the experiments pertaining to fowl tuberculosis, use was made of equipment corresponding to that made available in connection with other diseases. The experiments were begun in 1929 and were terminated in 1936. During this space of time two distinct populations were maintained in each of Lots 5 and 6. The first one was under observation for some - what more than three 150-day periods and the second one for the greater part of fourteen such periods. The two lots were populated by an identical number of fowls of which the freedom from tuberculosis had been definitely established. An attempt was made to keep the population density at approximately the same level. This however was not always possible owing to the development of a lather high rate of mortality arising from intercurrent causes, a phenom - enon particularly manifest in the less salubrious environent of Lot 6. The two populations occupying the latter sustained a death loss from causes other than tuberculosis of 117 birds above that observed in Lot 5, in which the mortality from intercurrent causes was also a high one. The high mortality from causes other than tuberculosis must, to a consider - able extent, be attributed to the type of fowls available for the experiments. All fowls used during the earlier phases of the investigation were of the Leghorn breed obtained from a high-production flock. They were older birds and in time they commenced to drop off as a result of senility and of various pathological developments in the reproductive organs. In the later stages of the experiments, which began during the later part of the third 150-day period, chicks about ten weeks old and which had survived in the coccidiosis experiments were used. Although in apparent good health and thrifty, several of these birds did not thrive when mixed with the older fowls and succumbed, in part, to various disorders or failed to show evidence of any definite disease upon autopsy. N'o doubt the considerable number of deaths due to intercurrent causes involved a number of birds which otherwise would have become tubercu - lous. Whereas such losses were common in both lots, a basis for comparison could however be maintained. Tuberculous infection was introduced among the inhabitants of each lot by means of fowls either inoculated or fed with fresh avian tuberculous material obtained from the field. The fact that not all of these birds developed tuberculosis can be attributed to their dying from other causes before recognizable lesions had developed. The first populations were composed of older fowls which, prior to actual exposure to the disease, had been gradually assembled. When a sufficient number had accumulated, 12 artificially infected birds were intro - duced into each of Lots 5 and 6. Of these 8 developed tuberculosis in Lot 5 and 9 died of the same cause in Lot 6. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">¦ . ¦¦¦ Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases The results of the exposure to tuberculosis infection of the inhabitants of the lots were rather disappointing, as only one of the exposed fowls developed tuberculosis in Lot 5 and only three in Lot 6. In view of the paucity of results and even more so because of the number of birds suc - cumbing to the influences of age and of occupational disorders peculiar to heavy layers; the first populations of both lots were destroyed for exam - ination shortly after the beginning of the fourth 150-day period of occu - pancy. The assembling of fowls to be part of the second populations was begun 45 days after the lots had been evacuated by the previous inhabitants and 11. weeks later the first artificially infected birds were introduced into the lots. The chickens initially exposed to tuberculosis infection were also mature birds. Their susceptibility to contact infection was not questioned until after the close of the third 150-day period, when it became apparent that the more aged fowls showed a considerable degree of resistance to this mode of infection. Only two exposure fowls had succumbed to tuberculosis in both lots in the course of the first three 150-day periods. Hence it seemed possible that, as in other susceptible species, tuberculous disease in birds also is more apt to come about during the juvenile period of life.' Therefore, beginning during the latter half of the third 150-day period, only chicks of about the age of ten weeks were admitted to the lots, when there was need to restore the desired population density. As a result the incidence of tuberculosis in both lots began to increase in the course of the fourth 150-day period as revealed by Tables 13 and 14. During the occupancy of the second populations of both lots, the oppor - tunity for contact infection was supplied by the introduction of a total of 30 artificially infected fowls into each lot. They were introduced in groups of not more than ten birds at different times. Of the fowls thus admitted, 21 died of tuberculosis in Lot 5 and 20 birds in Lot 6. As summarized in Tables 13 arid 14, a total of 87 fowls became tubercu - lous in the sanitary Lot 5, and in the less salubrious Lot 6 a total of 82 birds either succumbed to tuberculosis or were found to be tuberculous after dying from other causes. As already pointed out, it is quite possible that the number of fowls which developed tuberculosis in both lots constitutes only a part, no doubt a large one, of the birds potentially liable to tuberculous infection. The heavy mortality from a variety of intercurrent causes must have eliminated a substantial number of fowls which otherwise would have increased the tuberculosis death rate. The final results obtained in this investigation certainly tend to show that a given environment may be either sanitary or the very opposite with - out gteady modifying the incidence of avian tuberculosis after the latter has once been introduced. The apparent cause of this phenomenon may be associated with the prolonged longevity of the avian tubercle bacillus in extra-corporeal situations. </seg>
         <seg id="p024">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 118 The more or less adhesive character of the feces of the common fowl may also have been a contributory factor in keeping infective material from a more prompt subsidence into the deeper layers of the coarse gravel with which Lot 5 was covered. Whatever the cause or the modus operandi may have been, the evidence submitted tends to show that the mere provision of gravel as a covering lor poultry yards is not sufficient to play an important part in the prophy - laxis of (owl tuberculosis. Of a more positive hygienic importance is the incidental discovery of the rather marked resistance manifested by older birds to a natural exposure to tuberculosis as compared with that shown by younger fowls. Whereas, as a rule, older birds readily respond to artificial infection, it appears that this is not the case when they are exposed to direct or indirect contact infection in an environment where the opportunity for doing so is offered. From the results obtained in the course of the experiment here related, it is evident that after a fowl attains the age of two years or more without previously contracting tuberculosis, the chances of its doing so when placed in an infected environment are relatively remote. However, it should be kept in mind that mature fowls affected with tuberculosis constitute a very important reservoir of infection from which poultry yards may be constantly contaminated. Their prompt elimination should remain as an imperative measure in the control and eradication of avian tuberculosis. Of equal value in prevention is the safeguarding of the younger birds. Their manifestly greater susceptibility as established in the course of these experiments supplies an additional emphasis on the importance of keep - ing young fowls removed from contact with older tuberculous ones and away from ground befouled by the latter. </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases TABLE 13 RESULTS OF EXPOSURETOTUIERCULOSIS INFECTION UNDER SANITARY RESTRICTIONS. LOT NO.S - ItIf.UIS.DYPERIODSOFISODAYS. MORTALITY ATERAB.E DAILY POPULATION-DY ISO DAY PERIODS. FIRST POPULATION-454 DAYS. „;. D D ITy .o*i«o»i *» i«q»i _i, i_i-I_i_ i _ i _ i _ (_____ - ¦BRBIVITT . SECOND POPULATION.IOI.4 DAYS. INDUCED NY! t , 1 7l I7| ||07|M |M|IJ|»I Ifl liSllOfllT Ifl |4S I _ -TUBERCULOSIS , IT S 0 2 I _________ — _ IMOCUDVTIOH. . o TUIERCULOSIS Ul P DY 0 0 0 !____________ EXPOSURE. ¦ ¦ ¦ ' ¦¦ ~ ___, ____ __ OTHER CAUfIS- II SI IS t _ _ _ _ _ _ _ _ _' _ _ tuierculosis I I I T" I I 1 ¦ ¦¦¦ I I I J~~ 7 ¦noculltion. _ _ ,: _ 1 * « ' _ ° ° _ ° ° .5 TUIERCULOSIS g_ _________ ' ° •¦ ? 4 •- •• " ,0 '•• • ¦¦¦ • 4 s| OTHERCAUSES. »* II IS It 10 S* I* ST IX 12 IT S4 2t 3 £ •Vr'ioos. !E_l_l_Z_l___L_L_L_?!_LiiJLil - TABLE 14 RESULTSDFEXFOSURETOTUSERCULOSIS INFECTION WITHOUT SANITARY RESTRICTION*. LOTNO.4-ISSS.ISSS-RYPERIODSOFISOSATS. MORTALITY AVERASEbAILYPOPUtATION.PYIEOPAYPERIOPS. _ B FIRSTPQPUIATION-4S4DAYS. ___ MORDIDITY ~~I'0»i»l-UI-|-|-|-|-|-|-|-|r SECOND POPULATION. 1014DAYS. INDUCED STI "jTgTj —i |4o||t4|lot|lll|»»|lol|»o|EO|||l[M|«»|So| _ TUIERCULOSIS •V * 0 I '2 ___________ _ INOCULATION. — — — — — — — ¦ TUIERCULOSIS ~ 5 7 ¦Y O 0 I *____________ EXPOSURE. ______ __ J__ __. __ ___ ______ __. = -&gt; OTHERCAUSES. I&gt; II 2&gt; 2 _ _ _.. _. _ _ ___¦___ ** \ TUIERCULOSIS — = '== INOCugATION. ° __ V '.- T. ¦' ° ° ° ° ° ° ° _5 TUIERCULOSIS I _ ...AX... ° ° ° o • is is ix « s s a a • S3 EXPOSURE. w _ , _ a, t OTHERCAUSES. IS If If 42 2T TI 4* S4 20 IS 24 II II I _ periods -~T"* "T"T""TT""s~~TTo"TTTiT 7T ii" _ </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 COCCIDIOSIS (Lots 9 and 10) The general equipment of Lots 9 and 10 in which the coccidiosis ex - periments were carried on was of the same character as that provided in the ones in which the influence of environment on the incidence of other diseases was observed. Lot 9 provided a reasonably sanitary environment, whereas in Lot 10 no sanitary restrictions were imposed. The coccidiosis experiments were initiated in 1929 and terminated in 1935. As will appear from the description of what developed in the course of these years the experimental approach was subjected to certain changes in the equipment of the sanitary Lot 9. These changes were based on the results which became available as time went on. Other changes of experi - mental importance pertained to the selection of the chicks to be exposed to coccidial infection and to the criteria upon which conclusions could be founded. At first it was thought that the death rate would supply a sufficient indication of whatever environmental influences might affect the incidence of coccidiosis. This conception proved to be only partially adequate as a means to evaluate the worth of sanitary measures and in the end it was found to be expedient to depend also on the extent of coccidial infestation. In the presentation of the data secured in this investigation, the various observations are recorded by years, with the exception of the instances when the lots remained more or less continuously populated during longer periods. Experiments in 1929: About two weeks prior to populating Lots 9 and 10 the entire areas were sprinkled with earth in which the intestines of chicks affected with coccidiosis had been digested since the late summer of 1928. In order to assure the presence of more recent infective material in the lots, 43 chicks affected with coccidiosis were placed in each of the lots a day or two later. The lots were populated with chicks from six to eight weeks old on fune 3 and were evacuated October 30. The observations made in the course of the experiment are summarized in Table 15. The recorded data reveal but a slight mortality from coccidiosis and the results of the examination of the intestines established the fact that coccidial invasion was more pronounced in the birds of the sanitary lot than in those in the less salubrious one. The causes of this discrepancy could not be determined. The slight mortality was at the time attributed to the age of the exposure chicks with the thought that their susceptibility to coccidial infestation might have already somewhat declined. A subsidiary experiment to be related at its proper place proved this opinion to be erroneous. It is probably true that, as a rule, older chicks show a lower coccidiosis death rate than younger ones, but it appeared that they are by no means exempt from coccidial in - festation. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases Experiments in 1930: During the year 1930, two separate populations were maintained in each of the. two lots. The first populations were placed in the lots when the chicks were four weeks old after having been brooded under coccidiosis - free conditions. The second populations were brooded in the houses be - longing to each of the two lots, a practice also followed in the years follow - ing during the warmer season. The results obtained in the course of 1930 are exhibited in Table 16. They do not conspicuously differ from the ones recorded during the pre - vious year. Fig. s.—Chicks in Lot 10—June 22, 1934. Experiments in 1931-33: In the course of the period designated above, continuous populations were maintained in Lots 9 and 10. The chicks were admitted to the lots when they were approximately four weeks old and brooded in a cocci - diosis-free environment. \ They were added to the lots periodically and removed when they had served their purpose. In the following tables the dates of admission, re - moval, and their numbers are stated in detail. The experiments were initiated February 4j 1931, when 30 fowls were placed in each of Lots 9 and 10 for the perpetuation of coccidial infection even if this may not have been necessary. These birds remained in the lots until April 10, 1931, when they were removed in an apparendy good state of health. They were not challenged for the presence of coccidia. </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 Exposure Chicks Placed in Lots Exposure Chickj Removed l_u •» Lot 10 Lot 9 Lot 10 Dales Sol. Dales Nos. Dales Nos. Dates Nos. ¦I ,n |U|| 12') -I 2 l» 1931 129 8 7 1931 111 8 7 1931 96 * n |9,1 11)3 B II 1931 KM 6 I 1932 13 5 31 1932 9 x 17 I'Hl H) 8 17 1931 10 6 30 1932 36 6 30 1932 36 5 S M2 111 5 5 1932 111 7 13 1932 -I 7 13 1932 4 5 21 19J2 117 5 21 1932 116 7 20 1932 60 7 20 1932 69 7 211 1932 177 7 20 1932 177 B 27 1932 6 8 27 1932 6 'i H I'M. 61 9 13 1932 64 I 13 1933 3 I 13 1933 3 Total 70S Total 711 1 31 1933 4 1 31 1933 4 2 21 1933 69 2 21 1933 7t 2 23 1933 30 2 23 1933 30 ¦5 6 1933 20 4 12 1933 \0 Date lost 9K 5 6 1933 21 Date lost 130 Total 454 Total 489 The first exposure chicks were placed in the lots on April 29, 1931, and about one month later each lot had added to it two chicks affected with coccidiosis in order to provide an additional source of infection. The observations recorded in Table 17 show evidence of a conspicuous mortality from coccidiosis in both lots. Contrary to expectations, the death rate among the chicks inhabiting the reasonably sanitary Lot 9 was again much higher than among the inhabitants of Lot 10 in which they were without any sanitary protection whatsoever. No doubt the chicks were more at home and happier in the insalubrious environment. Aside from this, it was not possible to discover the cause of this unexpected phenom - enon. "B%xi^jff^Hßr^^lß^q__3rW^ffj V___Ti__vi_P» _r*"_t—M ¦'—_! "JLjeJTt iTnMrrVi ___&amp;. _^*_^^___^____PJ—M_Kir _¦_¦_** * Y__ra 30^__r_t Jr* "%_. '^___H _-F___A_H CSl^Mt -____[ M_ih_A *A'\-^-^_? __. ___F^_l_r^l_B__S^^*. J IKnl^l K.'^/J__i ______E_!____________P____f Ftc. 6.—Chicks in Lot 9—June 21, 1934. </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases There was no escape from the conclusion that the sanitary provisions in Lot 9 were wholly inadequate.; It was quite apparent that the gravel covering in the lot, the wire panels in the house, and the supply of uncon - taminated food and water alone were not sufficient as measures of pre - vention. The body wastes by their adhesiveness could remain on the surface of the gravel long enough for the sporulation of the oocysts and the bloody feces constituted a tidbit which was not passed up by the chicks. The results from the 1931-33 experiments showed conclusively that for the pro - phylaxis of coccidiosis, measures more stringent and adequate than the ones thus far employed would have to be considered. The 1931-33 ex - periments terminated on May 6, 1933, when the lots were evacuated. Experiments in1933-34: In the course of the 1933-34 experiments a more or less continuous chick population inhabited Lots 9 and 10. The birds were added in install - ments and periodically removed when the coccidiosis mortality among them had terminated. The additions and removals are set forth in the fol - lowing tables: Exposure Chickj Placed in Lots Exposure Chicks Removed Lot 9 Lot 10 .Lot 9 Lot 10 Dates . Nos.: Dates Nos. Dates Nos. Dates Nos. 5 10 1933 247 5 10 1933 247 6 26 1933 115 6 26. 1933 103 5 24 1933 50 5 24 1933 50 7 17 1933 193 7 .17 .1933 165 6 2 1933 25 6 2 1933 25 9 12 1933 272 9 12 1933 107 6 3 1933 25 6 3 1933 25- 9 27 1933 53 12 22 1933 51 6 5 1933 25 6 5 1933 25 9 30 1933 26 2 26 1934 1 7 17 1933 253' 7 17 1933 2541 .12 22 1933 63 3 7 1931 6 7 26 1933 77* 7 26 1933 77 1 2 26 1934 1 3 24 1934 44 9 13 1933 183' 9 13 1933 182' 3 6 1934 6 .... .... ... . .. .9.27 1933 53' 3 23 1934 28 .... Total 885 Total 938 Total 757 Total 477 !. One.tlay.oltl chicks,.brooded in houses.. The first additions were chicks four weeks old and a smaller number from five to six weeks old. They were brooded under controlled conditions. The last three additions consisted of one-day-old chicks which were brooded in the houses belonging to the lots. &lt; In the course of the experiments 53 chicks were removed from Lot 9 to Lot 10 in order to equalize the .population density of the two lots. Because the results* obtained in the course of the previous years had con - clusively shown that the means of sanitation thus far made available in Lot 9 were insufficient this lot was completely covered with one-inch-mesh hardware-cloth panels, leaving a space of four inches above the surface of the gravel. The first chick populations were placed in the two lots on May 10, 1933, three days after the installation of the wire panels. When the latter began gradually to sink into the gravel, it was found to be necessary to raise them </seg>
         <seg id="p030">AGRICULTURAL ExPLRIMtNT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 118 and to support them on small pieces of board. This was done on August 18, 1933, and the measure made it impossible for the chicks to gain access to any feed wasted from the feeder. The observations made in the course of 1933-34 are recorded by means oi Tabic 18. The evidence there presented clearly indicates that the covering of Lot 9 with wire panels did not fail to exercise an influence on the relative mortality observed in the two lots. When compared with the death rates recorded earlier in the pursuit of the experimental project, it becomes apparent that the situation had been '- Z-^um ___&lt; __i P^^''^_*2_?W_i _-^^^^S^B ' 7*^_H__^K K_gS§S &lt;• v'is^s&gt;x*_®*Pw _t^_if-B____L« hnS KSf:x.sS?®;s_ J'L i__&gt; k__?k^V^~^¦ ___9S_a _M_i w&amp;¥&amp; "£s-^_P»#'V'_JE_____P___j L_ ': U—lß_-_TT-B—_aW-—_r! Kic;. 7.— Chicks in Lot 10—August 28, 1934. reversed, the mortality in Lot 10 being more than three times higher than the one sustained in Lot 9. However, the deaths of 46 chicks from coc - cidiosis in the wire-covered lot showed also that the additional prophylactic measure had not entirely removed the possibility of fecal contacts and that obviously some other factor had continued to exercise its unfavorable in - fluence. Attempts were therefore made to discover any loophole through which coccidiosis could be disseminated. Continued observation of the equipment provided in Lot 9 and of the habits and behavior of its inhabitants in the course of the latter part of the experimental period here related revealed the apparent source of mischief. It was found to be associated with the type of sanitary feeder then in use in the various sanitary lots. Although this type of feeder was so constructed that the possibility of fecal contamination was excluded it had an unforeseen structural fault. The top of this hopper feeder (1) was made broad enough to shelter the chicks against rain when feeding. The feeder was placed in the center of the lot and afforded the only opportunity to follow the chicks' natural bent to roost on something higher than the level ground. Incidentally feces were deposited on the feeder top and coccidial oocysts were found in this material. It was further observed that the oocysts </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases had sporulated and that the chicks partook of the fecal matter and espe - cially so if it was in the least bloody. The feeder tops were cleansed only by an occasional shower and hence oocysts deposited by previous in - habitants were, no doubt, also instrumental in the promotion of parasitism. A new type of feeder was therefore designed and this equipment ade - quately protected its contents against fecal contamination without a/fording a roosting place as a receptacle for body wastes. It was installed before this lot was again occupied by chicks and was made to serve in subsequent experiments. The lots were evacuated March 23, 1934. __? \\*&amp;nZ- *mi 4_.__F^ _____ _;______________________n___P_____ ' ¦ _______________________________¦ ; I _-_i mm Fit!. B.—Chicks in Lot 9—August 28, 1934. Experimentsin 1934: Before the lots were occupied by the experimental chicks the improved feeder was installed in Lot 9. This feeder, designated as34B, is described in an earlier publication (2). Its front was placed flush with the fence enclosing the lot, its hopper opening being situated on the outside of the fence. It offered no opportunity for roosting and had the additional advan - tage of being so placed that entering the lot was unnecessary when feed was to be supplied. In the pursuit of the 1934 experiments four distinct populations were maintained in each of the two lots. By this arrangement the periods of occupancy were somewhat shortened. However, this measure had the advantage of securing the desired data from a maximum number of birds, The first two populations consisted of chicks four weeks old and the third and fourth populations were one-day-old chicks brooded in the houses available in both lots. The birds were confined around a hover and when they had grown to a size large enough to prevent them from passing under the hardware-cloth floor they were given the freedom of the lots. They were then about two weeks old. '.-.'."• </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 The year 1934 was an exceedingly hot and dry one. This may or may not have been responsible for a coccidiosis death rate as low as it turned out to be, even in the insalubrious Lot 10. The observations made in connection with the first populations indi - cated that mere mortality could not be accepted as a criterion for environ - mental influences on the incidence of coccidiosis. Therefore dependence was also placed on the degree of coccidial infestation as a means of determ - ining whatever part might be played by the character of the environment. Without neglecting the indications supplied by the death rate, an arbitrary determination of coccidial invasion was accepted as a routine practice and adhered to until the termination of the coccidiosis experiments. For this purpose either all or a considerable number of the chicks be - longing to a given population were killed and a microscopic examination for oocysts in the intestinal contents was made. To this end one speci - men was collected from each of the ceca and a third one from the upper part of the small intestine. The degree of coccidial infestation was recorded as + when only an occasional oocyst was revealed, as + + when a con - spicuous number was observed, and as + + + when their number was overwhelming. Although any arbitrary method is necessarily crude, the one followed at least offered a bird's-eye view of the degree of parasitism sufficient for comparison. The results were recorded in colors on the original protocols, of which Tables 22 and 23 may serve as examples. It is obviously inexpedient to incorporate all of them in the scope of a bulletin. The results of these examinations are numerically expressed in Table 21, in which all of the data which became available in the course of 1934 and 1935 are recorded; The numerical base for the calculations was the unit + and its multiples + + and + + +. The observations pertaining to the 1934 experiments are summarized in Table 19. In Table 21 it will be observed that the fourth population (1934) showed a marked degree of coccidial infestation. This could be attributed to the fact that the chicks concerned were hatched from eggs procured from outside sources. They became involved in a severe outbreak of bacil - lary white diarrhea. This alone caused a heavy initial mortality, while in addition the surviving chicks remained backward and runty to such an extent that when they were turned on the wire panels many of them were small enough to pass through the meshes to the gravel surface where, without doubt, oocysts were plentiful. The 1934 experiments were concluded on December 4, when the lots were evacuated with the exception of 25 chicks of each lot which were retained for the purpose of the maintenance of coccidial infection. Experiments in 1935: The experiments in Lots 9 and 10 carried on in 1935 did not differ materially from those of the preceding year, with the exception of the one pertaining to the fourth and last of the populations. </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases ¦ For the purpose of further controlling the effectiveness of the useof wire panels as a prophylactic measure and to demonstrate, if possible, that there still was a coccidiosis hazard associated with the bare gravel, the panels were removed prior to the admission of the 260 chicks constituting the fourth population of Lot 9. The results of this procedure are placed in evidence in Tables 20 and 21. They reveal that, although there was no conspicuous increase in the coccidiosis death rate, the relative degree of coccidial infestation was quite a high one among the inhabitants of Lot 9. It even exceeded the one re - corded in connection with the chicks inhabiting the insalubrious Lot 10. It was not possible to establish the cause of the relatively high degree of coccidial infestation observed in the chicks examined from the second population of Lot 9. Apparently through some fault in the equipment or a possible failure in its care and supervision some of the chicks made con - tact with the contaminated surface of the gravel. The possibility of oocysts being introduced by means of the bags in which the feed was delivered also deserves consideration in this connection. As revealed by Tables 20 and 21 it appears that the more stringent prophylactic measures brought about a marked decline of mortality as well as of the degree of coccidial infesta - tion. The experiments came to a close November 28 when the lots were evacuated. V Results—l929-35: The results obtained in the course of the coccidiosis experiments of 1929 - -35 supplied evidence that: .1. Chick mortality alone is not a sufficient criterion by which to evaluate the sanitary fitness of a given environment. 2. A more dependable measure of such a fitness can be obtained by the determination of coccidial infestation of the chicks serving in an ex - periment. 3. The more or less complete separation of the chicks and their food and water from fecal contacts, by the measures described, is capable of reducing both mortality and coccidial parasitism to a bearable minimum. ADDITIONAL OBSERVATIONS Aside from the principal purpose of the investigation, the relation of environment to the incidence of coccidiosis, certain other observations were made which may be recorded. Some of these pertain to the physical con - dition of the chicks used in the project. It was observed in the more severe outbreaks that the more marked mortality was of relatively short duration. It had usually ceased before the chicks, which were exposed at the age of four weeks, reached the age of eight to ten weeks. The chicks surviving the outbreaks commonly showed unthriftiness and roughened and dirty feathers. For a time their growth was arrested. These phenomena were always more marked among the inhabitants of the less salubrious Lot 10 than in Lot ?, even if the birds in the latter had sustained a rather severe assault by coccidia. .J </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 It was possible to record the average body weight of certain groups of chicks at the time they were disposed of. The weights in pounds are re - corded in the following table: Dales Lot 9 Lot 10 B 7 1931 3.10(1 2.970 ') 12 1933 0.878 0.552 11 .1 1933 0.818 0.636 12 22 1933 2.490 2.330 =&gt; 7 1934 1.5D1) 1.370 6 25 1934 1.311) 1.200 6 25 1934 2.470 2.400 5 10 1935 1.810 1.610 6 II) 1935 11.955 0.668 Average 1.703 1.526 Diflcrcncc 0.177 It appears from the data submitted that the average weight of the chicks which inhabited Lot 10 was always below that of their brooder mates which occupied the more sanitary Lot 9. The average difference was 2.832 ounces in favor of the latter birds, although at the time of weighing the chicks of both lots had already commenced to regain their thrift. The promptness with which coccidial oocysts may appear in the feces is revealed by the following observation: On May 8, 1934, a number of chicks were removed from Lot 9 to a large box stall in one of the stables in anticipation of their being killed and examined. This stall, entirely constructed of concrete, was clean in so far as this was possible by the use of shovel and broom. Some months before this stall had been used for the temporary housing of a number of fowls. For the purpose of examination the chicks placed in this stall were removed in installments on May 8, 10, 12, 16, 17, 19, and 22, 1934. The examination revealed a complete absence of coccidial oocysts. The remain - ing 35 chicks were killed and examined on May 23 and 24, 1934, and with the exception of only one they were found to be harboring oocysts in vary - ing amounts. Thus, on one day following the examination of chicks in which oocysts could not be found, nearly all of the subsequently examined birds belong - ing to the same group showed an abundance of oocysts. No doubt the coccidial invasion must be attributed to oocysts deposited by fowls a con - siderable space of time before. An opportunity presented itself for a subsidiary experiment designed to determine whether or not chicks approximately 16 weeks old (which had remained free from coccidial infestation) would still be subject to the latter if exposed in a badly contaminated environment—or to what extent age might exercise influence. The details of this experiment are exhibited by Table 24 and its explanatory legends. This table likewise supplies an answer to the question posed. </seg>
         <seg id="p035">35 Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases TABLE 15 COCCIDIOSIS EXPERIMENTS. toTSMos.»Asoio-ii»». OBSERVATIONS. DATES. LOT LOT T NO.t. NO.IO. INFECTED CHICKS S.SI _S If PLACED IN LOTS. t .iT ~7j~ TJTj" EXPOSURE CHICKS i . "JoT ~07 PLACED 111 LOTS. | *'* )"" | '0T INFECTEDCHICKSDEAD FROM COCCIDIOSIS. ( L_Jl___ EXPOSURECHICKSPEAO . FROM COCCIDIOSIS. ' EXPOSURECNICKS KILLED w ~~ - AND EXAMINED. &lt; ' EXAMINED CHICKS O KITH + +ORKOBE •" 20 I OOCYSTSININTESTINES. , .. EXPOSURE CHICKS DEAD &#132; . FROM OTHER CAUSES. __^ " * LOTS EVACUATED. 10.10 _. ¦_ TABLE 16 COCCIDIOSIS EXPERIMENTS-LOTS NOS.RANPIO-11.0. ) LOT NO.t. II LOT MOJO. OBSERVATIONS. DATES POPULATION. POPULATION. i I 7~ i I i EXPOSURE CHICKS S.SS Its 114 PLACED IN LOTS. r~~" ~~ Ijj I ~sT~ EXPOSURE CHICKS DEAD | ' 1 | ill FROM COCCIDIOSIS. ) . ~ _ 7 —7 —J — EXPOSURE CHIOS KILLED" 0 „ AMD EXAMINED. "j ~~~~ -^j_~ EXAMINED CHICKS S ¦ WITH ?+ OR MORE 5 —= =- OOCYSTS IN INTESTINES. •" _ » I [ _1_ EXPOSURE CHICKS DEAD , _ " . „ ¦ __F*S-__S—————. I I II LOTS EVACUATED. T.SS __» __ + " ——— TABLE 17 COCCIDIOSIS EXPERIMEHTS.tOTSMOS.PANPIO-mi.ltll. '¦¦ OBSERVATIONS. DATES. LOT N0.».|.0TH0.10 REMARKS. CHICKS PLACES IN LOTS i •_.'_. ,- I i r' . TOMAINTAIN INFECTION. I 1-*'" | &gt;0. | 10 AROVE CHICKS REMOVED I ,„„, I ~ I ¦ 5 FROM LOTS. )*.tO.'»l) 10 | 10 •_. ; EXPOSURE CHICKS L.._._| ... I ~ 3 P.ACEDINLOTS. « |TOTA.S.| 70S \ Til = INFECTED CHICKS IS.aH.II I I I I S PLACED IH LOTS. t. I.'l ' I I ll_ J EXPOSURE CHICKS BEAD ... I __ g FROM COCCIDIOSIS. . "" j -»' '?. ' EXPOSURE CHICKS DEAD _&gt; ... i . . 2 FROM OTHER CAUSES, i '«» I '«' £ EXPOSURE CHICKS 2 _.__.." DEMOTED FROM LOTS. t&gt; ¦ «4 41» , LOTS EVACUATED. S-S-ll _ | — </seg>
         <seg id="p036">36 Agriclltl-ral Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 TABLE 18 COCCIDIOSIS EXPERIMENTS.LOTS NOS.S AND 10-ISII-ISI4. OISERVATIQMS. I L°™k»; !*%!{&amp;_• I ««"*»«¦ EXPOSURE CHICKS ... , lt PLACED IM LOTS, tl J. EXPOSURE CHICKS DEAD &#132; , At or J H u FROM COCCIDIOSIS. g? gj EXPOSURE CHICKS KILLED 2 t7 4i . 2 •»? AMD EXAMINED. 2oi = _ EXAMINED CHICKS AFFECTED . . '"Si So WITH COCCIDIOSIS. ___ H 5 _3' EXPOSURE CHICKS DEAD &#132;4 177 "* £ _}_ FROM OTHER CAUSES. S, 2 o* EXPOSURE CHICKS REMOVED 704 477 • *¦ FROM LOTS. Tl I I __¦_____ TABLE 19 COCCIDIOSIS EXPERIMENTS.LOTS NOS.BANDIO- I*l4. ~~1 I LOT NO.t. II LOT NO.IO. I OBSERVATIONS. DATES. POPULATIONS. POPULATIONS. REMARKS. 111111141 I I 2 I 1 I 4j °* 4.7 114 M __D I I 1 EXPOSURE CHICKS -»_4 Sia"! jl* PLACED IN LOTS. y *n — S? L [t-aal I I m liis _s EXPOSURE CHICKS I I0 I I I I» I I I s«i DEAD FROM £--5 -I*-^ _ «} coccidiosis. ZZ ~ZZ Z_L ZZ ZZ ZZ 2I! i 2 EXPOSURE CHICKS _____ ZZ ZZ ZZ HZ ZZ ZZ ZZ "JJ DEAD FROM 2 —— TT — TTZZ E5 OTHER CAUSES. g IIBC-1 lIP a - EXPOSURE CHICKS *" HI I I I I ««l| I I SiS KILLED AHD iff- stfl -"' EXAMINED. ( I f l»4l~ I 1 liiT *" EXPOSURE CHICKS I HIT SO I I I T | _ RETAINED 111 LOTS. 11,4 I I I -till I 111 J EXPOSURE CHICKS ""l^llll *l"~T™" o TRANSFERRED FROM l.lt SO _. LOT NO. P. » I I I I II I I I w EXPOSURE CHICKS I 1 1 I 1 II 1 1 1 _ |l___g_________ '•» _ I [ M &lt; HEALTHY CHICKS _# _^ io7 __= P __E-E 5 REMOVED FROM LOTS. SJS 0 0 _ __Li —"oi —l~ —»"____i </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases TABLE 20 COCCIDIOSIS EXPERIMEHT9. LOTS HOS.S AMD 10- lIH. "^^~T"'~?otTioTs!^~Ti^~lo^-c~^&gt; m~~l^^ ODSERVATIONS. DATES POPULaYiOrTsTI POPULAt'IONS. [REMARKS. 1 *¦] •*'' j * llais I 4 EXPOSURE CHICKS T^ 57T ___l______i~j | | - PLACED IN LOTS. 7-11 170 ~ "~~" 170 ».a» gj§ I I~~i2-r j_ EXPOSURE CHICKS I LP-CZ_l_ I 1|"45 I I I DEADFROM *— -, -__ Ji__ _____ _- coccidiosis. j j )* -j ~" "**" TT " EXPOSURE CHICKS 115 ' I I I II 8 1 1 &lt; ¦ DEAD PROM « ¥ ; —J*.. . ¦ _ OTHERCAUSES. £ "^"si — — -5-- '¦-'_ i H Zl '* t &lt; EXPOSURE CHICKS J" __7» O P&gt; KILLEOAHD — ±»»_ -^1™ 5_ EXAMINED. P~f! _Zp_3~j lIP "¦ " HEALTHY CHICKS _______ T« ZZZ "~_ ZZ ZSI '~~ *" REMOVED FROM LOTS. ____ __0_ o*~ I _j__- '- __________! 1 I 1-o '_ TABLE 21 COCCIDIOSIS EXPERIMENTS-LOTS HOS.S AHDIO-1P14.1815. popula ICOCCID,Ol C0CCID,0- S.,5J_l 0RT*UTYI "tL*T«,'« •IMMOr I "?££ ___P_JK_______^g "HARKS. H0.1.14 0 O.SO 0 147.00 N0.2.14 0 1.11 O.SI 204.00 NO.B-1* O 5.55 10.20 151.00 M0.4.14 1.44 10A4 157.00 1(0.00 i.-.D. N0.1.15 0 11.14 1.E2 227.00 N0.2.1S 0.24 »*.*o IO4JOO 204.50 HO.S-'SS 0.14 10.27 14.29 200.41 ' ~~_~ ¦ —" " : ~~ ' ' ' r LOT NO.t N0.4.1S 1.15 14.17 141.21 115.11 WITHOUT I I II IwiRE PANELS. </seg>
         <seg id="p038">38 TABLE 22 Ij g _ 2B j I _.2» I I 43-30 1 | 7-3 I 7.5 | 7-« I luC" &gt; I I TTT Hi Li IT Tl ______ I I = IS i ii i i. j ""a IB ___________________H ________________¦ I -H _____________ _____________ ______________________ ____ ____ ____ .I ____ ____ ---------------------- hHHHH _h H-l _l __B-__l _l _l __¦ __fl __fl ____ __fl __fl -H __fl -H j______________________ __________________________ ______________ __________________________ ___________¦ _____________ ______________________ -_sl ¦ _________________________i ___________¦ _________________________¦ _____________ _____________ ______________________ ____ __________________________ ___________¦ -________________________l __________-[ _____ H o—— ¦i¦ s s ¦ _^SS I ¦ &lt;+++ II I II -_-_-_--H I -_H 2__ || __^_____| — B__BH I _¦__— si.— li II i i i I I ++ I _^_^_^H I _^_^_^H _^H _^H ¦ ¦ uix ¦ ___________________B ______ _____________ _______ BBI m __WBBIBBJ, —— ,-— II I I II I _i__l I «*&lt; + II _^_^_^_H I I _^_H _^_H _^_^_^_. _^_^_H _^_^H_H _H_-^ _H_H_H _H__ _i_H _H__He. Q-S ______________________ —^—E^~M~"~~N ¦ H __^E3 _____________ ____ II I I I I I ° —IB I _________¦ _^_^_^_H _^_H I I _^_^_H _^_^_I_H I I I II I u ¦ S S S3 S 9 _______ « 1 ' ~i ______________________ _^_^_^_^__ ¦ I H _^_H H^H ______________________ ______________________ ________________________¦ ___________¦ _______________________¦ ____________l ___________¦ _ H ___. __________________________ I __________________________ HI I ______________________ s\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\w \\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\\W -_-_-_-----¦ H^H^H^H^H^H ____ -_-_-_------l I I II II ' II I _^_^_^_l T/if A—ry coccidial infestation of 263 chicks maintained in the insaditbrious lot 10 (2nd population, 1934). Adapted from Supplement . 3 to Protocol Chart sa. </seg>
         <seg id="p039">TABLE 23 I.- ¦¦&#132;: =- : , ¦ &#132;. , .1 I C2C || «.2» 7.2 7.7 7-» I I H _________________________¦ _________________¦ HI ¦ HH^H^HH II ________________________fl _______________ ________L_____._________.___i &#132; i i c __________________________________ _¦ _¦ — _____¦ __rn_l II I _____________________________B BB BBS BB ____ 1 _______ _____ H H II I— 2T 1 111 !_¦ ¦ o-^—ml &amp;| I _______ 5 ____¦ §+++ || 11 11 1 1 11 I "• w I I I I I I ____.____________________.___l I _____________________________B I I ¦II I ¦_-_-_-_-_¦ _-_-_¦ I --— SI I 1111 II II ii i i I ii i __¦___ I _______ _____________________________¦ II _______ ____. ___________________________ ________________________¦ .............................I _______________¦ __________¦ S==__| _______¦ I II II -H I B_ _----------------------------B __¦ fl __¦ 8 1 \WmwmwM I _^_^_^_^_-^ _^_^_.^ I ¦ HI I H ¦ I ____ I ° ™ I I I _flflflflfl i flflflfl- 1 Hi ________________________¦ Hi ____ __________¦ I I fl B I Bflflflfl ¦ I II I II ________ ____________________________ _______________________________________________________________ ________ _______ II I II II I ___________________________ ______________I ______________________________! _________________N ____ _________________________H _____________________________H I _-________¦ H-l H The relative freedom from coccidial infestation of 189 chicly maintained in the sanitary environment of Lot 9 (2nd population, 1934). 'Adapted from Supplement 3 to Protocol Chart 5. </seg>
         <seg id="p040">AcRiciLTiRAL Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 TABLE 24 ________________________________¦=» ¦~l •""I ________ ¦ ____ 2 111 ++ + | I ____________________ I r - ===== i ii I _____¦ S5 II o || o —ill o lI - FIG.I. "6-2" I-it.. l.—T/ic decree of coccidial infestation of 4/i chicks which were retailed in l.oi 'i. They were hatched March 5, 1934, and placed in the lot April 7, 1934. When they were killed and examined on (mlf 26. 1934, they were 113 days old. Two o/ the original ill clucks retained in the lot hail died ami no coccidia were found in ihcm upon examination. Kit.. 2.—The degree of coccidial infestation of 47 chicks which were transferred from U)t 9 to Ijoi 10 on May 19. 1934. They were hatched March 5, 1934, and placed in Ijji 9 on April 7, 1934. When they were killed on fune 26, 1934, they ii-rrr ))i days old. One o) ihe original 50 chicks transferred to hot JO had died of coccidiosis and two had died /rom oilier causes although coccidia were found to be present in their intestines. &lt; Adapted from Supplement 1 to Protocol Charts S and 5i1.) REFERENCES 1. Van lis: Principles of Animal Hygiene and Preventive Veterinary Medicine (1932) (see Figs. 32 and 33, p. 162). 2. Van Es and Olncy: Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 306, 1937. </seg>
         <seg id="p041">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases BLACKHEAD ;¦.'•':¦..".." (Lots 3, 1-3, and 4) (Lots 2, 8, and 12) The experiments concerned with the influence of environment on the incidence of blackhead in turkeys were carried on in Lots 3, 1-3, and 4. In addition some collateral observations were made in connection with Lots 2, 8, and 12 which were previously occupied by barnyard fowls. .. Lots 3 and 4 were equipped in a manner comparable to the appointments of the ones in which other diseases were under investigation. As results were being obtained, some changes in the experimental technique were made in order to find answers to questions, which presented themselves as the work progressed. These changes will be described at their proper places in this account. . V Before the experiments were begun, both lots were sprinkled with equal amounts of dry earth in which the ceca and livers of turkeys affected with blackhead had been digested since the summer and autumn of the pre - vious year, In the course of the years which followed, no additional black - head material was introduced into the lots, with the exception of the ex - periments of 1934-36 when it was attempted to secure a more intensive exposure in Lot 1-3, The lots were populated with equal numbers of poults of identical hatch and brooded under sanitary control. As will be observed from the more detailed descriptions which follow, some changes were made when poults were transferred from one lot to the other. However, when the transfers were completed, the population density was about the same in the areas concerned. When in later experiments the sanitary lot was enlarged the population density was made to correspond to the different areas. Fig. 9.—Poults in Lot 1-3—June 21, 1934. </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 The blackhead experiments were of a seasonal character, the periods of occupancy extending over approximately six months. ' After the lots were vacated at the termination of each year's experiments, they were kept unpopulated and left undisturbed until the poults of the following year were admitted. Houses and equipment, however, were always cleaned prior to the repopulation of the lots. The poults were four weeks old when they entered the experimental lots. Turkeys surviving the exposure to blackhead were sold at the end of the season and their organs were carefully examined at the time of slaughter. Although these birds were in good health and state of nutrition, some of them presented minor blackhead lesions. Hence it was deemed expedient to depend more on morbidity than on mortality as a criterion by which to evaluate the obtained results. Owing to the seasonal character of the experiments, their results are reported by years. Experiments in 1929-30: The results recorded during the course of 1929 and 1930 are exhibited in Table 25. They leave no doubt with regard to the prophylactic influence of the gravel-covered and more sanitary environment in Lot 3. Experiments in 1951: Since the prophylactic value of a sanitary environment as compared with tbat of an insalubrious nature had been established by the results of the experiments of the two preceding years, the scope of the investigation could be broadened. Hence, efforts were made to determine whether or not a timely removal of the poults from a badly contaminated area to a safer one would increase their chances of survival. With this objective in view 60 poults were removed from Lot 4 to Lot 3 in four installments of 15 birds each. At the time of their transfer, they were 31, 38, 45, and 52 days old and had occupied the insalubrious lot 7, 14, 21, and 28 days respectively. Four of these poults died of blackhead in the sanitary lot, one of each installment. Seven of the poults so moved died of other causes. Thus only 6.66 per cent of the transferred poults succumbed to the disease, whereas the poults remaining in the less sanitary environment sustained a black - head morbidity of 28.28 per cent. Apparently a major part of the trans - ferred birds found sanctuary in the safer lot, even after inhabiting the less sanitary one for periods ranging from one to four weeks. Additional data pertaining to the 1931 experiments are supplied by Table 26. Experiments in 1932: In the course of the 1932 experiments the efforts of the previous year were repeated as may be ascertained from Table 26. Prompted by a desire to establish whether or not the blackhead morbidity could be further re - duced and to gain information bearing on the practicability of the measure, hardware-cloth panels were placed on the top of the gravel before the lots were populated. </seg>
         <seg id="p043">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases In installments of 15 each, 60 poults were transferred from Lot 4 to Lot 3 when they were 37, 44, 51, and 58 days old after a sojourn in the less sanitary lot of 7, 14, 21, and 28 days respectively. Four of the transferred poults developed blackhead in Lot 3 and one died of other causes. There was no other blackhead mortality in the sani - tary lot. As in the course of the 1931 experiments 6.66 per cent of the trans - ferred poults died of blackhead, whereas among the ones which remained in Lot 4 a blackhead.mortality of 20.08 per cent was sustained. ¦ • :' ,'j Fig. 10—Poults in Lot 1-3—June 23, 1934. . Of the transferred poults which died of blackhead in Lot 3, two be - longed to the second installment and two to the third one. These results confirmed the conclusions regarding the experiments of the preceding year. Experiments in 1933: The experiments conducted during 1933 differed from those under - taken in the course of the previous two years by the fact that the transfers of the poults were reversed. The purpose was to determine whether or not poults removed from the sanitary Lot 3 to the insalubrious Lot 4 would, in the face of exposure to blackhead, have their hazard reduced in compari - son with the birds inhabiting the less favorable environment. To this end four installments of 15 poults each were removed at intervals of two weeks. At the time of their removal, these birds had attained the ages of 46, 60, 74, and 8? days respectively. Seven cases of blackhead developed among the 60 poults thus trans - ferred. Qf these one belonged to the first group removed, four to the second group, and the third and fourth groups supplied one case of blackhead each. Thus the moved poults revealed a blackhead morbidity of 11.66 per cent, whereas the original inhabitants sustained a morbidity of 32.85 per cent from the same cause. Only two cases of blackhead developed in Lot 3. From what was revealed by the above-described experiments it appears that the younger a poult is at the time of exposure the greater will be its </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 liability to contract the disease. There is warrant for turkey producers to keep this simple fact in mind. Other details pertaining to the 1933 experi - ments arc supplied by Tabic 27. Experiments in 1914: Prior to the inauguration of the 1934 experiments two-thirds of each ol (he original Lots 1 and 3 were united in one, having an area of 2,400 square feet. Henceforth the lot will be designated as No. 1-3 on the records. The entire area thus made available was covered with one-inch-mesh hard - \^^^^k^^ Vjr\ I_|'^^^__^ ____Ht_/^iIS»3S-«II---M ___? ____Ew_jH I^^^^ ______Lv «_flßrf nv_j__K i_i__i _u &lt;______._____ ______Vlffl_________| _^ _____ ____*ti_____H fli ________¦___ __H H__ S^-H —fl—H.---__ R." ffllw-L. --_! Hii l-'it.. ll.—Turkeys in l.n 1-3—October 25, 1934. ware-cloth panels on stringers, supported by posts of such a length that the surface of the wire floor was on the average two feet above the ground. Prior to these changes the gravel was removed from the lots. Feed was supplied in hopper feeders similar to but larger than the ones finally adopted in the coccidiosis lot No. 9. The housing facilities of the original two lots were utilized. One of them was equipped for roosting and the other one was available for shade and protection against unfavorable weather. Drinking water was supplied in self-cleaning equipment such as was used in all the sanitary lots. These changes were made in order to determine the possibility of providing an absolute protection against blackhead. The new arrangements were further intended to demonstrate whether or not the resulting environment would be suitable for turkey production wherever a wider range was not available. The lots thus altered served until the conclusion of the blackhead ex - periments. Until that time the open area and the houses, also equipped with a wire floor, were not cleaned. All fecal matter dropped to the ground </seg>
         <seg id="p045">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases and the areas above always remained clean. This proved to be a labor - saving factor, which is deemed to be of some importance to people pro - ducing turkeys while otherwise employed. It may be stated at this point that the environment described fully met the .requirements for raising healthy and vigorous turkeys. The 1934 experiments and those of the succeeding two years were directed to reveal whether or not poults maintained under the rigid pro - tection provided could be caused to contract blackhead as a result of more intense exposure. With this objective in view there were introduced into r^slfl ______________________________PH_______l__-__ \s &gt;___________________________HHR9__|^^___ ___E___Q_9___i ___¦___: v -"'- HI ______________ ¦ V____aK!9^_wiiK_nl/^_H- M ____________ _____i______P!__***lH Ei ' *_-*! _k___^l _ui__i WSjf/-'\wjl\ B^^'i^?^!ivSifli _________¦ I ihe_P___&gt;y_____r -^_u^ißS_c_f__9 I Bmß_Ks__i^B_ — '. '.'S:^^9IHM Fig. 12—Poults in Lot •)—June 21, 193-1. Lot 1-3 14 poults fed with organs affected with blackhead, and ten poults similarly fed were placed in the less sanitary Lot 4- The data (Table 28) do not indicate that this procedure exercised any influence on the incidence of blackhead in the lots mentioned. None of the poults occupying Lot 1-., including the ones fed with blackhead organs, developed the disease in the course of the' experiment. Because, of what failed to come about in the sanitary lot, it seems extremely doubtful that such of the poults as contracted blackhead in Lot 4 did so as a result of being fed in the manner mentioned. The results confirm the opinion that it is difficult, if not impossible, to induce blackhead in susceptible birds by the forced ingestion of organs involved in the disease. Experiments in 1935: The nature of the experiments conducted in the course of the year 1935 is shown by Tabic 30. In order to determine the possibility of inducing blackhead among poults occupying the sanitary Lot 1-3 a number of birds originating in lots previously inhabited by common fowls were, at stated </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 intervals, admitted to the wire-covered area. These poults were only trans - ferred alter deaths from blackhead had occurred in the lots in which they were exposed to the inlection. Accordingly, 25 poults from Lot 2 were turned into the sanitary en - vironment on June 19, a similar number from Lot 12 on June 27, and .mother 25 from Lot 8 on iuly 2. Of these birds, 5 removed from Lot 2 developed blackhead. 6 originating in Lot 12 succumbed to the same cause, and only one o! those transferred from Lot H did likewise. It will lie observed in Table 30 that none of the 106 original inhabitants oi Lot 1-i became involved in blackhead. In consideration of the control nature ol the latter, it is apparent that the transferred poults which died of blackhead had contracted the disease in their original environments and they tailed to transmit the disease to any of the birds with whom they cohabited. Experiments in 1936: Owing to the negative results which followed attempts to induce black - head in the poults inhabiting sanitary Lot 1-3 by means of exposure to poults either led with blackhead material or exposed to natural infection, another effort was made to test the effectiveness of the sanitary measures taken in connection with Lot 1-3. Empirically developed opinion has pre - vailed among turkey growers that the incidence of blackhead has a certain connection with the cohabitation of turkeys and barnyard fowls. Further - more, earlier workers had successfully demonstrated the part played by the eggs ol the cecal worm (rlctcrakjs gallinae) in the etiology of the disease. It was therefore attempted to introduce the infection by establish - ing an indirect contact of the experimental poults with Hetcrakis-infested common fowls in order to find, if possible, a satisfactory answer to the fol - lowing questions: 1. Will the sanitary equipment of Lot 1-3 afford adequate protection against blackhead in poults after the lot has been inhabited by Heterakis - intested fowls? 2. Will the introduction of Hetcrakis-infested fowls into the insalu - brious Lot -I be followed by a materially increased blackhead morbidity among the poults inhabiting this environment? For this purpose 50 fowls originating in coccidiosis Lot 9 and an identical number oi birds taken from Lot 10 were transferred respectively to Lots 10 and 12 on November 28, 1935. On December 27, 1935, the birds in Lot 10 were removed to Lot 12 and the occupants of the latter to Lot 10. Similar transfers were made on January 15 and on February 15, 1936. In this connection it should be noted that in the course of the preceding years a number of the chicks inhabiting Lot 10 had developed blackhead and that poults maintained in Lot 12 had recently been involved in a marked blackhead morbidity. On March 30, 1936. 26 fowls from Lot 10 and a similar number from Lot 12 were removed to I_ot 1-3 and on the same day 19 fowls from </seg>
         <seg id="p047">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases Lot 10 and 18 from Lot 12 were transferred to Lot 4. All these birds were removed from the lots on June 11, 1936. In the course of the experiment 40 of the fowls were either killed or had died from natural causes. Of these, nine could not be examined, hav - ing had their viscera removed by lot mates or predatory rodents. Of the 11 birds examined, 24 were found to be infested by cecal worms and in seven these parasites could not be found. The observations made in the course of the 1936 experiments are presented in Table 32. iE!__-_l__^^^il!P^^Hß l-":o. 13.—Turkeys in Lot 4—October 25, 1934. One is tempted to conclude that the two cases of blackhead which occurred among the poults occupying Lot 1-3 and the increase of the blackhead morbidity rate in Lot 4 from 10 per cent in 1935 to 15 per cent in 1936 must be attributed to the Heterakis factor. If such conclusion could be sustained, it would indicate that chicken contact in a most sanitary environment may even there constitute a blackhead hazard although prob - ably only a minor one. The relative blackhead morbidity rates incurred by all lots during the period 1929-36 are summarized in Table 33. The results accumulated from experiments during this period conclusively revealed the effectiveness of the prophylactic measures against blackhead. The 977 poults exposed in Lot 3 (1-3) sustained a blackhead morbidity of 23 birds (2.35 per cent) whereas in the 871 in the insalubrious Lot 4, blackhead developed in 357 poults (40.98 per cent). Roughly expressed the poults maintained without sanitary protection were liable to. a blackhead morbidity rate 17.4 times greater than of turkeys kept under sanitary restrictions. " ADDITIONAL OBSERVATIONS ON BLACKHEAD It was deemed of interest to take advantage of lots vacated by common fowls which served in other experiments and to populate them with poults. </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 intervals, admitted to the wire-covered area. These poults were only trans - ferred after deaths from blackhead had occurred in the lots in which they were exposed to the infection. Accordingly. 25 poults from Lot 2 were turned into the sanitary en - vironment on June 19, a similar number from Lot 12 on June 27, and another 25 from Lot 8 on July 2. Of these birds, 5 removed from Lot 2 developed blackhead, 6 originating in Lot 12 succumbed to the same cause, and only one of those transferred from Lot 8 did likewise. It will be observed in Table 30 that none of the 106 original inhabitants of Lot 1-3 became involved in blackhead. In consideration of the control nature of the latter, it is apparent that the transferred poults which died of blackhead had contracted the disease in their original environments and they failed to transmit the disease to any of the birds with whom they cohabited. Experiments in 1936: (Kving to the negative results which followed attempts to induce black - head in the poults inhabiting sanitary Lot 1-3 by means of exposure to poults either fed with blackhead material or exposed to natural infection, another effort was made to test the effectiveness of the sanitary measures taken in connection with Lot 1-3. Empirically developed opinion has pre - vailed among turkev growers that the incidence of blackhead has a certain connection with the cohabitation of turkeys and barnyard fowls. Further - more, earlier workers had successfully demonstrated the part played by the eggs of the cecal worm (Hcteraltis gallinae) in the etiology of the disease. It was therefore attempted to introduce the infection by establish - ing an indirect contact of the experimental poults with Heterakis-infested common fowls in order to find, if possible, a satisfactory answer to the fol - lowing questions: 1. Will the sanitary equipment of Lot 1-3 afford adequate protection against blackhead in poults after the lot has been inhabited by Heterakis - iniested fowls' 2. Will the introduction of Heterakis-infested fowls into the insalu - brious Lot 4 be followed by a materially increased blackhead morbidity among the poults inhabiting this environment? For this purpose 50 fowls originating in coccidiosis Lot 9 and an identical number of birds taken from Lot 10 were transferred respectively to Lots 10 and 12 on November 28, 1935. On December 27, 1935, the birds in Lot 10 were removed to Lot 12 and the occupants of the latter to Lot 10. Similar transfers were made on January 15 and on February 15, 1936. In this connection it should be noted that in the course of the preceding years a number of the chicks inhabiting Lot 10 had developed blackhead and that poults maintained in Lot 12 had recently been involved in a marked blackhead morbidity. i On March 30, 1936, 26 fowls from Lot 10 and a similar number from Lot 12 were removed to Lot 1-3 and on the same day 19 fowls from </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases -. . . ". ' . ¦ ..' Lot 10 and 18 from Lot 12 were transferred to Lot 4. All these birds were removed from the lots on June 11, 1936. In the course of the experiment 40 of the fowls were either killed or ;had died from natural causes. Of these, nine could not be examined, hav - ing had their viscera removed by lot mates or predatory rodents. Of the 31 birds examined, 24 were found to be infested by cecal worms and in seven these parasites could not be found. The observations made in the course of the 1936 experiments are presented in Table 32. ML. _C—L. . ttJ___i__jait."-'_'_L -ii- b __________—__! En_l ___P if__l ______________ ___d_____fl_ ____L Kl vl B_S_P__r^^__^S_Si_v ¦m'-^z^T'^y-':- "_.'_.' r__&lt;_ '-¦'iWS&amp;sS&amp;2jSSSm F:o. 13.—Turkeys in Lot •)—October 25, 1934. One is tempted to conclude that the two cases of blackhead which occurred among the poults occupying Lot 1-3 and the increase of the blackhead morbidity rate in Lot 4 from 10 per cent in 1935 to 15 per cent in 1936 must be attributed to the Heterakis factor. IE such conclusion could be sustained, it would indicate that chicken contact in a most sanitary environment may even there constitute a blackhead hazard although prob - ably only a minor one. The relative blackhead morbidity rates incurred by all lots during the period 1929-36 are summarized in Table 33. The results accumulated from experiments during this period conclusively revealed the effectiveness of the prophylactic measures against blackhead. The 977 poults exposed in Lot 3 (1-3) sustained a blackhead morbidity of 23 birds (2.35 per cent) whereas in the 871 in the insalubrious Lot 4, blackhead developed in 357 poults (40.98 per cent). Roughly expressed the poults maintained without sanitary protection were liable to a blackhead morbidity rate 17.4 times greater than of turkeys kept under sanitary restrictions. ADDITIONAL OBSERVATIONS ON BLACKHEAD It was. deemed of interest to take advantage of lots vacated by common fowls which served in other experiments and to populate them with poults. </seg>
         <seg id="p050">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 The objective hoped for was to acquire additional light on the part played by common towls in the etiology of blackhead. The results of the first attempt in the course of 1934 are recorded in Table 24. The experiments were carried on in Lots 2 and 12. Lot 2 had been occupied by fowls from July 24, 1929, to April 4, 1932, and from May 7. 1932, to January 11, 1934. The lot had remained vacant since the last occupancy. Poults four weeks old were introduced into the lot on June 9, 1934, about five months after it had been vacated by the fowls. DAYS)m»]l»80|l.»l|l»»a|1»3»lt»&gt;»)1»»»)HM 70 SO f 1 __. M 30 _^""\ / 20 »/ 1_ / •m Itti o I I I I I I 1 I/ I Fit.. H.—The lime lapse between the exposure oi poults to blackhead at the ajje of four week., and tin- occurrence tit the first deaths from the disease in Lots 3, 1-3, and 4. Lot 12 was inhabited by common fowls from October 15, 1929, to February 17, 1931, from June 9, 1931, to April 4, 1932, and from May 20, 1932, to October 11, 1933. After that time fowls were occasionally, and for brief periods, kept in the lot. However, it was no longer possible to ascer - tain precisely when the last occupancy terminated. The interval between the last occupancy by fowls and that of the poults could not have extended over more than six weeks. The data shown by Table 29 make it quite clear that poults inhabiting cither one of the two lots succumbed to black - head in very large numbers. In the course of 1935 the observations concerned with the blackhead morbidity in lots previously inhabited by fowls and maintained without </seg>
         <seg id="p051">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases sanitary restrictions were continued. The experimental results are recorded by means of Table 31. It will be observed that in addition to Lots 2 and 12, another lot, No. 8, was also utilized.. This lot had remained vacant for a period of two years after the last fowl had been removed from it. Although it is apparent from Table 31 that a blackhead hazard still existed in Lot 8, the incidence of the disease was much lower than among the poults" which occupied Lots 2 and 12. It seems reasonable to assume that in the course of the long interval between occupancies, a quantitative or qualitative reduction of the etiologic factors had come about. - \. '• _____ ;;.--:" pro | 1 I I I I I 1 CENT. "2* &#132;so '•" '»« '»« «»3* IMB. 1»36 ;;-. »o ; ___ ___ -¦' ______ . ¦ " 80 i^--11-_ -ZZ ZlJj. __£____ \ ;¦¦,.¦¦: ¦ 2 \ BO \ _________ _________ A, _____ \ \ :::-.':-^-—-—————^-—¦=':-. o I 11 Fig. 15.-^-The decline of blackhead morbidity among poults inhabiting enclosures with - out sanitary restrictions for periods of approximately five months during eight con - secutive years—Lots 2, 4, and 12. ,', Note was taken of the general behavior manifested by mortality, espe - cially in connection with the poult populations of Lots 3, 1-3, and 4. With reference to the first deaths from blackhead in.poults exposed to environ - mental contacts at the age of four weeks, it was observed that the deaths occurring in the sanitary lot always lagged some days behind those found </seg>
         <seg id="p052">AcRictLTi'RAL Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 to take place in the less salubrious environment. The phenomenon suggests that in the last-named environment the abundance of infective material enabled the birds to gain access to it almost as soon as they were admitted to the lot. whereas in the cleaner area, they, as it were, had to hunt for it. As graphically presented by Figure 14, it appears that the time elapsing between the potential first contacts and the occurrence of the first deaths was subject to more irregularity in the sanitary lot than in the other one. In the latter the Hrst deaths occurred after more uniform periods even if the morbidity rate declined progressively in Lot 4 during the eight years of the investigation. This decline is depicted by means of the graphs in Figure 15. It appears that after the second year of occupancy of Lot 4 the blackhead morbidity rather rapidly declined down to the time when Heterakis-infested fowls were caused to inhabit the lots. The data thus submitted indicate that in an environment exclusively occupied by poults during approximately six months of each year and which remained vacant in the course of the in - terims, the blackhead ha/.ard is gradually reduced. Apparently the volume and infective properties of originally infective material was slowly being exhausted, cither by a process of biologic purification, by subsidence into the deeper soil layers, by the influence of age, or possibly by the potential blackhead victims themselves. These observations may also permit the deduction that under the con - ditions which prevailed in the experimental lots, turkeys per se do not serve the propagation of the etiologic factors. They emphasize the importance of the recognized practice of maintaining a turkey flock only in an environ - ment not inhabited by common fowls. After all, the latter constitute the principal source of blackhead infection. What took place in Lot 8 (Table 31) indicates that the common fowls may even leave a blackhead hazard behind for a considerable period after their elimination. The age group distribution of deaths from blackhead in poults exposed at the age of four weeks is graphically exhibited by means of Table 34. </seg>
         <seg id="p053">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases TABLE 28 i BLACKHEAD EXPERIMENTS!, LOTS NOS.J AND 4-IS2I AND IMO. " '' I ' '"* 11 &#132;1° " OBSERVATIONS. DATES I IOT I tOT „»» I LOT I «-0T DIf TES- H0... N0.4. PMESNO.I. N0.4. EXPOSURE FOULTS _.__ .__, ,„, «.« ... ... PLACED IN LOTS. CIS 102 ___ ____ ISI '•' CASES OP BLACKHEAD '.in . « &#132; « I , I ,_, OCCURRINQINLOTS. J ( 'j " \ " \. T \'" EXPOSURE POULTS DEAD I K I '( . I £' I _,_ I _, -¦¦;.¦. PRO- OTHER CAUSES. |. *' .¦¦ * g 40 .¦ • HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD. M.C S» ~\l 11.2 "ToT "7b~ TABLE 26 BLACKHEAO EXPERIMENTS. LOTS NOS.»AND«-I__IANP)»32. ~ ) )»»&lt; 11 i»»a | OBSERVATIONS. _i LOT I LOT „._.. I LOT I LOT REMARKS. _____ PATE&amp; NO.j. H0.4. D*TtS-N0.».|n0.4.. EXPOSURE POULTS I ,2, 50 ... -. „ so ,to PLACED IN LOTS. ** so l_» «-" SO 170 ===———————=————=——} j ___________L_________________J' I I OC : , POULTS TRANSFERRED - 0 F I .- I £* PROM LOT H0.4. _¦¦'-'¦ •"° ¦ ..— *°. — &#132; 5 _ .. —=!——= X o poults Transferred «__ _&gt;» So TO LOT NO. I. 4 I _| *~ I I _] — „J ¦ CASES OF BLACKHEAD I H ¦ I . | J _ I JJ &lt; OCCURRING IN LOTS. g ,0 " O * »» " £ H K -. *¦¦: =4 •_» EXPOSUREPOULTSDEAD 21 IS IO so + FROM OTHER CAUSES. ) al ,'". | IO *° '.. T HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD. H.tC 7* TT] 11.11 "JT "eT" TABLE 27 I _^_,____ ' BLACKHEAD EXPERIMENTS. LOTS NOS.3ANP4-H33. OBSERVATIONS. DATES. „^ ."^REMARKS. EXPOSURE POULTS I «.I7 I II PLACED IN LOTS. f C.l* "° 70 ¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦' txpflSUK poIIlVs i I TRANSFERRED __ CO ¦-___, ~ &lt; FROM LOT M0.3. j» j 5? EXPOSURE POULTS . I !_. a TRANSFERRED . •» _ CO S a TOLOTNO.4. «_" i - U : —=——_—_ . J , _____ ______ H J CASES OF BLACKHEAD O . . S3 OCCURRINQINLOTS. [ H * ,0 ™{_ EXPOSURE POULTSDEADI ' ;. _¦""•' A,* FROM OTHER CAUSES. 1 • « ~ HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD. U..S tat »4 </seg>
         <seg id="p054">54 Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 TABLE 28 BLACKHEAD EXPERIMENTS. LOTS NOS. 1.3 AND4- 1»34. OBSERVATIONS. DATES. H "T. N g°J REMARKS ExposußE poutTS * PLACED IK LOTS. |*_ ( '35 || '00 „ &lt; POULTS FED WITH I ( I ~ 25. BLACKHEAD MATERIAL 6.16 14 IO K ___ PLACED IN LOTS, j. | X g CASES OF BLACKHEAD . *"- OCCURRING IN LOTS. J ° 2* _ t- EXPOSURE POULTS DEAD g ° FROM OTHER CAUSES. »¦ * * . HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD. 11.8 140 ) 81 TABLE 29 BLACKHEAD EXPERIMENTS. LOTS NOS_ AMD 12-1834. OBSERVATIONS. DATES. LOT LOT N0.2.N0.12, EXPOSURE POULTS «_» 100 _ ___________OTS___r__rJ__" ___ CASES OF BLACKHEAD I ui _._ -- OCCURRING IN LOTS. | _{ ____ EXPOSURE POULTSDEAD _ I , I _ FROM OTHER CAUSES. f | HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD. 11.8 Tj ™ TABLE 30 BLACKHEAD EXPERIMENTS. LOTS NOS.I-3 AND4-1935. OBSERVATIONS. OATES. M o°J,jL_][ REMARKS. EXPOSURE POULTS ' " PLACED IH LOTS. | g-17 \ lo* | B0 BLACKHEAD OCCURRING | TOT . LC ' I ' . AMONG ORIGINAL POULTS. IUT&gt;L!,-| °!_" POULTS TRANSFERRED I I ~ I &lt; FROM LOT NO. 2. B ___ 'I ~ 5 BLACKHEAD OCCURRING 1 |j 2 IN POULTS TRANSFERRED TOTAL. 5 _ S FROM LOT NO. 2. | | ( -J POULTS TRANSFERRED [ 1 || 5 FROM LOT N0.12. B *'" " — H . — BLACKHEAD OCCURRING I ' ? _ IN POULTS TRANSFERRED TOTAL. 6 j. _ ° FROMLOTNO.It. I | j, £ ~POULTS TRANSFERRED I , . | &#132; [( *_ FROM LOTHO.B. ¦ | ' m9 )" j ~ . BLACKHEAD OCCURRING I I . ~ u IN POULTS TRANSFERRED TOTAL. I _ u&gt; FROM LOT NO.B- | | | I EXPOSURE POULTS DEAD ! TnT ..- I &#132; || , " FROM OTHER CAUSES. | TOT"'-| " | * HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD. lI.IT 191 |TO </seg>
         <seg id="p055">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases [ABLE 31 BLACKHEAD EXPERtMEH.TS.LOTS MOS.2.S AHBtl-IBSS. OBSERVATIONS. DATES. LOT LOT tOT .¦¦¦-.-¦¦¦¦¦¦•.¦ M0.2. HO.B. H0.12. EXPOSURE POULTS ,_ ,_ , PLACEDINLOTS. ""* "7 |", "* EXPOSURE POULTS _______L_ - TRANSFERRED 7.1 ~~M TO LOT MO. 1.3. Q.2T ~ P~~ ~j~~ CASES OF BLACKHEAD _ &#132; .. __ OCCURRINQINLOTS. 1 &lt; | ¦ | f__ | ___ EXPOSURE POULTS OEAD O I Hi I FROM OTHERCAUSES.] .*":" 2I |17 l0 HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD. II.S 3» «l 34 TABLE 32 BLACKHEAD EXPERIMENTS.LOTS NOS.I.3AND4-IMB. OBSERVATIONS DATES tOT LOT REMARKS ; -- ¦ I .|n0.i.3.||n0.4.| HETERAKISINFESTED FOWLS . 3.30 52 37 2 PLACED IN LOTS.:? | . ) \\ . : 5. . HETERAKIS INFESTED I ¦ ll 2 FOWLS ¦¦¦:.: 6.11 IB 30 . REMOVED FROM LOTS. 9 | ¦-*'. EXPOSURE POULTS "ll"""^ _. PLACED IN LOTS. *•'¦ '»&gt; I «00 a CASES OF BLACKHEAD .-.'.- Z\ 8 OCCURRING IN LOTS. j * ,5 &gt; ¦ .5 J _ EXPOSURE POULTS DEAD o ™ FROM OTHER CAUSES. •""':.'• ' ¦ ui -.__¦., ...;_.._ ..__.-¦ I ,______—{ _ "' HEALTHY TURKEYS SOLD: ll.» | 123 (E4 £ </seg>
         <seg id="p056">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 TABLE 33 BLACKHEAO EXPERIMENTS-!«» _I9 J*. THE RELATIVE BLACKHEAD MORBIDITY RATES IN ALL LOTS. . LOT YEARS. NOS. m9 I&gt;Bo |£3| |9|2 1933 jM4 IBM IMB 3 5.98 4.C3 *».Q» *&gt;3.ti3 1.53 _ _ _ 1.3 — _? 0 1.53 4 90.19 94.10 33.33 ___ 23.07 23.E3 10.00 18.00 2 — — — — — EE.OO _jt__ — 8 _-__¦_ — V».71 _ 12 _ _ _ _ _ 91.49 ___7 2E.47 A . INCLUDING 4 POULTS TRANSFERRED FROM LOT N0.4. A . EXCLUSIVELY POULTS TRANSFERRED FROM LOTNO.4. V . INCLUDING S POULTS i ¥ . INCLUDING I POULT ( TRANSFERRED TO LOT N0.1.3. Y . INCLUDING 6POULTS,/ TABLE 34 TMIAdOOUF DIST«I1UTIO« OHIO OIATMSKOIUIAeKMIADAIIOM POULT* MFOMD AT THI Atl Of fOUIIirHICSIIIMOIIIO«HS»COIITAmilATlBIII»IIIOIIIHIITt.-irWIH[l. |TH &lt;TH 7 TM| t TM "^TH | O TH M TM uTM |»TH 14TM ||T»I|«TH [T TH |»TM It TM tpTll I( tT tJ O I|P »4TII M™ J — — -J— —— — — &amp; IB (ji) ——^^t— ——-— == A- = — ===== ——- </seg>
         <seg id="p057">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases MISCELLANEOUS OBSERVATIONS ABSENCE OF DISEASE TRANSMISSION BETWEEN ADJOINING LOTS As already stated the experimental lots were so arranged that the ones maintained under sanitary restrictions did not adjoin the less salubrious ones. .... The lots occupied by each group of fowls were separated from one an - other by ordinary wire netting. This seems to be a rather questionable barrier against disease transmission. Yet, in spite of the fact that during the warm season flies were numerous within the experimental enclosures and that small, flying birds occasionally managed to squeeze through the meshes, no evidence was encountered to show that the common chicken wire was not an effective barrier. The only instance in which a disease apparently escaped from the en - closure in which it belonged could be attributed entirely to faulty judg - ment. After an outbreak of fowl cholera had terminated in its proper environment it was deemed expedient to make use of the. surviving birds to recruit the populations of lots in which another disease was under observa - tion. As a measure of safety, these, birds were removed to a. clean stable on October 10, 1930, and kept there until October 28 of the same year. Dur - ing the eighteen days of isolation all of these birds remained in good health and it appeared to be quite safe to make use of them as intended. All went well until November 25, 1930, when one of the transferred fowls died of cholera. More cases developed and between the date men - tioned and January 17, 1931, when the lots were evacuated, 19 birds had succumbed to the malady. Nine of these were transferred fowls, eight be - longed to the original inhabitants of the lot, and the remaining two had lost their leg bands and could no longer be identified. It was not until sometime later that the cause of the outbreak, latent infection, could be successfully demonstrated. : GRAVEL FOR POULTRY YARD SURFACING Although it was recognized that the covering of poultry yards with a thick layer of coarse gravel cannot find a wide application in poultry hus - bandry, there were reasons to believe that its use might materially con - tribute to the salubrity of a given environment. Z ¦']¦¦¦ This proved to be true in the case of certain diseases of which the etiologic factors are rather fragile, when not protected by a suitable ambient medium. In the experiments related above, this was apparently the case with fowl typhus and blackhead of turkeys, against which the gravel in the lots provided a marked degree of protection. On the other hand, in the case of such disorders as tuberculosis and coccidiosis of which the causative organisms are quite resistant to external influences, the graveled surfaces apparently afforded no protection at all. It may also be of interest to make mention of the fact that on some of the hottest days of summer the surface temperature of the gravel was </seg>
         <seg id="p058">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 118 about 16 degrees (F.) higher than on the surfaces of the corresponding lots. It seems even possible that on some days the temperature of the graveled surface may have attained a height lethal to some of the more delicate microbic causes of disease. HARDWARE-CLOTH PANELS IN POULTRY SANITATION The use of hardware-cloth panels proved to be an important factor in the prevention of fecal contacts and for the protection of young chicks and poults it has a definite place in poultry hygiene. The metal panels having a one-inch mesh were successfully used in brooder rooms for chicks and poults after they had attained the age of two weeks. Only occasionally did it happen that very small chicks managed to pass through meshes. On the other hand, the metal covering as used in the experiments appeared to he less suitable for continuously occupied areas in any latitude where winter weather has to be reckoned with. In the course of a rather mild winter it developed that common fowls kept in a wire-covered lot suffered from frozen feet, whereas the inhabitants of the corresponding dirt lots were entirely exempt from this type of injury. The hardware-cloth panels used proved to be durable and with reason - able care they should remain intact for several years. GENERAL CONCLUSIONS 1. An experimental attempt to determine whether or not healthy, non - reacting fowls exposed to others affected with bacillary white diarrhea would acquire positive blood titers by environmental contact, yielded neg - ative results. 2. The sanitary restrictions adopted afforded a manifestly favorable in - fluence on morbidity in the face of a fowl typhus hazard present in an environment occupied by the flocks concerned. 3. Although some evidence of the environmental transmission of fowl cholera was encountered it appears that the character of a given environ - ment exercises no manifest influence. The benefits of sanitary restrictions ;ue apparently canceled by the intensity and virulence of direct-contact in - lection. 4. In the transmission and dissemination of fowl cholera, apparently healthy birds, as infection carriers, play a dominant part. 5. A given environment may be either reasonably sanitary or the very opposite without greatly modifying the incidence of avian tuberculosis after tuberculous fowls have been introduced. 6. Healthy, older fowls showed a rather well marked resistance to avian tuberculosis when exposed by direct and indirect contacts in an environ - ment in which the opportunities for doing so were ample. 7. In the evaluation of sanitary measures in connection with coccidiosis of chicks, mortality alone cannot be accepted as a final criterion. </seg>
         <seg id="p059">Influence of Environment on Poultry Diseases 8. The determination of coccidial infestation proved to be a more de - pendable criterion by which to judge the sanitary fitness of a given environ - ment. 9. By the use of hardware-cloth panels combined with adequate pro - tection of the food and water supply against fecal contamination it was possible to reduce the incidence of coccidiosis to a bearable minimum. 10. Turkey poults were raised to maturity with a minimum blackhead hazard when maintained in an environment covered by coarse gravel, when food and water were provided in sanitary utensils and when contacts with common fowls were avoided. 11. Turkey poults may be raised to maturity in a restricted area covered by hardware-cloth panels without a blackhead risk even after the poults affected with the disease are introduced among them. -. 12. Poults maintained under a rather intense exposure to blackhead from one to four weeks may, to a considerable extent, find sanctuary when transferred to an environment where sanitary restrictions prevail. 13. The common fowl and its body wastes must be regarded as the fountain-head of blackhead infection. The blackhead hazard was still present in soil two years after common fowls were removed from the lot concerned. 14. In an insalubrious environment, exclusively occupied by turkeys dur - ing six months of each year, blackhead morbidity progressively declined in the course of seven years, until a temporary occupancy by fowls of the lot concerned caused morbidity to exhibit an upward trend. ¦.": . , [4M. ¦ </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>