<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00051.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00051.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Third Biennial Report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings and of the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds to the Governor of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1922-07-01">1922-07-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWENTY-THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Commissioner OF Public Lands and Buildings AND OF THB Secretary OF THE Board of Educational Lands and Funds TO THE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA JULY 1, 1922 By DAN SWANSON Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings and Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. 1922 THE BEACON PRESS LINCOLN, NEBR </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">STATE OFFICERS 1921-22. Samuel R. McKelvie P. A. Barrows Governor Lieutenant Governor D. M. Amsberry ... D. B. Cropsey George W. Marsh Clarence A. Davis Dan Swanson Secretary of State Treasurer ..Auditor Attorney General Land Commissioner John M. Matzen. ... Thome A. Browne H. G. Taylor ...State Superintendent Railway Commissioner Railway Commissioner Railway Commissioner Harry L. Cook STATI OFFICERS 1923-24 Charles W. Bryan Fred G. Johnson Charles W. Pool Charles D. Robinson George W. Marsh Governor Lieutenant Governor ...Secretary of State Treasurer Auditor O. S. Spillman Dan Swanson John M. Matzen H. G. Taylor Thorne A. Browne.. Charles A. Randall Attorney General Land Commissioner State Superintendent Railway Commissioner Railway Commissioner Railway Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p004">COMMISSIONERS OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS OF NEBRASKA F. M. Davis 1877-1880 A. G. Kendall 1881-1884 Joseph Scott 1885-1888 John Steen _ 1889-1890 A. R. Humphrey 1891-1894 H. C. Russell _ 1895-1896 J. V. Wolfe 1897-1900 George D. Pollmer 1901-1904 H. M. Eaton 1905-1908 E. B. Cowles 1909-1912 Fred Beckmann 1913-1916 G. L. Shumway _ 1917-1918 Dan Swanson 1919-1924 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">COMMISSIONER'S OFFICE, 1921-22 Dan Swanson Commissioner G. E. Emery _ Deputy Commissioner T. A. Boyd _....Chief Clerk Bert R. Anderson - .Bookkeeper Fred Royse Recorder and Delinquent Clerk Cecille M. Hanna Stenographer DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING. Robert Harvey, St. Paul _ State Surveyor E. B. Corning. Loup City _ _ Deputy E. C. Simmons, Pender Deputy B. W. Benson, Central City...._ „ Deputy W. S. Scott, Lincoln _ Deputy Forrest Coon. Gordon „ Deputy </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. Lincoln, Neb., July 1, 1922. To His Excellency, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor: Sir: In compliance with the constitutional requirement, I have the honor to submit the following report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, who is also the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, for the biennium beginning December 1, 1920, and ending June 30, 1922. IMPROVEMENTS During the past one and one-half years the following improvements were made: Outside repairs on the Governor's Mansion, a complete new roof, new siding, new gutters, etc., and two coats of paint. ESCHEAT LANDS During the present administration the State became the owner of the following escheat lands and lots: North Half of the Northeast Quarter i.V'i XE 1 ,,) and the North Half of the Northwest Quarter (N% NW4). Section 18, Township 17. Range 19. West of the 6th P. M., Custer County. East Half of the Southwest Quarter (EVfe SWil, Section 2, Town - ship 10. Range 19. West of the 6th P. M., Dawson County. Lot Nine (9) in Block Five (5), in College Addition to West Lawn, in the City of Grand Island, Nebraska. The above lands are under lease, and the lot was sold for $360.00, a: provided by Section 5215, Compiled Statutes, 1922. There was paid into the State Treasurer's office S140.38. from the estate (escheat) of Charles S. Black, deceased. INVENTORY OF PERSONAL PROPERTY The inventory of all furniture and fixtures belonging to the State located in the State Capitol and Governor's Mansion prepared during the last administration is complete to date, showing all property and the location of same. SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR FUND The Board of Educational Lands and Funds has paid compensation laims approved by the officers of the Spanish-American War Veterans: To July 1, 1922 _ | 5,570.70 Balance in bank 4,429.30 ToUl _ $10,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Accumulated interest to July 1, 1922, amounts to $222.80. leaving balance on hand of $4,652.10. SOLDIERS', SAILORS, ETC., RELIEF FUND bOut of the appropriation of $50,000.00 for the relief of ex-service men. •e has been paid to the finance officer of the American Legion 000.00, leaving a balance on hand of $25,000.00. The Board of Educational Lands and Funds has asked that $25,000.00 be included in the budget for appropriation by the next Legislature for the Soldiers' Relief Fund. t During the biennium the Board of Educational Lands and Funds has rchased bonds to the amount of $256,091.84, and the balance of the ,950,000.00 will be invested during this fiscal year. MINERAL LEASES During the biennium sixty-eight mineral leases have been issued. covering 40,747.51 acres of land located in the counties of Blaine, Box Butte. Cherry, Dawes. Franklin. Frontier, Garden, Logan, Rock, Sheri - dan and Sioux. REVIEW OF APPRAISEMENT The constitutional amendment which provides that no lands now owned or hereafter acquired by the State for educational purpotes shall be sold except at public auction became effective January 1. 1921. and the only lands sold since the last report was during the month of December, 1920, at which time applications for the purchase of 5.240 acres were approved, and appraisement as returned by the rounty com - missioners was increased $8,760.00. ISOLATED TRACTS The present law provides that a list of all isolated tracts of school lands containing less than forty acres, and all city lots held by the State, be prepared and the lands and lots appraised by the Land Com - missioner or by a representative appointed for the purpose, and upon expiration of the leases and where the lease title has been forfeited, sell the same at public auction to the highest bidder. A complete list of all such lands and lots has been prepared and several small tracts have been sold. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REAPPRAISEMENT OF LEASED LANDS 9 REAPPRAISEMENT OF LEASED LANDS During the biennium the lands under lease in three counties have been reappraised and the new valuation approved by the Board of Edu - cational Lands and Funds. This increases the yearly income of the state $27,173.67, and this increase is for the benefit of the educational funds and helps every school district in the state. The appended table shows the counties thus affected. COUNTY Old Value New Value Increase Yearly Increased Rental Cheyenne $ 74,960.00 $335,790.00 Deuel 27,699.91 113,893.60 Kimball 30,496.88 136,357.70 $260,840.00 $15,650.41 86,193.69 5,171.6: 105,860.82 1 6,351.61 Total ! $133,146.79 ! $586,041.30 $452,894.51 $27,173.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">* :port LAND COMMISSIONE1 :'S Rj §*■«"« oo s&gt; •♦ a&gt; t- o x •• S » at » « n_ r-_ us ss_ t- » § rtHllJio" t^ n &lt;O Si ■ X I — x c; ri x » mooc f; »N««X t-;t-OO «o V t-^ to ■» us ae » us e us s m e m « r?xxe -^ « *£ ri n x n n to us t-; 00 00 a&gt; M- oo •«■«• »Me • us t-;»aori» m — s • O r- si » T » m m o ' n t- u: » m » — «• z ri t- r i a ' ■ ■ : 1S n til m a." o « o o o eiooe »i us u: o c o us r-^ o e •-• t- I— o i-* O r- r? M o 00 ffCOO^Ot^US 0C-»?C© NM &gt;« US s id OS # A i- 00 ■ I IS 32 fl; &lt;e us » e t&gt;. x r~ © ■ us s «4 • «' © x o: © ' *- * — ui te — a-, -x e ■ n A x w h- «u;o ; ** ?c V ©* 1 •» 1 • .... i jijjiliiii ■ . S ■ . w . . . . i S : S. - : o : : : : ii'.i! : \ 2 ; ; : i His t iilil 4 :J *• : : f : : : : i §1 if : :1 : : : : « ■•3- 8 • ■ • • J e • b 2 "o -ajx^ : : c - ■ a S at c ■ £ ■- ~ . . I liltfl r ; I 11*1 i-ll ill* J 8 I * </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 RECEIPTS FOR THE BIENNIUM 11 RECEIPTS OF THE DEPARTMENT FOR THE BIENNIUM Rentals on lease contracts $566,755.15 Interest on sale contracts 225,089.04 Minus and added interest 17,434.86 Principal on sale contracts 99,580.73 Fees, December 1, 1920, to June 30. 1922 6,030.46 Total $914,890.24 TABLE SHOWING FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS, JUNE 30 1922 Total Total Total Total Acres Acres Un- Acres Acres Under Sale Lease classi- Acquired Deeded Contract Contract fled Total COUNTY Acres Adams 20,480. 18,600. 20,480. 18,600. 1,080. 800 Antelope 31,400. 18,120. 2,720. 10,560 1,600. 1,400 200. | (Univ.) Arthur 25.720. 25,720 25,720 Banner 26.880. 320. 1,280. 25,280 Maine 25,530.45 160. 880. 24,490.45 Kcone 23.675.28 19,463.50 1,477.53 2,715.77 18.48 Box Butt.-. 40,960. 762. 160. 40,038 Boyd 22,652.72 5,543.22 22,652.72 5,543.22 6,618.43 10,491.07 Brown 40,998.90 556.40 40,998.90 556.40 477. 39,965.50 Buffalo 30,813.29 22,547.32 30.813.29 22,547.32 1,080. 7,178. &lt;0 12.27 Burl 17,487.88 16,667.88 440. 200. 180. 640. 640 I Agr. (oil.) Butler 21,687.10 21,161.90 526.20 19.733.98 19,513.98 120. 100. i ('ass C. dar 26,964.36 26,245.36 40. 67». 1.920. 1,560. 40. 320 I Univ. I (Art. Coll.) 25,405.47 23,837.56 760. 807.91 Chase 33.280.00 1,585.48 33,280.00 1,585.48 1,080. 30.614.52 Cherry 245,169.21 2,741.23 10,536.06 231,891.92 (In yen n&lt; 43,840.00 853.00 42,987.00 •lay 21.240.00 20,580. Colfax 14.459.69 14.158.: 21.240.00 20.580. 240. 420 240. 420. ! 14.459.63 14.158.26 187. 114 43 Cumin* 19.044.70 18,964.70 19.044.70 18,964.70 40. 40 (Agr. Coll.) 960. 960 Custer 91.017 98 20,413. 21,758. 48.84C.98 • Dakota 7 163.19 5.768.81 65.50 818.05 510.83 (Univ.) 320. 320 (Agr. Col.) 640. 640. 603.92 36.08 Dawes 49.280. 892.43 49.280. 892.43 1.400. 46,987.57 Dawson 36.185.15 21.265. 36.185.15 21.265. 7.131.60 7,763.55 25 7.131.60 7,763.55 26. Deuel 16.800.70 • 1,031.22 16.800.70 • 1,031.22 1,038. 14,688.36 43 12 1,038. 14,688.36 43.12 Dixon 15,931.20 14,722.80 15,931.20 14,722.80 410. 744.40 64. 640. 640 i 2.240. 2,187.77 40. I .......... " 12.21 (Univ.) 640. 640. (Agr. Coll.) 4«. I 12 J3 Dodge 18,558.58 18,467.72 90.86 Douglas 9.160.23 8,918.69 40. ' 62. 13S.54 Dundy 33,257.01 777.99 240. 32,239.02 Fillmore 20,64(4.51 20.488.51 160. :&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Keya Paha 26,382.46 910.85 1.200. 24,271.61 Kimball 38.618.88 699.22 800. 35,095.54 24.12 Knox 42,893.81 25,350.62 5.067.66 12,475.53 | ( Univ.) ■ 4,480. 3,440. 200. 840. (Agr. Coll.). 33.491.20 28,921.47 4,170.73 399 Lancaster 31.236.84 29,863.16 Lancaster 31.236.84 29,863.16 607.21 764.45 2.02 (Saline) ... 32,789.44 30,775.22 1.331.16 673.64 9.42 607.21 764.45 2.02 (Saline) ... 32,789.44 30,775.22 (Normal) .. 12,804.80 12,724.80 1.331.16 673.64 9.42 (Normal) .. 12,804.80 12,724.80 80 Ml. Lincoln 97,892.89 15,150.49 Lincoln 97,892.89 15,150.49 10,431.31 72,210.89 100.20 10,431.31 72,210.89 100.20 Logan 20,480. 614.89 2,505.11 17,360 Logan 20,480. 614.89 2,505.11 17,360. 818.30 18,644.33 840. 30,252.63 Loup 20,393.28 930.65 Loop 20,393.28 930.65 818.30 18,644.33 McPherson . . . 31,092.63 840. 30,252.63 McPherson . . . 31,092.63 Madison 24,(39.43 22,119.4:! Madison 24.C39.43 22,119.43 320. 2.200 320. 2,200 (UntY.) i 2.240. 1.600. 480. 160 (Univ.) .... 2,240. 1.600. 480. 160 Merrick 14,976.21 11,846.62 Merrick 14,976.21 11,846.62 520. 2.609.59 520. 2.609.59 Monill 62 677.58 4.665.46 13,027.90 44.981.16 :i.«6 Morrill ] «2 677.58 4.665.46 13,027.90 44.981.16 :i.«6 Nemaha I 11,942.34 11.565.99 Nemaha 11.942.34 11,565.99 290.55 85.80 290.55 85.80 Nuckolls 21,049.10 20.089.10 Nuckolls 21,049.10 20.089.10 520. 440 520. 440 (UniT.) 4.881.68 3,741.16 1,023.42 117.10 (Unir.) .... 4.881.68 3,741.16 1,023.42 117.10 Otoe 21,992.44 21,452.44 280. 260 Otoe 21,992.44 21,452.44 280. 260 Pawnee I 20.034.85 19,754.85 200. 80 Perkins 31,523.75 65.13 160. 31,298.62 Phelps 20.228.60 16,788.60 1,800. 1,640 Pterce 20,480. 13,800. 1,200. 5,480 (Unir.) 3,197.67 2.798.31 i 399.36 i I. NG FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE LAND8, JUNE 30, 1922— (Continued) ATI Total Acres Acquired Total Acres Deeded Total Acres Under Sale Contract Total Acres Lease Contract Un- i classi- fied COUNTY Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage Garden Garfleld Gosper Grant Greeley Hall Hamilton m:i (Unlv.) .... Hooker Howard Jefferson Johnson Kfa'ney Keith 20,471.85 34,660. 25.602.80 24,637.31 63,826.61 20,480. 16,640. 30,845.68 20,475.30 19,507.71 20,487.56 20,400 69 25,920. 25,494.87 87,536.60 8.322.10 28,127.53 23,041.44 20,484.08 13,440. • 18,581.40 45,662.90 10,331.73 7,678.50 11,212.42 24,422.81 1.981.43 1,281.58 11,522. 3.805.68 12,035.30 16,808.25 20,460. 12,779.86 9i3.31 1,729.22 7,852.02 ; 2.SS0. 15,733. 17,887.93 13.076.67 14,440. 2,357.10 3,573.76 5,080. 3,830.78 3,611.3» 720. 2,998. 911.41 2,440. 213.2E I 3,036.91 i 1,424.59 51. 6,9«0. 1,522.10 120. 2,161.89 1,667. 800. 5.018.64 6,566.36 21,798. 3.50 10.559.60 214.50 58.329.10 4.69 18,478.42 2,120 26,120. 8.54 6,000 2,486.21 7.6« 4.518.65 65.27 23,582.10 23,714.65 72,784.58 3 920 26,007.53 5,141.52 5.03 929.15 363.33 3,341.40 38,204.64 82.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS 13 TABLE SHOW'NG FACTS RELATIVE TO STATE EDUCATIONAL LANDS. JUNE 30. 1922— (Continued) Total Total Total Total Acres Acres In COUNTY Acres Acres Under Sale Lease class! Acquired Deeded Contract Contract fled (Art. Coll.). I 10.114.56 9,354.56 I 240. 520 Platte 23,655.48 22,5(6.38 1.08f .10 Polk 16,787.68 15.705.68 160. 922 Red Willow . . . ' 25,485.30 8,139.50 4,739. 12,606.80 Richardson ... 10.400.00 9,510.00 320. 570 Rock 40.232.40 2,280. 3,240. 34.712.44 ! Saline 20,480. 20,360 120.0» Sarpy I 8,988.27 8,624.39 79. 284.88 Saunders 26,314.29 25.994.29 280. 40. | Scotts Bluff... 25.467.65 6,553.72 9,493.37 9,414.56 6.00 QpuirH Mstn Mun in an Pf ward 20,560. 20,440. 40. 80. Sheridan 94.472.07 j 3.292.87 4,565. 86,614.20 Sherman 20.477.20 11,467.72 2.658.96 6.350.52 - Sioux 80.972.22 530.40 2.549.60 77.8*2.22 Stanton 15.M*. 13,960. 1,040. 360 Thayer 20,472.35 18,614.35 1,440. 418 Thomas 25.600. 9.30 ' 25.590.70 ' Valley 29,453.62 14.712.09 3.450.65 2,290.88 Washington . . 13 849.86 12.100.26 872.40 780.30 96.SK) Wayne 15.360. 15,000. 360. • ( Agr. Coll. ) . 15,648.98 1 15,638.64 I 10.34 WVbster ; 20,480. 17,993.87 2,040. 440. 6.13 (Univ.) 17,803.48 14.970.33 1.512.34 1 1.320.81 1 Wheeler ; 20,480. 923. 2.000. 17,557. j York ' 20,480. 19,526.61 80. 873.39 2.977.847.30 I 1,192.584.88 1 196.869.31 1.586,884.10 I 1,509.01 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 14 THE STATE'S SCHOOL FUND Tbe temporary school fund is derived from the following sources: Interest on permanent school funds, rentals on lands under lease, inter - est on balance due on lands sold, bonus received as premium to secure lease contracts, interest on delinquent rental and interest and n.oney received for licenses, fines, fees, etc. UThis temporary school fund is apportioned twice a year to the dif - it counties in tbe state for the support of the public schools. Tbe permanent school fund is derived from the sale of educational lands, escheated lands, and 5 per cent of the purchase price of govern - ment lands sold within the state. This fund is invested in interest - bearing bonds in amounts at present as follows: Appended to this report will be found tables showing he acquisi - tion and disposal of tbe educational lands of the state, and the work accomplished by this department for the one and one-half year period. I have also attached hereto the rules and regulations now governing the lease of educational lands which may be of interest to prospective lessees A table of the fees charged in this department is also shown. Very respectfully. Commissioner of Public Lands and Building." DAX BWANSON 'ommon school .. $ 9.869.083.24 'ermanent University 242.616.40 igricultural college endowment 599,756.38 • ormal endowment 79.460.00 lessey endowment 4,900.00 Soldiers relief 236.000.00 Total S11.031.S16.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">EDUCATIONAL LANDS— SUMMARY 15 X, ■ ■ ■I I g M 00 X 1- 5 ». •f © 5^ M — ac * r^ x jj 3i "' &gt;n V 3i -&lt;r -f r- «* M "■* r»- t- &gt; : • : : • k • : ■ . . &lt; : : : : : 5 2 • : : : : d : : : : : o : : : : : * j if : : -i • •= • : 1 1 :- : : o z . : : r so - • • isif.i Q = &gt; J: = = III S — — — t- ■ 4 I I I P« If X S f- * *z ~ *•* 7-, V. \ m ic m J ; .. . J • i i i 1 ;! I Illi 1 | 2 S I I 1 S ■I • f i i - — * i» * m s t- ri 3-. Mt-Ml»x (, N ICXNV I | Mi M lii i i! ; I jl i : : Ig : |l|si iij 1 I 2 : 0. •o s s ■* t o c ! 1 I ! M ■ £ /. :: * m s nhh«o »' u; » * c i' * o a *' « U5 31 ,-. 30 OO«XO r-iooso_ '". T ™ t-. » V M te »i *• u; »" ef »J Ijjjj HI N S :2 : ; ] :S : : W i It! i Si||| lizig j I OS &lt; £ 3 | | I I' i j I </seg>
            <seg id="p016">ii jiMiniqn*nni|:«;Mlj •&lt;* : : : : : : : : : : : : 2 : :::"■": Ii M M M Ms 8 i NNM Mi M N!i : ,T* • • • • * . . . . igl ; : |3 |3 :S : j j !|S j js j iSS jg !; I o z 5 7 8S88&amp;838.*"M :SnS5£SS2gS22 :SS NS»t-!!MIS»«!*OH ; w S M " 5M S « N C S S ' « S H us » 5iioeoi-'*»HH . w" iOrt&lt;eio*M«M • » " « » rt . N t_ . to •3a S :SS : : :8 :i§S§ :| :§gi :g : :gg :g : "•o'S™ . &lt;e « . . . • . © ia jo j- . M &gt;ex o t- to •« • r £ § : M :::":§ ■ : : N * »:•::•■ • • • '«&gt; S5*iO»t^N»NiO»tC&gt;4 -u!KSC*»KHHnH ■ ■§£ S D Z HI s 111 I I K O S^5 ; ! ■ M. ©©O 'OOMOnMHO • 'OOMOt^O -«;c ■ " -i ■tfuJS »»•» ■ » « n o n h rt S • .«Se«ne -SiiS -ooV CSS ©m 3»«i-f&lt;»H» rj'«'«-«i r .» ?3S3 r-S j* J ♦» . H»10NOi«MT . ;«00 NX* 'i)KN '5" c s c -h pj ■ -h" « « m" . . « t-r : ; j - 3 | . : : : : N -, . SSS??S2*2SSSS :SS888SSS8SS :2S r^^NQOb-otovavnao ; * 13 'i x » u: » t» k x n " ui ua • h n e«« 00 o 10 » * n :H»iot-»««io"- ' S3 a* &amp; % « of eJ ■» to s&gt;« r- © t- c-^ • »&lt; »« cc V n cc" • us |l!liii^'!ii&lt;i&gt;i^illtjl!ll </seg>
            <seg id="p017">|] Mp;M;;M;MMhMMMM5 &lt;* : : : :S : : : : :3 : : : :::::::::::: : ! ! : * : ! i • •• ■ : : S : ! i ! i ! i i i ! i i J J J J . I . •"* I II : : : 3 : : : : :5 : : :::::: : : •ill* :::::* !§SS : S : : : : : !SS \ \ •*••• • .••••■ I I - « US © © Oft ■ M N C K C ft Lt M # t- » H » * rt M H fl&gt; H ■ t- tc 6 «s «&gt; l^o^pinfiNH^dtotbobtCHflCftd^* 'OO^HIO MN3i i5XLttDXXNHOOu:CO«C"-'WN*a &gt;^nho ; «ia^ e*^^ec^©^«&gt;eou5»Ht^©^ *"1 *"! - -h" ?• ifl « • o" t^94CH*e*tt» miou) Vnh« I : : :3S :::::: :§§S ::::::: :8S :g ': : !S8 : : : : : : :SiS \ \ \ \ \ \ \ :S? : l . • , -" ti r: -" v4H ■ O III! . — imtich .» •Bt-M»NHnoi»*f&lt;»» nice* • » » T "°. 1 " n . ' T " * * *! T ". "? T * *! T "••*!*• ' h o uj ui « 'cd 'ennnvH *d»ooo»c&gt;u3 |t^d«o) t- &gt;a » » ' ! -• o iot-H &gt;• r- «- N « e» . io oo • ic M« I ; f-t 9)«i&lt; «FiH H .MHi^^ .u:£r-nS .en ■ t^ ♦ » oo m ■ o » » « » » ■ n r* fh ih :-?!« " :« Mrtia .■•■«■« oo • n .con * ; afafaj . • te«e« • w « m ■ eo ih «e Kl "3 £ a 3 . :S5SS : : :8S :SSSSSS!g§S22§§SS ■ ■ ri oo ai ai ' * ' ■*• o 'NNHiaNeot*iOQdoooioe9t&gt;H ■ &gt;o«s " ' 'xn 'ssoonoonoNNNA'HOO'HO • ' AeoiQ« ' ; .CO** ;oc^H^ot~t~_^HC*^ou5 hxich I '. si o" « m" • • • &gt;o ■ r-'rf V h •"«■«« io ♦ o&gt; oo" »h e« I </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 I] : ■ : : 2 : : : : : ■ ::::::::; * x : : :SSj=S* : : : : :§ :| ::::::::: ■ • ■ — • • • ' ' '■"'.'.'.'.'.'.I'.'. |3 ::::::: : : : : : :S : : : : : :5S : : : :::::: :*S ! : : : ! :£ \\\\\ \i% \ \ ■ ;;;;••• — &lt;^ X . . ; si I] : : : : : : : : ::*: :S :::::: g :: : j : : :• j : :| : jlj :g : ! : ! ! ;5S ! is I ?? S £ S S S S 5 j § S £ R S 3 3 a S S 3 S £ I § I? £ S " M M ri nil : : : j :§Sg§§ ::§§:§::::: :ggg :§ i SS*«3 i :»i :» : i : : : iSSS : i ss-sf MsisssiS3=^5a:2saif*3tssta S S t; S s: ?i G t 1 s •; 2 =■.■-»■- :••••• -a*"*-*^ i P* H M *i — — — _ Ill 1 1 1 2121 i**St8S.Sfta. :^S)CtStt8Z.St 331.3 :8Ssig3s::?; iS2S5g£2pSgS M 3 S g S S i S S S 5 5 SSJt52££;S:22S£?"S 8 iliilii&amp;isiililllfiiililiii </seg>
            <seg id="p019">WORK OP THE BIENNIUM ]f C J I ■1 II I] ijiiifiii &gt;r 1 1 1» j» 1 1» m 1 1 1 1« ij8 ;:; ;;;;;;;;;;■©■©■© I . ::::::::::::: :3 :5 |I : ! i i i i i \\\\ S : :5 : ;2* : : : : : : x " ils i is : ! 2 i I s | | | | S5SS5gS2SS§SSSSg|?SSS§SSg2S 3t9S Iff 10 oo w SS »« H .©.« c » « h © n* © « ? S § 2 ; o oo S « j£ ec" «" oi" rc^o" « &lt;-« to m* a* h V us 'c^cisqus Lq : :§ : :g : :gg : : :S!g :SSS :S~:7f : :$ :tt Is] i :S : : S : : §S : : : S3 : S3g : i : : S : :g : gg s • • °. : ■ • • • • **•*'- ■ * 5 - ■ ■ ■ • • " ! i ! t f *■] I o z 5 z HI I EX! I = - - S M © JO • O t-; » 1 N r-; t-; t- ; US ; ■♦ O M S » « IN a » O S A .hs«V •!S e " ( "lSli'' &lt; ** 0 '*''"* 1 '"? « » to -J us :»ia©» W , W5O ri ? 1 :i rt — -~ _* ; 00 • i* • a .^NiNNt-NiovenriSitS-aSiSI • S g 5 5 £ z i OOOO9O -O0COO -O0^-003C— *O© - 80 30 O • O » O A *o*xe» •O'^o* 'r-«»eSrnc^ -Haoo -SoSo » x — « t-^ o •«■■«« ■ •»■ » o ■«• ro t- •«• w t- ' § 3 Si • o o 10 « »« n o&gt; » » ; n ©_ » n ; ism skhni) ;xoh ;S«Ish ~* ~* -UN- ** CO tt "9 t* tt ' Q* CO -fH^"^ I I as j §-oo •©oowooso'^oi.teust-oooiaMo • .s»h« -hscoo ■ e « « » n k e « o « 9 w n k 7i s 3 k 7] . .« n a« ;©»o iVvNensNe'iSMe'a'TKa'tiDogiN ' a«u;a "»ho ,9i«ii!«N«ais »-&lt;»Nt-,t-qf;»N ' ; » M t- • » m © -rtHHt-'He ei ©" ic" ©" »» ,-T ri '■ '• w! oo » u. O j f iiiiWIiiiSiiliiiiiiiiiili, f ' </seg>
            <seg id="p020">RULES AND REGULATIONS PERTAINING TO THE LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS. LEASE CONTRACT8 {The Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings may at least once In each year designate a day and hour for offering in a public manner •t the office of the county treasurer in the respective counties, lease con tracts on all of the educational lands, which may be subject to lease in that county at the time of such offering. The same shall be subject to ■'■■ ■ •• * "f same ail an IHJ SUDjeCt tO tease at an annual rental of six (6) per cent on the appraised value •rovided. that if two or more parties desire to lease the same land, the officer having control of the auction shall lease to the person who will pay the greater amount of cash bonus in addition to six (6) per cent on the appraised value as annual rental. Lease rentals are due in two installments, January 1 and July 1 of each year. If not paid within six months after due. the lease holders are declared delinquent and notice is sent them if their postoffice addresses * known; if unknown, advertisement is made in a newspaper. Ninety days after date of su&lt;-h notice lease contracts are declared forfeited and are subject to auction thereafter. (See Fees.) Delinquent lease holders are not permitted to bid at the sale of the lands they have forfeited, but at any time before the land is actually put on the auction block they may reinstate their leases by paying all back rentals and penalty fees. (See Pees.) All school lands under lease are subject to appraisement at any time the Board of Educational Lands and Funds so elects. The holders of lease contracts executed subsequent to July 9. 1897. are given the right, at the expiration of said contracts, to apply for new contracts. If the bid of the lessee shall be equal to the amount bid by any other person, the lessees bid shall be accepted. (This means that f at the close of the auction the lessees bid is as much as the highest &lt;M«r his bid shall be accepted.) If the highest bid received shall be e by a person other than the lessee, the value of all the improve- I land shall be appraised by the county board, which shall * made within thirty (30) days after the acceptance of the bid and • being signed, shall, within five (5) days, be filed with the county »-... . - - ' ""»"• "^ ""» "'in me county www -of the county in which the land is situated. The lessee and suc - bldder shall share equally in the costs of the apnraisement. Either .SJ? the * ncceMfnI bldder nwy. » dissatisfied with the appraise - •t within thirty (JO) days after the filing thereof, appeal therefrom • District Conn. The successful bidder, if he be other than the tner lessee, shall, within th'rty (30) days after the filing of the ■••■■*■•■*. pay to the county treasurer, for the use of the former </seg>
            <seg id="p021">LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS M lessee, the amount of the appraisement. Buildings, fencing, wells, cis - terns, irrigation ditches, windmills, orchards and trees considered im- tThe holders of lease contracts executed prior to July 9, 1897, are n the right, at the expiration of said contracts, to make application and receive new lease contracts upon said lands, and they will not 'pquired to compete tor the contracts, and the rate of rental will be same as stipulated in the old contract; Provided, that all of the al due on the old contracts has been paid. »No lands now owned or hereafter acquired by the state for educa - il purposes can be sold except at public auction. (See page 290, s of Nebraska, 1919.) The last Legislature made no provision for sale of educational lands, except as follows: The law provides that the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings shall make a list of all isolated tracts of school lands containing less than forty (40) acres and all undivided interests in realty and all city lots held by the State of Nebraska in trust for the permanent school fund; appraise the came, and upon the expiration of the leases and where the lease title has been Kted. offer the same for sale at public auction. To be «old by the y treasurer of the county in which the lands are located, to the highest bidder for not less than ninety (90) per cent of the appraised value. The purchaser shall pay not less than twenty-five (25) per cent in cash on day of sale, end the balance to be secured by sale contracts running ten years at six (6) per cent annual interest; the purchaser hav - ing the right to pay all of the unpaid purchase money or any part of 't in multiples of five (5) per cent of the total purchase price at any interest payment date. In the event the purchaser or the assignee does ■ pay the annual interest upon the unpaid purchase price within six months after interest becomes due, the land shall revert to the state. All school land leases issued during the year 1897, on and after July "»th. will expire January 1. 1923. at which time the lands therein described will be advertised and leased at public auction at the office of the county treasurer in the respective counties. The amount of school land authorized to be leased, direct or by renewal, to one person is limited to 640 acres. SALE CONTRACTS tThe owner of a sale contract may, at any time, pay any portion of purchase price thereof to the treasurer of the county in which the is situated; Provided all interest at that time earned and due has been paid; and when the principal is paid in full, other than the of the year, interest upon the obligation having been paid for th° re year, the county treasurer receiving such principal payments may </seg>
            <seg id="p022">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT the payer, out of any interest money then in his hands, the •o paid in advance in excess of the amount earned and due time said final payment is made. Refund receipts are furnished Land Commissioner for this purpose. All unpaid principal on sale contracts draws interest at five (5) per cent per annum, payable annually on January first of each year, in ad- Sale contract holders making final payment to the county r should also surrender their contracts, that same may be for- to Land Commissioner with receipt showing the full payment. NOTES No assignment of a school land lease or sale contract is valid until Wded in the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build- lacs. and will not be recorded if any interest or rental is due at the time uid assignment is offered for record. The original sale or lease contract must be sent in with the assignment or the latter will not be The contract will be returned with the recorded assignments. When a subdivision of not less than forty acres in any contract is new number is given the assigned portion on the ledger ac- ' and a certified copy of the original should be given to the assignee made as above, the original contract must be t or rentals as the case may be is adjusted to becomes lost or destroyed, a eerti- nay be procured by filing an affidavit at lost con - be used in lieu of the original for the purpose of or rental on a lease contract is not ■8 will collect "penalty" interest at </seg>
            <seg id="p023">LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS TA If lessee shall be in default of rentals for six months, or if pur- Kser shall be in default of interest for one year, County Treasurer 11 collect delinquent notice fee as set forth in table of fees under beading of "For Notice of Forfeiture." FEE8 For the issuance of a lease or sale contract $0.50 For recording assignments, for each contract assigned M Tor recording affidavit of lost contract. .50 For certified copy of a contract .75 For recording any instrument, each 100 words _ 10 For notice of forfeiture of lease or sale contract .50 For reinstatement _ ,54 For recording order of forfeiture, where redemption is made before auction, for each tract of 40 acres or less 50 Where publication in newspaper is required in lieu of ordinary de - linquqent notice, the actual cost of such publication is charged where redemption is made. For copies of maps or plats, each hour's work _ .40 rOTE: Fees payable to the state should be remitted by draft or money order payable to State Treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">the Oam » Wmtm •*• ttttmtam tfc»t» *•*• h—m i«»iva4 from I ar^ OOTav at WmMwm. D. C. tk* foU»wta« rccarJ» o* FltUO MOTlt rwik ifur Miritm- tktwwii Tp. rs. s*. « u»d .» x MM* ITir"— Pamll-I »■ ■■—il t«. 17. IK. 1» »««i M W ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p025">ownship 24 N. Range 24 W. Township 21 N. Range 25 W. Township 22 N. Range 25 W. Township 23 N. Range 25 W. Township 24 N. Range 25 W. Township 18 N. Range 2« W. Township 19 N. Range 26 W. Township 20 N. Range 26 W. Township IS N". Range 2" W. lwnship 20 N. Range 27 W. iwnship IS N*. Range 28 W 19 X. Range 28 W X. Range 28 W p 18 JT. Range 29 W V. Range 29 W X Range 31 W nee 46 W u U ADC </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">6I&gt; Chi. C. I ■I ■ N I! N 281 Count v ( 262 M. F 2«3 St. Paul 2*4 State 265 Lacy V ?66 r R 2«7 A. B. Pei 2«S State of 2*!t John Bis 270 State of The law proviri rffectwl br the surv </seg>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030">55^ oO"* 3 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>