<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00016">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00016</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>SIXTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home MILFORD FOR THE Biennium Ending November 30, 1904 TO THE GOVERNOR</title>
			            <date value="1904">1904</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-28</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p003">
337 

THE FIFTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA 
BRANCH SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HUME, 

MILFORD, SEWARD COUNTY, NEBRASKA. 

Being for the biennial period ending November 30, 1904. 
To His Excellency, the Governor of Nebraska, and to the 
Honorable Board of Public Lands and Buildings : 

Bentlemen — I would most respectfully submit the followreport 
for the biennial period commencing December 1, 
!, to December 1, 1904 : 

We have improved the home materially in the last two 
years, having built a new hospital, which cost about $20,000, 
a new power house, with new boilers, engine, and dynamo; 
wired all the buildings, both new and old, for electric lights; 
erected a standpipe, with pump and mains complete, for 
water and fire protection. We expect to have everything complete 
by January 1, 1905. 

Eie new hospital building is well built and finished in all 
right up to date, and will accommodate about fif taints, 
and will be a great comfort to the sick and feeble 
bers, and will make room for fifty more members in the 
ral building. 

This will make more necessary expense, as there will be at 
least fifty more to care for. To rightly care for these fifty 
patients in the new hospital it will require very much more 
help, and this help must be competent to care for the sick and 
supply the needs and comforts necessary to the sick people. 

employes' wages 

Estimate for running the home from April 1, 1905, to 
March 31, 1907. 

K would respectfully ask to have for employes' wages 
&gt;0, which I hereby itemize, naming each employe and the 
int he will receive per month : </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
339 

Printing and stationery f 150 00 

For general repair 2,500 00 

Commandant's cottage, and furniture 3,000 00 

Deficiency for employes' wages for the month of 
March, 1903 142 00 

Deficiency of Ed Cerf &amp; Co., March, 1903 - "&lt;l 

The food supply during the past two years has been sati* 

factory in respect to quality and quantity and has given 

cral satisfaction as far as I can learn. The members of the 

home have been very kindly remembered at different times by 

the Woman's Relief Corps and Ladies of the G. A. K. with 

nice cakes, jellies, and fruits of all kinds, which we all appre- 

ciate with grateful hearts. The conduct of the men has been 

remarkably good, with few exceptions, and very little diffi- 

culty experienced in maintaining excellent discipline. Alco- 

holism is the most serious question we have to contend with, 

and is, without question, the source of nearly all the miscon- 

duct we have in the home, and too frequently the cause of un- 

pleasant stories concerning the home and its management 

Without it the members are kind and obliging to each other, 

obedient to the simple rules of the government, and happy in 

the enjoyment of the comforts the home affords. 

Amount of Balance 

Appropriation 1903-4. On Hand. 

Officers' salaries f 4,180 00 f 696 67 

Employes' wages 5,000 00 822 00 

Fuel and light 3,000 00 901 13 

Maintenance. 20,000 00 |7,552 74 

V. and E. board 800 00 124 87 

Furniture and bedding 1,000 00 546 34 

Burial 700 00 158 30 

Drugs and surgical instruments. 600 00 198 88 

T. T. E. and P 250 00 48 09 
Library 75 00 3&lt;&gt; 
Stock feed and farm 500 00 34 

Farm implements 315 00* </seg>


            <seg id="p006">
340 


General repairs ? 2,500 00 

Hospital 20,000 00 $3,683 00 

Power and light 13,500 00 78 1 29 

I desire to express at this time my profound appreciation 

Kie able, earnest and unfailing support given to me by 
and every officer of the home, I have not at this time 
ved the report of the visiting and examining board, but 

hope to before this goes to publication. 

T here enclose the report of Dr. G. W. Brandon, which I 

ask to be made a part of this report; also the amount appro- 

priated, and amount expended up to November 30, 1904. 

liespectfully submitted, 

Chas. Penn, 

Commandant. 

Number present and absent November 30, 1904 115 

Number present November 30, 1904 88 

Per capita for period f80 38 

PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. 
To the Honorable Commandant of the Soldiers' and Sailors' 

Home, Milford, Neb., Charles Penn : 

Sir — In accordance with the laws of Nebraska pertaining 
to the soldiers' and sailors' homes, I hereby submit a report 
of the department to which I am principally connected as 
physician and surgeon, concerning the time from December 
1. 1902, to the present date, December 1, 1004, during which 
time I have had complete control of srnid department, and I 
must say with very pleasant and satisfactory results. I have 
written and filled about the usual number of prescriptions 
during the time, until this summer, when the health (except 
chronic ailments) has been extremely good. The standpipe 
gives us an abundance of pure and palatable water, the drainage 
is excellent, provisions, etc., of exceptionally good quality, 
and served in a palatable and cleanly condition, leaving 
little ground for complaint on that score. And, when we get </seg>



            <seg id="p007">
341 

I sick removed to the hospital just erected, we will have lit¦lse 
to wish for. Surgery in the institution in the last two 
•s has been of a minor type, and several small operations 
tumors, varicose veins, etc. There are no acute cases at 
sent, and no epidemic of any nature whatever has visited 
n the past two years, except acute alcoholism just after 
sion days, and no fatalities- from that. We have been 
pelled to send one inmate to the insane hospital, but he 
• lived a few weeks after. Several of the inmates died 
le away on furloughs. 

THE DEATH LIST. 

B. S. Hubbvd, age 35, chronic diarrhoea, at Flavelock, Neb.. 
March 11, 1903. 

tl &lt; 'oleinan. age 72. heart disease, died at St. Joseph's Hospital, 
St. Joseph, Mo., November 12, 1903. 

tad IT. Cooley, age 86, old age, died at Holdrege, Neb.. 
December 21, 1903. 

tes S. Stone, age 74, died of paralysis at Omaha. Neb., 
February 28. 1904. 

riam Elders, age 71, died of paralysis, Elk City. N 
May 5, 1904. 

tea E. Keed, age 76, catarrh and asthma, died at Lincoln 
Neb., May 26, 1904. 

ri M. Pallick, cancer, age 59, died at Hospital for Insane 
at Lincoln, Neb., August 4, 1904. 

The other deaths occurred at the home. 

John S. Patten, 74, grip, April 8, 1903. 

John Dart, 80, old age, April 10, 1903. 

Hugh Martin, 73, heart failure, April 14, 1903. 

John Kennedy, 73, died suddenly, April 25, 1903. 

Martin B. Bevard, 62, kidney disease and dropsy, August 24, 
1903. 

John Bryan, 56, tuberculosis, September 13, 1903 

Horatio Wellington, 63, obstruction of bowels, October 7, 
1903. 

William S. Davenport, 64, locomotor ataxia, October 18, 1903. 

Mapes, 65, epilepsy. October 24, 1903. </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
342 


Biam Burkhardt, 65, epilepsy, February 22, 1904. 
b Higlin, 73, old age, March 5, 1904. 

Hires Stewart, 67, paralysis, March 10, 1904. 
George W. Sutton, 68, stomach trouble, April 9, 1904. 
Charles Brewster, 70, general nervous debility, July 20, 1904. 
•gt A. Hamer, 73, general debility, July 27, 1904. 

There is very little complaint made to me by any one, and 
such as I do hear are from chronics that complain of any and 
ything. The authority seems to be respected and everything 
is pleasant. I will also take this opportunity to thank 
the executive officers and people of this great state for their 
generosity in providing for the worthy and homeless that so 
valiantly defended the flag that waves over and for the greatnation 
on the face of the earth. Hoping for a continuation 
of the prosperity that is now visiting our land and a 
continuation of peace, I have the honor of submitting the 

Geo. TV. Brandon^ M. I). 

Milford, Neb., December 4, 1904. 

To the Honorable John H. Mickey, Governor, and the Board 

of Public Lands and Buildings: 

We have the honor to submit the following report : 

10 have two soldiers' and sailors' homes in this state, and 
should be amply provided for by the present legislature 
le the appropriation must be made by the state for the 
itenance of our soldiers' and sailors' homes, the state is 
ibursed by the general government to the amount of one 
Jred dollars ($100) per year for each soldier supported, 
*h amounts to about one-half of the expense, and the 
rnment expects the state to provide well for the neeessiof 
these state institutions, and the people of our state exthe 
same. 

Kb have carefully examined a copy of the report made to 
by W. S. Askwith, commandant of the Soldiers' and 
?re' Home at Grand Island, and find that he has made 
y full, complete, and itemized report, and, without going </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
343 

into details, would hereby endorse the same, and ask that his 
report will receive your careful consideration. 

We wish to call your attention especially to better fire 
escapes for both homes. The amount asked for by Charle* 
IVnn, commandant of the Milford home, does not exceed the 
amount necessary for the next two years, and, with the in 
creased capacity, it will require a larger amount, in our opinion, 
than he has asked. The membership has gradually increased 
at the rate of about 12 per cent for the past two \ i 
and will continue to increase for at least the next four years 
at the same ratio. The reason for this increase lies in the 
fa«t that a large majority of the soldiers of the Civil war are 
now over sixty years of age, and, as they grow older, the 
per cent will increase who will desire to avail theniselv. 
Hie advantages afforded by the state of a comfortable home. 
At the present time there are about 475 men and 12") women 
(mothers, wives, and widows of soldiers) in the two homes, 
and the present capacity of the home is not equal to the demands, 
and, with an increase of membership, which is inevitable, 
there will not be room for the admission of all those 
who are entitled to be admitted as members. We would 
therefore recommend that an administration building l&gt;e 
built at each home, at a cost not less than eight thousand 
dollars (f8,000) for each building, thereby giving the room 
now occupied by the commandants and officers to the iueni- 

The legislature of 1903 made an appropriation of twenty 
thousand dollars ($20,000) for a new hospital at Milforti. 
The same has just been completed, but is not furnished. We 
would recommend that this hospital be furnished at once, so 
that the old and sick members who have been waiting so patiently 
may enjoy the conveniences of the same before they 
pass over to the world beyond. 

As there is not the room to take care of women at Milford, 
so that a man and his wife can live together, and as we believe 
that these old people at this time of their lives should 
not be separated, therefore we recommend that a flat, with </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
344 


B capacity of sixty people, be built at Milford, to be occu[ 
by the old soldiers and their wives, at least two rooms 
each couple. This will require an appropriation of about 
ive thousand dollars (f 12,000). 

tyou, or any committee of the legislature, desire any furinformation 
from our board, or any individual member 
of, we will gladly comply with your request* 

All of which is respectfully submitted, 

John Reese, 

President, Visiting and Examining Board Soldiers' and 
Sailors' Homes. 

Belle C. Bolshaw, 

Secretary, Visiting and Examining Board Soldiers' and 
Sailors' llonies. 

Robt. S. Wilcox. 

T. E. IlABBEBT. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>