<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00011.00008">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00011.00008</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS IN NEBRASKA PBULISHED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION, STATE OF NEBRASKA</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-19</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-21</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS and GROUNDS 

IN NEBRASKA 

nilUSHID »V TM1 

DEPARTMENT OF PUBUC INSTRUCTION 
STATE OF NEBRASKA 

VILLIAM K. FOVLER, State Superintendent 

LINCOLN. AntiL 1. 1902 </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
322 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Introduction 

A large number of new schoolhouses have been built in Nebraska 
during the past year, and the indications are that a larger number 
will be erected during the coming summer. It is hoped that a still 
larger number will be remodeled so as to secure better light and 
a better system of heating and ventilating, conforming to hygienic 
laws. This publication is issued in the hope that it may contain 
some help, direct or suggestive, to school boards, superintendents 
and principals. 

WILLIAM K. FOWLER, 

State Superintendent. 

Lincoln, April i, 1902. </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

323 

Acknowledgments 

The state superintendent desires to thus publicly express his 
thanks to many of the teachers, principals and superintendents of 
Nebraska, and to the secretaries of several boards of education in 
the state, for their kindness in furnishing photographs or engravings 
from which the illustrations in this volume are made. 

To Mr. John Latenser, of Omaha, the state superintendent feds 
particularly indebted. The superintendent is confident that the entire 
state of Nebraska will appreciate highly the ground plans. 
elevations, working drawings and specifications of the one-room 
schoolhouse reproduced in this volume, and the plans of the tworoom 
and four-room frame and brick buildings that are also reproduced 
herein. These were all made possible through the kindness 
of Mr. Latenser. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
324 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

School Buildings in Nebraska 

The illustrations in this publication have not been systematically 
collected, therefore they can hardly be said to be fairly representative 
of the school buildings in the state. Requests for cuts or photographs 
of school buildings were sent to all superintendents and 
principals in the state and were published in the Nebraska Teacher. 
From the city superintendents many cuts were received, and they 
are used in this volume. County superintendents and village principals 
sent in many photographs of village and rural schoolhouses, 
fully three-fourths of which were available for use, and half-tone 
reproductions from them appear in this volume. 

The pictures of sod schoolhouses will attract instant attention, 
but we hope our readers will not jump to the conclusion that they 
are the common type of schoolhouse in this state or that they are 
common in all parts of the state. These pictures will prove as 
great a curiosity to many of our readers in eastern portions of the 
state as they are to the inhabitants of Greater New York. As will 
be seen by Statistical Table No. I, in the back of this volume, there 
were last year (1901) 464 sod schoolhouses in the state of Nebraska 
out of a total of 6,773; an( l since 1893 the number of "soddies"' has 
been steadily decreasing. Very few of the next generation ot Nebraskans 
will have the pleasure of attending school in a Nebraska 
sod schoolhouse. They might go to school in poorer buildings than 
one built of sod, however, for it is as warm in winter and as cool in 
summer as any ordinary schoolhouse. although some of our lady 
teachers do object to the fleas and vermin that sometimes infest 
such a building. Many of our sod schoolhouses are well finished, 
Erly all are floored and plastered, and many are finished around 
doors and windows on the inside. Slate blackboards, patent 
ks, maps, charts, a school library, a globe and an international 
unabridged dictionary may be found in many of them. The better 
class of them have shingled roofs. A more complete description 
of several of these sod buildings accompanies the illustrations. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GBOUNM. 

325 

Some parts of Nebraska have more sand than wood or stone, and 
so have the children. It is not strange when we consider the character 
of our early settlers that they built schoolhouses when they 
built their homes, and of the only available material, — the tod 
of the prairie and sand-hill toughened and bound by the roots of 
the native grasses, cut out in squares and laid up in walls two feet 
or more in thickness. Nebraska will maintain the lowest per cent of 
illiteracy among the states of the Union if it is necessary to educate 
her children in dugouts, soddies, shanties, and log huts to do it 

We believe the rural and village frame buildings illustrated to Bt 
fairly representative of the frame buildings throughout the stale 
in country and town ; and the high school buildings, frame, brick. 
and stone, are an evidence of the pride that our cities take in their </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
326 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

The Country School 

The first requisite of a good school is a good teacher, it is true, but 
the best of teachers may be considerably handicapped by unfavorable 
environment, while the poorest teachers iray do better work if they 
keep school in a well constructed, nicely furnished, well equipped 
schoolroom. 

We hear much of the improvement of material school conditions today, 
compared with fifty years ago. The veterans of the Civil War 
compare the beautiful brick buildings in which their grandchildren attend 
school with the log houses where they sat on rough-hewn logs 
with their faces to the wall and their backs exposed to the teacher and 
the long horizontal wood stove in the center of the room, in the '50's; 
but these comparisons are too broad and sweeping. The beautiful, 
well furnished schoolhouses of stone or of brick in our cities and towns 
should not be compared with the log schoolhouses of fifty years ago, 
nor even with the little red frame schoolhouse of that time. It is true 
there is a material improvement in schoolhouses generally, but the improvement 
is greater and more general in city than in country. In the 
city more attention is now being paid to sanitary conditions and methods 
of heating and ventilating, to lighting and seating, and to improved 
blackboards and charts and better maps, adjustable window shades 
and curtains and desks, the arrangement of corridors and wardrobes 
and closets, etc. In the country the improvement is less marked. 
There are still many rural district schoolhouses built on the two-bythree 
plan; width two-thirds of the length, a single room without entry 
or vestibule, two or three widely separated windows in each side, and 

a door in the center of one end. The blackboard is usually plaster 
painted black, scanty in amount, and the desks are double patent ones. 
The wood-box may sometimes be found in one corner of the schoolroom 
as of yore, but filled with cobs, though more commonly the 
outdoor coal shed takes its place. Occasionally both are lacking, and 
the coal and wood or cobs are dumped on the bare ground. The 
pump may or may not be out of repair, and too frequently the outbuildings 
are the same dens of vice and hell-holes of contamination 
and pollution they used to be. Trees and shrubbery are too often 
lacking. These sad conditions, though not universal nor even general 
in some parts of Nebraska, are altogether too common. They 
are the conditions we hope to improve. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
SCHOOL BUILDI' &gt; OBOt 

327 

According to the School Laws of Nebraska, the legal voters in 
the common school districts shall, at the annual meeting, determine 
by vote the number of mills on the dollar of assessed valuation 
which shall be levied for all purposes, except for the payment of 
bonded indebtedness, which number shall not exceed twenty-fire 
mills in any year. A part of this twenty-five mills, not in excess of 
ten mills, may be used for the building, purchase, or lease of a 
schoolhouse in the district when there are no bonds voted for MKh 
purpose. The bonded indebtedness of a district shall not exceed 
five per cent on the dollar of the assessed valuation. Property in 
Nebraska is assessed at so low a rate,— one-sixth or one-eighth its 
real value, — that these limitations often work a hardship on the 
poorer districts. However, it costs the district but little more to 
build a schoolhouse properly heated, lighted, and ventilated, than 
to construct one without providing for these essentials. It coat* 
less to heat and ventilate a properly constructed schoolroom than to 
heat a poorly constructed one with no provisions for ventilation It 
may cost the parents more in the payment of doctors' bills, of medicines, 
and loss of school attendance, if their children are compelled 
to attend school in a room neither heated nor ventilated properly. 
It may cost parents more for oculists' bills and eyeglasses if their 
children sit in rooms facing windows or with cross lights, or with 
an inadequate amount of natural light or with the same supplemented 
by artificial light, than if they attend in a room lighted as it 
should be. School children cannot Iwgin to do the amount of work 
in a schoolroom improperly heated, lighted and ventilated that they 
could do in a schoolroom with these conditions as they should be. 
This is not theory, but a matter of experience. Neither teachers nor 
pupils can concentrate their attention upon the matter in hand as 
they should, in an uncomfortable schoolroom. These poor conditions 
may not result in the general breaking up of the health of the 
teacher or pupils, but they may result in a gradual impairment of 
the health and a derangement of the nervous system that will resnk 
in permanent physical injuries. 

Teachers generally are easily influenced by their «tirroun&lt;itngs. 
There are a few noted exceptions, Mark Hopkins, for instance, that 
simply prove this rule. A log might serve him in lieu of a modern 
schoolroom, but it will not do for the average Nebraska school </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
328 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

its surroundings and the interior. Our experience has always been 
that a school that was neat and clean in appearance was doing 
careful, thorough work, with excellent order prevailing, while a 
dirty, dingy, disarranged schoolroom was invariably a disorderly, 
inattentive, careless and slipshod school. If the aspect of the school 
premises is forbidding, it is not surprising that the children are 
reluctant to go to school and are pleased to get away again as soon 
as they can. There are too many school buildings and grounds in 
Nebraska whose appearance is apparently designed to encourage 
truancy. The condition becomes aggravated when the improvement 
of residences outruns the improvement of schoolhouses. Children 
are quick to notice contrasts and to make comparisons. They 
will compare their dusty, dirty, dingy, smoke-begrimed schoolhouse 
with its broken plaster, rusty stove and rough, knot-protruding 
floors, its broken, rattle-trap desks and dirty windows, with their 
mother's clean, neat, tidy kitchens, with their parents' homes where 
comforts and conveniences are multiplying, where plate glass windows, 
cedar trees and other evidences of prosperity and care and 
forethought attract one's eye as he drives from one schoolhouse to 
another. The appearance and conditions of the schoolhouse, in 
which our children spend one-half their waking hours every school </seg>


            <seg id="p010">
Fig I— A MODEL FLOOR PLAN 
The Sutherland Schoolhouse </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
329 

SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND UROUlfDH. 

The Sutherland Schoolhousc 

This is a newly erected district schoolhouse, located about five 
mil%s west of Blair. It is located in district No. jo. WasbJagloa 
county, and was erected during the same year as the new BWr 
high school building, and by the same architect. 

In the perspective we see the north side with its six window*, and 
the west end with the entrance in the southwest corner. The pupils 
face an unbroken east wall, with the strong, even light of the 
north entering from the left, and two smaller window* above the 
blackboard in the rear. Fresh air enters through a grating m the 
foundation wall near the steps, and is carried In' a galvanized iron 
duct below the floor to an opening below the stove, where it i» 
warmed and distributed. The foul air passes out through the registers 
in the floor by the north wall and in the wall near the ?love. 
This air heats the floor from below and the ceiling from above. 
The inlet and the outlets of the air are regulated by dampers. There 
are two rows of blackboard slates across the front wall, the upper 
one for the use of the teacher for copies, drills, etc. The teacher. 
from her natural position in the front of the room, may watch the 
pupils at the blackboard in the rear of the room and inspect their 
work, and at the same time "oversee" those at work in their seats. 
The wardrobe extends along the south side, is lighted by four windows 
placed high in the wall, and is furnished with sixty doable 
schoolhouse hooks, each with a numbered metal tag. 

Fig. I. a Model Plan, is the floor plan of this scboolhous*. Complete 
specifications, with ground plan, exterior view* and working; 
drawings for the construction of this schoolhouse, are published 
on the following pages. 

Had the building been located on one of the three other corners 
formed by the intersection of the roads the entrance might have 
been in the southeast corner of the building instead of the soothand 
the pupils, after passing through the wardrobe, would 
then enter the rear of the schoolroom, and visitors would enter ike 
front of the room from the entrance. The sunlight enters this tflHHltroom 
in the afternoon above the beads of the pupils. A door or 
window near the east end of the wardrobe, in the southeast comer </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
330 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT.' 

of the building, would permit the early morning sunlight to stream 
across the schoolroom through the inner door. 

But this building, though not perfect, is the best country scli'-.l-house 
in Washington county, and, we believe, in many Nebraska 
counties It is substantial in construction and beautiful in interior 
finish. 

Since its completion two other rural schoolhouses have been 
erected in Washington county on the same general plan. The original 
plans of the Sutherland schoolhouse are now on file in the 
office of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction at Lincoln. 

A Rural Schoolhouse 

Brief Specifications for Wo-k and Material Required for the Erection of a One-room 

Schoolhouse, in Accordance with Accompanying Ground Plans, 

Elevations and Work ng Drawings 

The Original at this Building wu Built in District No 20, Washington County, Nebraska. 

This building may be erected in the eastern portion of the state, 
complete, for $1,000.00. The original plans are now on file in the 
office of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction at Lincoln. 

GENERAL CONDITIONS 

The Board. 

The Board reserves the right to reject any or all bids. The 
Board will superintend the work, through the Architect or an especially 
appointed superintendent. The Board reserves the right to 
make any changes, omissions, or additions in and to the building, 
without voiding these specifications, the contract, or bond. 

The Board will recognize no extra work and will not pay for 
extra work, unless such work has been ordered beforehand by resolution 
of the Board. 

No alleged verbal agreement at variance with the drawings, 
specifications, etc., will be recognized. The Board will insure its </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
u-r 

• 

~ 84SfMf/VT fZ/W - 

imcH ' /n»r </seg>

            <seg id="p014">

- f//esT rioo/d fu/v - 

i'MfCH ¦ /fOOT. 

A RURAL SCHOOLHOUSE </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
333 


equity in the building from time to time as payments are made, bat 
the Contractor must insure his interest therein at his own cose. 

The Contractor. 

The Contractor will be responsible for the building until it* 
ceptance by the Board, and must make good all injuries sustained 
during construction from whatever cause. The Contractor hhmI 
show receipts (if the Board elects to ask for them) before rack 
payment. 

The Contractor must give a bond with two responsible Mimic* 
as provided by law, subject to the approval b] the Boa- 

The Contractor must finally deliver the building whole, perfect. 
and clean, within the contract time, and must correct all defects «•»-covered 
during the first month of use, unless the same are no fault 
of his. 

The Contractor must visit the site and examine same. The height 
of the first floor will be given, and the Contractor must clo all necessary 
excavation to bring the walls below frost. He mast ronow 
6 inches of the black earth under the building, to prevent decay nt 
vegetation under the building. 

Brick Work. 

The entire brick work, including chimney, is to be built of good, 
hard, sound brick, to be laid straight and true, neatly pointed op and 
to be washed down upon completion. There is to be a &lt;&gt;-inch brick 
wall extending under all interior wood partitions, for the rapport 
of partitions and floor joists. 

The smoke flue is to be plastered on the inside and is to be 12 * I a 
inches in size; it is also to be plastered on the outside, where it 
passes through the ceiling and roof. 

All wood is to be kept from the flue I inch clear. Smoke floe is to 
have an 8-inch thimble for furnace pipe. 

Plastering. 

Pth all walls and ceilings with So. i white pine or cypress 
with spaces, breaking joints every seventh lath. 

t Plaster all walls and ceilings, including inside of teacher's clmd. 
ree coats; the first two coats to be hard plaster of an improved 
inufacture approved by the Board, and the last coat to be a PW- 

Excavation. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
334 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

ter Paris finishing coat. All plastered corners are to be rounded. 
Care is to be taken that plastering which will receive artificial blackboard 
is absolutely straight and true. 

The wall which will receive blackboard is to be plastered as 
above specified, as if no blackboard were to be used. If natural 
slate blackboard is used, the first two coats of plastering are to be 
put on ready for finishing coat, and the finishing coat behind natural 
slate blackboard is to be omitted. 

Etering is to extend tight up against window jambs and door 
and down to floor behind base everywhere, to make the 
g warm. 

Carpenter Work 

Floor joists are to be 2 x 12 inch and ceiling joists 2 x 10 inch 
Uow pine, sound, dry and well-seasoned. All other framing 
lumber to be white pine or yellow pine, sound, dry and well-seasoned. 
Joists and rafters are to be in one length. 

Valleys are to be in two pieces 2x8 inches each, thoroughly 
spiked together. Exterior studding is to be 2 x 6 inches, 12 feet 
long. Interior studding is to be 2x6 inches, 12 feet long. Wall 
plate for exterior walls is to be 8 x 8 inches halved and pinned at 
corners, and mortised for joists. All sills for interior walls are to 
be 2 x 8 inches. 

Plates for exterior studding are to be 2x6 inches, double, and 
plates for interior studding to be 2 x 6 inches, double. All comers 
and angles are to be built up solid, no lath to run through. All 
joists and studdings are to be 16 inches from center to center. 

kPut double studding on each side of each door and window openly 
Schoolroom floor is to have one row of cross bridging 1x3 
Jies. 

Every pair of rafters is to have a 2 x 4 inch cross tie 8 feet 
long. The valleys will brace the roof in the other direction. 


Tower is to have bell deck, covered with I.X. tin, and to have 
3x3 inch scuttle, and also a scuttle in the ceiling of the schoolroom 
immediately under tower. 

The corner posts of the tower are to extend down to the top of 
ceiling joists and to be braced. Ceiling joists under inside tower </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
I 


— ft_5 


tew 

Shihlic Root 

~SO77i £L£VHT/ON " 

A RURAL SCHOOLHOl'Sf- </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
9 

-.-zti 

~A0&amp;// £L£l//tT/OA/ - 
A RURAL SCHOOLHOUSE 
</seg>
            <seg id="p019">
SCHOOL BTJILD1 

333 

posts are to be treble, and the roof of tower it to be thoroughly 
cross-braced. 

Porch. 

Porch is to be built as shown, of white pine, with Ji x 4 inch 
white pine flooring, and to have white pine step* i^ inch thick, 
with white pine railing and balusters. 

Ceiling of porch is to be first lined with roof sheathing, thai to 
have one layer of straw paper, and then to be covered with H x 4 
inch white pine ceiling. 

Ventilation. 

The ventilating flue is to be lined up with H x 6 inch yellow 
pine ceiling, and is to extend from under side of floor joists.to attic 
floor. On top of roof build a 12-inch globe ventilator of galvanised 

The ventilating flue is to have sliding board in schoolroom so 
arranged as to close off the ventilating flue entirely when school '» 
not in session. 

Below the second and fifth windows put a 10 x 10 inch ventilating 
register in the floor. The foul air will then pass directly 
through these registers down between the earth and the floor 
towards the ventilating flue, pass up through the ventilating flat to 
the attic, and spread all over the attic ; thence the air will pass oat 
through the globe ventilator in the top of the roof. In th« outside 
wall below the floor build an opening 1 foot 6 inches x I foot 6 
inches, and run a galvanized iron duct 1 foot 6 inches x l foot 6 
inches under the floor to the under side of the furnace. Under the 
furnace cut a hole in the floor 24 inches in diameter and permit 
the air to strike against the bottom of the furnace. Provide a 
tight door in the opening of the outside -wall so the cold air may 
be shut off from the school when it is not in session. (An nnli—rjr 
cast iron furnace costing about $45.00 f. o. b. is' to be placed Oftt 
the opening in the floor. The furnace is then to receive a galvanized 
iron casing extending from the floor to the top of the furnace. 
Bcold air will then strike the furnace, where it will be m jrild, 
between the furnace and the galvanized iron casing and paM 
nto the scl oo'ri&gt;t&gt;m. The furnace, casing and smoke pipe will 
not to exceed $Sn.oo set in place.) 

Bv the above method the foul air leaves the room at about 68 or </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
334 


7O degrees, will be drawn under floor and warm the floor, and it 
will be drawn through the ventilating flue to the attic, thereby 
warming the ceiling of the schoolroom. 

Sheathing. 

Cover all outside walls, entire roof, tower and entire floor with 
No. i sheathing. 

Paper. 

t Cover sheathing on all outside walls with one layer of good 
ilding paper (not tar paper), and cover the entire roof sheathing 
th one layer of tar paper. All paper is to be lapped 2 inches. 

Shingles. 

Cover the entire roof and tower with first clear red-wood or 
cypress shingling, laid 4 inches to the weather. Each shingle is to 
have two galvanized iron shingle nails. 

The shingles are to be dipped for two-thirds their length from 
the bottom up, into best quality Creosote Shingle Stain. 


Valleys and bell deck are to be lined with I.X. tin 14 inches wide. 

Ridges. 

Ridges are to be formed with two % x 5 inch boards 
Cornice. 

PTiice is to be as shown on drawing. The eaves are to be 
with paper and ]/% x 4 inch white pine ceiling. 

Outside Finish. 

Eiter table is to be i}£ inches x g x / 2 inches high, to have 1^x3 
cap and % quarter round underneath corner board. Window 
gs and door casings are to be ij^ inches thick and 5 inches 

Endow sills are to be i}£ inches thick. Outside window casing 
be so placed as to permit of storm sash at a later day. Care 
be taken that the building paper, extends under all water 
i, corner boards, door and window casings. 


All outside studdings are to be covered with narrow siding wkk 
y 2 inch lap. Siding is to be white pine or red wood. </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
I 

A RURAL SCHOOLHOUSE </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
- CROSS 5fC77GW~ 

i /me* - /rocr 

rural schoolhouse </seg>


            <seg id="p023">
335 

Interior Finish. 

Cover all floors with % x 4 inch tongued and grooved No. I 
yellow pine flooring; all joints to be smoothed after laying. A» 
soon as laid the floor is to receive one coat of boiled linseed oil 
mixed with 25 per cent turpentine. 


Provide a ladder from attic to bell deck. 


The outside door is to have double strength glass in upper panel. 
It is to be made of two thicknesses of white pine 1% inch each, 
making the door 2]/+ inches thick, to be paneled and flush moulded. 
All inside doors are to be No. 1 white pine stock doors with five 
panels, hand smoothed for oil finish. 

iThe two teacher's closet doors are to be 1^6 inches thick, to have 
.ee panels each. 

Jambs. 

Outside door jamb is to be 1^ inches thick, rebated. Inside door 
jamb is to be y% inch thick, and is to have door stops. 

Teacher's Closet. 

Teacher's closet is to have seven shelves 14 inches wide, to be pat 
on ratchets, so as to make them movable. 

Windows. 

Windows are to have 1 % inch yellow pine pulley stiles, 1 )i inches 
thick, to be filled with D. S. (double strength) glass. 

Sash is to be hung to cast iron weights with J4 inch Sampson or 
Silver Lake cord, to have 2% inch anti-friction axle pulleys, and 
all windows are to have 1% inch stool. 


Doors and windows are to have x 5 inch casing with plinth at 
bottom and to be mitered on top. 

Base is to be y% x 7 inches, to have % x 3 inch mould on top 
and quarter round at bottom. 

Chalk trough is to run all around room and to be I Ji inches 
thick, to be hollowed for chalk, to project 2 l /i inches, and to have 
'/&amp; x 5 • n &gt;-'' 1 apron. </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
336 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Picture Moulding. 

Run picture moulding all around school room, level with th« 
top of windows. 

Interior Finish. 

All interior finish, with the exception of doors, is to be best 
quality yellow pine, hand smoothed for oil finish. 

Painting. 

Kail tin immediately after laying and before covering, with 
ts of approved mineral paint. 

Paint all exterior woodwork with three coats of pure lineed oil, 
pure white lead and best English pigments, and color as selected. 

Eie first coat of paint is to be l /z French ochre, Yz white lead 
oil. After first coat all nail holes and other defects are to be 
ed. 

Varnish all interior woodwork three coats ; first coat is to be a 
liquid filler, second and third coats a good standard varnish, list 
price not less than $2.50. 

t Filler and first coat are to be rubbed down, last coat is to be 
wed on. 

Blackboards. 

Blackboards will be put on by the Board, and are not to be included 
in this contract. 

Hardware. 

Ee Carpenter will furnish complete and will put on all hard- 
Each window is to have a heavy sash lock, and one flush 
lift. Front door is to have 4^ x 4J/2 inch lock with three steel 
lers, two keys, and three 4J4 x 4^2 inch steel hinges. 

Each inside door is to have one tumbler lock and two 4x4 inch 
steel hinges. 

Teacher's closet is to have one tumbler lock to one leaf, the other 
leaf to be hooked to shelf, each door to be hung with two s l / 2 inch x 
3J4 inch steel hinges. 

All locks are to have solid knobs, elongated escutcheons. All 
hardware above specified is to be bronzed. </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
' 

-iw0m0////?L j&amp;r/0/y~ 

¦t/irc/f ' iroer 

A RURAL SCHOOLHOUSE </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
¦ 1 

* 


\ m*x 

t 

C*u~ 

/ 

&gt;. 

Jr-Um^ 

1c *., -4^.14 

)L2 

-*^mw^ 

StCTlPM 

T - 

Tmo hock rail 
Jo Him em to** tife I 


bzcrtON Titfro C*mm 7}m**m 

SP.tr*** M+L0 ***** 


*.# *j»» Ore f «e » MW&lt;«I </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
337 


Model Plans for VUlage Schools 

IOne who looks through this book carefully will be surprised at 
e difference in the appearances of the school buildings in the 
villages of the state. It is plain tt&gt; be seen that many of our school 
buildings are creatures of the imagination of architects with no 
knowledge of the actual needs of the schoolroom and with little care 
or forethought for the comforts and conveniences of the school 
children. Many of the buildings, however, that present a very respectable 
appearance in perspective possess abominable floor plant. 
Within the rooms, crosslights predominate, the light enters the room 
from the right, or from the right and rear, or from three sides, and 
in no inconsiderable number of schoolrooms in Nebraska the wall 
in front of the children is broken by one or more windows. In 
many cases the front wall is also broken by doors. Such a thing as 
a teacher's closet is unheard of, and the children hang their wet, 
steaming wraps, often with the odors of the kitchen alxmt them, in 
the schoolroom. 

The accompanying plans are designed to show how village school 
buildings containing two and four rooms may be constructed so as 
to avoid these difficulties. 

A MODEL TWO-ROOM FRAME SCHOOL BriLDING 

Here are the plans of a model two-room frame building for a 
small village or a thickly settled rural community. It is a twostory 
building, and may be heated with stoves or furnaces arranged 
according to the specifications for a rural schoolhouse pubiithai 
elsewhere in this volume. Read carefully the description of the 
Sutherland schoolhouse illustrated herein. At any time in the future 
a third room may be added according to the first floor platwo 
rooms may be added according to the first and second floor 
plans. 

A MODEL TWO-ROOM BRICK SCHOOL BUILDING 

These plans vary slightly from those of the frame building jaat 
described. Two cloak rooms are here provided for each Mrhootroom. 
one cloak room for each sex. Should future schoolrooms be constructed 
at any time, each room would be restricted to one cloak 
room. The shading; of the walls indicates window* or ooraaw* </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
338 


that may be bricked up with the construction of the original two 
rooms, but which may later be converted into doors or windows. As 
the rear walls of both the frame and brick plans have no openings 
whatever, it would not be a difficult matter to construct the future 
schoolrooms indicated on the plans, and then again double the 
capacity of the building by adding as much more on the rear side, 
remodeling the roof and opening passage ways from the rear of the 
halls. The possibility of thus increasing to eight rooms is reserved 
more particularly for the following plans. In Nebraska villages it is 
always wise to make provision for doubling the capacity of the 
school buildings at any time without necessarily doubling the expense 
of construction. 

A MODEL FOUR-ROOM FRAME SCHOOL BUILDING. 

This is practically the Calhoun school building illustrated herein. 
This building was erected last year at a cost of about $6,000. As 
may be seen by the plan, it contains ventilating flues for all the 
schoolrooms. Each room is similar in its arrangement to the one 
room in the Sutherland schoolhouse, in district No. 20 of the same 
county in which Calhoun is located — Washington. District No. 20 
Calhoun, and Blair are all in Washington county, and their new 
buildings were all designed by the same architect, Mr. Latense.. 
There is practically no difference in the interior point of view or in 
the arrangement of the Sutherland schoolroom, any schoolroom in 
the Calhoun building, and any schoolroom in the new Blair high 
school building. They are all arranged with the windows at the left 
of the children and an unbroken front wall before them. 

A MODEL FOUR-ROOM BRICK SCHOOL BUILDING. 

These plans differ but little from those for the four-room frame 
building, but the interior walls, like the exterior, are designed to run 
down to the foundation. For explanation of this, see the description 
of the Blair high school building. The capacity of this building 
may be doubled by duplicating it on the rear side, remodeling the 
roof, and converting the double window at the rear of the hall into 
a double door or opening it into an archway. </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
tT 

Cmm* »'• 

n. t*. . ru 


\ 
</seg>

            <seg id="p030">

¦ 

- 

IT. - ¦ 


'.-. •*. 

&gt; W 


, 

i HI HAL SCHOOLHOUSE 


jj 
| 8 
y 
«o 
! a 
!! 2 
2 
T 

1 
{ 
( 
5 
| 
¦ 

1 

r 
i 

?! 
I 

i 

woou Mvon^ 

&gt;*, 

S </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
339 

SCHOOL BUILDINGS 

School She 

Electing a site for a school building the principal items to be 
red are size, soil, drainage, sightliness and location in tht 
One acre of ground is little enough, — two or three mm 
would be better, — but the depth of the lot should exceed the «• 
by about one-third. The front part of the grounds should be sodded 
with blue grass and planted with hardy shade trees, not too cloae to 
the building. The ground should, if possible, be sloping toward tb* 
road or street, with no depressions. If the ground is quite lewd, 
artificial drainage should be resorted to. </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
340 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Seating 

Even when school buildings are properly constructed, and schoolrooms 
are lighted as they should be, much of the good that should 
result therefrom is counteracted by an improper arrangement and 
placing of the desks and seats of the children. School desks are 
usually made in six sizes, from No. I, the largest, to No. 6, the 
smallest. Sometimes they are numbered from A, the largest, to F, 
the smallest. No. i is sometimes known as the College or Normal 
School size and may be entirely dispensed with. No. 6 is the proper 
size for kindergarten children of four and five years of age and the 
smallest first primary children of five and six years of age. A five 
or six year old child that is above the average size for his age may sit 
with the greatest comfort in a No. 5 desk. The rural school, then, 
should contain a single row of No. 2 desks for the largest boys and 
girls, and a row of No. 6 desks for the smallest ones. If there are 
five rows of desks in the room there may be one row each, from 
front to rear, of Nos. 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6. If there are six rows of 
desks in the room, there may be two rows of No. 4. This selection 
will come nearer than any other in accommodating the ordinary 
country school. In too many cases children have desks too large 
for them. They sit on seats that are so high that they cannot place 
their feet flatly on the floor, with desks so high that they cannot 
write on them without elevating their elbows to the height of their 
rmlders. These conditions are very injurious to health, as well 
uncom f ortable . 

t Single desks should be used. The difference in expense is small, 
lile the effect on the order of the school and the independence 
d studiousness of the children is great. 

Only desks of the same size should be placed in the same row. 
The old fashioned school placed the small desks across the front, 
the largest ones across the rear, thinking that it looked better that 
way. Perhaps the desks do, but the children do not. The No. 2 seat 
is adjusted at a height to fit the No. 2 desk. 

Ethe main light comes in, as it should, from one side of 
schoolroom, the seats should be so placed that it will enter 
le left of the children. It is usually better to place the row of 
6 desks on the left side of the room and the row of No. 2 on the </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
. L .-.::: ::;k-;m« 


I 

1 

! 

I 

Cixmk Room 

X. 

Tun 

r 
r- 

i 

73 
8 

B 

I 

! i 

c:: 

i 
i 
73 
O 
O 

r."r:;3 </seg>



            <seg id="p034">
r 

i ; 

i 

i 

j 
I 
LJ 
a 
I 

i 
I &gt; 

tooy mvc 

wooy xvoiD 

51 

¦ 

d 

as. 

I 
— I 

I 

I 
\ 

O a: 
I! 

wooy xvon^ 

¦^¦^^^^¦¦^^¦¦M^^^ 

I 

3 </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
341 

SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

right side. From a position in front of the No. 6 row of desks the 
teacher can look over the heads of the smaller children on the left 
of the room (her right) to the larger ones at the right of the room. 
It may be preferable, however, to place the rows of No. 5 anrl 
6 desks in the center, No. 2 and No. 3 to the outside. The accompanying 
diagrams illustrate these two plans. 

might be seated according to the 
accompanying diagram. 

We place the smaller desk* and 
smaller children next the windows, 
as they form less obstruction to 
the light in its passage to the right 
of the room. 

Desks Nos. 5 and 6 should be so 
placed that the edge of the dead 
next to and in front of the chid 
shall be about nine inches from the 
back of the seat in which he is sitting; 
for desk No. 4 this distance 
should be about tan inches; No. 

T 

IZZ1 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

T 

IZZ1 

I I 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 5 

4 

3 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 5 

4 

3 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 5 

4 

3 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 S 

4 

3 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 5 

4 

3 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 5 

4 

3 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 5 

4 

3 

6 

5 

4 4 

3 

2 

3 

4 

6 5 

4 

S 

A village employing three or more teachers may seat three- fooithi 
if the pupils in each room with only two sizes of desks. One-cighlfc 

&gt;f the desks might be the next size larger and one-eighth the next 

ize smaller than the other two sizes used. The intermediate room </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
342 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Eleven or twelve inches; and No. 2 twelve o thirteen inches. In a 
jority of the schoolrooms of Nebraska the desks are so far apart that 
children are forced to lean forward in unnatural positions to make use 
of them in writing and drawing. 

The aisles at the sides and rear of the room should be about three 
feet wide and the others should be about twenty inches wide. 
</seg>

            <seg id="p037">
i 

l 

3 

I 
03 

_i 
I 

3 
I 

a. 
u. 

O 
o 
I 
30 
i 
O 
X 
x. 
o </seg>
            <seg id="p038">
Moon Mvcn? 

! 

' 

I 
a. 

1 </seg>


            <seg id="p039">
SCHOOL. BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

Outhouses 

Section 6a, subdivision V. of the School Laws of Nebraska for 
190 1 is as follows : 

It shall be the duty of school district boards to provide on every 
schoolhouse site, and keep in good repair and in clean and heakfcfal 
condition, at least two separate water closets or privies, located am 
those portions of the site the farthest from the main entrance to 
the schoolhouse, and as far from each other as the surrounding 
condition will permit ; Provided, That where adequate and separate 
interior closets are provided and maintained in good repair and 
healthful condition, the foregoing condition of this act shall not 

Rx&gt; many districts in the state this law is not enforced; In a 
stricts there is but one outhouse: in a larger number thtft 
o outhouses, but both are under one roof ; in a still larger 
number of districts the outhouses are, next to the schoolhoaM itself. 
the most conspicuous objects within forty rods, and children arc 
taught by their position and arrangement, by suggestion, by school 
room habit and inclination, even by their teacher's rules ¦tometimta, 
that the chief object of school attendance is to frequent tfct 

The outhouses at railroad depots, hotels, and school MMtafja 
often contain upon their walls the most obscene, foul and vulgar 
language and figures that may be conceived, written or drawn. 
This is not always the work of school children, even in the oathouses 
on school grounds, but often of the vagrant and the loafer. 
Every school outhouse should be provided with a stoat door and 
lock, and it should be locked at all times when school is not in 
session. That will insure its daily inspection, and with brush and 
paint or whitewash all marks should be covered up the day they ate 
made. Discourage such crimes. 

The two outhouses should be placed in the two rear corners of 
the school grounds and should be concealed by trees or shrubbery. 
A high, tight-board fence or a hedge should separate the rear quarters 
of the school grounds, and on the front half only should the two 
sexes be allowed a common play ground. 

There are children who have att nded the public trffflrh far </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
344 


several years who have seldom, if ever, asked to be excused from 
the schoolroom. There are others who leave the room each and 
every half day. Differently constituted, you say ? Yes, undoubtedly, 
but not by nature. The difference is, in a measure at least, in habit, 
in training. We know of parents who require their children to attend 
to their physical necessities before they start to school, in the 
morning and at noon. Such parents realize that the ordinary school 
outhouse will, unavoidably, disease the body and corrupt the mind 
of the child. They realize that the gathering of large numbers of 
children in such places does not improve their morals or their manners. 
They realize, also, what is of minor importance, that a child 
who leaves the schoolroom each half day not only interrupts the 
work, attracts the attention of the teacher, and distracts the attention 
of the pupils, both in his exit and his entrance, but also, if he 
loses ten minutes from his studies each time, loses sixty whole hours, 
or more than ten days in the course of nine months. A teacher 
should permit pupils to leave the schoolroom when necessary, and 
she should be cautioned not to constitute herself the judge of the 
child's physical necessities, but she should use all reasonable means 
to reduce the number to a minimum. One teacher has adopted the 
plan of excusing during the first five minutes after nine o'clock, while 
settling down and hanging wraps, pupils who think they may need 
to pass out before recess, and strange as it may seem, this almost 
entirely cures the evil of a string of pupils constantly going and 
coming. Pupils will not neglect play to attend to their physical 
necessities before school time, even with the tap of the bell five 
minutes before the hour to remind them. And in this connection, is 
it too much to ask of parents that they instruct their children in 
habits of cleanliness : the fathers their boys, and the mothers their 
girls r </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
I I 

I 

g 

Cloak Room 

i 

» 

fl 

&lt; 

i 

I 

z 

Iff 

i 

S 

i 

i 

r 

&gt; 

/ </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
wooy MVO13 

z - 
&lt; i 
1 
o 
&lt; 

i I 
i ¦ 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
345 


School Architecture 

The advantages derived from schoolhouses, whose exterior presents 
a beautiful design, is becoming recognized more and more 
every year. 

When the beautiful was taught unto mankind, says an exchange. 
the district schoolhouse was evidently left out of the list of Inky 
that might be called decorative. Square, grim, uninviting and uncompromisingly 
ugly, it stands at the most convenient crow roads 
or on some beautiful wooded slope, a menace to ethics of architectural 
beauty and a most helpful argument in childish minds against 
t attractiveness of education. There is little that could appeal to 
esthetic side of human nature in a building of this kind. 

Eie log buildings of pioneer days set the rectangular fashion of 
itecture through necessity, the materials used and the cr»de 
¦ employed requiring this. Times and conditions have chimed 
so radically since then, the materials and the workmen are so tnach 
more easily secured and better suited to the work, that much is now 
possible in the way of varying the old style. Especially where H it 
a two- or three-room building are there possibilities of archkectaral 
beauty. Straight, apparently endless roof lines can be broken with 
windows, and sharp angles softened in outline, with a small portico 
here and there to relieve the severity of the whole. The same amount 
of money carefully spent could secure so much belter results that 
school commissioners ought to feel inspired to try it sometime* sad 
see for themselves. 

From the district school may come the nation's leader*, rv 
Eiters, thinkers of the future, and the more they are given of the 
istic and symmetrical things in childhood the better will they 
nd in later years for the elevating and refining things of M 

Interiors where hare walls, straight wooden seats and a paatM 
lack of adornment are the daily environment of the country sfdti. 
offer nothing conducive to the esthetic development, and another 
helpful opportunity is lost. 

— The American School Board Journal, October, jyoi. </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
346 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Value of School Architecture 

Eomy is well, says a Southern school board member, but 
ies it is carried too far, and sometimes practiced in wrong 
ns. To the stranger the outward appearance of the school 
buildings of a city is taken as the indication of its educational standing. 
Of course the best teachers may teach in the shabbiest buildings, 
or the poorest in the finest buildings, but as a rule interest w 
education is indicated by outward appearances. A community that 
takes great interest in education, that demands up-to-date methods 
in the schoolroom, will demand up-to-date school buildings, and the 
absence of such buildings is taken as an indication of lack of progress 
in education. 

Nothing helps a town more than good educational facilities, or 
hurts it more than a lack of them, and as these facilities are judged 
by strangers to a great extent by the appearance of school buildings, 
it follows that nothing helps a town more than good school buildings, 
or hurts it more than a lack of them. 

But it is not for the effect on strangers alone that we need good 
school buildings. We need them for our children, for their health, 
for their comfort, for their education. The need of such buildings 
for the comfort and the health of the children will be conceded without 
a thought. A moment's reflection will convince any reasonable 
man that attractive and well arranged school buildings have an educational 
value. 

For men and women are largely made by their surroundings. 
Beauty is not without its utility. It has a great influence on the 
young. Children who are in their school lives to have attractive 
surroundings, other things being equal, will develop into men and 
women of better taste than those who have not. Life is not all 
utility, but even in a utilitarian sense taste is valuable. It cultivates 
a love for order, a fondness for system that has much to do 
with success. 

— American School Board Journal. </seg>


            <seg id="p045">
o 

JJ 

Q 

Q 

2 

J- mnET </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
I ! j^j g 

*1 

Z 

R 
z 
o 
o 
r 
xi 
o 
o 

: 

i 

« 

Cld^k Room 


A TWO-ROOM BUILDING 

1 From th6 AtFi^ricoti School BocltcI Journal, Chicswro, June. 1901) </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
347 


Rural Schoolhouse Heating and Ventilation 

BY S. J. RACE, REDWOOD FAM.S, MINN. 

The problem of wanning and ventilating small schoolhoases in 
rural districts where a common stove must furnish all the heat that 
is used is one of no small importance. Common sense here as elsewhere 
will achieve the highest results. 

As a rule the teacher must take care of the fires. He arrives at 
eight o'clock and finds the fire burning low, or else has gone oat. 
with an average temperature of 45 degrees. By nine o'clock he has 
managed to raise the temperature to 70 degrees. 

Ri a barbarous task that some school trustees set forth for 
teachers, who are expected to wade through the snow, somea 
mile, and then go into an icy cold room and there ouild a 
fire and await the warming of the room. Many trustees have fires 
built in mid-winter. It is economy to do so. No teacher is fitted to 
begin the day's work, if already her strength has been overtaxed by 
exposure in cold schoolrooms. 

Rre is one thing sure, the doors and windows must fit snug and 
All exposed windows must be provided with storm sash. The 
must be large enough to do the work easily without crowding. 
Fully one-half the stoves in use are too small. The fire pot should 
be at least sixteen inches in diameter and fully twenty inches deep. 
Nearly all modern stoves are fitted with sufficient cneck drafts to 
that a fire is at all times under perfect control. No matter how large 
the fire pot is, if the heat is not wanted, extra fuel is not consumed. 

Kd coal as fuel for schoolrooms is without doubt the best, the 
satisfactory, and the cleanest fuel. With it, fire in a good 
can be retained all night, thus giving a warm room in the 

Piere is no reason why the small rural school cannot be provided 
an adequate system of warming and ventilation. The physical 
ire of pupil and teacher demands it. Health is wealth. The 
should not exceed fifty dollars. Tnis allows for rebuilding the 
chimney from the foundation. I would recommend a single flue 
12 x 16 inches. This will give a chimney with an outside measurement 
of 16 x 24 inches. We have tried double flue chimneys, with 
two flues, each 8x12 and 12 x 12 inches, respectively. Thev work </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
348 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

EBut a single flue works somewhat better. The flue is warmer. 
ience the outward ' and upward movement of the foul air is 

Ehe iron register 12x16 inches for opening measurement should 
into the chimney within four inches from the floor (don't put 
in the chimney near the ceiling). Place the stove in a corner, 
one most out of the way. Don't put it in the center of the room. 
&gt; in the way then. 

Cut a hole in the floor 10 x 14 inches, over which place an iron 
register. Connect this opening with a box 10 x 10 inches wide and 
long enough to reach from the register in the floor to the outside of 
the foundation. Cover the end of the box with a coarse wire screen 
to keep out any animals. The box may be of wood or galvanized 
iron. '. Vood I believe is preferable. Surround the stove with a circular 
galvanized iron jacket 6 feet high and from 36 to 40 inches in 
diameter. The stove will determine the diameter of the jacket. 
Measure the diagonal base of the stove to determine the diameter of 
the jacket. Have a door 2J/2 feet by 4 feet cut in the jacket for removing 
the ashes and feeding the fire. Have the jacket strongly 
made. See to it that the door in the jacket is properly arranged so 
that ashes may easily be removed. 

I am often asked by school trustees, if the stove were placed in 
the center of the room, will not the heat be more uniformly distributed 
? I do not see how it can be. By this plan all the heat in 
the stove is forced by the flow of pure air from the outside through 
the fresh air box, directly to within a few feet from the ceiling. The 
only escape for it is through the foul air register in the chimney near 
:loor. The escape is by pressure. In a recent test of six schoolhouses 
the greatest variation found was three degrees, when measured 
the same distance from the floor. The thermometer should 
haag not to exceed forty inches from the floor. 

— The American School Board Journal, Chicago, July, 190 1. </seg>


            <seg id="p049">
li 

1 a 
::: 
5^ 

laoMQlMIKV </seg>
            <seg id="p050">
ll 

1 *? 
1*3 

r 

m i 

I; 

I 

o ' 

i 
0. i 

Wowanvn 

P 

I 
o 

h 
I* </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
349 


The Blair High School 

The new high school building at Blair was erected during the 
school yeaT 1899-1900 at a cost of nearly $40,000. This amount includes 
site, sidewalks, heating apparatus and about seven hundred 
dollars' worth of new furniture. Without these necessary accessories 
the building cost fully thirty thousand dollars. To pay for this 
building the School District City of Blair voted $32,000 in bonds, 
running twenty years with a ten-year option, with interest at four 
per cent. These bonds were sold at a premium of several hundred 
dollars, and the entire proceeds, together with nearly eight thousand 
dollars in cash in the treasury of the district, were expended in the 
erection of this magnificent building, under the supervision of the 
board, the architect, Mr. John Latenser of Omaha, and a superintendent 
of construction in the employ of the board. 

El total length of the building is 126 feet, its width is 79 feet 
end or wing is about 34 by 79 feet, and the central portion is 
j 60 feet square. It extends east and west, facing south. The 
main fronts are in the south and east. It is built of dark red pressed 
brick, with red stone trimmings, and with slate roof. The basement 
contains a boiler and fuel room in the northwest corner, toilet rooms 
under the twenty-five by twenty-eight foot schoolrooms, and vacant 
rooms in the three other corners. The first floor is devoted exclusively 
to primary and fifth grade pupils, and the second floor to the 
high school. The old Central building, containing the sixth, seventh, 
and eighth grades, is located to the northwest of the new building, 
but on the same block. 

All the walls shown on the first floor plan extend down through 
the basement to the foundation, with the exception of those between 
the hall and the two wardrobes near the center of the building ; and 
all those in and surrounding the two wings, the east and west ends, 
extend up to the roof. The inner walls of the central portion stop 
at the secon^ .oor, and the entire central portion forms on the second 
floor the high school assembly room. On the first floor there are six 
grade rooms. The two north central ones are occupied by third and 
fourth gradf". each with a seating capacity of forty-eight pupils. 
In these the children face east, and each room is lighted by five 
windows on the north, to the left of the children, and hall and door </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
350 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

windows to the right. There is slate blackboard on the front and 
rear walls of these two rooms, three and one-half feet in width, and 
above the front blackboard is another blackboard three feet in width, 
for writing copies, drills, and practice work. In each corner room 
there are five windows to the left of the children and two at the rear 
of the room. All east, south and west windows on both floors have 
opaque green shades with adjustable roller fixtures, permitting the 
rollers to be lowered from the top. Blackboards extend across the 
two inner walls of each corner room, three and one-half feet wide 
with three feet more above in the front, and three and one-half feet 
wide to the right. In every room there is an unbroken front wall from 
corner to corner. There fs a teacher's closet set into the wall to the 
right of the pupils. The ceilings are nearly twelve feet high. The 
pupils pass through the wardrobe and enter the rear of the room. 
The wardrobes are three feet six inches wide and have hooks numbered 
from one to sixty on the longer side. The steam-heated air 
enters each room near the ceiling, and the foul air vent is close to the 
floor, both openings being on the inner side wall of the room. The 
board of education room is used temporarily as a library. There is 
a drinking fountain on each floor. Each corner room has a seating 
capacity of fifty-four pupils. The two east ones are used for first 
and second grades, and the two west ones for the fifth grade. There 
are two other primary ward buildings in the city, but from the fifth 
grade up all pupils are concentrated at the new and old Central 
buildings. 

The high school assembly and study room has a seating capacity 
at present of 200 pupils, which may be increased to 225, leaving 
ample room for aisles. All the desks in the building are single ones. 
The pupils face east, receiving the main light from the north and 
left. The north windows are a little larger than the south ones. The 
ceiling of the assembly room is sixteen feet high, and is a beautiful 
design in corrugated metal. There are no pillars or posts in the 
room. Ten incandescent lamps, sixteen or thirty-two candle power 
at option, light the room at night. Slate blackboard extends across 
the front of the room, except at the opening, where there are double 
doors. There is a platform two steps high and six by fourteen 
feet in the front of the room. In the rear of the room near the corners 
are four bookcases built into the room, two on each side, with </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
\ 

« m 

"•I C 
» « -i 
« I S 
*. o 
I 

F*&lt;nc&lt;P«J %»» 

OKOSK. 

7 

r 
&gt; 

x 

X 
O 

o 

O&gt; 
rn 
8 
o 

I 
I 

c/i 
n 
x 
o 
o 
I" 

8 

? 

W*»D«OOf- 

J ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦ 

IS 
% . 2 

t 
Q 
o 
9 
r </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
g 

D 
x 
o 
x 
9S 
&lt; 
5 

3? 
o 
o 
K 
&gt;¦ 
j 
CD 
JJ 
M 
M 
&lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
351 


the entrance of the steam-heated air near the center of the room, and 
a foul air exit in each corner. 

THE BASEMENT 

The girls use the east entrance to the building^fxclusively, and 
the boys the west. After passing through the outer doors pupils 
may pass down to the toilet rooms in the basement in privacy, or up 
into the main hall. The toilet rooms also have outdoor north entrances 
for the use of the pupils of the old Central, and a trellis 
fence extends from one building to the other, dividing the grounds. 
As Rlair has no sewerage system, an improved system of dry closets 
is in use in the toilet rooms. The northeast and southwest corner 
basement rooms may be used in stormy weather for play or dinner, 
by the girls and boys respectively. The building is heated with 
steam. Radiators have been placed in halls and offices, but for the 
schoolrooms the indirect system, or gravity system, of heating and 
ventilating is used. The rooms in the basement directly below and 
corresponding to the first floor wardrobes are cold air chambers. 
There is no opening from these into the basement rooms, but there is 
a door into the hall or corridor. The basement window of these cold 
air rooms is kept open during the day, and the cold fresh air enters, 
is heated as it passes over and through coils of steam pipes, and then 
it passes up through flues to the rooms above, which it enters above 
the blackboards. By crank and chain the teacher may regulate the 
temperature of the fresh air that enters her room without reducing 
the amount of air. The raising and lowering of a damper attached to 
the chain permits the air to pass between the steam-heated coils, or 
around them, or partly between and partly around them. Foul air 
vents or exits are near the floor line, those of the second floor rooms 
being directly above the first floor inlets of fresh air ; the first floor 
outlets are built in between and divided from the two fresh air flues ; 
thus the columns of air in the foul air flues are heated and kept rising. 
The foul air vents for the two middle rooms on the first floor 
are in the floor, and galvanized iron ducts near the ceiling of the 
basement carry the foul air to the southeast and southwest corner 
stacks. The fresh air for the central portion of the building enters 
through the basement windows of the rooms below the secretary's 
and superintendent's offices, and is conducted through tunnels under 
the basement floor to cold air chambers below the wardrobes in the </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
352 


hall of the first floor. A flue from each of these passes up to the 
high school assembly room on the second floor, where the two have 
outlet into the room through registers fifty by twenty by thirty inches 
each. The foul air vents for the assembly room are in the four corners 
of the room, passing up and out through the ceiling and the 
highest parts of the roof. Steam and return pipes run from the boilers 
in the northwest corner to the system of direct radiation in the old 
C crural building. </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
i 
_ 
X 
o 
u 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
r™&lt; 

! 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
353 


Free High School Attendance 

Free attendance at public high schools for the graduates of our 
rural schools has agitated educational circles in Nebraska for many 
years. As each school district in the state is independent of all others 
in its organization, management and course of study, the pupils in 
rural communities do not have the advantages of those who live in 
the cities and villages where high schools have been established. 
Various laws have been devised to provide free instruction for the 
graduates of the rural schools in the established high schools of the 
cities and villages, but these laws have been successively declared unconstitutional 
or have proven to be unsatisfactory. That there is a 
demand for this free instruction cannot be successfully denied. The 
illustrations of the non-resident attendants at the high schools of 
Nelson, Ord and Auburn successfully prove this. In each of the 
high schools in these small cities there are enrolled a large number 
of pupils from the rural school districts round about. These pupils 
are, as a rule, and as their appearance indicates, the cream of the 
country schools, and not only maintain but raise the standard of the 
schools that they attend. The York County Graduates of 190a 
show the promising material that our rural schools furnish the high 
schools of the. state. This material should be assimilated. Every 
Kpil .in Nebraska should be granted free school privileges from 
: kindergarten to the university, as many now are. 

HIGH SCHOOL CADETS 

The military spirit is quite rife in the state and has been since the 
Spanish-American war. In many of the cities of Nebraska with a 
census of from 2,000 to 8,000 are found high school cadet organizations. 
The village of Elgin with a census of 250 children of school 
age has its company of high school cadets. 

LINCOLN COUNTY SUMMER SCHOOL 

On account of the lack of normal school facilities in the central 
and western portions of the state, summer schools held in connection 
with teachers' county institutes are common there. This illustration 
shows the type of the bright young people who teach school 
in the central and western portions of the state. This school was 
held during the summer of 1901* </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
354 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

WOMEN COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS 

Among the teachers of Nebraska, including city superintendents 
and principals, the women outnumber the men about three or four 
to one. Among the county superintendents the reverse is true with 
interest. At the present time there are sixteen women and seventyfour 
men among the county superintendents in the state. During 
the past biennium there were eighteen women. Mrs. Eva J. Case of 
Webster county retired from office January 9, 1902, after seven 
years' faithful and efficient work in that capacity. Miss Bertha 
Thoelecke retired from the office of superintendent of Lincoln 
county schools on January 9, 1902, after two terms of faithful and 
efficient service. Lincoln county is forty-eight by fifty-four miles 
in area, and is divided into 107 school districts. The dangers, privations 
and exposure to which the women county superintendents 
in the central and western portions of the state, the frontier counties, 
are exposed, are but little understood or appreciated, even by 
the people of their own counties. 

FILLMORE COUNTY TEACHERS' INSTITUTE, I902 

The teachers' institute is an annual evemt that is looked forward 
to with great interest by the teachers in many counties of Nebraska. 
It is the exchange and clearing house for a profession that gains its 
skill largely through experience and interchange of ideas. The 
Fillmore count)- teachers' institute for 1902, illustrated herein, faithfully 
portrays the selectness and intelligence, the beauty and 
strength, the true manhood and womanhood engaged in the teaching 
profession in Nebraska. The county superintendent occupies 
a central position in the front row, and the deputy state superin- </seg>


            <seg id="p061">
I 

I 

I 
</seg>
            <seg id="p062">I 

I 

i 
</seg>
            <seg id="p063">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUITM. 

355 

THE OLD MRLKOSK SCHOOLHOUSJC 

Eis a picture of the first schoolhouse in Melrosc, the first 
seat of Harlan county. This log schoothooM Mi all olhar 
js in Melrose have long since been removed or rand to Ike 
ground, as the county seat is now Alma. This bufldsag was 
erected in 1872 for a shoe shop, but it soon after cane into posse* 
sion of the school district and for many years served at a schootbouse. 
The other buildings in the town were nearly all removed 
to Orleans before 1878, but this schoolhouse was used for school 
purposes until 1885, when the school district was united with aa 
adjoining district. The photograph was taken in 18R3. Principal 
Harry F. Hooper, of Dorchester, owns the photograph from which 
our illustration was made and prizes it highly. He is the boy in 
the illustration who stands nearest the doorway. 

CEDAR BLUFFS GRADUATES 

One of the happiest annual events in the public school* of nearly 
all the smaller cities and villages in the state is the graduating exercises 
held at the close of the school year. Many of the villages 
maintain but one-, two-, or three-year high school courses, bat these 
schools make as great preparation for their "commenennent" exercises 
as the larger cities and, in fact, as many colleges and universities 
do. We present herewith an illustration of one of the 
bright classes in a village of a few hundred inhabitant*. 

BROWNVILLE SCHOOLHOUSE AND GROUNDS 

The Brownville school building was erected in 1866 at a coat of 
$30,000. It is of brick and consists of two stories and a baaaasaaL 
The main part of the building is forty-eight by sixty feet and the 
vestibule, which reaches the entire height, is ten by twenty feet. 
There are seven rooms twenty-four by thirty feet and a high school 
assembly room thirty by forty-eight feet. The bniiifif was dasigned 
to be heated with a furnace, but after a manbtr of jean 
the furnace was discarded and stoves are now used. 

The school grounds contain about three acres, ornamented with 
ninety shade trees, including oak, elm, catalpa, and one very fine 
linden tree nearly three feet in diameter. The old oaks shows) sa 
the illustration of Brownville Public School Grounds were large 
trees when the grounds were laid out for a public school site in </seg>

            <seg id="p064">
356 


ri Under these trees the future congressman, David H. Merand 
his schoolmates used to fill their pockets with acorns thirty 
years ago to make one another "come into camp" as do the youngsters 
of to-day, and under these same trees the teachers of Nemaha 
count)' hold a picnic from year to year. 

The high school department was opened in 1869 under the supervision 
of Chas. A. Baker, a graduate of Harvard. At one time the 
enrollment in all departments exceeded 600. For a number of 
years one of the rooms in the basement was used as a schoolroom, 
but as "westward the course of empire took its way," the school 
gradually declined until about five years ago, when there were only 
three teachers employed. This year there are 175 pupils under the 
charge of four teachers. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">

* 

&gt; 

* 

K 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p066">
s 

Z 

s </seg>



            <seg id="p067">
Rural School Conditions in Nebraska 

A general idea of the kind of school buildings in -this state may 
be gathered from the illustrations and descriptions in this publication, 
from the statistical table utowmg the numlx.'r of frame, 
brick, stone, log and sod schoolhouses in each county in the state 
during the school year 1900-1901, and Table Xo. I, showing the 
changes in the number of schoolhouses of the different materials 
from the year 1869 to 1902. Space forbids extended description of 
conditions in each of the ninety counties in the state, but we herewith 
submit information gathered by letter and by personal visitation 
in a number of representative counties. The conditions in different 
parts of the state are. so vastly different that personal inspection 
only would convince one of it or impress one with the difference in 
problems presented to any one concerned or interested in school 
conditions in Nebraska and their improvement. 

BANNER COUNTY 

Pere is a county in the extreme western portion of the state on 
Wyoming line, without a high school or a railroad in it. At the 
ity seat two teachers are employed, a term of eight months of 
ol is held during the year, and the principal is paid $30 per 
th. One-half the number of schoolhouses in the county are furnished 
with patent desks and slate blackboards. The other half 
have home-made desks and wooden blackboards. There are five 
districts in the county having practically no outhouses on the school 
grounds. 

BLAINE COUNTY 

Blaine county is situated in the central portion of the state. In 
this county there are nine rural schoolhouses. Two of these are 
frame and the rest are built of sod. In two there are patent desks, 
in two others there are both home-made and patent desks, and in five 
schoolhouses there are home-made desks only. Three buildings are 
furnished with slate blackboard, while the others have painted 
boards. One district has two separate outhouses, three have two 
under the same roof, and the rest have one or practically none. Two 
of the schools in Blaine county graduated pupils from the eighth </seg>

            <seg id="p068">
358 


county, although in some schools higher branches are being taught. 
Teachers are being paid from $25 to $40 per month. The county 
superintendent writes that quite an interest is being manifested by 
both patrons and pupils and that in the near future Elaine county 
will rank among the first in education. 

BOX BUTTE COUNTY 

This county is in the extreme northwestern part of the state. 
There are about sixty schoolhouses in the county, and nearly one-half 
the children in the county are in the city of Alliance. There are 
sixty-five square miles unorganized into school districts with perhaps 
a score or two of children living in this unorganized territory. 
About one-half the buildings have patent desks and the others homemade 
ones. Thirteen rooms have slate blackboards, five have hyloplate, 
five have cloth, four have plaster and twenty-nine have wooden 
blackboards. Nearly all schools are supplied with maps and charts, 
and all but two furnish text-books to pupils. 

CASS COUNTY 

E county is situated in the eastern portion of the state on the 
iri river. There are an even hundred school districts in this 
w . Five of these are organized as high school districts, viz., 
Plattsmouth, Weeping Water, Louisville, Greenwood and Elmwood. 
Union, Nehawka, Avoca, Eagle, Alvo, Murdock, South 
Bend and Murray are graded village schools employing two or 
three teachers. All the above are fairly well equipped with furniture, 
apparatus, etc. All except Nehawka and Murray are under the 
free text-book system. All the rural schools of the county have 
patent desks, though a considerable number have the senseless, noisy, 
out-of-repair folding desks. A large number of the schools have 
seats too large for the smaller pupils, and many of the desks are too 
far apart. This is a matter of great importance. One district has a 
paper blackboard, three have both wood and plaster, two have cloth, 
six hyloplate, thirteen wood, twenty-eight plaster and forty-seven 
have slate. Nearly all the blackboards are in good condition. Special 
attention has been paid to such matters. Ninety-five have two 
separate outhouses, three are under one roof and two have but one 
outhouse. Less than two years ago there were more than a dozen </seg>


            <seg id="p069">
t/i 

z 

tf </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
- 

I 

i 

i 

u 
Q 

R 

1 

! 

I 

1 

I 

k 

* 

1 

a 

1 

v 

I 

« </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

359 

DEUEL COUNTY 

Pere is another county in the western portion of the state, large 
rea, largely unorganized, with the Union Pacific railroad i 
through the extreme southern portion and the Burlington just 
beyond the northern boundary. There are about fifty schools in the 
county, thirty of which have home-made desks. About twenty-five 
have slate blackboards and the others are supplied with wooden 
blackboards. Every schoolhouse in the county has two separate 
outhouses. 

HITCHCOCK COUNTY 

This county is in the southwestern portion of the state. Threefourths 
of the schoolhouses are provided with patent desks. The 
others have home-made desks or some home-made and some patent 
ones. About one-fourth of them have slate blackboards, but the 
majority have plaster boards. One-half the districts have two separate 
outhouses, the others having but one each. The latter are 
mostly small schools of a few pupils. Some of their school boards 
thought it wise to procure a bookcase instead of erecting an additional 
outhouse. 

LINCOLN COUNTY 

I This is a large county in the west-central portion of the state, 
rty-eight by fifty-four miles in extent. It is crossed from west to 
st by the Platte river and the Union Pacific railroad. There are 
more than twenty sod schoolhouses in this county, but the schoolhouses 
generally are quite well furnished. Sixty-two school grounds 
are fenced, mostly with barb wire, while sixty-four others are not 
fenced. There are one hundred twenty-four buildings with patent 
desks and only two with home-made ones. Slate blackboards are 
found in seventy-seven houses, plaster boards in seventeen houses, 
wood in thirteen, hyloplate in eleven and cloth blackboards in eight 
school buildings. Seventy-five districts have a coal house, forty-one 
have a coal box. Eighty-four districts have two separate outhouses, 
twenty-four have two under one roof, sixteen have but one such 
building, and two have none. </seg>

            <seg id="p072">
360 

8TATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

RICHARDSON COUNTY 

This county is in the southeastern corner of the state, bordering 
on Kansas and Missouri. During the last term five new schoolhouses 
were erected, but as the county is an old one and was early 
settled there are many more that should be replaced soon. There 
are over one hundred schools in the county and all are provided 
with patent desks. Forty have slate blackboards, twenty have plaster, 
forty-four have wooden, and a few have some cloth or paper or hyloplate. 
Nearly all schools are fairly well equipped, but a few of the 
poorest districts are very inadequately provided with anything. 

SARPY CQUNTY 

EPhis is a county in the east-central portion of the state, south of 
uglas of which Omaha is the county seat. All schools are proed 
with patent desks, a few of which are in bad repair, and many 
of these are being replaced with single desks. About one-half the 
schools have slate blackboard. The others have plaster or painted 
boards. All have blackboards of some kind. This county has the 
two extremes in design of frame schoolhouses. The older buildings 
are of the familiar old box-car style, while the new ones are being 
built on modern plans. 

SAUNDERS COUNTY 

Saunders county is situated in the east-central portion of the 
state. Nearly all the schools in this county are provided with patent 
desks. There are a few home-made ones in two or three schools. 
Four-fifths of the schools have some slate blackboard ; many of them 
have nothing else. There are eight or ten with wooden boards, a 
few with plaster boards, and a few other schools with other kinds of 
boards, but all the schools in the county are provided with blackboards, 
and the slate boards are rapidly displacing all other kinds. 
There is not a district in the county without two outhouses, and 
only a few that have the two nnder one roof. </seg>


            <seg id="p073">
Si 

li 
as a 
S3 

1 

&lt; 5" 
U g 
&gt; s 
UJ « </seg>
            <seg id="p074">
r 

rf </seg>

            <seg id="p075">
361 


Our Illustrations 

The illustrations in this volume are believed to be fairly representative 
of the general appearance and condition of school buildings 
in Nebraska. Certain types, perhaps, predominate, and other typical 
buildings in the state are not represented, but a careful scrutiny of 
these illustrations and a study of Statistical Table No. I near the 
close of the volume, exhibiting the number of schoolhouses of wood, 
brick, stone, log and sod, respectively, will prevent one from forming 
a wrong impression of the actual material school conditions in 
Nebraska. The log schoolhouses form less than two per cent of 
the total number of schoolhouses in Nebraska, and the sod houses 
less than seven per cent of the total. Some of the latter may be 
valued at little more than the cost of the doors and door frames, the 
window sashes and window frames, the flooring, and the shingles 
where they have a shingle roof ; and from this low valuation we 
must range up all the way by hundreds, thousands, and tens of 
thousands of dollars to almost two hundred thousand dollars to include 
the cost of all the several kinds of school buildings in t!:e 
state. The value of. school district property in the state is estimate I 
at nearly ten millions of dollars. 

Although representative, these illustrations are not used here as 
models for school buildings. Some of them are far from it. Nearly 
all the photographs and cuts received at the state department are 
here used, principally for the purpose of showing what exists in the 
state and the great differences in conditions. Some of the frame 
and brick buildings herein pictured are very poorly arranged within, 
incorrectly lighted, without any ventilation except by doors and 
windows, and sometimes when the arrangement of windows makes 
an excellent light any good results have been counteracted by an improper 
placing and arrangement of the desks. The Sutherland rural 
schoolhouse in district No. 20 of Washington county, the new brick 
schoolhouse in district No. 3 of Fillmore county, the Calhoun building, 
the Blair high school building and the Omaha buildings, with a 
few others, may be referred to as models. 

One great obstacle to the erection of better school buildings in 
Nebraska is the small size of many of the districts and their consequent 
low assessed valuation. The school laws of Nebraska say that 
</seg>
            <seg id="p076">
362 


bonds for the purpose of purchasing a site for, and erecting thereon, 
a schoolhouse or schoolhouses may be voted and issued in an aggregate 
amount not to exceed five per cent of the last complete assessment 
of the taxable property of the district, except in districts having 
more than two hundred children of school age ; in districts having 
two hundred or more children, the amount of bonded indebtedness 
must not exceed ten per cent of the last complete assessed valuation. 
In many rural school districts of Nebraska the assessed valuation is 
only a few thousand dollars, and five per cent of the amount will not 
raise five hundred dollars for the purchase of a site and the erection 
of a schoolhouse thereon ; sometimes not two-thirds of the amount 
can be realized. In many villages of the state employing three or 
four teachers, with a school census of 150 to 190 children, requiring 
a four-room school building, the total assessed valuation is often 
not in excess of $50,000, five per cent of which would not build 
much more than one-half of a good four-room school building. The 
remedy lies in larger, richer, more populous school districts. Small 
districts with a few children are too highly expensive. 

NEW OMAHA HIGH SCHOOL BUILDING 

Omaha, the metropolis of Nebraska, very naturally boasts of the 
finest high school building in the state. The east wing only of the 
new building is now completed at a cost of about $190,000. It was 
dedicated Saturday, February 1, 1902, and on the following Monday 
morning the Omaha high school moved into its new commodious 
quarters. This wing contains about thirty rooms, including eighteen 
class rooms, two study rooms, laboratories, library, gymnasium, office 
rooms, etc. The class rooms are twenty-four feet square and 
designed to accommodate thirty pupils each. The study rooms 
will seat about 200 pupils in each. In place of cloak rooms 540 
double lockers are provided in the halls, and there are also twelve 
toilet rooms, four on each floor. The indirect system of steam heating 
is used and the plenum system of fan ventilation. Natural slate 
blackboards are used throughout. The lighting is from the left and 
rear of the pupils as they are seated. The building is solid and substantial 
in construction, artistic in exterior appearance and beautiful 
in interior finish, and constructed of the best material throughout. 
In future years the old high school building, of which all except 
the tower is now hidden from view from the east, will be removed </seg>


            <seg id="p077">
THE OLD MELROSE SCHOOLHOUSE </seg>

            <seg id="p078">CEDAR BLUFFS PUBLIC SCHOOLS GRADUATES OF 1902 </seg>

            <seg id="p079">
363 

SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

and a building similar to the illustration following that of the wag 
will take its place. 

DISTRICT SCHOOLS IN HALL COUNTY 

The school building in district No. 70 of Hall county was erected 
in the fall of 1886 at a cost of about $500. It contains patent desks, 
a blackboard made of poplar lumber and lampblack, bat no apparatus. 
The schoolroom is heated by a stove and ventilated by windows. 
There is a cloak room, although it is probably in darkness, 
and the schoolroom is lighted by three windows on each side. 

Pt school building in district No. 51 was erected in 1888 at a 
)f about $300. It contains patent desks, a small amo—t of 
blackboard and some charts. There is no entry way or cloak 
room, and, like the schoolhouse in district No. 70 and many others 
in all parts of Nebraska, it is lighted by three windows on each aide. 
It is heated by a stove and ventilated by windows. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 54, CHERRY COUNTY 

This sod schoolhouse was erected in 1897 at a cost of $50. The 
photograph of it was probably taken during an eclipse. It contains 
home-made furniture, about five feet of painted blackboard and no 
apparatus. It is lighted by one window on each side. There is no 
system of ventilation and none is needed. The irregular appear* 
ance of the comers is caused by cattle rubbing against them. The 
Eg is now protected by a wire fence. The roof is covered with 
"his is not a typical Cherry county schoolhousr Many good 
school buildings have been erected in that county within the 
ree years. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 69, BOCK COUNTY 

Eis building was not erected for school purposes. It is a home. 
chool is held in it It was erected in 1895 *"&lt;- * rnraashed 
modern desks, wooden blackboards, no apparatus and a slave, 
ighting is, naturally enough, very poor, while the chief charstic 
of the building is its warmth. 

WASHINGTON SCHOOL, NE1IAHA COUNTY 

This school is in district No. 24, and is just the ordinary type of 
school buildincr to be found in many school districts in the soath* </seg>

            <seg id="p080">
364 


eastern portion of the state. The teacher, Miss Hattie Miller, and 
the county superintendent, W. C. Parriott, both appear in the 
illustration. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. I, MERRICK COUNTY 

Fhis schoolhouse was erected in 1885 at a cost of about $1,200. 
I located at Lockwood station on the Union Pacific railroad, in 
southeastern corner of Merrick county. Its outward appearance 
is much the same as other schoolhouses in the eastern portion of the 
state. There are about thirty-five pupils enrolled, and the teacher, 
Mr. Edw. D. Patterson, is now serving his eighth year in that 
district. As may be seen in the illustration, it contains single desks, 
slate blackboard, a liberal supply of maps and charts, a dictionary, 
library, museum, etc. There are, however, no cloak rooms, and no 
system of heating and ventilating other than by the stove and windows. 
The room is lighted from the left, right and rear. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 19, FRONTIER COUNTY 

This curiosity in the shape of a school building was erected about 
1892 at a cost of $15. It is not a representative schoolhouse and 
never was. It was replaced in the summer of 1901 by a good frame 
schoolhouse. It contained home-made furniture, a small wooden 
blackboard, no apparatus, a stove and a system of ventilation through 
chinks in the wall. There was a door in one side and a window in 
each of the three other sides. Nearly all the school districts in 
Frontier county have good frame buildings, old-fashioned perhaps, 
but commodious enough and well furnished. There is only one 
log schoolhouse in existence in that county at present, and it is 
well built and properly furnished. 

THE LONG SCHOOL, OMAHA 

This building and the other Omaha buildings illustrated in this 
volume were all designed by Mr. John Latenser. The Long school 
cost nearly $25,000. It contains eight school rooms, an office and 
a supply room. There are also play rooms in the basement. All 
grades below the high school, including the kindergarten, are represented. 
The furniture, blackboard and interior finish are all of 
the best. It is heated with a furnace, and the gravity system of 
ventilation is in use. There are both cloak rooms and toilet rooms </seg>


            <seg id="p081">
k 

r^ 

r - 

I 

1 

I 

I 

A </seg>
            <seg id="p082">
I 

•"¦ 

m 

- 

™ 

1 </seg>

            <seg id="p083">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUltDo&gt; 

365 

Hi the building. All schoolrooms in buildings designed by Mr. 
Latenser are lighted from the left of the pupils by four, five or »r* 
windows, with perhaps two to the rear. 

FRANKLIN PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected a little more than a year ago at • 
cost of $8,000. It contains seven schoolrooms, two recitation rnnnw 
and a library, and it houses all the grades from the first to the tenth 
inclusive. The desks are patent ones, partly single and partly 
double. Green hyloplate blackboards are in use. It was botk 
for a system of heating by means of hot air, but stoves are Mil 
being used. There is no system of ventilation, but it contains cloak 
rooms. Some of the rooms are lighted from the left and rear, 
some from the right and rear. It contains broad halls and stairways, 
with three exits. The interior arrangement it quilt 
convenient. 

CALHOUN PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This is a model four-room frame school building erected oat 
year ago at a cost of about $6,000. Besides the four schoolroom 
it contains an office. It is the only school building in Calho— tad 
accommodates the ten grades there. One room has been seated 
with new single seats, while in the others the double seats from the 
old building are in use. The plaster blackboards are still in use, 
but at any time in the future these may be covered with natural 
slate. The building is properly heated and ventilated by the hot 
air system. All schoolrooms are lighted from the left and rear. 
A complete description of the floor plans of the building is givea 
elsewhere under Model Plans for Village Schools. 

THREE NORTH PLATTE HIGH SCHOOLS 

These illustrations show the evolution of the high school in oat 
of the most enterprising cities in the western portion of the state. 
North Platte, on the Union Pacific railroad. We have here the first 
log schoolhouse erected in the town in 1868, the old -fashioned 
brick schoolhouse that took its place in 1873, an&lt; ' tne modern high 
school building erected two years ago at a cost of $30,000. Thai 
latter contains an assembly room, eight schoolrooms, four class 
rooms, two office rooms and a library. There are also cloak tad </seg>

            <seg id="p084">
366 


toilet rooms. All grades from the sixth to the twelfth inclusive 
are represented in this building. Excellent new single desks, slate 
blackboard and all apparatus required for efficient school work are 
supplied. The building is properly heated by steam arid ventilated 
with air flues from each room. The rooms are also properly 
lighted. 

SUPERIOR SCHOOL BUILDINGS 

The North school in Superior was erected in 1890 at a cost of 
$12,000. It contains four rooms with grades below the eighth only. 
It is seated with single desks, furnished with plaster blackboard 
and heated with steam. It is ventilated, but the windows were 
arranged with reference to their appearance from the outside 
rather than with reference to the convenience and the eye-sight of 
the children within. 

The Superior high school building was erected in 1885 at a cost 
of $14,500. It contains eight rooms, including rooms for the first 
three primary grades, two laboratories, assembly and recitation 
rooms and an office. Its other equipment, heating and ventilation 
are similar to the North building of Superior. 

PLEASANT PRAIRIE SCHOOL, PAWNEE COUNTY 

This schoolhouse is located in District No. 14. It was erected 
in 1893 or 1894 at a cost of about $1,700. It is built of brick, and 
contains a large schoolroom that will seat seventy-two pupils in 
single desks. There is slate blackboard around the entire room, 
and it is well provided with maps, charts and apparatus generally. 
It is located three miles east of Pawnee City in the center of a 
school district comprising nine sections of land, with a total assessed 
valuation of $53,275. There are windows on all four sides of the 
room. The front and rear walls appear in the illustrations. The 
building has a tower with a large bell in it. The district has nine 
months of school each year, and pays the teacher a good salary. 

EUSTIS PUBLIC SCHOOL 

The illustrations used are of the intermediate department at 
Eustis. There is in that little village a two-room building erected 
in 1888 at a cost of $1400, containing the intermediate and grammar 
departments, and a one-room building for the primary department 
erected in 1899. The tw o buildings have a full block of </seg>



            <seg id="p087">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

367 

NEBRASKA STATE NORMAL SCHOOL BUILDINGS 

The Nebraska State Normal School is situated in the village of 
Peru, Nemaha county. The school grounds comprise sixty acres 
of native forest trees, located on the south side of town. The school 
buildings are upon an eminence overlooking the Missouri river, is 
a grove of oak and elm. The Campus is unsurpassed for natural 
beauty. The diversified landscape and rich flora and fauna afford 
rare opportunity for field work in science. 

Etie buildings consist of Normal Hall (the main recitation aad 
inistration building), the Library, the Greenhouse, the Power 
se, Mount Vernon Hall (the ladies' dormitory), and the Observatory. 
To these should be added the standpipe, the pumping 
station, the icehouse, and the carpenter shop in estimating the completeness 
of a material equipment equaled by few state normal 
schools. The Athletic Field, the basket ball grounds, and the lawn 
tennis courts furnish opportunities for healthful outdoor recreation. 
The buildings are heated by steam, and lighted by electricity. The 
Chapel, class-rooms, and model-school rooms — now newly repaired, 
refurnished, and improved — are well adapted to the work of the 
school ; and improvements are being made constantly to meet thr 
needs of the growing school. 

The Nebraska State Normal School came into being with th« 
public school system of the State. In providing for the education 
of her youth Nebraska planned from the first for the training of 
her teachers. The State Normal School had its beginning in th« 
year 1866 as the "Mount Vernon College," a private school under 
the control of the Methodist Episcopal Church. The first terra of 
this private school opened August 29, 1866, with thirty-eight students 
enrolled. The Principal, J. M. McKenzie. was the only 
teacher in this term. In August of the following year, the year in 
which Nebraska became a State in the Union, the property of this 
College, sometimes spoken of as the "Peru Seminary," was turned 
over to the Board of Education of the State Normal School. The 
first term of the "Nebraska State Normal School" opened October 
24, 1867, with three regular teachers, Mr. and Mrs. McKenzie aad 
Mr. P. M. Martin. Mr. McKenzie was Principal for four yean 
and was followed in rapid succession by Mr. Straight. Mr. Williams. 
General Morgan, Mr. Nichol, Mr. Wilson, Mr. Freeman, Mr. </seg>

            <seg id="p088">
368 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Thompson, and Dr. Curry, some of these gentlemen serving as Acting 
Principal for a few months only. No one served as Principal 
more than two years from Mr. McKenzie to Dr. Curry. Beginning 
with Dr. Curry in 1873, tne tenure of office has been somewhat more 
secure, though changes have been still too frequent to permit the 
working out of an educational policy by the Principal. Dr. Curry 
•erved six years ; Dr. Farnham, ten years ; Mr. Norton, three years ; 
and Dr. Beattie, four years. 

The first building for the school, known as "Mount Vernon 
Hall," was erected in 1866 by a subscription from citizens amounting 
to $8,000. This was a brick building eighty feet long by forty 
feet wide, three stories high. The Legislature in 1869 appropriated 
$10,000 for refitting this building and for current expenses of the 
school. Mount Vernon Hall was destroyed by fire in January, 1897. 
and was rebuilt in the same year as a modern dormitory with accommodations 
for ninety-four young ladies. The north wing of 
Normal Hall (the main recitation building) was erected in 1872 at 
m cost of $28,000. This building was enlarged in 1885 by the large 
south wing, containing the present Chapel, the Laboratories, and 
additional recitation rooms, at a cost of $20,000. The Library 
building, a frame structure costing $15,000, was built in 1887; the 
heating and lighting plant was built in the same y«ar. A good 
system of water supply was provided in 1896, which was completed 
by an eighty-foot steel standpipe in 1900. In the same year a large 
icehouse was built on the dormitory grounds ; and in the following 
year the Greenhouse and the Athletic Field were added to the equipment 
by private subscription. 

OMAHA GRADED SCHOOLS 

The Cass, Saunders and Pacific schools of Omaha are all much 
alike in their general plan and convenience of interior arrangement. 

The Cass school was erected in 1900 at a cost of $49,000. In 
size it is what is known as a sixteen-room building and in addition 
to the sixteen schoolrooms contains one principal's office, one teachers' 
room and play rooms in the basement. The eight grades below 
the high school are all represented in this building. It is furnished 
with the best single desks and natural slate blackboard. The indirect 
system of steam heating is used and the gravity system of 
ventilation. There is one cloak room in connection with each schoolroom 
and two toilet rooms in the basement, one for each sex. The </seg>

            <seg id="p089">
i 
0\ I O 

K£ ' MOUJi 

BASKETBALL 
GR0UUD5 

STAMP PI f&gt;F 

Mill 

A/O/fM/ 

ave: 

LIBRARY 

im 

CARPENTER SHOP 

6REEVH0I/SC. 

POWEfiHO&lt;/3£ 

ATHlET/C r/tLM </seg>

            <seg id="p090">
i 

¦ 

! 

i 

i 

I 

t </seg>

            <seg id="p091">
369 


pupils in each room are seated so as to face an unbroken front wmfl, 
with five or six windows at the left and two in the rear of the room. 

The Saunders school was erected in 1900 at a cost of $32,000. 
It contains ten schoolrooms, a principal's office, a teachers' room aid 
play rooms in the basement. It is similar to the Cass school in the 
features mentioned above, except that a furnace is used in hcatatf 
and a fan in ventilating. 

The Pacific school was erected in 1900 at a cost of $48,000. It 
is also a sixteen-room building and is very similar to the Caw 
school in interior arrangements and conveniences, heating, ventilation, 
cloak and toilet rooms. A greater difference is apparent in 
the illustrations of the Cass and Pacific schools than can be found 
when one is within the buildings. The differences are mainly in 
the "trimmings," although it cannot be honestly said that either 
building is over-trimmed. They are architecturally beautiful m 
their simplicity. 

SIDNEY PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1887 at a cost of $17,500. It it a 
substantial stone structure, although the entire roof and gable endi 
are of wood. It contains six schoolrooms, two recitation room*, 
one study and one library room. The furniture is modern and the 
blackboard a natural slate. The building is heated with a furnace 
and ventilated. It contains cloak rooms, but the schoolrooms are 
lighted from the left and rear or from the right and rear according 
to location. 

STERLING PUBLIC SCHOOL 

There are a number of school buildings in the state of Nebraska 
quite similar to the Sterling building in structure and appearaSGC 
The Syracuse building illustrated elsewhere differs but little from 
the Sterling schoolhouse. This building was erected in 1890 at a 
cost of $10,000. It contains six schoolrooms, and they have eleven 
grades in the building. The furniture is good, the blackboanls are 
concrete an&lt;J there is a fair supply of apparatus. The building i* 
heated with a furnace and properly ventilated. There are cloak 
rooms in connection with the schoolrooms, and the •chootrooaB) 
are lighted from the left and rear. 

COLERIDGE PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This four-room school building was erected in 1889 at a coat of 
$5,000. There are ten grades here, good furniture, slate black- </seg>

            <seg id="p092">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

370 

Psome apparatus. The rooms are heated with stoves with 
ent amount of ventilation through chimney flues. Cloak 
provided, but the light enters the schoolrooms from three 

CEDAR BLUFFS PUBLIC SCHOOL 

Piis schoolhouse is in district No. 107 of Saunders county. Part 
was erected fifteen years ago, and part of it last year, and it 
be seen in the illustration that no improvement was made in 
architecture on the addition. The cost of the building was 
about $6,000. It contains six rooms, including four schoolrooms, 
one recitation or office room and one room not finished. There are 
ten grades represented here. The high school room contains single 
seats, the others double ones. In three of the rooms there is slate 
blackboard. The rooms are heated with stoves with no arrange- 
Eit for ventilation. The halls are large and are used for cloak 
ms. The rooms are lighted from three sides. The building is 
vided with a fire escape. 

ANSELMO PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1889 at a cost of about $2,500. It 
is a four-room building, although only two of the rooms are now in 
use. The blackboards are of plaster. The rooms are heated with 
stoves and without a system of ventilation. The halls are used as 
Elk rooms. The building was poorly constructed so that it was 
essary to expend $400 on repairs recently. It is now reported 
&gt;e in good condition. 

DISTRICT SCHOOLS IN HALL COUNTY 

The schoolhouse in district No. 13 was erected in 1898 at a cost 
of $1,200. This building is like many another in the state, but it 
is larger than the average. There is a cloak room or entry way 
and a large, roomy schoolroom. This room is quite attractive with 
new desks, a good heating stove, clean walls, pictures, mottoes, 
etc., all of which make the room appear very homelike. The result 
is an excellent school spirit in that district and a crowded schoolroom 
whenever special day exercises are held. 

The schoolhouse in district No. 74 is a duplicate of the building 
in district No. 1 of Hall county. The latter is quite fully described 
• number of pages further on. </seg>

            <seg id="p093">
&gt; 
I 

I 
o 
X </seg>

            <seg id="p094">. 

— 

IB </seg>


            <seg id="p095">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROCVM. 

371 

GENEVA SCHOOLS 

The Geneva ward school, a two-room building, was okM ta 
1888 at a cost of $4,000. The first and second primary grades only 
are housed here. The building is a brick one with slate blackboards 
but it is heated with stoves, ventilated by means of door* and windows, 
and the rooms are lighted from the right of the childw. 

The interior view is of a third grade schoolroom in the high 
school building. 

The Geneva high school building, illustrated further on, was 
erected in 1883 at a cost of $7,000. It contains six 11 liiiiilnis— 
and one recitation room, and all of the grades from the third to 
the eleventh. The building shown in the illustration to the NV 
of the high school building is also used for school purposes and 
contains two rooms. The high school building contains slate Mackboards, 
good furniture and apparatus and is heated with Hutu 
without a system of ventilation. There are no cloak rooms m 
connection with the schoolrooms. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 7 OF PERKINS COUWTf 

Pis schoolhouse was erected in the fall of 1900 at a cost of JQ4-building 
represents three years of hard saving and piaaaaag 
on the part of the district. One year they went without school entirely, 
and then had to join two districts together in order to pat 
$200 with which to build this schoolhouse. The blackboards art 
home-made, and the ventilation is accidental and inci«lentaL Perhaps 
the chief characteristic of the building is the cheapness with 
which it was constructed. 

MINDKN HIGH SCHOOL 

This building was erected three years ago. It contains an assent 
My room, four recitation rooms, two laboratories and three graded 
schoolrooms, the latter for the accommodation of the fourth, nfth 
and sixth grades. It contains good furniture and apparatus and 
slate blackboard, and the building is heated with steam, bat is act 
ventilated. There are cloak rooms but no toilet rooms in the baild 
ing. The rooms generally are lighted from the left and rear. 

MAPLE GROVE SCHOOL, HAMILTON COCHTT 

This schoolhouse is located in district No. 14, two and OBO-awl 
miles southwest of Aurora. It was erected in 1885 a* a coat of </seg>

            <seg id="p096">
372 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

$1,000. There are two cloak rooms and a vestibule besides the 
schoolroom proper. It is seated with both single and double desks 
and has slate blackboards. The building itself is twenty-two by 
thirty-six feet with a twelve-foot ceiling. There is a large basement 
in the building walled up with limestone and divided into two 
compartments, one for coal and the other for cobs. The stairway 
is on the inside. The school grounds include three acres, covered 
with blue grass and surrounded with three rows of trees, ash, 
maple and box-elder. The flag seen in the illustration was won at 
a county fair. There is a twenty-foot flag pole not seen in the 
illustration. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 33, LINCOLN COUNTY 

The schoolhouse in this district was erected in 1889 at a cost of 
$2,500. It contains two schoolrooms, a grammar department and 
a primary department. There are patent school desks, slate blackboards 
and $800 worth of various kinds of apparatus. The rooms 
are heated with stoves but not ventilated. There are also cloak 
rooms and a sliding partition between the two schoolrooms. The 
district lies in the valley between the North and South Platte rivers 
in the heart of the oldest irrigated section of Lincoln county. The 
yard contains two acres of land and is fenced with posts and 
piping. It contains all kinds of fruit trees with a row of Carolina 
poplars around the outer edge. The district pays as high as $50 
a month to its teachers. 

ABIE PUBLIC SCHOOLS 

Abie is noted for the honor of always appearing first in the 
*'pr.*betical list of the graded schools of the state. The larger 
bail ding in the illustration was erected in 1887 at a cost of $1,000 
and the smaller one in 1896 at a cost of $500. The rooms are 
seated with double desks and heated with Move*. There is 110 system 
of ventilation. The light enters from three sides. The blackboards 
are made of slated paper. The buildings are located on a 
high hill overlooking the village. 

BURWELL PUBLIC SCHOOL 

I The schoolhouse was erected in 1898 at a cost of about $1,800, 
d burned in the spring of 1902. It contained four schoolrooms, 
each about twenty by thirty-two feet, entirely too narrow. Tea 
grades were represented in the building. The rooms were fur- </seg>

            <seg id="p097">
HASTINGS HIGH SCHOOL </seg>


            <seg id="p099">
373 

SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

nished with double desks and slate blackboards. The building wm 
heated with a furnace, but ventilated by means of the window*. 
The light entered from the left and rear of the pupils on one aide 
of the building, from the right and rear on the other side. Barwell 
has voted bonds for the erection of a new and a better buildinf . 

SCRIBNER PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This is an excellent six-room brick school building that cost abort 
$12,000 with site. There is a seventh room for recitation parposes. 
It is furnished with single desks, slate blackboard ami 
excellent apparatus. The rooms are heated with steam with ventilating 
flues in the chimneys. There are no cloak rooms or toilet 
rooms in the building. The children hang their wraps in the haiways. 
The pupils face a middle wall, receiving the main light frosa 

The interior views represent the high school with a beginning 
Latin class at the blackboard under the instruction of Prin. Chm. 
Arnot, now superintendent of Dodge county ; another high school 
class with Miss Eliza Scherzer as teacher ; the intermediate department 
with Miss Jessie R. Inches, teacher; and a grammar dt- 
Sment with Miss Nellie G. Golder, teacher. As may be seen fcy 
clocks in the illustrations, these views were taken shortly after 
call in the afternoon, and show the pupils at their regular 
•ol work in its every-day routine. 

KEARNEY PUBLIC SCHOOLS 

The Longfellow school in Kearney was erected in 1892 at a eoet 
of $40,000. This is the high school building of Kearney and otmtains 
thirteen rooms, including assembly room, recitation room*, 
laboratories, offices, library and two first primary schoolroom*. It 
is modern in construction, with single desks, recitation benches 
with arms, slate blackboards throughout and a full equipment of 
apparatus for teaching all the sciences. The Smead system of 
heating and ventilating is used. There are separate cloak rooms 
for the boys and girls and toilet rooms in the basement. The 
lighting is principally from the left, but with high windows in the 
rear. The halls are wide, with easy stairways. The building • 
furnished with city water in the halls and laboratories, and lighted 
with gas and electricity. The Longfellow and Whittier schools art 
placed in a beautiful park consisting of more than six acres in the </seg>

            <seg id="p100">
374 


heart of the city. This park is seeded with blue grass and clover, 
and well supplied with shade trees. 

The Alcott and Hawthorne schools, twin buildings, were erected 
in 1892 at a cost of $20,000 for the two. Each contains four schoolrooms 
and houses the first five grades. The rooms are furnished 
with single desks and provided with slate blackboards. The Smead 
system of heating and ventilating is in use, and cloak and toilet 
rooms are provided. In other particulars these two buildings resemble 
the Longfellow school. 

The Whittier school was erected in 1881 at a cost of $20,000. 
It contains seven schoolrooms and all grades from the second to 
the eighth inclusive. It is heated with steam, and the ventilators 
are in the walls. In interior arrangement it compares quite favorably 
with the more modern buildings of Kearney. 

The Kenwood school was erected in 1888 at a cost of $10,000. It 
is a four-room building for the first seven grades. It is heated with 
hot air, and in other particulars resembles the other buildings of 
Kearney already described. 

ORD HIGH SCHOOL 

E building was erected in 1892 at a cost of $13,500. It conve 
graded schoolrooms, one high school assembly room, two 
on rooms, a laboratory and an office. All grades are represented 
in the building except the first and second. It is seated 
with both single and double desks, and provided with slate blackboards. 
It is heated with hot air and ventilated with the Fuller 4 
Warren system. The cloak rooms are the wide halls. The lighting 
is good. 

FREMONT HIGH SCHOOL 

Ptis building was erected twelve or thirteen years ago at a co«t 
22,000. It contains one assembly room, six class rooms and 
offices. It is used exclusively for high school purposes. The 
Smead system of heating and ventilating is in use. The furniture 
is good, the blackboards are of slate, and there are cloak and toilet 
rooms in the building. When erected it was supposed it would be 
ample in size for many years to come, but Fremont has already </seg>

            <seg id="p101">
! 

I </seg>


            <seg id="p102">
AUBURN HIGH SCHOOL </seg>


            <seg id="p103">
375 

HARVARD HIGH SCHOOL 

The Harvard high school is the best schoolhouse in Clay county 
It was erected in 1894 at a cost of $12,000. It contains eight schoolrooms, 
one laboratory and one office, and houses eleven grade*. 
The blackboards are of the best slate, the desks nearly all single 
and the apparatus quite modern. The Smead system of heating 
and ventilating is in use, and there are cloak and toilet rooms. The 
lighting is excellent, mainly from the left and rear of the pupil* 
This is said to be one of the best equipped and best kept school 
buildings in the state. 

BEATRICE HIGH SCHOOL 

The Central school at Beatrice includes the high school, although 
it also makes provision for some of the grammar grades. It was 
erected in 1884 at a cost of $30,000. There are in it ten schoolrooms, 
three recitation rooms and two laboratories. It is furnished 
with single seats and provided with slate blackboards. It is heated 
by steam. All necessary apparatus and supplies for high school 
purposes and grade work are provided. 

CUMING CITY SCHOOL GROUNDS 

We wish to direct particular attention to- these school grounds, 
located about three miles northwest of Blair in Washington county. 
The grounds are 260 feet in width and 270 feet in depth, and when 
the photograph from which our half-tone was reproduced was taken 
in the early fall, the trees almost entirely obscured the school- 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 9, DODGE COUNTY 

This is a very common type of school building in the eastern part 
of Nebraska. It was erected in 1876 at a cost of less than $1,000. 
There is an entry way or vestibule used as a cloak room, and the 
room is lighted from both sides, the east and the west. It is seated 
with single desks and supplied with slate blackboard, maps, charts 
and a small library. Notice the tall trees about the building used as 
a wind-break, but there is no attempt in the way of shrubbery to 
improve the appearance of the grounds and conceal the outhouses </seg>

            <seg id="p104">
376 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

AUBURN WARD SCHOOLS 

The little city of Auburn, the county seat of Nemaha county, in 
southeastern Nebraska, has excellent, solid and substantial school 
twildings. 

RThe Athens school was erected in 1896 at a cost of $7,000. It is 
six-room building for the grades below the high school. Nearly 
art desks are single ones, the blackboards are made of liquid slating 
on plaster and charts and maps are provided. The Smead system 
of heating and ventilation is used. There are cloak rooms, but no 
interior toilet rooms. The rooms are lighted mainly from the left 
and rear of the pupils, and the interior of the building in general is 
quite neat and convenient in arrangement. 

Ee Antioch school is an eight-room building erected at the same 
as the Athens school and cost perhaps $1,000 more. It is quite 
ir in design, arrangement and furnishing to the Athens school. 

CRETE HIGH SCHOOL 

Ks building was erected in 1888 at a cost of $25,000. It conone 
high school assembly room, four recitation rooms, six 
i schoolrooms, two offices and three store rooms. All grades 
above the second are represented here. The building is furnished 
with single desks, slate blackboard four feet wide in all the rooms 
except the third and fourth grades, where it is narrower, and the 
usual amount of high school apparatus, maps and globes. It is 
heated with steam and well ventilated. The building has easy 
stairways and good cloak rooms. 

BEATRICE WARD SCHOOLS 

The Fairview school of Beatrice was erected in 1891 at a cost of 
$7,500. It is a four-room building for the first seven grades. It 
is furnished with single desks, slate blackboard, maps, charts, globes, 
E, and the Smead system of heating and ventilating is in use, 
the interior closets have been removed. There are cloak rooms, 
the schoolrooms generally are lighted from the left and rear. 

The South school was erected in 1886 at a cost of $8,000. It contains 
six rooms for the first seven grades, and is furnished with 
maps, charts, globes, etc., but the blackboards are of cloth. In other 
respects it is similar to the Fairview school. </seg>

            <seg id="p105">
ST. EDWARD PUBLIC SCHOOL 

HARTINGTON PUBLIC SCHOOL </seg>

            <seg id="p106">
PETERSBURG PUBLIC SCHOOL </seg>

            <seg id="p107">
377 


The East school was erected in 1888 at a cost of $10,000. It contains 
seven rooms for all the grades below the high school except 
the seventh. In all essential particulars it resembles the Soudi 
school. 

RED CLOUD HIGH SCHOOL 

The Red Cloud high school was erected in 1882 at a cost of !•.-000. 
It contains an assembly room, recitation room, a library aad 
an office and three graded schoolrooms. All grades above the second 
are represented in the building. The blackboards are of plaster 
or of cloth, and the building is heated with stoves. There are chimney 
flues for the exit of foul air. Some high school apparatus i» 
provided, but the building is without cloak rooms or toilet room*. 

MADISON HIGH SCHOOL 

This building was erected two years ago at a cost of $15x100, m 
chiding the steam heating plant. It contains a high school JiiunUji 
room, recitation room, laboratory, library, store room and six grade 
rooms. It is furnished with single desks, slate blackboard, some 
laboratory apparatus and a liberal supply of organs, pictures, etc. 
The building is properly lighted and ventilated. 

ASHLAND HIGH SCHOOL 

The original part of this building was erected in 1871 and an addition 
thereto in 1887 at a total cost of $16,000. It is an clewroom 
building and contains all grades. There are both single and 
B desks and slate blackboard. It is heated with steam and 
ed with outlets for foul air near the ceiling. There are cloak 
but no toilet rooms in the building. The rooms arc lightoi 
f from the left and rear. 

PONCA PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This excellent school building in northeastern Nebraska was 
erected three years ago at a cost of about $18,000. It contains ten 
schoolrooms, an office and a library, and has also two large hallways. 
All grades are here represented. The desks are modem 
single ones, though some double desks are still in use, and the black 
¦ 1 is of plaster composition. It is heated with steam and renti- </seg>


            <seg id="p108">
toilet rooms. The lighting is from the left of the pupils. In its 
system of heating, ventilation and lighting, its broad stairways and 
large, airy, well-lighted hallways, this building compares favorably 
vith any in the state. 

WAKEFIELD HIGH SCHOOL 

This building was erected three years ago at a cost of $15,000. 
It is of pressed brick and contains six schoolrooms, one laboratory 
and one assembly room, and houses all of the grades from the first 
through the eleventh. The blackboards are of slate and the furnimre 
and apparatus fairly good. The building is heated with steam 
and ventilated. There are cloak rooms, but no interior toilet rooms. 
The schoolrooms are lighted from the left and rear. The building 
has wide halls, easy stairways and conveniences of interior 
arrangement. 

HASTINGS HIGH SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1889 at a cost of $20,000. It contains 
ten rooms and accommodates all the grades from the first 
through the twelfth. It is furnished with single desks, recitation 
chairs, several kinds of blackboard and the ordinary amount of apparatus 
for instruction in the sciences. The building is heated with 
steam and provided with cloak and toilet rooms, but there is no 
complete system of ventilation. The lighting is mainly from the 
left and rear. 

GRANT SCHOOL, NORFOLK 

Fhe main part of this building was erected in 1886 and an annex 
898 at a total cost of $13,000. There are six schoolrooms and 
office, the former for the accommodation of the primary and the 
fifth grades. There are both single and double desks in the building, 
natural slate and plaster composition blackboards and some apparatus. 
The building is heated with hot air and ventilated. There 
are cloak rooms in the building but no toilet rooms. In general, 
the rooms are lighted from the left and rear. The rooms are all 
large and well lighted, but in the older portion they are poorly 
ventilated and not very well heated </seg>

            <seg id="p109">
GORDON PUBLIC SCHOOL 

COLUMBUS HIGH SCHOOL </seg>

            <seg id="p110">
MODEL ONE-ROOM SCHOOL 

American School Board Journal, June, 1901 

MIDDLESEX, N. Y., PUBLIC SCHOOL 

American School Board Journal, October, 1901 </seg>

            <seg id="p111">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND (»KOl7Nif8» 

379 

NORFOLK HIGH SCHOOL 

Phis building was erected in 1890 at a cost of $29,000. It coos 
an assembly room, three laboratory and recitation rooms, three 
e and library rooms and six schoolrooms. The desks are single; 
blackboards of plaster composition and the apparatus and equipment 
very good. The building is heated with hot air by the Smead 
system and ventilated. It contains both cloak and toilet rooms. 
The schoolrooms are lighted chiefly from the left and rear. The 
building contains commodious hallways, stairways, good ventilation, 
but not the best of heating. The general arrangements are quite 
convenient. 

AUBURN HIGH SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1886 at a cost of $8,000. It is n*«l 
exclusively for the high school grades and contains two assembly 
rooms, a class room, laboratory, office and book room. It it provided 
with single seats, liquid slating blackboards, maps and charts 
and apparatus for physics and chemistry. The Smead system of 
hot air is used for heating with ventilation. There are cloak rooms 
but no toilet rooms in the building. The rooms are lighted mainly 
from the left and rear. It is a neat and convenient building in all 
respects. 

ST. EDWARD PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1895 at a cost of $5,600. It contains 
four good schoolrooms for the accommodation of all the 
grades. The desks are mainly the old folding ones, though single, 
the blackboards are of slate and the apparatus insufficient. The 
building is heated with stoves, and ventilated by means of windows, 
transoms and doors. There are cloak rooms but no interior toilet 
rooms. All the rooms are lighted from the left and rear. 

HARTINGTON PUBLIC SCHOOL 

Pis building was erected in 1896 at a cost of $12,000. It conone 
laboratory and seven schoolrooms for the accommodaof 
all the grades from the first through the twelfth. The 
blackboards are of slate, and the building is heated with steam and 
ventilated. There are cloak rooms but no interior toilet rooms. 
The rooms are lighted from the left and rear. </seg>

            <seg id="p112">
380 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

ALLIANCE HIGH SCHOOL 

The older part of this building was erected in 1889 and an addition 
in 1899 at a tota ' cost °* $i5iOOO. It contains nineteen rooms 
for the accommodation of all the grades from the first through the 
twelfth, including schoolrooms, recitation rooms, offices, laboratories, 
library, boiler room and lunch room. Natural slate and 
hyloplate blackboards are in use. The building is heated with 
steam and ventilated. There are cloak rooms, but the toilet rooms 
are outside. 

COLUMBUS HIGH SCHOOL 

Re new Columbus high school was erected nearly four years ago 
cost of $27,000. It contains a high school assembly room, 
recitation rooms, three laboratories, an office and a library 
and three, graded schoolrooms. The desks are single, and those in 
the high school are adjustable with revolving seats. The blackboard 
is of slate and the apparatus all quite modern. The system of 
heating and ventilating is similar to the Smead system. The hallways 
are divided for cloak rooms and there are toilet rooms in the 
basement. The rooms are in the main lighted from the left or left 
and rear. The building contains ample hall space, excellent arrangement, 
abundant light, high ceilings and tinted walls. 

LOG SCHOOLHOUSE IN DISTRICT NO. 38, SARPY COUNTY 

This schoolhouse was demolished last year and its logs have been 
used during the past winter to heat the new frame building that has 
taken its place. This was probably the last log schoolhouse in the 
eastern part of Nebraska. It stood in a beautiful grove on Belle- 
Tue Island, only twelve miles from the business center of Omaha. 
The building was erected about thirty years ago and was used during 
the last sixteen years of its existence as a schoolhouse. R measured 
only sixteen by eighteen feet, with a six-foot ceiling. It contained 
twenty double desks and was lighted by means of three windows. 
An old-fashioned wood-burning stove, red with rust, furnished the 
heat, and the chinks between the logs where the plaster had fallen 
off provided plenty of ventilation. It has long been a question 
whether part of the land comprising school district No. 38 of Sarpy 
county was in Iowa or Nebraska, and on account of this uncertainty 
it was difficult to vote bonds for a new schoolhouse, but finally $800 </seg>

            <seg id="p113">
1 

I 

— ! 

t 

' 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p114">
s, 

« </seg>


            <seg id="p115">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

was raised in this way, and the same has been used in the construction 
of the new frame building. 

GRAND ISLAND HIGH SCHOOL 

R original part of this building, known as the Dodge building, 
ected in 1878 at a cost of $30,000; an addition in 1885 cost 
, and another addition in 1889, $11,000. The complete building 
contains twenty-one rooms, including all necessary schoolrooms 
and recitation rooms for the accommodation of all grades from the 
first through the twelfth. It contains both kinds of desks and slate 
blackboards. The apparatus is of the best, and there is a very 
E: reference library for the benefit of the high school. The 
is properly heated with steam, but is not ventilated. There 
k rooms in the building, but no toilet rooms. The schoolre 
lighted mainly from the left and rear. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 54, PERKINS COUNTY 

This old sod schoolhouse which the author had the pleasure of 
examining last summer was erected about the year 1888 at a cost 
approximately of $100. It contains two rooms, only one of which 
is habitable. There are in the building good double desks, a recitation 
bench, slate blackboards, and fully $200 worth of apparatus, 
including maps, charts and arithmetical blocks in abundance. There 
is one stove, with accidental and incidental ventilation, assisted by 
the cattle. The building does not belong to the district, but was 
borrowed by it for school purposes with the understanding that the 
district was to keep it in repair for the use of it without rent. A 
new schoolhouse has been or soon will be erected in the district. 
The side view shows a shed where the teacher and some of the 
pupils stable their horses during the school day. 

SOD SCHOOLHOUSE, DUNDY COUNTY 

This is the picture of a sod schoolhouse formerly used in district 
No. 9 of Dundy county, but it was replaced about three years ago 
by a nice frame building. The photograph was taken seven or 
eight years ago. The building was erected, in 1888 at a cost of 
about $125. The furniture it contained was all home-made except 
the teacher's chair. It was furnished with a bit of slate blackboard </seg>



            <seg id="p116">
!ch cost forty cents per square foot. The pupils lace the door, 
1 two windows on each side and no opening in the rear. The 
ding was, naturally enough, warm in the winter time and cool 
he summer. It was almost impossible to hear any noise from 
outside. It was plastered with native lime (soft magnesia rock) 
which pulverizes easily after being soaked in water a few days. No 
studding or lath were used, as the plaster sticks readily to the sod 
walls. The greater portion of the plastering was done during intermissions 
by the pupils, who were thus receiving their first lessons in 
clay modeling. . 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 83, CHERRY COUNTY 

This sod schoolhouse was erected in the fall of 190 1 at a cost to 
the district of $37.85, as the work and a part of the material were 
contributed by the patrons. The actual cost of such a building 
would be about $100. The furniture it contains is entirely homemade, 
the blackboards are painted boards, there is no apparatus, 
and the schoolhouse is heated with a stove and "native fuel." The 
district has never had to exceed six months of school during a 
year, and last year, on account of their inability to secure a teacher 
in time, they were unable to have more than three months. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 3O, HITCHCOCK COUNTY 

This school district has been discontinued, and the building is 
now used as a church and is known as "The Old Sod Church." 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 73, FRONTIER COUNTY 

? 

This building was erected about twelve years ago at a cost of 
$100. It was replaced last year by a good frame schoolhouse. It 
was a long, low building, devoid of beauty, though not uncomfortable, 
and is a type of many of the schoolhouses that existed in western 
Nebraska several years ago, but it is not characteristic of the 
more modern schoolhouses now in that part of the state. It contained 
patent furniture, the blackboards were of matched lumber 
painted black, and there were windows on both sides opposite each 
other. The children in the illustration are typical young Nebraskans 
that are determined to maintain for their state the lowest percentage 
of illiteracy in the Union, whether in order to do so the) 
must acquire their education in a sod house, a log house or a pressed 
brick building. </seg>

            <seg id="p117">
DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 54. PERKINS COUNTY— Front View 

DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 54, PERKINS COUNTY— SiJe View </seg>

            <seg id="p118">
DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 8}. CHERRY COUNTY </seg>



            <seg id="p119">
This view shows the south side of a sod schoolhouse with shingled 
roof. Like most of the sod houses, the ceiling is low. The room 
contains patent desks and about two square yards of slate blackboard. 
There is an old reading chart and a small dictionary in the 
school. There are two windows on each side, the north and the 
south, and a door in the east. The illustration shows some broken 
window glass. 

LOOKOUT SCHOOL, LOUP COUNTY 

This sod house is located in district No. 26, in a county without 
a mi'e of railroad. A wooden blackboard is exhibited to the left 
of the children. The low roof and lower door may be seen in the 
illustration, and the bright looking children are typical of the 
prairies and ranges of central and western Nebraska. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. I, HALL COUNTY 

This school district is almost unique in Nebraska in that in addition 
to a fine brick schoolhouse with porches and architectural ornamentation 
(see illustration) it provides a residence and garden for 
the use of the teacher. 

The first school ever established in Hall county was a private 
school in 1864, with only icur children attending: Frederick Stolley, 
Wilhclm Stelk, Christian Gottsche and Lina Schoel. The teacher, 
Theodore Nagel, received his pay in work performed by the parents 
of the children on the teacher's farm while he was teaching the 
children. Christian Gottsche, when sixteen years old, was killed 
by the Indians while out hunting on the Loup river. 

An attempt at organizing a school district under the laws of the 
state was first made in the year 1868. The district embraced all 
the territory of the present school districts Nos. 1 and 74, and considerable 
of the Grand Island school district, No. 2. All measures 
taken at that time were irregular and bungling and subsequently 
proved to be illegal, and much contention prevailed for several 
years on account of the high-handed and unlawful proceedings of 
those who claimed to be in authority. The party acting for the 
time being as director was also the teacher of the district school, 
and reports on one of the sheets of his record that, in the capacity 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 44, KK1TH COUNTY </seg>



            <seg id="p120">
of director, he inspected his own school three times that year. Taxes 
for school purposes were levied in the following manner, as for 
example: 

I. Every voter in the school district shall pay $2.00 into the 
school fund. 

2. On every forty acres of land claimed or owned by any settler, 
he shall pay $1.50 into the school fund. 

3. On every $100 assessed valuation of personal property, onefourth 
per cent shall be paid. 

P schoolhouse of the value of $250 (14X 18 feet) was built, but 
teacher received very little cash and had to take school orders 
his pay and sell them at a discount. Matters changed somewhat 
in the summer of 1870, when a second schoolhouse was built 
and the district was divided into two sub-districts, "west" and 
"east." It was not, however, until April, 1872, when Wm. Stolley 
was elected director of district No. 1, that radical changes took 
place. At that time two teachers were employed for nine months 
each at $40 per month. Gradually matters improved, and in the 
years 1884, 1885 and 1886 school district taxes were levied for 
the purpose of building two substantial brick schoolhouses, one 
for each sub-district. This plan was carried out, and on September 
1, 1886, both brick schoolhouses, as they are now in evidence, were 
accepted by the school board at a cost of $4,515.07. Soon after 
this, school district No. 1 was divided into two districts : the west 
end sub-district to be known as district No. 1, and the east end 
sub-district as district No. 74 (see illustration of this schoolhouse). 

Ethe annual school meeting in 1893, the sum of $1,200 was 
for the building of a teacher's residence and suitable outngs, 
and a tax of ten mills was levied for that purpose. In 
August, 1893, an additional acre of land adjoining the schoolhouse 
grounds on the east was bought for the location of the teacher's 
"home," and although much opposed by some tax payers, on the 
15th day of May, 1894, the contract for the construction of the 
teacher's residence was let for the sum of $1,000 in gold. The 
house was completed and turned over to the district on July 19, 
1894. The teacher's house is 22x28 feet and 14 feet in height, 
with an addition to the west of 12 x 16 feet and 10 feet high. The 
house has double windows for winter and window screens for </seg>

            <seg id="p121">
.' 

DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 30. HITCHCOCK COUNTY 

DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 73, FRONTIER COUNTY </seg>

            <seg id="p122">
DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 44, KEITH COUNTY 

THE LOOKOUT SCHOOL, DISTRICT No. 26, LOUP COUNTY </seg>



            <seg id="p123">
EUp to the year 1880 inclusive the district paid the teacher $40 P" 1 
with ; in 1881 they paid $45 per month (9 months) ; in 1882, $50 
per month (9 months) ; in 1883, $55 per month (9 months) ; and 
for the years 1884 to 1901 inclusive, the district paid $60 per month 
(9 months), and of late years provided the free use of the teacher's 
residence, out-buildings, and one-half acre of ground for a 
garden. The district also voted funds for the additional purchase 
of suitable pasture land for the keeping of a milch cow and family 
horse ; but so far the school board has not taken any action on this 
last departure. 

For much of this information the state superintendent is indebted 
to Mr. Wm. Stolley, director. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 3, FILLMORE COUNTY 

Pitil the summer of 1901 this school district used a frame buildwhich 
was as good as the average in many parts of Nebraska 
better than the average in some places. At that time, however, 
frame house was torn down and much of its material was 
utilized in the construction of a new and vastly better school building, 
made of brick. The old and the new buildings are both illustrated 
on the same page. The new building cost about $1,200, and 
instead of issuing bonds, a building fund was levied beginning two 
years before. The district thought it better to provide the necessary 
funds during the two years previous to the construction of 
the schoolhouse rather than during the five or ten years following 
its completion. They saved interest and some trouble. 

This new schoolhouse is the best one in Fillmore county, and is 
probably the only one that- is scientifically lighted and correctly 
ventilated. The pupils face an unbroken east wall, with a natural 
slate blackboard extending from corner to corner. The windows 
in the west wall, the rear of the room, are set high enough to provide 
another blackboard the entire length of that end of the room. 
The public road runs past the west end of the building, but the 
windows are so high that the school is not disturbed by passing 
teams, for the pupils cannot see out even if they should be standing. 
Along the north side of the building are four long windows reaching 
to the cornice above, and these with the high windows in the 
west waH furnish enough light even on the darkest days. This 
north wall with windows is not shown in the illustration. The vesti- </seg>


            <seg id="p124">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

bule leads into the schoolroom and into the cloak room. In the 
wall between the schoolroom and the cloak room is fitted a bookcase 
on the schoolroom side and shelves for dinner pails on the 
cloak room side. The schoolroom proper is 34 x 24 feet with a 12-foot 
ceiling. The cloak room is 16 x 7 feet, and the vestibule is 
eight feet square. The furniture from the old building is at present 
used in the new one, but scon will be replaced by new desks. The 
blackboards are of natural slate, and anatomical and geographical 
charts are provided. A stove is used for heating, and this will 
soon be provided with a jacket. Fresh air is admitted from the 
outside by means of a duct leading in under the stove. The children, 
of course, face the east wall and receive the light mainly 
from the left and partly from the rear. The floor is "dead," resting 
on a layer of mortar several inches thick, which makes it as solid as 
a wall. The author had the pleasure of visiting the school in this 
building last fall, and he thinks it compares favorably with the 
model rural schoolhouse in the Sutherland district. The Fillmore 
county building possesses one advantage in being built of 
brick. Its architect is Mr. T. J. Beals, of Geneva. 

TABLE ROCK PUBLIC SCHOOL 

Until January 10, 1902, the village of Table Rock used as a 
schoolhouse one of the most barn-like structures in the state, but 
since that date the children in that school district have been housed 
in one of the neatest, handsomest, most substantial, most convenient 
and commodious school buildings in any village the size of 
Table Rock anywhere in the state of Nebraska. The new schoolhouse 
is built of the finest home-made vitrified brick, with blue 
flint stone trimmings, also home-grown, and well finished woodwork. 
All the equipment and the furniture are quite modern. The 
building complete cost about $12,000. It contains an office, a laboratory, 
a recitation room and seven schoolrooms, all well arranged 
and correctly lighted. The natural slate blackboard is three 
feet in width in the upper rooms and four feet wide below. The 
building is heated with steam. There are cloak rooms, but no interior 
toilet rooms. Table Rock "celebrated" on the occasion of 
the dedication of its new school building, and Superintendent 
Wimberley's little girl recited an original poem concluding as </seg>
            <seg id="p125">

DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 1, HALL COUNTY 

TEACHER'S RESIDENCE. PROPERTY OF DISTRICT No. I, HALL COUNTY </seg>


            <seg id="p126">' 

DISTRICT SCHOOL No. 3, FILLMORE COUNTY 
This building was destroyed to make room for — </seg>




            <seg id="p127">
* r»'*'Ji« i*l 1 Lj I J 1 \j Cj ** I-' xjf tv \J kj *. I ' ¦ 

"So farewell to the old schoolhouse ; we are told 
We must bid it a sad adieu. 

Each girl and each boy will hail with great joy 
A welcoming into the new." 

PAWNEE CITY HIGH SCHOOL 

This new high school building was erected in 1899 at a cost of 
$13,000. It contains an assembly room, two recitation rooms. 
library, laboratory, office, store room and four schoolrooms for the 
grammar grades. The blackboards are painted upon the cement 
plaster. The building is heated with steam and ventilated by null 
of shafts heated by steam coils. There is a cloak room in connection 
with each schoolroom, but no interior toilet rooms. The rooms 
are lighted from the left and rear. The building is a plain bat a 
solid and substantial one, conveniently arranged. The walk arc 
tinted a shade of green. 

DORCHKSTHK PUIJLJC .-' ll'«.l. 

P Dorchester public school building was erected tn iHgo at a 
f $12,000. It contains six schoolrooms, a library and an oi- 
The rooms are large and well lighted and fu 
slate blackboard and single desks. The hallways are wide and M€ 
used for cloak rooms. The building is heated with furnace*. AN 
the grades from the first to the tenth inclusive are represented. 

CHADRON PUBLIC SCHOOL 

re Chadron public school building was erected in 1M6 at a 
of $20,000. There are nine school rooms, four on cadi faar 
and one in the basement. In the basement are alto apartments 
for the janitor's family and for the steam heating apparatus. Tktflt 
is no special provision for ventilation. There are no water closet* 
in the building. The attic rooms were once used for TvmnaMam 
purposes. Many styles and patterns of desks are represented, including 
both single and double ones. 

SYRACUSE PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This brick building was erected in 1890 at a cost of $ro.ooo It 
contains an assembly room, laboratory, recitation room, two store 
rooms and five schoolrooms for the accommodation of all the grades </seg>



            <seg id="p128">
and furnished with slate blackboards and good apparatus. It it 
heated with steam and inadequately ventilated by means of cold air 
shafts and dead air flues. There is a cloak room in connection witk 
each schoolroom, but no interior toilet rooms. The rooms are well 
lighted, mainly from the left and rear. The building resembles 
the one at Sterling. 

AINSWORTH PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was constructed in 1895 of common brick at a cost 
of $10,000. It contains a large high school room, a laboratory, a 
library and five schoolrooms for the accommodation of all the 
grades from the first through the eleventh. The desks are nearly 
told ones: The blackboards are partly of natural slate and partly 
felt The building is heated by hot air, with some ventilation. 

BRADY PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This two-room frame building was erected in 1893 at a cost of 
$2,000. There is a primary room located elsewhere in the village. 
The rooms are heated by means of stoves and lighted from both 
sides. Many of the pupils come from the country and several from 
other districts. The illustration shows the pupils as they are about 
to start for their homes in conveyances of different kinds, just after 

PRAIRIE QUEEN SCHOOL, SARPY COUNTY 

Piis schoolhouse in district No. 33 of Sarpy county was erected 
t 1884 at a cost of $1,000. It is a little better than the average 
I schoolhouse in Sarpy county and eastern Nebraska. It is 
ished with patent desks, slate blackboards, globe, dictionary, 

PAPILLION PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This is one of the best school buildings in Sarpy county, it was 
erected in 1892 at a cost of $20,000. It contains six schoolrooms, 
a laboratory, a library, play rooms, etc., for the eleven grades. It 
is seated with both single and double desks, furnished with slate 
blackboards, physical apparatus, maps, etc. It is heated and ventilated 
by means of the Smead hot-air system. There are cloak 
rooms, and also toilet rooms in the basement. The rooms are 
lighted mainly from the left and rear. The building is constructed 
of pressed brick, with wide hallways and stairways, and hard-wood </seg>

            <seg id="p129">
TABLE ROCK PUBLIC SCHOOL. 

Lj.-. 

TABLE ROCK PUBLIC SCHOOI . Past, as </seg>

            <seg id="p130">
PAWNEE CITY HIGH SCHOOL 

PAWNEE CITY HIGH SCHOOL 

Interior Views </seg>



            <seg id="p131">
GRETNA PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1898 at a cost of nearly $8,000 It 
contains four schoolrooms and two or three smaller rooms. It 1* 
furnished with single desks and slate blackboards, maps and globes. 
It is heated with steam and well ventilated. There are cloak roan*, 
but no interior toilet rooms. Two of the schoolrooms are lighted 
from the left and rear and the other two from the right and rear 
The building is faced with the very best buff pressed brick. The 
grounds are 255 x 382 feet, and they have 1,000 linear feet of brick 
pavement, four, six and eight feet in width. 

LONG PINE PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1888 at a cost of $4,000. It contaaM 
four schoolrooms and two recitation rooms for the use of th« eleven 
grades. The blackboards are of hyloplate. The building is heated 
with stoves but not ventilated except as shown in the illustration. 

WEEPING WATER PUBLIC SCHOOL 

Pis building was erected in 1890 except the third story, which 
added in 1899. The building cost $15,000. It contains ten 
rooms for the accommodation of all the grades. It is furnished 
with double desks and hyloplate blackboard, and is fairly well 
equipped with apparatus for the laboratories. It is heated with 
steam and ventilated. It contains cloak rooms but no interior 
toilet rooms. The schoolrooms are lighted mainly from the left 
and rear. 

CRAWFORD PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1891 at a cost of $20,000. It is 
situated on a high hill overlooking the village of Crawford, in northwestern 
Nebraska. It contains seven schoolrooms, a recitation 
room, library, laboratory, and some rooms in the basement where 
the children may play and eat their lunches, and also rooms in which 
the janitor and his wife live. The furniture is good, the blackboards 
of liquid slating and the apparatus fair. The building it 
heated with steam and ventilated. There are cloak rooms bat n* </seg>



            <seg id="p132">
ELGIN PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This building was erected in 1891 at a cost of $3,500. It is not 
in good repair and is difficult to heat and ventilate, but Elgin expects 
to erect a new school building soon. 

ARLINGTON PUBLIC SCHOOL 

The Arlington public school building occupies one corner of a 
block. The remainder of the block is in fine, large trees, and the 
district owns a quarter block across the street to the south which 
is used as a play ground. Arlington possesses fine grounds and it 
is to be hoped a beautiful, commodious school building will soon 
ornament them. 

PAXTON PUBLIC SCHOOL 

The Paxton school building was erected in 1896 at a cost of 
$2,500. It contains three schoolrooms, a library and a recitation 
room. The desks are single, patent ones, the blackboards are of 
natural slate, and matting covers the aisles of the high schoolroom. 
The rooms are lighted from the left and rear or right and rear and 
are heated with stoves. 

BLOOMINGTON PUBLIC SCHOOL 

Bloomington lost by fire in the summer of 1896 a brick school 
building similar in size and plan to the one herein illustrated. The 
present frame building was erected the same year at a cost of $6,000. 
On the first floor are three schoolrooms — a first primary nineteen 
by twenty-eight feet, and second primary and intermediate rooms 
each twenty-five by thirty-four feet; also large entry ways and 
commodious cloak rooms. On the second floor is an assembly and 
study room thirty-five' by sixty feet accommodating one hundred 
pupils, two recitation rooms, physical and chemical laboratories, a 
library and cloak rooms. The schoolrooms are lighted from the 
tides and rear. A furnace with ventilating system was installed, 
but at present stoves are used with the ventilating system still in 
service. Double desks are used for the first six grades, single seats 
from the seventh to the twelfth grades. The blackboards are of 
kyloplate. The school grounds are well stocked with hackberry 
and elm trees. </seg>

            <seg id="p133">
DORCHESTER PUBLIC SCHOOL 

CHADRON PUBLIC SCHOOL </seg>

            <seg id="p134">
AINSWORTH PUBLIC SCHOO! </seg>

            <seg id="p135">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 


SKWARD HIGH SCHOOL 

The Seward high school building was erected in 1874, but it is 
well preserved and still presents a pleasing appearance. The first 
floor rooms are used by the grammar grades and the second floor 
for high school purposes. Naturally, it is not heated or ventilated 
by modern methods. City water is carried through the building 
and lavatories are placed on each floor. The rooms are furnished 
jvith slate blackboards and single desks. 

VALENTINE PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This school building was erected in 1898 at a cost of $14,000, 
in.luding heating apparatus. There are six large well lighted 
school rooms and a recitation room. The building is heated by 

¦eans of hot air, with good ventilation. A large furnace heats the 
v^east rooms and two smaller furnaces heat the four rooms on 
k h^west and the recitation room. In the center of the building 
directly between the other furnaces is a cylindrical furnace for heating 
the halls and furnishing the children a place to warm their feet 
when the weather is very cold. The building is also furnished 
with six large, airy cloakrooms. All the schoolrooms are lighted 
from the left and rear. 

OLD SOD SCHOOLHOUSE IN SOUTHWESTERN NEBRASKA 

EPhe photograph from which this illustration is made was taken 
eral years ago. The building is located north of McCook, and 
5 probably intended for other than school purposes. The photograph 
was presented to Mrs. Nettleton while she was county 
superintendent there, and is highly prized. Notice the bright faces 
and tidy appearance of the children, and also the weeds and sun- 
Sower stalks that have grown on the sod roof of the schoolhouse. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. l6, KEITH COUNTY 

Ehis old sod schoolhouse was constructed in the fall of 1886, and 
down some time ago. It contained patent desks and slate 
kboards, and was well supplied with modern apparatus. It was 
ted by means of two windows in each side. 

RURAL DISTRICT SCHOOL, LINCOLN COUNTY 

T'lis old stone schoolhouse was destroyed several years ago oa 
aocount of a change of site, and a frame building was constructed </seg>



            <seg id="p136">
on the new scnoolnouse site, but the illustration will serve to show 
one of the types of schoolhouses in Nebraska, though there are few 
of this class. The material of the building is native limestone, 
taken from the hills south of North Platte. As the rocks are soft, 
to save time and trouble in cutting them the usual method is to 
make a concrete, and after the wall is built, plaster it on the outside 
and mark off squares in imitation of marble or granite blocks. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 41, DAWES COUNTY 

Pis log schoolhouse was constructed in 1888 at a cost of $50. 
-nade of hewn logs with sod roof. There are two windows in 
side. The desks are home-made, the blackboards are painted 
boards and the building also contains one set of charts and a wood 

A BALED STRAW SCHOOLHOUSE 

Some five or six years ago in district No. 5 of Scott's Bluff 
county there was erected a temple of learning, the walls of whicW 
were of baled straw, the floor was the primitive mother earth and 
the roof above presented a face of earth to the heavens. This roof 
sloped both ways and was made of slippery elm poles covered with 
sod. The building was sixteen feet long, twelve feet wide, and 
seven feet high. There was a window m each side and a door in 
one end. The bales of straw were about thirty-six by eighteen by 
fourteen inches, and were laid in mud instead of mortar. With half 
bales the joints were broken in the same way that bricks are laid. 
The bales were made of straw from which the wheat had been 
trampled by horses, there being no threshing machines in the country 
then. 

The school board at that time consisted of Mr. James Baxter, Mr. 
W. S. Fleming and Mrs. Fulton, all of Minatare. The gentlemen 
performed most of the labor of construction. The building was 
used but two years as a schoolhouse. The state superintendent endeavored 
to obtain a photograph of the building, but he can not 
find that one was ever taken. Like the temple of ancient Jerusalem, 
of that schoolhouse there is not left one stone (or bale of straw) 
upon another, as the cattle were allowed to range around it. However, 
from sketches and descriptions the accompanying illustration 
was produced, and we believe it will be quickly and easily recog- </seg>



            <seg id="p137">
PRAIRIE QUEEN SCHOOL, DISTRICT NO 33, SARPY COUNTY 

PAPILLION PUBLIC SCHOOL </seg>



            <seg id="p139">
object. Nor was it children alone that were benefited by that old 
hollow straw pile. There were two cows in that neighborhood that 
ate away the rough corners of the building, and at one side of the 
doorway they also ate a hole clear through the wall • By way of 
reciprocity the teacher and pupils milked the cows at the noon hour, 
Ifacre being no well at the schoolhousc, and when the cows tailed to 
appear at the luncheon hour, the two oldest girls were detailed to 
drive them in. One day when the director visited the school the 
teacher and pupils gathered wild strawberries nearby and then they 
milked the cows and all feasted together. The horses in that country 
stripped the roof poles of their bark where they could, and they 
tore away the sod to get at the bark until all 'round the edges no 
roof was left except the supporting poles. About 120 feet north 
of the schoolhouse was an outhouse two bales square and six feet 
high. A frame schoolhouse now occupies the site. We are indebted 
to Messrs. James Baxter and G. W. Sampson, of Minatare, 
and to Mr. A. E. Whiteis, of Gering, for much of this information. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 8, SCOTTS BLUFF COUNTY 

Eis is one of the two sod schoolhouses in Scotts Bluff county, 
county is probably making more rapid and substantial growth 
: present writing (fall of 190*;) than any other county in Nebraska. 
In proof of this we call attention to the school buildings 
recently erected at Mitchell, Scotts Bluff and Gering. In district 
No. 8 some of the patrons recently declared thev had no school 
building, but there are still over 400 school districts in Nebraska 
6: they believe that a sod schoolhouse is better than none. In 
rural districts in Scotts Bluff county the teachers are paid 
dollars a month and in two others sixty dollars a month. 
1 teachers in graded schools of that county receive fifty dollars 

SCOTTS BLUFF PUBLIC SCHOOL 

The Scotts Bluff school building was erected in the fall of 1900 
at a cost of $3,613. It is a frame building veneered with brick, 
and is sixty-eight by seventy-two feet. During the school year 
1900-1901 a six months' term was held with two teachers and an 
average attendance of fifty-four pupils. During the next school 
year there were nine months of school with an average attendance </seg>



            <seg id="p140">
of 120 pupils. During the present school year (1902-1903) there 
are four teachers with an average attendance of 151 pupils. The 
building is furnished with the latest patent single desks -id good 
book cases. There is an organ in the high school r&lt; in. The 
grounds are still in an unimproved condition. 

GER1NG PUBLIC SCHOOL 

Ei the illustration of the Gering public school we are looking 
heast. The west part of the building was erected during the 
mer of 1894, the central part in 1898, and the east part during 
the fall of 1902, at a total cost of $6,000. Each part is about 
twenty -five by forty feet on the ground ; therefore, the total length 
of the building is ninety feet, and the central part sets in from the 
south fifteen feet. It is a six-room building and five of the rooms 
are now occupied. At present the rooms are heated with stoves, 
but the basement is being prepared for a furnace. The rooms are 
furnished with single desks and there are two organs in the buiWing. 
There are also about 100 reference books. The blackboards 
are of plaster. The grounds are fenced and trees were set o«t 
during 1902. The attendance is about 250 pupils. 

MITCHELL PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This school is in district No. 31 of Scotts Bluff county. In 1899 
in the sod schoolhouse there was a term of four months, an enrollment 
of twenty-five pupils, and the teacher was paid thirty dollars 
a month. In 1901 in the new building they held seven months of 
school, with an enrollment of eighty-six pupils, and the two teachers 
were paid sixty-five and forty dollars a month respectively. 
This year (1902) the term is eight months with three teachers, 
who are paid seventy-five, fifty and fort)' dollars a month respectively, 
and a janitor, who receives fifteen dollars a month. The 
enrollment in the ten grades will probably exceed 100 pupils. The 
present school building is of frame sided with metal sheeting ia 
imitation of brick, but the mortar painting or penciling had not 
been done when the photograph was taken. The rooms are about 
twenty-one by thirty-two feet and eleven feet high. Hyloplate 
blackboards are in use. </seg>
            <seg id="p141">

LONG PINE PUBLIC SCHOOL </seg>

            <seg id="p142">
INTERMEDIATE ROOM, FAIRMONT </seg>

            <seg id="p143">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 


BAYARD PUBLIC SCHOOL 

E illustration of the sod schoolhouse at Bayard, in district No. 
Cheyenne county, is from a photograph taken in June, 1900, 
J a celebration held to commemorate the opening of a creamery. 
This old sod house has since been replaced by a commodious 
four-room frame building, an illustration of which appears on the 
same page with the sod schoolhouse. The two photographs from 
which these illustrations were made were presented by Dr. J. H. 
Long, of Bayard. 

UNION PUBLIC SCHOOL 

The Union public school building was erected in 1889 at a cost 
of $3,072. The two rooms below are each twenty-one by twentynine 
feet. The room above is thirty by forty-four feet and is used 
for high school purposes. There are also four large anterooms and 
a hallway. Any one of the anterooms may be used for a recitation 
room. The ceiling and walls of the schoolrooms are now papered. 
This school is well equipped with text-books, reference books, cyclopedias, 
and a library of more than 200 volumes. At present the 
building is heated with stoves, but it is proposed to put in a hot air 
furnace this fall (1902). 

STAPLEHURST PUBLIC SCHOOL 

This frame school building was constructed in 1889 at a cost of 
$3,000. It contains four schoolrooms and two large hallways. The 
rooms are lighted from three sides. The building is heated by 
stoves and ventilated fairly well. The desks are nearly all old, but 
single ones. The blackboards are mainly of natural slate. 

DISTRICT SCHOOL NO. 43, THAYER COUNTY 

This fine country schoolhouse was erected in 1899. Notice the 
effect of the porch in the general appearance of the building. The 
building is twenty-four by thirty-eight feet, and has a seating capacity 
of fifty pupils. 

JUNIATA PUBLIC SCHOOL 

The Juniata school building was erected in 1896 at a cost of 
$10,000. The building is a two-story brick and contains four large 
schoolrooms, one recitation room, an office, a dinner room and a 
basement. Two hallways, one on each floor, extend the entire </seg>

            <seg id="p144">

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

length of the building. The rooms are all provided with slate 
blackboard and furnished with single seats. The light enters from 
the left and rear. The building is heated by steam and well ventilated. 
Juniata has one other schoolhouse, a small brick building in 
the west part of town for the first and second grades. This building 
is kept as neat and homelike as could be desired. The interior 
view of the primary room shows the pride of the teacher in appearances, 
and the large building is also kept in the best of condition 
at all times. 

WISNER PUBLIC SCHOOL 

The main part of the Wisner school building was erected in 1888 
at a cost of $10,000; an addition was erected in 1895 at a cost of 
$3,000; and a second addition which does not show in the illustration 
was erected in 1901 at a cost of $4,000. The school grounds 
comprise an entire block set out in trees and shrubs and valued at 
$1,500 or more. The building contains eight schoolrooms, two 
recitation rooms, a laboratory and an office, and is heated with furnaces. 
The apparatus and library, exclusive of textbooks, are valued 
at $675. The building is furnished with single seats throughout. 
Twelve grades are represented in this building. The board of education 
and the citizens of Wisner exhibit an excellent school spirit. 

FLORENCE PUBLIC SCHOOL AND GROUNDS 

The Florence school building was erected in 1889. For the purpose 
of building and furnishing this schoolhouse and purchasing 
the site, the school district voted $13,000 in bonds. The building 
contains six schoolrooms with a seating capacity of fifty pupils each 
and an entertainment room which will seat nearly 200 persons. 
This will later be used as a high school study and assembly room. 
There is also an office fourteen feet square. A steam heating plant 
was recently placed in the building at a cost of about $2,000, and 
the rooms are ventilated in the old-fashioned way by raising the 
windows and inserting draught boards under the sashes. Notice 
particularly the beautiful grounds and the way in which they are 
terraced. 

M'KINLEY SCHOOL, LINCOLN 

Pnew McKinley school building in Lincoln is of brick with 
trimmings, eighty by one hundred ten feet, two stories and </seg>


            <seg id="p145">CRAWFORD PUBLIC SCHOOL 

WEEPING WATER PUBLIC SCHOOL </seg>

            <seg id="p146">
IMCTDI^'T C U /"*\ I ill y-y /%o ni TC3T* /~*/"^I Tkfpv 
1 'I o I n I C I -|i&gt;t - r*t t it,. IL.- IN O. Jo, dLJ K I v^vJLJ 1^ 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p147">
397 


l»sement in height. The two stories contain ten rooms, and above 
them is a fairly large and well lighted attic which will be used for 
light gymnastic and calisthenic exercises. The finishing throughout 
is polished oak, with maple floors in the halls and hard pine 
floors in the schoolrooms. The blackboards are of artificial slate. 
The lighting of the rooms is according to the most approved plans, 
with broad windows at the left of the pupils and high windows in 
the rear of the rooms. The gravity system is used for heating and 
ventilating. In the basement are toilet and storage rooms and three 
rooms for manual training, domestic science and art. The cost of 
the building, exclusive of the heating apparatus, was $25,000. The 
building is heated from an outside plant which is also used to heat 
the high school buildings on the same block. The additional expense 
for the heating plant was $5,000. </seg>

            <seg id="p148">
398 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

A Proposed School Law 

r PROVIDING FOR THE HEATING, LIGHTING AND VENTILATING 
PUBLIC SCHOOLHOUSES, AND FIXING PENALTIES FOR A 
VIOLATION OF THE PROVISIONS THEREOF 

Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska: 

EtoN I. It shall hereafter be unlawful in the state of Neto 
let any contract for, or to construct any public schoolor 
school building, or to reconstruct or remodel any oM 
schoolhouse or other building, to be thereafter used for school purposes, 
the lighting, heating and ventilating of which is not in full 
accord with the provisions of this act. 

Sec. 2. All public school buildings, hereafter constructed or remodeled 
for school purposes, must be lighted by windows placed in 
the rear and side wall or walls of each class and study room, and 
such windows shall contain glass surface of not less than one-fiftli 
of the floor space of each room ; and all desks and seats shall be so 
arranged that the windows shall be on the left and in the rear, s« 
far as possible, of the pupils. 

Sec. 3. All class and study rooms shall contain not less than fifteen 
feet of floor space and not less than one hundred and eighty fe«t 
of air space for each pupil. 

LSec. 4. All public schoolhouses or school buildings of four or 
jre rooms each, which shall hereafter be constructed or remodeled 
for school purposes, must be provided with such heating and 
ventilating apparatus as will facilitate the introduction of warm 
air, when occasion requires, into each class or study room, not less 
than eight feet above the floor line, with provision for the exit of 
impure air at the floor line ; and the whole shall be so arranged that 
the required temperature can be maintained throughout each room 
and the air changed in each room (measured at the exit opening) 
at least six times in each hour without lowering the temperature 
or creating a noticeable draft at or below the breathing line. 

Sec. 5. All closets and urinals must be so constructed as to provide 
for the separation of the pupils using the same. They must 
also be provided with vent flues, so arranged that all foul odore 
and air will be carried out below the brcathintj line* </seg>

            <seg id="p149">
399 


Sec. 6. Any contract for the construction or remodeling of any 
school building, not in conformity with the requirements of this 
act, shall be void ; and any public school officer or contractor who 
shall violate the terms and conditions of this act, by letting or accepting 
any contract for the constructing or remodeling of any 
public schoolhouse or school building not in conformity with this 
act, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be subject to 
a fine of not less than fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars 
for each offense. 

We believe that the standards for school architecture, including 
the proper seating, heating, lighting, ventilation and ornamentation 
of school buildings should be as definite as the standards for teaching. 
The law should fix the dimensions and all other requirements 
of school buildings as well as the size and character of school 
grounds. — From declaration of principles adopted by unanimous 
vote of the National Educational Association. </seg>

            <seg id="p150">
400 


The Rural School Problem: A Solution. 

-OLIDATION OF SCHOOL DISTRICTS, CENTRALIZATION OF SCHOOLS, 
AND PUBLIC TRANSPORTATION OF PUPILS. 

fhave great faith in the rural school, in its powers, and of what 
nay do for the individual pupil, but I think the result of its work, 
the average does not ccmpare with the work of the best city 
ools, and cannot under the present conditions. How to improve 
the present conditions is a serious problem, and I know of but one 
solution. Rural mail delivery is now spreading through this western 
country. Roads are being improved. Telephones are coming 
into common use in the country as well as in the cities. Several 
counties in the eastern part of the state have lately organized county 
telephone systems, and before long all calls for physicians, for supplies 
and provisions, for broken castings for farm machinery, for 
twine for the binder, for drugs and medicines and for hundreds of 
other little things will be by telephone, and thereby one-half of the 
time usually expended in securing them will be saved. 

We must enrich rural life and increase the advantages of the 
farmer and his family in order to counteract the flow of humanity 
from country to city. A census bulletin issued last year states that 
the percentage of population of the United States in cities of 8,000 
or more inhabitants has steadily increased each decade. It was 
3.4 per cent in 1790, 12.5 per cent in 1850, 22.6 per cent in 1880, 
29.2 per cent in 1890, and 33.1 per cent in 1900. The percentage 
of our population that lived in cities of 4,000 inhabitants or more 
in 1880 was 25.8 ; in 1890, 32.9 ; and in 1900, 37.3. These figures are 
significant. They mean that from 1880 to 1890 seven persons in 
every one hundred of our population moved from country or village 
to city and none moved hack. From 1890 to 1900 four or five persons 
in every one hundred moved from country or village to city 
and none moved back. What shall we do to be saved from our 
great cities? Shall we permit the decay and destruction of our 
E: country life, or shall we endeavor to bring some of the great 
forts and conveniences and advantages of city life into the 

Now for years we have been working at cutting up this state and </seg>

            <seg id="p151">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

401 

Hs counties into small school districts. Schools of a few pupils are 
the rule, and large schools are the exception. What inspiration can 
the pupils of a school of three or four or half a dozen have to do 
good work? There is no life, energy, inspiration, emulation or desire 
to excel. The school is dead spiritually and intellectually, and 
I have seen many a small school that might as well have been discontinued 
as far as practical results were concerned. You may be 
doing well under the conditions, but what are the conditions ? How 
could they be much worse ? Poor, battered old schoolhouses, sometimes 
lacking paint, with cannon-ball stoves, and cheerless yards; 
while in our cities we are building modern, scientific structures. 
correctly heated, ventilated, lighted and seated, often built of brick. 
sometimes with stone foundations and with beautiful surroundings. 
Many of the best schools of the state are in towns employing from 
three to six teachers. There they have but two or three classes in 
each room, with all the rooms in one building, a principal who may 
know what each class is doing, thereby securing better and closer 
supervision than is possible in larger places, and a janitor to look 
after school property. 

Why do you not have the same in your rural communities ? It is 
not an impossibility. Let me suggest to you what has been done 
in some of the eastern states. Thirty &gt;ears ago in Massachusetts 
they began centralizing their rural schools by public transporlaUini 
of pupils in vans or wagons. About ten years ago the plan had 
reached Ohio, and in the last few years it has spread into Indian*. 
Illinois, and is now being strongly advocated in Iowa. Briefly the 
plan is this : Instead of nine rural districts with about four sac* 
tions of land each, teachers with salaries of about $35. and an average 
enrollment of twenty pupils, we have in the center of the 
township a brick building of four rooms, with forty-fire popib) in 
each room, and two or three grades only. We may have a principal 
of considerable training and experience, who receive!! a snhvjr 
of from $60 to $75, and teaches the highest room. The three other 
teachers receive about $45 each. There is a janitor who look* after 
the building, its heating plant, its toilet rooms or outbuildings and 
the grounds generally. There may be sheds in which the horse* 
are kept during the day. The pupils are gathered from iinm 
parts of the township by covered vans or wagons that start at 
</seg>
            <seg id="p152">
402 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

lished route, picking up the children along the way and delivering 
them at the schoolhouse at about 8:45; distributing them again 
after four o'clock in the afternoon. Where the plan has been in 
operation, the drivers selected are clean, capable, sober men, not 
given to profanity or tobacco, and are paid $25 or $30 per month. 
They furnish their own team and wagon, with lap robes, and as a 
rule, carpet their vehicles and provide seats ; let me say right here, 
that in bad weather, in rain or storm or strong wind, I would rather 
my child would ride five miles in such a vehicle than walk one or 
two miles. In pleasant weather, I would just as soon have him 
walk as ride. 

CONSOLIDATION OF SCHOOLS 

P&gt; overcome the many disadvantages in the present rural school 
m in Nebraska, and for the purpose of giving every farmer's 
and boy in this noble commonwealth opportunities equal to 
those of the girls and boys of the village and city, we recommend 
to the careful consideration of every rural school board and to the 
fathers and mothers in these rural districts the consolidation of 
schools and the transportation of pupils. Consolidate, or centralize, 
the weak districts into a common central school, conveying the 
pupils from every part of the greater district or the congressional 
township to and from the central schools by means of covered vans 
or wagons, in charge of clean, capable, careful drivers. Such a 
plan would now be legal, as the six-mile limit in the formation of 
school districts has been removed. And we already have the transportation 
law. Notice the following provisions of Nebraska School 

1. One district may be discontinued, and its territory attached to 
other adjoining districts, upon petitions signed by one-half of th« 
legal voters of each district affected. (Subdivision 1, Section 4, 
Fourth Condition.) 

E'he six-mile limit in the formation of school districts has been 
ed, and districts may now be formed extending more than six 
in any direction. 

EThe district board may (and usually should) close the weaker 
smaller schools in a district and transport the pupils at public 
nse to any other school in the district. A board of education of 
y, or a board of trustees of a high school district, by a two- </seg>

            <seg id="p153">
SCHOOL BUILDI 

403 

thirds vote of the entire board, or a district board of any school d*»-trict 
in this state when authorized by a two-thirds vote of those 
present at any annual or special meeting, is hereby empowered to 
make provision for the trans|x&gt;rtation of pupils residing within ami 
district to any other school (within said district) to which said 
pupils may lawfully attend, whenever the distance from Mich schoota 
shall render it impracticable for said pupils to attend without transportation. 
(Subdivision 5, Section 4b.) 

4. Or, the district board may close school and transport their 
pupils at public expense to a neighboring district without forfeiting 
the state apportionment. A board of trustees of a high school dktrict. 
•r a district board of a school district in this state, when authorised 
by a two-thirds vote of those present at any annual or special meeting, 
is hereby empowered to contract with the district board of any 
neighboring district for the instruction of (all) pupils ruiuwip, m 
the first named district in schools maintained by the neighboring 
district, and to make provision for the transportation of said papa* 
to the above-named school of the neighboring district wider the 
conditions named in the preceding section ; Provided, That school 
districts thus providing instruction for their children in neighboring 
districts shall be considered as maintaining a school as required 
by law; Provided, further, That the teacher of the lilt ¦— ag 
school shall keep a separate record of attendance of all pupils from 
the first named district and make a separate report to the daractar 
of said district. 

Cidea of consolidation and transportation is not original with 
has proven a success in many states east of Nebraska. The 
of the plan may be briefly stated as follows: 

1. It permits a better grading of the schools and classification of 
pupils. Consolidation allows pupils to be placed where they can 
work to the best advantage, the various subjects of study to be 
wisely selected and correlated and more time to be given to radiations. 
Pupils work in graded schools, and both teachers and pupih 
are under systematic and closer supervision. 

t. It affords an opportunity for thorough work in special 
nches, such as drawing, music and nature study. It also alhHM 
enrichment in other lines. 

3. It opens the doors to more weeks of schooling and to school* 
•f a higher grade. The people in villages almost in variably </seg>

            <seg id="p154">
404 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

lengthen the school year and support a high school for advanced 
pupils. 

4. It insures the employment and retention of better teachers. 
Fewer teachers are required, so better. teachers may be secured and 
better wages paid. 

E makes the work of the specialist and supervisor far more 
e. Their plans and efforts can all be concentrated into someangible. 


Kadds the stimulating influences of larger classes, with the 
g enthusiasm and generous rivalry. The discipline and 
I obtained are invaluable. 

7. It affords the broader companionship and culture that comes 
from association. 

8. It results in a better attendance of pupils, as proved by experience 
in towns where the plan has been thoroughly tried. Attendance 
is from 50 to 150 per cent greater, more regular and of 
longer continuance, and there is neither tardiness nor truancy. 

Pit leads to better school buildings, better heating, lighting and 
lating, better equipment, a larger supply of books, charts, maps 
apparatus. All these naturally follow a concentration of people, 
wealth and effort, and aid in making good schools. The larger 
expenditure implied in these better appointments is wise economy, 
for the cost per pupil is really much less than the cost in small and 
widely separated schools, but the cost in nearly all cases is reduced. 
Under this is included cost and maintenance of school buildings, 
apparatus, furniture and tuition. This expenditure may be inaugurated 
gradually, by removing four or five of the better school 
buildings to the central location for temporary use. 

10. It quickens public interest in the schools. Pride in the quality 
of work done secures a greater sympathy and better fellowship 
throughout the township. Pupils are benefited by a wider circle of 
acquaintance and culture resulting therefrom. The whole community 
is drawn together. 

11. The health of the children is better, the children being less 
exposed to stormy weather, and avoiding sitting in damp clothing. 

K Public barges used for children in the daytime may be used 
isport their parents to public gatherings in the evenings, to 
\ courses etc. </seg>




            <seg id="p157">

405 

SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

13. Transportation makes possible the distribution of mail 
throughout the whole township daily. 

E[. Finally, by transportation the farm again, as of old, become* 
ideal place in which to bring up children, enabling then) to se: 
the advantages of centers of population and spend their evenings 
and holiday time in contact with nature and plenty of work, 
instead of idly loafing about town. 

We are in the midst of an industrial revolution. The principle 
of concentration has touched our farming, our manufacturing, oar 
mining and our commerce. There are those who greatly fear the 
outcome. There are those who prophesied disaster and even the 
destruction of society on the introduction of labor-saving machinery. 
We have adjusted ourselves to the new conditions thus introduced. 
Most of us believe that we shall again adjust ourselves to 
the new industrial conditions. The changes in industrial and social 
conditions makes necessary similar changes in educational affairs. 
The watchword of today is concentration, the dominant force is 
centripetal. Not only for the saving of expense, but for the better 
quality of the work must we bring our pupils together. No manufacturing 
business could endure a year run on a plan so extravagMt 
as the district system of schools. </seg>

            <seg id="p158">
406 


Statistical Tables 

SCH( 

ilhous: 

in neb: 

ho. or 
SCHOOL 
DISTRICTS 

WOOD 

BBICK 

¦TOMB 

SOD 

1870.... 
1873.... 
1878.... 
1881.... 
1884.... 
1886.... 
1890.... 
1891.... 
1892.... 
1893.... 
1894.... 
1896.... 
1880.... 
1887.... 
1898.... 
1899.... 
1900.... 
1901.... 
lWl«.... I 

377 
797 
1863 
2680 
3271 
3834 
4667 
6243 
6417 
6610 
6630 
6641 
6893 
6731 
6741 
6703 
6706 
6708 
6674 

""tie" 
848 

2772 
3433 
4656 
4932 
5159 
5317 
5385 
5520 
5544 
5590 
5606 
5704 
5760 
6631 

"ie" 
46 

92 
176 
235 
242 

267 
294 
293 
298 
302 
304 
313 
312 
320 
827 

6*" 
30 

29 
66 
46 
31 
39 
36 
31 
36 
29 
32 
36 
33 
42 
25 
26 

80" 
138 

........ 
220 
210 
184 
188 
146 
151 
,-140 
159 
159 
137 
141 
112 
132 
121 

3" 
76 

338 
367 

496 
528 
734 
732 
698 
690 
622 
603 
517 
606 
464 
436 

* •KM 1 't 

• Includes 1 iron 

.nd 1 baled 

itrmw. t Ii 

icludes Z iron, t Includes I iron. 

•• Includes </seg>

            <seg id="p159">
SCHOOL BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. 

407 

SMALL SCHOOLS IN NEBRASKA 

ietaiUd statement of the number and distribution of the small rural ttkotL 

in Nebraska 

THE PROBLEM: WANTED— A SOLUTION 

COUNTY 

ATTEHDANCF. 
OP S PUPILS 
OK LESS 

ATTSKDAIfCB 
ABOVB 3 »UT 
ROT MO* K 
THAN 10 

ATTXHDAItCF ATTriDtHCl 
ABOTK M BUT AWOVP V, OTT 
HOT M &gt;« K WOT X 
THAM ¦ T«*-&gt; 9 

Adams 
Antelope 
Banner , 
Btaine 
Boone 
Box Butte 
Boyd 
Brown 
Buffalo 
Bnrt 
Butler 
Cass 
Cedar L 
Chase 
Cherry 
Ch^ytnne 
Clay 
Colfax 
Cunring 
Custer 
Dakota 
Dawes 
Dawson 
Denel 
Dixon 
Dodge 
Douglas 
Dundy 
Fillmore 
Franklin 
Frontier 
Furnas 
Gage 
Garfield 
Gosper 
Grant 
G-eeley 
Hall 
Hamilton 
Harlan 
Hayes 
Hitchcock 
Holt 
Ho*ker 

1 
9 
9 
2 
2 
12 
1 
3 
6 
1 
2 
2 
5 
11 
5 
25 
•J 
2 
1 
19 
0 
15 
6 
15 
1 
0 
I 
8 
1 
7 
6 
2 
3 
2 
4 
0 
6 
2 
2 
2 
9 
11 
58 
1 
1 

7 
-'7 
7 
4 
IS 
¦ 
12 
17 
IS 
II) 
11 
•jo 
ii 
¦21 
3 
I 
10 
¦ 
4 
20 
14 
•-•» 
•Jl 
7 
4 
19 
11 
20 
3) 
16 
22 
11 
U 
3 
19 
6 
11 
21 
15 
34 
6b 
0 
12 

14 
4 
¦1 
l.t 
19 
11 
44 
16 
S, 
M 
9 
14 
'.'I 
n 
u 
n 
17 
13 
23 
7 
19 
29 
14 
10 
17 
14 
33 
¦ 
66 
6 
19 
1 
15 
20 
Xi 
24 
13 
16 
29 
1 
1» 

? 
13 
3 
16 
s 
s 
] 
§ 
I 
21 
9 
¦ 
1 
24 
i </seg>

            <seg id="p160">
408 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

TABLE II— Continued 

COUNTY 

ATTEND V MCE 
OP 5 PUPILS 
OB LESS 

ATTKNDANCK 
ABOVE S BOT 
MOT MORE 
THAN 10 

ATTENDANCE 
ABOVE 10 BUT 
NOT MOBS 
THAN 15 

ATTEDDAKCI 
ABOVE 15 BUT 
NOT MORI 
THAN JO 

Johnson 
K»arney 
Keith 
Keya Paha 
Kimball 

2 
0 
0 
20 
5 
7 
• 
5 
17 
2 
1 
0 
I 
4 
C 
0 
I 
4 
3 
31 
3 
2 
5 
0 
9 
1 
10 
1 
1 
0 
3 
2 
18 
5 
4 
2 
4 
0 
0 
2 
0 
1 
0 
12 
1 

16 
10 
7 
15 
24. 
4 
22 
6 
30 
3 
9 
14 
2 
8 
18 
7 
19 
19 
6 
14 
.7 
16 
8 
6 
23 
10 
21 
11 
4 
8 
5 
14 
39 
21 
9 
13 
13 
0 
5 
18 
4 
19 
11 
8 
13 

23 
22 
4 
16 
1 
34 
aa 
¦ 
6 
4 
20 
2 
13 
21 
2T) 
19 
31 
21 
4 
30 
22 
22 
18 
18 
24 
13 
32 
7 
19 
3 
32 
18 
21 
¦ 
15 
27 
I 
4 
ID 
9 
30 
2f&gt; 
4 
24 

16 
21 

Knox 
Lancaster 
Lincoln 
Logan 

Loup 
Madison 
Mcl'herson 
Merrick 
Nance 
Nemaha 
Kuckolls 

Otoe 

Pawnee 
Perkins 
) helps 
Pierce 
Platte 
Polk 
Red Willow 
Richardson 
Rock 
Saline 

Sarpy 
Sauntlers i 
Scotu Bluff 
Seward 
Sheridan 
Sherman 
S'oux 
Stan ton 
Thayer 
Thomas 
Thurston 
Valley 
Washington 

Wayne 
Webster 
yr~.:::::::::::::::: 

4*9 

1362 

1687 

1243 </seg>

            <seg id="p161">
409 


Eese statistics are taken from the annu.U report* of the county »u\miiUt»mAof 
Nebraska for the school year 190C-1901. They show that Ik* MMH 
ils are greater in number than moat of us knew. There arc «9 seaaaai 
with an average daily attendance of five or lew; 1 ,841 with tea or Icaa; 3.MB 
with fifteen or leas; 4,771 with twenty or less. There are aboiH 6.300 strictly 
rural school districts in Nebraska . This makes nearly th ree-f onrtha of omr rani 
schools in each of which is an average daily attendance too sanall for rigaajaa, 
interesting and profitable work, either educationally and socially or aaaacMry. 
No time need be spent in rehearsing these facts. No school cms claiw eomtUtions 
for good work if it have less than twenty-five pupils; yet there a*v 
rural schools in Nebraska in operation with an average daily attcadaace raaging 
from one to twenty pupils. I believe we are all ready to anite apoa tMa 
proposition — the pupils in these small rural schools must be coUectad mto 
larger and better schools with better teachers, better paid. " It daw sat Matter 
how much we deplore the condition which makes co— olidarioa of acaaafti 
necessary, the fact remains that it is the only rational solutioe of the MaaaBa 
that has been offered." 

WILLIAM K. FOWLBR. 

S/a*V SwtVnu/r^ 'lent 

Lincoln, Nbbr., December 31, 1901. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>