<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Relation of Environmental Conditions in Poultry Houses to Winter Egg Production</title>
               <date value="1930-08">1930-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 247 August, 1930 The Relation of Environmental Conditions j in Poultry Houses to Winter Egg Production CHAUNCEY W. SMITH ; De|fartment »'f Agricultural Knicintfrinu "IffisWifcarSe-.-- ' tS^WTf^l l' ■gl^if'^' 'l It''" The four similar- houses seen in this picturej were each divided into two unit*. These eijrht units constituted the housing plant for this experiment. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. HuiiK. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Summary .... , .. :i Introduction ..•'... &#132;....: ..'... ..:.... ~&gt; Detailed Description of Units ..:. The Effect of Temperature on Winter Egg' Production . - • N Temperatures maintained in the various units.. 8 Egg production in relation to temperature.: . . l:'. The EfFect of Humidity on Winter Egg Production 1&lt;! The Effect of Air Change and Air Movement on Winter Egg: Production .... -I Carbon dioxide tests.: -1 The effect of stirring the air. 24 Changing air rapidly and steadily. -'"&gt; Air changes caused by heat... • . -' Commercial ventilators .. -*' Artificial Lighting :.'... ..... 29 General Discussion.. .... 30' </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARV :'. ■ ■ • ' ' ■ " '"--.■ Insulation had a beneficial effect on winter egg production. The uninsulated check house was always low in egg production in January and February. Closing a house up tightly all night during] the winter season had no detrimental effect, on ..winter egg ■ production. This procedure showed no merits that would warrant its being recommended for • general practice. It did show that hens can thrive in an environment where there is very little air change. The use of a small stove to lower the humidity but not to raise the temperature appreciably- proved to be of doubtful value as measured by winter egg production. ] 'Steam-heated radiators, when used to keep a minimum temperature of 50 F. in poultry houses, increased egg production in December, January, and February. A smaller increase was produced in December than in the latter months. The hens in the | heated houses slumped during March, when their production fell slightly below that of the hens in the unhented houses: The following figures give a comparison of the egg production in the heated and the unheated houses for four months, taken over two, three, and five seasons. Fifty degrees F. was; arrived at as optimum in the light of two years' experience in heating houses. Thus, the first two years during which steam-heated radiators were used did \ hot give results as favorable to the use of heat as the last three years, :&gt;nd the figures taken for the two seasons and three seasons are con - . Ridered more indicative of the value of heat i in poultry houses than ■ the figure's taken over the entire five seasons, i Tin- ciigx prr hen per month hy which the heated /louses excelled the iinhetited hoimen when averaged over 5,\ 3, and iZ seasons Dec. ■ Jan. Feb. March 15)2-1-25 to 1928-29 inclusive 0.9 1.4 0.6 -1.1 l:'2tS-27 to 1928-20 inclusive 0.4 13.7 2.1 -0.5 " 1927-28 to l'.»28-2'i inclusive 2.2 J4.1 1.5 -1.2 No correlation was found between humidity and winter egg pro - duction. The heated houses had a very low humidity. The house Closed tightly at night had an- abnormally high humidity for Nebraska. A commercial ventilator was installed in ohe of the heated houses and used the last two seasons of the experiment. A heated house, identically the same with the exception of its not having a commercial ventilator, was used for comparison. The ■ only provision made for ventilation in this latter house was muslin-covered transoms and windows. The following tabulation gives the totals of the average eggs per hen in each house for 1927-28 and 1928-29: Nov. Dec. Jan. Feb. March House with commercial ventilator 14. 6 14.8 28.1 27.8 35.8 House with no commercial ventilator ... 15.5 18.0 28.7 26.1 34.7 The small differences between these two houses were no more than one would expect in houses alike in all respects. A commercial ventilator was also installed j in one of the unheated houses and used the last two seasons of th!e experiment. Another unheated house just like the first but having no commercial ventilator was used for comparison during- the' last two Seasons. The total eggs per hen for the seasons 1927-28 and 1928-29 by months were as follows: Nov. Dec. Jan. Feb. March House -with commercial ventilator 16.8 113.1 22.1 23.6 36.4 House with no commercial ventilator.... 12.7 |13.3 19.9 24.1 35.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 November and January showed an advantage for the house with the commercial ventilator. During the ■ other months the advantage alternated between the two, as it might be expected to do in houses having no differences. These comparisons made over two seasons and involving four houses and 740 hens indicate that the use of a commercial ventilator will not increase winter egg production sufficiently to pay for the ventilator and its installation. An electric fan for stirring the air was operated in one of the heated houses for three seasons and produced no results warranting the installation of the same. An exhaust fan, which moved large quantities of air from one. heated unit the last three seasons of the experiment, produced no re - sults warranting its installation. . Muslin-covered transoms offset much of the advantage gained by insulation. They permit but little air change. Artificial lighting is a very potent factor in increasing egg produc - tion in the winter. One unheated and uninsulated house was arti - ficially lighted two seasons before lights were installed in all houses. During those two seasons its production exceeded that of any other house. The research covered by this bulletin involved 8 houses and 4,527 hens and was carried on for seven seasons. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Relation of Environmental Conditions in Poultry Houses to Winter Egg Production CHA'UNCEY W. SMITH I The purpose of this experiment was to determine the effect on winter egg production of the following environmental con - ditions: (a) Temperature when changed by i (1) Insulation, (2) Closing a house tightly all night, (3) A small stove, (4) Steam-heated radiators ; ! (b) Humidity when changed by (1) Closing a house tightly all night, (2) Steam-heated radiators, I (3) A small stove, (4) Commercial ventilators, (5) An office fan; (c) Ventilation as occurring in (1) A house closed tightly all night, (2) A house having an office fan, (3) A house having an exhaust fan, (4) Houses steam heated and with muslin-covered transoms, (5) A house steam heated and with a commercial ventilator, (6) A house not heated but having a commercial ventilator, (7) Houses both heated and imheated having tran - soms covered with muslin ; (d) Artificial light, which lengthens the active period and therefore the feeding period of poultry each day. Work on this project was begun in the fall of 1922 and was concluded in the spring of 1929. Eight units were used in this experiment. By a unit is meant one-half of a 20 x 40-foot, shed-roof poultry house, having walls of drop siding and being 9 feet high in front and 5 feet at the rear. A partition thru the center of each house divides it into. two parts, each 20 x2O feet. These parts will hereafter be referred to as units. All of these faced the south. Each one had originally three double-sash windows in the front or south side with transoms above, the transoms being covered with muslin for ventilation. Several of these units were changed somewhat to meet the needs of the ex - -1 The author wishes to acknowledge the assistance received from Professor F. E. Mussehl of the Poultry Department and Professor O. W. Sjonren of the Agricultural KnKtneerine Department. The experiment was conducted co-operatively between the two departments. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 2-47 J Un ' f - •• Urorerf £//&gt;,7j. o^rf VintilaHon. 3 ilnlfinif ii-i-i. hn — i — i — I 1 ■ = ~ SL. -£. o_ t_ f__ £_ h_ D_ c_ f_ _c_ !*_■ - &amp; c \o \ c I - j Z — ' „ aaLjaaa* , . jp^j j . - ts2i2tun_«u_,u__ \ '_ ; i - '■'?'?.'- , . " ' ***•" ' '*• -f ''""■'■ . j i. 'f}fd »* '/; nail' fcare. ■ '. ':'■"'% "'!* ~'' *~'" ■""&gt; &lt;'»r«M with ~,;*rr a , „&lt;;„/. ■-■ c^,,X"*"&lt;.;r.v.,"!° /r "'" c '"' r " J *** FlG unitT N / 1 u 1 1 lI n,'h anCl kin r,' &gt;f P«.'!??«.-.»*&gt;UiImum temperature in lu»at,&lt;l I v,.n conditions relative- to insulation, lights: &gt;t,,v... |ment maintained :n each unit nil seasons of the expori - periment, as can be noted in Figure 1 and in the -detailGfl description which follows. Figure- 1 rives c t il I I i , f, , „,. tion on all units and should bejSSiM to^fSquenth ?' l™fa fal? of ?92^ re rn S? t d r thrUOU - t -^.^"^ent. beginning in S tail ot 1922. Lmt C was included in the fall of 1923 and 'ill thef'aH of 8^" 8 - , U ' litS D ' 5' F ' G ' and H wenfaddec! 1 the fall of-1924 and were used all seasons thereafter , ihe number of pullets in each unit varied a little from season to season, as can be seen by referring to Figure 1 ?S Snfts numberwa8 evenl - v distributed thru the Severn' Lights, which were automatically turned on at 5 \. m thus increasing the length of the working day for the nulled were installed in Unit H in the fall of 1924. ' They were used again in Unit H the following season, 1925,26 The Results of°TrJ?ff S - e i^P seasons proved so conclusively the advantage of art ficial lighting for poultry houses that lights, auto- Sf3 lof°ff3 ted T^ in f Unit^ H&gt; W f re installed in * U »"«?£ tne tan ot 1926. Therefore, the only comparisons that can be made from these data regarding the effect of lights on winter nn?fJ"f S 10 ? mUSt be made betwee » Unit H and the other units for the two seasons, 1924-25 and 1925-26. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production detailed description of units •n-Hri !!.,1 A hZl USe^ as a Qh # from the pefifinning- It had no a t hnal heat and no ventilation other than windows with C^ ' i° n V ?l . C0 V t ei ; etl 1 with . mu , sl i. n - Nothing was done to sur.tne an m it. It had no insulation. L nit B was lined with wall board at: the beginning of the shie'-lnir'^t th %} ranso ™ were boarded up tightly, both in - side and out. Storm doors and storm ! windows were fitted which were closed each evening at 4 o!clock and opened the next morning at 7. The only change in this unit was the addi - tion oi lights during the last three years. I nit C was first used during the season of 1923-^4 It had no insulation the first season but a small coal-burning brooder stove was used in it. during the cold weather. The following season it was lined with wall board and the space between the drop siding and the wall board was! packed with mineral W °,n:&gt; ;\* I brooder stove was again iised during the season ot 1924-25. A stove was not used in this or any other unit aiter that season. Unit D was included in the experiment in the fall of W4 It was lined with wall board and equipped with 117 square teiu of steam-heated radiation surface. The heat supplied to this unit was automatically controlled by a thermostat which could be regulated for a minimum temperature. The mini - mum temperatures used during the experiment were: 70' F. in 1924-25, 65= F. in 1925-26, 50' F. in 1926-27, 50 c F. in 1927-28, 50" F. in 1928-29. This unit had a commercial ventilator installed in the fall ot 1927. Unit E was included in the. experiment in the fall of 1924 It was lined with wall board and furnished with 117 square teet of steam-heated radiation surface. The heat supplied was" automatically controlled as in Unit D, but for different minimum temperatures, which were: 60' F. in 1924-25, 60' F. in 1925-26, 50 n F. in 1926-27, 50 F. in 1927-28, 50' F. in 1928-29. Muslin-covered transoms and windows were depended upon for ventilation in this unit thruout the experiment Unit F was fitted for use at the same time and in identically the same manner as Units D and E. The only difference </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 between Unit F and the other heated units at first was in the minimum temperatures maintained, those for Unit F being: 50° F. in 1924-25, 55° F. in 1925-26, 50° F. in 1926-27, 50° F. in 1927-28, 50° F. in 1928-29. An electric office fan was installed in Unit F in 1926-27 for the purpose of stirring the air. It was used three seasons, 1926-27, 1927-28, and 1928-29. Unit G was fitted for use at the same time and in identically the same manner as Units D, E, and F. It was lined with the same kind of wall board and had the same number of square feet of steam-heated radiation surface. It differed only in the minimum temperatures, which were : 40° F. in 1924-25, 50" F. in 1925-26, 50° F. in 1926-27, 50 ' F. in 1927-28, 50° F. in 1928-29. . An exhaust fan was installed in the fall of 1926 and used each season thereafter. It moved the air at a rate of about 300 cubic feet per hen per hour. Unit H was first used during the 1924-25 season. It had no steam heat and no insulation. It differed from all other units for two seasons by having lights automatically turned on at 5 o'clock each morning. In the fall of 1927 it was lined with wall board and the space between the drop siding and the wall board was packed with mineral wool. A commercial ventilator was installed at the same time one was installed in Unit D, and of identically the same type. Unit H was used with this equipment the last two seasons of the experiment. and permitted a comparison of the action of a commercial ventilator on a heated with the action on an unheated unit. It also permitted a comparison between two unheated units : one having a commercial ventilator and the other not having one. THE EFFECT OF TEMPERATURE ON WINTER EGG PRODUCTION TEMPERATURES MAINTAINED IN THE VARIOUS UNITS The environment with regard to temperature was changed in the poultry houses in this experiment by the following means : (a) Different degrees of insulation in poultry house construction, (b) Closing a house tightly all night. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production - (c) A small stove, (d) Steam-heated radiators. Two units were used during the first season of the experi - ment, 1922-23, which show by comparison the effect of in - sulation on the temperature of a poultry house. Unit A had no insulation. Unit B was lined with wall board and had storm doors and windows, which were closed from 4 o'clock each evening until 7 o'clock the next morning. As shown in Figure 2 and Table 1, the greater protection provided in Unit Table 1. — Temperature record for a period of six days, j Febnmry 6 to 11 inclusive, 1923 \ - Average Average of Average of Average Unit temperature, maximum minimum fluctuation Fahrenheit ■ I temperatures j temperatures per day i Degrees • Degrees Degrees Degrees A 29.9 37.8 , 21.6 ' 16.2 ■ *"■(.■■'•• ' ! B ; 37.5 41.2 31.3 9.9 ■ ' ■ I- ■ I Outside....! 22.9 32.2 12.2 20.0 . ! ' I ■Rpfor to Figure 1 (or a &lt;1 tviil.-il description of each unit. / '-." y=-.-i&gt; Jan. II -16 Jan3S-30 i*mi£0J*3 J*nZ:-?7 j»n X-Jt I91&amp;-2J f/j-%t "/h*7'eS "?9l : i'-S&lt;S '/9JO-27 isSr-23 &amp;%e-23 ■j O~ A.vr&lt;-.&lt;jf eutilde trin£cra'r*re 1- ■■•:■■■•■■•".." r i 1 liiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiyii Fk5. 2. — A comparison of the average temperatures in the Units A, B, C, and H, and outside temperatures for six consecutive cold days in each of the seven seasons, 1922-23 to 1928-29 inclusive. It shows the average increase in temperatures that may be expected from use of insulation. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of each unit. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 2-47 Table 2. — Temperature record for a period of'-' six days, January 1 to G inclusive, W2J t ' :..■ i ■ . ■ .'".". Average Average of Average of Average Unit temperature, maximum minimum fluctuation Fahrenheit temperatures temperatures per day -Degrees Degrees Degrees Degrees A......... ! 12.0 24.8 0.8 24.0 B •• -6.7 35.0 I8.. 1 ? 16.7 .. C. . ■ 20.4 36.S 4.2 , 32.6 Outside... 4.8 14.2 '• -9.0 • 23.2 'lt.;fi : r u, Figure 1 fur :. detail .1 ,1. m-ripiiftn •■( -a.-!, unit. B maintained an average temperature 14.6 degrees higher than the average outside temperature and 7.6 degrees higher than the average temperature of Unit A over a period of six days. 'February 6 to 11, inclusive, 1923.. During the 1923-24. season, the same two units were used. A and B, which served again to compare t he average tem - peratures of an insulated with an uninsulated house. The re - sults i with regard to temperature can be seen in.' Figure: 2 and Table 2. Unit B, the one insulated, maintained, over ~\ six-day period, January 1 to 6 inclusive, an average tem - perature 21.9 degrees higher than the average outside tem - perature for the same period and 11.7 degrees higher than the uninsulated Unit A. During each of the five following seasons, 192 4-25 to 1928-29, there were four units which could be used in com - paring the effect of insulation on poultry-house temperature, Figures taken from a six-day period, January 1 1 to 16 in - clusive, 1925, show that Unit B, the one lined with wall board and fitted with storm doors and storm windows, which were used from 4|P. M. to 7 A. M., averaged: ■ ,7.9 degrees higher in temperature than the check. Unit A, 4.9 degrees higher than the .lined and packed Unit. C, 8.5 degrees higher than Unit H, which was similar to Unit A, and 24.1 degrees higher, than outside. These results can be seen by referring to Figure 2 and Table 3. The fact that Unit B averaged higher in temperature than Unit C, which was not only lined with wall board but had the space between the drop siding and wall board packed with mineral wool, and contained a small brooder stove, must be accounted for by the use of the storm doors and windows on </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production Table S.—Tenipemture record for a period of six days IStU'lHtV-Z 11 to Ui inclusive, 1025 ' r,,;, » Average Average of Average of Averaee Unit temperature, maximum minimum fluctuation Fahrenheit temperatures temperatures "per day Degrees Degrees rkg~re~c~s~ ~~De~g~re~e~s A -' . • 2M 39.7 21.3 18.3 11 ;)7 - 5 46.7 30.8 15.8 :J2 -« 44.5 23.8 20.7 H&gt; . 29 -° 40.7 20.7 ' 20.0 Outside 13.4 20.8 4.7 1 6 2 'liefer u, Fi Bur &lt;. 1 for u detailed d. wription c,f each unit. ~" ~~ ' Unit B and also by the fact that the transoms on Unit B were hi Unit C P 5% WhilG the&gt; ' Were °" ly °° Vered with muslin H.^-f ' r foo! ke u fro^ a . f, x : lla y P eriod . January 25 to 30 in - clusiye, 1926 show that Unit B maintained an average tem - perature 2 8 degrees higher than Unit A, 0.5 degrees higher Mah Ul Vi C&gt; degreeS higher than Unit H - and IS'-S degrees higher than the average outside temperature. It: must be remernbered that so far as insulation was concerned, UnitI A and.H were identical that season. These comparisons for the season of 1925-26 are shown in Figure 2 and Table 4 Table 4— Temperature record for a period of six days Janiuiry 25 to 30 inclusive, 1926 ■ ..I i — ===== TTn&gt; 1 * Aver age , Average of I Average of Average temperature, maximum minimum fluctuation _ * ahrenheit temperatures temperatures | per day Degrees Degrees Degrees Degrees A 41:5 49.1 32.3 16.8 B "4.3 49.1 36.0 13.! C • ■• 43.8 47.8 37.8 10.0 H • 41 - 3 47.2 31.3 15.9 Outside 31.0 37.8 21.8 16.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 Table 5 furnishes the figures for the following comparisons for a six-day period, January 20 to 25 inclusive, 1927 : Unit B averaged 3.3 degrees higher in tempei-ature than Unit A. Unit B averaged 5.2 degrees higher in temperature than Unit H. TABLE 5. — Temperature record for a period of six days, ' January 20 to 25 inclusive, 1927 Average Average" of Average of Average Unit temperature, maximum minimum fluctuation i Fahrenheit temperatures temperatures ' per day Degrees Degrees Degrees ' : \ Degrees A 31.3 38.3 24.3 14.0 B 34.6 39.8 27.7 12.1 C 35.9 38.3 28.9 9.4 H ... 29.4 36.1 21.9 . 14.2 Outside.... 14.5 21.5 I i 6.2 15.3 Unit B averaged 20.1 degrees higher in temperature than outside. Unit^B averaged 1.3 degrees lower in temperature than Unit C. These results are shown graphically in Figure 2. Figure 2 and Table 6 give the results regarding insulation for the period of six days, January 22 to 27 inclusive, 1928 : Unit B averaged 6.2 degrees higher than Unit A. Unit B averaged 2.2 degrees higher than Unit C. TABLE 6. — Temperature record for a period of six days, January 22 to 27 inclusive, 1928 Average Average of Average of Average Unit temperature, j maximum minimum fluctuation Fahrenheit j temperatures ; temperatures j per day Degrees Degrees Degrees Degrees A 35.3 . 46.7 25.3 .21.4 B... 41.5 50.6 33.5 17.1 C 39.3 .47.4 . 30.8 ■ 16.6 H 37.7 44.7 . 29.6 15.1 Outside.... 25.2 34.9 10.8 24.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production Table 7. — Temperature record for a period of six days, January 20 to 31 inclusive, 1929 Average Average of Average of Average Unit temperature, maximum minimum fluctuation Fahrenheit temperatures temperatures per day Degrees Degrees Degrees Degrees A ..:.... 29.3 37.3 j 20.7 16.6 B. ■. .. .V.\ ... 32.7 37.5 i 24.4 13.1 C ........ -33.3 36.4 25.8 10.6 H 31.3 35.5 26.0 9.5 Outside.... 8.8 14.7 2.7 12.0 Unit B averaged 3.8 degrees higher than Unit H.- Unit B averaged 16.3 degrees higher than outside. Figure 2 and Table 7 give the results for a six-day period, January 26 to 31 inclusive, 1929: Unit B was on the average 3.4 degrees higher than Unit A. Unit B was on the average 0.6 degrees lower than Unit C. Unit B was on the average 1.4 degrees higher than Unit H.- Uriit B was on the average 23.9 degrees higher than outside. EGG PRODUCTION IN RELATION TO TEMPERATURE The effect of temperature on winter egg production in houses whose differences in temperature have been primarily due to differences in amount of insulation used in construc - tion is shown in Figure 8, (page 20) where the average tem - peratures for five winter seasons are shown and directly above them the egg production for the corresponding poultry house units. The following arrangement gives the relative stand - ings of the units in egg production for five seasons: Units arranged according Units arranged according to Seasons to descending temperatures descending egg production 1924-25 :■■-■ BC A H HA B C 1925-26 BCAH HCAB 1926-27 CBAH CHBA 1927-28 - B G H A H B C A 1928-29 |p:B H A BACH By considering one unit at a time, it can be seen that in temperature Unit A , the check, which was a plain drop - siding unit with no insulation, was third three times and • "Unit H had a commercial ventilator in it during the seasons of 1927-28 and IB2S-23. This was the only condition in which it differed from Units A and B other than in insulation.' </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 fourth twice, while in egg production it was second twice, third once, and fourth twice. Unit B, the one lined and closed tightly at night, was 'first three times in temperature and second twice, while in egg pioduction it' was first once, .second once, third twice, ami fourth once. Unit C, with walls lined and packed with mineral wool, was first in temperature twice, and second three times, while in egg production it was first once, second once, third twice, and fourth once. Unit H, the one with lights all seasons and walls lined and packed the last two seasons, was third in temperature twice, and fourth three times. In egg production it was first three times, second once, and fourth once. This unit was arti - ficially lighted two seasons before lights were used in' all other units: There is reason to believe that it was the lights which caused it to rank first in production two years. The fact that Unit A, the one with no insulation, was never first introduction and was last two out of five times affords evidence for the value of insulation. One observation can be made at this point regarding the futility of basing con - clusions on one year's results. In 1927-28, Unit II had its walls packed with mineral wool and a commercial ventilator installed in it. and it was first in egg production. The follow - ing season with identically the same equipment it was last. That some difference in temperature might be accounted for by differences in air movement is self-evident. Thruout this experiment Unit A depended on muslin-coverecl transoms and windows for ventilation. Unit B depended on windows. Unit C depended on muslin-covered transoms and windows and Unit H depended on muslin-covered transoms and windows until the last two seasons when it was equipped with a commercial ventilator. Since one of the primary Objects of this experiment has been to determine the protection within these various units during the coldest days, figures taken over six-day periods for comparisons have been taken for six con - secutive cold days. During those .periods the windows were' not opened for ventilation and the units were- dependent on the other means provided. • Consequently the fact that the windows were used in warm weather need not lie considered in using the figures of tables submitted in this study. It will be seen that so far as ventilation is concerned. Units A. ('. and H were alike until the last two seasons when II had a commercial ventilator. . For three seasons. 1924-25. 1925-26, and 1926-27. it is a case of comparing Unit B with no provision for ventilation with Units A, C, and H, which had muslin-covered transoms. By referring to the arrangement of units , according to de- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production scending temperatures and descending egg production as given on page 13, it is seen that Unit B is first three times in temperature and second the other two times. This would seem to point strongly to the conclusion that lessening the amount of air movement makes it possible to maintain higher average temperatures. Regarding egg production, Unit B was first once, second once, third twice, and fourth once. No gain or loss in egg production, it would seem, can be attrib - uted to the small air change permitted in Unit B. Where Unit H had been consistently last in temperatm^e for the seasons of 1924-25, 1925-26, and 1926-27, it stepped up one place (luring 1927-28 and 1928-29. During the last two sea - sons two changes had been made in Unit H: its walls had been lined and packed and a commercial ventilator had been installed. The more favorable temperatures shown during the last two years would seem to have been due to insulation rather' than ventilation. A small stove was used in Unit C two different seasons, 1923-24 and 1924-25. Figure 2, Table 2, and Table 8 show the effects of the stove the first season. Units A and C were alike in other respects.. The stove raised the temperature of Unit C above that of Unit A but not equal to the average temperature, of Unit B. Of course it would be possible to install a stove and fire it so that the temperature of the unit in which it \vas located would be higher than that of any unit depending on insulation alone. In this case the purpose was to take the chill off the room and determine the effect on the poultry. The production f.or the three months, January, February, and March, 1924, as shown in Table 8, would indi - cate that the small amount of heat used had helped. The production in Unit C was consistently higher than that in Unit A. During the 1924-25 season, Unit C was lined with wall hoard, its walls were packed with mineral wool, and it was supplied with, a small stove. Figure 2 and Table 3, to - gether with the arrangement of the units as shown on page Taklk 8 — .4 record of the number of hens in Units A, B, and C and their' egg production for three months — January, Febi'uary, and March,^924 ____; Unit Hens . Total ejrs s Product ion Number , Number Per cnl A . 104-101 1287 13.9 B ......,......: 107-104 1634 17.1 C ::..-. ..'..: | 103-97 1626 18.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 217 13, make possible the following comparisons. The average temperature of Unit C was higher than that of Units A and H, but not so high as the average temperature in Unit B. The egg production in Unit C that season was the lowest. Com - parisons are not so readily made for the season of 1924-25 as for the previous season because there were more points of difference among the units. If the low production in Unit C is to be attributed to environmental conditions, one of the following should take the blame: Walls lined with wall board, Walls packed with mineral wool, The use of a small stove. There are reasons for believing it wrong to say that be - cause Unit C was low in production that year, insulation and heat are detrimental. On the contrary, they are usually bene - ficial. It seems to have been one of those instances .when the unseen factor has predominated. Finally, temperature was affected by . steam-heated rad - iators maintaining predetermined minimum temperatures in four different units, D, E, F, and G. During the 1924-25 season, those minimum temperatures were as follows: Unit D, 70° F.; Unit E, 60' R; Unit F, 50° F. ; Unit G. 40* F. Among the steam-heated units, D, E, F, and G, Unit E. the one having a minimum temperature of 60° F.. showed the most favorable results.. It was thought that 70' F. was too higli when the work was begun, and 40° F. was thought to be too low. The 1924-25 work substantiated those views. The following season, 1925-26, the minimum temperatures maintained in the heated units were as follows: Unit D. 65' F.; Unit E, 60° F.; Unit F, 55° F. ; Unit G, 50' F. During both seasons, 1924-25 and 1925-26, the dust in the heated units was a serious problem. It was agreed at the conclusion of the 1925-26 season to use 50° F. as a minimum temperature in the steam-heated units for future work and consequently all steam-heated units had that minimum tem - perature regulation for the following three seasons' work. Figures 9, 10, and 11, (pages 24 and 25) show that when the averages are taken over a considerable number of seasons the heated units show a decided advantage in egg production during the months of January and February. THE EFFECT OF HUMIDITY ON WINTER EGG PRODUCTION No attempt was made in this study to increase or decrease the humidity within the poultry units by artificially adding to or subtracting from the moisture of the air before it was admitted to the units. On the other hand several conditions were created which did change the relative humidity within </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production the units a very considerable amount. These conditions were as follows: (a) Closing a unit up tightly all night, as was done with Unit B, raised its relative humidity. (b) Heating units with steam lowered the relative humid - ity. This was done in Units D, E, F, and G. (c) A small stove lowered relative humidity. (d) A ventilating system, which moved the air faster than ft would otherwise have moved, affected the relative humidity. (e) An office fan, which stirred the air, changed the rela - tive humidity. Continuous records of the relative humidity, both inside and out, were taken during the entire period of the experi - ment. Figures 14 and 15 (pages 29 and 30) show the rela - tive humidity of all the units and the relative humidity out - side. These figures illustrate how the humidity data were recorded. As can be seen, the i-elative humidity of the heated units fell below the outside relative humidity most of the time, while that for the unheated units was above the outside relative humidity for the most part. The facts are shown graphically in another way in Figures 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7. M Avmragr /Vumtter of Cg&lt;/s per Hen from Dec I to Apr I ■ C2 Relative Hum.dily C per cent) — Average Jan S6-Jf (/nclujiyr) ISSS :.;•;■■■:■&gt;.-: ,■■■■. ;•; £eo ■ • n ■ ■ T'&lt; :.fl f n ■ P R uliiiiii A BCD £ r C H UNITS Fig.- 3.— A compai-.ison of the average relative humidity and the average number of eggs per hen in all units for the season 1924 - i:i2"&gt;. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of each unit. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 I92J - t9se MB Averay Numhmr of £$f* per Han from No* I to Apr. I F77] Relaf$v0 Humidity (per e*r&gt;t) — Averoge Jan 26—Jan. JHmclut **)192G * m n n ' ■ n ' 1 0 / R ■•'■'■ / ill! I II li ll I I "111111111 &gt;i a c o ■ l r g h ■ UNITS Fig. 4. — A comparison of, the average relative humidity and the average number of ettps per hen in all units for the season 1925 - 192G. See Fiff. 1 for detailed description of each unit. 1Q26-f9s7 ,•■•■"" ' ' i ■■ Asc roue N umb*r of Cyos "par- Hen frOTt '-■ . / to Apr I F2Z Relative Humidity (percent) ~A*«rayv Jan 23 -Jan. 2B ( ineluu* e) fs2 7 !- n ' . '. . n .:. * 7 ° v\ R f\ ■ ■■■■' r ■ * ■ . / n .■■•■■• 'i 1/ I" - 7 7 ■ / I' ll: ; i • '• in in in ly in ih ih ih /A C O C F G H UNITS Fig. 5. — A comparison of the average relative humidity and the average number of eggs per hen in all units for the season 1926 - -1927. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of each unit. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production 1927-1923 TZA Reiat-ye ~&lt;*n,sr* (per cent ) Average Jen /6 — fea 4(tr.cluSiV€)/9£&amp; , 9&lt;- - ; ■ . i Bo "■■■■■ '::'..'■■-■;': ■' 5" • •' Fl . * ro / ■••;■■■. * ' y\ ' / ■ ' n v ; ' ' r ■ pi / s 1 ., / / / / ..' ; / / / tf ' ' / / / / / \\V- - * / &gt; / i / „ ' ', ' &lt; . ' ' &lt; ' , , ' ' / ' ' ' / - B K I 1M ■ M 1M IM |[/| m\A |[J /! a c : a ■ f c a h UNITS Fir.: G. — A comparison of the average relative humidity and the average number of eggs per hen in all units for the season 1927 - 1928. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of all units. 1928-1923 mm Average Mumb*r of Lqj-s ' per Hen from V». / to Apr. I ZZ2 Relative Humidity (per cent)— Average Jan 16- /&gt;b IC (inclusive) 1&amp;43 A B C 0 E r C H UNITS Fig. 7. — A comparison of the average relative humidity and the average number of eggs per hen in all units for the season 1928 - -1929. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of each unit. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 Dec. to Mar Nov. to Mar Dec. to Mar Nov. to Mar A/ev. rv Mar mcluziv* tnc/ujiv* mclujtv* mclustvt iricluitr* 1924 - IS2S 1925 "1926 1926 - 1927 192 7' /923 /923 - 1923 70 Illlllllllllllllllll so -jj-- BBBBBB3B 3BBBBBBB BBBB Fig. B. — Average temperatures over six-day period for each of live years and the eggs per hen from each of the unheated units. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of each unit. A small stove lowered the relative humidity considerably in Unit C during the 1923-24 and 1924-25 seasons. The pro - duction in Unit C showed favorably in 1923-24, as can be seen by Table 8, but unfavorably in 1924-25, as can be seen from Figure 8. Commercial ventilators were used on Units D and H during the 1927-28 and 1928-29 seasons. Neither of these units showed any unusual variation in humidity from those with which they could be compared. Consequently, if the com - mercial ventilators had affected egg production favorably, it could not have been attributed to the effect they had on rela - tive humidity. An office fan was used in Unit F three seasons, 1926-27, 1927-28; 1928-29. The average relative humidity in this unit differed but little from that in the other heated units with which it could be compared. Any value, therefore, that stirring the air might have can not be attributed to a change made in humidity. There are no doubt regions where the rela - tive humidity is so high for long periods of time that it reflects adversely in the egg production of poultry, but after this study of its effects for seven years it seems there is no evi - dence that adverse conditions regarding humidity are like'y to occur in Nebraska with any of the prevailing housing methods. The relative humidity of Unit B was consistently </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production high each year, as can be seen from Figures 3 to 7 inclusive, and yet its egg production reflects no corresponding differ - ence, either favorably or unfavorably. The conditions main - tained within Unit B were as conducive to an abnormally high humidity as any are likely to be in any poultry house in Nebraska. The average relative humidity in the heated units was as low as is likely to occur in any poultry house in Ne - braska. The egg production was usually higher in the heated than in the unheated units, but the evidence would attribute this increase to the heat rather than to the lowered humidity. THE EFFECT OF AIR CHANGE AND AIR MOVEMENT ON WINTER EGG PRODUCTION Air change and air movement were made to differ in the several units by the following means: (a) Unit B was closed up tightly all night. (b). Unit F had an office fan which stirred the air within it. (c) Unit G had an exhaust fan which changed the air at a rate which would supply about 300 cubic feet of air per hen per hour. (d) Steam heat caused the air to move thru its natural course faster than it would have done otherwise. (e) Commercial ventilators. The rate of air movement was obtained in some instances from the records of CO 2 tests, in others by the use of an anemometer. Table 9 gives the results of CO.. tests for the first- year. They are sufficient to show that air change had been successfully stopped in Unit B where the COo content ranged from 50 to 70 pai-ts in 10,000 where the outside air contained only from 3 to 4 parts of CO^ in 10,000. Figure 16 (page 33) shows the arrangement of the apparatus as used in making the tests, and the following description will assist those who are interested in the methods used in making the CO.. tests. Those who take for granted the accuracy of the work and care only for the general conclusions may skip the following section. CARBON DIOXIDE TESTS Four 19-liter, bottles were filled with a saturated solution of calcium chloride because of its lack of affinity for CO*. A bottle of the solution was then taken to each unit in which a sample was to be taken and one bottle was used to take a sample of the outside air. The samples were taken at seven o'clock in the morning; care was taken to disturb the air conditions within the unit as little as possible. The calcium chloride was poured out of the 19-liter bottles into another container, the solution being displaced by air from within the house. The bottle was then tightly sealed and taken to the laboratory to be tested by a </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 gravimetric method, observations having been made at the time of taking the sample of the barometric pressure ami the temperature. • w . In . Figure 16, (page 33) C represents the sample of air *irst with valve 1 closed and 2 open, pinch cock 4 was opened allowing water from B to siphon into D, and the air from 1) thus was torced thru the soda lime bottle E, where any CO It^^ 1 "" 1 would be absorbed. From E it was passed thru the H,SO, drying bottle F, where any water the air contained was absorbed. This was continued until it was certain that the apparatus was filled with air from which the CO. and the H,.O i had been removed: Therefore this air could add nothing to the weight of the tube I, which absorbed the CO. from the sample. The bottle E contained soda lime, a mixture of NaOH and CaO. This reagent not only absorbed the CO. but also most of the water from the air which was passed thru it When enough air had been passed thru the apparatus to make certain that no air. remained containing CO., the valve 2 was closed, the absorption tube I inserted and valve 1 opened. There was usually considerable pressure in the sample bottle due to the expansion of the air on being brought from the cold chicken houses to the warm laboratory. It was therefore necessary to open the valve 1 cautiously. This pr C &lt; - sure was sufficient to cause air to pass thru the apparatus for a period of five minutes or more before any. displacement fluid needed to be used. But as the pressure' within the sample lowered to that of the room, the pinch cock :', was opened and the solution from A allowed to siphon into C. This drove the sample of air thru the apparatus. It was first dried in F then passed thru the Ag.SO, solution G where any fumes such as those of HC1 were absorbed. This precaution was felt to be unnecessary. Consequently, in our work for 1024 and 1925 this Ag,SO, tube was omitted. A CaCl drying tube H was next encountered. This absorbed any moisture that might have passed the H,.SO, tube. The sample then reached the absorption tube I. which contained two materials: Lewis lye and CaCl,, separated from each other by a plug of glass wool. The CO, was absorbed by the Lewis lye and II 0 was a product of the reaction involved. To make certain that none of this water was carried out of the absorption tube, the CaCl, was added, which absorbed the water. J contained the same ingredients as the absorption tube but in the re - verse order. Both CO, and H,0 would be absorbed from the air before it could reach the absorption tube, in case any back pressure accidentally occurred at any time. The absorption tube. I was weighed immediately, after the apparatus had been filled with air from which CO. and HO vapor had been removed. It was Weighed again" after the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 o TABLE 9. — The results of carbon dioxide tests made in Units A and I!; also the results of tests h on tmt side air 2 ■ Volume 'o( ■ &lt;:Oi in sample | I'arlii of ('().■ in I'l.n" Temperature Hariimetrr Vnlunu 1 of • sumpl.' at . Weight of at 32° P. 10,000 at 82" F. jX pate gurnplp taken sum|:l ■ whrn when sitnipli 1 samplu (!U? in sample ' and 860 mm; and 760 mm. Hi? y' tnki'n wtmplo lafccn was taken ■ tllo mm. 11k 11k by viilumc pj h"l. I'. ■ '■ | Clt, ctlttimttrrit M'u. ri'tttiiiuttT* \ drum* ' Cu. rtiitirmtrrs 2-l^-l!)'il ... ... OJtsklc •_'S.:!11 1S.4S0 1S,7:1II .011^ 7. HI 3.8J &gt; 2-15-l!)2:i ..; . Outside ' I 29:576 19,180 20,280 j .012-1 fi.27 3JJ9" C 2-12-l!121 Unit A 32 28.811 . 19,270 1 S.2-II) .0705 35.65 19,54 -^ 2-l. r .-!92! .. ... Unit A . 70 29.57(1 19,271) 17,(i80 .0721! :!6.7fi 20.S0 ~ 2-15-192.1 . Unit II 21 -'!i..".7fi 19,105 ■■ 19,550 • .2722 1:17.80 70.10 p* 2-18-192^ Unit It ilO 29.0SI 19,465 19,000 .2192 110.00 58.10 W 2-18-1923 Unit It :W -29.084 19,480 lfl.OOO .2450 12-1.00 B5.10 gi 2-21-1923 Unit A :I7 29.080 19,465 18.730 .08!)fi 24.20' n 2-21-192.1 Unit A 3'. 29.080 I9,',80 18.7:10 .09.18 25.85' |T) . - j. ! .,_ ! ' 5 'Th.e muslin vcntilltora nv« the windows wcro covered with tar papt'r the nislit before this sample was taken. Two window? 'n Unit A were always O dropped one notrh at niKlit for ventilation. These windows were open this amount on niKhts preceding the taking of all samples from this Unit A. C . ■ H </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 2-47 entire sample had been passed thru it. The difference' in weight between the two readings gave the COj absorbed. The weighing was done on a scale weighing in grams to the fourth decimal place. A counterpoise was used to lessen the -error due to hygroscopic moisture. Table 9 gives a summary of the tests made in 1923. THE EFFECT OF STIRRING THE AIR It has often been stated that discomfort in a. room is due to the lack of air movement rather than to its high CO. con - tent, its temperature, or its relative humidity. Acting upon this idea it was planned to stir the air in one unit by means of a fan. In the fall of 1926 an 8-inch office fan was installed in the upper middle front of Unit F and directed straight back into the house. .It was used all the time except on mild days when the doors and windows were opened and the hens turned out into the yard. The use of such a fan would not be expected to affect the CO.. content of the air or its rate of change. The fan was used three successive seasons. 1926-27-. 1927-28, and 1928-29. By noting the egg production for those three seasons in Figure 10 and that for Unit F in particular, it will be seen that of the heated units, Unit F was highest in total production in January when averaged over three Seasons. During the other months it was only a good average. The use November December January February March Two Jeojans Two Seasons Two Seasons Two Season Trvo Secse-i 40/917-O IB28-9 1927-0 I92O-9 1327-8 /32B-9 I927B 1326-9 1927-B J926-9 jj ZZ3 Heated Units W^UnheuTrJ Units ' a JO ■ , '/ 111 SiS if A BC DC. r C H ABCOCrCH ABCDLFGH ABCOCTGH AO C O L F OH Fig. 9. — Total eggs per hen per unit for November, December, Janu - ary, February and March of the two seasons, 1927-8 and 1928-!). See Fig. 1 for detailed description of each unit. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production * 1 "™'" Decmmbmr Jonuery ' February March ? a %°Z°"' rt "~' e S ' oso "* Thr " Season, Three Seasons Three Season, 1926-7 1920-7 1926-7 IO26-7 1926-7 I9Z7-B 192S-9 1927-e 1926-9 1927-6 I92O-9 /627-0 IS2B-0 I0Z7-0 1928-9 ss -j ED ■•«of.t.' Unltj U\ ■■ Unheafed Units ■ - - 4S ' ■ ■*" D ' ' fl • ' ' JS , ' ■ ■ f ' ■ ' , ' a oc ot ra h a, ac oc re h abcdc re H -. s c o l re h a o c nc r a h Fig, 10. — Total eggs per hen per unit for November, December, Janu - ary, February and March of the three seasons, 1926-7, 1927-8, 1928-9. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of- each unit. November Decembtr January February March riff ■Seiaonj five Seasons FTre Seasons FTre ■Seasons FTre Seasons /9&amp;-S 1924-5 /92-f-J IBZ4-S 1924-S ??ii"S '.t 26 ' 7 I92S ' 6 I92O-7 iaZS-e I9Z0-7 I9ZS-6 I92O-7 I92S-C 1926-7 IS27-O 1920S 1927-e 1923-9 I927-O 1920-9 1327-e I92O-9 I327~B /9ZO-Q (H3 Healed ' Unl/j Oj ■■ CIn/tcated Units ao ■ ■ , 70 ' . , I* n RR n H :H - : :: \*o ■■■: /, ::; ABCOerOHAaCDCFCH ABC O CrOH A3 CO CF CH ABC D CFCH Fig. 11. — Total eggs per hen per unit for November, December, Janu - ary, February and March of five seasons, 1924-5, 1925-6, 1926-7, 1927-8, 1928-9. See Fig. 1 for detailed description of each unit </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 table 10. — Air-chaiige data compiled from tests with an anemometer in Unit G during March, 1927 . Linear velocity 1 Air Air ■ Air Ontaide Date, 1!&gt;2J air ■ per 'minute changes . per hour rondjtinn* ■ per minute ': per hour ( per hen I Ftit &gt; Cubirji-'t , Xumber ] Cubic fret March 8 : 24119 ' 47:1 -10.13 322 Str.&gt;lii! wind (r-rn 2321 4"&gt;fi 9.77 HUP south 2373 46fi 9.98 318 2:lfi2 IB I 9,94 :il" Mnrrh 9 . . 2:121 45t&gt; U.77 31 1 Wind from ihi - 2275 448 H.fiO . 306 mirth 2226 137 • 9.36 298 ■ ' 2207 4:1.1 U.28 29.". March IT 2199 4:)2 9.25 294 Light breiwhl'iW - 1 2234 4:19 9.40 299 Ing from south' . Windows open . .. 2216 ' 4:19 9.10 29!) wert. March 17 1 2154 42:1 SUMS 288 2110 414 8.87 282 2160 ■ 424 9.0H 290 Windows iI.imiI 2167 126 ' 9.12 291 ' . • ■!'• 2191 i:lO 9JJ1 29:1 TABLE 11. — -4 record of the air change made in Unit G during [March, 1928 Linear velocity Air Air. Air Outside Date, 1928 ' air per minute changes per hour condition* ; per minute . per hour , per hen hot Cubic fat Sumbrr Cubic frrt March IB S:00 a. m. 20:)6 :I9U.O6 8.S. r . :l. r i7.M Ccld, ilimdy.plr. r.i: 198. r i M89.00 834 348.0 wind from north. 20H6 404.00 8.67 362.0 Windows clo«-d. 2008 . . :)97.00 K.52 355.0 2095 416.00 8:93 .172.0 March 23— 3:00 p. m. ' 22:« 443.00 9.52 397.0 Clear, warm, stn.r.K 2095 . 400.00 8.58 358.0 wind from south. , 2179 432.00 9.27 . 386.0 Windows dosed. 2231 443.00 , 9.52 397.0 2245 445.00 9.55 398.0 March 24 —1-1:00 a. m. 2222 441.00 9.46 394.0 Clear, cold, flight 2232 443.00 9.52 397.(1 breeze from north 2211 438.00 9.42 392.0 Windows closid. : I 2221 142.00 : 9.48 395.(1 2222 441.00 9.46 394.0 March 27— 8:00 a. m. 2122 421.00 i 9.03 376.0 Cold, cloudy. Mill. 1 2123 i 421.00 ! 9.03 376.0 Windows clnsid. 2207 438.00 ! 9.42 392.0 1 2135 . 423.00 I. 9.08 : . 379.0 2296 456.00 ] 9.78 408.0 of the fan had evidently done no harm ; it might have ac - counted for a slight increase in production but its. effect was too slight to warrant much consideration. CHANCING AIR RAPIDLY AND STEADILY An exhaust fan having a 6-inch, flue was installed in the upper front of Unit G in the fall of 1926 and used for three seasons. King 3 has given 35 cubic feet of air per hen per 1 P. H. KinR : Ventilation for Th8eUing#, Itttrnl Schootn, and Stnhfm ( published ir. 1908 at Madison, Win.), p. 41. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production hour as the minimum recommended air change. This fan moved nearly 300 cubic feet of air per hen per hour. Tables 10 and 11 give some data taken from. Unit G for two different seasons. It is readily seen that air was being changed in Unit G at a much greater rate than any one would reasonably advise; nor was the- temperature of the unit made too low on account of the air change because it was steam heated with a minimum temperature of 50° F. If fresh air will make hens produce' in the winter, those in Unit G most cer - tainly had an opportunity. A study of Figure 10 with par - ticular attention to the production of Unit G shows that Unit G was only an average. Therefore it can be said that there was nothing in the record of Unit G to encourage the use of artificial ventilation by means of a fan. AIR CHANGES CAUSED BY HEAT It is well known that in heated houses rate of air change is increased over what it would be in the same houses if not heated. It is reasonable to assume, therefore, that the air movement was greater in the heated units than in those not heated but having the same means for ventilation. Steam heat was used in four units, D, E, F, and G, for five seasons. During the first two seasons they all depended on muslin- January 1929 Fltf. 12. — A six-duy portion of the temperature record of the un - heated units and the outside temperature. It shows the fluctua - tion of temperature in those units. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 ~S C-OOQ / © \ 0900000 O 0O3GOOO OOO ■QOOQOOQQOOQQ&lt;Xy%y? jj BiitiiiniMam i 1 43 ...;:■■ y&gt; l_ ■ '_ 0, __ — - — — . | r : : ■ 1 J? 1 t*\ Unit a o o ?*° f \ • •. Unit£ c e . 5! ■ \ «»)f&gt;. a-, — « ... .:•? If- / A A UnltG f \ •- IO . I . \ \ Outside m . »■ , ■ n ° "'■'■'. ' '. I V / January /9Z 1 ) Fig. 13. — Temperatures of the heated Units D, E, F, and G, and the outside temperatures for a six-day period, January 2G to 31 in - clusive, showing how nearly alike the temperatures were in tru - ncated units and how they were recorded for the entire period of the experiment. covered transoms for ventilation. ■ All other units except Unit B had the same means. It is impossible to make any clean - cut distinctions between the beneficial effects of heat and those effects due to air movement caused by the heat. If. however, air movement .in the heated units had been respon - sible for improved conditions, the use of the commercial ventilator in Unit D and the exhaust fan in Unit G would have been expected to produce more tangible results. COMMERCIAL VENTILATORS During the last two years of the experiment. Units D and H I were each equipped with the same type of commercial ventilator. Both units were lined with wall board and the walls of Unit H were packed with mineral wool. The main difference between the two units was that Unit D was steam heated and Unit H was not. From the production records of these two units for the last two seasons as given in Figure 9, it is seen that Unit D was high among the heated units by a small margin for the months of February and March. For the entire season it was only average. Unit H was the best </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production 9Si ' — ■ ■ ■ . - i l^P^^V-y^ZT" A, f Unit A » » / . \J j Un,TH 0 o If- V I f Outside ■ ■ j- : \ 2 6 ? T PR ? ft .!/» .11 January 1929 Fig. 14. — A six-day portion of the relative humidity record of the unheated Units A, B, C, and H, and theoutside relative humidity. It shows the relative humidity to be higher in the units than out - side most of the time, and highest in Unit B. ill production among the unheated units during the months of November and January. Its advantage in January over Unit B was small. ARTIFICIAL LIGHTING Artificial lighting, which lengthens the working day of hens in the winter, has a very decided effect in increasing produc - tion. The production in Unit H for the two seasons, 1924-25 and 1925-26, when it was the only unit equipped with artificial lights, is convincing proof of their value. The production in Unit H for those two seasons was better than in any other unit, heated or unheated. From December 1 to April 1, 1924 - 25, the average production of the hens in Unit H was approx - imately 5 eggs more than from those in the next highest pro - ducing unit. From November 1 to April 1, 1925-26, the average production of the hens in Unit H was approximately 13 eggs more than from those in the next highest producing unit. This evidence has been corroborated from so many different sources now that it does not seem advisable to devote more space to it. Artificial lights can do more to increase </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 2-17 winter egg production than any other purely physical change in the environment of hens thus far observed. GENERAL DISCUSSION Table 12 and Figures 9, 10, and 11 afford a study that can be pursued deductively. The final results are shown in Figure 9 for two seasons, in Figure 10 for three seasons, and in Figure 11 for five seasons. Those individual units ami groups of units which excelled during any one or move months car 1 . easily be seen. During the 1927-28 and 1928-29 seasons, the production from the heated units was consistently higher than from the unheated units during the months of December. January, and February. The production in the heated units fell a IiU'k. below average in March. During November there were no • consistent differences between groups. These results an evident from Figure 9. Combining the three last seasons' production, practically the same results are found as when taking the two seasons. 1927-28 and 1928-29. The three seasons' results are shown graphically in Figure 10. The four heated units excel indi - vidually, and as a group for January and February. They- Unit O o ~j J JT\ Unit £ x j&gt; / f\ ■ 0S n \A/"S J" UniT r * *f J . January I9Z9 Flo. 15. — A six-day portion of the relative humidity record of the heated Units D, E, F, and G, and the outside relative humidity. It shows the effects of heat, a small fan and an exhaust fan en relative humidity. • " </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Table 12.— Average nvJmbenyf eggs per hen in each -unit, for the last life seasons of the r ;. experiment . ~ i 1021' 1O'"&gt; ! 192G 19"7 i I'fH • 1924 ! 1925 \ l!i2G 1027 IMS JU .Unite Months tM .1926 { 1927 i^8 | : Unit j _ Mm,tl&gt;s ; [ ; 192B | 1927; 1928 t»29 g November. 6.7 .'.'... j- 7.2 | .7.3 (November . ol'.... I' !'.V 6.0 , ,-. : w A January 11.1 1.0 H.5 11 A ' 6,6 E January 4.4 ; 3.G j M.6 6.S l;0 tfl March y :::.::: ml 2ol 17J ZOJ is| ,j ; March : --.^--..J5- 9 __Ji£_ _ 2 i;Ll iJI^.. 3 9 _ 5 November ' • G 5 ■ fi.2 I fi.5 i Ncivimlirr 6.:1 X.O .4.0 M neccmbfr S.9 20 6.4 7.0 : 5 4 • . i !&gt;.■&lt;■&lt; mb.r :..: 4.5 6.8 4.2 1.4 1.2- g March.. 18.5 21.2 20.0 17.5 18.1 , . | March. 16.7 . 20.7 ,-M UA ! *_^__ o ■ November..."... 7.7' -3J) "'...:■ "^ &lt;!•« ! vl ' m tl' r ..., 21 si : ?"*| I |S Decemlx-r 4.8 5.9 1.9 7.8 7.0 I ! )pcombcr ; 3.9 J.I 5^ -1 5.8 &gt;_, I) January 13 j 3.8 l.t.8 17.5 lo.li II January | ... 17.8 | 7.3 &gt; . ; Fnbruary 10.2 13.0 l".(i 13.5 14.3 ; ftbrtmry. ....... 6.8 20.4 ; 17.fi 4 j •'••. o March. 14.9 20.fi 10.!) 20.0 , l.VS ; March I 17.5 23.0 j JO., I 19.0 j 17.4 ,_, ~Tho averagoTumbcr "of eggs per hon 'for tho s-as.m" 1924-1925 »as gotten by .lividin K the total number of nw lai&lt;l each month in each unit by the Q original numlie? of bifdTpMin each unit. For all other sewon. the mortality eacb month wa S dwljrte.1 before calculations «fre made. g </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 November.... I liV | %6 --J"i" r " b,rffar, f T ~7Sp7rv^'S; " ~ ~- ~— ~ . December i oT'.?? "Jf] - 27 ■ 7!M 27.75 3.45 jf M7 ■ /^,'" r!r i&gt;"«a« Du /,, 1M ~ „ - W November. 7Bn I or»r "IT*- "~j~ ■ — — ■ — . — n ' ' ' ll T &lt;&gt;t«l- ■•-...! siio ha-.as'l «i 12 I lirrs,:,,.:;,, " rT" .•-■- — --—----ill 6 - 376 1495 31,57 20.76- .m C . . . ' .' ■ . ro ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Poultry Houses and Winter Egg Production SJ!? B ifS«!2? n ii' t ?f 5 H^ ?* ur $ for 4 ™ SS^tGSe liSht thanin FW 11&gt; o Unit , H is placed in a more favorable ngnz man in figures 9 and 10. It must be remembered that during the 1924-25 and 1925-26 seasons Unit H Tas the onfy SrodSfi^w ai ' tificia l "#&amp;** and that this inc'easld the Production in H very materially over any other unit. Figure 11 averages the five seasons and the advantage that Unit H 7f Apparatus for Car boh Dioxide Tesr &gt;"-": V-Z-T C *•*■«» Ctlcium Oi.de ■Him: Wi:£ i P&amp;$^3isr e ~*' I ■ . f ~ $/&gt;•&gt;« C/.., t^rf, FlG idJ C Ss. SketCh ° f tl]C apparatus uscd in making the carbon diox - had for two seasons places it in a morei favorable light than is done when averages for only two or three seasons are ta ken. during which period all units were equipped with artificial lighting. During January and February, when the heated units excelled there was not enough different amon| the four to account for any of the differences in the manner of treating them Unit D had a commercial ventilator "n - stalled in the fall of 1927. This added equipment gave Unit Unit O F?3 P £rffl ad f van t a^ i " the aviage of two yea ?s Unit b had the office fan in it for three years. This eauiD - me nv m + a , de t u° a PP recia ble change in the production for Unit L^ 1 , 1 three-year period. Likewise Unit G, with the ex - aust fan giving a large air change, had no appreciable ad - .\antage ovei V th , e period. Unit E, the only one of the four heated units which had had no accessories added </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 247 other than the steam heat and lights, averaged as well -as any of the heated units. Among the unheated units, A, the check, with no insulation, no heat, and no artificial ventilation, was consistently low in January and February. Unit B, which was closed up tightly during the night, was about average among the unheated units. Unit C, having walls lined and packed, was better than the 'average among the unheated units. Unit H, which had the commercial ventilator the last two years of the experi - ment, showed to an advantage in 1927-28 and to a disad - vantage in 1928-29. When its average is taken over two years, it was high in November and January. Unit C had its Avails lined and packed identically the same as Unit H. The only difference between the two the last two years was that Unit H had the commercial ventilator and Unit C did not.. Unit H was better than Unit C during the 1927-28 season but poorer than C during 1928-29. Table 13 puts the production for one season in terms fit dollars and cents. The prices of eggs used were the-quota - tions at Lincoln. Nebraska. This table may aid those who are anxious to see what must be- done to make the use of heal in poultry houses pay. The average value of the eggs per hen from the heated units for rive months, November to March inclusive. 1927-1928, was $1.85, while that for the unheated units was SI. 52. The value of the eggs per hen in the heated units exceeded that from the unheated units by 33 cents; One hundred hens in heated units produced an income $83.00 greater per season than a like number in unheated. units. The number of hens necessary to pay for the installation of a heating system, its fuel and care, then becomes merely a matter of calculation. ■ ' . ■ ." 15111 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>