<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SIXTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1905 AND 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1905 AND 1906 a&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA INSTH ITE FOR THE BLIND. NEBR. CITY, NEBR., DEC. 1, 1 !m H. Micki ernor: Impliance witli Section 12. Chapter 26, oi the law- ■&lt;&gt;. the Board of Ti f the Nebraska In- I'.lmd have the honor to transmit herewith the cntli liit'Miiia] report (or that institution upon the work mplished during the period ending November 30, 1906. Respectfully, John 0. Detweiler. John W. Steinhart. K. W. Wiiidhain. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF TRUSTEES. NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND. NEBRASKA CITY, NEBR., DEC. 17, 1906. To the Governor The Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute tor the Blind the honor to submit the following report: The affairs of this institution have run smoothly during two years. Ite death of Clinton Oreutt occurred Jan. '27. 1906. lie had n himself thoruly in sympathy with the work of th&lt; his I keenly felt by pupils and t&gt; ell as by his associates on the hoard of trustees His place was I by the appointment of John (). Detweiler, of Omaha. ■n the expiration of the second term of Charles X" Windham, of Plattsmouth, was appointed t d him. A few changes have been made in the force of teachers. tporl of the superintendent, which foil" the affairs of the school, and is made a part of this re] Respectfully submitted, John O Detweiler, President. Term of office expii John W. Steinhart. Secretary. Term of office expii R. W. Windham. Term of oftic*' </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. NEBRASKA CITY, NEBR., DEC. 1, 1906. To the Board of Trustees. Nebraska Institute for the Blind. : t required by law. I herewith present to your honorable body tement of the affairs of this institution covering the bien - period frcm December 1, 1904, to November 30, 1906. The hiennium has been marked by no untoward circumstance. No serious outbreak of disease has occurred. Little Hubert _g was brought to death's door by what seemed tubercular meningitis, but neaped as by a miracle. He is with us in better health than before his long illness. Mildred Searles passed suc - cessfully thru a siege of typhoid fever. She was taken sick at the same time with Hubert, shortly after arriving at school in the fall of 1905, evidently having the disease in her system when she came. Every such case makes us the more alert to see that our premises are in good sanitary condition. Our water supply. I from the Missouri river, and passed thru a Pasteur- Chamberland filter, has proven to be thoroly safe and wholesome. I regret to say that two of our teachers, Miss Annie Sidwell of the literary department, and Miss OeiUlide Sousley of the music department, have been obliged, on account of ill health, to leave us. Coming to the school at about the same time, some ten years ago, they had, by their faithful and conscientious work, as well as by their many lovable traits of character endear - ed themselves to all with whom they came in contact. Their places have been filled by Miss Winnifred Bortis of Glenville, and Miss Elizabeth Hemler of Beatrice, who bid fair to become as useful as their predecessors. I he spirit among the pupils has changed remarkably during past few years. The chafing under ordinary school discipline the rebellious attitude exhibited toward constituted author - have almost entirely disappeared. All take hold of the k cheerfully and earnestly. Indeed, in numerous instances, ils need restraint rather than urging on in their school work. As is usual in schools for the blind, our school pursues lines of work of a threefold nature. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">469 The basis of our work is the literary department, so called, wherein is pursued the studies of the public schools generally. The work of this department of the school is divided into twelve grades, or years, embracing the teaching of the little beginner to read from letters raised on the surface of the page, and the final work of the high school in Latin, physies, and geometry. ihe mane department carries the pupil thru a well graded *se in vocal and instrumental work, adapted to the capacity he learner. &gt;ils have sufficient musical I :e it profitable to spend much time in this department, but all having such talent, everv opportunit furnish - :or its cultivation. The industrial department combines manual training with the teaching of trades, or occupations. The little child bereft of nghr, accustomed to having every want supplied even before it can be made known, ('(tmes to us often times sadly incapable of forming the simplest manual operations. Under sympathetic guidance the feeble fingers are trained by easy stages, thru the •y of stringing spools, buttons, and beads, and other suitable •ises, until they become willing and efficient servants of the controlling mind. fit June three young ladies, and one young man, graduated our school, and at the present time are carrying on their in life with credit to themselves and to their friends. The trade of piano-tuning continues a favorite occupation for blind men having the requisite musical and mechanical ability. eral of the graduates from this department of our school work are doing good work, and are supporting comfortably themselves and those dependent upon them. Our boys and girls are taught also to make hammocks and fly-nets. This a pation brings some revenue to quite a number. During the past two years the pupils and teachers of this •I have been given, thru the thoughtful kindness of friends, several rare treats. Mr. Clement Chase, of Omaha, sent tick - i admittance to Parsifal and Lucia di Lammermoor, ■ by the Conned grand opera company. Some twenty a\ themselves of the opportunity, and it is needless to say that </seg>
            <seg id="p006">470 \V o much indebted to Mrs. Joy .Morion for the pie; ■ ii'itl hop rla were L'ixcii full liberty to examine to I many ol historic and artistic \ ■ [ to Mrs. Morton for ;i iiiusic;i] Eru tin* kiixli klr. Henry Katxenstein, our pupila i irioua attraction! I by on&lt; I worth} thai thru the ben Mrs. Fork, the blind of the whole eonntrj the ad\ of a magazine published in the point to them. Mr. L. 11. Muck, formerly lor and publisher of tb in the point print, informs m* that he such Iliat he will In- able to scud his to all blin. - who may wish it. B shall - e the n id addreases ■ s my thanks to the various local and - &gt;rs which have sb kindly noticed the work of the school. it of all connected with the scl 1 to the old notion that this institution is anything of the urn. hospital, or "home". The idea, plant. •f the education of the blind, still flourish iiy of our citizens, ami it is only by slow rooted out. mectioM. ii peculiar pleasure t that our school ut on the accredited li^ ity. After a visit by the high school i r T. Morej Hodgman, of the university, lie « e no reason why. as we were doing the i other hiirli hould not enjoy privih hey. In dm the had listened to his report reditneni was received. During the past two years 86 pupils h;r enrolled on and 1: </seg>
            <seg id="p007">471 8 was lost after reaching years of maturity. They came h&lt;- purpose of learning how people managed to get al mt sight, and did not need to stav tor a great length reral children have been reported to as having too little sight to enable them to attend profitably the common schools, whom, as yet. it has been bnpossibli into our school. In eases the parents are prevented by a mistaken ootioi kindness, from tending away the afflicted child; in other i the parent fears the child will not receive proper vhile again others have no knowledge of the school, and some ap - ■itly do not care to give the child an opportnnit; tny friends of the school were much disappointed in failure to become a law, of the bill introduced at the last sion of the legislature, designed to remove the school from the realm of practical politics. It has seemed to those most el conversant with the school and its history, that your honorable body should have the appointing of the officers of the school. I have been credibly informed that the present law. under which the school is governed, was originally drafted with this ide but was later changed t&lt;&gt; its pri Mauds the school is in the rather anomalous position of ha a dual head, both heads subject to the same appointing power. but neither subordinate to the other, except negatively. E would urge the advisability of building an addition on the ill of the main building, with reference, primarily, to furnish - better kitchen facilities. The present kitchen is dark, and from location sends the fumes of cooking thruout the house. Fur - r, it furnishes practically the only from The proposed location would remove the objections noted. The floor above the kitchen would provide room for our library, which OW inconveniently situated, and rapidly becoming i&gt; qnate to our needs. The new location would place it in immediate connection with the schoolrooms, while the room now in in the library could be used profitably for work in manual train - for which there is. at present, r The third floor would provide an addition to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">472 Thus several purposes would be served. With the ex - ,&lt;&gt;n of enlarging the barn, I see no reason for further addi - to our buildings for years to come. r several years past I have secured, wherever practicable, ,f land, on which to raise vegetables, stock feed, etc., &gt;ur own use. As we have a team and the requisite imple - ments it has in every instance proven very profitable. The itated the hiring of any extra help, so that returns have been nearly clear profit. Land adjoining us has, however. !&gt;• early utilized by the owners the past season that I have been unable to get any sufficiently close to ■ &gt;nvenient. I secured three acres about a mile distant last ig and u by statement following, for an expenditure of $23.00, produce to the value of $137.25 was returned. Now, round immediately joining the State's prop - on the north, which, I think, could be secured, and I am in that its pur. ate could not fail to be a : Stable investment. we have no place, except in grove and small or - chard, to turn our cows in the summer time, while the land red to would be a great help in this respect. During the summer of 1905 the main building was given three coats of paint, which enhanced its appearance greatly, besides preserving the surface from the rapid weathering which had begun in many places. During the summer just past the boiler house and barns have also been thoroly painted, giving &lt;-ur place a fresh and clean appearance. I would express my appreciation of the evidence of confidence &gt;sed in me by our most excellent governor, and to you, the ibers of the board of trustees. I am under many obligations your uniform courtesy, and support in various trying posi- bwill be found the usual information relative to for the past biennium, the amounts estimated as carry on the work for the next two years, various made by the pupils, products of garden and land hired, ) names of graduates, and pupils enrolled as required Respectfully submitted, J. T. MOREY, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">473 PHYSICIANS REPORT. the Honorable Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute tor the Blind, Nebraska City, Nebraska. I riflemen — I herewith submit my biennial report for the ending Nov. 30, 1906. During this period there has been aratively little severe sickness. During the winter of 1904 ■ there were two cases of typhoid fever of ordinary ■ity which r I. also one case of meningitis which I after a long severe illness. There have been quite mber of cases of fevers of a mild nature. The hygienic conditions of the school are excellent and in a general way the health of the pupils and teachers has been excellent during this period with the exception of Miss Sidwell one of the instructors who has suffered from organic heart dis- ; 1 1 1 &lt; 1 its complications which finally compelled her to r&gt; her position in the institution. The drinking water is all filtered making it clear and healthy. Ereniittiiu ! in perfecting healthful meas - cleanliness, pure air, . industry and conformity hool regulations and duties are the watch-words of the •intendent, instrii' d students. Bhool was never in a healthier nor more prosperous con - n than now. in my judgment. '•tfully submitted, W. T. NEAL, Physician. OFFICERS AND TEACHERS, NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR BLIND. Hon. John H. Mickey Governor BOARD OF TRUSTEES. John O. Detweiler President John W. Steinhart Secretary Robert W. Windham OFFICERS. J. T. Morey, A I n Superintendent and Steward Annabel R. Morey Matron </seg>
            <seg id="p010">474 TEACHERS Literary Department. ate for Blind History and Literature eb. St. mi- History ami Literature ir. Institute for Blind) Primary 1 department. A. Loeb Heidelberg, German} Violin. Orchestra and I » belli Ilemlri an Conservatory, Lincoln, Neb Pianoforte, Theory, History of Music Pip* Jessie Emeriek (Xebr. University School of Music) iltnre, Pianoforte, Chorus work Industrial Depari ■ Piano tuning, Carpet-weaving, ipbell (Illii i- Blind) Typewriting, Libn •i t Matro rton i Main M 1» Phy« EMiOI.I.MEN'l THE BIENXUM. r 1. 1904, to November 30, 1906. Pupils- Age. P. O. Addp Nativity. Date of Ad'm. 15 (b . Nebraska Sep. 17. William Nebraska Oci Bla ° ; " UL_Fn ont, Neb. Colorado Sep. 2. 1 '&gt;. city. Neb. Nebra inton, Neb. Iowa 1Mn4 1' Neb, Nebraska Sep. ]&gt;'&lt;. 1905 ebraskaSep. h,. ■ ■bum . 4i' Nemaha, Neb. Nebn 14 .Lincoln, Neb. Nebraska Sep. 10, ■ 1. Albert I Lincoln. Neb. N Sep. 10, William Id L Sep. 11 Bewi Iwork, Don I Business &lt; 'ollegre </seg>
            <seg id="p011">475 nark. Rena riger, Lueile lt-r. Frank eke, Ludwig ■y. Fern 8 .Reynolds, Xeb. Xebrask .W Point, Neb.._NebraakaNov. .Havelock, Neb. Xebrask tanaha, Xeb Xebrask .Pawnee ('.. Neb_NebraskaNov. Kearney. Xeb. .Nebraska Sep. .Omaha, Xeb Xebrask. .Sp'gview, Xeb. Nebraska .Blair, Neb. c &gt;hi .Taliiiafrp, Xeb. 1 1 1 n i&lt; &gt; i s .Oct. ..Blue Hill. Xeb ... Wyoiniti ■_ ; ui 1 , Xel). _Nebrask .Lincoln, Xeb. Xebrask . Alvo. Meb. N'ebraskaNov. .Tilden, Neb . Kan r-rok'bow, Xeb. Kai&gt; ■ !., Neb. .Win .Arcadia, Xeb. NebraakaOet. .Agnew, Xeb. Illinois Oct. .Albio iraskaSep. .Calloway, Xeb. .Nebraska Sep. ''iialia. Neb- Xebi imalia. Xeb. Xebi Nebraska Nov. . Lincoln. Neb NebraskaSep. I\. City, Mo .Missouri Sep. .Arapahoe, Xeb. [owa ( "I 'ire V'w, X"b..Xe!&gt;i .Sutton, Meb NebraskaSep. .Rain, Neb. NebraskaSep. .Upton, W Kansas Sep. Platts'th. N( .Beatrice, Nel . Hershey. Xeb. .Nebraska Nov. Hershey. Xeb. .Nebraska Nov. .MeCook, Xeb. -Nebraska Feb. Omaha. Xebr Ireland Jan. 8 11 ..1:1 Einir. Kenneth hurt. Bruce •an. Henry He, I.. P&gt; 7 It!. 1 i.;. i .16 15 27 t, Clarene on, ! Irieh, Jane g, Hubert low, Edward es, Pre 1 2] .26 ID 13 20 I agton, Hiunia .18 Irley, Leo mi. Lloyd leman, Clara I. Nola 1.1 1 ( Hl4 19 11 I Rose 21 [lultstedt, Oe Jennings, Leona Johnson, Junes Journey, Wallace ntz, Kdna i:&gt; .27 15 Hi Epom, Christina 2H rick. Lewis 1") hall. Mar; Bine. Walter 12 Omaha. Neb Iowa Sep. nson. Alia J Xedeau. Kas. Illinois Sep. 4ti .... W. Point. Xeb. German in -Bracken, Neb. Nebrasi Br. Otto ek. Vera 1, 1 t 1 1 ). &gt; ■ I. Clyde LaNone, Hlina 2- Leonard, Klizalu-tli is, &lt;;icii 18 strom, Anna 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">476 ford, Henry 13 .Ashland, Nebraska Sep. 10, U ineoln. Neb Nebraska Sep. 20, Danella air. NV: Nebraska Sep. 8, 17 KVari \ebraskaJan. 8, L A. ille. ICon Minn. L 6, i. Minnie 16 _WynH&gt;re, Neb Missouri Sep. 10, Louisa 18 Lincoln, Neb Kansas Sep. 2, Anna L5 Lincoln. Neb NV!&gt;raska Sep. 2, \&gt;b. \ &gt;ep. inoo 1896 1S96 1891 Lushton. Neb. ...Nebraska May 6, VebraskaSep. 16. encamp, Nina 14 Omaha. Neb Nebraska 11 Fairbury. Neb. NebraskaScp. 13 t Henry &gt;k. Neb. Nov. 19, r. Minnie naha, Neb. Iowa .Sep. 5. Alma naha, N Nebraska Sep. 6, rson. Anna 26 Wolbach. Neb. NebraskaSep. 14. 1904 1903 1900 1899 1904 Be, Mil der. Harry .1 l'aso. Tex. ...low; I Neb. City, Neb. Nebraska Oct. 24. ',-tkland. Neb. -Nebraska Sep. 13 h. James 18 .-Oakland. Neb. NebraskaScp. 13 31 Oakland. Neb. Nebraska S t -p. 13, ■.e, Sophia 21 _ Verdigris, Neb. Nebraska Dee. 3 Walker, Eiuesl l( Pawnee C, Neb. NebraskaSep. 17, l.lell, May 19 So. Omaha. Neb .So Dak. Sep. 20, Waldron, Charlotte.- 8 Carroll. Neb Iowa .Nov. 3, Is, Geor^ -31_G'd Island, Neb. ...Ontario Jan. 3, 22... ..Omaha. Neb. fowl - p. 28, Whitehill, Vere 15 Auburn, Neb. NebraskaSep. 6, -1. Walter Auburn, Neb. NebraskaSep. 17, iiia. Charles 20 Omaha, Neb BohemiaSep. 13, 1903 1906 1905 1903 1899 1905 l!»02 GRADUATES OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND Self- Name. aduated in. Year. P. O. Address. Sustaining. Aaberp, Albert I. 86 Bazille, Nebr. Yes. Bin Nebr. City, Nebr. B C Teeumseh, Nebr Yes. &lt;r. A! 7.P.T '9S Battle Creek. Mich. .....Yes. Da '9': XeUr. City. Nebr Yes. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">477 ter, Harry B. '97 Omaha, Xebr. sford, Ann;', L. Lawrence, Kansas '86 Nebr. City, Xebr. .'90 Madrid, Xebr. Brace, Clark L. Brown, Gertrude L. Rums, .fames T. "98 Kenesaw. Xebr. ..Deceased. '00 Marqnette, Xebr. Yes. J. T. B. Campbell, Lucy L. Clark, Roy L. P. id, Harry L. T id, Sarah L. '94 Long Island, Kans. ..._Yes. '88 Brock. Xebr. L. Criin. Einina L. '86 Xemaha, Nebr. l es. Bder. William B. s. Frederick L. "98 Lincoln, Xebr. ..Yes. '86 Alexandria. Xebr ..Yes. ■ nleau, Remi P. T. '9 9 Rapid City, S. D. Yes. Duncan, Sylvia L. '99 Stella, Xebr. holm. Christian L. '83 Louisville. Xebr Yes. William L. '86 Lincoln, Nebr Harmon. Mary L. '86 Buffalo Gap, S. D Yes. Frank P. ■1, Paul T. Bhausen, Hans L.T.P.B. ibaugh. William T. B. '01 Omaha, Xebr Yes. '02 Xebr. I br. —Yes. North Platte. Xebr Yes. '9: l Diller, Xebr. Yes. '96 Genoa, Nebr. Hollingsworth. Ferd L.B. Hollingsworth, Xora L. Johnson, Ingwald B. Johnson, Jennie L. P. J&gt;&gt;nes. Clarence T. L. '9:» Fremont, Xebr Yes. Xebr. City, Xebr .Yes. Jones. Frances L. '96 Xebr. City, Xebr Yes. '94 Xebr. City, Xebr. '01 Wilber, Nebr. Yes. '96 Cozad, Nebr Yes. '97 Red Cloud, Xebr. Yes. -&lt;. Josephine L. Knapp, Anna L. P. Lanham, Alma L. is, Clarence B. rom, Christina L. I. '06 Hershey, Xebr -Yes. _'. DeKa. L. I. '04 Burr, Xebr Yes. '96 So. Omaha, Nebr. Yes. Ma thews, Golda L. McAuley, Mary L. P. Miller. E. J. L. '8(5 Graf. X.'br. Yes. '9 9 Lincoln, Nebr Yes. '94 Nebr. I Yes. '94 Lincoln. Nebr. .Yes. DeLong, &lt; llara I*. '0 3 Omaha, Nebr. Yes. '99 ..._Yes. "98 Xebr. City. Xebr Yes. '94 Madison. Xebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">478 tin, Nora L P. V. &lt; 1 1 \ ( .|»r. L. 1' Guide Bock, Nebr. Mollina, Julia L. "86 Salem, Nebr. No le. Bell I, "94 Grant, Nebr. I'la L. .'nl Stromsburg, Nebr. I- P *98 Bnn ess, Xebr. Adalbert L. T. H. ■ ■ Omaha, Nebr. L I I H.-atricc Nebr. •mv L. '8 Grand bland. Nebr. V lin, Minnie L John L.T.B.V. Los A' al. Bl. I. Wolbach. N B. Pern, Nebr. Peru, N'ebr. tay LV.T. I, ■in^r. Nebr '94 Wl&gt;r City, N'ebr. V ri&lt;-k. Afaud L. I,. P.I. aha, Nebr. L. B '04 Albion, Xebr. I. *94 Battle Creek, Micl rles li. 1'. ' ilia. Nebr. rtcrary l)«'i&gt;t.: 15 Broom-making j V Violin: P — Piano; I Industrial Dept. During the past two ipils have been instructed in the a and tri No. Pupils. \v nrk jioiiit 26 'IT w York point 30 Arithi mar ■ - History • lit History 6 &gt;ry 7 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">479 bra ■• .1 isli Literature ("ivies • )rLT;iii Violin ( orne! ( Clarinet Flute r band instruments 12 ■ culture 13 Mn&lt;_nii&lt;j I theory Harmony 11 i music &gt; illtlillL' m making • ■t weaving 14 mock netting i ■I ng i machine &lt; ting beting : ii bead-work -work I )ol[ : ■ 17 ARTICLES MADE BY PUPILS DURING THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOV 30, 1906 SEWING. teen iheeta, one hundred twenty-one pillow slips. 12 nap- Ki roller towels. 22 hand towels. 42 tea towels. 34 i cloths. !l dust cloths. !» aprons. 1 dress. ■] pieees iinderw.- mount of mending elothea and darnic , v . ,]|,i|, ineut </seg>
            <seg id="p016">480 KNITTING AND CROCHETING. Six shawls, 2 fascinators, 2 mufflers, 2 pairs mittens, 3 hoods, 4 pairs slippers, 2 wash cloths, 1 toilet set, 3 pairs boots, 4 jack - 6 yards lace. RAFFIA AND REED WORK 16 baskets, 2 frames. 2 mats. BEAD WORK. ir large baskets, 65 small baskets, 78 broom holders. 41 boxes, 30 bracel' _' candle sticks, 66 napkin rings, ips, 3 vases, 7 pitchers, 9 ball holders. 6 watch cases, 1 tea 24 necklaces, 3 frames, 2 letter cases, 2 rose balls. BROOMS, HAMMOCKS, ETC I dozen of brooms, 1!»4 yards of carpet. Besides, there were made a large number of fly nets and hammocks ; also a consid - erable amount of chair - ,\as done in this depart- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">481 I "IT J«K CM I : ■ • • i -r-r — T. i ■: \ — f. •: -r ■ -. - 1 -r r -r — ' - = V, § : — s 3 - p pepn * - 2 -Bjacloj(ld\ - — i - - 1 — / — — — i - / z — y. 8- . r- i - — ~- i- - • I — ~ r; C ~ — I - — / Z — —:-.— /- - z 9 x S 9 9 - .- — = I I«V&gt;J. ii UOllHI.lrlH.nl *i;l uouBl.Iil idd is •(-,■(,;[ -c — — x -r r-. — — -I n ■ — -l r — • : s ■ '. : • • / ' : rf «• • • : : - i* : - : : • ..:-.:=.= . . ••= . : 32 • 5 : • 5 :s : : :£ : : :?•= : i . : : i \ \ . = ■ i-j rilK^ili — I </seg>
            <seg id="p018">482 TABLE SHOWING CLASSIFICATION OF ALL EXPENDITURES. Year Ending Year Ending ation— Nov. 30, '05. Nov. 30, '06. Salaries and wages . $10,067.52 $10,0: Istuffs 315.53 367-4 r 276.22 42( 143.51 64.19 and canned i:'&gt;" . fish and poultry 852.D4 812.24 l&lt;1.00 17 91.52 I 1 ir and syrup 270.12 24 - and coffee 41.01 :.54 41: tationery, and printing 15 170.18 ■ nd furniture 243.41 i light 1,988.05 attendaj lical and sur. sup... 45&gt;v71 and impro\ 1,180.02 715.16 nd oils ] - 51 Filling ice house 131 1.97 71 . ■il instrunit- t .4 ! &gt;2 i'd 1.20 '.00 J4.57 $19,330.59 $1 KEMEXT SHOWING THE AMOUNT OF CASH RECEIVED AND EXPENDED DURING THE BIENNIAL TERM END - ING NOVEMBER 30, 1906. RECEIPTS. hand December 1, 11*04 155.40 ie and 183.90 is and i 1 3.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">483 t warp 9.51 Hammocks *»70 Point and typr. paper App 11.00 120.00 r and elothing for indigent pupils from countie^ Tuition and hoard from non-resideni pupils r rental sing 3 •cllaneoui Total ■ t77i' ■TEMENT OF CASH ACCOUNT FOR THE BIENNIAL. I TINTED. EXPENDITURES. mock-cord and viwj^ ght and exp n ] •A supp] Is and bead-wire y pump h for pupils i' mill Lawn mowers k and bells 11 1 i t warp bator h'xtuns ■ • ir exhibits I i&gt;n wheels </seg>
            <seg id="p020">484 Lg resolutions 5.00 115.66 v. &amp;u£ LOF CDS* Jo »*s\j and clothing for indigent pupils 71.81 nig apples 14.50 5.00 1.25 2.00 - and plants •■ 20.67 •ription for papeib ■ 32.15 !• article on school 8.00 try supplies ■ 19.85 5.(K) l, er 25.18 of land 18.00 9.00 41.71 ■■llaneous articles 58.50 Total $1,343.44 Bah hand November 30, 1906 | ESTIMATE OF REQUIREMENTS FOR THE ENSUING BIENNIUM. • f superintendent $3,600.00 f matron . 1,000.00 Salaries of teach, r- . 9,000.00 f employes 7.500.00 Livii uses (groceries, meat, &amp;c.) - 9,000.00 and liehts 6,000.00 ter rent 800.00 800.00 iture, bedding, &amp;c. 700.00 and laundry supplies and gen. repairs 1.300.00 phone rent 150.00 onery and printing 300.00 ■id medicines 250.00 nd musical instruments 500.00 '■al attendance 600.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">485 Library 150.00 Loping industrial department 250.00 tin gent exper 300.00 I it ion to main building for kitchen, library, and ex - tension of chapel; for equipping same; and for moving and repairing pipe organ 10,000.00 [ BMENT SHOWING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES ON THREE ACRES OF LAND, RENTED, FOR YEAR 1906. t | 18.00 | 18.00 potatoes $75.00 potatoes $75.00 1 ■ ds bought 5.00 ■ ds bought 5.00 By !&lt;• tons cane 50.00 By !&lt;• tons cane 50.00 alance 114.25 To balance 114.25 By 1 ton beets 5.00 By 1 ton beets 5.00 5 bus. turnips 5 bus. turnips By 10 bus. tomatoes . 2.50 By 10 bus. tomatoes . 2.50 By 10 bus. carrots 2.50 By 10 bus. carrots 2.50 $137.25 $137.25 $137.25 $137.25 rEMENT OF NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND IN Dl'.NT WITH THE AMERICAN PRINTING HOUSE FOR THE BLIND. BEGINNING JULY 1, 1904, AND ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1906. 1904 1904. 1904. Dr. July 1, To balance *16.95 July 1, To balance $16.95 By quota, 1904-05 _$147.13 By quota, 1904-05 $147.13 9, To mdse. 35.50 9, To mdse. 35.50 31, To mdse 15.10 31, To mdse 15.10 1905. 1905. 1005. 1, To mdse 65.60 1, To mdse 65.60 By balance 9.27 By balance 9.27 Apr. 18, To mdse 23.25 Apr. 18, To mdse $156.40 $15 $156.40 $156.40 June 30, To balance._..$ 9.27 June 30, To balance.~..$ 9.27 By quota, 1905-06 $137.95 By quota, 1905-06 $137.95 i0, To mdse. 70.25 30, To mdse. 70.25 1906. 1906. 1906. 1906. Feb. 13, To mdse 1.06 Feb. 13, To mdse 1.06 23, To mdse 6.83 By balance 33.21 By balance 33.21 Mar. 23, To mdse 6.83 Apr. 12, To mdse 65.50 Apr. 12, To mdse 65.50 4, To mdse 18.25 May 4, To mdse 18.25 i $171.16 $171.16 June .30, To balance June .30, To balance $33.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">486 CLOSING EXERCISES. Friday, June &lt;»th. 1905, Jit 2 p. m. Mareh W. Orchestra. a Rev. II. L. H si — Romanza. op, 28 No. 19 Buck Charles Zadina. by touch Gow Nona West, Merlon Conn in Mathematics rte Quartette — Choeor des Filenses du Vaisseau Fantuin,- W. Nona W ItUl, Anna i, Edna Koontz. i raphy 'lute enc-hat Mozart Alard Vere Whitehill. \hibit • -The Lily and the Bluebell Smith Nona W Diploma presented to Merton Conn, graduate in piano-tuning, by Mr. Charles Nownes, president of the Board of Trustees. rica F. Hopkinson Smith m»o1 and Audience Standing. Keinain standing for "ii Rev. J. W. - ANNVAL CONCERT. Thursday Evening, June 8th. L9( O'clock. PROGRAM. March of the 1 rom Athalia MendeN Orch' Pianofortes — Mennetto from Op. 7 Oreig Nona Wesi. Miss Sousley. . appelle — toi </seg>
            <seg id="p023">487 String Quartette— Apple Blossoms Roberts rBowe, Vere Whitehill, violins; Mr. Bruce, Mr. Loeb, viola iind 'cello: Organ Accompaniment by Miss Soiisley. Hie Ni^'ht has a Thousand Ejm Parsons —In the Dark. In the Dew Coombs Alma Seume "Erening Star" — From Tannhauser W« John Bowe, Vere Whitehill. violins; Mr. Loeb, Nona V. Edna Koontz. 'cello and pianoforte; Charles Zadina. organ. Affaire d'Amour Pui Orchestra. n — Toccata d'Evry Charles Zadina. is the work Wu _ Merton Conn. Nona West, Alma Seuine. Violin — Legende, Op. 17 Wieniawski John R' ! — O Dry Tl n . del I; Orchest ral Accompaniment. Nona West. Pianoforte— Rondo Capriccoso, Op. 14 Mei Charles Zadina. Orchestral Accompaniment I sley. Nations, Offer to the Lord" Mendel-- Senior Chorus. GRADUATING EXERCISES. Friday. June 8th, 1906, at Three O'clock, .March — Constitution Henninger Orchestra Invocation Rev. C. A. Mastin oforte Quartette— Mazurka, Op. 6, No. 3 N Nona West. Anna Severson. Rose Ilusa. Edna Koontz. \ Needle in a Straw </seg>
            <seg id="p024">488 ,adian Boat Song . Beach Nona West. Henry Schneider. George Cozad. limes rles Zadina. Nona West. Organ — Foil Xicode Charles Zadina, I Parker Nona West ■llini Artot ir Ilultstedt. Iresa, and Presentation of Diplomas John II. Mickey, Governor. Firman ooL ANNUAL CONCERT. Thur- oing, June 7, 1906, at Eight O'clock. mre — La Dance Blanche Boieldieu Orchestra. Meditation Flagler Edna Koontz. Sincrelee Willie Currie Weidt Henry Schneider. Organ — Sonata. C minor, Op. 56, Xo. 3 Guilmant Allegro maestoso e con fuco Adagio Charles Zadina. Senior Choir. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">489 Haydn No. 1. Andante Pieo Adagio, Cantabile Presto. Rondo all Ongarese r Hultsti'dt, Mr. Loeb, Miss Sousley. Mia Stella Confidente ... Robaudi Nona West. &lt; iapriceio Brilliant, Op. 22 Mendelssohn Charles Zadina. md Pianoforte. Miss Sousley. ■phony Eroica I&gt; Mareia Funebre Finale Allegro niolto String Orchestra. ERAL INFORMATION. The Nebraska Institute for the Blind, located at Nebraska ol and is conducted solely for the purpose of educating the blind children of the state who are normal except as to siirht : it is in no sense an asylum or a hos - pital — simply a school. The law provides that only those of suitable age and capacity shall In- admitted, and the rule has I that pupils een the ages of six and twenty-one are eligible for admis- Tuition, board and medical attendance are furnished free to all who are admitted: bill parents or trnardians are expected to provide suitable clothing, pay all traveling expenses to and from the institute, and take charge of the pupil during the summer vacation. (e school year begins on the second Wednesday in September doses on the second Wednesday in -Tune, unless otherwise :ated. It is expected that all pupils will be present at the ing of the term, and, except in case of sickness or unavoid - necessity, remain to the close of the term. F.ach pupil must come provided with an adequate supply of comfortable clothing, which must be replenished from time to time, as becomes necessary. Each article should be distinctly marked with the owner's name, and must be sent in good condi - tion. The supply should embrace the followin </seg>
            <seg id="p026">490 Bys — Two hats, two suits of clothes, two extra pairs of four pairs of rospenders, two night shirts, tooth \n - and hair brush. i Is — Two woolen and two cotton dresses, four aprons, three : dresses, tv of summer and two suits of winter un - two dark and two light skirts, six pairs of stockings, andkerehiefs, a wrap. hat. rubbers, two pairs of shoes, I i, hair brush, clothes brush, and comb. A small sum of m &gt;uld be provided each pupil, to be I at the office, to pay for postage, repair of shoes, . Kl to attend church on each Sunday niorn - lahle weather. a t such places as they or their parents Eiy be admitted to the iiool during the school year upon payment of ily. in advance: provided, that no such person shall i to the exclusion of any resident of the si K.itable age and capacity, and possessing good, moral leter, will be admitted; but in case, after a fair trial. it or manifests repeated disregard of the school s, he will be discharg ofanity, obscenity, the use of intoxicants and 'iejr for llv prohibited. brought to the institute until a L&lt; :■ had b I from the principal. Persons \U know of blind children are requested to in - thein ef ihi Iiool, and send their add i the principal All inqnii Lrding the admission of Is will be promptly answered. Ki insure prompt delivery, all letters and express paekagi pupils sliould be ad of the "Nebraska In - r the Blind." Bpils will be permitted to write to, and receive letters from. •r mem I the family only, except by permit the superintend— t. HOME INSTRUCTION FOR THE BLIND. the child coin hool, parents, brothers, rfl lish much with a little painstaking, and </seg>
            <seg id="p027">491 the child thus becomes interested in acquiring knowledge, and H with a feeling of pleasant anticipation, rather than aver- E&gt; following is piven by way of suggestion as some of the s upon which blind children should be instructed before ing school: It' all. they should not only be allowed but required as i ;is possible to help them- .| thein - ■ walk erect and independently, to care properly for clothing and their person. Induce habits of observation, urmge them to explore the house, the barn, the premises rally, to examine the cat. the dog, and other domestic ani - . and teach them their habits. Let them handle the tools learn to use them. tihe same time, unless they come at the age of six , • , they should learn to count, add. and subtract small D and the multiplication table; learn to spell the i id their meaning and use; the geography of the farm, , county, and state, and other facts which every child should Beading with the fingers should _rin early. If neg - ■ I, the I never he made good. A delicacy and nice iniination of the I' touch is seldom acquired after the age of fifteen or sixteen years. Bphabel sheets and other matter in embossed type will be ly furnished. In making application for admi- 1. Give full name of applicant. 2. Where horn ; year, month, day of month. Parents' names 4. Are parents related in any way by birth; if so, in what degree? Are parents liv ti. Address of parent or guardian. Where was applicant bornf Was applicant horn blind' If not, at what age v 9. What was the cause ? </seg>
            <seg id="p028">492 11. Is applicant of sound mind and susceptible of mental culture! 12 ! y deformity! 14. Has applicant any .r eruptive disease? i&gt;lieant been successfully \ 16. If so, when was vaccination performed? 17. Does applicant use tobacco or spirituous liquor in any form? 18. As all pupils are expected to attend church at least once uaday, what church is it desired that applicant attend? I. Who will provide clothing, keep same in proper repair, necessary traveling expenses, and take charge of appli - during vacation? B. Docs applicant promise to abstain from the use of fob spirituous liquors, in all forms, while a pupil of this school? </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>