<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska State Penitentiary LANCASTER, NEBRASKA.  BIENNIAL REPORT OF T.W. SMITH, WARDEN TO THE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA AND THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">LANCASTER, NEBRASKA. BIENNIAL RERORT or TO THE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA AND THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS GOVERNOR BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS E. B Cowles. Commissioner, President Lawson G. Brian. State Treasurer Ceo C. Junkin. Secretary of State. Secretary Arthur Mullen. Attorney General rC LAM IN PtINTINC COMPANY UNIVERSrlY PLACE. NEM T. W. SMITH. Warden Hon. Ashtoo C. Shalleobcrger </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">ROSTER OF OFFICERS AND EMPLOYES F. W. Smith AYarden Matron Mr- T. W. Smith A. Welton Deputy Warden Huff Chaplain Dr. II. B. Lowerv Prison Physi Fhomaa J. Ward Tlerk .M. ( C. -T. McCarthy D-Tiiiis McMahon [. Cavanaugh I Heilman Engineer Day Cell II Day Turii Key Clans Pah] Night Turn E: Jenkins Sullivan ry Evans lokely Night Chapel Guard Day Yard Foreman R. McDonald Night Watchman John McNeil Emerson A. G. Con Night Cell House Keeper Convict Kitehen Guard F Cell House Keeper Cell House Keeper (nighti b Frahm E Andrew Ringenber Lanndry Guard r \. C. Tucker Guard Shirt Fa Guard Shirt Factory Harry Wagner John Bark I'. Eikenhary an Pendarv P. Morgan tries Berry A. Eeklcy Shop Keeper Shop Kt Shop Keeper Shop K. Shop Shop K. • Yard Man hapel Guard Wall Guard Wall Guard man Tim Slattery John Hudson •I. F. LaFollett •T. J. Koani 1 Bd. P. Mullane </seg>
            <seg id="p004">T. W. SMITH, Warden </seg>
            <seg id="p005">WARDEN S REPORT Nebraska state Penitentiary, Lan To His Excellency, the Governor, and the Honorable Members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings: Gentlemen :— As warden of the Nebraska State Penitentiary, I have the honor to submit to you. for your consideration, a de - tailed report of the doing! in s.iid institution covering the Hiennum ending November 30, 1910, to which is annexed tii - of the physician, chaplain and the financial and statistical reports of the clerk. IThc statistical tables snow the total number »f | ived during this period is 430. I On the 30th day of November, 1910, the total populatii prison inmates numbered 42l&gt;. Of this number there wen hired. (1 Indians and 1 Korean. Four females are in - led in these numbers: two white and two colored. The con - s number one to each 2711 of the population of the state. -us for the year 1910 noi being available, we are unable to : the census of the race population. Of the 42ti prisner - inder sentence of death, :{!! life imprisonment, 2."&gt; have ses covering a period of from 10 to 40 years, while the re - ning number are under sentences of from b" months to 10 Earnings of the Institution The total earnings of the institution from nil sources as hown by the financial statment embodied in this report amount to $136,947.47 as compared to $99,079.67, covering the amount ived from all all sources in the preceding Biennuin, or a difference of $37,867.80. Of this sum 01 was derived from the labor of convicts on contract as against $71,323.81, re - •d from this source covering a like period during the pro - ceding Biennum, or a difference of $22,482.21. The total population of the institution at the (dose of the r | p,. ,.(»(] ijjir Biennum on -SOtl! 11^10 the count ■* </seg>
            <seg id="p006">54 i^M) COMMISSIONER'S R] t &gt; nf 4i2ti inmates, while the average number of prisoners in th Kit ut i«&gt;n during the period covering inch biennium show bui ;i lit difference. Yel from the labor of the inmates daring periods, the biennium shows an increase in the amouni noney turned into the treasury from this source of $22,482.21 On the 28th day of July, 1908, ;i renew il of contract wis entered into with the Lee Broom &amp; Duster Company \&gt;\ tin - terms of which 250 men are employed in the making of broofl a daily wage of SS nenta to the state. This contract covi ■tl of three years. The IMatte Shirt Co., on the 1st day of January, 11)10, entered into a contract with the State, wherebv Kmen are employed in the manufacture of shirts at a daily pcnsation to the State of sixty-two and one-half cents. This racl likewise eovers a three year period. tinder these contracts all the prisoners in the institution, able available for labor are employed, save and except tl $e duties are required in the operation and maiutenauc institution. The financial statement made herein shov. tly increased revenue in the receipts from labor of con it is safe to say that with a prison population of -4.")() and a rervative management, the institution will be on a self sustain basis. The legislative appropriation for maintenance for tin Innium covered by this report was worked out upon a l&gt;.i - cents per day for each inmate upon an estimated population of •. When the appropriation was finally made upon this calculation, it was reduced $10,000 from the sum originally erted in the penitentiary budget. tThe maintenance fund will perhaps show a deficit at the he biennium covering the period for which this fund was ap - jriated and made available, viz: on April 1st, 1911, of about 000.00 When it is taken into consideration that the inaiu - ince appropriation was reduced $10,000 from the amount inally shown to have been necessary, and the further fact that e is due the institution from the State the sum of $10,038.42 electric current furnished for power and lighi for orthopedic ital. the State Capitol and grounds. Home of the Friendless and the Governor's mansion, the financial condition of the in stition will in reality close the period covered by the appropria </seg>
            <seg id="p007">55 ciency appropria- shed upon a basis of three ly measured by meter. The Betterments. 44 I ■ ial which entered intu .15 ami this sum paid buildings anil re From this fund . Ho. The n XI •Ml! I feed the 11s to the amount of id satisfied from the \ hen considered in article which | the institution, the financial to the statistical table in this isuii population, details in eon - institution, including the con- Eu,n witl hi of the ral lunds on hand. L-tnal cost for the pn&gt;- in thr 1'latti- ■ry. licet - ■r and sanitary 1 boilers, motors ildings, fixtures and it iuii of this money lit of the destine- ion as warden on the destitute of supi prisoners I. The deficiency ap- l» of $16,000 was ex- (factory ami highly grati- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">56 Clothing and Uniforms. RTlie cadet blue woolen uniform for winter use is continued, the cadet blue, 1 have substituted a dark blue cotton uniform summer wear which is conductive to both comfort and omy. Stripes are used only in e ises of punishment to prisoner! and it is with a great deal of satisfaction that I am able to re that it has been found necessary to resort to this mode of punish - ment in but two instances during my administration. The lock - has been abolished and has proven a wholesome innovation iu point of discipline. This change was welcomed and highly appreciated by the inmates. Legislative Recommendations II would most urgently recommend the enactment of a law (riding for the selection of a parole officer whose duty should to investigate the personal conduct of prisoners on parole and r environment and surroundings. It should further be made duty of this officer to assist discharged prisoners in receiving jloyuient and exert every effort to the end that those leaving prison should receive every eiieouraginent whereby they may ome useful members of society. The history of the penitentiary shows that the average times served by life convicts is less than ten years. 1 would therefore :uinend that the parole law lie so amended that life prisoners may be subject to the provisions of this act, after they have • (1 a period of 12 years provided the conduct of the pria has been good during the entire period. This provision would put the life prisoner on a merit basis and would no doubt prove Table to our present pardon or commutation laws in that would result in placing a paroled life prisoner under the direct jurisdiction of the givernor subject at all times to be recalled and recommitted in the event the prisoner failed to conform to the provisions of the parole contra' The commitment record of the penitentiary shows that more than one-half of the inmates of the institution are under the age of 30 years. There are 102 prisoners who under the ;i_ &gt;. Out of these young men there are but few who have rved in any penal institution. It is a source of regret port that during the nftned within </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE PENITENTIARY be walls of the institution a number &lt;&gt;f young nder Bit is littl ization a] than a crime against our advanced ide, ial reform to place these young boys in an ature. whose associates are old offenders and I have exerted every effort to i older prisoners hut it is impossible to acconip- mstitntioii ot this 1 hardened criminal* boys from the lish this end with t institution taxed to its capacity It should requi of the legislature tl nothing further than to call to the attention deplorable condition to have provision made \\\ and inhuman condition may be corrected. n I would recommend that either a tract the end that this mil a reformatory established thereon or that ol at Kearney (which under parole provisions isi-d for this purpose, by dividing it he Industrial School proper, from these transferred from the penitentiary and nd surrounded by such influences and the making of useful members t. unfortunately as it may be. will result in ■ ironmt society hose who mu ucated and confirmed in the under preseii Illl hool of cr Convict Earnings I nder tl it ti the Lee Broom &amp; Duster Company rs have allotted to them a certain and the I ( S 1 I a day's task, the wage for which amount ot work w mi the St; r is by his skill and industrv alii prison* ter amount of work than the allotted task, he f the pay for this additional service in the form u this source the prisoners during the bit'iinum irn out a gr Eives for hinu vertime. Ft ed and ree&lt; 22.usti.yi) Some prisoners earn as much I pon a basis of the entire prison popula - ;."&gt;(&gt;.2d for each inmate. This money is all unts upon the books of the institution and B*2o.(H&gt; per moil a this rep kept in tepars is disbursed under many instances forwarded under the direc needy dependent relatives, while other tion of the inmatt chase articles for from lfi to 18 years of ag tin this connec be purchased Industrial ScIh if juvenile com ulted in greatly reducing the numbers in that institution ■Miy, Ilif ininat young men who sli&lt;&gt; placed in an atmoa] rders of the various prisoners. The fuuds ar I 1 1 ht'ir personal comforts and enjoyment. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">58 LAM) COMMISSIONS ORT The Female Department. I The i'cmalf ward shows ■ total of 4 prisoners, fcvery reason - provinon is provided for their comfori and an effort is eou - itly made n&gt; provide a means oi useful and healthful oeeupa - . For the greater part the time of the occupants of the ale ward is consumed in mending and caring for the clothing he prisoners. The sanitary condition of this ward, as . where throughout the institution is in perfect keeping with provisions made for their genera) eomforta. Discipline of the Institution No inhuman treatment is resorted to or permitted in the discipline of the institution during my administration. The old tyrannical ideas of torture havi methods of persuasion and words given way to the more modern of encouragement which h is re- Ied in a much greater respect among the prisoners for the ers and a desire to conform to the rules of the institution. ler this system, the number reported to the warden or deputy misconduct has been reduced to ,1 minimum. In fact, less than &gt;er cent of the prison population is reported for violating the s of the prison. In this connection 1 desire to most sincerely lk the officers, guards and employees who have so faithfully loyally assisted me in carrying on the work of the institution maintain^ a standard of economy, discipline and efficiency result of my beat effort and highest ambition. I The most demoralizing condition in the institution which I forced to contend with as warden is the so-cailed dope habit. pe) seemed to lie a legal tender and in general circulation ng the prisoners. Experience with this drug and its &lt;\r - alizing effect upon the men who seem addicted to its use is ailing. Its use is destructive of the morals, self-respect, honor all that is good in a human being. Doctor Lowery, the peni - iary physician, rendered an invaluable service in eradicating evil. His report to me which is appended is of interest in connection. Kl am here to assert that any warden who fails to make an oic effort to prevent the presence and use of dope in his in ution is a positive enemy of mankind. I ■] &gt;ik I | i \ t 11 | | 11*11 11 I 1 \ 1 1 I ilt 1 I 1 4 k I \ I * M 1 til 1 *" l" 4 *tf]tllflf A I (I W 1 * lit t I 1 V </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE PENITENTIARY 59 Uency, the Hon. Ashton C. Shallenbers Bka, for having appointed m&lt; den of this institution, and t&gt; dings for their friendship, to the responsible posit, the Hoard of Public Lands and lssistance and co-operation. I trulv grateful In the discharge of mv dutit ; I have a high appreeimti many good people wl Iheir counsel and ad To tlu generously assisted in easting How the pathway of the prisoners and rs and a ray &lt;&lt;[ sunshine along bringing to them messages of 1 shall ever be thankful. My als of tlie several departments Bil cheer and encouragement, reciatioii goes forth to the oftii t;ate for their uniform kinds my administration. and courtesies extended dur- During my two years' of administration of this institution tained. I am not unniimlfid of th splendid assistance rendered by the several heads of their r Po the superintendents* and the test teachers of the prison Sunday School for their splendid earnest work in behalf of the inmates as well as myself have sincere thanks. I To the guards for your humane and considerate treatment of inmates and the loyal support rendered the management and r protection of the State's property are the well-earned eii - imns of the public as well as mvself. §A complete and detailed statement from the several depart - ts attached shows the financial, sanitary, physical, industrial reformatory condition of the institution. In conclusion, the institution today presents more the indus - trial reformatoiy than a penitentiary. T. \Y. SMITH. Warden. REPORT OF BOOKKEEPER NEBRASKA STATE PENI- TENTIARY TO THE WARDEN. I Herewith will be found reports of the financial operations this institution for the biennium closing .November 30, 1910. which four months of the time was occupied by your pre - r. Also ling the prison population. •tfully submitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Maintenance Fund. balanec of appropriation of l!t&lt;&gt;7 Deficiency appropriation, 1909 ■^ 4 — &gt; 1 o t Total resources • IfficiTs salaries Employes w For eoal 10,462% tons Cord wood. :{t&gt; eordi lothin" food, medicines and inci dentals Balance fund Nov. :M. 191(1 Office and Contingent Fund. Knee November 30, 1908 ropriation 1909 ended Md Balance General Repairs. tun- November 30, lltos ropriation 1!»&lt;)'J $ 5,000 00 16,000 00 121,00 Appropritainn. 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE PKNITKNTIAKV 61 State Gash Fund. Balance on hand December 1. 1906 Received during the biennium 16,73 Fund for Keeping U. S. Prisoners Received from I'. 8. Treasurer and deposited with Treasurer. |579.84. Sale of Penitentiary Lands Halan.-e November 'W. 1908 ring's of the Institution During the Biennium Ending No - vember 30, 1910. Expended during; biennium Hal nice November, 1!)1l&gt; Current over Capital lines t . Governor's Manxion, Capital builil- ir«rs iiid jrrniinils. Orthopedic Hospital and State School of tin- Friend!. Dii from state — :&lt;:{4.til4 K. W. II.. (a :{«• - 12 Earning*) from contractor*: I ee Broom and Duster ( '&lt;&gt; Platte Shirt Co. I 8 months I From counties for safe keepen Vv in keeping U. 8. prisoners Farm products 'liAVl "&lt;&lt; Sale of harher tickets 132 Sale of meal tickets ' 4" receipts Chapel stand :&gt; 11 -* :i Junk, ra^rs. hones, ice. cinders, special convict labor 1,10 - , - </seg>
            <seg id="p014">62 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Farm Products. 1909 1910 Wheat, tifi2 hu 595 85 Wheat, 1.150 tin M.U4 .»,. EMM hehs ota, 100 Im s. 30 Im Onions. 10 lu in 0(1 Onions. 20 hu Swi-w (Mini. 260 hu Tomatoes, 200 bo 312 (Mi Sweet corn, 260 Im 100 oo Tomatoes, loo hu ns. 10 hu Watermelons, 1,000 Ion un Watermelons. 2,000 300 00 Turnips. 250 hu 10 hu toes, (too hu Hay, s T 240 00 &lt; •,!;,.. 30 T loo oo Straw, 50 T 120 00 Alfalfa, W T 50 00 Spinache. 100 !U oo Ducks, loo HO For the Two Years. K. 2,550 l.u 1,402 50 Corn, 4,000 l.u 2,000 00 ure, 25.000 lids :!?:&gt; 00 Cabbage, 20,000 hda BO (id Lettuce, 400 beha t;:&gt; 00 Carrots, 30 bu 15 0(1 BeetB, TJ bu Ke&lt;l peppers, 1 bu 17 50 Beans. 10 l»u 12.-) M Turnips. 150 l&gt;u 75 00 17 50 Peas, 10 bn 17 50 560 00 Potatoes, 500 bn 50( 64 00 Hay, :&gt;(&gt; T 500 00 Ii.'. 10 T iw, 50 T alfa, 1.") T Eiache, 50 sucks ks. 182 kens. 400 uir.-ir 200 00 Chickens, 200 1(14 lojoi n»i Veal, 3.053 lbs Pi.-k.-ls. 343 gal Batter, 1.040 ll.s Lard. 7,200 |ba Efga, 1.460 dot fork. 81,135 lbs i-ive hotrs on hand. 370 hoa«i </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE PENITENTIARY 63 Report uf Cuiviii Cash FiiihI. showing tin- amount received. iiid alto tlic amount expended during the hiennium. eovenng he v.'iirs 1909 and 1910. Leaving a balance November Wth id, November Wth. 1008 lalance on hand, November 30th. 1008 i&gt;r the hienniura by prison -- 22.0* i; ing the biennium by prisoner 21,893 12 prisoner et on hand, November 30th, 1010 $ 3.7&lt; [ing a gain of daring th* biennium over the urin «r the biennium over tin ennium, 1908. The expendi - all eonviel order* bcbI I'l id nt the elose &lt;&gt;f the bienniam, 1908. The expendi- the hienmnm covered nil convict order* &gt;&lt;'tit oal itution, n!s ■&gt; eovered ;ill tr msiictions between the insist inn of the trwnHferrinfj of money, from one money, from on&lt; ther for obligationH, contracted while in the insti - 1 durinft the biennium Rbon moun&lt; p inmateo during the biennium together with the obligations due them during the biennium. urn ing the biennium with a I - 1,760.76. uin with a I' a V/hich Prisoners Were Received During Biennium. 4 Cavf 2 Pierce 3 Were Received During Biennium. Knties I rom V/hich Prisoners ins 4 U»g« 1^ 1M H 6 Polk 1 Red Willow i 2 II, ]t 1 Rich irilsiin 10 it 2 •! •ITiTson in Sarpy 4 &gt; 14 Johnson 1 Stanton •&gt; ( 1 Keith fi Saundera 1 Keya I'aha 2 Sewnrd 4 ( !» Kearney 1 Sheridan i ( 6 Kimball 1 Thayer 3 H Th. 1 H </seg>
            <seg id="p016">64 LAND COMMISSIONE1 i 4 Dixoa 1 ),u\ilc 6 Lancaster Lincoln 29 Thurston Valley 6 4 12 Madison Morrill Xance Washington Wheeler 9 14 Douglas Dakota Franklin Tu-iiiis 112 Webster Y-.rk 4 Xi-malia Xuekolls 4 1 .&gt; 4 T t;il ( )t(n •i Pawne • ) Showing number of prisoners received each year since tin •stablislnnent of the penitentiary 1869 IT 189(1 1!H 1870 30 189] 17!) 1871 23 1892 167 1872 i*.") 1893 206 1 1879 ■'"&gt; 1 BQ3 •&gt;&lt;&gt;»: 1873 22 1894 261 •&gt;■) 1ST! ±\ 189o !!»:: is?.") 44 1896 1876 4!&gt; 1897 I'll 1*77 lo 1898 139 1878 63 1899 142 1879 92 l'KHi 150 7!) 1901 ITS 1881 74 ' 1902 153 1882 7ii 1903 135 1883 71 l!&gt;04 208 W S 4 107 1!io:&gt; J70 137 IMoii 204 l ss '&gt; Ho I!»o7 219 1^ S 7 itii 1908 204 1888 i:&gt;:{ 1909 I'll 2oo l!)lo 192 Total 5560 J Holiest registered Dumber, 5,561. Average number received 132.16. rE SENTENCES IMPOSED ON PRISONERS DURING THE BIENNIUM. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE PKNITENTIARY 65 • Mir year M Three years and under five years Five years and including ten years Between ten and twenty 8 Including twenty years and to hut not including fort t I V . 1 ( I '• -;i I li t KThe table at the head of the page should, hut does not. - I". S. prisoners who served three and four month - ly. Kyear and under two year years an&lt;l under thr EDUCATIONAL ADVANTAGES. Able to read and write at time of reception Unable to read or write at time of reception o. HABITS PRIOR TO ARREST Alleging temperate habits 1 !J Claiming to be intemperate RELIGIOUS TEACHING Denomination! of church in which prisoners received during the liiennium were taught. Methodist l"(l Kpiseopal Catholic 127 Peoples Church 1 Kaptist 62 Free Methodist 1 Presbyterian 27 Greek Church 1 Lutheran 26 Korean 1 Congregational 16 Christians 1 [Tnited Brethren 7 No religion Christian 19 NOTICE </seg>
            <seg id="p018">LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 66 STATEMENT AS TO GUILT OR INNOCENCE Kiit guilt of crime for which sentenced y guilt of crime for which sentenced s EXHIBIT Showing the Dumber of each kind of offences for which commitments were issued since the establishment of the peni- tentiary. Larcenous operations 4.:524 ults on the person 1.114 Arson 54 Perjury 14 Having burglar tools 11 micting railway tracks !» Child stealing i Gambling 4 Bigamy *i Malicious injury to property Selling liquor to Indians Blackmail Illegal voting Wife desertion .) A lultery ■&gt; Train wrecking 1 Prize fighting 1 Procuring a felony 1 Seduction 1 AGES ■years and under to 30 years !";! 31 to 40 years 41 to 50 years. s 51 years and over </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATE PENITENTIARY 67 CENSUS OF U. S. PRISONERS Those received during the biennium who admit having served previously. Reform school graduates 8 Present December 1. 1908 Received during bienniim Discharged Transferred to Leavenworth, Kas FEMALE WARD Women prisoners present December 1, 190ft Received Discharged Pardoned Present .November. :{(). 101n Having served one previous year [laving served two previous terms Not known to have served previously Present November 30, 1910 i ASSIGNMENTS Of inmates of prison at the close of biennial period. Engineers department Cell-house help Laundry, tailor and shoe shop Blacksmith, painter and carpenter Vegetable cellar : Shop runners (latemen Employed in greenhouse </seg>
            <seg id="p020">68 I^\NI) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Policing yard Employed at stockyards Farmers, teamsters and cartincn Working in yard In deputy's office Library and chapel stand Female department In warden's office Biarden's house and kitchen e room and guards' birber rds' (jiiartermaster Bks and assistants ers and butchers Kti-rs. dishwashers and scullions nd wounded Ber death sentence ho|)s Excused from duty CRIMES FOR WHICH PRISONERS WERE CONVICTED DUR ING THE BIENNIUM Arson Assault to rape &gt; lit to kill and wound Assault to injure 12 9 Abetting shoot to kill Hurglary 1 Hurglary with explosivi Child stealing ■&gt; •) KM against nature '-aling 4 Chicken stealing ! Bicealing stolen property bezzlement Forgery 4'. Fornication 1 (Jrand larceny Horse stealing 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">69 1 ny from person 17 ny as Bailee 1 Manslaughter - Murder, h'rst degree 15 Murder, second degree s Maning mppOrt of family 1 ailv •&gt; Obtaining money under false pi Obstructing railroad track Obtaining money under false pretenses t Uses / Obstructing railroad track •ling stock . i Poisoning stock Receiving stolen property £ Robbery Shoot to kill Shoot to kill Shoot to wound Sin iot to wound to wound 1 Stab to wound i Selling mortgaged property Selling mortgaged property Steal and carry away Steal and carry away Wife desertion . Wife desertion GENERAL STATISTICS GENERAL STATISTICS Regarding prisoners received during the bienninm Civil Condition Regarding prisoners received during the h\&gt; Civil Condition Married at time of reception Unmarried at time of reception Total Married at time of reception ["nmarried at time of reception s Total 424 Parental Guidance and supervision Both parents living at time of conviction Father living at time of conviction _ Mother living at time of conviction Neither living at time at conviction Total Parental Guidance and supervision Moth parents living at time of conviction Father living at time of conviction Mother living at time of conviction Neither living at time at conviction Total THE BIRTHPLACE THE BIRTHPLACE Of prisoners received during the biennium. Foreign born 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">70 54 Nebraska 324 Other states 424 Total CENSUS OF PRISON 4:$:i 424 4 Returned to prison from parole t.f this hiennium returned to prison »f former hiennium period* returned ived for sake keeping D. S. Prisoners received E barged by expiration of sentence mute by Governor anil discharged loned by Governor and discharged Released on parole K nanded by order of court aped from prison Executed prisoners discharged Hon. T. W. Smith, Warden. I Dear Sir: — Although I am not the official Chaplain. I wish to to you and to every officer and guard of the institution, sincere thanks for the courtesy shown to me while acting as tholie Chaplain to the Catholic prisoners of the state. Not y has every mark of respect been shown, but every assistance en that would tend to bring about the spiritual uplift of the n and bring me in closer touch with such of life's unfortunates are your charges. In regards to the prisoners, I must say that lave always been cordially received by them, regardle ;ir denomination and my visits looked forward to by many h interest and pleasure. ROBERT F. MORAN, Catholic Priest. Eber praMBi December 1. 1908 ived daring tin- biennium '&gt;n eonuutment mmittcil by court orden </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE PENITENTIARY 71 NOTES I think it proper to add to my report by making mention sum*' things that aided bm in my work. Realizing that I have been assisted much in the discharge of my duties as Chaplain, I wish to acknowledge my obligations and express my thanks to all who have helped me in ray work in any way to make it successful. I wish to thank the Warden for his advise and assistance and numerous courtesies toward me in my work for I realize that without tlie cooperation of the Warden I should have been at a loss many time to know what to do. I wish also to express my thanks to the Matron for her services in the Sunday school and to Mi&gt;s .Mary Smith for her assistance at the piano in both church and Sunday school services and also to Miss Louise Smith for her services as a teacher daring my term as Chaplain in the Sunday school as her work has been efficient and appreci ited by the class. I wish to express my thanks to Mr. Flansbarg and Mr. Bower for their work as Superintendent over the Sunday school also tn Messrs. Cordner, Aul and miller for their services as teachers who have seemed to ■pare no pains in trying to do the work as well as in their power. I would fail to do my duty did I not make mention of Mrs. McKeene for her untiring work in the Sunday school as well as Christian work in other ways, Mrs Corey has been also a diligent and faithful teacher for some time, and any others who have assisted I wish to express my thanks for the same. I should certainly fell that I had not done ju - did I not mention the efficient and apparently untiring work of Mr. Bus as a choir director for church and Sunday school services. I wish to express my appreciation of the work done in the prison by Father Moran pastor of St. Thomas Or. phantage. Father Moran visits the prison regularly once each month and some times oftener in the interest of those who are members of the church he represents, ministering to their needs in a spiritual way of all those who seek his services. Ilis work here is voluntary on his part and beneficent to those he visits and advises. I wish to express my appreciation of the coiirtesi. Deputy Warden Welton. Clerk Ward, St.' wart Carlin and I Hileman. In many ways they have made the work of the Chap - lain easier and more successful. The last in order but not the least in importance is the fact of the good will of the inmates of </seg>
            <seg id="p024">72 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT the prison. No person could ask for better treatment than I have received at the hands of the inmates during ray term of service as Chaplain. Fur all of which I am truly thankful. I feel that it is not my duty to make recommendations hut I wish ite that 1 fully endorse those made by the Warden. JAMES IUFF. Chaplain. REPORT OF THE SCHOOL The school of instructions for the inmates of the institution has lieen continued during my term and its work has been fairly done and the inmates benefited thereby. It is hard to tabulate the results. Men are coming and K"i"£ all the time, its average ■een about forty. Many of the pupils have learned to read and others have made much advancement in the common Kn&lt;rlish branches. Many more would attend the school were it possible to them on account of a place practical for all to attend. 1 have used the help of other inmates as teachers and find them efficient workers. 1 have no trouble in usinj.' them nor (Jo I find any objection to their presence. I make it a rule i every man present and personally note his progress and en - courage him in every way possible. My assistants receive no compensation and they at least merit this note of appreciation from me. The state should consider this feature of the Chaplains work and provide for its continuance under most favorable cir - cumstances. While it may not be the place for favorable argu - ment on the subject of a Penitentiary school yet I am satisfied that it would be both beneficial and profitable for the state to make the school a permanent part of its discipline. The argument that would maintain in the non-education of the convict would compel the everlasting ignorance of any person. JAMES IITFF. Superintendent. ■ Financial statement of the Sunday School from July 15, 1909, November 23, 1910. Collections, cash * 21 Disbursements : Papers Supplies $ 110 70 22 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">73 STATE PENITENTIARY Tickets 38 50 10 00 181 51 Incidentals Balance on hand REPORT OF THE CHAPLAIN December 1. 1910 Hon. T. \V. Smith, Warden Nebraska State Penitentiary ■ Sir: — I have the honor to submit to you my report since July 15, 1909. K During said time there have been maintained with un\ai larity religoiM service* consisting of preaching and Sunday o] in the prison chapel every Sunday morning. t These services have been well attended. There has bee: Kge attendance of nior than 450 persons including visitors at «] service and an average of about 2:5.") persons including ors at the Sunday school session a steady increase of &lt;r :e. »The attendance of prison inmates at the Sunday chool ses - s has steadily increased the number reaching as high a - of a possible 440. triie contribution! of the visitors have maintained the running of the Sunday school. ippended sinnminar; I We have been assisted in many ways by outside help teaching in the Sunday school, some by conducting the ie by furnishing entertainment by way of sinking, reading. To those who hare we return our rty thanks. They have come to us at their own expense of e and money, receiving only their car fare and that r&gt; Iie. They have at least this e tried to help a person in n ■nee and the gratitude of th them considered a greater » pleasureable reflection that they ed. this coupled with a good con - •e who have been helped will be mpensation than any money con- LI am glad to record the fact there are those in this busy world can feel an interest in their fellowmen though this.- uu-n be </seg>
            <seg id="p026">74 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT for the time being under the ban of the law and to some exten t exiled from society. I My associations with those who are confined for cause, have :ed me to the conclusion that the best cure for crime and ndant raftering is found in obedience to the plan laid down our Saviour and known as the Gospel of Christ, where that s to reform there seems to be no hope. I am satisfied that religous services have an influence for good on many of those 1 are confined behind the wall of the penitentiary. Few are verted but many are favorably impressed with the truth as ght by our Master. Were it possible to hold social services I lk more good might be accomplished. JAMES HUFF, Chaplain. REPORT OF THE LIBRARIAN I The library contains about 3,000 volumns, during the past bteen months there has been no additions to the libray ex - t by donation and only about fifty volumns as there has been funds to use for the purchase of books. We think that for the size of the library we have as good as can be found in any similar institution in the country. While it is true that fiction forms the largest class of literature read (in this we resemble the outside world), yet many read History, me and Poetry and some read Philosophy and the measure of thoughtfull and instructive reading done by the men will bear favorable comparison with equal numbers of the outside. Wheth - er this be creditable to the men or to the state. It is a fact that e very large measure of intelligence is confined within the walls of the state prison. This fact only adds difficulty to the question of crime and its cure. The much heralded declaration that intelligence lessens crime will bear careful criticism before it is allowed to go unchallenged. I The reading of the library has been largely augmented by adreds of copies of papers and magazines donated by friends the prison. Where these are of a late date theiy are welcome iition to our supply of reading and the men appreciatee them </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE PENITENTIARY 75 Pi that contributes to the good discipline of plenty &lt;&gt;t' good reading matter circulated occupies time that would be spent in ways I order, it prevents brooding that would &gt;r despair, it improves the mind, improves lie mental capabilities for the living of a KThe library is sadly in ■ i new catalogue and there is unds available for the printing of one which will cost about and in i that amount these should be an appropria - of at least $100 yearly to keep the library up to the standard 1 would recomend to you that such appropriation should be d for as the matter of continued use of about 300 voli. wears them out so they require to be replaced with JAMES HUFF, Librarian. REPORT OF PRISON PHYSICIAN To Warden T. W. Smith : For the biennium ending November 30, 1910, I have the honor to report as follow The sanitary condition of the prison is excellent, so far as its administration is concerned. It is not well located, but the clean - liness of the cells and the wholeaomeneai of the food arc ly to be commended. tThe health of the inmates lias been satisfactory. Syphilitics segregated, none such being allowed to cell with non-syphili - prisoners, and a separate bath tub is kept for their use. se persons are given anti-syphilitic treatment for one or two ■s or as long as any symptoms of the disease remain. One patient died of pulmonary tubercnli took up the work of prison physician. Since then I ha\. mended consumptives to be parolled. for as we have no isolated hospital wards, we would have been obliged to put them in the general hospital, and such a course, it seems to me, would have been inhuman. One of the urgent needs of the institution is an hospital. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">76 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT While we have but few cases of severe illness, slight ailments are very common and the same is true of accid' During my incumbency, the average number of prescription per month has been 682 and of surgical dressings 279. On taking charge of the hospital. I found it almost barren of equipments, i- veil the most necessary things for carrying on the work were lacking. An excellent operating chair has been purchased, much to the advantage of the patients and convenience of the doctor. The hospital had not even the simplest means of cleanliness, such as those used in disinfecting and sterilizing. We have added Dr. Leinninger's fumigator and a Cook sterilizing outfit. Where there are so many injuries as we have here the best facilities and the greatest care arc necessary to prevent infection. By means of the additions above referred to, and the services of a most efficient hospital steward, the patients have been spared much suffering and the State meanwhile has been a gainer both in time and money. I Writers on criminology and especially when treating of in reform, all agree that the morphine habit is one of the demoralizing features of prison life, hurting not only the ms, but those engaged in the illicict traffic as well. The id" as every physician knows, is wholly incapable of any lined effort at character-building, and is utterly unworthy of dence, a moral, mental and physical wreck. Thomas De cy, in his "" Confessions of an English Opium Eater," gives the mild musings of a literary genius, a more or less agree - "pipe dream", and no true picture of the desperate condition man with criminal inclinations to contend with. I The illicit morphine traffic in our prisons is not only vicious, by general consent most difficult to break up. Usally there so many 'roads" and they are so tortuous, it is very hard ferret them out. The dense ignorance of those implicated, veil as the eternal silence of all connected with such an in - iition is only known to the reformer who is obliged to enter n his work without help or sympathy. Notwithstanding this, sn the present administration took charge of the institution, it i decided to break up this damnable traffic, a traffic which has aded not only this insttiution, but every penitentiary in Ameri - and owes its existance to a love of gain, the victim paying ay times the market price for the drugs he uses. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">STATE PENITENTIARY To destroy this baneful hnirinc—, it was i essary for th€ administration to have in charge a man of high character iron will. These are the traits that have enabled the ward. stop the smuggling of drugs within the prison walls. About thirty n treated for the habit: many We ho| have been permanently eared. Some are abnormal or d&lt; erat.s. and took morphine because of these defects. Othen apparently normal who contracted the habit because of bad rounding*. Such, if restrained for ■ considerable time, may form correct habits of thoughi and action and so be permanently en The cause having been removed, they will cease to be criminals A nuintu Id me that if they could be cured of the -dope' habit, they would not regret their term of imprisonment. The person cured have in every way improved and arc doing Ix work, so that both the State and its wards are the gainer Since the reform began, only twice has the drug found its way within the walls, then in small quantities and to but few Its presence was promptly discovered and the offenders punished. This is the first successful effort in the history of the institu tion to keep opium and whisky from the convicts for two secutive years. As a matter of fact, it lias generally been held by in authority that the thing could not be done, but I congrat- ulate the present administration upon the fact that it has lone in this institution and by an intelligent and sustained effort. may be done in any other state prison. Respectfully submitted. II. B. DOWRY, Physician to tin- Nebraska Stntc IVnitrnti-irv • i * . </seg>
            <seg id="p030">LAM) COMMISSIONERS REPORT 78 38EJ8AV *- •&lt;n B ci -1- QD "t X X t^ 2 pain.wxy P^'Cl pajaajsue-ij. papuBiuay pauopjEj padE.isg painuiuio ,■) c -r — t- paioaBj t~ P32J.IKIJ.ISIQ rtH-rr--HHHr--n«H Y-tlHr-l H « H jjg rt t- &lt;O « O O « X p3H]UI padB.isg uin^^&gt;^ paioa^a 'paiuniatf £ N h m oo + t- X t~ 00 N [ I s M fc b». u 8&gt;.!? l- u l- v. jjj^ a. ieTtsia^igijgibSiSS u u Z$S&amp;&amp;3£x5x£AZ$6£ </seg>
            <seg id="p031">79 t- I t— «D r- b u'G &gt;&gt;£ ►&gt; (jo** *i &gt; d ,-•_£ s^S &gt;&lt;bi*; « &gt; Z r! «■: cc : *fi : '- — — — __—— — --—— — = /; : ct r- t- ifi r: c. c ■ — re c W : ut *^ tc -r ~ re c&gt; _ I wet c c m: - c -- ci x t: cc.rCr:c.ct-c gj « cc ; *_2 — — — H '"^ i2 "*" — — IZ — — £Ju ct — ( re ci t cc cc O »~ — c C! i— cc *- o t- re ~- re — re c t r- r- K w: * •* ;» r c! ct | _^^ r^.__»_^_^^. — _._•_-_•„• — --»- — —-—- — — ■—■ I cc a « o ci i' c - c :.' c - - &gt;• i — !■ cc ».- c w c -r r: cc L, I &gt;ft c&gt; «t *rt — — -•■ — -■ — t: :: ;: — r i* •• T t ! rt ct ■•* l r4- — -^ —^- — —^ —^ -^~" ~*~ ' ~. t ~ — — r- 25 « « -r *&lt;^ « *ft t -r — .—. •* | -^^ &gt;^^ !M — xctcoecocccr- — — r: 2 « n -r i 1 : - «: i* -r f r: ci w t c^ .r p: * &gt;" i* "T t ci w « w^ I *^" *^ "^ ■ "^ ■ ' -^*» *^ *^ ™^ « I — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — «| i- o: t w oo c » - p; w r : -rCO?&gt;*rtOi«— o n * i* t «.t &gt;•" t - r; r --•ciftf'rciww "■— " **' ™* ■ ■ ■ ' ■ ' _, I n o « o ?■ :i f^ - w n O) n ft oc c r. « c c o r c ci Jl « Tf t v: - L:i--rTpcr:oiKKr, rrc-rifiictfpiKf: I w^ ~^ cc oi cc cc re cc re *^ *c ■? co co a I o n " c - — — - w c« -t -r -r «-- — »- - 1 eo eo — — — — — — — — — -• — — — — — — — _ »_ I m tc -f o — o (C t :i &lt;* c &gt;" t-^&lt;«os^ tt t t i* w « i 1 : t t k C! * r f; " " r i*. c - t w w n «« I n o ci C - o c t - '* * i: oc f- '■* k 1 : ci c »■* t- oo « — -r »T5 &lt;-•: o »« — ■n* cz a cc cc re cc re -t- *.c *.c -r i- ct cj cc J2 v * t « «: &gt;ft •- •* * k e) x r: t r: t i.- vft -r f w ci -* I *° *° w 3 i i « g i « 5J "* t -r , I OM---r::fT'-*5ixxf!CbC'CTOOh«r)ec Tp -r i-c «c 't o — — r: ci cc re cc re cc cc •- ■ ■ — . i 00 r. :: - i- :i r: - - i- a ci x C it '" - C - n C! - x * 2 I c '- Ir-N — O — ore— — i- cr " C- — - C 0) N !• O m t t «: '■* »-t — — — — — — — . — — _ — — — — — — — -r-r — _,-— . — — I r- t O (C - C - '". Cl N &gt;•* .^ C - »- f ! X « N t- O co cc -r -T — *~ &lt;-: ■" -* -I- r- rc r-. — * -r :• ?! :i i n •? o tc t - i: i: o cc o :i c ei - x - - c t- cc -r ■* -r *■" »-c *.c -^ -r ce e; re -r -r re r? .-: kc ic -r — ■ I to » x ■: :j CO n w cc c &gt;." * - c ~ c r ■ *— — — — — — — — -" — — — — — — — — — — — — — « CO -^ CC — — — — — — — — -r — — — — ■ i «D'T(OccciHi*tOT^x&gt;ncccotocac | t ec-rrc-r»ft«-co-p-rrcciccce^rccccce«.*'*»r; — I « - »- ;i o x r. c w cr. O n ' e^co^cc^fin-rw^^^ccrcrcrc— - r. :i r. I »r © i* n c n c *■ r; c c r; c n - &gt; — -r -r r- r-« co ■«■ co f *n -r «-- — -r re ?&gt; cc re t re re .— •- ■* — - | "7* *^* *^ "*" *^ " "^ " *T "*" "*" T •*" *^ "^ "T 1 T ""^ [ GOaO »O&gt;9 - -r. - O O O O O O O O O O O OOOOOOOOOOCOO — — ■-''— — »-&lt; — c. c 1 - C- ? * ?• *• ci ?• * -" Jiooicnoc&amp;c&amp;oo) </seg>
            <seg id="p032">80 T r Counties from which prisoners were received, giving crime, ter &gt;f prisoner and occupat ion, rceeived during the Biennium. t'uuntv Crime Adams Adams Grand larceny Man slaughter Man slaughter Larceny 1 32 Barber &amp; En 19 Barber 6 41 Farmer lope lope Antelope 21 Painter 29 Farmer Larceny from person Murder Horse stealing Statutory rape Rape Fanner Farmer t; M 90 Farmer 1 &lt;&gt; lit Chaff eur Bufflao Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Brown Burglary Shoot to kill Forge rv Forgery Hog stealing Burglary 26 Laborer 1 26 Farmer Larceny from person Larceny from person stealinp 21 Waiter Painter 1 6 41 Fireman Attempt arson Forgery Forgery Burglary Burglary Burglary 20 Baker 30 Waiter Carpenter 1 Grand larceny Rape Farmer l Farmer Grand larceny Grand larceny. Grand larceny Grand larceny Grand larceny Murder l&lt; 41 Horseman 56 Peddler 29 Farmer Dea th 24 Bookkeeper stealing ... Man slaughter ... Break and entry Forge r\ 6 20 Show'n 16 Farmer Hutte Hutte Hutte Hutte Hutte Hutte Hutte I'herr •&gt;ok 24 Lineman Forgery Robbery 1 22 Painter Farmer :i0 Miner Steal and carry away Assault to rani l 88 Laborer 28 Ranchman nit to injure Murder 2° 34 Farmer I Horse stealing Rape 19 Farmer 28 Farmer Horse stealing i lorseman Selling mortgaged property 22 Farmer Vs. Mo. Age Occupation ( obtaining monev under f.i pret&gt; I :.". Laborer Life 29 Mason ■27 Horset 38 Contractor 38 Electrician 21 Lather 29 Sew'g Mi- 1. ilesman 49 Shoemaker 47 Cigar maker Life 28 Laborer </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE I'KNITKXTIAKY 81 I Crime t Hu Printer uster Burglar H uster Horse stealing 20 Ranir M Farmer k Farmer H A Laborer ) U utter erk B H enter Farmer Mai Florist" tmster \\ .'I %!■ rter mixer ir \ H SO Farmer r. Baker 4t Farmer 27 Maihinist M v A M 'i hevenne Burglarv and grand ?!1! I), S3 :}."&gt; Bartender 19 Laborer 21 La! Dodge Dodge F. R 1!) Laborer 40 Laborer 47 Laborer H Dodge w F Tailor Dodge Dodge Dodge Teamster Plumber Burg steal 50 L;i TK st nat Painter TK Burglary Vs. Mi i. Ak'&lt; ' &gt;&lt; [ upation If, Laborer 40 Ranchman Cattle s Burglar 20 Horseman 18 La' :',7 Farmer Switchmar Shoemaker Laundrvman 25 Br'k &amp; switch'n 1", Farmer 19 Teamster 2\ Laborer lerk 20 Tailor A br. me. is Fireman Tailor </seg>
            <seg id="p034">82 LAM) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Countv Crime Dawes 18 Laborer Dawes... Dawes ... Dixon Dixon .. Dixon Dakota Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Burglary Burglary 18 Laborer 23 Clerk Assault to rape Forgery Assault to rape Robberv 20 Farmer an Farmer 29 Switchman 40 Machinist Burglary Burglary Burglary Robbery Burglrry Burglary 21 Farmer 20 Laborer 19 Laborer Break and enter Robberv 4 Cook Cooper Grand larceny Burglary 20 Fireman Embezzlement Burglary ?1 Attorne 4 29 Laborer Break and enter Forgery . Baker Labon Murder I" Life 31 Laborer Larceny from person Robberv 20 Rancher Robbery Robberv id 32 Baker &amp; cook 10 27 Barber Shoot to kill W Waiter* barber Break and enter Break and enter Stab to wound Forgers ?0 Laborer 22 Stone mason Laborer 48 Painter Break and enter Break and enter Horse stealing Forgery 49 Teamster 40 Laborer 48 Laborer 20 Farmer it to kill 24 Laborer Break and enter Burglary Break and enter Murder 1° Railroader Arson '20 Laborer Break and enter Break and enter Horse stealing. Forgery 9 34 Laborer 1 IS Laborer 21 Cook 28 Railroadc Robbery Burglary Burglary Laborer Barber Larceny from person Grand larcenv Brick mason Embezzlement Grand larceny Teacher of law Vs. Mn. Age Occupation Obstructing railroad tra 10 49 Cook -.' Farmer 50 Sign painter i 20 Teamster ■?T Laborer 1 6 10 Carpenter ?."&gt; Laborer il Laundryman ?i Housekeeper </seg>
            <seg id="p035">83 Vs. Mo. Age Occupation County Crime 6 30 Laborer Douglas Grand larceny 28 Housekeeper Douglas Murder 1&lt; 24 Cook Douglas Break Laborer Douglas Break 17 Laborer Douglas Murder l c I)eu th 36 Baker Douglas Break and enter Douglas Break and enter Laundryman Douglas Break and enter Douglas Assault to kill Douglas Forgery Waiter Douglas Larceny from person Cook Douglas Murder 1' Life Laundryman Douglas. Assault to wound 6 21 Laborer Grand larceny.. Miner Douglas Douglas Stab with intent to kill Laborer Murder Teamster Douglas Douglas Larceny from person 1 fi 24 Printer ■k Douglas Break and enter Butcher &amp; co Laborer Douglas Robbery 24 Douglas Burglary Laborer Douglas Burglar) Ml Teamster Horse stealing Fire'n &amp; n Murder l c Ship builder Porter Douglas Robbery Douglas Rape 4S Porter Waiter&amp;barr Douglas Assault to ki * Douglas Forgery 20 Laborer Porter Douglas Robtx 24 Laborer Douglas Break and enter 28 Douglas Laborer Grand larceny 39 Douglas Grand larceny •&gt;7 Laborer Robbery Laborer Douglas Douglas Forgery 6 26 Butcher Waiter Douglas Murder 1&lt; Dea th 39 Douglas Break and ente 21 Waiter Porter Douglas Robber 10 Douglas Murder Life Farmer Douglas Larceny from person 10 Waiter Douglas Break and enter Laborer :■"&gt; Douglas Break and enter Laborer Douglas Break and enter Laborer Dougl Break and enter Barber 29 Douglas Break and enter Electrician Farmer Douglas Brea nt 24 Douglas Break and ente Porter Douglas Robberv Laborer Douglas Grand iarceny Iron worker Douglas Brc l!i Cook Douglas Br d enter Fireman Douglas Break and enter 19 Farmer Robbe Douglas 24 Waiter i </seg>
            <seg id="p036">84 LAND COMMISSION-UK'S RKHORT r :i Countv Crime Ys Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Break and enter Grand lar&lt; Murder 1" 30 Steamfitter 4 28 Cook II 36 Laborer Assault to kill and wound Murder Break and enter Break and enter Maining 20 Window trii 26 Cook t Waiter Douglas Break and enter Waiter Douglas Break and enter 1 &gt;ecorator 26 Cook Douglas Break and enter 6 Douglas Assault to kill 21 Laborer glas Break and enter Waiter Douglas Larceny from person 23 Telephone 38 Fireman 21 Teamster 20 Messenger 10 Waiter Break and enter 6 Douglas Break and enter Douglas Break and enter Murder 2° 13 Franklin Forgery 1 8 Carpenter Furnas Grand larceny Horse stealing Furnas Grand larcenv 1 Furnas Ob. money under fls. pretence Bank cler Murder 1« Lit Barber Bigamy 49 Laborer Burglary and larceny Laborer Burglary and larceny 21 Laborer 40 Cook Burglary Grand larcenv Robberv Forgery Forgery Forgery Grand larcenv 26 Porter Man slaughter Farmer Laborer Break and enter Grand larcenv Horse stealing Forgery Burglary and larceny Tailor Horse stealing Laborer 1 Forgery 40 Laborer 20 Domestic Hamilton Burglary Hamilton ... Assault to do bodily injury ilton Horse stealing ilton Grand larcenv ilton Shoot to kill 30 Laborer 24 Cook ft b i ilton Assault to kill it Harlan Grand larceny Farmer M'&gt;. Age Occupation I Laborer 6 34 Waiter Douglas 23 Farmer 17 Farmer 17 Laborer 35 Laborer 24 Bar tender 19 Tele, operatr 58 Farmer 28 Cement \ n 18 Launrlryman 56 Farmer 18 Fanner Robbery Ob. money under fls. pretence Rape Machinist Carpenter Waiter 34 Rancher 30 Tailor </seg>
            <seg id="p037">TATK PENITKNTIAHV 85 Crinr M Age Occupation ( unty 47 Farmer woum Harlan Grand larcen lerk Br enter Laborer 19 School tea 21 Laborer ird Burglarv and larce II Farmer Farmer Painter Laborer all Johnson Forgery Jefferson .... Burglar Burglar Burgl Jefferson .... Burgl liner Jefferson Burg ntractor 18 Painter 41 I. iT Hog stt Lab- Keith Murder 2 Keith M mal Keith Telegrapher man K&lt; t, Keith P Keya Pah H Keva Paha Horse stealir Farmer Rancher Laborer Bar tend armer F Knox Horse stea Knox Grand lar&lt; Knox Forgerv, raised forged er Knox Horse stealir Farmer Knox Horse stealir 20 Farmer Kearney. painter &amp; paper Laborer Kimball Burgl Electric engir H Baker Laborer n Forgery B Ranchman Farmer Ranchman itt Lincoln Horse stealing !:' Far Far R 1 Miner Lincoln F Wai' Lancaster Painter ft crp't Carpenter Lancaster .... Burglar Lancaster ... Burglar Laund ister .... Grand larcer 82 Ilousekeef IS Laborer 'her aster .... Assault to dr&gt; bodily injur ister .... Assault t ■ilt to do bodily inlur </seg>
            <seg id="p038">86 &amp; blk Crime Farmer Laborer 20 Painter l Horse stealin ('.rand larcen 25 Cook &amp; i 41) Clerk 24 Fireman Embezzlement ■ Rapt Madison Man slaughter ' I Waiter Grand larcen) Machinist Farmer Mornll Horse Stealin 1 Hurglarx Farmer Miner Burglar Laroenv and bailer \ em aha Grand larcen\ (■rand larceny \ em a ha Break and enter ii Farmer 32 Carpenter 21 Farmer Assault to rape Lolls Burglary Laborer Nn.kolls 26 Laborer 44 Teamster 4:. Blacksmith .oils Larceny from person .oils Rapt kolls Burglary Burglarv Burglar} Stork m Assault to do bodilv injur\ Burglary with explosive Burglary with explosive Child stealing Farmer 28 Lahore Grand larcen Grand larcen 25 Labort V.i JFarme Vs. Mo. A(e Occupation I ister Larceny from person . ister Lan-eny from person ; -ter Porgei ister Porgen ister Burglary rand larceny • '.rand larceny ster Larceny from person . Burglary Jter Assault t&lt;&gt; do bodily inju ister Embezzlement rand larceny ster (iranfl larceny ister Horse stealing -'ti Machinist 22 Farmer 24 Operator :t2 Xurse &lt;V wa 27 Shoemaker 54 Painter 2:t Laborer M R. ft If. •J'.i Attorney 24 Actor .'!« Dressma 24 Farmer ."&gt;&lt;; Laborer Forrarj rmer 30 Fireman :&gt;&lt;&gt; Hod rarri *&gt;0 Farmer 40 Teamster 23 Laundrvm Forgery ilt t«i wound Non-support &lt;&gt;f famil Grand larcenv Grand larc-em (&gt;.! pr. hgr. ft pa 2.! Printer 43 Cook Embezzlement Larceny from p Forgery Farmer Laborer Laborer :t:i Cook &amp; l»a 31 Carpenter 34 Farmer :•&lt;! .Farmer Assault tu kill and murde </seg>
            <seg id="p039">\ A A R ,i w A w B \ A T A ■v A R H ,\ Ptr ft A f it 6= </seg>
            <seg id="p040">88 i_ount\ Crimi Farmer Grand larcen Valley Concealing stolen proper Yallev Assault to raj' &gt;0 Farmer Laborer Farmer Kington Burglary _ ington Burglary _ ington Grand larce ington Grand larce Coal miner a bo re Labf Lab 28 Tramp \ssault to WO Grand larceny York Chicken steali York Burglarv Ma sot Farmc Plasterer Farmer Mo. Age Occupation Washington Break and entt ster Burglrry </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>