<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00034">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Vitamin A Content of the Milk of Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey Cows</title>
               <date value="1931-02">1931-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 54 The Vitamin A Content of the Milk of Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey Cows H. P. DAVIS AND I. L. HATHAWAY Department of Dairy Husbandry Lincoln, Nebraska February, 1931 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY A comparative study of the vitamin A content of milk produced by Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey cows was made by comparing the growth produced by SGO rats receiving milk from these breeds as their only source of vitamin A. Albino rats 24 to 28 days old, and weighing between 35 and 45 grams, were fed a vitamin A free basal ration composed of 18 per cent casein, 78 per cent corn starch, and 4 per cent salts. One gram of dried. yeast daily was fed separately as the source of the vitamin B complex. The antirachitic factor was supplied by irradiation of the corn starch with a Cooper Hewitt quartz mercury vapor lamp run at 2.4 amperes, 250 volts. This ration was fed from weaning until ophthalmia was incipient or there was. n cessa - tion of growth. When this point was reached, the basal ration was supplemented with one, two, and three cubic centimeters of milk. One group of rats was fed Holstein milk, while the other group received milk from one of the other breeds. Negative controls received only the vitamin A free diet and positive controls received the basal ration supplemented with one-tenth of a cubic centimeter of cod liver oil. In each comparison mijk was taken from two groups of four cows. Each group represented a breed and all the cows were from, the Ex - periment Station herd. They were selected for uniformity of age, siage of lactation, number of lactations, and stage of gestation. In general the cows in each group were milked the same number of times daily, and received the same feed. The average food consumption per cow was approximately 20 to 25 pounds of silage, 15 to 20 pounds of grain, and 20 pounds of alfalfa hay. An aliquot portion of the milk produced at each milking during :i 24-hour period was taken from the selected group of cows of each breed. This milk from each breed was pooled separately, and a repre - sentative sample was taken. The milk .was bottled in one-half-pint bottles and stored at 0° G. until used. The results showed some slight irregular differences in the gains produced by the milk from the different breeds. When these "differ - ences were considered in view of the individual variation of the ex - perimental animals, they appeared negligible. This conclusion was substantiated by a statistical examination of the data. From the re - sults of this study in which the- experiments were duplicated, it was evident that under the conditions of these experiments, the difference in the vitamin A content of milk from Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, or Guernsey breeds is insignificant. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Vitamin A Content of the Milk of Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey Cows H. P. DAVIS and I. L. HATHAWAY I It is universally known that cows of the Jersey and Guernsey breeds produce a more yellow-colored milk than cows of the Holstein and Ayrshire breeds. Some of the most potent sources of vitamin A are materials having a yellow color, such as cod liver oil, butterfat, and egg yolks. Further - more, Jersey and Guernsey milk has a higher average content of butterfat, and vitamin Ais a fat-soluble vitamin. In view of these facts it seemed possible that there might be a dif - ference in the vitamin A content, of milk from these breeds. In a survey of the literature only one reference was found which reported any studies of the relative vitamin A potency of milk from the different breeds. Holmes (5) studied the vitamin A content of butterfat from Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, Dutch Belted, and Devon milk. He reported that the data obtained were not sufficient to permit more than general conclusions, and that no attempt should be made to compare the breeds since in his study the age, feeding, period of lacta - tion, and number of lactations were not identical for the cows of the different breeds. The present study of the relative vitamin A content of milk produced by Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey cows was made by comparing the growth produced by 560 rats. These rats were allotted into different groups and fed milk from these four breeds as their only source of vitamin A. COLONY MANAGEMENT The rats used in these experiments were Albino rats whose parents were obtained from the Wistar Institute at Phila - delphia, Pennsylvania. Those used in Experiments I and II were housed in a basement room having west light. Those used in the other experiments were housed in a first-floor room having east light. Both rooms were ventilated with ventilating fans and heated with steam. During the cooler seasons the temperature within the rat laboratory was main - tained as near 24° C. as possible, but during the warm seasons the temperature rose considerably higher. The breeding cages were 48x43x30 centimeters and were made of angle iron frames, to which sand-screen wire netting was soldered. The experimental cages were approximately 28x28x28 centimeters and had wire netting on four sides. A false bottom of 13-millimeter screen was placed in each experi - &gt;Tho junior author had chame of the laboratory and is largely responsible for the work, which was orieinated . by the senior author. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 54 mental cage. Shavings were used for bedding in the breeding cages. During the last two experiments the shavings were sterilized by dry heat at 110° C. for 24 hours. The cages were cleaned biweekly and sterilized with steam. McCollum inverted-siphon water fountains were used in all cages. Pans, essentially the same as the McCollum feeding pan described by Greenman and Duhring (3), were used in the experimental cages and small galvanized-iron feed containers were used in the breeding cages. The breeding colony was maintained by rearing animals solely for breeding purposes. Experimental animals were destroyed with ether when the experiments were .completed. One male was mated with one to three females, and the breed - ing animals were first, mated when from 90 to 120 days of age. Fifteen to seventeen days after colonization, the females were placed in individual cages where they reared their young until weaning at from 24 to 28 days of age. An accurate record of the mating, date of birth of each litter, and sex of each rat born was kept. The breeding stock was reared on a ration composed as follows: Stock Ration 1 ""■. Wheat 2,900 grams Peas 750 grams Yellow corn 2,800 grams Alfalfa flour ...... 500 grams Meat scraps 1,000 grams CaCO. 150 grams Oatmeal -750 grams NaCl : 100 grams In addition, sprouted oats were fed ad libitum daily. The sprouted oats were replaced by milk for the breeding animals in the last two experiments. The ration was prepared by grinding finely all the ingredients and then adding 2 per cent by weight of cod liver oil.- The feed was freshly mixed each week. When the young rats were to be used foi' experimental purposes the breeders were placed on the following ration : ground whole wheat, 66 per cent; whole milk powder,''? 33 per cent; NaCl, 1 per cent; and sprouted oats ad libitum. The antirachitic requirements of the breeding rats were supplied by irradiation of this ration for 4.0 minutes at 60 centimeters in a layer one to two millimeters in depth, using a Uviarc Poultry Treater.' Eddy (2) showed that a layer of milk powder, two millimeters thick, placed about 30 centi - meters from the source of light and irradiated with ultra - violet light for a period of two to five minutes, acquired suf - ficient antirachitic power to prevent rickets in rats when the ■ * Mead Johnson and Company. Kvar.svillc, Indiana. 'The whole milk powder was "Crcmora A", obtained from the Dry Milk Company, New York City. *Type R. I. Special 100. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Vitamin A Content of Milk powder constituted 5 per cent of the diet. Wieland (12) irradiated a layer of milk powder three to four millimeters in depth for 30 to 45 minutes at a distance of 60 centimeters and reported that it cured the bone changes in rachitic children. Supplee and Dow (10) irradiated dry milk, containing 12 per cent butterfat, and reported that its antirachitic and calcifying properties were enhanced. When the young were weaned the breeders were again placed on Stock Ration 1. An abundant supply of tap water was furnished the breeding colony. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE The plan adopted was similar to the method of vitamin A assay for cod liver oil as outlined in the United States Phar - macopoeia (8) . A unit was to be the minimum daily quantity of milk required to cure induced symptoms of vitamin A starvation in young rats and to cause a gain in weight of from two to four grams per week for a period of eight weeks. It was believed that if the unit for each breed was found to be approximately the same, then the conclusion would be justified that the vitamin A content of the milk from the different breeds is equal. Preliminary experiments showed that very small quantities of milk must be used if only an average gain in weight of from two to four grams per week was to be ob - tained. These small amounts were not adequate to maintain growth satisfactorily throughout the eight weeks of the ex - perimental period. In order to have a sufficient range of quantities to take care of any great fluctuation that might occur in the potency of vitamin A the plan was adopted of feeding milk in one, two, and three cubic centimeter quantities. It was believed that if the differences in gains were not sig - nificant when Holstein milk (the lowest in fat and color) was compared with the milk of each of the other breeds, then the conclusion would be justified that the vitamin A content is the same. Rats 24 to 28 days old, and weighing between 35 and 45 grams, were placed on a vitamin A free basal ration composed as follows: casein, 5 18 per cent; corn starch, 0 78 per cent; and salts (McCollum No. 185) (7), 4 per cent. Yeast 7 was fed separately from the basal ration. One gram of dried yeast was allowed each animal daily. As a rule, the animals consumed the allowance of yeast readily. The antirachitic •A special erode of purified casein (No. 463) was purchased from the Casein Com - pany of America. New York City. It was extracted continuously for five days with 95 per cent ethyl alcohol. « Powdered starch was obtained from the Corn Products Refinine Company New York City. ' Compressed yeast was furnished through the courtesy of the Fleischmann Yeast Company, and was dried in a current of air at room temperature. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 54 factor was supplied by irradiation of the corn starch of the basal ration. One hundred grams of starch was spread uni - formly over an area 60 centimeters square in metal trays and then irradiated for 40 minutes at a distance of 60 centimeters. Steenbock and Coward (9) reported, that they had experienced no difficulty in activating corn starch. The experimental animals received distilled water to which iodine was added once each week according to the method of Sure (11). Each experimental rat was weighed daily on a balance sensitive to one gram, and a record of the amount of food consumed was kept. The litters were allotted so that, as far as possible, related animals were in each group of the experiment. A negative control, receiving only the basal ration, and a positive control, which received the basal ration supplemented with one-tenth of a cubic centimeter of cod liver oil daily, were selected from each litter except where several litters were started on the milk supplement at approximately the same time. The feeding of milk was begun when ophthalmia was in its incipient stage, or when there was a cessation of growth. As a rule, the pre-experimental or depletion period lasted for about five weeks, while the feeding trial was carried on eight weeks. Milk was taken from four typical cows of the two breeds to be compared. All the cows used were from the Experiment Station herd. They were selected as shown in. Table 1 for uniformity in age, stage of lactation, number of lactations, and stage of gestation. The cows in each group were milked the same number of times daily and received the same feeds. The cows milked four times per day received Ration 3, while those milked two or three times per day received Ration 4. These rations were composed as follows : Ration 3 . Ration 4 Corn 200 lbs. Corn 250 lbs. Oats 200 lbs. Oats ; 250 lbs. Bran 150 lbs. Bran 300 lbs. Hominy 50 lbs. Cottonseed meal 200 lbs. Linseed oil meal... 50 lbs. Salt 10 lbs. Gluten feed 100 lbs. Lime 5 lbs. Beet pulp 100 lbs. Bone meal ■ 5 lbs. Cottonseed meal 50 lbs. Salt 10 lbs. Lime 10 lbs. Bone meal '. 5 lbs. The average daily food consumption per cow was approx - imately 20 to 25 pounds of silage, 15 to 20 pounds of grain, and 20 pounds of alfalfa hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Table l.—A comparison of the cows which ±iiP]^jed_th^ jniUc_JestedJor_Vitamin A ■*" * ~~~ — — ■ - Times "■"••■ Experiment Cow ■ Ration milked Months Lactation Milk Average Number Number Breed Number daily Age fresh periods Bred produced fat '. Number Yrs.Mos. Number Number Date Lbs. P.cl. 201A Hoi 3 4 3-7 2 2 Not bred 59.1 H 299 Hoi 4 3-8 3 2 Not bred 50.7 X ksq Tpr 4 2 3-2 8 1 2-0-27 15.9 5.2 5 593 Jer. 4 2 2-4 3 . 1 "- 2 - 2 ° 10 -° . ~ 201A Hoi 3^ ~T "~4-0 7 2 12-25-28 48.1 290 Hoi" 3 4 lo 4 2 12-26-28 58.1 3.5 O tt 298 Hoi 4 3 4-4 12 2 Not bred 20.1 | Milk 207A Hoi: 4 3_ 3-9.7 3 Not bred 19.5 | Ja^9 -gT- je, - 3 • 4 " 5-5 , 8 , ~ 3 M4* 2,6 § S' £: 4 3 « 3. 2 12-13-28 21.2 O 595 Jer. 4 3 2-4 4 J_ __[_!__ 2^ H^L 3^ I 4l 10 2 12-25-28 56.5 . | 01c a Hol 3 4 2-7 .3 1 Not bred 50.8 ■■jo fjiipr 4 3 2-5 6 1 11-^d-io 14.0 4. 1 \jl Guer! 4 3 2-7 7 1 11-20-28 20.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Table 1. — A comparison of the cows which supplied the milk tested for Vitamin A — {Continued) ~~ ' Times Experiment Cow Ration milked Months Lactation Milk Average Number Number Breed Number daily Age fresh periods Bred produced fat Number Yrs.-Mos. Number Number Date Lbs. P.cl. 5 201A Hoi. 3 4 3-10 II 3 8-24-29 69.0 £ IV 210A Hoi. 3 4 3-3 .6 2 9- 6-29 50.0 w Milk 219A Hoi. 4 3 3-0 ' 10 1 4-21-29 22.0 3.45 £ stored 207A Hoi. 4 3 4-7 5 3 Not bred 34.4 . *" Nov., 1929 -■■ fcrj 139* Guer. 3 4 4-6 H : ' Not bred 41.6 X 142 Guer. 3 4 . 3-2 3 2 Not bred 29.1 ? 144 Guer. 4 ■ 3 2-11 8 . 1 7-8-29 20.0 4.8 r/ , 146 Guer. 4 3 2-10 4 1 10-22-29 17.6 H 218A HoL 3 4 2-11 8 1 3-4-29 43.8 219A Hoi. .3 4 2-10 7 14- 2-29 37.8 W V ' 228A Hoi. 3 4 2-6 3 1 6-20-29 37.7 3.1 £ Milk 226A Hoi. 3 4 2-7 3 1 Not bred 41.4 W stored — ■ — — .g Aug., 1929 39 Ayr. 4 3 3-8 5 ■ 2 5-18-29 21.4 o 40 Ayr. 4 '3 i 3-6 1 2 Not bred 40.4 X 48 Ayr. .4 3 3-0 8 1 3-12-29 20.8 4.3 . M 55 Ayr. i 1 3 3-5 6 1 6- 5-29 23.4 2 262 Hoi. 3 4 • 9-9 3 7. Not bred 90.9 r . 228A Hoi. 4 3 3-0 10 1 6-20-29 24.6 S VI 226A Hoi. 4 :i 3-1 9 1 Not bred 23.4 3.55 5 Milk 207A Hoi. 4 3 4-10 7 3 Not bred 24.8 Z stored : v- ; : — — = en Feb., 1930 50 Ayr. . 3 4 3-3 2 1 Not bred 42.0 ** 53 Ayr. 4 :t 4-0 . 5 1 12-20-29 20.0 49 Ayr. 4 3 3-10 5 1 ■ 12-13-29 21.1 4.05 _. 40 Ayr. 4 3 : 4-0 7 2 11- 7-29 23.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Vitamin A Content op Milk An aliquot portion of the milk produced at each milking during a 24-hour period was taken. This milk was bottled in one-half-pint bottles and stored at 0° C. until used. Storage of butter below 10° C. does not lower its vitamin A content according to Drummond, Coward, and Watson (1). Holmes (4) reported no decrease in the vitamin A content of cod liver oil which had been stored from six months to one year at a low temperature and out of contact with the air. Jones, Murphy, and Moeller (6) showed that no serious de - terioration had taken place in the vitamin A content of eggs which had been held in storage for nine years in a frozen condition. The results of the various experiments are summarized in Table 2 and are statistically examined in Table 3. From the data presented in these tables it is apparent that as in most biological experiments, there are slight irregularities in the results. Such differences generally occur, since, despite the utmost efforts at standardization of experimental technique, there are always the individual reactions of experimental ani - mals. In these experiments, as has been noted in detail pre - viously, care was taken to keep the comparisons free from such extraneous factors as heredity, disease, prenatal feeding, environment, and like conditions of milk production. It should be noted in this connection that in the two trials in which Holstein milk was compared with Jersey milk the latter milk furnished an average of 2.5 per cent more fat than the former. In the two trials in which Holstein milk was com - pared with Guernsey milk, the Guernsey milk afforded an average of 1.27 per cent more fat than the Holstein milk. In a like manner the Ayrshire milk supplied an average of .85 per cent more fat than the Holstein milk. Since fat is chiefly utilized for the production of energy it might seem that the groups of rats receiving Jersey, Guernsey, and Ayrshire milk would have an advantage over the groups receiving Holstein milk. " If it is true, as has been stated by some students of nutrition, that rats eat in accordance with their energy re - quirements, these differences in energy value were probably without effect since the basal ration was fed ad libitum. Furthermore, it is well known among dairymen that the fat globules in the milk of Holstein and Ayrshire cows are on an average smaller than the globules in Jersey and Guernsey milk. Since the smaller size of fat globules means a greater dispersion of the fat, it has been maintained that milk having small fat globules is more digestible than milk having large fat globules. It would seem, therefore, that these differences in energy values on the one hand were counterbalanced by greater digestibility on the other hand. It is believed, there- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">TA^J'~?T m ul ? f - the . aver W e 9aiw in weight of rats fed various daily quantities of milk produced by Holstem, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey coios as the source of Vitamin A Experiment 1-Milk.toredAugu.t 7, 1928 "Experiment II-Milk stored January 7 1929 "^ % Pos.contro. 95.16 Neg. contro! Di e d V _J^eLrol__ Sl6 Ne K . control « Total 97 rat., 6 po, it ive and 5 negative control,. T^T^a^T^^ VL , and 3 negative contr^T * E *P"in.entIH-Milk,tored April 23, 1929 stored November 6. 1929 • = OJ Hoffeinmilk Averagegain^O^mi.k Averagegam H^| --Jfc Average gain • Quernseymilk Average gai" &gt; 1 '30-38(21)); '*|'" ''T C iK»5 c. c. dram. £? . Total 100 rats, 8 positive and 8 negative controls Tobil mi ™t« in „ '.u- T7^ 7- — ' — " ° - -____ lom I»4 rats, in positive and 12. negative controls fjj Experiment V— Milk stored August 2, 1929 f,.™ t m - t vr mi -. r,T : -~== ■ — . , __ ■■ Experiment VI— Milk stored February 10, 1930 l_j H^ejn^k Aven^egain A^jrerrHJk "' Averse g^n ' ™p milk Averagegain Ay^r, rniH, .Averagega^" &lt;= D 3 , ".13 :l .•: «-M 2 ■ 58.09(11)) 2 - P °^ Ontr0 ' Neg.contro, l)i,d__ , Pos. nintro! tlgjg Neg. c^ntro, S° - „, .,. T&lt;&gt;ta ' , 103 ","• " POaiUve ".llJgtl^qgtnj^ Total 95 'rats, 10 positive and 17 ne ga tive control. " '" *" </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Vitamin A Content of Milk fore, that the vitamin A content of the milk was the primary factor which affected the gains in weight of the rats. Holstein milk was compared with Jersey milk in Experi - ments I and II (Table 2) . In the first trial the average gains of the groups fed one, two, and three cubic centimeters of the Jersey milk were 6.40^3.75, 9.35±4.91, and 10.07±5 88 grams greater, respectively, than the gains of the correspond - ing groups receiving the Holstein milk. When the differences are divided by their probable errors, values of 1.70, 1.90, and 1.71, or approximate odds of 2.98-1, 4.00-1, and 2.98-1 were obtained respectively for the different groups. Since only differences of 3.2 times the probable error or odds of 30-1 are considered significant, it is evident that no difference in the vitamin A content was established. Milk from these two breeds was compared a second time in Experiment II. The three groups fed Jersey milk gained respectively 10.98±4 25 6.50±3.32, and 1.82±4.29 grams more than the corresponding groups fed Holstein milk. Their differences divided by their p !-°« o« Ie errors equal respectively 2.58, 1.95, and .42, or odds oi 9.89-1, 4.00-1, and less than 1-1. It is apparent that the differences are not statistically significant and that the con - clusions drawn from Experiment I are confirmed. In other words, the results of feeding 168 rats showed no significant difference between the milk from the Jersey and from the Holstein breeds as a source of vitamin A. Holstein and Guernsey milk were compared in Experiments III and IV. In the first trial the average gains of the group red one cubic centimeter of Guernsey' milk were 3 99±3 05 grams greater than the gains of the group fed one cubic centi - meter of Holstein milk. On the other hand the groups fed two and three cubic centimeters of Holstein milk gained re - spectively an average of 2.76±3.24 and 7.00±3.15 grams more than the groups fed corresponding quantities of Guernsey milk. These differences of the three groups divided by their probable errors were respectively 1.30, .85, and 2.22. In the second trial, Experiment IV, the Guernsey groups gained re - spectively 2.02±3.39, .43±4.77, and 5.92±5.54 more than the corresponding Holstein groups. The differences divided by their probable errors were .59, .09, and 1.06. The conclusion may therefore be drawn that there was no difference in the vitamin A content of the milk of the Guernseys as compared with the milk of the Holsteins. Holstein milk was compared with Ayrshire milk in Experi - ments V and VI. In these experiments the gains produced by the milk of these two breeds were so nearly equal as to leave little doubt of the equality of these milks as a source of vitamin A. In the first trial the difference in gains of the one and two cubic centimeter groups was .86±3.58 and </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Table 3. — Average gains in weight of rats produced by the milk of Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey cows as the source of Vitamin A — statistical examination of results ' Difference Experiment Quantity Number of rats Mean gain per animal and P. E. Difference of means and P. E. ■■ Approximate 2 Number milk fed in each group of the mean in grama of difference in grama P. K. of D. odds ** c. c. Hoistoin Jersey Holstein Jersey M 1 15 15 53.00*2.65 59.40 * 2.GB 6.40*3.75 1.70 2.98 — 1 &gt; I -2 11 14 f&gt;G.50*3.41 75.85*3.5:1 9.35*. 1.91 . 1.90 4.00 — 1 W 3 14 It f&gt;8.07*3.10 78.14*5.00 • 10.07*5.88 1 1.71 2.98—1 £ Holstein Jersey Holstein Jersey 1 8 10 30.12*11.20 41.10*2.79 10.98*4.25 2.58 9.89—1 hrt II 2 | 10 10 41.30*2.70 47.80*1.91 6.50*3.32 1.95 4.00—1 L J 3 11 11 59.45*2.90 fil.27*3.1fi 1.82*4.29 .42 Less than 1 — 1 Holslein Guernsey Holstein Guernsey 1 13 8. 30.38*2.03 34.37*2.27 3,99*3.05 1.30 1.63—1 W III 2 11 10 42.16*2.70 .19.10*1.79 2.76*3.24 .85 Less than 1 — 1 £3 .3 II 14 58.28*2.51 51.28*1.86 . . 7.00*3.15 2.22 6.26—1 &gt; Holstein Guernsey Holstein Guernsey ' ' . hrj 1 18 12 45.23*1.6.1 . 47.25 *2".O7 2.02*3.39 .59 Less than 1 — 1 L7 IV 2. It 14 71.85*3.35 72.28*3.10 . .43*4.77 .09 . Less than 1 — 1 rn '3 13 .14 77.92*3,71. 83.84*4.11 .1.92*5.54 1.06 1.00 — 1 H Holstein Ayrshire Holstein Ayrshire ' W 1 15 15 55.80*1.65 56.66 * 3.18 ■ .86*3.58 .24 I*ss than 1 — 1 O V 2 15 15 (18.40*2.72 69.40*3.05 1.00*4.0(1 .24 Less than I — 1 (E 3 j 15 15 77.13*3.06 73.80*2.65 3.13*4.01 .82 Less than 1 — 1 Hobtein Ayrshire Hobtein Ayrshire " 2? 1 12' 12 45.66*2.09 41.25*2.75 .4.41*3.45 ■ 1.27 1-19—1 Pi VI . 2 12 11 GI.OH t 2.39 58.09*2.18 4.99*3.41 . 1.45 1.90—1 £-. 3 10 10 69.50*4.13 7fi.80*4.86 7.30jt 6.M I . 1.14 1.18—1 p) 'The following formulae were u&lt;ed in thew ralrulatiiins: ' m (1) M = 2^ n • . (3) P. E. of the mean =.C745 S.I). ' M = arithmetical averutu'. \ sum "f the vuriuli^. n tutal vuriuu-s. , — " (2) S.D. = \l S(Fd-l P. E. -- probable error. ■ J , n . d=devialnn iif.aelas.Hfri.nl the im-an. ' • (1) p. E. of a difference = v' a' + b' ' S.D. deviation, n numlK-r "I individuals. a«=P. E. of .first mean. F --frequency. I, ]\ p;| ,,f second mean. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Vitamin A Content of Milk 1.00±4.09 grams in favor of the groups fed Ayrshire milk, while in the three cubic centimeter group there was a differ - ence of 3.33±4.04 in favor of the group fed Holstein milk. These differences divided by their probable errors were .24, .24, and .82, respectively. In the second trial, Experiment VI, the group fed one and two cubic centimeters of Holstein milk made an average of 4.41±3.45 and 4.99±3.44 grams more gain than the groups fed the same quantity of Ayrshire milk. In the three cubic centimeter groups there was a dif - ference of 7.30±6.38 grams in favor of the group fed Ayrshire milk. These differences divided by their probable errors were respectively for the three groups 1.27, 1.45, and 1.14. From these results it is apparent that the Holstein and Ayrshire milk were equal as a source of vitamin A. From the data presented herein it seems evident that under the conditions of these experiments, the difference in the vitamin A content of milk from the Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey breeds is insignificant. ACKNOWLEDGMENT The writers aire indebted to Mr. J. O. Culbertson of the Department of Agronomy forhis kind assistance in the statistical examination of the results. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 54 literature cited 1. Drammond I, J. C Coward, K. H., and Watson, A. F. 1921. LXVII Researches on Vitamin A. VII— Notes on thf Factors Influencing the Value of Milk and Butter a! Sources of Vitamin A. Biochem. Jour., 15:540-552 2. Eddy, W. H. ' . 1927- 44^20-32? MlLK P0WDER As AN Antirachitic. Arch! Ped., 3. Greenman, M. J., and Duhring, F. L. 1923&gt; S^ HN p.,h N h C th E w T . HE LBIN0 Rat for Research P, It  - 1-109 Institute of Anat. and Biol., pp. 4. Holmes, A. D. - 1924. Studies of the Vitamin Potency of Cod Liver Oil VI- The Effect of Storage of Livers on the Vitamin 4 16?295?297°. P C ° D U ™ ° IU J ° Ur - Indus ' and Enjrin Ghent 5. 1925. Vitamin Potency of Cod Liver Oils. XI— Buttfr Fats Produced on Summer Feed. Jour. Indus, and En^n! Chem! G. Jones, D. B., Murphy, J. C, and Moeller, O 1J25. The Effect of Long-continued Storage at Low Tfmi&gt;fjia- Physiof 71 H :l05S UN A C0NTENT ° F kGGS - Am " : J° - 7. McCollum, E. V., and Simmnnds, N. 1918. A Study of the Dietary Essential Water-soi.lbi.e B in kelation to its Solubility and Stability Towards're - agents. Jour. Biol. Chem., 33:55-89. 8. Pharmacopoeia of the United States of America, Tenth Decennial Kevisions. 9. Steenbock, H., and Coward, K. H. 1927. Fat-Soluble Vitamins. XXVII— The QUANTirATiVE DE - TERMINATION of Vitamin A. Jour. Biol. Chem., 72:765-779 10. Supplee, G. C, and Dow, O. D. 1927. Antirachitic Properties of Irradiated Dry Milk \mer Jour. Diseases Children, 34:3G4-71 " AmeT ' 11. Sure, B. 1923. Dietary Requirements for Reproduction. I Thf \utri tive Value of Milk Proteins from the Standpoint of Reproduction. Jour. Biol. Chem., 58:681-709 • NII0INT0F 12. Wieland, E. 192T " m^w^" l NDI ? ECT Phototherapy of Rickets. Schweiz Med. Wchnschr., Basel, 57:169-192. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>