<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Use of Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle</title>
               <date value="1930-03">1930-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 239 March, 1930 The Use of Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle w. p. snyder Bulletin 28 of the North Platte Experiment Substation W. P. Snyder. Superintendent THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE "EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY Ten short yearling heifers were fed shelled corn and alfalfa hay for 140 days after they were on a full feed of corn. Nine similar heifers were given the run of a field of alfalfa from the time they were on a full feed of corn, June 11, until alfalfa pasture was no longer available, October 9, a period of 120 days. They were fed corn and alfalfa hay for the remaining 20 days. . . The heifers on corn and pasture gained faster than those on corn and hay until about September 3, at which date their average gain' per head had been 38 pounds above that of the other lot. Between this date and October 9, they lost 15 pounds of this margin. At the end of the 140 days, when finished for market, the weights showed that tho .pasture-fed heifers had gained 20 pounds per head more than those on hay. The two groups were in about the same condition of finish when marketed. The pasture reduced the amount of corn inquired to produce 100 pounds of gain 55 pounds, and lowered the cost of 100. pounds of gain $1.08, after $2.50 per head was allowed for pasture. While on pasture 4 months, the heifers ate the equivalent of ap - proximately 1,000 pounds of alfalfa, dry weight, per head. This would indicate that an acre of fair alfalfa would furnish pasture for 6 cattle on a full feed of corn. Considering both the preliminary and the experimental periods, the heifers fed on alfalfa pasture and corn returned a profit of $4.09 per head (see Table 5) more than those fed alfalfa hay and corn with $2.50 per head allowed for the pasture eaten. Adding the above amounts we find that the heifers paid $6.59 per head for grazing on alfalfa pasture 120 days while on a full feed of shelled corn. These figures are given not^s conclusive, but only as the result of one summer's work. They should not be given the same weight as the results of several tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Use of Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle W. P. SNYDER* Some feeders are following the practice of pasturing alfalfa with cattle on a full feed of corn, seemingly with good results. This test is an attempt to get accurate records on this method in comparison with the common practice of feeding corn and alfalfa hay in a dry lot. FEEDING AND MANAGEMENT The plan was to feed two similar lots of cattle under like conditions except that one lot would have alfalfa pasture and the other alfalfa hay. Both lots were to have a full feed of shelled corn. Twenty short yearling heifers were selected for the test. They were the younger and lighter yearling heifers from a herd of high-grade Hereford cattle. Their winter ration had been largely prairie 'hay. They were in thin flesh. Their average weight when purchased was about 375 pounds. This had increased to nearly 400 pounds at the time the test proper was begun. In this report the lot on alfalfa pasture is called Lot 1, the other one, Lot 2. PRELIMINARY FEEDING The plan was to put all of the heifers on a full feed of corn as quickly as possible and to put half of them in the alfalfa pasture as soon as the heifers were taking all the corn they cared for. They were started May 23 on about 5 pounds per head daily of corn and cob meal. This had been doubled by the end of ten days. By June 11, or two and a half weeks after they were started on corn, it was deemed safe to turn into the alfalfa pasture. For details as to the rate of in - crease in grain fed, see Table 6. WEIGHING The plan was to use as the initial weight the average from three weighings taken under similar conditions on three con - secutive days, to take one weight at the end of each 28-day period, and to close the test with weighings on three con - secutive days. Individual weights were taken on each heifer. More weights rather than fewer were taken. Four initial weights were taken instead of three. Since this is pioneer work we are giving more details in this report than would otherwise seem advisable. It is quite probable that the man who is feeding cattle grazing on alfalfa will be interested in following the progress of the two groups * Credit is due to Mr. O. J. Grace for looking after the cattle during the experi - ment, and to Professor H. J. Gramlich for assistins in the preparation of the plans. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin, 239 very closely and in interpreting the results in the light of his own experiences. Possibly he will be able to account for seemingly unusual variations in weights and gains which we are unable to explain. Table 1. — Weights at various times thruout the test Lot 1. — Full feed of corn and alfalfa pasture, June 11 to October 29. Lot 2. — Full feed of corn and alfalfa hay, June 11 to October 20. i , Lotl T Lot 2 June 11 390.0 J 396.0 • July 9 462.2 462.0 August 6 556.6 538.5 September 3... 632.2 600.0 October 1 712.2 698.0 October 9 718.9 702.0 October 29 :..... 773.0 * 759.0 ' 1 Average of four weighings. : Average of three weighings. PASTURE The heifers were given a field of alfalfa that was an old stand. In a few spots, weeds had replaced the alfalfa. There were four acres in the field. Parts of this were mowed at times to give assurance that there would be succulent feed at all times. Because the early part of the season was quite dry, the growth of the alfalfa was slow, and it was not very succulent. A very heavy rain fell on August 27, followed by weather that favored a rapid growth of vegetation. The alfalfa grew very rapidly, and became unusually succulent. The experienced feeder would have changed to a less succulent ration, if circumstances had permitted. Cattle driven from the pasture at such a time and weighed individually would be Jikely to show a more or less uneven and rather heavy shrink. The original plan was to keep the heifers on pasture until a killing frost had occurred. The killing frost date came much later than usual ; in fact, it was difficult to determine at what date the growth of the alfalfa stopped. Because of this delay and due to the unusual succulence of the pasture, the heifers were removed to a dry lot October 9. From that date the roughage of both lots was alfalfa hay. A record was kept of the alfalfa cut in a similar, adjacent field which was not pastured. After crediting the heifers with the hay cut in their pasture, the record indicates that they should be charged with about a half ton of alfalfa hay per head. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle hafirSooo 6 ; 113^ f ° r - ha ™ si ? n S tWs alfalfa and valuing ***n ffl 10 - 00 P er ton "* the stack, each heifer is charged $2.50 for pasturage. This seems a low charge for alfalfa Kp^ WG Sh0Uld H k&lt; T int0 consideration the fact that these heifers were on a full feed of corn and therefore did not eat much roughage. If these figures are fairly represent ■ative, then an acre of alfalfa that cuts 3 tras of hay shoSd furnish pasture for 6 head of cattle on a full feed ofcom HEALTH OF CATTLE One heifer in Lot 1 on the alfalfa pasture became sick and hE rtf U l l ¥" - She had lo^ 65 Poundl^S 11 days Her weight at the beginning of the test and one-tenth of the SpH SS " ntll , th f date she went off feed have been elimin? S ft I There was no evidence to indicate . . RESULTS INCREASE IN WEIGHTS In considering the increase in weights taken from time to akin a f?hi i, r T ember that ° nIy ° ne - day wei * hts were taken, that the heifers were moved some distance from the pasture to the scales and that weights were takln on each heifer. Much variation may be expected under these con - ditions especially among the heifers on succulent feed How - ever, the individual weights given in Table 7 show a quite uniform increase in weight thruout the feeding period During the next 28-day period, from July 9 to August 6, the heifers on pasture gained over a half pound per head tLT T u Sn l h °lt V^ ry lot This difference might, in part, be due to the fact that one lot had more fill than the other at weighing time. The third 28-day period, August 6 to September 3, also shows a considerably faster gain on pasture— .51 pound per ™?h r -S e - F ? r th . ese three 28 " day Periods, the gains per head in favor of pasture were 6.2, 17.9, and 14.1 pounds. The total increase in weight for the average heifer on pasture over the heifer in the dry lot for these three periods, was o8. 2. pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin, 239 The next 28-day period, from September 3 to October 1, shows the hay lot gaining faster than the pasture lot. During these four weeks, the average heifer in the dry lot gained 18 pounds more than her mate on pasture. The daily gain per head on pasture was 2.86 pounds and in the dry lot 3.50 pounds. Probably again an uneven fill may account for a part of the difference. This period reduced the lead held by the pasture heifer to 20.2 pounds. The last 28-day period extended from October 1 to 29. As the heifers were removed from pasture and weighed on October 9, the period is divided into two sections, the first of 8 and the second of 20 days. For the 8-day period, the gains of both lots were unexplainably low. The heifers of Lot 1 gained .83 pound and those of Lot 2, only .50 pound per head per day. During the 20-day period, both lots were fed corn and alfalfa hay. The average -daily gain for those which had previously been on alfalfa was 2.71 pounds, and for those that had been in the dry lot from the beginning, 2.85 pounds. Considering the last 28-day period as a whole, the average daily gain per head was the same for both lots, 2.17 pounds. For the entire time the heifers of Lot 1 were in the alfalfa pasture, June 11 to October 9, 120 days, the rate of increase in weight per head daily was 2.74, and the total gain per head was 329 pounds. Corresponding figures for the average heifer in the dry lot are 2.55 and 306 pounds. This shows a gain of 22.9 pounds per head for the heifers on pasture above the gain made by the heifers on hay. For the entire time of the test, June 11 to October 29, 140 days, the heifers that grazed on alfalfa pasture for 120 days and were later fed alfalfa hay for 20 days gained, on the average, 383 pounds per head, or at the rate of 2.74 pounds per head [daily. The heifers that were fed alfalfa hay thru - out the entire test gained 363 pounds per head, at the rate of 2.59 pounds per head daily. The increase per heifer in Lot 1 over the heifer in Lot 2 was 20.1 pounds. Both groups were fed all the shelled corn they would eat thruout the entire experiment. </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin, 239 gain is $8.62. (See Table 4.) The amount of the pasture charge is based on the hay cut from the part of the field not pastured as explained on pages 4 and 5. Table 3. — Amount and costs of feed, alfalfa pasture not in - cluded Lot 1 | Lot 2 1 Corn per head (Pounds) 1,991 2,088 Corn per head (Bushels) 35.5 37.3 Alfalfa hay per head (Pounds). 134 779 Corn per head daily (Pounds) 14.22 14.91 Alfalfa per head daily ' (Pounds) 6.7 5.56 Corn per 100 pounds of gain (Pounds) 520 575 Alfalfa per 100 pounds of gain (Pounds).... 215 Cost of corn and alfalfa hay for 100 pounds of gain (Dollars) -. 7.97 9.70 1 For only the finishing period of .20 days. Table 4. — Amount and cost of feed, alfalfa pasture 1 included as 1000 pounds of hay dry weight, valued at $2.50 Lotl Lot 2 Corn per head (Pounds) 1,991 2,088 Corn per head (Bushels) 35.5 37.3 Alfalfa per head (Pounds) 134 779 Alfalfa pasture per head (dry wt.) (Lbs.).. 1*000 Total alfalfa hay per head (Pounds) 1,134 779 Corn per head daily (Pounds) 14.22 14.91 Alfalfa per head daily (Pounds) I 8.1' 5.56 Corn per 100 pounds of gain (Pounds) I 520 575 Alfalfa per 100 pounds of gain (Pounds). ...I 296 215 Cost of corn and alfalfa hay for 100 pounds of gain ' (Dollars) , 8.62 9.70 1 Estimated on tonnage cut on an adjacent field not pastured. ' Cost of alfalfa for Lot 1 — 1000 lbs. (&lt;i&gt; Vi &lt;• n pound and 134 lbs. ff? 'ir a pound. s This future includes an estimate of the equivalent of pasture eaten in dry hay. HOGS FOLLOWING On August 10, three spring shotes weighing 112 pounds each were put into the alfalfa pasture with the heifers of Lot 1. They were fed no grain. On October 9, they were taken to the dry lot with the heifers. During the 60 days while following the heifers in the pasture, the three shotes gained 190 pounds — a little over one pound daily per head. From </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle October 9 to 29, a period of 20 days, while the three shotes were in the dry lot with the heifers, they were fed 10 pounds of corn daily. They gained 60 pounds in weight at the rate of one pound each daily, during this period. The increase in weight during the entire time the shotes were with the heifers, 80 days, was 255 pounds. This increase at 9 cents per pound, less the cost of the 200 pounds of corn eaten at 84 cents per bushel leaves a profit of $19.95 on the shotes fol - lowing the 9 heifers in Lot 1. This gives a credit of $2.22 for each heifer. Also, on August 10, three spring shotes weighing an aver - age of 108 pounds were put with the heifers in Lot 2. They were not fed grain until September 14. From that time until October 29, they were given 10 pounds of corn daily. They ate 450 pounds of corn worth $6.75, with corn valued at 84 cents per bushel. They made a total gain of 315 pounds dur - ing the 80 days at the rate of 1.31 pounds per head daily. At 9 cents per pound, the value of the increased weight was $28.35. After paying for the 450 pounds of corn eaten by shotes, there is left a credit of $21.60 or $2.16 each for the 10 heifers. RENTAL PAID BY HEIFERS FOR PASTURE In the. discussion under "Financial Statement" (see Table 5), we find that after charging $2.50 per head for pasture, there was a profit of $4.09 more per head on the pasture heifers than on the hay-fed heifers. This plus the $2.50 already charged gives $6.59 per head more return from the heifers that grazed on alfalfa pasture than from those fed hay. SALE AND SHRINK The final weights were taken October 28, 29, and 30. The heifers were then shipped to Omaha, exhibited at the Ak-Sar- Ben Stock Show, and sold November 6. Both lots sold at $15.25. The shrinkage was 44 pounds per head in Lot 1 and 43 pounds in Lot 2. The percentage of shrink was 5.6 and 5.5. The dressed percentage, shrunk 2 per cent from hot weights, was 60.1. Twelve carcasses graded prime and seven choice. These are the two highest grades of the Cudahy Pack - ing Company, the purchasers of the cattle. The selling weight per head, 722 pounds, was a desirable weight at the time they were marketed. The handy weight, thoro shrink, and the finish all tended toward a top price. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin, 239 FINANCIAL STATEMENT The profit on the entire transaction is of some interest aside from the experimental problem. Two. of the chief factors in profit and loss are the purchasing and the selling prices. In this case, the conditions of both the purchasing and the sell - ing were unusual and probably did not represent the actual market worth. The decision to conduct this experiment was not made until almost time to begin the feeding. It was necessary to select and purchase the heifers without delay. They were selected from a herd of a few hundred yearling heifers that the owner had not intended to sell. This required paying a rather high price. We shall let $14.00 per 100 pounds be the purchase price. That was about the market value of similar heifers in our feed lot at that date. The average weight was 375 pounds. The selling price, $15.25, was high, but the shrinkage, 43 pounds per head, or 5.5 per cent, was heavy. Probably the one balanced the other. Accepting these figures we find that the average heifer cost $52.50. The interest on $52.50 at 8 per cent for 6 months is $2.10. The cost of feed was $34.18 per head, including a pasture charge of $2.50 each on 9 head. This gives a net profit per head on the corn-alfalfa pasture lot of $14.43 and on the corn-alfalfa hay lot of $10.34. The difference is $4.09 per head in favor of alfalfa pasture. Table 5. — Detailed financial statement Lot 1 Lot 2 Cost of heifer $ 52.50 $ 52.50 Interest 2.10 2.10 Cost of feed preliminary period, May 23 to June 11 2.73 2.73 Cost of feed, June 11 to October 29 33.03 35.21 Selling price, net 102.57 100.72 Credit from hogs 2.22 2.16 Profit per head ~ 14.43 10.34 </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>