<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Vegetative Composition and Grazing Capacity of a Typical Area of Nebraska Sandhill Range Land</title>
               <date value="18??">March 1940</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 117 Vegetative Composition and Grazing Capacity of a Typical Area of Nebraska Sandhill Range Land A. L. Frolik and W. O. Shepherd Department o£ Agronomy LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MARCH, 1940 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Pa&lt;;k Introduction 3 Rt-vicw dt Ijicraturc 3 I-lim.itc 4 S..il» 5 MrlliiiK (&gt; Mapping 0 'Y\']k analysis fi Classification irf vegetative typo 8 ('ira/iny capacity compulations 9 (iencral Vegetative O&gt;ndititins 9 Relative lm|xirtancc at Major Vegetative Tv|k:s '. . 10 \'cj.'cuiion (jjm|x»ition and DcMTtption ot the Major Types Id Dune-sand (1)) type II Dry-valli) (Mi) ty|x- H 1 Iry-mcatltiw (M 2) tyiw Mi Wet-meadow (Ml) t\(K'i 18 .Sallcrau (MIDy type 19 /•¦|irj(!f Productivity of the Major Tvjk's 2(1 Wet-intadow (Ml; tvpc- 2} Dry-mcailmv (M 2) type 2i Salt^rass (MID) type 24 Dry-vallo (Mil type 26 l)iini-&gt;and (/)) type 27 ("jrrvin^l (Capacity of the Major Types 20 Importance ot the Maior Sandhill K(tra&gt;ic S[)ccie.s 2V V.rz^n 29 Forbs 32 Shrubs . 32 Poisonous plants 33 Summary 33 Apjx-ndix 1 36 ¦\pix-ndix II 38 Literature t-itt-cl 39 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Vegetative Composition and Grazing Capacity of a Typical Area of Nebraska Sandhill Range Land A. L. FROLIK and W. O. SHEPHERD • The sandhill area of Nebraska occupies approximately 20,000 square miles of the central portion of the state (I), 2 Being unadapted to culti - vation, the land is for the most part still covered with native vegetation. It is utilized primarily for the production o£ livestock, chiefly cattle. During the period 1931 to 1938 the sandhills carried annually an average of 1,041,000 cattle, which amounted to 31 per cent of the total number'in. the state. 3 According to a report prepared on the western range (16), the, management practices used in the Nebraska sandhills have gained national recognition as a good example of range conservation in the United States. The purpose of this study was to investigate the floristic composition and the economic importance of the vegetation, as reflected by livestock carrying capacity, of the major types of grazing lands in the sandhill area of Nebraska. Accordingly, a survey of a typical area; was conducted in 1937.'* The area selected, comprising approximately 114,000 acres in one block, was in Cherry county (Fig. 1). It included the Valentine Migratory / County &#132; . ¦ V; \ SANDHILL 110101 "^^ ; \) ¦ :. &#132; S-K-^......,.; C&lt; "¦ ¦¦¦¦ v :-: ;:: . V'¦ ¦;::;.: .§.\f... :&gt;.&gt;,^:; ; .\ Flo. I.—-Geographic location (crosshatched). of the sandhill range area surveyed in the study. (Generalized from a soil map made by the Division of Conservation and Survey, University of Nebraska.) . :• Waterfowl Refuge, which is about 25 miles south of Valentine. At the time of the survey the refuge had just been started and the range land in - cluded within its boundaries had been grazed prior to this time by ranch - ers as privately owned range. ' --.'¦ .... . .¦¦'/¦''.' REVffiW OF LITERATURE . One of the earliest authentic accounts of the condition of the flora of the Nebraska sandhills is given by Webber (20). His report of a several-day 1 Auocute Professor md Graduate Assistant in the Ucpartmcnt of Agronumv. retpcctivcly. 3 Complete ciutions may be found on p. 39. . -¦ . v ¦ '. . '. 'Data from the State and Federal Statistician, State Capitol, Lincoln. ~ " . ¦.'¦¦. • Tlie survey was conducted by the Nebraska Agricultural Eiperimen! Station in cooperation with the Division of Conservation and Survey of the University of Nebraska and the Cooperative Range Survey of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. . . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 collecting trip in Thomas county in 1889 is interesting from an historical ; point of view. Rydberg (10) in 1895 made a study of a tract just south of the area concerned in the present investigation. His work was primarily taxonomic. A few of his general statements concerning relative abundance of the major species are not entirely in accord with those of other early reports. An ecological analysis of the vegetation of the sandhills, probably the earliest, was made by Pound and Clements (8) in 1900. They describe and explain the composition of vegetative "types" and "formations." In a report on the sandhill region of Sheridan and Cherry counties, Smith and Pound (13) in 1892 described the flora of the dunes, the wet valleys, and the dry valleys and mentioned the topographic and drainage conditions. In another paper restricted to grasses, Smith (12) discussed the value of each of the common species. A more recent and comprehensive study of the Nebraska sandhills was reported by Pool (7) in 1914. His report, which includes an exhaustive bibliography, gives a full account as well as an ecological interpretation of the flora. A description of the vege - tation of similar sandhills in northeastern Colorado has been recendy pub - lished by Ramaley (9). The flora of the Colorado sandhills is generally of a more xeric nature than that of Nebraska. Keim, Frolik, and Beadle (4), in a study of the prairie hay region of north central Nebraska, determined the botanical structure of several types of native vegetation by forage yield. With this exception no data have been published concerning the relative importance of the major forage species or vegetative types in the sandhill region. CLIMATE Climatic conditions in general are more favorable for cattle production in the sandhill region than in most of the other western cattle-producing regions (2). Seasonal distribution of rainfall is favorable for the vegeta - tion and the growing season is comparatively long. Over three-fourths of the annual precipitation falls between April 1 and September 30 (Table 1). The mean annual precipitation is nearly 19 inches. Table I.— Average monthly and annual precipitation and mean tempera - ture for the period 1889-1916 at Valentine, Nebraska- 1 Mean Mean Month Precipitation temperature Month Precipitation temperature In. °F. In. °F. lanuarv 0.54 21.3 July 2.79 73.8 February 0.54 23.3 August 2.37 71.5 March 1.25 33.4 September 1.26 62.1 April 2.18 46.3 October 1.14 49.2 May . 2.73 56.5 November 0.61 35.3 |unc . 2.97 67.1 December 0.57 25.0 Annual 18,95 47.1 1 Taken from U-S.D.A. Weather Bureau records. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">• ¦! Nebraska Sandhill Range . The mean annual temperature of the region is about 47 °F. Although the extremes in temperature have been from —40° to 108°, periods of ex - treme temperatures are usually of short duration. The average range of the mean monthly temperatures is about 50 degrees. The last killing frost in the spring usually occurs during the first or second week in May. The first frost in.autumn is expected during the first two weeks of October. The frost-free period varies from 130 to 160 days. :"'. Protection from strong winds afforded by the dune topography aids the catde in withstanding temperature extremes. The average wind velocity is about 10 miles per hour. Table 2. — Annual precipitation for the. period 1930-37 at Valentine, Nebraska. 1 Year Precipitation Year . Precipitation . ¦'¦ ¦'.'. : '•¦ !"• "• ' In. .-¦ 1930;.. ;. 22.43 1934. /.......;..:....,.... 11.52 1931 .'." ...:.... : 14.64 .1935...................... 16.80 1932..;:.:.... 16.05 . 1936.. 12.50 1933......,...:........... 17.74 1937,.......,......:...... . 11.13 Average,. 1930-37,...........;-.,..-.'.-.". .'..,..... ":.. .V........:. 15.35 .'. - -1 Taken from U.S.D.A. Weather Bureau records. ' " From the recent precipitation trend as shown by the annual records of the years 1930-37 (Table 2), it will be noted that the year during which the survey was conducted, 1937, was the driest of a series of drouthy years. The cumulative effect of the drouth has no doubt brought about profound changes in the vegetation. ¦ '"SOILS'''..;:. The soils of this area are typically sandy and loose and are particularly susceptible to wind erosion (6). Because of their absorptive nature very little runoff occurs and surface drainage is undeveloped. The two main soil series, which are associated with the dune sand, are Valentine and Gannett, The material of the dunes is grayish-brown, incoherent sand of medium or fine grades, the medium sand predominating. Con - sidering its sandy nature, this dune, sand is unusually retentive of moisture. The.Valentine series is represented by two types, Valentine sand and Valentine loamy sand. Valentine sand differs from dune sand only in having a less hilly relief and a trifle more organic matter in: its surface layer. It occurs chiefly in the dry valleys and in the pockets between the dunes. The Valentine loamy sand is heavier in texture and contains more organic matter than does the dune sand. , Gannett loamy sand has developed in poorly drained depressions and valleys of the sandhills. Some of, the most typical areas occur as narrow strips bordering the numerous lakes. Even in dry seasons the ground water is within six feet of the surface and during prolonged periods of rainy weather it may rise to the surface of this soil type. In general there </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 is a close relationship between these soil types (and dune sand) and the vegetative types as classified in this survey. This is to be expected since both are governed largely by such factors as topography, texture, and mois - ture content. METHODS The methods commonly employed in range survey work were adopted with some refinements for this study. The examiners 5 conducting this sur - vey were trained by an expert range examiner 0 for two weeks before the work was initiated. The detailed procedure used will be discussed in four sections: mapping, type analysis, classification of vegetative types, and graz - ing capacity computations. Mapping All mapping was done with plane tables equipped with peep-sight alidades. A scale of six inches to the mile was used, which permitted con - siderable detail. At least two corners were located in each section for reference points. Grazing types were mapped to a minimum unit of ten acres. In the highly productive hay-meadow type, areas as small as two acres were noted. Because of the importance of marsh areas to game man - agement, no minimum was set for them. Marsh types smaller than one - tenth acre were often mapped. Groves, individual trees, and clumps of shrubs were indicated on the maps. A complete map, too large to include in this bulletin, has been prepared by the Division of Conservation and Survey, University of Nebraska. Type Analysis Two methods of vegetative analysis are in general use among range examiners. These are usually referred to as the ocular reconnaissance method and the square-foot density or point-observation-plot method (5,14). In using the ocular reconnaissance method, an experienced examiner passes through a representative portion of a type, estimates the average density, and notes the species composition. By the square-foot density method, examination is restricted to a series of plots each 100 square feet in area and the density of each species is recorded in square feet of ground surface covered by the foliage. The density determined by the latter method is also an estimate but lends itself rather readily to checking by actual measurements. For this reason, results obtained by the square-foot method of determining density are generally considered more accurate and standardized than those of the ocular reconnaissance method. Both methods, however, have distinct advantages (15). The method of vegetative analysis used in this survey did not conform exactly to either of the two methods described but was a modified combina - -0 The Bcltl party conducting the survey consisted of W. O. Shepherd, Chief, John Bcngrson, Leßoj, Hansen, anil Ward Henderson. • A. L. Rocmcr of the U. S. Forest Service. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Nebraska Sandhill Range . \ tion of the two. In place of mentally carrying a moving average of plant density and composition when walking through a type as is done in the case of ocular reconnaissance, the examiners restricted their detailed exam - inations to large plots (about 50 feet in diameter) and then averaged-the plot estimates for the type write-up. These plots were not marked out but served to focus attention on a limited area, thus increasing accuracy and ease of analysis. The plots were located at definite intervals. The number of plots taken within any given area was governed somewhat by the size of the type. The standards adopted were essentially those recommended for the smaller plots of the square-foot density method (4): three plots for 10 to 20 acres; five plots for 20 to 80 acres; and ten plots for 80 to 640 acres. The total density of a plot or a type was the percentage of ground surface estimated to be completely covered by the foliage when viewed direcdy from above. Spreading forbs or clumps of grass were visualized as being pressed together or raised at an angle so that all of the normal open - ings between the leaves were completely filled without unduly overlapping or crowding the foliage. Density was judged on the basis of normal plant de - velopment during the season. Accordingly, estimates made early in the sea - son took into consideration normal growth expected in late-growing species. Foliage density was considered to be a sound basis of vegetation an - alysis for the forage surveys. One advantage of this criterion is that den - sity of perennials is not. greatly affected by current climatic fluctuations. Changes in the composition of vegetation are likely to be the result of the cumulative effect of conditions of several previous years, instead of any one year. Range surveys to be of value must be applicable to more than the season during which they are made. Although the present inventory was taken during a season of exceptionally adverse moisture conditions, the results are probably similar to what would have been obtained at least during the several preceding or following years. The type composition was based on the relative proportion of the total density that was contributed by each of the species in the type. In analyz - ing the composition of a plot, the examiner first estimated the percentage of each of grasses, forbs, and shrubs. Then within these categories the species were evaluated as to their relative abundance according to density or ground cover. Unimportant species of grasses and forbs were lumped together as "others," provided each group made up less than three per cent of the total density. Festuca octoflora, 7 an annual grass, is omitted in the summary because it fluctuates gready from year to year. During 1937 it was unusually abundant. .•' According to the specifications of one of the cooperating agencies, write - ups were made for each type in every section. Briefly, a write-up consists of a type designation or classification, its location, its vegetative density, a list of the principal species together with their percentage composition ratings, productivity calculations, and comments concerning conditions 'All nomenclature is according to the usage of Hitchcock (3) for grasses, and Rydbcrg (11) for other specie,, with a few exceptions. ... </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 and situations affecting the use of the type. If the type was rather uniform, one write-up often served for several or at least parts of several sections. The write-up numbers were recorded in pencil on the original map; the location of the area analyzed was described in the write-ups. Hence the analysis of any portion of the area surveyed may be obtained by procuring the write-up number from the map or a description of the location of the type and referring to the original data. 8 Density estimates were checked by clipping and bunching the vegeta - tion of a small measured plot in an approximately normal position so as to form a measurable portion of 100 per cent density. Then the original density was easily calculated by dividing the area of the portion com - pletely covered by the total area of the plot. Uniformity among the exam - iners was maintained during the season by frequently estimating plots to - gether and checking the estimates by cutting and bunching the vegetation for actual measurement. Classification of Vegetative Types Inasmuch as a portion of the area had been carefully mapped pre - viously, 1' it was deemed advisable to continue with the classification used on these maps. The following are the type symbols and designations that appear on the final maps. J): Dune sand vegetation largely of a scmibunchgrass type. M3-. Dry valley or bunchgrass of dry meadows type. M1: Wet phase of tall-grass meadows. M2: Dry phase of tall-grass meadows or transition type between M3 and Ml. Mil): Saltgrass or alkali meadows. Marsh: .Von-forage, hytlric vegetation. Additional type designations were indicated on the write-up sheets in accordance with the standards of the Western Range Survey (5). Of the 18 standard range types adopted by the Western Range Survey, only two occur to any extent in the sandhills. These are the tall-grass and the meadow types. In the present survey many subtypes were determined by the relative abundance of the major species. The subtypes were designated by the standard symbols of three of the dominant species listed in order of decreasing importance. According to accepted standards, the symbols consist of three letters. The genus symbol consists of the first three letters of the genus name, all capitalized. For species symbols, the first capitalized letter of the generic name is followed by the first two lower-case letters of the specific name. For example, a write-up may be designated thus: IT.CIo-STI-Bhi, indicating that the vegetation being described belonged to the tall-grass type and to a subtype composed primarily of Calamovilfa longifolia, Stipa sp., and Bouteloua hirsuta. Where the determination of the species was unimportant or where the species could not be readily identified, the genus symbol was used; other - wise the species symbols were used. &gt; On file, llcpartmcnt o( Agronomy, University ot Nebraska College of Agriculture. * Mapped in l°lo l.y Conservation and Survey Uivtiiofl, University of Nebraska. </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Nebraska Sandhill Range Acreage data were obtained by the use of a planimeter on a copy of the original map. The scale of six inches to the mile used on this map permitted quite accurate measurements. The data are reported as weighted averages of the numerous write-ups summarized according to the broad types by which they were mapped. '•'."¦ Grazing Capacity Computations The index of forage productivity of any range type is usually referred to as the forage factor or forage acre factor, which is obtained by multi - plying the average density of the type by its average "utilization rating." The term "utilization rating" is here substituted for the term "palatability rating" often used in range surveys. The former refers to the relative amount of forage removed per unit of ground cover of a species when the latter is correctly utilized (Appendix I). The forage factor was obtained for each type as follows. The average composition rating (per cent) of each species was determined, and that rating multiplied by the accepted utilization rating for the species. The sum of all these individual species products is the weighted utilization rating of the type. This last figure multiplied by the average density gives the forage factor or utilizable forage of the type. The computation may be expressed as follows: Summa - tion (per cent composition x utilization rating) x density = forage factor. A forage acre is a theoretical unit used to express the amount of forage on a given area. It is derived by multiplying the number of surface acres by the forage factor explained above. The number of forage acres required to support a mature cow (or animal unit) for a definite period (month or year) is referred to as the forage acre requirement. Then, by dividing the number of forage acres by the forage acre requirement per animal unit, the. carrying capacity may be expressed in the standard units of animal months or years. The computation may be expressed as follows: Forage factor x surface acres '= forage acres _ Carrying capacity Forage acre requirement per animal month Z~ (animal months) The determination of the forage acre requirement; by means of which the forage acre data are converted to terms Of grazing capacity, is as im - portant as any phase of the range survey work and required a supplemen - tary study in connection with this surVey.' Seven pastures, for which use records were available, were located in the vicinity of the surveyed area. These pastures were surveyed by the usual methods and the forage acres of each computed. By dividing the calculated forage acres by the aver - age capacity (cow months), as determined from actual use records, an average forage acre requirement per month was determined (Appendix II). GENERAL VEGETATIVE CONDITIONS Because of the high absorptive capacity of the sandy soil, the area sup - ports a more luxuriant type of vegetation than would be expected on the heavier soils of the midwest region. The sandhill grassland is currendy </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 classified as tall-grass prairie, a postclimax of the true prairie association (19). In a broad sense the flora of the sandhills is strikingly uniform. This fact is noted by various investigators (7, 8, 10, 13). In 1914, Pool (7) described six upland grass associations and one hay - meadow association which applied to this territory. Pound and Clements (8) in their paper of 1900 are in general agreement with Pool's account. Drastic composition changes have evidently occurred since the time of these earlier studies, probably due to drouth and grazing. Only a general cor - relation exists between their analyses and the present one. There is some evidence to indicate that at an earlier date (10) the vegetative composition more closely resembled that of the present time. RELATIVE IMPORTANCE OF MAJOR VEGETATIVE TYPES The acreages of the five major types of grassland and the areas covered by marshes and lakes are shown in Table 3. Of the total acreage, 913 per cent is covered with grassland vegetation and 8.7 per cent with marshes and lakes. The dune sand vegetation is by far the most important type, Table 3.— Relative acreages of the major range types in the surveyed area of the sandhills of Cherry county. Per cent of Per cent of Type Acreage total acreage grassland acreage D—Dune sand. 72,"-K7 63.6 69.7 Mi—[&gt;r\ vallcv 16.61(1 H.5 15.8 M2—i)rv meadow ''.250 8.1 8.8 Ml—Wet meadow 3.227 2.8 3.1 MII&gt;-Saltgras S ... . 2,688 23 2.6 Total grassland KH.762 "1.3 100.0 Marvh 5,073 -U Lake 4.92-r -U ... Total acreage surveyed 1M.75 0 8.7 covering 63.6 per cent of the total area and 69.7 per cent of the total grass - land acreage. The other types, in order of decreasing importance as to area, are as follows: dry valley 14.5 per cent, dry meadow 8.1 per cent, wet meadow 2.8 per cent, and saltgrass 2.3 per cent. VEGETATIVE COMPOSITION AND DESCRIPTION OF THE MAJOR TYPES The vegetative types conform rather closely to the soil types of the area. The dune-sand type occurs on the dune sand. The two meadow types occupy the Gannett soil zones and the dry-valley vegetation appears on the soils classified in the Valentine series. Areas of salt accumulation are indi - cated by the saltgrass type. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Nebraska Sandhill Range Dune Sand (D) Type In this type were included all of the sandhill areas having a rolling or choppy topography. It is usually demarcated from the valley types by a rather abrupt change in slope and in composition of the vegetation. The characteristic aspect of the dune-sand type is due largely to Cala - movilfa longifolia, but it is somewhat modified by Sporobolus cryptan - drus. Although unobtrusive in appearance, Bouteloua hirsuta ranks second to Calamovilfa in percentage of ground covered. These three are the most important constitutents of the type and together make up nearly 70 per cent of the total grass density (Table 4). The average, density of this type is 15.9 per cent with respect to foliage cover. ¦-..•. Table 4.— Average percentage composition of the dune-sand (_) type : based on foliage density. Grasses and grasslike plants' '. Percent Percent Calamovilfa longifolia 21.2 . Stipa cornata ...... 0.6 Bouteloua hirsuta :. 18.1 Bouteloua 'gracilis. '.'. . 0 5 Sporobolus cryptandrus :-.,; 15.7 Carex spp. (dune) '[ 0A Muhlcnbergia pungen5........... 9.2 Juncus! 5pp.,............ .0.2 Andropogon scoparius. 5.5 Koclcria cristata. [, 0.2 Andropogon ha11ii.............. 3.4 Agropyron 5mithii............'. 0.1 Eragrostis trich0de5............. 2.0 Others.... ..... 0.2 Panicum 5pp.,................ 0.9 ' '_ Rcdficldia flexuosa. ....¦;¦¦.,.. 0.8. Total grasses, 79.0 Forbs .'.;¦. Helianthus spp. ......6.2; Solidago 5pp............ 02 Chcnopodium a1bum............ 2.7 ' Artemisia caudata.:'.... 0.2 Artemisia ghaphalodcs ...... 0.8 Pctalostemon 5pp......... 0.1 Eriogonumannuum.......... 0.7 . Rumex 5pp....... "¦' ol Euphorbia 5pp......,....:,.... 0.4 Others ..:.-..:....ZZ. l!l Psoralca spp., ... 0.4 Salsola pestifcr.:....... :.. 0.2' . Ambrosia 5pp...:.. .:... 02 Total forbs. 13.3 ;¦¦ Shrubs . Yuccaglauca. &#132;...,.,,..,. 3.5 Amorpha cancsccns,..... '.. 06 R05a5pp...................... 2.7 Rhus toxicodendron........ &#132; o'l Prunus bcsscyi 0.8 .' .".''- - '.. ...'¦• Total 5hrub5.......... -... 7.7 &gt; Teuuea aeiofiora, an annual, comprised 1.2 per cent of the total. -' The shrubs often occupy a conspicuous place in the general aspect of the dunes, even though contributing only 7.7 per cent of the density. Yucca gfxtuca is the most abundant shrub, closely followed by Rosa arkansana Yucca tends to be most abundant on the looser dune areas and is relatively </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 scarce on the more stabilized dunes. Its abundance is also related to the intensity and the season of grazing; the species usually increases in abund - ance with overgrazing. Forbs comprised 13.3 per cent of the vegetative density during 1937. Four of the five most abundant species were annuals, Helianthus petiolaris together with a small amount of H. rigidus (a perennial), Chenopodium album, Eriogonum annuum, and Euphorbia petaloidea. The most abund - ant perennial was Artemisia gnaphalodes, which ranked fourth among the forbs. Only 12 were considered of sufficient importance to be listed as separate species in the summary. The dune type as shown in Table 4 represents the averages of many write-ups, covering a wide variety of vegetative conditions. For this same type. Pool (7) lists three associations: the bunchgrass, the Muhlenbergia, and the blow-out associations. The corresponding classification of Pound and Clements (8) includes the bluestem type of the bunchgrass formation and the blow-out formation. Considerable change appears to have taken place with certain species. It is of interest to quote Pound and Clements (8) concerning the com - position of these "types" in 1900: "The bluestem formation ... is charac - terized . . . almost always by Andropogon scoparius, associated with Cala - movilfa longifolia and Stipa cornata. . . . Andropogon scoparius is the predominant member of the formation throughout the area. No less abund - ant, but less important in the formation, is Stipa cornata. . . . Calamovilfa longifolia ... is more common than Stipa in the eastern sandhills but in the sandhills of Sheridan county and Cherry county it is less often met with." Pool states, "The bunch-grass of widest distribution and of most fre - quent controlling influence is Andropogon scoparius." He adds further that of the widely distributed grasses which "seldom occur in sufficient abundance to lend a conspicuous color to the association, much less be - come dominant . . . the species that may become locally important . . . are Andropogon hallii, Calamovilfa longifolia, Stipa cornata." In no instance in the area surveyed in 1937 was Andropogon scoparius found to be the dominant species in a write-up nor did it ever comprise more than 16 per cent of the vegetative density. Its average composition of 5.5 per cent signifies the present status of A. scoparius in the general dune type. This indicates that this species has been very materially reduced in importance. Weaver and Albertson (18) state that "as a result of the great drought of 1934-37, the most important upland dominant, Andropogon scoparius, has suffered great destruction in the southern half of Nebraska." The present survey indicates that this species has also been severely reduced in the sandhill region. In a study published several years earlier (1895), Rydberg (10) agrees more closely with the present analysis when he lists Calamovilfa first among the most characteristic plants of the sandhills. In his list Andro- </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Nebraska Sandhill Range pogon scoparius was fifth, A. hallii sixth, Stipa spartea seventh, and S. cornata eighth. It should be pointed out, however, that Rydberg's study was confined largely to three counties, Grant, Hooker, and Thomas, which adjoin Cherry county on the'south, j It is significant that Boutelouai hirsuta and Sporobolus, which in the present study ranked second and third respectively in the composition of the dune type, are scarcely mentioned in earlier reports. Speaking of B. hirsuta, Pound and Clements (8) say that it "occurs in numerous but widely separated localities as an occasional inhabitant of this (bunch-grass) formation." They do not list B. hirsuta as occurring in any other asso - ciation. Pool (7), on the other hand, lists it as a principal species of his Muhlenbergia association, but only among the secondary species of the more important bunchgrass association. B. hirsuta, then, must have in - creased considerably in comparatively recent years. Sporobolus likewise has evidendy increased in prominence in the vege - tation of the dunes during the past two decades. Although it now con - tributes about 16 per cent to the total density of the dune type, Pool listed it among the secondary species. Pound and Clements assert that "S. crypt - andrus is occasionally met with in this (bunch-grass) formation in the heart of the sandhills." Smith (12) implies that it is not significant on the dunes but writes, "It is quite common in the rich meadows. . ." In severely overgrazed localized areas/the type here classed as dune-sand vegetation closely resembles Pool's Muhlenbergia association. In an analysis covering more than one hundred acres of formerly abused range, Muhlen - bergia was the dominant species, comprising 38 per cent of the foliage cover. Next in importance among the grasses were Calamovilfa, compris - ing 18 per cent, and Bouteloua hirsuta, furnishing 8 per cent of the foliage cover. Ten per cent of the density of this particular area was due to Yucca, which is commonly associated with Muhlenbergia. The condition of this area was however an exception. Of the 80 write-ups covering the dune type, in only one, in addition to the example already mentioned, was Muhlenbergia recorded as comprising over 15 per cent of the composition. In some portions of the dune type Muhlenbergia was not of sufficient abundance to justify a composition rating and.was merely indicated as being present in traces. As previously quoted, Pool attaches considerable importance to And - ropogon hallii as a species in his bunchgrass association. With A. scoparius he ranks it as one of the two dominants of this association although he points out that it is distincdy subordinate to the former in abundance. Pound and Clements say that A. hallii is one of the four most important species in the bluestem formation (dune), being especially abundant on the tops of the hills but that it is much less important than A. scoparius. Similarly, Rydberg (10), Smith and Pound (13), and Smith (12), rate A. hallii quite high among the sandhill grasses.: Its composition rating of only 3.4 per cent of the vegetation in this survey indicates that A. hallii must have decreased in abundance since the </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 earlier studies. The change has not been so conspicuous, however, as in the case of A. scoparius. The fact that A. hallii is very palatable to livestock has probably resulted in its decrease in abundance. Eragrostis trichodes was generally rated as somewhat less important in the sandhill flora than Andropogon hallii by former investigators. Although in relation to the latter its position may be unchanged, it probably was formerly more abundant. It was observed to be particularly abundant on slopes of northern exposure which have been protected from glazing and appears to be among those which are least tolerant of grazing. As reported by other investigators (7, 8, 10, 12, 13), Redfieldia flexuosa was common in and around blow-outs where sand was being shifted or deposited by the wind. These instances were of little consequence over the whole area, however, as indicated by an average composition rating of 0.8 per cent for this species. A striking deviation from the situation in the Nebraska dune-sand type occurs in the sandhills of northeastern Colorado where Ramaley (9) reports Oryzopsis hymenoides as being the dominant of the loose-sand and blow-out community. Oryzopsis was extremely rare in the area covered by the present survey. The dune-sand type is undoubtedly largely responsible for the stability of the sandhill livestock industry. Because of edaphic conditions and the root and growth habits of its major species, this type supplies forage dur - ing critical periods when the dry-valley type fails to produce much feed. During the summer of 1937, a severe drouth year, the amount of forage produced in the dry-valley type was very low while the dune-sand type yielded considerable forage. Moisture is available during drouth periods in the dune sand for a longer period than it is in the finer, more compact dry-valley or Valentine soils. 10 Dry Valley (M3) Type This type ranks second in size although it covers only about one-fourth as much acreage as does the dune-sand type. Considerable variation in vegetative composition was recorded for this type. Some relatively level but very sandy areas were included in this category although the vegeta - tion resembled that of the dunes. On the other hand, a few firm valley bottoms dominated by Bouteloua gracilis were also mapped as M3. Com - positional gradations between these two extremes were often so gradual or the number of subtypes so great that to have attempted to refine the type classifications for mapping would have been impracticable. Variations in composition were adequately taken care of by numerous composition analyses. In general, the dry-valley type is developed on the Valentine sand soil type and takes in the dry valley bottoms and slopes to the base of the dunes where there is usually a rather sharp break in gradient. The maximum ecological development on the "harder" soils of this type under protection from grazing would probably be a mixed prairie '.' Unputilitheil Jala by W. L. Toliteail. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Nebraska Sandhill Rance association similar to that described by Weaver and Clements (19) for the table lands of western Nebraska. Pool (7) classifies part of the vege - tation of these sites as belonging to the short-grass "formation" but un - doubtedly, as pointed out by Weaver and Clements for the short-grass region in general, it is a grazing disclimax of the mixed prairie association in the sandhills. On some of the Valentine soils of the valley slopes and on the less compact valley floors, the maximum development is dominated by Stipa cornata as discussed by Pool. Being an early growing grass, Stipa is grazed heavily in the spring before most of the associated species have produced much forage. Consequendy, Stipa has suffered severely from grazing and it is replaced on grazed lands in the heavier soils by short grasses and in the sandy soils by species less palatable or more tolerant of grazing. This species has been reduced to about one per cent of the aver - age composition, ranking twelfth among the perennial grasses (Table 5). Table s.— Average percentage composition of the dry-valley (M3) type based on foliage density. Grasses and grasslikc plants' 1 ... ¦",..'¦¦.¦ ' Percent Percent Sporobolus cryptandrus. .'. 13.8 .Stipa c0rnata...........;:.'.... 1.1 Bouteloua gracilis ......A 13.5 Spartina pectinata.. 0.9 Calamovilfa longifolia. 12.4 Poa 5pp....... 0.9- Panicum virgatum............. 12.4 Andropogon furcatu5........... 0.6 Bouteloua hirsuta. 8.0 Sorghastrum nutans 0.4 Andropogon scoparius.. ...12 Andropogon hallii....'. ..... 0.3 Juncus 5pp...... ..:...:... 2.7 Koelcria cri5tata............„. 0.1 Agropyronsmithii......: ... 2.7 0ther5...................... 0.5 Distichlis stricta... 2.0 Carex spp. (meadow) 1,6 .•'•.' . Eragrostis spp. ....'.....,,- 1.1 Total gra55e5,.............. 78.2 ../. .-Forbs '¦ Chcnopodium a1bum........... 5.9 Equisetum spp.... ;......, 0.2 Artemisia gnaphalodcs.......'. 4.5 Polygonum spp..: 0.2 Salsola pectifer.. .':'.... . 2.8 Leptilon canadense 0.1 Solidago 5pp.................. 2.0 Psoralea spp... 0.1 Helianthus 5pp...:............ 1,4 Aster spp. 0.1 Ambrosia psilostachya 0„ Others ............,,;.,,,,,,. 1,9 Artemisia caudata.... ...... .:. 0.3 . Eriogonum annuum... . 03 Total forbs. 20.4 ' ~~7 :—: """ T~-^, —-. : ¦¦ - "-Shrubs ..... Rosa spp.. .....' 0.8 Amorpha canescens... :.. 0.6 Total 5hrub5.............. 1.4 'Fenun oelofara, art annual, comprised'l2.7 .per cent of the total cover. It ii omitted and the calculation, are ,o adjusted. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 The average percentage density composition of the dry-valley type is dominated on a rather equal basis by four species: Sporobolus cryptandrus, Bouteloua gracilis, Calamovilfa longifolia, and Panicum virgatum (Table 5). Agropyron smithii is especially abundant on the land that has been cultivated or otherwise severely disturbed in the past and allowed to go back to native vegetation. It is interesting to note that Pool (7) does not mention Sporobolus as being in any of his associations which correspond to the dry-valley type, in which it is now the most abundant species. An outstanding characteristic of the dry-valley type in 1937 was the abundance of Festuca octoflora. In percentage of ground cover, Festuca ranked higher than any other species, comprising 12.7 per cent of the total cover. Pool commented on this same condition in his short-grass association. He states that ". . . many of the more open, somewhat sandy areas . . . are covered by dense communities of Festuca octoflora." This abundance of Festuca is not the usual thing, however, according to the residents of the region, but occurs intermittently. Because of its transient nature and its lack of grazing value, Festuca is omitted from the final tabulations of this type. Forbs occupy a rather conspicuous place in the dry valleys. The most abundant in 1937 was Chenopodium album, an annual. Artemisia gnapha - lodcs ranked second. This species is especially characteristic of valley slopes where it is often conspicuous as large, rather dense societies of the light - gray plants. Societies of Solidago spp. are also sometimes common in the aspect of the dry valleys. Other common forbs in order of decreasing im - portance were: Salsola pesiifer, Helianthus spp., Ambrosia psilostachya, Artemisia caudata, Eriogonum annuum, Equisetum spp., and Polygonum spp. (Table 5). Shrub vegetation is quite insignificant in the dry-valley type. Rosa arkansana and Amorpha canescens, the only shrubs of any consequence, each contribute less than one per cent to the average density. Opuntia spp. and Neomamillaria spp. are present occasionally but only in insignificant amounts. This type no doubt suffered considerably from the effects of the drouth. Although its composition contains a considerable proportion of sod-form - ing grasses, the average ground cover of perennial vegetation was only 15.5 per cent. Including annuals, this density figure would be 20.0 per cent. The average density, exclusive of Festuca octoflora, was 17.5 per cent. Dry Meadow (M2) Type Classified in the M2 category was the vegetation of the valleys which did not satisfactorily fit into the M3 (dry valley) or the Ml (wet meadow) types. Ideally, this type would be characterized by the dominance of species ordinarily found in subirrigated meadows in which the depth to the ground-water level is intermediate between that of the wet meadows and sites beyond the influence of the ground-water (4). Numerous topographi - cal irregularities occur, however, resulting in mixtures of Ml and M3 </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Nebraska Sandhill Range -.'¦¦.! types too small to map separately; such mixtures were included in the M2 type. During favorable years most of the M2 meadows would produce a satisfactory crop, of hay although the crop would usually be lacking in quantity or quality as compared with that of the Ml type. ' ' •'. Table 6.—Average percentage composition of the dry-meadow (M2) type based on foliage density. Grasses and grasslike plants Percent ¦¦¦•¦;' Percent Panicum virgatum............. 13.5 Bouteloua graci1i5............ 1,. 1.4 Spartina pectinata.., .;! 11.4 Agropyrori smithii.......: '¦-... 1.4 Andropogon furcatus. '9.8 Bouteloua hirsuta, ...:.... 1.3 Distichlis 5tricta...;......,..... 8.6 Eragrostis spp. 13 Carcx spp. (meadow) 62 Andropogon 5c0pariu5.......... 1.2 Poa spp. 5.5 . Phleuni pratense. ..'.' 1.2 Sorghastrum nutan5....;.'.'..,.; 4.9 Calamagrostis 5pp......... ..... 0.4 luncus spp.. . 4.6 Scirpus amcricanus ......1.. 0.3 Sporobolus cryptandrus......... 3.0 Elymus canadensis ...[.. 0.2 Calamovilfa longifolia 2.5 Supa cornata &#132;.....:.. i.. 0.1 Agrostis a1ba.........- ..... 2.4 0ther5..,......,........!. 1!.. L0 Hordeum jubatum....., 2.0 I .. Festuca octoflora.., ¦¦¦:..,..... 1.9 Total grasses, ....1.. 86.1 ' -¦•¦'. "¦: Forbs. : '-: . I : . __ Chenopodium a1bum........... 3.0 Leptilon canadensc. i/. 0.8 Solidago spp :.. :¦'......'. 1.8 Vernonia 5pp.............,.!.. 0.4 Ambrosia spp .1.4 Trifolium 5pp.............. j.. 0.1 Salsolapestifer... 1.2 0ther5....................:.. 1.9 Artemisia 5pp............. ...;;' \2 Polygonum 5pp..... 1.0 *r Helianthus spp. ..,¦........'... Q.9 Total f0tb5............ i.. 13.7 ¦.''.-: Shrubs ¦ '.''. "¦" Amorphacanescens....' ;•...:• 0.1 Ttosaspp... :..).. 0.1 . Total shrubs......, &#132;.-. i .','¦ 0.2 -Table 6 presents the average composition of the dry-meadow type which with 9,250 acres, occupies third place among the five major forage types (Table 3). The average density is 32.0 per cent. ( There is a rather gradual reduction in the importance of j the com - paratively numerous component species (Table 6). Listed in order of decreasing composition percentage the important species of the; M2 type are: Panicum virgatum, Spartina pectinata, Andropogon furcatus, Distichlis stricta, Carex : spp., Poa spp., Sorghastrum nutans, and funcus spp. The great diversity of the type is indicated by the inclusion in its average com - position of significant amounts of Calamovilfa, Sporobolus, and Distichlis along with the wet-meadow species. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 Only an insignificant number of shrubs, Amorpha canescens and Rosa arkansana, was recorded in the dry-meadow type but the forbs comprised 13.7 per cent of the total density. Two annuals, Chenopodium album and Salsola pestifer were among the most abundant species but the remaining important forbs were perennials. Of the latter group the most important were Solidago spp., Ambrosia spp., Artemisia spp., Polygonum spp., Helianthus spp., and Vernonia spp. The average density of 32.0 per cent is surpassed only by that of the wet-meadow type (40.4 per cent) which is similar to the better parts of the M2 type. Most of the M2 type is suitable for hay land but some of it is grazed. Wet Meadow (Ml) Type The choice hay meadows were designated as the Ml type. This type included the wettest sites of the grassland. Vegetation of a more hydric nature was mapped as marsh. No vegetative analyses were made of the marsh type. When bordering a marsh, the Ml type is often bounded by a belt of willow shrubs (Salix spp.). Some of the meadows are flooded dur - ing a part of the spring season in normal years. Only 2.8 per cent (3,227 acres) of the total acreage, or 3.1 per cent of the grassland surveyed, was classified as wet-meadow type. Although ranking low in acreage this type is high in productivity having an aver - age density of 40.4 per cent, which is considerably higher than any of the other types. Table. 7.— Average percentage composition of the wet-meadow (Ml) type based on foliage density. Grasses and grasslikc plants Per cent Per cent Spartina pccrinata. 16.4 Eragrostis spp 2.1 Andropogon furcatus 10.1 Distichlis stricta 1.5 Panicum virgatum 9.6 Scirpus americanus 1.2 Agrostis alba 9.4 Hordeum jubatum 0.9 Poa spp 8.5 Elymus canadensis 0.3 Carcx. spp. (meadow) 8.2 Agropyron smiihii 0— Sorghastrum nutans 5.8 Andropogon scoparius 02 Phleuni pratense 5.1 Others 3.0 [uncus spp . 3.8 Calamagn.stis spp. 2.2 Total grasses '. ... 88.5 Forbs Polygonum spp. 2.3 Artemisia spp 0.3 Ambrosia psilotachya 1.6 Apocynum spp 0.2 Solidago spp 1.0 Rumcx spp 0.1 _ptilon canadense 1.0 Taraxacum officinale 0.1 Chenopodium album 0.9 Verbena spp 0.1 Helianthus spp 0.9 Agastachc spp Q.l Trifolium spp 0.9 Others 1.7 Acmispon americana. 0.3 —— Total forbs 11.5 </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Nebraska Sandhill Range All of the dominants of the wet meadows are desirable hay and pasture species. The eight most abundant in order of decreasing importance are: Spartina pectinata, Andropogon furcatus, Panicum virgatum, Agrostis alba, Poa pratensis, Carex spp., Sorghastrum nutans, and Phleum pratense (Table 7). Forbs constitute 11.5 per cent of the average density in the meadows. Unlike the major grass species, most of the more common forbs are not desirable forage plants. The most abundant wet-meadow forbs were: Poly - gonum spp., Ambrosia psilostachya, Solidago spp., Leptilon canadense, Chenopodium album, Helianthus spp., and Trifolium spp. Polygonum muhlenbergia was especially abundant in small depressions where a fluc - tuating high water table had excluded the meadow grasses. In such places it often formed pure societies. Species of Trifolium provide desirable for - age and definitely increased the value of the meadows (4). .:.. Distinct zoning and considerable diversity of the dominant species char - acterized those areas which were classified as wet-meadow type. As pointed out by Keim, Frolik, and Beadle (4) this is a direct response to ground - water level. In the wettest portions, Cart?* and Spartina may comprise almost pure stands although Calamagrostis spp. and Muhlenbergia dsperi - folia are often associated. Where previously planted, Phleum pratense and Agrostis albapersist well. Ordinarily Panicum, Andropogon, Sorghastrum, and Poa control the less hydric portions. This type is seldom grazed except during the winter and early spring months when the meadows are commonly used as feed lots. ,¦'.'. Saltgrass (MID) Type The saltgrass type was the smallest of the types mapped, comprising only 2,688 acres or 2.6 per cent of the total grassland. The average density is 31.1 per cent. Because of the distinctive character of its one major dom - inant species and also because of its restriction to saline soils, the saltgrass is the most easily recognized and delimited of all the sandhill types. This type is usually grazed. Typically, Distichlis stricta forms almost pure stands of rather open sod. It was repeatedly observed that the density of the sod increases if the salt - grass is judiciously grazed but that if it is completely protected from grazing the accumulation of old vegetation thins the stand considerably. Topographical irregularities, too small to map, account for a part of the variation in the average composition (Table 8). However, there is usually some association of saltgrass with several other species such as Hordeum jubatum, Panicum virgatum, ]uncus spp., and Agropyron smithii. Hordeum isa.pioneer of the saltgrass sites and rapidly invades areas exposed by a receding water table. If the water table becomes stabil - ized at a high level, the Hordeum zones will ultimately be taken over by Distichlis in saline areas. Because of its inconspicuous habit during drouth A. smithii becomes much less apparent in the vegetative aspect during dry seasons. The unusually dry conditions during 1937 may have caused this </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 Table 8. — Average percentage composition of the saltgrass (MID) type based on foliage density. Grasses and grasslikc plants Per cent Per cent Distichlis stricta 45.8 Poa spp 1.2 Hordeum lubatum 10.5 Festuca octoflora 1.1 Panicum virgatum 5.1 Muhlenbergia aspcrifolia 1.0 Juncus spp. 4.1 Bouteloua hirsuta 1.0 Agropyron smithii 3.6 Andropogon furcatus 0.8 C.irtA .pp. (meadow | . 2.rt Calamagrosti.s .spp 0.5 Spartina pectinata. 2.0 Sorghastrum nutans 0.3 Scirpus auuncanus 1.8 Scirpus validus 0.3 .S/x,r,&gt;b(,lus cryplanilrus IA Others . 0.8 Calamotilfa longifolia 1.4 Total glasses 85.3 Forbs S.ilm&gt;l.i iK-stiler 5.1 Polygonum spp 0.3 ()iuni.|.i.iliuiii allium 3.6 Vernonia spp 0.2 Ambrosia spp ].2 Euphorbia spp 0.1 Solidago spp 1.0 Others 1.9 Helianthus spp U.B Ltpulon canaden.se 0.5 Total forbs 14.7 species to be slightly under-rated in this survey when compared with its foliage cover in a normal season. No shrubs ordinarily occur in the saltgrass type, but during 1937 the forbs were quite common. They were predominantly annual weeds, Salsola pestifer and Chenopodium album, and were most abundant at the edges of the Distichlis or the Hordeum zones where drouth had left exposed areas uncontrolled by perennial vegetation. FORAGE PRODUCTIVITY OF THE MAJOR TYPES The average productivity of a type may be expressed as its forage factor (capacity index) which is the product of the average density (cover index) and the weighted average utilization rating (value index). Figures 2 and 3 show the relative ratings of the types according to their average density, weighted average utilization rating, and produc - tivity. In order of decreasing forage productivity pet acre, the types fall in the order of (1) wet meadow, (2) dry meadow, (3) saltgrass, (4) dry valley, and (5) dune sand (Fig. 3). The Ml type ranked highest both as to cover index and value index, possessing a dense as well as highly pal - atable vegetative composition. The M2 indices were similar but lower than those for Ml. The saltgrass type compared favorably with the M2 mead - ows in density but being the lowest type in palatability it ranked third in productivity. The value indices of the dry-valley and the dune-sand types were almost identical but the lesser density of the latter places it lowest in productivity. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Nebraska Sandhill Range .1 I I I I--J— 1 "3 i__^SFp ===:p y °__^j ;;;i!_U^:__.-; if- — _ a —-—_— —w — „ to .-Percent Fie. 2.—Average densities and weighted utilization ratings (relative) of the major types. ¦&gt;^r- ill V, 1~^1: . ¦-"-_! ______ ¦-¦¦' ¦ • - ¦ ¦ 1 I I J .1 V2 1 . I ,1 • .-•¦¦¦ ma- ¦ i : &gt;'. 1 J ¦'.: 0 .05 .10 .15 .20 .25 .30 Average forage f&amp;otor ; Fie. 3. —Productivity of the major types, based on their average forage factors. </seg>
         <seg id="p022">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 117 Table 9.— Relative productivity of the significant species of the wet - meadow (Ml) type. Weighted Per cent (brasses and grasslikc plants utilization rating,l of total per cent productivity Spartina pectinata 8.18 15.0 Andropogon furcatus 8.10 14.9 Poa spp 6.77 12.4 Agrostis alba &lt;5.59 12.1 Carcx spp, (meadow) 5.73 10.5 Sorghastrum nutans 4.81 8.8 Phleum pratense 4.06 7.5 Panicum virgatum 3.37 6.2 Calamagrostis spp. 0.88 1.6 (uncus spp 0.76 1.4 Eragtostis spp. 0.62 1.1 Scirpus americanus 0.61 1.1 Distichlis stricta 0.31 «•&lt;&gt; Agropyron smithii 0.14 0.3 Elymus canadensis 0.14 0.3 Andropogon scoparius 0.09 0.2 Hordeum jubatum 0.09 0.2 Others 1-45 2.7 Total orassf.s 5270 96.9 Forbs Trifolium spp 0.67 Polygonum spp 0.24 .... Chenopodium album u.19 .... Ambrosia spp 0.16 .... Solidago spp. 0.10 .... Taraxacum officinale U.07 .... Artemisia gnaphalodcs 11.06 .... Rumix spp. 0-01 A[*&gt;cynum spp. 0-00 .... Acmispon americana 0.00 .... Agastachc spp 0.00 .... Helianthus spp &lt;100 Verbena spp. 0.00 .... Lcptilon canatlcnse 0.00 .... Others 0.18 Total h.rbs »¦_ 3.1 Weighted utilization rating 54.38 100.0 Average density 40.4 .... Forage factor-' 0.2197 1 Percentage composition X uttli_.iti»n rating (Table 7 and Appendix I). 3 Density X weighted utilization rating. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Nebraska Sandhill Range ' Wet Meadow (Ml) Type Table 9 indicates the productivity importance of the component species of the type mapped as Ml. The most abundant species have high payabil - ity ratings (Appendix I), which account, for the favorable value index (average utilization rating) of 5438 and forage factor of 0.2197. The consistently high payability ratings of the dominant species account for the high correlation between the average density and the relative produc - tivity of the important species. Spartina, Andropogon furcatus, Poa, Agrostis, and Carex ate the lead - ing species in forage production. When this type is used only for hay, Poa is probably overrated in this report since the utilization rating tables are based primarily on pasture conditions. Forbs contributed only about three per cent to the productivity of this type, although they comprised over 11 per cent of the average density. Dry Meadow (M2)Type The M2 type ranked second to the Ml type in.productiviy, having a forage factor of 0.1488 (Table 10) as compared to 0.2197 for the Ml Table 10.— Relative productivity of the significant species of the dry meadow (M2) type. Weighted Per cent Grasses and grasslikc plants .' C utilization rating, of total \ percent productivity Andropogon furcatus .. . ..............:.. ¦ 7.80 ,16.8 Panicum virgatum..............................-.'. 6.77 14.6 Spartina pectinata.^.......,......,/.. ...... 5.68 12.2 Poa 5pp...........;.,..,.:.................... 4,40 9.5 Carex spp. (meadow).. 4.36 9.4 Sorghastrum nutan5...............: 3.43 7.4 Sporobolus cryptandrus .... ..,.",;..::.. ...'.,:¦ 1.77 3.8 Calamovilfa longifolia..... ......... ....•..-..: 1.75 3.8 Distichlis stricta.. ......................... 1.73 3.7 Agrostis alba... .................. ... 1.67 3.6 Juncus 5pp.................................... 0.92 2.0 Phlcum pratense ..... 0.92 2.0 Agropyron smithii... .0.81 1.7 Andropogon scoparius 0.49 1.0 Eragrostis 5pp.................................. 0.38 0.8 Bouteloua gracilis..; ................,.../.. 0.29 0.6 Bouteloua hirsuta ......... 0,27 0.6 Hordeum jubatum .....................;.•....... 0.21 0.4 Calamagrostis spp. 0.17 0.4 ¦ Scirpus americanus. '.'. . 0.15 0.3 Elymus canadensis ........ '.:.-....'.;..'•.'....... .-.;¦ 0.10 0.2 Stipa comaa .................................. 0.08 0.2 Festuca octoflora &#132;.....:.............,...v......'.. 0.00 0.0 ¦' Others ................. ...^.::.!.:... .0.50 1.1 . Total grasses... ..:..,......,;...........;., 44.65 96.1 </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 Table 10. — Continued. Weighted Per cent Forbs utilization rating, of total per cent productivity Chenopodium album 0.60 .... Arremisia spp. 0.24 .... Salsola pcstifcr 0.24 .... Solidago spp. 0.18 .... Ambrosia spy.. 0.14 .... Trifolium spp. 0.12 .... Polygonum spp 0.10 .... Vernoma spp 0.00 .... Helianthus spp 0.00 Lcptilon canadcnse 0.00 .... Others ' 0.20 Total korbs 1.82 3.9 Shrubs Aroorpha canescens 0.02 .... Rosa spp 0.01 Total shrubs 0.03 Weighted utilization rating 46.50 100.0 Average density 32.0 Forage factor 0.1488 meadows. The average density of this type was about 20 per cent less than that of the Ml. Although the major dominants of the wet meadows were likewise the most abundant species of the M2 meadows, the latter type contained a greater variety of species and also a larger proportion of less palatable kinds, thus reducing its value index. The six species which contribute about 70 per cent to the productivity of the meadows mapped as M2 are: Andropogon furcatus, Panicum, Spar - tina, Poa, Carex, and Sorghastrum in order of decreasing importance. The order of importance by productivity is quite different from that of density composition (Cf. Tables 10 and 6). For example, Distichlis ranked fourth in density but ninth in productivity. Forbs constituted about 14 per cent of the density of this type but only 4 per cent of its productivity. Saltgrass (MID) Type Because of its high density, which compares favorably with that of the M2 meadows, the saltgrass type ranks third although its palatability index is the lowest of all types (Figs. 2 and 3). The capacity index, or forage factor, 0.0803, of the saltgrass type is about one-third that of the Ml type. The single dominating species of this type, Distichlis, comprised 46 per cent of the foliage density and 35 per cent of the forage productivity </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Nebraska Sandhill Range (Gf. Tables 8 and 11). Nine other constituents, which together furnish about 48 per cent of the forage of this type, are in order of decreasing im - portance, Panicum, Agropyron, Carex, Hordeum, Calamovilfa, Spartina, Poa, Scirpus americanus, and Sporobolus. Forbs, mainly Salsola and Chenopodium, furnished 8.5 per cent of the productivity of. this type as compared with a density composition of 15 per cent. Table 11. — Relative productivity of the significant species of the saltgrass (MID) type. Weighted Per cent Grasses and grasslike plants utilization rating, of total percent productivity Distichlis stricta. ...; 9.16 35.4 Panicum virgatum ..................... -,-. 2.55 9.9 Agropyron smithii ......,........:. „ •••• 2,14 8.3 Carex 5pp........,.........:...... ........ 1.83 7.1 Hordeum jubatum ........ ........: 1.05 4.1 Calamovilfa longifolia ..........;.......,......, 1.00 3.9 Spartina pectinata:................:........ ; 1.00 . 3.9 Poa spp.. .............. ¦.-.,,..;.'.';&gt;'.-.'.;.'. 0.95 3.7 '.. Scirpus americanus 0.88 3.4 Sporobolus cryptandrus 0.86 3.3 Andropogon furcatus .............'.............. 0.61 2.4 Juncus spp. .. 0.41 1.6 j Sorghastrum nutans ... .....:.....:..... 0.23 0.9 Bouteloua hirsuta ....... .......'...,...,.'... 0.19 0.7 . .¦....' / Calamagrostis 5pp.............. 0.19 0.7 ; Muhlenbergia asperifolius ......!................ 0.10 0.4. I Scirpus validus 0.03 ' : . 0.1 j Festuca octoflora ...........:..... 0.00 . 0.0 1 Others...; ..¦..:.....'..:".....v...-..'......... 0.45 1-7 '. '[ Totai. crass;.. ......:..:........:. ...... -23.63 91.5 ..-Forbs. Salsola pestifcr ................................ 1.04 .... Chenopodium album . ;.": 0.70 Ambrosia 5pp.................................. 0.12 50\iia%05pp............................... 0.10 ... Polygonum 5pp..."..'.'.'.,..'.. ....0.03 Euphorbia spp. ............... .... 0.00 .... Helianthus 5pp.........:.. ...:... 0.00 j Leptilon canadcnse.........-............: ... 0.00 .... Verrionia spp. ..................:.....:... ' - 0.00 •--.. .... Others .:.....:...:......;.:......:.:.....:...; 030 .... Total roRBs 2.19 8.5 Weighted utilization raring;.................:... 25.82 100.0 Average density..... ....,...:.............. 31.1 .... Forage fact0r... ....:...:....:....:...:........ 0.0803 .... </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 Dry Valley (M3) Type On the basis of utilizable forage produced per acre, the dry valley type ranked fourth, only the dune sand type being lower in this respect. The forage factor of the M3 type, 0.0609, was only slightly higher than that of the dune type, 0.0548 (Fig. 3). The difference in the value ratings of these Table 12.— Relative productivity of the significant species of the dry valley (Mi) type. Weighted Per cent (irasscs and grasslike plants utilization rating, of total per cent productivity Calamovilfa longifolia 7.57 21.7 Sporobolus cryptandrus 7.21 20.7 Panicum virgatum 15.4 Bouteloua gracilis 2.36 6.8 Agropyron smithii I.™ **•" Bouteloua hirsuta »&gt;3" 4.0 Andropogon scoparius '-12 52 Carex spp. u-96 2-8 Poa spp °-61 '•' Stipa cornata ".58 1.6 (uncus spp. 0-48 1-4 Andropogon furcatus 0.46 1.3 Spartina pectinata 0.41 1.2 Distichlis stricta 0.34 1.0 Eragrostis spp ".30 0.9 Sorghastrum nutans 0.22 0.6 Andropogon hallii 0.16 0.5 Koclcria cristata 0-07 0.2 Festuca octoflora 0.00 0.0 Others 0.26 JU Total t.Rsssf.s ¦ — 31.28 BSU&gt; Forbs Chenopodium album 1-03 .... Artemisia gnaphalodcs 0./9 .... Artemisia caudata 0.62 .... Salsola pestifer 0-49 Solidago spp. 0.17 .... Ambrosia spp. 0.05 .... Equisctum spp 0.02 .... Psoralca spp 0.02 .... Polygonum spp. 0.02 .... Asrcr spp. 0.01 .... Helianthus spp 0.00 .... Eriogonum annuum 0-00 - -• • Leptilon canadcnse 0.00 .... Others 0.17 Total i-orbs 3.39 ?.7 </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Nebraska Sandhill Range Table 12.— Continued. Weighted Percent Shrubs utilization rating, of total percent productivity Rosa spp. ;........ 0.14 ...:. • Amorpha cane5cen5............ — ...... o.ll' Totalshrubs. 0.25 0.7 Weighted utilization rating. ................. 34.92 100.0 Average density — —......... 17.5 .... Forage factor.¦¦¦¦¦......¦¦ .."¦.¦¦¦...¦ . \ 0.0609 two similar types is due to the difference in density. Their average pal - atability ratings were almost identical (Fig. 2).. As illustrated by Table 12, three species, Calamovilfa, Sporobolus, and Panicum, furnish nearly 60 per cent of the total forage. It may also be noted (Tables 5 and 12) that the ratings of the major species in forage production and density composition are considerably different. Bouteloua gracilis, for example, ranked second in density, contributing about 14 per cent of the vegetation, but this species contributed only about 7 per cent to the productivity of the type, ranking fourth in this respect. Forbs were more abundant in the M3 type than in any of the other types. They constituted 20 per cent of the foliage cover. Some of them ' have a low utilization rating and'accordingly furnished slightly less than 10 per cent of the forage. This type: apparently suffered considerably from the drouth and prob - ably has a higher potential productivity than this survey has indicated. Dune Sand (D) Type Although by far the most extensive and on the whole the most impor - tant in the sandhill region, the dune-sand type is lowest in productivity (Fig. 3). Its average utilization, rating of 34.5 per cent compares with that of the dry valley type but the average density of Jess than 16 per cent gives it a forage factor of 0.0548, the lowest of the five major types (Table 13). Calamovilfa is the major species of the dune-sand type. This grass alone contributes over 40 per cent of the productivity of the type, nearly twice as much as does the second ranking species, Sporobolus cryptandrus (Tables 4 and 13). Together these two species furnish about 64 per cent of the forage while an additional 22 per cent comes from Bouteloua hirsuta, Andropogon scoparius, and A. hallii. Forbs and shrubs account for 2.8 and 2.3 per cent, respectively, of the total forage as compared with an average density of 133 and 7.7 per cent. </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 Table 13.— Relative productivity of the significant species of the dune sand (£) type. Weighted Per cent tirasses and grasslike plants utilization rating, of total per cent productivity Calamovilfa longifolia H-23 41.2 Sporolxilui cryptandrus *-n- 23.2 Bouteloua hirsuta 3.4/ 10.1 Andropogon scoparius 2.1- 6.2 Andropogon hallii L l)2 5.6 Muhlenbergia pungens 0.88 2.6 F.ragrostis spp. 0.4 C&gt; . *-J Pantcuoi spp. 0.44 1.3 Stipa cornata 0.32 0.9 Carex spp 0.2-t 0.7 Redncldia flexuosa 0-15 0.4 Koclena cristata u-13 0.4 Bouteloua gracilis 0.10 0.3 Agropyron smithii 0.08 0.2 /uncus spp "•0') 0-1 Festuca octoflora "-00 0-0 Others 0.10 JU Total grasses 32.73 94.9 Forbs Chenopodium album 0.52 Artemisia gnaphalodcs 0.15 .... Psoralca spp 0.0/ .... Salsola pestifer 0.04 .... Artemisia caudata 0.03 .... Ambrosia spp 0.02 .... Solidago spp. 0.02 .... l'claltrstenium spp. 0.01 .... Rumcx spp. 0.01 .... Euphorbia spp. . 0.00 Helianthus spp 0.00 Eriogonum annuum 0.00 .... Others 0.11 Total forbs 0.98 2.8 Shrubs Rosa spp. 0.7,1 .... Prunus besseyi 0.16 .... Amorpha cancscens 0.11 .... Rhus toxicodendron 0.00 .... Yucca glauca 0.00 Total shrubs 0.78 2.3 Weighted utilization rating 34.49 100.0 Average density 15.90 .... Forage factor 0.0548 </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Nebraska Sandhill Range CARRYING CAPACITY OF THE MAJOR TYPES The unit forage acre is derived as the product of the forage factor times the total acreage of the type. By dividing the number of forage acres by a forage-acre requirement, the carrying capacity may be expressed in cow or other animal months or years. The dune-sand type surpasses all of the other types combined in total carrying capacity because of its extensive acreage. Of the total forage acres Table 14.— Average carrying capacity of the sandhill range types. Dune Dry Dry. Wet Salt- Type. -:¦'. sand 1 valley meadow meadow grass . Total Surface acre5.:........... 72,987 16,610 9,250' 3,227 2,688 104,762 Forage acres' (F.A.)....... 4,000 1,012 1,374 709 216 7,311 Per cent of total F.A...... 54.7 13.8 18.8 9.7 3.0: 100.0 Capacity (cow months).. .-. 34,188 8,650 11,744 6,060 1,846 |62,488 Surface acres per cow month 2.13 1.92 0.79 0.53 1.46 j 1.91 * Surface acres per cow year . 25.6 23.0 ' 9.5 .6.6 17.5 j 22.8 1 1 Weighted averages. . .'j in the surveyed area, 54.7 per cent were in the dune sand, 18.8 per cent in the M2, 13.8 per cent in the M3, 9.7 per cent in the Ml, and 3.0 per cent in the MID types, respectively (Table 14). ' , I '¦¦ ¦ As an average, 2.13 acres of the dune-sand type of range are required to support one cow satisfactorily for one month. The average numbers of acres required of the other types per cow month are: 1.92 of M3, 1.46 of MID, 0.79 of M2, and 0.53 of Ml (Table 14). The weighted average capacity of the entire area surveyed, including hay lands, was 1.91 acres per cow month. In other words, 22.8 acres would be required to support one cow for a year. Excluding the hay meadows, ix. the Ml and W. types, the average capacity of the grazing types was 2.07 acres per cow month or 12.4 acres per cow for a grazing season of six months. j. IMPORTANCE OF THE MAJOR SANDHILL FORAGE , SPECIES :'-"¦;..:"• To evaluate properly the various forage species of the area surveyed, their percentage composition in the types were weighted by the relative importance of the type as to its contribution to the total density and to the total productivity. Based on the calculations reported in Table 1 15, the ratings vary considerably according to whether they ate considered from '. the point of view of density or of productivity. Grasses ¦'.'..';".¦¦ I, ..''"' Calamovilfa longifolia was the most important species in the region from the standpoint of both foliage density and the amount of forage furnished to livestock. This species comprised 14.8 per cent of the total vegetative density of the area and 26.1 per cent of the estimated utiliza- </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Agriclxtl-ral Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 Table importance of the major forage species. Per cent contribution Per cent contribution to in vegetative density total forage production Calamovilfa lonjrifolia H.B Calainovilfa longifolia 26.1 nouulc.ua hirsuta 12.1 Sporobolus cryptandrus 16.4 Sporobolus cryptandrus 11.8 Bouccloua hirsuta 6.4 Panicuni virgatum 4.7 Panicum virßatum 5.8 Andri&gt;p&lt;&gt;Ron scoparius -1.0 Andropoßon furcatus 4.9 .Spartina pectinata 3.8 Spartina pcctinala 4.1 OisikMis strkta 3.7 Andropogon scoparius 4.0 noutultma gracilis 2.5 Carcx spp 3.8 Andropogon furcatus 2.3 Poa spp 3.4 Andropogon hallii 2.1 Andropoßon hallii 3.1 Cam &gt;pp. 1.9 Sorghastrum nutans 2.4 F.ragrostis spp. 1-7 Distichlis stricta 2.0 (uncus spp. 1.6 Agrostis alba 1.9 Poa spp. '.6 Agropyron smithii 1.3 Sorghastrum nutans 1.1 Bnutcloua gracilis 1.2 Agrostis alba 1.0 F.ragrostis spp 1-2 Agrops ron smithii 0.9 Phlcum pratense 1.1 Murdrum iuhatum 0.9 [uncus spp 0.8 Stipa cumata 0.5 Stipa comata 0.8 Phlcum pratense 0.5 Hordcum jubatum 0.2 Other grasses 7.0 Other grasses 3.6 Total grasses 80.5 Total grasses 94.5 Forbs 14.6 Forbs 4.2 Shrubs 49 Shrubs 1.3 blc forage. It is a tall, rather coarse grass and accordingly furnishes a con - siderable amount of forage per unit of ground cover. Although it ranks quite low in preference, cattle consistently graze Calamovilfa throughout the year. Some additional characteristics make Calamovilfa one of the im - portant stabilizers of the sandhill livestock industry. It not only begins growth fairly early in the spring but it remains green throughout the summer and until frost in the autumn. Furthermore, it retains its pal - atability fairly well upon curing in the fall on the range. Inference from the writings of earlier investigators indicates that Calamovilfa was probably less abundant two or three decades ago than it is at the present time. It therefore withstands well both drouth and grazing. Because of the vigorous rhizomatous habit, Calamovilfa spreads rapidly in the dune sand and accordingly plays a major role in stabilizing exposed dunes and blow - outs. Bouteloua hirsuta was the second ranking species on the basis of foliage ground cover, comprising 12.1 per cent of the vegetative density, but con - tributed only 6.4 per cent to the forage production of the area. Being a short grass, it produces a relatively small amount of forage per unit of ground cover. In addition, its habit of growing in scattered small tufts is not conducive to a high degree of utilization, as is the case with the sod- </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Nebraska Sandhill Range forming B. gracilis. Reference to earlier reports (7, 8, 12, 13) indicates that B. hirsuta is much more abundant at present than it was formerly. Sporobolus cryptandrus contributed 11.8 per cent of the vegetative cover of the area and it furnished 16.4 per cent of the forage. According to, these percentages, Sporobolus does not produce quite so much forage on the same amount of ground cover as does Calamovilfa, but it is much more palatable than the latter. During much of the season of grazing cattle prefer Sporobolus to most of the other dune species. Its decumbent habit of growth, especially when grazed, limits the degree of utilization of this species and reduces the hazards of overgrazing. Sporobolus makes considerable regrowth if moisture conditions are favorable in early fall. It has: undoubtedly increased in importance in recent years as a result of drouth and the consequent decrease of other species such as Andropogon scoparius. '.- Panicum virgatum furnished 4.7 per cent of the density composition and 5.8 per cent of the productivity. It occurs to some extent in every type but it is most abundant in the M2 meadows. Although it is primarily a component of the hay types, it is also a good pasture grass. It not only has the desirable characteristics of yielding much forage and being highly preferred by cattle, but it also seems to be quite tolerant of grazing. It affords no winter pasture, however, for after maturing on the ground, it is avoided by cattle. Andropogon scoparius contributed four per cent both to the total den - sity, and to the total productivity of the area. Undoubtedly A. scoparius suffered severely from the. drouth. Early, accounts of the sandhill flora ranked this grass as the dominant species of the area. The drouth of recent years and the numerous dead crowns of A. scoparius bunches still remain - ing in the area significantly account for discrepancies between the present rating of this species and those of earlier reports. A. scoparius seems to be less desirable as a pasture grass than are its major associates. Its dried stems are unpalatable and unless it is grazed down annually the stems per - sist as dense clumps preventing the utilization of current growth, which is moderately palatable. Andropogon furcatus and Spartina pectinata ranked fifth and sixth, respectively, in productivity and ninth and sixth in density. These are primarily utilized, for hay but are very productive and highly palatable when pastured. Even the coarse Spartina is kept closely grazed if the cattle are turned on it. while the current year's growth is young and succulent. Distichlis stricta ranked seventh in total density but only twelfth in productivity. This grass is valuable because of its vigorous sodding habit and its persistence under trampling and grazing, for windmill sites, yards, and the like, where most other grasses would be destroyed. In such places, it is kept closely grazed all season but it usually maintains a fairly good cover if moisture conditions are favorable.. Bouteloua gracilis ranked eighth with respect to ground coyer, but fifteenth in productivity. This grass is highly preferred by cattle, j but be- </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Acrici-lti'ral Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 cause of its short growth both the volume of forage produced per unit of ground cover and the percentage of the forage utilized are rather low. It is important only in those dry valleys having a fairly heavy soil. Andropogon hallii ranked tenth both in density and in productivity, contributing about two per cent to the total density and three per cent to the productivity. This species, occurring mainly in the dune type, is highly palatable and produces considerable forage in relation to ground cover. Carex spp. contributed 1.9 per cent to density and 3.8 per cent to pro - ductivity. F.ragrostis spp., Juncus spp., and Poa spp. contributed 1.7, 1.6, and 1.6. respectively, to total density and 1.2, 0.8, and 3.4 per cent, res - pectively, to the total forage production. Forbs Only 4.2 per cent of the area's productivity was calculated to be fur - nished by forbs although they contributed 14.6 per cent of the foliage cover. Helianthtts spp. were, on the whole, the most abundant forbs. Although no differentiation of species of Helianthtts was attempted dur - ing the survey, an annual sandhill sunflower, Helianthus petiolaris, was the most common. Helianthus spp. occurred to some extent in all types but were most abundant in the dune type. The annual species is unpalatable hut parts of the plants of the perennial species are often eaten by the cattle. Two more annuals, Chenopodium album and Salsola pestifer, ranked second and fourth, respectively, in abundance. These were most common in the dry-valley and the saltgrass types although they occurred to some ex - tent in all types except the Ml. These species are slightly palatable but are undesirable as forage plants. They have probably been favored in recent years by environmental conditions which have thinned somewhat the perennial foliage cover. Artemisia gnaphalodes ranked the highest in foliage cover of the peren - nial forbs. Next in order of importance were Solidago spp. and Ambrosia psilostachya. These occurred in all the types but Artemisia and Solidago were most abundant in the M3 and M2, while Ambrosia occurred most often in the Ml, M2, and MID. Artemisia is heavily grazed by catde. Ambrosia is much less palatable but it is sometimes grazed slightly. Solidago glaberrima is quite palatable but two or three other common species of Solidago are seldom grazed. Eriogonum annuum and Euphorbia petaloidea are characteristic of the dune-sand type but their foliage density is not important. They are unpalatable to cattle. Psoralea lanceolata and P. argophylla are scattered throughout the dune-sand and M3 types but collectively they play an insignificant role in the total density. The former is unpalatable but the latter is grazed to some extent. Shrubs Shrubs contributed about five per cent to the total density of the area and a little more than one per cent to the total forage production. Yucca glauca was the most important species of the shrub group with respect to </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Nebraska Sandhill Range foliage cover, even though it occurred only in the dune-sand type. Rosa arkansana, which occurred most commonly in the dune type but also appeared in the M3 and M2, ranked second. Prunus besseyi and Amorpha canescens were about equal in importance. Prunus was primarily restricted to the dune type while Amorpha was about equally distributed between the dune and the M3 and also occurred to a slight extent in the M2 mead - ows. With the exception of Yucca these shrubs are all palatable to cattle. Poisonous plants The sandhill ranges are remarkably free from plants that are decidedly toxic to livestock. Senecio riddellii, which causes "walking disease" of horses and catde (17), is fairly common on some parts of the dune type. As a rule it causes little concern among ranchmen in this section. Trouble can be avoided by keeping catde out of infested areas during the spring season (17). Cicuta occidentalis occurs occasionally in wet meadows but is not present in sufficient amounts to cause poisoning. Triglochin maritima occurs only in rare instances near saline marshes where it is not likely to be grazed. SUMMARY '&#132;'¦' A vegetative survey of a typical sandhill range area was conducted in the eastern part.of Cherry county during 1937. The survey covered a total of 114,759 acres, including the land of the Valentine Migratory Water - fowl Refuge. The vegetation of the five major range types of grassland was mapped on a scale of six inches to the mile. The survey was conducted according to a modified combination of the two commonly accepted methods of vege - tative analysis used by range examiners. These two methods are the ocular reconnaissance method and the square-foot-density or point-observation-plot method. Composition as to density and as to productivity and livestock carrying capacity were determined. The types were identified and desig - nated as follows: dune sand vegetation (D), dry valley or bunchgrass of dry meadows (M3), wet; phase of tall-grass meadows (Ml), dry phase of tall-grass meadows or transition type (M2), and saltgrass or alkali mead - ows (MID). Total vegetative density and composition of each of the types were computed by determining the percentage of ground cover contributed by the foliage of each species. The productivity of each type was evaluated by.determining its forage factor (species composition x utilization rating x density). The percentage contribution of each type to the total productivity of the area was calcu - lated. The livestock carrying capacity of each type was obtained by calcu - lating the number of forage acres (number, of surface acres x forage factor) and dividing this figure by a forage acre requirement per animal month. The latter was determined by a supplemental study of a number of pastures whose capacities were established by use records. A summary of the per - tinent data is presented in Table 16. ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 There have been decided changes in the composition of the vegetation of the sandhills during the past two or three decades as determined in a comparison of the results of this survey with the reports of earlier investi - gators. Andropogon scoparius and Stipa cornata, previously reported as being important species on the dune sand, have materially decreased in abundance; Andropogon hallii, mentioned as a dominant by some of the early writers, has also apparently decreased. Calamovilfa longifolia has probably increased somewhat. Bouteloua hirsuta and Sporobolus cryp - tandrus, which are either scarcely mentioned or enumerated as secondary species by the earlier writers, have increased considerably and are two im - portant species at the present time. They rank second and third, respec - tively, in density, being surpassed only by Calamovilfa longifolia. The grasses contributing two per cent or more to the entire area with respect to vegetative density are listed in order of decreasing importance as follows: Calamovilfa longifolia 14.8 per cent, Bouteloua hirsuta 12.1 per cent, Sporobolus cryptandrus 11.8 per cent, Panicum virgatum 4.7 per cent, Andropogon scoparius 4.0 per cent, Spartina pectinata 3.8 per cent, Distichlis stricta 3.7 per cent, Bouteloua gracilis 2.5 per cent, Andropogon furcatus 1.1 per cent, and Andropogon hallii 1.1 per cent. Forbs and shrubs contributed 14.6 and 4.9 per cent, respectively, to the total density. The grasses contributing two per cent or more to the entire area with respect to forage productivity are listed in order of decreasing importance as follows: Calamovilfa longifolia 26.1 per cent, Sporobolus cryptandrus 16.4 per cent, Bouteloua hirsuta 6.4 per cent, Panicum virgatum 5.8 per cent, Andropogon furcatus 4.9 per cent, Spartina pectinata 4.1 per cent, Table 16.— Summary of pertinent data from a range survey of a typical area of sandhill range land in Cherry county, Nebraska. 1) Mi M2 Ml MID Dune Dry Dry Wet Salt- Total and Type santl valley meadow meadow grass averages Total acreage 72,987 16,610 9,250 3,227 2,688 114,7591 Average density a 15.9 17.53 32.0 40.4 31.1 Weighted average utilization rating -' 34.49 34.92 46.50 54.38 25.82 .... Forage acre factor 0.0548 0.0609 0.1485 0.2197 0.0803.... Forage acres 4,000 1,012 1,374 709 216 7,311 Per cent total acres 63.fi 14.5 8.1 2.8 2.3 Per cent total range acres 69.7 15.8 8.8 3.1 2.6 .... Per cent forage acres 54.7 13.8 18.8 9.7 3.0 Capacitv (cow months)* 34,188 8,650 11,744 6,060 1,846 62,488 Surface acres per cow month 2.13 1.92 0.79 0.53 1.46 1.91" Surface acres per cow year 25.6 23.0 9.5 6.6 17.5 22.8s 1 Marshes constituted 5.07i acres or 4.4 per cent of total area, and lakes covered -1,924 acres or 4.3 per tent of ihc total area surveyed. Range area included all the surveyed land except (he marshes jnd ihc lakes and totaled 104.762 acres. : Per ccni. -1 Uncs not include Festuca nctnftnra which would raise the average density to 20.0 per cent. ' Fnrajj* acre requirement used in calculations was 0.117 per cow month. 0 Weighted averages. </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Nebraska Sanohill Range ¦ Andropogon scoparius 4.0 per cent, Carex spp. 3.8 per cent, Poa spp. 3.4 per cent, Andropogon hallii 3.1 per cent, Sorghastrum nutans 2.4 per cent, and Distichlis stricta 2.0 per cent. Forbs and shrubs contributed 4.2 and 1.3 per cent, respectively, to the total productivity. Plants poisonous to livestock are of no great importance. </seg>
         <seg id="p036">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 117 APPENDIX 1 Utilization Rating (Palatarlitv ') Table and Check. List of Plants Used in the Ranue Survey of tuf. Sandhills in Cherry County, Nebraska. Utilization Grasses and grasslike plants Symbol rating Agropyron smithii Western wheatgrass Asm 60 Agrostis alba Rctltop AGR 70 Andropogon furcatus Big bluestem Afu 80 Andropogon hallii Sandhill bluestem Aha 60 Andropogon scoparius I.itr/c blucstcm Asc 40 Aristula spp Triple-awn grass ARI 20 Bouteloua gracilis Hluc grama Bgr Z0 Bouteloua hirsuta Hairy grama Bhi 20 Animus commutatus Hairy chess Bco 20 Brnmus inermis Bromegrass Bin 80 Carex spp. (meadow) Sedge CAR 70 Carex spp. (dune) Sedge CAR 20 Oalan.agrostis spp Blucjoint CAL '10 C.alamagrostis canadensis . Blucioint Cca 40 Calamovilfa longifolia Sand reedgrass Clo 70 Crnchrus pauciflorus Sandbur Cpa 20 Cyperus spp Sedge CYP 70 I listichlis stricta Saltgrass DIS 20 Echinochloa spp Barnyard grass ECH -10 Elymus canatlcnsis Wild rye ELY 50 Eragrostis spp Lovcgrass ERA 30 Eragroslis irichodes Lovegrass Etr 50 Fcsiuca octoflora Six-weeks fescue Foe 0 Honlcum iubatum Wild barley Hju 10 Juncus spp Rush JUN 20 Koclcria cristata Junegrass K.OE 50 Leersia spp Rice cutgrass LEE 20 Muhlenbergia aspcrifolia Scratchgrass Mas 20 Muhlenbergia pungens Blow-out grass Mpu 10 Panicum spp. Panic grass PAN 40 Panicum virgatum Switchgrass Pvi 50 Phalaris arundinacea Reed canary grass PHA 80 Phlcum pralcnse Timothy PHL 80 Poa spp Bluegrass POA 80 Rcilficldia flcxuosa Rcdfield's grass RED 20 Scirpus spp. Bulrush SCI 50 Scirpus americanus Bulrush Sam 50 Scirpus validus Great bulrush Sva 10 Sorghastrum nutans Indian grass SOR 70 Spartina pectinata Sloughgrass Spe 50 Sporobolus cryptandrus Sand dropsecd Scr 60 Stipa cornata Western needlegrass Sco 60 Stipa spartca Needlegrass Ssp 60 1 ¦'I'aljiatiilny. as used in range surveys, is the percentage of the total current year's growth, within reach i&gt;{ stuck, w which a species is prized when the ranee unit is properly utilized under the best practical range management" (4). In this survey this concept of "palatabilily" was changed somewhat 7he ratines in this tahle jrc intended In evaluate the important species according to the relative amount of edible forage prodoccd per onit of ground cover, when they arc correctly utilized. </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Nebraska Sandhill Range APPENDIX I— (Continued) Utilization Rating (Palatablity '•) Table and Check List of Plants Used in the Range Survey of the Sandhills in Cherry County, Nebraska. I '. ~~ Utilization Forbs •-¦-.;. Symbol rating Acmispon americanus.........Prairie trefoil.. ACM 0. Amaranthus spp..' Pigweed AMA 20 Ambrosia 5pp......... AMB 10 Ambrosia psilostachya ........Perennial ragweed............ AMB 10 Apocynum 5pp..........^....D0gbane ....... —....— APO 0 Artemisia 5pp....... ....Sage ........ •• ART 20 Artemisia caudata............Green 5age...... Aca 20 Artemisia gnaphalodes Prairie sage Agn 20 Aster spp. ............¦¦ Wild aster AST 10 Atriplex 5pp.......;.......... Saltbush ATR 10 Chenopodium album Lamb's quarters CHE 20 Cicuta occidentalis .......:.'... .Water hemlock..: ....,.... Coc 0 Cycloloma atriplicifolium Winged pigweed............. CYC 0 Equisetum spp. ..Horsetail...... ••¦•••• EQV .'." Eriogonum annuum . .... Umbrella plant ........... ERIO 0 Euphorbia spp. ..............Spurge .................... EUP 0 Glycyrrhiza 1epid0ta..........Wi1d licorice...... .;... GLY 0 Helianthus spp :........ .Sunflower .................. HEL 0 Lepachys columnifcra....:.... Prairie coneflower..:. ..Leo 20 Lcptilon canadcnse.......... .Marestail LEP 0 Lygodesmia spp . Skeletonwccd : LYG 0 Pctalostemum spp. .......:.. .Prairie clover.... Pet 10 Petalostcmum oligophyllus White prairie c10ver........!. Pcto 10 Pctalostemum purpureus .... .Purple prairie c10ver.......... Pctp 10 Pctalostemum villosus -&#132;. ..Hairy prairie clover :........ v Petv 10 Physalis spp. .. Ground cherry .._...... ..PHY 0 Plantago pur5hii.............W0011y plantain ...:......... Ppu 0 Polygonum spp .... .Smartweed ...POL 10 Polygonum muhlenbergii.. Perennial smartweed...'. . POL 10 Psoralea 5pp................. .Wild alfalfa. PSO 20 Psoralea argophylla .......... Silver-leaved wild alfalfa .. PSO 20 Psora/ea lanceolata.; .Wild alfalfa PSO 20 Rumex spp .D0ck............. RUM 10 Salsola pestifer :.;.........'. .Russian thi5t1e......:........ SAL 20 Senecio riddellii ..... .....Riddell senecio .......... Sri 20. Sideranthus spinulosus...' . Cut-leaved sideranthus .... SID 0 Solidago spp.... Goldenrod .......;.... SOL 10 Taraxacum officinale..........Dandelion TAR 50 Trifolium spp. ......;..... ..Clover ..................... TRI 80 Triglochin maritima &#132;... Arrowgrass ................. Tma 10 Verbena 5pp.................81ue.vervain,. —........... VER 0 Vernonia spp. ..¦ .....¦..lronwced ¦¦;¦¦¦¦¦...... VERN 0 ¦ Shrubs . ¦' ' :.• '••• ¦ Amorpha canescens...........Prairie shoestring ..... ... AMO 20 Opuntia 5pp.................Prick1y pear —.... OPU 0 Prunus besseyi.. Sand cherry.. PRU 20 Rhus toxicodendron..........Poison ivy ..... .......... RHU .0 Rosa 5pp........... ..Wild rose.... ROS 20 Yuccaglauca... ".......... ..;Soapwced : .¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦ ;VUC 0 </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Acrici'ltvral Experiment Station Research Bulletin 117 APPENDIX II I )i mvvi ion or riir. Ft.RAi.i. Ai:kk Rf.quirkmf.nt pf.r Animal Month for the Grazing Lands of rut. Nebraska Sandhills (Ciikrry Coi;nty) According to tiie Stand - ards hi nil Si rviy. Forage acre Forage Forage requirement L&gt;cauon i.f pasture Acres acre factor acres per cow month Piercv—M 1 I- 45(1 O.IIAJ 28.4 2 55 0.134 7.4 i 15 11.091) 1.4 4 115 0.087 111.0 5 440 D.dS'J 26.4 73.6 0.090 hero—C 600 0.073 43.S 0.091 I'iercy—l I 1,465 0.067 98.1 2 30 0.070 2.1 3 70 0.077 5.4 4 15 0.066 1.0 5 60 0.090 5.-) 112.0 O.OHU I'icro— I) 1 840 0.065 5-1.5 2 295 0.069 20.3 3 4-15 0.060 26.7 101.5 0.125 Keller 1 227 0.030 6.8 2 1.133 0.062 70 2 77.0 0.175 Harms 1 352 0.066 23.2 2 128 0.069 8.8 32.0 0.154 I'iiro— A I 300 0.061 18.3 2 3.220 0.df.0 193.0 i 155 0.029 4.5 4 345 0.078 27.0 5 460 0.125 57.5 6 230 0.100 23.0 7 160 0.087 14.0 337.3 0.101 Average 0.117 ' Name of man upon whose ranch the pasture is located. -" Refers to vegetative types within a pasture. </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Nebraska Sandhill Range . literature cited 1. Condra, G. E. 1920. The Soil Resources of Nebraska. Univ. of Nebr. Cons, and Surv. Div. Bul.!l5. 2. Hedges, H. ',¦;.. 1928. Economic Aspects of the Cattle Industry of the Nebraska Sand - hills.Nebr. Agr. Exp; Sta. Bui. 231. 3. Hitchcock, A.JS. 1935. Manual of the Grasses of the United States. U.S.D.A. Misc. Pub. 200. 4. Kcim, F.'D., Frolik, A. L., and Beadle, G. W. 1932. Studies of Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. ißes. Bui. 60. 5. Intcr-agcncy Range Survpy Committee. '.'.'. 1937. Instructions for Range Surveys. Western Range Survey Conference. (Mimeo.) 6. Moran, W. ).,ietal. 1938. Soil Survey of Holt County, Nebraska. U.S.D.A. Bur. Chem. and Soils, Series 1932, No. 27. 7. Pool, R. J. 1914. A Study of the Vegetation of the Sandhills of Nebraska. Minn. Bot.;Studies 4:189-312. 8. Ppund, R., and Clements, F...E. • ¦ ¦ 1900. The Phytogeocraphy of Nebraska (2d cd.). Jacob North Jc Co., Lincoln. 9. Ramalcy, F. ' 1939. Sand-hill Vegetation of Northeastern Colorado. Ecol. Mono. 9:1-51. 10. Rydberg, P. A. 1895. Flora of the Sand Hills of Nebraska. Contrib. U. S. Nat. Herb. HI, 3. 11.. :¦" • 1932. Flora of the Prairies and Plains of Central North America. New : York Bot. Garden. 12. Smith, J. G. 1892. Grasses of the Sandhills of Northern Nebraska. Ann. Rep. Nebr. State Board Agr. 13.. —and Pound, R. 1892. Flora of the Sandhill Region of Sheridan and Cherry Counties and a List of Plants Collected on a Trip through the Sandhills in July and August, 1892. Bot. Surv. Nebr. 11. ; ; 14. Stewart, G., and Hutchings, S. S. 1936. The Point-observation-plot (Square-foot Density) Method of Vege - tation Survey. Jour, Amer. Soc. Agron. 28:714-722. 15. Stoddard, L. A., etal. 1938. Range Conditions in the Uinta Basin, Utah. Utah Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. .'283. '"'¦' - -16. U. S. Senate Document 199. ; 1936. The Western Range. 17. Van Es, L„ et al. 1929. On the Nature and Cause of "The Walking Disease" of North - western Nebraska. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 43. 18. Weaver, J. E., and Albertson, F. W. 1939. Major Changes in Grassland as a Result of Continued Drought. Bot. Gaz. 100:576-591. 19. Weaver, J. E., and Clements, F. E. 1938. Plant Ecology (2d cd.). McGraw-Hill Book Co. 20. Webber, H.J. 1889. The Grasses of Central Nebraska. Ann. Rep. Nebr. State Board Agri - culture. WV4MI &#132; </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>