<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00004">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00004</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FIFTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA, PRESENTED TO THE GOVERNOR JANUARY 30, 1902.</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
FIFTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT 

or thi 

Agricultural Experiment Station 

( *W 

NEBRASKA 

Presented to the Governor January 30, 1902. 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL. 

U. S. Agricultural Experiment Station, 

The University of Nebraska. 

To His Excetlency, H. P. Savage, Governor of Nebraska : 
Sir : — In accordance with the act of Congress approved 

Kh 2. 1887, and the act of the general assembly of the 
: of Nebraska approved March 31, 1887, establishing and 
ating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith 
omit the Fifteenth Annual Keport of the U. S. Agricul- 
Experiment Station of Nebraska. 

DimUrr. 

The University of Nebraska, January 29, 1902. 

GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE. 

State of Nebraska, Executive Department, 

Lincoln, January 30, 1902. 

KA. Burnett, Director V. S. Agricultural Experiment Staqf 
Nebraska : 
: — I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Fifteenth An- 

nual Report of the U. S. Agricultural Experiment Station 
of Nebraska. Ezra P. Savage, 


E. A. Burnett, </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION. 

THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY). 

E. v. Fokell, Kearney, President Term expires 1904 

Geo. F. Kenower. Wisner Term expires 1904 

Edson C. Rich, Omaha Term expires 1906 

Juo. L. Tketeks, Lincoln Term expires 1906 

Elisha C. Calkins, Kearney Term expires 1908 

Carl J. Eksst, Lincoln Term expires 1908 

J. S. Dales, Lincoln, Financial Secretary • 

THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE 

E v Fokell E. Benjamin Andrews E. A. Burnett 

THE VISITING COMMITTEE. 

4. WS K Bror «,. | "- Board of Agriculture 

E. F. Stephens The State Horticultural Society 

THE STATION OFFICERS 

E. A. Burnett, B. Sc Director and Animal Husbandman 

T. L. Lton, B. S. A Attuciate Director and Agriculturist 

Wm W. Marshall Extcutive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

A. T. Petbrs, D. V. M Animal Pathologist 

Charlks E BmM, Ph. D Botanist 

m H. Nicholson, M. A Chemist 

A U Haeckek, B. Sc. A Dairy Husbandman 

Lawrence Bblner, B. Sc Entomologist 

E. H. Barbouk, Ph. D Geologist 

R. A. Emerson, B Sc Horticulturist 

O. V. P. Stout, C. E Irrigation Engineer 

G. D. Swezey, MA Meteorologist 

A. T. Wiancko, B. 8. A Assistant Agriculturist 

H. R. Smith, B. Sc Assistant Animal Husbandman 

J. H. Gain, M. D. C Astittant Animal Pathologist 

Henry B. Slade, B. A Assistant Chemist 

S. W Perin Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm 

1 By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska approved and 

in effect February 16, 1899, the State Treasurer became exofflcio custodian 

of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1, 1899. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
TABLE OP CONTENTS. 

Report of the Director — page 

Experimental Work 7 

Staff 7 

Improvements 8 

Cooperative Experiments 8 

Station Extension 9 

Publications » 

Acknowledgments 10 

Financial Secretary's Report 11 

Some Forage Plants for Summer Feed— T. L. Lyon and A. L. 
Haecker 18 

Preliminary Account of Variation in Bean Hybrids — R. A. Emerson 80 

Study of Sorghum Poisoning in Cattle (Preliminary Report)— A. T. 
Peters N 

A Study of the Enzyms of Green Sorghum (Preliminary lleport)— 
Henry B. Slade 56 </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
FIFTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT. 

EXPERIMENTAL WORK. 

The work of the Experiment Station for the current year 
has been directed along the lines followed in previous years. 
Some new problems have been taken up along lines of animal 
pathology. The work in agriculture, animal husbandry 
and animal pathology has been strengthened by the addition 
of new workers. Special work has been done in immunizing 
hogs against cholera, in sorghum poisoning, and in cornstalk 
disease. Problems in soil culture, rotations of crops, 
forage, and cereal improvement are receiving attention 
in agriculture. The questions of hardy varieties of 
fruits, of mulches, of irrigation, and of hybridizing are 
under investigation in horticulture. The relative value of 
different kinds of roughness is engaging the attention of 
the departments of Animal Husbandry and Dairying. The 
Station Chemist is co-operating with other departments in 
analysis of grains and forage plants and with the department 
of Animal Pathology in an effort to discover the poisonous 
principles which sometimes cause death of horses and cattle 
on stalk fields and of cattle pastured on sorghum. 

STAFF. 

A number of changes in the staff have taken place. 
Chancellor E. Benjamin Andrews resigned the position of 
Director July 1, 1901. Mr. E. A. Burnett was elected to succeed 
him. 

Mr. A. L. Haecker was elected Dairy Husbandman and 
given full charge of the Department July 1. 

Br. R. W. Thatcher, Assistant Chemist, resigned August 
accept a position as Assistant Chemist of the Experi- 
I Station of the State of Washington. Mr. Henry B. 
e succeeded Mr. Thatcher on October 1, 1901. 

Dr. J. H. Gain was elected as Assistant in Animal Path- </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 

Agricultural Expcrimt anka 

ojogj •"iU^iisiij J.S7V/J.J aijQ iwr. yv . xi. J. licit r6siiTD©d. us T jfth 
oratory Assistant in Animal Pathology August 1, 1901. 

Mr. H. R. Smith was elected Assistant in Animal Husbandry 
and entered upon his duties October 1, 1901. 

On July 1, Mr. S. W. Perin was promoted to the position 
of Assistant in Agriculture, and Mr. A. T. Wiancko was appointed 
Assistant Agriculturist November 1. 

K. A. A. Hunter is doing special work in cornstalk diswith 
the Departments of Animal Pathology and Botunder 
appropriations granted by the Legislature of 
for special investigations of cornstalk disease. 

IMPROVEMENTS. 

E-ing the current year many improvements in equipment 
been made. The construction of a cattle barn by the 
irsity has increased the facilities for feeding cattle and 
iven better quarters for stock. 

§ Director's office has been moved to the northwest 
of the Station building, formerly occupied by the 
, and the Station library has been removed to the 
floor, directly above. 

Eie work of the Station has been promoted by the special 
•opriation of the Legislature of $2,500 for experiments 
ornstalk disease to be expended under the supervision 
le Department of Animal Pathology in co-operation with 
Departments of Botany and Chemistry. This work is 
? carried on and progress is reported. 

B Station has been furnished animals and feed by the 
rsity to carry on experiments in animal husbandry, so 
ttle expense was incurred by the Station in such work. 

CO-OPERATIVE EXPERIMENTS. 

Co-operative experiments have been undertaken by the Departments 
of Agriculture and Horticulture with the Agricultural 
Students' Association upon deep and shallow plowing 
of corn and with tests of mulches in the garden. The 
Department of Agriculture has furnished seed to carry on 
about five hundred tests of winter wheat m various parts of 
the State, especially in the west and north, in an effort to extend 
theTwinter wheat area. </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
9 

EU. S. Department of Agriculture is co-operating with 
llowing Departments of the Station ; Agriculture, in 
tring seeds of forage and grass plants for testing; 
&gt;1 Pathology, in distribution of blackleg vaccine; Horre, 
in cross-breeding certain varieties of corn ; Entoy, 
in distribution of the grasshopper fungous disease. 

STATION EXTENSION. 

Seven members of the Station staff have assisted in Farmers' 
Institutes during the past season. The addresses at 
these meetings furnish a means of disseminating information 
of the experiments conducted at the Station. It also furnishes 
the opportunity for Station men to become acquainted 
with the needs and conditions of the farmer, and enables him 
to bring out the practical features of the subject under investigation. 
Much is to be hoped for in this acquaintance of 
the experimenter with the practical conditions under which 
the farm operations are carried on, and much benefit will result 
from a mutual acquaintance and confidence between the 
Station experimenter and the producer who is to benefit by 
the results obtained. 

The Experiment Station is in close touch and sympatny 
with the work of all State societies which meet at the University 
each year, including the State Board of Agriculture, 
the State Horticultural Society, the State Dairymen's Association, 
the State Live Stock Breeders' Association, the State 
Swine Breeders' Association, the State Veterinary Medical 
Association, the State Poultry Association, etc. 

PUBLICATIONS. 

I accommodate the increased mailing list, bulletins are 
published in fifteen and twenty thousand editions, and 
Annual Report, containing the financial statement and 
i of the more technical experimental work of the Departs, 
is published in an edition of 2,500 copies. 

The publications of the Station during the period covered 
by this Report are as follows : 

Fourteenth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor 
January 24,^901. </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 


Fin No. 68 (Vol. XIII, Art. III). Feeding Skim- 
Calves. By A. L. Haecker. Distributed March 22, 

Bulletin No. 69 (Vol. XIII. Art. IV). Some Forage 
Plants for Summer Feed. By T. L. Lyon and A. L. Haecker. 
Distributed March 30, 1901. 

Bulletin No. 70 (Vol. XIII, Art. V). Locusts or Grasshoppers. 
By Lawrence Bruner. Distributed March 30, 

Kletin No. 71 (Vol. XIV, Art. I). Sheep Feeding Exents 
in Nebraska. (Second Experiment.) By E. A. 
itt. Distributed September, 1901. 

ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. 

The Station is indebted to the following persons or corporations 
for favors received during the year : 

1M. Allen, land and labor for sugar beet experiments. 
)paganda for Nitrate of Soda, fertilizer. 

German Kali Works, fertilizer. 
Swift &amp; Co., fertilizer. 

Wohanka &amp; Co., sugar beet seed 

American Steel and Wire Co., 80 rods woven wire fence 
and gate. 

Eureka Grain Grader Co., grain grader. 

Kansas Experiment Station, winter wheat and inoculated 

Iowa Experiment Station, winter wheat. 
Ohio Experiment Station, winter wheat. 
Burlington &amp; Missouri River R. R. 

IE. &amp; M. V. Ry. 
ion Pacific Ry. 
R. I. &amp; P. Ry. 

Missouri Pacific Ry. Co., etc. 

Ee number of home and foreign newspapers on agrisubjects 
are exchanged with the Station for bulle- </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
11 

Fifteenth Annual Report 

FINANCIAL SECRETARY'S REPORT 

THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA 

FINANCE OFFICE 

The Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 

in Account with the United States 

Appropriation of 1900-1901 

RECEIPTS 

Received by the State Treasurer, from the Treasurer 
of the United States, the Congressional appropriation 
for the year ended June 30. 1901 116,000 00 

EXPENDITURES. 

Salaries I 8.368 88 

Labor 2,62166 

Publications K*3 *1 

Postage and stationery 499 94 

Freight and express 129 SI 

Chemical supplies 116 43 

Seeds, plants and sundry supplies 646 08 

Fertilizers 5 00 

Feeding stuffs 160 00 

Library 226 fi« 

Tools, implements and machinery 201 28 

Furniture and fixtures 91 60 

Scientific apparatus 442 26 

Live stock 66 75 

Traveling expenses 265 *» 

Contingent expenses 24 IS 

Building and repairs 574 16 

$15,000 00 S15.000 00 

J. S. Dales, 

Financial Secretary. </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 


FINANCIAL SECRETARY'S REPORT 

The Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 

Supplemental Statement 

Receipts and expenditures for the benefit of said Station, 
of moneys received from other sources than the United 
States, for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1901 ; received and 
disbursed by the State Treasurer as a part of the University 
Cash fund : 

SI, 894 78 11,894 78 
J. S. Dales, 

Financial Secretary. 

State of Nebraska, | 
Lancaster County, f 

It is hereby certified that the accompanying report of the 
Financial Secretary of the Agricultural Experiment Station 
of Nebraska, for the year ended June 30, 1901, together with 
the supplemental statement thereto, has been carefully compared 
from time to time, by the finance committee of the 
Board of Regents of the University of Nebraska, with the 
books of account and the vouchers filed, found correct and 
approved. (Signed) E. v. Forell, 

President of the Board of Regents of the 
I'nivernty of Nebraska and the Gov- 

erning Board of said Station. 

Lincoln, Nebraska, January H, 1902. 

Balance June 80. 1900 
Farm products, stock, services, etc 

t 689 01 
1,205 77 

EXPENDITIRES 

Band stationery 
and express 
riants and sundry supplies 
stuffs 
mplemen ts and machinery 
re and fixtures 
«k 
June 80, 1901 

I 

170 28 
10 60 
148 16 
81 04 
268 17 
127 66 
7 16 
148 88 
M M </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
13 


SOME FORAGE PLANTS FOR SUMMER FEED.' 

BY T. L. LYON AND A. L. HAECKER. 

A very important phase in the present trend of farm practice 
is the substitution of annual forage plants for permanent 
pastures and meadows. This is especially pronounced in 
the trans-Missouri and other western states. It is the result 
of an attempt to obtain a larger amount of pasturage or 
rough feed for winter use from a given area of land, and is 
naturally most largely followed in regions where perennial 
grasses and clovers grow less luxuriantly and where the 
natural fertility of the soil is sufficient to endure such treatment. 
To be immediately profitable the increased feed produced 
must more than counterbalance the added yearly expense 
for tilling the soil and planting the seed. In estimating 
the ultimate profit, the latter charge must have added 
to it the greater deterioration in the soil when cropped continuously 
than when periodically seeded to grasses or clovers. 

OBJECT OF THESE EXPERIMENTS. 

kin conducting the experiments to be described, the object 
s been to gather information on the following points of inrest 
to farmers and others : 

1. The relative values of certain forage plants for pmsturage 
by milch cows. 

I The relative values of some of these forage plants for 
soiling milch cows. 

»The values of certain of these crops for milk and butt 
production when pastured, as compared with the value 
3 same crops when soiled. 

The pasturage tests carried on in 1900 were a repetition of 

¦An abstract or this report wu published as Bulletin No 89 of this </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

Agricultural Experiment Station of Neb, 

those made in 1898, ' the intention being to note such variaation 
as might be induced by a difference in climatic conditions 
or in the individual preference or aversion of animals 
for a certain feed. 

PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT. 

Plots of land, one-fifth acre in size, were sown to each of 
the forage crops to be tested. The crops raised on these 
plots were sown at the time of year considered most favorable 
for the germination of the seed and development of the 
plant. This had been ascertained approximately in previous 

When a crop on a test plot intended to be pastured reached 
a stage of growth at which it was considered fit to pasture, 
it was fenced by a system of movable fencing, and one of the 
dairy cows was placed 'in the enclosure. The cow was allowed 
to remain on the plot day and night as long as it afforded 
sufficient pasturage. She was then removed, and the 
number of days she was kept on the plot was taken as indicating 
the length of time that one-fifth acre of the crop in 
question would maintain one cow. One acre may then be regarded 
as affording pasturage for five cows for the period of 
time determined by the test. Water was brought to them in 
tbe paddocks, and during midsummer shade was provided in 
the corner of each plot. 

!hen the crop was to be soiled, cutting was begun on the 
e day that the cow was turned on the similar crop fenced 
lasturage. As much green forage as was needed for one 
was cut daily until the entire crop on trie plot was coned. 
In some cases a one-tenth acre plot was used for the 
ng test. The cow used in the test was kept in a box 
in a cool, darkened barn and received the green feed 
h daily. Both in the pasture and in the barn the cows 
ived durine the summer of 1900 no other feed except a 
If ul of grain at milking time. In 1898 each cow received 
pounds of bran and two of ground corn daily. 

Each cow was pastured, in 1900, on a mixed grass pasture 
composed of prairie grasses, blue grass, brome grass and 

'Nebr. Station. Bull. 58. </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 


wdiig clover, ior st ie&amp;si on© ffloniiu oeiore Deing placed od 
the test crop whether soiled or pastured, and for at least one 
month afterwards. An exception to this occurred in the 
tenon of the cows pastured on rye, for which test they were 
taken off of dry feed. For convenience the time is divided 
into Periods I, II, and III. 

Period I constitutes the month previous to the time the 
cow was put on the test crop. 

Period II is the time she was on the test crop, with the exception 
of the first five days. The first five days were not 
included in this period because it was desired to ascertain 
the effect of the feed upon the animal, and it was considered 
that this could not be definitely noted until five days after 
the change in feed had been made. The second period varies 
in length, depending upon the time during which the animal 
was pastured or soiled upon the test crop. 

Period III is the month following the time she was taker 
off the test crop, excluding the first five days. 

During Period I, the cows were weighed once a week: 
during Period II, twice a week; and during Period III, once 
a week. It was desired to ascertain whether the animal lost 
or gained in weight on the test crop, as compared with the 
mixed grasses. It was therefore necessary to show whether 
she was gaining or losing during Periods I and III, and to 
compare this with the gain or loss during Period II. For 
this purpose the average of the first two weighings of each 
period was compared with the average for the last two, as 
indicating a gain or loss in live weight. It was considered 
that this would show the tendency to increase or decrease in 
weight more accurately than would a comparison of the 
average weights for each period. A gradual increase in 
weight might be expected, owing to the advance in the 
period of lactation. The cows were milked twice a day 
throughout the three periods. Each milking was weighed, 
all milkings for each period added and divided by the number 
of days in the period to show the average daily, milk production 
for that period. The average daily milk yield for 
the three periods may then be compared to indicate the effect 
of the feed upon the milk flow. A gradual falling off is to </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 


be expected owing to the advance in the period of lactation. 

The percentage of butter fat was determined semiweekly 
in composite samples of the milk. The total weight of milk 
for the period multiplied by the average per cent of butter 
fat was taken as representing the total weight of butter fat 
produced, and this figure divided by the number of days in 
the period as giving the average daily production of butter 
fat. This may also be expected to decrease gradually with 
the advance in the period of lactation. 

Ke fact that the cows pastured differed from one another 
ly in respect to the amount of milk and butter fat prol 
does not, of course, invalidate the experiment, for 
test crop is compared directly with the mixed grasses, 
Dnly indirectly with the others, through their relations 
i mixed grasses taken as the standard. 

Table I shows side by side the results obtained with each 
crop in 1898 and in 1900. It must be remembered, however, 
that in 1898 the cows were pastured on alfalfa during Periods </seg>


            <seg id="p017">
17 

I 

•Jt»jiv «nnr a^inr sr^.T 8 S3 

imdMOQ ! -ft Xinf SI *nv S SS * 5 § 

SMdj.00 1 « 1&lt;J»8 

¦6!-ld*B '¦ ES g * 

X!D *• 

QJOO 

&gt; Sny ?i^™* * *? 

¦&gt;B«H SliQAl *' f Inf 

Cans *»¦ 

oet- 

mnqSJog 9 

i 

n any ji"S S 8 SS 

ronq&amp;ios si Xinf 

ismw Kaonr -Sl^inf | t: 2 *^ 

S3 

?I 3-1 

3 5 5 3 

19IIIK 41 t IOf 

? Utiv 


njoo nsipni gg aanf 'iXinf *"^^ ' * 1* 

O X X 

*^ia 8Xinf ! » 1 *™ | **Z* R e S 

J»«X™iqM »*™ W 1 ""- -fLl *¦ 

! ojoo n»|pni oeaonr ft *P&gt;r S^ 8 * 8 6 S3 
Z-l ' saa - 
I P « M^o «"* «~«r z**% * » S2 

1 »Jgo »°"f w igg g ¦ «S 
I »*h ttnt u*m s^5 t s ss 

i ¦ 
- 

a 

»^a 

I *»K 

IS **K 

S»3 

s a? 

— 

g i 

ai 

aXH 

&lt;H 

SS» 2 2 SJC 
838 - - - 

* I 

: 

| 
I 

E 
I 
I 

¦ : . a" : a : a . : 
: : : .3 is :¦§ ; ; 
¦ -m o • o ¦ a 
siiis || i| || 
ifftfiptii 
z«^.&lt; &lt; &lt; a 

3 
I </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 


ANALYSIS OF PASTURAGE TESTS IN 1900. 

Relative Amounts of Pasturage Furnished. 

A glance at Table I shows that the crop furnishing the 
largest amount of pasturage auy one year was sorghum in 
the summer of 1898. In 1900 a much smaller amount of feed 
was secured from this plant. The crop giving the greatest 
amount of feed in 1900 was rye. The annual plants furnished 
considerably more feed than the perennials, alfalfa 
and Bromux inn- mix. Cowpeas furnished a third more pasturage 
than alfalfa, and of fully as good quality. This, however, 
was during a limited period, to which pasturage on 
cowpeas must be confined more or less closely. Alfalfa and 
Bromus inermis can, on the other hand, be pastured early and 
late. It will be noticed that five one-fifth acre plots were 
required to furnish pasturage continuously from May 1 to 
August 13. This is, in other words, one acre of land for 
each animal during that period, which is not a particularly 
large feed production, nor would it seem to be a very profitable 
use of the land when the cost of annually preparing the 
soil and sowing the crop is taken into consideration. To be 
sure, the amount of pasturage obtained from one-fifth acre 
of alfalfa or Btmmtu tmtrmk does not compare favorably even 
with these figures, as it would require two acres of alfalfa 
and nearly four acres of Bromiw inermin to furnish pasturage 
for the same length of time when calculated in the 
same way. As far, therefore, as can be judged from these 
experiments the permanent pastures require from two to 
four times as much land for each animal as do the annuals. 

One important feature of the annual plants is the season at 
which they furnish abundant succulent feed. 

Many of the permanent pastuie grasses cease growing during 
the hot and dry weather of midsummer and early fall. 

Bsuch times cows are tormented with flies, and with the 
i dry grass for feed they are apt to greatly decrease in 
milk flow and thus spoil them for profitable fall and 
r producers. </seg>


            <seg id="p019">
19 

~ 

I 9 af« *- •« « 
I Z 8i H o + 4- 

- 

+ 

* 

a 

'l. 

r 

&gt; 

a : £ 

fS 

tt 

i 

?: 

I : t £ 

? S 

&gt; 

_a . — ¦ ; 
as a - a 
S « a c &lt; 

7 

i 

I 

"3 

I 


*~i : re = 

atnoi}] 

+ 

¦4 

1 

"¦il'llV I 

S 

8 

I 

m*i«o3 

?T 

I 

svadMo.-) I $ 

I 

7 

S 

•moo 

? 

— 

•UJO3 

1 

9 
+ 

~55" 
+ 

T 

f 

5 

III II q?f.li &gt;s 

•1»II!K I 

inii|j(jiis I ijl *y 
+ 4- 
S " S~ 
-v&gt;nm % + * 
•wihk [I 5. t + 
njoa 2 § S 
n«!POI 1 + + 

! i 

S I 

5 

If 
— 

•QJ0.1 
nBiinq - 
SB.lJ 
pg« »i«o I 
SKOll I J 

+ 
T" 

I 
I: 

B </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 


average gain or loss in live weight for Periods I and 
III as expressed in the second line of the table is determined 
by adding the gain or loss in live weight for each of these 
periods, and dividing by two. It indicates the average gain 
or loss on the mixed grasses for one month, and by eliminating 
any change due to advance in the period of lactation 
gives a result which may with perfect fairness be compared 
with the loss or gain for Period II. The latter period varies 
in length in different tests, but this does not affect the significance 
of the comparison. 

"The third line shows the increased gain or loss of weight 
on the test crop. 

Ki figures obtained in 1900 are not of much significance. 
o»nt indicated is a greater loss of weight when legumicrops 
were fed, confirming in this the results of I 
ass on Kafir corn was, however, greater than on either 
i legumes, but this is possibly due to an error in weigh* 
to the animal losing in condition. 

Kspt in the case of Kafir corn the crops that occasioned 
rease in the production of butter fat occasioned the 
; falling off in live weight. 

It will be noticed that there was considerable variation in 
the loss of weight on the duplicate plots of rye. 

A great difficulty was experienced in obtaining accurate 
weights, due to the irregular habits of the animals on the test. 
For although the animals were weighed before watering, 
they varied greatly as to their time for grazing and this 
feature alone would cause a difference of from fifty to sixty 


a </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
, I 

i nfjf dcnojg j 

I 

0 W JL 

«»!«;iv 

! 

S»*lMOJ 

¦i • I 

1 

SIjdMO.I 

3 B . « 
2 2 -j- 

§ 

« fc 8 
» 00 j 

i 

njoo 

s « a 
« 43 — 

¦ 

-r 

s a s 
S 2 7 

I 

| 

uinqSJOS 

f 

i 

I 

mnqAios 

19II1H 

S « ? 
s w s 
:¦ £ ?• 
Sc 8 Z 
887 

I 
s. 

I 

latHH 

I 

I 

* S 8 
* « i 

oioo unipui 

i 

« S 3 
S 8 7 
s »; i 

oj&lt;» o*ipni 

OJOO Olipnl 

is a s 
5 8 7 

1 T 

r»sdpnnBi«o 

= S 8 
2 !! I 

II 

I 

8 S 8 
8 8" S 
" ; » 

I 

! 

»*H 

= * 1 

| 

a.«M 

S 8 « 
8 S ~ 

H 

1: 
ill 
¦:ll 
o : o jj 
5 ? I 
6 5 J 
1= 1 5 
I- I I 

! 

- </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 


In order to make a fair comparison of the milk flow on the 
test crops and on the mixed grasses the average daily milk 
flow for Periods I and III is given. The decrease due to advance 
in the period of lactation is thus compensated. 

Itcept in the case of cowpeas, alfalfa, and Bromus inermis 
e was a decrease in the milk flow when the cows were 
ured on the test crops. This decrease, except in the case 
wnus ine /-»«!&gt;, distinguished the leguminous crops from the 
rs. White Kafir corn occasioned the least falling off of 
of the other crops, and rye, oats and peas, Indian corn, 
sorghum had a nearly similar effect upon the milk flow, 
e millet ranked somewhat below the others as a milk 
ucer. 

Elie tendency of the cows to shrink in milk and butter 
production while on the plot would be more likely to ocowing 
to the changed environment. 

E nearly all cases the animal was taken from the herd 
re she had an abundance of rich pasture of mixed grasses 
placed on the plot, where she remained night and day 
i but one kind of forage to eat. 

The flies and heat were nearly always bad at this season of 
the year, which in itself often causes a shrinkage in flow- </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
a 

1 

miSMKUg 

,. 

l 

«»I*JIV 

8 

jL 

. . 

T 

T-l! 

I 

nadMOQ 

»• 

Z 2] 

bixlaoj 

-Ll 

¦ 

1g U1O3 

2 

I 

fc 

Tl 

UJO.1 

E 

I 

I 

mnqSJCS 

t 

I 

I 

T" 

mnqaios 

~¥ 

«~8 
I 

1 

I 

»»IHH 

1' 

1 

T 1 s t i 
i»init - 1 
g uoo a« pa I j 1 

1 

I 

I " 

uoo a«ipai 

~ff 

I 

,= 

I " 

pu» »i»o 

8 

3 S 
I 

c 

pin n«o 

8 

r 

1 

i 

1 

*h| 

~8 

s = 
I 

~8 

l" 

1 

«i 

s 

I 

WtH 

= 8 
- + 

3 

I 

a : a 
3 i 31 ¦ 
ill 
fill 
ijj i| ] </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 


alfalfa and cowpeas, again accentuating the value of leguminous 
plants for feeding milch cows. 

Ere in 1900 proved to be one of the poorest feeds for proog 
butter fat, while in 1898 it was one of the best. The 
for 1898 was with a cow that was nearly fresh and that 
increasing in milk and butter production when put on 
jlot. This without doubt largely accounts for the inse 
as shown in the table. 

Millet was the poorest in 1898 and one of the two poorest 

Oats and peas, Indian corn, sorghum, and Kafir corn were 
of intermediate value both years. 

COMPARISON OF SOILING AND PASTURING CERTAIN CROPS. 

Eiring the summers of 1899 and 1900, tests were made with 
; of these crops to determine the relative amounts of 
furnished by a given area of land when used for pasig 
and when used for soiling ; also the effect upon the 
weight, milk flow and butter fat production when the 
s crops were fed in each of these ways. Table V shows 
•esults obtained during each period in these tests. </seg>


            <seg id="p025">
25 



5 S S 5 S§g 8 S 

njoo 

n«,p nl ; P^n'".! 

I o» ao I in 

«JI«JIV S 5 8 8 55 ¦ 

X 

» 

«JI"JIV 

« 

S 39 

I a »7 

I 

"•JWIV paituwj • ***.*-. S S 

I 

?» 

j_ Tl ?J 

W 

njoo § S 2 I S3 
n«T Pni P 8 "^ - | § goo 

,isr 

i 

1 

¦mnqjjjoy 

P9IJOS 

¦ 

Z 

S l' 

arnqJijos 
ranqSjog 

P9|ios 

I 

I 
f 
I 

s 

— e 
8 I 

8 

C i 

i 

i\* 

ranqjljos 

paaaiBVj 

I 

s 

s 
l" 

90 
f, 

S3 

? 

! 

I 
1 

1 
! 

i 
¦ 
a 

a '. 
Ij 
22 
k. a 
— — 
il 
il 
T3CU 
¦ 

3 : ft. g :g 
O O x a&gt; 
© «" © ® •"" ® ¦-" © ( „ c J4 </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
Agricultural Experiment Station of Neb\ 

'/ j.*i 

ll 

pfl[lOS 
naoo iiBipui 

* 

s 

x 
I 

- 

I'- 

'pajn)S'«(l 
njo.) nBipnj 

OS 
7 

s 
r 

f 

i 

pajujsBd 

7 

§ 

o&gt; 

i 

5 

«JI«JIV 

T 

t 

£ 

4 
f 

pajn)B«d 

+ 

I 

! 

«JI«JIV 

I 
I* 

paiios 

X 

I 
I 

S 

ninq8jo§ 

tnnq&amp;ioc; 

1-1 

o 
1 

S 

i 
i 

cnnqftios 

P9[IOS 

nnu|2tj(&gt;s 

m 
i 

+ 

ee 

7 

o 
7 

t 

H 
J 
3 

I 
I 

I . t : | : 
~3 ~ : o : 
¦!¦ ° : — " 
a : : 
5 * m ' ~ - 
»J k] «l 
l £ &gt; </seg>


            <seg id="p027">

pa[ios 
nao3 I 

I 

s 

I 

'pdjnisvd 

1 
3&gt; 

00 

s 
f 

ajoo 

I 

f 

pajnisBcI 

5 

I 

pa(ios 

-p3[IO8 

i 

¦ 

I 

I 

! 

_ 

r 
painisBd 

s 
I 

i 

1 

P3|IOS 
lunqiljos 

I 

¦ 

I 

pajnjsBd 
ninq2jotj 
p«[!os 
mnq8aos 

I 
so 

s 
I 
I 

s 
09 
s 
T 

p«[!os 
mnq8aos 

I 
I 

s 
T 

* 

tnnq3jo«; 

O 
a 

s 
CO 

I 

¦3 : -g : "g : 
.2 : -c : -c : 
t* 33 • I 
£ : &lt;2 : (£ : 
| I I*! lj 
• : i I ! 
I : ¦ • I : 
&gt;? '¦ "o : 
1= I j • ; 
H ?= 1= 
4 4 1 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
M 

Agricultural Expermttmk station of Nebr 

¦k 

x 

pajios 

ajoo 

3 § § 

pajniped 

ojoo 

* 

»- » e 

pajnjsBil 

«JI«JIV 

¦&lt; 

71 

»} 

•pa|ios 

oj ao « 
eo sfi o 

•paarnssd 

«JI«J[V 

K 

g 2 E 


pa[ios 


mnqiijot; 

: 

|&gt; pajnimd * B 

&lt;B 

»- t- 

uinqajos 

« 

2 

pojinsBd 
mnqSaog 

3 » o 

= 

s 

c 

? : I 

£ : g . S 

&amp; : £ 

3 

J!-o i : -2 
s~ Id § 
5-8 *¦« E 

&gt; 


eS 

J&amp;l I 

I 

|§ §8" 1 : 

! 

¦&gt;&gt;¦ M 

C" to 3; sj 

5t = c </seg>


            <seg id="p029">
29 

AMOUNTS OF FEED PRODUCED. 

Erill be noticed that the difference in food production 
from less than two to more than three times as much 
soiled as when pastured. Economy in the use of land 
arked feature in the practice of soiling. 

Kan corn produced less feed when soiled than did either 
um or alfalfa. Sorghum produced the greatest amount 

Ere is very little to be learned from this table of live 
ts. There seems to be no uniformly greater or less 
n in weight from either soiling or pasturing. Alfalfa 
oned, on the whole, a greater loss of weight than either 
other crops. (See Table VI. ) 

I all tests, with but one exception, the amount of milk 
need daily by the crops when pastured was greater than 
i the same crops were soiled. The average difference 
Ik yield for the pasturing over the soiling was 2.95 lbs. 
lay for each cow. (See Table V. ) 

I ere was uniformly a greater amount of butter fat pro-1 
daily by each crop when pastured than when soiled, 
average increased production of butter fat occasioned 
asturing all crops tested was . 14 lbs. per cow per day. 
would amount to about .16 lbs. butter calculated to an 
¦un of one-sixth. (See Table V.) 

Accepted for publication March 25, 1902. </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 


PRELIMINARY ACCOUNT OF VARIATION IN BEAN 
HYBRIDS. 

BY K. A. EMEKSON. 

INTRODUCTION. 

Now that practical plant breeding is being given more attention 
than ever before by horticulturists generally and 
particularly by Experiment Station workers, it is important 
that the principles underlying plant improvement be given 
special study. At present there are few well-established 
laws of plant improvement. The assertion that there are no 
laws of hybridization, that the whole subject is empirical, 
is perhaps true at present, but it does not follow that laws 
will never be found. Work like that of Gregor Mendel with 
peas 1 must be done with many groups of plants before it can 
be said that there are no laws of variation in hybrids. Likewise 
the direct effect of a plant's environment in originating 
definite variations must be studied extensively before any 
general statement can be made regarding it. 

The writer's work in hybridizing beans is the beginning 
of what it is hoped may some day yield important results. 
The work was begun at Washington, D. C, in 1898, and has 
been continued at Lincoln, Nebr., since the spring of 1899. 
The study has now progressed far enough to afford a fairly 
accurate idea of the quality of variation in bean hybrids. 
The next step must be a quantitative study of variation. 
From such study only can we hope to arrive at general laws 
of variation and inheritance. Statistical studies, however, 

E'Abhandlungen des Naturforschenden Vereines in Briiun, Bd. IV, 
(1866), translated in Journal of Royal Horticultural Society, Vol. 
VI. pp. 8 88, (1901). </seg>


            <seg id="p031">
31 

Buire large numbers of individuals. Certain characters 
iously yield themselves to quantitative determination 
re readily than others. 

SELECTION OF KACES. 

The work has been confined for the most part to dwarf 
and semidwarf races of the common kidney bean, Phaseohu 
vulgaris. Some work has been done with dwarf races of the 
small and large Lima beans, P. lunutus and P. lunatw* macrocarpus 
respectively, but this has not been carried far enough 
to yield important results. Attempts at crossing Lima 
beans with kidney beans have so far been unsuccessful. 
This paper, therefore, has to do only with racial hybrids 
of kidney beans. 

For the first work, races were chosen which differ as widely 
as possible from each other in one or more of their characters. 
Some of the more important characters that have 
been combined in various ways are yellow, green, and bluegreen 
pods, stringy and stringless pods, long and short pods, 
round and flat pods, white, red, brown, black, and variously 
mottled seeds, oblong and nearly round seeds, etc. In later 
work, which has had some practical as well as theoretical 
bearing, races have been united to secure in their hybrids 
certain definite preconceived combinations of characters. 

METHODS OF WORK. 

The parent races once selected, several seeds are planted 
in flowerpots in the greenhouse and each plant is given a 
number to distinguish it from other individuals of the same 
race, as, for instance, (1) Davis, (3) Mohawk. The numbers 
are recorded with the names of the races on all labels and in 
all notes. The plants are started at any time during winter, 
the only precaution necessary being to have them mature 
their hybridized seeds in time for spring planting out of 
doors. Repeated attempts to hybridize beans in the field 
during summer in this climate have resulted in almost total 
failure, while success has always followed the greenhouse 
work. Under more favorable conditions field work would 
have the important advantage over greenhouse work of af- </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
32 



fording large numbers of individuals from which to select 
parent plants of special merit. 

Kidney beans are perfectly self-fertile. In a warm, dry 
atmosphere the anthers begin discharging pollen as soon as 
anner petal of the flower bud begins to unfold and behe 
bud has opened sufficiently to expose the wing petals 
(PI. I, fig. 3). The writer has often observed pollen grains 
on the stigma of a partially expanded flower, though the 
main part of the.'pollenjs caught by the hairs on the style 
just beneath the stigma."^ It therefore becomes necessary to 
emasculate the flower buds before they begin to open. Since 
emasculation — a difficult operation in bean flowers at best — 
is more difficult in case of very small buds (PI. I, fig. 2), and 
the Bower buds increase in size rapidly just before 
opening, emasculation is delayed until shortly before the 
bud opens (PI. I, fig. 4). The bud is carefully opened (PI. 
I. fig. ."(with a small pair [of forceps. The spiral keel is 
torn open at the upper end, exposing the stigma and anthers 
(PI. I, fig. 6). The latter are carefully pinched off without 
injuring the pistil (PI. I, fig. 7). The stigma is usually receptive 
at the time emasculation is performed. Pollen from 
another race is therefore applied at once. To accomplish 
this a pistil with its load of pollen (PI. I, fig. 8) is torn from 
a mature flower (PI. I, fig. 1) of the race which is to be used 
as staminate parent, and the pollen is rubbed off onto the 
stigma of the emasculated flower bud. If pollen is scarce, a 
single anther is held on a pin point and pollen adhering to 
: ubbed off onto the stigma. A label bearing the record 
of |the hybridization'and a number corresponding to a notebook 
entry is then fastened to the flower stalk and the hybridized 
flower is covered with a paper sack (PI. I, fig. 10), 
to afford protection*against insect pollination. This protection 
is often unnecessary in'the greennouse^but is always 
used to insure against possible accident. After a few days, 
when the pods have set, (PI. I, fig. 9,) the sacks are removed 
in order that the pods may develop normally. 

¦ien ripe, the hybridized seed is gathered and compared 
self -fertilized seed from] the two parent plan ts to deterwhether 
any tendency toward xenia exists. When all </seg>


            <seg id="p033">
33 

danger of frost is past (about June 1), the seed is planted 
in the garden. At first it was the custom of the writer to 
plant the seed and grow the first generation of the hybrids 
in the greenhouse and then grow the second generation out 
of doors, thus growing three generations in a single season, 
but the practice has been abandoned. It is good where 
quick results are desired, as, for instance, in teaching hybridization 
to students, but much more satisfactory results 
are secured in the long run by growing the hybrids in the 
garden, where they usually yield a larger crop than in the 
greenhouse. 

Before the hybrid plants growing in the garden begin 
blossoming, each individual is covered with a cage of wire 
netting (PI. I, fig. 11) to prevent cross-pollination by insects. 
This is necessary where the object of hybridization is the 
study of variation in the hybrids, but is probably unnecessary 
where the object is merely the improvement of beans 
by hybridization. The writer has found only about four per 
cent of hybrid forms in lots of bean plants the preceding 
generation of which was grown in a field with over one 
hundred races most of which were in blossom at one time. 
Notes are kept of the peculiarities of the hybrid plants. 
When ripe, the seed is gathered and compared with seed of 
the parent races. Samples of the seeds and pods and sometimes 
of other parts of the hybrid plants are saved for comparison 
with future generations. The rest of the seed is 
kept until the following spring and suwn to produce the 
second generation. Plants of the second and third generations 
and sometimes of the fourth generation are treated 
like those of the first generation. 

When the hybrids have passed their period of great variation 
and appear fairly well fixed, which usually occurs in the 
fourth or fifth generation, the seeds of any plant which it is 
desired to test further are planted together at a considerable 
distance from other beans and the plants are grown without 
protection from insects. 

Be the object of the writer's work with hybrid beans 
en mainly to study variation, he has not practiced seuntil 
satisfied that the new types had become fairly </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
34 


B"" 11 established. When the object is the improvement of 
s by hybridization, selection could well be started in the 
I generation and sometimes even in the second generaonly 
plants showing desirable qualities being preserved. 

VARIATION IN THE FIRST AND LATER GENERATIONS. 

Gaertner believed that variety hybrids show marked dissimilarities 
even in the first generation, while specific hybrids 
are quite uniform. Focke' agrees with Gaertner only 
if by variety is meant an unstable form, and states that racial 
hybrids are commonly as uniform in the first generation as 
are specific hybrids. Webber and Swingle say :* 

"Almost all who have worked extensively in hybridizing 
plants have noted the curious fact that races of cultivated 
plants, even though very diverse, produce very variable hybrids 
in the first generation, while usually by crossing wild 
species closely resembling each other hybrids are obtained 
which are constant in the first generation." 

In a later article, however, Webber says :• 

''In the crossing of races and species the hybrids in the 
first generation are usually nearly alike, exhibiting in general 
the same intermediate characters. In the second generation 
of these hybrids, however,' there is almost invariably 
iter variation." 

All racial hybrids of beans yet produced by the writer 
show little variation in the first generation and pronounced 
variation in the second and third generations. A few examples 
will illustrate this. PI. II, figs. 3-6, show sample 
seeds from four hybrid individuals of the first generation of 
Golden W&lt;*x x Mohawk. While not exactly alike, they are 
as nearly so as the individuals of either parent race (PL II, 
figs. 1, 2). In the second geneisation (PI. II, figs. 7-21) great 
variation is seen in size, shape, and color markings. The 
pods produced in the second generation are as diverse as the 
seeds, some being green, some yellow, and some greenishyellow, 
some being stringy, like those of Mohawk (PI. II, 
fig. 40), some nearly stringless, like those of Golden Wax 

¦ Pflanzen-Mtschlinge, pp. 472. 489 

'United States Department of Agriculture Yearbook. 1897. p. 8M. 
'Cyclopedia of American Horticulture. Vol. HI. p. 1865. </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
Fifteenth Animal Report 

35 

(PI. II, fig. 39), and others showing various intermediate 
forms. In the third generation the variation is continued 
(PI. II, figs. 22-30). The twenty individuals (PI. II, figs. 
) grown from seed, like that shown in PI. II, fig. 14, are 
certainly remarkably uniform in color markings but exhibit 
considerable difference in shape. Furthermore, the pods of 
these same individuals were very unlike. Those bearing the 
seeds shown in PI. II, fig. 24, were stringy, while those bearintrthe 
seeds shown in PI. II, fig.25,-were nearly string 
some of the pods were green, some yellow, and some greenish-yellow. 
In the fourth generation the same striking uniformity 
in color markings is seen (PI. II, figs. 33, 34). There 
11 some difference in shape of seeds, however. One 
plant of each group had stringy pods, all the others having 
practically stringless ones. In color the pods were uniformly 
greenish-yellow. In the fifth generation (PI. II, fig-18) 
the individuals of each group were as uniform as those 
of most races. (Compare PI. II, figs. 1, 2.) The plair 
each group were uniform in habit of growth. The pods were 
all rather long, flat, yellow, nearly stringless. The seeds of 
each group are uniform in shape, size, and color markings. 
This uniformity is the more remarkable when it is noted that 
the characters of these fifth-generation hybrids appeared in 
the third generation. (Compare PI. II, figs. 36, 31, 23, 13; 
37, 32, 23, 13; 38, 35, 30, 21.) Davis x Blue Pod (PI. Ill, figs. 
19, 20).and reciprocally Blue Pod x Davis (PI. Ill, fig-28) 
gave rise to seven individuals of the first generation (PI. 
Ill, figs. 21-23, 29-32), all of which were remarkably alike 
not only in seeds but also in plants, pods, and flowers The 
second generation (PI. Ill, figs. 24-26, 33-36), was made up 
of very dissimilar individuals. Keeney x Davis (PI. Ill, 
figs. 1,2) yielded a few forms in the second generation (PI. 
Ill, figs. 4-8). One of the individuals of the second generation 
(PI. Ill, fig. 6) produced several quite distinct thirdgeneration 
forms (PI. Ill, figs. 10-17.) Uniformity in the 
first generation is shown in PI. Ill, fig. 56, the result 
of Navy x Challenge Black (PI. Ill, figs. 54, 55), and in PI. 
Ill, figs. 62, 63, the progeny of Currie x Golden Wax (PI. Ill, 
figs. 61, 60). The uniformity in all these cases is just as 
well marked in plants, pods, and flowers as it is in seeds. </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
36 


CHARACTERS OF HYBRIDS. 

Common ('harurtern. — Characters common to both parent 
races are usually reproduced in the hybrids with little variation. 
In some cases, however, new or atavistic tendencies 
assert themselves, as will be noted later, producing hybrid 
characters unlike those common to the two parents but the 
rule is as first stated. When two races both having yellow 
pods are crossed, the hybrids of the various generations as 
a rule produce nothing but yellow pods, and when both the 
parent races have green pods the hybrids have pods similarly 
colored. Examples of the former are, Wardwell x Golden 
Wax, Golden Wax x Keeney, Jones x Golden Wax ; and of 
the latter, Stringless Green x Warwick, Stringless Green 
x Giant Stringless, etc. In case both parents have striDgy 
pods, as, for instance, Davis x Blue Pod, Davis x Scarlet 
Flageolet, Mohawk x Scarlet Flageolet, or both have nearly 
stringless pods, as Golden Wax z Keeney, Wardwell x Challenge 
Black, Jones x Golden Wax, etc., the resulting hybrids 
show the characters common to their parents. Similarly, 
dwarf races produce dwarf hybrids, races having seeds of 
the same shape produce hybrids having the same shaped 
seeds, etc., etc. 

I&gt;if&gt;r&lt;nti&lt;i&lt;iny Ckmrmekn. — Characters which differentiate 
two parent races usually unite in hybrids of those races to 
form intermediate characters. These hybrid characters are 
made up of the parental characters, either blended together 
or united unchanged in mosaics of small or large pattern. 
(See Webber and Swingle, "Hybrids and Their Utilization 
in Plant Breeding." 1 ) 

it — Blue Pod x Davis yields hybrids the ground color 
of whose seeds is light brown, a blending of the brown color 
of the Blue Pod seeds^with the^, white color of the Davis 
Many individuals of the second and later generations 
show a perfect blending of color between the white flowers 
of Davis and the dark bluish-purple'flowers of.BUie Pod and 
between .the light-green leaves and stems of Davis and the 

Biited States Department of Agriculture Yearb &gt;ok, 1897, pp. 880. 
0. </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
nth Annual Report 

37 

dark blue-green leaves and stems of Blue Pod. The white 
seeds of Navy unite with the black seeds of Challenge Black 
to form spotted seeds the light spots of which, however, appear 
gray, a blend of black and white. 

When a nearly stringless podded race, like Golden Wax, 
is crossed with a stringy podded race, like Mohawk, many 
of the hybrid individuals of generations later than the first 
have stringy pods the strings of which are less strongly 
developed than those of Mohawk. The perfectly stringless 
podded Challenge Black crossed with the stringy podded 
Navy produced hybrids which in the first generation developed 
very weak fibers along the sutures of the pod (PI. II, 
figs 42-44). Currie, stringy podded, (PI. II, fig. 45,) 
crossed by Golden Wax, nearly stringless podded, (PL II, fig. 
46,) produced first-generation forms having pods with shorter 
and weaker strings than Currie. 

Intermediate shape in seeds of hybrid beans is common. 
Examples are, Navy x Challenge Black (PL III, figs. 54-56), 
Currie x Golden Wax (PI. Ill, figs. 60-63), Golden Wax x 
Mobawk (PI. II, figs. 1-6, 10, 15, etc.). The intermediate 
shape of seeds is well shown in hybrids of Stringless Green 
x Warwick. The ratio of length to thickness of seeds in 
Stringless Green was found to be about 2.26, in Warwick 
1.92, and in hybrids of the first generation 2.11. 

Mosaics. — When the white-seeded Davis (PL III, fig. 40) is 
crossed with the red-seeded Scarlet Flageolet (PL III, fig. 
41), the seeds of the first generation (PL III, fig. 42) and 
some of those of later generations (PL III, fig. 44) are 
spotted — red and white. At first sight the light-colored 
spots on these seeds seem tinted with red, as though formed 
by a blend of the red and white of the parent races, but, upon 
inspection with a lens it is found that the reddish tint is 
produced by very small specks of red on a white ground 
color. Small white specks are also often found scattered 
through the red spots of the hybrid seeds. An exactly similar 
mixing of colors occurs in hybrids of Currie x Golden 
Wax (PL III, figs. 60-63) and Ward well x Challenge Black 
(PL III, figs. 57-59), where small specks of black and purple 
give the white ground color of the light spots a shaded or </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
38 


E appearance. In these color mosaics the patches of 
vary from very fine specks to large spots and stripes, 
ings of this sort are common in the seeds of such r 
jhawk, Warwick, Refugee, Valentine, etc., which are 
only said to be mottled. 

From these small-pattern color mosaics we may pass by 
irrados to mosaics of a larger pattern. Seeds of hybrid 
beans, instead of presenting a mosaic of the seed colors of 
the parent races, may show the color of one parent combined 
with the seed shape of the other parent, thus exhibiting a 
sort of large-pattern mosaic. Examples of this are seen in 
PI. Ill, figs. 12. 18, third-generation forms of Keeney x Davis 
(PI. Ill, figs. 1,2), and in PI. II, figs. 11, 12, 14, 17, etc., second-generation 
forms of Golden Wax x Mohawk (PI. II, figs. 
1, 2). Going a step further, hybrids may produce seeds 
which take all their characters (colors, shape, size, etc. ) 
from one parent, and pods having the characters (color, 
shape, stringiness, etc. ) of the other parent. Or, a hybrid 
may closely resemble one parent in the habit of plant and in 
all characters of pods, and the other parent in seed characters. 
A case of this kind is seen in PI. Ill, fig. 9, thirdgeneration 
hybrid of Keeney x Davis (PI. Ill, figs. 1, 2). 
This individual was perfectly dwarf and produced white 
seeds like Davis. Its pods were shorter than those of Davis, 
more like those of Keeney, and also as stringless as the 
Keeney pods. 

Mosaics may also be formed of characters of one parent 
united with the blended characters of the two parents. For 
instance, in fifth-generation hybrid forms of Golden Wax x 
Mohawk (PI. II, fig. 38), the seeds are plainly intermediate 
between the parent races in shape, while the pods of these 
individuals were like Golden Wax in having a yellow color 
and being nearly stringless, etc. In first-generation forms 
of Navy x Challenge Black (PI. Ill, figs. 54-56) the colors of 
the two parent races are blended to form gray spots, as noted 
previously, and with these gray spots occur spots of pure 
black. When mosaics are made up of the separate characters 
of both parents and the blended characters of both, there is 
a sort of triple mosaic, or perhaps it is sufficient to say that </seg>


            <seg id="p039">
39 

saic in the same individuals. A few individuals of the thirdgeneration 
hybrid, Blue Pod x Davis, had perfectly green 
leaves and stems, like Davis, brown seeds, like Blue Pod, 
and flowers in which the dark bluish purple of Blue Pod 
was plainly diluted by the white color of Davis. In some of 
the fourth-generation forms of Golden Wax x Mohawk (PI. 
II. fig. 33) the seeds have the color of Golden Wax and the 
shape of Mohawk, and the pods are nearly stringless like 
Golden Wax but are greenish-yellow in color, in which the 
two parent colors blend. 

Entire Return to One Parent. — From blends and small -pattern 
mosaics where the characters of the two parents are united 
more or less equally in all the parts of the hybrid forms, to 
mosaics of large pattern where the characters of one parent 
may be dominant in one organ, the characters of the other 
parent may be dominant in another organ, and characters 
of both parents may blend in a third organ, passage 
is effected by easy stages. Similarly, the passage from 
hybrids having nearly all their parts like one parent and 
only a few parts like tbe other parent, to plants which cannot 
be distinguished from the one parent or the other, re 
quires no great leap. In second- and third-generation hybrids 
of Blue Pod x Davis numerous individuals were so 
nearly like Davis and several were so nearly like Blue Pod 
that they could scarcely be distinguished from those races 
by any characters of plant, pod, flower, or seed. The considerable 
number of reversions in this case is specially noteworthy 
because of the fact that the two parent races differ 
in nearly all their characters. In case the two parent races 
are differentiated by a few characters only, as, for instance, 
Keeney and Golden Wax. which, except for a very slight difference 
in shape of seeds, are distinguished mainly by the 
dwarf habit of Golden Wax and the semidwarf habit of 
Keeney, it might natural ly be expected that a considerable 
number of hybrid individuals would closely resemble the 
parent types (PI. Ill, figs. 50, 51, 53). 

Dominant and Recessive Character*. — When hybrid forms of 
second and later generations return to a parent race in any </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
40 


character, the reversion seems to be in accord with no law 
unless there be a definite numerical relation, not yet established, 
between the various hybrid types. As regards the 
first generation, on the contrary, certain parental characters 
seem to dominate the hybrids. Mendel' discovered this in 
pea hybrids and termed dominant those characters which 
were transmitted entirely or almost unchanged, and recess -ve 
those which became latent in first-generation forms but reappear 
in later generations. In the single combination that 
he effected between races of kidney beans a long plant axis 
and green pods were dominant characters. This observation 
is borne out by the writer's study. When semidwarf 
races like Keeney and Navy have been crossed with dwarf 
races like Davis, Golden Wax, and Challenge Black the firstgeneration 
forms were all semidwarf. The recessive character, 
strictly dwarf plants, appeared in the second generation. 
Similarly, when green-podded and yellow-podded races 
are crossed, the green color of the pod is dominant, occurring 
alone in the first generation, the recessive color appearing, 
together with intermediate forms, in the second and 
later generations. 

Other characters which, while not strictly dominant, yet 
tend to impress themselves strongly upon the first-generation 
hybrids are dark seed colors and stringless pods. The 
following examples will illustrate the tendency as regards 
dark-colored seeds: Golden Wax x Mohawk yielded hybrids 
the seeds of which closely resemble Mohawk in color 
(PI. II, figs. 1-6); Davis x Scarlet Flageolet produced hybrids 
with mottled red-and white seeds in which the red predominates 
(PI. Ill, figs. 40-42). In a similar way black is the 
predominant color in seeds of first-generation hybrids of 
Navy x Challenge Black (PI. Ill, figs. 54-56), Wardwell x 
Challenge Black (PI. Ill, figs. 57-59), and Currie x Golden 
Wax (PI. Ill, figs. 60-63). The same tendency is even more 
strikingly brought out in Keeney x Golden Wax, the hybrid 

¦Abhandlungen des Naturforschenden Vereines in Brflnn, Rl IV, 
1886, translated in Journal of Royal Horticultural Society, Vol. XXVI, 
pp. 7. », (1901). </seg>


            <seg id="p041">
41 

(PI. Ill, figs. 50-52), and in Keeney x Davis (PI. Ill, figs. 
1-3), where the latter parent has pure-white seeds and the 
former parent seeds which are at least one-half white and 
where the hybrid seeds have the dark color of the Keeney 
seeds over their entire surfaces. 

In the matter of stringiness of pods, that is, the development 
of fibers along the sutures of the pods, hybrids of the 
first generation usually have stringless pods or pods with 
the strings feebly developed. Keeney x Davis (PI. Ill, figs. 
1-3) yields hybrid pods that approach the nearly stringless 
character of the Keeney pods, though pods with prominent 
strings like those of Davis appear in later generations (PI. 
Ill, figs. 5, 10). Golden Wax x Mohawk yields hybrid pods 
(PI. II, fig. 41) resembling in stringiness Golden Wax (PI. 
II, fig. 39) much more clusely than Mohawk (PI. II, fig. 10). 
The stringy-podded Navy (PI. II, fig. 42) crossed by the perfectly 
stringless-podded Challenge Black (PI. II, fig. 43) 
produces hybrid pods (PI. II, fig. 44) with verv weak strings. 
The perfectly stringless-podded Stringless Green (PI. II, fig. 
48) crossed by the very stringy-podded Warwick (PI. II, fig. 
49) yields hybrid pods (PI. II, fig. 50) which are practically 
stringless. An exception to the general rule is Currie x 
Golden Wax (PI. II, figs. 45-47), where the hybrid pods are 
about midway between the parents in stringiness. It is possible 
that a more extended study will show that certain varieties 
are preponderant as regards stringiness and that this 
is not a matter of dominant and recessive characters at all. 

¦ or Atavistic Characters. — Occasionally hybrids exhibit 
characters which neither parent race possesses. In Davis 
x Blue Pod (PI. Ill, figs. 37, 38) the dark blue-green 
color pf the pods of the latter race is dominant in the firstgeneration 
hybrid forms. On this blue-green ground color 
appear numerous spots and splashes of red (PI. Ill, fig. 39), 
which fade to dull purple as the pod dries, the blue-green 
color at the same time fading to brown as in the case of the 
Blue Pod race. In the second-generation forms the recessive 
pod color, yellow, appears sometimes alone but often 
Dearly covered with red or purple spots which were proiui- </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
42 


nent in the first generation. This peculiar coloration has 
appeared in every first-generation hybrid where Davis has 
been used as a parent race; as, for instance, Keeney x Davis 
(PI. Ill, lip. 3), Davis x Scarlet Flageolet (PI. Ill, figs. 42, 
44, 4J), in which cases the ground color cf the pods is yellow, 
I ilor common to the two parents, making the red or purple 
markings very noticeable. This coloration likewise appears 
whenever Mohawk is used as a parent race, and the 
same tendency has been noticed in hybrids of certain other 
Red or purple spots are not prominent in the pods 
of any of the races noted : and yet traces of red can occasionally 
be found in pods of Mohawk and Davis. So far, when 
any indication of these colors has been seen in the pods of 
the parent race the colors have become very prominent in 

An even more peculiar circumstance is the coloration of 
hybrid seeds corresponding to that of the pods. In Davis x 
Blue Pod the ground color of the seeds of the first-generation 
hybrids is apparently, as noted before, a blend of 
brown and white, but on this ground color are spots and 
stripes of red which fade to bluish purple (PL III, figs. U'-36). 
The same colors are seen, with the same tenancy 
toward stripes, in second-generation forms of Davis x 
Scarlet Flageolet (PI. Ill, figs. 45, 47). In' this case the 
ground color of the seeds is yellow or light brown, unlike 
the colors of either parent race. This yellow or brown 
ground color, striped and spotted with red or purple, is common 
in the seeds of several races of beans, such as Horticul 
tural. Dwarf Horticultural, Goddard, etc., all of which have 
pods spotted with red. It therefore seems probable that 
such races as Davis and Mohawk came originally either directly 
or indirectly from races similar to Horticultural, Goddard, 
etc. Another striking resemblance between the seeds 
of these races and those of the hybrid forms in question is 
the occasional occurrence, in both the races and hybrids, of 
seeds with very little of the red color, and again, of seeds almost 
entirely red. In PI. Ill, fig. 49, are shown three types 
of se«»ds occurring in the Dwarf Horticultural race and in PI. 
TTF Her AA tYin aBmQ itmnc f-w*\Tr\ a H^rK^i/1 i r\A i \7iA nol r\t 4-Iia 
111. lip. ** » Lilt? SttlJJtJ L y 1IUU1 a ll\ ul 111 UlUIVlUUal Ul vll(? </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
43 


third generation of Davis x Scarlet Flageolet. In both cases 
the striped seeds are most common. The occasional very 
light or very dark colored seeds occur on the same individual 
plant and sometimes in the same pod with the striped ones. </seg>


            <seg id="p045">

EXPLANATION OF PLATE I. 

Fig. I. 

Mature flower of common kidney bean. 
Flower buds too small for emasculation. 
Flower bud with banner petal beginning to open 
Flower bu&lt;] ready for emasculation. 

I 

ft 

4 

Flower bud with banner and wings turned back, showing keel. 

5. 
ft 

Flower bud, keel torn open, exposing stigma and anthers. 

Flower bud emasculated. 

Style of mature flower. 

si 

Young pod. 

Bean plants, with paper sacks protecting cross-fertilized flowers 
from insects. 

10. 

Bean plants, covered with wire netting to prevent cross-pollination 
bv insects. 

11 </seg>



            <seg id="p047">

EXPLANATION OF PLATE II. 

l. 

Seeds of Golden Wax. 

¦&gt; 

Seeds of Mohawk. 

Ml 

Representative seeds from four individuals of first-generation 
hybrids of Golden Wax x Mohawk. 

7-12. 

Seeds of six second-generation hybrids from seed like that 
shown in fig. 8. 

1S-21 

Seeds of nine second-generation hybrids from seed like that 
shown in fig. 6. 

Seeds of thirty third-generation hybrids from seeds like 
those shown in tigs. 18, 14. 17. 19, 21. 

»-» 

31-35 

Seeds of 37 fourth-generation hybrids from seeds like those 
shown in figs. 33. 26. 27. 30. 

86-38 

Seeds of 63 fifth-generation hybrids from seeds like those 
shown in tigs 31, 32, 36. 

Part of a pod of Golden Wax. 

: 

Part of a pod of Mohawk. 

Part of a pod of first-generation hybrid, Golden Wax x 
Mohawk. 

41 

Part of a pod of Navy. 

5 

Part of a pod of Challenge Black 

Part of a pod of first-generation hybrid, Navy x Challenge 
Black. 

Part of a pod of Currie. 

s 

Part of a pod of Golden Wax. 

Part of a pod of first-generation hybrid, Currie x Golden 
Wax. 

47 

Part of a pod of Stringless Green 

;; 

Part of a pod of Warwick. 

Parts of pods of first-generation hybrids. Stringless Green x 

50. </seg>



            <seg id="p049">
EXPLANATION OF PLATE ITL 

Fig 1 

Seed and part of pod of Keeney. 
Seed and part of pod of Davis. 

¦ 

H. 

Seed and part of pod of first-generation hybrid Keeney x 
Davis. 

4-s 

Seeds and parts of pods of five second-generation hybrids. 

0-18. 

Seeds and parts of pods of ten third-generation hybrids. 

Seeds of Davis. 

Seeds of Blue Pod 

Seeds of three first-generation hybrids of Davis x Blue Pod. 

Seeds of eight seeond-generatiin hybrids. 

Seeds of four first-generation hybrids of Blue Pod x Davis. 

Seeds of 26 second-generation hybrids. 

I 

Part of pod of Davis. 

Part of pod of Blue Pod. 

Part of pod of first-generation hybrid, Davis x Blue Pod. 

: 

Seed and part of pod of Davis. 
Seed and part of pod of Scarlet Flageolet. 

Seed and part of pod of first-generation hybrid, Davis x 
Scarlet Flageolet. 

M 

Seeds and parts of pods of three second-generation hybrids. 

43-45. 

Seed and part of pod of third-geDeration hybrid. 

M. 

47,48. 

Seeds of two third-generation hybrids. 

Seeds of Dwarf Horticultural. 

: 

Seed of Keeney. 

51,60 

Seeds of Golden Wax. 

Seed of firtt -generation hybrid, Keeney x Golden Wax. 

I 

Seeds of three second-generation hybrids 

Seed of Navy 

Seeds of Challenge Black. 

.V..57. 

Seeds of three first-generation hybrids. Navy x Challenge 
Black. 

Ml 

n. 

Seed of Wardwell. 

M. 

Seeds of first-generation hybrid, Wardwell x Challenge 
Black. 

n. 

Seed of Currie. 

Seeds of two first-generation hybrids, Currie x Golden Wax. 

¦,«. 

Accepted for publication May 8, 1902. </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
50 

Agricultural WtpmrtmtmA Station of Nebraska 

STUDY OF SORGHUM POISONING IN CATTLE. 
(PRELIMINARY REPORT.) 

BY A. T. PETERS. 

Eie experiments with sorghum to determine the cause of 
ti from cattle running in sorghum fields were undertaken 
le Department of Animal Pathology during the summer 
901, as the result of numerous inquiries which came to 
Station asking for remedies and reporting deaths of ans 
that had been pastured on sorghum or bad broken 
sorghum fields. In most cases these animals did not 
larly pasture upon sorghum but broke into the fields 
i adjacent pastures or as they were being driven past 
fields of sorghum. Investigation proved that the animals 
did not die from bloat as has been reported by many agricultural 
papers. Many cases were reported where death occurred 
without .bloat and in so short a time that no other 
theory except that of poison seemed tenable. In most instances 
where losses of this kind were reported, the sorghum 
had been stunted in its growth and was not entirely healthy 
and vigorous in its appearance. 

We visited many fields where animals had died, but generally 
found these animals in so advanced a stage of decomposition 
that satisfactory post mortems could not be held. 
Often the animals had been buried, and when other animals 
were turned into these fields they refused to eat the sorghum 
and no infomation could be secured. 

Analyses of sorghum from many of these fields, in the laboratory, 
failed to show any poisonous principle in the sample, 
which had necessarily been cut several hours before it 
could be submitted to a chemical examination. 

In the spring of 1901, special effort was made to further </seg>


            <seg id="p051">
51 

placed in the leading State papers to the effect that the Experiment 
Station would send a veterinarian to investigate all 
cases of so-called sorghum poisoning, if notified in time to be 
of assistance or to secure any information. We responded 
to numerous calls of this kind, but in most instances where 
animals were turned upon the sorghum for the express purpose 
of poisoning them they refused to eat, and no data 
could be secured. 

In response to one of these calls, received through Dr. W. 
A. Thomas, State Veterinarian, I reached the farm of Mr. 
Foss, near Aurora, at 7:30 a. m., on August 3, 1901. Two 
days previous, fifteen head of his cattle had broken into a 
sorghum field, where they had remained twenty minutes. 
They were then driven into another field and were not seen 
again for several hours. When seen, three were sick, all of 
which died within a few hours. The symptoms were drowsiness, 
running at the eyes, twitching of the muscles, numbness 
Of the limbs, staggering gait, animal could not stand, 
involuntary passing of urine. On August 2, two more cows 
broke through the fence and were on the sorghum field five 
minutes. One hour later, one of these animals, a four-yearold 
cow, was very sick, but finally recovered. The animal 
ed liberal doses of alcohol as an antidote and had fully 
recovered on the morning of August 3, when I arrived at the 

We turned a small yearling steer on the sorghum at 8 :30 
A. M., but he refused to eat any sorghum, and after thirtyfive 
minutes two more animals were turned into the sorghum, 
where they remained until 10 a. M., when only one, 
a small, red steer, had taken any sorghum, and he had eaten 
only a few leaves. They were then turned back with the 
herd. At 10:35 a. m. the small, red steer acted somewhat 
drowsy, but soon recovered. 

At 11 a. M. we turned ore red heifer and one yearling 
steer on the sorghum. The heifer was the only animal that 
ate any quantity, and, as subsequent examination showed, 
she ate only one and one-half pounds of green sorghum. At 
11 :10 A. M. this animal dropped to the ground. Upon close </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
52 


examination it was found that she had stopped chewing her 
cud and there was a peculiar twitching of the muscles of the 
nose and head and also of the body. The animal was very 
dull. At 11 :15 sbe was taken out of the sorghum field and 
allowed to lie in a stubble field. When lying down her head 
was turned toward the abdomen, presenting the symptoms 
of a horse having the colic. The eyes seemed dull and gave 
off a watery discharge. There was a partial paralysis of the 
tongue and great quantities of saliva running from the 
mouth. The limbs and ears were cold. The pupils of the 
eyes dilated, pulse not perceptible, mucous membrane of 
the rectum protruding, involuntary discharge of urine and 
faeces. Upon pricking the animal with a knife on the lower 
limbs it showed no feeling. This animal was closely watched 
in the field by Mr. Foss and myself and we feel sure that 
she did not take any weeds, but simply a small amount of 
sorghum, eating only the tops of the leaves. At 1 : 30 v. m. 
the animal was still lying on its right side, all the musrlo 
of the head were contracted and showed involuntary twitch 
ing. The limbs were paralyzed and the animal was uncunscious; 
the mucous membrane of the mouth was of a salmon 
color. At 2:35 p. m. the animal was in great pain, and it 
was apparent that she would not recover. At the sugges 
tion of Mr. Foss the animal was killed in order to hold a 
post-mortem examination. 

Post-Mortem Examination. — Animal still warm. The bowels 
were opened and contents of paunch carefully noted : 
there was in all one pound and a half of sorghum leabe 
found in the paunch. No sourness of the contents. The 
same was immediately put up in Mason fruit jars with clean 
water and brought to the laboratory. The blood had a pe&lt; u 
liar sweet smell like that of mint (?). It coagulated slowly. 
The mucous membrane of the intestines normal, all 
other conditions of the animal normal. Made particular examination 
of the pharynx (throat), epiglottis, and esophagus 
and found that there were no leaves lodged over the same. 
If this had occurred the animal would have died instantly 
and not within three or more hours as our record shows, and 
would have died in the state of asphyxia and not presenting </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
53 

&gt;•'/&lt; Annual Report 

Pif acute poisoning. In eleven post mortems 
ted, careful search has always failed to rees 
obstructing the pharynx, epiglottis, or 
ch would have caused death by asphyxia or 
We brought two jars full of the leaves taken 
rhere the animal died, and took them to the 
chemical examination, which is not yet corn- 

One case of sorghum poisoning is reported from sorghum 
that had been cut several hours before feeding. Mr. E. F. 
Stoner, of Chester, cut sorghum at 8 o'clock p. M. August 2, 
which was fed to three milch cows at 8 A. m., August 3. 
About 9 o'clock A. M. these animals were first noticed to be 
sick. One died within an hour and fifteen minutes. The 
other two recovered within twelve hours. On August 6 I 
visited this sorghum field and made an examination of the 
sorehum, which was not fully matured. It was comparatively 
free from weeds. At 5:45 we placed a cow in this 
sorghum field and allowed it to eat as much cut sorghum as 
it would, up to 8 p. M., when it had consumed about twenty 
pounds. At 7 a. m., on August 7, the animal showed no 
effects of sorghum poisoning, and no bad effects followed. 

f'tution. — While a number of animals have died from 
sorghum poisoning in various fields, they constitute only a 
small percentage of the animals that have been pastured on 
sorghum each season. So far as our records go, they indicate 
that if animals are poisoned from eating sorghum it occurs 
when they are first turned in the field and is not likely 
to follow after they have been on the pasture some days It 
would therefore seem safe to turn a single animal upon the 
sorghum for a few hours and if it does not suffer any bad 
effects it will be safe to turn in the balance of the herd. 
Care must be taken in this case to observe that the animal 
turned in actually eats some of the sorghum, as it is very 
often true that an animal taken out of a herd and turned into 
a strange field does not eat on account of its strangeness 
under the new conditions. 

The investigation of this subject is not complete and the 
work will be prosecuted during the coming season in an </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
r&gt;4 

Agricultural Experiment Station of Xvbraska 

II to determine accurately the cause of this disease. A 
number of chemical analyses have'already been made 
many analyses remain to be completed. In this work, 
i has been carried on by the Department of Chemistry 
injunction with the Department of Animal Pathology, 
Chemical Department has been able to separate cervegetable 
enzyms from sorghum. A report of such 
is herewith attached. </seg>


            <seg id="p055">
55 

rDY OF THE ENZYMS OF GREEN SORGHUM. 
(PRELIMINARY REPORT.) 

BY HENRY B. SLADE. 

The continued loss to farmers of valuaole stock, especially 
in years of drouth, from green sorghum has Jed to various 
theories as to the cause, but as yet no reliable explanation 
has been advanced. The fatal effects have been quite generally 
ascribed to an unknown poison of a virulent character. 
The characteristic symptoms of the disease are those 
of a toxic substance acting upon the central nervous system. 
Somewhat similar effects have been observed by Hildebrand 
1 from the subcutaneous injection of such ferments as 
emulsin and myrosin in rabbits as also from the products of 
their activity. ' In Northern Africa cattle have been affected 
in a similar manner by certain species of the Egyptian 
vetch (Lotus arol/ifits). Dr. Wyndham R. Dunston* has 
found that the poisonous properties of the [plant are [due to 
the prussic acid formed by the action of a new enzym, lotase, 
upon lotusin, aglucoside present in considerable auantities 
up to the time of the ripening of the seed. The glucoside 
then disappears leaving the plant perfectly harmless. 
Tsuno, a Japanese investigator, has found in ordinary hemp, 
Oorchorus capsularis, a poisonous glucoside, corchorin, which 
affected horses and cows in Japan with much the same 

•H. Hildebrandt, Zur Kentnisa der pbysiologischeu Wirkung der bydrolytischen 
Fermente, VirchoWs Archiv, Bd. 121, Hft. 1, S. 1, (1890). 

K Hildebrandt, Wciteres a. hydrolytische Fermente, ibid., Bd. 1*1, 
S. 5, (1898). 

•Wyndham R. Dunstan, The Nature and Origin of the Poison of Lotus 
arabieus. Royal Society Proe, Vol. 67, p. 224, (1900); Vol. 68, p. 874, </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
56 


symptoms as in the case of sorghum or cornstalks." Blyth 5 
states that the death of many cattle in England in the fall of 
the year is due to colchicine, the alkaloid of Colchicum autiiiiiHule, 
or common meadow saffron. Investigations of this 
problem in the Western States have shown that in many 
canon poisonous weeds are the source of the trouble." 
Whether ordinary sorghum can elaborate such a poison 
through an abnormal process of plant growth is the main 
problem in the research which has been undertaken on the 
fatal effects of green sorghum. 

B considering this question, three closely related lines of 
' have been planned : 

(1) What enzyms are present in green sorghum ; 

¦ What poisonous products may be formed thereby 
the constituents of the plant ; 

BWhat poisonous substances, if any, may be present in 
of abnormal growth. 

In case a poison is present through a pathological metabolism 
of the cane the unformed ferments present may play 
an important part in its production. A study of the 
enzyms of green sorghum hence becomes necessary. The 
role of these substances in cereal plants makes it probable 
that at least several enzyms are present. The only research 
bearing upon the enzyms of common sorghum I have thus 
far found is the study of glucase made by Beyerinck in 
1895.' Beyerinck found glucase in sorghum and in other 
grasses as well as in corn which was the main cereal investigated. 
The author followed the procedure of Geduld* in the 
preparation of the enzym. He outlines the method as fol- 

Three and one-half kilos of the horny endosperm from 

•K Tsudo, Ueber das giftige Prineip in den Samen von Corchorus 
capsularis. Monatsh. f. praktiscbe Tbierheilkunde. Bd. 6, S. 456. (1890). 

•A. W. Blyth, Poisons; Effects and Detection, 1884. p. 891. 

•The Poison Parsnip in Western Washington, Wash. Exp. Sta., Ball 
46. (1M1). 

KW. Beyerinck, Ueber Nachweis und Verbreitung der Glukase, das 
der Maltose, Centralb. f. Bakteriologie und Parasitenkunde, 
Abth., Bd. 1, S. 829. (1896). 

•Ibid., b. 888 </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
Fifteenth Annual Report 

57 

six kilos of corn were ground fine and extracted 
at 15° C with five liters of distilled water with the 
addition of 500 cc of 96 per cent, alcohol and two 
grams of tartaric acid. At the end of thirty hours 
the liquid was filtered and precipitated by mixture 
with a like volume of 96 per cent, alcohol. This process was 
repeated and the second precipitate thus obtained used for 
enzym experiments. The first precipitate was treated in ex~ 
cess with distilled water containing four grams of tartaric 
acid per liter and some alcohol. The precipitate proved but 
little soluble even after standing and frequently shaking. 
The insoluble portion was separated by filtration and the 
filtrate precipitated with alcohol. The three precipitates 
were dried and pulverized. Of these the least soluble 
proved richest in glucase. » 

&gt; 

E cording to the experiments of Beyerinck the glucase 
obtained is quite insoluble in water so that its presence 
ater extracts is apt to be overlooked. It changes malinto 
glucose, and starch into glucose and a dextrin 
h is then further altered to glucose. It is present in 
endosperm of the sorghum seeds before germination in 
quantities. 

Glucase gives a blue coloration with guaiac and hydrogen 
peroxid according to J. Reynolds Green* who nevertheless 
disputes the value of this reaction as a reliable test for enzyms 
10 According to the same authority glucase acts upon 
glucosides 11 splitting up amygdalin with the production of 
another glucoside and grape sugar. It differs from the 
action of emulsin in producing no prussic acid. 

Rthe present instance a number of preliminary experis 
as yet unfinished have been planned. The sample of 
mm used in the first series of experiments was gathered 
from a patch of second-growth cane on the University 
farm. The stalks were from one to two feet high and were 
growing vigorously as the result of the rain of the two days 

•J. Reynolds Green, The Soluble Ferments and Fermentation, p. 196, 

¦"Ibid., p. 396. 
"Ibid., p. 180. </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
58 


previous. The cane appeared to be perfectly normal but 
was refused by a young steer which had been put on short 
rations for two days and then turned into the patch. The 
leaves and stalks of the sample were separated, reduced to a 
pulp, macerated for 18 hours with water and a second lot 
with a 10 per cent, solution of sodium chloride, 500 cc of the 
solvent being used to 100 grams of the pulp. A little chloroform 
was added in each case to prevent fermentation. The 
extracts were then filtered and their diastatic activity tested 
with a dilute starch paste made by boiling one gram of 
powdered starch in a little water and making up to 500 cc. 
One cc of the starch paste thus contained 2 mg. of starch. 
15 cc of each extract were heated in a water bath at 45° -55° 
C for one-half hour with 5 cc of the starch paste and one 
cc tested from time to time with 2 cc of a .2 per cent, solution 
of iodine in potassium iodide. As a control, 2 cc of the 
iodine solution were mixed with an amount of starch equal 
to that in the 1 cc tested, and the relative action upon the 
starch determined by the difference in the color between the 
test and the control. A rough comparison of the strength 
of the various solutions tested was thus attained without resorting 
to the more lengthy method with Fehling's solution 
which would have involved a correction in each case for the 
reducing power of the original extract. 

Under these conditions extracts were obtained which in 
each case showed more or less action upon starch. The water 
extract of the leaves gave only a slight blue color with 
iodine while the water extract of the stalks gave no reaction. 
In the saline solutions the reverse was the case. The saline 
extract of the leaves gave no reaction while the saline extract 
of the stalks still gave a blue color. A control in each 
case with amounts of starch and iodine equal to those of the 
original tests gave the usual dark blue reaction. In a second 
test after an hour's digestion with only half the amount 
of extracts, similar results were obatined. 

Osborne and Campbell" state that sodium chloride may 

"Green, p. 67. </seg>


            <seg id="p059">
59 

increase the activity of a diastase sevenfold while Name" 
finds that the favorable action of salt in the case of malt 
diastase is maintained until the proportion reaches 4 per 
cent. As the above tests were made within the percentage 
limit of increased activity the saline extract in each should 
have been the more "active. Moreover, the proteids extracted 
by the saline solutions should have increased their diastatic 
effect." However, in the case of the stalks the water 
yielded a more active extract than the 10 per cent, sodium 
chloride solution. This'Jack of uniformity in the strength 
of the various extracts as determined by their action upon 
starch suggests a qualitative difference in the enzyms extracted 
by the two solvents in both the stalks and the 
leaves, a point which remains to be investigated. 

With guaiac and hydrogen peroxid each extract yielded a 
blue coloration. These reactions could not be obtained after 
a few hours in the case of the water extract of the leaves 
while the same extract preserved out of contact with the air 
continued to give the characteristic color of the reaction 
after several weeks. This could be accounted for on the 
supposition that the color in the first instance was produced 
by an enzym such as an oxidase which loses this original 
property through its gradual oxidation, while in the other 
cmob the reaction may have been due to the presence of plucase 
or some other enzym. The observed darkening of the 
pulp and juice of the sorghum together with the peculiar 
odor evolved after a time is additional evidence that an 
oxidase is present as also that the enzyms of the water extract 
of the leaves is not the same as in the other extracts. 
Wi'h guaiac alone no color was developed with any of the 
extracts. 

Catalase 1 -' did not appear to be present in any of the extracts. 
Loew describes an insoluble form, a-catalase, 1 * 

1 "Green, p. 67, 
"Ibid., p. 66. 

¦D. Loew, Catalase. A New Enzym of General Occurrence, Departof 
Agriculture, Washington (1901). 

¦•Ibid , p. 18. </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
60 


•which could easily be overlooked on account of this property. 
A further test was therefore made with the sorghum 
pulp itself. 100 grams of pulp treated with 300 cc of water 
and 50 cc of hydrogen peroxid yielded 17 cc of oxygen in 
fifteen minutes. The expressed juice of the cane also showed 
a vigorous catalytic action upon hydrogen peroxid. The 
presence of the insoluble form of catalase was thus clearly 
indicated. Since « -catalase may be extracted most readily 
by dilute alkaline solvents 17 an extract was prepared by digesting 
for three days 5 grams of the dried and powdered 
sorghum from a second sample with 500 cc of a .2 per cent, 
solution of sodium carbonate and the usual small addition of 
chloroform. 40 cc of this extract with 10 cc of hydrogen 
peroxid yielded 7 cc of oxygen in 15 minutes. In the same 
length of time an extract of tobacco under like conditions 
yielded 18 cc of oxygen. The alkaline extract thus obtained 
showed a diastatic activity in a greater degree than the water 
extract, despite the known hindering action of sodium 
carbonate on diastase. '" In half an hour the same amount 
of starch was wholly converted into erythrodextrin. I-ioew 
found no diastatic activity in his preparation of catalase." 
The diastatic ferment in the sorghum extract hence appears 
to be present as an admixture. Its activity in an alkaline 
medium, however, seems to indicate that its nature is different 
from that of the enzym extracted by water. This conclusion 
has not been verified. In agreement with the results 
of Loew &gt;0 this preparation of catalase gave no blue 
coloration with guaiac and hydrogen peroxid. 

K* enzym answering to the glucase of Beyerinck was 
ired from the sorghum by expressing the juice from the 
sand stalks, decanting the clear liquid from the depossediment, 
filtering through cheese cloth and treating 
an equal volume of 95 per cent, alcohol. The flocculent 
pitate.(A) separating after a short time was caught 

E.oew, p. 14. 
ireen, p. 68. 
ioew, p. 10. 
bid., p. 10. </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
nth Annual Report 

61 

upon a filter and thoroughly washed with 95 per cent, alcohol. 
The alcoholic washings were made up to a volume 
equal to the filtrate and the two mixed. A still larger precipitate 
(B), separating more slowly than the first, was thereby 
obtained. By repeating the process a third precipitate (C) 
was obtained. These were dried, powdered and preserved 
for further experiments. With guaiac and hydrogen perioxid 
A gave no reaction and C gave only a faint blue color. 
B, while still moist, gave a fine blue color like that of the 
original juice and appeared to contain most of the substance 
affording this reaction. The dried preparation failed to 
yield this reaction although it still possessed a diastatic 

With starch paste prepared as described above, a solution 
of B containing 2 mg. in each cc showed a distinct reaction. 
10 cc of this solution completely altered 5 cc of starch paste 
to erythrodextrin in one hour. The activity of this preparation 
appeared to be influenced to some degree by the 
strength of the solution. Thus in a given time 10 mg. of 
starch were easily changed to a soluble form by 10, 5 or 4 
mg. of the enzym in 20 cc of water while 1 mg. had little or 
no effect on the same amount of starch. Sodium carbonate 
checked the activity of the enzym, .05 per cent, being more 
than sufficient for this purpose. Hydrochloric acid in quantities 
from .25 to .0025 per cent, appeared to have no effect 
upon the activity of the enzym. The evidence as to the 
action of acids upon diastase is conflicting" and in this case 
needs further verification. 

The same preparation acted upon a solution of maltose so 
that a given amount of this substance gave almost twice the 
amount of reduction with Fehling's solution after digestion 
for an hour at 38° C. Amygdalin after several hours' digestiou 
with the enzym remained unchanged. Saponin, santonin, 
and digitalin were tried with similar results. A solution 
of egg albumen was likewise unchanged by the 

From the above preliminary experiments it is apparent 

Green, p. 67. </seg>

            <seg id="p062">
62 


that green sorghum contains a number of enzyms. Diastase, 
glucase, n-catalase, and an oxidase appeared to be 
present with considerable certainty. Variations observed in 
the course of these experiments may be due to mixtures of 
these enzyms but are suggestive and may lead to the isolation 
of others than the foregoing. In the light of the results 
obtained a more extensive series of tests are planned. 
None of the enzyms thus far found in the sorghum appear to 
be the source of poisonous products but until a more thorough 
examination is made no definite conclusions can be 
formed. The work thus far has been of a most general 
character and is preliminary to the main research which 
still remains to be undertaken. 

Accepted for publication March 2O,'19O2. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>