<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00002.00015">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00002.00015</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH BEATRICE TO THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. DECEMBER 1, 1890. OMAHA, NEB.: HENRY GIBSON, PUBLIC PRINTER. 1890.</title>
               <date value="1890">1890</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-29</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2007-03-28</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>Thomas J. Wattenbarger</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item> 
         </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
L HLKl* rilrj^^lAlj xvliirvJJKA 

? THF. 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTION 

Feeble- Minded Youth 

BEATRICE 

Tii IUK 

BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS 

l&gt;i:&lt;EMBF.R I, 189C 

M \ 1 1 \ N 

n HI GIBSON. IM IS1.II PRISTI ! </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
Com. Public Lauds and Bldgs. . .President 

&gt;kk\ . Secretary of State Secretary 

Hi 1. 1. Treasurer of State 

Attorney ( Jeneral 

K- 

RESIDENT OFFICERS. 

SUPERINTENDENT, 

J. T. ARMSTRONG, M. D. 

MATKOX, 

Miss Mai .(.if. Wood 

TKACHEKS. 

Miss Mattie McLean, 
Mrs. Marik Armstronu, 
.Miss Hattie Spooner, 
Miss Emily Moore. 

I'LKRK. 

Henry Webstkk. 

BOdKKKEPKK. 

II . I-'.. Smi </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
- 

WE PORT. 

1 of Public Lands and Buildings: 

accordance with the requirements of the 
unit tin- third biennial report of this intxl 
ending November (0,1890. It has been 

~tant. uninterrupted growth and improvement. 
nations made l&gt;y the last legislature for boilerark, 
etc., and ice-house, also tire-escapes, has 

led under the direction of your board, resulting in 
buildings suitable to our future needs. The fire, 
roomy, of easy descent and well adapted to our 

of our household has been j&lt;ood. having hail 
liseases with the exception of one ca&gt;- 

i 

t 

August, L889. The disease must have been con . 
e institution, as the child was taken sick 
I four days after being admitted. Thecase was 
ind by usin^ due precaution the spread of 

ed. I'he number of deaths for the two 
Epilepsy, one: phthisis pulnionalis. three: 

ve at present 184 inmates. 86 males and 48 females. 
iportionate number of girls is due to having less 

¦ them than for toys, the latter having a separate 
hl;. They were admitted from counties as follows: 

Male. Female. Total 

A dam - 

¦2 4 6 

Antelope 

I 1 3 

Burt 

1 o 1 


¦2 i 4 

Buffalo i» 2 i 

iphtheria, one: marasmus, two; dysentery. 


M.I </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
Box Butte 

0 

1 

: 

4 


9 

Cumins 
Dakota 
Douglas 
Fillmore 
Franklin. 
Frontier. 
Furoas. . . 



Hamilton 


JeflersoD 
Kearney 


Lancaster 
Lincoln... 

MadisOD. 
Merriek 
Nemaha 
Nuckolls 

Pawnee 

Perkins. 

Bed Willow 
Richardson. 

oJirp \ * 

SauDders 
Sherman. 
Sheridan. 
Stantou. . 
Thayer. . . 
Valley. 

BiiiRton. 
ter 


Home for Friendless 

426 </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
tnber of applications for admission is 264, of 
male-, and 99 for females. The number of 
ave been much larger had it not been 
apacity of the institution was so limited that 

lid be given t&lt;&gt; the many letters of ap 

ace formal applications were not 

HI. 

ho make application for the admission of 
expecting that their demands will be recog- 

ivision l&gt;c made for those who are counted in 
•&lt; m^us. and yet no action is taken to secure for 

a and training. The demands are so urgent and 
r it would he very hard and almost impossible 

ivercrowding, were it not for the certainty of its 
evils. In my judgment there will be at least MO 

idmission during the next biennial period. 1 
&gt;f Ml.; feeble minded porsons in the state bj 

15 
M 

1 


la 

« 

.15 

II 

3 

:; 

¦&gt; 

i 

« 

n 

: 

: 

427 </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
Lancaster 
Lincoln ... 

lt; 

Madison 

Xemaha 
Nuckolls 

Pawnee 
Perkins. . 
DourIhs . 
Dundy 
Fillmore.. 
Franklin 
Frontier.. 



Hamilton 
Harlan .. 


Hitchcock. 

fzr. 


Richardson. 

Red Willow- 
Saline 


Saunders 
oti w&amp;rd . ¦ 
Sheridan. 
Sherman. 
Stan ton. . 
X DA\ ri . . . 

M 


Washington 
Webster 



428 </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
429 

INSTITUTE KoK FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH. 

Moderation of the increasing demand for admission, 

th&gt;' applications already made, provision should be fured 
for at least one hundred and fifty or two hundred addi- 

Iti order to provide for one hundred and fifty 

would be necessary to erect two additional cottages, 
ving a capacity of seventy-five or eighty, and addi- 

u dining-rooms, school-rooms and a larger kitchen. The 

r'ii and dining-rooms should be in a separate building 
removing all danger from fire), built so that future addi- 

d be made, and should be large enough to accommo- 

than three hundred, applying the rooms now 

it 

for those purposes to school- rooms, dormitories, etc. 
'he present arrangement of the engine-room and boiler- 

-•¦ is very inconvenient and, much of the time, require* 
xtra man in that department. The engine-room, located 

Id boiler-house building (which, as mentioned in my 
&gt;rt. ha&gt; twice been damaged by wind storms and re-18 
not likely to stand the constant jar of the machin- 

zardous to let remain there machinery worth 

thousand dollars. The laundry-room, 
ngine-room, from which we get power, 

we only had a capacity for seventy in- 

h our present number, is not any too large 

©rn. The state should ereM a good brick build- 

ontain engine, dynamos, etc.. laundry 

-" thai additions could be made as desired 
It will be necessary for these purposes to have 

Eopriations as follows. Two cottages and furnishing 
'. etch 196,000; engine-room, laundry and shop building, 
XKh kitchens, cooking apparatus and dining-rooms, $15,000. 
lake more room for employes, the attic of the boys'cotcould 
be finished and good rooms made for male ernes 
at a small cost. I estimate for the purpose of finishing 
furnishing same that $2,000 will be required. Experience 
surely demonstrated that it is not only poor economy, but </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
utter wastefulness, to put up buildings ilia! arc to* 
very short time, as well as inconvenient. The growl 

institution lias been very rapid, and fro 
cations, and the known number of -u 
who should be provided for, atnpli 
for such general purposes ad kitchen, din 
To put up buildings that in from t\\&lt;&gt; 
entirely inadequate and ill arranged for 
is wasteful extravagance, oftentimes re 

WATER SlPPI.'i 

• 

made bv Professor H 

\ 

A I 

Silica. 

Carbon dioxide 
Iron oxide. . . . 

» 

Lime 
Magnesia 
Salt 

Sulphur trioxid 

4 

After ;i thorough trial it \va 
either boiler or laundry use, and ale 
cooking purposes. The well was thei 
since used it to supply an additional I 
closet purposes. This is the only ua 
he full capacity will be necessary for thii 
ncreasin^ demand of the institution. The 
nadequate for boiler and household uses 
several times a day. The storage capacity 
much of the time without water, ihoiiirl 

1 

mall we art 

sing the pun 

night and day. This makes an additional expense for 1 

430 


to overcome the inconvebi 

The tubular *rell completed in 
supply of water, but. unfortunati 
be used for general purpose! 

mg {Hiinju'd drj </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
have we a sufficient supply for laundry and 
The health of the institution absolutely 

abundant supply of wholesome water. At a depth 
»ur new well conclusively proves that deep wells 

&lt;¦ vicinity would he a failure. The only availpresent 
is either a sufficient number of wells 

¦nek. as the old one or the small creek near the 
The water in the creek would he unfit for house- 

• &gt;. and the water in surface wells, while good, 
able to contamination from' the sewers from the 
It such wells should be used, the sewers already 

1 be replaced by others made as tight as possible, 
substances in solution are not removed by filtering 


iny depth of sand. Only matter in suspension is 
thus leaving the water clear and sparkling without 
the cause of infection. The city of Beatrice ha* 
extending an eight-inch water main to the institu- 

i 

ved 

co«1 of laying (estimated by the city engineer at 
which would he credited to the state and no further 

I 

(.KKi. (K) 

(i be made for water consumed until the charges 
this sum. This is a subject of the greatest importhe 
most expedient plan should be adopted at once 

I 

n 

in abundant supply for future requirements. Unless 
ed to connect with the city water-works, some pro&gt;uld 
be made immediately for the storage of water in 
anks sufficient for at least two or three days' supply. 

1 

e is also necessary in case of fire, as we would be 
plesa should such an accident occur. 

i 

v 

K.Pl CATIONAL DEPARTMENT. 

itial improvement is shown in school and kinderrk 
and there are few, if any, cases in which no 

rten v 

has been made. An industrial class in sewing was 
1 in &lt; tctober. 1889. and put in charge of one of the 


riraniz 

¦ two hours each day, and we feel that the work 
members will compare favorably with work done 

icher 

lone liv 

431 </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
by any child. Eight do preliminary work; nine do plain sew 

ing: nine do Kensington outline, hemstitching, drawn worl 

k 

and miscellaneous fancy work: two do knitting ;nid tlnv 

crocheting. For the hoys a small class in brushmakin 

\va 

formed last September and put under tli&gt;' diivot 

bookkeeper. Some have already become quite profit 

all have taken great interest, an 

ea^er for that part of the day spent in ' 

all. 532 hour-' work has \&gt; 

500 brushes have been made in addit 

building. The work was begun w 

what could be accomplisl 

am confident that 

will more than pa 

work self-supporting 

should also he taken up, as 

more land providi 

tar 

manual training cai 

the end to be sougl 

lead. The hest resu 

by kee]&gt;ing tin 

Ir 

dividing eacli d;t\ in 

Manual training develops i 

school to industrial work i- sii 

mental work for another. It 

manual training develops neati 

usefulness. The results accomp 

time sufficient improvement can be in 

under guidance, of a good percentag 

most favorable circumstances, howevi 

the fact that the mental incapacity of ai 

a 

not be entirely outgrown or removed. 

LAND. 

Kam still of the opinion, expressed in my first report, that 
tracts of land are not only a matter of economy, the 

432 </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
•t- wholly supplying the institution, thus greatly 
i. cost of maintenance, but are also of great use- 

farm produi 

mna t! 

le training and physical development of the pupils, 
I pursuits being peculiarly adapted to persons of 

ra 

since the majority of the people of our 
! in farming, the pupils should be taught that 

able to follow under the direction of their 
rned to their homes. Land in Nebraska is 
i&lt;&gt;w than it ever will be in the future, and 

ised while it can be had. adjoining the present 
being compelled later on, as in some other 

uv • three mile?, from the institution, a matter 
&gt;nvenience, besides removing it where it cannot 

reel management. Many of this class arc not able 
whole day. and if the farm is near by they can de- 

netit from it. preventing idleness and requiring 

ittendance. their labor being at the same time 

been obliged to lease several acres of land for 
rears bj reason of the last legislature failing to 

m asked for. The leased ground has been 
tditional help. During this biennial period 

n and garden products, at market prices, 
14.000.00, a list of which will be found on an- 

\l [S&lt;"EI,1,ANEOUS 

iture appropriated $'2110.00 for improvement 
i has been expended for fence, sidewalk. 

-. shrubberj . grass seed. etc. The amount was too 
ike more than a few of the most necessary im- 

mall to n 

provement 

wildings require the renewal of a large amount of 
d the rooms in the central building, occupied by 
hould be wainscoted. This will require a large 
the appropriation asked for repairs. The painting 

Both I 

plaster, an 

children 

amount of 

433 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
of roofs aud the outside of buildings i* also badlv 


Pipe covering should be put on the steam-pipes tlm 

itrh tl 

tunnels and in basements, as it would save the f 

fuel in one. or, at niost, two year 

The amounts asked for in inv estimates for the al&gt; 

&gt;ve pi! 

are no more than are necessary, and no doubt 

e 

lature will make the appropriations when the need for thei 


We desire to express our appreciation and thank 

following newspapers sent gratuitously to the ins 

The State Journal. Red Cloud Chief and the'Seward I 

c 

For Christmas, 1H.sk and 1889, tl 

wintr "lonat ions w 


C. T. Raynolds &amp; Co., Chicago, 96.00 
Officers and employes First Natk 


United States Wind Engim 


F. Godfirnon, Falls City, ?2.5O. 
Henry Boeraen, Grand Island. $2. 
Alf MacMahon, Beatrice. |6.00. 
F. D. Kees. Beatrice. $5.00. 
Mrs. Carl Nelson and Mrs. P. M. 
C. F. Wilber, Beatrice, $5.00. 
Jeorge Holmes, jr.. Omaha. $10.01 
J. L. McCiee &amp; Co., Beatrice. 16.00. 
John W. Harper, Beatrice. 82.00. 
John Boyles. David City, $5.00. 
Omaha Rubber Co.. books. 

Mr. Cox, package for Annie L. 
Unitarian Sunday-school, Beatrice. c&lt; 
Miss Mahlen. Beatrice, package. 
Dr. Joseph Neville, Omaha, package. 
L. E Walker, fceatiice, package. 

ka 

434 


Miss Gardner. &lt; &gt;maha, H.ihi </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
435 

Ill TK FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOl'TH. 

Beatrice. 72 Christmas cards. 
Smith. Beatrice, toys, books, etc. 

incy s 

Detroit, package each year. 

n that Mis-; Turner, who has been in the 

istitution almost since its opening as launn 
accident a short time ago. which has since 

imputation of her hand. Owing to herfaithmanagement 
we have never had to employ 
Ip in that department, and I feel that it is the 

ite, from the standpoint of justice and humanity, 
with an amount which, while not sufficient to 
¦r for the loss, will at least enable her to fit her. 

ipalion whereby she can maintain herself. 
•gular visiting days have been established and 

i- open to visitors every day but Sunday. We 
the public visit us and are glad to note the con 
ling number of visitors and the interest which 
uniits visiting their children are allowed to re- 

i 

I 

of 1889 we had the honor of the annual session 
ation of Medical Officers of American Institu. 

\ 

e- Minded" at this institution, and a large numwere 
read and discussed. The meeting demon- 

\- 

ie work is progressing rapidly, and more and 
fin- taken. The states where such institutions 

[Uipping them better than ever before as 

a obtained and new institutions are being 
I feel that our young western state and in- 

\&gt; 

n was highly complimented by securing the 
h a body of men. The members of the associa- 

m-titut 

mi.-1't in 

t only those of the United States, but also 

ii&gt;n inclu 

' anaua 

bted to the officers and employes for their faith- 

I am iml 

iatrice, package. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
K performance of duty, and to you. tin- Hoard 
Is and Buildings, for your hearty co-operation £ 
I pertaining to the welfare of the institution. 

1 I U Oi l( 

.ind Buppor 

Additional tables and estimates are appended 

Respectfully submitted 

.1. T. Armstri inu, Superi 
Beatrice, December !. 1890. 

ltelldt'N 

TABLE 'iF SCHOOL ATTAINMENTS 

RKCH 

Bio words 
l&gt;\ Bic-ht 

Rea i etaai 

¦ First 
Third and Fo 

Bead Ik 

Make DO Btt 

Form strokes on sla 

Form letters uid eas\ w&lt; 
Write words In copy-boi 

Writ.' fairlv 

B letters liorne with 
letters home with( 

A R I I 1 1 \l (• 

Count to five. 
Count to ten 
Count to fifty 

Count indefinitely 

Combine numbers to five 
Combine numbers to ten 
Work in addition 

¦! 

Kin subtraction 
in multiplication 
in division 

D 

436 



Bno atti-a 
a few wi 
indistiu 
fairly.. 
well 

Have no id*&gt;a of numln-r 
Count to three </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
437 

INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOl'TH. 

TIME. 

Male. Female. Total. 
.46 26 7S 

s or minutes 
hours 

I 8 13 

m 

9 7 It 

minute 

15 9 24 

\ \I.1K &lt; &gt;F MONEY. 

H 
H 
5 
s 
14 

IS 
It 
I 
6 
I 

\ 


i) 

COLORS. 

! 

IT 

I 
4 

3 

K 

in 
II 
M 

20 
Ml 

Ml SK 

S 

6 
28 

l 
II 
I 
M 
¦&gt; 

\ 

r, 


21 

9 


3 

•) 


la 

11 

::: 

20 

und 

w 

11 

m 

II 

Ki'il: M'HY. 

&gt;n only 

I 

9 
1 
8 

n 


6 

t. 

hy 

. 16 

i 

LANlU'AftE. 

i word 

11 

8 

i 

¦ 

o 

3 

Distingc 

11 

H 

Reproduce Btorl 

5 

3 

Compost- Btoriea from iiictures 

9 

6 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
Draw simple forms 
Map drawing 

Free hand dmwi 

Perforating and sewl 
Paper weaving 

Pap^i fotdiDi: 

Chamber work 
Scrubbing 

Sweep 

Make beds. 

Ironiui? fairly 
Ironing well 

K shirts wel 
dishi-s 

it iu kitcli. 

Learning to make beds 
L •arniuf,' to scrub 

Learning to iron 

LIST OK A.KTICL.E.S MAD 

S 

Gingham ilresd 
Chemise 


KBK-CitM 8C;ilfovets 


Pin cushions 

Photograph i-ase. fancy 
Satin shopi&gt;iiig-baK s •-• 

te^ crocheted aeedle-case 
eted lace, yards 

Crocheted feathor-edsre lace, vat 
Crocheted mats, set 

l 

Night-dresses 
Drawers, pain 
Splashers 

i 

Sideboard scarf 

438 </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
Kra,se». 
s 


439 

NSTIT 

UTE FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH. 

I ill i 

[ARY OF WOKK DONE BY CHILDREN. 



loan 

US 

5997 

w 

146 

17536 

18451 

17»* 

9235 

t 

6» 

assigned for lack of mental development, as 

i 

led in application blanks 

93 

ii 

n childhood M 

I of accident : 21 

n 

15 

S 

i 

« 

inal meuiugitis 4 

Brain fever j 

V 

Wouuil in hcml 2 

lalnutrition in infancy 1 

iDRuinlty 1 

- re use f totMoeo \ 


i 



PRODLTT OF FARM 

AND HARDEN. 

bunches 206 

m 

t, bushel* gg 

ige, ht-Hil.-i 45jjj 

Qower, be«ds. , 14 

reen. dosen ears 865 

jshels 285 

ishela . U 

fodder, staocks wo 

i 

_• clant. ImsbeU 4 

4 </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
440 

LAND COMMISSIONER S REPORT. 

Melons 

Milk, quarts 


Onions, dozen bunches 
Onions, bushels ... 

Peas, bushels 

l 

Potatoes, Irish, bushels 
Potatoes, sweet, bushel 
Peppers, bushel* 

Radishes, dozen bunchi 
Squashe.-. 

i 

\ ! K 

¦inane 
ur»- a, i«l lit 

Farm suppl 
Office suppi 
il and 
Library aoi 
Amusement 
Medk-inc- 

Cows 

Laundi v apparal 
Cooking appara) 

Paints and oil 
Improvement 

Pumps and machin 
Water supply 

Salaries of oflicer- and 

Engine-room, laundry and -h 

en' 

Bin and dining room ami [urnishic 
dditional cottages uii'i furnishing 
Ing and furnishiujj altic of preset 
ing for steam-i'»' &gt; e- 

It 

Turnips, ljii&lt;-h&lt;-l 
Tomatoes, bush 

Repairs and lm| 
Incidentals </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
INFORMATION. 

n was established by the state of Nebraska 
eeble-minded children between the ages of 

11 

ears, who are. by reason of their affliction, 
mal advantages of our public schools, and 
iuse of their physical weakness, are neces- 

and protection, the prime object of said 

all be to provide special means of improvement 
irtunate portion of the community who were 

\ disease have become, imbecile or feeble-minded, 
well adapted course of instruction, reclaim them 
• helpless condition, and through the development of 
lectual (acuities fit them as far as possible for use- 

in society To this end there shall be furnished them 
gricultural and mechanical education as they are ca- 

¦ of receiving." — Section 2, Chapter 52. Session Laws of 
aska, 1886. 

lucation &gt;&gt;f this class includes not only the simple 

of instruction taught in our public schools and in the 
rten, where that is practicable, but embraces a course 

g in the more practical matters of every-day life, the 
n of habits «f cleanliness, propriety and self-reliance, 

levelop and enlarge their capacity for useful 

hen of this class are often feeble in body as well as in 

mil. Their gait and voluntary movements are generally 
nperfed and slow, and their special senses inactive and un- 

Boped. Physical training and development, therefore, are 
tial in order that their mental improvement may be 
permanent, hence the importance of gymnastic and 
henic exercises in connection with our school work. 

The very feehle power of attention must be cultivated and 
increased by the most attractive means. The special senses 
must be trained and educated, vicious habits corrected and 

441 </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
442 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

the idea of obedience and moral obligation must be ii 

and nourished. 

Some who are only backward and undeveloped from 


misunderstood and abused, can be improved and reclain 

special means, others can be made orderly and 

&gt;e 


docile and industrious, anil all can be improved in tli 

eral condition and habits 

i 

» 

persons must have special care, treatment and ins 

which cannot be ; obtained in the family at hom 

medical practice, or by any of the ordinary m- 

instruction ; and it is only in some institution — well-arrai 

and directed for the accomplishment of these sp 

that they can receive such benefits. Each in 

¦¦ 

Children, residents of Nebra 

and those who have such mark 

of intellect, or those who by re. 

are unable to receive the benefi 

ordinary methods of instruct! 

ing free of charge, except the expen 

and transportation to and fron 

information will be cheerfulh given 


In order to secure these bjessintrs. iiii&gt; Ha 

must be studied fi*m a t&gt;liv 

treated as it^ peculiarities may ¦i( j m </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>