<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report Board of Education Nebraska State Normal Schools</title>
               <date value="1919-01-01">1919-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Biennial Report Board of Education NEBRASKA STATE NORMAL SCHOOLS — To- His Excellency KEITH NEVILLE Governor Compiled by H. E. Reische, Secretary LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JANUARY 1, 1919 CHADEOK JOUXMAL PRIHT </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Directory BOARD OF EDUCATION NEBRASKA STATE NORMAL SCHOOLS MEMBERS APPOINTED Dan Morris, Kearney -..Term expires 1919 H. E. Reische, Chadron _ __Term expires 1920 Frank Pilger, Pierce _ Term expires 1921 W. S. Heitzman, Osceola _ Term expires 1922 T. J. Majors, Peru Term expires 1923 MEMBERS EX-OFFICIO G. E. Hall, State Treasurer _ Lincoln W. H. Clemtnons, State Superintendent Lincoln OFFICERS OF THE BOARD Dan Morris. President Frank Pilger, Vive-President H. E. Reische. Secretary G. E. Hall, Treasurer STANDING COMMITTEES Auditing: Hall,. Heitzman, Pilger Executive: Morris, Majors. Reische. Pilger Instruction : Majors. Reische, Heitzman Printing- Clemmons, Hall. Pilfjer Rules : Clemmons. Majors, Hall SCHOOLS IN OPERATION PERU, opened in 1867 WAYNE, opened in 1910 KEARNEY, opened in 1903 CHADRON, opened in 191 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL His Excellency. Keith Neville, Governor of Nebraska. Sir : — Complying with the law governing the Board of Education having control of the Nebraska State Normal Schools, we herewith transmit to you the biennial report and statement of expenditures made by this Board from December I. 1016. to December 1, 1918. All original vouchers are on file with the auditor of public accounts and duplicates are on file in the office of the Board of Education. Respectfully submitted, H. E. REISCHE, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p004">ESTIMATES It is estimated by the Board that $750,000.00 will be required for maintenance and $250,000.00 for buildings and necessary improvements during the next two years. A mill levy is essential at this time. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">FINANCIAL STATEMENT Levy 85-100 of 1 mill — 90 per cent appropriated. Raised from 10,17 tax levy 4403.350.13 Raised from 1018 tax levy 434,480.15 Raised from remaining 10 per cent of 1015-1916 tax levy 81.806.81 $910.72709 Sat Aside for Maintenance Chadron Kearney Pern $125,000.00 . 185.00000 .. 203.000.00 .. 150.000.00 Wayne $663,000.00 Amounts Paid Out for Each School for Physical Plant Improve - mrnti. Furniture. Enuipment, and General Expenditures. December 1, 1916. to December 1, IMS. Chadron Kearney Peru .4 40.760.67 95,619.56 26.15736 &amp;.45467 Wavne Extension of Campus 29.58982 2.237.14 Wayne Board expense $256,819.22 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION DISBURSEMENTS BY THE BOARD The following items include expenditures by the Board of Educa - tion for all purposes, other than maintenance of the four schools during the biennial period from December elusive. i, 1916, to December I 1918, in- 1916 Dec. 1 1 H. E. Reische. Board expens Dan Morris. Board expense T. J. Majors. Board expen; $ 3188 e 8.44 n 8.02 e A. L. Caviness. Secretary alary 100.00 28.00 Star Publishing Company advertisement for bids State Journal Co.. Bindin Board minute 9.00 Harry Porter. Secretary supplies 4.75 475 J. H. Crarlrlock. Wayne Gymnasium Architect 322.38 ymnasium Architect I. H. Craddock. Kearney Gymnasium Architect 148.62 Gymnasium Architect Eugene Morey. Kearney Auditorium 4-5° ditorium City 01 Kearney, paving 6.504.4^ Walter Knutzen. Kearney gymnasium 8.41 1.80 Walter Knutzen. Kearney vmnasium Bausch &amp; Lamb. Peru training school 75 f&gt; 7 H. W. Bedell, Peru training school 13.80 ch B. K. Cole. Peru training school 22.00 Cornell-Searle Co.. Peru trainnig school 28.80 Crane Co.. Peru training school 4-86 O. L. Duncan. Peru training school 68.25 General Electric Co.. Peru training school 663.53 Hardy Furniture Co.. Peru training school 445-2O L. L. Horton, Peru training school 8.25 F. M. Ivans. Peru training school 56-88 R. B Knapp. Peru training school 83.25 John I.ankemper. Peru training school 12.00 L. L. Mason. Peru training school 69.50 P. C. Mason. Peru training school 132.00 E. E. Madiadis. Peru training school 375 Nebraska School Supply House. Peru training school.. 162.68 Oliver Machine Co., Peru training school...- 3.3°7-4° Prest-O-Lite Co.. Peru training school 123-55 Rudge &amp; Gunzel, Peru training school 3.108.87 J. P. Riddle, Wayne Gymnasium 18.268.20 F. E. Mnllholen, Chadron east wing 4.475-°° 1917 19.84 Jan. 15 A. L. Caviness. Board expense *44 Dan Morris. Board expense </seg>
            <seg id="p007">BIENNIAL REPORT 7 H. E. Rcisehe, Board expense _ 31.88 Frank Pilger. Board expense _ n.go J. Majors. Board expense _ _ _ _ 8.92 Mabel P. Scouit, proof reading 14.60 W. F. Bailey Co.. printing summary _ 97.92 Kearney Hub. biennial report „ 201.60 J. C. Stitt. Architect, Chadron east wing 93.18 State Engineering Co., Chadron east wing _ 132.00 Harry M. Plnmmer. Chadron east wing 500.00 I". E. Mullbolen. Chadron east wing K E. Mullholen, Chadron east wing 1,105.00 Hibbard Brick Co., Kearney school Hibbard Brick Co., Kearney school _ 800.00 Jas. Morton &amp; Son. Peru training school 474-04 J. C. Woodie. Peru training school C. Woodie. Peru training school 20.00 W. S. Vance. Peru training school 15.00 Omaha School Supply Co., Peru training school 39903 Meek Lumber Co.. Peru training school _ 83.25 he McGraw Co.. Peru training school 69.83 Korimeyer Co.. Peru training school _ 48.05 H. G. Glasgow. Peru training school 25.00 I.. Di Mean Peru training school 46.25 e 1- air. Peru training school 99-41 H. I. Caiilkins. Peru training school _ 175.00 R. J. Armstrong, Peru training school 19.40 E'mer Dovil. Peru training school 1.566.65 J. P. Piddle. Wayne Gymnasium 4,505.00 A] r. 24 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., Peru training school 33-00 Western Electric Co., Peru 700.15 W. S. Vance. Peru training school 51.87 Western Electric Co.. Peru training school 90.51 Ridge &amp; Gtinzei. Peru training school 1,193.29 Thomas Charles Co.. Peru training school 236.01 Korsmeyer Co.. Peru training school 204.83 Cornell-Searle Co.. Peru training- school 212.64 The Fair. Peru training school 12.08 Fisher Bros.. Peru training school _ 33.50 Meek Lumber Co.. Peru training school 30.95 Nebraska School Supply Co.. Peru training school .... 94.58 Peabody School Fur. Co.. Peru training school 23.50 Peabrdy School Fur. Co.. Peru training school 49382 Geo. B. Peck Dry Goods Co., Peru training school 196.80 F. W. Rische &amp; Son. Peru training school 7,804.19 Orchard it Wilhelm Co.. Peru training school _... 123.70 James P Riddle. Wayne Gymnasium 5,310.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION C. J. Burke &amp; Son, Wayne Gymnasium 1.44475 G. A. Fuchs &amp; Son. Kearney Auditorium 1. 175.00 Kearney Plumbing &amp; Heating Co., Kearney Aud 547 25 Western Heating &amp; Plumbing Co., Kearney 75.60 W. F. Crossley, Kearney Auditorium 7307 Burgess-Geandon Co.. Kearney Auditorium 900.00 H. A. Webbert. Kearney school 15.00 J. C. Stitt, Chadron east wing 81.00 Harry M. Plummer. Chadron east wing 824.00 State Engineering Co.. Chadron east wing 76.00 F. E. Mullholen. Chadron east wing 4,500.00 H. A. Webbert. Board expense, voucher blanks 18.75 A. L. Caviness, Secretary salary 100.00 June 20 F. E. Mullholen. Chadron east wing 60.00 Harry M. Plumber. Chadron east wing 700.00 Willard F. Bailey Co _ _ 4.00 The Kearney Hub 6.00 The Kearney Democrat 3.00 Kansas City Scenic Co.. Kearney aud 1,875.40 Eugene Morey 2.50 W. F. Crossley. Kearney Auditorium 10.235.08 A. H. Andrews Co., Kearney School 1,580.73 Walter Knutzen. Kearney Gymnasium 5,007.60 Frank Pilger. Board expense 11.04 A. L. Caviness, Secretary salary 100.00 H. E. Reische, Board expense 31.88 A. L. Caviness. Board expense 17.64 The Kearney Hub 7.50 Dan Morris. Board expense 22.88 T. J. Majors. Board expense 11.02 J. H. Craddock. Architect Peru training school 1.534.00 The Zahner Mfg. Co.. Peru training school 107.88 Elmer Dovel, Peru training school 2.65 Western Electric Co.. Peru training school equipment.. 15.75 F. E. Mullholen. Chadron east wing 3,960.00 J. C. Stitt. Chadron east wing architect 69.00 T. J. Majors, Board expense 11.02 A. L. Caviness, Board expense 2909 H. E. Reische. Board expense 3363 Frank Pilger. Board expense 13.64 July 30 J. P. Riddle. Wayne Gymnasium 12.100.57 Harry P. Holdenan. Wayne Gymnasium 835.00 Denzel Manuel Furniture Co., Kearney Auditorium '37-00 Burgess.Granden Co.. Kearney Auditorium 120.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">BIENNIAL REPORT 9 W. F. Crossley, Kearney Auditorium _ 6oi.Il J. H. Craddock. Kearney Auditorium architect 664.63 Chas. W. Macklin, Kearney land 2.360.00 F. E. Mullholen. Chadron east wing 341800 J. C. Stiitt, Chadron east wing architect 51.27 G. E. Hall, Board expense _ 17.18 Frank Pilger, Board expense _ 14.92 T. J. Majors. Board expense ..: 8.92 Frank Gartner, Wayne grounds _ 359-20 H. E. Reische, Board expense _ 37.10 W. S. Heitzman. Board expense 8.72 Luther O. Draper Shade Co.. Wayne Gymnasium 388.15 Crane Company, Wayne Gymnasium 28.77 Crane Company, Wayne Gymnasium 4,407.82 Estate of J. E. Houtz, Peru training school 163.79 R. T. Allgood, Peru training school 3385 H. W. Lawrence. Peru training school 63.85 Lester Clary. Peru trainnig school _ 10.00 D Donovan &amp; Son. Peru training school 4.50 The Korsmeyer Co., Peru training school 3'5-39 W. F. Crossley, Kearney Auditorium _ 5.937'O Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., Wayne Gymnasium 164.80 Oct. 29 Kearney Plumbing &amp; Heating Co.. Kearney Gym 8249.00 H. E. Reische, Secretary salary 100.00 Geo. C. Snow, printing 12.50 H. E Reische, supplies and postage 6.18 W. H. Clemmons, Board expense 12.94 T. J. Majors, Board expense 34-58 G. E. Hall. Board expense _ 31-88 Frank Pilger, Board expense 22.06 Dan Morris, Board expense - 36.21 Walter Knutzen, Kearney Gymnasium 8^65.87 Dan Quinton, Kearney basement 3,000.000 W. F. Crossley, Kearney rural school 2,000.00 Western Plumbing &amp; Heating Co.. Kearney Gym 973-62 J. H. Craddock, architect Kearney Gymnasium _ 3&gt;6.42 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., Kearney school _ 1,023.76 Cornell-Searle Co.. Peru school - 6.23 Elmer Allgood, Peru school 74-25 O. L. Duncan, Peru school - 64.35 Fred Houtze Estate, Peru training school 284.75 Robert Sandberry, Peru school - ~ 43-25 Roy Slinker, Peru school - - - 5535 E. B. Vance, Peru school ..: — 110.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Glenn Parriott. Peru school „ 44-IO York Michel. Peru school _ 164.25 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm Co., Chadron east wing 109.50 Harry M. Plummer, tunnel Chadron school 1.963.20 Rudge &amp; Guenzel. Chadron east wing 288.20 John Wanamaker. Chadron east wing _ 101.80 Marshall Field &amp; Co.. equipment Chadron east wing... 39/0 Harry M. Plummer. Chadron east win*;; 2.465.00 J. C. Stitt. architect Chadron east wing 123.42 The Estate Stove Co.. equipment Chadron east wing.. 221.25 Industrial Education Co.. equip. Chadron east wing... 207.43 Lewis &amp; Conger Co., equipment Chadron east wing 34-67 Harry M. Plummer, Chadron east wing 663.00 F. E. Mullholen. Chadron east win? 5.100.00 D* w Wire &amp; Iron Works. Wayne Gymnasium 156.85 J. P. Riddle, Wayne smoke stack 3.2-3 12 J. H. Craddock architect Wayne Gymrtasium 726.08 W. C. Wightman. Wayne, lot for campus extension 200.00 John A. Spere, Wayne, lots for campus extension 4'Qoo El'.a J. Pile. Wayne, lots for campus extension 1.200.00 C. F. Whitney, Wayne, lots for campus extension 249.00 John Short. Wayne, lots for campus extension 2.479.00 Tucker &amp; Main. Wayne, lots for campus extension 500.00 R. H. Skile. Wayne, lots for campus extension 850.00 Chas. W. Reynolds, Wayne, lots for campus extension 47400 E. C. Perkins. Wayne, lots for campus extension 825.00 A. S. Mitchell, Wayne, lots for campus extension 1,40000 C. A. Martin. Wayne, lots for campus extension 2.409.00 Winifred P. Main. Wayne, lots for campus extension... 389.00 J. G. W. Lewis. Wayne, lots for campus extension 17500 Mary M. Johnson. Wayne, lots for campus extension 500.00 Emma Hart, Wayne, lots for campus extension 2200.00 Dora M. Grimsley. Wayne, lots for campus extension 424.00 Kate M. Gaertner, Wayne, lots for campus extension... 250.00 Furchuer Suerig &amp; Co., Wayne, lots for campus ext 250.00 U. S. Conn, Wayne, lots for campus extension 392-57 E. B. Chichester, Wayne, lots for campus extension... 200.00 C. A. Berry, Wayne, lots for campus extension 850.00 Jessie Beckenhauer. Wayne, lots for campus extension 250.00 C. C. Bastian. Wayne, lots for campus extension 299.00 Sunderland Machinery &amp; Supply Co., Wayne Gym 2.781.75 New Foundry &amp; Mfg. Co., Wayne Gymnasium 34107 E. H. Marchant. Wayne Gymnasium 37-25 A. E. Herring. Wayne Gymnasium 143.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">BIENNIAL REPORT ii Evans Brown Lumber Co., Wayne Gymnasium _ 25.25 C. H. Fisher, Wayne Gymnasium _ _ 268.54 Emerson Planing Mill, Wayne Gymnasium _ 875 C. O. Evans. Wayne Gymnasium _ 16.36 Crane Co., Wayne Gymnasium 1,872.67 Joe H. Cox, Wayne Gymnasium _ 37-00 Evan A. Chapman, Wayne Gymnasium 4.40 C. A. Chase &amp; Co., Wayne Gymnasium _ 1,336.10 Lestner Berkner. Wayne Gymnasium 70.13 American Radiator Co., Wayne Gymnasium . 487.86 U. S. Radiator Corporation. Wayne Gymnasium 17.50 E H. Sheldon &amp; Co., Wayne Gymnasium 35-93 Wm. B. Caife &amp; Sons, Wayne Gymnasium 315-00 Freeport Gas Machine Co.. Wayne school 485.00 Electro Bleaching Gas Co., Wayne school 35955 Durand Steel Locker Co., Wayne school 929.24 U. S. Conn, Wayne Gymnasium .'. 581.65 A. B. Lake, Kearney school 152.50 918 Jan. 21 H E. Reische, Secretary salary 100.00 Dan Morris, Board expense 8.92 T. J. Majors, Board expense _ 9.16 Frank Pilger. Board expense 12.40 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense _ 8.04 H. E. Reische. Beard expense _ 33-82 Omaha Printing Co., Board expense 4.54 C. J. Burke. Kearney Gymnasium _ _ 4'3-7O aie Engineering Co., assigned. Kearney Gymnasium 564.44 G. A. Thompson. Chadron east wing 600.00 J. C. Stitt, architect Chadron east wing 119.15 Harry M Plummer. Chadron east wing 609.00 F. E. Mullholen. Chadron east wing 7,334.00 Wallare Bros.. Wayne, lots for campus extension 374-O0 Samuel Barnes. Wayne, lots for campus extension 4.099.00 U. S. Conn. Wayne, lots for campus extension 13.00 P. C. Crockett. Wayne, lots for campus extension 374-OO Carrie O. Garrett, Wayne, lots for campus extension... 1,899.00 W. O. Cunningham, Wayne, lots for campus extension 350.00 F. L. Hughes. Wayne, lots for campus extension 48.00 Henry W. Lessman. Wayne, lots for campus extension 250.00 Leroy V. Ley, Wayne, lots for campus extension 54.25 Mch. 15 W. A. Hunter, Wayne, lots for campus extension 720.00 Walter A. Hunter. Wayne, lots for campus extension... 1,430.00 G. H. McGee, Wayne, lots for campus extension 600.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION D. S. McVicker, Wayne, lots for campus extension... 225.00 Burrett W. Wright. Wayne, lots for campus extension 850.00 April 8 Kearney Plumbing &amp; Heating Co.. Kearney Gym 7.230.00 Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Co., Board expense .... 2.35 H. E. Rcische. Secretary salary 100.00 T. J. Majors. Board expense _ _ 1+92 Walter Knutzen, Kearney Gymnasium 10,196.35 Dan Morris, Board expense 8.44 Frank Pilger, Board expense 12.42 H. E. Reische, Board expense 68.61 State Eng. Co., assigned. Kearney Gymnasium 30.18 Wm. B. Scaife &amp; Sons, Kearney Gymnasium 625.00 State Eng. Co.. Kearney Gymnasium 114.88 Harry M. Pulmmer. Chadron school _ 200.00 State Eng. Co., assigned. Chadron east wing 266.42 State Eng. Co., assigned, Chadron east wing 269.58 June 10 H. E. Reische, Secretary salary _ 100.00 J. H. Craddock, architect Kearney Gymnasium 773-48 State Journal Co., Board expense 9.50 July 29 Dan Morris, Board expense 38.56 T. J. Majors, Board expense 10.02 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense 17.85 G. E. Hall, Board expense _ _ _ 9.67 Frank Pilger, Board expense — 3829 H. E. Reische, Board expense 4502 H. E. Reische, Board expense _ _ 46.18 Nov. 15 Frank Pilger, Board expense _ 1538 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense _ 10.40 T. J. Majors, Board expense _ . 12.76 H. E. Reische, Secretary salary ...._ 100.00 Harry Porter, Board expense _ 1.95 H. E. Reische, Board expense _ _.._ 53.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 13 Nebraska State Normal School Chadron To the Honorable Board of Education of the State Normal Schools: Gentlemen — I hereby certify that the accompanying report is, to the best of my knowledge, a true and correct statement covering the re - ceipts and expenditures of the Chadron State Normal School for the biennium beginning December I, 1916. and ending December I, 1918. I am pleased to submit at this time a report of the conditions of the Chadron State Normal for the past two years, and to suggest the needed improvemnets for the ensuing biennium. Very respectfully yours. ROBERT I. ELLIOTT, President. The past two years have been as difficult in school work as in any other line of work, owing largely to war conditions. This School has done all it possibly could in the various relief movements, and a great deal of effort on the part of the faculty has been devoted to the war activities. Cn account of the scarcity of men in the country, many of the young people have been unable to attend school. Many who intended to come have been urged to teach, and enter the various lines of other work. In spite of this fact, the attendance at the Chadron State Normal has in - creased, and this year will show the largest enrollment in the history of the school. The attendance, however, has been, and will continue to be very irregular for the present year, on account of the influenza. NEED OF TRAINED TEACHERS We see more clearly than ever that the public school is the founda - tion of democracy. Having won the great victory against autocracy at a tremendous sacrifice, both in life and in property, we appreciate more than ever the real meaning of democracy and what is needed for its permanency. The word "school" is synonomous with "democracy" and the teacher is the great factor in the school. Since this is true, we in the State Normal Schools must see to it that teachers are properly trained for the work. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION M HIGHER SALARIES FOR RURAL AND CITY TEACHERS In this connection 1 cannot hesitate to say that although the need tor trained teachers is urgent, we cannct hope to secure the best young people for this calling unless better inducements in the way of compensa - tion are forthcoming. Other lines of work which requires scarcely any preparation, are paying far better salaries than are paid the teachers who have spent from two to six years in training. In my opinion, this is one of the big things before those who are interested in the public schools and in the institutions which furnish teachers for the public schools, namely, the Normal Schools. IMPROVEMENTS During the past biennium, many minor improvements have been made. The east wing of the Chadron Normal has been completed and partially equipped. It now contains the departments of music — voice, violin and piano — domestic science, manual training, expression, edu - cation, a science lecture room and training school. All these depart - ments are fairly well equipped. A smoke stack, adequate to the needs of the heating plant, was built during the past year. AGRICULTURE 1 fee work in agriculture nas reccivec mucii attention during the past biennium. bevtral acres ot ground have been broken and are used to raise the needed vegetables for the dormitory. A dairy barn has been constructed and everything is now in excellent shape lor a rapid devel - opment of this phase of the work. '1 he hog house, chicken house and many other minor improvements will be needed very soon. This work, it seems to me, is unusually important, owing to the fact that Western Nebraska is in an agricultural area unlike any other part of the state, and therefore the agriculture department of this School can render a great service in adapting itself to the needs of Western Nebraska. BUILDINGS NEEDED There is but one building on the campus which is completed, and that is the dormitory. The main building should be finished by adding approximately thirty feet to the west wing. This additional space could house the library, the commercial department and a number of recitation rooms. The work should be completed during the biennium, as we are already in need of more room. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL •5 GIRLS' DORMITORY A girls' dormitory, adequate to the needs of the Institution, should be constructed during tin. next bienmum. At the present time, it is im - possible for us to accommodate in the dormitory, all the girls who at - tend trom out of town. We are unable, therefore, to give them as close supervision as we should like to give. The new dormitory should house about two hundred girls, and be modern in every respect. The present dormitory could be given over to the boys of the School. The boys who come here from a distance cannot be given the proper atten - tion under the present arrangement I know of nothing that is more needed than the close supervision of the maiority of boys who come to school. I am decidedly in favor of the dormitory plan for State Normal Schools. GYMNASIUM At the present time, we have no suitable place for the physical training classes. Ihere is no place for basket ball and other indoor games, but the gymnasium of the Railroad Men's V. M. C. A. This is about one mile from the Normal, and is very unsanitary and undesir - able in many respects. Young ladies ought not to be compelled to go so far for their physical training and basket ball. We should have a modern gymnasium, with all the up-to-d^te equipment, such as swim- ming pools, rvnning track, etr. By all means this should be erected during the coming biennirm. AUDITORIUM At the present time all the large functions of the School must be held in one of the down town theatres, on account of the lack of seating capacity in our Chapel. Several programs given during the year are so largely attended that the Chapel cannot accommodate the crowd. It is impossible for us to put on class plays and entertainments of this kind in the Chapel. They should be given in the School, but this will be impossible unless an Auditorium is erected. EXTENSION OF THE HEATING PLANT In the present heatinrr plant, we have two boilers. Another boiler should be added. This will necessitate the extension of the heating plant. The coal bins of the present heating plant hold only three cars of coal, and should hold ten. In order to make it large enough for this amount, it will be necessary to enlarge the coal bin addition to the heating plant. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">10 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION RURAL SCHOOLS There has been a great deal of talk about training rural school teachers, but as yet very little has been accomplished in this direction. There is decided scarcity of properly trained rural teachers in Ne- braska. It is largely the function of the Normal School to train both the rural and city teacher. In order to do this, it is necessary that a rural training school be maintained. Such a school should be erected on the campus and a great deal of encouragement should be given the young people to enter these rural courses. Too much emphasis cannot be (riven this phase of the Normal School work FACULTY The faculty, on the whole, is doing excellent work. With more buildings, improvements in the plant and better equipment to work with, much more can be accomplished. The next year or two will be the great year of the Institution, provided the School is brought up to the standard, so far as buildings are concerned. The faculty is. willing and able to do its part. CHADRON STATEMENT OF ENROLLMENT FOR THE BIENNIUM 1916-17 S. S. 1917 1917-18 S. S. 1918 Collegiate 63 9b 63 130 beconaary _ 92 tit&gt; 96 bo rreparaiory _ _ _ 79 70 77 90 Specials — e 15 40 45 Totals .242 267 278 345 Training School ..: 140 '40 Enrollment for the present year to December 1, 1918 Collegiate . — - 68 Secondary - - 7*&gt; Preparatory - — 94 Specials - — - — 43 275 Training School - i« Very respectfully ROBERT I. ELLIOTT President. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL "7 CHADRON Financial Report for Biennium, Beginning December 1, 1916, and Ending SUMMARY OF MAINTENANCE FUND Salaries of president and office force for biennium $11,241.66 Salaries of faculty members for biennium 63,697.50 Salaries of employees for biennium 6,710.62 Total cost of telegraph and telephone _ 28532 Total cost of fuel for biennium _ 6.144.00 Total cost of departmental supplies for biennium 4,501.05 $90,580.84 Balance December 1. 1916 _ .$12,075.20. Normal at Board meeting Amount appropriated to Chadron April 24. 1917 3-266.44 $16.24173 1916 Dec. 15 December, 1916, payroll $ 3.35708 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 148.21 R. C. King, conference of registrars 21.58 Ethel L. Delzell conference of domestic science instructors 29.88 W. G. Fritcher, drayage 112.85 Ralph Myers, labor _ _ 8.50 Harry Plummer. plumbing _ 64.15 W. W. Fascoe. repairing 3.20 W. A. Danley. eraser, tubes, basket ball 9.50 Chadron Journal, printing _ _ 7830 Randall Bros., toilet paper 6.60 M. E. Smith, dry goods 22.13 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 741 Johnson-Beghtol Co.. dry goods 1.46 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., folders _ 53-90 Remington Typewriter Co., ribbons 6.10 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 502.91 Wm. A. Kaun Music Co.. music 2.57 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 32.05 Chadron Hardware, hardware 3-»5 Intermountain Railway, Light &amp; Power Co., lixht 103-61 December 1, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">,8 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION W A. Potts, domestic science laundry 4.43 Schwieger Lumber Co.. coal 10.25 J. A. Munkres, D. M. groceries 25.75 Regina Cockrell. dormitory dishes 14.80 Water Commissioner, water 67-45 Carl D. Town, painting office _ 50.00 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. domestic science sup - supplies 4.32 The Prang Co., M. S. supplies 4.32 Harry Plummer, plumbing and materials ... 18.10 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm. typewriter desk 6.00 J. A. Munkres. domestic science supplies. ... 8.05 Library Bureau, tables, shelving, labels 215.65 Kewanee Boiler Co.. grate bars 20.50 Intermountain Light &amp; Power Co.. service 56.71 Erwin Hopt. grain types "-35 Gillam-Moorman Co.. bookcase 15.00 W. G. Fritcher. drayage 81.30 A. Flanagan. M. S. supplies 12.15 Robert I. Elliott, trav. expense, cash adv. 66.11 Charles Christensen, B. B. made goels: irons 700 Chadron Journal, bulletins and envelopes. .. 89.85 Chadron Hardware Co.. hardware 29.15 Chadron Furniture Co.. shades and frames 10.75 Carpenter Paper Co.. toilet paper 14.00 Advance Pump &amp; Compressor Co.. rings... 6.64 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. 643.41 1917 Jan. 23 Feb. 24 Mar. 31 January. 1917. payroll 3.374.20 February. 1917, payroll 3.378-72 Garden City Educational Co.. M. S. sup - plies _ 7 99 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 27.59 Carl Fischer, music 245.37 Fillmore Music House, music 11.08 Leo Feist, orchestra music 6.26 W. A. Danley. office supplies and basket ball - 0.00 Everett Frain Co., manual training equip 208.30 Dalton Adding Machine Co., paper 3.00 C. G. Conn Co.. musical instruments 18.72 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. paints 45.73 Chamberlain Metal Weather Co.. strips 67.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 19 Chadron Furniture Co., furn. and repairs... 100.90 Chadron Chronicle, adv. and dodgers 4.70 Carpenter Paper Co.. towels and toilet paper _ 16.00 Boston Cooking School &amp; Co., D. M. sup - plies 18.32 W. S. Bostder, extension work 14775 Beckley-Cardy Co., class records 7.30 Becker-Hazelton Co.. D. S. dishes 6.88 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., repair micro - scope 2.25 Irving G. Banghart &amp; Co.. D. S. supplies... 24.06 Schwabe Bros., grass seed 26.00 Harry M. Plummer. plumbing 18.15 J. A. Munkres. D. S. groceries 4585 C. M Henderson, tuning pianos 19.00 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., D. S. supplies 12.15 Willard F Gailey Co.. env and half tones.... 51.20 Fred Crites, flag 8.00 J. W. Good, seed potatoes _ 75.00 Chadron Laundry. S. S. laundry 7.59 S. L. Clements, orchestra (0.61 Chadron Hardware Co.. hardware 6a.I5 Carl D. Town, paints, varnish, etc I4-5O Intermouniain Railway. Light &amp; Power Co., current 13300 Wyoming &amp; Nebraska Telephone Co., service 43-2O W. G. Fritcher, drayage 105.25 Graves Studio, pictures _ 8.00 Hale Specialty Co.. office supplies 2.10 Hall &amp; McCreary. M. S. supplies 2.96 Industrial Education Co.. D. M. supplies 10.64 Johns-Manville Co.. engine house supplies . 10.24 Kalamazoo Vegetable Parchment Co., D. M. supplies _ 4.22 Bruno C. Keefer Co., musical instruments 8.50 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. bookkeeping sets 12.80 H. E. McCroskey. repairing clock 8.00 Milwaukee Lace Paper Co.. D. S. supplies.... 5.18 Ralph Myers, labor and materials ..._ 72.00 Nebraska School Supply House, com. sup - plies _ 52.07 Parsons Furn. &amp; Undertaking Co., frames 2.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">JO STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION J. W. Pepper &amp; Son, music 4.75 Perkins Bros. Co.. notary seal 2.24 Harry Porter, office supplies 1.30 The Prang Co., M. S. supplies 9.92 Frederick Post Co.. paper, prints and ink .... 10.38 Wm. Reinheimer. typewriter _ 50.00 Remington Typewriter Co.. carbon paper .... 1.58 G. Schirmer Co., music 65. 7Q Singer Sewing Machine Co., D. S. machine 26.64 Standard Oil Co.. gas 17.P2 J. H. Stough. pictures for bulletin 5.00 Siinderland Machinery supplies Co.. engine house _... 2030 Y. M. C. A.. B. B. games iq.no Robert I Elliott, expense ..._ 287.03 W. T. Stockdale. extension work 35.42 I. H. White &amp; Co.. hardware 11.62 Morison Lumber Co.. lumber 9615 The Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 628.84 The Kearney Daily Hub. printing 13.00 Balance reverting to general fund 154.29 $16,241.73 $16,241.73 4125.000.00 Appropriation for biennium beginning April 1, 1917 March payroll _ _ _ _ 3.363.°8 $128,363.68 March, 1917, payroll _ 3,363.68 April, 1917, payroll _ _ 3.461.20 May, 1917, payroll _ 353+49 July 25 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 20.45 Underwood Typewriter Co., stencil paper... 21.60 Carl D. Town, paint 8.30 W. T. Stockt ale. extension work 78.14 Standard Oil Co., gas machine gas 17.82 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., table linen _... 34.69 Schwabe Bros., garden seeds 10.65 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., dishes for dorm 147-88 Red Cross Drug Store formaldehyde 1.45 Randall Bros., toilet paper _ 10.85 Harry Plummer, plumbing I3-7O R. B. Perrine, team for three months 60.00 W. W. Pascoe, well casing and gal 3I-7O J. C. Neff, tuning piano _ 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 21 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co., lumber 84.96 J. A. Munkres. D. S. groceries 16.00 M orison Lumber Co., hardware 56.40 H. E. Morey, silverware 8.00 Miller &amp; Paine, office rug _ 44-00 The Jewell Nursery Co., trees - 10.00 lutermountain Railway, Light &amp; Power Co., services and labor '78-91 Ideal School Supply Co., pottery 6.50 Hammond &amp; Stephens, B. E. Degree _ 2.00 L. A. Halverson, viola - 35-00 (iillam-Moorman Co., steel plow 18.00 W. G. Fritcher. drayage — 64.10 A. Flanagan Co.. M. S. materials 22.67 Robert 1 Elliott, expense 267.00 Thomas Charles Co.. drawing and const. work - 26.76 Chadron Laundry, laundry — 5-°3 The Chadron Journal, notices 2.10 Chadron Hardware Co.. hardware 39.10 Chadron Furniture Co.. chairs and pads .... 43-0° The Chadron Chronicle, bills, badges, pro - grams — - 10.10 Charles Christensen. sharpen plow 3-5° W. S. Bostder, expense _ — 78-20 The Willard F. Bailey, bulletins 3" 73 W. T. Stockdale, extension work 15.34 J. H. White &amp; Co.. hardware 180 June. 1917. payroll _ 3,621,00 July 13 Wyoming &amp; Nebraska Telephone Co., service - 47-8o Whitebread Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 373S 8 July. 1917. payroll 3.598-37 Aug. 11 Chadron Furniture Co.. rent on turn 15.00 The Chadron Chronicle, cards 26.30 Meek Lumber Co.. lumber for man. training 30.00 W. G. Fritcher. freight - 4-O0 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 170.72 Carl D. Town, paints, brushes, etc 13-75 Garden City Education Co., pictures, etc 1.00 Hammond &amp; Stephens, diplomas 35.85 Intermountain Railway. Light &amp; Power Co., service 35-72 Merwin O. Johnson, orchestra bells — *&gt;.oo </seg>
            <seg id="p022">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Midwest Red Cedar Producing Co., M. T. lumber 167.07 Middle West School Review, advertising... 10.50 Dalton Adding Machine Co., ribbon 1.00 T. S. Denison &amp; Co., plays .85 Henry A. Dreer &amp; Co., points weeders and iron 3.90 Chadron Garage Co., drive 3.00 Chadron Garage Co., drive 3.00 Chadron Hardware Co.. hardware 5&gt;-8s Chadron Hardware Co.. hardware 51.85 . he Chadron Journal, invitations and prtg. 25.50 he Chadron Journal, invitations and prtg. 25.50 Chadron Laundry, domestic science laundry 10.88 Chadron Laundry, domestic science laundry 10.88 Charles Christensen, freezer handle 2.50 Charles Christensen, freezer handle 2.50 C. H. Stoelting, science supplies 219.91 C. H. Stoelting, science supplies 219.91 Stein way &amp; Sons, pedals for piano 2.11 Stein way &amp; Sons, pedals for piano 2.11 If. E. Smith &amp; Co.. domestic science sup - plies 7.56 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. domestic science sup- plies 7-5° Water Commissioner, water rent 99-35 Water Commissioner, water rent 99-35 James White, curbing driveway 357-30 James White, curbing driveway 357-30 J. H. White &amp; Co., fencing 83.52 J. H. White &amp; Co., fencing 83.52 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 66.50 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 66.50 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 R. B. Perrine, use of team 60.00 R. B. Perrine, use of team 60.00 Harry Plummer, plumbing 54-10 Harry Plummer, plumbing 54-10 P. P. Prondfiit, lumber and posts 63.30 P. P. Prondfiit, lumber and posts 63.30 Randall Bros., toilet paper 9.68 Randall Bros., toilet paper 9.68 Red Cross Drug Store, drugs 2.25 Red Cross Drug Store, dru Schwabe Bros., cultivator 26.00 Schwabe Bros., cultivator 26.00 August, 1917, payroll _ _ 804.00 August, 1917, payroll _ _ 804.00 September, 1917, payroll 3.784.38 September, 1917, payroll 3.784.38 October, 1917. payroll _ 3.836.76 October, 1917, payroll _ 3.836.76 Nov Beckley-Cardy Co., class records 7.60 Beckley-Cardy Co., class records 7.60 10 W. S. Bostder( extension work „ 44-17 W. S. Bostder( extension work „ 44-17 The Chadron Chronicle, printing 8.25 The Chadron Chronicle, printing 8.25 Chadron Furniture Co., shades, hampers, chairs _._ 4470 Chadron Telephone Co., service 31-55 Chadron Telephone Co., service 31-55 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 12.63 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 12.63 Mrs. Regina Cockrell, dom. sci. dishes 2.40 Mrs. Regina Cockrell, dom. sci. dishes 2.40 W. A. Danley. piano 265.00 W. A. Danley. piano 265.00 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 71.66 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 71.66 Susan R Frazier, study center 17.60 Susan R Frazier, study center 17.60 W. G. Frjtcher, drayage _ 43-OO W. G. Frjtcher, drayage _ 43-OO Gillam-Moorman, hinges and hooks 3.25 Gillam-Moorman, hinges and hooks 3.25 Intermountain Railway, Light &amp; Power Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 2i service 74-64 S. C. Johnson &amp; Son, dye and wax 11.30 Kewanee Boiler Co., grates _ 121.65 E. E. Morey, clock 2.50 R. B. Perrine, use of team _ 80.00 Harry Porter, carbon paper 5.50 The Prang Co., M. S'. supplies '9-39 Randall Bros., toilet paper 8.20 Leora A. Rustin. study center 10.10 Remington Typewriter Co., ribbons 12.47 Red Cross Drug Store, Victrola and rec - ords 38.00 Standard Oil Co., gas and floor dressing... 60.23 W. T. Stockdale, study center 39-87 G. A. Thompson, decorating _ 1.645.00 Carl D. Town, brushes, cement 25-30 Underwood Typewriter Co., duplicator ink 15.00 Water Commissioner, water rent 53-IO Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 267.25 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 10.85 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 130.62 York Blank Book Co.. bulletins 14700 Chadron Garage Co., drives 12.00 Schwieger Lumber Co., lumber 47-01 J. S. O'Hare. cave and walks 392-75 Morison Lumber Co., lumber and coal 13785 Chadron Hardware Co., hardware 69.99 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. dom. sci, materials... 1336 Carl Fischer, music 9.30 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 562.24 Merwin O. Johnson, expenses _. 20.67 Nov November. 1917, payroll 3.868.73 December, 1917, payroll _ 3,859.39 1918 Jan. 2. January, 1918. payroll 3-774-5' Ki R. E. Varndley. music and platform 19.26 Western Electric Co., fuse plugs 17.87 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., agr. equipment 135-57 Water Commissioner, water rent 21-45 Underwood Typewriter Co., duplicator ink 1790 C. H. Stoelting Co., lab. materials 50.06 W. T. Stockdale, study center 78.18 M E. Smith &amp; Co., sewing materials 3.80 L. C Smith &amp; Bros. Type Co., typewriters. ... 420.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co.. dom sci equipment 582.88 E H. Sargent &amp; Co.. Lab. equipment 12.44 Leora A. Rustin. study center 3105 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. dishes, chairs, desk 88.65 Hotel Rome, headquarters 5.15 Remington Typewriter Co.. Com. supplies .... 53-94 Red Cross Drug Store, turp. and'varnish 3.10 P. P. Proudfit, lumber _ 2.75 Harry Porter, paper and binder Harry Porter, paper and binder '&gt;.(« Harry Plumimer, plumbing 20.01 Harry Plumimer, plumbing aaoi Leonard Peterson &amp; Co.. Lab. equipment... 848.90 Leonard Peterson &amp; Co.. Lab. equipment... 848.00 R. B. Perrine. use of team 160.00 R. B. Perrine. use of team 160.00 J. C. Neff, tuning pianos ._ 12.00 J. C. Neff, tuning pianos 12.00 Nebr. School Supply House, paper, chalk 74-36 Nebr. School Supply House, paper, chalk 74-36 J. A. Munkres, dom. sci, groceries 63.45 J. A. Munkres, dom. sci, groceries 63.45 A. W. Mumford. colored plates 1. 16 A. W. Mumford. colored plans 1.16 Morison Lumber Co.. lumber and coal 247-*) Morison Lumber Co.. lumber and coal 247.80 H. E. McCroskey. repairing clock 9.00 H. E. McCroskey. repairing clock 9.00 H. F. Maika. plaster paris 2.85 H. F. Maika. plaster paris 2.85 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. music 54-7 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. music 54-7 Intermountain Railway. Light &amp; Power Co.. service _ _ 17893 Intermountain Railway. Light &amp; Power Co.. 17893 service George Bros., letter heads 48.65 George Bros., letter heads 48.65 W. G. Fritcher. drayage 146.80 W. G. Fritcher. drayage 146.H0 Susan R. Frazier. study center 52.01 Susan R. Frazier. study center 52.01 O. C. Erlewine, disinfecting 20.50 O. C. Erlewine, disinfecting 20.50 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 574-42 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 574-42 William Elmorc. dom. sci. dishes 3490 William Elmorc. dom. sci. dishes 34°o Eberbach &amp; Son. corks _ 2.25 Eberbach &amp; Son. corks _ 3.25 Eugene Dietzgen. poles, tape, target 2073 Eugene Dietzgen. poles, tape, target 2073 W. A. Danley. ink. paper, mailing tubes 54-3O Ross F. Curtice Co.. 2 pianos 600.00 Chas. Christensen. repairs on farm imp. 2 no Chicago Apparatus Co.. minerals 6.2; Thomas. Charles Co.. M. S. supplies ijj Chadron Telephone Co.. service 24-15 Chadron Hardware Co., hardware 57-45 The Chadron Drug Co.. drugs 3.40 The Chadron Chronicle, receipt books 37-OO W. S. Bostder. study center 40,30 The Beghtol Co.. toweling 1.50 American Radiator Co.. air valves 15.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. coal I.574-2I Feb 26 February. 1918, payroll 3-797 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 25 March, 1918, payroll 3,793.72 Apr. 20 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 44577 The American Multigraph Co., supplies 3.7a Richard E. Yarndley. music for glee club.... 10.70 Wyoming &amp; Nebr. Telephone Co.. service 14.15 Woodruff Bank Note Co., bulletins and fnvs 97-35 L. L. Williams, hay 24-70 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 1.614.55 Western Electric Co.. mazda lamps 47-76 Carl D. Town, brushes and labor 19.88 Water Commissioner, water rent 42.45 G. A. Thompson, painting 540.70 Sunderland Bros. Co., blackboard 370.92 Standard Oil Co.. gas machine gas 17.36 W. T. Stockdale. study center 68.46 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. D. S and Agr. materials 12.40 J. W. Skeen. making tables 24.00 Omaha School Supply Co. window shades... 207.74 Nebr. School Supply House, adv. chairs 412.68 J. A. Miinkres. D. S. groceries 52.44 R B. Perrine. use of team 80.00 Harry Plummer. plumbing and materials... 333.01 Harry Porter, paper, ink. guides, pencils 85.10 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. dormitory dishes 20.80 Randall Bros., toilet paepr 7.00 P. P. Proudfit. lumber and plaster 9.15 Leora A. Rustin, study center 10.73 Morison Lumber Co., lumber _ 111.05 E. E. Morey, cleaning and repairing clock.... 1.00 Middle West School Review, advertising... 10.50 H. F. Maika. first aid remedies 2.80 J. S. Latta. M. S. supplies 5.51 J W Jenkins Sons Music Co.. orch music... 1.54 Intermountain Railway, Light &amp; Power Co., service 110.69 Hyde &amp; Satterlee. B. B. suits 28.49 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co., brushes _ 36.00 F. R. Hartranft. screws for M T..._ 1.70 R. W. Graves, photos 11.05 Grand Rapids School Equipment Co.. M. T. 1,652.45 Garlock Packing Co., washers, rings 8.14 Garden City Ed. Co., M. S. supplies 6.20 W. G. Fritcher. drayage 108.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">2(1 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION* Susan R Frazier, study center ... A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 3*58 34-19 Democrat Printing Co., ink, order cards Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies Chicago Flag &amp; Decorating Co.. flags.. Ethel Delzell. milk 3-4" 23.26 39SO 300 Chadron Hardware, hardware 71.58 Chadron Furniture Co., chairs and casters Chadron Drug Co., disinfectants 38-4O 2.50 Central Scientific Co., chemical supplies April, 1918, payroll 4377 Apr. 30 i.t)722l) 3683.80 May, 1918, payroll June 18 Jacob North &amp; Co., bulletins V. M. C. A., use of Gymnasium 254-33 1200 Wyoming &amp; Nebr. Telehpone Co.. service Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co. coal J. H. W.hite &amp; Co.. hardware 14.00 321.18 23583 Western Electric Co., fuses 744 American Multigraph Sales Co.. repairs Baker Bros Engraving Co., cuts 317" 66 Chadron Chronicle, programs Chadron Furniture Co.. chairs Chadron Hardware, hardware SoO 41 SO 171 43 Chadron Laundry, laundry for dom sci James Chaulk. seed potatoes 18.21 24. oo W. M. Chaulk. use of team G. M. Cook, hay ... SS-oo l8.il Ethel Delzell. milk 300 Distilled Water Ice Co.. ice Kate Driscoll. ribbons O. C. Erlewine, disinfecting A. Flanagan Co.. M. S. supplies George Bros, stationery 2-75 37O 16.00 34-57 2.V&gt; 8.oo XT. C. Hackler. seed potatoes H. F. Maika, bon ami. san flush _ J. A. Munkres. dom. sci. groceries The Nebraska Teacher, advertising (.ffice Equipment &amp; Supply Co.. env J. S. O'Hare, raising basement windows. Parsons Furniture &amp; Undertaking Co., fu 1. 10 40.40 500 2375 90.00 migating 54-70 P. P. Proudfit, lumber and posts Randall Bros., toilet paper 5-5° 9-25 Roberts Bros., drayage Q.OO </seg>
            <seg id="p027">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 27 June 29 Aug. I Alex Sherrig. cards, bills, advertising 24-45 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., dry goods * 15.12 Standard Oil Co.. gasoline 19-44 E. O. Sweet, barn rented for cow 3.75 Underwood Typewriter Co., stencil paper... 20.40 June. 1918, payroll 3.835.44 Bill Christensen, drayage 8.50 Juply. 1918, payroll 3-999-47 H. F. Maika. ink 2.30 M orison Lumber Co., lumber 56-55 The Morrill Mail, printing bills 7.00 Ralph Myers, screens 404.00 Susan R. Frazier, study center 15.06 (lillam-Moorman Co., hinges, keys, locks .... 2.95 Intel-mountain Railway. Light &amp; Power Co., mdse., labor 40725 R. 1 Elliott, cash advanced 831.27 Enterprise Sand Co., sand for smoke stack 30.80 A. Flanagan Co.. M. S. supplies 15.85 \V. A. Dan ley. books 2.25 Creamery Package Mrc. Co.. dairy supplies 14.09 Distilled Water Ice Co.. ice 8.80 The E. C. Brown Co.. Agriculture supplies .... 12.10 Chadnm (laruge Co.. drives IO.0O Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 24.68 Milwaukee Lace Paper Co.. dom. sci. sup - plies 4-40 J. A. Munkres. dom. sci. groceries 74-86 Grand Rapids Equipment Co.. M. T. equip. 3.62 Harry Plunniier. plumbing and repairing... 103.50 Parsons Furniture &amp; Undertaking Co. furn. 56.50 Northrop. King &amp; Co.. seeds 25.27 The Xebr. School Supply House, paper 13.75 J. C. Neff. piano tuning 15.00 R. B. Perrine. use of team 185.00 William Perry, hauling gravel 24.75 Charles Christensen. repairs 24.45 Eugent Dietrgen Co.. M. T. supplies 15.59 The Beghtol Co.. M. S. supplies .60 Central Scientific Co. D. S. supplies 11.00 Western Electric Co.. lamps 7-5° Wyoming &amp; Nebr. Telephone Co.. service... 25.70 Leora A. Rustin. study center 14.12 W. T. Stockdale. study center 44-7» </seg>
            <seg id="p028">» j8 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION W. H. Welch Mfg. Co., diplomas and cert. 51.09 Water Commissioned, water rent 43-8o Carl D. Town, brush 1.00 Standard Oil Co., gasoline _ 19.62 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., materials for D. S 4.40 Aug. 12 The Skinner Irrigation Co., watering system _ _ 54.75 Roberts Bros., drayage 5O-5O Remington Typewriter Co., rib. and straps 7.25 R. E. Varndlty, music for glee club 24.52 J. H. White, farm supplies 10.31 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, dishes 78.75 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., floor dressing 111.30 Chadron Hardware Co., hardware 482.46 Chadron Journal, printing 62.01 Chadron Laundry, dom. sci. laundry g.&lt;«&gt; Aug. 30 August, 1918, payroll I.353-1O September. 1918, payroll ..._ 3.945.25 October, 1918. payroll _ 3.994-55 P. P. Proudfit, material for smoke stack. ... 478.90 The Prang Co., M. S. supplies 8.81 Harry Porter, M S. and office supplies 37-8o Harry Plumnier. plumbing 595-55 VV. R. Pettycrew, labor 238.15 L. C. Smit hTypewriter Co., ribbons 9.08 Singer Sewing Machine Co., machine 5712 Schwieger Lumber Co.. lumber 41.80 Schwabe Bros., seeds, repairing fountain... 13.31) Roberts Bros., drayage 116.00 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 1,601.04 Red Cross Drug Store, drugs 7.10 Remington Typewriter Co., ribbons 15.7; M. E. Smith &amp; Co., dry goods 14.71 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 5.8; Vestal Chemical Co., supplies and fixtures.... 81.00 Nov. 18 Underwood Typewriter Co., stencils 28.56 Guy Taylor, drayage ....*. 14.10 B. G. Taylor __ 18.00 W. L. Talbert, typewriter _ 81.31 Standard Oil Co., oil 9.69 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., wands _... 4.32 D. Snyder, contract for smoke stack _... 1,630.00 D. Snyder, work on barn _ 740.00 Gillam-Moorman Co., supplies .95 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL *&gt; The Garlock Packing Co.. packing 12.50 The Hickok Producing Co., oil 04 5" Great Eastern Chemical Co.. chemicals 45.00 Grand Rapids School Equip. Co., supplies 18.12 Maxro-Ross Co., ribbons and carbon paper 125.50 Creamery Package Mfg. Co.. cream stirrer .57 Lewis &amp; Conger. D. S supplies Kewanee Boiler Co.. grate bars Wyoming Nebr. Telephone Co.. service Woodruff Bank N'ote Co.. bulletins and env. 3-51 57.00 20.35 60.60 Martin Ford, roofiing '. 1. 00 Mrs. A. L. Andrews, disinfectant ClnHron Furniture Co.. furniture 3-70 182.25 Chadron Chronicle, printing +50 Chadron Garage Co.. drive 1. 00 Charles Christensen. labor 2.05 William B. Duck Co.. practice sets Thomas Charles, kindergarten supplies 27.00 18.61 C uster County Chief, subscription Enterprise Sand Co., sand 150 30.80 A. Flanagan Co.. M. S. supplies '. Harry Fahnestock. hauling Parsons Fnrn. &amp; Undertaking Co.. casters The Omaha School Supply House, chalk Omaha News Co., books 47-45 5O 6.80 4.80 40.08 A. X. Palmer Co., paper and pens 10.45 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware Northwestern Quarry Co., rock Omaha Hardwood Co.. lumber 260.81 5&amp;8o 408-45 J. S. O'Hare, first payment on contract 443 30 Henry Moshier. use of mower J. A. Munkres. D S. groceries Nebr School Supply House, supplies 4.00 29-7O I577I H. E. McCroskey, repairing Middle West School Review, advertising 6.00 12.00 Morison Lumber Co., balance on account... Intermountain Railway Light &amp; Power Co., 18.45 lijjht and fixtures 968.99 Freeport Gas Machine Co., supplies and labor 48750 Roberts Bros., drayage 117.00 F. Fahnestock. water ~ 4180 Distilled Water Ice Co., ice _.. D. Snyder, gas plant, etc 2-75 87.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 30 Balance 1916 Dec. 6 Jan. 4 68 ■0.31 3" 1423 $128,363.68 $128,363 INSTITUTION CASH in fund December 1, 1916 S3. Sent state Treasurer 1X1 American Book Co.. text 28.K8 6.95 Nebr. School Supply House, paper Ginn &amp; Co.. texts Allyn &amp; Bacon, text 1 11.29 _&gt;6.8o American School of Home Ecc Carpenter Paptr. towe.li A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supp Garden City Educational Co. nomics. hook 10.00 lie 17 M. S. sup- plies 925 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. text M2 The McGraw Co, mazda lamj J. C. Neff. tuning pianos The Manual Arts Press. M. T. 14.91 6.00 jppliei »5 1. A. Parks, music for pub. school work Harry Porter. M S. supplies 13 7 io.8? Row. Peterson 8; Co.. M. S. books Silver. Burdett &amp; Co.. M. S. books W. M. Welch MfR. Co.. dip. and certificat Webb Pub. Co.. texts 54-48 3-84 75.00 15-33 Welles Bros. Pub. Co.. reference books A. C. McCiurg &amp; Co., texts 20.33 Red Cross Drug Store, record The Macmillan Co., texts 180 Alyse Swedberg. music instructions 84-44 5.50 Sent State Treasurer Alysc Swedberg. music American Book Co.. book 102.61 .*&lt; &lt;&gt;- C. M. Henderson, rep. and tuning piano 1917 A llliani Perry, labor 12.00 *. B. Perrine. use of team I35«J iVhitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 728.00 November, 1918, payroll 3.99012 $111,789.82 Balance in fund December I, 1918 16.573-86 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 3i reb. I Sent State Treasurer Feb 361.95 Mar. 3 Sent State Treasurer 4OM5 Apr. 5 Sent State Treasurer r - 5 Sent State Treasurer 185.85 May i Sent State Treasurer _ Houghton. Mifflin &amp; Co., books 25.15 May 1 Sent State Treasurer 229,5 Houghton. Mifflin &amp; Co.. books 25.15 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 19.211 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 19.20 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., books 11.25 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., books 11.25 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 14.17 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 14^7 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books _ 7.76 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books The Macmillan Co., books 61.29 Chas. E. Merrill Co., books... 3.74 Scott. Foresman &amp; Co.. hooks 3.84 Alyse SweJberg. piano instruction 14230 F. E. Volland &amp; Co.. M. S. books 1.70 Paul \V. Thomas, orchestra instruction 104.43 Paul W. Thomas, orchestra instruction June 1 Sent State Treasurer June 1 Sent State Treasurer 590.12 July 1 Sent State Treasurer I Sent State Treasurer 58915 July 2.=, A. H. Clark Co.. books 3.78 nly 25, A. H. Clark Co.. book Educational Pub. Co.. texts 3.60 (&gt;. Schirmer Co.. music 2.72 Alysc Swedberg. music collections 129.02 Alysc Swedbcrg. music collections Paul Thomas, music collections 77-97 Paul Thomas, music collections R. R. Perrine. use ot team 4000 R. R. Pt an Isaac Pitman &amp; Sons, text books 15.63 Isaac Pitman &amp; Sons, text books 15.63 Auk. I Sent State Treasurer American Rook Co.. books _ g.68 Aujr. 1 Sent Suite Treasurer 632.08 American Rook Co.. books _ g.68 Bnblis-Merril Co., books 10.02 Bobbs-Merril Co., book Arthur Clark Co.. hooks 4.90 ( ireap Publishing Co., books 1.48 Industrial Ed. Co., hooks 7.89 Lyon &amp; Healy Co 12.81 Benj. H. Sanborn &amp; Co II2 Silver. Burdett &amp; Co., hooks 5.95 Silver. Burdett &amp; Co.. books 595 Alyse Swedberg. music collections 114.50 Alysc Swedberjj, music collections 114.50 Paul Thomas, music collections 77-44 Paul Thomas, music collection University Pulithing Co.. books 136.14 Sep. 1 Sent State Treasurer _ Sep. 1 Sent State Treasurer _ 159-05 Oct. 1 Sent StateTreasurer Oct. 1 Sent StateTreasurer 910.20 Nov. 1 Sent State Treasurer _ The Manual Training Arts Press, books 1550 John P. Mann, violin instruction 26.75 Nov. 1 Sent State Treasurer _ 634.10 The Manual Training Arts Press, books 15-50 John P. Mann, violin instruction 26-75 The Macmillan Co.. text books 4.04 The Macmillan Co.. text books 4.04 4.04 Houghton. Mifflin &amp; Co., text books 14-35 Houghton. Mifflin &amp; Co., text books 14-35 Ginn &amp; Co.. text books _ 5896 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">.?5&lt;i.44 403.60 619-55 53008 X STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co.. bkpg. sets 24.73 D. C Heath &amp; Co., books _.._ 26.27 G. A. Crancer. music _ 1.06 American Book Co.. books _ 20.33 The Century Co., text books 14.40 Ailyn &amp; Bacon, books 121.30 Nebraska School Supply House, paper 7+53 Isaac Pitman &amp; Sons, text books 39-78 H. M. Rowe Co., text books 20.46 Chas. E. Merrill Co.. text books 4.80 Nov. Q (j. &amp; C. Merriam Co., dictionary...- 10.80 Row, Peterson &amp; Co. books 7..32 Benj. H. Sanborn &amp; Co., books .79 Scott. Foresman &amp;Co.. M. S. books 1.44 Silver, Burdett &amp; Co., books _ 39-54 C. H. Stoelting Co.. psychology 67.88 Alyse Swedberg, music collections 211.91 Paul \V. Thomas, music collections 4529 Sewell E. Townsend, violin collections 108.50 Richard E. Yarndley. instruction 1 18.13 G. Schirmer Co., music 64.70 Edw. J. Walt, orchestra music _ 20.85 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 151.61 Garden City Ed. Co., M. S. supplies 20.58 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co., M. T. equip. 215.17 Dec. I Sent State Treasurer 1918 Jan. 4 S'ent State Treasurer Jan Sewell E. Townsend. music collections ios.2 Alyse Swedberg. music collections 210.00 Mid-West Red Cedar Products Co.. chests 381.91 The Macmillan Co., books ._ 50.88 Lyon &amp; Healy. music 4.62 Lincoln Fine Arts Shop, picture 6.00 The H. R. Hunting Co., books. 4.50 Ginn &amp; Co.. books 75 A. Flanagan Co., books, pencils 7.34 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 2.66 R. E. Yarndley, music collections 228.00 Feb. 4 Sent State Treasurer :. — 1.024.25 Sent State Treasurer Mar. 4 Apr. I Sent State Treasurer Apr. 20 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co., M. T. ma- terial 106.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 3.1 I.yon &amp; Healy. music 4.98 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. bookkeeping sets 80.64 Industrial E&lt;1. Co., book 3-6o D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. texts 6.81 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co.. texts 12.76 Carl Fischer Co.. music 6.26 The Century Co.. tex ■5-3O American Book Co.. text book 17.41 Allyn &amp; Bacon Co.. books 4.30 Richard E. Yarndley, vocal instruction 33500 Webb Pub. Co.. books 1.43 Sewell Townsend. violin instruction 181.75 Sewell Townsend. violin instruction 181.75 Alyse Swedberg. piano instruction 29722 Alyse Swedberj?. piano instruction 297.22 Silver. Burden Co.. books 28.67 Silver. Burden Co.. book: Edw. J. Walt, music G. Schirmer Co.. music t Sent State Treasurer .... 28.67 Edw. J. Walt, music 50.31 5O3I G. Schirmer Co.. music to be sold to stu 22.34 be sold to stu 22.34 May 3 Sent State Treasurer May 3 429.0; June 7 Sent State Treasurer _ R. E. Yarndlev. music collection 253.00 R. E. Varnd'ey. musir collections 8.14 I nut- 7 Sent State Treasurer _ "63.52 R. E. Yarndlev. music cc Election Elections 253.(10 R. E. Yarnd'ey. musir cr 8.14 Sewell K Townsrnd. music collections 14285 Sewell E Townsend. nm Alysf Swedberu. music c sic collections ollections 142.85 08.25 Alysc SwedberK. music collections 08.35 Rand McNally &amp; Co., text books .50 Rand McNally &amp; Co.. text books 50 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co.. lumber sold to students 122.49 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co.. lumber sold indent 13J40 Mid-Wist Cedar Products Co., chests 67-57 Mid-West Cedar Products Co., chests 67.57 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. texts 1.70 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. texts 1.70 Carl Fischer, music „ _ 6.08 Carl Fischer, music „ _ 6.08 Ruth Baerneil. music collections 56.00 Ruth Bagwell, music collections 56.00 American Book Co.. books _ 10.90 American Book Co.. books _ 19.00 July 9 Sent State Treasurer July 9 Sent State Treasurer 810.35 Aug. 8 Sent State Treasurer _ Aug. 8 Sent State Treasurer _ 831.40 Aug. 12 Allyn &amp; Bacon Co., texjs .54-00 D. Appleton &amp; Co.. text books _ 2.33 Edw. W. Walt, music to be sold to students 3.14 The Prang Co., art supplies 2.66 H. R. Condrey. books to be sold to students 8.40 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. text books _ 4.32 Houffhton Mifflin &amp; Co.. text books 19.80 Little Brown Co.. book .48 The Macmillan Co.. text books 22.08 Isaac Pitman Co.. text books 43-84 Ruth Racrnell. music collections 277.00 Sewell Townsend. music collections _ 74^5 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION *3-35 $13,934 and Ending 1.848.0. 10.00 10.00 R. E. Yarndley.music collections 310.00 Alyse Swedberg, music collections 39-00 Bobbs-Merrill Co., text books 12.84 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co., bkpg. sets... 13.82 • Gregg Publishing Co., text books G0.12 American Book Co., text books 6470 Sep. 14 Sent State Treasurer Nov. 6 John Wiley &amp; Sons, books 13.02 R. E. Yarndley, music collections _ 181.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon Co.. books 115.20 American Book Co., books 5°-52 Ginn &amp; Co., books 22.32 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 20.77 \V. A. Kaun Music Co.. music to be sold to students 3.98 Macmillan Co.. books 48.00 H. M. Rowe Co., sup. to be sold to students 58.83 G. Scmirmer. music to be sold to students 28.12 Southwestern Pub. Co.. bookkeeping sets. 2.2\ Alyse SwedberR. music collections 247.00 University of Chicago Press, books 1.64 Balance in fund December 1, 1918 5.890.64 $13034 CHADRON Financial Report for Biennium, Beginning December 1, 1916, December 1, 1918 LIBRARY Balance in fund December 1. 1916 1916 Dec. 6 Sent State Treasurer Dec. 15 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding books 70.94 Democrat Printing Co., ink 1.34 The H. R. Hunting Co., books 19.50 G. F. Putman's Sons, book 1.50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., library books 305.03 1917 Jan. 4 Sent State Treasurer Jan. 17 Star-Herald Printing Co., subscription 1.50 A. C McClurg Co., books 200.23 The Alliance Herald, subscription 1.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 35 Feb. 1 Sent State Treasurer 70.00 Mar. 3 Sent State Treasurer 500 Apr. 5 Sent State Treasurer 5-00 May 11 McDevitt-Wilson's Inc., books _ Mcuevitt-vvilson s Inc., books _ 57.70 Nebraska State Journal, subscription 6.50 Nebraska State Journal, subscription 6.50 Mclntosh Steropticon, slides 90.30 Mclntosh Steropticon, slides 9030 Omaha Nebraska, subscription 2.00 Omaha Nebraska, subscription 2.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., books 5.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., books 5.00 World-Herald, subscription 4.00 World-Herald, subscription 4.00 A. L. A. Publishing Co., subscription 1.00 A. L. A. Publishing Co., subscription 1.00 Chadron Journal, subscription 3.20 Chadron Journal, subscription 3.20 Arthur M. Clark, Books _ n.50 Arthur M. Clark, Books _ n.50 H. R. Hunting Co., prints and pictures 2.85 H. R. Hunting Co., prints and pictures 2.85 2.8s Henry Xalkan. hooks 2750 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 301.88 H. W. Wilson Co., magazines 268.34 July 1 Sent State Treasurer _ 545-00 Sent State Treasurer _ July 25 The Gordon Journal, subscription T he Gordon Journal, subscription 2.go 2.00 The Bee Pub Co., subscription 2.75 Auk. i Sent Stati- Treasurer Sent State Treasurer 25.00 Columbia Law Review, books 1.50 Columbia Law Review, books Do-ld. Mead * Co.. books 5.67 Library Bureau, shelving _ 96.10 V C. Mc( ItirR &amp; Co., hooks 135-15 H. W. Wilson Co.. books 6.00 Oct. I Sent State Treasurer 355-00 Nov. 1 Sent State Treasurer 25.00 Dec. 1 Sent State Treasurer 4C00 1018 Jan. 4 Sent State Treasurer 15.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., books 86.95 Middle-West School Review, subscription 1.25 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 45-OI H. W. Wilson Co.. magazines 177.00 Feb. 4 Sent State Treasurer 90.00 Mar. 4 Sent State Treasurer 500 World Pub. Co., subscription £00 Custer County Chief, subscription 1.50 A. L. A. Pub. Board, book list I.OO A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books „. 147.35 May 3 Sent State Treasurer _ 5-00 June 10 Sent State Treasurer _ 15.00 June 18 B. H. Baumwart. Bee Pub. Co., sub 5.00 Library Bureau, shelving _ 75.51 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 July 9 Aug. 8 May 18 720.00 IK) $37930. STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 140.96 Nebr. State Journal, subscription 6.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding magazines.... 2.56 H. W. Wilson Co., subscription 23.00 Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer Dodd, Mead &amp; Co., Inc., books 106.30 The Kearney Hub. subscription 4.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 70.82 The H. R. Hunting Co., magazines and books _.... 192.80 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 00.93 Balance in fund December I, 1918 1.007.70 $3793 02 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 37 Nebraska State Normal School Kearney Kearney, Nebraska, December I, 1918. To the State Board of Education Gentlemen : I have the honor to submit herewith a report of the condition and progress of the State Normal School at Kearney, Ne- braska, for the biennium beginninj cember i, 1918. This report include priated and other funds of the ins expenditures from each fund, and the school. December i, igi6, and ending De - i a detailed statement of the appro - itution. a summarized statement of suggestions for the development of Very respectfully GEORGE S. DICK, President. Kearney. Nebraska. December 1, 1918. 1 HEREBY CERTIFY that the attached report, covering the fi - nances of the State Normal School at Kearney. Nebraska, from Decem - ber 1, 1916. to December 1, 1918. is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belif GEORGE S. DICK. President. Subscribed in my presence and &gt;f December. 191K worn to before me this 5th day (Seal) .1 ELLIOTT. Notary Public DEVELOPMENT OF THE SCHOOL In planning for the growth and report will take into consideration development of this institution, our the following: I. The needs of a fully equipped State Normal School at Kearney II. Kearney's present condition the part of this equipment al- ready here III. Material equipment necessary to complete the plant THE NEEDS CF A FULLY EQUIPPED TEACHERS' SCHOOL If a teachers' school is to successfully serve the people, its equip - ment must be Rood in these five lines: (1) Faculty. (2) Libraries and Laboratories. (3) Buildings and Furniture. (4) Campus. Playgrounds, </seg>
            <seg id="p038">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION" 38 Garden, and Farm. (5) Ways and mean? of carrying the service he people — to teachers not enrolled ip the institution FACULTY. Men and women, to carry on this important work and he responsible for the success of the inst'tution and its service, must be carefully selected for their education, training, and success. They must he inspiring, sympathetic, and of the highest type of all-round Christian character: they must be persons of exemplary habits wh real devotion to service causes them tr&gt; live effective lives in their spirit )f successful co-operaticn with the other factors that go to make a real LOCATION' AND ARRANGEMENT. These buildings should be carefully located and wisely chosen, artistically arranged, and well keni campus, playgrounds, gardens, and fields. The supply of teachers, library, laboratory, buildings, and grounds must be such by selection classification, arrangement, as to meet every need of a student in his education and training. It must be remembered that he is going out to undertake the physical, mental, moral, and spiritual education and train - ing of tomorrow's citizenship, as he takes charge of the boys and gi^ls of today. EXTENSION WORK AND FOLLOW-UP SERVICE. There must be ways and means of connecting up with the people in charge of. and with others interested in. the public schools of the state. Wirh the teachers at work, school officers, patrons and their children, there must be constant and live contact, not only that these may be helped, but also that the teachers' school may be ever alive to real conditions and always alert for improvements in matters of teacher-training. This phase of service is generally known as "extension work." as it is the way in which the institution and its equipment is effectively carried out to the people. Among the various ways in whirh this service is rendered, the following are the most common: (a) Real academic work and enter - tainment for those unable to enroll in the school, (b) A study of the teachers' school: they must have in every sense the qualifications and the true spirit of real teachers. LIBRARIES AND LABORATORIES. This faculty mist have the necessary tools that will enable them to Ho the very best tenchin r ac- cording to the latest approved educational theory and practice. Thete tools may be known as Libraries I aboratories. Equipimnt rnd Sup- plies for both indoor and outdoor work BUI! D'XGS AND Ft'RN'ITU»E. These teachers with their libra- ries and labratories. must be housed in substantial, spacious attractive. suitably furnished buildinps. with abundanre of the rijfht kind of 1it»ht. heat and ventilation. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">CHAr&gt;R(,N STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 3'/ organization, management, and teaching of the public school for teach - ers and school officers, (c) Inspirational work— that which follows up these good things with constant care ?nd helpfulness for those who have graduated from the school as well as for the assistance of the large per cent who have not had this val due every graduate or student wht teach. able training. This service is justly goes out from a Normal School to KEARNEY'S PRESENT CONDITION I. Three central buildings. There are three central buildings well planned all under one roof, which is especially good for the protection, convenience, and economy of time to students, and helpful in the general management of the school. In these buildings are offices, recitation rooms laboratories, and an excellent library well planned, finely lighted. and containing 15.000 up-to-date, carefully selected books well adapted co a teachers' school. The library is in charge of specially trained effi - cient librarians. There is also a well organized training school consist - ing of kindergarten primary, and grades to and including the tenth, furnishing a general laboratory for the anplication of principles under - lying the most modern ideas of school organization, management, teach- ing and training. In this trainins practice. It is now located in crow modations. school the seniors get their valuable led quarters ana needs better acenm- New buildings. Since last r iennium the new auditorium has been ol the much needed convenience for oses. lectures, entertainments. It has completed and furnishes the schr the various activities — chapel purp a complete stage setting equipment, including a fine concert grand piano. This auditori'-m adds greatly to the success of the management and entertainment of the school, as well as to more careful and thorough work of the En-rlish Department. The third floor of this building houses the Mt'sic Department, including piano, voice, and public school music. Two of the Christian organizations have comfortable, well fur - nished rooms here. The new gymnasium has been completed, furnishing a home for he Department of Physical Education. The use of this building has been turned over to be used as barracks for the Students Army Train - ing Corps. But upon the demobilization of the soldier boys, the build- ing and its equipment will revert tc its original use s' Additions and Improvement modeled and furnishes excellent re mercial Department. (a) The old chapel has been re - 3ms for the rapidly growing Corn- (b) There was excavated sufficient space under the west end of the </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' 4" south wing of the main building to furnish three very suitable room: for the Department of Industrial Training. With this added space suitable machinery and other equipment can be properly installed. (c) The central heating plant has been materially enlarged and improved by t'nr addition of underground space for coal. This plant nv.'ets the demands in even the mos't severe weather and, with very few excrptions. a'l rooms are kept comfortable. (d) The one dormitory accommodates about eighty young women. The rooms are comfortably furnished, well heated and lighted. The large reception room on the first floor is freely used by the students. The boarding department accommodates two hundred sixty stu - dents during the regular year, but in summer term iooo to 1200 meals are served daily. Excellent board is served at $3.50 per week. 4. Rural Demonstration Schools. To meet the demands for the training of rural teachers, there are associated with this institution two demonstration schools One is an eight grade school housed in a fine new. well planned and carefully equipped building, grounds and surroundings to be completed in most up-to-date plans. This is known as the Glenwood school and is located about four miles north of Kear - ney. The second is a very artistic, well planned bungalow building, known as the Victor school, and about six miles northwest of the city. MATERIAL EQUIPMENT NECESSARY TO COMPLETE THE PLANT 1. A Training School Building. The characteristic feature of any teachers' school is a well planned, thoroughly equipped, spaciously housed training school. This plant is much in need of such a building, in keeping with the most progressive ideas. A well planned rural dem - onstration and observation school building, on the campus, would be a great aid and convenience for the rural teacher-training work. 2. Library Building. The near future will demand a building dis - tinctly set apart for a home for the library. 3. More Dormitories. Dormitory life being desirable for students, we recommend the erection of two. one for young women and one for young men. ENROLLMENT Regular Year Collegiate Secondary Music Total 1916-17 339 17 summer term 6oo Total for year and S. T., count ing each student but once... .904 509 "413 28i 35 655 368 23 991 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 4' iQ'7-i8 299 218 32 949 '18 Summer term 5K2 322 32 935 Total for year and S. T.. count ing each student but once 803 467 1270 1918-19 Sept. 9, 1918, to date .242 167 38 447 1916-17 Correspondence students _ 33 Study Centers 161 1917-18 Correspondence 50 Study Center 365 1918-19 Correspondence (To date) _ 52 Study Center 107 (Note. — Music Students are not matriculants of the school and are scheduled for music only.) Number of Faculty Members _ 36 Number of Employees (regular) _ 8 Number of Employees (student) 11 CERTIFICATES AND DIPLOMAS 1916-17 Elementary „ 66 First Grade State _ 118 Degree — Bachelor of Eudcation 11 1917-18 Elementary Rural _ 12 Advanced Rural 4 Elementary State 51 First Grade State _ _ _io2 Degree — Bachelor of Ans in Education 23 FINANCIAL STATEMENT Maintenance: Amount in fund December 1, 1916 $ 37,727.44 Disbursements: 1916 Dec. 15 Kearney News and Stationery Co.. office supplies _ $ 13.35 George S. Dick, traveling expense 38.22 Albert C. Killian. dept. supplies 113.31 George S. Dick, reimbursement 349-28 Electric Fi.xture &amp; Supply Co.. light and 65.02 wiring E. A. Eck. repairs _ 16.90 Marion Wellers. traveling expense H-94 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel and lumber 1,285.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION +-' Cora O'Connell, traveling exp _ 7.63 Heasley Grocery Co., dept. supplies 2345 Kearney Telephone Co., 23.95 C. F. Bodison Hdw Co., general supplies... 113.38 Midway Hotel, exp. of speakers _ 10.50 Denzler-Manuel Furniture Co., furniture.... 9.00 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 39.80 Kaufman &amp; Wernert, dept. supplies 6.70 Nebraska Cash Grocery Co., dept. supplies 13.55 J. F. Saup, manager of Opera House com- mencement 15.00 R. M. Murphy, office exp.. advertising 10.00 Burgess-Nash Co., furn 12.05 Midway Gas Co., fuel 12.29 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., light 118.90 Scully Steel &amp; Iron Wks, rep. heating plant 35-2O City of Kearney Water Works, water 39-15 United Chemical Co.. general supplies 12.00 The McGraw Co., lights 19.52 Atlas Relief Map Co.. equipment 1 15.1m American Medical Assoc. dept. supplies 8.88 The Willis Music Co., dept. supplies 24.18 C. H. Stoelting Co, dept supplies 38.22 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 18.65 Beckley-Cardy Co., office supplies 3797 H. A. Webbert, printing 39-55 F. C. Scott, furniture 7.50 Nebr. School Supply House, furniture 9.70 Warwick &amp; York., dept. supplies 2.25 Western Union Telegraph Co 3108 Dec. 18 December pay roll 6.497.80 1917 Jan. 16 Trippensee Plantarium Co., equipment 2750 Bob Mclntyre. repairs _ 2.50 Kearney Foundry &amp; Machine Co., repairs.... 3305 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture 290.00 Armour &amp; Co., janitor supplies 18.75 Cornell Photo Supplies Co., dept. supplies ... 12.15 F. H. Schurger, repairs 34-36 C. J. Burke &amp; Son. repairs 30.67 C. F. Bodison Hardware Co.. gen. supplies 14.00 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co.. gen. repairs 18.13 George S. Dick.«reimbursement 102.84 Kaufman &amp; Wernert. dept. supplies 1.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 43 Gaston Music Co., dept. supplies _ 3.00 Midway Gas Co., fuel _ 6.93 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co., dept supplies.... 161.05 Denzler-Manuel Furniture Co., equipment.... 110.80 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel 484.95 Western Union _ _ .75 Kearney Telephone Co 10.55 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., office sup. 4.50 Kearney Steam Laundry Co 15.95 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Powers Co.. light .... 150.60 City of Kearney Water Works 39,78 Hamilton Bros., repairs _ _ 2.75 H. A. Webbert. printing and office supplies 19.15 Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing 6.55 J. D. Saunders. dept. supplies 6.83 John W Pickens. dept. supplies 3.38 George S. Dick, traveling expense 11.52 Jan. 24 Feb. 24 Mar 29 May 4 January pay roll _ 6,343.10 February pay roll _ 6,458.45 March pay roll _ 6.334.65 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., light. ... 306.03 Columbia College of Expression, dept. sup. 21.95 George S. Dick, president, reimbursement .... 664,13 George S. Dick, traveling expense 45-02 (iaston Music Co., equipment 25140 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co., dept. supplies 16.70 J. D. Saunders. dept. supplies 38.38 C. F. Bodison Hdw. Co., dept. supplies 24.70 Heasley Grocery Co., dept. supplies 39-95 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co.. fuel _ 2,376.80 Kearney Telephone Co 40.60 C. P. Lucas, general supplies and repairs ... 130.69 W. F. Crossley, repairs 35.25 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., office sup. 3.90 H. A. Webbert. printing and office supplies 82.75 Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing and office supplies 93.66 City of Kearney Water Works 85.52 Kaufman &amp; Wernert. dept. supplies 46.13 Downing Saddlery Co.. dept. supplies 5.62 Kearney Steam Laundry Co _ _ „ IO-35 Kearney Hardware Co.. general supplies '5-&gt;S • West Disinfecting Co., janitor supplies 112.50 Middle West School Review, office exp., ad 5.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">+* $ 36.130.04 $1,596.50 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Nebraska Teacher, office exp.. ad 10.00 10.00 Nebraska School Supply House, equipment 1 10.67 Nebraska School Supply House, equipmen i in The McGraw Co., lights 99-04 The McGraw Co.. lights 39-«»4 Thomas Charles Co.. dept. supplies 31-37 .!! Hall &amp; McCreary, dept. supplies 31.00 Hall &amp; McCreary. dept. supplies Beckley-Cardy Co., office expense 6.00 Bausch &amp; Lomb Co., dept. supplies 8.10 Underwood Typewriter Co.. dept supplies 16.35 The Arco Co.. janitor supplies 135. 70 Midland Chemical Co., genera! supplies 9150 College Book Store, dept. supplies 7.68 College Book Store, dept. supplie .68 The Prang Co.. dept. supplies 3.08 Monarch Note Book Co.. dept supplies 2.74 Monarch Note Book Co.. dept supplies Zaner &amp; Bloser. dept. supplies 6.36 Zaner &amp; Bloser. dept. supplie 6,1 J. Manz Engraving Co.. office expanse. 3.23 J. Manz Engraving Co.. office exr"'nse I G. M. Davis Regulator Co., general s&lt;ip - plies and repairs &gt;!..&gt;; plies and repair Schaar &amp; Co.. dept. supji University of Montana, d Bigsby-Rotary Mfg. Co.. Reading Hardware Co.. c W If. Welch Mfg. Co.. p Kansas State Normal, der McKinley Publishing Co.. Publisher Railway Guide A. Flanagan &lt;fe Co.. office The McConnell School Pi Daniel Starch, dept. supji (ieorge Bros., printing Schaar &amp; Co.. dept. supplies 5.27 pi University of Montana, dept. supplies 5.1m I,-, Bigsby-Rotary Mfg. Co.. repairs 1.53 n-i 1.53 Reading Hardware Co.. office expense 1.44 ■ffice expense i 4» VV. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. printing 16000 nt in ifin.oo Kansas State Normal, dept. supplies 250 1 supplie ;o McKinley Publishing Co.. dept. supplies 12.46 pt. supplit 12.46 2 no Publisher Railway Guide, office expense 2 no office expens A. Flanagan &amp; Co.. office expense 1787 The McConnell School Pub. Co.. equipment 25.00 2? no Daniel Starch, dept. supplies 20.10 George Bros., printing 125.65 I2S.6S Jas. B Clow &amp; Sons, general supplies 4.00 Jas. B. Clow &amp; Sons, general Mipp! Duncan's Print Shop, priming Warwick &amp; York. dept. supplie* Duncan's Print Shop, priming 172.66 Warwick &amp; York. dept. supplies 18.10 Grand Rapids School Equip. Co., equipment 231.50 Grand Rapids School Equip. Co.. equipment Eimer &amp; Amend, dept. supplies Eimer &amp; Amend, dept. supplies 74-9" Minneapolis Paper Co., general supplies 98.50 Minneapolis Paper Co., general supplies King's Department Store, dept. supplies H. A. Small, general supplies King's Department Store, dept. supplies 7.47 34-9R 34"f&gt; W. L. Stickel Lumber Co.. dept. supplies Western Union Telegraph Co.. time service Midway Gas Co.. fuel 9.50 59-94 40.01; Kearney Daily Hub. printin C. J. Burke &amp; Son. repairs 3v# Balance reverting to Normal School Fund </seg>
            <seg id="p045">191 July \ 4 $185,000.00 KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Maintenance Apr-J i, 1917 to April 1, 1919 Disbursement*. Disbursement!. April pay roll 6,514.10 May pay roll 6,072.00 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Powers Co., light... 26.35 Pathe Exchange, office expense 7.50 George S. Dick, reimbursement 889.49 George S. Dick, reimbursement.. George S. Dick, traveling expense 889.49 George S. Dick, traveling expense 30.94 3O-94 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., general supplies... 79.90 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., general supplies.. Kubon Wood Finishing Products Co., jan 79-90 Kubon Wood Finishing Products Co., jan - itor supplies 500 itor supplies 5.00 Kaufman &amp; Wernert, dept. supplies 6.95 6.95 Kearney Telephone Co 42H5 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel Central Power Co.. light F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel -238.55 Central Power Co.. light 107.96 Midway Gas Co., fuel 10.43 Midway Gas Co., fuel Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Powers Co., light City of Kearney Water Works Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Powers Co., light. ... 35.23 City of Kearney Water Works 29.63 Kearney Daily Hub, 1 printing 47-35 The Willard F. Bailey Co., printing 513-99 The Willard F. Bailey Co., printing Western Union Telegraph Co. Meek Lumber Co., dtpt. supplies ... Harry Porter, ofrice supplies 51399 Western Union Telegraph Co. 5.14 5-14 Meek Lumber Co., dtpt. supplies 150.00 150.00 Harry Porter, office supplies 11.76 11.76 ■/ Carpenter Paper Co., janitor supplies 31.00 Carpenter Paper Co., janitor supplies Burgess-Xash Co.. office 31.00 Burgess-Xash Co.. office 8.00 8.00 Oliver Machinery Co., dept. supplies 21.25 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., dept. supplies 6.65 Mclntosh Stereopticon Co.. equipment 86.18 Cambridge Botanical Supply Co., dept. sup. 4.50 Bigsby-Rotary Mfg. Co., janitor supplies... 2.18 Nebraska Cash Grocery Co., dept. supplies 38.25 International Harvester Co., office exp 2.90 Enterprise Planing Mill Co., furniture 30.00 June and July pay roll 13.603.50 Kaufman &amp; Wernert, dept. supplies 54-86 The McGraw Co., lights 97-6o George Bros. &amp; Griffiths, office 2.36 Denzler-Manuel Furniture Co., furniture C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., general supplies B. H. Patterson, office expense 14O.80 14.80 8.00 George S. Dick, reimbursement. . George S. Dick, traveling expense 086.42 20.53 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">4&lt;. STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION" J. D. Saunders, dept. supplie 3« 2« Thomas Charles Co.. dept. supplies Gaston Music Co., dept. supplies City of Kearney Water Works Western Union Telegraph Co 58.91 5&lt;&gt;75 '9-35 5-79 17.70 Kearney Telephone C Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co.. office Kearney Floral Co.. groundi &lt;&gt;-5. Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heating Co. repairs W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co., dept supplies .... F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel ).- Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co., general supplie Kearney Artificial Ice Co.. dept. suDpIies Hutchinson Nurseries, grounds &lt;&lt;7 I5.8o Wm. V Didriksen. imp. of grounds _ The A. H. Andrews Co.. dept. supplies Denver Fire Clay Co., dept. supplies Bausch &amp; Loni'b Optical Co.. dept supplies Underwood Typewriter Co., dept supplies Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture IO.IJO 4-8o 1 6 20 (1.- 1913 162.50 20.89 Nebr. School Supply House, dept supplies Middle West School Review, office expense Rand McNally Co.. dept. supplies 4-75 1. 00 Vocational Supply Co., equipment The McGraw Co.. lights 49-69 53-90 H. A. Webbert, office supplies Bob Mclntyre, repairs I4-4O J. A. Beatty. office expense 7-5" C. H. Stoelting Co., dept. supplies Beckley-Cardy Co., office supplies August pay roll 36.72 IO.73 Aug Sep. Oct. Nov 1.338.00 6.087.40 6.204.00 September pay roll October pay roll ..... a6 -'7 IJ Midway Hotel, exp of speakers Central Power Co., light 15-45 56.04 Nebr. School Supply House, furniture Hamilton Bros., repairs 905-54 3-15 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co.. dept. supplies Kansas State Normal, dept. supplies Western Heating &amp; Plumb Co.. equip, and 1.30 6.78 repairs 200.95 Nebraska Teacher, office expense, ad Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., office 500 8.00 -'5-45 I7-2O 28.OO H. A. We'ibert. office wpptic </seg>
            <seg id="p047">CHADROX STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 4; E. A. Miller, office expense, fram. picture... 220.50 Standard School Supply Co.. furniture 7.1-50 Standard School Supply Co.. furniture 75-50 Henline Drug Co.. office exp., motion pict. 174.17 Western Supply Co.. office expense 8.31 Western Supply Co.. office expense 8.31 A C. Ktllain Clothing Co. playground equip. 2820 F H. Gilcrest Lbr. Co.. dept. supolies 5.00 International Harvester Co.. office expense 6.og International Harvester Co.. office expense 6.09 Calif. Normal School, dept. supnlies 22.10 22.10 Kearney Steam Laundry Co ♦ 18.40 Kearney Steam laundry Co ♦ 18.40 Charles A. Haz'.ctt. dept. supplies 41.51 Charles A. Haz'.ett. dept. supplies 41.51 Kearney Telephone Co 53.05 Kearney Telephone Co 53.05 R. W. Sample, labor 65.00 R. W. Sample, labor 65.00 Lambert's Bakery, dept. supplies 3.34 Lambert's Bakery, dept. supplies 3.34 F. H. Schureer. repairs 202.65 F. H. Schurger. repairs 202.65 Central Power Co.. light 69.39 Central Power Co.. light 69.39 A. Flanagan Co.. office supplies 23-35 A. Flanagan Co.. office supplies 23-35 American Med. Assoc. dept. supplies 8.06 American Med. Assoc. dept. supplies 8.06 Ward's Nat'l Science Estab.. deot. supplies 38.90 Ward's Nat'l Science Estab.. deot. supplies 38.00 Industrial School Service, dept. supplies ... 50.00 Industrial School Service, dept. supplies ... 50.00 Lnited Chemical Co.. general supplies... 130.00 Lnited Chemical Co.. general supplies... 130.00 Hammond &amp; Stephens, office expense 2.20 Hammond &amp; Stephens, office expense 2.20 Wrought Iron Range Co.. repairs 4.90 Wrought Iron Range Co.. repairs 4.00 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., general supplies ... 69.02 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co., general supplies . 58.97 H. A. Small, janitor supplies 77-13 Western Union Telegraph Co 9.75 L'nion Construction Co., imp of grounds 164.00 \. Hospe Co., equipment 1,400.00 Rees Ticket Co., office expense, 38.88 Beckley-Cardy Co.. office expense 10.80 Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing 78.75 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 17065 Pub. Railway Guide, office expense 2.50 Vocational Supply Co., dept. supplies 14.94 Rand-McN'ally Co.. dept. supplies 9.80 Empir Store, office exp., commencement ... 1.90 The Willis M-sic Co.. dept. supplies 579 Maxro-Ross Co. office expense 75.00 H. A. Webbert. office expense Wm. Lewis &amp; Son. dept. supplies City of Kearney Water Works 57-55 1640 3871 Minneapolis 'Paper Co.. general supplies W. M. Welch MT K . Co.. printing 115.00 252.50 A. T. Anderson, office expense 8t.on </seg>
            <seg id="p048">4* STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' Central Scientific Co.. dept. supplies I5&amp;52 S. A. Curtis, dept supplies 6.19 The Anchor Package Co.. rep. heating plant 98.15 George S. Dick, traveling expense 66.06 (ieorge S. Dick., pres.. reimbursement 638.06 N'ov. 24 Dec. 17 November pay roll 6.504.00 December pay roll » 6.438.60 1918 Jan. 21 Jan. 26 January pay roll 6,574.-40 tjeorge S. Dick, traveling expense 73-55 Dan Quinton, Ren. fund — contract _ 3.463.05 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heating Co.. gen. fund ... 2.162.10 Albert B. Lake, gen. fund— architect 158.00 Albert B. Lake. gen. fund— architect 158.00 \V. F. Crossley. gen. fund 237.50 W. F. Crossley. gen Hastings Foundry Cc Hasting* Foundry Co.. gen. fund — permanent improvement 630.13 improvement The A. H. Andrews ( (ieorge S. Dick, pres Munson Supply Co.. The A. H. Andrews Co.. gen. fund — audito. 16.72 George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement 702.09 Munson Supply Co., office supplies 15-5O Olive M. H. Strong, equipment 25.00 Olive M. H. Strong, equipment 25.00 Central Power Co., light 271.22 Central Power Co.. light 271.22 Lincoln Fine Arts Shop, office expense 9.00 Lincoln Fine Arts Shop, office expense 9.00 L. A. Koeppe, furniture 13.00 L. A. Koeppe, furniture 13.00 F. C. Scott, furniture - ■ 24.00 F. C. Scott, furniture - ■ 24.00 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 56.75 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 56.75 \V. F. Downing, janitor supplies 1785 \V. F. Downing, janitor supplies 1785 C. P. Lucas, gen. supplies sand repairs 43-45 C. P. Lucas, gen. supplies sand repairs 43-45 Kaufman &amp; Wernert. office supplies 25-57 Kaufman &amp; Wernert. office supplies 25-57 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co.. general supplies. ... 71-54 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co.. general supplies. ... 71-54 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat Co., gen. supplies 72.90 Kearney Telephone Co _ 52.55 Kearney Telephone Cc F H. Gilcrest Lumber Co.. fuel 3.657.05 F H. Gilcrest Lumber Co.. fuel 3.657.05 Gaston Music Co., dept. supplies 45-55 Gaston Music Co., dept. supplies 45-55 City Water Works 57-46 City Water Works 57-46 L. E. Smith, furniture 4.00 L. E. Smith, furniture 4.00 Hotel Rome, Assoc. Headquarters 5.15 Hotel Rome, Assoc. Headquarters 15 Adams Paper Co., general supplies..-. 5.24 Adams Paper Co., general supplies..-. 5.24 E. A. Eck, dept. supplies.. 2.15 E. A. Eck. dept. supplies.. 2.15 Western Union Telegraph Co 9.65 Western Union Telegraph Co 9.65 The Willard F Bailey Co., printing 102.75 The Willard F Bailey Co., printing 102.75 H. A. Webbert, office supplies 12.80 H. A. VVebbert, office supplies 12.80 Kearney Steam Laundry Co 12.00 Kearney Steam Laundry Co 12.00 C H. Stoelting Co., dept. supplies 72.94 C. H. Stoelting Co.. dept. supplies 72.94 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., office sup- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Feb. 23 Mar. 25 Apr. 13 4" KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL plies 6.IO Midland Chemical Co., general supplies 202.50 Claflin Printing Co.. printing 80.00 N'at'l Chemical Products Co., gen. supplies 21.50 Fred Medart Mfg. Co.. playgroud equipment 201.55 The McGrew Co., lights 59-'3 Klopp-Bartlett Co., office supplies 84.00 A. Hospe Co., equipment 10.10 Thos. Charles Co., dept supplies 58.52 A Flanagan Co.. dept. supplies 10.50 Vocational Supply Co., equipment 199.82 Russell Sage Foundation, dept. supplies 2.00 The A. N. Palmer Co.. dept. supplies 12.35 Hutton Pharmacy, office expense 0.85 Bob Mclntyre. general repairs 12.05 Frank Holton Co., repairing band instru - ments _ 49-90 February pay roll 6.248.80 March pay roll 6420.55 George S. Dick, reimbursement 1.085.83 Kearney Telephone Co 39.05 George S. Dick, traveling expense 142.85 C. F. Bodinson Hardware Co., gen. supplies 71.15 City of Kearney Water Works 67.65 Central Power Co.. light . 273.06 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel 4.380.25 Kearney Steam Laundry Co 8.23 Empire Store, office expense 6.50 Kearney Daily Hub. printing 16.25 H. A. Webbert. printing and office supplies 82.85 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co.. office sup. 11.55 Western Union Telegraph Co 6.77 Willard F. Bailey Co., printing 88.88 Gaston Music Co., dept. supplies 3700 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 7.50 Middle West School Review, advertising... 10.50 University Pub. Co.. dept. supplies 10.46 Klopp-Bartlett Ptg. Co., office supplies 9.78 Amer Multigraph Sales Co., repairs 19.48 A. Hospe Co.. dept. supplies 7.50 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture 589.85 Nebr. State Railway Com., maps for office 2.75 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 69.28 The McGraw Co., lights _ : 84.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 50 Harry Porter, office supplies 9-n Vocational Supply Co.. equipment.. Tablet &amp; Ticket Co.. dept. supplies 341-52 6.76 Am. Wood Working Machinery Co., gen eral fund _ 1.130-51 Imperial Brush Co., janitor supplies 22.85 Ruben Woodfinishing Wood Products Co janitor supplies IO.OI Ward's Nat'l Science Estab., dept. supplies The Prang Co.. dept. supplies Charles A. Hazlett. office expense 13.00 3581 2.04 Russell Sage Foundation, dept. supplies 500 Apr. 26 May 24 June 13 April pay roll 6,38530 6.340.00 1.354-30 May pay roll Kearney Heat. &amp; Plumb. Co.. gen fund Kearney Heat &amp; Plumb Co.. repairs and supplies 175-3O 838.20 George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement Fred Medart Mfg. Co., gen fund— gym equipment 4.436.3«' Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co.. dept. supplie Kearney Hdw. Co., general supplies 1578 28.00 Lambert's Bakery, dept supplie 6.30 Smith &amp; Strain. labor 6.40 W. L. Stirkel Lumber Co.. dept. supplies .... Sengsbusch Ink Well Co.. office supplies .... The John Church Co . dept. supplies Ward's Nat'l Science Estab.. dept supplies Edward C. Elliott, dept. supplies The A. N. Palmer Co., dept. supplies York Blank Book Co.. printing 2255 832 -V 38.50 1 2. SO 192.06 07.68 The McGraw Co.. lights International Harvester Co.. office expense 12.41) Beckley-Cardy Co.. office supplies. C. H. Stoclting Co.. dept. supplie 22.4.? 53 i o Remington Typewriter Co.. office expense Thomas Charles Co.. dept. supplies Frank Major, gen fund — permanent imp. McKinley Pub. Co., dept. supplies 6-75 62.77 279-55 3 31 Burgess-Granden. gen. fund — gym. fixtures City of Kearney Water Works Gaston Music Co.. dept.. supplies Downing Saddlery Co., dept. supplies W. R. McCauley. dept. supplies 560.35 2323 6-35 4.00 9.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co.. general supplies .... 53.74 Kearney Telephone Co 18.70 Willard E. Bailey Co.. printing m.40 Central Power Co.. light 167.70 Electric Fixture Supply Co.gen. fund— gym 31.50 George S. Dick, traveling expense 11.37 June 28 June pay roll 7,068.30 July 20 July pay roll _ 7,046.10 Aug. 3 Kaufman &amp; Wernert. dept. supplies 80.72 Aug. 5 Empire Store, general supplies _ 23.12 W. R. McCauley. general supplies, glass 5.00 George S. Dick, traveling expense 127.09 Western I'nion Telegraph Co 11.20 Thos. D. Wood. dept. supplies 7.20 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 The A. H. Andrews Co.. dept supplies 4.20 Walter Knutzen. general fund 15710 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat. K.vni Co.. gen. fund — 245-3° American Electric Co., equipment 10.50 Woodruff Bank Note Co.. printing 283.12 Am. Wood Working Mach. Co.. equipment 381.00 Vocational Supply Co., dept. supplies 14,78 Kearney Floral Co.. grounds 26.00 A C. Killian Clothing Co.. flags 7.20 City of Kearney Water Works 101.08 Central Power Co.. light 13223 F. C. Scott, furniture _ 44.50 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co.. office supplie 17.35 Kearney Daily Huh. printing 27. y&gt; The Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing 87.55 W. L. Stickel Co.. dept. supplies 14.35 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. ( eneral supplies. ... 93.07 Midway Hotel, office expense — speakers... 9.50 Kearney Steam Laundry Co _ 10.05 H. A. Webbert. printing and office sup 122.10 122.10 F. H. (jilcrest Lumber Co., fuel and lumber 254.43 Dan Quinton. general fund _ 276.63 Kearney Telephone Co 33-45 George S. Dick. pres.. reimbursement 1,009.23 Aug. 26 August pay roll _ _ 1 ,376.25 Sept. 27 September pay roll 6,107.60 Oct. 26 October pay roll 6,315.35 Nov. 16 George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement 1,365.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' George S. Dick, traveling expense 72-39 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat. Co.. perm. imp. 155.40 The Globe-Wernicke Co.. dept. supplies... 16.15 Vocational Supply Co., dept. supplies 6.75 Beckley-Cardy Co., office supplies 14-40 Keuffel &amp; Esser Co.. dept. supplies 16.52 Tablet &amp; Ticket Co., dept. supplies &gt;o-99 C. J. Lemkuhl. equipment 61.25 Leedy Mfg. Co., dept. supplies _ _... 3.78 A. B. Lake, contract, Collins School 104.00 W. F. Crossley, Collins School 2,840.70 L. A. Koeppe, furniture 12.00 Wm. V. Didriksen, imp. of grounds 10.00 Yawman &amp; Erbe Mfg. Co., equipment k/j. 10 West Disinfecting Co., general supplies 73-5O Pittsburgh Plate Glass Co., general supplies 81.59 The Anchor Pkg. Co., genera] supplies '0.35 The Gardner-Governor Co., gen. supplies 24.19 Luther O. Draper Shade Co.. furniture 26.21 Carpenter Paper Co., janitor supplies 65.10 J. 1. Holcomb Mfg. Co., janitor supplies 517.1 1 W F. Crossley. repairs _ 184.30 T. F. Crawford, repairs on wiring, audi - torium 141-65 L. C. Smth, office supplies 8.00 Penn. Oil Consumers Co., supplies, heating plant _ _ 26.20 Middle-West School Review, advertising. ... 10.50 American Electric Co.. equipment 15.30 ClaHin Ptg. Co.. printing bulletins 89.00 T. A. Tollefsen, repairs 20.00 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies... _ 64.40 S. A. D. Henline, dept. supplies 13.30 Crane &amp; McGlenen, office expense 5.00 Charles A. Hazlett, office expense _ 8.25 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., office sup. 8.30 Kearney Floral Co., commencement 7.25 A. C. Killian Clo. Co., playground equip. 6.50 W. F. Downing, janitor supplies 25.20 Kearney Hdw. Co., general supplies 59-45 Frank Major, dept. supplies 68.62 Frank Holton &amp; Co., band equipment 90.00 Central Power Co, light _ 150.30 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., general supplies... 66.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">3 KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Kearney Telephone Co. W. I.. Stickel Lumber ( Winter Byles. Publisher. Hutton Pharmacy, office City of Kearney Water cearney i elephone Co 76.30 W. I- Stickel Lumber Co.. fuel and lbr 4.127.45 Winter Bylcs. Publisher, office expense 2.50 Hutton Pharmacy, office expense 3.J0 xpense 3.J0 City of Kearney Water Works 33.50 Works 33-50 Western Union Telegraph Co 22 , 4 Western Union Telegraph ( 22.14 King's Dept. Store, dipt, supplies 14.70 King's Dipt. Store, di npp»es 14.70 The WiUard F. Bailey Co.. printing... 71.95 mr NMiiara t . Bailey Co.. printing 71.95 The Kearney Daily Hub. uta. and ofhre The Kearney Daily Hub. ptg. and office supplies I447O »nd ornc H A. Webbert, office supplies 60.35 Manuel-Schoonover Furniture Co., turn 270.70 daston Music Co.. dept. supplies 61.50 Dan Quinton, contract Nov. 25 November pay roll Dan Quinton. contractor, permanent imp 74396 November pay roll gjg, $,76,703., Balance December 1, 1018 aw.e )i8 8, »6.88 SUMMARY OF EXPENDITURES FROM MAINTENANCE FOR BIENN1UM 13094 793-1 .924.ofl Expenditures from last appropriation, as per item- ized statement herein $ 36 $36 Expenditures from present appropriation, as per T jv itemized statement herein 176 176 $212. Salaries of president and office force ....$ 14,270.60 Other services, as speakers, etc 581.51 Record books and printing 3.3-24-37 Telegraph and Telephone _ 509.37 Postage 1.663.47 President's traveling expense 639.54 Office supplies, expenses, etc 2,608.08 Express, freight anil drayage 1,556.54 Salaries of faculty members II 1.328.00 Departmental supplies 4,618.76 Extension work 242044 Furniture and equipment 13.206.65 Salaries of employees , _ 19,250.00 Kutl 13.400.88 Li 8 nt 2.787.24 Waur - 5^.06 Genera] supplies ?4 l J3oo </seg>
            <seg id="p054">M STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' Improvements and additions to plant Depreciation repairs 13,199.76 2.944.56 Ground 588.05 $212.92406 INSTITUTION CASH Receipts Amount in State Treasury December 1, 1916 S 1,262.36 Treasurer July Deposited with State Treasurer Aug. 23. Deposited with State Treasurer Oct. 16, Deposited with State Treasurer Nov. 6, Deposited with State Treasurer Treasurer Treasurer Treasurer Mar. 9, Deposited with State Treasurer Apr. 8. Deposited with State Treasurer May 4, Deposited with State Treasurer June 12, Deposited with State Treasurer July 11 Deposited with State Treasurer Aug. 8, Deposited with State Treasurer Sept. 12 Deposited with State Treasurer Oct. 11 Deposited with State Treasurer Disbursement! : 1916 Dec. 16 E. A. Eck, dormitory $ J. D. Saunders, laboratory . Kearney Telephone Co., dorm Heasley Grocery Co., lab Denzler-Manuel Furniture Co., dormitory Midway Gas Co., dorm 8.25 23-41 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., dorm City of Kearney Water Works, dormitory Underwood Typewriter Co 77-4O •25-51 8 5 .i8 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., lab University Publishing Co., text-book A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., text-book Schaar &amp; Co., lab 7°-55 7.16 5-52 83-31 Aug. 27. 1914 H. A. Small, janitor sup. (error) 12.40 Mar. 7. 1917 Deposited with State Treasurer i.gni.24 1.526.70 2.825.03 1.044.32 4^0-33 Dec. 6, Deposited with State Jan. g. 1918. Deposited with State Feb. 11. Deposited with State </seg>
            <seg id="p055">KEARXEY STATE NORMAL SCHGOl A. Flanagan Co., text-book Central Scientific Co., lab.. 8.63 14-12 The Gregg Publishing Co., text-book Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 427O 5io8 Silver. Burden &amp; Co., text-book Charles Scribner's Sons, text-book D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text-book Henry Holt &amp; Co., text-book (jinn &amp; Co., text-book Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book Oliver Typewriter Co G. Schirmtr, text-book Kearney Steam Laundry, dormitory II. 10 Geo. E. Troxel, dormitory IO.OO Burjjess-Xash Co., dormitory 21.00 F. C. Scott, dormitory Mrs. Olive M. Strong, piano instruc [().(»! Dec. 18 Mrs. Olive M. Strong, piano instructi Montague Worlock, voice instruction.. 89.25 111 Montague Worlock, voice instruction 84.88 1917 Jan. 17 Jan. 24 Midway Gas Co., dormitory Olive M. Strong Midway Gas Co., dormitory Olive M. Strong M. Worlock Feb. 24 Clive M. Strong M. Worlock Mar. 29 Olive M. Strong M. Worlock May 11 American Book Co., text-book Thompson, Brown &amp; Co., text-book D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text-book 5- '4 25-75 Charles Scribner's Sons, text-book University of Missouri, text -book Thos. W. Crowell Co 136 1.20 7.01 Silver, Burdette &amp; Co., text-book Gregg Pub. Co., text-book Longmans Green &amp; Co., text-book Benj. H. Sanborn &amp; Co., text-book The Omaha News Co., text-book ... Charles E. Merrill Co., Text-book Row, Peterson Co.. text-book _.. 19-99 31-88 1790 "75 93-6o 21.86 54-0O Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book Ginn &amp; Co., text-book 1939 49-38 Boston Book Co., text-book Houghton Mifflin Co., text-book Lyons &amp; Carnahan. textbook 8o.94 21.60 2352 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">16 STATE BOARD OF KDUt "ATIOX Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., dorm, furniture... Remington Typewriter Co., equipment .... Burges;,-\ash Co.. dormitory equipment 27 5« I5-IO 55-5" John Anderson Pub. Co.. textbook (i. Schirmer. textbook 137-83 University Pub. Co.. text-book 39-7&lt;&gt; E. P. Dutton &amp; Co.. text-book 4.69 June Gian &amp; Co., text-book 5.10 Daniel Starch, text-book 3.00 Western Supply Co.. equipment j8&lt;&gt;.85 Omaha News Co.. textbook 21. 00 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 27.16 Midway (jas Co.. dormitory u.83 Midway (jas Co.. dormitory 12#3 Central Power Co., dormitory lijiht 39-39 Central Power Co.. dormitory light 39-39 Kearney Telephone Co.. dormitory 5. 50 550 M. Worlock. voice instruction 8lj8 M. Worlock. voice instruction 81.38 .?• C-live M. Strong, piano instruction 94-5O Clive M. Strong, piano instruction 94-5O Olive M. Stroag, piano instruction 105.00 instruction ios.ix) M. Worlock 101.38 M. Worlock 102.38 Olive M. Strong 253JJ8 Olive M. Strong 252.88 If. Worlock 259.88 M. Worlock 259.88 Aut Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book 28.38 Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book 28.38 ao Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., text-book 2.S0 Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., text-book 2.S0 Silver, Burden &amp; Co., text-book 4.01 Silver, Burden &amp; Co., text-book 4.01 The Macmillan Co.. text-book 4300 The Macmillan Co.. text-book 43-00 Henry Holt &amp; Co., text-book 8.03 Henry Holt &amp; Co., text-book 8.03 Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book 31-47 Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book 31-47 D. C. Heath &amp;. Co., text-book 36.76 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. text-book 36.76 Ginn &amp; Co., text-book 27.34 Ginn &amp; Co., text-book 27.34 Houghton Mifflin Co., text-book 86.20 Houghton Mifflin Co., text-book ri6.20 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., text-book 10.48 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., text-book 10.48 American Book Co.. text-book 17.27 American Book Co.. text-book 17.27 University of Missouri, text-book 1.20 University of Missouri, text-book 1.20 College Book Store, text-book 6.53 College Book Store, text-book 6.53 City of Kearney Water Works, dormitory 21.15 rmitory 21.15 The Elm Tree Press, text-book 36.00 University Publishing Co.. text-book 34-&gt;2 The Century Co., text-book 51.20 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. text-book 161.76 Gregg Pub. Co., text-book 29.65 Oct a8 Olive M. H. Strong, piano instruction 81.38 M. Worlock, voice instruction 60.38 Oct Olive M. H. Strong 36.75 -y XI. Worlock. voice instruction 120.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Nov. 9 Central Power Co., dormitory light Bausch &amp; l.omb Optical Co.. lab Sturgis &amp; Walton Co.. text-book... G. Schirmer, text-book E. A. Eck, dormitory repairs City of Kearney Water Works, don Central Power Co.. dormitory light McKinley Pub. Co.. text-book The Century Co., textbook 34-71 70.40 5«-5O G. Schirmer. text-b( ...k 25- 1 4 6. so ter Works, dorm dormitory light.. 43-66 Central Power C 7339 McKinley Pub. Co.. t xt-book 44-8o The Century Co., textbook 26.48 Xov. 9 University of Missouri, text-book. Nebraska Cash Grocer Co. laboratoi The Macmillan Co., text-book Heasley Grocery Co., laboratory .... Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book Lyons &amp; Carnahan, text-book Scott, Foresman Co., text-book D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text-book Henry Holt &amp; Co., text-book American Book Co., text-book Ginn &amp; Co.. text-book University Pub. Co., text-book! Nov. 9 University of Missouri, text-book Nebraska Cash Grocer Co. laboratory The Macmillan Co., text-book Heasley Grocery Co., laboratory Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book 2.40 16.28 6o.i9 39 1 1 10.99 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, text-book 8g.6o Scott, Foresman Co., D. C. Heath &amp; Co., te Henry Holt &amp; Co., t American Book Co., t Ginn it Co.. text-boi University Pub. Co., t Olive M. H. Strong. M. Worlock, voice in Olive M. H. Strong... text -book ext-book.. . I2.0O 6.88 xt-book 26.09 text-book jok 90.28 36-5 text-book 6.08 Nov. 23 Olive M. H. Strong, piano instruci M. Worlock, voice instruction 8+88 piano mstructi m truction i6i.oo Dec. 17 Olive M. H. Strong M. Worlock 1918 Dec. 17 79-63 M. Worlock 94-50 1918 Jan. 21 Olive M. H. Strong M. Worlock Jan. 21 Olive M. H. Strong M. Worlock 78.75 H2.86 Jan. 25 Arthur P. Schmidt, text-book Central Power Co., dormitory light Normal Cash Grocery, lab Nebraska Cash Grocery, lab City of Kearney Water Works, dori Kearney Hdw. Co., dorm, repairs Kearney Steam Laundry, dorm The John Church Co.. text-book Jan Arthur P. Schmidt, text-book Central Power Co., dormitory light Normal Cash Grocery, lab 32.86 167.10 37 92 Nebraska Cash Grocery, lab City of Kearney Water Works, dorm. 23- 1 o 46.14 Kearney Hdw. Co., d Kearney Steam I. aim The John Church C&lt; Cambridge Botanical American Book Co., 4045 Ji.on 235O Supply Co., lab ext-book 56.8 5 2925 Ginn &amp; Co.. text-book 17-27 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. text-book Charles Scribner's Sons, text-book The McKinley Pub. Co., text-book G. Schirmer. text-book 8.88 7.68 '3 44 -M.OO Gregg Pub. Co.. text-book 56.93 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">5« STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION The Macmillan Co.. text-book 8040 Schaar &amp; Co.. lab 50.40 Burgess-Nash Co., dorm 18.00 Silver. Burdett &amp; Co.. text-book ■*]■*} Feb. Olive M. H. Strong 78-75 -M M. Worlock 1 18.12 Mar If. Worlock 12338 as Olive M. H. Strong 82.2; Apr. -'.? George S. Dick, pres.. reimbursement 154-53 Ginn- &amp; Co.. text-book 3'-44 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. textbook 16.00 Houghton Mifflin Co.. text-book 12.48 American Book Co.. text-book 10.72 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. text-book 1 2.00 G. Schirmer. text-book , 38.08 The Prang Co., text-book 16.65 Richard G. Badger Pub., text-book 12.00 Central Power Co.. dorm, light 50.66 Normal Cash Gro.. lab :. 10.37 Gregg Pub. Co.. text-book 29.83 The Century Co.. text-book 1536 5-J J. D. Saunders, lab 28.40 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 06.53 Eimer and Amend, lab 279.11 Robinson &amp; Miller, lab 12.77 The Macmillan Co.. text-book 24.10 Charles E. Merrill Co.. text-book 8.45 The Newton Co.. text-book 10.00 E. P. Dutton &amp; Co.. text-book 4.25 Yawman &amp; Erbe Mfg. Co.. text-book 10.80 Apr. j6 Olive M. H. Strong, piano instruction 1I5-5O M. Worlock, voice instruction 153-12 May M. Worlock H5-5O 4 Olive M. H. Strong 42.W June ■3 George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement 34-08 Central Power Co.. dormitory light 1508 City of Kearney Water Works 24.90 Burgess-Nash Co., dormitory 16.00 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. text-book 3.1 1 Allyn &amp; Bacon, text-book 16.00 Scott &amp; Foreman Co., text-book _ 31.04 Ginn &amp; Co., text-book 36.19 Williams, Browne &amp; Earle, text-book 1 1.34 Cambridge Botanical Supply Co., lab 1.46 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">M KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Nchrasba Cash Grocery Co., lab 69.92 June 28 M. Worlock 94-50 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 61.25 July 19 M. Worlock ; __ 256.25 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 201.00 Aug. 6 George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement 55-43 Ginn &amp; Co., text-book 66.88 The Macmillan Co., text-book 16.00 Houghton Miflin Co., text-book 21.28 American Book Co.. text-book 29.93 D. C. Heath &amp; Co, text-book 32-59 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 62.93 Central Power Co.. dormitory light 79-43 Nebraska Cash Grocery Co., lab 43-35 Kaufman &amp; Wernert, dormitory 18.20 The Gregg Pub. Co.. text-book- 45-31 The Denver Fire Clay Co., lab 8670 The Century Co.. text-book 15.36 The Prang Co., text-book 22.35 A. Flanagan Co.. text-book 259 Aug. 26 II. Worlock 76.2: Mrs. H. J. Hull 70.12 Sept. 27 Mrs. H. J. Hull 37.63 M. Worlock 3325 Oct. 26 Mrs. H. J. Hull 92.75 M. Worlock 109.38 Nov. 16 Charles Scribner's Sons, text-book 40.51 Row. Peterson &amp; Co..text-book 4.61 Eimer &amp; Amend, lab 106.45 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, lab 127.68 E D. Patton. text-book 2.78 Kearney Artificial Ice Plant, lab 4.00 Underwood Typewriter Co., typewriter 42.00 Silver Burdett &amp; Co.. text-book 18.95 Ginn &amp; Co. text-book 10.53 The Omaha News Co., text-book 4-34 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. text-book 11.40 F. H. Schurger, dorm, repairs 196.25 Allyn Si Bacon, text-book 13.47 Central Power Co., dormitory light 69.37 Nebraska Cash Grocery Co., lab 17.33 W. R. Macauley, dorm, repairs 61.58 George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement 66.08' City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 20.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION («. The Century Co.. text-book 87.60 A. Flanagan Co.. text-book 800 The Independent, text-book 9-5O Ward's Xat'l Science Esiab.. lab 3»-77 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lal 20.13 rmislcit &amp; 1'arker. dorm, repair &lt;)2.8o Houghton Mifflin &amp; Co.. text-book 3251 The Macmillau Co., text-book 8.80 American Book Co., text-book 7 5i Current Events, text-book 3-3 83. 1 2 Dec. 1 Balance $8,824.30 SUMMARY Textbook 3.256.89 Dormitory— Water Light .. 338.78 Fuel (gas only) Furniture 84.2 470.20 54I-84 Repairs Laboratory — Domestic Science 3498i Physical Science Biology 820.09 238.03 508.03 Typewriter Department Music, Instruction. Etc. LIBRARY Receipts: Amount in fund Dec 1, 1916 Mar. 7, 1917 Deposited with State July 5, Deposited with State Oct. 16, Deposited with State Nov. 6, Deposited with State Dec. 6, Deposited with State Treasurer Treasurer.. Treasurer Treasurer Treasurer icnry Holt &amp; Co.. text-book II.III 67.66 The Gregg I'ul). Co., textbook Xov. J6 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction M. Worlock, voice instruction II.9O2.45 5&lt;&gt;4-lo </seg>
            <seg id="p061">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 61 Jan. 9, Feb. 11, Mar. 9, Apr. 8. May 4. June 12. July II, An K . 8. Sept. 12, Cct. 11, 1918 Deposited with State Treasurer Deposited with State Treasurer.. Deposited with State Treasurer Deposited with State Treasurer. Deposited with State Treasurer Deposited with State Treasurer.. Deposited with State Treasurer Deposited with State Treasurer Deposited with State Treasurer. Deposited with State Treasurer 15.00 150.00 45.00 500 5-00 5.00 2.180.00 10.00 5-00 750.00 $12,404.17 Disbursements : 1916 Dec. is George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement Walter Knutzen. supplies _&gt;'.oo 9-5O Waldorf Bindery, books .. W. A. Hixenbaugh., books Current Events, books 154.80 1890 250 Geo. Bros. -Griffiths Co.. office supplies Cosmopolitan Print Co., prints 2.25 2.O8 The H. R. Huntting Co. books A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books University of Chicago Press, book The Baker Taylor Co., magazines 29.23 187.59 1. 00 6.00 Agricultural Extension Division, pamphlets 2.10 1918 Lincoln Fine Arts Shop, pictures George S. Dick. pres.. reimbursement Jan. 17 5-25 10.00 May u Miller &amp; Paine, books .... J. M. Hanson-Bennett, M W. R. Matthews, pictures Augustine Book Concern. University Prints 27.71 gazine Agency ■294-45 4.40 books 10 51 2.14 Arthur H. Clark Co., bo. k&gt; 28.00 Nebraska State Historical Assoc. dues Ward Bros., books 2.00 19.00 Art Metal Construction Co., equipment Home &amp; School Arts Shop, pictures Hastings Tribune, subscription 121.50 10.20 2.0O Aurora Republican, subscription George S. Dick, pres.. reimbursement Tablet &amp; Ticket Co.. office supplies. ... The H. H. Wilson Co., books 1.00 8.15 2337 50.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">OJ STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Gaylord Bros., office supplies James T. White Co., books John R. Anderson Co., books Dodd, Mead &amp; Co.. books Waldorf Binder Co., books The H. R. Hunting Co., books The Elson Art Pub. Co., pictures A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books George S. Dick, pres., reimbursement A. Flanagan Co., supplies 38.88 8.00 37 10 i+i3 5*77 183-93 58-5O 711.10 July -25 11.00 39 33 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books The H. R. Huntting Co., books Nat'l Education Assoc, dues .... Boston Book Co.. books 1-24-3^ *.£] 2.00 5050 Waldorf Bindery Co, books... Library Bureau, furniture .... Thomas Charles Co.. supplies Public School Pub. Co.. book A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books Dr. H. E. Dearholt. books 131.90 239M 17.16 Aug. () 3&gt;9 299.82 8.00 Thoms &amp; Eron. book 7-5O Arthur H. Clark &amp; Co., books Gaylord Bros., office supplies Waldorf Bindery Co., books E. A. Miller, framing pictures The H. R. Huntting Co., books M. E. Healey, books 360 2O JO Aug. Nov. 14 68.77 9 6+45 28.21 7 15 Library Bureau, furniture A. C. McClurp &amp; Co.. books 13 39 32592 1918 Jan. 25 Kearney Daily Hub. printing 47.00 The Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing.. J. M. Hanson-Bennett Co.. magazines A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 6.00 3O500 366.81 The H. R. Huntting Co., books D. Appleton &amp; Co., books Library Bureau, furniture Dennison Mfg. Co.. office supplies Scott, Foresman &amp; Co.. books Educational Press Co., books Waldorf Bindery Co.. books The H. W. Wilson Co . books Amer. Academy of Politic &amp; Social 33-15 349 57-5O 3-67 7.20 Apr. 13 5oo 13775 31-00 Sci.. books 255 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL f'3 Arthur H. Clark Co., books 4-5O N. V. Times Current History, books 28.00 H. A. O'Leary, books _ 2.35 Nebraska State Historical Society, dues 2.00 The World Pub. Co.. subscription 2.60 Bee Pub. Co.. subscription 2.50 The Tribune Co.. subscription «75 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 239.97 George S. Dick. pres.. reimbursement 14.30 June 14 Harry P. Whitmore. pictures _ 7.60 Ward Bros., books _ 38.50 National Educa. Assoc , dues 2.00 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm. prints _ 12.00 Library Bureau, furniture 34-71 A. C. McClur;? &amp; Co.. books 213.12 Thomas it Eron. books 31-75 Hastings Daily Tribune, subscription 3.00 Aug. 8 Samuel French, books +35 The Annalist, maeazine 4.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 190.50 Mississippi Valley Historical dues... 3.00 American Genetic Assoc. dues 2.00 Elson Art Pub. Co.. pictures 480 Georjje S. Dick. pros., reimb. ptg. and post 34.00 Nov. 18 A. C. McOur R Co.. books 40.32 Waldorf Bindery Co.. books 58.56 Waldorf Bindery Co.. books 58.56 University of Chicago Press, hook 1.07 University of Chicago Press, hook 1.07 The World Pub. Co . subscription 3.85 The World Pub. Co . subscription 3.85 The Bee Pub. Co.. subscription 6.20 The Bee Pub. Co.. subscription 6.20 C. S. Hammond &amp; Co.. map 1.00 1. 00 Custer County Chief, subscription _ 6.00 George S. Dick, pres.. reimbursement 4.15 5,644.12 Balance December I, 1918 $6,760.05 SUMMARY Books, newspapers, periodicals 4,673.04 Furniture and equipment 507.94 Supplies 255.24 Printing, postage _ _ 117.00 $5,644.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' &lt;&gt;4 Nebraska State Normal School Peru Peru, Nebraska, December 2. 1918. To the Nebraska State Board of Education : Gentlemen : 1 am pleased to submit herewith the biennial report of the State Normal School. This report includes a detailed statement of the receipts and expenditures for the biennium up to December 1, 1918, together with an estimate of the funds needed for the next biennium. I am taking this opportunity to give a brief outline of the essential needs of the institution if it is to do its part in the unusual demands of the reconstruction period which the coming biennium opens. This school in common with other educational institutions of the country has suffered by a smaller attendance than any biennium for several years. You will notice, however, in the detailed statement of en - rollment which follows, that each year of the biennium we have had more than 1.000 students in resident attendance, compared with the en - rollment of about 1.200 for each of the years of the preceding biennium. The enrollment to date for the prsent year is about 85 per cent of the enrollment at the corresponding date last year The following is a de - tailed statement of enrollment during the biennium beginning with the regular school year September. 1916. and ending with the Summer School of 1918. Very respectfully E. L. ROUSE President. D. W. Haye. Permit me at this time to express my most hearty endorsement of the administration of President D. W. Hayes. Whatever of success has come to the school in this biennium must be accredited to him. In leaving the school he accorded the new president every courtesy. Rec - ords, reports, details of administration, prospects for immediate future growth, and ultimate ideals were carefully placed before me. My one ambition shall be to justify his recommendation and your selection of myself as his successor. The Patting of Two Ex-PretidenU During the year the Institution has been called upon to mourn the loss of two of its distinguished ex-presidents. At the ripe old age of eighty-seven at the. home of his daughter in sunny California. Dr. J. M. McKenzie closed his eventful life. In November, apparently in the </seg>
            <seg id="p065">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL fa prime of his usefulness as Head Professor of the Psychology and Edu - cation at the Kirksville. Missouri, State Normal School, Dr. W. A. Clark was suddenly called to his great reward. In the death of these two men the school recognized the passing of two of its best friends. Buildings anil Material Equipment In January. 1917. the Training School was moved into the splendid new T. J. Majors Training School Building. If you could see the difference in the spirit of teachers and pupils alike you would realize just how wise an expenditure of money had been made. Many visitors have pronounced it the most ideal training school build - ing in the United States. For the lack of funds it was impossible to decorate the walls of this building. Funds should be provided for this at once. The most imperative need of the Institution is a new Science build - ing. T his department at present is housed in an old frame structure en - tirely inadequate. ["he new building should be of modern, fire-T&gt;roof, 111 construction to cost approximately .000 The $25,000 appropriated for the remodeling of the old training chool building during this biennium has not been used. I ask for a itnilar appropriation to be spent during the summer of 1919. When this is done it will furnish a splendid lie School Art. Public School Music. housing for the Manual Arts. Pub - and Private Music Departments, home-like and comfortable by re - st tha' it be closed for the Summer e spent in making these necessary The Dormitory should be made plumbing and re-plastering. 1 sugj;e School of 1019. and at least $10,000 r improvements Your attention has been called by other presidents to the extremely poor accoustics of our chapel audi $3,000 to $4,000 to correct this. If po; summer. orium. It will cost approximately sible it should be done this coming Our Library of J5.000 volumes is very ample quarters provided for i outgrowing what seemed to be the only a few years ago. Very soon some provision must be made for expansion here. Campus Peru's extensive wooded campus should be one of her most valuable assets. In order to make it such we should secure the advice and plans of an expert landscape gardener. There should be an employee who would give his entire time to the care of the campus. He should be provided with a power mower and other essential equipment to facili - tate his work. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION (*&gt; Looking Backward A few of the outstanding features of our work during the present biennium will now be mentioned. The Affiliate Rural School under the very efficient management of the Department of Rural Education and the Misses Ola Breedon and Harriett Arms has fully demonstrated the value of the experiment. It serves as an observation and practice school for all students preparing for rural work. 1 he community is well sa'istied with the management of the school under this new relationship. A larger number of the children will continue their education in the Training High School and the Normal. I most heartily recommend the continuance of the project and suggest that we affiliate two more schools the coining biennium. The extension courses and Study Center work brought the school into a most promising relationship with ambitious young teachers and prospective students. It is also to be noted that we reached 470 stu - dents in this work last year. Junior Red Cross and the influenza epi - demic forbade any such work this semester. It is our purpose to con - tinue and expand this phase of our work. Our Held coach is keeping touch with the work of our graudates. In visiting the schools where these teachers work he always calls upon the High School. Many students are thus brought into personal touch with the Normal School. More of his time should be given to this work. Looking Forward The training of the teachers tor Junior High Schools is one of the problems that the normals must face immediately. This type of school is being organized in many towns in Nebraska. To meet this demand we have organized a Junior High School. The entire third floor of the new Training School is given over to this work. There is an en - rollment of 125 students. We will need another teacher in this depart - ment in order to make this new organization fuction most adequately. It is proposed to combine the extremely practical work that is being done by the Hygiene and Physical Education departments with the school nurse and infirmary department for the training of visiting nurses for the schools of Nebraska. There is coming a demand for this. It is our purpose to meet it for the year 1910. S. A. T. C In common with other normal schools of the state Peru attempted to meet the demands of the times and provided for a Student Army Training Corps unit. Because of the unusual competition in this part of the st;il c we enrolled only forty men Most of these came from our </seg>
            <seg id="p067">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 67 own immediate territory. It will be one of the means of calling the attention of the state to the school. The experiment was too badly broken into by ll\e influenza epidemic and the sudden demoralization that followed the signing of the armistice to make any adequate esti - nia'c of ilir movement as an educational experiment. Needs for the Coming Biennium ollnwing estimates represent the minimum needs for the bi- of president and office force $ 18.800 Administration, salaries Faculty 138.750 Assistants Employees 1.200 18.500 b Administrative expenses, graph and telephone, f including printing, tele - istage. president's traveling 5. express, drayage, freight supplies, and extension ser- speakers, departmental vice 14.500 Physical Plant 1 Furniture and equipment, fuel, light, water, general supplies, depreciation and repairs 26.500 Total maintenance $218,250 Ihy ical Plant improvements — Additions, overhauling and modernizing old buiid- $40,000 Improvement of grounds _ _ 5,000 Science Hall - - _ 75.000 ENROLLMENT Reg. Year S. School Reg. Year S. School 1016-17 1917 1917-18 1918 Collegiate students in resident at- tendance 447 JO5 461 ■U Secondary students in resident tendance 1K5 *M 211 130 fa Extension students 37 -7 V Study Center 40 412 Total n* 5jg '/f&gt; M The following estimates re| ennium l&gt;esinnina r April I, 1919. 1. Operation Expenditures — a. Salaries. se&gt;., office supplic </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 STATE BOARD )F EDUCATION In elementary training school. not included in the ahove 155 15s 136 u8 Totals for each year of the biennium. counting none twice 1916-17 1917-18 Collegiate sudents in resident attendance Se-condary students in resident attendance Extension students 744 667 3&lt;&gt;i 34O - 37 58 Study Center 40 41 i 40 412 Total 1 182 1477 In Training School, elementary grade ■155 136 Enrolled the present year up to December I, 1918: Collegiate students in resident attendance... -■-'4 Secondary students in resident attendance Extension students \ I«S 36 Total 448 In Training School, elementary grade 1JJ I916-17 1917-18 The number of graduates from advanced courses 182 147 Number of students receiving Elementary Certificates .... 79 77 // Number of students receiving life certificates 139 119 ' Number of faculty members teaching full time, 1918-19 (excluding office force and assistants), 36. Number of employees : Regular _ 8 Students 5 5 CONDITION OF THE FUNDS OF THE PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL, PERU, NEBRASKA, FROM DECEMBER 1, 1916, TO DECEMBER 1, 1918 MAINTENANCE FUND Balance Dec. 1, 1916 $ 42.03 1 .54 Standard Oil Co. gasoline oil and gas 70.40 The Nebraska State Journal, two transfers 16.50 ioi6 &gt;ec. II Sligo Iron Store Co., man. tr. supplies F. W. Stetzer, hauling coal The Pressure Cooker Co., cooker R. D. Overholt, traveling expense R. D. Overholt, reg. cash adv. frt., telephone R. D. Overholt, reg.. cash adv. frt 1+38 2507 15.00 18.62 116.09 225.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 6c Sunderland 1 Mch. &amp; Supply power house _ Co., supplies __ 2,843.43 VV'hitebreasi Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 2,037.14 VV'hitebreasi Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 2,037.14 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 710.94 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 710.94 R. D. Overholt, ret., cash adv. postage, rent, supplies _ _ _ 174-54 R. D. Overholt, ret., cash adv. postage, rent, supplies _ _ _ 174-54 Xemeha County Republican, ptg. bulletins 48.00 Xemeha County Republican, ptg. bulletins 48.00 Midland Glass &amp;. Paint Co., glass 6.81 Midland Glass &amp; I'aint Co., glass 6.81 L. L. Mason, labor 4500 L. L. Mason, labor 4500 W. W. Mardis, dom. sci. and janitor sup.-.. 66.18 W. W. Mardis, dum. sci. and janitor sup.-.. 66.18 Magic City Printing Co., envelopes 30.00 Magic City Printing Co., envelopes 30.00 The Lincoln Fixture &amp; Sup. Co., showcase 28.00 The Lincoln Fixture &amp; Sup. Co., showcase 28.00 H. W. Lawrence, work 7.65 H. W. Lawrence, work 7.65 King Foundry Co., globes 7.70 King Foundry Co., globes 7.70 Emma E. Knight, traveling expenses 7.92 Emma E. Knight, traveling expenses 7.92 R. B. Knapp, labor _... 47.50 R. B. Knapp. labor _... 47.50 H. W. Jons-Manville Co., supplies power house _ 26.69 house _ 26.69 Loyd Hays, work 10.00 Loyd Hays, work 10.00 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 82.57 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 82.57 Freeport Gas Machine Co., mantles and globes _ 6.75 Freeport (jas Machine Co., mantles and globes _ 6.75 Fisher Bros., general supplies 66.33 Fisher Bros., general supplies 66.33 D' L. Duncan, labor _ 32.50 D' L. Duncan, labor _ 32.50 D. Donovan, general repairs 28.10 D. Donovan, general repairs 28.10 Cudahy Kenning Co., oil ..._ 18.80 Cudahy Retining Co., oil ..._ 18.80 Crane Co., supplies _ 45.49 Crane Co., supplies _ 45-49 H. \j. Cole, general repairs 1389 H. v. Cole, general repairs 1389 C. C. Clark, hauling coal 58.92 C. C. Clark, hauling coal 58.92 Central Scientific Co., lab. supplies 27J9 Central Scientific Co., lab. supplies 27.39 E. P. Carey, livery demonstration schools 29.25 Burgess-Granden Co., light fixtures 2645 George W. Bruwn, study center work ext 4500 H. W. Bedell( labor _ _.... 19.50 W. W. Barnes, general repairs 152.32 Am. Multigraph Sales Co., ribboii and type 10.98 C. H. Stoelting Co., laboratory supplies 41.66 J. W. Able, hauling coal 9'-3i December salaries _ 6,786.10 1917 Jan. 17 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 689.62 E. W. White, doin. sci. groceries 13.85 Standard Oil Co., oil _ 35.66 F. C. Smith, traveling expenses 38.11 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">STATE B ARD OF EDUCATION' II F. C. Smith, water com., water rent Sligo Iron Store Co, man. training rep F. W. Setzer. hauling coal 216.26 20.06 7.00 K. D. Overholt, reg*.. cash adv. postage, tele phone i.j. R. D. Overholt, reg., cash adv. in. dray and exp exp 1205b R. D. Overholt, reg.. cash adv. supplies 150.96 F. \V. Rische &amp; Son. general repairs Peru Canning &amp; Mlg. Co., ice dom. sci The Perolin Co. of America, oil F. \Y. Rische &amp; Son. general repairs 18.50 Peru Canning &amp; Mfg. Co., ice dom. sci 7.07 7-97 The Perolin Co. of America, oil 5781 ;7-8i Office Equipment &amp; supply Co 189.15 Office Equipment &amp; supply Co 189.15 N. O. Nelson Equipment Co., closets 11570 X. O. Nelson Equipment Co., closets Nebr. SchooJ Supply House, exam, paper Meek Lumber Co.. supplies H5/O Nebr. School Supply House, exam, paper 153-68 153-68 Meek Lumber Co.. supplies 89.98 The McGraw Co.. supplies 94-76 94-76 H. W. Lawrence, work. gen. repairs 5.05 5-65 The Korsmeyer Co.. powerhouse sup 45148 451.48 S. C. Johnson &amp; Son, manual training sup... 5565 55-05 J. I. HolcomVXl fg. Co.. soap base 8.90 8.90 Imperial Brush Co., janitor's supplies 75.35 Imperial Brush K Good, depariment supplies 5.47 E Good, depanment iuf H. G. Glasgow, work on c Fisher Bros., department D. Donovan &amp; Son. rep. A B Dick Co., dept. suy plit 5-47 H. G. Glasgow, work on campus 1750 ampt 17 50 Fisher Bros., department supplies 20.25 upplie 2O.25 D. Donovan &amp;■ Son. rep. and dent, sup 3184 Jl-«4 A B. Dick Co.. dept. supplies 5.75 li B. R Cole, work 16.25 B. R d.le. work in C. C. Clark, hauling coal 27.37 C. C. Clark, hauling coal The Castle Hotel. N. S. T. A. II. W. Hedell. general rcpai Clark Bruce, tuning piano 37 The Castle Hotel, N. S. T. A h.io II. W. Heilell. general repairs 82.50 82. so Clark Bruce, tuning piano 4.50 4-5&lt; W. W. Barnes, dept supplies 7.55 W. W. Barnes, dept snpplii J. W. Able, hauling coal ... January salaries J. W. Able, hauling coal 37 .64 January salaries 6,879.go February salaries 6,935.90 March salaries 6.945.00 May 9 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm Carpet Co tiles and book cases 38.65 book case S. VV. Hacker, posters and printing 67.00 67-OO F. M. Gregg, extension work— study center General Elec Co., general repairs A. Flanagan Co., model school supplies 3o.oo ;o 3-55 Fisher Bros., office ssupplies D. Donovan &amp; Son. hardware 18.45 46.19 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">PFK STATE NORMAL SCHOOL P John N. Dillon, work 70.00 70.00 Democrat Printing Co.. dept. supplies _ 15.30 Democrat Printing Co.. dept. supplies 15.20 Crane Co.. general repairs 18.70 Crane Co., general repairs 18.70 Crane Co., general repairs 1 1 20 Crane Co., general repairs 11 20 Ted A. Lowell, work on campus 3.00 d A. Cowe.11, work on campus 3.00 C. H. Coiigdon, supplies 3.00 C. H. Congdon, supplies 3.00 Commonwealth Commercial Co., man. training supplies _ _ 4908 Commonwealth Commercial Co., man training supplies _ _ 49-o8 H. O. Cole, janitor's supplies 15.59 H. O. Cole, janitor's supplies 15-59 Cobb, Whyte &amp; Laemmer Co., mod. tables 150.00 Cobb, Whyte &amp; Laemmer Co., mod. tables 150.00 C. C. Clark, hauling coal 13474 C. C. Clark, hauling coal 134-74 Central Scientific Co., lab. equipment 138.56 Central Scientific Co.. lab. equipment 138.56 VV. C. Burgess, meat. dom. science 4.70 VV. C. Burgess, meat. dom. science 4.70 (ieo. VV. Brown, extension work — study center 7500 rk — study 75O0 Irving (i. Bangart &amp; Co., drawing suppies .... 4.13 uppies .... 4.13 H. W. Bedell, hauling coal 108.75 H. W. Bedell, hauling coal 108.75 John A. Krashear Co.. telescopic eyepiece 5.14 ipic eyepiece 5.14 Baker Bros. Engraving Co.. cut Summer School poster 13-65 Baker Bros. Engraving Co., cut Summer poster 13.65 Baker Bros. Kng. Co, half-tone new bldg. 3.76 Atkinson Mentzer &amp; Co., drawing model stands 10.00 \lkinson Mentzer &amp; Co., drawing model ands iaoo I. VV. Able, hauling coal 220.52 J. VV. Able, hauling coal 220.52 I). W. Hayes, traveling expenses 108.93 I). W. Hayes, traveling expenses 108.93 E. J. Newman, photographic work 8.20 E. J. Newman, photographic work 8.20 Xeinaha County Republican, bulletins &gt;3&lt;&gt;-37 s'emaha County Republican, bulletins 130.37 Memaha I ounty Herald, exam, paper 2915 Memaha I nunty Herald, exam, paper 2915 Xebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Nebrask ertising 10.00 Xebr. School Sup. House, office supplies 27.76 Xebr. School Sup. House, office supplies 27.76 .Xebr. Material Co., cement man. training .... 3.00 Xebraska Material Co., lire clay 19-50 Xebr. Buick Auto Co., general supplies 34-00 Mamie R. Mutz. exten. work — study center 5.00 Jas. Morton &amp; Sons Co., keys _ 3.26 Win. Material Co., cement mar training... 3.00 Nebraska Material Co., lire cl Monarch Paint Co., general repairs 32.50 Meek Lumber Co.. lumber _ '77-39 The McGraw Co., man. tr. equipment 81.92 J. 1. Holcomb Mfg Co.. janitor's supplies. ... 7.30 Henkle &amp; Joyce, general repairs 37-5O J. A. Hays, traveling expenses 3.92 Ofiice Equipment Co., envelopes 71-50 Oliver Machinery Co., planer knives 19-35 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co., lumber </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Balance July 25 $+2,031.54 $203,000.00 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' manual train in. 3865 The Omaha School Supply Co. supplies 4.00 R. D. Overholt, reg.. cash dom. science adv. tel., potsage. 8597 R. D. Overholt. reg.. cash express ..._ adv. frt. dray and R. D. Overholt, reg.. cash R. D. Overholt. reg., cash and sen. supplies R. D. Overholt, reg. cash and gen. supplies adv. gen. sup 0360 adv hauling coal 122.66 Harry Porter, science department Harry Porter, mimeograph paoer T. J. Railsback. general supplies. ... 56.6 5 4-^5 1175 The Roessler &amp; Hasslachcr Chcm. Co.. art supplies 24.14 N*. R. Rogers, powerhoi: Laurance Rouse, work ... Singer Sewing Machine C F. C. Smith, water com., Veda Smith, accompanist Standard Oil Co.. oil e supplies 275 gym. classes 5.40 house and general sypplies 110.98 L'nderwood Typewriter Co.. duplicat. ink Jack Weaver, work 5.00 300 T. E. Vance, janitor's supplies Western Electric Co., supplie E. W. White Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lbr. John Co. Woodie. haulin R. D. Overholt. reg.. cash Co.. coal coal adv. postage and envelopes April 24. IQ17 MAINTENANCE Appropriation . biennium beginning April 1. 1917. to April 1. 1919 Netnaha County Republican, bulletins John Able, hauling coal _ 355-68 64-95 7&amp;43 4OO2 adv. hauling coal 6.oo -&gt;.. tewing machs. 173.48 watc rent 236.83 &lt;/..«4 Simderland Mch. &amp; Supply Co, power- </seg>
            <seg id="p073">\(\ STATE NORMAL SCHOOI I 7.? G. C. Adams &amp; Nelson Co., tools man. training 21.84 21.84 Atkinson, \ientzer Co., drawing mod. stand 2.50 Vtk E. P. Carey, auto livery 45-f&gt;5 45°5 H. K. Cole, work on campus 6.25 t,.J C. C. I lark, hauling coal 58.24 5«-24 3-44 A. B Dick Co., stencil and dermax 3.44 1)1, 1). Donovan it Son, general repairs and netting 5O-Q4 Donovan it Sun, lfener 50.04 12.50 Charles Kpler, work 12.50 ( Fisher Bros., supplies 20.07 20.07 I M. E. Good, domestic science supplies 2.88 188 Hammond &amp; Stephens Co.. degree diplomas 100.00 :i mas 100.00 D. VV. Hives, traveling expense 00.60. U. \Y. H I.. L Horton, work on campus 5.00 k on c 5.00 ]-eo Jewell, work — grading 10.00 10.00 Joe Koeler. meat — domestic science 4.20 4-x) H. U. Landolt, dom. sci. supplies ar.d lab 23.80 and lab 23.80 W. H. Lawrence, work 108.00 108.00 M. C. I.eriYr. extension w&gt;rk — study center 15.00 1S-0O l.inde Air Products Co, oxygen 26.75 Products Co, oxvccn 2"75 H. M Mackprang, engine room supplies 8.60 W. VV. Mardis. laboratory and dom. sci 15.43 J. D. McAuley, wnrk 40.00 Meek Lumber Co., lumber, coke, lime 32.60 mber. coke, lime 32.60 The McGraw Co., step ladders 7.28 Middle-West School Review, advertising... 1050 Milwaukee Dustless Brush Co., brushes 66.00 Milwaukee Dustless Brush Co.. brushes 66.00 A. J. Morley, rep, and tuning chape! piano... 5.00 \. J. Morley, rep, and tuning chape! piano... 5.00 Nebraska Material Co., cement 280.80 2S0.H0 ,\ E. J. Newman, prints and tilling in diplomas 2*1.78 R. D Overman, reg.. cash adv. frt. dray, exp 24857 dray, exp 248 tame, tel- R. D. Overliolt. reg., cash adv. postage, tel - ephone i-J7-4&lt;&gt; IJ7.40 R. D. Overliolt. reg.. cash adv. com. exp 347/2 wi. exp 347.7 R. D. Overholt, reg., cash adv. work grounds and laundry 4510 work 45 10 R, D. Overholt. reg., cash adv. telephone and supplies 47-42 • '•leu Parriott. work 38.50 Co. nf America. P 57-8o Peru Canning &amp; Mfg. Co., ice and ammo 13.16 R A 66. K. A </seg>
            <seg id="p074">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' i William lrante, hauling coai Pyrene Mfg. Co., tire extinguisher Kudge &amp; Oiicnze) Co. drawer pa F. C Smith, traveling expense Scott Tyler, work on campus 59 .20.00 4'7 470 5-uo Stacy v ance, work 5.00 5-0" W. S. \ ance, work ai new building 40.0U 40.00 E. W. White, supplies 18.72 18.72 Whitebreasi Coal &lt;* Lumber Co., coal Elmer Wilson, Editor, Peruvians Whitebreasi Coal cv: i-iimbcr Co., coal 1,48074 1,480.74 2UO.OU Elmer Wilson, Eiluor, Peruvians 200.00 J. C. Woodie, hauling coal _ 9^1 J. C. Woodie, hauling 9. 21 Ed. F. Wright, rooi repairs and labor 3/7-0O 377-00 Bishop &amp; Bedell, livery, general repairs .... 3 R. D. Overholt, rug., cash adv., frt, dray and Bishop &amp; Bedell, livery, general repairs .... 52-/U ,2./o Aus, R. D. Overholt, reg.. cash adv., frt, dray and express 54.92 express 54-tH 5O-/O Meek Lumber Co., lumber, liine, tile 50./0 Meek Lumber Co., lumber ili- John Able, hauling coal 5.44 John Able, hauling c E. W. White, towelin Stacy Vance, work Sunderland Bros. Co.. Frederick Post Co, n a 1 5-44 E. W. White, toweling 3330 33 3O Stacy \ ance. work 3.50 3-iu Sunderland Bros. Co.. washed gravel 304-ju washed gravel an. tr. supplies 3O4- 5' Frederick Post Co., man. ir. supplies 13.12 11 litj Standard Oil Co., gasolene, gas and oil 29.58 Standard Oil Co.. gasolene, gas and oil ■su-58 Merle Pawley. psychology assistant 20.00 Charles Parnott. janitor tor Honey-creek school 13.50 r tor H'nieycreek R. D. Overholt, reg., cash adv. telephone postage, frt, and com. address 23707 Lash adv. telephone m. address postage, t rt, and cc R. D. Overholt. reg., cash adv. work on new building 03.75 Omaha Hardwood manual trainin; umber Co, lumber ioj.42 Oliver Machinery C A. J. Nystrom &amp; Cc E. J. Newman, filtir man. train, material 3500 geological map names on diplomas. etc 14.(1(1 73.00 Nemaha Co. Republican, com programs N'emaha Cn. Herald, printing IIHUILJ 3-7 Nebraska Teacher, ariv crtisinf S.00 Nebr. School Supply Murray Iron Work H use. flags, office sup 310.00 Co 'lianpal training machinery 25500 Midland Chemical ( Vock Michel, labor The McGraw Co., c&lt; n liquid snap 4.00 140.28 I5.» tton waste </seg>
            <seg id="p075">7 PER ATE NORMAL SCHOOL W. W. Mardis. Dutch Cleanser Magic City Printing Co.. printing H. M. Mackprang. general supplies W. H. Lawrence, work Korsmeyer Cn.. electrical supplies Grant Kingsolver, water com., water rent 2.85 21325 358 18.80 180.32 4-' 227.60 VVhitebreast Coal &amp; I.uml ■er Co., coal 37376 Imperial Brush Co.. janitc r's supplies 35.40 Alonzo Huston, work .-. 7.00 nitor's supplies... 3.30 12.00 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense _ 104.28 H. W. Foght. fees and expenses, rural work 101.00 Fisher Bros., office supplies 123.00 3250 10.30 Central Scientific Co., sci. lab. supplies 146.00 William Bogle, work 24-75 Bishop &amp; Bedell, oil for engine work 7.05 11 Co.. halftones for bullet 74-45 Frank J. Armstrong, work 164.50 American I Co., college view a ita 1 6.oo R. T. Allgood. labor 6.19 K. D. Overholt. rash a laundry, gas work, supplic July 25 Apr May salarii June salarie ep. 26 September salaries Aug. 27 August salaries Oct. 27 October salaries Nov. 22 November salaries Nuv R. D. Overholt. reg., cash adv., frt. dray and express _ — 333-37 The Willis Music Co.. music for chorus 2.40 Elmer Wilson, work „ 47-5O J. 1. Holcomb Mfg. Cc I.oyd Hays, labor Eureka Supply Co.. paper tow;l O. L. Duncan, work D. Dnnovan &amp; Son. hardware 33-92 John Dillin. labor 7.00 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co., May Festival music 17.38 &gt;rncll- Searl to., repairs — closets 2.80 «797 6.944.40 6.90330 7.590.90 7.184.40 7.076.03 1.52700 7,140.65 7,23730 July salarie </seg>
            <seg id="p076">TAT1 )1 DUCA \ J. VV. York &amp; Sons, repairs for band 32.2 E. W. Whit mi! ri »&lt;« Whitcbreast Coal h Lumber Co., coal i.Son.f hotnas \Y Work 137.W W. M. W Mfu'. I ,1 la 374' Burgess-Granden Co., hraseolites 75-45 Hauscli It Lomb Optical Co.. lab. equip 54 a6 I nit id Theatre Equipment Corporation. moving picture machine 285.75 t n #-, Stacy Vance, work 02.00 Stacy Vance, v » Sumkrlaml Machine &amp; Supply Co.. 126.30 1 Sunderlaml Machinery &amp; Supply Co., hot water valvea io.c)8 inderland Machinery K water valvea 11 W. Scott Tyler, wurk 23.75 W. Scott Tvl C. H. Stoetting Co.. laboratory apparatus .... 20.84 C. H. Stocking Co.. laboratory apparatus ... 20.84 Wilbur Einmert. work 40.00 Wilbur Emmert. work S. \V Hacker, printing 164.30 Julian P. Fritz &amp; Sons, biology equipment 145.00 Julian P. Friez &amp; Sons, biology equipment 145/ t Manly Furniture Co.. tireless cooker lo.qo Hardy Furniture Co.. tireless cooker lo.qo D. \V. Hayes, traveling expense 68.97 D. W. II 68 J. I. Holcomb Mfs. Co., soap — janitor's sup. 6.60 J. I. Holcomb Mt'jr. Co., soai) — janitor's sup. 6.60 a Hillyarcl Disinfect. Co.. janitor's supplies . 13400 Hillyard Disinfect. Co.. janitor's supplies . M4Oi amtor s siipnlit 1 Homer C House, study center work 20.20 Homer C House, study center work 1 F. C. Jean, institute expenses 4.30 F. C. lean t W. X. Delzell. institute expenses 20 10 W. N. Delzell. inst W. X. Delzell, expenses for State Fair week 4485 W. N. Delzell. expenses for State Fair week 44.8 Crane Co., general repairs 5944 Crane Co., general repairs 59-44 Frederick Carl, physical apparatus 15.00 Frederick Car apparatus 15 E. P. Carey, auto livery 11.00 E. P. Carev. auto livery I I IK. Bishop &amp; Bedell. aiUo livery .". 21.40 Bishop &amp; Bedell. aiUo livery .*. 21.40 W. \V. Barnes, paint and brush 425 W. W. Barnes, paint and 425 Irving G. Banghart &amp; Co.. bookpress and paste 9.15 Irving G. Banghart &amp; Co.. bookpress and paste 9.1 J. X. Dillon, work 9520 J. X. Dillon, w k 95 20 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co.. music for chorus and glee clubs 35.02 Chas. H. Ditson it Co.. music for chorus and glee cl;i 35-02 D. Donovan &amp; Co., general supplies 39 45 D. Donovan &amp; Co.. general supplies 39 45 Eimer &amp; Amend, laboratory equipment 15136 Eimer &amp; Amend, laboratory equipment 1 5 1. 36 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., snare drum and folios 2429 J. W. Jenkins' Sons M snare drum and folios J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., band music 1688 J. \V. Jenkins' Sons Mas The Kahler Pottery Co., C. G. Kinsolver, water ci c Co.. band music laboratory equip, m., water 4-50 1 60.0s </seg>
            <seg id="p077">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Joseph Koler. meat for alligators The Korsmeyer Co.. electrical supplies Library Bureau, riling cases 5.80 17.22 Hi; cases 7.90 Carroll Lewis, work I4-5O John Laukcmper. running motor The Omaha Nebraskan, advertising Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co.. lumber Hsher BrOS.. wnpral muni;.. —"""i"'. i mining motor 4.00 The Omaha Xebraskan, advertising ,5.00 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co.. lumber 174.60 Hsher Bros., general supplies 36.94 K. J. Newman, pictures 5 I0 Xcmaha Co. Republican, letter heads 33^50 Xemaha Co. Republican, letter head H. Morgenstern. coal for infirmary H. Morgenstern. coal for infirmary 29.35 National Refining Co., floor oil 6aoo National Refining Cc Vock Michel, hauling Meek Lumber Co, It floor oil Vock Michel, hauling coal 151 80 Meek Lumber Co. lumber, lime. sand. etc. 208.49 .1. D. McAuley. work 535O J- D. McAuley. work Carl Mackprang, wor R. D. Overholt, ree.. Carl Mackprang, work , 7S0 R. D. Overholt, rest., cash adv. telephone, postage, telegrams, infirmary rent. _ 123.92 postage, telegram R. D. Overholt. rei? r 123.92 R. D. Overholt. reg.. rash adv postage, tel - ephone, work 175.55 hone, work The Plant World, atmometers 1M0 Plant World, atm etc _ Floyd Pa'mer. Sept. and Oct. salary , laoo Harry Porter, stencil material : &amp;,- Harry Porter, files " J. W. Scarborough, sand 70o Laurancr Rouse, work so E. I.. Rouse, institute expenses for organ - izing study centers ,3^8 Standard Oil Co.. engine oil. gasolene, and kerosene , IT .... ' 24.OO ( H. \\ . Lawrence, work 88on Standard Oil Co.. oil and gasolene ." I23O Standard Oil Co.. gas. gasoline and oil 7628 State Jorr Co.. refund book , 50o Sutherland Bros. Co.. sand and stone chips 24170 Jack Weaver, work -g Oct. salary Harry Porter, stencil material Harry Porter, files 2.25 J. W. Scarborough, sand Laurancr Rouse, work E. I.. Rouse, institute pi 7-on 66. so .. Kouse. institute expenses for organ - izing study centers 13-28 Standard Oil Co.. en kerosen 24.60 H. \\. law U k 88.90 Standard Oil Co.. oil Standard Oil Co.. ga: State Jour Co., refun Sunderland Bros. Co. Jack Weaver, work December salaries asolene 12.30 asoline and oil 7628 book 15.00 ;ind and stone chips 241.70 78.25 Dec. 13 December salaries .. ,,,,,, 1918 7.2I2-73 Dec 13 Jan. 2, W. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. physical apparatus 900 Amer.can Multigraph Co., multigraph sup.s 21.50 W. W. Barnes, general supplies Bishop &amp; Bedell, batteries Geo. W. Brown, study center work E. P. Carey, livery W. W. Barnes, general supplies ,„ D:_l oni... . /-^" 8.40 4500 26.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 8 The Claflin Ptg. Co.. letter heads and env. 122.50 A Crago. study center work 1500 Crane Co., general repairs 205.04 \V: N. Delzcll. work as field coach 17 34 W. N. Delzell. study center work 2500 D. Donovan &amp; Son. general supplies 16.50 Enterprise Plan. Mill, cupboards and seats 63.60 Enterprise Plan. Mill, cupboards and seats 63.60 Fisher Bros, general supplies 2270 Everett Prain Co.. basswood panics : 6.75 Everett Prain Co.. basswood par ( The Gamble Hinged Music Co.. May Festi - val music '5 00 The Gamble Hinged Music Co.. May Festi - val music '5 00 Henry J. Green, laboratory apparatus I4-0O Henry J. Green, laboratory apparatus 14-00 F. M. GresR. study center work 25.00 F. M. Gregg, study center work J?'»&gt; S. W. Hacker &amp; Co.. printing . «•&amp;&gt; 8.S0 S. W. Hacker &amp; Co.. printir Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co. coal .1.9675" Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co. coal 3-9"7 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense fr)-33 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense 8u-33 B. Clifforod Hendricks. study center work 1000 B. Clifforod Hendricks. study center work 10 Hotpoint Electric Heating Co.. repairs for irons 4-7^ ng t irons 4-/K J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co.. polishope 14*10 I. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co.. poiishope 1400 H. W. Johns-M;mville Co.. genera! repairs 60.51 Magic City Printing Co., envelopes -5 75 F. C. Kean. shidy center work 1500 F. C. Kean. study center work (". (1. KiBglolver. water com., water i x 2.?7 C. (j. Kingsolvir. wa v Kline-Smith Publishing Co.. bulletins 2*1.7.2 Kline-Smith Publishing Co.. bulletins 26 The Korsineyer Co., general repair* 116.76 The Korsinever Co.. general repairs 116.76 Meek Lumber Co.. lumber 37-9' Meek Lumber Co.. lumber Yock Michel, hauling coal 195-39 Yock Michel, hauling coal '95-39 The Murray iron Works Co.. steam valve rod "&gt;•&lt;•" The Murray iron Works Co.. steam valve mil rod "&gt;•&lt;•" Mamie R. Mutz. study center work .10.00 Mamie R. Mutz. study center work 30.00 Office F.quipment &amp; Sup. Co.. order blanks 29.50 Office F.quipment &amp; Sup. Co.. order blanks 29.50 The Omaha School Supply Co.. oak tables 10.00 The Omaha School Supply Co.. oak tables 10.00 R. D. Overholt. reg. frt.. dray and express. cash advanced 176.22 R. D. Overholt. reg. frt.. dray and express, cash advanced 176.2 R. D Overholt. reg., sta.njis. telephone. cash advanced 3°' 84 Nona Palmer, study center work 45°° Pearl Regan, commercial work 3.11 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., model school sup 112.25 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., cork carpet 709.20 Standard Oil Co., oil and gasoline... 77.97 Thos. E. Wilson Co.. basketballs 43 5° Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co.. general rep. 4015 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">I &lt;&gt; PERI STATE NORMAL SCHOOL I. W. York &amp; Son. r and and orchestra in 16785 st rumen ce equipment... 43 30 lamps i'3-95 Jan. Feb. Mar Apr 21 Arthur H. Thomas ( Ward's Natural Scit Western Electric Ci Irl W. Wright. pip&lt; X aid. annual catal 467.78 W W. Mardis. soda asr Whitebreast Coal &amp; Luml The McGraw Co., wireles Meek Lumber Co., lime Vock Michel, hauling c( Midde-West School Rev Mamie R. Mutz. study ce •Mo Tiber Co.. coal 3.563.92 10.80 ess st mid plaster 7.80 al 13864 w. advertising... 10.50 work 40.00 advertising loon Id. booklets 25.00 6.06 rk Oscar Oakes. Pern N Nona Palmer, studv c lalites 100.00 work 45.00 Co., in Mach. &amp; pply Co., power- 1). W Hay D. VV. Hay. xpen 64.92 civ., dray. frt. and 59-51 528-55 B. C. Hemlrick idy center work 30.81 Co., janitor's sup 81.20 Her work 20.00 janitor's supplies liter work Imperial Brush I F. C. Jean, study J. VV. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., music, drum heads, stands The Korsmeyer Co, wireless apparatus Louis Lewis, police duty H. M. Mackpraiia. general repairs — American Multigraph Sales Co.. coupon book for ribbons 893O 18.98 500 29.66 24-50 Zahner Mfg. Co. don The McGraw Co.. c 21 January salaries 18 Kcbruarv salaries .... 7-209.24 7.200.90 March sa 7.oio 8s abora^ry furnace 18.00 ice Estab. lab. appar. 25.00 electrical supplies... 103.18 7-65 N'emalia County He I ho Nebraska Teach* Xfinalui Count v Htr supplies .... 79.08 express - . D. \Y. Hayes, prin.. cash adv.. post., dray and envelopes Hillyard Disinfectan H. C. House, study c&lt; 20.00 86.00 2O.0O </seg>
            <seg id="p080">STATE B ARD OF iDLCA'I ION' A) S. H. Avey &amp; Co., rent of pianos 156.00 Irving G. Banghart &amp; Co.. an supplies 6.31 Geo. W. Brown, study center work 2500 E. P. Carey, auto livery ll -5° E. P. Carey, auto li Thomas Charles Co., A. Crago, study cen W. N. Delzell, work W. N. Delzell. study Thomas Charles Co., model school sup 20.30 model school sup. ;r work A. Crago, study center work 150° 15-00 W. N. Delzell, work as held coach 53-H as held coach center work 53-H W. N. Delzell. study center work 5 0° 500 J. N. Dillon, carpenter work 60.80 J. N. Dillon, carpenter work U&gt;.8o Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co., festival music 67.39 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co., festival masic D. Donovan &amp;. Son. general supplies. ... 67-39 D. Donovan &amp; Son, general supplies 16.36 16.30 The William B. Duck Co.. wireless appa. 51-39 The William B. Duck Eagle Lock Co., keys Fisher Bros., general 51-39 Eagle Lock Co.. keys - 13-03 13-03 Kisher Bros., general supplies... 161.93 lOi.yj F. M. Gregg, study center work 2000 20.00 C. G. Kingsolver. water com., water 24032 com., water 8 April salaries - - 6.947-9O May salaries 6,869.43 Apr. May June May salaries 10 E. VV. White, ribbon for diplomas 13-64 Stacy Vance, work on grounds 18.00 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Supply Co., engine room repairs — 29.78 E. W. White, ribbon 1 Stacy Vance, work on Sunderland Mach. &amp; it diplomas grounds .... lu 18.00 upply Co., engine 29.78 room repair J. A. Stephenson, work on ground* 54-°° J. A. Stephenson, work on ground* 54-0° Standard Oil Co.. cylinder oil Standard Oil Co.. cylinder oil 25.01 25.01 Sinclair Refining Co.. power house sup 3** 53 Sinclair kenning Co., power house sup 3#53 D. W. Hayes, print., cash adv.. ieL, frt., laundry, etc 179-67 L). W. Hayes, print., cash adv.. iel., frt. laundry, etc '79-67 X. R. Rogers, repairs - 6.90 X. R. Rogers, repairs - 6.90 Nona Palmer, study center work 30.0c Nona Palmer, study center work 30.00 E J. Newman, names on diplomas i8.l£ 18. 18 Nebraska Material Co., stone dust 308c Nebraska Material Co., stone dust 3080 National Refining Co.. floor oil 2O.8t National Refining Co.. floor oil 20.80 Mamie R. Matt, study center work Jaa Mamie R. Matt, study center work Miller &amp; Paine, sign cloth _'()(«) Miller &amp; Paine, sign cloth «&lt;* S.00 Yock Michel, hauling coal U7-4' Vock Michel, hauling coal U7-4 1 Meek Lumber Co.. lumber and plaster 212.9I Meek Lumber Co.. lumber and plaster 212.98 Woodruff Bank Note Co.. record sheets 16.51 16.50 L. J. Worth. Bus Man. Peruvian. ;*&gt; copies Peruvian aoaoi Peruvian 200.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. coal 1.813.7; Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. coal 1.813.7; H. M. Mackprang. general supplies 7-3 H. M. Mackprang. general supplies 7-3t Lincoln Nursery, hedge 43-7 Lincoln Nursery, hedge 43-75 Carroll Lewis, work on grounds 12.0 12.00 H. W. Lawrence, work on grounds 76.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Aug. 14 8. PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL The Korsmeyer Co.. powerhouse and man. training supplies 18.92 Clyde Ivers, work on ground 12.00 r. L. Jean, study center F. C. Jean, study center 10.00 B. Clifford Hendricks. study center work 5.00 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 59-48 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 59-48 Curtis, Fowler &amp; Paine Co., screens 68.00 Curtis, Fowler &amp; Paine Co., screens 68.00 D. Donovan &amp; Son, general supplies n 82 D. Donovan &amp; Son, general supplies n 82 H. M. Dressier, work at school garden 4.00 H. M. Dressier, work at school garden 4.00 Fisher Bros., general supplies 12.98 Fisher Bros., general supplies 12.96 F. M. Greg;^, study center work _ 10.00 10.00 S. W. Hacker, printing 124.65 W. Hacker, printing 124.65 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co.. Mazda lamps 15.00 A Crago, sudy center work 5.00 A Crago, sudy center work 5.00 E. P. Carey, livery 45.75 E. P. Carey, livery 45.75 Geo. W. Brown, study center work 15.00 15.00 The Book Supply Co., duplicators 1275 The Book Supply Co., duplicators 1275 D. W. Hayes, prin., cash adv.. frt., dray and exp 87.76 D. W. Hayes, prin., cash adv., frt., dray and exp 87.76 W. N. Delzell, expenses as field coach 32.65 W. N. Delzell, expenses as field coach 3265 .1 June salaries 6,928.30 June salaries 6,928.30 July salaries 6,790.70 July salaries 6,700.70 Harold Brown, work on walks, etc 45 90 Harold Brown, work on walks, etc S. H. Avey &amp; Co., piano rent 130.00 S. H. Avey &amp; Co., piano rent 130.00 Bishop &amp; Bedell, livery trips and batteries 12.40 Bishop &amp; Bedell, livery trips and batteries 12.40 Francis Cooper, manual training assistant 75-00 Crane Co.. repairs 28.66 Crane Co.. repairs 28.66 D Donovan &amp; Son. general supplies 18.95 D Donovan &amp; Son. general supplies 18.95 C. E. Wagner. Delco — lights, products bat - teries 72.50 C. E. Wagner. Delco — lights, products bat- teries 72.50 Wilber Emniert, work on grounds 15.00 Wilber Emniert, work on grourds 15.00 Fisher Bros., general supplies 2505 Fisher Bros., general supplies 25.05 S. W. Hacker, envelopes and cards 22.00 S. W. Hacker, envelopes and cards 22.00 Hillyard Chemical Co., janitor supplies 59.38 Hillyard Chemical Co., janitor supplies 50.38 D. W. Hayes, prin., cash advanced postage 14696 D. VV. Hayes, prin., cash adv., frt. dray and exp.. tel 140.41 H. W. Lawrence, work on walks and haul. 6330 H. M. Mackpran^, supplies 46.90 W. W. Mardis, janitor supplies 25.35 Meek Lumber Co., supplies 320.81 Milwaukee Dustless Brush Co., Justless cleaner 25.50 J. A. Stephenson, painting 690 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">Sj STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Stacy Vance, work on walks E. W. White, supplies 106.50 12.80 .19-5" Woodruff Bank Note Co., printing bulletins H. U. Landolt, training school supplies The Korsmeyer Co.. electric light wire C. G. Kingsolver. water com. reading me- 12.71 12.48 ter and rent 167.19 A. B. Kinton. work on new bldg. grounds Jacob Huffer. work on school gardens D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 1710 3°- 50 U6-97 D. W. Hayes, prin.. cash adv for sup. Irl W. Wright, supplies 355-86 9.90 Charles Parriott, janitor work 13-5O Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co.. man. tr supplies 28576 E. J. Newman, tilling in diplomas, etc Nemaha County Herald, receipts and num- 14.40 bering same 22.50 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising Mamie R. Mutz, study center work August salaries 7-5O Aug. Sep. Nov Nov 97O 52.60 C. F. Beck, institute expense 31-98 Peru Canning &amp; Mfg. Co.. ice books Harold Brown, work on grounds C. C. Birchard &amp; Co., song books, chapel Crane Co., powerhouse supplies 12.50 25-5&lt;) 2400 59-73 Earl Coulter, hauling coal as per contract Willard Cowell .work 42135 73-5O Churchill &amp; (jrindell. song books, mod school 17.27 62.11 Cornell Sear! Co., dormitory repairs Hammond Typewriter Co., mimeo shuttle 350 Sunderland Mach.. &amp; Supply Co.. power- house supplies 37-50 Sunderland Mach.. &amp; Supply Co., power- house supplies 9&gt;579 Standard Oil Co.. oil and gasoKne 30.96 The Register, advertising 10.00 Mamie R. Mutz. study center work 10.00 23 August salaries 1,672.00 23 September salaries 6,203.50 2 October salaries 6.466.25 18 Stacy Vance, auto to Omaha. S. A. T. C 11.50 Stacy Vance, "work on grounds 11340 E. J. Newman, lantern slides W. W. Barnes, supplies </seg>
            <seg id="p083">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 83 S. W. Hacker, printing and supplies 85-25 Chas. Haas, repair work VVillard Griffith, janitor work F. M. Gregg, institute expense M. E. Good, supplies E. E. Good, agent, infirmary T. F. Gockley, work Fred J. Gilbert, meals Board Fisher Bros., supplies 9.00 12.00 3«-27 4-75 rent 90.00 71-40 Education 3.75 .1 55-18 E L. Rouse, traveling expenses SM E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 51.06 207.22 15580 E. L. Rouse, services rendered Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. lsal. due on cork car- 74-80 pet Royal_ Typewriter Co., typewriter and cou - pon book _ 74.5O 3100 Sinclair Refining Co., engine oil L. C. Smith &amp; Bros.. Type Co., rental and coupon book i8.oo Standard ;.il Co, oil and gasoline Star Publishing Co.. adv. S. A. T. C... State Journal Co.. S. A. T. C. ad \Y. \\ Stcphenson. work on campus John Thorp, work in boiler room cement and Underwood Typewriter Cc rental and coupne book T. E. Vance, supplit Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lbr. Co.. 8 VVhitebreast Coal &amp; Lbr. Co., M Nebr. School Supply House, ex cars coal 1,781.10 cars coal 1,132.12 am. paper and Ha 146.49 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 5-75 E. L. Kousc. prin., cash advanced E. L. Rouse, prin., cash adv. supplies fc.. L. Kouse. services rendered 124.19 E. L. Rouse, prin.. frt.. dray and express 556.76 E. L. House. . prin .cash advanced supplies 656.79 Sunderland Mch. &amp; Supply Co repair* 97 5O Xebr. School Supply House, supplies Mamie K. Muth, institute fees and exp. D. Donovan &amp; Son, supplies i+35 A. B. Dick &amp; Co., general supplies 7-21 W. N. Delzill. institute and State Fair ex. 101.15 Harry Porter, mailing tubes 16.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">-1 Salaries $203,000.00 $ 15.71 1.78 STATE BOARD 0 EDUCATION' Standard Electric Time Co.. tapes for clock 8.50 Martin Grate Co, repairs 117.00 H. If. Mackprang supplies 12.85 H. W. Lawrence, work 9'-58 The Korsmeyer Co.. lamps 103.50 The Korsrheyer Co., rep. and buzzer sets 43.0; C. G. Kingsolver. water com., water rent .... 191 24 Keuffel &amp; Esser Co., man. tr. repairs 84.89 Keuffel &amp; Esser Co.. man. tr. repairs 84.89 R. W. Kelly, cash adv. for freight 402.66 R. W. Kelly, cash adv. for freight 402.6b Kansas City Feature Film Co.. films 15.90 Kansas City Feature Film Co.. films 15.00 Oliver Mach. Co, man. tr. repairs 15.50 The A. X. Palmer Co.. pens and holders .... 2.65 The A. X. Palmer Co.. pens and holders... 2.65 E. L. Rouse, traveling exp. S. A. T. C 26.75 E. L. Rouse, traveling exp. S. A. T. C 26.75 The Republican, refund and order books.... 20.2 The Republican, refund and order books .. 20.25 J. A. Parks Music Co.. music 4.96 J. A. Parks Music Co.. music 4.96 Remington Typewriter, rental 3 machines 9.00 Remington Typewriter, rental 3 machines 9.00 Andrew Rader. work ■. 66.75 Andrew Rader. work : 66.75 Mrs. R. J. Pyles. cleaning in dormitory 14.00 Mrs. R. J. Pyles. cleaning in dormitory 14.00 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 29.03 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 29.03 P. C. Hayden, batons, music, etc 9.25 P. C. Hayden. batons, music, etc 9.25 Hillyard Chemical Co. supplies 56.00 Hillyard Chemical Co.. supplies 56.00 Hugh House, work _ 12.00 Hugh House, work 12.00 H. C. House. S. A. T. C. trip expenses 9.00 H. C. House. S. A. T. C. trip expenses 9.00 H. C. House, institute expenses 6.54 H. C. House, institute expenses 6.54 F. C. Jean, S. A. T. C. expenses 5.34 F. C. Jean, S. A. T. C. expenses v 5.34 F. C. Jean, State Fair expenses 16.95 F. C. Jean, State Fair expenses 16.95 W. F. Hoyt, institute expenses and fee*;... 19.54 Kingsley House, work .-. .*.. 12.00 Nov. 25 November salaries _ _ 6,555.03 Dec. 1 Balance December l, 1918 29.538.47 $203,000.00 SUMMARY OF MAINTENANCE FUND of President and Office Force for biennium i ock Michel, hauling coal diddle West School Review, advertising ileek Lumber Co., 4 T coal infirmary kleek Lumber Co. sand and cement 103.21 10.50 44.00 8.27 leo. A. Medsker, work ieo. McKnight, work fireman _.. 65.40 2484 r. Forrest Adams, work 45.00 A'. \V. Mardis. supplies 3-35 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 85 Dec. 6 Sent State Treasurer 21 1. 21 Dec. 11 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. chemical lab. sup... 78.98 Waldort Bindery Co.. binding books 9&lt;-35 Rita Thomas, private piano lesson 115.00 Chas. Scribner's Sons, textbooks 10.5 Chas. Scrihner's Sons, textbooks 23.52 Scott Foeesman &amp; Co.. textbooks 28.80 Rudge &amp; Giu'iizel, typewriter desk 21.25 A. N. Palmer Co., model school pens 6.49 A. N. Palmer Co., model school pens 6.49 Oxford University Press, textbooks 1100 Oxford University Press, textbooks 1100 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co.. lumber 212.58 N'ettie Meyer, private voice lessons 70.00 King Foundry Co., electrolites for dorm 82.00 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., music 20.73 Hardy Furniture Co., linoleum for dorm 416.15 M. E Good, groceries for dom. sci 6.65 Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks 24.57 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks v 34-32 J. Fischer &amp; Bros., music 4.86 Emerson College Publishing Co., textbooks 8.40 Fischer Bros., mod. school and lab. sup 960 Salaries of Faculty Members for biennium .... 126,392.78 Salaries of Employees for biennium Total cost other services, as speakers, etc .... 17436.97 964.65 Total cost record books and printing Total cost telegraph and telephone Total cost postage .... 3.034-41 207.52 .... 683.98 Traveling expense of President 713.96 Total cost office supplies, etc Total cost freight, dray and express .... 1. 447-62 ... 4.287.29 Total cost departmental supplies Total cost extension work .... 3.27283 94183 Total cost furniture and equipment Total cost fuel _ _ _ .... 2.364.99 .... 15,619.50 Total cost light : 619.41 Total cost water _ Total cost general supplies .... 1. 1 79.95 .... 2.527.75 Total cost depreciation repairs Total cost additions physical plant .... 2.259.92 858.70 Total cost improvements grounds 5IS5O INSTITUTION CASH Balance reported December I, 1916 $ 6.516.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">8o STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION D. Donovan &amp; Son, man. tr. and model school _ 140.00 Douglas Printing Co., books 25.00 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co., music 47-40 Thos. Y. Crowell Co., books 4.80 Thos. Charles Co., mod. school supplies... 20.81 C. C. Birchard &amp; Co.. music books 10.00 American Book Co , books 41-76 University Publishing Co., books 0.08 Irvin Caldwell, dorm, mail for Dec 3.00 191 7 Jan. 4 Sent State Treasurer 199-54 Jan. 15 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., lab. supplies Rita Thomas, private piano lessons Scott, Foresman &amp; Co. books Rudge &amp; Gucnzel Co.. sewing class sup Peru Elec. Light &amp; Power Co.. light for hospital October and November R. D. Overholt. reg.. cash adv. lab., book and music Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons Meek Lumber Co., coal for hospital The McGraw Co., dormitory electroliers .... 325.12 Manual Arts Press, books H. U. Landolt, groceries domestic science 48.84 Korsmeyer Co.. conduit for dormitory elec- troliers 4020 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. music 19 32 Fisher Bros., dormitory repairs _ 615 C. V* Claus. dormitory repairs 9.20 Alice Barclay. December and January sal- ary as nurse 150.00 Allyn &amp; Bason, books 2720 Irvin Caldwell. mail carrier January 300 Irvin Caldwell. mail carrier February 300 Irvin Caldwell. mail carrier March 300 Feb. 5 Sent State Treasurer 2,038.50 Mar. 6 Sent State Treasurer 342.60 Apr. 4 Sent State Treasurer 374-53 Apr. 24 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. coal 1.085.68 E. W. White, domestic science supplies 40.79 Western Biological Supply Co., lab. sup... 10.20 The Van Evern Co , book covers 95.00 T. E. Vance, dormitory supplies 3"-45 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 87 University of Chicago Press, books 5.37 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 192-53 Chas. Scribner's Sons, books 36xn G. Schirmer, book 1.38 W. B. Saunders Co., book 25.56 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., mirrors and labora - tory supplies _ 32 64 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., books 48.06 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriter rib. 28.00 Rand McNally &amp; Co., books 17x0 Mrs. M. J. Pyles, cleaning dormitory. 10.00 The Plant World, laboratory supplies 24.40 Peru Canning &amp; Mfg. Co., ice dom. sci 5.50 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co., lumber man. training _ 106.55 R. D. Overholt, reg., books and supplies, cash adv _ _ 5.75 R. D. Overholt, reg., books and laboratory cash adv _ 2443 Nebr. School Supply House, slated cloth 12.00 National Federation of Musical Clubs, mu - sic books 5.00 Miller &amp; Paine, model school supplies 340 Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons 20049 A C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books _ 18.67 W. W. Mardis, domestic science and jan - itor's supplies 5.35 Manual Arts Press, books 6.25 The McMillan Co.. books _ 9744 1-yon &amp; Healy. music pads _ 3.33 J. B. Lippincott Co.. books _ _ 12.00 H. U. Landolt, domestic science supplies.... 56.89 Joe Kolar. domestic science supplies _ 6.88 Industrial Book &amp; Equipment Co., books.... 7.25 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 68.88 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 38.81 Helen Harman. clay modeling work. 5.00 The H. VV. Gray Co., books _ _ 15x10 The Gregg Publishing Co., books 24 59 M. E. Good, domestic science supplies 11.90 Ginn &amp; Co.. books _ 104.80 Funk &amp; Wagnalls Co., books 421 Fisher Bros., department supplies 53-33 Henry Field Seed Co., laboratory supplies 545 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 29409 186.14 .092.11 Thomas Charles Co.. model school supplies 30.02 Thomas Charles Co. mode! shool-sup 70.78 Thomas Charles Co.. laboratory supplies .... 11.80 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory supplies 75-79 J. A. Beattie. Xeb. Semi-Centen. pamphlets 10.00 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., sci. dept sup: 106.93 Barnes' Pharmacy, department supplies 5365 American Book Co.. books 4564 American Book Co.. books 4564 S. H. Avey &amp; Co., piano rent , _ 156.00 S. H. Avey &amp; Co., piano rent , _ 156.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon., books 24.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon., books 24.00 Dr. Clare B. Cornell, intelligence test cards 7.00 Dr. Clare B. Cornell, intelligence test cards 7.00 J. W Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. drum heads 8.16 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. drum heads 8.16 May 2 Sent State Treasurer # May June Sent State Treasurer June 5 Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer July 6 Sent State Treasurer July 25 Barnes' Pharmacy. Victrola records 21.25 21.2 The Gre^tf Pub. Co. tyewrtter manuals 12.00 12.00 Geo. F. Landers, band music 5.63 Geo. F. Landers, band music 5.63 H. U. Landolt. model school dotn. sci 8.68 H. U. Landolt. model school dom. sci 8.68 The Manual Arts Press, books 4.70 The Manual Arts Press, books 4.70 Nettie Meyer. 87!^ per cent tuition private voice lessons 18945 Nettie Meyer. 87!^ per cent tuition private voice lessons 189.45 A. C. McClurs &amp; Co., books _ 3.87 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books _ 3.87 R. D. Overholt, reg., cash adv., books, ac - companist, etc 17 72 companist. etc 17 Harry Porter, certical folders 10.00 lO.'.XJ Rita Thomas. 87 1-2 per cent tuition private piano lesson 14540 E. W. White, model school domestic sci. 7.21 Irvin Caldwell, carrying mail for April 3.00 Irvin Caldwell, carrying mail for May 3.00 Frederic Kuhlman, carrying mail for June 3.00 Frederic Kuhlman, carrying mail for July ... 3.00 Aug. 4 Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks 2-35 M. E. Good, dom. sci. and handwork sup 2.89 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 35.83 Fisher Bros., model school drawing and George E. Ellis, domestic science supplies 2.38 Educational Publishing Co. books E. P. Dutton &amp; Co., books 8.67 1324 Chas. H. Ditson, music 67.18 Cudahy Packing Co.. laboratory Thos. V. Crowell Co.. books David C. Cook Publishing Co, books 500 19-95 3.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 !68. 3 i 33-30 1.739-Ko 129.90 PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Cudahy Packing Co., psychology supplies 1260 Thos. Charles Co., handwork material 0.78 9.78 Thos. Charles Co., model school supplies... 12.06 W. C. Burgess, meat 1 fin 1.60 Joseph Kolar, meat 1.60 7056 I5-4O 14-93 American Book Co., textbook 13-71 John Wiley &amp; Sons, textbook 30.07 16.05 112.10 L'nderwood Typewriter Co., repairs and supplie 2073 Rita Thomas, private Silver, Burdett &amp; Co.. Jean L. Schaefer. priv Rand. McNally &amp; O&gt;. piano lessons 253.60 book 2.56 ate violin lesson 73-5O model school books 4.80 32.50 Peru Canning &amp; Mfg Co.. ice Pageant Committee, pageant book illus Pageant committee, janitor supplies R. D. Overholt, reg.. cash adv. supplies 438 43-25 26.41 and work 2913 114.70 Meek Lumber Co., lumber for man. tr. 8.56 106.10 Lyon &amp; Healy, music 4-5O Lincoln Drug Co., ointment can H. U. Landoit, laboratory sup 7.80 1 1. 01 Houghton, Mifflin &amp; Co.. books 7-15 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., book 36.59 Aug Si-p Sep Oct. Oct. Nov Xov Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer Ralph Patrick, carrying mail for Sept 3.00 .'( .? Sent State Treasurer Ralph Patrick, carry mail for October ri 300 (. Sent State Treasurer Western Stoneware Co., clay for model- 7 handwork 1565 Favor, Rohl &amp; Co., man. training supplies... 473 P. Blakiston's Sons &amp; Co., book VV. W. Barnes, supplies D. Appteton &amp; Co., textbooks E. \Y. White, supplies D. Van Nostrand Co., textbook &lt;;.n Van Evern Co., book cover Mrs. R. J. Pyles. cleaning dormitory N'ettic Meyer, private voice lessons M anii ill, ui Co, books Lincoln UniK Lo., ointment cans 2.26 Thos. K. Lewis Co., manual training sup 18.27 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. music </seg>
            <seg id="p090">Oil STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION ing 7-85 E W. White, domestic science supplies 1578 I^hn Wiley *• Sons textbooks 1720 World Book Co.. model school books 1.30 D. Knowiton &amp; Co.. model school books 1.80 The McGraw Co.. manual training supplies 569 Lyon &amp; Healy, pitch pipes 2.40 H. M. Macprang. man. training supplies... 19.17 The Macmillan Co.. textbooks tor model school _ 3° 63 Charles E. Merrill Co.. books 4-04 Jeanette Meyer, private voice lessons 153-28 Nebraska School Supply House, model school supplies 54-32 R. D. Overholt. reg.. cash adv.. postage and work 39-7° dom sci. sup. 2Q..14 R. D. Overhoit. re&lt;*.. cash adv. and work Peru Cannine &amp; Mfe. Co.. ice 4.3° The Prang Co.. books and paint 734 Public School Publishing Co.. books 1.83 Rand. Mc\ally &amp; Co.. model school books 24.96 Row. Peterson &amp; Co.. mod. school books. . 4.19 The A. Schoenhi" Co k : ndi"-T3i an ; -"n's t*° Scott. Foresman &amp; Co.. model school books 13.68 Charles Scribner's Sons, books 6.47 Arthur H. Thomas Co.. laboratory sup 16.23 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 241 04 University Publishing Co.. mod. school sup 28.91 T. E. Vance, dormitory supplies 16.35 D. Van Strand Co.. textbooks 20.16 The Cudahy Packing Co.. psychology lab. supplies _ 3.75 American Book Co., model school supplies, books 4J94 S. H. Avey &amp; Co., piano rental 130.00 C. L. Barnhouse. band music 2.88 Business English Publishing Co., textbooks , 19.20 C. V. Claus, paper hanging 11.00 Thos. Y. Crowell Co., mod. school books... 13.16 Thomas Charles Co.. mod school books... 56.15 Churchill-Grindell Co., mod. school music books _ _ _ 6.56 W. L. Davenport, milk and cream 19.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">Nov Dec. 15 Dec. 5 1918 Jan. 8 Jan. 21 &lt;n 161.31 107.82 PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL D. Donovan &amp; Son, dormitory supplies 1 17.10 Carl Fischer, band music .-. 4-51 Fisher Bros., dept. supplies 104.21 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 18.70 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 13-44 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks 46-27 H. U. Landolt, domestic sci. supplies 22.66 Little, Brown &amp; Co., mod. school books 4JS0 Ralph Patrick, carryinj Ralph Patrick, carryinj Sent State Treasurer... mail for Nov. mail for Dec. 3-oo 3.oo Sent State Treasurer Cedric Falkey. carrying mail for Jan 3.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon Co.. books 11.52 Irving G Banghart &amp; Co., drawing sup 12.38 W. W. Barnes, departmental supplies 39-75 Thomas Charles Co.. kindergarten supplies 28.29 Devoe &amp; Reynolds Co.. man. training sup 14.98 A. B. Dick Co.. dermax paoer 3.44 Eimer &amp; Amend, laboratory supplies 9.92 Fisher Br&lt;~&gt;s . departmental supplie* 18.73 fiinn &amp; Co.. textbooks 105.12 The fireojtr Publishing Co.. books 6.86 S. W. Hacker &amp; Co.. books 27.00 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 3.98 Her &amp; Co.. alcohol 3665 Troquois Pith. Co.. model school books 3.29 D. H. Know'.ton &amp; Co. model school books 4.50 H. U. Landolt. lab. and dom. sci 22 77 **// John Lane &amp; Co.. art magazine 5.00 The Macmillan Co.. books 29.04 W W. Mardis. domestic science supplies... 6.48 Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons 94.71 Nat. Lbr. Mfg Association, display racks 12.50 Nebr. School Supply House, pencils and blotters 25.55 R. D. Overholt, reg., gen. sup. cash adv 43.63 A. N Palmer Co.. model school sup 20.95 Harry Porter, ink 3.00 The Prang Co., model school supplies 8.30 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 171.82 Charles Scribner's Sorts, mod. school books 3.36 Silver, Burdett &amp; Co., books mod. school 18.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 STATE B ARD OF EDUCATION 1.499- '4 SO.OO )i.q; !O.Q7 University of Chicago Press, books 3.83 University Publishing Co., books 17-5' E. W White, domestic science supples 11.89 Feb. Feb. Feb. Mar Mar Apr. Sent State Treasurer K Sent State Treasurer i') Ctdric Farley, carrying mail Fit) 300 ( Sent State Treasurer Cedric Farley, carry mail March 3.00 8 Sent State Treasurer \V. L. Davenport, milk and cream 14-03 Cudahy Packing Co., laboratory supplies M. E. Good, laboratory supplies 10.79 H. Channon Co., man. training; iup The Century Co, textbooks 14-4° Central Scientific Co.. lab. equipment 12.00 Central Scientific Co., lab. equipment 17.07 Business English Publishing Co., textbooks 5.35 C. C Birchard &amp; Co.. music for festival 5.05 VV. W. Barnes, departmental supplies 1185 A. H. Barber Creamery Sup. Co.. lab. sup. 12.30 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 18.00 Kramer Publishing Co., textbooks 6.89 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. books 11.29 The Hill &amp; Griffith Co. man. train, sup 7.41 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 8.40 D. W. Hayes, Prin., departmental sup 3'9-78 i he Ijrc- 1 .;-' 1 i;l&gt;lisii:iu' L.O.. textbooks 4.31 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 109.77 Ginn &amp; Co, textbo&lt; Ginn &amp; Co., books Sam Fox Publishin ■ k- 13 44 "5 36 Co., band and orch. I2.8O music E. P. Dutton &amp; Co. books 11.48 J. N. Dillon, plastering at dormitory IO.OO Progressive Printery, books 9.5; Mrs. R. J. Pyles, cleaning dormitory. 2242 The Plant World, repairs 13.60 Omaha Hardwood Lbr. Co., lbr. for man. tr. 82.16 Jeannette Meyer, private voice lessons 129.25 A. R. Marsh, meat for domestic science.... 4.47 H. M Mackprang, man training supplies ... 13.97 H. U. Landolt, laboratory and domestic sci. supplies 107.82 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., textbooks 15.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 93 J. B. Lippincott Co., books 10.44 ■ ■ • ■» ww»mu ........ ..... ............. Ill .1/1 E. W. White, model school domestic sci - ence supplies _ 29.58 ence supplies _ agjg John Wiley &amp; Sons, books •. iaog jonn wiiey &amp; bons, books r. 10.69 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lbr. Co., coal 1087.02 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lbr. Co., coal 1,087.02 Western Biological Supply Co., lab. sup 4.10 Western Biological Supply Co., lab. sup Webb Publishing Co., textbooks 34.98 Webb Publishing Co., textbooks 34.98 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons „ 115.07 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 115.07 Silver. Bur.ieire &amp; Co.. model school books 13.44 Burikite &amp; I hool books 1344 Rand. McNally &amp;_Co.. books 12.00 Rand. McNally &amp;_Co.. be oks 12.00 C. A. Radmacher. tuning pianos 6.00 C. A. Radmacher. tuning pianos 6.00 Cedric Farley, carrying mail for April 3.00 May 3 Sent State Treasurer tT7ee Cedric Farley, carrying mail for April 3.00 May 3 Sent State Treasurer May 3 Sent State Treasurer May 7 Sent State Treasurer May 7 Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer 5400 May 21 Cedric Farley, carry mail for May 3.00 May 21 Cedric Farley, carry mail for May 3.00 Jun. 10 Sent State Treasurer , ._ „.„ l€ll&lt; . niiiiiin _ 924.30 Jan. 8 Sent State Treasurer (error in rec.) .04 Jan. 8 Sent State Treasurer (error in rec.) 04 June 10 Emil Asclier. music +2 , The Boston Music Co.. music for festival 5.71 June 10 Emil Asclier. music 4-23 The Boston Music Co., music for festival 5-7 1 1 h;is M. Uitson Co.. music for festival 30.4c 11 Co.. m c for festival Oliver Ditson Co.. music for festival 8.11 Oliver Ditson Co.. music for festival 8.11 The Henry Field Seed Co, seeds 2.45 The Henry Field Seed C seed 2-45 Fisher Bros., departmental supplies 4.78 Fisher Bros., department al supplies 4.78 Fritz &amp; Shier Music Co., trombone mouth- P' ece 6.1 1 Fritz &amp; Shier Music Co trombone mouth- 6.1 1 Ginn &amp; Co.. textbooks 24.96 24.06 D. W. Hayes. Prin.. cash adv. gen. sup 196.00 adv. gen. sup 196.90 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbooks rfrao D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbooks ,6.30 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbooks IO.80 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbooks IO.80 H. L l.andolt, lab. and dom. sci. sup 51.15 H. L l.andolt, lab. and dom. sci. sup 51.15 SilS I-yon &amp; Healy. music stands , 0 .8o i.yon « nealy. music stands ,0.80 E. W. White, lab. and dom. sci. sup 22.05 H. M. Mackprang. dormitory sup 24.00 E. W. White, lab. and dom. sci. sup 22.05 H. M. Mackprang. dormitory sup 24.00 24.00 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 88o The Macmillan Co., textbooks 880 The Macmillan. Co.. textbooks +54 The Macmillan. Co.. textbooks _ Nettie Meyer, voice lessons ioonn Nettie Meyer, voice lessons 100.00 Peru Canning &amp; Mig. Co.. ice for dom. sci 22.64 Mrs. R. J. Pylos. work at dormitory 17.13 L. C. Smith &amp; pewnter 32.5O Clayton F. Summy. music _ _ IO Rita Thomas, piano lessons ""« 1 iiuuids, piano lessons 14000 Underwood Typewriter Co.. repairs 8.50 The Van Evern Co., book covers 7700 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. diplomas _ 30^00 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 'J4 Chester Sandberg, dormitory mail June 3.00 July 6 Sent State Treasurer 1.795-79 July 20 Earl Church, dormitory mail. July 3.00 Aug. 2 Sent State Trejfturer 4O5S7 Aug. 14 Henry J. Green, thermometer 4.00 The Gregg Pub. Co., typewriter books 5.36 D. Appleton &amp; Co., textbooks 12.77 Irving G. Bang Art Co., are supplies 3044 W. W. Barnes, dorm., man. tr., lab. and hospital supplies _ 27.60 hospital supplies Central Scientific Co., lab. sup 3.95 Central Scientific Co., lab. sup _... Cudahy Packing Co., lab. sup 3.76 Cudahy Packing Co., lab. sup hithcf Bros., man. tr. and lab. sap hithcf Brits., man. tr. and lab. sap 22.143 Gamble Hinged Music Co.. music. "En- Gamble Hinged Music Co.. music. "En - chanted Swans." chanted Swans." 4.00 M. E. Good. lab. supplies M. E. Good. lab. supplies 4.70 F. W. Kerns, violin lessons F. W. Kerns, violin lessons 97'3 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks Houghton Mifflin Co.. textbooks 5.5 Houghton Mifflin Co.. textbooks Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks Henry Heil Chemical Co.. lab. sup Henry Heil Chemical Co.. lab. sup. D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 3.?-75 D. \V. Hayes. Prin., music, lab. and tcxth. D. W. Hayes. F'rin., nwisit. lab. and tcxth. A85 Davida Monfort. expression lessons Davida Monfort. expression lesson « .3.80 H. M. Mackpran.4 dorm and lab: supplies H. M. Mackpran.4 dorm and lab: supplies 64.20 H. L*. Landolt, domestic science supplies Mrs. E. Roselle Priel. voice lessons Mrs. E. Roselle Priel. voice lessons 85.00 Remington Typewriter Co., pads and roll - ers Remington Typewriter Co., pads and roll- ers 1C.00 Silver. Burdette &amp; Co., textbooks Silver. Burdette &amp; Co.. textbooks 24.00 The Uni. of Chicago Press, textbooks 1274 The Uni. of Chicago Press, textbooks Rita Thomas, piano lessons Rita Thomas, piano lessons 120.00 L. C. Smith &amp; Bros. Type Co., 2 mach and rental '.. L. C. Smith &amp; Bros. Type Co., 2 mach and rental .'. 190.75 Sep. 2 Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer : 164.41 VValtei Johnson, dormitory mail. Sept Sent State Treasurer Walter Johnson dormitory mail. ; ct D. Van Nostrand, textbooks Sep. 23 Waltei Johnson, dormitory mail. Sept 3.00 Oct. 3 Sent State Treasurer 1,529.40 Nov. 2 Walter Johnson dormitory mail. 1 ct 3.00 Nov. 16 D. Van Nostrand. textbooks 25.20 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., seven cars coal _ _ 711.86 Silver, Burdette &amp; Co., textbooks 10.95 Rita Thomas, tuition, private lessons 220.00 Unversity of Chicago Press, books _ 20.66 E. L. Rouse, Prin., frt. adv. for coal 57-75 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL v5 E. L. Rouse, Prin., lab. sup, work and music 31.26 Mrs. E. R. Priel, tutition private lessons.... 140.00 National Map Co., maps 6.00 Davida Monfort, tuition private lessons 3-93 A. C. McCIurg &amp; Co., textbooks 6.17 Manual Arts Press, books 7.07 .wacmillan Co. textbooks 120.92 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbooks Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbooks 9.00 H. U. Landolt, domestic sci. supplies 24.52 H. U. Landolt, domestic sci. suppli 24-52 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books Henry Holt &amp; Co., books _ 22.58 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books _. Henry Holt &amp; Co., books _ _ 2846 Gregg Publishing Co., books _.... Gregg Publishing Co books 2400 H. Herpolsheiner Co., curtain gooi H. Herpolsheiner Co. curtain goods 22.50 Ginn &amp; Co.. books Ginn &amp; Co.. book Ginn &amp; Co., book 163.02 Ginn &amp; Co., books 20.31 Fred Gilhret. woven wire Fred Gilhret, woven 300 The Cudahy Packing Co . laboratoi The Cudahy Packing Co . laboratory sup.s 7.70 upplies 4.60 D. Donovan &amp; Son. supplies D. Don nan &amp; Son. Fisher Brr.s.. supplies Fisher Brr.s.. snpplie 70.26 M. H. Blarketer. Fixing sewing niac M. H. Blarketer. l.xii sewing machines.... 14.25 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory su Central Scientific ( laboratory sup 63.06 American Book Co.. books American Book Ci books 21.98 Allyn &amp; Bacon Co., books Allyn &amp; Bacon C book 3041 Row. Peterson &amp; Co.. textbooks .... Row. Peterson &amp; C textbooks 4.22 Allyn &amp; Bacon Co.. books hooks 59.38 Rand McNally &amp; Co., textbooks Rand McNally &amp; Cc Walter Johnson, d textbooks 4.32 Nov Nov Nov. 25 Walter Johnson, dormitory mail, rmitory mail, Nov , 3.00 N'ov 16 W. W. Barnes, laboratory supplies Balance Dec. 1, 1918 340 Balance Dec. 1, 1918 5,922.40 $21,788.92 $21,788.92 SUMMARY SUMMARY INSTITUT1C Receipts INSTITUTION CASH Receipt. Total received for dormitory Total received for dormitory $ 3,694.30 Total received for domestic science laboratory _ „ _ 529.90 Total received for domestic science laborat Total received manrai training 5377° Total received physical science laboratory 232.75 Total received biolosy laboratory 433.25 Total received agriculture laboratory . 28.75 Total received textbook rental _ _ 4.459-93 Total received typewriter rental 799-95 Total received piano rental and private music 4,083.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">&lt;/&gt; STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Total received sale of property 442.67 Total rtceived extension work 285.00 Total received handwork and modeling 107.50 Total received received elocution _ _ 308.75 $18.75759 Expenditure* Total cost of textbooks $ 3238.45 Total cost water, light, fuel at dormitory Total cost dormitory furniture and repairs Total cost domestic science supplies 2.88436 1.326.39 581.00 Total cost manual training 738.70 Total cost physical icienci Total cost biology 57389 IS2OO Total cost agriculture 26.iT Total cost typewriting supplies 545.4* Total cost music fees and private music Total cost training school supplies Total cost from sale of property 3-930.ni 554- 5" 753-66 Total cost elocution 1773 Total cost extension work Total cost hospital 139-82 5O79I Total cost clay modeling and handwork 79^4 $16,050.39 LIBRARY Balance reported December 1. 1916. $ 2.446.07 1916 Dec. 6 Sent State Treasurer 20.00 Dec. 11 B. S. Anderson &amp; Co.. books Association Press, books 5.85 ■Mo 66.00 29.97 Ernest Hertzberg &amp; Sons, bind magazines A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books Moore - Cottrell Subscription Agencies, 376.40 magazines Omaha Bee. renewals. 2 copies' 8.00 The Science Press, sub. School &amp; Society G. E. Stechert &amp; Co., books 5 75 2145 Waldorf Bindery, binding books 95-.V Western Publishing &amp; Engraving Co., book The H. W. Wilson Co.. periodicals io no 3200 Edgar S. Werner &amp; Co.. book i8no </seg>
            <seg id="p097">•)7 130.00 20.00 10.00 10.00 1,350.00 50O 695.00 3.00 PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL R. D. Overholt. reg., cash adv. supplies Gayiord Bros., supplies J. D. Bishop, 2 copies Nebraska State 29.10 11.40 IOI7 Feb. May Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer The Boston Book Co., World Publishing C 7 6 4 Apr. May Apr. 4 book index ub. to World- Waldorf Bindery C&lt; Rand McNally &amp; Co G. P. Putnam's Sons. Polk-McAvoy Direct and newspaper Democrat Printing Co.. supplies Burgess-Granden Co.. brascolite Burgess-Granden Co.. brascolites Sent State Treasurer Jul. 6 Aug. Oct. Nov. Sent State Treasurer Sent State Treasurer 7 3 (1 July Baker &amp; Taylor Co.. books H. W. Wilson, agricultural index Nov. 7 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., lantern slides R. D. Overhnlt. reg.. books, papers, sup. 2O.OO 9.07 R. D. ( verholt, re library books and 3614 The New York Time The Nemaha County bound magazines .... 38.00 Herald, printing for 18.50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co The Macmiilan Co., b Library Bureau, gen. books 11.61 54O up. for library 18.85 Ernst Hertzberg &amp; Sons, binding books... 113.38 Dodd. Mead &amp; Co.. vear book 7.20 7.20 Democrat Printing Co. library notices 18.20 Journal Herald books k&lt; books ry Co., gazeteer and directory K. D. Overholt. cash adv. supplies R. D. Overholt, ren.. cash adv. majjazines Library Bureau, siijiplie flit State Treasurer Gaylord Bros., library supplies magazines library &gt;oks </seg>
            <seg id="p098">gg STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Raker &amp; Taylor Co.. library sup., books 5.34 Baker &amp; Taylor Co., reference books 546-2/ Dec. 5 Sent State Treasurer 1000 1018 Jan. 8 Sent State Treasurer 15.00 Feb. 5 Sent State Treasurer 7O.oo Apr. 8 Sent State Treasurer 10.00 Jan. 21 Dodd. Mead &amp; Co., books 18.00 (Jinn &amp; Co.. books. 2.88 Mci&lt;&gt;re-('-&gt;ttre11 Sub. Agencies, magazines. ... 404.70 McDevitt Wilson's, books 3-55 McDevitt Wilson's, books 3.55 The Omaha Bee. 2 yearly subscriptions Ron The Omaha Bee. 2 yearly subscriptions Ron R. D. Overholt. reg.. cash adv. books and papers 9.10 papers 9.10 Prof. J. E. Weaver, books 4.50 Prof. J. E. Weaver, books 4.50 The H. W Wilson Co.. library books 42.75 The H. W Wilson Co.. library books 42.75 Democrat Printing Co. library supplies 8.91 Apr. 8 Democrat Printing Co. library supplies 8.91 Waldorf Bindery Co.. binding books and magazines 20.90 The State Journal Co.. two subscriptions 12.00 Library Bureau, library cards 12.75 D. W. Hayes. Prin.. cash adv. library sup. 10.98 Wm. If. Belcher, klips 259 American Academy of Political and Social Science, books 4.25 June 10 Sent State Treasurer 10 10.00 July 6 Sent State Treasurer 1.295.00 Aug. 2 Sent State Treasurer &gt; 10.00 Ott. 3 Sent State Treasurer 610.00 June 10 D W Hayes. Prin.. cash adv., books and papers 8.67 A. C. McCiurg &amp; Co., reference books 15.21 The World Publishing Co., subscription 500 S. W. Hacker, cards 18.50 S. W. Hacker, library notices 6.00 Waldorf Bindery, reminding books 359-50 Baker Taylor Co., reference books 506.12 Nov. 18 E. L. Rouse, Prin., back number magazines 23.70 H. W. Wilson Co., index and periodicals .... 39-75 Wm. Clark Breckenridge. library books 9.75 Moore-Cottrell Subscription Agency, mag- azines 394-80 The H. R. Hunting Co., binders 31-75 The Plant World, one book 3.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 99 J. E. Richardson, Nemaha Atlas for library 10.00 Balance November 30, 1918 I,g32.6i i. 93261 $6,721.07 $6,721.07 SUMMARY LIBRARY FUND Receipts Total received for matriculations _ .$ 4^75.00 Expenditure* Total cost books and periodicals 4 4.324-84 Total cost furniture and equipment _ 210.42 Total cost supplies 100.50 Total cost printing and slides _ 62.70 $4,78846 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">lim STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' Nebraska State Normal School Wayne Wayne. Nebraska. December I, 1018. To the State Board of Education f Normal Schools Gentlemen: I am pleased to Wayne State Normal School. Thi: expenditures during the past two ye of the school for the ensuing hieni war has had a demoralizing effect 11 as the attendance. Notwithstandin senior class was the largest in the tendance was almost up to the no hrr.h the biennial report of the includes a detailed report of the ars and suggestions as to the needs him. As with other activities, the pon the work of the school as well ad last vear ?ry of the school and the at- mal Faculty w chanjjis have taken pi "r faculty. However, in the leadins and assistants who were employed nine years ago. are still rendering take this occasion to compliment departments the same professors at the opening of the school nearly splendid service. I am pleased to the members of the Wayne State Normal faculty for their fine spir -Normal faculty for their fine spirit of co-operation. They have co - operated not only with the president of the school, but they have been loyal to one another-a thin- vitally necessary to any educational in - stitution which hopes to fulfill its mission. Almost every year jinde the organization of the school one or more members of the faculty have taken a leave of absence for further study and preparation They hare returned with new ideals, greater enthusiasm, broader vision and better preparation for their work. An occasional year of absence for further preparation is always encowa«ed. Permanent Improvement During the past two years the Physical and Industrial training bu.lding has been completed and partially equipped. This building pro - vides both shower baths and plunge baths for both young men and youn- , .,„,,,.,,,,, uuiii ytjunjf men anil youn-» women. Besides a good gymnasium, it has also a large room for light calisthenics. Other departments provided for in this building are do mestic science, domestic art. industrial art. manual training, mechanical drawing. During the |&gt;ast hicnnirn </seg>
            <seg id="p101">» WAYXE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 1OI The power plant has been entirely remodeled and enlarged. The campus has been extended one-half block east, one full block The building now being used by the training school is poorly suited to the purpose. It is small, not well arranged, poorly built, and cannot he heated during severe weather. The importance of the training school demands that as soon as funds arc available a modern building should be erected for this de - partment. The cost of such a building will probably be $75,000. exclu- of furniture Rural School Another need not less in importance but less expensive it a building for a model rural school This should be erected during; the ensuing biennium. With our enlarged campus a suitable site is available for it. It should have every equipment and convenience necessary in a model rural school. The advantage of having the rural training school on the grounds, and as a part of the Normal School proper, should be apparent. Those preparing to teach in the country may thus go from their class work to the rural demonstration school and again return to their class work without inconvenience or loss of time. 11 school is now conducted in one of our large Our rura recitation rooms. The children are from nearby country districts. The patrons of these districts are eager to avail themselves of the oppor - tunity offered in the rural department of the State Normal School, and Mini from school without expense to the Campu* The enlarged campus should be platted by a competent landscape gardener, so that all work done on the grounds hereafter may be in harmony with some definite plan. Well laid out and well kept grounds are as much of an inspiration to the student as are good buildings and equipment south and our full Mock west. This extension involved title to thirty- three pieces of property. All of these titles have been secured. How- ever, title to four tract's had to he secured through condemnation and appraisal proceedings. An appeal on the appraisal has been made by the owners of two of these tracts and the matter is pending at the present time in the district court. Needed Improvements </seg>
            <seg id="p102">STATE B'.'ARD OF EDUCATION U,J Lights The lighting facilities are both unsatisfactory and expensive. Since the organization of the school, current has been purchased from the city. At the present time the expenditure for lights is nearly $2000 a year. A system of our own can be installed for not to exceed $4,000. The expense for operating it should not be over $1,000 a year But little extra fi-el would be reauired as the exhaust steam from the engine to drive the generator could all be utilized to heat the water Student Army Training Corp* The S. A. T. C. has been a w an experiment. While it has not give it a fair trial. I am inclined t ar emergency enterprise as well as been ir. operation long enough to o the opinion that military training and teacher training do not go well together. As a war measure any - thing which is of value to our country should be done, but in normal times 1 feel that some other kind for the training of soldiers. of an institution should be utilized Our unit consisted of 106 enlii who received the military training being under the required ajrc of eif of high school rank and rontribu ted men and a few additional ones but were not eligible on account of :hteen. All of these young men were ted quite materially to the general scholarship of the student body. Numerous and conflicting orders rela - tive to the work of the members of the unit served continually to dis - organize rather than to unify the effort? of all concerned. Should universal military training in our schools ever be in - augurated. I hope that the normal schools which are intended primarily for the training of teachers, may be exempted from 1 his line of in - struction. With the return of the country to normal conditions the splendid growth of the school w,hicli was interrupted by the war, may reason - ably be expected to be resumed. The growth of the institution will depend upon the continued harmonious working of the factors that have achieved the present success— co-operation of students and faculty, of the Normal Board of Education, of the people of Nebraska, and of their representatives in the legislature The noticeable and material improvements of the past eight years whereby magnificent buildings and a beautiful campus crown the Hill where the school had its feeble beginning, the large enrollment even dr.ring the war period, the in - creased confidence of the people of northeast Nebraska in the value of the instruction, all indicate what may reasonably be hoped for in the future. With pleasure in the achievements already attained, the friends of the Wayne State Normal join in asking that her future be assured in our hot %vatcr system </seg>
            <seg id="p103">by ti D&lt;. i o.i Educa in WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL ■ the continued generous support of the people, the Board of mi and the law givers, that has thus far been accorded her. Respectfully submitted U. S. CONN, Preside ATTENDANCE RECORD Enrollment Graduates '9io-11 539 3 1911-12 662 -M "912-13 737 33 1913-14 '. 701 A* 1914-15 790 51 1915-16 925 6j •916-17 g 37 74 IQI7-18 821 75 APPROPRIATION FUND Maintenance State Normal School at Wayne Balance December I, 1916 Transferred from General Fund $23,608.43 2.108.35 1916 re. it Payrnl! for December 4.450.00 J. J. Ahem, supplies 4-47 Auto- Vac Duster Co.. janitor supplies 950 Boyd Hotel expenses. Grand Lodge officer 6.5(1 Carpenter Paper Co.. toilet paper 25.00 Carhart Limber Co.. hardware 39-7' U. S. Conn, cash advanced 99'5 U. S. Conn, advanced for frt. and exp 83.09 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 3283 U. S. Conn, extension work 125.00 L T . S. Conn, advanced for sundries 20.76 H. B. Craven, hardware 45°o Curtis Sash and Door Co.. storm windows 180.00 torm window A. Flanagan Co.. rubber mat'ing, etc 112 62 Fulton Mfg. Co.. service wagon 8.00 Gasoline Supply Company, gasoline 1312 Grand Rapids School Equipment Co., bench 21.00 A. E. Hering, labor on grounds 12.75 Harry Masten. hauling coal 253.38 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 1542 Metropolitan Supply Co.. blackboard 35-70 </seg>
            <seg id="p104">1O4 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' Neva Milner, services as pianist National Wood Works, lumber Nebraska Democrat, printing Nebraska Teacher, advertising 14.40 227.65 32.00 75° Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental and toll Harry Porter, mimeograph supplies Rand. McNally &amp; Co.. globe and maps .... W. D. Redmond, office expenses 22.45 14.10 21.40 expens 162; Roberts Drug Co.. laboratory sup Ralph Rundell. janitor supplies .115 17.00 Standard Oil Co.. oil 338 E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co.. domestic sci. equip Standard Oil Co . supplies 88.35 fifus Wayne Herald, printin 21.2, Wayne Herald, printing bulletin 75«&gt; Wayne Roller Mills, City of Wayne, light. W. M. Welch life ( West Disinfecting Co Whitebrcast Coal Co Whitebreast Coal Cc boiler compound water and power 6.20 2Q8.8o . diploma supplies 2928 6i.oo Cnal , coal 1.7 1 2.92 2.021 13 1917 Jan. 15 C. A. Chance &amp; Co . lumber U".2K 40.67 U. S. Conn, advanced for frt. and exp. U. S. Conn, advanced for postage Crane Company, heating supplies ....... Gasoline Supply Company, machin? gas A E. Hering. labor on grounds 54-84 113 79 3630 1425 W. H. Hoguewood. drayage I. T. House, extension work 25.80 25.00 E. J. Huntemer. exp. for heating plant. ... Jones' Book Store department supplies Harry Masten. hauling coal 2d.8« 65 95 14-45 J. G. Mines, clock and repair 4-75 Nebr. Telephone Company, rental and toll Omaha Paint &amp; Glass Co.. paint and oil .... Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass '3-75 68.85 43-35 Harry Porter, examination paper Standard Oil Company, gasoline 32 5O 1125 Thordarson Electric Mfg. Co.. transformer U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 2300 30.72 Jan. 23 Feb. 27 Mar. 29 Payroll for January . Payroll for February Payroll for March 4.427 50 4.52500 3.40000 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">Apr. 24 105 $122,108.45 WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Thomas Charles Co., supplies 14-15 U. S. Conn. adv. for frt. and exp 105.38 J. J. Ahern. janitor supplies 31.61 Thomas Charles Co., kindergarten sup 78.27 Clarke's Garage, repairs _ 4.20 tlaflin Printing Company, summer bulletin 186.00 Central Meat Market, meat for domestic science 20.30 Central Meat Market, meat for domestic science 20.30 Crane Company, heating supplies 211.55 Crane Company, heating supplies 211.55 H. B. Craven, hardware 64-55 H. B. Craven, hardware 64.55 C. A. Chace &amp; Company, lumber, sand, etc 130.72 Carhart Lumber Company, hardware 72.50 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 7337 U. S. Conn, advanced for postage 5784 C. E. Conger, drayage 20.85 Central Scientific Company, lab. supplies... 159.06 s ■-- rf- «-« - +1 * Wm. H. Duck Company, electric supplies ... 12.85 Felber's Pharmacy, glue 3.75 Frank Gaertner. piano rent, etc 126.55 Gasoline Supply Company, oil 80.58 H. H. Hahn, extension work 35O0 A. E. Hering. labor on grounds 24.88 W. H. Hoguewood, drayage 28.45 J. T. House, extension work 45-0O Tier &amp; Company, alcohol 16.51 Kearney Daily Hub, Catalogue envelopes... 50.00 J. G W. Lewis, extension work 30.00 Midland Glass &amp; Paint Co.. supplies 48.47 Harry Masten. labor on grounds 15-75 Nebraska School Supply House, chairs 141.60 Nebraska School Supply House crayon 7.00 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 Orr &amp; Orr, domestic science supplies 14459 Harry Porter, mimeograph supplies 11.75 Roberts Drug Company, supplies '5-30 Roe's Ideal Grocery, supplies 3.60 Standard Oil Company, gasoline 3612 G. H. Thompson, hauling coal 87.03 Thiele-Scarf Company, supplies 3.00 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., floor paint 24.75 Balance March 31, 1017 .74 $122,108.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 July 25 Aug. 8 $150,000.00 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION MAINTENANCE Appropriation biennium be 1917, to April 1, 1919 Payroll for April Payroll for May Payroll for June Payroll for July +52500 4.50417 4.940.00 4.872.50 Alice Banks, services as anist 13.00 ldenrod 100.00 8.55 30.00 I4-3O U. S. Conn, traveling ex^ U. S. Conn, advanced for freight, e L". S. Conn, advanced foi U. S. Conn, advanced for U. S. Conn, advanced for L*. S. Conn, advanced for Crescent Machine Co, re ndrie school annual menciMiient labor mir? L A. Fanske. regula clock H. H. Hahn. extension work Blanche Heath, pianist for phys trainin A E. Herini;. labor 3o.oo Jones' Bookstore, office and dept. supplie Nebr. Telephone Co.. rental and message University Publishing Co.. language les 3.1&lt;X» sons. etc. 26.02 City of Wayne, light service and water power 248.52 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries U. S. Conn, advanced for postage, etc 28.28 *2-9i 6435 J. J. Ahern, domestic science supplies Baker Bros. Engraving Co. .halftones J. A. Bcattie, bookiets 77.20 12.58 400 Carpenter Paper Co., toilet paper H. J. Chaulkins &amp; Co., repairs for kiln C. A. Chase &amp; Co., lime, lbr. and cement Thomas Charles Co, art supplies U. S. Conn, advanced for lecture 28-75 19.81 328.20 62.09 2&gt; .«) ginning April I, Alice Banks, services as p I. H. Brittell. Treasurer. C Central Scientific Co.. laboratory supplies J. J. Coleman. extension work C. E. Conger, drayage !5.0O 16.20 56.43 1825 W. H. Hoguewood. drayage J T. House, extension work 44-O5 A. H. Abbott &amp; Co.. art supplies 5-&lt;&gt;2 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL in; L'. S. Conn, advanced for frt., exp., etc 73-6o H. B. Craven, hardware '53-7O C. M Craven, photographic views _ 21.50 Devoe &amp; Reynolds, art supplies 10.43 J. H. Foster, carpenter work 14.00 Gasoline Supply Co., gasc aioline Supply Co.. gas ohne 37.40 ne 37.40 A. E. Hering. labor A. E. Herine. labor ; 116.55 116.55 \\ . H. Hoguewood, dray \\ . H. Hoguewood, dra yage 27.50 age 27.50 ■1 Jones' Bookstore, general Jones' Bookstore, general supplies 11860 supplies 11860 Lyon &amp; Healy. band instri i.yon &amp; Healy. band instr uments _... 71.90 uments _... 71.90 The Mcfjraw Company, el The Mcfjraw Company, e lectric supplies 42.10 ectric supplies 42.10 The McGraw Company, el lectric supplies 31-9* ectric supplies 31-92 Middle-West School Revi' iew. advertising.... 10.50 ew. advertising.... 10.50 ev Midland Glass and Paint varnish, etc' Midland Glass and Pain varnish, etc' : Company, glass, 8o-43 19.80 Company, glass. Neva Milnir, pianist 19.80 National Wood Works, hi training National Wood Works. 1 imbrr for manual _ _ 88.00 imbrr for manual training 88.00 Nebraska Democrat, office Nebraska Democrat, offic e records 164.00 House, atlases 14-57 ecords 164.00 Nebraska Sihool Supply ] House, atlases '4-57 Tlie N'i-i&gt;raska Tcachtr, ai dvert'sing 5.00 rental 14.00 ing 5.00 Nebraska Telephone Co.. ntal 14.90 re- Orr Si Orr Company, dom Orr Si Orr Company, dom lestir science sup. 45.23 tic science sup. 45.23 Roberts Drug Co.. Alaba&gt; Roberts Druy: Co.. Alabr :Stine. etc 9.40 tine, etc 9.40 Row. Peterson &amp; Compnj y. readers 22.50 readers 22.50 Sargeant &amp; Company, doi Sargeam S: Company, d &gt;or checks 7.87 ir cherks 7.87 C. J. Shea Roofing Co., gi C. J. Shea Roofing C rravel, roof, etc 314.38 ravel, roof, etc 314.38 Sioux City Stationery Cor paper Sioux City Stationery C mpany. blue print mpany. blue print 700 700 Sunderland Machinery C&lt; mixer 'ompany. superior 76.00 Simderland Machinery C ompany, superior 76.00 mix( U. S. Rubber Co., hose, sp U. S. Rubber Co.. h r&gt;rinkler, etc 28.20 etc 28.20 John Van Range Co.. grate, plates, etc 10.85 Wayne Herald, printing _ 7185 City of Wayne, light service and water power 106.56 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., laboratory sup 73.85 West Disinfecting Co.. janitor supplies 65.75 \lice Wills, pianist _ 9.60 Aug. 28 Payroll for August _ 1,145.00 Oct. 3 Payroll for September 4,715.00 Oct. 2&lt;J Payroll for October 4,715.00 Nov. 9 J. J. Ahern, supplies _ 17.20 American Hook Co.. dictionaries, etc „ 16.36 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">rat STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION' American Federation of Art. art exhibit 5.00 Carpenter Paper Co., toilet paper 3900 Claflin Printing Co. printing bulletin '58.54 Clarke's Garage, repairs 4.55 C. E. Conger, drayage 1505 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 34-82 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries _ 12.83 U. S. Conn, advanced for freight and exp. 96.36 L'. S. Conn, advanced for postage and .drayage _ 90.61 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor U. S. Conn, advanced for sundrie 10.13 32.02 U. S. Conn, advanced for frt.. exp.. etc 16360 Felber's Pharmacy, supplies 8.25 Gasoline Supply Company, gasoline 9570 Gasoline Supply Co.. gasoline 5.56 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 19.19 H. H. Hahn. dean, traveling expenses 1893 Hawk-Eye Compound Co., compound ' 27.00 VV. A. Hiscox, supplies 6.30 W. H. Hoguewood, drayage. delivering coal 232.25 Houghton. Mifflin &amp; Co.. arithmetics 5.76 Huse Publishing Co.. advertising _... 20 16 Otto Ingwerson, carpenter work 38.40 Jones' Book Store, supplies _ _... 17.52 J. G. W. Lewis, extension work 38.15 The McGraw Company, electric sup 41.30 The Macmillan Company, books _„ 6.62 Mutual Film Corporation, repairs for pict - ure machine _ _ 7.90 Nebraska Democrat, cards, stationery 1725 Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental and toll 3655 Nebraska School Supply House Moulthrop seats _ 222.65 Nebraska School Supply House, office sup. 30.70 A. C. Norton, painting _ 128.13 Omaha Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 21.00 Harry Porter, supplies _ 47.26 The Prang Co., art supplies _ 5 60 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., readers 7.24 Walter Savidge, motion picture machine... 150.00 Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., readers 10.56 Sioux City Journal, advertising _ 17.64 Sioux City Tribune, advertising _ 20.5&amp; </seg>
            <seg id="p109">IOQ WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Standard Oil Co., oil and gasoline 56.91 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 30.02 University Publishing Co., readers, etc 12.46 John Van Range Co., repairs 4.58 Ward's Natural Science Estab., lab. sup 74- ( &gt;&gt; Wayne Herald, printing 3970 Wayne Herald, advertising, printing 6.40 Wayne Herald, advertising, printing City of Wayne, electric light service and City of Wayne, electric light service and water power 167.92 water power 167.92 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co. supplies 142.03 W r . M. Welch Mfg. Co, supplies 142.03 Whitebreast Coal Co.. coal 27103 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 271.03 Whitehreast Coal Co.. coal 771.03 Whitebreast Coal Co.. coal 771.03 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., microscopes.!.. 118.80 N'ov. 24 Payroll for November 4,740.00 Dec. 18 Payroll for December 4.74500 1918 1918 Jan. 26 Lester Beckner. salary as fireman 101.75 Jan. 26 Lester Beckner. salary as fireman 101.75 I arhart Hardware Co., hardware'. 7.07 Carhart Hardware Co., hardware' 7.07 Central Scientific Co. laboratory sup 107.30 Central Scientific Co. laboratory sup 107.30 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lumber, sand, cement 28742 Thomas Charles Co.. department sup 22.54 Thomas Charles Co.. department sup 22.54 Clark's jarage. repairs 14.60 Clark's jarage. repairs 14.60 L". S. Ci&gt;nn. cash adv. for frt.. etc 687.49 L". S. Cirnn. cash adv. for frt., etc 687.49 I" S. Q/nn. casli advanced tor labor 68.47 I" S. Own. casli advanced for labor 68.47 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 25.28 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 25.2B L'. S. Conn, cash advanced for postage and drayage 95-75 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for postage and drayage 95-75 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 35.24 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 35-24 Consolidated Coal Co.. coal 37763 Consolidated Coal Co., coal 377-63 H. B. Craven, hardware 177.65 H. B. Craven, hardware 177.65 H. B. Craven, equipment, supplies 114.50 H. B. Craven, equipment, supplies 114.50 E. C. Drew &amp; Son. drayage 12.00 12.00 Emerson Planing Mill, sawdust 10.00 Emerson Planing Mill, sawdi'st 10.00 Claudius Evans, labor 11.69 Claudius Evans, labor 11.69 B. S. Fleming, grading _ 110.30 no.30 B. S. Fleming, hauling coal on contract 444-88 B. S. Fleming, hauling coal on contract 444-88 Great Eastern Chemical Co., supplies _ 38.86 Great Eastern Chemical Co., supplies _ 38.86 Herald Printing Co., letter heads 29.25 Herald Printing Co., letter heads 2925 W. H. Hoguewood. drayage 56.00 W. H. Hoguewood. drayage 56.00 Hunt-Holm-Ferris &amp; Co., electric supplies 142.38 Imperial Brush Co., janitor supplies 5600 Imperial Brush Co., janitor supplies 5600 Otto Ingwerson, carpenter work 70.00 Otto Ingwerson, carpenter work 70.00 Joesting &amp; Schilling, repair of steam cook - ers 12.70 32.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p110">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION no Jones' Book Store, department supplies 58-45 J. G. W. Lewis, expense for extension work 15.00 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 45-22 Morgan's Toggery, athletic supplies 58.00 Nebraska Democrat, printed blanks 7.00 The Nebraska .School Supply House, paper 28.20 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising _ 250 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental and toll.... 35-95 A. C. Norton, painting 174.80 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 221.54 Frank Powers, drayage _ _ 26.50 The Prang Co., art supplies _ 13-79 Ralph Rundell. janitor supplies 22.50 Standard Oil Co., oil _ 16.01 Sunderland Bros, repair work 70.30 John Van Range Co.. repair of range 33-K3 J. H. Wright, hauling boiler 7500 City of Wayne, light and water poyer 255.18 Whitebreast- Coal Co.. coal 2.039.4(1 Earl E. Bruce, labor 18.45 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., fire brick 313 30 Crane Co., heater 1.0R2.80 Crane Co.. heating supplies 4"999 Alex Holtz. bricking furnace _ 204.50 E. J. Huntcnur. labor 201.7; Keenan Structural Slate Co.', equipment.... 1.600.00 A C. Norton, painting 135.00 Sunderland Machinery Co.. pump 1. 120.00 The Korsmeyer Co.. lighting fixtures 400.50 Farwell. Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co.. yquipment 13314 J. A. Fay &amp; Egan Co., equipment 644.60 Fred Medart Mfg. Co.. equipment.. 681.27 Nebraska School Supply House, slate 8392 E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co.. equipment 340.98 January payroll 4.85350 Feb. 26 February payroll 4,765.00 Mar. 23 March payroll _ 4.747.50 Apr. 12 J. J. Ahern, domestic science supplies 52.38 Baker Bros. Engraving Co., cuts 9.18 I. H. Brittell. expenses, extension work 18.26 Budget Committee, Goldenrod 100.00 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for labor 1391 U. S. Conn, cash adv. miscellaneous 20.25 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for postage, etc. 92.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL in U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 156.70 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for frt., etc „ 294-83 Carhart Lumber Co., repairs 5.60 I he Carpenter Paper Co.. paper 36.25 Thomas Charles Co., art supplies 14.72 Thomas Charles Co., art supplies .t 17.6a Clark's Garage, repairs 3.75 Crane Heating Co., heating supplies 76.97 Crane Heating Co.. heating supplies 145-42 Crane Co., fixtures _... 485.53 C. M. Craven, photographs _ 4.00 H. B. Craven, range 67.10 H. B. Craven, hardware "5-25 Farwell. Ozum. Kirk &amp; Co 6.03 Farwell. Ozmun. Kirk &amp; Co.. supplies 16.79 L. A. Fanske. timing watch 8.50 J. A. Fay &amp; Egan Co.. equipment 410.90 A. Flanagan &amp; Co.. art supplies 3.38 B. S. Fleming, hauling coal 12088 Garlock Packing Co., supplies 18.09 (■rand Kapids Equipment Co.. cqilpiment. ... 369.OO A. G. Grunemeyer, plumbing supplies '3-75 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co., mats 20.60 W. H. Hn£iirwnod. drayage 9.00 J. T. House, expenses extension work 20.00 Otto Ingwerson, carpenter work 72.00 Jones' Br&gt;rk Store, department supplies 36.50 Earl Lewis, plumbing 49.05 Marsi'ine Lewis, pianist 8.60 The McGraw Co., electric lamps 69.36 Metropolitan Supply Co., supplies- 104.63 Middle-West School Review, advertising .... 10.50 National Refining Co., oil 10.54 Nebraska Democrat, envelopes, blank 0.75 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 Nebraska Telephone Cp., rental and toll.... 29.30 N. O. Nelson Mfg Co.. plumbing supplies.... 172.13 A. C. Norton, painting 335.87 Office Equipment Supply Co., envelopes 31.75 Philleo &amp; Harrington Lumber Co., sup 2.35 Harry Porter, office supplies „ '33-01 Frank Powers, drayage _ i?-45 Taylor-Holden Co.. drawing paper 5.63 A. V. Teed, expenses, extension work _ 40.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION llj S. R. Thebald &amp; Co.. supplies 19.07 University Publishing; Co.. records 7.33 City of Wayne, light and wa'er power 341-3O Wayne Herald, printing 23.00 Wayne Herald, printed blanks 720 Whitebreast C6al Co. coal 910.36 Apr April payroll _ 4735-O0 May 23 June 16 May payroll 4.697.70 American Book Company, readers 1536 American Printing Co. offi-e supp!ies 185.50 Baker Bros. Engraving Cjq.. halftone Carpenter Paper Co.. paprr 4.(11 43-51 Thomas Charles Co.. art supplies 76.16 James B. Clow S: Sons p!nmhing supplies 0.36 U. S. Crtnn. traveling expense 1504 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for frt.. etc. 5806 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for v sundries V. S. Conn, c^sh ad-- for comml^Tnem U. S. Conn, cash advanced fo^^postage 6402 in .so dravagf QO.12 Devoe it Raynolds. v arf supplies Fortner's Feed Mill, grass seed Freeport Gas Machine Co.. fixtures Frank Gaertner. funiture i8.i7 17.6s «8 154-fo Gasoline Supply Co.. gasoline W. H. Hoguewood. drayage J. T. House extension work Marsaline I ewis. pianist Ramona McElroy. pianist The McGraw Co.. electric supplies Metropolitain Supply Co.. transformer J. G. Mines, repair work on clock The Nebraska Teacher, advertising The Nebraska Democrat, printing The Nebraska Democrat, commencement 104.84 26.35 33.&lt;» I7-2O 1 6.oo 42-98 27-5° 5.00 500 1675 28.50 programs Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental and toll. Northwestern School of Taxidermy, clay Pennsylvania Salt Mfg. Co.. alum 2375 10.25 12.25 The Prang Co., art supplies ... Standard Oil Co., gasoline ... The Wayne Herald, printing 20.98 24-93 33 34 City of Wayne, light and water power W. M. Welch, Mfg. Co., rural certificates 35io6 3030 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">IIJS WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., laboratory supplies 125-54 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co. certificates 505.00 505.00 Charles M. Reynolds, registering deeds 29.85 York Blank Book Co.. bulletin 170.74 June 26 June payroll 4.91750 July 19 July payroll 4.93O.0O 6 Carhart Lumber Co.. hardware 31.82 Carpenter Paper Co., i&gt;aper towels 9.00 9.00 C. A. Chase &amp; Co., lumber and supplies 115.J4 C. A. Chase &amp; Co., lumber and supplies 115.J4 Thomas Charles Co., industrial art supplies 72.32 Thomas Charles Co., industrial art supplies 72.32 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 15.57 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 15-57 U. S. Conn, traveling expense 17.90 U. S. Conn, traveling expense 17.90 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for frt.. etc 41.61 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for frt., etc 41.61 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for postage, etc. 47.05 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for postage, etc. 47.05 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 188.23 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 188.23 H. B. Craven, hardware 30.65 H. B. Craven, hardware 3065 Crescent Paint &amp; Mfg. Co., paint 42-35 Crescent Paint &amp; Mfg. Co.. paint 42-35 Farwell, Ozum, Kirk &amp; Co., mower 18.60 Farwell. Ozum, Kirk &amp; Co., mower 18.60 H. H. Hahn, extension work 30.00 H. H. Hahn, extension work 30.00 W. H. Hoguewood. drayage . 5.40 Jones' Book Store, art supplies 3233 Jones' Book Store, art supplies 3233 The Nebraska Democrat, printing 12.00 12.00 The Nebraska Teacher, advertisin 2.50 Nebraska Telephone Co., rentals and tolls 15.75 Norfolk Daily News, advertising 10.08 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 14-55 S. R. Theobald, material for pageant 4.14 The Tribune Co., advertising 14-70 Fred W. Walz, abstracts 14-50 City of Wayne, light and water power 124.16 Minnie Will, pianist 8.60 Aug. 26 August payroll _ _ 1,255.00 Oct. I September payroll 4,882.50 Oct. 26 October payroll 4,895.00 Nov. 18 J. J. Ahem, janitor supplies 28.28 Bee Publishing Co.. advertising 13.80 Carhart Lumber Co., hardware and electric supplies , 22.73 Carpenter Paper Co., soap _ _ 22.50 Thomas Charles Co., art supplies 7.74 U. S. Conn, traveling expense 6029 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 109.12 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for frt., etc 1,867.60 Crane Co., plumbing supplies 22.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p114">$150,000.00 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION H4 Farwcli. Ozmim. Ki^k &amp; Co. copinfj saws . 12 41 B. S. Fleming hading coal on contract 53743 B. S. Fleming hai'ling coal on contract 53743 Oarlock Packing Co.. plumbing supplies 33-8S Oarlock Packing Co.. plumbing supplies 33-8? Gasoline Supply Co.. gasoline 100.58 Gasoline Supply Co.. gasoline ino.58 General Electric Co.. electric equipment I.oio 1.1 \V H. Hoguewood. drayage 1125 J. T. House, extension and institute expx 69.59 Huse Publishing Co.. advertises _ 13.44 Huse Publishing Co.. advertises _ 13.44 Huse Publishing Co.. advertising ..'. 36.06 Huse Publishing Co.. advertising ..! 36.96 W. H. Lerch. charts 22.00 W. H. Lerch. charts 22.00 J. G W. Lewis, institute expense 20.14 J. G W. Lewis, institute expense 20.14 The McGraw Co.. electric equipment 27.47 The McGraw Co.. electric equipment 27.47 The Mcraw Co.. electrvc equipment 71-33 The Mcraw Co.. electric equipment 71-33 Nebraska School Sup. Housp. equipment 136.00 \ebraska School Sup. House, equipment.... 2^)9.40 Nebraska Telephone Co.. renta! and tolls 48.30 J. R Rundeil. janitor supplies 32.00 Sioux City Journal, advertising 19.60 Standard C\\ Co.. gasoline 37-17 United Theatre Equipment Corporation repairs 12.08 Uni. of Chicago Pre University Publishin; John Van Range Co., City of Wayne, light . phonetic cards 11.88 Co.. class records ... 10.37 repair of range 26.05 and water power 382.22 The Wayne Herald, printing 19.-0 W. If. Welch Mfg. Co Whitebreast Coal &amp; L York Blank Book Co.. filing cabinet 27.00 umber Co.. coal catalogs 246.00 246.00 Nov. 25 November payroll _ 4,955.00 Balance November 30. 1918 23.648.43 $150,000.00 INSTITUTION CASH FUND December I, 1916, balance on hand _ _ _ _ _..^ 2,686.15 Total amount remitted to State Treasurer from December I, 1916. to December I, 1918 _ 17.052.70 1916 Dec. 18 Payroll for December 5900 Model Pharmacy, 500 Murestco 37 50 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 12.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">101 US WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 186.43 U. S. Conn, refund to students 34-65 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 6.39 American Book Co., textbooks 15.31 Ginn &amp; Co.. textbooks 11.34 Greg;? Publishing Co., textbooks 6.49 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 1734 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbooks 16.64 Lea &amp; Febiger. textbooks 28.68 Rand. McNally &amp; Co., textbooks 6.72 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., textbooks 8.33 Sioux City Iron Co., steel _ 36.67 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co, paint, etc 29-04 Central Meat Market, meat for dom. sci 7.80 Ralph Rundell. supplies for dom. science... 35-34 Earl H. Fife, song books 8.16 Earl H. Fife, song books 8.16 Mrs. A. Sherhahn. laundry work 5.30 Mrs. A. Sherhahn. laundry work 5.30 I. P. Lowry. tuning pianos 1000 mm J. W. York &amp; Sons, drum 14.25 J. W. York &amp; Sons, drum 14J5 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriter 40.00 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriter 40.00 Goodyear- Marshall Publishing Co., texts 8.78 Goodyear- Marshall Publishing Co., texts 8.78 Jan. 17 Curtis Sash &amp; Door Co., storm sash 59.20 Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental 6.00 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass 25.15 City of Wayne, light and water power 140.70 A. N. Palmer Co., textbooks 12.00 The Macmillan Company, textbooks 10.58 Geo. F. Rosche &amp; Company, textbooks 7.51 Carl Fischer Music House, textbooks 9.75 Central Scientific Co., supplies 6230 Central Scientific Co., supplies 22.01 Jan. 23 Payroll for January 72.20 Feb. 24 Payroll for February _ 67.80 Mar. 29 Payroll for March 1. 199.40 Apr. 24 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 42.35 American Book Company, textbooks 11.40 D. Appleton &amp; Co.. textbooks 23.31 B. Blakiston's Son &amp; Company, textbooks 28.80 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks : 4184 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbooks 3.54 Hinds, Hayden &amp; Eldridge, textbooks 16.56 Houghton. Mifflin &amp; Co., textbooks 22.61 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 1 IK. Little Brown &amp; Company, textbooks 7.20 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 163.65 Charles E. Merrill Company, textbooks 24.00 U. S. Conn, cash refunds to students 45-85 VVhitebreast Coal Company, coal _ 76964 A. N. Palmer Co., Palmer Methods 7-3** Apr Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., textbooks 86.40 M A. Flanagan Company, textbooks _ 4-07 Carpenter Paper Co., supplies 35-25 City of Wayne, light and water power 435 44 Theo. Presser Co., music books _ 47-25 Theo. Presser Co., textbooks 9.83 Taylor-Holden Co., drawing paper 10.03 Xeilen &amp; Henderson, letter corner stone... 27.00 W. A. Jones Machine Co., brass bushings.... 700 J. W. York &amp; Sons, band instruments _. 77-85 Russell &amp; Irwin Mfg. Co., keys 29.82 Platt Iron Works, supplies 8.85 Nebraska Telephone Co.. services 33 75 Metropolitan Supply Co., blackboard 51.00 The McGraw Company .electric supplies... 08.02 National Wood Works, lumber 64.00 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co.. textbooks 17.01 A. M. Helt, galvanized pipe - 15.00 Willis Music Company, music supplies 2836 Joesting &amp; Schilling Company, kettle 80.00 July payroll for April 65.OO -■5 Payroll for May 5600 Payroll for June 58.00 Payroll for July - 66.00 J. C. Nuss, brooms, paint 29,40 John Van Range Company, stove repairs 4.52 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., textbooks 21.44 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. sets Co., bookkeeping 8.91 Nebraska Telephone Company, rental 12.00 Mrs. Mary Meyer, services as nurse 20.00 Frank Gaertner, furniture 55-25 H. B. Craven, pictures hinges, etc 30.15 Henry Worthington, heating supplies 34 36 U. S. Conn, advanced' for sundries 4207 U. S. Conn, refunds to students _ 19-90 John W. Evans, tuning pianos 10.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 13.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL C. Penn, cleaning and repairing halls 17.50 Aug. 8 U. S. Conn, refunds to students 19.50 R. B. Judson Company, mattresses 14.25 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 7.50 J. C. Nuss, brooms _ 42.00 Central Meat Market, supplies for dom. sci. 17.15 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 6.48 University of Chicago Press, textbooks 11.19 Henry Holt &amp; Company, textbooks 50.10 Sturgis &amp; Walton Co., textbooks 43.20 Ward's Nat. Sci. Estab.. lab. sup I5-5O Frank Gaertner, furniture, piano rental.... 225.35 Oct 3 Payroll for September _ 5200 Oct. 29 Payroll for October 56.00 Nov. 9 Emma Hart, cleaning halls, etc 0.00 Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental 9.80 A. C. Norton, painting and kalsomining... 264.03 C. Penn, labor 104.00 U. S. Conn, refunds to students _ 34.20 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 6.00 Ginn &amp; Company .textbooks 15.71 Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks 12.35 Henry Holt &amp; Company, textbooks 406 Macmillan Company, textbooks 16.80 Charles E. Merrill Co., textbooks 12.00 Rand, McNally &amp; Company, textbooks .... 6.00 Rand, McNally &amp; Co., textbooks 10.32 Silver, Burdett &amp; Company, textbooks 10.80 Scott, Foresman &amp; Company, textbooks 7.20 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory supplies 10.84 University of Nebraska, lab. supplies 4.20 Wm. H. Anderson, ice for domestic science 7.50 J. J. Ahem, supplies for domestic science 4964 Mrs. Mary Philbin, laundry work for do- mestic science ~ 11.25 J. J. Randall, janitor supplies, etc 8279 J. Fischer &amp; Brother, music 7.20 Willis Music Company, music 6.51 Nov. 26 Payroll for November 66.00 1917 Dec. 18 December payroll 53.00 1918 Jan. 26 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 18.00 J. C. Nuss, dormitory supplies _ 4385 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">IIX STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION" Western Glass &amp; Paint Co.. supplies 80.58 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co.. supplies 90.25 Western Glass and Paint Co.. supplies 65.77 Whitebreast Coal Co. coal _ _ 1,800.05 U. S. Conn, cash refunds to students &gt;7-3o American Book Company textbooks 22.43 (jinn &amp; Co., textbooks _ 34-1*3 Gregg Publishing Co.. textbooks 8.04 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbooks _ 9.33 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 32.40 The Macmillan Co, textbooks '. _... 20.96 Charles Scribner's Sons, textbooks 28.00 Silver, Burdett &amp; Co.. textbooks 1205 Ward's Science Estab. J. Fischer &amp; Brother. January payroll laboratory supplies music books 347 '«;.«&gt; Feb. Mar Apr. February payroll March payroll Consolidated Coal C Mrs. George Denkin Nebraska Telephone *&gt; 635O 13 rs 72.OO coal 1-11*4 ;er. washing blankets Co., rental 10.50 18.00 City of Wayne, electric light service 24308 U. S. Conn, cash refunds 13-35 American Book Company, textbooks American Book Company, textbooks 4-77 u.52 20.68 D. Appleton &amp; Co.. textbooks Ginn &amp; Co.. textbooks J9.il Gregs? Publishing Company, textbooks Henry Holt &amp; Co.. textbooks The Macmillan Co.. textbooks Webb Publishing Company, textbooks National Wood works, lumber 24-78 48.40 960 45-50 9.60 Apr. National Wood Works, lumber for man - ual training 15 I22.6O J. J. Ahern, domestic science supplies 95.82 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries Orr &amp; Orr Company, supplies 10.55 3i8 Remington Typewriter Co., repair of ma - chines Chicago Music Supply Company, sheet mu 12.60 sic Willis Music Company, music — 4.95 Russell &amp; Erwin Mfg. Co., keys 12.92 Apr. 25 April payroll _ _ _ 70.75 &lt;&gt;&gt;'. </seg>
            <seg id="p119">May 23 June 16 June 26 July 19 Aug. 6 119 WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL May payroll 64.00 U. S. Conn, cash refunds to students 1560 Frank Gaertner. furniture 187.30 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co., janitor supplies .... 9305 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 12.00 A. C. Norton, painting 173-25 Western Glass &amp; Paint Company, calcimo 24.33 (linn &amp; Co., textbooks 1392 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 1392 J. J. Ahern. domestic science supplies 38.97 J. J. Ahern. domestic science supplies 28-97 Central Meat Market, domestic sci. sup. 12.83 Central Meat Market, domestic sci. sup. 12.83 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory supplies 26.23 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory supplies 26.23 Ward M. Randol. laboratory specimens... 32.00 F. H. Vail, repairing and tuning pianos 5250 Fritz Dankinger. labor 112.00 Gregg Publishing Co.. textbooks 15.15 B. S. Fleming labor 211.90 Cliff Penn. labor 16.50 June payroll 79.38 July payroll : 74 So U. S. Conn, refunds to students 17.50 C. A. Chace &amp; Company, dormitory sup 76.IO H. B. Craven, dormitory supplies 35-8o Mrs. George Denginger. laundering 12.60 Felber's Pharmacy, supplies 9.10 Webb Publishing Co.. textbooks 12.58 U. S. Conn, cash advanced 14.25 National Wood Works, lumber 112.50 Fritz Denkinger. labor 62.40 B S. Fleming, labor 215.28 C. W. Hiscox. mower _ 85.00 Oct. 1 September payroll „ 65.00 Oct. 26 October payroll 65.00 Nov. 18 U. S. Conn, cash refunds to students 35-45 Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental 12.90 Nebraska Telephone Co., connection 25.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 463.65 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 551.27 J. C. Nuss. wall paper Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental 6.24 6.00 A. C. Norton, painting 63.00 City of Wayne, light and water power... American Book Company textbooks D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbooks 105.00 26.19 10.80 Row. Peterson, textbooks 8.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION" \2l&gt; Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. coal American Book Company, textbooks. ... American Book Company, textbooks. ... Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 6g6So 843 I2.0O 33-62 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks Gregg Publishing Co.. textbooks D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbooks The Macmillan Company, textbooks.. Charles E Merrill Company, textbooks Rand, McNally. textbooks _ 37 44 6o.oo 29.70 09.64 8.06 8.64 12.68 Row, Peterson Co., textbook Silver. Burdett, textbooks .... 9-90 J. J. Ahem, domestic science supplies Central Scientific Company, thermometer National Wood Works, lumber _... 2954 9.70 Ij.OO Remington Typewriter Co.. typewriters J Fischer &amp; Bro.. music IQ6.00 9.84 The Willis Music Co.. music 1 6.22 J. W. York &amp; Sons, orchestra supplies C. A. Chace &amp; Company, repair supplies Fritz Denkinger, labor _. 1574 V 3 '0.2, 70.25 A. C. Norton, calsominin 163.20 7940 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Company, paint The Tribune Co.. advertising 7^.52 November payroll Nov 65.00 Balance November 30. 1918 4.19305 $19,738.85 $10,738.85 LIBRARY FUND Balance November 30. 1916 $4,006.37 Receipt* 1916 Dec. 31 Matriculation fees for December 225.00 1917 Jan. 31 Matriculation fees for January 250.00 Feb. 28 Matriculation fees for February _ 15.00 Mar. 31 Matriculation fees for March 10.00 Apr. 30 Matriculation fees for April 5.00 Expenditure* 1916 Dec. 16 N. E. Fain, reference books _.._ 70.80 U. S. Conn, advanced for subscriptions .... 10.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">iai 1,330.00 10.00 680.00 500 20.00 14500 WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Macmillan Co.. reference books W. H. Wagner, reference books F. E. West, History of the World ... Harry P. Whitmore, framed picture Macmillan Co.. reference books 32.81 W. H. Wagner, reference books 50.00 F. E. West, History of the World , 20.00 2O.OO Harry P. Whitniore, framed picture 18.25 1 8.2; 1917 1917 Jan. 15 Democrat Printing Co.. index cases, etc 570 Moore-Cottrell Sub. Co., periodicals 33-9O Paltridge Metal Equipment Co., wall stacks 135.00 Apr. 24 D. Appkton &amp; Co., year book 3.00 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., reference books 12./8 Bee Publishing Co., subscription 300 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., reference books 12./8 Bee Publishing Co., subscription U. S. Conn, advanced on subscription 300 U. S. Conn, advanced on subscriptions 13.00 13.00 Henry Holt &amp; Company, reference books... 41.97 Henry Holt &amp; Company, reference books... 41.97 A C. UcClurg &amp; Co.. reference books 148.23 \ C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books 148.23 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 112.52 112.52 Norfolk Daily News, subscription 3.00 Norfolk Daily News, subscription 3.00 Russell Sage Foundation, reference books 3.27 World-Herald, subscription 4.00 World-Herald, subscription 4.00 H. W. Wilson Company, Reader's Guide... 8.00 H. W. Wilson Company, Reader's Guide... 8.00 R. L. Polk &amp; Company, Directory of Ne - braska 7.00 R. L. Polk &amp; Company, Directory of Ne- braska 7.00 June 30 Matriculation fees for June June 30 July 31 Sep. 30 Oct. 31 Nov. 30 Aug. 8 Matriculation fees for June Matriculation fees for July Matriculation fees for September Matriculation fees for October Matriculation fees for November A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books Waldorf Bindery Company, binding peri- July 31 Matriculation fees for July Sep. 30 Matriculation fees for September Oct. 31 Matriculation fees for October Nov. 30 Matriculation fees for November Aug. 8 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 112.25 112.25 Waldorf Bindery Company, binding peri - odicals 64.76 64.76 Nov. 9 Crowley, the Magazine man, subscription list 238.30 238.30 Am. Educational Society, encyclopedia 2655 Am. Educational Society, encyclopedia 2655 Chicago Tribune, subscription 8.00 Chicago Tribune, subscription 8.00 Dodd, Mead &amp; Company, year book..._ 6.30 Dodd, Mead &amp; Company, year book..._ 6.30 The Methods Co., public school methods... 24.75 The Methods Co., public school methods... 24.75 Sioux City Journal, subscription 3.00 Sioux City Journal, subscription 300 Sioux City Tribune, subscription 3.00 Sioux City Tribune, subscription Waldorf Bindery Co., binding periodicals... 731 Harry P. Whitmore, framed pictures 171-75 Howard-Severance Co, International dic- tionary 8520 Dec. 31 Matriculation fees for December 1918 Jan. 31 Matriculation fees for January 385.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION ■aa Feb28 Matriculation fees for February IOOO IO.OO Mar. 31 Matriculation fees for March Apr. 30 Matriculation fees for April I5.oo Jan. 26 D. Appleton &amp; Co., reference books 4-83 Arthur H. Clarke Co., reference books 4-5° U. S. Conn, cash advanced 17.88 Houghton. Mifflin Co.. reference books 12.87 Library Bureau, supplies 78.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books 07.01 A. C. McChirg &amp; Co., reference books 214-40 Remington Typewriter Co.. typewriter 75.00 Harry P. Whitmore, picture 100.00 H. W. Wilson Co. book index _ 8.00 Apr. 12 Library Bureau, equipment 77-68 A. C. McClurg Co.. reference books 5&gt;'9 Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons, renewal pages 10.00 Norfolk Daily News, subscription 3-°° Public School Pub. Co., reference books. 5°3 Underwood &amp; Underwood, school views. 172.60 etc. Waldorf Bindery Co.. binding 3200 World Publishing Co., subscription 5-°° June 30 Matriculation fees for June 1,07500 July 21 Matriculation fees for July 500 480.00 Sept. 30 Matriculation fees for September Nov. 30 Matriculation fees for Oct. and Nov. 50.00 June 16 U. S. Conn, cash advanced 23.50 Library Bureau, cards ■ «6.oo A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 88.31 Aug 6 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co.. year book 5-57 N. E. Fain, reference books 45-00 The Howard Severance Co., dictionary 20.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 21.18 The Maemillan Co., reference books 22-25 B. F. Yard, pictures 3°-oo Nov. 18 D. Appleton &amp; Co., reference books 11.66 Bee Publishing Co., subscription 7-25 Arthur H. Clark Co., reference books _ 4-50 U. S. Conn, cash advanced 12.48 The Wayne Herald, printing pamphlets 15.40 Waldorf Bindery Company, binding 5-35 The Tribune Company .subscription 4-00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 29.38 Library Bureau, magazine rack 145-°° </seg>
            <seg id="p123">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL US Industrial Management, charts N. E. Fain, reference books Balance November 30, 1918 500 48.50 57 1 2.05 $8,73137 $8,731-37 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>