<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00011.00007">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00011.00007</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>SUGGESTIVE PROGRAMS FOR SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES ISSUED BY THE Department of Public Instruction FOR THE USE OF THE SCHOOLS OF NEBRASKA</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-19</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-21</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
SUGGESTIVE PROGRAMS 

FOE 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 

ISSUED BY THE 

Department of Public Instruction 

FOR THE USB OF THE 

SCHOOLS OF NEBRASKA 

WILLIAM K. FOWLER, SUte Superintendent 

LINCOLN, 1901-1902 </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
204 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

BY WAY OF INTRODUCTION 

Department op Public Instruction, 
Lincoln, Nebraska, February 1, 1901. 

To the Teachers of Nebraska: 

Ifhis department takes pleasure in presenting to you these suggestive exes 
for Special Day programs, in the hope that they may prove a material 
valuable aid in making more interesting to the school children of our 
red state these holidays and anniversaries. May these exercises lighten 
1 labors, brighten their work, enliven your school, and impress upon the 
Is of all patriotic sentiments. 

We beg no one's pardon for asking the schools to observe the anniversaries 
of the birth of Lincoln and of Washington ; the children will thank us 
for including a day to be devoted to the study of their poet and his verses; Nebraskans 
generally are proud of the origin of Arbor Day and of its founder, 
their distinguished fellow citizen, the Hon. J. Sterling Morton ; the agriculturists 
of our state are interested in the preservation of our insectivorous 
birds, and all are interested in the care and increase of the native birds of 
Nebraska; the observance of Memorial Day grows sweeter, brighter, and 
better with the passing years; Library Day is growing constantly in importance 
and value in our schools and in the rural communities ; Thanksgiving 
Day is a part of our national history, and Nebraska's bountiful harvests 
erase her to rejoice with her sister states; and Christmas Day is a fitting 
close to the commemoration of special days, containing in a large measure 
the children's hopes, their elders' reminiscences, and the common religion of 
all, with " peace on earth, good will to men." 

I Teach patriotism ; teach love of beautiful characters, of kindly sentiments, 
of nature; teach appreciation of pure literature; teach thankfulness for 
bounty bestowed by the great giver of all good; and teach peace and 
iwill, self-sacrifice and all charitableness. The future destiny of this 
on must be worked out in the homes and the schools of the land. This 
ruction need not displace the multiplication table and the art of correct 
ling, but it must have a place. 

Use these exercises judiciously. Do not adopt them in whole, but adapt 
them in part. Use what is best suited to your needs. Local conditions and 
requirements vary. Consult the authorities and texts referred to. You may 
find there something better suited to your peculiar necessities. Remember 
this publication is for the ensuing two years, the biennium 1901 and 1902. 
It should remain the property of the schoolroom for that length of time, as 
a teacher's desk copy. 

Prepare your programs for these special days, alternating music, recitations, 
special exercises, etc., and assigning parts, and then publish them in a 
local or county newspaper. Send printed or written invitations to your 
patrons to attend the exercises. Do not attempt to observe all these special 
days each year, but bring in every one during the next two years. 

high hopes and best wishes for a continued successful observance 
hese special days, I am 

Sincerely yours, 

William K. Fowler, Superintendent. </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
BROWNVILLE PUBLIC SCHOOL </seg>



            <seg id="p005">
205 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

Lincoln's Boyhood and Youth 

fHE Statesman or the military hero born and reared in a log cabin is a 
familiar figure in American history; but we may search in vain among 
our celebrities for one who3e origin and early life equalled Abraham 

Lincoln's in wretchedness Hard work was his early lot. 

ti a mere boy he had to help in supporting the family, either on his 
r's clearing, or hired out to other farmers to plough, or dig ditches, or 
wood, or drive ox teams; occasionally also to " tend the baby " when the 

farmer's wife was otherwise engaged. He could regard it as an advancement 

B higher sphere of activity when he obtained work in a " cross-roads store," 
~e he amused his customers by his talk over the counter; for he soon 
nguished himself among the backwoods folk as one who had something 

to say worth listening to. 

Every printed page that fell into his hands he would greedily devour, 

and his family and friends watched him with wonder, as the uncouth boy, 
after his daily work, crouched in a corner of the log cabin or outside under 
a tree, absorbed in a book while munching his supper of corn bread. In this 
manner he began 10 gather some knowledge, and sometimes he would astonish 
the girls with such startling remarks as that the earth was moving around 
the sun, and not the sun around the earth, and they marveled where "Abe" 
could have got such queer notions. Soon he also felt the impulse to write; 
not only making extracts from books he wished to remember, but also composing 
little essays of his own. First he sketched these with charcoal on a 
wooden shovel scraped white with a drawing knife, or on basswood shingles. 
Then he transferred thorn to paper, which was a scarce commodity in the 
Lincoln household; taking care to cut his expressions close, so that they 
might not cover too much space, a style-forming method greatly to be 
commended. Seeing boys put a burning coal on the back of a wood turtle, 
he was moved to write on cruelty to animals. Seeing men intoxicated with 
whiskey, he wrote on temperance. In verse-making, too, he tried himself, 
and in satire on persons offensive to him or others. Also political thoughts 
he put on paper, and some of his pieces were even deemed good enough for 

publication in the county weekly. 

Thus he won a neighborhood reputation, as a clever young man, which 

Increased by his performances as a speaker, not seldom drawing upon 
self the dissatisfaction of his employers by mounting a stump in the field 
keeping the farm hands from their work by little speeches in a jocose and 
stimes also, a serious vein. At the rude social frolics of the settlement 
jecame an important person, telling funny stories and mimicking the 

itinerant preachers All this made him a favorite in backwoods 

society, although in some things he appeared a little odd to his friends. Far 
more than any of them, he was given not only to reading, but to fits of 
abstraction, to quiet musing with himself, and also to strange spells of 

melancholy, from which he often would pass in a moment to rollicking oat- 

bursts of droll humor. But, on the whole, he was one of the people nmom </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

206 

whom he lived ; in appearance, perhaps, a little more uncouth than the most 
of them, a very tall, rawboned youth, with large features, dark shriveled akin, 
and rebellious hair; bis arms and legs long, out of proportion; clad in deerskin 
trousers, which from frequent exposure to the rain had shrunk so as to 
sit tightly on his limbs, leaving several inches of bluish skin exposed between 
their lower end and the heavy tan -colored shoes; the nether garment held 
usually by only one suspender, that was strung over a coarse home made shirt; 
the head covered in winter with a coonskin cap, in summer with a rough straw 
hat of uncertain shape, without a band. —Carl Schurz. (Published by special 
permumon of Houghton, Mifflin &amp; Co.) 

# # 

The Death of Lincoln 

OSLOW to smite anfl swift to spare, 
Gentle and merciful and just ! 
Who, in the fear of God, didst bear 
The sword of power, a nation's trust I 

In sorrow by thy bier we stand, 
Amid the awe that hushes all, 

And speak the anguish of a land 
That shook with horror at thy fall. 

Thy task is done ; the bond are free ; 
We bear thee to an honored grave, 
Whose proudest monument shall be 

The broken fetters of the slave. 

Pure was thy life ; its bloody close 
Hath placed thee with the sons of light, 

Among the noblest host of those 
Who perished in the cause of Right. 

—William Cullen Bryant. 

* # 

The Hard-Work Plan 

FROM the lowest depths of poverty 
To the highest heights of fame, 
From obscureness of position 

To a bright and shining name ; 
From the mass of human beings, 

Who compose the common clan, 
You can earn your way to greatness 
By the Hard- Work Plan. 

Twas the key to Lincoln's progress, 
Twas the route to Webster's fame; 

And Garfield, by this method, 
To distinction laid his claim; 

And all earth's noblest heroes, 
Since this old world first began, 

Have earned their way to honor 
By the Hard-Work Plan. 

— SueoeM. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
207 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

Lincoln Exercise 

FIRST CHILD. 

KEASE listen, dear friends, while little ones tell 
Of Abraham Lincoln we all love so well. 
b was born in Kentucky ninety -one years ago, 

The twelfth of February, this much I know. 

SECOND CHILD. 

His home a log cabin, his parents were poor, 
Many trials and hardships he had to endure ; 

re had not, as we have, good teachers, and few 
Were the books from which most of his knowledge he 

drew. 

THIRD CHILD. 

O, sad was his heart when his dear mother died, 
And no preacher to pray the lone mourner beside. 

r&gt;or lad! he was only nine years that sad day, 
When in the dark grave she was hidden away. 

FOURTH CHILD. 

fis heart was so tender, I know he was kind, 
For when the poor doggie was crying behind, 

re waded the dark, muddy stream, and the cur 
Took up in his strong arms and carried him o'er. 

FIFTH CHILD. 

Lknow he was honest, he never could bear 
To wrong any one in the least, if aware ; 

Have you heard how he walked three long miles ere he 
slept, 

To return the change which he unwittingly kept ? 
sixth child. 

t&gt; manly, so humble, so noble, so brave, 
The foe of the bully, the friend of the slave. 

ro wonder the hearts of the people he won. 
Who made him the President, March— '61. 

SEVENTH CHILD. 

tsptember, eighteen hundred and sixty-two, 
Throughout all the world how the glad tidings flew I 

rlien Lincoln proclaimed the poor slaves' liberty, 
And said all in bondage hereafter were free. 

EIGHTH CHILD. 

E)r freedom he labored, for freedom he died, 
For weak ones, and helpless, like Him crucified; 
aw the heart of the nation with sorrow did swell, 

When he by the hand of the murderer fell. 

NINTH CHILD. 

rbout Abr'am Lincoln, this one thing I know, 
He will long be remembered by high and by low, 
great object lesson — that one humble-born 

May rise and the highest position adorn. 

—Annie W. Woodruff, in Teachert' World. </seg>


            <seg id="p008">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S HEPORT. 

The Name of Lincoln 

THERE'S a name that brings a picture 
Of a man great souled and grand ; 

One whose deeds on History's pages, 
Carved in bold relief shall stand. 

There's a name that brings a picture 
Of a time when blood was shed, 
When the boom of cannon sounded 

And the star of War was red. 

There's a name that brings a picture 
Of a shackled race set free, 

Brought from out the ban of bondage 
To the joys of liberty. 

There's a name that brings a picture 
Of a nation bowed in woe, 

For the hand of an assassin 
Laid a noble spirit low. 

"Tis the name of martyred Lincoln 
Calls these pictures from the past, 

And that name with the Immortals 
Shall endure while earth shall last. 

—Susie M. Best, in Teachers' World. 

# # 

A King 

"WrE talked of kings, little Ned and I, 
If As we sat in the firelight's glow ; 
Of Alfred the Great, in days gone by, 

And his kingdom of long ago. 

Of Norman William, who, brave and stern, 
His armies to victory led. 

Then, after a pause : "At school we learn 
Of another great man," said Ned. 

"And this one was good to the oppressed, 
He was gentle, and brave, and so 

Wasn't he greater than all the rest? 
'Twas Abraham Lincoln, you know." 

"Was Lincoln a king? " I asked him then, 
And in waiting for his reply 

A long procession of noble men 
Seemed to pass in the firelight by. 

When, " No," came slowly from little Ned, 
And thoughtfully ; then with a start, 

" He wasn't a king — outside," he said, 
" But I think he was— in his heart." 

—Ella Matthews Bangs, in St. Nicholas </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
209 


Readings 

i 

«*TT*HE Old World and the New, from sea to sea, 
A Utter one voice of sympathy and shame! 

Sore heart, so stopped when i'. a r last boat high, 

Sad life, cut short i 1 - triumph came. 

I 

Peace! Let the sad procession go, 
While cannon boom and bells toll slow 
And go, thou aicred ear, 

Bearing our woe afar. — R. H. Stoddard. 

Ill 

"Rest, noble martyr ; rest in peace 

Rest with the true and brave 

Who, like thee, fell in freedom's cause 
The nation's life to save." 

IV 

Thy name shall live while time endures, 
And men shall say of thee, 
"He saved his country from its foes, 

And bade the slave be free." 

V 

O God! before whom we in tears, 
Our fallen chief deplore ; 

Grant that the cause for which he died, 
May live forevermore. 

—Gurley. 

* * 

" The First American" 

GREAT captains, with their drums and guns, 
Disturb our judgment for the hour, 
But at last silence comes ; 

These all are gone, and, standing like a tower, 
Our children shall behold his fame, 

The kindly-earnest, brave, foreseeing man, 
Sagacious, patient, dreading praise, not blame, 

New birth of our new soil, the first American. 

— From LoioelVs "Commemoration Ode. 

# # 

Lincoln as a Military Hero 

the Black Hawk war broke out, young Lincoln helped to raiae a 
W company of volunteers and was chosen its captain. The company 

k afterward disbanded, but young Lincoln, determined to serve in the 
gn, enlisted as a private, and lived a soldier's life for the next three 
;. Referring to this experience in a congressional speech in after years, 
icoln said : " By the way, Mr. Speaker, did you know I was a military </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
210 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

hero ? Yea, sir, in the days of the Black Hawk war, I fought, bled, and came 
away. Speaking of General Case' career, reminds me of my own. I was not 
at Stillman's defeat, but I was about as near it as Cass to Hull's surrender; 
and, like him, I saw the place very soon afterward. It is quite certain I did 
not break my sword, for I had none to break; but I bent a musket pretty 
badly on one occasion. If Cass broke his sword, the idea is, he broke it in 
desperation ; I bent the musket by accident. If Cass went in advance of me 
in picking whortleberries, I guess I surpassed him in charging upon the wild 
onions. If he saw any live, fighting Indians, it was more than I did, but I 
had a good many bloody battles with the mosquitoes; and although I never 
fainted from loss of blood, I can truly say, I was often very hungry." 

a a 

Lincoln's Method of Study 

(After his Cooper Union speech, February 27, I860, Mr. Lincoln visited, among other 
|ilane, Norwich, Conn. The following is his answer to a question of Mr. Gulliver, In the 
railway train on his way back to New York :) 

TXTELL, as to education, the newspapers are correct; I never went to school 
W more than six months in my life. But, as you say, this must be a 
product of culture in some form. I have been putting the question 
you ask me to myself, while you have been talking. I can say this, that 
among my earliest recollections, I remember how, when a mere child, I used 
to get irritated when anybody talked to me in a way I could not understand. 
I don't think I ever got angry at anything else in my life. But that always 
disturbed my temper, and has ever since. I can remember going to my little 
bedroom, after hearing the neighbors talk of an evening with my father, and 
spending no small part of the night walking up and down, and trying to make 
out what was the exact meaning of some of their, to me, dark sayings. I 
could not sleep, though I often tried to when I got on such a hunt after an 
idea, until I had caught it; and when I thought I had got it, I was not satisfied 
until I would repeat it over and over, until I had put it in language plain 
enough, as I thought, for any boy to comprehend. This was a kind of passion 
with me, and it has stuck by me; for I am never easy now when I am handling 
a thought, till I have bounded it north, and bounded it south, and bounded 
it east, and bounded it west. Perhaps that accounts for the characteristic 
you observe in my speeches, though I never put the two things together 

Oh, yes! I "read law," as the phrase is — that is, I became a lawyer's 
clerk in Springfield, and copied tedious documents and picked up what I 
could of law in the intervals of other work. But your question reminds me of 
a bit of education I had, which I am bound in honesty to mention. In the 
course of my law reading, I constantly came upon the word demonstrate. I 
thought at first that I understood its meaning, but soon became satisfied that 
I did not. I said to myself , "What do I mean when I demonstrate more than 
when I reaton or prove f How does demonstration differ from any other 
proof?" I consulted Webster's Dictionary. That told of " certain proof ," 
"proof beyond the possibility of doubt ; " but I could form no idea what sort of 
proof that was. I thought a great many things were proved beyond a possibility 
of doubt, without recourse to any such extraordinary process of reasoning 
as I understood "demonstration " to be. I consulted all the dictionaries 
and books of reference I could find, but with no better results. You might as 
well have defined blue to a blind man. At last I said, " Lincoln, you can 
never make a lawyer if you do not understand what demonstrate means;" and 
I left my situation at Springfield, went home to my father's house and stayed 
there till I could give any proposition in the six books of Euclid at sight. I 
then found out what " demonstrate " means, and went back to my law-studies. 
— From " Words of Abraham Lincoln," published by the Western Publishing 
House, Chicago. </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

211 

Lincoln and the Dying Soldier Boy 

rIE day in May, 1863, while the great war was raging between the North 
and the South, President Lincoln paid a visit to one of the military hos- 

pitals, says an exchange. He had spoken many cheering words of 
sympathy to the wounded as he proceeded through the various wards, and 
now he was at the bedside of a Vermont boy of about sixteen years of age, 
who lay there mortally wounded. 

¦Taking the dying boy's thin, white hands in his own, the President said, 
tender tone : 

"Well, my poor boy, what can I do for you ? " 

The young fellow looked up into the President's kindly face and asked : 
"Won't you write to my mother for me ? " 

"That I will," answered Mr. Lincoln ; and calling for a pen, ink, and 
paper, he seated himself by the side of the bed and wrote from the boy's dictation. 
It was a long letter, but the President betrayed no sign of weariness. 
When it was finished, he rose, saying: 
" I will post this as soon as I get back to my office. Now, is there anything 
else I can do for you ? " 

The boy looked up appealingly to the President. 

"Won't you stay with me? " he asked. " I do want to hold on to your 

»Mr. Lincoln understood the boy's meaning. The appeal was too strong 
lim to resist; so he sat down by his side and took hold of his hand. For 
hours the President sat there patiently as though he had been the boy's 
er. 

RWhen the end came he bent over and folded the thin hands over his 
LSt. As he did so, he burst into tears, and when, soon afterward, he left 
hospital, they were still streaming down his cheeks. — From "Bert Lincoln 
ie»," by permission of James E. Gallaher &amp; Co. 

a 0 

Lincoln's Famous Speech 

(At Gettysburg, November 18, 1863.) 

I^OURSCORE and seven years ago our fathers brought forth upon this 
F continent a new nation, conceived in liberty, and dedicated to the propo- 

sition that all men are created equal. Now we are engaged in a great 
civil war, testing whether that nation, or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, 
can long endure. We are met on a great battle-field of that war. We have 
come to dedicate a portion of that field as a final resting place for those who 
here gave their lives that that nation might live. It is altogether fitting and 
proper that we should do this. But in a larger sense we cannot dedicate, 
we cannot consecrate, we cannot hallow this ground. The brave men, living 
and dead, who struggled here, have consecrated it far above our power to add 
or detract. The world will little note, nor long remember what we say here, 
but it can never forget what they did here. It is for us, the living, rather 
to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have 
thus far so nobly advanced. It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the 
great task remaining before us. that from these honored dead we take 
increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of 
devotion ; that we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in 
vain; that this nation, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom, and that 
government of the people, by the people, and for the people, shall not perish 
from the earth. 

COMMENT ON THIS SPEECH. 

On November 19, 1863, two orators met on the memorable field of Gettysburg. 
One was gifted in oratory, learned in schools and from books; the </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
212 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

other was skilled in the 'witchery of speech' as gathered from the riTer, th© 
forest, and the plain. Both spoke. The speech of one lies dumb and meaningless, 
unread and unremembered, while the speech of the other, rooted in 
the memory of man, and oft repeated, will live with the literature of the race, 
growing grander and sweeter in pathos and in beauty as the years shall gather 
around and about it. One was a brain effort, the other was a heart effort. 
One spoke words that were heard, the other words that were felt. One was 
art, the other genius. One was Edward Everett, the gifted scholar of New 
England, the other was Abraham Lincoln, the gifted railsplitter of the west. 
—Judge Tenney. 

EVERETT'S LETTER ON SAME. 

I The day after the delivery of these two speeches, Edward Everett 
te Mr. Lincoln as follows: "My dear Lincoln: Could I flatter myself with 
thought that I came as near the central idea of the occasion yesterday in 
* hours as you did in three minutes, I would be a happy man." The rewas 
characteristic of Mr. Lincoln. He wrote: "My dear Everett: Yours 
&gt;ur Gettysburg speeches at hand. It would not do for Edward Everett to 
:e a short speech or Abraham Lincoln a long one. Yours, A. Lincoln." 

* * 

r coin's First Speech in the Supreme 
Court 

(The case being called, Mr. Lincoln appeared (or the appellant, and according to Judge 
Treat, spoke as follows:) 
HONOR:— This is the first case I have ever had in this court, and I 
X have examined it with great care. As the court will perceive by looking 

at the abstract of the record, the only question in the case is one of 
authority. I have not been able to find any authority sustaining my side of 
the case, but I have found several cases directly in point on the other side. 
I will now give the citations and then submit the case.— Published by permission 
of Rhodes &amp; McClure. 

s * 

tst TalK with Friends After Receiving Telegram 
of His First Nomination 

(This telegram was received in the Journal office at Springfield. Immediately everybody 
wanted to shake his hand, and so long as he was willing, they continued to congratntate htm.) 
— (with a twinkle in his eye) — You had better come up 
\JI and shake my hand while you can; honors elevate some men, you know. 

Well, gentlemen, there is a little short woman at our house, who 

Kbably more interested in this dispatch than I am; and if you will excuse 
will take it up and let her see it. — Published by permission of Rhodes &lt;fr 

a 0 

Washington and Lincoln Compared 

rHE greatest names in American history are Washington and Lincoln. 
One is forever associated with the independence of the states and formation 
of the Federal Union; the other with universal freedom and the 

preservation of the Union. Washington enforced the Declaration of Independence 
as against England; Lincoln proclaimed its fulfillment not only to </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
213 

&amp; downtrodden race in America, but to all people for all time who may seek 

B protection of our flag. These illustrious men achieved grander results 
nankind within a single century, from 1775 to 1865, than any other men 
accomplished in all the years since first the flight of time began, 
ihington engaged in no ordinary revolution; with him it was not who 

Ed rule, but what should rule. He drew hi i sword not for a change of 
i upon an established throne, but I vhich 
d acknowledge no throne but the i: 

accepted war to save the Union, the safeguard of our 1 

\-:ab- 

lish it on "indestructible foundations" as forever ble." 

To quote his own grand words: Now we are contending 

under God shall have a new birth of freedom, and that 

people, by the people, for the people, shall not perish from 

Each lived to accomplish his appointed task. Ear he un- 

Ided gratitude of the people of his time and each i t and 
¦increasing reverence by posterity. The fame of each wi !ie; it 
grow with the ages, because it is based upon imperishable service to 
mity; not to the people of a single generation or country, but to the 
e human family, wherever scattered, forever.— William McKinley, in 

Porter's Life of McKinley, by permission of the N. Q. Hamilton Publishing 
. v. Cleveland. </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
Washington 

Khis person, Washington was six feet high, and rather slender. His limbs 
ere long; his hands were uncommonly large, his chest broad and full, 

his head was exactly round, and the hair brown in manhood, but gray at 
fifty ; his forehead rather low and retreating ; the nose large and massy, the 
mouth wide and firm, the chin square and heavy, the cheeks full and ruddy in 
early life. His eyes were blue and handsome, but not quick or nervous. He 
required spectacles to read with at fifty. He was one of the best riders in the 
United States, but, like some other good riders, awkward and shambling in 
his walk. He was stately in his bearing, reserved, distant, and apparently 
haughty. 
Shy among women, he was not a great talker in any company, but a careful 
observer and listener. He read the natural temper of men. but not always 
aright. He seldom smiled. He did not laugh with his face, but in his body, 
and, while calm above, below the diaphragm his laughter was copious and 
earnest. Like many grave persons he was fond of jokes and loved humorous 
stories. He had negro story-tellers to regale him with fun and anecdotes at 
Mt. Vernon He was not critical about his food, but fond of tea. He took 
beer or cider at dinner, and occasionally wine. He hated drunkenness, gaming, 
and tobacco. He had a hearty love of farming and of private life. 

There was nothing of the politician in him, — no particle of cunning. He 
was one of the most industrious of men.' Not an elegant or accurate writer, 
he yet took great pains with style, and after the revolution carefully corrected 
the letters he had written in the time of the French war, more than thirty 
Tears before. 

He was no orator. He never made a speech. The public papers were 
drafted for him, and he read them when the occasion came. 

»It has been said Washington was not a great soldier; but certainly he 
ted an army out of the roughest materials, out-generaled all that Britain 
d send against him, and in the midst of poverty and distress, organized 
&gt;ry. He was not brilliant and rapid. He was slow, defensive, victorious, 
made "an empty bag stand upright," which Franklin says is "hard." 

I Some men command the world, or hold its admiration by their ideas or 
r intellect. Washington had neither original ideas nor a deeply cultured 
i. He commanded by his integrity, by his justice. He loved power by 
tnct, and strong government by reflective choice. Twice he was made 
itor, with absolute power, and never abused the awful and despotic trust, 
monarchic soldiers and civilians would make him king. He trampled 
heir offer and went back to his fields of corn at Mt. Vernon. 

t Washington is the first man of his type : when will there be another ! 
yet the American Rhetoricians do not dare tell half his excellence ; but 
people should not complain. — Theodore Parker, in "Our Country in 
try and Prose." (By permission of The American Book Company.) </seg>



            <seg id="p016">! </seg>





            <seg id="p017">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

Birthday of Washington 

(May be sung to America.) 

FIRST PUPIL. 

thou festal morn! 
WW Never be passed in scorn 

Thy rising sun. 
Thou day forever bright 

With Freedom's holy light, 
That gave the world the sight 

Of Washington. 

SECOND PUPIL. 

Unshaken 'mid the storm, 
Behold that noble form — 
That peerless one, 

With his protecting hand, 
Like Freedom's angel, stand, 
The guardian of our land, 
Our Washington. 

THIRD PUPIL. 

Traced there in lines of light, 
Where all pure rays unite, 

Obscured by none; 

Brightest on history's page, 
Of any clime or age, 

As chieftain, man or sage, 
Stands Washington. 

FOURTH PUPIL. 

Name at which tyrants pale, 
And their proud legions quail, 

Their boasting done ; 

While Freedom lifts her head, 
No longer filled with dread, 
Her sons to victory led 

By Washington. 

CLASS IN CONCERT. 

Now the true patriot see, 
The foremost of the free, 
The victory won. 

In Freedom's presence bow, 
While sweetly smiling now 
She wreathes the spotless brow 

Of Washington. 

Then, with each coming year, 
Whenever shall appear 

That natal sun, 

Will we attest the worth 
Of one true man to earth 
And celebrate the birth 

Of Washington. </seg>


            <seg id="p018">
216 


Acrostic for Washington's Birthday 

Note.— If n 

. r-'n they mU'lit have letters coyered with different 

adored tissue r 2 ' "" ¦ - laurel, or boxwood, If obtainable. 

W-hy ..re v. ; gathered here today, 

j^-~'l what v.ould our friends all have us say? 
8-urdy a hero our theme should bo, 

H-onored his name, on land, and 
|-nquire thou the name of our hero true? 
N-oble, courageous, a patriot too, 
¥-uiding through trial our " Ship of State." 
-ruly his name we can all call great. 
O-'er this broad country, each daughter and son, 
H-ow welcomes the name — George Washington. 

—Louise M. Byrnes, in The Teachers' World. 

a a 

A " New Physical Culture " Exercise for 

Washington's Birthday 

Commands — 1. Recited— 2. 

1. At-tention. 

2. George Washington always gave individual attention to the calls of duty. 
1. Po-sition. 

2. Washington always made the best of any position in which he might be 
placed. 

1. Heels-raise. 

2. His very presence would always raise the spirits of his army, and his roice 
would inspire them with courage. 

1. Heels-sink. 

Eor would his own spirits s*nk, for his trust in God was unbounded, 
ips-firm. 

res, his firm, unwavering trust in God was what sustained him during 
the darkest hours of the Revolution. 

1. Po-sition. 

¦ His position as commander of the Revolutionary army was one of grave 
responsibility, but ably and successfully did he fill it. 

1. Peet-close. 

2. At the close of the war he retired to his home, Mt. Vernon, after having 
bid farewell to his beloved army. 

1. Feet-open. 

¦His grand character and noble life cannot fail to open to us a lofty standard 
of courage and patriotism. 
Heads backward-bend. 

¦ Let us then backward bend our thoughts to-day towards the memory of 
this great man who atill " Lives in the hearts of his countrymen." 

i. Heads upward-raise. 

2. At the same time let us upward raise our thankful hearts to our Heavenly 
Father for having sent us in our hour of need this " Father of His 
Country." — Washington. 

8alut*-right (or left), faoe-march. 

— Louise M. Byrnes, tn The Teachers' World. </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
217 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

George Washington 

k(The following exercise may be given by sixteen pupils. Each pupil has a large pasteboard 
Eter hung about the neck. The letters arp cover^l with gilt pap&gt;T, turned and displayed at 

the beginning of the Terse as it is recited. The letters in order spell "George 

Washington.") 

General Washington's name we praise, 
In tributes now our voices raise. 

Earnest and true, he was noble and good; 
I'd be like 'SWishinpton — that I would! 

Obedient always — a manly boy; 
His playmates he did not annoy. 

Right in word, in act, in deed; 
In classes he would alwaj-3 lead. 

Good and thoughtful, always kind, 
Such boys make friends we always find. 

Eager to learn he improved each hour. 
This gave to him great strength and power. 

Wisdom he sought, and in this land, 
No greater general could command. 

Alert and quick to do his work; 
A duty he would never shirk. 

Strong in body and strong in mind, 
No greater general can we find. 

Happy to do for his country and men, 
He bravely fought for freedom then. 

Illustrious soldier, statesman, friend, 
Our country's cause he did defend. 

Noble in thought, in action sure, 
Great suffering he did endure. 

Great was the work of this soldier's life; 
He conquered the foe in the bitter strife. 

True to his country, as president, he 
Ruled his people in "the land of the free." 

Obedient still to duty's command, 
He loved our own, free native land. 

Noted, obedient, great and grand, 
Did ever a greater man live in our land? 

(The first four boys recite In concert the following, forming 
a circle at the appropriate words.) 

Four brave little laddies, 

Wearing loyal badges. 

In a row together, standing hand in hand; 
Make a manly circle, 

Join hands all together, 

So one link we've fastened of a loyal band, </seg>



            <seg id="p020">
THE NEXT FOUR GIRL8 RECITE : 

Four true little lassies, 
From the world's great masses. 
In a row together, standing hand in hand; 

Swing into a circle, 

Join both lads and lassies, 

So two links we've fastened of a loyal band. 
(As the two groups come together, four hands meet and 
cross, thus uniting the two circles.) 

THE NEXT FOUR REPEAT : 
We four make a circle, 
Join each hand to hand ; 

And a third link we have fastened of our loyal 

band. 

Battlefields may lie 
Before us by and by, 

But strong we'll be to fight in freedom's land. 

THE LAST FOUR REPEAT: 
Four more little lassies 

From our brightest classes, 

In a row together, standing hand in hand; 
Make a loving circle, 
Join we to the others, 

So four links are fastened in our loyal band. 

ALL REPEAT : 
Four strong links for greatness; 
In our chain to-day, 

Strong and good as Washington's brave loyal 

band. 

Strong, obedient, tender, 
Our love together render, 

For Washington's great goodness and our own 

fair native land. 

ALL SING TO THE TUNE OF "LIGHTLY ROW." 

Gayly sing, gayly sing, 

Washington's great fame we bring. 

Joyfully, joyfully, 

Sing his praise to-day. 
May our lives be good and great, 
And we armed for any fate, 

Joyfully, joyfully, 

Sing his praise to-day. 

(At the beginning of the last four lines, the groups sepa- </seg>


            <seg id="p021">
219 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

One boy should 

hinging empty at h: 

For Two Boys 

be dressed as an old soldier— soldier's uniform, and right coat «law 
side. The other boy is dressed as an old man— spectacle*, tall hat aod 

OLD MAN. 

were at Valley Forge, old friend? 

SOLDIER. 

Aye, aye, sir, that I was, 

Fighting for love and freedom, 
My country and Liberty's laws. 

I got a ball right here, sir, 
And that at Bunker Hill; 

Ah, man! 'twas seven long years for us, 
Those battles I see still. 

OLD MAN. 

And you were at Trenton, soldier ? 

SOLDIER. 

Aye, stranger, on that day, 
The fight was long and bitter 

Ere the English foe gave way. 

OLD MAN. 

You fought under Washington, soldier ? 

SOLDIER. 

Yes, stranger; we would tread 
Through cold and fire and battle 

And follow where he led. 

OLD MAN. 
And he was a right good General ? 

SOLDIER. 

Ah ! that he was. To me 
There never lived a greater, 

His equal ne'er could be. 

OLD MAN. 

You've lost an arm, brave comrade ? 

SOLDIER. 

Yes, sir; my loss is gain, 

t&gt;r I gave that right arm gladly 
And did not mind the pain. 

r&gt;r independence I gave it, 
For the flag I love so true, 

hd had they needed thit arm 
'd have given it gladly, too. 

OLD MAN. 

Ah, you have honor, soldier. 

SOLDIER. 

Men make me a hero now, 

But many a hero ne'er was crowned 

With laurel on his brow. </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
220 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

A hero dies for his country, 

The earth knows not his name, 

But angels kind watch o'er him, 
In Heaven they know his name. 
And all deeds brave and loyal 

Are recognized in Heaven ; 
And the crown of love is granted 

Whose life, for love, was given. 

Thta may be followed by singing by the bchool: "Battle Hymn of the Republic." 

— The Helper. 

a a 

Dialogue 

Costumes. — Two girls may be dressed quaintly in white cape, white kerchiefs, fall 
tkirte, hair done up with high-back combs, spectacles, etc. 
Two boys representing the men of Washington's time, may wear knee breeches, oldfashioned 
coats trimmed with silver or gold lace if possible, three-cornered hats trimmed 
with same lace. Deep lace ruffles on the sleeves and shirt bosom, wigs, buckles at the knee* 
and on the shoes. 

Two ladies are knitting and sewing. A bell rings. 

BRS. A.— Who can that be ? (Goes to door.) 
Enter two gentlemen. 
I'm so glad to see you both ; please be seated. 

MR. A. — Thank you. (Removes his hat as he comes forward.) Have you 
¦een Washington to-day? 

Mrs. B. — He passed the house on horseback not more than an hour ago. 

Mr. B. We are sorry. We hope he will accept a third term as president. 
He is a kingly man. 

I Mr. A. — Indeed he is. He was born, you know, the year I was, in seven. 
thirty-two. We played together. He had no sisters, but two older 
hers. A fine, manly fellow Washington was ; fond of athletic sports. He 
d pitch the heaviest bar of all of us. He was strong. 

¦Mr. B.— At school he would divide the boys into two armies, the French 
the Americans. We fought our battles with corn-stalks. 

BMrs. A.— Yes; he is so kind and true that every one loves him. He was 
od pupil in school. He learned very fast. He began to be great right 
e in the school room at Bridges' Creek. 

KMr. B. — I used to see him often when he was surveying, measuring off 
it plantations and planning roads, walls, and fences. One day I called 
iim when it was bitter cold. He had slept on a bed of leaves that night 
was then doing his own cooking. 

Mrs. B. — What a brave soldier he has been! I was glad enough to see 
the English army go home after seven years of that bitter war, and leave our 
ry free to make her own laws. My brother , you know, was one who 
to death in crossing the Delaware in the snow and sleet. But we must 
not think about our own sorrows. Here, gentlemen, let me give you a cup ol 
tea. (Offers cups of tea.) 

I Mr. A.— I'll say "yes" to-day, but I should say " no" most decidedly if 
were seventy-three and this tea of yours what the English wanted us to 
. How that tea did go into the Boston Harbor ! How indignant we all were ! 

BMrs. A.— We had reason to be. Such oppression and suffering was a 
s injustice. 

¦ Mr. B.— Well, we shall have to ride on to Mt. Vernon if we wish to see 
Washington. 

Mrs. A. — It's a grand old place with its lawns, porches, and large, airy 

BMr. B.— Yes, and I am thinking Washington would far rather retire in 
it there than take hold of this government a third term. Good-day, ladies. 

— The Helper. </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
221 

SPECIAL DAY EXEKCISM. 

An Estimate of Washington 

XjVDR many years I hare studied minutely the career of WMkfemt, aad 
f with every step the greatness of the man has grown spaa me, for saaty • 

I sis has failed to discover the act of his life which, under the eaaasttaasef 
ime, I could unhesitatingly pronounce to hare been an error. Saeh ham 
my experience, and although my deductions may be wrong, they at least 
been carefully and slowly made. I aee in Washington a great aoMier 
fought a trying war to a successful end impomribie without Ma ; • great 
sman who did more than all other men to lay the foundation* of a raaab 
hich has endured in prosperity for more than a century. I Bad la Mai a 
¦elous judgment which was nerer at fault, a penetrating fUM wMea bathe 
future of America when it was dim to other eyes, a great iataOoetaat 
l a will of iron, an unyielding grasp of facts, and an unequaled stioagm 
itriotic purpose. I see in him too, a pure and high-minded geatlseaaa of 
tless courage and stainless honor, simple and stately of manner, Mai aad 
rous of heart. Such he was in truth. The historian aad the biographer 
fail to do him justice, but the instinct of mankind will sot fail. The ml 
needs not books to give him worshipers. George Washington will ati 
receive the lore and reverence of men because they see sabodlad an Ma 
noblest possibilities of humanity.— Henry Cabot Lodmm 4a "Jaeartsaa 
Statesmen Series." By permission of HoughUm, JftfHa 4&gt; &amp;. 

0 0 

Washington 

IIAOARA stands alone, unrivaled among the oataraola of «arth, aad aaa 
might as well attempt to create it, as by pan or pencil to gfoa aa adequate 
description of it. Thus Washington stand* so •amrnwi ia ate 
binations of his life, character, and career, — aa fortunate aa he waa great 
as good as he was great and fortunate, — that one might aa well aaderto 
create as describe him. I shall not attempt it, bat this I Hay say, that 
more I read history, the more I study biography, the more I unMaiylaH 
an nature and aim to form correct moral a st I mates of own, the store ate 
acter of Washington, in its glorious beauty, in the august subtiarity of Ma 
adid combinations, looms up before my imaginations, my feeUaga, aad arj 
¦ment, as the grandest to be found in the aalhaaHi wards of oar race, 
those records, short and simple, that contain the gHottoaja goapai of A* 
of God. 

Does any one maintain that in the raising up of soeh a man to h» ate 
leader of our fathers in their revolutionary struggle, to be ate atodel, gaafts, 
and inspiration, in all coming time, to the new dereiopaent aad Biwaiaaa 
which humanity is to make on this continent, ho aaaa nnthlag woadarMry 
providential? That in all this struggle, ha finda no special tohea of ate 
benignant purpose of the Almighty in regard to the interests of Hbarty aad 
humanity in this land? I can only answer, that I enry not the eoMaeas or 
skepticism of his heart. Such a man is wanting in the groat OMsjeat of faith. 
—faith in the invisible, the spiritual, the eternal,— which has erer beea eae or 
the noblest attributes of the noblest minda. 

Most persons will recognize, and delight to reoognlaa, the hand of Ot§ hi 
that glorious revolutionary struggle of our fathers, whose tmpnrta—a oaa 
never diminish and the memory of which can never die. 

Ewas the first stern conflict between the despotism of the Old World aad 
berty of the New. In that conflict, liberty triumphed, lifting af ear 
¦y "from impending servitude to acknowledged indepaadaaaa.' r aad atea 
3h should stand before us today as "the Lord's doing, ¦arriln— hi oar 
* a testimony to his gracious purpose to Liriwaota the interests aad proof 
humanity in our land and throughout tat world. — AmmmI K. Latkrvp, 
inklin Fifth Reader. </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
222 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

The Character and Career of Washington 

¦^T|rHEN reflecting upon the character and career of Washington, the 
ff mind becomes impressed with a degree of solemn awe and reverence 

which is inspired by the contemplation of no other human being. 
We seem to be gazing upward to that Olympus on which he now serenely sits, 
as upon the form of one who belongs to that majestic race of beings to whom 
the ancient Greeks and Romans ascribed qualities and honors almost divine — 
to some modern Achilles, Hercules, or Theseus. Other distinguished men 
inspire us with a noble, but with a much less profound and impressive, sentiment. 
Frederick the Great excites our admiration for his superior strategic 
skill as a warrior. William Pitt and Hamilton extort our applause for the 
splendor of their stately and resistless eloquence. We commend Marl borough 
and Wellington for their uniform and singular success on the battle-field. 
We admire Metternich and Talleyrand for the profundity and intricacy of 
their state-craft. We at once praise and pity Napoleon for the grandeur and 
the insanity both of his intellect and his ambition. But to Washington alone, 
of all illustrious men, do we ascribe the full perfection of heroism; and him 
only do we contemplate with a reverence and admiration which are unmixed 
with the slightest alloy of censure, untarnished by the least sentiment of 
detraction. Of him alone can we say that his various qualities were precisely 
such, and so proportioned and balanced, as under the peculiar circumstances 
of the case, all wise and good men would wish them to have been. In a word, 
Washington was a masterpiece of human excellence on whom no improvement 
could scarcely have been effected, even by that great creative power 
which first called him into existence.— Samuel M. Schmucker, in "Life and 
Ttme$ of Alexander HamiUon." 

0 0 

What Washington Stands For 

T^JO MAN ever stood for so much to his country and to mankind as 
X^l George Washington. Hamilton, Jefferson and Adams, Madison and 

Jay, each represented some of the elements forming the Union. Washington 
embodied them all. They fell at times under popular disapproval, 
were burned in effigy, were stoned, but he with unerring judgment was always 
the leader of the people. Milton said of Cromwell that " war made him great, 
peace greater." The superiority of Washington's character and genius were 
more conspicuous in the formation of our government and in putting it on indestructible 
foundations than in leading armies to victory and conquering the 
independence of his country. " The union in any event," is the central 
thought of bis farewell address, and all the years of his grand life were devoted 
to its preservation. He fought as a youth with Braddock and in the 
capture of Fort Duquesne for the protection of the whole country. As commander-in-chief 
of the continental army, his commission was from the congress 
of the united colonies. He inspired the movement for the Republic, 
was the president and dominant spirit of the convention which framed its constitution, 
and its president for eight years, and guided its course until satisfied 
that moving safely along the broad highway of time it would be surely 
ascending toward the first place among the nations of the world, the asylum 
of the oppressed, the home of the free. 

Do his countrymen exaggerate his virtues ? Listen to Guizot, the historian 
of civilization: "Washington did the two greatest things which in 
politics it is permitted to man to attempt. He maintained by peace the independence 
of his country, which he conquered by war. He founded a free 
government in the name of the principles of order and by re-establishing 
their sway . " Hear Lord Erekine, the famous of English advocates : " Too are </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
SPECIAL DAY KXKKCI8E8. 

223 

the only being for whom I have an awful reverence." Remember the tribvse 
of Charles James Fox, the greatest parliamentary orator who «rer itijwl the 
British house of commons: "Illustrious man, before whom all huriu— d 
greatness sinks into insignificance." Contemplate the character of Lord 
Brougham, pre-eminent for two generations in every department of asms* 
activity and thought, and then impress upon the memories of jtmr eMMrva 
his deliberate judgment: "Until time shall be no more will a tart of the 
progress which our race has made in wisdom and virtue be derltod from 
the veneration paid to the immortal name of Washington." 

Chatham, who, with Clive, conquered an empire in the east, died broke** 
hearted at the loss of the empire in the west by folliee which sw Ma awei 
and eloquence could not prevent. Pitt saw the vast creations of hudjaliimsry 
shattered at Austerlitz and fell murmuring: " My country! how I love my 
country! " Napoleon caused a noble tribute to Washington to be read a* Um 
head of his armies, but, unable to rise to Washington's greatness, wUaaaaal 
the vast structure erected by conquest and cemented by Mood, to nrinieter to 
his own ambition and pride, crumble into fragments, and an exile and a prisoner, 
he breathed his last babbling of battle fields and rarnagn WaammjtM, 
with his finger upon his pulse, felt the presence of death and nalaWj rertowmg 1 
the past and forecasting the future answered to the summons of the glim messenger, 
" It is well," and, as his mighty soul ascended to Ood, the mad was 
deluged with tears and the world united in his eulogy. Blot oat from the 
page of history the names of all thegreat actors of his time in the drama of 
nations and preserve the name of Washington, and the osntfy will be fa&gt; 
nowned.— Chauncey M. Depew, on the One- Hundredth Anmtmrumrg •/ a%e 
Founding of Our Government. 
</seg>

            <seg id="p026">
224 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Henry Wadsworth Longfellow 

A Grammar School Exercise 

Arranged by A. C. Scammell. 

Motto for the Day: "/ Will Be Eminent in Something." 
Song by the School— "Psalm of Life." 
Reading selections from "The Building of the Ship." 
Quotations from Longfellow's writings. 

FIRST PUPIL. 

When the wanderer, lonely, friendless, 
In foreign harbors shall behold 

That flag unfurled, 

Twill be as a friendly hand 

Stretched out from his native land, 

Filling his heart with memories sweet and endless.— Patriotism.. 

SECOND PUPIL. 

Though the mills of God grind slowly, 
Yet they grind exceeding small. 

Though with patience he stands waiting, 

With exactness grinds he all. — Retribution. 

THIRD PUPIL. 
Intelligence and courtesy, 
Not always are combined. 
Often in a wooden house, 
A golden room we find. — Art and Tact. 

FOURTH PUPIL. 
When by night the frogs are croaking, 

Kindle but a torch's fire, 
Ha! how soon they all are silent 1 

Thus Truth silences the liar. —Truth. 

FIFTH PUPIL. 

Live I, so live I, 
To my Lord heartily, 
To my Prince faithfully, 
To my Neighbor honestly, 

Die I, so die I. — Law of Life. 

SIXTH PUPIL. 

K Henry Wadsworth Longfellow was born in Portland, Me., "The Forest 
," on the 27th of February, 1807. He died March 24, 1882, at Cambridge, 
sachusetts. </seg>


            <seg id="p027">/ 

HENRY W. LONGFELLOW 

From Pollard a Advanced Reader, published by the Wtrttr* PubtUUmf 
Houte. Chicago.</seg> 

            <seg id="p028">
MOUNT VERNON 

Copyright 1898 by A. W. Elton dt Co., Boat on. 

From a carbon photograph from a negative directly from original, published 
by A W Elson &amp; Co.. Boston. </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
225 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

8EVENTH PUPIL. 

I When he was fourteen, he entered Bowdoin College. White then he 
Le to his father, "I will be eminent in something. I hare a moat voracious 
etite for knowledge. To its acquisition, I will sacrifice everything 

EIGHTH PUPIL. 

¦At the age of nineteen, he was appointed Professor of Modern I iiigiisges 
iowdoin College. To prepare for this position, he spent three jreen hi 
ly in Europe. 

NINTH PUPIL. 

¦At 27, he accepted a professorship in Harvard University. He made Me 
e in Cambridge, in the "Old Craigie House," which had been the bmh 
Washington, when he took command of the army. 

TENTH PUPIL. 

¦Among his lifelong friends were Sumner, Prescott, Hawthorne, Bmeraoa, 
ssiz, and Lowell. 

ELEVENTH PUPIL. 

He was a descendant of the John Alden and Priacilla Mullens, whose Irvea 
he wove into the beautiful Puritan romance, "The Courtship of Miles StaaaV 

TWELFTH PUPIL. 

Reading— Selections from "Courtship of Miles Standish." 

THIRTEENTH PUPIL. 
Two other loved American poems are "Evangeline" and "Hiawatha. 

FOURTEENTH PUPIL. ' 

Reading — Selections from "Evangeline." 

Singing -"The Arrow and the Song." 

FIFTEENTH PUPIL. 

He was early fond of reading. His favorite book was the Sketch Book of 
Washington Irving. He enjoyed only the best books of the beet authors. Y»» 
he wrote to his mother, "There is no book in which I read with so ararb aftterest 
and profit as one of your letters." 

SIXTEENTH PUPIL. 

Longfellow was the poet of every-day life. He is one of omt ass* pops)* 
lar poets. 

SEVENTEENTH PUPIL. 

All common things, each day's events, 
That with the hour begin and end, 

Our pleasures and our discontents, 

Are rounds by which we may ascend 
EIGHTEENTH PUPIL* 
Honor to those whose words or deeds. 

Thus help us in our daily needs. 

And by their overflow, 

Raise us from what is low. 

NINETEENTH PUPIL* 

He loved children, and was loved by them. He is called the poet of 
childhood. 

TWENTIETH PUPIL. 

Recitation— "Come to Me, 0 Ye Children." </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
226 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

TWENTY-FIRST PUPIL. 

He wrote his first verses at the age of thirteen. They appeared in the 
local paper. He was grieved to hear the criticism, " That poetry is very stiff. 
Besides, it is borrowed, every word." 

TWENTY-SECOND PUPIL. 
The heights by great men reached and kept, 

Were not attained by sudden flight; 
But they, while their companions slept, 

Were toiling upward in the night. 
TWENTY -THIRD PUPIL. 

Recitation—" Excelsior." 

TWENTY-FOURTH PUPIL 

Among the world's favorite poems are his, "The Village Blacksmith," 
"The Old Clock on the Stairs,'* " Paul Revere's Ride," "The Beleaguered 
City," and "The Footsteps of Angels." 

Recitation by School—" The Old Clock on the Stairs 

TWENTY-FIFTH PUPIL. 

Recitation—" Paul Revere's Ride." 

TWENTY-SIXTH PUPIL. 

After visiting the Arsenal at Springfield, Mass., he wrote — 
Were half th power that fills " the world with terror," 

Were hal the wealth bestowed on camps and courts, 
Given to redeem the human mind from error, 

There were no need of arsenals and forts. 

TWENTY-SEVENTH PUPIL. 

He had a generous nature. Nobody was ever turned away from his home 
with a heavy heart. "When I cannot help the one who comes to me in 
trouble," he said, " I always keep him to dinner, and try to send him away in 
good spirits." 

TWENTY-EIGHTH PUPIL. 

¦A schoolgirl, a stranger, wrote for an original poem. " I could not writ* 
said Mr. Longfellow, " but I tried to say ' no' so softly, that she would 
k it better than • yes '." 

TWENTY-NINTH PUPIL. 

Bin the height of his fame, when the great of Europe and America came 
is house, he could take time to go to the Police Court, to get the fines of 
or German woman remitted for stealing some apples. 

THIRTIETH PUPIL. 

When so busy with work that he rose at five o'clock in the morning, he 
could take time to send off seventy-five autographs, because he could make 
people happy by so doing. 

THIRTY-FIRST PUPIL. 

Where'er a noble deed is wrought, 
Where'er is spoken a noble thought, 

Our hearts in glad surprise, 

To higher levels rise. 

THIRTY-8ECOND PUPIL. 

His later years were brightened by many proofs of the children's affec- 

THIRTY-THIRD PUPIL. 

When he was seventy-two, a lovely present came from the school children 
of Cambridge, an arm-chair made from wood of the horse-chestnut tree, under </seg>


            <seg id="p031">
227 

to every child who came to see and sit in the chair. 

THIRTY-FOURTH PUPIL. 

Recitation— "The Children's Hour." 

THIRTY-FIFTH PUPIL. 

I The next year, fifteen thousand children of Cincinnati. celebrated ta» 
;'s birthday with recitations from his poems and ringing of hi* songs. H« 
te them to live up to the best that is in them, so that thrlr mnmi— nl mfrhl 
hat of Euripides. 

THIRTY-SIXTH PUPIL. 

KThis monument does not make thee famous, O Euripides, bat the* Mke 
monument famous." 

THIRTY-SEVENTH PUPIL. 

His marble image stands in Westmister Abbey, in the Poet's Corner; bat, 
better still, he lives in the hearts of the people of two haiai spheres. 

THIRTY-EIGHTH PUPIL. 

His songs have power to quiet, 
The restless pulse of care. 
And come like the benediction. 
That follows after prayer. 
Close with volunteer stories gleaned from the poet's life. 

—The Ttmthm* WoHd. 

0 * 

The Building of the Ship 

(Extract.) 

THOU, too, sail on, O Ship of State! 
Sail on, O Union, strong and great! 
Humanity with all its fears, 
With all its hope of future yean, 
Is hanging breathless on thy fate I 
I We know what Master laid thy keel, 
What workman wrought thy ribs of steel. 
Who made each mast, and sail, and rope, 
What anvils rang, what hammers beat. 
In what a forge, and what a heat 
Were shaped the anchors of thy hope ! 
Fear not each sudden sound and shock, 
Tis of the wave and not the rock; 
Tis but the flapping of a sail, 
And not a rent made by the gale! 
In spite of rock and tempest's roar, 
In spite of false lights on the shore, 
Sail on, nor fear to breast the sea. 
Our hearts, our hopes, are all with thee, 
Ou hearts, our hopes, our prayers, oar tears, 
Our faith triumphant o'er our fears 
Are all with thee; are all with thee. </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
228 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S' REPORT. 

Children 

COME to me, 0 ye children ! 
For I hear you at your play, 
And the questions that perplexed me 

Hare vanished quite away. 

Ye open the eastern windows, 
That look towards the sun, 

Where the thoughts are singing swallows 
And the brooks of morning run. 

In your hearts are the birds and sunshine, 
In your thoughts the brooklets flow, 

But in mine is the wind of autumn 
And the first fall of the snow. 

Ah, what would the world be to us 
If the children were no more? 

We should dread the desert behind us 
Worse than the dark before. 

What the leaves are to the forest 
With light and air for food, 

Ere their sweet and tender juices 
Have been hardened into wood, — 

That to the world are children ; 
Through them it feels the glow 

Of a brighter and sunnier climate 
Than reaches the trunks below. 

Come to me, O ye children ! 
And whisper in my ear 

What the birds and the winds are singing 
In your sunny atmosphere. 

For what are all our contrivings, 
And the wisdom of our books, 

When compared with your caresses, 
And the gladness of your looks? 

Ye are better than all the ballads 
That ever were sung or said, 

For ye are the living poems 
And all the rest are dead. 

a a 

The Children's Hour 

BETWEEN the dark and the daylight, 
When the night is beginning to lower, 
Comes a pause in the day's occupations. 

That is known as the Children's Hoar. 

I hear in the chamber above me 
The patter of little feet, 

The sound of a door that is opened, 
And voices soft and sweet. </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
PAUL REVERES RIDE 

By permission of Educational I'ublihinjf &lt;&lt;»n paov </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
THE LONGFELLOW HOUSE, CAMBRIDGE 

From the Children'* Se and Header, Cur, published by Oinn A Co. </seg>


            <seg id="p035">
SPECIAL DAY EXEKCI8B8. 

Prom my study I see in the lampUgtat, 
Descending the broad hall stair, 

Grave Alice and laughing Allegra, 
And Edith with golden hair. 

A whisper, and then a silence : 

Pet I know by their merry eye* 
:y are plotting and planning together 
o take me by surprise. 

A sudden rush from the stairway, 
A sudden raid from the hall I 

By three doors left unguarded 
They enter my castle wall! 

They climb up into my turret 

er the arms and back of my chair; 
I try to escape they surround me; 
They seem to be everywhere. 

They almost devour me with hi writ. 
Their arms about me entwine, 

Till I think of the Bishop of Bingen 
In his Manse-Tower on the Rhine. 

£o you think, O blue-eyed banditti, 
Because you have scaled the wall, 
ich an old mustache as I am 
Is not a match for you all ! 

I have you fast in my fortress, 
And will not let you depart, 

rit put you down into the dungeon 
In the round-tower of my heart. 

And there I will keep you forever, 
Yes, forever and a day. 

Fll the walls shall crumble to ruin, 
And moulder in dust away. 

* * 

The Arrow and the Song 

T SHOT an arrow into the air, 
X It fell to earth, I knew not where; 
For, so swift it flew, the sight 
Could not follow it in its flight. 

I breathed a song into the air, 
It fell to earth, I knew not where; 
For who has sight so keen and strong. 
That it can follow the flight of a song T 

tong, long afterward, in an oak 
found the arrow still un broke; 
.nd the song, from beginning to end 
found again in the heart of a Mead. </seg>


            <seg id="p036">
STATE sri'KRINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

The Old Clock on the Stairs 

SOMEWHAT back from the village street 
Stands the old fashioned country-seat. 
Across its antique portico 

Tall poplar-trees their shadows throw; 
And from its station in the hall 
An ancient timepiece says to all, — 
" Forever— never 1 

Never — forever ! " 

Half-way up the stairs it stands, 

And points and beckons with its hands, 
From its case of massive oak, 

Like a monk, who, under his cloak, 
Crosses himself and sighs, alas ! 
With sorrowful voice to all who pass, 

" Forever — never ! 

Never — forever ! " 

By day its voice is low and light ; 
But in the silent dead of night, 
Distinct as a passing footstep's fall, 
It echoes along the vacant hall, 
Along the ceiling, along the floor, 
And seems to say at each chamber door,— 

" Forever — never ! 

Never — forever I " 

Through days of sorrow and of mirth, 
Through days of death and days of birth, 
Through every swift vicissitude 

Of changeful time, unchanged it stood, 
And as if, like God, it all things saw, 
It calmly repeats those words of awe, — 

" Forever — never ! 

Never — forever ! " 

In that mansion used to be 
Free-hearted hospitality; 

His great fires up the chimney roared, 
The stranger feasted at his board ; 
But like the skeleton at the feast, 
That warning timepiece never ceased, — 

" Forever — never ! 

Never— forever ! " 

There groups of merry children played. 
There youths and maidens dreaming strayed ; 
O precious hours ! O golden prime, 

And affluence of love and time ! 
Even as a miser counts his gold, 

Those hours the ancient timepiece told, — 
" Forever — never ! 

Never — forever ! " 

From that chamber, clothed in white, 
The bride came forth on her wedding night; 
There, in that silent room below, 

The dead lay in his shroud of snow; </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
SPECIAL DAY KXKKCISES. 

231 

To the 

JWjrwugM, 

And in the hush that followed the prayer, 
Was heard the old clock on the stair,— 

" Forever — never I 
Never — forever ! " 

All are scattered now and fled, 
Some are married, some are dead ; 
And when I ask, with throbs of pain, 
"Ah 1 when shall they all meet again f " 
As in the days long since gone by, 
The ancient timepiece makes reply, — 

" Forever — never ! 

Never— forever ! " 

a 0 

From My Arm-Chair 

children of Cambridge, who presented to me, on my n i «•*/ mocmt MRM^, 
1879, this chair mad- from the wood of the Village PllOlnU— i*&gt; dMS*JS* BW. 

AM I a king, that I should call my own 
This splendid ebon throne? 
Or by what reason or what right divine, 
Can I proclaim it mine ? 

Only, perhaps, by right divine of song 

It may to me belong; 
Only because the spreading chestnut tree 
Of old was sung by me. 

Well I remember it in all its prime, 
When in the summer-time 

The affluent foliage of its branches made 
A cavern of cool shade. 

There, by the blacksmith's forge, beside the street, 
Its blossoms white and sweet 

Enticed the bees, until it seemed alive 
And murmured like a hive. 

And when the winds of autumn, with a shoot 
Tossed its great arms about, 

The shining chestnuts, bursting from the sheath. 
Dropped to the ground beneath. 

And now some fragments of its branches bars* 
Shaped as a stately chair, 

Have by my hearthstone found a home at last 
And whisper of the past. 

The Danish king could not in ail his pride 
Repel the ocean tide; 

But seated in this chair I can in rhyme, 
Roll back the tide of time. 

I see again, as one in vision sees, 
The blossoms and the bees, 

And hear the children's voices shout and call, 
And the brown chestnuts fall. </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
232 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Co 

bold. 

I see the smithy with its fires aglow, 
I hear the bellows blow, 
And the shrill hammers on the anvil beat 

The iron white with heat ! 

And thus, dear children, have ye made for me 

This day a jubilee, 

And to my more than three-score years and ten 
Brought back my youth again. 

The heart hath its own memory, like tne mind, 
And in it are enshrined, 
The precious keepsakes, into which is wrought 
The giver's loving thought. 

Only your love and your remembrance could 
Give life to this dead wood, 

And make these branches, leafless now so long, 
Blossom again in song. 

—From the Children's Second Reader, Cyr, published by Ginn A 

a a 

A Longfellow Exercise 

(Each pupil learns one of the following stanzas from Longfellow's poems and 
targe letter, printed on cardboard, In front of him and repeats his Terse.) 

LIFE is real ! life is earnest ! 
And the grave is not its goal. 
"Dust thou art, to dust returnest," 

Was not spoken of the soul. 

O STAR of strength ! I see thee stand 
And smile upon my pain ; 

Thou beckonest me with thy mailed hand, 
And I am strong again. 

NOTHING useless is or low, 
Each thing in its place is best ; 

And what seems but idle show 
Strengthens and supports the rest. 

QOD sent his singers upon earth, 
With songs of sadness and of mirth, 

That they might touch the hearts of me*, 
And bring them back to heaven. 

FOR, like strains of martial music, 
Their mighty thoughts suggest 

Life's endless toil and endeavor, 
And to-night I long for rest. 

EACH heart has its haunted chamber 
Where the silent moonlight falls ; 

On the floor are mysterious footsteps ; 
There are whispers along the walls. </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
233 


LABOR with what zeal we will 
Something still remains undone, 

Something uncompleted still 
Waits the rising of the sun. 

LTVES of great men all remind us 
We can make our lives sublime, 

And, departing, leave behind us 
Foot-prints on the sands of time. 

bFEAR not in a world like this, 
And thou shalt know ere long, — 

Know how sublime a thing it is 
To suffer and be strong. 

K speak of friends and their fortune* 
And of what they did and said, 
ill the dead alone seem living 
And the living alone seem dead. 

— Arranged by D. C. Murphy, in The Moderator. </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
234 

STATE SUPERINTKNDKNT'K REPORT. 

Eyecuttve Chamber, 
Xincoln, Hebraaha. 

proclamation bp tbe Governor: 

observance of Arbor Day has contributed in the 
past in no small degree to the growth and improve^ 
ment of Nebraska's forestry and foliage. It has 
transformed vast expanses of prairie into picturesque woodland, 
increasing the landscape beauty of the state and making 
it more desirable for those seeking opportunities for investment, 
and affording comfort and pleasure for those already 
here. This practice, which has added so much beauty and 
value to the state In the past, should not only be maintained 
in the future, but should be enlarged upon to the greatest 
practical extent. On each recurring Arbor Day every citizen 
of Nebraska should add at least one tree to our forestry and 
foliage, which shall serve the double purpose of being both 
commemorative and beneficial— commemorative of the mental 
genius of our distinguished citizen, Hon. J. Sterling Morton, 
author of Arbor Day, and beneficial in the way of increased 
comfort and value. 

By authority vested in me by law I therefore do hereby 
proclaim and designate Monday, April 22, 1901, as Arbor Day, 
and I earnestly request of the citizens of this State and all 
school children, to observe this oscasion by the planting of 
trees and beautifying shrubbery. 

In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto subscribed my 
name and caused to be affixed the Great Seal of the State of 
Nebraska. Done at Lincoln, the capital of the State of 
Nebraska, this fourth day of February, in the Year of Our 
Lord, 1901. 

Governor, 

CHARLES H. DIETRICH 

Attest 

GEO. W. MARSH, 

Secretary of State </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
235 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

PROCLAMATION-ARBOR DAY 

EXECUTIVE CHAMBER 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA 

1 VIRTUE of the authority vested in me by law, I, Ezra P. Savage, Governor 
of Nebraska, do hereby proclaim Tuesday, April 23od, IMS, 
Day. 

Eie extensive use of timber in manufacture and in public and private 
vements is, and for some years has been, a heavy drain upon forest 
ces, and unless expansion along this line keeps pace with (levaatatfoa. 
s consequences mast ultimately be the legacy. 

i Forestry is both useful and ornamental. While, strictly •peaking, for 
1 may not be indigenous, still splendid results have attended every annual 
effort to develop our resources in this respect. Experience baa deitrated 
that tree culture may be prosecuted a* successfully in Nebraska 
i any of the so-called timber states. Both soil and climate are adapted 
For this reason there should be no relaxation in the planting of treea. 
i succeeding Arbor Day should add at least a half-million trees and 
bs to our woodland estate. It means wealth, picturesqaeaeaa. and com 
and eventually will be a powerful magnet in the attraction of capital 
population to Nebraska. 

In the observance of Arbor Day on this occasion I do earnestly and respectfully 
request that the day be specially observed by the children of taw 
public schools and by citizens generally, and that in addition to faithfully diecharging 
the obligations of Arbor Day a tree be planted commemorative of 
our late and greatly beloved president, William McKinley. A MeKinley 
memorial tree will furnish food in after years for both solemn and impressive 
reflection, and will be a merited tribute to one who daring hit Hfe 
exhausted his best efforts and taxed his best energies to promote the welfare 
an i happiness of his country and countrymen. 

¦In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and eanaed the 
a seal of the state to be affixed. 

Done at Lincoln, this 15th day of March, A. D. 1902. 

By the Governor, 

EZRA P. SAVAGE 


' W. MAHB. </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
236 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

*T*HE erasure of forests and groves from the lands of the United States is 
X nearing completion. All over the globe hillsides, valleys, and plains are 

being rapidly denuded. The consumption of forest products increases 
each day. During the last twenty-five years the vast pine forests of Michigan, 
Wisconsin, and Minnesota have vanished from view. The ax and the 
saw no longer find destructive employment within the dense forests of those 
states. Every twenty-four hours the American people consume the wood 
products of more than 25,000 acres of forests and groves. 

i[n view of these stupendous and startling facts, it behooves all citizens, 
:ially teachers, to try to find a way of preventing entire forest denudation 
e globe. The esthetic side of arboriculture has been illuminated in the 
als and the literature of the country on every Arbor Day since 1872, when 
anniversary began its beneficent career. Therefore, the opportunity for 
itilitarian in tree-planting and tree-conserving has arrived. The woodi 
still left to us must be conserved. Waste places must be reafforested. 
y intelligent American farmer must plant a reasonable area of his lands 
rest trees. He must also carefully prune and care for whatsoever he may 
left to him of woodlands. 

At the risk of parading a personal experience, to be characterized as 
egotism by critics, I briefly give the narrative of my own care of native forests 
and of the planted trees at Arbor Lodge. 
In June, 1855, 1 became a squatter upon a quarter section of land now 
known as Arbor Lodge. Out of }60 acres then claimed there were between 50 
and 00 acres of brush and indigenous forest trees. Carefully the brush along 
the ravines and creek was cleaned out. The better shaped young trees were 
properly pruned. The old and decaying trees were cut down for fuel. For 
45 years the trees upon the area named,- together with trees planted and 
trimmed in orchards and in rows along drives, have furnished abundant fuel 
for domestic purposes and likewise thousands of fence posts for use about the 
place. The quarter section of land was selected because I thought that the 
timber growing upon it would in time more than pay the price I gave for it, 
which was $650 for the squatter's right to take the land and become a preemptor, 
and then $200 more in gold,- or $1.25 an acre, paid to the Government 
of the United States for a clear title, when the land office opened at Omaha 
During these 45 years (now nearly 46 years), it is within bounds to say 
that, with the furnace, range, and open fire grates, there has beep consumed 
each year $200 worth of fuel. This makes an income from the original patch 
of native timber, which has been properly conserved, of $9,000. And it is most 
agreeable to my judgment as to the possibilities of our native growths, to 
¦tote with great satisfaction, that there is more good timber in that grove today 
than there was when I first saw it. 

In cutting out I have always first taken the dwarfed, maimed, or decaying 
tree* of all varieties, and secondly, the pig-nut hickory. My experience proves; 
that by careful and judicious management, a few acres of woodlands may be 
perpetuated as fuel-and-post-producers generation after generation. 
Planted groves may be made very useful and cause rough and untillable </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
THE LATE HON. J. STERLING. MOKTOV PATHS) </seg>




            <seg id="p045">
237 

SPECIAL DAY EXKSCI8BS. 

planted in rows running north and south, four feet apart — the HI nv Besaa^ 
of cotton wood, the next row of black walnuts, white oaks and snHlbark hiekory. 
and the third row of maple or box elder ( or, better «till , of oatalpa saeasoaa &gt; 
will make through the right sort of thinning-out pmm, within §ve year* 
from their planting, sufficient fuel for an ordinary household. 

Ill groves should be planted in rows running north and soath. T*e hard 
i must be planted between the rows of soft wood* whieh are gwiiwBy 
ly growing trees. Thus the swiftly growing tree* becoaM dotm far the 
f growing nut-bearing trees between the rows. All trees reara apaajd) 
?ht, and when they are shaded from the eastern sun in taw montag aai 
estern in the afternoon, they make a much mom rapid and rifforno* apgrowth 
than when they stand out in the open plain rarrounded by aaaall 
day. 

These hints are thrown out hastily, as the Honorable 9npertniaadeat of 
Public Instruction, Mr. W. K. Fowler, well known, because of a harry-up 
telephone message received from him this afternoon. My intent in, if posefate, 
to arouse practical men and women to the vast important-* of forest eoa**rvation 
and arboriculture in Nebraska and everywhere throagaoat th* United 
States. J. STBHJM Mmmsj. 

Arbor Lodge, Nebraska City, Neb., January 29, 1901 

a 0 

Why Do We Observe Arbor Day? 

¦ OUR relatively new country this may arise. 
In the same line we may ask : 

Why did Alexander the Great plant with his own hand* hundreds of tret* 

¦early every province of Rvssiain Europe ? 
Why did Charles II plant wffh his own hands nearly every tree la the 

avenue at Windsor? 

Why did George III have such a mania for tree planting? 

Why did Queen Victoria personally superintend the planting- of ova? 

5,000 trees near London, and at places she visited ? 

Why has the Prince of Wales planted on public nrrssioas so many trss 

at home and abroad ? 

Why are so many great arborctums and parks of vast exteat msiatalar it la 

all parts of Europe ? 

Why is every tree labeled with botanic and common name in pi 

gardens, parks, and even public avem 

Why are the elements of forestry and horticulture taught in the eoaaaoa 

schools of Germany? 

Why are so many forestry schools supported in every part of eoattessMal 

Euro'pe'f 

In all cases the purpose is to create a public senttaiaat favorable la tsaa 

planting, and to familiarize the people with the best apse tea aad varieties of 

trees and the best modes and methods of planting aad msnaaiaf them. 
During the past century the rulers and educators of Ttarope, from the 

king down to the common school teacher, have kept before the people taosa 
few primary facts in regard to trees, that our commerce, home •betters. 

furniture, machines, landscape effects, depend upon tree planting and foraaS 

preservation. $ 

Only this constant education of the masses would permit the mainteaaare 

of the rigid forest Iaw3 of nearly all continental Europe. 

RIt has been said that the Europeans may disagree on question* of polities, 
;ion, etc., but on the forestry question, from prince to peasant, ther asjrso 
at least 33} per cent of the entire area of the country mast be kept la 
&gt;er blocks properly distributed for economic iw» and climatte aflMt. </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

238 

This public education also renders possible the system of fruit trees by 
Ifee roadside, the beautiful little park and flower garden at the railway station, 
and tree and shrub groupings and effects everywhere, such as we cannot 
reach with our present public sentiment. 

KTo us this work is new. With a forest wealth in extent and number of 
table species not excelled on the earth, the first moves in the occupation of 
continent have been in the way of wasteful forest destruction. 

K3ut a new era is dawning. In many ways that cannot here be enumerwe 
hare commenced the good work which a century of growth has made 
y complete in parts of Europe.— J. L. Budd, Ames, Iowa. 

a a 

Springtime 

Air— "Auld Lang Syne," 

THE winter storms have passed away, 
And springtime now is here 
With sunshine smiling all around, 

And heavens blue and clear. 

The gifts of Nature brighten earth, 
And make her garden gay; 

They give a cheery greeting bright 
On this, the Arbor Day. 

The birds with gladsome voices sing, 
Each its melodious lay, 

And music swells each little throat 
On this, the Arbor Day. 

The trees put forth their greenest leaves 
On this, the Arbor Day, 

And welcome now the chosen tree 
Which we shall plant to-day. 

— Ellen Beauchamp. 

a a 

The Gourd and the Palm 

(A Persian Fable.) 

«ITOW old art thou?" said a boastful gourd, 
11 As o'er the palm tree's crest it poured 
Its spreading leaves and tendrils fine, 

And hung a bloom in the morning's shine. 
"A hundred years!" the palm tree sighed; 
"And I," the saucy gourd replied, 
"Am at the most a hundred hours, 

Yet overtop thee in the bowers!" 

Through all the palm tree's leaves there went 
A tremor of self-content. 

"I live my life," it whispering said, 
*• See what I see, and count the dead ; 

And every year, of all I've known, 
A gourd above ray head has grown, 
And made a boast like thine to-day: 
Yet here 7 stand— but where are they T" 

— Light* to Literature, by Rand, Me Sally &lt;t 0». </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
SPECIAL DAY KXKRCIBES. 

239 

A Useful Gift 

ONE day wee Willie and hi* dog 
Sprawled on the nursery floor 
He had a florist's catalogue, 

And turned the page* o'er. 

Till all at once he Rave a spring, 
" Hurrah ! " he cried with joy; 

" Mamma, here's just the very thing 
To give your little boy! 

" For when we fellows go to Tirhffttl, 
We lose our things, you know; 

And in that vestibule 
They do get mixed up so. 

" And as you often say you can't 
Take care of 'em for me, 

Why don't you buy a rubber plant 
And an umbrella tree ? " 

—Caroline WelU, in 91. JWrtriat. 

a a 

When the Green Gits B&amp;cK in the Tree* 

Ethe spring when the green gits back in the trees, 
And the sun comes out and stays, 
nd your boots pull on with a good tight nqoeese, 
And you think of your barefoot days; 

Ehen you ort to work and you want to not, 
And you and your wife agrees 

r's time to spade up the garden lot — 
When the green gits twk on the trees. 

Well, work is the least of my ideea 

I When the green, you know, gits back on the trees. 
lien the green gits back in the trees, and bees 

Is a-buzzin' aroun' agin, 

tthat kind of a " Lazy-gb-as-you-pl— tt' 
Old gait they hum roun' in ; 

rhen the ground's all bald where the hayrick Mood 
And the crick's riz, and the breeze 

C&gt;axes the bloom in the old dogwood, 
And the green gita back in the trees — 
I like, I say, in such scenes as these, 

The time when the green gits back in the trees. 

r~hen the whole tail feathers o' winter time 
Is all pulled out and gone, 

fad the sap it thaws and begins to climb, 
And the sweat it starts out on 

r feller's forrerd, a-gittin' down 
At the old spring on his knees — 

I kind o' like jes' a loaferin' roun' 
When the green gits back in the Uees 
Jes' a-potterin' roun' as I-durn-please, 

When the green, you know, gits back in the tows. </seg>


            <seg id="p048">
240 

Oi. A. X Cj bU x t*rv 1^ A Ej^i J_/J*jW A O KtPORT, 

Motion Song--The Trees' Story 

BY THE PRIMARY CLASS. 

Tune— "Comln' Thro* the Rye." 

*t *HE trees lift up their branches tall ; 
X Their leaves dance in the breeze; 
"Oh, ho!"' they sing, "for what care we? 

We're living at our ease." 

But presently the woodman comes, 
With axes sharp and bright, 

And choosing him a tall pine tree, 
He works with all his might. 

"Oh, see! the tree is falling now," 
It lies upon the ground; 

The axes cut off each twig and bough, 
And round it chains are bound. 

Two horses pull the tree along 
Until a stream they find, 

On which the tree floats to the mill, 
Where waits the miller kind. 

He lays the log before the saw, 
And back and fourth it goes, 

Until the mill is full of boards 
That lie in long white rows. 

And then the children's father buys 
Shingles and beams and planks, 

To build his house for which we must 
Give tree and woodman thanks. 

— Grace Butterileld, in Little Men and Women. 

# * 

Song of Dedication 

Air— 'Colombia, the Gem of the Ocean." 

THE tree we are planting this May day 
Is chosen with tenderest care; 
May beauty adorn it hereafter, 

And clothe it with usefulness rare. 

May green leaves appearing each springtime 
Be leaves of a fair book of fame, 

And spread to the breezes the story 
Extolling the new-given name. 

The tree is an emblem of greatness, 
As, springing from one tiny seed, 

It mounts ever upward and onward 
An emblem of greatness, indeed ! 

The birds sing the praises to others, 
The winds carry swiftly the tale, 

The tree is the monarch of forest, 
Of bill, valley, greenwood, and dale: 

em Beauchamp. </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
241 


The fie&amp;rt of* the Tree 

WHAT does he plant who plants a tree ? 
He plants a friend of sun and t&gt;ky; 
He plants the flag of breeze* free; 

The shaft of beauty towering high; 
He plants a home to heaven anigh 

For song and mother-croon of bird 
In hushed and happy twilight heard — 

The treble of heaven's harmor 
These things he plant* who plant* a tree. 

What does he plant who plants a tree T 
He plants cool shade and tender rain, 

The seed and bud of days to be, 
And years that fade and flush again 
He plants the glory of the plain; 
He plants the forest's heritage; 

The harvest of a coming age; 
The joy that unborn eyes shall see — 
These things he plants who plants a tree. 

What does he plant who plant* a tree ? 
He plants, in sap and leaf and wood, 

In love of home and loyalty 

And far-cast thought of civic good — 
His blessing on the neighborhood 

Who in the hollow of this hand 

Holds all the growth of all our land — 
A nation's growth from sea to sea 
Stirs in his heart who plants a tree. 

—Henry C. Bunner, in Tfcs OwM»rf 

a 0 

Italian Tree Day 

P.NS appreciate a good thing if it is American. Ov After dnr, 
has been a grand success in nearly every atate in the Union, I* 
adopted by them with even more official enthusiasm than with as. 
iter of public instruction, Professor Baccelli, has eatabHahftd "Tree 
1 the first ceremony was honored by the presence of the queen sjkf 
of 7,000 children took a part. These exercises mire of so smss) 
•e that the London Times' special correspondent telegraphed Mala to 
g English paper: 

"Rome, November 21. 

I" The interesting ceremony known as the ' Festa den albert,' or ' turn 
' took place this morning in the presence of Queen Marfrhertta oa the 
Latina. Some 7,000 children from various Roman schools took part hi 
•eremony, which consisted chiefly in planting a large iwahar of fWBM 
i. "Tree day' has been organized by Professor Baccnlli. minister of 
ic instruction, in order to instil into the minds of Itaiiaa ehJMns) 
rence tor, and a sense of the value of trees, and to stimulate the 
mting of trees throughout Italy. Professor Baccelli Jismn hearty 
Tatulations upon his public-spirited initiative." 

ESuch interchange of educational ideas can but do much to brine nation* 
sympathetic activities and unify their domestic purposes.— Jomrmml •/ 
¦Mm. </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
242 

8TATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

A Little Planter 

DOWN by the wall where the lilacs grow, 
Digging away with a garden hoe, 
Toiling as busily as he can — 
Eagr and earnest, dear little man! 

Spoon and shingle are lying by. 
With a bit of evergreen, long since dry. 

" What are you doing, dear ? " I ask. 
Ted for an instant stops his task, 
Glances up with a sunny smile, 
Dimpling his rosy cheeks the while; 
" Why, it's Arbor Day, you see, 

And I'm planting a next year's Christmas tree; 
For last year, auntie, Johnny Dunn 

Didn't hare even the smallest one, 
And I almost cried, he felt so bad, 

When I told him 'bout the splendid one we had 
And I thought if I planted this one here, 
And watered it every day this year, 
It would grow real fast — I think it might; 
(His blue eyes filled with eager light;) 
And I'm sure 'twill be, though very small, 
A great deal better than nothing at all." 

Then something suddenly comes between 
My eyes and the bit of withered green, 
As I kiss the face of our Teddy boy, 
Bright and glowing with giving's joy, 
And Johnny Dunn, it is plain to see, 
Will have his next year's Christmas tree. 

a 0 

Planting Trees 

(For four little boys.) 

FREDDY. 

IF we are all to choose and say 
What trees we'd like to plant to-day, 

Seems to me 
None can be 

Half so good as a Christmas tree! 
For surely even a baby knows 
That's where the nicest candy grows, 

Candy on a Christmas tree — 
That's what pleases me ! 

CHARLEY. 

Planted out 'twould never bear — 
But after all why should we care ? 

The richest thing 
Is what we bring 

From sugar maples in the spring. 
So, now I'll set a Maple here, 
For feast and frolic every year 

Sugar from a maple tree— 
That's what pleases me ! </seg>


            <seg id="p051">
SPF.i I A I. DAY EXERCISES. 

WILLIE. 

Sweets are good most any day, 
But as for trees, I'm bound to say, 

A shag -bark tall 
Is best of all 

When once the nuts begin to fall. 
And so a Hickory tree I'll set 
And piles of nuts and fun I'll get. 

Nuts from a hickory tree — 
That's what pleases me ! 

JOHNNY. 

I shall plant an apple tree, 
That's the best of all for me; 

And each kind 
To suit my mind 

On this one with grafts 111 bind. _3 
Ripe or green, the whole year through, 
Pie or dumpling, bake or stew, 

Every way I like 'em best, 
And I'll treat the rest! 

—Eudora 8. Bumttrad. 

a a 

Part Recitation with Motions 

(BY THE LITTLE ONES.) 

ALL. 

(Fingere tapping deska.) 

Patter, patter comes the rain, 
Over hill and over plain. 

FIRST ROW OF PUPILS. 

Clasp hands in front, raise them gradually, till ran circle Is fui»J»4J 

Higher, higher climbs the sun, 
Now our spring is just begun. 

SECOND ROW. 

Motion as If scattering seeds In aisles.) 

Scatter, scatter seeds once more 

Now that winter days are o'er. 

THIRD ROW. 

(Both hands on desks raised gradually to full length, all rows same i»ottoa) 

Upward, upward into light 

Creep the shoots, tall and upright. 

FOURTH ROW. 

(Motion : arms still raised, swaying from right to left.) 

Boughs are swaying to and fro, 
As the breezes come and go. 

FIFTH ROW. 

(Aims lowered gradually to desks; lingers moving to represent fluttering bloasoa*.) 

Blossoms sweet with perfume rare, 
Flutter down through soft warm air. </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
244 

STATE 5?TTPE^lTNTlJ*T^JT^inVP' fil "Ris^'Drf^ pt 

SIXTH ROW. 

(Hands raised as In the act of catching ) 
Now catch the fruit of red and yellow, 
In the fall when ripe and mellow. 

ALL. 

(Hands gently clasped as if guarding the seed.) 
"We guard the seed to plant next year, 
That fruit for all may then appear. 

— Journal of Education. 

a 0 

Arbor Day Exercises 

Decorations.— Secure stencils of the Charter Oak, Washington Elm, and California 
Giants. Draw in colors upon the board a border or branch of oak and. acorns, or pine and 
oooet. Upon rustic fruit-stands place ferns or palms. Hanging baskets of Tines at the windows 
add to the beauty of the room. 

Arbor Day Song 

Air, "My Bonnie." 

THE breezes of spring wave the tree-tops 
The flowers so sweet bloom again, 
O, joyfully birds sing of springtime, 

While flying o'er mountain and glen. 

Chorus : 

Sing here, sing there, 

Sing of the springtime to-day, to-day. 
Sing here, sing there, 
Sing of the springtime to-day. 
O, glorious country of freedom ! 

Our lives we will make pure and sweet; 
Thou givest to us this bright springtime 

With hearts full of love we now greet. 

Chorus. 

Then shout for the oak in the Northland 
And answer, O South, with the palm. 

And we who inherit this Union 
Sing. gaily our Nation's great psalm. 

Chorus.. 

Suggestive Poems 

Bryant.— Inscriptions for the Entrance to a Wood, A Forest Hymn, 
Among the Trees, Autumn Woods, A Winter Piece, The Planting of the 

Holmes.— Spring, Under the Washington Elm, Spring has Come. 

Longfellow. —An April Day, Spring, The Hemlock Tree, Selections 
\ Hiawatha's Sailing. 

Lowell.— To a Pine Tree, The Oak. The Birch Tree, Sunthin' in the 
Pastoral Line (beginning, " First comes the blackbirds," ending, " Barb'ry 
droops ito strings o' golden flowers "), The Maple. 
Whittier. — Funeral Tree of Sokosis, April, The Pine Tree, A Dream of 
Summer, The Mayflowers, The First Flowers. </seg>




            <seg id="p055">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES* 

245 

Historic Trees 

(Exercise for nine pupils 

FIRST PUPIL. 

We sing of trees, historic, old, 
That swayed before the breeze; 

No trees in cur broad land have seen 
More memorable deeds than these. 

The Charter O&amp;K 

\D PUPIL. 

A Royal Charter was obtained 
In sixteen sixty-two; 

The Colonies of Connecticut 
A bond of union drew. 

I Tien Andros came with sixty men 
The Charter to revoke, 

Brave Captain Wadsworth hid it safe 
Within the Charter Oak. 

-R.C.Adam: 

THIRD PUPIL. 

They love their land because it is their own, 
And scorn to give aught other reason why ; 

¦ shake hands with a king upon his throne 
think it kindness to his majesty. 

— Fitz-Greene Halleek. 

Elm at Philadelphia 

FOURTH PUPIL. 

Esnn, a treaty with Indians made, 
'Neath a spacious, tall elm tree, 

tVhile sun, moon, and stars endure, 
In peace we'll live with thee." 

riese were the words of the Indian chief, 
In sixteen-eighty-three. 

In Philadelphia this chartered right 
Was made 'neath a tall elm tree. 

FIFTH PUPIL. 

Long as thine Art shall love true love, 
Long as thy Science truth shall know, 

r&gt;ng as thine Eagle harms no dove, 
Long as thy Law by law shall grow, 

Lory? as thy God is God above, 
Thy brother every man below — 

So long, dear Land of all my love, 

Thy name shall shine, thy fame shall glow. 

—Sidney Lanier. 

SIXTH PT7PIL. 

I speak of the elm at Cambridge, 
Where Washington took command; 

tnd that vast army true and brave, 
Now liberty for our land. 

t'ith muskets clean and courage true, 
In seventeen seventy-five, 
ur men marched valiantly to fight, 

For Liberty each did strive. </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
246 


SEVENTH PUPIL. 

When the battle is won, 

And the land from traitors free, 

Our children shall tell of the strife begun, 
When liberty's second April sun 

Was bright on our brave old tree. 


The Apple Tree of Appomattox 

EIGHTH PUPIL. 

The Army of North Virginia 
Was yielded by Robert Lee 
In eighteen hundred sixty-five 

Near the famous apple tree. 

Near Appomattoi's old Court- House, 
Arms, artillery, all, 

Was ceded to Grant that April day 
With slavery's great downfall. 

NINTH PUPIL. 

The change for Which he prayed and sought, 
In that sharp agony was wrought ; 

No partial interest draws its alien line 

Twixt North and South, the cypress and the pine. 
The sword was sheathed; in April's sun 

Lay green the fields by Freedom won, 
And several sections, weary of debates, 
Joined hands at last and were United States. 


ALL REPEAT: 

Hurrah for the oak, the apple and elm! 
Hurrah for all these trees! 

No trees in our broad land have seen 
More starring deeds than these. 

(All sing to air " Battle Hymn of the Republic.") 
The beauty of the stately trees 
We sing aloud to-day. 
These stirring deeds of history 

In loving hearts shall stay. 
For peace and love and Union 
Evermore we now will pray, 

As we go marching on! 

Glory! glory! hallelujah! 
Glory! glory! hallelujah! 
Glory! glory! hallelujah! 
His truth is marching on ! 

— Ella M. Power$ </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

247 

Urili 

[The following may be given by six girls. Each wears a crown made of colored leaves 
•lit from paper). Around her waist she wears a bright scarf of scrim (of the color of th* 
•fwwn). In her hand each carries a branch of laurel.] 

of the color of th* 

FIRST PUPIL. 

Green crown and sash. 

A STATELY elm with leaves of green, 
O'er-spreading far on high 

Its canopy of fresh spring leaves, 

All hail the elm ! I cry. 

SECOND PUPIL. 

(Crown of pink and pink sash.) 

I'd crown the peach with blossom pink 

And fruit so luscious sweet; 
Bending low the pale pink buds 

Of the peach tree, I would greet. 
THIRD PUPIL. 

(Crown of white and white sash.) 

A crown for the cherry blossom pure, 

With its little petals, white; 
A pure white carpet nature dons : 
'TIS a rare and happy sight. 

POURTH PUPIL. 

Red crown and sash.) 

The early maples in the swamp, 
So bright, bo red are they, 
My eye delights to gaze on these 

Throughout the fresh spring day. 

FIFTH PUPIL. 

(Gray crown and sash.) 

And I the catkins seek and love 

With early buds of gray; 
Each silvery bud this new-born spring, 
Seems dearer every day. 

SIXTH PUPIL. 

(Yellow crown and sash.) 

The leaves of yellow birch I like, 
All fluttering in the breeze, 
Turning, twisting, chasing fast 

And quivering as they please. 
ALL REPEAT. 

We have a crown for every tree, 
And beg each tree to stay ; 

Our boughs, unchanging as our hearts, 
All wave this Arbor Day. 

I Music, "Marching through Georgia." Branches wave and the six girls march around 
circle, each depositing her bough on a rustic flower-stand. Sashes (which have been 
kbout the waist but loosely) are untied and grasped in the bands about six inches from the 
. All stand in line. Music changes to " Hail Columbia." 1. Sash held in front horizontanns' 
length. 2. Sash held against waist horizontally. Repeat four times. 3. Sash 
above the head at arms' length horizontally. 4. Sash resting on head, held horizontally, 
•at four times. 5. Hold sash perpendicularly at right side. 6. Sash raised horizontally 
e head. Repeat four times. I. Sash held perpendicularly at left side. 8. Sash ralsei 
:ontally at left side. Repeat four times. 

K Repeat the same motions while kneeling. Repeat first movement, followed by the third, 
times. Repeat second movement, followed by the fourth, four time*. Repeat fifth 
nent, followed by the seventh, four times. Repeat sixth movement, followed by eighth, 
tees. All rise, passing oat to music. </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
248 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

What We Owe Trees 

TXID you ever stop to think how much we owe to trees ? Let us see. 
mJ You have learned in school that trees purify the air by taking out of it 

gases which are hurtful to man, and also that they purify the springs of 
water at their roots; consequently you understand why it is that terrible 
fevers have so often followed the cutting down of forests in a new country. 
But do you know, too, that the health-giving quality of trees is only one of 
their many virtues? 

I Not the least of these is the prevention of floods, and the drouths 
h follow floods. You will wonder how this is. Now you know that if 
hang out a piece of wet cloth in the sun and wind it will become quickly 
The water in it has evaporated. So it is with the open spaces where 
s are no trees. And the moisture which has all at once been absorbed 
he air is discharged in torrents instead of in gentle rains, as would be 
»se if there were trees and it was absorbed gradually. Here again comes 
ae question of health, for floods and drouths are as hurtful to man as 
soil which suffers from them. 

B. way in which trees help us greatly, which is not often thought of, is, 
eventing so great extremes of heat and cold as there would otherwise be. 
geographies tell you how the ocean equalizes the climate of places upon 
; is upon the same principle that trees modify climate, though in a 
degree. 

I Their effect upon desert land should be spoken of as well. It has been 
id that, where trees have been planted to keep off the winds of the ocean 
i such land, in a short time crops could be raised. This is because the 
Is take up moisture very quickly. When they cease to blow, therefore, 
low less hard, the rainfall is increased. Indeed, it has been thought that 
1 the terrible Sahara desert itself , might be made fertile by planting trees, 
known that springs of water in the oases disappear if the trees are for 
reason destroyed, and also that new springs appear in the spots where 
¦ have been made to grow. 

None, perhaps, can appreciate so fully their loveliness and charm as those 
who have crossed the desert plains of the great West. How the passengers 
on the overland train crowd about the little plats of grass (carefully guarded 
&gt;n fences), where trees are growing, while such exclamations as "Oh! 
don't they look good?" "How it rests one to see those trees!" "I never 
appreciated trees before ! " are heard on every side. 

Now of their use as homes for birds and animals. 

I See that nest on the top bough ? Hear those robins twittering from the 
j r sprays above our heads, while from bough to bough dart the nimble 
rrels, peering at us with sharp eyes as much as to say, — "O,.you poor 
&gt;le, you have to be shut up in boards and bricks and roofings. You are to 
itied ! Don't you envy us, and wish you were as free as we ? " And the 
Jpecker taps, taps away on the old trunk industriously getting his dinner, 
these, our lesser brothers and sisters, would be bereft indeed were they 
ived of their leafy habitations ! — Eleanor Root. 

a a 

Carl Morton's Orchard 

rHE death of Carl Morton, which has caused so much sympathy to go out 
from the people of Nebraska to his bereaved father, recalls the beautiful 
incident recently recorded by J. Sterling Morton in the Conservative 

¦ once reprinted in these columns. It was entitled " His Orchard ": 
It was a bright, balmy morning in April more than a quarter of a century 

ago. The sun was nursing the young grass into verdure, and the prairie was 
just beginning to put pff its winter coat of sombre colorings. Tranquil skies </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
249 


and morning mists were redolent at Arbor Lodge of the coming resurrection 
of the foliage and flowers that died the autumn before. All about the cottage 
home there was hope and peace; and everywhere the signs of woman's watchful 
love and tidy care, when suddenly, toned with affectionate solicitude, 
rang out: 

i"Carl, Carl! " but no answer came. Down stairs, up stairs, at the barn. 
. in the well, everywhere, the mother's voice called anxiously, again and 
a. But the silence, menacing and frightening, was unbroken by an anfrom 
the lost boy. At last, however, he was found behind a smoke house. 
ly digging in the ground with a small spade, though only five years of 
and he said: " I'm too busy to talk. I'm planting an orchard," and sure 
igh he had set out a tiny seedling apple tree, a small cottonwood, and a 
I elm. 

¦The delighted mother clasped him in her arms, kissed him and said: 
lis orchard must not be destroyed." 

And so now 

" I hear the muffled tramp of years 

Come stealing up the slopes of Time ; 
They bear a train of smiles and tears 
Of burning hopes and dreams sublime." 

I The child's orchard is more than thirty years of age. The cottonwood is 
ant now, and its vibrant foliage talks, summer after summer, in the evenbreeze 
with human-'.ike voice, and tells its life story to the graceful, swayelm 
near by, while the gnarled and scrubby little apple tree, shaped, as to 
lead, like a despondent toadstool, stands in dual shade, and bears small 
}t apples, year after year, in all humility. But that orchard must not be 
royed. It was established by the youngest tree planter who ever planted 
lis tree planter's state, and for his sake and the memory of the sweet soul 
nursed and loved him, it lives and grows, one cottonwood, one apple tree, 

" But O, for the touch of a vanished hand, 
And the sound of a voice that is still." 

Ee memories that live and bloom in trees, that whisper of the loved and 
summer leaves, are as imperishable as the seasons of the year — imas 
the love of a mother. — Nebraska State Journal. 

0 0 

An Arbor Day Symposium 

r] submit herewith the views of many of the state superintendents of 
our beloved country on the subject of Arbor Day, written expressly for 
this publication by request of the state superintendent of Nebraska. 

The ingenious teacher can use these expressions in an exercise, representing 
a Congress of these states, with each state represented by a pupil who shall 
express the views of the superintendent of his state. Nebraska's representative 
may act as chairman, reading the Governor's proclamation, or come in 
in alphabetical order, using a part of the Hon. J. Sterling Morton's excellent 

0 0 

Arkansas 

FHE groves were God's first temples," and, to the lover of nature, 
nothing is more restful, more suggestive of that quiet dignity, ana 
power, and grandeur that should mark the highest type of human 

kind than a brotherhood of venerable trees. 

In the springtime, when the woodland sprites are clothing the forests in 
vernal foliage, and the life-bearing current is forcing its way through trunk, </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
250 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

and branch, and twig, they tell of the glorious dawn of nope that springs 
from the source eternal and kindles anew in every aspiring breast the desire 
to do and dare and rise triumphant from the ashes of defeat. 

* -In summer, when sun, and wind, and storm, have added new strength and 
beauty to their growth, they show forth the power that unity and steadfast 
purpose have in developing, by slow degrees, all that is best and noblest in 
our being. 

I When autumn colors, by unseen artists used, have tinged their leafy garb 
i most varied and attractive hues, and boughs are bending 'neath the fruitof 
which the early blossoms gave fair promise, in voiceless, yet eloquent 
sal, they urge that man shall strive to be rich in yield of fruit as fair, when 
«rn suns mark his declining years. 

I When winter, cheerless and sombre, wraps their forms and leaves them 
if t of all that erstwhile made them so rich in beauty and so freighted with 
wealth of yet unfathered harvests, they bid us learn of them; so that, 
n, earth's labor over, we, too, shall stand stripped of all that wealth, or 
th, or beauty gave, ready to be ushered into the great beyond, others shall 
ler inspiration from our labors, now ended, and life's highest aim to them 
1 be to bless and benefit the time and place that know them. 

J. J. Doyne. 

0 0 

Colorado 

XJTOW much of our enjoyment of nature and our appreciation of its beauty, 
XX how much of the universal exhilaration in the abounding life of spring, 
are due to the trees it would be impossible to estimate. Let us not 

neglect the cultivation of the aesthetic and moral perceptions of the subject, 
while impressing the practical. 

I A great, refining, ennobling influence is brought into a child's life with 
enthusiasm for planting, tending, and watching the growth of flowers, 
s, and trees, and sympathetic inspiration to such work on the teacher's 
can hardly fail to communicate this enthusiasm. 

Mrs. Helen L. Grenfell. 

a a 

Florida 

tITH her princely pines and tropical tangles sunny Florida joins the Arbor 
Day procession. Her children are learning to love this day because 
it brings them closer to the "Great Heart of Nature" and helps them to 
and appreciate the boundless profusion of vegetable beauty with 
i she is blessed. They love to plant trees that the state may become 
more beautiful as time goes on; they love to care for them, for in the 
ction of the weak and helpless they learn true manliness and woman- 

Florida greets her sister states and joins them in "Long live Arbor Day." 

Respectfully submitted to Hon. W. K. Fowler in response to his request 
of Jan. 81st., with all best wishes for the success of his laudable undertaking. 

Wm. N. Sheats. 

J* J* 

Georgia 

rJOR Day in this state occurs in October. On the last Arbor Day oar 
children planted nut trees, pecans, walnuts, hickory, etc. The iiita 
was to give the children a notion of the value of these trees as fruit 

was to give the children a </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
251 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

A single pecan tree in the southern part of this state will yield some 
years as much as $60.00 worth of fruit. An English walnut will be perhaps 
equally as valuable. We hope in a few years to have not only the benefit of 
the shade of these trees during the warm 'lays of spring and summer, but we 
desire that the children may enjoy their truit in the autumn. 

G. R. Glenn. 

J* jft 

Illinois 

XTJTHY not have a small tree nursery connected with your school ? Get per- 
WW mission of the directors to fence off a corner of the school grounds for 
that purpose. Prepare the ground with intelligent care. Plant seeds 
of the elm, maple, wild cherry, oak, and walnut as soon as they ripen. Sow 
thickly. Thin them out when necessary. Cultivate them as you would a garden. 
Study them as they are growing. This is the way to know, and one way to 
learn to love trees. By-and-by you can supply young trees for "Arbor Day" 
to all the neighborhood. Plant trees, and protect their growth. You will 
thereby increase the wealth of the State and reform and ennoble the lives of 
her children. " Plant; Life does the rest! " 

I Your Arbor Day will not be a complete festival if you forget the birds 
flowers. If the groves were " God's first temples," the birds must surely 
) been the first choristers, and the good "Autocrat" said that "The 
ml of Nature is always a flower." Plant flowers, then, and teach the 
iren tocare for them, and to welcome and protect those most sensitive and 
itiful of all nature's children, the singing birds. Make your Arbor Day 
aval instructive, inspiring, ennobling, and follow it up by a more intelli; 
and loving study of Nature in all her varied forms. You can do the 
e no higher service. Alfred Bayliss. 

*&gt;* 

Indiana 

rHE observance of Arbor Day in the schools of the country is partly the 
result of a codviction that in the education of children something more 

tthan a knowledge of the text-books is necessary. Nature is a wonderorker, 
and no one can watch her and learn of her ways without realizing 
she has much to teach that cannot be found in books. The time was 
l it was thought that all education came through the study of books, but 
it is almost universally recognized that one may know a great deal of 
s and yet have missed some of the best things in education. Too many 
le go through the monotony of their daily occupations without seeing 
ieauty that not only brings cheer but gives wisdom. Such persons do not 
i how to aid nature in keeping the world beautiful, but often retard her 
oing injury to trees, plants, and shrubs. They are unconscious of the 
ir that lies in a lovely flower, a stately tree, or a graceful vine, to influlife 
and mold character. 

t Arbor Day has come again to remind us that we can do much to make the 
es about us more attractive. If we all make an effort to place trees, 
lbs, and plants into the school grounds, it will be only a few years until 
s of the yards which are now desolate will be transformed into places 
;h all will admire. When we have done our part, and the branches of the 
3 begin to spread themselves, even a very little, the birds will come, and 
n they are sure that they can stay with safety, nests will be built. In at 
t one school yard in the United States squirrels play on the same ground 
i the children with no fear of harm. It is hoped that you will take an in-3t 
in the planting of trees, and that you will then tryto encourage th« 
s to build their nests near the school house. Frank L. Jones. </seg>

            <seg id="p062">
252 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Indian Territory 

*¦ *HE average Indian possesses a high regard for trees. He may be said 
M. to reverence them. He never destroys them except as he finds it neces- 

Ksary to use them. Neither does he look with favor upon the action of 
rhite man who relentlessly destroys the trees to make room for crops, 
noble red man sees in such acts the destruction of his hunting grounds. 

Kn his journeys, the Indian uses certain trees as guide posts ana they 
frequently used instead of corner stones, to define the boundaries of 
claims or tracts of land. The Indian considers trees as living, growing 
js, and when the avaricious white man destroys his forests, he feels lone- 
i — feels that some of his dear friends and associates are gone. 

Bfes, indeed, the Indian is heartily in favor of your Arbor Day movement 
hopes that the time will soon come when every paleface who cuts or 
T&gt;ys a tree will be required to plant another in its stead. 

John D. Benedict. 

a 0 

Iowa 

rOULD you rear a monument more noble than marble and more enduring 
than granite? Plant a tree that may furnish shade for the weary 
or fruit for the hungry in future years. 

"Heaven and earjh will help him who plants a tree; 
And his work its own reward shall be. 

May the spirit of Arbor Day pervade the entire year, and may we all be 
stronger in heart and purpose for its proper observance. 

Richard C. Barrett. 

* * 

Kansas 

A RBOR DAY should be appropriately observed by the schools. Children 
./^ should be taught to plant trees upon the schoolhouse grounds, and at- 

tention should be called to the many beautiful lessons that nature 
teaches us. The schoolhouse grounds and the immediate surroundings 
should be made as inviting as possible. It requires but very little effort to do 
this. Unfortunately many schoolhouse grounds are bleak, and barren, and 
without a tree or bush. Such conditions should not be allowed to exist. A 
few trees not only afford shade for the pupils, but give relief to the landscape. 
Nature's beauties are God's imperishable gifts to the children of men. I 
firmly believe that we should not only encourage the children to plant trees 
on Arbor Day, but we should teach them to care for them in order that they 
may "grow and grow all the summer day." Frank Nelson. 

a 0 

Maine 

¦pHYSICAL surroundings are either a means of grace or the efficient cause 
X of degradation. Groves were God's first temples, and trees are God's 

greatest silent teachers. 
What the local community does for the local school is worth more than all 
that can be done for the school by the State. Our interest depends largely 
upon our efforts and sacrifices. We have talked too much about the school; 
the schools will be better when we do enough for them so that we talk about </seg>


            <seg id="p063">
I 

1 

5i </seg>

            <seg id="p064">i 

&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p065">
253 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

Maryland 

TkTEBRASKA is the mother of Arbor Day. She can with peculiar appror^l 
priateness celebrate its next observance by rendering a program which 

Iis more than local in its make-up, and which will arouse national inter- 
Maryland schools share the spirit so manifest in Nebraska to increase 
tsefulnsss of Arbor Day celebrations. Aside from any consideration of 
' beauty and comfort, the trees of our schoolhouse grounds are factors 
h enter into the healthfulness of the school locality. It is a well-known 
that the tree feeds upon the gases and poisonous matter exhaled from the 
an lungs. They rob the air of these impurities and make it fit for our 
Is' use. We should protect them and increase their number if for no 
r reason than from the health standpoint. We can hardly dissociate 
. the care of the tree, the protection of our birds. The school children 
I take up and carry on this important work also. M. B. Stephens. 

J. J. 

Massachusetts 

VE spirit of Arbor Day is that of a deep love for trees — a love that includes 
their beauty on the one hand and their service on the other. This lore 

has a thousand aspects and a thousand degrees, for the beauty and the 
service that call it forth are as varied as the trees that grow and the needs of 
earth and man to which they so admirably minister. There is the beauty of 
the stately pine, the rugged oak, the graceful elm. There is the service of the 
fragrant eucalyptus that brings health to the deadly Campagna, of the versatile 
palm that makes habitable the waste places of the tropical belt, of the 
humid forest that holds back the waters of the rainy season to bless the dry that 
follows after. The problems of the trees are also wiihout number. There is 
the problem of the East — to save its forests where now they abound. There is 
the problem of the West— to make forests abound where now they are unknown. 
A forest murderously ruined by the lumberman's axe is like a field of battle 
when the fighting is over— a sight to make humanity weep. Not so the 
forest that springs into life from the treeless plain. And so the mission of 
Arbor Day varies as the trees themselves. One blessed thing, however, is 
common to all the Arbor Days of the land we love, and that is the spirit to 
make the most of God's useful and beautiful trees. Frank A. Hill. 

m a 

Michigan 

IHE planting of trees on Arbor Day should be, and is an exercise of vast 
importance, not only from an economical point of view, but in the 
stimulating of a spirit of patriotism shown by the earnest thoughtfulfor 
the generations to follow; but it should be remembered that there is 
• virtue in keeping a tree alive after it has been planted, than in the first 
ting. If pupils in our publio school are allowed to neglect a plant reng 
attention, water to drink, food to nourish it, they are learning lessons 
h dull the sensibilities and lower the moral standard, the effect of which 
be felt throughout life. 

Kam most heartily in sympathy with, and am glad to encourage your 
Dblob Pall. 

j* o* 

Minnesota 

/"• KN IAL sunshine and gentle showers are calling forth the slumbering bud 
vJ and the vernal green. The robin is here to greet and serve us. The thrush 

and the oriole will shortly'join him, and they will come again and again to </seg>

            <seg id="p066">
254 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

I ten our people with their song, so long as there are trees to nest in and 
a to cheer. Providence did not intend that any portion of this fair state 
irs should become or remain a treeless waste, mute to Nature's cheeriest 
i. We have hill and dale, upland and meadow, myriads of lakes, 
ms and purling brooks, all set in a garniture of trees, and flowers that 
I unrivaled on the continent. Let us preserve and enhance our beauinheritance. 


Greed and ignorance have conspired to partially denude our forests and 
our woodlaud, but an intelligent, home-loving people have already done 
much to clothe our prairies and beautify our homes with Nature's shelter. 

Gov. John Lind. 

Jl Jk 

Missouri 

EHOUSANDS of rural schools in Missouri are located on beautiful blue 
grass lawns, shaded by hardy native forest trees. Many school premises 
are on bleak prairies, unprotected from heat or storm. Our children are 
rally lovers of nature, and are learning, in regular school lessons, to 
tify school grounds. 

I Missouri has an association of boys and girls known as "Vine, Vegetable, 
Flower Growers." As results of this movement, both school and home 
nises have been greatly ornamented by growing vines on porches, fences, 
s, and stumps; many waste places, more particularly at home, have been 
rerted into gardens, and nice crisp vegetables put on the market by chill 
ten and twelve years old ; potted plants adorn the windows of schools and 
ies in fall and winter, and their yards in spring and summer. 

W. T. Carrinoton. 

* * 

New Jersey 

To the School Children of Nebraska: 

IT AM glad that through the courtesy of your state superintendent, I am to 
X have a word to say to you on Arbor Day. The importance of this day is 

now so generally recognized that it is observed in the schools of nearly 
every state and territory in the Union, and you have learned to look forward 
to it with increasing interest and pleasure. The trees are indeed most valuable 
to us. Throughout the year they bring us kindly ministries. 

Though indebted to the trees for so much, it seems to me that while caring 
for them we should also have a thought for those who are both their friends 
and ours. I am sure you will agree with me in thinking that the birds are 
faat as near and dear to us as the trees, and that it is also our duty to do all 
that we can to protect them. They not only appeal to what is best in us and 
serve to strengthen our love of the good and beautiful, but add much to the 
brightness and cheer of our daily life. They also help us all they can in our 
warfare against the insect pests which do more or less harm to about everything 
that grows upon the lawn, the farm, or in the garden. 
When the birds are such good friends of ours, what a strange and 
unnatural thing it is for any of us to be enemies of theirs ! How cruel for 
any of us to rob or tear down a nest built with so much labor and care ! To 
deaU'Oj the home in which they expected to rear their little ones and which 
is lust as dear to them as our homes are to us ! How wicked for anyone 
with sling-shot, toy rifle, or firearms to kill them ! To take the one glad, 
tree, precious life to them given ! 
What a shallow and heartless vanity to wear the feathers, the wings, 
and sometimes the entire plumage of our most beautiful and useful birds as 
ornaments. Those who do so, not only advertise their approval of their 
merciless slaughter, but furnish its direct cause. Those who make the 
demand are more than equal partners in guilt with the hunters, who provide 
the pitiful supply. </seg>

            <seg id="p067">
255 


Ah: life, ami joy, and song, depend upon it. 

Are costly trimmings for a woman's bonnet." 

Bf the wholesale destruction of our feathered frieftw is to continue, the 
will soon come when you will no longer be waked 'by bird-song in the 
ing, and when you shall stroll through the fields and woods the brigh 
lappv form of life which gives them their greatest charm will be absent. 

I[ have however great hopes for the birds, if all the boys and girls in oar 
ic schools shall take a proper interest in them and learn to appreciate 1 
' beantv and usefulness. This would srive these most beautiful, innocent, 
helpless of God's creatures at least one champion and friend in mrailj 
y home. 

As your state was the first to establish Arbor Day, I hope it may also to 
the first to require the observance of Bird Day in connection with it. 

¦With best wishes for the welfare of both the birds and you i sel Ma, and 
for the success of your exercises on Arbor Day. C. J. Baxter. 

* # 

New York 

A KBOK DAY has been very generally observed in this state for the past tea 
/\ years, and I have every reason to believe that its observant*? has been of 
great value to the commonwealth. While the immediate result* 
planting of trees and the beautifying of school grounds have exceeded aw 
expectations; 1 believe that the real value of Arbor Day exercises is the 
cultivation, in the rising generation, of a love of Nature and an appreciation 
of the value of trees and plants. 

I confidently expect that the near future will see a large increase in the 
number of citizens who are warm advocates of a state system of fortify, 
carefully planned to protect our rich agriculcura' region* from the losses now 
so prevalent from occasional drought. In addition to this practical application 
there necessarily comes an immense amount of good tn oar people 
from the ethical development that accompanies a love of tree and •' 
and shrub, a culture and refinement so necessary to soften the anperttiea 
incident to American rush for wealth and position. 

ClIAKT.r." I! 

North Carolina 

rset apart a day to be observed by pupils as "'Arbor Dny" » eaji 
nentiy fitting as to the participants but a lesson of great utility topairo— , 

Kvery refined instinct responsive to Nature's hamwt— . every ioM&lt; 
impulse and hope for coming generations, every consideration of iatemat 
calls for the observance of a day on which attempt is warts to raatava 
pristine beauty, comfort and usefulness to land denuded of its •rtgfcaaj 
growth and covering. Earnestly wishing you sacews, 1 asm, You 


¦» * 

Oregon 

I F "he who lias made two blades of grass grow where only one grew laifasa" 
I is to be deemed a public benefactor, what is to he said of him wao 

B makes a tall tree to bend its leafy boughs where nothing bat rtaptiaass 
1 sway before? 

Within him shall grow up a deep satisfaction. As every twig str*tea#» 
itself into the air, as every leaf bad swell &lt; hefon 
more and m &gt;re, the blessedness of his earlv purpose When tarrmighty, 
protecting tent above him he shall feel that he has Welpetl t • re»li»» 
the world's great plan of life and growth, that he is. in&lt;l </seg>

            <seg id="p068">
256 


Pennsylvania 

rHE benefits which result from Arbor Day are easily shown. The observance 
of this day has led to the planting of millions of trees. It has 

made the rising generation familiar with the uses and the charms of our 
forests. It has drawn attention to the value of trees for shade, for fruit, and 
for the arts. Very many of the pupils of our public schools have learned how 
the reckless and wanton destruction of forests may ruin, and has ruined, 
some of the richest countries on earth. They have learned that coal and 
water are the chief sources of the mechanical power which lies at the basis of 
oar industrial prosperity. They have been taught that the vegetable growth 
in geological ages was transformed into the coal, which is so useful in the 
warming of our houses, in the preparation of our food, in the lighting of our 
cities, and in the running of our machinery. They have been taught the relation 
of trees to our water supply, without which neither man, nor his crops, 
nor his beasts of burden can survive. They have been taught that a sufficient 
flow of water can only be preserved by preserving the forests on our hillsides 
and mountain tops, and that the roots of the trees help to hide it away in the 
depths of the earth until it is needed. Nathan C. Schaeffer. 

j* J» 

Rhode Island 

it A R BOR DAY" is Natures day. Trees, shrubs and flowers all have a 
f\ place in it. And equally entitled to recognition in its festivities and 

K celebrations are the sweet-voiced inhabitants of tree and shrub. — the 
iful birds. Indeed, Mature is so much a unit, and so thoroughly at one 
herself, that it is practically impossible to approach her from anyone 
without being attracted and charmed by her manifold beauties. 

I The practical side of the subject, important as it is, has never appealed 
is so strongly as the sentimental or aesthetic. The fact of the almost 
•lute divorce of a large portion of human life from all contact with, and 
wledge of. Nature is forced upon us every day. Arbor Day, if rightly 
zed. may restore the union. To that end I welcome the day and give 

thanks for its institutiop. Thomas B Stockwell 

Jt Jt 

South Carolina 

»RBOR DAY is becoming more and more a part of the school exercises in 
our state. Our foremost teachers devote much time to it, imbued with 
the idea of the preservation of our forestry and the stimulation of a de- 

|&gt;n to trees and shrubbery. We are not very far advanced so far as results 
soncerned, for it is only within the past few years that we have been payattention 
to Arbor Day, yet some good has been done and the idea is 
ring, John J. McMahan. 

# * 

Wisconsin 

*T*HE observance of Arbor and Bird Day in the public schools has grown 
JL out of the conviction of the people that in the education of children 

something more is necessary than a knowledge of books. 

I This day comes just when the birds, following close upon the heels of the 
eating winter, seem in their glad notes to be exulting over the defeat of 
forces of the frost king, and the breaking of the icy fetters with which he 
bound the earth. At the same time they are sounding paeans of joy, over 
ire's new birth as shown in purling brooks, leaping rivers, and rippled 
«, smiling in the face of the springtime sun, like the smile of childhood 
?onsive to the mother's loving glance and caressing touch ; as shown by 
emerald green of grassy fields and leafy woods, and the unfolding flowers 
ch, like gems of beauty, dot hillside, plain, and valley, bursting into 'ife 
er the magic touch of spring. </seg>

            <seg id="p069">
257 

SPECIAL DAY EXEKCMM 

As the spring is the time of awakening life, the advance herald of tao fal 

rounded year, the budding promise of later fruitage, «o tb* otamm «f 

Arbor and Bird Day in the schools should be the oocisioa for the awakaaiag 
thoughts, ideals, and interests which shall unfold and ripen into aaaaar rwv - 

erence for life in its myriad forms, into w .lor sympathies, into gmttler atoa* 

ners, into lore of nature's beauties, and into nnhWnhjHBPUr A* tlM •prtag 

time is but the promise, the beginning of what the later year to to MM, m 
it must be followed by the heat and by the refraabiag rate* of saaaaar, Mi 
by the cool of autumn, so the exercises in the school on Arbor m4 BM Day 
should be but the promise, the beginning of what in to be reaooai ta th* 

child's development throughout trr 

The lessons and suggestions of this day are bat the sand* wafea awi tnr 

It unfolding, development, and final fruitage, the Ilia glilf rain and (to*warmth 
of intelligent, persistent effort by the milliiislsiili iialni ' '*¦»- 

lowed later by the cool reasoning which jnattftaia this appaa 

L. D. Ham 

# 

# 

Native Trees of Nebraska Worth.v illUsitlon. 

By Geokoe L. &lt; farrmn 

Division of Forest 17. 1° S. Department of Africa 

I REE planters am often prone to overlook the good qnaliti* - 
species. The purpose of this paper in to bring the n*»rit» "f Ik' 
ten native trees before thf [&gt;e&lt;&gt;]&gt; h th« boa* thai Um 
llent silvicultural properties of some 
1 may be better appreciate*! in the h ¦•l-r»-k» »mii« In h« law 
ing point of the tree floras of th« &gt;. Kaat •• 
itly the state is very rich in na 

|-.r 

State Board of Agriculture for I s -«oaa 
shrubs that are probably native to the state Of thi« llM. on 
regarded by the writer of sufficient hardiness or importaaa* &lt; 


E large scale. Boxelder, Cotton w. Ma le have 
se it is believed that these trees have been planted aim 
lance than is profitable. 

Black Walnut. 

l./uglant nigra 

I he Black Walnut is common in the oaatora aad ¦¦rtaira a»rt« of ib* 
in the river valleys. Its range fur economic planting aboaM h» Haritai 
r closely to the eastern half of the state, but may &gt;- dy 
west of this section in the Republican Kiver valley Tb* «n4l baat 
I for its growth is porous, alluvial loam containing a jwwi'l taaarjr of 
s. On the treeless plains, it should seldom bo a4aataamoaf* la law 
bottoms. 

The wood of the Walnut is rather heavy, moderately hard M 
very durable in contact with the soil. It has brcn asod mmwi im\y in ta» 
past for posts and fuel, but is becoming too valaabl* for mmHi asoa. FlraV 
class Walnut lumber retails at $100 per thousand ton ifhly »ria*rf la 
cabinet making. The standing trees in the plantation of Mr A J Aaslarson 
of Oakland. Nebraska, have made an annual growih for Um paal » vaara 
equal in value to the annual value of the average corn eraa taat eoald a* </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
258 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

grown on the same land. Two-thirds of the trees have been removed in 
thinning this plantation and no account has been kept of their value. This 
estimate is made upon the value of the timber for fuel and posts and not for 

I lie Walnut, in good soil, is a rapid growing tree. When it grows in 
ground, it forms a round head and branches profusely. If planted in 
proximity to other trees, it develops a tall, straight trunk, free from 
, and valuable for economic uses As the tree advances in rears, its 
if growth is retarded and its sapwood is gradually transformed into the 
valuable dark-colored heartwood. It requires from 60 to 100 years 
the time of planting to completely mature the wood of the Walnut, 
te life of the tree is much greater than this period. 

I 'his tree reproduces from seed. A plantation should be started from 
planted in the permanent site, rather than from transplanted trees. 
ig to the presence of a tap root the tree is not easily or profitably transed. 
The seed should be planted in the autumn or stratified where it will 
posed to freezing, and planted in the early spring. 

Bie Walnut is a light-demanding tree. It should be planted in mixtures 
ference to pure plantations. It will thrive associated with Kim. Oak, 
, Hickory, Locust, Ash, Pine and Red Cedar. 

Bed Cedar 

{Juniperu* virginiana.) 

Irhe Ked Cedar is the most widely distributed conifer in the United 
s, and is common in Nebraska, throughout the northern, central and 
¦rn parts of the slate. It has been largely eradicated from parts of its 
e habitat by the recklessness of man. It deserves to be planted exvely 
for economic purposes throughout the state. It is especially de^irfor 
a hedge or windbreak. 

Ehe soil best suited for its growth is retentive, clay loam. It can adapt 
to a great variety of soils and thrives on the sandy, alkali valley of the 
i River or on the loess buttes surrounding the headwaters of this stream 
s tributaries. The tree endures great extremes of heat, cold and drouth. 

I lie wood of the Red Cedar is light, fine-grained, soft, not strong, and 
lingly durable in contact with the soil. The timber is prized highly 
kilroad ties, telegraph poles. anH fence posts. It is used very extenin 
the manufacture of lead pencils. In its southern range, the Red 
sometimes attains a height of 80 feet and a diameter of 3 feet. Near 
rthern limit it seldom exceeds 30 feet in height. It is rapid growing 
e first 15 or 20 years of its life. 

|[t reproduces by seed. The germination of the seed is not easily 
red by the planter. Some successful growers of Red Cedar seedlings 
nmend that the '-berries" should be gathered in autumn and bruised 
mixed with strong lye or wet wood ashes. In three weeks the resinous 
ring will be decomposed and the seed should then be washed clean. 
¦ may be stratified for keeping or planted at once. The seed bed is 
:hed about 6 inches deep with old hay, and this mulch is kept on during 
irst summer after planting. The mulch is removed before the growing 
&gt;n of the second year The seedlings are kept from "damping off" by 
lkling the bed, early in the spring, with about a quarter of an inch of 
i, dry sand and covering the same with a tight roof for some weeks, 
young trees should be shaded until the latter part of the first season of 
- growth. Seedlings should usually be transplanted from the seed bed 
e end of the first year. 

The best method of starting a plantation is to secure trees once transplanted 
and plant these in th- forest site. The best size for this purpose is 
10 to 12 inches high The most favorable season for the transplanting of the 
Red Cedar in Nebraska is in May. If the planter will take up a ball of </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
SPECIAL DAY II II III I— ¦ 

259 

earth with the roots of the young tree, the cbaace* far sarrww will as 
Kly increased. The Red Cedar may be planted wither in p«ir«&gt; p mMmw 
mixtures. It thrives exceedingly well in nanlight bat will also ea*iars 
shade. Green Ash, Haekberry. and Oak make exreltoat aasnatsjsa tar 
ed Cedar. 

Rock IMne (Bull Pine, Pinu* ponderoaa of the ¦¦rssrta*. 

(Pinua pondrrota tcropulonm 

I be natural distribution of the Kock I'int- in th# f*aif*«i Mai' 
ghout the Rocky Mountain region. It m also found 10 la* ft 
n the prairies of Northwestern Nebraska exteadiag down the Miobrara 
,- more than half way across the state. It should he aiaatsd tar 
imic purposes throughout the state. The soil beat adapted for iu 
th is a dry, sandy loam. It thrives on very barren soil, bat will nnpiiad 
alacrity to improved surroundings. 

Il'hc wood of the Kock Pine is compact, rather hard, Mroag. na»-ied, 
and not durable in contact with the soil. It affords a T»ry gawd 
ity of general purpose lumber. This specie* is a very rapi 
he arid plains, it seldom attains a merchantable sis*, but ia IB* wsurs 
main ranges it develops a good-siaed bole aad attains a height »fN in 
feet. The Rock Pine reproduces by seeds which are easily eailssssd 
grow very readilv. The seed should be sown in the fall aad th* ysjas; 
ts should be shaded during the first season. The sssdltas* saaajM asabe 
transplanted when one year old in order to sabdae the lay mat, 
r the plants have been successfully transplanted one*. they raajMs* very 
i shade. The planter of this species will hare the bast •aeeaae by ptaat,he 
seeds in a seed bed, transplanting the trees in narerry mm at ta* 
of one year and growing them under intensive outturn until they af* 
b enough to be set in the forest site. The greatest dfawdvaatag* la 
Iling this Pine is iu Up root, which may be —bd— d by ropaatad masting. 


I The Rock Pine is a good tree to plant in pure plaaiatioa*. it bmt he 
intageously mixed with Red Cedar. Black Hills Banns, Orasa Ash. • ?•« 
kberry or Walnut. It is a light-demanding spselss aad ihsaH aat a* 
sd with broad-leaf species of morn rapid growth than imelf It shssjli 
&gt;lanted extensively in the sand hills of Nebraska aad Kaasas. 

Honey Locust. 

OUditna triacantho* .&lt; 

KThe Honey Locust grows native in the iniirhsssisi s ¦nssltss af ths 
t. It is usually found indigenous in rich river linllnis bat Its raas)s U&lt;r 
tomic planting embraces a large portion of the stats. It will grow sjssV 
ely well on the arid uplands of mid lie and western Nebraska. 

BThe best soil for its growth is alluvial Imm containing larg* naaatltiss 
rganic matter. It has been known, however, to thrive &lt;»n las Issss elay 
ch underlies a large proportion of the high prairie of ths stats, ll sadsjssa 
it extremes of drouth and heat. 

I The wood is heavy, hard, strong and fairly durable ia eoalast wiih Iks 
The bright, reddish-brown heart wood is rather uuaiss giatasd. aad hi 
:&gt;ted for posts,*fuel. and the manufacture of farm isialssjaats. Th* 
ey Locust is a rapid growing tree. When grown ia ths for** 
¦a'ight, tall trunk with a spreading top. Ths tree is asaally thorny hat 
eties are now propagated that are entirely thorn I—. 

KThe Honey Locust reproduces abundantly and easily from sssd. Ths 
; ripens in the fall and should be collected and utored dry aatil plaatiag 
) in the spring. Before planting, it should be pat into ssaMiag waMr. 
stirred until the water cools down to about HO degree* PahraaarH It </seg>

            <seg id="p072">
260 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

should then be allowed to remain in the water two or three days. The seeds 
that (well and rise to the surface of the water should be planted while yet 
moist and the remainder should be given another scalding. This process 
may be repeated until all the good seeds have swollen. 

A forest plantation of this species should be started from trees that have 
been grown in nursery rows. The fibrous root system of the Honey Locust 
adapts it peculiarly to transplantation. It is a light-demanding species and 
thrives well associated with the Elm, Hackberry, Spruce or Red Cedar. 

Green Ash. 

*. 

(FraxinuB lanceolata.) 

I The Green Ash is common along streams throughout Nebraska. It is 
of the most important trees in the prairie regions, and should be planted 
iughout the state. Its great hardiness adapts it for planting in soils and 
atious where scarcely any other broad-leaf tree will thrive. It has surd 
on many abandoned timber claims where other species have died. 

BThe best soil for the growth of the Green Ash is a heavy, stiff clay coning 
a large percentage of organic matter. It seems to prefer the alkali 
mbo" which is often found in low swales on western river bottoms. It 
make a fairly good growth on rather sterile soil, and for this reason it 
M-uliarlv adapted to planting on the arid western plains. 

I The wood of this species is hard, heavy aud strong, and rather coarsened. 
It is of use in the manufacture of agricultural implements, cares, 
and furniture, and may be substituted for White Ash timber to a large 
mt. It makes excellent fuel. In arid situations, the growth of the tree 
it rapid. Th&lt;s ability of the tree to adapt its rate of growth to inhosble 
situations is the quality that makes it so hardy. On fertile river valit 
grows very rapidly. 

The Green Ash reproduces by seed and coppice growth. The seed ripens 
in the fall and should be gathered as soon as ripe and planted or stored for 
keeping over winter. If stored the seed keeps best when "stratified" between 
alternate layers of s'ightly damp sand. It has been successfully kept 
over winter in a cool, dry place without being stratified. When stored dry, 
the seeds should be soaked in warm water for several hours before planting. 
The percentage of germination is not very high, hence the seed should be 
sown in abundance. The young seedlings are very susceptible to frost, and 
for that reason spring sowing is to be preferred. The planter should grow 
the seedlings in nursery rows and transplant them into the final forest site 
at the end of the first year. 

KSreen Ash thrives best when planted in mixtures with such trees as the 
or Hackberry. If planted in pure plantations the grove should be interred, 
at the time when tillage ceases, with Wild Plum, Choke Cherry, or 
Black Currant. These shrubs will endure shade and keep the ground 
from grasses and weeds. 

Slippery or Red Elm. 

'Elmv.it pubescens.) 

The Red Elm is found in the eastern half of Nebraska. It is very much 
lost abundant than the White Elm. It should be planted for economic purposes 
throughout the eastern half of the state. It makes its best growth on 
river valleys but will endure rather poor and sterile soil. In the most favorable 
situations it never makes as large a tree as the White Elm. 

¦The wood of the Red Elm is very much superior to that of other tnetni 
of its family. It is heavy, hard, elastic, strong, and quite durable in 
.act with the soil. It splits easily when green. The heart wood is brown </seg>

            <seg id="p073">
261 

SPECIAL DAY KXfCKCISBS. 

in color, and the layer of light-colored sap-wood is usually very thin. The 
wood of this species is used largely in the manufacture of farm impleweata 
and carriages, and for these purposes it is superior to Oak. It to am valnad 
for railroad ties, posts and fuel. 

It reproduces by seeds and coppice growth. The Maria arc hoc— to) 
great abundance and ripen in the late spring. The fruit of the Bad Ha 
should be collected as soon as ripe and planted immediately. TIm favaat 
plantation should be started from trees grown in nnnwry row*, and transplanted 
to the final site at the end of one year's growth In plaatiag tap 
seed of the Elm, the grower must be careful not to cover it too deep. 

The Red Elm is moderately tolerant of shade and i* a good tree to ptaat 
hi pure plantation* or mixtures. It will do well associated with the Wai a at. 
Locust, Haekberry or Kentucky CoftVetree. If planted in rloae plantation*, 
it develops a tall, straight bole free from limbs. It haa been n&lt; . 
tree planters and nurserymen. The rapidity of growth and the value of the 
timber of this tree should induce farmers to plant it on a large • -ale 

Kentucky Cofleetre*. 

(Qymnocladus dioieun.) 

Erhe distribution of the Kentucky Coffeetree is through the eastern third 
ebraska. It is a very rare tree. It should be planted I 
rn half of the state. It is a very hardy tn-f. of flow growth, aari far 
reason has been largely neglected by tree pla - pi ml— — law 
results on fertile river valleys, but will thrive on sandy or gravelly 

Eie wood is heavy, coarse-grained, strong, moderately hard, aad ilaracontaet 
with the soil. The sap-wood is thin ami the beartwomi. of a 
reddish-brown color, is very suitable for cabinetwork an'! 
The timber is but little known at present. The tree tommUmmm at 
a height of 100 feet and a diameter of 8 feet, bat in aetmNjr nrarh 

The Kentucky Coffeetree reproduces from seed whirh is home in pod* 
in great abundance by the pistillate individuals and ripens in the fa. ' 
forest plantation of this species should be started from tree* in&gt;» 
nursery rows The bony seeds need scalding, aa is the cane with tW Ho— y 
Locust, in order to insure germination. The seedling* should be traaaplanted 
into the forest site when one year old. 

The Kentucky Coffeetree is a light-demanding specie* and thrive* wall 
associated with Ash, Walnut, Hickory, Elm, and Oak. 

Bar Oak. 

(Quercu* macrocarpa. 

E'he Bur Oak is distributed throughout the eastern half of Nebraska It 
hardiest of the Oaks and deserves to be widely planted. It will thrive 
most any well-drained soil, but reaches its greatest perfection in Ike 
ie states, on fertile, alluvial river bottoms. 

Irhe wood of this species is heavy, hard, somewhat brittle, mart* gf alaad. 
durable in contact with the soil. It is used very largely aa a anbatitma 
iVhite Oak in the manufacture of machinery, carriage* aad fnrnitar*. 
valued for railroad ties, fence posts, and fuel. Under the ¦oat favor 
conditions this tree grows to be 100 feet tall and 4 or 7 fact is diaaMtar 

I The Bur Oak is a slow growing tree and for ibis reason it haa baaa very 
h neglected by tree planters. This habit adapts it to endure arid, in 
&gt;itable situations, and really constitutes its best qua ity It repmdao** 
i fruit and from coppice growth. The acorns ripen in the fall of the Ant </seg>

            <seg id="p074">
262 


Eand should be immediately collected and planted. The acorns are 
ntly infested with the larva; of insects and, if this is the case, they should 
ited with carbon-bisulphide before planting. The fruit should be 
d in the site where the trees are to grow, as the Oak is not easily transplanted. 
The Bur Oak may be advantageously associated with the Red 
Cedar, Rock Pine, Green Ash, and Hackberry. 

White Elm. 

(Elm.li* americana .) 

Ebe White Elm is common along the streams throughout the state. It is 
' the hardiest of our native trees. It should Be freely planted for 
mic purposes throughout the prairie regions. The best soil for its 
h is deep, rich alluvial loam, but it can adapt itself to very poor, 
i or dry situations. 

The wood of the young White Elm tree is not usually considered valuable. 
When the tree reaches maturity it affords timber that is used very 
largely instead of Oak in the manufacture of farm implements, carriages, 
and flooring. The wood is rather heavy, coarse-grained, tough, difficult to 
split, and moderately strong. Compared with Oak it is inferior. The tree 
on good soil is a rapid grower. On poor soil it adapts its rate of growth to 
the food supply, and for this reason it is an excellent tree for the arid western 
prairies. 
The reproduction of the White Elm is by seed which ripens in the spring 
and letains its vitality but a short time. The fruit should be collected and 
planted as soon as ripe. The trees should be grown in nursery rows and 
transplanted into the forest site when one or two years old. The White Elm 
is » good tree to grow in mixtures with Ash, Walnut, Honey Locust, or 

Hackberry. 

[Celtic occidentalit.) 

The Hackberry is common throughout the eastern and central parts of 
the state and is found along the Niobrara River almost to the Wyoming 
boundary. It is seldom found in great abundance, but grows scattered 
among other trees. It should be planted almost as extensively as the Green 
Ash. It is an excellent shade tree, superior to the Elm, and for that purpose 
it should have a wide distribution. The soil best suited for this species is 
deep, rich, alluvial loam. It will endure very barren, arid situations, and, 
for this reason, it should be planted on the arid western prairies. 

(The wood of the Hackberry is heavy, coarse-grained, somewhat brittle, 
of medium hardness. It is not durable in contact with the soil, but 
:es excellent fuel. This species reproduces from seed which is occasionally 
le in great abundance. The one-seeded fruit when ripe is a brownishale 
colored drupe, almost as large as a pea. The fruit ripens in the fall 
should be collected at once and stratified in moist sand or planted. The 
should be planted in nursery rows and the young trees should be carer 
tended until two years old, when they will be of the right size to transit 
into the forest site. 

P'he hackberry is an excellent tree for pure plantations, but since its 
sr is not valued very highly for anything but fuel, it is generally advisto 
associate it with some other species more valuable for commercial 
oses. It is tolerant of shade and will grow well under almost any of 
ight-demanding species. It may be advantageously mixed with Oak. 
Larch, Red Cedar, or Pine. </seg>

            <seg id="p075">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

263 

On Behalf of a Higher Civilization 

ARBOR DAY celebrations are instituted not to glory o*»r tfcsaaa 
achieved, but to consider and take heart for the achievement of thiaga 

we have neglected ; to create and stimulate proper ¦raitiirmt rsgaftfaaf 
our duties as true citizens in one particular direction, namely: To wi as 
enlightened consideration and treatment of trees and forests. 

KTo the man who bases his action on mere reasoning of cause sad «Mk 
sees that the enormous drain on our forest resources most soon exhaust 
rirgin supplies, that the denudation of hills and mountains leads to unesTwater 
stages, to deterioration of agricultural lands, who realties the great 
omic importance of a rational use of our forest resources, to him the idea 
¦medying the evil by Arbor Day celebrations appears indeed inadequate. 

I But the world is not moved as much by knowledge and re— osi as we arc 
to think. Our conduct, even in our individual lives, falls short of fuMDlthe 
dictates of knowledge and reasoning. Much less does our prugi— i *n 
•orate capacity as communities and states depend solely on the— attributes 
he mind. The great mass is moved by emotion rather than by reason, by 
heart rather than by the head, by sentiment rather than oy argument. 
Hence, reforms which appeal directly to our sentiments are comparatively 
ly accomplished, and even reform movements of an economic nature, saea 
be forestry movement, instead of appealing only to the judgment, will Sad 
Ivantageous to stir up the emotions, the interests of the heart, to sdMBja 
ser sentiment which leads to action. 

I; is for this purpose, I take it, that Arbor Days are instituted, namely, 
nulate our sentiment on behalf of a higher civilization, of better things, 
rase our feelings against existing abuses, and to create an appreriatioa 
se-growth, be it from an economic point of view or that of bp.uity . It is 
' designated to take your mind and heart away from the busy life, the 
w horizon between brick walls, into the forest, to contemplate its task, 
nsider its needs, to arouse in you a sentiment which win lead you to 
» co-operation in reforming our present treatment of the same. 

I There are two points of view from which we may look upon the fmesiif 
ement; the one which the thinking lumberman and forest owner would or 
lid take, considering only the perpetuation of supplies of useful material 
:h the forest resources yield ; and the other, a broader one, which ths 
esman and every patriotic citizen is bound to take in addition, namely, 
&gt;idering the role which the forest plays as a factor in our civilization, as a 
sral condition of our country, which, if altered in an irrational manner, 
iriably leads to the misery of the whole community. 

I /The fact that forest destruction has a most detrimental effect upon ths 
r of our rivers, upon the conditions of our agricultural lands, upon climate 
health to some extent, makes the forestry question one of general interto 
the community, and the fact that these influences upon other cultural 
ditions can rarely, if ever, concern the private forest owner who is interid 
only in the profit which he can draw from his property, makes it neess 
f lot the community itself, or its agent, the state, to look out for its own 
¦rests, present and future. For the state alone is as long-lived as ths 
¦st ; the individual lives for to-day, the community may even outlive ths 
Sequoias, and hence must guard the conditions of its future welfare. 

I There are many questions, commercial, financial, municipal, which 
ate the public mind, that if left alone either adjust themselves, or whose 
istment can be deferred without detriment. Whether the tariff be high 
&gt;w, whether gold or silver be the standard, whether we have a Lirge ship', 
fleet, or let the English carry our goods, these are all matters which we 
decide at any time, and any evil consequences resulting from a miitalna 
cy can be rectified in a few years. 

But whether the fertile lands are turned into deserts, forests into wasts 
places, brooks into torrents, rivers changed from means of intercourse and 
power into means of destruction and desolation, these are questions of much 
more immediate importance, which must be considered and solved at the 
proper time. As slowly as the evils of forest destruction become apparent, 
just so slowly only can they be repaired, and often they become irremediable. </seg>

            <seg id="p076">
264 


Delay in adjusting private and communal interests in the forest-cover 
invariably lead to disaster. All European nations have learned this lesson. 
They know that to leave the mountain forest unreservedly to the exercise of 
private property rights is bound to bring misfortune, not only to the mountains, 
but to the plains below, to the country in general. 

I Miserable farms, with more than half their agricultural soil lost by erofunowed 
and gullied and washed, all in consequence of irrational clearof 
mountains and hillsides, are found in all parts of the Union, and 
?ially in the Southern and Middle States; and in the Prairie States it is 
so well known that a shelter belt against the constant drying winds is a 
ome protection, that no advocacy for planting it should be needed. 

EJut while these protective featuies of a forest-cover are not to be under-1, 
it has also become plain that supplies of wood material, this most 
itial factor of our civilization next to food crops, are waning; that the 
¦al forests show signs of exhaustion and that a new crop must be started 
fostered. Arbor Days should be used to impress this fact upon the 
s of those who celebrate them. 

Ehe need of wood supplies is, indeed, more essential than the beauty, 
ment, and shelter which trees give. Trees must be cut as well as 
ited; and to be able to cut them in the future, more must be planted in 
•esent, more of the young crop, and a better kind of crop than nature, 
isted, is apt to grow, must be allowed to take the place of the old crop 
it has been used. 

B.s farmers are needed to produce food crops, so foresters are called for, 
&gt;duce wood crops, to celebrate, not Arbor Days, but Arbor Weeks and 
¦ Months, to devote themselves to the reproductien as well as the ratharvesting 
of wood crops. &lt;* 


New York State has made a beginning in that direction- by instituting a 
State College of Forestry, where all the technical details of the raising, treatment, 
and rational harvest of tree crops and the manner of managing forest 
properties for wood and revenue production are taught. And, that there 
should be not only preaching, but practicing, a large tract of forest land has 
been set aside, where the manner of harvesting the old crop and of starting 
the new croD is beinsr demonstrated. Last spring's "Arbor Weeks" have 
resulted on this tract in the planting of 95 acres of burnt over slash to pine 
and spruce, and the coming spring's "Arbor Weeks" will see 250 acres of 
ground from which the old, over mature wood has been removed so replanted ; 
and on an another 250 acres the young, volunteer growth will be allowed to 
preserve the forest by replacing the harvest of old trees. 

Thus Arbor Day, the beautifm festival, which is to inculcate appreciation 
of tree growth, has already borne practical economic results. 

B. E. Fernow, 

Director New York State College of Forestry Cornell University, Ithaca. </seg>



            <seg id="p079">
265 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

Bird Trades 

THE swallow is a mason, 
And underneath the eaves 
He builds a nest and plasters it 

With mud and hay and leaves. 

Of all the weavers that I know, 
The oriole is the best; 

High on the branches of the tree 
She hangs her cozy nest. 

The woodpecker is hard at work — 
A carpenter is he — 

And you may hear him hammering 
His nest high up a tree. 

Some little birds are miners ; 
Some build upon the* ground ; 

And busy little tailors too, 
Among the birds are found. 

— Lincoln Literary Collection. 
{By permission of The American 

Book 


# # 

Our Little Martyrs 

SHALL we care when nesting- time 
Brings no birds from any clime ; 
Not a voice or ruby wing, 
Not a single nest to swing, 
Midst the reeds, or higher up, 
Like a dainty fairy cup ; 
Not a single little friend, 
All the way, as footsteps wend 
Here and there through every clime, 
Not a bird at any time ? 
Does it matter? Do we care 
What the feathers women wear 
Cost the world ? Must all birds die ? 
May they never, ntver fly- 
Safely through their native air ? 
Slaughter meets them everywhere. 

Scorned be the hands that touch such spoil ! 
Let women pity and recoil 

From traffic barbarous and grave, 
A.nd Q\iicklv strive the birds to save. 

—George Klingle. 

I 

R 

D 

41 

DAY 

M A 

Y 

1 5 </seg>


            <seg id="p080">
- 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

My Robin 

WTIEN I was a child, beside our door, 
In a green and spreading sycamore, 

There sung each morning, with note as clear 
As a crystal brook, and full of cheer, 

A Robin. 

I watched his plumage in childish glee, 
And fancied he sang his song for me; 
And the melody lingers in heart and brain, 
Making me often a child again — 

My Robin. 

I look for his coming in early spring, 
When the crocus opens, and maples bring 
Their crimsdn tassels to kiss the breeze, 
And the sunshine dallies with new-leaved trees, — 

My Robin. 

I hear him sing as the sun goes down, 
And the stars come out o'er the silent town; 
But there's never a harsh or mournful note, 
That wells afresh from the warbler's throat, — 

My Robin. 

And I learn a lesson of hope and cheer 
That carries me on from year to year; 
To sing in the shadow as in the sun, 
Doing my part till the work is done,— 

My Robin. 

— Sarah K. Bolton 

* * 

Lost— Three Little Robins 

OH, where is the boy, dressed in jacket of gray, 
Who climbed up a tree in the orchard today 
And carried my three little birdies away? 
They hardly were dressed, 

When he took from the nest 
My three little robins and left me distressed. 

j'O wrens! have you seen, in your travels today, 
A very small boy, dressed in jacket of gray, 
Who carried my three little robins away? 

He had light colored hair, 

And his feet were both bare, 

And he was most cruel to me, I declare. 

O butterfly I stop just one moment, I pray; 

Have you seen a boy dressed in jacket of gray, 
Who carried my three little birdies away? 

From his pretty blue eyes 
One might think he was wise, 

But he must be wicked for one of his size. </seg>


            <seg id="p081">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

O boy with blue eyes, dressed in jacket ofgrayl 

If you will bring bark my three robins today, 

With sweetest of music the gift I'll repay; 

I'll sing all day long 

My merriest song, 

And I will forgive you this terrible wrong. 
Bobolink! did you see my birdies and me, 
How happy we were on the old apple tree, 

rl was robbed of my young, as you see? 
Oh, how can I sing, 

Unless he will bring 

My three robins back, to sleep under my wing ? 

— Lincoln Literary Collection. 

(By permission of The American Book Company.) 

* 4 

Birds' Nests 

*Y*HE skylark's nest among the grass 
A And waring corn is found ; 

The robin's on a shady bank, 

With oak leaves strewn around. 

The wren builds in an ivied thorn 

Or old and ruined wall ; 

rie mossy nest, so covered in, 
You scarce can see at all. 

The martins build their nest of clay, 

In rows beneath the eaves ; 

While silvery lichens, moss, and hair 

The chaffinch interweaves. 

The cuckoo makes no nest at all, 

But through the wood she strays, 

Until she finds one snug and warm, 

And there her eggs she lays. 

fie sparrow has a nest of hay, 
With feathers warmly lined ; 

Pie ring-dove's careless nest of sticks 
On lofty trees we find. 

IDoks build together in a wood, 
And often disagree ; 

The owl will build inside a barn 
Or in a hollow tree. 

The blackbird's nest of grass and mud, 

In bush and bank is found ; 

The lapwing's darkly spotted eggs 

Are laid upon the ground. 

The magpie's nest is girt with thorns 

In leafless tree or hedge ; 

The wild duck and the water-hen 

Build by the water's edge. </seg>

            <seg id="p082">
268 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

&gt; 

Birds build their nests irom year to year, 
According to their kind, — 

Some very neat and beautiful, 
Some easily designed. 

The habits of each little bird, 
And all its patient skill, 

Are surely taught by God himself 
And ordered by his will. 
— Lincoln Literary Collection. 

(By permission of The American Book Co 

# * 

A Lesson From the Sparrows 

I AWAKENED one morning early, 
The great city slept near by, 
And the first faint coming of daylight 

Flushed pink in the eastern sky. 

The cool, sweet breeze stirred gently, 
The trees had revived again, 

And they lifted their green, wet branches 
Refreshed with the cool night rain. 

Earth lay in a calm, still waiting 
Before it awoke to toil, 

And the new day breathed its blessing 
On the children of the soil. 

As the dawn grew clear and stronger 
And the rosy east grew bright, 

I thought of the hearts that still wished for 
The silence and peace of the night, — 

Hearts that were faint in life's battle, 
That had lost their faith and trust, 

That saw not the glory of living, 
But dragged out their lives in the dust. 

And lo ! as the sun rose brighter, 
From under the eaves T heard 

The first fain i twitter of rapture 
From the heart of a little bird ! 

And another and then another 
Caught up the joyful lay, 

And louder swelled the chorus 
As they greeted the new-born day. 

They were only the Father's sparrows, 
But they knew His tender care, 
For they fall not to earth without Him, 

Or flit in the sunlit air ! 

And I thought if we would but remember 
The same Lord guides our days, 

We, too, would greet each new morning 
With a p®an of joyful praise ! </seg>



            <seg id="p083">

CDITPT AT r» i V V Y K*R^T^U"^ 

A Nest in a PocKet 

¦ LITTLE bird went to and fro, 
In spring, the nesting season, 
And sought for shelter high and low, 

Until, for some queer reason, 
She flew into a granary, 

Where, on a nail suspended, 

The farmer's coat she chanced to see, 
And then her search was ended. 

The grain was heaped up to the loft ; 
There not a creature met her; 

The coat had hollows deep and soft — 
Could anything be better? 

And where it hung, how safe it was, 
Without a breeze to rock it! 

Come, busy little beak and claws, 
Build quick inside a pocket! 

Three speckled eggs soon warmly lay 

Beneath the happy sitter; 
Three little birds— oh, joy! — one day 
Began to chirp and twitter. 

And then— ah, can you guess the tale? — 
The farmer came one morning, 

And took the coat down from the nail 
Without a word of warning! 

Poor little frightened motherling — 
Out of her nest she fluttered, 

And each unfledged, small, downy thing 
Its terror piping uttered. 

The good man started back aghast, 
But merry was his wonder 

When, in the pocket, he at last 
Found such unlooked-for plunder. 

rie put the coat back carefully: 
" Tis well I have another; 

You need not be afraid of me, 
You bright-eyed little mother. 

I know just how you feel, poor thing, 
For I have youngsters, bless you ! 
There — stop your foolish fluttering — 
Here no one shall distress you." 

Then cheerfully he walked away 
To tell his wife about it- 

How in the coat the nestlings lay 
And he must do without it. 

She smiled, and said she knew he could, 
And so, all unmolested, 

The mother birdie and her brood 
Safe in the. pocket rested, 

Till all the little wings were set 
In proper flying feather; 

And then there was a nest to let, 
For off they flocked together. 

The farmer keeps it still to show 
And says that he's the debtor; 

His coat is none the worse, you know, 
While he's— a little better. —Lights </seg>

            <seg id="p084">
270 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Bird Game 

(Half of the children are to be birds, and each is to have a name— orioles, swallows 
rotates, etc. The other children take the part of boys and girls asking questions. All join in 
tkaohoros) 

CHILDREN. 

WHAT must you do this summer day. 
Summer day, summer day? 
Up in the trees in the sunshine gay, 
What must you do, little birdies? 

BIRDS. 

Build our nests on the elm tree bough, 
Elm tree bough ! elm tree bough ! 
See how fast we are working now, 1 
Building our nests, little children. 

CHORUS. 

Twittering, twittering, sweet and low, 
Twittering, twittering, as we go, 

Hark to the song of the birdies! 
Fluttering, 1 fluttering, to and fro, 
Fluttering, fluttering, swift or slow, 

See the dear little birdies! 

CHILDREN. 

What is the song you sing so sweet, 
Sing so sweet, sing so sweet? 
What are the words you all repeat, 
Merry and glad, little birdies? 

BIRDS. 

Twee! twee! twee! we are singing sweet, 
Tweet! tweet! tweet! tweet! tweet! tweet! 
Love is the song we all repeat ; 

Love is our song, little children 

CHILDREN. 

What will you do when the day is done, 
Day is done, day is done? 

What will you do in the setting sun? 
What will you do, little birdies? 

BIRDS. 

Fold our wings and sweetly rest,' 
Sweetly rest, sweetly rest. 

Sleep so safe in each tiny nest,* 
That's what we'll do, little childi«n. 

CHILDREN. 

Where will you go when tne summer goes, 
Summer goes, summer goes? 

Where will you go when the north wind blows? 
Where will you go, little birdies? 

BIRDS. 

Spread our wings 5 and away we'll fly, 
Away we'll fly, away we'll fly, 

Spread our wings and away we'll fly, 
Away to the South, little children. 

-Selected. 

1. Waring motion with both hands. 2. Hands above the head waving to and fro. 3. Hand* 
folded like folded wings. 4. Hands held in shape of nest. 5. Flying motion, arms outspread. 
-Primary Education/Tune, 1806. ' ~ </seg>

            <seg id="p085">
From Margaret Miller's " My Saturday Bird Clou," by perminion of 
D. C. Heath A Co 
</seg>


            <seg id="p087">
271 

SPECIAL DAY KXERCISES. 

I Used to Kill Birds 

1USED to kill birds in my boyhood, 
Bluebirds and robins and wrens, 
I hunted them up in the mountains, 

I hunted them down in the glens 
I never thought it was sinful — 

I did it only for fun — 

And I had rare sport in the forest 
With the poor little birds and my gun. 

But one beautiful day in the springtime 
I spied a brown bird in a tree, 

Merrily swinging and chirping, 
As happy as bird could be ; 

And, raising my gun in a twinkling, 
I fired, and my aim was too true ; 

For a moment the little thing fluttered, 
Then off to the bushes it flew. 

I followed it quickly and softly, 
And there to my sorrow I found, 

Right close to its nest full of young ones, 
The little bird dead on. the ground ! 

Poor birdies ! For food they were calling ; 
But now they could never be fed, 

For the kind mother-bird who had loved them 
Was lying there bleeding and dead. 

I picked up the bird in my anguish, 
I stroked the wee motherly thing 

That could never more feed its dear young ones, 
Nor dart through the air on swift wing. 

And I made a firm vow at that moment, 
When my heart with such sorrow was stirred, 

That never again in my life-time 
Would I shoot a poor innocent bird 1 

* * 

Franklin's Birds' Nest 

VKTE present herewith an illustration of a home-made bird's nest, now in 
jfjf the office of the state superintendent. Mr. Lew Franklin of Lincoln, 

Nebraska, has suggested that the cultivation of gourds be encouraged, 
and the gourds be utilized for birds' nests. Boys may be as easily interested 
in the manufacture of birds' nests as in their destruction. 

I The illustration above represents an old-fashioned, long-handled gourd, 
ng between two branches of a tree that extend one above the other; an 
ling about the size of a half-dollar is cut into one side just above the 
er for the entrance and exit of the bird. Two discs are used; one is 
wed to the bottom of the globular part of the gourd and to a block within 
nd the other is slipped down over the neck. The upper disc affords some 
ter from the rain and storms, and both furnish resting places for the birds. 
ie wool, cotton batting, straws, strings, etc., may be seen protruding 
1 the opening of the nest and lying loosely about on the discs. The 
rd is swung between two branches as some protection from the cats, 
s should be taught to act as foes and not as allies of the cats in these 
ters. "&gt; 

The cultivation of the gourd commenced in Asia and Africa long before 
the dawn of history. They were used for water bottles and for dishes. The </seg>

            <seg id="p088">
272 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

small, pear-shaped ones were used for ornaments, and others were used for 
lanterns. The French people used the seeds to flavor soups. Gourds were 
Benous to the American plains. In the early history of America, they 
used for the sake of economy; one was always at the spring or well for 
ing purposes ; larger ones were used for dipping boiling water, small 
, soft soap, apple butter, etc. Small one§jrere and still are used to place 
eking heels or toes when the stocking is required to be darned. 

We hope to see an immediate increase in the cultivation of gourds for 
on as birds' nests. 

Dear Love shall reign from East to West, 
And shall bring Peace from North to South; 
The timid bird shall build her nest 

In the grim and silent cannon's mouth. 

0 0 

Ten Things We May Do to Help 
Bird Life 

XpIRST— Set out about our homes and school grounds trees, shrubs, and 
M, other plants most valuable to attract birds and furnish them food from 
their fruits, berries, or seeds. 

Second - Scatter crumbs and grains where the birds can get them. 

¦Third —Place shallow dishes of water at convenient heights for the birds 
rink and bathe. 

Fourth— Place nesting material in their way at the time of nest building. 

¦Fifth — Where cats are kept, train them to keep away from nesting 
ons. 

Sixth — Watch for opportunities to help and protect the fledgelings until 
able to fly. Thousands of young birds every year leave their nests a day or 
two before their wings are quite strong and fall an easy prey to cats or other 
enemies. We can place them in a cage near the nest, and often the old birds 
will continue to feed them. If not, they should be fed and watered regularly 
about every hour during daylight until they become able to feed themselves. 
Caged birds should be liberated as soon as it is evident that they cannot be 
made happy and contented in captivity. 

t Seventh— Provide bird houses and sheltered nooks for the nests. Dr. 
ge says the proper size for a bird house is six inches square floor space 
eight inches high. A single opening near the top should be made two 
es in diameter for most birds, although for wrens, chickadees, and the 
Her birds, one inch i3 sufficient and will serve to keep out the English 
row. Houses may be made with several compartments of these propor- 

Eiohth— Arrange safe places of shelter about our houses and barns, in 
order to save as many birds as possible during the storms. 

K Ninth— Refuse to wear birds and their plumage that is obtained by 
ghter. If you must wear feathers, remember that made wings, quills, and 
ich plumes cost no bird its life. The wings are made from the feathers of 
s used for food. 

Tenth— If you have a bird to tame, place it in a clean cage, supply it 
with water and food for the first day, being careful not to frighten it. By the 
morning of the second day, when all the food in the cage has been eaten or 
removed, offer it suitable food on the end of a slender wand, perhaps several 
&gt;ng at first, and gently approach until the morsel is in reach of his bill. 
If he takes it, try another, moving up a little closer. If not, let his appetite 
sharpen a little, or get a longer stick. By this method and a little patience 
any young bird can, in three days, be tamed to take things from your hand.— 
Colorado "Arbor Day Notes." </seg>


            <seg id="p089">
273 

Topography of Bohemian 

Waxwing 

1 Upper Mandible. 
2 Oilmen . 

3 Nostril. 

4 Forehead. 
5 Lores. 

6 Superciliary Stripe. 
7 Crown. 

8 Crest. 

9 Occiput. 

10 Auriculars or Ear Coverts. 
11 Nape. 

12 Interscapular Region. 
13 Back. 

14 Scapulars. 
15 Tertials. 
16 Rump. 

17 Upper Tail Coverts. 
18 Tail Feathers. 

19 First Primary. 

20 Primaries. 

21 Tarsus. 

22 Hind Toe. 

23 Outer Toe. 

24 Middle Toe. 

25 Inner Toe. 

26 Abdomen or Belly. 

27 Secondaries 

28 Side. 

29 Greater Wing Coverts. 
30 Middle Wing Coverts. 

31 Breast. 

32 Lesser Wing Coverts. 

33 Carpal Joint. 

34 Jugulum. 

35 Throat. 

36 Chin. 

37 Gape. 

38 Lower Mandible. 

TYPES OF BILLS AND FEET 

39 Strongly hooked bill of Hawk. 
40 Falcate bill of Mexican Crossbill. 
41 Tubular nostril of Fulmar Petrel. 
42 Raptorial foot of Long Eared Owl. 
43 Lobate foot of Pied Billed Grebe. 
44 Palmate foot of Duck. 

45 Totipalmate foot of Cormorant, 
</seg>
            <seg id="p090">
274 


A Key to the Higher Groups of North 

American Birds 

r Birds with toes connected by web or membrane. 
6 All four toes so connected. — Pelicans and Cormorants, 
bb Only three toes so connected, or with feet lobed. 

c Nostrils tubular. — Petrels, Albatrosses, etc. 
cc Nostrils not tubular. 

d Bill either turned up or down. 

c Bill turned up, bird less than two feet long. — Avocet. 
ee Bill turned down, bird more than two feet long.— Flamingo. 

dd Bill neither turned up nor down, variously formed, 
e Feet webbed. 

/ Wings long, extending beyond tip of tail. — Gulls, Terns. 

ff Wings short, not extending to tip of tail. 
g Legs attached to body normally; bill serrated.— Ducks 

and Geese. 

gg Legs attached to rear of body; bill not serrated.— 

Loons and Grebes, 
ee Feet lobed. 

/ Tail very small, nearly absent. — Grebes, 
ff Tail present, well developed. 

g Bill strong, in color white.— Coots. 

gg Bill slender, in color black. — Phalaropes. 

AA. Birds with webbing between toes very slight or absent. 
b Bill strongly hooked. 

c Colors bright, fruit eaters.— Parrots, etc. 

cc Colors not bright, flesh-eaters. — Eagles, Hawks, and Owls, 
bb Bill not strongly hooked. 

c Hind toe small or absent, if present elevated. 
d Lower portion of thigh not feathered. 

c Bill slender, hind toe small or absent.— Plovers, Sand- 

pipers, etc. 

ee Bill not so slender, hind toe larger. — Cranes, Rails, and 

Gallinules. 

dd Lower portion of thigh feathered. — Grouse, Quail, and 
Turkey. 
cc [Hind toe well developed. 

d [Base of upper mandible with a soft swollen structure.— 

Pigeons, Doves, etc. 

dd [Base of upper mandible without soft swollen structure. 

e [Toes 2 in front and 2 behind, or else 2 in front and 1 

behind. 

/ Tail feathers stiff, bill chisel-like.— Woodpeckers, 
ff Tail feathers not stiff, bill not chisel-like. — Cuckoos, 
ee [Toes 3 in front and 1 behind. 

/ Feet small and weak. 

g Toes more or less grown together. 

h Bill small and weak. — Swallows, 
hh Bill long and strong. — Kingfishers. 

gg Toes not grown together. 

h Bill long and slender, colors bright. — Hum- 

mingbirds. 

hh Bill short, colors dull. — Nighthawks, Swifts, etc. 

tFeet larger and stronger.— Crows, Jays, Blackbirds, 
Shrikes, Sparrow, Wrens, Thruthet, Warblers, etc. 

0* XZVfUGf* </seg>

            <seg id="p091">
275 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES, 

The Bluebird 

XpEW, indeed, must be the boys and girls who are not acquainted with this 
JC beautiful harbinger of spring, and who do not look forward to its coming 

with the greatest eagerness. 

¦WTien he first comes, in the sunny days of March, his song is exceedingly 
and cheerful, as he sits on the topmost twig of a leafless tree, pouring 
ris little heart in the gladness of his return. 

In a few days, with the arrival of his more sober spouse, nest hunting 
begins and when a satisfactory site is chosen, work commences in earnest. 

I Although the birds are quite abundant about our towns, and even cities, 
le early spring, they are forced by the hordes of English Sparrows to 
their summer homes in the country where these pests do not venture in 
i numbers. So we must seek them in some box in a friendly farmer's 
lyard or in a deserted woodpecker's hole in a quiet shady grove or garden 
e post. After cleaning out the cavity a soft loose nest of dried grass is 
t within, and usually lined with a few feathers picked up about the barn-1. 
Then the fragile, sky-blue eggs are laid, one each day until four or 
are deposited in the nest. During the time of these labors the male enlins 
his mate by frequent snatches of song. Often he will bring a choice 
&gt;f grass or a feather or perhaps a fat juicy worm and turn them over to 
with many chirps and twitterings. 

B After about fifteen days of patient incubation by the male and female in 
i the queer, naked misshapen little creatures break from their shells and 
l their gaping mouths for food. 

Now comes the trying time for the parent birds; to obtain food for their 
young and to guard them from harm until they can care for themselves. The 
male has very little time for singing now, but joins the female in the hurried 
search for worms to fill the hungry little mouths. It seems as if they are 
never satisfied, but their growth is very rapid and before long black pinfeathers 
appear on the wings, head, back and where the tail will be. These 
soon develop into strong coarse feathers, whose shafts are surrounded by soft 
grayish down, which gradually disappears as the birds become strong enough 
to fly and partially take care of themselves. 
Two broods are raised in a summer and if the spring be very early even 
three, so you see there is little wonder that as summer wanes, saddened by 
the approach of grim old winter, and worn by the labor of feeding so many 
hungry mouths during the summer months, their song grows plaintive and 
sad. Still they linger with us through sunny September and crisp October, 
delaying their departure as long as possible, as if regretting to leave the 
places which are doubtless filled with happy memories for them. At last 
with a sad farewell song they launch into the air and begin their long flight 
to the sunny Southland where perhaps the boys and girls are looking for 
them as eagerly as we did in the early spring. 

M. A. Carriker, Jr. 

a 0 

What Our Birds Eat in Summer 

T&gt; Y ACTUAL observation 221 distinct kinds of birds are known to regularly 
Ij raise their young in Nebraska, while 60 others may do so occasionally. 
The nesting of all these birds within the state is very significant since it 
is during the growth of the young that a large amount of very highly nutritious 
food is required. From the standpoint of the farmer and fruitgrower this 
fact is of the utmost importance, because most young birds are fed almost entirely 
on an insect diet during the time spent in the nest and for a short time 
afterwards. The same can also be said of many of the birds that leave the 
nest as soon as hatched. Therefore during the growth of the young birds the 
quantity of such food which is gathered by the parent birds over the entire </seg>

            <seg id="p092">
276 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

state must be relatively enormous. Talcing as a basis for our estimations the 
figures given in my leaflet entitled "A plea for the protection of our birds" 
Irould have about 75,000,000 birds or approximately 35,000,000 to 40,000,000 
i that nest here. Should each pair of this large number rear four young 
s would be required a sufficient food supply for from 140,000,000, to 160\ 
XX) young birds alone. If, as we suggested in that paper, a single bird 
on an average 25 insects per day, the enormous number of four billions of 
:ts or 35,000 bushels of 120,000 insects would be required each day to 
the young birds alone. But young birds need much more food than do old 
, therefore we should at least double this quantity for the young birds. 
i to this must be added that required by the parent birds while taking care 
le young. Again estimating as above, the grand total of 86,000 bushels 
17 car loads of 20 tons each would be the required amount of insect food 
ur Nebraska birds during a single day, allowing 50 pounds for the weight 
bushel. — Lawrence Bruner, University of Nebraska. 

0 0 

Birds in Their Relation to Man 

*|*HE birds form a carefully organized army which is intrusted with the 
JL great task of policing the earth. They cone and go on the " wings of 

Kthe four winds" that they may the more readily perform their allotted 
Each species by nature has been assigned its special portion of this 
work, hence the various ways that different birds work and the widely 
lilar haunts frequented by them. It is by this means that the God of 
liverse has provided for the maintenance of an equilibrium in nature. 

Birds can be useful to man in many ways. They can benefit him by carrying 
the seeds of various plants from place to place so as to assist him in 
establishing new groves in which to find shelter from the cold of winter and 
a refuge from the broiling noonday sun in summer. They plant various shrubs 
by the wayside that spring up and later are laden with luscious fruit. They 
also carry the spawn of fishes and small crustaceans among their feathers into 
new waters, and feed upon the countless seeds of weeds that are scattered 
broadcast over the face of the earth . Some kinds live almost exclusively on 
insects, while others hunt out the small rodents that would, if left to themselves, 
destroy great quantities of grain and other vegetation. Still other 
birds benefit mankind by acting as scavengers in the removal of putrid and 
other offensive matter which would endanger our health. In addition to all 
these varied direct benefits which are brought about by the presence of birds, 
man is further indebted to these creatures for the cheer which their gay music, 
bright plumage, and pleasing manners bring to him. 

• 

ft would be ridiculous, on the other hand, for me to assert here that no 
injury ever results from the presence of birds on the farm or in the orchard. 
Quite a number of different species are continually stepping over to the 
wrong side of the "ledger," as it were, and committing depredations of 
various kinds which, if considered alone, would render the perpetrators liable 
to severe punishment — in some cases even unto death. Some of the crimes 
that can be charged to the feathered tribe are cherry and berry stealing, grape 
puncturing, apple pecking, corn pulling, grain eating, the unintentional carrying 
from place to place of some kinds of scale insects that happen to crawl on 

But we can go even further when summing up the benefits that man may 
derive from the birds. A great many kinds provide him with excellent food, and 
downy pillows, while others furnish sport and pleasure to a large number of 
men and boys who seem to require a certain kind of entertainment while 
accompanied with dog and gun. Dead birds, when embalmed as mummies 
and attached to the headgear worn by some girls and women, are also claimed 
to cause much happiness in the world. • ?* </seg>

            <seg id="p093">
277 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

their legs and feet, the possible spreading of hog cholera by crows and buzzards, 
the robbing of the poultry yard, and lastly some birds are accused of 
making noises that awaken us from our slumbers in the morning. 

A few of these crimes are genuine and are to be deplored, while others 
are more imaginary than real. A few of them could be prevented in part or 
altogether, while others might be diminished if we were inclined to take the 
trouble to do it. f 

After all that can be said pro and con, concerning the usefulness of birds 
in general, there remains no doubt in the minds of thinking people as to the 
value of these creatures. It is only the vicious, biased, and thoughtless persons 
who continue ruthlessly to destroy birds indiscriminately without first 
pausing to consider whether or not it is a proper thing to do, whether it is 
right or wrong. 

During the early days of the settlement of a country when the pioneer 
breaks up the virgin soil and sows his seeds, the fowls of the air come from 
the " four quarters of the globe" and devour that which is sown before it is 
covered. At this time great caution must be exercised in handling the matter 
or later on even more and greater calamities will visit the tiller of the soil. 
When the birds come to eat the seeds as they are being put into the ground, 
scare them away, and presently they will return to attack the insects that 
otherwise would destroy the growing plants. — Lawrence Bruner, University 

0 0 

The Nesting of Our Birds 

a bird nests, there is its home, and though most of our feathered 
W friends are driven southward in the fall by scarcity of food and to 

escape the rigorous northern winter, among the first evidences of the 
spring are the returning birds, pressing northward again in defiance of even 
snow and ice, toward the home they left a few short months before. Almost 
before it is reached the courtship begins and soon follows the choosing of 
mates, the selection of a location, the construction of a nest and the beginning 
of incubation. 

The location, chosen with the greatest care and after due deliberation, 
may even later be deserted and the nest removed if after its beginning dangers 
appear to threaten the safety of the young. Its nature is as varied as 
the nature of the various birds themselves; but instinct, moulded by the experience 
of the previous generations, leads each to choose that which best 
serves its purpose. Floating on the water at the margin of a pond is the 
soaked and soggy raft of the Grebe, slung in the cat-tails and rushes above 
the cosy ball of the Long-billed Marsh Wren or the basket of the Red-winged 
Blackbird, while in a little hollow in the sand are arranged the eggs of the 
Sandpiper, protected by their color from all but knowing eyes, and still farther 
back in the trackless meadow those of the Duck are hidden in the grass. Out 
on the wind-swept prairie the nest of the Shore-lark is sunken beside some clod, 
and the eggs of the Nighthawk in lieu of any nest at all rest directly on the 
ground, while in the thicket under the shelter of the trees the Warbler builds 
her dainty cradle side by side with the clumsy heap of twigs collected by the 
Thrasher. Safe in a tunnel in a bank the Kingfisher and the Bank Swallow 
hide their pure white eggs, and in cavities in trees, hidden also from the 
light, are the ivory treasures of the Woodpecker. The Hawk, scorning concealment 
or protection, places his platform high in a towering tree, the Heron 
bis in some secluded swamp, but at the tip of a swaying limb by the roadside 
the purse of the Baltimore Oriole is safer than either from the foe. Many 
birds delight in man's society and haunt the barn, the shed, the porch, the 
trees and shrubbery about the house, and even enter cbimnw's to rear their </seg>

            <seg id="p094">
278 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

In choice of materials the bird is guided by the necessities arising from 
the location of its nest, the time of year when made, and the physical abilities 
of the bird, mud, moss, grass, sticks, cloth, twine, hair, and fur all coming 
bandy on occasion, while to the Chimney Swift its own saliva serves as glue. 
Some of our birds are hatched before the end of winter, and poorly would 
the young of the owl in its coat of heavy down fare in the warmth of the 
later days of spring. The young of most birds hatched thus early in the season, 
and those of waterbirds, which need protection from the dampness, are 
downy, while those which later, fed on the insects, enjoy the warmth of summer 
days are naked when they leave the egg. 

During this period, as a rule, both birds share equally the labor, but 
there are not wanting lazy dandies, as even the lovable Bluebird, that spend 
their time on song and toilet when their domestic spouse toils to collect material 
for their home. On the other hand, there are strong-minded females, 
among the phalaropes, who pose as the representative of the household while 
their dull -colored mates perform the family duties. In most cases the male 
has sufficient gallantry to bring his sitting mate an occasional tidbit, or even 
to relieve her while she goes for exercise or in search of food, but among the 
Ducks'are shameless Drakes who go off in a crowd to enjoy themselves, leaving 
their families to fare as best they may. 

The eggs are brooded for a time the length of which is in proportion to 
their size, the female Humming-bird sitting but ten days, some of our largest 
birds three or even four weeks. The love of birds for nest and eggs is slight 
at first, but rapidly increases, and reaches its full strength with the hatching 
of the young, which are the objects of tenderest solicitude. 
When hatched the young of waterbirds and fowls— Quail, Grouse, and 
Prairie Chicken— are able at once to swim or run about, but the care of the 
parents is required by most young birds for many weeks, and it is usual if but 
one brood is reared in a season, for the family to remain together till the coming 
of the fall brings round again the time when all leave on the fall migration.— 
Robert H. WolcoU, University of Nebraska. </seg>

            <seg id="p095">
A WOODLAND SCENE 

From the Children'! Fourth Reader, Cyr, Qinn &lt;t Co </seg>

            <seg id="p096">
vvtiitt 

3\%v«-- 

I 

: . C 

! 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p097">
279 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

•¦ *IME only enhances the lasting value and demonstrates anew the true 
X significance of these inspiring observances. Whatever may be the char- 

acter of its temporary problems, this liberty loving nation is not and 
never can be forgetful of the immortal heroes of the civil war. 

The debt of gratitude which we owe to the nation's defenders can never 
be repaid, either by this or future generations ; yet the acknowledged gift of 
the obligation each year, in various forms and in a multitude of places 
throughout this broad land, purifies our ideas and brings us all together in 
sympathy of sentiment and unity of purpose. 

Generations come and go and the issues for which they fought and died 
soon pass into history. But the living principles of undertakings worthily 
accomplished, for an unselfish purpose, abide forever and guide us to a nobler 
destiny and still greater achievements as a nation.— President McKinley. 

0 a 

What Can the Children Do ? 

FIRST CHILD. 

WHAT can the little children do, 
When Decoration Day is here, 
To show their love for soldiers brave 
Who, fighting for their country, gave 
The life that was to them so dear ? 

SECOND CHILD. 

We'll bring the lovely flowers of spring 
That in the fields and gardens grow, 

t And on the soldiers' graves to-day 
Our garlands we will gladly lay, 

. | Our loving thoughts of them to show. 
THIRD CHILD. 

We'll raise aloft the " stars and stripes" 
On this Memorial Day, to show 

We honor those who for it bled. 
Some now are living, many dead, 
For this was many years ago. 

FOURTH CHILD. 

We'll sing our patriotic songs; 

We'll truly sing with heart and voice, 
And to our country we'll be true, 
And honor our " red, white, and blue," 
And in our freedom we'll rejoice. 

— Laura F. Armitage in Journal of Education. </seg>


            <seg id="p098">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Which General? 

Sometimes mamma calls me " general" — 
I wish I knew which one ; 

But I always try to tell the truth, 
So I hope it's Washington. 

But when I tell my papa that, 
He laughs loud as he can, 

And says if she calls me "general," 
She must mean Sheridan, 

Because whenever she wants me, 
And I am out at play, 

I nearly always seem to be 
'Bout " twenty miles away." 

— Kate W. Hamilton 

0 0 

Our Flag 

MARY. 

TELL me, who can, about our flag, 
With its red, and white, and blue ? 

How came it to have so many stars, 

And of pretty stripes so few ? 

JOHN. 

The thirteen stripes are for thirteen states 

That first into the Union came ; 

For each new state we have added a star. 
But have kept the stripes the same. 

BESSIE. 

The number has now reached forty-five ! 

So here's an example for you : 

Take " the old thirteen" from forty-five, 

And how many states are new? 

CHARLES. 

Thirteen from forty-five ? Let's see ; 
Well, three from five leaves two, 

And one from four leaves three • there'll be, 
Of new states, — thirty-two. 

ALL IN CONCERT. 

And these all reach from East to West, 

To both the ocean shores ; 

And over all the proud flag waves, 

And the Bird of Freedom soars ! </seg>



            <seg id="p099">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

A Memorial Gift 

!.- 

(Far four pupils 

FROM woodland and field, 
In this bright month of May, 
What flowers can we bring 

For Memorial Day? 

2 (dressed In red, holding columbine) .— 
I am sweet columbine, 

And I nod my gay head 
As I offer you freely 

My blossoms of red. 

S (dressed In white, holding daisies! — 
I'm a tall, slender daisy, 

With my petals of white. 
Take a few of my blossoms, 

Their faces are bright. 

4 (dressed in blue, holding violets) .— 
We violets sweet, 

Though half hid in the grass, 
If you search you may find us, 

My dear little lass. 

1 (taking the bouquets and holding them up). 
What more can we wish 

Than the red, white, and blue 
Of nature's sweet flowers 

For the brave and the true? 

Nellie G. Jerome 

* * 

Four Soldier Boys 

This short exercise may be given by four little boys with soldiers' caps and capes. 
bean a small flag. All march in to drum beats, and stand in line. 

FIRST SOLDIER. 

AN HONEST soldier I would be 
And serve my country, grand and free. 
I'll fight for truth, be good and great, 
I'll bravely march and fear no fate. 

ALL (WAVING FLAGS). 

" Hurrah ! Hurrah ! Wave, flags, wave ! 
Wave for the soldier who is true and brave ! 

SECOND SOLDIER. 

A loving soldier I would be, 

And serve my country, grand and free. 
Loving God and loving man, 

I'll always do the best I can. 

ALL. 

Hurrah ! Hurrah ! Wave, flags, wave ! 
Wave for this country and our soldiers brave! </seg>



            <seg id="p100">
THIRD SOLDIER. 

A soldier brave I'll try to be, 

And serve my country grand and free 
In dangers I'll be brave and true; 
This for my country I will do. 

ALL. 

Hurrah ! Hurrah ! Wave, flags, wave ! 
Wave for the country and our soldiers brave ! 

FOURTH SOLDIER. 
The best of soldiers we will be, 

And serve our country, grand and free. 
Honest, loving, brave, and true, 
O, much for our country we can do ! 

ALL (MARCHING OUT). 

Hurrah ! Hurrah ! Wave, flags, wave ! 
Wave for the country and our soldiers brave I 

* * 

Meaning of the Colors 

FIRST PUPIL. 

RED, from the leaves of the autumn woods, 
Of our frost-kissed northern hills; 
Red, to show that patriot blood 
Is beating now in a hurrying flood 

In the hearts of American men. 

SECOND PUPIL. 

White, from the fields of stainless drift, 
On our wide western plains; 

White, to show that as pure as snow, 
We believe the Christ light yet shall glow, 

In the souls of American men. 

THIRD PUPIL. 

Blue, from the arch of the winter sky, 
O'er our fatherland outspread; 

Blue, to show that as wide as heaven, 
Shall justice to all mankind be given, 
At the hands of American men. 

ALL TOGETHER. 

Red, white, and blue, and the light of stars, 
Through our holy colors shine ; 

Love, truth, and justice, virtues three, 
That shall b'^om in the land of liberty, 

In the he. of American men. </seg>

            <seg id="p101">
283 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

"I'm Only a Regular" 

J^L CANET : The battle was over. In the midst of the dead and dying 
.EZs were two New York volunteers and a soldier of the regular army, lying 

there suffering in the burning sun. Suddenly the regular saw an 
opportunity to get a canteen from a dead Spanish sharpshooter. With difficulty 
he crawled the 300 yards necessary to reach the water. But instead of 
quenching his own thirst, wounded as 'he was, he painfully dragged himself 
back to his comrades, and died lifting the canteen to their lips. " I'm only a 
regular," he said, " you fellows have folks at home waiting for you " 

4» * 

A Tribute to Our Army 

rHE following ia part of the farewell address issued by the Spanish 
soldiers before their embarkation for Spain at the end of the Spanish- 

American war. It is a tribute of appreciation to our army for complying 
with the instincts of a humane nation in their fighting: 

i Soldiers of the American army: We would not be fulfilling our duty as 
-born men, in whose breasts live gratitude and courtesy, should we 
ark for our beloved Spain without sending to you our most cordial and 
ere good wishes and farewell. We fought you with ardor, with all 
strength, endeavoring to gain the victory, but without the slightest rancor 
ate towards the American nation. We have been vanquished by you (so 
generals and chiefs judged in signing the capitulation), but our surrender 
the bloody battles preceding it have left in our souls no place for 
ntment against the men who fought us so nobly and valiantly. You 
jht and acted in compliance with the same call of duty as we, for we 
&gt;ut represent the power of our respective states. You fought us as mer, 
to face, and with great courage. 

You have given honorable burial to the dead of the vanquished; have 
cured their wounded with great humanity; have respected and cared for your 
prisoners and their comfort, and, lastly, to us, whose condition was terrible, 
you have given freely of food, of your stock of medicines, and you have 
honored us with distinction and aourtesy, for after the fighting the two armies 
mingled with the utmost harmony. 

RWith this high sentiment of appreciation from us all, there remains but 
ipress our farewell, and with the greatest sincerity we wish you all hapssa 
and health in this land, which will no longer belong to our dear Spain, 
will be yours, who have conquered it by force and watered it with blood. 

# # 

The Southern Soldier 

of the North have had drawn for you with a master's hand the pic- 
X ture of your returning armies. You have heard how, in the pomp and 

K circumstance of war, they came back to you, marching with proud and 
rious tread, reading their glory in a nation's eyes. 

BWill you bear with me while I tell you of another army that sought its 
ie at the close of the late war— an army that marched home in defeat and 
in victory, in pathos and not in splendor? 

I Let me picture to you the footsore confederate soldier, as, buttoning up in 
faded gray jacket the parole which was to bear testimony to bis children 
is fidelity and faith, he turned his face southward from Appomattox in 
il, 1866. Think of him as ragged, half starved, heavy-hearted, enfeebled 
rant and wounds; having fought to exhaustion, he surrenders his gun, </seg>

            <seg id="p102">
284 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

wrings the hands of his comrades in silence, and lifting his tear- stained and 
pallia face for the last time to the graves that dot the old Virginia hills, pulls 
his gray cap over his brow and begins the slow and painful journey. What 
doe* he find— let me ask you who went to your homes eager to find in the welcome 
you had justly earned, full payment for four years' sacrifice— what does 
he find when having followed the battle-stained cross against overwhelming 
odds, dreading death not half so much as surrender, he reaches the home he 
left so prosperous and beautiful? 

I He finds his house in ruins, his farm devastated, his slaves free, his stock 
d, his barns empty, his trade destroyed, his money worthless; his social 
sm, feudal in its magnificence, swept away; his people without law or 
1 status, his comrades slain, and the burdens of others heavy on his shoul. 
Crushed by defeat, his very traditions are gone ; without money, credit, 
jrial, or training; and beside all this, confronted with the gravest probthat 
ever met human intelligence— the establishing of a status for the vast 
r of his liberated slaves. 

What does he do— this hero in gray with a heart of gold? Does he sit 
down in sullenness and despair? Not for a day. Surely God who had stripped 
him of his prosperity, inspired him in his adversity. As ruin was never 
so overwhelming, never was restoration swifter. The soldier stepped from 
the trenches into the furrow; horses that had charged federal guns marched 
before the plough, and fields that ran red with blood in April were green with 
the harvest in June. Never was nobler duty confided to human hands than 
the uplifting and upbuilding of the prostrate and bleeding south, misguided 
perhaps, but beautiful in her suffering. In the record of her social, industrial, 
and political evolution, we await with confidence the verdict of the world. 
— Henry Qrady. From Stickney 1 s Fifth Reader by vermission of Oinn &amp; Co. 

# * 

member the Maine- A Beautiful Tribute to 
its Noble Dead 

Delivered in House of Representatives, March 21, 1896, by Hon. Robert G. Cousins, Iowa. 

TkTO HUMAN speech can add anything to the silent gratitude, the speech- 
X^l less reverence, already given by a great and grateful nation to its dead 

defenders and to their living kin. No act of congress providing for 
their needs can make a restitution for their sacrifice. Human nature does, in 
human ways, its best, and still feels deep in debt. 

K Expressions of condolence have come from every country and from every 
le, and every nerve of steel and ocean cable has carried on electric breath 
sweetest, tenderest words of sympathy for that gallant crew who manned 
Maine. But no human recompense can reach them. Humanity and time 
ain their everlasting debtors. 

It was a brave and strong and splendid crew. They were a part of the 
I and bone and sinew of our land. Two of them were from my native 
of Iowa. Some were only recently at the United States Naval Academy, 
b they had so often heard the morning and the evening salutation to the 
that flag which had been interwoven with the dearest memories of 
lives, that had colored all their friendships with the lasting blue of true 
ty. But whether they came from naval school or civil life, from one 
or another, they called each other comrade— that gem of human lane 
which sometimes means but a little less than love and a little more than 
dship, that gentle salutation of the human heart which lives in all the 
lages of man, that winds and turns and runs through all the joys and 
ws of the human race, through deed and thought and dream, through 
and toil and battlefield. 

Efo foe had ever challenged them. The world can never know how brave 
were. They never knew defeat; they never shall. While at their posts 
ty, sleep lured them into the abyss; then death unlocked their slumber- </seg>

            <seg id="p103">
285 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

Ing eyes but for an instant to behold its dreadful carnival, most of them just 
when life was full of hope, and all its tides were at their highest, grandest flow ; 
just when the early sunbeams were falling on the steeps of fame and flooding 
all life's landscape far out into the dreamy, distant horizon; just at that age 
when all the nymphs were making diadems and garlands, waving laurel 
wreaths before the eyes of young and eager nature — just then, when death 
seemed most unnatural. 

¦Hovering above the dark waters of that mysterious harbor of Havana, the 
k-winged vulture watches for the dead, while over it, and over all, there 
ie eagle's piercing eye sternly watching for the truth. 

I Whether the appropriation carried by this resolution shall be ultimately 
ged to fate or to some foe shall soon appear. Meanwhile a patient and a 
iotic people, enlightened by the lessons of our history, remembering the 
i of war, both to the vanquished and victorious, are ready for the truth 
ready for their duty. 

" The tumult and the shouting dies — 

The captains and the kings depart — 

Still stands thine ancient sacrifice, 

An humble and a contrite heart. 
Lord God of Hosts, be with us yet. 
Lest we forget — lest we forget." 

* * 

rlcome to Company G of the "Fighting 
First" 

MR. PRESIDENT, Ladies, and Gentlemen : On behalf of the Local Executive 
Committee, I have the honor to pronounce the sentiment which 

I thrills the heart and electrifies the soul of every man, woman, and child 
his vast multitude, Welcome ! Welcome! A thousand times welcome to 
brave boys of Company G, of the " Fighting First." These hundreds of 
lan faces, glowing with sympathy and joy, " In this spacious temple of 
firmament," turn reverently to heaven and proclaim their gratitude unto 
nd providence for being permitted to grasp the hands of these heroes in 
?oroe home. 

Hail, Sons of Columbia ! Fortunate, fortunate men ! With what measure 
of devotion will you not thank God for the circumstances of your extraordinary 
lives ? You are connected with two hemispheres. You have carried a 
victorious banner twenty thousand miles. Heaven saw fit to ordain that the 
electric spark of Liberty should be conducted through you, from the New 
World to the Old. 

" Strongholds of Tyrants you did greet, 
In the cause of freedom, you did meet 

To strike for the oppressed. 

You hoisted the flag that knows no stain, 

You waved defiance unto Spain, 

And the battle cry, ' Remember the Maine, 

Was heard around the world." 

I Sons of Nebraska mothers, the events of this day bring to our minds that 
il day, 1898. That day you parted with those you loved to enlist in the 
y of freedom. That was a day that tried our souls. The child gave its 
er, the maiden her lever, the wife her husband, and the mother her son to 
cause of humanity. Under flaunting flags, you hurried to our Capital 
¦ to await orders. You then crossed the prairies, climbed the mountains, 
sailed the seas, prepared to do and to die for the eternal right. 

¦The gory fields, the hospitals of pain, weary marches under a tropical 
guard duty in the awful storm, the whistle of the Mauser bullet, "The </seg>

            <seg id="p104">
286 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

roar and shriek of the bursting shell," the gallant charge and the triumphant 
shout are a part of your thrilling experiences. 
With what delight we hailed your letters from far-away Luzon I How 
eagerly we sought the press dispatches after each battle, to see if any of Company 
O had fallen. How we have longed for you to be mustered out; and now 
you come back to us, "marching with proud and victorious tread, reading your 
glory in a Nation's eyes." 
But alas! you are not all here, Walker, Hague, Spivey, Forby, Stotsenburg! 
Our eyes seek for them in vain amidst this brave band. They have 
answered the roll call on high, and live only to their country, in her grateful 
remembrance, and their own bright example. "Let us not too much grieve 
that they have met the common fate of men." They lived long enough to 
know that their work had been nobly done. The sky on which they closed 
their eyes was cloudless. The record they, left those near and dear to them 
was above reproach. They wrought wiser than they knew. They are at rest. 
Monuments and eulogy are indeed due such heroic dead. 

t "Human beings are composed not of reason only, but of sentiment as well, 
that is neither wasted nor misapplied which is appropriated for the purs 
of giving direction to sentiments, and opening proper springs of feeling 
lie heart. ' Let the ceremonies of this day proclaim the importance of 
achievements of Company G and other patriotic sons of the First Neika. 
Let mothers teach the full meaning of this welcome to the children 
ome. Let the memories of this occasion stand as a mighty Gibraltar 
nst those days of criticism and disaster, which, as they come on all nations, 
t be expected to come on us also. 

BLet desponding patriotism turn her eyes to this heroic picture, and be 
red that the foundations of our national power still stand firm, and that 
gates of hell shall not prevail against us. 

Again, heroes of Company G, we welcome you. We welcome you for 
what you have done; more than that, we welcome you for what you are. We 
welcome you as friends of liberty and humanity; we welcome you as those 
who have made Old Glory the flag of the seas. We welcome you as defenders 
of the greatest, the grandest, and the best government on the face of the 

Sons of Columbia! 

"You who with gallant Dewey fought, 

And counted human life as naught, 
If, at such priceless cost it brought 

A birthright for the free," — we welcome you 

Sons of Nebraska Mothers! 

"You who crushed out tyranny, 
Set fellow-men from thraldom free, 
And ended the tyrant's sway," — We welcome you! 

In the name of liberty, in the name of humanity, under a flag 

without a stain — we welcome you ! 

— Elizabeth Stultz, of Geneva, on the return home of Company G 

of Vie first Nebraska. 

# £ 

The Essence of Patriotism 

*T*HE essence of patriotism lies in a willingness to sacrifice for one's 
M. country, just as true greatness finds expression, not in blessings enjoyed, 

tbut in good bestowed. Read the words inscribed on the monuments 
id by loving hands to the heroes of the past; they do not speak of wealth 
rited, or honors bought, or of hours in leisure spent, but of service done, 
lty years, forty years, a life or life's most precious blood he yielded up 
he welfare of his fellows — this is the simple story which proves that it 
iw, and ever has been more blessed to give thau to receive. </seg>

            <seg id="p105">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

287 

The officer was a patriot when he gare his ability to his country and 
risked his name and fame upon the fortunes of war; the private soldier was 
a patriot when he took his place in the ranks and offered his body as a bulwark 
to protect the flag; the wife was a patriot when she bade her husband 
farewell and gathered about her the little brood over which she must exercise 
both a mother's and a father's care; and if there can be degrees in 
patriotism, the mother stood first among the patriots when she gave to the 
nation her sons, the divinely appointed support of her declining years, and as 
she brushed the tears away, thanked God that he had given her the strength 
to rear strong and courageous sons for the battlefield.— W. J. Bryan. 

*¦ * 

Col. Ingersoll's Remarkable Vision 

(One of the most eloquent extracts In the English Language. Published by permissio* 
of Rhodes 4 McClure.) 

*¥*HE past, as it were, rises before me like a dream. Again we are in the 
X great struggle for national life. We hear the sound of preparation — the 

music of boisterous drums — the silver voices of heroic bugles. We see 
the thousands of assemblages and hear the appeals of orators. We see the pale 
cheeks of women and the flushed faces of men; and in those assemblages we 
see all the dead whose dust we have covered with flowers. We lose sight of 
them no more. We are with them when they enlist in the great army of freedom. 
We see them part with those they love. Some are walking for the last 
time in quiet woody places with the maidens they adore. We hear the whisperings 
of the sweet vows of eternal love as they lingeringly part forever. 
Others are bending over cradles, kissing babes that are asleep. Some are 
receiving the blessings of old men. Some are parting with mothers who hold 
them ana press them to their hearts again and again, and say nothing 1 ; and 
some are talking with wives and endeavoring with brave words spoken in the 
old tones to drive away the awful fear. We see them part. We see the wife 
standing in the door with the babe In her arms — standing in the sunlight 
sobbing — at the turn of the road a hand waves — she answers by holding high 
in her loving hands the child. He is gone, and forever. 

KWe see them all as they march proudly away under the flaunting flags, 
)ing time to the wild, grand music of war — marching down the streets of 
afreat cities— through the town and across the prairies — down to the fields 
lory, to do and to die for the eternal right. 

We go with them one and all. We are by their side on all the gory fields, 
in all the hospitals of pain — on all the weary marches. We stand guard with 
them in the wild storm and under the quiet stars. We are with them in 
ravines running with blood, in the furrows of old fields. We are with them 
between contending hosts, unable to move, wild with thirst, the life ebbing 
slowly away among the withered leaves. We see them pierced by balls and 
torn with shells in the trenches of forts, and in the whirlwind of the charge, 
where men become iron with nerves of steel. 

Ke are with them in the prisons of hatred aad famine, but human speech 
ver tell what they endured. 

¦ye are at home when the news comes that they are dead. We see the 
en in the shadow of her sorrow. We see the silvered head of the old 
bowed with the last grief. 

The past rises before us, and we see four millions of human beings governed 
by the lash — we see them bound hand and foot — we hear the strokes of 
cruel whips— we see the hounds tracking women through tangled swamps. 
We see babes sold from the breasts of mothers. Cruelty unspeakable! Out,rage 
infinite! ' • </seg>

            <seg id="p106">• 


288 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Four million bodies in chains — four million souls in fetters. All the 
sacred relations of wife, mother, father, and child trampled beneath the brutal 
feet of might. And all this was done under our own beautiful banner of 
the free. 

The past rises before us. We hear the roar and shriek of the burning 
shell. The broken fetters fall. There heroes died. We look. Instead of 
slaves, we see men and women and children. The wand of progress touches 
the auction-block, the slave-pen, and the whipping-post, and we see homes 
and firesides, and school-houses and books, and where all was want and 
crime, and cruelty and fear, we see the faces of the free. 

I These heroes are dead. They died for liberty — they died for us. They 
at rest. They sleep in the land they made free, under the flag they rensd 
stainless, under the solemn pines, the sad hemlocks, the tearful willows, 
embracing vines. They Bleep beneath the shadows of the clouds, careless 
e of sunshine or storm, each in the windowless palace of rest. Earth 
r run red with other wars— they are at peace. In the midst of battle in 
roar of conflict, they found the serenity of death. I have one sentiment 
the soldiers living and dead— cheers for the living and tears for the dead. </seg>

            <seg id="p107">
A*LBWV**B HOlUlUSTi BrlUwnaLDt I Til* "OOuTM TI|T&lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p108">
K 

A MClMtlM TALE. 

Mrs. Wilson's Interesting book. " Picture Study in Elementary Sohoola, </seg>


            <seg id="p109">
289 

Public Schools and Education 

N open school-house, free to all, evidences the highest type of advance 
/lL civilization. It is the gateway to progress, prosperity, and honor, and 

tthe best security for the liberties and independence of the people. It 
e strongest rock of the foundation, the most enduring stone of the temple 
berty, our surest stay in every storm, our present safety, our future hope, 
the very citadel of our influence and power. It is better than garrisons 
guns, than forts and fleets. An educated people, governed by true 
il principle, can never take a backward step, nor be dispossessed of their 
enship and liberties. 

I Permanently engrafted upon the policy and legislation of the state, it is 
to all ; to it all are invited and welcome, without money and without 
b. It is supported with boundless generosity by the people of the state, 
1 to the children of the humblest citizen or exiled sojourner within our 
s, as freely and ungrudgingly as to the native born or the children of the 
b opulent. Within its jurisdiction all distinctions, social, political, and 
fious, are banished; all differences hushed, all barriers removed. It 
gnizes neither party nor church, creed, condition, nor station, but free as 
lir we breathe, its bounties and benefits fall in equal measure upon all. 

These advantages should be sacredly cherished, never lightly regarded. 
The time to enjoy them is in youth; no other time is so opportune. If neglected 
then, they are reasonably certain to remain forever unimproved. We 
have no time to wait in this short, hurrying life. The early years are the 
golden ones for preparation ; not a moment should be squandered. It might 
be otherwise could we realize the sentiment of the old rhyme : 

Could a man be secure 
That his days would endure 
As of old, for a thousand long years, 
What things he might know, 

What deeds might he do, 
What reap and what sow, 

And all without hurry and care! 

iBut it is all otherwise ordained; " our brief span " admits of no idleness, 
Ditering by the way. The to-morrows are too full to be crowded with the 
erdays. We must move on and forward. We must learn that every day 
new day, with iWown distinctive and commanding duties, and cannot 
ie for the yesterdays unimproved. To-morrow's tent must be pitched in 
fields; to-morrow's thought in advance of yesterday's. We must keep 
&gt;r be crowded out. 

You can afford to appear here in any department, from the primary to 
the high school, poorly dressed, if your necessities require. You can face 
the sharp and sometimes humiliating contrast with your better dressed 
classmate, for be assured that attention to your studies, thought and industry 
in your work, and a hearty realization of your advantages and duties, will 
remove these differences in a few years. With your growth and progress, 
your pafcrhml «w»4 shabbv clothes will be wholly forgotten, or if recollected, 

ibrary 

Day 

t 

OCTOBER </seg>

            <seg id="p110">
290 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

remembered only to your honor, and your independence will stand as an 
example worthy of emulation by the struggling boys who are to follow you. 
The poor and shabbily clad boy, with a clean face and clear head, seeking 
and appreciating the advantages of the public school, will win his way against 
all opposition. His future is assured. The want of the time is manly men. 
men of character, culture and courage, of faith and sincerity; the exalted 
manhood which forges its way to the front by force of its own merits. Self 
earned stations are the best and most secure; self -earned reputations the 
most lasting. What you hare fairly acquired by your own brain and conscience 
and mind belongs to you. It is your throne from which you cannot 
be misplaced ; your scepter, which you alone have a right to wield. It is your 
priceless possession. A man may get rich in a day or an hour by the quick 
tarn of a fortunate speculation, but the only wealth which lasts and wears is 
that which builds steadily up through honesty, industry, and sacrifice. — Wm. 
McKiniey, in Porter's Life of McKinley. 

* * 

The Council of the Books 

ONE day the books in council met 
To crown the greatest one. 
The laurel wreath was all prepared, 

The Council was begun. 

The Dictionary took the floor 
In ponderous volumes two : 

" I hold the wisdom of the world, 
Pray give me what is due." 

Then came the Cyclopedia; 
His volumes were two score. 

" I've twenty words for one of yours, 
Now which deserves it more ? " 

The novels said, " We please the world." 
The essays, "We instruct." 
Said Robert's Rules, " Clubs are the things, 
I show how to conduct." 

Shakespeare, in Russia leather dressed, 

Spoke eloquently, too. 
The books nodded their wise old heads 
And wondered what to do. 

A little gay First Reader came 
With photographs galore, 

And colored pictures on each page — 
" What could you ask for more ? " 

"I teach the babies how to read, 
They learn it without trying. 

That I'm entitled to the crown 
Surely there's no denying." 

Then came a curious battered thing 
For such grand company ; 

The Horn Book from the museum shelf 
With A and B and C. </seg>

            <seg id="p111">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

291 

For shame it could not lift its ha*d, 

It looked upon the ground, 
But a great thunder of applause 
Rose from the circle round. 

They took the laurel from the shelf 

And crowded the Horn Book king. 
" For we are all your followers," 
Said the grand books in the ring. 

—Bertha E. Bush. 

0 a 

A Life Lesson 

THERE! little girl; don't cry! 
They have broken your doll, I know; 
And your tea-set blue, 
And your play-house, too, 

Are things of the long ago; 

But childish troubles will soon pass by, — 
There 1 little girl; don't cry! 

There! little girl; don't cry! 

They have broken your slate, I know! 
And the glad, wild days 
Of your school-girl days 

Are things of the long ago; 

But life and love will soon come by, — 
There! little girl; don't cry! 

There! little girl; don't cry! 

They have broken your heart, I know; 
And the rainbow gleams 
Of your youthful dreams 

Are things of the long ago; 

But heaven holds all for which you sigh, — 
There! little girl; don't cry! 

— James Whitcomb Riley, in " Child Rhymes," Copyrighted. 

(By permission The Bowen- Merrill Company.) 

a a 

The Most Appropriate Gift 

A GOOD book is the most appropriate gift that friendship can make. It 
/jl never changes, it never grows unfashionable or old. It is soured by no 

t neglect, it is jealous of no rival; but always its clean, clear pages are 
to amuse, interest, and instruct. The voice that speaks the thought may 
e or grow still forever, the heart that prompted the kindly and cheering 
nay grow cold and forgetful ; but the page that mirrors it is changeless, 
il, immortal. The book that records the incarnation of divine love, is 
best gift to man, and the books which are filled with kindly thought and 
&gt;us sympathy, are the bejt gifts of friend to friend. — Royal Path of Life </seg>

            <seg id="p112">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

292 

The Influence of Books 

P[E influence of books upon man is remarkable; they make the man. 
You may judge a man more truly by the books and papers that he reads 

(than by the company which he keeps, for his associates are often, in a 
ner, imposed upon him; but his reading is the result of choice, and a 
who chooses a certain class of books and papers unconsciously becomes 
s colored in their views, more rooted in their opinions, and the mind bees 
fettered to their views. 
All the life and feeling of a young girl is fascinated by some glowing lore 
since, is colored and shaped by the page she reads. If it be false, and 
fc, and foolish, she will be false, and weak, and foolish, too; but if it be 
, and tender, and inspiring, then something of its truth, and tenderness, 
inspiration will grow into her soul and become a part of her very self, 
boy who reads deeds of manliness, of bravery, and noble daring, feels the 
it of emulation grow within him, and the seed is planted which will bring 
i fruit of heroic endeavor and exalted life. — Royal Path of Life. 

0 0 

The Best Society in the World 

*¥*HE best society in the world is that which lives in books. No taint of 
X vulgarity attaches to it, no petty strife for place or power disturbs its 

harmony, no falsehood stains its perfect truth; and those who move 
habitually in these associations find a strength which is the more controlling' 
because moulded by genius into forms of grace and refinement. 

I There is a certain monotony in daily life, and those whose aims are high, 
who lack the inherent strength to stand true to them amid adverse inaces, 
gradually drop out of the ever-thinking ranks of the aspiring. 
y are conquered by routine and disheartened by the discipline and labor 
. guard the prizes of life. Even to the strongest there are hours of weaki 
and weariness. To the weak and to the strong, in their times of weaki, 
books are inspiring friends and teachers. Against the feebleness of 
vidual efforts they proclaim the victory of faith and patience, and out of 
uncertainty and discouragement of one day's work, they prophesy the 
er and richer life, that grows strong and deep through conflict, sets itself 
e and more in harmony with the noblest aims, and is at last crowned with 
or and power. — Royal Path of Life. 

0 0 

The Value of College Training 

W% EV. Dr. J. P. John, ex-president of the De Pauw University, a wise, en-4^ 
terprising, and skilful educator, says: " Is it worth while for the wood- 

tman to stop an hour in the morning to grind his axe? He may be in a 
,t haste to reach the scene of his daily work, but the greater his hurry, the 
¦er he can afford to tarry at the grindstone. He may greatly desire to see 
chips fly, but they will fly all the more rapidly when he comes an hour 
with a sharp p.xe. He may hope to accomplish an unusually large day'8 
£, but he will chop more wood in the one hour at the grindstone than he 
Id have done in two hours with a blunt axe. A nine-hour day with a keen 
rument is longer than a ten-hour day with a dull one. 

KWhy should a young man at eighteen hurry into his life work with a 
intempered, intellectual blade? Let him stop four or five years at the 
e grindstone. The 'expectation of life' for a man of eighteen is a little 
orty years; that is he has a mathematical prospect of living until he is </seg>

            <seg id="p113">
SPECIAL DAY EXEKCISES. 

293 

fifty -eight years old. Shall he work forty years with ft dull instrument and 
with the odds against him, or shall he halt for five years at the beginning in 
order to get ready, and then work thirty-five years with a keen blade, and 
with the odds in his favor? Which is the longer life to a young man just entering 
upon his vocation — forty more years on a low plane with contracted 
horizon, narrow opportunity, and small capacity, or thirty-five more years on 
a high plane with extended horizon, wide opportunity, and ever increasing 
capacity? Thirty-five may be more than forty. Thirty-five hours on an express 
train means a greater distance than forty hours on a log wagon. The 
college graduate at twenty-three lives longer in his remaining thirty-five 
years from commencement day than does his fellow who hastens into business 
at eighteen in the forty years that yet possibly remain to him. 

" Let the young men and women of this generation stop and get well 
ready before plunging upon a career at which they have but one chance." 

a 0 

Quotations 

SWEET are the uses of adversity, 
Which, like the toad, ugly and venomous, 
Wears yet a precious jewel in his head ; 
And this, our life exempt from public haunt, 
Finds tongues in trees, books in running brooks, 
Sermons in stones, and good in everything. 

— Shakespeare. 

¦A little philosophy inclineth a man's mind to atheism, but depth in philihy 
bringeth men's minds about to religion. — Bacon. 

BA cheerful temper, joined with innocence, will make beauty attractive, 
pledge delightful, and wit good-natured. It will lighten sickness, poverty, 
affliction, convert ignorance into an amiable simplicity, and render delity 
itself agreeable.— Addieon. 

Oh, wad some power the giftie gie us 
To see oursels as ithers see us ! 
It wad frae mony a blunder free us 

And foolish notion. 

What airs in dress and gait wad lea' us, 
And e'en devotion. 

—Burns 

Might I give counsel to any young hearer, I would say to him : Try to 
frequent the company of your betters. In books and life, that is the most 
wholesome society ; learn to admire rightly; the great pleasure of life is that. 
Note what great men admire; they admired great things; narrow spirits admire 
basely, and worship meanly.— Thackeray. 

¦Knowledge is of two kinds : We know the subject ourselves, or we know 
re we can find information upon it. — Johnson. 

K Reading without purpose is sauntering, not exercise. More is got from 
book on which the thought settles, for a definite end in knowledge, than 
1 libraries skimmed over by a wandering eye. A cottage flower gives 
5y to the bee, — a king's garden none to the butterfly. — Lytton. </seg>

            <seg id="p114">
294 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

The Study of Pictures 

Ib Teachers Who Are Interested in Pictures and Picture Study: 

We're made so that we love 
First when we see them painted, things we have passed 

Perhaps a hundred times nor cared to see ; 
God uses us to help each other so, 

Lending our minds out. — Robert Browning. 

i Children delight in pictures. Every child-lover knows how intently and 
i what delight the baby's eyes gaze upon the pages of the beloved picture 
:, long before the words which describe the picture can be spoken or even 
irstood by the young student. The childish chatter is an attempt to exs 
the delight in the treasure and the thoughts suggested by the picture, 
he child grows older, pictures continue to be a source of pleasure. He 
ea the familiar objects, talks about them, asks questions about them. 
b he unconsciously grows in the power to see and to tell what he sees, 
fat by the many willing helpers who turn the pages of his book and interits 
pictures. 

KWe have been slow in our school work to follow the teaching of children's 
srience. Although we have always known and always recognized the 
i's interest in pictures, we have not used them in the school room to the 
nt that they might have been used, nor in such a manner as to yield the 
itest advantage. 

KThe writer remembers a class of children in whose hands were placed 
« new readers beautifully illustrated with full-page pictures. The new 
ks which had just been brought into the room, were given to the children 
1 the brief direction, " Turn to page 85 and begin reading at the top of 
page." 

" Theirs not to reason why, 
Theirs not to make reply." 

The obedient fingers turned to the page indicated, and the curious eyes 
were allowed no moment to linger over the pages which tempted them with 
their fascinating pictures.- Yet here was the " Delectable Land," which 
might have been opened to them to their lasting advantage. Here the 
children's interest was assured, and no artificial incentive needed to be pre- 

Another class, under similar conditions, had a different experience. 

" Here are new books," the teacher said to the children. " You will enjoy 
reading these stories, I know. But you will find pictures in them as well 
as stories. Before we read, let us look at the pictures and enjoy them." 

KThe children eagerly opened the books. They found, as a frontispiece, a 
r of Rosa Bonheur's " Norman Sire." 

frhe children talked about the picture, compared the horse with horses 
they knew, admired the noble head, the fine eves. As they turned the 
s of their books, they found other pictures of animals, " The Lions at 
e," and "Coming from the Fair." Their comments were free, their 
bions ready. Nobody thought of the picture as a picture. The convern 
centered about lions and horses only, and expressed the children's 
est in animals. 

It was the teacher who called the attention of the children to the name 
written underneath the first picture, " Rosa Bonheur." This they inferred, 
must be the name of the one who made the picture. 

The teacher then explained that the pictures in the book were copied from 
photographs of the original pictures which the artist painted. If the children 
were to see the painting they would find it colored and much larger than the 

K Looking again with a new interest at the other pictures, the children disired 
the same name written below them. " Did Rosa Bonheur paint this 
are, too? " "And this? " " Did she paint any others? " " Does she paint </seg>

            <seg id="p115">
8PECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

295 

picture of the little girl tending the baby?" "Is this the painter's name 
(sr the picture ? " "Yes, Meyer Von Bremen. On this page you will find 
her picture of his." Thechildren found the picture of " The Pet Canary," 
talked earnestly about it. " I like that picture. I wonder if it is the 
3 little girl?" "What queer chairs ?" "What a funny window." "This 
has been knitting, too." 

I The teacher threw some light upon the German exterior, explaining that 
was a picture of a home in the country where the artist lived. Then she 
rtioned, "What did Meyer Von Bremen paint for you?" "Children," 
the ready response. "And what did Rosa Bonheur paint ?" "Animals," 
e quite as readily. " Do the pictures tell you anything about the artists?" 
children hesitated. "You remember, ' The Children's Hour'?" suged 
the teacher. " You thought that Mr. Longfellow wrote about children," 
Because he loved children," volunteered a child, as the teacher paused, 
should think Meyer Von Bremen liked children, too," observed another 
lghtfully. "And Rosa Bonheur must like animals," added a third. 

Kfhey turned again to the pictures, and decided, after some discussion, 
Rosa Bonheur not only loved animals, but was able to make us love them 
ir by her painting. 

Such study has a legitimate place in the school curriculum. Happily, it 
is now emphasized in some degree in the drawing. It should also appear in 
connection with the reading. The picture is intended to throw light upon the 
lesson which is illustrated. The children should be taught to read the picture 
as well as the story. 

I Fortunately the abundance of cheap good reprints, and the careful illusion 
of text -books, place the means for such study within the reach of every 
her and pupil. It will not be long before the picture will take its proper 
e with the song and the poem as a factor in elementary education. — Exit 
from an article on "The Study of Pictures," by Sarah Louise Arnold, 
Reading: How to Teach it," by permission of Silver, Burdett and Com- 

0 a 

Practical Suggestions 

(Taken from Mrs. Wilson's excellent little books on Picture Study in Elementary SchOBli 
Numbers land II, to which teachers are referred for further information.) 

A GOOD background for pictures and bits of statuary is essential. For- 
J^L. tunately, in modern school houses the walls are most frequently painted 

a cream color, which not only harmonizes well with the usually yellow 
woodwork, but also sets off tne pictures to the greatest advantage. 

I With regard to the pictures, two externals are essential: First, that they 
1 be large; and second, that they shall be suitably framed. It is a great 
ptation to buy four small pictures rather than one large one. If you are 
ing for your own room, then perhaps the choice could be defended. But 
school room, which is a place for study, for work, the dignity which comes 
l the size counts for more than variety. Then, too, the children remain 
tie room but a year at most. Let them carry away with them the deep 
ing remembrance of a few large pictures well hung. 

I Framing. — Plain moulding with no ornate projections to catch the dust 
worry the eye is a safe choice. Very wide mats and frames are out of 
e in the schoolroom. The usual rule forcolor is that the frame should corond 
with the middle tone of the picture. In the long run unexpensive oak, 
or birch frames will be the most satisfactory. s. 

I Small pictures have their value, and should be given from time to time 
nporary place on the walls. When, for instance, the children are studying 
Barly colonial history of our own country, what could be better than a line, </seg>

            <seg id="p116">
296 


Eines, on a level with the children's eyes, of the series of the pictures 
o graphically illustrate the conditions and facts of the settlement of 
husetts, viz., the series by Boughton, and the corresponding pictures 
r and Rothermel ? 

An excellent way to keep them permanently is to passe partout them. 

Materials. — Passe partout paper, which comes in all colors, gummed, 
put up in small rolls; photographic mounts the size desired; glass of a size 
to correspond with the mounts; bottle of library paste; and gummed suspension 
eyes or rings. 
With these materials proceed as follows: Cut away neatly all the white 
margin, or if preferred leave a white margin of less than one-eighth of an 
inch in width; place the trimmed picture in the middle of the mount and 
secure it there by applying paste to the corners or upper edge of picture; 
paste the passe partout paper for one-half its width to the edge of the 
glass, which has been thoroughly cleaned; place the mounted picture, face 
down, on glass and paste free edges of paper to back of mount; on the 
middle of the back glue the suspension eyes or ring. — Jennie B. Adams, 
Department Stenographer. 

I Calendars. — This is an excellent way to use the smaller pictures. The 
ndar pads cost but a few cents. "Rembrandt mounts," 8x10 inches, 
:e the most convenient mount. On each of these paste an appropriate 
ure. Below the picture fasten the leaf for the month on the calendar. 
jr pressing the mounts — always an essential when paste is used — eyelet 
q and fasten them together. 

A most effective Millet calendar may be made in this way: — Use a portrait 
of Millet for the cover mount, then for each month choose the following 

Iopriate pictures: — 
January, Girl Spinning. 
February, Woman Churning. 
March, Labor. 
April, Potato Planting. 
May, The Sower. 
June, . Going to Work. 

July, The Gleaners. 
August, The Angelus. 
September, The Rainbow. 
October, Feeding the Hens. 
November, The Wood-Chopper. 
December, Mother and Child. 

I For a like purpose, the pictures of Rosa Bonheur, Breton, Dupre, Corot, 
themselves with equal appropriateness to the change of seasons. Equally 
resting calendars may be made from the pictures of Botticelli, Raphael, 
ens, Van Dyck, Velasquez, Murillo, Rembrandt, Sir Joshua Reynolds, 
Burne-Jones, to mention the better known and more popular artists only. 

Course. — To those who prefer to make their own course, I would suggest 
a picture for each month, selecting always something appropriate to the 
season ; for example, a scene reminiscent of vacation sights, or a summer 
picture from another land. Perhaps for those who have left their mothers for 
the first time, a Madonna, or to put them even more at ease, a picture of some 
of their pets at home, would be suitable for September. For October, show 
them a harvest picture. November may be celebrated with one of Boughton's 
reminders of the Pilgrims and Thanksgiving, or with something suggestive of 
preparation for winter. In December come the Madonnas. Then devote the 
winter months to the study of the old masters. With the end of winter comes 
appropriately enough the study of some of the modern masters. In the spring 
take up the study of some of the outdoor scenes which belong to this season, 
while in the summer months suitable outdoor scenes, or, better still, pictures 
of summer in distant lands. — Picture Study in Elementary Schools, by Mrs. 
L. L. Wilson. 'By permission of The Macmillan Co.) </seg>

            <seg id="p117">
JOHN ALDEN AND PR1SCILLA 

By 1*1 mission of The Pra g Kducat i»» I ( </seg>


            <seg id="p118">F 

"KISS ME" 

Courlety of G. P. Brown &lt;fr Co., publUher* of Brown's Famous Pictures, 
Beverly, Mam. </seg>

            <seg id="p119">
297 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

Thanksgiving Proclamation. 

¦ Never before in the history of Nebraska hare the citizens of this state 
more cause to be thankful for worldly blessings than at present. 

Our hearts and our homes are tilled with happiness and prosperity is 
manifested everywhere. 

Though but recently sorely stricken with grief through the loss of our 
dearly beloved president, there is consolation in knowing that since his 
death outraged justice has been satisfied and pqblic sentiment has more 
firmly than ever been moored to that precept which at any sacrifice directs 
the conservation and preservation of law and order. 

A more beautiful or impressive example of devotion to principle and 
justice can be found nowhere in history than the American people with 
bruised and quaking hearts still standing resolutely upon the high moral 
principle that even under such conditions the majestv of the law should be 
maintained. This unwavering obedience to established law must of necessity 
cast rays of light across the pathway of posterity and ripen into higher 
enlightenment and more exalted civilization. We should be thankful that 
tha vacancy in the presidency has been filled by one whose sympathies are 
anchored in the hearts of the people, who is imbued with patriotism and 
who possesses rare judgment and splendid executive ability. While the 
bereavement was sad and distressing, we should be thaukful, too, that humanity 
has in a degree been compensated through the stimulation of that 
sentiment which is calculated to promote the evolution of human genius and 
public morality. 

I At peace with the world, with our labor employed, our commerce and 
e expanding, our nation at the head of the great powers of the world 
rapidly extending its commercial supremacy over the waters of the 
&lt;e, with good prices for our products and with contentment everywhere, 
iinly we of all the people should in prayerful gratitude offer up thanks 
rovidence who has given so unsparingly of these material tokens. 

(hat our gratitude and appreciation may be attested, I, Ezra P. Savage, 
nor of the state of Nebraska, by virtue of the authority vested in ma 
v do hereby appoint and designate Thursday, November 38th, 1901, as 
for Thanksgiving, and I do hereby recommend that the transaction 
blic business be suspended on that date and respectfully request that 
tople repair to their accustomed houses of worship and reverently offer 

hanksgiving 

NOVEMBER 

28 </seg>

            <seg id="p120">
298 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 


cause 1 to be 

Savage 

up thanks to Him who has so carefully supervised our affairs 
given so generously of His blessings. 

In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and 
affixed the great seal of the state of Nebraska. 

¦Done at Lincoln, this 6th day of November, A. D., 1901. 
Lhe Governor, 

Ezra P 

George W. Marsh, 

Secretary of State. 

J J* 

A Thanksgiving Hymn 

CAN a little child like me, 
Thank the Father fittingly? 
Yes, oh yes! be good and true, 
Patient, kind in all you do ; 
Love the Lord and do your part, 
Learn to say with all your heart: 
Father, we thank Thee I 
Father, we thank Thee I 
Father in Heaven we thank Thee! 

For the fruits upon the tree, 
For the birds that sing of Thee, 
For the earth in beauty drest. 
Father, mother, and the rest, 
For Thy precious loving care, 
For Thy bounty everywhere, 
Father, we thank Thee! 

Father, we thank Thee! 

Father in Heaven we thank Thee! 

— Mary Mapes Dodge. 

0 a 

Praise God 

PRAISE God for wheat, so white and sweet, 
Of which we make our bread ! 
Praise Him for yellow corn with which 

His waiting world is fed! 

Praise God for fish and flesh and fowl 
He gave to man for food ! 

Praise God for every creature which 
He made and called it good ! 

Praise God for winter's store of ice, 
Praise God for summer's heat! 

Praise God for fruit trees bearing seed, 

"To you it is for meat! " 
Praise God for all the bounty 
By which the world is fed! 

Praise God, ye children all, to whom 

He gives your daily bread! 

—Selected </seg>

            <seg id="p121">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

299 

* 

• 

&gt; 

Little Paul's Thanksgiving 

THEY tossed him and they squeezed him, 
And they kissed him one and all; 
They said, "You blessed, blessed boy ! " 

And "Darling little Paul !" 

But they didn't give him turkey, 
Nor any pumpkin pie, 

And when the nuts and grapes went round 
They slyly passed him by. 

But he didn't seem to mind it, 
For in the sweetest way 

He sat and sucked his little thumb 
His first Thanksgiving day. 

-Selected. 

* * 

A Little Boy's Dream 

THANKSGIVING night I had a fright. 
I thought I heard it said 
That turkey dear was coming near, 

But hadn't any head ! 

Thanksgiving night, oh, awful sight ! 
I thought the turkey came, 

And then he said, "Who stole my head? 
I'd like to know your name." 

Thanksgiving night no more delight 
Take I in turkeys bold, 

For then it seems they come in dreams 
And make your flesh turn cold. 

— Laura Rountree Smith. 

* # 

When the Frost is on the PunKin 

the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock, 
TV And you hear the kyouck and gobble of the struttin' turkey-cock, 
I And the clackin' of the guineys and the cluckin' of the hens, 
And the rooster's hallylooyer as he tiptoes on the fence ; 
O, it's then's the times a feller is a feelin' at his best, 
With the risin' sun to greet him from a night of peaceful rest, 
As he leaves the house bareheaded and goes out to feed the stock, 
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock. 

They's something kindo' hearty like about the atmusfere 
When the heat of summer's over and the coolin' fall is here— 
Of course we miss the flowers and the blossoms on the trees, 
And the mumble of the hummin'-birds and buzzin' of the bees; 
But the air's so appetizin' ; and the landscape through the haze 
Of a crisp and sunny morning of the early autumn days 
Is a pictur' that no painter has the colorin' to mock- 
When the frost in on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock. </seg>


            <seg id="p122">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT S REPORT. 

The husky rusty rustle of the tossels of the corn, 
And the raspin" of the tangled leaves as golden as the morn; 
The stubble in the furries kindo' lonesome-like, but still 
A-preachin' sermons to us of the barns they growed to fill; 
The strawstack in the medder, and the reaper in the shed ; 
The hosses in theyr stalls below— the clover overhead! — 
O, it sets my heart a clickin' like the tickin' of a clock, 
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock! 

Then your apples all is gethered, and the ones a feller keeps 
Is poured around the cellar floor in red and yeller heaps ; 
And your cider-makin's over, and your wimmern-folks is through 
With theyr mince and apple-butter and theyr souse and saussage, tool 
I don't know how to tell it — but ef sich a thing could be 
As the angels wantin' boardin', and they'd call around on me — 
I'd want to 'commodate 'em — all the whole-indurin' flock — 
When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock. 

— James Whitcomb RUey, in "Neighborly Poems," copyrighted. 
By permission of Bowen-Merrill Co. 

* # 

A Thanksgiving Dialogue 

(A ragged little boy, a street waif, enters stage and recites as 
Indicated. He should be a (air reciter, able to be heard by alU 

BOY. 

THEY call this Thanksgiving, 
A day to be glad ; 
But how can I keep it, 
A poor, hungry lad ? 

I sleep in a cellar, 

I live on the street; 
How can I be thankful, 
I've nothing to eat? 

(He sits down on a box as If on the street, when along comes 
* little girl dressed for the street and carrying a package.) 

FIRST GIRL. 
A happy Thanksgiving 

To you, little man. 

Each one should be thankful 
The best that he can. 

BOY. 

You're kind, little lady, 
But tell me, I pray, 

Why I should be thankful 
On this happy day ? 

FIRST GIRL. 

I'm going to visit 
A blind little friend ; 

Suppose this poor blind boy </seg>


            <seg id="p123">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

He can't see his parents, 
The beautiful light; 

He sits sad and lonely 
In one starless night. 

BOY. 

Pass on little stranger, 
I can't spare my eyes; 

I've one gift of value 
Which I ought to prize. 

(She passes on.) 

SECOND GIRL. 

(Enters stage, dressed for calling.) 
Good morning! glad morning! 

Why are you so sad ? 
Today is Thanksgiving, 

When all should be glad. 

BOY. 

I've only one blessing 

Which I've learned to prize; 
Although I am wretched 

I'm glad for my eyes. 

SECOND GIRL. 

I'm going to visit 

A lame little boy; 
He can't walk a step, 

Yet his heart's full of joy. 

He once sold the papers, 

The best on the street ; 
Until the cars caught him 

And crushed both his feet. 

He lives in Black alley ; 
His parents are dead ; 
A cripple, he's thankful ; 

But you hang your head. 

BOY. 

I, too, am the quickest 

On foot, the boys say : 
For seeing and walking, 

I'm thankful today. 

(Second girl passes on.) 

THIRD GIRL. 

(Enters stage and carries a basket and bundle. 
My poor little stranger, 

Why are you so sad? 
Today is Thanksgiving, 

When all should be glad. 

BOY. 

I'm thankful this morning, 

For eyes and for feet ; 
No more, for I suffer 

For something to eat. 
I'm poverty's orphan, 

You're wealth's child, I know- 
Pray what do you carry, 

And where may you go? </seg>

            <seg id="p124">
302 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

/ 

THIRD OIRL. 

I hare here a dinner, 

Some books, and a toy 
For poor Billy Mason, 

A deaf and dumb boy. 
He wants to hear music, 

And talk like the boys; 
He lives in lone silence, 

So few are his joys. 

(Third girl passes on.) 

BOY. 

(Rising and speaking in an earnest manner.) 
My eyes are my diamonds, 
My feet are true friends, 
My ears bring me music, 

My speech comfort lends. 
Though hungry and ragged 

On this happy day, 
I'll brace up and hustle; 

The will makes the way. 
That boy should be thankful, 

Though poor and distressed, 
Who has all the powers 

With which I am blessed. 
I'll earn what is needful, 

No longer repine; 

Though poor yet I'm favored, 
With powers divine. 
I know if I labor 

And live the right way, 
I'll always be thankful 

On this happy day. 

He retires.) 

— T. B. Weaver, in School Education. 

a a 

A Patriotic Thanksgiving 
Exercise. 

This exercise may be given by six pupils; two dressed as Indians, two 
as Negroes, and two as Puritans. The Indians may dress in brown blankets 
trimmed with bands of yellow, a gay-colored fringe around the bottom, 
leggins, beaded moccasins. Their head-dress may lie a band of red card 
board, on the Insid* or which are sewn long, stiff feathers. Bits of gold, 
¦Uyer, and tin may adorn thr front of their blankets. Their faces may be 
painted in streaks ot b-own and red. (Water colors are harmless.) Bow 
and arrows should be hung over the back of each , and each may carry a 
tomahawk. 

The two Pilgrims may be dressed In long cloaks or capes and broadrimmed 
hats, and ria* ram' iruns over their should 

The two V-. 1 r-olor thoir faces with burnt cork, wear checked 
trousers and i;a\ Kach has a flag. 

The six march In to the roll of a drum. 

FIRST INDIAN. 

1 THINK of the days when with swift-footed step 
Through the wilderness wild I bounded. 

I think of the chiefs, our Indian dance, 

As our songs through the forests resounded. </seg>

            <seg id="p125">
SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 

303 

I have stood in many a bloody war, 
With warriors dying about me, 

Strong I've stood by the burning stake, 
Whence the bravest would never flee. 

F fighting, in hunting, in fishing— al!, 
have joyed in the face of danger; 

But ah ! we were driven and crushed and killed 
By the white and merciless stranger. 

SECOND INDIAN. 

I will go to my tent and lie down in despair; 
I will paint me with black and sever my hair; 
I will sit on the shore where the hurricane blows 
And reveal to the God of the Tempest my woes; 
I will weep for a season on bitterness fed, 
For my kindred are gone to the hills of the dead ; 
But they died not of hunger, or lingering decay; 
The steel of the white man hath swept chem away. 

—Selected, 

FIRST PURITAN. 

O, see what wonders meet our eyes! 
Another land, and other skies! 
Columbian hills have met our view! 
Adieu! Old England's shores, adieu! 
Here, at length, our feet shall rest, 

Hearts be free, and homes be blest. — Upham, 

SECOND PURITAN. 
Great God! we thank Thee for this home, 
This bounteous birth-land of the free; 

Where wanderers from afar may come 
And breathe the air of liberty ! 

Still may her flowers untrammeled spring, 
Her harvests wave, her cities rise : 

And yet, till time shall fold her wing, 

Remain Earth's loveliest paradise ! — Fabodie 

FIRST NEGRO. 

Guided by our country's laws, 

for truth, and right and suffering man, 
ours to strive in Freedom's cause, 

As Christians may, as freemen cant 
Still pouring on unwilling ears 

That truth oppression only fears. — Whittier 

SECOND NEGRO. 

Rail on, then, "brethren of the South," 
Ye shall not hear the truth the less; 

»seal is on the Yankee's mouth, 
o fetter on the Yankee's press ! 

From our Green Mountains to the sea, 
One voice shall thunder, We are f reef 

—Whittier, 

ALL REPEAT. 

By our altars, pure and free, 
By our Law's deep-rooted tree, 
By the past dead memory, 

By our Washington ; </seg>

            <seg id="p126">
304 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 


By our common parent tongue, 

By our hopes, bright, buoyant, young, 
By the tide of country strong, 

We will still be one. 

"Fathers ! have ye bled in vain? 
Ages ! must ye droop again ? 
Maker ! shall we rashly stain 
Blessings sent by Thee ?" 
No! receive our solemn vow, 
While before thy throne we bow, 
Even to maintain as now, 

"Union, liberty." 

—Selected. 

"America" should then be sung as It is sung at Hampton Institute, Va. 

WHITES, NEGROES, AND INDIANS 8INQ 
My country, 'tis of thee, 

Sweet land of liberty, 

Of thee I sing. 

INDIANS. 

Land where my fathers died, 

PURITANS. 

Land of the pilgrim's pride, 

NEGROES. 

From every mountain side, 

Let Freedom ring 

INDIANS ALONE SING THE SECOND STANZA. 
My native country, thee, 

Land of the noble free, 

Thy name I love. 
I love thy rocks and rills, 

Thy woods and templed hills, 

My heart with rapture thrills 
Like that above. 

NEGROES SING THE THIRD STANZA. 
Let music swell the breeze 
And ring from all the trees 

Sweet freedom's sonjj. 

Let mortal tongues aw ike, 

Let all that breathe partake, 
Let rocks their silence break, 

The sound prolong. 

WHOLE SCHOOL AND ALL JOIN IN SINOING LAST 8TANZA. 

(School rises.) 
Our fathers' God, to thee, 

Author of liberty, 
To thee we sing. 
Long may our land be bright 

With freedom's holy light 
Protect us by thy might, 

Great God, our King. 

—Ella Marie Power*. </seg>



            <seg id="p127">
Landing of the Pilgrims 

rHE breaking waves dashed high 
On a stern and rock-bound coast, 
And the woods against a stormy sky 

Their giant branches tossed ; 

And the heavy night hung dark 
The hills and waters o'er, 

When a band of exiles moored their bark 
On the wild New England shore. 

Not as the conqueror comes, 
They, the true-hearted, came, 

Not with the roll of the stirring drums, 
And the trumpet that sings of fame. 

Nl . as the flying come, 
In silence, and in fear. 

They shook the depths of the desert's gloom 
With their hymns of lofty cheer. 

Amid the storm they sang, 
And the stars heard and the sea ; 

And the sounding aisles of the dim woods rang 
To the anthem of the free. 

The ocean eagle soared 

From his nest by the white waves' foam, 
And the rocking pines of the forest roared: 

This was their welcome home. 

eiere were men with hoary hair 
Amid that pilgrim band; 

Why had they come to wither there. 
Away from their childhood's land ? 

There was woman's fearless eye, 
Lit by her deep love's truth ; 

There was manhood's brow serenely high, 
And the fiery heart of youth. 

What sought they thus afar ? 
Bright jewels of the mine? 

The wealth of seas, the spoils of war? 
They sought a faith's pure shrine! 

Ay, call it holy ground, 

The soil where first they trod! 

rioy have left unstained what thrrp they found! 
Freedom to worship God ! 

— Mrs. Hemana. 
</seg>
            <seg id="p128">
306 


CHRISTMAS IS COMING. 

JVom the Finch Primer, by permiinon of Ginn A Co., Chicago. 

To Prevent a Mistake 

When Santa comes down the chimney 
With his heavy pack of toys, 

How does he know which stockings are girls', 
And which belong to boys ? 

Suppose he should fill boys' stockings 
With tea-sets and dolls — Oh, my! — 

And should give tops, guns, and marbles to girls! 
Wouldn't there be a cry? 

It's no use to borrow trouble 
At this time so full of joy, 

But I'll pin this note on my stocking's toe: 
" Dear Santa, I'm a boy." 

— Laura F. Armitage. </seg>


            <seg id="p129">
307 

A Christmas Eve Thought 

IF Santa Claus should stumble, 
As he climbs the chimney tal 
With all this ice upon it, 

I'm afraid he'd get a fall 

And smash himself to pieces— 
To say nothing of the toys! 

Dear me, what sorrow that would bring 
To all the girls and boys ! 

So I am going to write a note 
And pin it to the gate— 

I'll write it large, so he can see, 
No matter if it's late, — 

And say, "Dear Santa Claus, don't try 
To climb the roof to-night, 

But walk right in, the door's unlocked, 
The nursery's on the right!" 

¦St. Nicholas, 

a a 

Hang Up the Children's Stockings 

HANG up the children's stockings, 
And ring the happy chimes, 
For peace and love shall reign on earth 
In merry Christmas time — 

Mementos of that other morn 

In Bethlehem where Christ was born. 

Some homes in every nation, 
In city or in town, 

Still keep tha dear old customs 
The past a as handed down, 

And celebrate them year by year, 

As Christmas crowns the world with cheer. 

In English homes, 'neath mistletoe, 
They sing the Christmas song. 

While o'er the Yule-log's rugged side 
The bright flames creep along, 

And scarlet holly berries glow 
Among the green boughs bending low. 

We decorate the branches 
Of Christmas trees with cheer, 

An emblem of thanksgiving 
For all the fruitful year. 

And Santa Claus brings dolls and drums, 
To glad expectant little ones. 

O, day the best and dearest 
Of all the seasons, bring 

The hope of every Christian heart, 
The birthday of our King; 
The one glad day of joy and mirth, 
When God's best gift was sent to earth. 

—Selected. </seg>

            <seg id="p130">
308 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT 

Christmas Joy 

(Tune: " There's a Good Time Coming, Help 

It On.") 

THERE'S a gladness all around, 
Christmas joy! 

There's a gladness all around, 
Christmas joy! 
Smiles can easily be found, 

Mirth and happiness abound, 

Christmas joy, Christmas joy, 
Christmas joy, joy, joy! 
There's a bustle through the street, 

Christmas joy! 

There's a bustle through the street, 

Christmas joy! 

Bundles, bundles do we meet, 
Laughing crowds and tripping feet, 
Christmas joy, Christmas joy, 
Christmas joy, joy, joy! 

Savory odors fill the air, 
Christmas joy! 
Savory odors fill the air, 

Christmas joy! 

Busy housewives everywhere 
For their friends a feast prepare, 

Christmas joy, Christmas joy, 
Christmar joy, joy, joy! 

a a 

A Feel in the Christinas Air 

THEY'S a kind o' feel in the air, to me, 
When the Chris'mas time sets in, 
That's about as much of a mystery 

As ever I've run agin! 

Fer instunce, now, whilse I gain in weight 
An* gineral health, I swear 

There's a goneness somers I can't quite state — 
A kind o' feel in the air. 

They's a feel in the Chris'mas air goes right 
To the spot where a man lives at! 
It gives a feller an appetite — 
There am t no doubt about that! 
And yit. they's aomepin' — I don't know what — 
That follows me here and there, 
And ha'nts and worries and spares me not— 

A kind o' feel in the air. 

Is it the racket the children raise? 
W'y, no! — God bless 'em! — not 
Is it the eyes and cheeks ablaze — 

Like my own wuz, long ago? — 

Is it the bleat o' the whistle and beat 

6' the little toy-drum a'nd blare 
0' the horn?— No! no/— it's jest the sweet— 

The sad-sweet feel in the air. —James Whitcomb Riley. </seg>


            <seg id="p131">
309 

SANTA CLAUS IS COMING 

From the Finch Primer, by permUaUm of Ginn &amp; Co. 

A Christmas Gift 

This she- dialogue may be given by two pupils, a boy and a girl. The girl should h«Te tm 
o&gt;A doll In her arms, the boy should carry an old drum with the head broken. 

GIRL. 

This doll Kris Kringle brought last year, 
Gone is one eye, her hair, her ear; 
And now some new ones he must bring, 
The kind that walk and talk and sing. 

BOY. 

Here is a drum I had last year, 
You see it sounds now very queer; 
I left it out once in the rain, 
I've begged for other new drums in vain. 

GIRL. 

(Seating herself at a table.) 

Let's write a letter to Santa Claus, 
Telling him what to bring, because 
It must be hard to bring, you see, 
The very things we want; Dear mel 

(Girl reaching for paper, Ink, and pen, writes. Presently she reads :) 
" I'll have a hundred wax dolls when you come, 

And please bring a nice, rich sounding drum; 
Bring hundreds of books and games, a store, 
And a thousand candies and lots more." 
The letter is done and now we'll away 

And mail it to him right off to-day. 

BOY. 

I guess he'll think 'tis very shocking, 
To expect so much in one small stocking. 

-Ella M. Powers, in the Intelligence, </seg>

            <seg id="p132">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

310 

Christmas Fairies 

Pit two small boys— Queen's pages, saying in concert: "Hear ye! Hearye! Hear 
court of the Christmas Fairies 1b about to assemble. Make way (or the Queen of 
»!" They arrange chair for throne, foot-stool, etc., then stand one on each side of 
back. Enter Queen and two maids of honor; Queen takes place and maids stand 
each page. Pages and maids say in concert:) 

Gentle Christmas Fairy Queen, 

Here thy Maids and Pages stand. 
Touch us with thy wand so green, 

We'll obey thy least command. 

(Queen rises and touches first maid with her sceptre and says:) 

¦Dear Good-Will, do all the boys and girls in the world still remember 
and love you ? 

I Good- Will — Nearly all are my friends. Some poor children have never 
•d about Good- Will, and they quarrel and sometimes hurt one another and 
i bad wishes. But I am going about all over the world as quickly 7 as I can, 
hing them what a good fairy "Good Will " is and how happy I can 
e them. 

(Queen touches second maid, saying:) 

Your name is Peace. Do you make people peaceful at Christmas time ? 

¦Peace — Yes, and all the year. I keep little girls quiet and good and 
&gt; them from being afraid, and I make the little boys play their games 
lout quarreling. 

First Page. — Your majesty, the other Christmas Fairies are coming. 

(Enter First Fairy.) 

Ben — Welcome to our fairy court, Sprite. Where have you been and 
re you done. 
it Fairy (girl)— I am the fairy of Christmas Beauty. I have gone 
the world with my holly and mistletoe and evergreen. I have helped 
he churches; I have hung wreaths in the windows; I have helped the 
o bloom. But, best of all, I touched a little girl's thoughts and she 
i think of the poor little girl around the corner who had no beauty in 
e. Then I led the little girl down the dark street and smiled upon 
e she put flowers in the window and hung evergreens over the fire- 

Second Paoe — Another fairy comes. 

(Enter Second Fairy (boy) says:) 

Bil, Christmas Queen. I have worked through all the year to fill boys' 
with Christmas feeling, and now it is Christmas time and I am happy. 
good boys are waiting for Santa Claus, and they are all going to do 
ing to make Christmas happy for someone else. 

Pages — Who comes here ? 

(Enter two fairies— boy and girl. They say in concert :) 

Oh, Queen and Fairies, if you could have seen what we have seen! 
All— What was it? 

The Girl — Oh, such happy children ! Hundreds and hundreds of them I 
The Boy — And we helped to make them happy. 
The Girl — Yes, we whispered to them about Christmas and Santa Claus. 
The Boy — And stockings and candy. 
The Girl— And they will be up early Christmas morning and they'll play — 
The Boy— And skate and coast. </seg>

            <seg id="p133">
311 


their busy fingers could make some one, and they are dressing dolls and making 
aprons and warm hoods and— Oh, the whole world is happy. It is €¦ 

The Boy — And so many boys are saving their pennies to buy skates and 
mittens for poorer boys. We have worked well this year. 

(All the Fairies recite In ooncert: 

"Everywhere, everywhere, Christinas to-night. 
Christmas in lands of the fir tree and pine, 
Christmas in lands of the palm tree and vine, 
Christmas where snow-peaks stand solemn and white, 
Christmas where corn fields lie sunny and bright! 
Christmas where children are hopeful and gay, 
Christmas where old men are patient and gray, 
Christmas where peace, like a dove in his flight, 
Broods o'er brave men in the thick of the fight, 
Everywhere, everywhere, Christmas to-night! 
For the Christ-child who comes is the master of all, — 
No palace too great and no cottage too small." 

(Enter last Fairy as if in great hurry. He rushes to his plae*&gt; without stopping to bow to the 
Queen as the others hare done. He says : ) 

I know I'm late, but have been working very hard. 
Queen — Where have you been? 

Last Fairy — Helping Santa Claus. Oh how we have worked ! There 
were the dolls and drums and skates and books and dolls' carriages and toy 
engines and boats and wagons and candy and oranges and nuts and warm 
mittens and pop-corn and toy furniture and— and- Oh, so many things all to 
be packed in that little sleigh; and the reindeer to harness and— Oh, there 
will be some happy children tomorrow ! 

All— Welcome to dear old Christmas. 

(All sing with school any suitable Christmas song. At end of song Queen leaves throne and 
followed by Maids, Pages, and Fairies in procession, walks from room.; 

—Helen Morri* Sedgevxck. 

0 a 

A Christmas Exercise 

8cene:— An ordinary room or schoolroom. Teacher seated beside 
a desk; children dancing about the room singing. 

Tone:— " Rock-a-Bye Baby.' 

DANCE we together, happy and gay, 
Cheerily singing of Christmas Day. 
Backward and forward, then to and fro, 
That is the way the children must go. 
Little care we, though loud the winds blow, 
Skies may be gray and fast fall the snow. 
Put away books, be merry and free, 
Christmas is coming! Hurrah, say wa! 

TEACHER. 

So you think Christmas is coming ? 

CHILDREN. 

Of course we do, it's almost here, 
And Santa Claus, too, is drawing near. 
We can almost hear the jingling of bells 
That of bis coming always tells. </seg>

            <seg id="p134">
312 


TEACHER. 

And what will you do at Christmas. 
My dear little girls and boys ? 

CHILDREN. 

Be merry as birds the livelong day, 
Have candy and lots cf toys. 

TEACHER. 

My dears, do you think that the wisest way,— 
Is that all you will do on Christmas Day ? 

CHILDREN. 

We will speak the truth, whatever we do, 
And try to be honest, brave, and true. 
Thoughtful for others, patient alway. 
That's what we will do upon Christmas Day. 

TEACHER. 

That I am sure is a better plan, 
Be kind and do all the good you can. 

(Knocking outside; sound of bells and some one singing.) 
Tune:— "Oh, Have You Heard Geography Sung?" 

Here I come knocking now at your door, 
Now at your door, now at your door; 
Here I come knocking now at your door, 
While Christmas bells are a-ringing. 

CHILDREN. 

Who is there ? 

(Door opens and Santa Clans puts in his head.) 

SANTA CLAU8. 

I am Mr. Santa Claus, 
Only come to call. 

Here's a lot of Christmas things, 
You can have them all. 

(Puts his pack on the threshold.) 

CHILDREN. 

Thank you, Mr. Santa Claus, 
You are welcome here. 

Please step in a moment, sir, 
And pass the time of year. 
We are only boys and girls 
feeping Christmas Day, 
nd welre always glad whene'er 
r e see you come this way. 

SANTA CLAD8. 

Nay, I must not wait for you, 
I have far to go. 

Over Afric's burning sands, 
Russia's steppes of snow. 
With my reindeer, like a bird, 
Through the air I fly. 

Time is up — now little folks, 
I am off — good bye. 

(Goes away singing while the bells ring, until the sound la lost In 
the distance.) </seg>

            <seg id="p135">
313 

SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES. 

thit 

Tune:—" The Spanish CaTaller." 
Oh, farewell, farewell ! 

I can no longer stay 

For I must away o'er the snow, dears; 
The short winter's day 

Will soon speed away. 

Remember and be true where you go, dears. 
(Children join hands and dance around, reciting:) 

Old Santa Claus has gone 
To other lands afar, 

But O, he's left such loads of toys, 
Hurrah! Hurrah! Hurrah! 

(Knock at the door; enter child, bearing a Christmas tree.l 

CHILD. 

Here's a little Christmas tree, 
Ail with toys 'tis laden. 

Pretty gifts old Santa Claus 
Brought for each wee maiden. 

BOYS. 

(Beginning to cry.) 

For the girls, O, dear! O, dear! 
Where then, axe our toys ? 

TEACHER. 

Don't you fear, good Santa Claus 
Won't forget the boys. 

Just outside, I'm sure I see, 
Trumpet, fife, and drum, 

Hoops and marbles, skates and sleds, 
Each one will have some. 

(Enter children ringing small bells.) 
We are little Christmas bells. 

Don't you hear us ringing ? 

(Enter Carol singers.) 
CAROL SINOERS. 

We are merry Christmas Waifs. 
You shall hear us sing. 

They sing " Beautiful Christmas Time."; 

{Written for Teacher' t World and adapted for 
program by Department of Public Instruction.) 

jeautiful Christmas Time. 

Adapted to the tune "Hail Columbia." 
B autiful this, our Christmas time, 
Beautiful bells, with silv'ry chime, 
Beautiful words are these we say, 
Beautiful words are these we say, — 
Jesus, our King, is born today, 

Jesus our King is born. 

Beautiful angels came of old, 

Sang to the shepherds near their fold; 
Beautiful story told to them, 

Beautiful story told to them, — 
Jesus is born in Bethlehem, 

Is born in Bethlehem. </seg>


            <seg id="p136">
STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Beautiful songs they sing today, 
Sweeter by far than earthly lay; 
Join in the chorus, all who sing, 
Join in the chorus, all who sing, — 
Joy to the world, our Lord is King, 

Joy, our Lord is King! 

— Prom Sunshine Melodies. 

\ Enter several children dressed to represent popoorn 
and nuts. Pop-corn wears yellow and white and 
has a string of pop-corn around his neck; nuf wear 
brown. 

POP-CORNS. 

We are little pop -corns, and 
Wnen around the fire 

Christmas Eve, you're sitting all, 
No one can jump higher. 

NUT8. 

We are Christmas nuts so brown, 
That the boys are bringing. 
Crack us while the merry girls 
Christinas songs are singing. 

CHILDREN. 

Don't you think we well may be, 
Ha PPy, glad, and gay, 

When so many things we have 
For our Christmas Day? 

TEACHER. 

Yes, my little children; and 
Thank the One in heaven, 

Who, from out His boundless love, 
Christ '8 birthday has given. 

CHILDREN. 

Won't you tell the story, pray, 
Of that first glad Christmas Day? 

TEACHER. 

Yes, I'll tell it. 

CHILDREN. 

Now? 

TEACHER. 

Nay, wait, 

Someone stands outside the gate. 
Don't you hear their voices ring? 
'Tis a Christmas song they sing. 

(Voices outside singing.) 

Tune:— "What a Friend We Have in Jesus." 
We are coming, we are coming, 
Wh^re our bright rays all may see, 
We are coming, we are coming, 
Now to grace your Christmas tree. 
For we know that God is saying, 
As each ray doth shimmer down, 
That a Babe for you, dear children, 
Now is born in Bethlehem town. 
(Enter sererel children. They wear buff dresses and 

a band of gilt paper about their foreheads, with one star 
In the oeafer.) </seg>

            <seg id="p137">
315 



Who are you? 

STARS. 

Don't you know us? 

Then, on some starry night, 
Look upward to the heavens, 
You will see us shining bright. 
Our homes are in the ether; 
We are stars that gem the sky ; 
And we come to you, dear children, 
From that blus dome up on high. 
We've come to tell unto you, 
How once, when he looked down, 
Upon the humble dwellings 

In ancient Bethelem town, 
We saw where, in a stable, 
All cradled in the hay, 
Within a lowly manger, 
The Baby Jesus lay. 

FIRST STAR. 

I saw out on the hillsides, 

The wondering shepherds, bowed 
Before the heavenly choir, 
A shining, glorious crowd. 

SECOND STAR. 

Their ladder reached the heavens 
And loud their voices rang, 
As to the awe-struck shepherds, 
The heavenly chorus sang. 

"Peace, peace on earth," they chanted, 
"Good will, good will," and then, 

"Glad tidings we are bringing, 

Unto the sons of men." 

THIRD STAR. 

I shone within the stable, 
And there the shepherds saw, 
Before that Baby bending, 

In mute, adoring awe. 

FOURTH STAR. 

Far off, across the desert, 

From their distant Eastern home, 
With balm and myrrh and spices, 
I saw three Wise Men come. 

FIFTH STAR. 

Twas I who went before them, 
Through all the weary way, 
And shone above the stable, 

Where the little Christ-child lay. 

SIXTH STAR. 

And when the Wise Men found Him, 
Led by a guiding star, 

I saw the precious jewels 
They brought Him from afar. </seg>

            <seg id="p138">
316 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT^ REPORT. 

TOGETHER. 

Then when the Babe they'd worshipped,— 
Each Wise Man, well content, 

Back to the Eastern country, 
By another pathway went. 
This is the precious story, 
So old, yet ever new, 

And we have come, dear children, 

To tell it unto you. 

(Tune: "Lightly Row.") 

ALL SING. 

Prom the starry realms of space, 
We have come a weary way, 
To help the little children keep 

A merry Christmas Day. 

CHORUS. 

We are shining, shining for you, 
Shining for you, little children dear, 
For Christmas Day is ever the best, 

The best of all the year. 

CHILDREN RECITE. 

O, little stars that came to earth, 
To tell us of the Christ-child's birth, 
We welcome you and, hand in hand, 
Together a united band, 

Let us so gaily march along 

And wake the echoes with a song; 
And while to heaven the chorus swells, 

Loud let us ring the Christmas bells. 

(They Join bands and march two by two around the stage, ringing bells and singing 
Christmas Welcome.) 


The Christinas Welcome 

Tune: " Tramp, Tramp, Tramp." 

When the summer time is passed and the harvest housed at last, 
And the woods are standing bare and brown and sere, 

When the frost is sharp at night, and the days are short and bright, 
Comes the gladdest, merriest time of all the year. 

CHORUS. 

Shout, boys, shout the hearty welcome ! 
Greet old Christmas with a roar! 

He has met us with good cheer for this many a merry year, 
And we hope he'll meet us all for many more. 

Then away with every cloud that our pleasure might enshroud, 
And away with every word and look unkind; 

Let old quarrels all be healed and old friendships closer sealed, 
And our lives with sweeter, purer ties entwined. 

Since we know the blessed power of this happy Christmas hour, 
We will keep its holy spell upon our heart, 

Thit each evil thing within that would tempt us into sin, 
tf forever from our peaceful souls depart. 

— Lizzie M. Hadley, in Song Knapsack. </seg>

            <seg id="p139">
317 


Christmas 

thousand years of the world's existence rolled painfully and wearily 
\./ along, and no Christ. Two thousand years and no Christ. Three thou- 

sand years and no Christ. Four thousand years and no Christ. 

iBut the slow century, and the slow year, and the slow month, and the slow 
r at last arrived. The world had had matins or concerts in the morning, 
vespers or concerts in the evening, but now it is to have a concert at midit. 
The black window shutters of a December night were thrown open, and 
e of the best singers of the world, where they all sing, stood there, and 
ing back the drapery of cloud, chanted a peace anthem, until the echoes 
ill and valley applauded and encored the hallelujah chorus. 

¦ At last the world has a Christ, and just the Christ it needs. Come, let us 
go into that Christmas scene as though we had never before worshiped at the 
manger. Here is a Madonna worth looking at. I wonder not that the most 
frequent name in all lands and in all Christian centuries is Mary. And there 
are Marys in palaces and Marys in cabins, and although German and French, 
and Italian, and Spanish, and English pronounce it differently, they are all 
namesakes of the one whom we find on a bed of straw with her pale face 
against the soft cheek of Christ in the night of the nativity . 
All the great painters have tried on canvas to present Mary and her child, 
and the incidents of that most famous night of the world's history. Raphael, 
in three different masterpieces, celebrated them. Tintoret and Gurrlandjo 
surpassed themselves in the adoration of the Magi. Correggio needed to do no 
more than his Madonna to become immortal. The Madonna of the Lily, by 
Leonardo da Vinci, will kindle the admiration of all ages. Murillo never won 
greater triumph by his pencil than in his presentation of the Holy Family. 
But all the galleries of Dresden are forgotten when I think of the small room 
of that gallery containing that Sistine Madonna. Yet all of them were copies 
of St. Matthew's Madonna and Luke's Madonna of the Old Book, which he 
had put into our hands when we were infants, and that we hope to have under 
our heads when we die. 

Behold in this Bible scene, how, on that Christmas night, God honored 
childhood. Christ might have made his first visit to our world in a cloud, as 
he will descend on his next visit in a cloud. In what a chariot of illuminated 
vapor he might have rolled down the sky, escorted by mounted cavalry, with 
lightning or drawn sword. Elijah had a carriage of fire to take him up; why 
not Jesus a carriage of fire to fetch him down ? Or, over the arched bridge 
of a rainbow, the Lord might have descended. Our Christ might have had 
bis mortality built up on earth out of the dust of a garden, as was Adam, in 
full manhood, at the start, without the introductory feebleness of infancy. 
No, No ! Childhood was to be honored by that event. He must have a child's 
light limbs, and a child's dimpled hand, and a child's beaming eye, and a 
child's flaxen hair, and babyhood was to be honored for all time to come, and 
a cradle was to mean more than a grave. Mighty God ! May the reflection 
of that one child's face be seen in all infantile faces. Enough have those 
fathers and mothers on hand if they have a child in the house. A throne, a 
crown, a scepter, a kingdom under charge. Be careful how you strike him 
across the head, jarring the brain. What you say to him will be centennial 
and millennial, and one hundred years, and one thousand years will not stop 
the echo and re-echo. 

E[en, women, nations, all earth, and all Heaven, behold the child ! Is 
any velvet so soft as a child's cheek ? Is there any sky so blue as a 
s eye ? Is there any music so sweet as the child's voice ? Is there any 
) so wavy as a child r s hair ? 

K Behold also that on that Christmas night, God honored motherhood. Two 
;ls on their wings might have brought an infant Savior, to Bethlehem 
iout Mary's being there at all. When the villagers, on the morning of 
ember 25 awoke, by divine arrangement, and in some unexplained way, </seg>

            <seg id="p140">
318 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

the child Jesus might have been found in some comfortable home of the Tillage. 
But, No, No ! Motherhood for all time was to .be consecrated, and one 
of the tenderest relations was to be the maternal relation, and one of the sweeteat 
words, "mother." In all ages, God has honored good motherhood: John 
Wesley had a good mother, Samuel Budgett had a good mother, St. Bernard 
had a good mother, Doddridge a good mother, Walter Scott a good mother, 
Benjamin West a good mother. In a great audience, most of whom were 
Christians, I asked that all those who had been blessed of Christian mothers 
arise, and almost the entire assembly stood up. Don't you see how important 
it is that all motherhood be consecrated r Why did Titian, the Italian 
artist, when he sketched the Madonna, make it an Italian face r Why did 
Rubens, the German artist, in his Madonna, make it a German face ? Why 
did Joshua Reynolds, the English artist, in his Madonna, make it an English 
face ? Why did Murillo, the Spanish artist, in his Madonna, make it a 
Spanish face ? I never heard, but I think they took their own mothers as the 
type of Mary, the mother of Christ. When you hear some one in sermon or 
oration speak in the abstract of a good, faithful, honest mother, your eyes fill 
with tears, while you say to yourself, that was my mother. 

The first word a child utters is apt to be "mother," and the old i. ji in his 
dying dreams, calls "Mother! Mother!" It matters not whether she was 
brought up in the surroundings of the city, and in an affluent home, and was 
dressed appropriately with reference to the demands of modern life, or 
whether she wore the old-time cap and great, round spectacles, and apron of 
her own make and knit your socks with her own needles, seated by the broad 
fireplace, with a great black log ablaze on a winter night. It matters not 
how many wrinkles crossed and re-crossed her face, or how much her shoulders 
stooped with the burdens of a long life, if you painted a Madonna, hers 
would be the face. What a gentle hand she had when we were sick, and what 
a voice to soothe, and was there any one who could so fill up a room with 
peace, and purity, and light ? And what a sad day that was when we came 
home and she could greet us not, for her lips were still forever. Come back, 
mother, this Christmas day, and take your old place, and, as ten, or twenty, 
or fifty years ago, come and open the Old Bible you used to read, and kneel 
in the same place where you used to pray, and look upon us as of old when 
you wished us a merry Christmas or a happy New Year. But no! That 
would not be fair to call you back. You had troubles enough, and aches 
enough, and bereavements enough while you were here. Tarry by the throne, 
mother, till we join you there, your prayers all answered, and in the eternal 
homestead of our God we shall again keep Christmas jubilee together. But 
speak from your thrones, all you glorified mothers, and say to all these, your 
sons and daughters, words of love, words of warning, words of cheer. They 
need your voice, for they have traveled far and with many a heart-break since 
you left them, and you do well to call from the heights of Heaven to the valleys 
of the earth. Hail, enthroned ancestry! We are coming. Keep a place 
right beside you at the banquet. 

" Slow -footed years! More swiftly run 
Into the goal of that unsetting sun. 
Homesick we are for thee, 

Calm land beyond the so a." 

— Rev. T. DeWitt Talmage. </seg>

            <seg id="p141">
319 

SPECIAL DAY KXKKCMBB. 

References for Special Days 

Abraham Lincoln 

Baldwin's Story of Abraham Lincoln for Young Reader*. — Werner 

¦Baldwin's Story oi J 
sol Book Co., Chicago. 

¦John Burns of Gettysburg, The Little Drummer, Jennie M' Neal, Little 
en, in Ballads of American Bravery.— Silver, Burdett ft Co., Chicago. 

¦The Soldier's Reprieve, in Our Country in Poem and Prose.— American 
k Co., Chicago. 

The Words of Abraham Lincoln.— Western Publishing Howe, Chief. 
Best Lincoln Stories. — James E. Oallaher &amp; Co., Chicago. 

Lincoln's Speeches. — Rhodes &amp; McClure, Chicago. 
Morse's Life of Lincoln. — Houghton, MifBin ft Co., Boston. 

George Washington 

Baldwin's Story of George Washington for Young Reader*.— Wotmt 
School Book Co., Chicago. 

The Rising of '76, Independence Bell, At Valley Forge, Our Country is 
Poem and Prose.— The American Book Co., Chicago. 

¦Washington's Rules of Conduct and Farewell Addrem. — Ainm»octa 
Chicago. 

Irving's Life of Washington.— A. L. Burt, New York. 

Henry Cabot Lodge's Life of Washington. Hooffhton, MiMta ft Ce., 

Exercises for Washington's Birthday, Dick's Festival Reciter.— Dtek * 
Fitzgerald, New York. 

Kow to Celebrate Washington's Birthday in the School »¦¦¦¦—«. 1 
rg A Co., New York. 

Henry W. Longfellow 

A Longfellow Program. — American Journal of UMaatoa, 8*. Lena* 

A Longfellow Day.— Published in The Helper, by fleheei Uwaatea O 
Minneapolis, Minn. 

¦Program for Longfellow Day.— Published in The Teeeaert' WorM, by 
tis Publishing Co., New York. 

¦How to Celebrate Longfellow's Birthday in the Mwai Roeav-E. I. 
ogg &amp; Co., New York. 

Arbor Day 

To a Pine, The Oak, The Birch Tree.— Lowell. 

Forest Hymn, Planting of the Apple Tree.— Bryant. 
¦ The Sycamores, The Trailing Arbutus, The LoatbenBaa.Tae Fataa Tmm. 

The Builders, Hiawatha's Sailing, Description of FtoiMH in fiaaaillnn. 
— Longfellow. 

Under The Washington Elm, The Lart Leaf.— Hoimn. 
Arbor Day Songs and Exercises.— Dick * FHagoraM, Mew York. 
How to Celebrate Arbor Day in the School Rooav X. L. KeUoajr * Oh, 

New York. 

Arbor Day, Edited and Compiled by Horn. Babwi W. Tmntmm 

K.i uui j-/ay . £iuiwu aiiu vuiupiivu urjr nu«i. nwvrt vw , r «rm^. wvbotbw 
n. J. Sterling Morton, Author of Arbor Day. 8ta— Journal Cn., Las- 
Nebraska. 

Arbor Day: Its History and Obeerrance.— N. H. gggl— lea, Qiwh— I 

Printing Office, Washington, D. C. </seg>

            <seg id="p142">
320 

STATE SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT. 

Bird Day 

The Birds of Killingsworth, The Herons of Elrawood, The Legend of the 
Crossbill.— Longfellow. 

Our Friends in Feathers and Fur, Nature's Reader. — American Book Co., 

BOnr Feathered Friends, Margaret Miller's Saturday Bird Class.— D. C. 
th ft Co., Chicago. 

Birds Before Uncle Sam.— The Macmillan Co., New York. 

Memorial Day 

Patriotic Quotations.— The Whitaker &amp; Ray Publishing Co., San Fran- 

Our Country in Poem and Prose.— American Book Co., Chicago. 
»¦» , • u _ T» 1 TT ~ ITU Al — 1 n..WK.L: /"I _ f 

Patriotism in Prose and Verse. — Educational Publishing Co., Topeka, 
Mammas. 

Ballads of American Bravery.— Silver, Burdett it Co., Chicago. 

KA Memorial Day Exercise. — Dick it Fitzgerald, New York. 
The Broom Drill, The Fan Drill, The School of the Soldier.— E. L. Kel- 
I k. Co., New York. 

Library Day 

Little Boy Blue.Wynken, Blinken it Nod, Pittypat and Tippytoe.— Eugene 

Child-Rhymes by James Whitcomb Riley. — The Bowen-Merrill Company, 
Indianapolis. 
Dick's Comic and Dialect Recitations. — Dick it Fitzgerald, New York. 

Authors' Days.— E. L. Kellogg &amp; Co., New York. 

Thanksgiving 

Thanksgiving Exercises. — Dick Sc Fitzgerald, New York. 

KHow to Celebrate Thanksgiving in the School Room.— E. L. Kellogg it 
New York. 

Christmas 

Long Afore I Knowed Who Santy Claus Wuz.— Riley 

Jest ' Fore Christmas, The Peace of Christmas Time, Christmas Treas- 

A Christmas Entertainment.— Dick it Fitzgerald, New York. 

A Visit from St. Nicholas.— Fourth Reader of Stepping Stones to Litentore. 


KThe Christmas Angel, A Christmas Star, The Christmas Dolls, in Prose 
Verse. — American Book Co., Chicago. 
How to Celebrate Christmas in the School -Room.— E. L. Kellogg it Co., 
rYork. 

For All Days 

Special Day Programs.— Published by the Department of Public Instruction, 
Lincoln, Nebraska, in former yean. 


[W 

HTT 1^ 

— — </seg>


            <seg id="p143">

»? 

*i; ff ijtf 

¦H 

i 


*» 


*J» - 

»5 



'- — 



til asr 
*¦ — 


« t i : 


fc — 




/ 

u, ¦ 

' ~ 


_r 

m n %* 

-.S:. 

~ ••. 


my ihtp 

-/. 

a 


* 


i si a 

' . « 

x 


, 

•• v 

«ft. v 


* 



X 

» 

ff* *J HHh 

tttt H- 

• ¦*• 



ffi^Ii* - 

ti 

'• ••, 

.. ... 

ivi- T+H-f 




-*-" 



m l 

mmL 


In? s" % * 





W 

,. . • x 

iiniu 

• 

- . - ¦ * 


tro « r- 

sffffl Si-nflti 

i"- 

n*s5 — 


ffi£ f *K 

¦im 

*m oit 


A SPECIMEN PAGE FROM SONfiS OF THE YEAIT 

i vl neir collection of word* and nulodiea for Ike rmrimmimmitmm im 4mUm 
*chool life by John Hyatt Brewer and Fredme B»4*mtt "Tlilf te 
Maynard. Merrill &lt;t Company. 29, 31. and 33. Em* NimtUmdh «m( 
.V^w Fork.) 

iS inn 
&lt;5 ili- 

-r ± *x 

L.:i S "' 1- »; 
iSte gjj ... . • 
; | hi";:, -m vi'- </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>