<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Preparation of Laboratory Specimens as an Aid to the Diagnosis of Animal Diseases</title>
               <date value="1922-06">1922-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">&lt; 1" llill June. IW3 The Preparation of Laboratory Specimens as an Aid to the Diagnosis of Animal Diseases VAN ES AND I.. V. SKIDMORE DEPARTMENT OK ANIMAL PATHOLOGY AND HYGIENE VGKICITLTUKAL EXPERIMENT STATION' THE IMVKRSITY OF NKHHASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Pape Introduction General directions Laboratory to be advised The importance of cleanlines Identification of specimens Laboratory not an oracle -i Need of discrimination Four types of examination 1 Patho-anatomic examinations Bacteriologric examinations Serologic examinations ParasitoloKic examination More specific directions Tuberculosis Glanders Actinomycosi Anthrax Blackleg Hemorrhagic: septicemia Hog cholera and other swine diseases Poultry diseases H Rabies 1&lt; Abortion H </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Preparation of Laboratory Specimens a an Aid to the Diagnosis of Animal Diseases I.. VAN ES AND L. V. SKIDMORF. DEPARTMENT OF ANIMAL PATHOLOGY AND HYGIENE INTRODUCTION Manv problems in connection with animal diseases require their Rotation the implication of methods which can only be Ifiiaken mi properly equipped laboratories. This ordinarily i i . i 1 1 involves the collection, packing, and shipping of samples of s|&gt;eci - nifii-. Tin- manner in which this i&gt; done is a most important factor anil to a very large extent is responsible either for the M or for the failure of the undertaking. The discussion of the subject to which the following pages ■«■ devoted is taken in hand in the hope that it may provide lidance to the veterinarians and others who mav have occasion o reipiire the assistance of a laboratory in the solution of dMMMC iroblems. (iENERAL DIRECTIONS Before consideration is given to more &gt;j&gt;ecitic methods, it seems advisable to make mention of certain details of general im - portance. Among thex'. emphasis must l&gt;e placed on the need of having the specimen a&lt;'companietl by as complete a description f tile problem as possible. LABORATORY TO BE ADVISED Not only should the laboratory Ih&gt; notified that certain ma - terial is being sent, but the nature of the latter should be stated. The kind of animal and the part of the body from which the apecuM ii taken should Ih&gt; mentioned. A brief description of the symptoms of the disease involved will l&gt;e useful, while i he suspected nature of the disease or its tentative diagnosis -hould lie jriven if this is at all possible. When the material per - tain&gt; to an outbreak of disease, knowledge as to its course and U-lnivior in the herd or flock will be as useful to the laboratory worker as to the practitioner or owner. THE IMPORTANCE OP CLEANLINESS Another important detail is the need of collecting the speci - mens with regard to a maximum degree of cleanliness. Whether they 1h&gt; taken from the living or from the dead, absolute cleanliness must U' observed, and this should be persisted in in </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nkhhaska Enmn Station. Circii.ar 1&lt;&gt; 4 I f I I all further handling of Mm material, no matter what type &gt;&gt;f examination !*■ required. In the ewe of autopsies, this rieanlmess can hot Ik* promoted by ■ systematic and orderly method oi procedure; while, when' material is collected from the living animal, tli.- hum aseptic t.'clini«|iit' wludi n paad awpoa follow - -hoidd find application. IDENTIFICATION OF SPECIMENS AYhen material in one -hipment is taken from more than we animal it should be provided with proper identification nark- VII parcels &gt;liip|M-.l -hould !»■ plainly addp*»«d ■ml should show the mum «nd iddirss of the dipper. It shmihl I* •.•mrinlMT.-l thai prepaid &gt;hipn..nt- a- a nil.' aiv moiv prompt l&gt; lelivered. . , , , ,. In tin- cullfction ipd packinp "'' ■"»««™« l «&lt; fl "' """'■ cl inite purpoweK. dose attention should !»■ friven to tlic in specific directions furnished when dealiiift with th*we «jmm .!!&gt;«■-. Shipment should Ik- made at a lime when there i - least portability of tli.' specimens being k.-pl "&gt; wtnn «ni offices or |M»t office- over Snn.lav- or holiday-. LABORATORY NOT AN ORACLE mission of special teal tnd thiit i-. tliat many method- and in order Before en&lt;rajLriny in the di more thing remain* t" '"■ ~ - i|l(l cannot 1m' Milved by laboratory disappointment the patron «rf a can do and what it cannot do. lalnililUil'V -lioill It i- a mi-takei a peep into a micro-cope m laboratory worker ran solvi - aiiv prohlem. There are many which In- cannot a- yet sijvi wliile there «re others in which the solution involves cultivation method- and animal inoculation-. NEED OF DISCRIMINATION Certain dkwwe* can be diafno*il with ■ fair derive ,,t accuracy by IiIimmI examination-, but in many thi- i- as yei inipowsible. Neither i- il always powiMe to tell by _ the exaiin nation of a jriven arpan wmit mav be the cau-e of disease, roi instan.'i. bnoratories frequently receive samples of Irfuml am are asked to determine whether or not a given animal died o blackleg, when the sender of such a specimen was MM aware o the fact that the fuuii of l.lacklejr aw usually Bbaenl from tin 1&gt;I(mm1. while they always can be found in the alerted muscle* It i- necoMirv therefore that a mea-ure of discrimination 1h- iimm in the seiHliiijr &lt;tf specimens for the solution &lt;&gt;f the ram* problems. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I'lIK 1*KKI"AR.\TIOX ok LaIWIRATOKY Sl'KI IMKN 5 I" I ii tii I I \ I I I I i ii it FOUR TYPES OF EXAMINATION" The Material received at the lal&gt;oratorie- for diagnostic pnr- MM call WUllly Im' roushlv divided into four jrroups in ac - .rdance with the t_v|M- of examination re&lt;|iiirc(l. Tllt'V a IV tilt' nnen&gt; sent for anatomic (pathologic), bacteriolagie. «a •. and panisitolojrir examinations. Their treat meiit m to illei-lion lid packing somewhat varies a n&lt; I htMicp this inu.st Im - ciilKilled -eparatelv. In :i few eases the diagnotor may raqwre iat tli«' material -ul&gt;mittei| bt looked into from fill angles, illll) it i- sometimes aclvi able tliat it Im 1 prepared in more tlian ir«Y, PATHO-ANATOM1C EXAMINATIONS I lie aiiiitoinic examination of diseased animal- or their gans lia- a- it- purpose the reeojfiiit ion of the dJMSW involved the rhsngeii it prodncen in the orjrans. Sn&lt;-h disea-e- aa tohcr - o«is, jrliindfi-. lifcrolmcillosis. liojr choh'ni. and many others ;ive their di&gt;l inctive mark&gt; upon one or -everal organs bjr which ev can lie n i co&lt;riii/.ed. Material requiring tin- kind of examination -hoiiM Ik* mi - ll soon after the death of tile animal and in an clean si inner aa possible. ( )rf;ans or ti»nes sent to a lalniratoi'V should ver l«" washed, a- the water used i- apt to chanjre tlie original lor. If weather conditions permit, the material should he -^nt the fre&gt;h &gt;t;ile. that i&gt;. without the in 1 of preservatives. Thi- iiiportant, a&gt; the latter an 1 a|&gt;t to change the origiaal color may make it impo~&gt;il&gt;le to u-c the material also for hai tllin ic HXiniilUtioi). [^Irfe piece- of tissue inav. however. 1h- i— i — — — .■ --. in powdered Korax. Thin d&lt;M-~ not penetrate verv deeplv II iiTlainlv retard HMrrore decomposition during warm icr. A- a rule, -mailer piece- decompose le&gt;- rapidlv than one-, during tranxtt. Wlien piece- of orjrans are s&lt;Mit in h -late, tliev -lionltl he removed from the body in the -I manlier po--il&gt;le and not 1m&gt; permitted to come in cont-ict ■n.V other ol&gt;je&lt;t or -ill&gt;stance. 'I'hev -hoidd lx- Wl'apped. r.'feiahlv in a few layers of ehee-ecloth or muslin. When tho-c nitric- are not procurable, a loose wrapping of a porous kind of ipef (papef toweling or new- paper) may he the next choice. lach piece -liould he wrapped -eparatelv and the ditfeivnt pack - p»s -liould not he piled on top of one another, the abject heiag peiniil a rather free ace •— and circulation of air iirouud them. After their collection they can he placed in the 1m&gt;.\ to l&gt;e -ed for shipping. Pliis boa -liould never \te made air-tight &lt; : must h* of rather open construction, so that the moisture giren rf l&gt;y the material will not !&gt;;■ retained within. the package. This </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 NkHKASKA KXI'KKIMKM Station. Cum i.ak If. is of special importance when a considerable hulk is beinjr in - cluded in the shipment. When small pieces are lH-in&lt;r sent. this feature is not so important provided the container is quite roomy. There should Ik 1 an abundance of excelsior, hay. sawdust, or chart lietween the specimens and the sides, bottom, and top of the box a~ well as U-tween the niMM parcels compri-injr t hi- -liipiiient. Ill the cas«' of poultry and the ■nailer farm animals, the whole carcass can 1m- shipped after l&gt;ein&lt;r prepared like the larger piece-. The shipping of i«rc*iwpii during the warmer weather can not. however, alwav- U- advised. V.'hen it is done nevertheless, the wrapping of the carcass should Ik- sprinkled with formaldelivdi before Im-mi^ placed in ilie box. A siifrimnn l&gt;ox ready for shi| While it is preferable that tissues for pathologic examination Ik.- sent in tlie fiv-h stale. tlii&gt; cannot always Ih- done, owing to the lonjr periods involved in transportation. In -u»-li cases -mall pieces inav be placed in a Id per cent solution of formalin.' This i- even preferable in the case of tumors sent for microscopic examination. Care must, however. U- taken that the liquid has altout ten times the volume of the tissues sent, in order to bring :■ ) m &gt;■ 1 1 the desirable degree of fixation. Of tumors, the whole niav !»' sent: but when tlii- is not 1 The formaldehyde solution uf rummtrce is 4iip|&gt;osed to contuin 40 p**r MM of formal - dehyde iraa. A truod solution for preservinK and fixing Umm should contain i pt-r cent of the k»s. or. in other word*, one part of the utrontr commercial solution to nine parts of water. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">r L\iM&gt;n\T&lt;nn Si-KiniKNs I'lIK l'ltK.I'Al: A I ION 7 ilc. -mall pieces may Ik- taken, preferably from the growing iririn. in mu-Ii a wav that a small bit of the invaded, normal mains attached. lk\ nature should never 1m- sent for any MVpaH whatever iled container- unless it Ih- frozen or packet! in ice. Nothing is more inducing to rmpid putrefaction than the placing of a juicy iriran in a tightly sealed jar or can. When sections of intestine uv -ent. they can be ligated on both ends and preferably U - packed in such a manner that thev cannot come in contact with BACTERIOLOGIC EXAMINATIONS In many problems connected with disease of animals, the atomic examination is not sufficient, me characteristic lesions frequently absent. In quite a large number of such cases it uilv possible to arrive at a definite diagnosis by the finding nd identification of the causative microorganism. In some ■a-e- tlii— can 1m&gt; done bv h simple microscopic examination, hut &amp; — w — w reat majority require animal inoculations or the use of culture method**. It is thu- necessary not only that the organism - premmed to ba present in the material be in a living or viable state but that they be not accompanied by a great assortment of bacteria of putrefaction. If it is thus essential to have ma ferial taken, packed, and shipped under the best possible con - dition of fnflhneflfl and cleanliness. a&gt; was pointed out above, it i- doubly -o when a bacteriologic examination is in prospect. Knrtliernioiv. -ample- which are to serve for this purpose cannot l»e submerged in preservatives or antiseptics. a&gt; those substances will al&gt;o kill all organisms of disease. At the most the packing of lane pieces of material in powdered l&gt;orax can l&gt;e allowed. The use of ice is often indicated in oases of this kind. On the whole, the apecimens -ent for bacteriologic examination need not Im' verv large. They can l&gt;e wrapped in clean gauze, placed in a clean, ctaaed fruit jar. and thus packed in a candy pail full of cniflhed ice or WIOW. Pieces of organs may also l&gt;e [&gt;ennitted to freeze and be shipped in a frozen condition, provided that enough •Trapping be supplied to prevent thawing during transportation. In the case of whole carcasses the freezing should not be carried too far, as the thawing proce— would require too long a period for practical pwpoam Small samples of milk. pus. or blood can Ik' sent in crushed ice iii the manner already indicated, or they may Ik 1 placed in a large, thick walled, sterile test till*', closed with a sterile rubber -topper and placed in a hole drilled in a block of ice by means Material taken from orniu or ti»iu'&gt; of :i more &lt;&gt;r !»■&gt; ■tliiT materials in tin- shipment. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Kxi'Kkimknt Station. Cuktlai l« 8 I ga brace and larjre bit. The hole i&gt; tlit'ii closed bv mean- of ii ug of &lt;-&lt;)tton and the block is wnppad in burlap and placed in abundance of liav or excelsior. ned in a block &lt;if Fhi. 2. Specimen conta Another mutable method of paekmjr in which a low |K»rature t«"ii&lt;l~ to kt-cp the MpeetRira frrxb invoJvw the n :i thanm bottle or jar. Specimen ami rantaincT an' prpri chilled and the whole packed in -&lt;&gt;mr non-cooductiii^ mat I In many ciw- il i- advisal&gt;l&lt;- to Head M&lt;mhI linear- : witli tlie other matt-rial taken from an animal or csrcttK the preparation of ■Marx, ordinary micruMrope Jides arc fei"iv«l. l»ut when those in not availaUlr ;i pie«f of com I'd il window jrla*.-. may l&gt;e used. In either cane the Kiirface of tli must be tlioroly cleaned and freed from yiea-c by 1 1 1 « - u - of jrasoline. alcohol, or ether. 'I'lie «mr ix maile by dippin the edge of a clean visiting card in the blood to In' n-cd an ai then Maa| thi&gt; edp- over the imrface &lt;&gt;f the jrla — in -u manner that a very thin Klin of Mood is distributed over it. This is permitted to dry thorolv in the air and after drvness is se- cured the carrying the Klin is wrapped m a piece of plain paper or tinfoil, after which it is ready for ship- F |.;. .!. Method of preparing blood </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The I'kki'auation ok I^xbokatory Specimens 9 int'iit. It i- alwa\s tatter to send more tlian one slide of the aMM iiniiiial. iiml caw should Ik&gt; taken that they I*' not &lt;rlned together by the omission of drying and wrapping. I'ii- may !«■ collected in a iride-moiithe&lt;l. sterile Ixittle, land with ■ sterile Copper; or it niav Ik- -utticient to collect i small quantity on a riterue &gt;wal&gt;. kept in a -terile test What A &gt;\val&gt; i&gt; prepared by wrapping a l&gt;it of al&gt; - -orlx'iit cotton on a piece of wire, placing it in a rest nil*-. pliifTfriiifr the seme with non-al&gt;*orl&gt;eiit cotton, and sterilizing it by means of dry heat (kitchen oven). The method otfer&gt; the advan - tage tliat. while -mall quantities of pus or &lt;lis - rharM can DC collected, there is no need of soil - ing the Hnjrer&gt; of the operator. Thi- i- especially ini|ioitant when virulent discharge i s -ii&gt;|&gt;e&lt;tcd I (f landers). i In tile ca-c i&gt;f certain &lt;li&gt;e:ise--. it i~ ailvi&gt;al&gt;lc to colle&lt;-t the blood on abaarWal material and to |»ei-niit it to dry rapidly by exposure to the air For tlii: — purpoHe rods of planter of Pari f common i-halk. or even clean paper can SEKOLiHUC EXAMINATIONS Seroloffic exaniinationM for the detection of employed. For IiIimiiI or m'I'iiiii desired 1)V the &lt;sential that dur- lhi&gt; purpOM BUtall &lt; | n:t lit it ie- of iVoin the MMpeeted aniinals arc lahoratorv worker. It i- hishlv « ing the collection and further manipulations the specimen! l&gt;e ntwtd and kept in a perfectly -terile container. Sterile collecting needlea &lt;&gt;r rannlaM and contaiiier&gt; are tlni&gt; pivriH|ni&gt;ite. while rare inu-t be taken to &lt;riiard a&lt;rain&gt;t interenrrent fontamination. I'ln 1 samples from most of the farm aniinaU are secured by the insertion of a hypodermic needle or cannla into the jugular vein ami under the usual precaution*, which raajUTC no further description. Blood from &gt;wine i&gt; ln'^t olitaiui'd by snipping a piece of the tail after a thoro cleansing of the part&gt; and by collectinjr the tine -tre-im or drop- of blood which issue from the severed Vessel into the vial or hottle to Im - u~ed for shipping. Fhi. 4. — 8w«b us*d for the col - lection of pun or &lt;li?*charire. .... ... ... -•-.- ---1 .- -.- --"I - — — - mlfr to encouragr the rapid formation &lt;if iMiiiin ilix-asf^ iiri 1 now widely </seg>
            <seg id="p010">NkBRASKA ExTKIilMKNT STATION. ClRCl LAH 16 10 For the purpose of collecting, the following method is raeom - mended. Prepare and sterilize the required nuinl&gt;er of heavy tad tubes or shell vials, each one provided with a good cork Copper which is roughened on the lower surface. Permit to flow into each container from ten to twenty cubic centimeters of blood and eldM container by means of the stopper. While the blood is still liquid, the tube or vial is turned upside down and in tlii&gt; ]M&gt;sition the clotting of the blood is permitted to take place. When the coagulation is complete the tube with the blood chit in its upper part is again placed in its pro|&gt;er position and put iu the cooler overnight. The serum will then gradually How to the bottom and the red clot remains attached to the cork. Tkc latter is then carefully removed and the adhering clot is -liaken off. The cork is replaced in the vessel, which is then ready for vessel, which is then ready f&lt;&gt;i' bottle- with a constricted neck shipment. It is self-evident that bottle- with a roafitrirt cannot lie used for this purpose. b c Another method j&gt;eiiiiit&gt; the use of ordinary small dispensing l&gt;otlles. A two-ounce bottle, previously sterilized, is tilled one - half full of blood and closed with equally sterile stopj&gt;er. Before the Mood clots, the bottle is placed in ■ slanting position and this is maintained until the clotting is complete. The container i- MS. ■"&gt;. Method of procuring mtudi sample? a. Vial partially filled with liiguid bU*n b. Position for clotting of the blood. c. Clot attached to stopper, and s.-rur collected in lower part. ;»a </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Preparation ur Laboratory Sncumi 11 i \\ i ii fl ten II foi i placed in the upright position &gt;&lt;&gt; that the serum will col in the free space within the vessel, from which it can b&lt; which it can I* laboratories ir often appealed to. for the detection :uul i ideation of aiiiinal parasites. The material required lav rpow niries largely with tlie problem confronting tin- per the field. In thf case &lt;&gt;f the micraicopic itiagnniiw &lt;&gt;f the iiaiaiiitti skin titm I -caliics and mange), the speciniens sent should consist r;i|&gt;injrs from tin- affected skin areas. As much as possible rather recently affected part&gt;. such as the margin of the iscil patches, should l&gt;e selected for the collection of samples. leu paoroptic mange is suspectttl the irTapiay inav hi' inade lerficiilly; but in the case of presumed sarcoptic lesions, the i pin^r- must take in the entire epidermis. In suspected follic- r iiiiiiifjfc it i- usually sufficient to forward a small quantity lie |)iis squeezed out of the affected areas or pustules. Wide - ithed \ials are the l&gt;est &lt;-ontainers for .shipment of this ma - al. lint when the latter is dry it can also l&gt;e forwarded in it 1 \ closed DapeY envelopes. When discharjre. pus, or similar iiiilmtam cm are to In- examine«l i\ idence of parasites, they should alwaji b&gt; sent in a con- l\ removed by mean* of a pi|M»tte. a c Flu. 6. Method of procuring serum sample^ a. Vial partially filled with liquid blood. b. Slanting position during- clotting. c. Sample after separation of serum. PARAS1TOLOCIC EXAMINATIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nkbraska Kxi'kki.mkm Station. Cwn i.ai: H 12 -•iderable quantity if at all ]x&gt;ssihle. Fwes -hould In- placed in a self-sealer and should have added alMtut one-tenth volume of the formaldehyde solution of commerce. (Jross parasites. sn«-h as the intestinal worms and the like. should l»f placed in a H&gt; |mt cent solution of thr formaldehyde dilution as sold by tin- dru«r trade, in water to which a bil of '&lt; iiimi salt lias U-en added. MORE SPECIFIC DIRECTIONS While the directions offered above ;ire probably -utficient. it ■IT not Ih' amiss to consider briefly the — | &gt;«-«-i m 1 requirement- for the collection and preparation of specimen* pertainm&lt;r to some of the more common problenw which are to he referred to a laboratory. Tl BERCl 1.O81S TaberculotttM i- now more commonly diagnosed in the li&lt; by means of the tuberculin te-t than was formerly the earn. A result the lal&gt;oratory is appealed to in ~( mm-i:i 1 CMH only. I material to he sent for tlie parpoat &lt;&lt;f recojrnizinjr tin- preaei or abMraoe of thi&gt; dixeafie mav rarv. If taken from th&lt;- il&lt; animal, preference is. of rowrae, pveii to any part which - lesions and in particular to the enlarged I ymphnode- perta to the region* involved. If po— -ilile. the hitter should !«&lt;■ in their entirety, without having been cut into. — - — -- . — r» .-- When the problem pertains to a livin&lt;r animal, the di-cli or «i lotion* of the orphan or pad nuspet'ted -hoiil«l Ih* sent : \ in exceptional cases it may be pontuble to swur*. by exoisio l»v the liarp&lt;K&gt;niiifr of the orpan by meana of a large ~traijrht (ishhiNtk. sufficient material for a Imcteriolojric examination (iLANDERS The same practice should Ih&gt; followed in the DM lalxiratorv is to determine the absence or presence of glander* in tis.sue or excretions. Since the more common u~e of the mallem. liilM)i-atorv examinations for thi~ purpcMe ha\e become leas popu - lar than they were at one time. When material i- taken from the carcass, that which show- lesions i- to be sent. This commonly involves the na&gt;al septum, luiifis. -kin. and above all the en - larged lymphnodes. The la&gt;t named a- well m ilie still inUd nodules of the skin are preferred. When the iprrimrnn are to U - taken from the living animal, the &gt;u&gt;|&gt;ectcd lymphatic enlarge ments or skin nodules must We opened in a sterile manner and the contents removed by means of a -mall -poon or curette or cotton swab and platted in a sterile container. The ane of mmbI </seg>
            <seg id="p013">I'lIK I'iEKI'Al: A I KiN OK L.\ltO|{.\T&lt;&gt;K&gt; Sl'KI I.MKNS 13 I t cai li. &lt;&gt;t alwav- Iciid to conclusive results. Uvaiise even in actiiul form. Sometimes, however, this is all tliat can he obtained ; u Much of tin- kind of work i&gt; now iniiiecessiiry. lie raw the I'in te-t a- ■ rule renders ■ anore prompt and equally definite In addition to the bacteriologfic test and tin- nalMn i callcil . -&lt; &gt;t 1 1 1 &gt; I t-i 1 1 t-i 1 1 fixation test ran he made. Thi- L r i&lt; i « — i ami for it- purpox- a Mood or -cimiii saiuplc miiiinl involved i&gt; to be rollrrted and forwarded in the already de«crihe«l. ACT1NOMYCO8IS \\ lien actinoinx i-o»i- (lumpy jaw) i&gt; swyected. it i&gt; Muftrient ml to the lalxuatoix a l&gt;it of the pn&gt; which an l«- obtaiard i the le-ion- or in forward the affected titMiie it-^'lf. ANTHRAX Km' the | &gt;i ii'| »(&gt;-i- of a Laboratory riiairnoMis of anthrax, it i&gt; rule a&lt;lvisab4e to nend a xariety of nntciirn i In the Kr&gt;t il blood HOaearM on mwroacope slides (or common Ik 1 &gt;iilnnitted. HIuimI dried on a platter &lt;&gt;f l'ari- i piece of common chalk, or even a piece of paper, ia a nen extremely iix-ful in the diasnoHia of anthrax. When material i&gt; taken (taring an autopxy, the &gt;hipinent to lahoratory should, in addition, include the spleen or part &lt;if ami the lymphnodeN belon^inK to the region -iis|M'cteil - i i »ir iiiNolveil. When an auto|)-v i&gt; not advi&gt;al»le land tlii&gt; ninonly the ewe on account of infection danger), one of ir- of the car«a-&gt; may be sent far examination. When thi.» itcmplatcd. a &gt;trin&lt;r should Im' tijrlitlv drawn around the it it- lia-e and x-ciirelv tied. The part is then cut off without irliinir the Htrina*. ami the cut surface of the ear thorolv wared a hot iron, in order to diminish the possibility of disease IllisHMin hjr the specimen. BLACK LE&lt; When material i- to be &gt;ent to a laboratory for an exainina - for lilacklejr. the miix-ulat lire of the carca-.- should l&gt;e •lied for di&gt;colored and frothy areas, and pieces taken from -anic -hoidd U' -cut. It i&gt; not u&gt;uallv possible to find the |&gt;&lt;»r of a liiu-UTiolojric &lt;liiif»iit»is of jrlautler- specific (iijxiiin&gt;ni i~ not constantly present in h nt. even if tliciv h |&gt;r&lt;»|HM-t that tin 1 cxami- [■ repeated. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nkhkaska r If mm I Station. I'iwi i.ak It 14 blackleg bacillus in the 1&gt;1(mm1 or internal organs. Smears made from toe affected muscle are desirable additions to the material sent. HEHORKHAI.il 8EPTICEM1A The laboratory diagnosis of hemorrhagic septioomia requires fresh specimens of organs showing lesions as well ;i- the In-art mid spleen. HOG CHOLERA AND OTHER SWINE DISEASES In hog cholera a bacteriologic diagnosis in the strict sense of the word cannot l&gt;e made becau.se the causative agent can U - neither seen nor cultivated. Yet the problem of diagnosis in this disease sometimes seems to offer difficulties, ami material is forwarded for an opinion. When this is required, ormns or parts of organs showing lesions should always l&gt;e included in the shipment, in addition to the kidney, bladder, -tomach. intestine* and various lymphnodes. When possible it is always beat to submit the carcass of an animal recently dead with the itinr— • This should be done in the ease of any swine disease (aside from hog cholera) which may require laboratory examination as i means or aid in diagnosis POILTRY DISEASES It is often imitwi that laboratory aid be given in tin- dug m»is of poultry diseases. In this instance, it is likewise prefer - able to have one or more recently dead fowls shipped For fht purpose, packed according to the suggestions made. RABIES If the presence or absence of ral&gt;ies is to U- established by laboratory methods, the head of the suspected animal should in - sent in its entirety and care should be taken that thi- 1«- damaged as little as possible. It is needless to say that a dog's head with the brain partially demolished by a close range shotgun charge will not be apt to reveal anything of a conclusive nature ao far as rabies i&gt; concerned. Suspected rabm maierial should always l&gt;e accompanied by a statement as to whether or not a panon wm bitten by the suspected animal. ABORTION In suspected abortion cases, the afterbirth or even the fetn - niay l&gt;e submittwl. provided the material be fresh and free from contamination. Blood or serum samples may 1h&gt; submitted for *erolofjic examination, and they should be prepared according to the directions given above. • M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>