<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eleventh Biennial Report OF THE Girls' Industrial School for Juvenile Delinquents AT GENEVA, NEBRASKA FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">Eleventh Biennial Report OF THE Girls' Industrial School for Juvenile Delinquents AT GENEVA, NEBRASKA FOR THE </seg>
            <seg id="p003">BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Hon. E. B. Cowles Land Commissioner Hon. Addisson Wait Secretary of State Hon. Walter A. George State Treasurer Hon. Grant G. Martin Attorney General OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES Lyda J. McMahon Superintendent Miss May McMahon Matron Miss Louise Shaffer A. Grade Manager Miss Mary E. Donohue B. Grade Manager Miss Frances Virgil Secretary Miss Anna Mackenzie Sewing Teacher Mrs. Ida Clark Cooking Teacher Mrs. Clara Barnes Laundry Teacher Mr. Cashen C. Murray Farmer Mr. Joseph Huberty Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p004">REPORT To His Excellency, Chester H. Aldrich, Governor of Sekraska: In compliance with law I herewith submit the eleventh biennial report of the Girls' Industrial School. Progress has been our motive and we have achieved our object. The success of the management is due largely to the encouragement given, and the far sightedness of our governor in permitting the teachers and co-workers to be selected by the one responsible for results, thereby avoiding discord, and making it possible to work harmoniously. Association with the Board of Public Lands and Buildings have been pleasant in the extreme and the feeling of interest which was continually felt dispelled all hesitancy in approaching the proper source when council and advice were needed. Repair and Improvements Owing to total destruction of barn by lightning, a new one was built, the old power house remodeled, roof raised one story and coal bins enlarged to the capacity of four cars. New septic tank put in for accommodation of sewage, cement conduct built between main building and power house, where steam and water pipes can be kept in proper condition, avoiding continual expense of repair. Main building improved by laying new floors, paint - ing and repapering. Several hundred feet of cement walk were laid. Implement house and feed shed built, and all outside buildings painted. Needs of The Institution Our crowded condition will make it necessary to build a new building as soon as possible. We can only reasonably put thirty - five beds in each of our two dormitories, and have at present a population of eighty-six. I cannot too earnestly urge the neces - sity of proper accommodations for classifying our inmates. We have had children five years of age ; women of twenty and twenty - one, and a growing population of colored girls. I invite the closest investigation of our honorable legislature, and implore their aid in the solution of the problem on hand. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Ethe new building we should have a dormitory, school assembly room and general dining room large enough for ■Is as we are rapidly increasing, having received more girls in the last six months than during any former biennium. This room should have outside ventilation. Our present dining room is a center room in the basement, and cannot be conducive to health where so many are assembled and no inlet for fresh air. Rhe conservative estimate that I will submit as an amount ite to manage the institution for the coming biennium is as Maintenance $30,000.00 Placing children in homes 1,200.00 Superintendent 3,000.00 Matron 600.00 Family managers 1,800.00 Employees 7,500.00 For new building 50,000.00 General repairs 5,000.00 School and Domestic Work P Looking back a few years, the progress made along the lines hool and detail work repays us for the effort; the problems occurrences arising here, are well thought over and consid - ered. I often begin the day wondering what new thing will be presented for decision, and I almost invariably find that al - though I have lived among the same class of people for ten years, something new and frequently difficult of solution presents itself. Our girls are like inmates of other institutions and yet unlike them: like, that they must be assisted physically and mentally, to be restricted as to their liberty and habits; unlike, that they are not to be considered prisoners or helpless weaklings, but rather well-feeling, full of energy, healthy looking, untrained, and helpless as to the individual application of their strength or possibilities. The girl must be made over, the institution be - comes her mother, her physician, her mentor. She must be kept from the error of her former life by precept, lack of tempta - tion and by tactful, (I might say) scientific discipline. This cannot be accomplished without the assistance of the proper help and it is to this I refer in making mention of the "far sighted - ness" of our present governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, (KNKVA With all care exercised in the selection of help such as in - quiries, in person, by letter, recommendation from former em - ployers amounts to nothing — the crucial test of the individuals capabilities and adaptability are to be found out only by actual trial. I have found it to be true that young women who give excellent service in many lines of work are not capable of suc - ceeding in another and this is not in disparagement of the par - ticular persons, it is simply a matter of human experience. I would have only women of good clean habits possessed a willing - ness to do the duties assigned them, ambitious to succeed, at - tentive and painstaking in their obligations, eager to learn, not restive under discipline, frugal in their habits and as a conse - quence careful of the state's property and loyal to the institution. Such people usually have an object in life and they realize that whatever is worth doing is worth doing well. Then, each teacher must fit into her own department, there as manager receive the untrained girls; teach them not only the art of cooking, ironing, sewing or whatever it may be, but reach out, and take hold of the character and help in process of remoulding and making over. My present corps of efficient workers, are doing this and by way of illustration I will make mention of our cooking depart - ment. There is likely to be a sameness in the food provided in an institution but by the tactful and motherly supervision of Mrs. Clark, the girls are made to feel an interest in the careful preparation of the meals, an appetizing odor is found coming from this department, our plain substantial dietary has frequent changes, with as much variety as possible, clean neat table equipment and perfect service. The help of this splendid assis - tant brings out the essential home comforts, and more content - ment, wholesome training and good discipline can be obtained by the proper attention, preparation and tabling of food, then we are sometimes apt to admit. The same rule holds good in each department, the family managers working conscientiously and striving to inculcate principles of morality, integrity and am - bition. The detail manager teaching economy, self-reliance, and personal responsibility -each an important factor in the process of achieving good results. E'he helpful assistance of Mr. C. C. Murray should not be oked, as a competent manager he has had general super - over all outside work; boiler room, farm, stock, hones </seg>
            <seg id="p007">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT and repairs about the buildings. His interest has not been measured by the remuneration received for his services as an all - around, good institutional man is invaluable. EIn conclusion I wish to thank my teachers for their loyalty me in their support of my plans, and to credit our success irely as a result of their effort and faithful service. I have said that the girl comes to us unkempt, untrained and too frequently diseased, and that the institution becomes her mother. The duties then of this institution are to educate, to protect and give shelter, to strengthen the mind with standards and ideals, to alleviate, to cure, to encourage, to correct and chastise, always in love, never in anger, in humanity and charity to comfort, to amuse, to enlighten, to employ, to build up right and truth, to tear out wrong, falsehood and error. E[s there anything that I have mentioned that a good parent d not do or desire? Reduce our work "to its lowest terms t not come into the category of parental duties. And now leaving the situation to the kindest possible con - sideration of our legislature, and trusting they make it possible for me to properly care for the wards of Nebraska, I am, •Respectfully and obediently yours, Lyda J. McMahon, Superintendent. Table No. 1 APPROPRIATIONS FOR THE BIENNIUM Balance on Hand Ap- Available Resources Nov. 30, propriated Total Expended Balance 1»1U 1VII •fficere' salaries . ..., $966.80 | $6,400.00 $7,366.80 $6,299.70 $1,067.10 :mployees' wages. 1,104.83 6,000.00 7,104.83 5,710.46 1,403.37 iaintenance 4,444.85 20,500.00 24,944.85 ! 24,177.56 767.29 'lacing children in homes 96.77 1,000.00 1,096.77 i 1,014.04 Table No. 2 REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS On Hand November 30, : Appropriated Total Expended 1910 1911 - $665.00 $2,500.00 $3,165.00 $3,164.19 , 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">GENERAL STATISTICS Table No. 3. Cost per capita for total expenditures and current support during the biennium: Officers' salaries $ 6,299.70 Employees' wages 5,701.46 Maintenance 24,177.56 Placing children in homes 1,014.04 Bber present at this institution Nov. 30, 1910 53 ber since received including Nov. 30, 1912. .79 ber returned from parole 34 :« BPotal number cared for during biennium ber paroled during biennium ber out on parole Nov. 30, 1912 166 40 23 Number discharged 20 Number at this institution Nov. 30, 1912 86 166 Average number at institution during biennium. ... 66 Present capacity at the institution 80 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Table No. 4. Cash Statement Received No Nov. 30, 1910 $ 668.79 5830 pounds $5.40 314.32 Old engine belt 15.00 Groceries sold farmer 22.79 Hog' 86.90 4170 pounds $6.85 287.64 Total amount of cash received $1,395.94 Paid Out May 1911, incidentals $110.89 F. B. Bentley 332.25 Burd Miller 30.00 June 1912, incidentals 136.92 J. M. Ashbrook for three hogs 63.25 I. P. Heath, one cow 65.00 Aug. 1912, incidentals 131.39 Oct. 1912, incidentals 125.84 Total amount of cash paid out $995.54 Balance cash on hand Nov. 30, 1912 $400.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">PHYSICIAN'S REPORT Lyda J. McMahon, Superintendent Girls' Industrial &gt;'&lt; Geneva, Nebraska: Dear Madam: In response to your request for a report on my department will say, that the health of the inmates excepting a little incidental sickness of short duration and slight conse - quence has been good. We have had no epidemics of any kind, were it not for disease contracted before coming to the institution but little medical attention would have been needed, and these cases have usually yielded to treatment. The rapid increase of population tending to over-crowding is making it more difficult to maintain the sanitary conditions necessary to prevent sickness. We are in need of better hospital facilities, more sleeping rooms and play I trust the next legislature will not over-look the growing demands and will make an appropriation sufficient to supply the needs of this class of unfortunate girls. That they may have opportunity in this home to in a measure make up for what they have been earlier deprived of and go out into the world with a feeling of responsibility and obligation to their Creator, them - selves and their benefactors, knowing as evidenced by their home life here that they have friends who are interested in their future welfare, a benefit which many of them have never before known. Very truly yours, R. Woods, Physician. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>