<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>In Memoriam.  ALEXANDER K. GOUDY.</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">In .Abemoriam. ALEXANDER K. GOUDY. I he grim messenger called ;ii the home of A. K. Goudy on ening, Jun. ad tho' he had been looked for for and his approach guarded against, and his coming known it twilight be came without disturbing the surround - ing the rustle of a leaf, and the life course of Mr. an end and sorrow ho' unmixed with bit : • n that hoi The full' held at the home on Friday afternoon and the ■iious and funeral sermon in support ol of the d quietlj hile a numb - liiends who had been hi- stora iii f the 1 useful life led by the one « and exi tulations to those who bad been D to him I" with him had ever made life worth h i rth. Iv ho came forward with congTatalatloi companion and others could look back on &gt;e, and words of coodoli ident McBrien, K SuperintoBdeo ad their words « rtune. •mains were laid to rest in Mt. Vernon c&lt; Ilexander Kirkiiatrick Ooud] in in Ohio, •sided in Nebn married to Alice Daily in and ui&gt; to the time that his healti one of il educa icher, principal i superintendent and iiilierintendent of public instruction, and was not only an earnest or. but a strict ntious man. THE AUBURN GRANGER. Prof. A. K. Cioudy I knew fin i-acher in the state normal &gt;1 at Peru, wl i wenty-four o as the insti and civics. He v r to us, but soon his I instructor, his kindly manner and helpfulness, his calm dignity and personal magnetism. 1 humor won our respect, our ■■■ ration, and our love. Of '• of teachers from whom I ha\ d instruction only a f&gt; j few, do I count as great teachers. Mr. Goud the tiul' ues. l </seg>
            <seg id="p003">II S REPORT In one sense he gave his life (or the people of Nebraska. For one who spends more than a quarter of a century in actual school work U subject to a physical strain that can be endured only by the stoutest heart, by nerves of iron. In a measure, he was a victim of the ab - normal tension, the nerve-racking strain that characterizes the public school system of Nebraska. P career as state superintendent of public instruction was by a genuine devotion to the best interests of the schools; full for pupils and teachers. His religion was a religion of help - -the true religion. I never went to him for help but that he with a genial smile, a hearty hand-clasp, a helpful word and advice that sent me back to my work full of hope and cour- EAs an educator he belongs to us all, to the state, and to-da La mourns his loss. The hundreds of his pupils and the teachers were his associates, all of whom learned to call him friend, to-day for him and mingle their tears with those of her who feels his noet keenly. To her our hearts go out in fullest sympathy. He was my teacher and I loved him, and this I hold is the high - est tribute that one man can pay to the memory of another. C. J. PIERSON. Auburn, Nebr., June 15, 19U6. Mr. Goudy was not only a tower of strength to me in my work, but a firm, personal friend. As I think of his work I am impressed by its permanent, enduring qualities, and that seems to me especially pleas - ant to dwell upon, in view of the fact that he was so early in life obliged to withdraw from the activities that he loved. You speak of the helping hand which he extended to the begin - ning teachers. It seems to me that his great aim as state superin - tendent was to make vital the connection between the sod schoolhouse and the university, the struggling district school teacher and the college professor. Perhaps we in the west felt this most keenly because we were in the land of the sod schoolhouse. I am very sure Et many a poorly equipped teacher and many a district school olar received his vision of higher and broader things through Mr. idy't inspiration. EHis work was never time serving, never superficial, never selfish, upon that foundation we, who have worked with him, feel that him. "the best is yet to be." MARY E. HOSFORD. r Formerly county superintendent of Lincoln county and secre- Nebraska State Teachers' Association.) Oberlin, Ohio, August 1, 1906. EIn the death of Hon. A. K. Goudy, on the 12th inst., the state sustained a great loss. His life was a life of usefulness and his e was that of humanity. To his many friends he was noted for </seg>
            <seg id="p004">III his generous spirit, for his wise counsel, and for his devotion to the Interests of others. He was best known to the state as an educator of high rank; he was in charge of the Pawnee City Academy for a number of years, was teacher in the Nebraska State Normal school, and was state superintendent of public instruction for four yean. Through his peculiar influence there has dawned upon many a young person new Ideals which resulted in the living of a more complete life. He was happy in disposition, witty and tactful in speech, and modest and unassuming in manner. As a friend to mankind and a benefactor to his state we mourn his departure. H. B. DUNCANSON. elt has been more than twenty years since I first became ac - inted with the late A. K. Goudy. Our first meeting was about 1884 1885 in institute work at Tecumaeh, where he was an instructor I was attending my first institute as a prospective teacher. As an institute instructor he had few equals. The inspiration and the help I received in that institute have accompanied me all through my work in teaching. The beginning teachers felt at home with this man. He extended to them a helping hand. He was their friend. It was my privilege to be associated with him as a county super - intendent while he was state superintendent. We always welcomed him to our county institute. His wit and his humor always enlivened the institute and his encouragement taught us that life is real, earnest, and worth living. It is no disparagement to any of his predecessors or to any of his successors in the office of state superintendent of public instruction to say that no man before him and no man after him has given the state better service in this office than Mr. Goudy. EThe one act of his administration which stands out prominently, which is probably the greatest act of any one administration of this i, is the "Free Text Book Law," which was enacted during his first term. This is the best free text book law in any state of the Union. Teachers of the present generation, with the district uniform - ity of text books as provided under this law, have little idea of the difficulties that confronted teachers as well as pupils under the old law of pupil ownership of text books. Our free text book law stands aa an enduring monument to Mr. Goudy. He was systematic in all of his work. He made system the hinge of business. He knew that without system there is no business. P3e was a master of classic English. He was sparing of his s, but used them with great precision. "To hear him talk was watching some one crossing a brook on stepping-stones. His noun had to wait for its verb or its adjective until he was ready; then his speech would come down upon the word he wanted to use and not Worcester nor Webster could better it from all the wealth of their huge vocabularies." </seg>
            <seg id="p005">IV I-ORT On the day of his death I drove from Peru to Auburn with my old friend, Professor C. J. Pierson of Auburn, and who had ju - y returned from Manila. As we left Peru the liveryman di i - i drive past the farm home of Major William Dailey. i i Mr. Pierson If this would not take us by the home where Mr. and Mrs. Goudy were living. He replied that It would. I suggested that we should stop and shake hands with them for old friendship's Mr. Pierson agreed th. "uld do this, but called my attention to the limited time at our command for making the Ml— null I train for Lincoln that afternoon. As we passed the home of I Dailey my friend asked me If we should stop and shake hands Mr. Goudy. I said. 'Yes." We stopped our team, but not seeing Mr. :v around the I to Mr. Pierson, "Let us drive on; it ■ nly annoy them and us to stop for so short a time any» had driven well past the home when all of a sudden a feeling came me that I could not stand it to pass by where .Mr. Goudy lived without tl ;inds with him, and so we turned our team round and ri Mr. Gone to the buggy. We got out and shool a ith him an.: good old d EMr. Goudy. laughing, laid one hand on Mr. 1 'her on niiii' id: "When shall I gi her i El joined them b 'When shall W( I again?" all laughed. After tli "d Mr. Qondy how he ng along. His reply was: "] am trying to mi b I am alive when I know I am not." And then ou - r« serious nature. W&lt; iu good-bye and dro - our train. While we knew i irong physically that day, both Mr. • in and myself remarked that we ha'i -een him brL of the English language. We dis - cussed his great « the public and both agreed that it w. r such a man to rly appreciated while living. Elt was a ■ me the next morning when I received from ing that Mr. Goudy died a few hours talk with him. Our commonwealth has lost a noble citizen food he did will live after him. he brigh now his lot l&gt; The : •-art is filled, his won. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>