<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Experimental Hog Feeding</title>
               <date value="1920-09">1920-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 175 September, 1920 Experimental Hog Feeding H. J. GRAMLJCH and E. L. JENKINS AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 Nebraska Experiment Station Buljjbtin 175 SUMMARY EXPERIMENT NO. I 1. The complete substitution of shorts for tankage in a ration to hogs receiving shelled corn and alfalfa hay did not prove justifiable in that it reduced the daily gain .43 pound, reduced the feed consumed daily by 1.12 pounds and increased the cost of 100 pounds of gain by 77 cents, at the same time decreasing the profit by $1.J&gt;."&gt;. which is a very material reduc - tion. Lots 1 and 2. 2. The addition of shorts to a corn and tankage ration proved to be justifiable in that it increased the daily gain from 1.50 pounds to 1.68 pounds and increased the profit per pig from $3.37 to $3.90. although it made a more expensive gain by 7 cents per hundred pounds. Lots 1 and 3. 3. The substitution of hominy feed for corn when fed with tankage reduced the daily gain from 1.50 pounds to 1.2 pounds, reduced the daily feed consumption and increased materially the feed required to produce one pound of gain. It caused a very marked increase in the cost of 100 pounds of gain, it being $10.60 in comparison to $12.30 where the corn was fed. It likewise made a very heavy loss in contrast to a material profit made by the pigs fed on corn and tankage. Lots 1 and 4. 4. The addition of hominy to a corn and tankage ration increased the daily gain by .1 pound, increased the daily feed consumption by .2 pound, increased the cost of 100 pounds gain by 20 cents and increased the profit 29 cents. Lots 1 and ft. 5. A ration of ground corn, semi-solid buttermilk and alfalfa hay compared to a ration of shelled corn, tankage and alfalfa hay, showed an increased daily gain of .00 pound, an increased corn consumption, and an increased cost of 100 pounds gain by $3.07. No profit was shown by the lot fed buttermilk, whereas the lot receiving tankage showed a profit of *'. :M. Lots 1 and 0. 0. The hand feeding of ear corn twice per day versus the feeding of shelled corn in the self-feeder in conjunction with tankage and alfalfa in self-feeders resulted in a slightly less gain, in a rather larger feed consumption, especially of tankage, and in a more expensive gain by 7!) cents per hundred pounds: also in a lessened profit by 89 cents. Lots 1 and 7. 7. The addition of .0(5 pound of alfalfa hay per day to a ration of ear corn and tankage increased the daily gain by .11 pound, decreased the food required to produce one pound of gain by .5 pound, decreased the cost of 100 pounds gain by $1.32 and' increased the profit by $1.60. Lots 1 and 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Experimental Hog Feeding 3 EXPERIMENT NO. II 1. The addition of alfalfa to a corn and tankage nition increased the daily gain .27 pound \mr pig, incrot*ed thtr daily ration materially, decreased the feed required to ))roduce one pound of gain and reduced the cost of 100 pounds of gain from $13.75 to $13.18. It likewise increased the profit per head from 01 cents to $2.00. The alfalfa in this test could have been charged at $41 per ton and the profit would still have been the same. Therefore the addition of the alfalfa proved to be very profitable. Lots 1 and 2. 2. The addition of tankage to a corn and alfalfa ration increased the daily gain from 1.08 pounds to 1.71 pounds, increased the total food consumed daily from 6.04 pounds to 8.32 pounds, reduced the amount of feed required to produce one pound of gain and likewise reduced the cost of 100 pounds of gain by 30 cents. At the same time it increased the profit per head from 45 cents to $2.09. The tankage in this instance could have been valued at $KiO per ton and the profit would still have been the same. Lots 1 and 3. 3. The grinding of both corn and alfalfa and feeding the same as a mixture composed of nine parts of the former to one of the latter, in comparison to shelled corn and alfalfa hay fed in separate self-feeders, resulted in a slightly lower jrain. namely, .00 pound in contrast to 1.08 pounds, a smaller con - sumption of corn and a greater consumption of alfalfa and a somewhat more expensive gain, namely, $13.(50 in contrast to $13.48. Due to this difference and the fact that the pigs in lot 4 made a somewhat smaller gain, the profit is but 12 cents in contrast to 47 cents where the corn and alfalfa fed whole. EXPERIMENT NO. Ill 1. The feeding of tankage in a self-feeder where hogs were fed ear corn and alfalfa hay in conjunction increased the daily gain .1&lt;&gt; pound when compared to hand feeding the tankage. It likewise reduced the amount of feed required to produce one pound of gain, reduced the cost of 100 pounds of gain by $1.55 and increased the profit per pig by $2.03. Therefore this method of feeding gave a very decided advantage. Lots 1 and 2. 2. The feeding of tankage in the form of a slop in con - junction with ear corn and alfalfa versus feeding it dry increased the daily gain .15 pound, decreased materially the feed required to produce one pound of gain, decreased the cost of 100 pounds gain $1.27 and increased the profit per head $1.(58. Therefore the feeding of the tankage in the form of a slop proved to lx&gt; very justifiable. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 4 EXPERIMENT NO. IV 1. The feeding of tankage in the self-feeder with a corn and alfalfa ration in contrast to shorts in a self-feeder with a corn and alfalfa ration increased the daily gain 30 per cent, increased the food consumed per day by a considerable margin and although it increased the cost of producing 100 pounds gain by 31 cents, it actually increased the profit $1.00 per head. It would therefore seem that the use of tankage at the prices figured in this test is justifiable in preference to short* as a supplement to corn whore fed witli alfalfa. EXPERIMENT NO. V 1. The feeding of a ration of ground corn and semi-solid buttermilk to a group of 16 pigs carried from the weight of 51 pounds to 255 pounds, resulted in a daily gain of 1.33 pounds at a cost of $13.(58 per 100 pounds gain, and a profit of SI.90 per pig. The food required to produce one pound of gain in this lot amounted to 3.54 pounds of corn and 1.38 pounds of buttermilk, a total of 4.02 pounds. Considering that the butter - milk contained (55 per cent water this is a relatively efficient gain. Tn fact, reducing the buttermilk to a 10 per cent water content, we would have one jwund of gain produced upon 4.14 pounds of feed. EXPERIMENT NO. VI 1. The addition of oil meal to a corn and alfalfa ration increased the daily gain from .85 pound to 1.29 pounds, reduced the cost of 100 "pounds of gain from $19.38 to $13.13 and changed a lass of $3.11 to 05 cents profit. In other words, the addition of the oil meal proved highly justifiable. EXPERIMENT NO. VII 1. The feeding free-choice of corn oil cake and tankage as supplements to a corn and alfalfa ration versus mixing the two in the proportion of 75 per cent corn oil cake to 25 per cent tankage resulted in identical daily gains, somewhat less feed consumption per day and per pound of gain, and a reduction of $1.28 in the cost of 100 pounds gain. It likewise caused the pigs to net $1.01 more profit per head for a feeding period of 63 days. This difference in profit and cost of gains is largely due to the relative cheapness of the corn oil cake compared to tankage. The pigs having free access to both corn oil cake «nd tankage consumed 60 parts of corn oil cake to 40 parts of tankage. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Experimental Hog Feeding 5 EXPERIMENTAL HOG FEEDING Winter of 1917-1918 INTRODUCTION The experimental work embodied in this bulletin was con - ducted during the winter of 1917 and 1918. It will be noted that a good many lots of hogs were fed and that in most instances the lots were comparatively large. This was made possible by the provision of extra equipment afforded through the closing of the State Serum Plant on the University Farm, the same being turned over to the Animal Husbandry Depart - ment for experimental hog feeding during the winter season. As a result, sufficient lots, feed space, weighing facilities and other accommodations were provided to conduct feeding opera - tions on a relatively extensive scale. The hogs used in this work were purchased when most of them weighed from 100 to 135 pounds, and were in what would l&gt;e classed as good feeder condition. As would be expected they consisted of a vast motley of nondescripts, representing some of the blood of practically all of the breeds of lard hogs. After purchasing, they were treated with the double serum treatment and not put upon experiment until approximately one month later. Owing to the fact that these hogs were purchased in many different groups it was impossible in starting an experi - ment to divide the hogs so as to have all of a size. In several instances there was considerable variation between the largest and the smallest pigs in each lot. However, considerable can - was taken to divide so as to have approximately the same numl&gt;er of the different sizes in each group. The project was started with a desire of obtaining some statistics covering the economy of gains where different rations were fed to hogs on full feed. At the same time, it was thought that with the government's urgent call for greater pork produc - tion, the University could be of no more direct assistance than to utilize the splendid equipment at the serum plant in pro - ducing pork during this critical time. The Regents very kindly assigned a revolving fund to be used in carrying on the enter - prise. In all. some 700 hogs were handled. Some were placed in large pens and fattened for market without keeping experi - mental data. These in the main consisted of odd-sized hogs that were in any way unfit for experimental work. At one time the Department carried an investment of $35,000 in hogs and feed. The figures which are given in the various tables in this bulletin show only the feed cost per pig. AVe have not taken </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bii.i.etix 175 into account labor, death rate, or equipment. It will Iks noted in glancing thru this bulletin that in the main the feed cost per hundred pounds gain approximated $13.00. Considering that the hogs «old at an average price of $1(&gt;.5O per hundred pounds, it would seem that the entire project should show a reasonable profit, assuming that too much death loss was not incurred. The hogs cost, vaccinated. $17.50 per hundred pounds. The death low was not unusual. One group that was purchased subject to temperature test was found to be affected with cholera and rejected. Aside from this group no unusual amount of disease was encountered. The financial status of the winter's work shows that the affair was practically an even break. Were full interest to be charged against the investment, the balance would be on the red side. However, as the state does not pay interest we have obviated this part which a private feeder would have to take into account. In the tables, we have figured interest against the hogs, which is no more than fair and which is always done in figuring experimental work. METHODS OF FEEDING The method of feeding thruout all of this work was to allow the hogs all they would consume. In most instances, self-feeders were used ; in several instances, especially where ear corn was fed and where ground corn was feel mixed witli buttermilk, the ration consisted of what they would clean up nicely at each feeding. Some criticisms may be made of the work reported in this bulletin because of the fact that a full feed was used in each case. It was thought better, however, to work everything out on a btisis of the self-feeder method of feeding, inasmuch as work done in previous trials at this station and at other stations has shown consistently that for winter feeding the full feeding method has proven the most economical, especially where self - feeders are used. COST OF HOGS The Hist hogs purchased for this experiment coat, vacci - nated, but $17.00 j&gt;er hundred pounds. The majority cost $17 50 and a few towards the close cost $18.00. Most of the hogs were purchased uuvaccinated and the price of the serum added to their initial price to secure the figures above. It has been deemed advisable in reporting this work to establish a uniform price on all of the hogs, and in doing this we have decided upon $17.50 per hundred as a fair figure. Likewise the first hogs which were marketed sold relatively lower than the later ones. as low as $15.85 being received in Omaha for several loads. The laU'r loads realized $17.00 Omaha. As we found that </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Experimental Hog Feeding 7 including shrink and shipping expenses, from 35 ce»ts to K) cents per hundred pounds was required to cover the difference Ictween Omaha price and Lincoln price, we have decided to use a figure of $l(i.."&gt;() per hundred pounds as the uniform selling price. This means that the hogs sold on an average of SI. on per hundred less than their cost as stock hogs. PRICES AND QUALITY OF FEEDS I SEI) A.- the work reported in this bulletin was planned in ad- vance, we were able to make extensive purchases of feed luffs and consequently to use a uniform price for each feed thruout the winter. The mill feeds and tankage were purchased in carload lots. The corn was purchased largely on the ear. After filling the available crib room a large quantity was hauled by the shuckers thruout December and January and piled in long ricks on the ground. Approximately 12,000 bushels of ear corn were thus purchased and stored. Most of this was shelled later as needed. The feeds being purchased in large quantities were in the main bought at slightly under the average price existing thruout the winter. This would apply especially to some of the mill feeds which sold considerably cheaj)er at the time they were ■ x * purchased in Noveml&gt;er than later. In order to overcome any advantage which we might have due to the buying of these feeds in large quantities we have used what would be considered a fair price for each feed rather than the actual cost price to us. To illustrate, tankage is charged in all experiments at $100 per - — — 7 r*~ e — — i — ' i ton, whereas it cost $N7.00 per ton laid down. Corn was charged at $1.40 altho the cost averaged $1.12, and in the main the corn was not of the best grade. However, considering quality, corn was perhaps higher in price during the winter season this year than at any previous time. As a result, this showed rather to the disadvantage of the hogs. The average water content of the corn used approximated 20 per cent. This naturally tends to cause a slightly larger requirement of corn to produce 100 ]K)itnds gain than where the drier corn is used. The prices used in these tests were: Corn $ 1.40 per bushel Tankage 100.00 per ton Shorts 44.00 per ton Hominy 60.00 per ton Oil meal C0.00 per ton Semi-solid buttermilk 3.50 per hundred Corn oil cake 60.00 per ton Alfalfa hay 25.00 per ton </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 EXPERIMENT NO. I Eighty Day Test. November 10, 1917, to January 29, 1918 Shorts and Hominy Feed as Corn Substitute. Shorts Hominy Feed, Tankage and Semi-solid Buttermilk as a Corn Supplement. THE VALUE OF ALFALFA HAY IN THE FATTENING RATION Table 1. Lois 1,2 and S Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Number in lot 20 20 20 we are facing what might be termed a tankage famine, or putting it in another way, the tremendous demand for tankage is causing the producers to be unable to fill all of their orders, and this boosts the price of tankage to such a point as would tend to limit orders to the available supply. Because of this condition in the tankage market it becomes necessary that we find a substitute for tankage in fattening hogs and it was because of this that the three lots reported were fed. RATION Shelled corn Tankage Alfalfa Shelled corn Shelled corn Shorts Shorts Tankage Alfalfa Alfalfa ______________ .verage initial weight .verage final weight .verage gain .verage daily gain 137.5 264.103 126.603 1.563 135.9 227.672 91.773 1.133 134.3 270.137 135.837 1.677 'ounds average daily ration Corn Shorts Tankage Alfalfa 6.756 ' .447' ' .06 5.23 .779 .112 6.811 .8405 .36 .034 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Shorts Tankage Alf alf a 4.322 .286 .052 4.616 .687 .01 4.061 .601 .214 .02 Cost per 100 pounds gain $12.30 $13.07 $12.37 Profit per pig, based on cost of $17.50 per cwt. and selling price of $16.50 per cwt. with interest at 7% $1.42 $3.90 $3.37 Nutritive ratio . . . . 1:7.9 1:9.9 1:7.7 While tankage is a com article of feed for the hog, ii paratively recent production as an s use has increased so rapidly that </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Experimental Hog Feeding 9 In lot 2 shorts was supplemented to the corn ration to ascertain the advisability of omitting tankage entirely, whereas in lot 3 shorts was added to the corn and tankage ration with the idea of seeing whether the shorts could not be substituted for part of the tankage in supplying the protein of the ration. The hogs in these three lots weighed at the opening of the test approximately 135 pounds. The feeds were provided in self - feeders in each instance and were fed in separate compart - ment* so that the hogs consumed their rations by the free - choice method. Experiment 1. lot 1. Ration, corn, tankage and alfalfa Regarding the gain secured, lot 1, which received shelled corn and tankage, exceeded 1.5 pounds per day, to Ik&gt; exact 1.56 pounds, whereas in lot 2, receiving corn and shorts without tankage, the gain was but 1.13 pounds, and lot 3 made the largest gain of the three lots, and in fact the largest gain of the entire experiment, namely, 1.68 pounds per day. Thus in so far as the gain is concerned, the partial substitution of shorts in the corn and tankage ration shows a big advantage. The daily feed consumed runs considerably higher in both lotw 1 and 3 than it does in lot 2, the corn amounting to »'&gt;.7('&gt; pounds in lot 1 and to 6.81 pounds in lot 3, in contrast to but 5.23 pounds in lot 2, showing a corn consumption of approx - imately 1.5 pounds less in lot 2 than in the other two lots. The tankage consumption in lot 1 is .45 pound and in lot 2 the shorts consumption amounts to .78 pound, while in lot 3 .84 pound </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 10 of shorts and .36 pound of tankage were consumed daily, indicat - ing that lot 3 consumed practically as much shorts as did lot 2 anil as much tankage as did lot 1 in addition to the heaviest corn consumption of the three lots. While the pigs in lot 3 proved to be the heavy eating group, they did not require more feed to produce one pound of gain because of their additional daily gain. In fact, they required considerably less than did the pigs in lot 2 and virtually the same as those in lot 1. the corn required in the three lots amounting to 4.3 pounds in lot 1, 4.62 pounds in lot 2 and 4.06 pounds in lot 3. In addition, lot 1 required .20 pound of tankage, lot 2 .09 pound of shorts and lot 3 .5 pound of shorts and .21 pound of tankage. Hence the total feed required to Experiment 1, lot 2. Ration, corn, shorts and alfalfa {&gt;roduce one pound of gain approximates five pounds in each ot, being slightly above in the case of lot 2 and slightly below in the cases of lots 1 and 3. Considering the quality' of the corn used, these are relatively efficient gains in each 'instance. The cost of gain in the three lots does not vary materially, especially as between lot 1 and lot 3, this being slightly in favor of lot 1, even tho they did not gain as much as those in lot 3. The cost is $12.30 in lot 1, $13.07 for lot 2 and $12.37 for lot 3. Hence, the cost of gains shows rather to the detriment of lot 2. Under the profit per pig column, it is noted that while lots 1 and 3 are relatively close and both show a good profit, lot 3 has the advantage by a sufficient margin to warrant arivinjr </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Experimental Hog Feeding 11 the ration credit for the same. Compared with the profit in these two lots, the profit in lot 2 looks comparativ.lv low. The profit is $3.37. $1.42 and $3.90 respectively. THE SUBSTITUTION IN WHOLE OR IN PART OF HOMINY FEED FOR CORN WHEN FED WITH TANKAGE AND ALFALFA Hominy feed has been in increasing favor with stockmen generally, due to the fact that since corn has become bo high in price the hominy has been purchaseable at a more reasonable figure and, generally speaking, men have considered it an eco - nomical feed to use. Hominy is a by-product of the corn kernel after the same has gone thru a dry milling process and the corn flour and cornoil has been extracted. In the main, it consists of parts of the starch, the hull and the germ. Table g. I Lots 1, hands Lot 1 Lot 4 Lot 5 Number in lot j 20 20 20 RATION ■ Shelled corn | Hominy feed Shelled corn Tankage Tankage Hominy feed Alfalfa Alfalfa Tankage Alfalfa Average initial weight | Average final weight '\ Average gain 137.5 138.55 136.3 264.103 235.588 270.43 126.603 97.038 134.136 Average daily gain j 1.563 1.198 1.656 1 , Pounds average daily ration Corn Hominy feed ' Tankage ! Alfalfa ' 6.756 5.55 1 5.396 1.33 .447 .699 .524 .06 .163 .04 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Hominy feed Tankage Alfalfa 4.322 3.351 4.504 .803 .286 .583 .336 .052 .136 .024 . — — i ! I Cost per 100 pounds gain Profit or loss per pig based on cost price of $17.50 per cwt. and selling price of $16.50 per cwt., with interest at 7% $12.30 $16.60 $12.50 $3.37 —$1.67 $3.63 Nutritive ratio 1:7.9 1:9 1:6.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 The test reported herein embodies three lots of pigs, one fed on a straight shelled corn and tankage ration, a second receiving hominy feed and tankage, and a third receiving both shelled corn and hominy in conjunction with tankage, the feeds in each case being in separate feeders. Alfalfa was supplied to all lots. In no instance did they consume much of this, as one would naturally expect, considering that they were fattening hogs and on a very heavy feed of grain. These hogs weighed 137 pounds average at the time the test started. They were on trial 80 days, and at the conclusion their weights varied from 235 pounds to 270 pounds: hence they were well finished. Experiment 1. lot 3. Ration, corn, shorts, tankage and alfalfa By referring to the rate of daily gain it will Ix 1 noted that the greatest gain was made by lot 5, receiving both hominy and corn in connection with tankage, their gain being 1.66 pounds. The next lot in rate of gain was lot 1, receiving straight corn and tankage, their gain being 1.56 pounds; the poorest gaining lot was the one receiving hominy feed and tankage. They show a gain of but 1.2 pounds. This shows a marked difference as be - tween the first two and the latter, and would seem to indicate that the hominy and tankage together, while producing a good gain would not prove as efficient as either of the other combinations. By referring to the daily ration consumed it is noted that the pigs in lot 1, receiving corn and tankage, consumed 6.76 pounds of corn and .45 pound of tankage, whereas those in lot 4 con - sumed but 5.4 pounds of hominy and .7 pound of tankage, and </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Experimental Hog Feeding 13 those in lot 5 consumed 5.55 pounds of corn, 1.33 pounds of hominy and .52 pound of tankage. In other words, lot 5 con - sumed more pounds of corn per day than lot 4 did of hominy. In conjunction to their corn, lot 5 consumed 1.33 pounds of hominy. Their tankage consumption was not quite as great as that in lot 4, there being a difference of .17 pound. The total feed consumed daily amounts to 6.09 pounds in lot 4 and 7.40 pounds in lot 5, and therefore a much greater feed consumption per day in the lot receiving both corn and hominy. It will be noted that the daily ration of hominy in lot 5 approximated one-fourth of the daily ration of corn which they consumed, indicating that the hogs liked corn much better than hominy, inasmuch as they had free access to both at all times. From this, it will b? noted that where pigs had access to both corn and hominy their appetites were apparently considerably better and they ate considerably more total pounds of feed, than where, as in lot 1, corn and tankage were fed or as in lot 4 where hominy and tankage were fed. In lot 1 the total consumption of feed amounts t&lt;&gt; 7/2 pounds in comparison to 7.4 in lot 5. As regards feed required to produce one pound of gain, in lot 1 it required 4.32 pounds of corn and .29 pound of tankage or a total of 4.61 pounds, whereas in lot 4 it required 4.5 pounds of hominy and .58 pound of tankage, a total of 5.08 pounds and in lot 5 it required 3.35 pounds of corn, .8 pound of hominy and .33 pound of tankage, a total of 4.48 pounds. These figures show that the feed required is slightly higher in lot 1 than in lot 5, receiving hominy in addition to the corn, but that it was higher in lot 4 than in either of the others. Due to the extremely large amount of feed required to produce one pound of gain in lot 4, it is an expensive gain, in fact the most costly gain of the entire test, the cost here being $16.60 in contrast 'to but $12.30 in lot 1 and $12.50 in lot 5, a difference of over $4 per hundred pounds. With such a difference in the cost of the gains made we must of necessity expect a big disparity between profits on the three lots. Lot 1 shows a profit of $3*37 and lot 5 a profit of $3.63, indicating that the addition of the hominy increased the profit slightly. However, upon referring to lot 4 it is found that it shows a loss of $1.67. This is quite a heavy loss and is a very marked divergence from the profit obtained in lots 1 and 5. In fact, this is such a heavy loss in comparison with the profit shown by the other lots that we must draw the con - clusion that the ration used is not practical, with the prices which were used in this test. The results secured herein conform to those secured in a later test in which it was found that whereas hominy, when fed </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 with corn and tankage, proved to cheapen the ration, when fed alone with tankage it proved to be an expensive factor and to cause the highest cost of any lot in that exj&gt;eriinent. also. In this experiment we find upon checking hack that on a basis of the returns made by the corn and tankage in lot 1 the hominy feed in lot 4 returned a valuation of $40.00. whereas it actually cost $00 per ton. From this it would be seen that with corn at $50 per ton, one would not be justified in feeding hominy and tankage to the complete exclusion of corn unless hominy could l»e purchased at a less price than $40.90. In lot 5, we find the hominy returned a greater value: $55.10. As corn is charged at $50 per ton the hominy therefore proved to ht&gt; slightly greater in efficiency than the corn. However, owing t&lt;&gt; the fact that the hominy was selling relatively high and was charged in this test at $60 it does not show a material advantage from its addition to the ration. TANKAGE VERSUS SEMI-SOLID BUTTERMILK AS A SUPPLE - MENT TO A CORN AND ALFALFA RATION Table S. Lots 1 and 6 Lot 1 20 Lot 6 Number in lot 20 Shelled corn I Ground corn Tankage Semi-solid Alfalfa buttermilk Alfalfa Average initial weight 137.5 133.3 Average final weight 264.103 266.22 Average gain 126.603 132.92 264.103 266.22 Average gain Average daily ration 1.563 1.641 Pounds average daily ration Corn Semi-solid buttermilk . . Tankage Alfalfa 6.756 7.057 2.017 .447 .06 .237 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn 4.322 4.3 Semi-solid buttermilk 1.229 Tankage , .286 Alfalfa .052 .144 Cost of 100 pounds gain $12.30 $15.23 Profit based on cost price of $17.50 per cwt. and selling price of $16.50, with interest at 7%. . . $3.37 Nutritive ratio 1:7.9 1:6.9 lot. I SI RATION 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Experimental Hog Feeding 15 Inasmuch as Hemi-solid buttermilk is being used quite ex - tensively in fattening hog rations the trial outlined below was worked out. This semi-solid buttermilk is a product put out by the creameries and consists of buttermilk evaporated down to one-seventh of it- original volume. In feeding it. it is necessarv that it be diluted and the company's recommendations were fol - lowed in feeding this lot of pips, in that corn was ground and mixed with the diluted buttermilk. The buttermilk pigs gained .08 pound more than the tank - age group. Likewise, they consumed considerably more feed per day, the corn being 7.0&lt;&gt; pounds in lot 0 in contrast to 6.7'i pounds in lot 1. While lot 1 consumed .45 pound of tankage, lot fi consumed 2.O2 pounds of buttermilk. The pigs in lot &lt;&gt; consumed relatively so much more feed than those in lot 1 in proportion to the increased gain which they made that they proved the more expensive gainers. While the amount of corn EAR CORN VERSUS SHELLED CORN WHEN FED WITH TANKAGE AND ALFALFA Cost per 100 pounds gain $12.30 $13.09 Profit per pig, based on cost price of $17.50 per cwt. and selling price of $16.50 per cwt., with interest at 7% $3.37 $2.48 Nutritive ratio. 1:7.9 1:7.5 •Reduced to a shelled corn basis. Tabi ,lei. Lot Loi it '*■/ a* « Lot 1 Lot 7 Number in lot dumber in lot. . 20 20 RATION Shelled corn Tankage Alfalfa Ear corn* Tankage Alfalfa -I Average initial weight Average final weight Average gain 137.5 264.103 126.603 134.4 257.112 122.715 Average daily gain t 1.563 1.515 'ounds average daily ration Corn Tankage Alfalfa 6.756 .447 .06 6.756 .447 .06 6.704 .573 .17 'ounds feed per pound gain Corn Tankage Alfalfa 4.322 .286 .052 4.425 .378 .144 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 16 required to produce one pound of gain in the two lots is prac - tically identical — 4.3 pounds — whereas it took .29 pound of tankage in lot 1, it required 4.23 pounds of buttermilk in lot ♦&gt;. As tankage was charged at 5 cents per pound and buttermilk :ii 314 cents per pound, naturally the difference causes quite a difference in the cost of producing 100 pounds gain. In lot 1 this amounted to $12.30, in lot 6 to $15.33. a difference of $3.00. Due to this difference in the cost of gain we find the profit amounting to $3.37 in lot 1, while lot &lt;&gt; made neither profit nor gain. While the buttermilk ration increased the gain slightly over the corn and tankage ration, yet owing to the greater amount of feed required to produce the gains we find that the buttermilk did not prove economical and in this trial gains are not suffi - ciently greater to warrant recommending its usage in fattening hogs for the market. The major portion of the corn fed on the farm where pro - duced is fed on the ear. This practice obviates the expense of shelling and is usually looked upon as rather the better method of feeding, inasmuch as the hogs eat somewhat slower than where fed the shelled corn. The two lots reported here were fed shelled corn and ear corn to ascertain the relative gain which could be secured and the relative efficiencv of the two. We find that lot 1 gained slightly more than lot 7, altho a very narrow margin of difference, and both lots showed n highly satisfactory gain, the daily gain being 1.56 pounds in lot 1 and 1.52 pounds in lot 7. Reducing the ear corn to ;i shelled basis, we find that the daily corn consumption in the two lots is practically identical, being &lt;&gt;.7t&gt; pounds in lot 1 and (&gt;.7 pounds in lot 7. In conjunction with this we find that the pigs in lot 1 consumed .45 pound of tankage while those in lot 7 consumed rather more, namely, .57 pound. Hence, virtually the only difference in the daily ration consumed by these two lots of pigs was the taking of .13 pound more tankage by lot 7. A« lot 7 did not gain quite as much as lot 1 and consumed just as much corn and a trifle more tankage, we find that the amount required to produce 1 pound of gain runs rather higher in lot 7. The corn amounts to 4.43 pounds and the tankage to .38 pound in this lot. In lot 1 the corn amounts to 4.32 pounds and the tankage to .29 pound. As a result of this slightly greater amount of feed required to produce gains, we have a more expensive gain in lot 7, the cost being $13.09 whereas it is $12.30 in lot 1, a difference of 79 cents per hundred pounds. This difference causes a difference in the profit of these two lots of 89 cents per pig. From this test it would seem that the use of shelled corn was rather more satisfactory than the use of ear corn when fed </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Experimental Hog Feeding 17 in conjunction with tankage and alfalfa hay. Unless there should be a material objection to the shelling of corn, it would seem that based on the results obtained here a slightly greater gain might be secured and at a somewhat less cost of feed. It must be remembered that the pigs in lot 1 received their shelled corn in a self-feeder, whereas those in lot 7 were hand fed what ear corn they would consume twice daily. The fact that they consumed considerably more tankage than the ho^s in lot 1 may be explained as follows: Often after the corn is cleaned up a hog will become hungry before the next meal and eat more tankage than he needs and can use economically. Apparently that is what resulted here and is the primary cans* 1 for the more expensive gain in lot 7. If one must hand feed ear corn it is possible that the best results would accrue from handfeeding the tankage also. The excess of tankage consumed by pigs that have it in self-feeders and that are hand fed corn THE FEEDING OF ALFALFA HAY WITH A CORN AND Profit per pig, based on cost price of $17.50 per cwt. and selling price of $16.50 per cwt., with interest at 7% $3.37 $1.71 Nutritive ratio 1:7.9 1:7.2 l.l.Ml I HiL HA 1 11/11 Table 5. Lots 1 and 8 I Number in lot ... Lot 1 Lot 8 c 20 •JO RATION Shelled corn Shelled corn Tankage Tankage Alfalfa celled c Tankaj, Alfalfi U -Allan; .verage initial weight . .verage final weight . . i verage gain 137.5 264.103 126.603 132.75 250.524 117.774 .verage daily gain 1.663 1.454 'ounds average daily ration Corn Tankage Alfalfa 6.756 .447 .06 7.053 .433 i 'ounds feed per pound gain Corn Tankage Alfalfa 4.322 .286 .052 4.851 .298 lost of 100 pounds gain . . $12.30 $13.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 does not injure them but on account of its cost does increase the cost of the gains. Inasmuch as most Nebraska feeders have an abundance of alfalfa hay we find that they prefer keeping it before their hogs at all times. It has been proven that its use in connection with the carrying of breeding stock is very justifiable. In this trial we attempted to ascertain the advisability of supplementing alfalfa hay to a corn and tankage ration for hogs that are beim: finished for the market, there being a possibility that hogs finishing for the market and receiving grain from self-feeders would consume so much of this that they would not eat sufficient alfalfa to materially affect their gains. By comparing the two lots referred to we find that we have a greater gain in the lot having access to alfalfa hay. the gain here being 1.50 pounds compared to 1.45 pounds in lot 8. The corn consumption in the lot receiving alfalfa hay was slightly less than that in lot 8, the difference being .3 pound. The tank age consumption was almost identical and the alfalfa hay con - sumption amounted to but .06 pound per day. This seems like a trifling amount of hay. However, it had been found by ex - perience that hogs being finished for market on self-feeders do not consume much in excess of this amount. The feed required to produce one pound of gain runs considerably higher in lot 1 than in lot 8, a difference of .53 pound. The tankage con - sumption is almost identical and we find in addition .05 pound of alfalfa hav. The cost of putting on 100 pounds of gain amounts to $12.30 in lot 1 and $13.02 in lot 8, a difference of $1.32 which may be ascribed to the addition of the alfalfa hay. Due to this greatly increased cost in lot 8 we have a much less profit than in lot L this amounting to $1.71 in lot 8 and $3.37 in lot 1. From this trial we may draw the inference that the addition of alfalfa hay to a corn and tankage ration increased the rate of daily gain, decreased the cost of gain and increased the profit quite materially. Possibly some other factors may have been responsible for a portion of the difference in the results obtained with these two lots. However, as there were 20 hogs in each pen and as they were fed under identical conditions it is safe to assume that conditions in so far as the care and feeding were concerned did not cause the difference in the results. From this test we would not hesitate to say that the addition of alfalfa hay to a corn and tankage ration is very justifiable and that plenty of good fourth cutting hay should be kept before the hogs at all times as what little they consume will materially increase the gain and increase the profit. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">EXPERIMENTAL HoG FEEDING 19 EXPERIMENT NO. II Sixty-eight Day Test. February 14, 1918, to April 22, 1918 A comparison of Pigs Fed Corn Supplemented with Both Tankage and Alfalfa, Tankage Alone, and Alfalfa Alone: Also Ground Corn and Ground Alfalfa. In the spring of 1918 four lots of twenty pigs each averag - ing Iwtter than 1-1-0 pounds per head were started on a 68-day test to ascertain the relative value of supplementing corn with lx&gt;th tankage and alfalfa, tankage alone, alfalfa alone, and in the fourth instance supplementing ground corn with ground alfalfa, all lots ln'ing fed from self-feeders. Average initial weight Average final weight . . 143.85 144.55 I 141.00 144.85 260.25 242.47 ; 214.30 212.45 Average gain 116.40 97.92 73.30 67.60 Average daily gain 1.71 1.44 1.08 .99 Pounds average daily ration Corn Tankage Alfalfa .31 6.76 5.62 .8 .577 4.99 .577 .21 .42 .555 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Tankage Alfalfa 4.27 4.7 .47 .4 5.2 5.04 .122 .387 .56 Cost per 100 pounds gain $13.18 $13.75 $13.48 $13.69 Profit per pig, based on cost price of $17.50 per cwt., selling price of $16.50 per cwt., and interest at 7 ( ,' c . . . $2.09 $0.91 I $0.47 i $0.12 Nutritive ratio 1:7 1:9 1:9.1 1:8.8 I\A 1 lUil O Lot I: Corn, tankage, alfalfa Lot II: Corn, tankage Lot III: Corn, alfalfa Lot IV: Ground corn, ground alfalfa Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 umber in lot i 20 20 20 20 i i i I RATION Corn Corn Corn Tankage Tankage I Alfalfa Ground corn Ground </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 20 DOES IT PAY TO ADD ALFALFA TO A CORN AND TANKAGE RATION — LOTS 1 AND 2 Comparing first lots 1 and 2, fed corn, tankage and alfalfa versus corn and tankage, we note that in the case of lot 1 the daily gain was considerably larger than in lot 2, it being 1.71 pounds and 1.44 pounds respectively. The food consumption in lot 1 was likewise somewhat heavier, the daily corn consumption, amounting to 7.31 pounds in lot 1 and C.76 pounds in lot 2, the tankage to .8 pound versus .58 pound in lot 2, while lot 1 con - sumed .2 pound of alfalfa in addition. In other words, the total food consumed daily amounted in lot 1 to 8.4 pounds in contrast to 7.34 pounds in lot 2, a difference of slightly over one pound per head. It will be noted that Jot 1 consumed .2 pound per day of alfalfa and at the same time .5 pound additional corn and .22 pound more tankage than did lot 2. The addition of alfalfa to this lot would not necessarily be expected to increase the corn and tankage consumption as it did. The nutritive ratio of the ration received by these two lots amounted to 1 :7 in lot 1 and 1 :9 in lot 2, the latter appearing to be a rather wide ratio, altho considering that the hogs were quit&lt;&gt; heavy at the opening of the test and that they had free acce^ to corn and tankage at all times, it doubtless was sufficiently narrow to meet their demands. Under feed required to produce one pound of gain we find that the pigs in lot 1 required .43 pound less corn, .07 pound more tankage and .12 pound of alfalfa more to produce one pound of gain than those in lot 2. Due to the fact that con - siderably less corn was required we find the cost of producing 100 pounds of gain in lot 1 to be but $13.18 in contrast to $13.75 in lot 2. As a result the profit in lot 1 amounts to $2.09 in con - trast to 91 cents in lot 2, a very marked difference in favor of the lot receiving the alfalfa. A COMPARISON OF CORN, TANKAGE AND ALFALFA VERSUS CORN AND ALFALFA — LOTS 1 AND 3 Practically every hog producer in the state of Nebraska has available upon his farm corn and alfalfa. The question is often asked whether it is necessary to feed tankage to hogs when corn and alfalfa are available. By referring to the figures con - cerning lots 1 and 3 we find an interesting check on this point. It will be noted that the pigs in lot 1 receiving tankage in addi - tion to corn and alfalfa made a daily gain of 1.71 pounds, whereas those on a straight corn and alfalfa ration gained but </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Experimental Hog Feeding ■11 1.08 pounds, thus a very marked difference in the rate of gain in favor of the tankage lot. Under feed consumed per day we note that the tankage lot consumed 7.31 pounds of corn while lot 3 took but 5.02 pounds of corn. In addition lot 1 took .8 pound of tankage. Likewise, lot 3 consumed more alfalfa than lot 1, in fact, double the amount, namely, .42 pound. Adding the feed in the two lots, however, we find that lot 3 consumed a total of but 6.04 pounds whereas lot 1 consumed 8.32 pounds, an increase of 33 per cent. It is of interest to note the nutritive ratio of the rations in these two lots. In lot 1 it is 1:7 whereas in lot 3 it is 1:9.1, the wide - ness in lot 3 being due to the fact that the pigs did not con - sume as much protein due doubtless to the fact that the alfalfa was so bulky that they were unable to consume it in large enough quantities to properly balance the ration. Under the feed required to produce one pound of gain we find that there was a material saving in the amount of corn required in the case of lot 1, 4/27 pounds l&gt;eing required, while in lot 3 it took 5.2 pounds, almost one pound more. Lot 1 consumed .47 pound of tankage to the pound of gain. However, they consumed but .12 pound of alfalfa while lot 3 consumed .38 pound. Owing to the fact that the tankage in this trial is valued at quite a high figure, the cost of 100 pounds gain does not show a big advantage for lot 1, the figures here being $13.1S in lot 1 in contrast to $13.48 in lot 3. Due to the greater total gain of the pigs in lot 1, however, they show a much larger profit per head, namely $2.09, in contrast to 47 cents in the caw of lot 3. In this test the tankage is charged at $100 per ton. It could have lieen charged at $1(10 and still the profit per head would have lieen the same in lot 1 as in lot 3. A COMPARISON OF SHELLED CORN AND ALFALFA HAY FED IN SELF-FEEDERS VERSUS GROUND CORN AND GROUND ALFALFA HAY MIXED AND FED IN SELF-FEEDERS — LOTS 3 AND 4 In order to ascertain the advisability of fixing the per - centage of alfalfa to corn consumed by fattening hogs, lots 3 and 4 were planned, lot 3 having access to shelled corn in one feeder and alfalfa hay in the other and determining by the free - choice method the relative percentage of each which it would consume. Lot 4 was fed ground shelled corn and ground alfalfa mixed in the proportion of one part of alfalfa to nine parts of corn. This test shows the advantage, if there be such, of feed - ing the alfalfa in the ground form. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 22 It will be noted that lot 3, receiving the whole corn and hay, gained 1.08 pounds whereas lot 4 gained .99 pound, some - what of an advantage in favor of the lot on the whole feed. Under daily ration we find that lot 3 consumed somewhat more corn, namely 5.62 pounds, whereas lot 4 consumed 4.0!) pounds. However, lot 4 consumed more alfalfa than did lot 3, this amounting to .56 pound in the case of lot 4 and .42 pound in lot 3. In other words, while the pigs in lot 4 were required to take their ration in the form of one part of alfalfa to nine parts corn, the pigs in lot 3 of their own free will took one part alfalfa to each thirteen parts of corn, and likewise consumed a greater total amount of feed, namely 6.04 pounds in contrast to 5.55 pounds in lot 4. The nutritive ratio is slightly narrower in the case of lot 4, being 1 :8.8 there versus 1 :9.1 in lot 3. To produce one pound of gain lot 3 required slightly more corn and slightly less alfalfa. The cost of grinding the feed in lot 4, together with the additional corn required, was sufficient to raise the cost of 100 pounds of gain to $13.69 in contrast to $13.48 in lot 3. The profit is 47 cents in lot 3 as against 12 cents in lot 4. It would seem to be indicated by these results that requiring the pigs of the weight used in this test to take one part of alfalfa with each nine parts of corn was not justifiable and that requiring the consumption of so much roughness would limit the grain consumption to such an extent as to lower the gains an&lt;l profits per pijr. EXPERIMENT NO. Ill Eighty-four Day Test. November 30, 1017, to February 22. 191 A Comparison of Methods of Feeding Tankage in Con - junction with an Ear Corn and Alfalfa Ration. Owing to the fact that most hog feeders use ear corn rather than shelled corn during the greater part of the winter season, it is difficult to feed tankage so that all hogs receive the proper amount. The use of the self-feeder for tankage where the ear corn is hand fed. as it must of necessity be, may cause too great a consumption of tankage and this has caused many to defer using this method. The method of hand feeding the tankage morning and night is common usage. In some instances it is fed dry but usually as a slop. The three lots in this test were planned with the view of ascertaining the advisability of using the self-feeder for tankage where ear corn and alfalfa form the balance of the ration, likewise of hand feeding the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">&gt; I I K.Xl'KRIMENTAL HoG FEEDING ■&gt;, tankage dry twice \wv day versus feeding it wet twice [mt day The pigs in each lot were to have a full feed of ear corn. th&lt; same to l&gt;e fed twice per day. In the case of the self-feeder lot the plan was to allow what tankage the pigs would consume a all times. The per cent of tankage to corn in the case of lot •2 and 3 was varied as the experiment progressed. At the open ing it was fed on a ten per cent basis. Towards the close i was cut down to ."&gt; per cent. RATIONS Lot I: Corn, tankage (self fed), alfalfa Lot II: Corn, tankage (hand fed dry), alfalfa Lot III: Corn, tankage (hand fed wet), alfalfa Number in lot RATION Average initial weight Average final weight . Average gain Average daily gain Pounds average daily ration Corn Tankage Alfalfa Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Tankage Alfalfa Cost per 100 pounds gain Profit, based on cost price of $17.50 per cwt., selling price of $16.50 per cwt. and interest at 7% ... Nutritive ratio Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 20 20 20 Ear corn Fankage S. F. Alfalfa Ear corn Tankage H. F. dry Alfalfa Ear corn Tankage H. F. wet Alfalfa 140.3 273.02 132.72 137.75 257.03 119.28 138.65 270.866 132.216 1.58 1.42 1.574 7.169 .566 .133 7.04 .648 .131 7.12 .67 .109 4.54 .358 .084 4.96 .456 .092 4.524 .426 .069 .1 $13.25 $14.80 $13.53 $2.51 $0.48 $2.16 1:8.9 1:7.38 1:7.36 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 TANKAGE SELF-FED VERSUS TANKAGE HAND-FED DRY IN A RATION OF EAR CORN AND ALFALFA HAY — LOTS 1 AND 2 By comparing lots 1 and 2 we note that in lot 1, which received tankage in the self-feeder, a daily gain of 1.58 pounds was registered, whereas in lot 2, which received tankage hand fed dry, a daily gain of but 1.42 pounds was made, a difference in favor of the lot receiving the self fed tankage of .16 pound. The daily corn ration in lot 1 amounted to 7.17 pounds in con trast to 7.04 pounds in lot 2. The tankage amounted to .57 pound in lot 1 and .65 pound in lot 2. The alfalfa consumption was the same in each lot, namely, .13 pound. In other words, the pigs receiving tankage in the self-feeder actually consumed somewhat less per head daily of this than did those in lot 2. They likewise consumed slightly more corn. The feed required to produce one pound of gain is somewhat less in the case of lot 1, chiefly due to the fact that they gained more per day, as the total amount of feed consumed per head daily is practically identical in the two lots. The corn required in lot 1 amounted to 4.54 pounds, whereas in lot 2 it amounted to 4.96 pounds. Tin* tankage in lot 1 amounted to .30 pound, whereas in lot 2 it amounted to .40 pound, the alfalfa .08 pound in lot 1 and .00 pound in lot 2. or practically the same. The nutritive ratio of the ration consumed by lot 1 is 1 :8.i) whereas that of lot 2 is 1 :7.4. lot 2, therefore, taking a considerably more narrow ration. However, for pigs carried from 140 to 270 pounds, a period in which they are largely adding fat to their bodies rather than growing, the ratio of 1 :8.9 would prove sufficiently narrow. Due to the fact that more corn and more tankage were re - quired to produce one pound of gain in lot 2 than in lot 1, the cost of 100 pounds of gain runs materially higher in the caw of lot 2, namely, $14.80 in contrast to but $13.25 in lot 1. The profit, likewise, shows a material advantage for lot 1, due to the relatively cheaper and greater gains, the amount here being $2.51 in contrast to 48 cents in lot 2, hence a very material advance in favor of the lot receiving its tankage in the self-feeder. Doubtless a word regarding this method of feeding would not be out of place here. Had not the pigs in lot 1 received all of the ear corn which they would consume it is doubtful if the feeding of tankage in the self-feeder would have proven economical as they would undoubtedly have consumed much more tankage and made relatively more expensive gains. There is a possibility likewise that the greater tankage consumption in lot 2 could be partially attributed to the fact that where the </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Experimental Hog Feeding 25 tankage is hand fed there is bound to be some loss and that th" pigs may not have consumed all of the tankage poured into their troughs. In drawing the summary of this trial it would cer - tainly seem fair to say that the use of the self-feeder for tank age where the corn is fed on a full feed basis was justified. A COMPARISON OF THE DRY FEEDING OF TANKAGE VKKSUS FEEDING IT AS A SLOP IN CONJUNCTION WITH A FULL FEED OF EAR CORN AND ALFALFA — LOTS 2 AND 3 In the case of lot 2 the tankage was scattered dry in tin* feeding trough. In the case of lot 3 the tankage was previously wet and made into a rather thin slop. Otherwise the rations were identical in the two lots. It will be noted that the pigs in lot 3 made a considerably larger gain than those in lot "2. namely, 1.57 pounds in contrast to 1.4-2 pounds. The pigs on the wet tankage consumed slightly more corn and tankage and rather less of alfalfa, the figures here being 7.12 pounds of corn per day in contrast to 7.04 pounds for lot 2. The tankage amounted to .07 pound in lot 3 and .63 pound in lot 2. Th;. 1 alfalfa amounted to 1.11 pounds in lot 3 and 1.13 pounds in lot 2. Inasmuch as the two lots consumed practically the same amount of feed per day, the greater gain made by lot 3 would naturally make them the more economical gainers. The nutri - tive ratio is almost identical in these two lots and is what would l)e considered a relatively narrow ration for pigs of this size. • r o Under feed to produce one pound of gain we find that in lot 2, fed dry tankage, 4.09 pounds of corn were required, whereas in lot 3, 4.52 pounds produced one pound of gain. As regards the tankage, lot 2 required .40 pound whereas lot 3 required .43 pound, the alfalfa required being a very nominal amount, — .0!) pound in lot 2 and .07 pound in lot 3. Due to the marked reduction in feed required in lot 3 we have gains produced at $13.53 in comparison with $14.80 in the case of lot 2. As a result of the greater and the more economical gain in lot 3. the profit there is $2.10 in contrast to 4* cents in lot 2. From this trial it would seem that the feeding of tankage in the form of a slop is very justifiable where pigs are receiving a ration of ear corn, tankage and alfalfa hay. In comparing lot 3 with lot 1. the pigs which received their tankage in the self-feeder, we find a slightly greater daily gain in lot 1 at some 28 cents less cost per hundred pounds and an increased profit of 35 cents. Hence it would seem that the self - feeder for tankage is more desirable than the feeding of the slop, especially considering the greater amount of labor and inconvenience involved in the latter operation. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Buiaetin 175 26 EXPERIMENT NO. IV The Supplementing of the Corn and Alfalfa Ration with Tankage versus Shorts. Tn this test, which extended over a long period, namely. 153 days, two lots of 16 pigs each were used, the initial weight being approximately 50 pounds and the final weight in tlv proximity of 200 pounds, the plan l&gt;eing to carry these pigs front the weight of 50 pounds until ready for market. In the case of lot 1. a ration of corn, tankage and alfalfa hay was fed, and in Jot 2, a ration of corn, shorts and alfalfa hay, the desire being to ascertain the relative value of tankage and snorts as a supple - ment to a corn ration where the protein roughness, alfalfa, is supplied in addition. *Ear corn was fed the first 100 days, then shelled corn. l\.-\ 1 1U.1 O Lot I: Corn, tankage, alfalfa Lot II: Corn, shorts, alfalfa I Lot 1 16 Lot 2 16 umber in lot . 16 RATION Corn* Tankage Alfalfa 51.31 222.67 171.36 1.12 Corn* Shorts Alfalfa 50.31 182.56 132.24 .864 Initial weight Final weight Average gain Average daily gain . Pounds average daily ration Corn Tankage Shorts Alfalfa i 4.67 .49 '.'.'.'.'.'." ' .22 ' 3.76 .57' .17 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Tankage Shorts Alfalfa 4.16 .44 '.'.'.'.'.'.' .196 4.34 .66 .19 Cost of 100 pounds gain $12.85 $12.54 Profit per pig, based on $17.50 cost, $16.50 selling price, and interest at 7 % $5.47 $4.47 utritive ratio 1:7.4 1:8.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Experimental Hoc Feeding 27 By referring to the table above we note that the pigs receiving tankage averaged 1.12 pounds pain per day, whereas those receiving shorts gained btit .86 pounds per day. a difference in favor of the tankage lot of .26 pound, or in terms of per - centage, a 30 per cent greater gain. The daily ration is of interest. We find that considerably more corn was consumed in the case of lot 1, namely, 4.C&gt;7 pounds, whereas in the case of lot 2, receiving the shorts, supplement, 3.7(&gt; pounds were con - sumed, a difference of .91 pound. The tankage consumed by lot 1 amounted to .4'.) pound, whereas in lot 2 the shorts amounted to .57 pound. The alfalfa consumption was relatively light in both lots, being .22 pound in lot 1 and .17 pound in lot 2. It is of interest to note the relative percentage of supplement to corn taken by these two lots. In the case of lot 1 the tankage consumed amounted to 9.5 per cent of the ration. In the case of lot 2, the shorts consumed amounted to 14 per cent of tin* ration. These figures indicate that the pigs received sufficient supplement to satisfy their needs in less quantity of tankage than of shorts. Under feed required to produce one pound of gain, lot 1 took less corn and less supplement. Due to the relative cheap - ness of shorts in contrast to tankage, the cost of 100 pounds of gain is somewhat less in the case of lot 2, namely. $12.54 where - as in lot 1 it is $12.85. a difference of 31 cents. However, on account of the greater gain made by the pigs in lot 1 the actual profit per head is $1 greater, being $5.47 in contrast to M.47 in lot 2. Therefore, from this test it would seem that the use of tankage as a supplement in a corn and alfalfa ration produces materially greater gains, increases the food consumed per day. and altho it increased somewhat the cost of 100 pounds of gain. the actual profit j&gt;er head was increased, due largely to the greater gains made. EXPERIMENT NO. V The Use of Semi-Solid Buttermilk in Connection with Ground Corn for Developing Pigs from a Weight of 50 pounds to a Marketable Condition. Sixteen pigs of very uniform size and condition, averaging 51 pounds per head were kept on a ration of ground corn and semi-solid buttermilk over a period of 153 days, the plan being to ascertain the gains which might be secured by using this ration; likewise to secure the cost of gains where pigs were fed </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 in this manner through the growing and fattening stages. The feeding was done twice per day, the semi-solid buttermilk being diluted with sufficient water to mix well with the ground com, the mixing being done in each case immediately before feeding and the directions put out by the manufacturers of the butter - milk being followed as regards the relative proportion of corn to buttermilk, the amount being as nearly as possible two pans of buttermilk to five parts of corn. By noting the above table we find that the pigs made a highly satisfactory gain throughout this test, namely, 1.33 pounds per day. In doing so they consumed 4.7 pounds of corn and 1.84 pounds of buttermilk daily. To produce each pound of gain 3.54 pounds of corn and 1.38 pounds of buttermilk were re - quired. Figuring the buttermilk at 3*4 cents per pound and the corn at $1.40 p?r bushel, the cost of 100 pounds gain amounted to $13.68. The profit per head amounted to $4.99, »i very satisfactory figure, especially considering that the pigs sold at $1 per hundred less than their initial cost price. The nutri - tive ratio of this ration is relatively narrow, 1 :6.37. This would be considered a good ration for young growing pigs. However, it would soem that the percentage of buttermilk to corn could umber in lot I 16 16 RATION Ground corn Semi-solid buttermilk ===== initial weight Average final weight Average gain 50.94 255.12 204.18 Average daily gain 1.33 'ounds average daily ration Corn Buttermilk 4.71 1.84 ■• Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Buttermilk ... 3.54 1.38 ... Cost of 100 pounds gain $13.68 Profit per pig, based on $17.50 cost price, $16.50 selling price and interest at 7% $4.99 Nutritive ratio 1:6.37 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Experimental Hog Feedinc ■2U have been altered after the pigs reached the 200-pound stage to advantage. By increasing the percentage of corn the ration ■would have been widened and the gain might show somewhat cheaper. As stated previously, however, this lot of pigs was fed as recommended by the manufacturer of the consolidated buttermilk, a produce which has come into considerable promi - nence as a pig feed during recent years. EXPERIMENT NO. VI The Addition of Oil Meal to a Corn and Alfalfa Ration. Two lots of fifteen pigs eacli were fed through a period of sixty-three days. In lot 1 shelled corn and alfalfa were fed in feeders. In lot 2 shelled corn, oil meal and alfalfa were fed in self-feeders. The pigs weighed at the opening approximately 137 pounds; hence were good-sized, thrifty shoats. The purpose of this test was to ascertain whether the addition of oil meal to the corn and alfalfa ration would be justifiable. i\.-\ t iuna Lot I: Com, alfalfa Lot II: Corn, oil meal, alfalfa Lot 1 Lot 2 , dumber in lot. . 15 15 i Corn Corn RATION Alfalfa Oil meal Alfalfa RATION Average initial weight . Average final weight . . Average gain Average initial wei| Average final weigl Average gain I ight 136.86 137.73 ht 187.62 215.13 50.76 77.4 Average daily gain ... \verage daily gain i .846 1.29 I Pounds average daily ration Corn Oil meal Alfalfa Pounds average da ( uuuua oitiogc Kit* Corn Oil meal Alfalfa lily ration 6.22 6.07 .513 .475 .434 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Oil meal Alfalfa Pounds feed per p&lt; Corn Oil meal Alfalfa iound gain 7.47 4.71 312 .56 .336 Cost per 100 poun&lt; ids gain $19.38 $13.13 Cost per 100 pounds gain Profit or loss, based on $17.50 per cwt. cost price and $16.50 per cwt. selling price, interest »t7% i —$3.11 $0.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 175 Referring to the daily gain we find that the pigs receiving the oil meal gained 1.20 pounds whereas those in lot 1 gained .846 pound ; hence a fifty per cent greater gain in the case of the lot receiving oil meal. Under the average daily ration we find lot 1 consumed &lt;''.±2 pounds of coin, while lot 2 consumed 6.07 pounds of corn. In addition, however, lot 2 took .51 pound of oil meal. The alfalfa consumption was approximately the same, being .47 pound in lot 1 and .4:5 pound in lot 2. As lot 2 had free access to both the corn and oil meal we find that thi»y took the two in the proportions which should best suit their need*. The oil meal consumed amounted to 7.75 per cent of the ration. Due to the increased gain made by lot 2 we find, a material reduction in the amount of corn required to produce one pound of gain in this lot. it being 4.71 pounds, whereas lot 1 required 7.47 pounds. The oil meal in lot 2 amounted to .31 pound. The alfalfa was somewhat greater in lot 1, it being .5(5 pound in contrast to .34 pound in lot 2. Due to the relatively low gain made by the pigs in lot 2 the feed required to produce one pound of gain and the cost of 100 pounds of gain show materially to their disadvantage. At the prices of feeds used it cost $19.38 to put 100 pounds of gain on lot 1 and $13.13 on lot 2. The financial status v of lot 1 shows $3.11 loss per head, whereas lot 2 shows a profit of !)"&gt; cents j&gt;er head. From thi - trial it would seem that the addition of the oil meal to a corn and alfalfa ration was indeed justifiable, especially at the prices used in this calculation. EXPERIMENT NO. VII The Free-Choice Supplementing of a Corn and Alfalfa Ration with Corn Oil Cake and Tankage in Separate Self - feeders versus Mixing the Two in the Proportion of 75 per cent of the Former to 25 per cent of the Latter. Of recent years an ever increasing demand for tankage h;is tended to cause this commodity to become relatively high in price and at times hard to secure. A number of substitutes for tankage to supply protein to the fattening hog's ration have been used. Among these one which has given quite satisfactory results in a number of trials is corn oil cake, a by-product of the corn kernel consisting of the corn germ after the fat has l&gt;een extracted by pressure. This product contains 20 per cent protein, whereas tankage contains a guaranteed 60 per cent protein content. Some parties have adopted the nWhod of feeding their hogs with each product in a separate self-feeder. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Experimental Hog Feeding 31 in this way the pigs having free access to what earn oil cake and tankage they wish. Others have adopted the policy of feed - ing the corn in one feeder and a mixture of corn oil cuke and tankage in the other, the most preferred percentage of each in the mixture l&gt;eing 7"&gt; parts of corn oil cake to 2-"&gt; parts of tank age, alfalfa being allowed at will in both instances. In this trial the two methods as outlined above were fol - lowed. Pigs weighing approximately 136 pounds were used, there being fifteen in each lot. and they were carried through a jjeriod of 63 days. Number in lot 15 RATION Corn oil cake Corn oil cake 75' Tankage 25' f Average initial weight Average final weight . Average gain Average daily gain 1.308 Pounds average daily ration Corn Corn oil cake Tankage Alfalfa .894 .324 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Corn oil cake Tankage Alfalfa .675 .168 .247 Cost of 100 pounds gain Profit based on $17.50 per cwt. cost $16.50 selling price, interest at 7%. The rate of gain is practically identical in the two lots. In the case of lot 1 it is 1.31 pounds and in the case of lot 2, 1.30.^ pounds. The feed consumed per day in lot 1 is 5.13 pounds of corn versus 4.75 pounds of corn in lot 2. The corn oil cakf amounts to .66 pound in lot 1 and .89 pound in lot 2. The tank - age, on the other hand, is reduced in lot 2, it being but .22 pound Lot 2 Corn Alfalfa 135.46 213.99 78.53 4.75 •&gt;•&gt; 3.63 $12.25 $1.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Experimknt Station Bulletin 175 in contrast to .44 pound in lot 1. The alfalfa consumed i&gt; - alinost identical, being .35 pound in lot 1 and .32 pound in lot 2. Thus we see that the main difference in the amount of feed con - sumed per day was a reduction of approximately .4 pound of corn, an increase in the amount of corn oil cake and a material reduction in the amount of tankage in lot 2. To produce one pound of gain the tankage required amounted in the case of lot 1 to .34 pound, whereas in lot 2 it amounted to but .17 pound. The corn oil cake amounted to .51 pound in the case of lot 1 and .(58 pound in the case of lot 2. Hence in producing one pound of gain the tankage required was cut approximately in two where mixed with the corn oil cake as in the case of lot 2. The corn required to produce one pound of gain is considerably les&gt; in the case of lot 2. it being 3.(53 pounds in contrast to 3.!&gt;&lt;&gt; pounds in the case of lot 1. As a result of the material reduction in the amount of tank - age required to produce one pound of gain, likewise the amount of corn required, the cost of 100 pounds of gain shows quite a little in favor of lot "2, it being #12.25 in contrast to $13.53 in lot 1. It might be stated that the corn oil cake is charged, in compiling these figures, at a charge which is practically the same as that of corn. Considering that tankage is charged at $100 per ton, any reduction in the amount of tankage consumed, provided it can be displaced by a cheaper commodity, such a&gt; corn oil cake, should result in a somewhat more economical gain, as it has done in this case. The profit on these two lot.^ of pigs amounted to 69 cents in the case of lot 1 and $1.70 in the case of lot 2. This shows $1.01 in the case of lot 2. From this test it would seem safe to draw the conclusion that the mixing in advance of the protein supplements, corn oil cake and tankage requires the pigs to take a greater amount of corn oil cake than of tankage and cheapens the gain materially, thereby leading to an increased profit. The mixing of these two feeds did not influence the rate of gain as we note by the table that this remains the same. r,M» </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>