<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  GROWING HOGS IN NEBRASKA.  PART I.  THE COST OF A 50-POUND PIG, AND THE COST OF KEEPING BROOD SOWS.  PART II.  THE COST OF GROWING PIGS ON ALFALFA PASTURE AND GRAIN.</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">I N KBKASK \. HI LLKTI N OF THK Vi.Kim.TrRAI KXPERIMENT STATION OF NKKIiASKA. win GROWING HOGS IN NEBRASKA PART I THE COST OF A 50 POUND PIG. AND THE COST OF KEEPING BROOD SOWS PART II. COST OF GROWING PIGS ON ALFALFA PASTURE AND GRAIN \SK A • i intendent. ; i fli 1 INC ,-KA : A ne 30, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD THE STATION OFFICERS THE WORKING STAFF ■ PM E K. K I.r Trimi &gt; How Ram I.pt B - - T. A R F Hdwai:|i I V V VftH W. W I FKIT7 Kn 8. W. I'KRIN. F'l- rr A n &lt; &gt;J NKBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 iirood sow - i 1 ■ 12 ■ if grow in '.:08- Kinai. M ui 14 — t- of keeping broud SO ami th'- 'ing 24 ■ d of 2.". tilts 1 i, Bhowtni .27 . . 28 on alfalfa pasture and grain... of 1904 and 1 em alfalfa pasture lUier of 1908 31 fnii jrain and alfalfa pasture. Record of ■ ■ummer of 1 Si&gt;9 :ain and alfalfa pasturf. Record of . - - . aimer of 1910 In and alfalfa pasture. Record of 37 . miners. . 37 of hogs when marketed (I9u9- 1 »m&gt;. 38 »rj 39 1 art I . 39 Cart II 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">GROWING HOGS IN NEBRASKA. P. sNVUK.R. INTRODUCTION. tin- results of several \ t-;i is* work in grow h.i has formed an important part of the I'nriiii: i he si ten tin- hoga have run in alfalfa |&gt;as id during the winter* they have been fed alfalfa ha\ in w 1 1 1 1 grain. ■&gt;■ &gt;ost of the average pi&lt;: when it has reacheil nf '&lt;» lli&gt;. ami the cost nf keeping lirood sows. ?ie iiisi df j_'aiiis on the pig from the time it pounds until it was taken from the pasture to the ot in the fall. At the end of his part a siimman is diiatc the nisi ot tin fat hoc when marketed. ihe piys from the time thev were taken from i lie fall until thev were marketed will appear V. 123. 1 : 1 1 1 1 • - 1 i 1 1 No. 123 will ht published in technical edition jiivinj: the details of th. llv. and a popular etlition which will deal without giving man.\ of the details. The ill In- sent to the people whose names are M he ti chniial edition will 1m- sent onlv to those r n his bulletin the term "••out" include* &lt;ml\ the cost of feed and the ordinary risk: it does not cover the equipment ibor in- i In inti list on the investment. tplan followei! in determining the rnoi of the ."iiipound ]&gt;\£ keep a record of ihe cost of keeping the dam a ,\ear and til it had reached the required weight, and </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 to ehaffje all thin cost to the pig. after iadactiag th. the IMMW in the wrijrht of the sow durinj; the \ ••:ir. W i have taken m tin- price of hog* t Ik- averaj rai for baga ■&lt; North I'latii- daring tl 1911. This price - Ml |«-r UM poaada We haw- tab awraj;*' price llial we hav .ir rora iliirin^ the sum M t lit- prujH i |&gt;[!&lt;« foi ron A - l&gt;nlletin. This is 47 par haakcL Tl» kind* oi feH are which uc coi - Im- Illi ■ |i|'o&lt;|lli ! - in order to deliver then at N'ort Tin- prk • &gt;ll(iw &lt; Orn. per bu^ Wheat, i' 'illsllr! Oil-meal. Tank Alfalfa &lt; 'hopped Alfalfa ha\ . per ton I IK luilcd in tilt- BiajOl in i In- &lt;l ire iIt'|H-inls on i ■ heiag IM, h «• i m oa Raavai it at -~&gt; (&lt;nts per moath a I fid fraim, or aae half of that am full ration. Piga have tx Kl otht-r than alfalfa is tern* the tahfc ■d alfalfa or alfalfa meal was a part ■•: .m\ ration in the incut, all the graia «a&gt; gronad. The alfalfa with the graia; the chopped alfalf.i w,i^ |&gt;ul in the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Bponivd over it. The feed was moi&gt; • Dg |int in the trough. The f»-«-«l was weighed k feed. OMCfH where the sows MR •irniwin*: time and while the litters were B- 'iimi^h f»d w.-is weighed and mixed at reral days. - ii. w:it&lt;-r at all times unless tlie wiMther • r froze i|iiicklv. I &gt;nrin&lt;r such times i I limes e.lch ilav or .IS often as there was :m\ thai llif Ikil's i:ired for it. Water was supplied in ns of a irravitv water system that kept fresh i hi trniiirlis at all tin the Mliles the term "pel . ent" I'; I is used in h. treijrhi of the feed &lt;riven daily in eaaipai "ii |,. .mi. Is weight of the hog* • Mm- first ;md last w.-i-lits ■ • -f i ? r i« • ii I • &gt;( tli.- Ii.il' A ."!',' ratios is ."! pounds of fc&lt;Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 PART I THE COST OF A 50 POUND PIG AND THE COST OF KEEPING BROOD SOWS T)m- .1 In tli&lt;- win'. ' ion on ■ mit &lt;if .-Ii.it ■ "Idinur tbi EXPERIMENT VJ RKfORP OF SIX ORAP1 Thisc sciw v hsi&lt;l r:ii«&lt;-(l uiti- imm4 in -Tub IWV7 '1 no ir r wint«T s&lt;'t in. hut m on :i!f;ilf:i nflntiire Fi thf dr» «inti-r until farrowing tini«- ttn\ «.i. fed alfalfn li-i \ • orn T'ntil in Jann:irv tin- &lt;i&gt;rn f&lt;&lt;1 nmnnntvd I ' im ..f Hw « I'M dnririL' I th it wan in&lt;T.-;is.-«1 IV iximateli It illicit l&gt;&lt;- i '.f I 50 ftOII I* : i Tl *1 kl&lt; ■! • • r i Ipit :mmI Iiuwcvit. l» k&lt; ■&lt; | ■ .) (in t Ik npprnfloh fv ;il! our • </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Bud all th»' alfalfa hav thev wanted, and during the winter -iwn to r I aowfl wrif^mi l.SfiO lhs. and had 37 pig* Tin- sows averaged 310 lhs. and the On lini' 2fl tl n weighed 1.805 lhs. and irln'il 1.500 His. The sows had maintained ml tin |iiirs had trained 1.070 lhs. The grain • 28 to June 20 hv the sows and the pigs that ate with &lt;nd hv the pigs in the creeps 2.012 lh*.. a His . or rtc,:: lhs. of era in for 100 lhs. of pain. The l.iih ffain per pisr was "7 lh The total amount of fi'd from .Taniiai-\ 27 till the pi^s wn-e weaned was &lt;;.&lt;&gt;!)." .I: 100 lhs. weight of piijs weaned. This Ann not include the eost of keeping the sow prior to 27 nr&gt; OF TWELVE PT T RE BRED SOWS. SPRTNO OF 1908 fail-owed durinjr M«rHl and the earlv part of 1 90S • sown and pii^s when put into the pasture were \pri' % M&gt;w«. 2.1BH His. : 42 pigrs. H20 lhs. ft I sows. 1.4S." lhs : 18 piirs. 300 lb*. inwn, 710 lhs.: 17 pijrs. 215 It*. Total us. }.:&gt;7r. lhs.: ft! pics. 1.125 lh«. 12 wft 3r.r, Ihs- 0) pisrs. 12 lhn. K.Tnne 20 the 12 w»w» weighed I.1MI lhs. Thev had lost r the time thev were sin-klins their litters on pastnre 270 r 12 lhs. eai-h Darinf this time thev and the pigs which ME i' lS . of arain. On .Tune 20 there were 93 pi^s. one of the 01 having died. -' ll.s :ln d had gained 2.155 lhs.. or 23 lhs. per pi(f </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 The fnt;il ronihini ■' 'I ih in ..f 1 WS il I fun a as n t mixed pntin f&lt;-&lt;l r from flic (im&lt;' f;irr..wt«l Tlu ilf;i |.r..h:il.lv «1 .itc rtTord &lt;if tin tf the :i tin Ml i M\i-r;itrc weight of '_'! gain. If «&lt; dtdnrtiny from I LMUM-il "ii ;ilf;ilf nf flu r&lt;&gt;F bro&lt;. Murii nini: « it I 1 I ■ frvd 1" tmslii is i f corn mix^l cntin f"&lt;l in " </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Pip. 3 Afced brood sows. I Ins sh&lt;i\w&lt;l ;i ir; till during the winter (i'.i for feed ake ;i favorable record »t farrowiag i r rowed \v;is !t. This was Illllll'l- III ri-.iwt-il only "_' pi^s .mil :! ttim only 5 k Mini litter frcwi the date of farrow- ■ iinil :unl had reached a ■ eight at Tin it wiTc 6 ]&gt;\&gt;is per sow when thin woighi |mt sow when thr |&gt;iji» &lt;i slmws ■ gaia of M H»s. |kt how Novciiiber 1 Three sows &lt;lid not farrow ration in tin* statement below. per mo ll»s. whi-ii the otlirrs far ■tii ;i slight profit from them. This h. ."ill |.«m iid |»i&lt;i slightly. The m shows fairh accvratelj the cost reached the averaaje weight • </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 lb«. each. The charge &lt;&gt;f $1.50 for pastvn rents j&gt;er month far the how and for the litter whea th. with her. It is only an estimate. If t h i&gt; charge covers th. of alfalfa for tin- satire time the K»va are on pasture durii .. year. then thi in November 1. 19W ■her 1. 1909. should be credited. This would I*- ahoa. lbs. wore (mi r £'_'.!»&lt;( nior. a This w.mld h.n . •-&lt;] the iost of - 1 •;•_' per l" 1 ' ll&gt;s. The n indiijitcs th.i ■ pound pif rT OF PRODUCING 'WIN vor.vc. son t August 1. 1998, 23 «pi .d to Ih rinjr litters. They ru n in an alfalfa pasture aad irere mtion of one half corn and one half wheal until Novem Th&lt;',\ were M LfiS rail daih per n«t II reifht. W Me more than :i m&lt; I'd farrowed. ]•• To cost of :i ■■st of feed fi il\ *■! -i\\ C, Hi" H,v ii -i wt-i^'lii and time \&gt;, L at .".(I II- ■ ■4 uf "iii poun </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 (je dail\ gaia w;is S7 Ib. It required 'Mi Ilis. of gain. This imMM in weight !IO0 Ilis This dues not include the cost of the W ith lion's ;it *.-..'.»o per hundred, these gilts paid 99 li&gt; wheat and rorn. considering "&gt;8 lbs. of I liiishel. Tin- average weight of the gilts - 71 »i His and November 7. 156.8 lbs. The results Table 1. 'Mi- 7. •_' L'ilts were added to this lot. making a total Tln\ \\fii- put int" a •". am- field that had been sowed t&lt;&gt; ! • is furiiishi d only a small anionnt of green feed, but Tin- ration from this date until the iri Its Bn ken tu tin- farrowiag houses was :\ parti &lt;rrain and 1 j&gt;art .1 nlfalfa. The (trail was 1 part corn and 1 part bar The L'rain wan ground, mixed with the alfalfa in the stened with water. They ate of this mixture I dailv. or :!.0(&gt; lbs. jter 1 •»'• lbs. weight of the .■•|iiired MS lbs. of jrrain and 18! lbs. of alfalfa for _: iin Tl»' cost of grata and alfalfa for 1&lt;&gt;&lt;&gt; lbs. of gain 1 ivfTflge daily gata per head was .SS lh. The \&lt;i\cnibcr 7 \\ us IBS lbs., and on January 1R. • weiirM was taken on the 25 silts together. 21S.fi -nits ( if this feeding |&gt;eriod froTii November 7 to ven in Table 1. ni of groin pn sow from Amrnst 1 to November 7 was \n\emlxM' 7 till she farrowed, the oost of all The '.1st of grata from the date of farrowing • rajEP (n'lr weighed T&gt;n lbs. was *10.18. There is I t. . tin- H.M for pasture. This is an estimate which we feel is prwaabhr too high. This makes the total cost ■ i] for the sow from Aag—t 1. 10ftS. till the pig« were ■ d and had reached the average weight of 50 Ib*.. about .lulv 1. 1009. •*•_"_'") The ihanre for the alfalfa nastnre is snffl cient probabh' to carrv the sows thru till August 1. eomplet- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 This would redw M t&lt;»t;il at 27&lt;i Iha Tli. would he 1*31, whi.l ta |U M Tli - onoh \vh&lt;'n ttn </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 / w '/ iKiiini/ tOW*. Hrionl of H (jiltx 1909). M 'I l, I, l!«l», Period 2, Nov. 7, 1908, to 7(1 71 8 152 l.'pti S 813.« til 6 455 15;{ 60S MM 1 M 1 M 2 17 012 5 :c{ 2.M 2 ix f 2 ft»i 2.92 114 182.8 At .4 cent per head - t:ain. and this E7, li«&gt;K Jan. 1, I '■ </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 l»r Si fMUf at 1 to \.-ihIht 7 ■ iiiImt 7 to (arrowing and at M In 18 Pasture •• inuii - |kt month. I 5&lt;l 10 pound i:\i-i.ki\ii.\ BKlX' EIT till- |lij:s WlTi- « ran in alfalfa . • it bout oil the alfalfa in th&lt;- fall. Oaring iual j;aiu for Mtm Im^s nuninf "i. .. •aiu wheu in thin fieah about .."&gt; Hi. per head d &lt; &gt;u Oetatar 29, L909, 2M of i for Bprinf; litters. The «Hfh1 »\ th«- Hi wm 8,460 Iba. each. Thev wen- put in a ."&gt; acre tield that had ban wheat. This furnished mow pea teed The ration for sows during the winter was alfalfa ha\ and ear corn. Tin &lt;lail v. weitrhiii'' the kowb i KINA "/ producing u notes. Retonl .// .'.; ,/,// iveragx , </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 r 1 1 1* ■ next two weeks. I Miring e.\tremel\ cold • ■hi ii was increased. TIh average mean - and the MCnga amount of corn 7.", His. This aWwi that the Iiol: n i shelled) )&gt;er HMt lbs. of their weight. - over 1 per ent. The last veifjM before farrowing was M Fein-nan 13. The M sows on this 7.ti."iU lbs., or '.'&gt;X-.Ti ll»s. per head. This shows a h during tiie winter. W I gain of ..V&gt; Hi. each There was led. in addition to the corn, ti tons of alfalfa raised at *&gt;.uo per ton. The ha\ fed per bag was .:i ton &gt; I'll ■ lilies (licked off (he Va\cs and tiuer stems • i .under was gives, to the cattle. The hugs prolialilv airda ol ilie total value out of the alfalfa or :1 mo i Ml - ■.Illl. V___ B|iii' ton .2 of a ton would cost f MM) for alfalfa lia \ ,.-. n October l'!t and I'ehniarv 1&amp; l&gt;uring the sam&lt; on tlie Bvcrage, each sow ate ~M'l bushels of corn. This at .. per liushel 14. The cost of the alfalfa and I in this exjKTinient from October L'!t to Felnuar.\ : tu produce tin His. weight increase was $."&gt;.O4. ere taken from the field to the farrowing house as LfTOWiBg a|&gt;|iroached. After they were put into the fed a mixed grain ration containing ."ill par Jo per ••cut wheat. M per cent ennner. and 1(1 pax • -"\\ from Felirtian U until each sow •I p&lt;r siiw. The average weight jmt sow at far - tfM t.;:; Ilis There was a gam of 111.5 lbs. per head • n Ortoha 29 and the date of farrowing. The cost of feed ■ iu .lining that time was ft.lt. If we add 25 cents per iiiuiith for 4 months as the cost of summer pasture after the 1909 litter wi - M &lt;if keeping a sow from the time • aniim MM - until she was readv to farrow </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Bfrim litter ami to put her iato ■ good cond was f 7.1;: U t tti inure than an ;n s. in this eMK the item of ewt would he about one do in raiai Ie of the 2(1 sows wan not in pig, The others farrowed from h :: to April 7. The average larrowiag date Mag M Then- is ■ farrow in&lt;: record m 1 v it liefore farrowing was f_'7.."i His. ami after farm llts Thesi veigMi were takes within two dayi of farrowiii};. B! average nun reifiht |K-r pij; when farrowed ■B weight ot li'lc i ol p of 1 1 Hi*. |M-r - nl after th&lt; On March "Jti. I h&gt; • II tile South I' liurnt one burowing houw and the litter of anotlier *..\\ red aiul i on the market \ - bt*r litter uas alxmt four C of them lived, lint crowded out a weaker lorn. This left i: th litter* W hile in the farrow injr MMW i mixture of Hi i&gt;er ceni eiit alfalfa meal for a time, hut .•ed h\ oil inea!. The . i.st s4 time was $1.17 per head Ie Bows with .'{"i pigs were put on pasture Mai. with 42 pips were turned in April 5; and _ low* with 1&gt; were turn*-*! in April 13, *■ and was an averaire of 7 p%i pet MM Uhile on paatate the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 I and re f » «i ■ ratios «&gt;f ."&gt;(» j&gt;er cent corn, 45 |&gt;er •ill ." per cent oil meal and the pigs were fed A corn in "creeps." The cost of the feed {»er sow and litter sture until !&gt;."&gt; pigi had rtadHi the average weight of ."&gt;n « &gt;\vinjr to the loss of so nianv sows, it is diffi - ■ In- exact cost of raising these pigs. Yet. b.v the per sow. we can arrive at quite mx ante irht (if these IS sows wlien their litters were a ISM ■ His., and in 1!Hi&gt;. when the j.ijjt* were lis. This shows an increase in weight ■ boh during 'lie vear. The cost of feed per sow from _"i till the time of farrowing was f(i.i:{ jm-i- sow. and rowiBK time mi I i I the average weight of the litters w ;is L r the nisi per sow and litter was |lit.:!ii. \\ &gt;■ 1 :nlil to this ilie , nst of pasture which was BUM from the ■ !!»••!&gt; litter was weaned until the l'.tlt) litter was Phe total cost of keeping a sow one year and rearing . Iftragr weight of M Ihs. was. in this experiment. 1 Then _ r ;iin of !!."&gt; lbs. on each sow. which, at $5.90 worth fS-tt. This leaves *12..*?S as the cost -if ■ 'ling ."id lbs. each. This shows that the cost of the rate of $:?.:?!&gt; per 100 lbs., or |1.70 for a n&lt;l pig. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 FINANCIAL STATEMENT I*rd of ro»t of krcpin,) ,,!,: mil I - anil litti i IT .Illlv 1. 1 !♦&lt;!•». 1 suw w *ni !•;» I ll»s i-.nn it 17 HI l!i 10 t Mis. ciiiHi. 1". 2 Mi- ;ilf:ilf;i n 2 !"!i ;ilf:ilf;i h;t&gt; Alfulffl [tHP a ainl !ul\ 1. 1910. cost of I'RonrriNO * w r &gt;«» •• April of tlint \i;ii- m tlif - ,Y H His XIi.- v mn in :in all twr 9. and wen' fed ;i mMlinm Drain ration. Tr of 3 parts slirllcil ™ni rmI 1 p;irt u r rniitid wh fher 12 hours The«p 25 pilts while mi Hlfalfn pasture frrnn \utriist hiImt 9. 11 works, wore f&lt;-&lt;l '_' &lt;;v u, s ,,f (jrain dilib ■ if weipht. Thf ■fcnfr dmi w-fiirlit \\;i&lt; 1 14t Hk On »h» nvenpo the*e hops :itc .1.12 lbs. of {rr:tin daily There were rpqiiirod for 10f» 11&gt;8 &lt;r.uii Sftit Ihn of the (Train mixture. Thf&gt; silts &lt;rHinp&lt;1 at the rati P .8 of a pound daily The cost of the trrnin for 100 Ihci. fEHin wha f».*! ."v coimtinir oorn </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Fig. 5. Young brood bows. K|k»f imsh.-i Mini wheat HI per !&lt;••• lbs., then lit 70 ets. |mt bushel. Will. iMfli was a margin of *■_'.:{! over the K_ ;iin m each KM lbs. of pork produced. Tf tip alf;ilf;i pasture \v;is included, this margin would be re- ! sliirhth Bl lir jrilts wen own to rye. Owlag to dry put into a 3 acre field that had wi-athf&gt;r the rye made but little Ki llnwcviT. it gave the hops something to work at and irnishod pxerriae. tn this date until the jrilts were placed in the farrowing house, which was from March 2&lt;&gt; to May 4. the ration consisted &lt;&gt;f I part* jrrain to 1 part ch«p|x&gt;d alfalfa. The grain was half corn and half harlev until January 11. when the barley was re - '1 hn \\ln-at Tin rxact |ni&gt;portions of the different grains ami lli»" alfalfa fin as follow </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 &lt;ir-.iiii ration, eon ."l l |mt eei1 •_'1.4 |MT _'T 5 per '■••in JkitIcv 1 tM i.o per "■•■nt Tntnl ration imtii ■ |IMI || h I . « Im ! Iiiivi- I lilt- Tli. tlicv \wt ■ nf 1 1 Miir ■ flllf.l Hill) lint n\ ■ - .tlT.lt.!. f..r litnre Bt&gt;w Tfci tnd iiikIit |ir&lt;i|Mi- rnndii i&lt; ItnriiiL' tli&lt;- 19 • &lt;::iiiii-il '.t.'i iii ear* p#r ri;t\ IhB. of ;tlfiilf:i. or ;i I. HM jrrnin ft-*] wwuM in 1 '' d;)il\ : the Mai f'&lt; I pw 10(1 !l «!:• i 1 x Th«-rc w. i. I :hm! Ml Iha (•&lt; :ilf:,'fi I )..• | n- th.' | aiwiuiii&lt;&lt;l in thin hiilli-titi l&gt;8. gain :ilx&gt;v»' flic &lt; ■■ ■ •■■lit 2 I 3 per &lt;&lt;ti i </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 I tfecas gilts during the wiuttT iitv. The gain was made with sufli isfactor&gt; weights at farrowing time; Mcfc nature as to produce growth rather than t'.u . and tin- ration was economical. While still in tin- ticld after March U and before being put in «ing house, the gilts at« j . on the average. 139 lbs. of d .:."&gt; lbs. of alfalfa. At farrowing time and after far mi not d I as is usually expected. One ■ &lt;\ in lie not in pig. One litler was dead when farrowed mother died within 4S hours after U-ing farrowed. The in- latter litter died ;t few da.\ s later. Two other gilts n the pigs were less than two weeks old. Tliis left onl\ rith their litters. We do not know the cmbc of tliis *\:is evident l\ some disease present. The L'4 hows ured 193 pigs, an average of s pigs each. l • Mowing house before farrowing, these •_'! gilts mixed ratios •&gt;! grains and alfalfa. The amount of this Im each sow vaa 28 M&gt;s. The average weight of the - - .'.^m Ilis . and after farrowing 'I'M) lbs. - of :'.il His. per sow it farrowing time. The I of the litters Wils L8.C His. Therefore the ilcllial 11* Ilis. The average weight per pig w. imes of farrowing and ik ing turned on alfalfa mi the average, •"&gt;■'! lha. of grain. There M( M I 133 pigs turned on alfalfa pasture. This waa an bow. On Mav SI the 20 sows weighed on J77 His. and the L3S pigs averaged Lf lbs. each. Ie jiigs wen- taken away from the sows when each lot ied the weight of ."id lbs. per pig. Two lots containing 56 weight lul.v 7. one lot of 30 on July 26, and a f 4 1 pigs on August !». There were 130 pigs when the 50 i| w. On these dates the average weight lbs. Thi&gt; w:is a loss of !) lbs. per sow </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 while saefcliag the pip*. The taaa m Mm nvi :irnl tin- yaiu on tin- |&gt;ijis after birth 8,175 lit*, or ;i in : ( - anil pi&lt;;s of ni-.irlv ti.(MMi Hi- The amount of f&lt; from the d;it&lt;- of t;irn.w jiii_r until the 54)-po«a4 wight t;ik.'ii w:is 1 1 ii.:&lt;, |hi II*. wheat ;in«1 ■howl ili His. of fci-d w;i&gt; rci|uircil tn i|in&lt;- [M His "t f£:i ' " |l - th«* I' - in tin- i! i \\ • ■ i i; 1 1 1 of tin- (■ _ ■ alfalfa pasta m t&lt;&gt; iIhs. The and oil i IB fiillnw lit- jiicii -&lt;liii. indicate* tliMl il I "i ( ' i ili' • I \Vh&lt; in Ili-sli and •lulv M, 1110, 221 imsli.is win.. i i ; tinshfls harlej . ;it )■ 1 1 paatvre, at flJMI per bead -liil\ l'm.* linn. 3 sows died 8.182 Mm., at |6.90 ■',n )&gt;&gt;■ Ki ::. 1909, T&lt; LMt. 609 bush In corn ; : til iik-;iI. ,-u *:!o.mii per ton r.iM,l ll.s. chapped itlfalfa. bI flO.Ofl per ton 130 j.ij:s. (i.:,(Mi lbs.. ;if $a.S!» ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 -/ timing hou-h Record of 2ii giUx (1909-1910). (19091910). » in :(7 ** Peri.,.1 1. P * nod Q 2 ' Aug. I Nov. 9 Period 2, Pelted 1, Periu.1 1. Aug. :i to Nov. 9 Au£V' Nov. 9 to to to *° Nov. 9 March 15 March 15 Nov. 9 i 37* % corn °. rn y.m% barley ,25% wheat chopped alfalfa 98 126 I 37* % corn ■, Penod 1; \ ™° co . r " 37*% barley | 26% wheat chopped alfalfa . Period 1 ) rtodlj ]!£ &lt; 96 126 in experiment 98 155 6 78 H in experiment 98 155 6 71 ; 8 78 * 155 6 155 fi 276 * 276 4 155 ei 78 .8 78 K 1-H) ■« •6 y i •., be. .8 ■ 1'W lbs. ga 390. i;«) i.s. (fain, lbs. 138. *ain, lbs. :»l. 568 &gt;. train. $;}.58* $4 ..{0 i:« r UKI lbs. Kain. 2 .31 1 «0 i a !.■ laily 018 0tf 313 4l» ■ K, lbs.. U12 100 lbs. wt. of 1.9 ■ 10(1 ltw. wt. of 2 »W 2 52 ■ pig, lbs. llii 2 216 0 &gt;f alfalfa pasture is not included. If we charge these pigs .4 mill, the cost of the pasture per 100 pounds gain would be 49 cents. This would raise the cost of 100 pounds of gain 5 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 71 1«4 11 u ■ +Mt*+%» Haw** Coat of »:rain p»- xiniale dates. i In (o farniw ! 1 August l to farrowing dai.- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 EXPERIMENT IT. &gt;WS WITH FALL LITTERS, SHOWING THE r OF A 50 POUND PIG. 910, from September 10 to 1"&gt;. seven sown far - .vrremely hot when the majority of v.il :iiiil .is a result a \erv small niimlMi sf K~&gt; mi»v bad raised &lt;prinjr litters th;it were waaMi attout in- months before the fall litters came. Dwtag ■ nilis th.\ ran on alfalfa pasture without irrnin. fall litters. They were then jzi\ ••!« I ■ n Ilis for tli«' seven head. The cost of this grata MM \t 25 .is per month, per head, the cost of the alfalfa n ili.- u.iiiiiiiL' of the s|H-i ii&lt;r litter ami the farrow I fall lift.- would 1m&gt; $IM per head. We do not have i of them 1 mvi Mav SA. arid ttierefore consider that reigfet from Mav 20 to Septem»x&gt;r 10 paid for ..f frrnta and the pasture. There was. prohaMv. .I.rahle profit (iuriiiir this time, as this ohnrsre for pasture ■ nt a&gt;&gt;.&gt;ut S rt. per head dnilv and under these eon usua'lv -jaiiis ") lh. daily, or ■ daily &lt;rain worth not Vive the weight on Mav L'O. we tte«rin with the (lintel? after farrowinp. The following ■( »iat if we charge these sows with their weijrht im itelv after fari.iwinc at ■R.flO and with the weijrht of their it that time at |6.M and also charse them with nil the feed and credit them with their weijrht when their pijrs are el :it *."i &lt;M) we have to credit the weight of their pip» nt onlv *:V7'i per hundred when they have reached the RO-pnund B order to halance the account. The 23 pics thnt died hartred ajrainst the snws This record shows thnt when all 1 ;mi) 'us* ;ire included, the cost of the 50-pnnnd pie in thih *i or at the rate of $3.7B per 100 lb«. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 I- -rage result* of the live pNeaiiag lota of hop* in&gt;l the coHt &lt;&gt;f the ."(I pound pig wan ft.ll, or at the r;i'. |kt 1IH&gt; ll*t This does not include emt "f lahor 01 or interest on in vestment FINANCIAL STATKMENT lilishck \v nnheln 1i;ii-|i\ :U I 1 leather 1' -inn fall litttrs in 1910, nn'i ■•it ml pit). S.-|.!.iiiImt Id J.«»7r. His ill $.*.!«» _&gt;. 117 IU.. ;.t |6.9fl - |MT I &lt;. l.f. 15 Ibe.. at p.7&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 PART II. THE COST OF GROWING PIGS ON ALFALFA PASTURE AND GRAIN EXPERIMENT 16. .Rl&gt; OF FIGS DURING SUMMERS OP 1904 AND 1906. •••n merits were conducted in which spring pigs weir grmri .In medium, and full rations of grain and alfalfa pasture •wing table, No. 4. is taken from page 16 of Bulletin Dm item of cost is corrected to agree with the pries ■his bulletin. ordiag to this taUe the daily gain per pig varied from "Js i us His., iepeadiag principally on the amount of grain ■ -1 of the j^rain for 100 lbs. of gain was from $1.02 ■ffieult to estimate the cost of the alfalfa pas - n l&gt;\ each lot Those which were fed a light ration ii .is much us those fed a heavier ration. It ina\ Ik - ■ •t. per head dailv where a .5 per cent ration M, .."i it. daily where a 1 i&gt;er cent ration of grain t ct. «l;iil.\ where a 2 jht cent ration of grain was fed. in.l 3 ct. dailv where a full feed was given. When this charge h.- . heapest fail is not alwa.vs the gain made largelv alfalfa pasture. total cont of 10(1 lbs. of gain on these pigs, when th&lt; - ..f the alfalfa is calculated as given above, varies from |2.10 to Tin- tvenge of the cost of gains on all these lots is If the price charged for alfalfa is approximately correct. data wnuld indicate that there is more profit from feeding i intiliuiii or full grain ration than from feeding a light grain i:itioii. The cost of jrains is about the same, but the hogs fed tlit* most i^raiii u;a&lt;le ihe fastest gains. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">r 5 _ __ _ - - g i - - .5 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 EXPERIMENT IT IHRl\i; SUMMER OP 1908. u mi ." lots. .1 total of Ififl piixs. ilur HW Two luts nf 48 I'iL's e;ieh were f - «i'iv fed 11J dam. .hkI 1 lot of 23 i it inns varied ns well as tho nntnnnt of t Tin' re.. ml mi tins.- is L'ivi'i' in Tnblo .". T.ots 3S lid tl mi-.- clis.usscd iiinfi' fullv in Rullctin 123. . &lt;l ffimi ".7 lbs to 71 ll&gt;s when this rt'.iiril •HI frnin .It2 Hi t«i 0&lt;; Ih txT hond dailv. or an Bfl Hi daily. Th«&gt;\ r«'niiir«'d M9 His of irrnin for Tin- rust of prain for MM lhs paia wiw * ■ -iirlit (if flics.- pifl \\;is 100 lhs. Thov were fed u&lt;-i- lieMil dtiilv or 2.44 'ns. dnilv ]mt &gt;t tlie hoc. The nvcviire weiirlit of 1&lt;&gt;0 iiiirs tin n.-istiii-e in tlic f:lll wns iri&lt;5 lhs Tt is I nts :!S rind :W. which were on n niodinni I i i, .1- lie:ul dMiiv f(ir imsturo. nnd T.ots in ;in«l ■ ;ih(int ;i full iM - :iin ration. S r-t I ira* we find tint the iivoniL'i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Orovimg Hog* im \ Tabi Ufu pasture /.'• 40 tl 411 tl u Date |§ I : At. last wen ■ ha. train, 1 ■ i 1 rai t Grain f«l d»ily p. Av. mean weitfhi f«"i pin 7»&gt; "■ Knj; the MloviBf | «r i ■-•• fur alf;ilf Cost of alfalfa pasture )&gt;•■■ piK daily ' alfalfa pa-tu;- $ii it. ii4 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 EX PERI M KNT 18. TRINO THE SIMMER OF 1909. ■ rammer nt" 1!»u&lt;». we have the record of &lt;i lots of the •; ' I table shows tin 1 r;itions fed and irives th - lli* ]&gt;\ii* ran in alfalfa paatanai The yr:i in I from nearly a full ration to a medium ration. - ii tin- several lots varied. An average of - bImmM nive approximate!;! the results that would btained bi the farmer tnm his |iitrs durini: the suiMiner. I ■ ■• them fO€ti rare and allowed them to run on pp. In some of these lots the cost of trains is it than usual On the whole the enst of grains dnrin? the ! 1909 is higher than the am age. .. weight of the pijrs whea these l-ei-ords 1m"_';hi and when the tests closed. 19tJ It's, j.er atf. &lt; ii;e daily saia per |&gt;iL r waa ''&lt;~ Ih. The irrain fed d:til\ - ■ . ei^ht of the pit* was about 2.M H&gt;s.. or the amount fed per pig daily ahawt -•"''• Hmv There t«N r^ininHi - if i:rain for lflfl Ilis .if jjain. The cost of the &lt;rrain for - if train w.-is *."!. "J.". If we charge the |&gt;itrs .^ et. each : i\ for alfalfa pasture, we find that the cost of pashm for I from SS eta. to 7:5 ets.. aVpeadfan larjelv lia feil. This cost for pasture raises the rain to ?."! ":! </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 ! . /,', II)** D * | I r pig, lb&gt; IK. II &lt; kaigtefl following f alfalfa pa* Bp.-r Itm f _ain • Tl </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 EXPERIMENT lit mi RING SUMMER OF 1910. : of _'n oM Miws IMS and I!»l(i" and tl Record ml 1910" indicate that the cost of the lii-st Si ■ about .«::.•;» per Ifit lbs. After th.u '■• | &gt;i 1 1 on definite experiments ami otbera held his. There is a record "it 113 pigs for aome .i.lird i he ."id i ml weight. They ran on al m ■!•(■ j;i\cii a full feed of soaked ran. The p i, jier pin was 7"_' Ib. Thej ate '-'To Ihm, of grain for ii. The ii, si nf the grain eaten for 1im» lbs. of gain average nuinU-r of da\s each pig was in the iiiiii^ this time was MX If we charge these pi»s .l' nf H b per daj for pasture, or half as nmeh as we charge _- mi full feed, the coal of the alfalfa pasture pet IM pigs was L'l i-is. This makes the total «. ■ Is. a niilar record "ii '••" |iij:s shows thai they gained, on the laih .51 Hi. and ate ::n:U ll»s. of prain for ion II,. ~t of graia to produce L08 His. gain was |2.55. If if the alfalfa as for the 1 1."{ |iij;s. thi&gt; ;• coal of 100 llis. of gain to *l\!):!. Theae |iij;s van i: compareil to their weigh! as the M af ■ ion Id not Im' any comparisons drawn between these he condition! of the pijjs and feed were not the i lot. and the record* are not such as to give ver\ |iarisuiis. The history of these two lots is given to indicate the cost of of these pi&lt;:s until the\ were di\ id&lt; d into lota, on which the records could Ite kept more accurately. - l'Iii |ii«:s would indicate that the cost of - ii wei&lt;xlit was .*J.7ll. The following table &lt;;ives i he record on these pins after ihrv were separated into six lots. Comparisons should not be drawn too freely between these lots. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 as all conditions were not alike fur .ill lots. The lots M and fed with the intention of making the |&gt;i»s dd in size and condition. Lot 18, lar example, wai Ninall |&lt;i}:s. some of whii-h were wmnj:. The talile shows thai I I S.09 li IMII lbs. weight of the pi-rs. This is nimh more than wt narih roosMer ■ full feed The ration was ■ mixti, id a small , _■•• of tai These pig* bed on the ilailx Tho • all tin "wrata" "! the lief.: hail remai kaMi H|&gt;|m of pnaJa aVvelopi were on thai \soiilil Im- I was .HH III |m r p ;in\ other lot. Ihi' Iferent I Hkeralh I gain. Tli tkcae re for 1&lt; tc. or onl&gt; aboi - lots. Tln- Htill In- staking Imt little prol The ilailv gain per pig on 11 !Xi Hi. anil the :111101ml of pom for loi BO Ills. These |. I i. eil i hi li The ainoiiiil il the I l(Mt His. of &lt;;ain ranyiil fron | »hh li is mni'li higher than thai for the u1 \'.&gt;. am whieh the rveard is for only t; 1 thai at th&gt; of the paHtnre season. If we ihai_ i-aih pel for pasture, we will make the ! for loo |ha aa follows: Lot 44, ft 12.54; lot IT </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 .ml l.nt I'.t. &lt;::7i Tlif total cost of ion B- kf|ii fur luiidiiifr. from June M hi ■7 The average &gt;nst of jrrain ami paatajrc )f - s: 1 . :;i |, (I - |«g |l, s . Al this i| mi Ilic :i\it - 1 tit • I."»S 1 !l)s. ■ mil ■ •Ifaifn fMattirt /■'• U ■ M 47 H l!i _ !l An- I tu lo 1.14 1 14 2 81 2 H 2 M 1 01 •i on w mi I.4H 2 !N ■ ■ - - 2 4.". ti t$ 2 77 12ti 121 3 s7 B 14:) % $1 H7 $1 IS SI 01 $0 7S t.M 2 9* 4 96 SUMMARY OF RECORD ON PIGS DURING SUMMERS ■ ■ill in Tiililr I ;_'iYt s tin- ihil.i i»a 'J i:{ |iiy;s during tin- M ot I'.mii mill 1 tMMV. Tin- rusi «.f KMI |I)h. o f gain - i Thr record "f !«• pif-'s in I'.Kr Table .".. shows th&lt; - ,f I(M ll.s. i.f ipiia in hr 9UK. Tin- raeawi of 1!»8 pig« in Tabtr R. slmws tin- roal to he f:{.7."{. The rword of 17!t piini in 1!Mii indicate* thai the east of trains* on them was at the • /« during tmmmcr of !!&gt;!&gt;&gt;. 1 rn Miied 29 II M l:&lt;2 91 91 91 91 H . . tba 6ii M ii 4:t 1l':; 7 152 i; I3H S Mil' 7 132 lt&gt;4 (P -7 5 si y B 7 91 H Wi »&lt;y - M 320.8 216 546 7t; &gt;i : </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 i.m- of 9;;..': i per iuu lbs. The con&lt; «i UW fnilli \i-:ir In v &lt;;t r hut I Daring l !»&lt;m bb4 i:mm, ii&gt; ill, i ii during ihe lai u ami I longer, ami t alfalfa. \ ■ .iir I 19H Tin &lt; '•-! of IIMI Itw. gain betn i ami Ulwic 11 llic v&lt; *4 hi. I f 1 1n- ln.j: had Imih marketed at 'I - nf the fe&lt;-tl r»'&lt;|iiiif(l i«i prodi ami develop bin u.-l K ht M.Mllll ha\r b hoifB hail not Ixt'ii in •"» COST OF HC&lt; HI Bf lip ■w *i.::i Tt |..r Kin Tin- &lt;n&gt;i nf urn ! ln»us were niiirkitiil. in Bt. As ror» :iinl .. nhall i&lt;iii&gt;i&lt;l&lt; r tin lot </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 Enid have iH't-n at the rate of $.'. "7 ■In- continuity of tins wed was broken &gt;f putting the pig* into lots to throw lijrht &lt;m .1 that data at our command indicate Imve is fairlv accurate SUMMARY lents ar«' based on the results of the pre - • I should lie considered in the light of the Ml pertain to feeding hogs on alfalfa if:. hn\ is supplied under eonditions CM ■K .11 the Substation at North IMatte. PART I. I of the fen I for keeping old sows from the time one • il .in average weivrht of ."(I His. per pig ng Miter has reai-h&lt;'d the same weight is ahout ■■1 Tills inrliides the eost of feed eaten h\ tin ■ i-n:ji weight is M His The inerease in the :' two ve.ir old sows durini: the vear will i f keepins: them. ROW* froi the HiM the\ weitrh M ~r&gt;t-i tiir litters iTPragc •"•&lt;• ll»s. nrl • nf keepinir old sows, hut tho inervasp v .-ihove the IWWIK in the Weight '-;t of keeping yonntr sows loss mlt old sows. ir and t'te eost of keeping her intil their average weight was ."(I H&gt;s.. in these tests, was | 26 for each 1(1(1 His weight of the piirs when their 1 lbs. The cost of the ."Opnnnd pig ns here i.ited was *'_\K'.. In this account the sow wsis jriven credit for )•■ ■ lit during the vear The investment and red </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 l*iurnl pijr pttimni bj tU i ami rhi' one pn i"illi- I tin- hcril sf Ski illdcd mil\ tin 1" i»f tli»' herd of j oqbk - I kijit mi :i &lt;•&lt;-&lt; m i ■ Is. PART II - ■ I record &lt;\&lt; th:it tl ijjht v II tilt ■sum </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>