<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  GROWING CROPS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">\ :&gt;i iv 1 KKKASKA. BULLETIN I 1 1 K \i;riclltural experiment station UK NKHKASKA. GROWING CROPS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. w \TIOX. \ MSI \ I I • • \ol: III \'l \ I I i , N'BBI </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENI STATION ( » i \ i ■: 1 : i : THE GOVERNING BOARD ' • V V </seg>
            <seg id="p003">.. I * i wheat to available water wheat in&lt;l ■ oats rop and tillage rop and tillage with drilling grain grains i' and tillage on yield of corn 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">' CANYOM PASTURE I *-j 1 l 42 S3 . T«»LI . S \ J MM KIV1I \|\| &gt;IN / PLATTP \LBW 1/ // BEMCI b L "T B i B T ! I 13 20 " *° • ■ 2 B "3 "" B " 4 " A A /\ :. 1 Ma </seg>
            <seg id="p005">W. HIHK. INTRODUCTION. 1 \c the results of the priaeipal ii ;it the North IMattc Experiment s, Mished in 1!)&lt;IM. This report flops not inn- Broni many of the experiments in crop rotation The results of these experiment! will i- more years" records have been sernred. n of many of the problems touched in this roa to Bulletin 118, copies of \vhi&lt;-h are «fill »-&lt;• who have followed the results of exj&gt;eriments - it ion will have noticed that the yields of grains v during the past three seasons. In fact practically roduced in 1911. In 1910 the precipitation only 1(1.7 inches. The moisture remaining in the I he preceding years enabled the crops to make a small ''!" &gt; ■ on with a very light rainfall during the growing r the rpops grown in 1011 had practically no &lt;&gt; draw upon and were obliged to depend nfall of the season. This was not sufficient rially as the growing season was extremely -I -ri n*r small grain crop was killed hv ■ tily a few inches high. The small spring SOI N i :• tilled land headed out and would have made a Ml liushels of wheat and L'D bushels of oats and had the grassliopj&gt;ers not come in Fran the nd fields of dead grain and eaten the grain an Marring the injury from grasshoppers. turner tillage for spring grain and for corn ry dry years would have been cpiite favorable. In spring was late and cold. Small grain made a very _ v\ tli I Miring May. June, and -Inly, when the small '•rop is made, the temperature was low and the precipita - it The yield of small grain was therefore light. How - the rain came early enough to make a good corn crop and in of ton </seg>
            <seg id="p006">lli~ ml a ninth il 6 ftiniln in Beruriug - the variation in the i-limati t— om. lii one N'afion the spring mav mImiim' ml favorable wcatli. with the .1 &lt;-rit ■ until tlh • icU properlv handled Bl lln- ilicoillf of tl" • lit ion of tln&gt; cniintr Bn - fall. Tl t jrix inj; cuiisiilcrnhle k. rather than devoting :ill &lt;&gt;iu </seg>
            <seg id="p007">. -'id yielding over •'{•• Inishels wii mi Field l!l mi the l;ilde. This : i.loui'd in lunc The } ichls \ 1.1.7 Inisliiis. wiili .in average &lt;&gt;f I- bunhwli .il ion friilll Se|.teinl&gt;er 15, 1!MI."i. to .lulv 1. - ■ \ n on rammer tilled land in Field" ihr table. The average yield on the mubbmt tilled ■ liiishcls per ;i&lt;r«-. The portion of Field 18 not 1 iili il land rted I'll luishils per a«re. The precipitation ■ Jnlv I. l'-HiT. mas i::.71 incli. Rummer tilled hind in Field \\ ;is sown mi i In tii t ."i :i&lt; res in Field 51 on summer tilled Tile in Id in 1 '-&gt;(►*.» \\;is 57 Itllshels |mi it over 57 Imshels for ilie ;i\ ■ Id Mi. which had produced 5(1 hnnbelf illshi'.s in I'.MI^. The ;iieri|,|t;ilion for the i in. I'.inT. t« lnl\ 1. mils. w:is i::.f.r. 1007. «r:i» plowed nnd renown to Id 5 M rli.- I'll 1* jilt] .» \\ ;|S </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 mber 21 -- ili«l urn - ■ ■ ■ 111 Tile ' _ ■ i !!•. ; i; • luring tin i« winter vfceal 1 1 * as a I I!H1 from ■ winterkill. ■&lt;! h </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Kid We tune th;ir tin- arerage \iHd m ihiin i hi- \ itlil in Field H"&gt;. Tl i i &gt;■ t -jin ri that ■ portion of Field II: n ■ ii.;i\ \ rain on .Inn.- in. lflfl. Probably il II*. ilitl not make a hijrhri- yield than nth. « hi' h waa n\ iitlo\M-il. been cut sepsi _:i\en I yield of .if li-ast 25 linshels "ii for ilir growing waaon I September Ins. KM of witltll- wlll-.lt ptffl nil • : Minh land ami si-vt-ral plat* of « ln-at frown •■I* t&gt;f Milage ami sci il Im-«I preparatim I \ lna.i-i Held &lt; Fii-lil 17 1. on tin- bmca-laad. ■ ran of si-iilin^. I inic (if si-cding ainl *i of winter wheat. This leM iravi- an I-"! •". luisliils |n-v ai-i-i- ill l'.tH'. Tin- lo\- ■ it nrre from Ohirka wheat sown September IS ;n per acre, «nd tin- hiiihist yield wan "_'l basaela Mr Kid sown Oiiohcr § at four |«-iks |mt ield for tin- wheat on the i;il»lt- land was 11' hn- Foiir plats which were rammer tilled in 1911 mad? an luisliils per acre. Nine plats drilled In an aw-riiffc \ - 1 I » 1 of I" IhisIu-Is per am ■ i K lowed prain utnbble iiaxi- an areracv yield &lt;&gt;l 10.2 The total iniiipitation for tin- growiB| • lnl&gt; li was 11.11 iinhi-s. A loiisidi-ralih- per on i aim- as snow which utelted ami earaned • ■iilil not pitii-liati- tin- fi-o/i ii soil. VVinteb Wh Available W'mki:. niaiiv ioni|iarisons of y ielda of winter wheat li il and tiiMs i-i-oppi il i-ai-h year, and tin - l.ilili No 1 for the tirst four years were not &lt;!nparisoii availaltle now. mi uniform as » i should desire, shows </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 publinhii _ the f :i &lt; T tli;H tin HUT li'hi^c Bad i he liiiiln i in r l illiil l.i n&lt;1 \\ i In- tiinr of ■ - ha* been ."i.Yl h &lt;•!■« &gt;|'| m&lt;1 ll'.T ' H | - ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 summer tilliag. The mi i rilled 1 ill tin- tWO (TOfM nil till ■ producing one crop producing tn i on land ■ 'it. 1 :, si i 10.SII 1 1 tl fair idea of the antonst of work reqi _■. we have prepared the above table. Tliis taMc nii work put uti the fields dnriBg tlir various rork repaired will vary with changing clii and other factors. The UOK nearl\ the the right time the less the labor rei]i Weeds niav be killetl with a •miifr. but it will require disking if nWj - reral varieties af winter wheat have ' ii durinji the |&gt;ast MWII \cais. Turke\ Bed m\&lt; kept at the hea&lt;l of the list fur tirst rnnk in « deals have proved verv similar here. The -&lt;&gt;n and the time of ripening havi In fact an\ differences noted have been SO under variation of the soil on the plats. The beats have Itet'ii so similar under our con them practically the same far 'his </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 hniil '■ B H I ■ I |»r«*|Mi has »i«miI&lt;&lt;1 ■ jiikI 1912. M hull T ion. \\&lt;- iilit;iim il liiiilni t thnn Marked dinTerein ■ itnn&lt;l dm ami thick *e*&gt;diBK. the thinlv »i iiliil |&gt;l;its iiiimiIh i dt plant* 1 1 * • • 11 ill' iii.ii vu-l.l fi-iini tin- pfaitD tliinlv Mrded thai tlici-r «;i^ ;i Mtuiller ihimiImt nf plantt the rain fell. Tin- ptaata on i In- thinl&gt; -&lt; i«lti| plats mai inciii. the lifji.ls nrr (o^fw *nA better tilletl Prom Cht \;\h\v. it woulil Hew thai Team when that* ia plent.i aaa hiryi-h mndf iif ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p013">! that this work was done -• of the weed* bad Ihh-h destr&lt; ( her* tl • ingw of ireeda evaning in - letter to dm ;i j." rln- practice "&gt;f potting oa abom • •i-nstiilks. a loss amount (probably i ami aboat two pccka on sum - fflcient moiatnre. early staled ■eeded grain und roaaeqnentty There ;ir&lt;- [riven in T;ible - - • different Times of seeding winter warrant the drawing of delniti !h soil tn the proper time for needing. inf.ill w;is liifrh mid uliin there were 1 needing time, we obtained bi ore September l"&gt;. There - ! in siipimrt the fall growth wirh • lr&gt; thai the wheat was in danger of bring • ■! hi dromth early in the nnrteg. hen the soil was deflcieni in moisnin - - bare ghm better remilta. Oliaer - ■ !ii| us to iM'licvc that flic failure of the well dnring dr.i Meaasna lias not vinterkilling as to injury dnc to draatk early If tin i|H*ing. the ilrirst stirfai-f soil is usually growth hai been prodneed. regardlesa . ■ llMi'iil'Tllt'lMIH'kf II Pi' I *O 1 1 1 • ' 1 1 X t Of 81 1908 1910 I'M I I'M.' Average llu. Hu. Bu .'&lt;u. Bu. Bu 12.1 12.6 37.1 13.9 10.2 :!7 1 in.' 31.1 i us I'M : l 12.0 *(•". 117 i(i.7 ::7.n : 15.4 14.8 :;7 1 1.,:; !■ ■ e \;ilne in indicating tin- relatioa &lt;&gt;f rhi- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">more vigorous :ttnl lm-hw famtci I &lt;n the |&gt;lauta &lt;&gt;u tin- rarlier appded ]■ \\ •mill th;it ;i ditfi-ifiiir of vi inia - ..f tin- tu*i\ at • (lillniTHc in i In- \ icltl of \\ inii-r \\l&lt; .'! tin- proper titm winter iriM*a1 ■!■ 'imt &lt;&gt;f available muwtuw in 'if 1 1 tin i ilt'i.ililr moistun If tin iiilf \t\ \\ Ir is thai tl»' ' til" ' The fol - iii 1911. TImti • '■ll ~ 'I ■ mil all tin- nondi i iir « In Ml « :i- f!T&lt;&gt;« I </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 :iis variety this year is doubt I. ss due I his p»at to a much greater extent tha 1911. as the crop was killid by droutl Table 7 shows tin* rtaulti obtained from nj: whciit at &lt;liff«M'«'tn ratn of wpdiag ,. iti.iriiii'r &lt;&gt;f stH^linf:. and tli&lt;- preparation . for iill of these plats, (lie onlv varying ni «&gt;f wi^I usetl n 1911 owinp to drouth and hot winds I lie results of three \ears' work in testing •&gt; -lit times of m-eding are shown in Table §t It will l» noted that in each of these tests we have obtained our ield from tin- earlier needing. The weather conditions unfavorable for jrertnination at the time of the ntrond The the eliniiltie conditions m.-n iiallv 8 1907 0 1910 1912 :/. Hit. Hl( KU. 1.5 \»t i i 29.0 3 1 . I Mi 9&lt; l 2U l I l i 1 MM xprinii nlntit from &lt;///'/ ■a annually cropped hi ml. If n rut /'.•■ l»12 A Eltu. Hi,. Hu Bit 7 1 tvj I </seg>
            <seg id="p016">that the t'iirl " ■ &gt; _ fhad '■■ g. This ; I&gt;poh:iti]\ busbflw inort- per .mi - </seg>
            <seg id="p017">H Of sjllilKI I'll) lit •a lamroer till... killed bj dmutk. ted had it • Is. Kini Fablei ■ 13, 17. and 23 Mirk in PleM 41. whi&lt; h i- rarrted on in &gt;o \- ulture InvpstigAtioi I'liint '' - In T.ililr II) nre (riven tin- renolti oMti So testa are civen for I. In 1907 tin is were rangfat by ■ ■ - w n just before m i later than the rarietiet wen- mmti with a fair itaad. In l'»ll tin- variitv test .nil u.is lost from drouth. In the rlier rarietifla hare fire* tin- t«&gt;&gt;t ,n which the later rarietiea made :i fnvur 910, ;iii«1 then tli"\ did not vicld ;in I s During the drier years the advantage .(■ii even more pronounced. Of the Hurt mil it one of the earliest aad has ranked ield. It is a few days earlier thai the Kher - ..ii tried only one yea'. It ranks with i matnriti and gave a lt I vit»ld. Klc l&gt;a\ have on the average ripened ;ii nbnwt the same seeding to Ii.m\&lt;&gt;i Ium heea rooqI . I'oiir an ■ few darn later than &gt;u n imdi r similar I'MIs IWS I'll" 1!'1_&gt; Avi-rm- Hu. Hu Hn. Hu. ft", flu .') r, 22 7 .':; ii B.x I2.N i" 11 :; I I 11.2 17 -' ■ i l .-, i 7 ; :. 1 1 l .", ! ■ Hi.", 18.0 l^ii IO.o id be ilivicltd by two in twicf as : </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Hu. Hu Hit 15.1 17 0 « W.3 4 71 il 4 -' \o ''POi* \^ As ri&lt;i 18 Id. Sin. i In 1 a with i ill. ) i&gt; hi </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 _'ll 66.(1 April § April JO 1 1 '• 7.7 l!l V _'l S 15.0 ■ ut h whii h kill. (1 ill &lt;i:o[' ami Tii.i.auk.- In Table 13 ;in - nm four dilTeieiit methods of preparing The lowest average rieW slmwn is froa altbo this method gave better remit* In 1912 t! iMc- is i|iiiic marked ■ r than M summer tilled Intnl. The ■! l 1012. with the abnormally heai ■ !&gt;:iill\ run together nnd baked. i previously oo-nrred i&lt;&gt; i li«- murc extent [linking wm hardly BuflBrieoi I plowinn or rornstalk land foi . i ■]&lt;-&lt;!. The table shows thai three rears i- tilled i;iinl has (riven the highesi y le ilie \ ii'lil of ilie sunimer tilled pla I hcsc p| a Tun \i\u-s &lt;&gt;ut of three. )'irhl ni hiixhrl- e than either fall plowed oni ntubhle &gt;&gt;r </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 •■ iind • i </seg>
            <seg id="p021">B Wul'k ill !• i liailev. : 1 1 1 &lt; 1 three This indicates thai seeding si\ pecka I ••!! better reaiilta rli;m either ling have iriven much Foil' picks seems to he the -- i . 1 1- 1 1 • \ &lt; nt nth ■Iiiui ) k /&lt;/ i/i tiiixln Is i» i 1 I' I bop ami Tillage. Table 17 !/ive&gt; tlit- ■.rli\ mi grand prepared \&gt;y foot differ - namely. q&gt;riog plowed luirlcv stubltle. disked corn •.ill plowed li;irlr\ •*tul»li|c. :mil siiiiiinci- tilled land shows in the t.ilili- l&gt;v fall plowed barlev ■firing plowed. Hither of these methods has &lt;iiven urns than ilisLnl non Btabbie. It is a (juestion. how ■in- arerage inoreaac from plowing hag paid for the extra nt of labor. The results for l!t(i!t show a very low yield on fall plowed barley itabble. and a verv little incresise on summer either sprint, plowiBg &lt;n- disked corn land. The I'.MIX I'KI'.I l'llll 1912 \ Hu Hu H&gt;&lt; Hh. Hh. 17 J T t 15 H : I'm. i, r, is? Itt.O - 1 I- 1 :; 17 7 Hif. 5.5 110 I Hull.— 21 'ii- Hulles* 21 - »:i ; ; l i! in th. blo lii gir«m i lie ! tlirrf • lini; hail ■ April 1 April 10 11.0 April J&lt;&gt; It J ■ March 17 Mai Hi.'-' \pril 8 \pnl v April 19 p.i s ■a ins; to drouth. April Failure </seg>
            <seg id="p022">&gt;usl\ ;iili oted tin- w li. ilaina^rd barlr\ oil tin- full plowed plat ami tin - for the four ,iImi\ e 1 1 eld. win double disked in i In - hail bfm in |i&gt;\\' il iii i In- Rpriny. The frop of IfMMi u j- ■.« n i»n .&lt; i 'i Ii;i&lt;1 lM-fii in nals tin' I i-ar and was double iliskiil I in the sjuiiiL;. I'll"' lalili show - _i\fri tin 1 liiirlu'st \ ii'lil ul an&gt; l\ to « Improved i\i,. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 ■ n nt rut, -x of »ce,l iidi. Yield I- I'm" 1912 \ Hu Hh. Ha. /;«. 20.7 Heeding i:a\e tin- best results. Tho - Hiiii ll\ Im nn favorable, \\ ) a Id ill IiiixIii Is jti i ■ RKII WITH DRILLING GRAIN 'i si-. li;i\f lict-ii iuiiiIikMmI to • ; 1 1 i \ «- yield* uliiiiiuiil froni seeding xmall :nl rovcrinf! ttiih ;i burrow, and by M&gt;wiBf witli I ■hilii inns were identical fur the |&gt;l;its ln-i n«r he minim r ut leediaf. I hiring eadl • iIkmi «nd rimi'fi- li.-ivr bera &lt;m eon sttibble The li;irlc\ h;is been oa fall plowed wheat i \\ licit mi summer tilled Iniiil. Tlie ;iver - nhowri in T.ililc 19 indicate that Arilliac 'men sjniirj w hell I ■'. IpiisIicIs per acre, of li;irle\ 7 :1 I o;ils 1.8 linshcls per ;nre. ;in&lt;l nf einiiii &lt;&gt;ii]\ i\\n years' results are iriven from bread - dinjE winter H'heat. I'rcxioiis in 1!»11 the winter wheat ■ Hue thru with sinh n fnmparatiTely poor stand tha bad e:iili year disked the plat asd reeeeded t&lt;&gt; ■ Bpriag Kraia. However, after the ■eaaon &lt;&gt;f 1910, which ahowed thai a thin stiind ini^hr !«■ ;ui ad\;iii!;iL r c diirin&lt;: drj veal's, the br&lt;mdc;isr |,|;it left lii the spring of 1011 the broadcast seeding 17 5 HIT 1IIJ I &gt; &gt;u- lit &lt;^i\ i s tin- results obtained eding fiiimt'i'. Two \|.nl I I -Ml 11.5 Viarrh 1 7 ManH .'II 7 7 s &lt;*" \|,' \|.nl I" 1 1 n 7 1 r. droutk. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">I l'Hii 1911 I I'M.' 24 1 17 I Pi lllll\ I'l |MI- .(111 11.11 SB |mt .-in) ik i !i&lt;l Had tin work Ii.iii »im i .|. lhc «.i .Is would h;i\, •ii |i;iit u&lt; i In « linh \\ &lt; &gt; 1 1 lit h. isturii 'li&lt;l not teat. :mmI llu- |&gt;l;mi&gt; matured quite uorinfl Iti ! . ! ill 1 1 i IWk-&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 • full* i c.ikIm. led tests have l*fii la .it i lie several s|&gt;rinj: small ■on i his iisi has ben on disked ram ■ •! has Inmmi sown with a press drill mi well veil in |niinids. since the nunil. Cafe nilleli limrc pearly the feeding value Is. Any uf these grains may !«• M to 'In- Inilless grate* will produce linn h the fed in lilies llminir in ;i ii« m nl sulisrituti- for ■ ■I Wheat lias .1 Feeding value shoal 10 ' I mi ii .inn. It is probable that the rriatin ■ grains iIim s nut \ar\ if the The remilts indicate that diinini wheat and &lt; .! |MT ai-fe than an\ uf the other eUt ■ inrtx. Inn h a, hit I It xx \if nlillll rniltl it "\ i«-i » i |i , t Poundit /'unti/M fSmndM t'omuit I&gt;n*hcl9 :.iki Jll I.I.B-J ss»i ;_"&gt; l.lj:; *70 I'll 1 Is !N)7 IS 1 III 1.142 iORN. Variety nora have Im-«mi foodnoted riic Dumber of varieties ur strain ged from Ml to 35. The variation in .i i I "i i-&lt;- in ."■&gt;:_' liushi'ls per am-. Th&gt; j - that have bera ;r..« n each \eai- has not ■ r all years, bat each aeaaaa the Sulistation l medium sized rurn. lias l&gt;een aMMMg the lead iiid. nil the average, mai be runsidered one i&gt;f the 0 Other variety that has |&gt;n&gt;\ed its superior. of flies. i seems evident that the which nave ■« n in this part of the state for 'tnl i&gt;i-..; rted are superior to those brought in fn nt climatic conditions. Varieties s7«i 1J7 1,151 l'&lt; J </seg>
            <seg id="p026">ricd Iiitc !lu\ QJUIlllI v. tlliM ikI have i In !i from - ill thiin - I taring 1 1n- p thf j iclds ol &lt; • &gt;i-ii on - plowed ran stiiMilr. R|trinf! plowed - |il&lt;i»cil siiui'I ((rail atnhble. ■■&lt;! ii:ii&lt;- rmm. Tin- ran «:i&gt; planted |hm in Talilc •_':: 0 In i!tl i there m ■ rei . I ■ ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p027">17 9* :^J 25.0 2\ '.t 35.1 27 -'J'&lt; in .-, J7.a ss 32.2 I'he table shows very little ditTciin. e or in the tinal average lK-t ■ ring small &lt;rr;t in stulilile for cop*. » more time in do the plowinsr in the isi-d ami the irroutid is to l&gt;e plowed. I will settle and list easier than s not have in this same tield i II i a conipai - i.ill grata stubble without |llll wl»g '" table we have rack a test, but have naJv ■ rotation con is listed into iniall hniii any preparation. In 1910, only one half - made and no corn. This was the Mill in. ike corn. In 1911 and in 1912 it made the - irork is in Field 41 on the tableland. The • ii!|iaied with those from the bench land i • ' .in We hare several years' data on ral ■ in depths and on late cultivation. This mtradirtori results lhat we havt Ml - out of four late cultivating with one ! ther two \ears it caused an Hi • opinion that the increase came from thi ration destroved weeds iii such an extent that the damage done by breaking the h cultivating at different depths aai usin^r. The ihciks Bpldom agree in th«- thing in mltivatii to 1m&gt; to keep ■ - rrnji anil tillage "» i/t**M Field ',t. Yield i . 1!M)7 1906 I'.hi^i 1910 1912 nu. iiu. /;«. r.u. Hi,. /;«. 28 7 * .;s i, 29.0 8.9 -;t 1 24.6 " 31.6 24 0 25.8 I 6 M.0 M I 19 1 1 W.I M.1 3J -'i. 1 with </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 i]falf;i t 1 | &gt;I1T I ' uml - &lt; • • 1 1 1 1 1 - 1 1 1 cant- laorgfcnnii is the nh ■ plsini when In l'.M 1 . \\ lien s|niny « i ml w lien ~&lt;" ii \\ ;i&gt; - ■ KtMilis We h:lM' ) I : I ■ 1 I dariafi dn • ear* \ duwii ti ■ ■ and turn row*, tmi i ■lai ,,i|ii |.iis&gt;ili|\ during &gt; I 11 1(1 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">fen i'i •iiuiliiv an animal yield of 1.." to '2 tons per Pud including 1909. In HUn there was to | &gt;; i \ for cutting. tln&gt; there was some • plains winterkilled daring the ver\ try 1 ami daring the early part of t Lie summer. thai the main portkN ot the field was ; \ - !i..iniiiv r this letd. which is i little lower ■ mm surplus water froai the higkar lands. - made snme hav each year. It would have |Hi8ture for koga. One tiling noted on the is the weaker alfalfa plants WCTC Alfalfa in th. would I'ome iii after each rain to eaaiBCte with the ■ ins tor what moisture there was. It niav l»e that earl.T anil i-ontinued. would have Keen lieiie I i he western portion of the state, on the lands, are successfully jjrowinp alfalfa in rows by cultiva- Tlic\ have found it verv |irofltat)le when a good seed crop ■ 'iiiinend it even for hav. Where there is .ind. mi the tatileland farms, that will receive flood we would recommend sowinjr a sufficient acreage of al - o at least afford pasture for ho^s. B'if the valle\ lands, where the she«&gt;t water is not han thirt\ feet l.elow the surfai-e. alfalfa does well, giving </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Hthr.-&lt; to four nr • ason. ..t ;i ton or m i-. Tli&lt;- mi t &gt; troul &gt;i &lt;ni ill. wtmmi ilurin^' tin- dri. Where &gt;h ■ from the surf;i' ■ sow the :ilfillf;i lilllil IMOHt of the \\cr«ls ha by tilliii^f and plenty of mi r four fii-i ill soil. j •■ plan iif tin i\ :mi&lt;I IS mi tin- table-land. ■ ion « ; ili tin- &lt; &gt;tli. ■■• ol I '!■ i IndtMtn . l iniiil Ktatea I »i ; |hii-|mim- nf tin- h ink i&gt; in ill ~ - » ■ I lilla^r Tin- plats arc two red* • idi &lt;■■ i ighl ■■kiag oae-teatk acre, sad aw anrnagi &lt;&gt;f from twn &lt; li. The ihhiiIm-i- ol p is t h&lt;- mmilM-r of w-ars r&lt;i|iiir»-il to p plet&lt; one Tin- i nip that is shown on Mrh pla lii Table "Jl w land \* ■■ ROTATION AND TILLAGE METHODS ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p031">&gt;pa \i- in the rotation from Z toward A. kc rotation No. 4-". In this rotation t lie oats on i hi Hill and to plat 15 in VM'2. and back 1913. Cora follows the oata and rve follows ht rotations follow this same plan. i p i : 1 1 ~- which grow the mum crop coatiaaow h i there is a plat marked A Karlev S. IV smi on this plat each vear on sprinj; plowing. The irked 1! I'.arlev F. I'. gl»WB Itarlev i-ach vear on Opposite tlie&gt;»e plats in Sei-ies "i are two i .1 &lt; l!arle\ and the other I), summer fallow. On ran r tillage and Itarlev alternate each vear. There ■■■in- plats that grow wheat, four that jjrow oats, and ow corn continuously after the same preparation as i In- barley. In Field V.K check plats, winter wheat. • i &lt; and all plats in Series •',. A to H. are contiiuioiislv name methods and crops. s are arranged so that each is different from ■ Mat ion in only one particular. A fair example is .Minns 1. -. and :!. In These three rotations wh.at mi fall plowing, spriiij: plowing, and disked eon ■ante as these excepting tliat corn i« • r tillage. In rotations !• and 1 tin s ( c|Uii ■ p! rhe&lt;*king </seg>
            <seg id="p032">A ? ? LJ o I a a^I : &lt;ou6 ■■ M$ c ! 5 • o I. * « I C o 2 - 5 c &gt;*■ ■ 0 Q » 1*2 1^ :'- 2 • £ 2 ? * S * o o k i i O Jf 2: ►- c s s IkJ * v I &lt;/&gt; a. I i i 1 - v ff s s. — a. ! — 5^ - I! -^ 2 O o irs .. I c &lt;s I s a ! I i 2 1 1 3 I _k* Ife 1U I I 1 &lt;j 3 55 c I ~ o rifsTsin is i i life « » IL 1L U S &lt;6 C &lt;^ W3 ° i/&gt; Z « K or -. § e i K O a: </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 iW/«b S P-SOSIKS CLOWIN6 CrP-E/MM.V FALL PLOWING 1 ED IN PRCPMRIM6 TOR &amp;CIOINB. P-P/ICK Bli.ivc ;if prisinr si\ rear*' remlta i&gt;n rotations. ■ I in this liiilli-lin MMne &lt;if t lit- rt-snlts. yrt W« tM'lievt- ||.&lt;!i.i«l of t i nit' is wrmiH heforr \\&lt;- ran draw de Mi- 1 niirlii&gt;icnis iis to xvhirli ;ii'c the lust i-iitatiuiis. From _i\cii ii will Ih' Hea that entail uifthodg give - one year under certain cliinatir runditions. . &gt;t In r mi thuds uiw rht- iN-st results the fnlltnvinjr vcsir un rtnditiona. If defini'r ntnrlnnion* ai* will !•&lt;• ihe fi'sults uf averaj T \ni.i: l'i. ROTA TION AND TILLAGE METHODS FIELD 49. I9i2 ' mat rm | |* —/f ,, '" •» "jy, I r»] I C HI I'm ; . -' &gt; ■ &gt;v wfy&amp;[. a su»~i*&lt;iill^ rp | ' * ■MM __:_.__ '• ' '" r j.c» 1 1«TT" : ? e °" 1 1 c copn rp '- c coffx r o " -- ■ ' : " w P^JccTS] JM «*■ jPRt | ;„ - - - - ■ ■ e*m*l I i ii ■ - I flKU *i IS -9hU__] " r * -•' wt&lt;IT c fP ". w ,yg»t" * w^£ w *fg*p 0 ■ a t ■■ r * 7' I P *• f&gt; w H W. .'. 0". </seg>
            <seg id="p034">CLIMATIC CONDITIONS Average Precipi far/on by Months for Z8 Vecro at North Platfe 3i JI5 ,^V7V~77 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 -&lt;&gt;. i F\ * V / - Tt to X &gt; frn Xv L» * 4 i k. : ■ SI ao [ii f %^ i - • I pi I I 1 / -&lt; M 2| | S 3 - »♦ I" : - j </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 I '. X </seg>
            <seg id="p037">u \ ( braaku 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ; s </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 -a*" — -3 = - ii l - « - 3 :S 28 i ;9 i§2 fl _5 - -- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 y. w»si SUMMARY ■ Bed Mini Khai r ilu-rc L Spring •rniins Ii.im- | ■I i. n land tmt smmiK r tilk B at all prutitahlt- tn - 7 s. i . ] i iiij oats, barley .'111(1 etni average 1-fSllltH. ■In all sprin&lt;r small grains tin »t ■rerafp results. I Oil) III 1 H i i: </seg>
            <seg id="p041">in this lo.iilit.x. n practically all ea u : ..stin&gt;r. barley have produced more feed per I iins. • ii much more profitable that) Mr riilmiiii has proven thp b«^it annual for "veil profitable eitkei as a pnstroe nablr forage crop th:it ean kr ftowm •ii tin- talilt- land it is of qneationaMc v.ilur «Ihmi - of :il&gt;nnil:tnt r.ii I vlii'ii ill off \V;ltt&gt;r "" </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>