<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Public Documents of Nebraska 1917-1918 Vol. 1</title>
               <date value="1917-1918">1917-1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1917-1918 VOL. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY 51231GB UNI, UNO! AND T%M» FOUNDATIONS 1 1S49 I </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS VOL.1 1. Governor's Proclamation and Message, Keith Neville, 1918. Governor's Message, Keith Neville, Retiring Message, 1919. 2. Governor's Message, Samuel R. McKelvie, Inaugeral Address 1919. 3 4 Secretary of State, Biennial Report, 1917-1918 a. Appropriations, etc., 36th legislative session, 1919. 5 Auditor of Public Accounts, Biennial Report, 1917-1918 Insurance Board, Biennial report, 1917-18. O 6, 7. LU Q 8 9 Treasurer, Biennial report, 1917-1918 Commissioners of Public Lands and Buildings, Biennial port, 1917-1918 Re- Board of Commissioners of State Institutions, Biennial T&gt;ort, 1917-1918. R«- 10. Superintendent of Public Instruction, Biennial Report, 1917-1918 11. Board of Education, Biennial Report, 1917-1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">PROCLAMATION AND MESSAGE OF KEITH NEVILLE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE THIRTY-SIXTH SESSION EXTRAORDINARY NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">PROCLAMATION By virtue of the authority vested in the Governor under Section 8 of Article 5 of the Constitution of Nebraska, I here - with call the Legislature to convene in extraordinary session at 12 o'clock noon, March 26th, 1918, to consider the passage of the following legislation, to-wit: 1. An act to extend the franchise to electors in the military and naval establishments of the United States and the State of Nebraska : an appropriation to carry out the provisions thereof and such amendments to existing election and primary laws as may be necessary to harmonize same. 2. An act to extend protection to civil rights of Nebraskans in the military and naval establishments of the United States engaged in the present war. 3. An act denning the crime of sedition and prescribing penalties therefor. 4. An act denning the crime of sabotage and prescribing penalties therefor. 5. An act to legalize the Home Guards. 6. An act to repeal the Mockett Law. 7. An act to submit to the voters at the next regular election an amendment to the state constitution affecting declarant voters. 8. An act conferring upon the State Board of Educational Lands and Funds authority to execute mineral leases upon school lands and to validate leases previously executed. 9. An act to correct error in Section 4387, being a part of Chapter 87 of the Session Laws of 1917. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">4 GOVERNOR'S PROCLAMATION 10. An act to appropriate salaries for the State Insurance Examiners and for the State Bacteriologist. Witness my hand and seal this eighteenth day of March, 1918. KEITH NEVILLE, Governor. I SEAL] By the Governor CHARLES W. POOL, Secretary of State for the State of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">cTWESSAGE Gentlemen of the Legislature, in Extraordinary Session Asseci bled: The regular session of your Honorable Body adjourned in April, 1917, a few days after the declaration that a state ui war existed between our Country and the Imperial German Government. It was impossible to foresee, at that time, what changes in the laws of our state would be necessary to more fully coordinate the patriotic desire and enthusiastic impulse to serve, that upon every hand animated our citizenship. It has been almost a year now since we, in defense of humanity, in defense of our liberty, our honor and our ideals, entered this frightful and devastating conflict. We know now how our wealth and resources can best be utilized and we are fast com - ing to a full realization as to what the war means to our people. In ever increasing numbers, the red and white service flags, with one or more blue stars, are appearing in the windows of the homes throughout Nebraska and from day to day, as the supreme sacrifice is made, gold stars of never diminishing luster, are replacing those of blue. There are thousands of vacant chairs before the hearths and firesides in the homes of our peo - ple, and it is in the interest of the young men who have left these homes, that this session has been called. If the legisla - tion designated in the proclamation calling the special session is enacted into law, it will result in much benefit to Nebraska's sons in the service. Soldiers' Voting Law. The soldiers' voting law passed at the last session of the legislature is wholly inadequate to meet present day conditions. General Pershing, who commands the American Expeditionary Forces in France, has pointed out the impracticability of send- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">6 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE ing election commissioners to organize polling places and hold an election on a designated day as provided for in the present law. Such a system would, without doubt, greatly interfere with military operations and is not to be thought of. Every - one, however, will be impressed with the necessity of extending the franchise to the red blooded men, the very best type of American manhood, who compose our fighting forces. After careful consideration, I am convinced that a system of voting can be devised that will be as simple for the soldier as writing home and one that will not in the least interfere with military operations. I recommend legislation providing for direct mail voting by absent electors as being the only practical and feasible method of collecting the votes of those in the military and naval service. Moratorium. The protection of the civil rights of Nebraska's sons in the military and naval establishments of the United States en - gr.ged in the present war is a matter of plain justice and is equally as important as the passage of laws to enable them to exercise the right of franchise. These men who have so nobly responded to the supreme obligation of citizenship, many of whom left their homes, farms and personal property encumbered by mortgages at the time they entered the service, will be much relieved to know that their civil interests will be protected in their absence, and that their wives and children will not be deprived of the necessities of life in an effort to keep their property intact. I feel that you will all realize the importance and justice of such legislation. Sedition. No state in the Union is more patriotic than Nebraska and this fact is amply established by the ready responses of our state to every obligation imposed by the war situation. There are </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THIRTY-SIXTH SESSION 7 those in our midst, however, some of them citizens, who have more or less openly given aid and comfort to our enemies, while others, less bold, have covertly done so. The time has come when the last vestige of sedition must be stamped out. Those who belittle our nag, our Country and our cause, those who would retard our war preparation or obstruct the operation of the selective service law, those who, with the intent to aid our enemies, in any manner insiduously interfere with our efforts to successfully prosecute our right - eous cause, have no place in Nebraska, and in order that such cases may be more expeditiously disposed of and due punish - ment imposed, legislation should be enacted to bring them within the jurisdiction of the courts of the state. Sabotage. The crime of sabotage should also be denned and covered by state law. There have been numerous instances where grain and other products, greatly needed for the maintenance of our army and for the armies of our allies, have been destroyed by fires of suspicious origin. There have been instances where wheat has been permitted to mould in the bins rather than have it utilized by our government in this period of national need. It is equally as criminal to allow grain to rot in the bins as it is to fire it in the stack, and drastic penalties should be inflicted upon those who perpetrate such outrages in an effort to destroy property that is an asset to our Country in this crisis. Home Guards. There are more than two hundred companies of Home Guards in our State. They are composed, for the most part, of patriotic citizens, who, through age, dependents, or other causes, are denied the privilege of serving their Country in the military or naval establishments. There are also many young men who have joined the Home Guard in order that they might be taught the rudiments of military tactics before entering the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">8 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE service of their country. These organizations have taken a leading part in all phases of war activities, and their services have been of incalculable value to the State and Nation. Legislation should be enacted giving them legal status as an auxiliary of the National Guard. Mockett Law. Some years ago, a law known as the "Mockett Law" was passed by the Legislature. It provides that when a petition of fifty signatures is presented to the board of a school district, any foreign language designated must be established as a course of study. The operation of this law has been most unsatisfac - tory, enabling as it does, a small minority of the patrons of a school district to dictate the school policy. Such legislation is vicious, undemocratic and un-American and its repeal will be universally endorsed by the people of Nebraska. Constitutional Amendments. The time has come when steps should be taken to make citi - zenship the qualification of an elector. The objects to be accom - plished by amending the constitution are twofold: First, to encourage those of foreign birth, who would make desirable citizens, to become such; second, to withhold the privileges of citizenship from those who would not assume its full responsi - bilities. I have no patience or disposition to temporize with the man of foreign birth who has enjoyed every advantage of citizenship and who now in the hour of our country's peril is in sympathy with our enemies and covertly lending aid and comfort to them. With the aid of federal and state laws they should be placed where they will no longer be a menace. On the other hand, no good end can be accomplished by disfranchising a considerable number of friendly aliens, many of them natives of our allied nations; others the subjects of neutral countries and some of </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THIRTY-SIXTH SESSION 9 them, whose loyalty to our Country cannot be questioned, the subjects of countries with which we are at war. We gain noth - ing if in disfranchising the alien enemy we disfranchise a greater number of alien friends who will, at the earliest possi - ble moment, become desirable and patriotic citizens. With these considerations in mind, I recommend that an amendment be submitted for the consideration of the voters at the next regular election, making citizenship the qualification of an elector, and allowing those declarants who are voting at the time of its enactment, a reasonable period in which to com - plete their citizenship. Potash Leases. It is well known that in certain parts of Nebraska there are school lands containing deposits of potash which, under present war conditions, are exceedingly valuable. The interests of the State demand that these properties be developed at the earliest possible moment. It is also more than probable that oil will be discovered within our State in the near future. The Board of Educational Lands and Funds, for the pur - pose of protecting the interests of the State and to bring rev - enue to the school fund, has executed some two hundred and twenty-seven mineral leases on various parcels of school lands throughout the State. The Board assumed that such authority was conferred upon it by Section 5845 of the Revised Statutes for 1913, a part of which Section reads as follows: "And (the Board) shall have general management and control of all such lands and make therefor the necessary rules not provided by law." Inasmuch as there was no existing law authorizing the execution of mineral leases, the Board assumed that the above quoted section of the Statutes conferred such right and the leases were executed. In a recent decision, the Supreme Court has held that per - sons holding agricultural leases on school lands have, by virtue of such leases, no interest in minerals that may be upon such lands, 51231GB </seg>
            <seg id="p013">GOVERNORS MESSAGE 10 and that the Board of Educational Lands and Funds has no authority, under existing law, to grant mineral leases upon the school lands under their jurisdiction. The persons entering info mineral leases with the State did so in good faith ; they have, in many instances, spent considerable money for development purposes and money due the State in royalties will shortly find its way into the Treasury thereof. 1 strongly urge that authority be granted the Board of Edu - cational Lands and Funds to execute mineral leases, and if jus - tice is to be done to those who have, in good faith, previously entered into such leases with the State, some way must be de - vised to validate such contracts. Corrective Measures. 1 have included in the proclamation calling the Legislature into extraordinary session, the matter of correcting what is ob - viously an error in Section 4387, being a part of Chapter 87 of the Session Laws of 1917, and one that has developed a condi - tion vitally affecting the sanitation of the city of Omaha and the health of its citizens. I also recommend that salaries be provided for the State Insurance Examiners and for the State Bacteriologist, which items were not included in the appropriation bill of the regular session in 1917. Nebraska's War Record. The legislation submitted for the consideration of the extra - ordinary session is, with the possible exception of the correc - tive measures, of vital importance to the whole people of Ne - braska. None of it is of a political or partisan nature and prac - tically all of it has a direct or indirect bearing upon the war situation in which our people are so vitally interested. The en - actment of laws upon the subjects designated will materially strengthen the effectiveness of Nebraska's cooperation with the federal government. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THIRTY-SIXTH SESSION 11 In patriotic zeal and endeavor, no State has been more enthusiastic than Nebraska. Upon a per capita basis we lead all of our sister states in subscriptions for war savings stamps and in donations to the Red Cross; our allotments of liberty bonds have been subscribed; our quotas for the army and for the navy have been greatly over-enlisted and few States have excelled Nebraska in any phase of war work activities. In conclusion I express the conviction that your every act will be inspired by the same lofty and patriotic sentiments that have enabled Nebraska to achieve so wonderful and enviable a war record and that the session will be productive of results which will not only protect the interests and advance the wel - fare of Nebraska's sons in the service, but will also enable those who must remain behind to render more effective support to the cause for which they fight. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>