<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-First Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1918-02-01">1918-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA THIRTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA l'KKNKNTKIl TO IMI CnUKMili I I- It K I AK\ 1, 1 '. &gt; 1 H LINCOLN. NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD HON. 1UANK L HALLER, Omaha Term expires January, IBID HON. VICTOR li. LYl'OKI), l-'alls City Term expires January, lulu HON. KDWAKI) V. IlKOWN, /'resident. Davey, Term expires January, I US I Term expires January, IM1 Term expires January, l!)S:i Term expires January, M3:i HON. JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln.. HON. I'HII.ir L HALL, Lincoln... HON. HARRY I). LANDIS, Seward ft SAMUEL AVERY. I'll. I)., I.I.. I).. Chan W. (i. HASTINGS, A. II.. Acting Chancellor *). S. DALES, M.l'ii.. Financial Secretary Chancellor THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. liURNETT. I). Si., Director C. W. PUGSLEY. II. Sc., Director of Extension Senit \i. V. CKAWKORI). A. It., Hullctin Editor W. W. MARSHALL, Executive CU rk THE WORKING STAFF I'". W. Upson, I'm. I).. Agricultural Chemistry L. W. Chase, M. E.. A. !•'.. Agricultural Engineering j. II. Gain, M. I). C. Animal Pathology M. II. Swk.nk. A.M.. Entomology H. C. Imi.i.kv, A. M., harm Management U. V. Hiiwakii, A. M., Horticulture (i. A. Lovrland, A. M., Meteorology V. E, MissKMi.. U. Si., Poultry Husbandry Jamks Cowan, M. !•'., Superintendent Experimental Station, Valentine t I. W. Calvin, It. Sl, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry tf(i. K. K. Link, I'm. 1)., Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology J. Ralph CooPBR, M. S., Associate in Horticulture H, W. f HURtTON, Jm., B, Sc., Assistant in Plant Pathology and Physiology • My nn ml nf Mir t .rwloinl itrr nf Ilir Slate nf Nrlirn.kn. uprorfd oml In rffrcl I'Vliniiiiy 1', IHVU, Ilir Slntr I'rrnaiirrr In riimr it nfiiin cMKloiliiili ill the K.H|)rrllnrlil Slnllnti Tumi nn ami it ft •• Drlnllril Ifom i Mil, , '.if Iliy l.nipl Airkullurt, Cnllril Si.ii, ■ Dcpnrtmrnt n( ARrlrtillurr, Wn«lntmi ■'". I). •'. tlimnlnl Iruvr nf nlinrmr fur military •urnr rv Mi, i i in i 'I imvr Df iti'»rnt (TIIK KKIJKNTS OF Til K UNIVERSITY W. W. ItcRH. I!. Si ., Agronomy T. A. Kikssklb.m ii, A. M.. Agronomy H. J. (inAMi.it ii. I!. Si'.. Animal Husbandry I. II. Krandhrn, M. S. A.. Dairy llutbandry l.AWKKNt e Kkinkk. I!. Si., Entomology E. Mk.mi Wii.ciix, Ph.D., I'lant I'otholoay and Physiology W. P. Snyhkk, M. S.. Superintendent lixptrimental Station, North Plattc J. A. Hcii.iikn, U. Si.. Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell ••I.. I.. Ziwik, It. S( .. Agronomist, North Platte L &lt; ). Vosk, H. Si., Aitittant in Agricultural Chemulry Kkwin Hiii'T, II. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy W. II. N«vkns, M.S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry H. U. Si'ArniMii, A. M., Assistant in I'ann Matiagtmtnt </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I.K'ITKH CIK THANHMITTAI. TitN tlNtVHNIIITV IIF NHMNAKMA AllNM'UI/IMiMAI. WHhMMIMfN't' HTATIUN tu III* Nifi'vlh'Hi'ii, hiiih Svi'ilh', Q&amp;vnm§r ut NpUiutkni HIM In ai'i'iirilttlii'M Wlllt Him Mil (if I'iiiihium m|i|iihvmiI Mnrt'ti II. IM7, wild Him ncl nl Him HcimtmI AmkiiiIiIv i.r Him HImIm nf Ni'lti'MAkM H|i(M'iiVMij Miiri'li III, INMTi mxImIiIuIiIii(» Mild imiiiiImIHiw t'lin'i I ill mImIIiiiik, I Idivh Him hiiiiui 1 Iimi'mwUI* In ■hiImmII Him Thiiiv liml Aiiinii.l I(m|hiH of ihn Agrli'iilliiutl I'^Iimi IliiMiil Hliillnn nf NmImhmU M. A, MnMNwi'T, hltpvhn I'Vl.riKiiv I, IIHN NTATKiiK NHHHAMHA, Ii'NMI'UTIVM MMI'AHTMMNT I.INi'iil.N, l''Mlil'liwiy I, IIHK Ml', N&lt; A Ililt'HVtt, IHl'PI'ttn' Nilmi«l,u .\unnilhmil h't/ii " mini Slu Hun I NIK I hni'Mliy HcklinwlMiltfc iwmIiiI nl Hn&lt; Tlilrly f1r»l Aiminil lli'iiiirl nf Him A«i Irnllimil I\|mh IiiumiI HUUnn of Nulinuktt Kkiitii Nmvm.i.h. (lui'Ptllllt, lJ0VI4fCNl)ll'H f'tCKTIKirATI'S </seg>
            <seg id="p005">• "Ml Mh 'I'lic IMIIHmI ItimlH nf Mil' NtMlltlH 1,1'iiM mi 'I iiiii.hiiiiiii Ml It II ln|i"illiiWlliil Wlllh til VII Nhw Wh^iIihmiIhI Kmiim» NIihm|i KhmiIihm &gt;in I'lM h'HllllH I'M* 'I'tmtlHM I'iml iif Milk I'imiIhmimh t&gt;'MMM MmMHHMIMXMI NIIMllM Wllllt'l WIlHHl NhIwIImM i« i« I* I* llHl MHlm'llMim I* WhIHI ll*&lt;l|IIIINIMHMl« Mr I'lMM* i 'mil MiiIhIImii mill NliHfHliinHlN M|tiH»lliM MM'li'" * • I'lMHl CiIIimIiici .iMil I 1 inlxft I'mIhIm I||H'«IIhhIIm||» « «l I'iiimM llllMMllMH ♦ i I'Iu'IiiImhI MIihIIxn mm NUhMn IIIHMHItJ OHMltlHMM Ml Null. •'i i inn I'iihIim linn .11 • II «il • 'iinn nl Mt liiiiMiiiii. Iii«mi» I'MMlIU Will It till • III ♦ H Ti'i'llllli'Ml Im»m»II«hIImIi« I H»' NmiIIi I'IhIIi' WillmlMlliiM Kill MM" I'mi|i« ll&gt;'itll» ..i Ml I'MMiji llllHHllMM Ml WlnlMt Him iiimmiI Mmwi i '"ii * ii'iii Ml • VII Till' V .ill-Ill Ilii' MiilmlHlliili Kmimuh Ortfi I'iiIhImm ■mm • hi ♦ &gt;" •«i" • 'in ..in Tim NnMiiililii» Huh. ui inn Hlmn|i KnmiIIhm 'I'll* HUllMII HlMfT llll|IIM«HIMMIlU • It 1 • • • \i'IihmwIi'iImiiii&gt;iiI« ..I iiiiwiiiMi'. &lt; -.- 1 * i n ■■ m t . lilii'flm'd lift If* </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Miinuil Ili'imil ill I hi' \*l IihIIiiihI IHIi'H.Ihii Nt'Mli'i' Itl f IHM PnillM Itllll Vtntnlillili'x OtUltf PhIi MklillilU I'll tlllt'Hi ItMtM Wnih Ml W»lxh«liill H|i. tli*i« in AnHimiIIiiik AlfMMMf .NmHiihI IIii»IimihIi» Hull* IIU»llMlllll&gt; Amll'lllllHHl I'lllMlllt'i'lllld WiiliiiniiliiKy N'llllll MHIIIIHI'IIIIMII Mllll Mill llHIIIM Him lli'iilluin «»« HHHl HNHll • «•&gt; NNHVll mnvll Win h nl |iS«liiimliiii H|ii'i'iiill«l» in lliiniK hii MMMinii ■• I'HIIIllMK llmiMMIRll'NllMM Itllll l'i»lillill« ri'iii'iii'i«' i iiii 1 1 ii i n« Wiiinwn'* hIimii I'liurMM I'IhiImk I'miiI i'miiiiiiiIkihi .11 oil Oil .in .mi Dim • ii. rmiiiU AkiIimiIIiiimI Annul Wiiih I'iiImIiik* IiIVK MIlH'll lM»MM«t' I 'Mill I III llmU'iil Hint Ihimi'l I'mU MmkollHM Ili'lli'lill NiMiilmiu • i. •I.I • I.I • I.I Illllllll IHIflKlllll Will h Hum* lit'iiiinmiuiliiih AMi'iiio KlIIMHI'lMt WUlKlllxlll MlV •«&gt; «»tll &lt;&lt;• </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT I MIIIMII N HI HOIIH Tht« work nf llu&lt; Nnlirimku AtfHnilliintl I'l h |i»&lt;»-i rtt«»n I MU llnti for Him I'lirri'iil yi'iir him lii'nii im CitlhiWNI Tin' riinilH itf Him HUlliili HI'm iiIiIhIiimiI fl'nill Hi rim miiiiitum. imnii-lN Tin' 1 1 til rli unit Ailmim h|i|ii'ii|ii'ImIIiiiim mw i'mi'mIvuiI I Mini Hill I'l'lli'llll (IllVUI'llltlunt III IIIIHIIIIllM mIuIWII ll,V I Id' Hiiiiiii'iiil Hiiii.'iiM'iii of tliU lli'iiuii In Hililllliui, I'Mi'UIn IiiimIm n|i|irii|Mliiti'il Im khmi'I'iiI l'nlvi&lt;i'Mlty nmlnli'iniiii'ii urn MUt imllli' liv HlU lli'H''Hl" I'M iiiMM illlilliil l|li|llll'lltll'lltH Mttll IINKll rill' HHIIltl'lllll'lllllI Will It Tin' IiihI 1,1'uImIiiIiii'h iiiiiiIm iiii ii|i|ii'ii|H'ImUiMI (if I'jn.DIMI fill 1 • i|n.i inn ni mI work fur tlu&gt; IiImiiiiIiiiii ImihIihiIiiii AihII I, IHI7 Tlii'v nUi ii|iiini|irlnl«i| 1111,11011 Im liiVMMtl||MlliiH III Aiilinnl I'ltihiiliiKVi (llO.ilOII In llin Hliiln KliliminliilllM, wlm In Hi.' KiilimtnliiKlnl nf Him Kh|imiIimmiiI Hliillnn, mill |lt,lHMl In Him Mlnl'i IIiiIiiiiImI, wlm l« tlli&lt; HnliiliUI nf Him I&lt;1n|imiIiiiimiI HI Ml l.lll, ||| I Illll k" "I' Wlll'k III I'llllll I'llllinlnt/S MM ni'HllMIShl MMMM Tin' ImmI I.KtflnltillirM liiMiln Mil n|i|ii iiin lill lull nf fllU,IMMI fill' (Hi Mlfl'iHIitltiy fitrin, whli h Iiii* mIiii'm Iimhii | IuikmiI, It 1'IHImInIm nf Hill hi ■rim nf lilliil Ivlnil (HIM Mlllt nlin Imlr Ilillux mi I mill nil" lull" imi Hi nf Him |H'imhmI fiirni ntin|Mi«, iIudi 1 1 1 mil n« I lin »niilliWM«l iiiimi'Imi 1 nf hmi'IIiiii iiiiiiiIiui' III, In lnwin»lil|i iiiiinliMi' III, nf I'HlitfM iiiiiiilinr 7 nii»l nf Him (till |irlnil|ml nii'iiilliiii, III l,mini«lnr I'niinlv, Ni'lnii &lt;Um, Tmii IIiiiihmiiiI iliilliil« WMN hImm n|i|irn|il'UtlMl| fill' n lli'lll nimiiiiiinii 1 1 nil I n i in, In lin I... ..I. ill in Him I i nil Imlt iff Ni'linmloi I'lliilily NI'I'mn nf Imnl him Iimmii imnhimMil fnc lhl« |iiii|mi«i', iImmi'I'IIiimI im Him w.'^I Inilf nf Him «nnl|lWi'M i| I. i nf NMi'lInn mnnlim lilt, In IiiwiimIiI|i iiinnli"i III, nf ihiim" mini Iimi lit, Mi'i'ni'illinr In Him I&gt;iiIImi| HImI«". llnvni'nniMiil Hnrvi'V, I iImiI In I'wm I'liiinly, Nnlnimkii Tin* Mini" iniiltMM illrui I ii|ilirn|iilMl|n|iM itUn fur Him IiihIii liiimiii' nf HilliNltillniiH ttl Niii'lh I'ImIIm, VmImiiIIih' mimI Mlhlii'll, Nulilimkli, Mini fnc Him Ayili hIIiiimI I'lulmmlnn HmivIcm mI Him I'mIImiim nf Am i. iilinif mnl Im Him N.'ImmU Milinnl nf Alll'li'llllllI'M Ml ('lll'IU, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Atii'h'uthn'ul N*iit&lt;iii»t&lt;nt Htuliutt iif NpIiiiwIhi 8 I'Imii* nf wink ttiti iii'm|ihi'mi) liy MHi'h ilMpMitniMiil nl llm lit'giiining nf Him I'Mlunimr yuwr, •wvuring Him Ilium nf Iiivmm - llgtttiun |iiii|mibhiI Cur Hiii nil runt viuir, mi Ilitil Him work of Ilin HliilHMl IllHV plugrum* »y*tMiuullriOly, ill urruntum-ii with ii|i|iriiviu| iiIiiiim. Tin- in tfi'iil ntuMMMlly fur I'lili'iinu inln imw him* nf Iiivmh liiriilliin whh riiMiiuiiMilili' I'm' ihn iiiiniiitmi nf Hu&lt; nuw uurniimny l.irm mill li ult Chi'iii Hint fill' Urn iippnipl'llttlnn nf $'Jn,O(ID fur Him iiiaiiili'iiuiM in nf MKptu'lliiMuUl Mini (tMinniiMli'Mtliill work during i lu&lt; lilunniiiin. Nhn ii t'wilinii, KK|iurliiiMiitH In fuMilIng Uinlm upon ilu irinii iHlluim Iimvm liuuti rtii'i'lml on fur ft numliMC nf M-.ii - Twn hiiinlri'il mill ttlghty Imnlm wurn pun luui'il tmi'ly III Hi'p li'inlinr, 11117, Mini wi'ii- fmi fur Hi! iliiyn upmi mmvdi'mI iIiMimimiI niliiiim, huii' nf thumi luU wurn run In inniiii.hu, with ii I In I fit lmy or ii pniti'ln MiipplKiiiKiil Ilkn nil mxiil nr ml I mi ««iM&lt;il iiikmI In iiilillllmi, OHimi' lutM wurn fwl on MllNgf with illlti'i't'iil ui m in rutlmm (hu&lt; lot whm run nil tfi'HHN pnnturt', with n light gt'Hln mi imi ilui iiiK iiu- inii.'i pin i nf Hid ptu'luii, Tin' liiiiilm wlileli wi'ii' pimliirwl In tin- nu iill.'hl with (&lt;ot&gt; immi'i'il nii'til ur nil iiu'hI muiiIk tliM hltflt^Mt flnUh Ml uppriix* lniMlnly Him Inwunt nmt ut gMlllM, Tlin lot run upmi gl'MNM pudtuii' with h light grnln rut inn IuwmciI th« i'IhI ur tht&gt; pi'iiuii ituiili' the i hi'iipt'oi u» i n Imi wi'i'i' nut mi wt*ll flnUhwi ill Hit' miiiI of Him MHpMrlniMiil it« Him i'urnf)i&lt;lil Imnlm, I'm Fnilinii, KmvumiI IuIm nl' hng» Ihivk Imu-u inl upon illlfMi'Miii rMlluiiH iJurlnu Him IhmI yuMi 1 , nil of the experlmentM ii'iuliiiu to nhow tliu MHvIng of liiimr Mini Him rMlMtivo ncunniny Of gMlllH wIlMI'M w&lt;lf-f|i.i(|iM'» WMI'M IIbimI III fMttKlling hutfM fill' Hi' 1 ninrluM (lorn mul imilwitfM with wlfttlfM hMy prnvnd to lit* m lU'Hi'tit'Hl iiimHiikI of fttllunlng hogH on u Imi'um i'oiiiiiimi 1  - cImI wmIm. On iiiTiuinl nt Him MCHrclty of pork mul purk liruiluctH, IMXI hngM wi'i'M purt'linmul In NiivmiiiIimi', lit 17, Mini lliMHti Hru in'inuf fi'il nut upon m muuliMi' of Nimiiiui'il ntliniix 'I'Imw rnpi-1 liiii'iiU MI'M lint yt'l rnliiplnti', lull Him luillrittliUlM MI'M iiiiii m pnu'iii'iilly full riitlon of *• ft corn with tMnkMge f«d In Mnlf-fi'tuli'iM will priivi' mm Mi'i'Mptuliln mm Hiiy mfthodM or I'MllolIM UHttd. In thtfMf I'Hpt'rlllll'lllo, HM III pt'KVlnllH tfMtH, ('Oil* (li'iim-d luittiTiiiilk ti'il with corn ithvm ruplil kiiIiim, but nl n I'Mlhttr hlghur comI thnn whoro tMtikugM wmh UMtid to furnlNh the protuln nupplumunt, </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thi it v (it'll Alumni Hi i»ni 9 t'nw Ttwtityi Antmviiiliniin. Ihiiiny Him v»mr, Him ('nw 'IWing AmiihUUimim Iimvm Iimmii iihtuhmmiI from dun lit flvM, ttlHl Hill llltl'liml III lllU Wlll'k IlUN IIIMlMI'lHlly iMHI'UHNMd' Tilt) moult ii! Him ('nw Tn«tlll|f A««nclullnilM hti« Ilium In frlvM Him fitiniiir mi ttnuraUi |&lt;|"» nf Him vkIiim «*r m»mIi now winy iimii'ii, miulilliitf him to ili«|nmn (if mull cow* mm hcm illi|Hii||lillilr Kllll llli'li'llV to InHI'UMMM lllU HVUI'HtfM |l|'llhl iff Him hind, i'ti*t ill Milk 1'itnhivlltiH. Within Him piutl vmmi 1 , MMtl'il tlvti mi niii)ii'iiii'iili&lt; Iihvm Ihuiii nnli'inil lulu wllh thti I ' i ■ 1 1 • •* I Hiiilt'H |)i&lt;|i(ii'lMii&lt;nl of Airiii'iillui'ti wiuMtiliy h iiuhl Mtfoiil l» hIhIIiiiiimI mi I'tkiilllUin, Nnlii'iiMku, In wn'iirn iicciirNU* milit mi Hi'' iiimI iiC lit 1 1m ihiiiIih linn 'I'ln'oc ilnlu whnii MfUMd will fimiUh it IihmIm fur ilntcimlnlni Hie vmt ■! which milk uml milk product m cxii lie iirniliH'i'il mill Mold to lit** IcmiIm, itml will tiUn iiiiliiMli' whNt cIhm ni' i'iiwm mihI wimt t &gt; i •• &gt; of fin m i I In' Mil' milMl lirnOlillili' l''iirin Miiiiniii mi ill SlntlirM, Kmimi Mwiiiiki'Iiii'IiI nIiiiIIkh ItMVM Ili'i'll MihlltllH'il Mm I li ( / Him HIITl'Ill S 'I'll I, MlnllU I hi' illlMH iinlii Mii'd In tin' Im»i Anmml Ui'imii In addiiinii, mm lnvnwii itMlluii I nt ■. liiM'ii inuili' Inln Him ciimI «»f Mollltltf fl'itltl Hu' ittr dnnr I"' Hu' rniminiiKi 1 , m» l'i'|iiil'ti'd III ( 'Iri'lllrtl' Nn, A, Mludli'd nf Him imi'IIiimIb nf itci'iiiinlliiir hiiIImIiIm fnt 1 Him ivor&gt; ittfi' fKi'iiHM 1 Iimvh hImh mm iiihIi'I'ImIu'ii miuI m lioiikk(u&gt;iniur form ili'Si'liijind which nmy lt« u»od for llil* iiiii'imimm, HihIi form li«x lii'i'ii In unmi (tftimnd liy fwi'inni'x who wihIi In iImImc mint* Hi« ini'llind by which Uhcm nn fnt'in Iiiiiiiiium ni'm Dkiii'i'iI. Winlti Whetit NrlvvUuH, About 11,000 mmImcUoiim of com moii Turkey Id-d whtmt Irnvt* lim«ti mimiIm mi Hi" Ni«lir««k« Hin lion, Htld oi'vi'ImI luinilii'il of IIm'mi' i|i'U'ln|ii&lt;i| to a MUifM when i In- 1 1 Mi'ld miuI i|iiiiliiv could lit' ili'li'i'inliinil, TIii'mm or four of Ilinwn |iI'oiiiIm&lt;&lt; to hi' of h lull Mcniiomlc VMlUK, (hi Si'h'i'llitttn, Vtirli'lv tuMtM of ohIn, covt&lt;i'lnir fiflcnn ytmi'K, Hhow Hint curly variulluH Hl'« l»wtU*r ttdwplcd mid ylnlil iiini'i' In IhU Mlnli' IIimii liilc VHI'IftlMH, 'I'll Im hhcomh ylnld, cov (M'lntf h 12-yMHf iini'loti, miiiimImiI mi hvmchjtm of 11,1 lnintn&lt;U pur mtu ovnr Him InIm viu'IhIIi'm with which lluvv witi- cmn imrwi, A whltM KhiM-Hon mil, known hm N«tlir»&lt;tk»» No, 'il, \H* lii'i'li (|i'Vi'l(ip«d mill di"l i llmli'il to u llnilli'd i-hIi-iiI A four-ycMi' uvMi'Hirit rank of the Marly naU iimmiI In HiIm (•xput'lmmU In: Hurl, ill, ft; Toxhm Hod, H'J.fti N«&lt;hruMkn No, 'Jl (while KhMfMon), (III); orltfliml Kherwm, A4.I. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Atlt'h'tiH mill h\t'iinhnt&lt;nt Shillmi uf Nrlmi*ktt 10 liiilli'lln No, UK), OmIm IttVMMtlifMtliitiM, tf!vt&lt;M it i|i&lt;iuili&lt;il t ••|mii I n| Him win Ii III nil! UlM'.llltMlliUi With i Hrifiiln mi iiht uf {'vufm, Kx|im|'IiiimiiI« mi llu&lt; WHter i ct|it I ft in&gt; nl . id i iii|m linvi' Iimmii iniilliiiiKil I lllltllll'Mll mill fifty |mliiiin'li'i'u Iimvm Iimmii iikimI mill I hi' win k ill' inmimi i l'*|H'l'lll|H|ll* llMN llMMll flll'llll'l rillllllllinil Ci'iif) UnluUini mill h'i'itllUi'i' H^fwihiivnlit, Twn IiiiiiiIi'imI mill Iwi'iiU linn iiIhIm )mv« bffti mil mmIiIm *Of lt'ftllll|f VMl'Iniln niliilliiiiK mill fiM'llllMMt'N In ilii|ii|'inllit&lt; wlntl NtMiUMM nf irojM Will HlVi' Ilii' Im-«I NVlM'MlfM Vli'liU Mill) wlml Ini'llllHtil'M, If tlliy, him linrnMHI'y 111 umIi'i to iimilmr inimliiuiin ihmIIIx limn Miilniiin liiini m.i|i» Sininiiiui */(/&lt;/(*. Tin* I'lMipii iiIImi work In hI inly of "inilUlll* M|l|llt&lt; Mil llMllU I lll'HII I'lllllllllll'll Mllll UlK I'MNIIHm llf IH'MVlllllN VMHI'N llMVK llMI'll t'lltlfll'IIIMll, »||IIW|||(| Illlll till |MM'MIM1 wlin wImIimn In MImUm Mining (Mil nf ii|i|ili' mi hniiU inn mIIumI In im'kIim'I •iniivliix ihmiiiIIiij/ In Ilin IimhI hiiuwn nii'llimli, I'lnitl I'nlhiiliiitii innl I'liii'iniliiini Kill' lnvi'»ill(»Mllnii&gt;i III lilmil |tliVMlnln|ty, it cukhmi'i Ii iMliniitlniy U lit prtmM nC I **• I »t w (M|lll|l|MMI Wllll H|IMI'lMl IIMMII'MIII*, Mill 1 |lll ( V»llllllMli III |ll'll|lM'l I net' ill |irnMii|il litiii'llvi', il iit&lt; In Him ImmiIIHI'MI'V wIIIhIimwhI nf pi 1 , A. It, I'mvU In miiImc Aiiiiv iwryMi Mini nf Mr, (I, K, l&lt; I, Hilt In nmliMlnlti' ln«|ii'i I hm wiil'h fill' Him I 1 H, Mk|iniIiiimiiI llf Atnli iiHiim' Wllll Him . iiiii|iIi&lt;I hill ul I It.- Inlmi hIum , II I- ItlniniMil Ik hImiI ml hi' win It ii|inii Him •Hum" lirn|Mil itml Him hmvmimI liliyNlnlntflcNl ih'iiIim'Ih mmih'ImImiI with niir kmiimimI Hlllllli'M llf Him pnliilii |ll'nlilMin Hi NkIm-hmUm I'ImIIiiiIiimi v ■ IihIImm tin v*' mIh i w ii Him) II In |mimIIi|m In tfl'nw cni'll pliiiiU In imiiiIiIi'IiiMm m|m» uiiiImi m|m|||m i uinlllluii* TIim iinm nf IliU llU'llllliljlM Will iiihI&lt;m iiiinnIIiIm Mil M«tinl iImImiiiiIiiiiIIihi hI Him innl, Ir urn , 1*1(1 &gt; I'll !*%• lllll'I'mil'ifHIllNltlN III »IImk»' fniiinillnii TIlM IIIVmrI Illlll Inn* III jilitlll IIMlllllllltfy llMVM ImI'H.V I It iniihinul In Hid •mvmkiI i mIiiiIIm iii'iiIki'Ih, Hm miiiiii wnl'h Into Iimmii ilmiM nil Him Nulniitlni I'lmil IiUmiixm Miiivmv Mill) hi'Vi'I'mI inlimi iIUmmkm |iimIiIi'|iim |'!^Im|i«Ivm •lni|li'« nf Him m|i|mm IiIImImi 1 mhiIm'I 1 |imvi' imi'iillv Imumi |iiiIiI|m|imiI TIm Iimvm ImIiI Him IhiiihImIIhii Cm 1 ii niniM mlluiiiil ini'l Innl iif iii'iii'Miliii'M In I In' i mil ml nf Hill, lijf fin mil' iimi.iI *hi Iiiiim m|iii|m i||«mii*m MIiiiIIm i III imhUImiiim nf tm Inn, i vmiImIImm In Ililn iIUmmdm m« Wi'll H« llfi&lt; hltlniV Mllll |i|lV«liil'iKliiil mIiiiIIim nf Him |imIIiiiM"M mI'm linw ill jHNWMMi IIhIIimi hhImmmIvm IImIiI nNjii'ilmi'iiU wn|'n ininlin led Hi Him miilinl iif Putin linn will nf Him Him ri'innvul n( Him </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THIi'fH'fti'iit Annual Ht&gt;\mrl 11 111 d'H ml viinniliti M'«i(iii ni'tir Him Mtmti Mini i 'Him i'mniiIU •i|i|'"iti to I ml I* tt t •• Hull wIiki'k I (in imlluiKi'li I* widely ilUlrlli itii'ii In Him will I««»m fiivtn'ttliln i'»«milu from thin muttind (if ronlrol will In' wMi'iit'Mil Hum In mill In which fumiiium will iiIkiiU Imvn not w|i|it&lt;rtim|, It In cmi'ImIk tlmt PumiHinn in I'l'l it'll tllllKl'M mIiOIIIiI tlOt llM MIII|llllV"ll fill' ».'l'l| |IMI'|MINM, Tll»' I'ii'mIi'kI Ihi|iii of MMMMNM n|i|u&lt;ni'« to IIm uliiliu Hih linn of nmImm! lltK dlNUNMM'KNlNUnl Htl'NlMM llf |II|ImIhMM, 'I'li'iiiini'iii foe ltd imIiiiiIkm iii Din niiliiiHi'v fiii'iimlilt'liyili' Miihilioii wim fouiiil to Mtitlrnlv t'llinlimU' inlllnl mtint, In tnn iliHik or iiiilii'MltuI phil, ltd |ini I'i'iil of Him Iimn4m wmcm ilimlinyi'il t iv miimiI I'nhiiii Im i »iiiiiiiin)i» IiivmmI Imm( Iimim to ilninrmlni* Him riMi|iiMiii'y with whli'h low vit'lilinir mIi'mIiin ori'iir within vhHm IImm mi til In ilHi'i mini' I In 1 |iiiMllilirili&lt;M foi 1 ImoImIImk itltfll vd'lil Hilt ulniln* wen' nlMili'il In ii imiiiiIh'i or IiImi'hh In wkhImiii Ni'licnohii In Him N|il'lli|( of MM 7 TIimnm IiivmmI IgNtloiin MI'M IimIiim ihiiIimI on In i'oii|iiiiMllon wllh iiotnto growm-M mI Ihn followlllll IioIiiImi UhiiIhii, AIIImIM'm, KIimIihII, iiimI MIiimImm' At I'MI ll Of HlMMM IIOlltlM MMVMCllI IiIIHiIiimI IlllllVllliml IllllMI'M WMI'M |ilnilli'il m'|iiiliih'ly, In Mil I'Wmmm Him IhIiMI'M WHri flli Into four pull*, initklnM four IiIIIm for imiiIi Iiiiimi 'I'Iimmm wmI'm Iimi'VmmImiI mm|imI'iiImIv, wMlifliKil Mini imi'O|«|m nimli' At •nun' iioIiiIm, I'lmlv Ohio unit Trliini|in vmcImUmm wmih ImiIIi HMMll III nllli'l lO f'OinllMI'M Illi'll Mi|il|lllli|lllv Hmmi! HlllWII iniili'i iliv IiiihI iiiiiillllnim wit* miiii|imii'i| wllh MMMfi (frown Minlt-1 ImImhIi'iI iiiinlllloiiN, liolh on InlMiili'il Mini ihv ImihI Till' |II|I'|MIMM of III l» WOI'H lit 10 IMoImIm Illtfll VIkIiIIIIM Ml I Hill" of jioliifoMM, iImIi'I'IIIHim Him |ll'ii|n'l ioi'IIiiiiIm of mmmiI mkIiu IIhii mill Him iiiIm|iImIiIIHv "I' illlfMi'Mli) vmHmIImm IMltW lllffUfWll iiiiiiiiiionM mill fin id. 'i lo iImIkmoiiim In hioiimimIIoii wllh m lulu HiiiiHimiii Hhtli'M Him vmIim' of wmmImiii NhIii«»mh |ioInIomn for HoiiIIimi'ii nmi'iI I'timn Inliiiillnti: TIlM I i«&lt;|f ImIhI )M »&lt; of I II In iioiiIm mo iiii|iI'o|ii'ImIIoii io i •iM'iiiniM" Him i|mvm|o|ioimiiI of |i|Hii|t M'l'ltfN lion In wmmImi'D NmIh'mhN/ I'ihImi HiIm »i|i|ii»i|iiIhIIhii, h |miio|i II'I'IhmIIoii jilmil wmm mmImIiIIhIimi! on Him mhomiiiiimiiImI fmiii nl Noclli I'ImIIm, NmIicmmMi hiiiI h nkI'Im of AmMd wmch ImIiI oi|l Wltll M VJKW llf Wllli'llllH hIioIII HI MI'I'MM Of lilllll fulfil Hilt liiiiiiii TIim iiml at Mi'"wlntf miiih iiiiiImi' |nini|i iHlUHlion Wl I Iim hImiIImiI, TIim MimI well |inl down fill) liol flil'lllHll H Miif Hi li'iil Nll|l|ilf of wiilm, no Hull ii mmioimI |iolnl IihiI lo Iim mmmh II |M IimIImVMII Illlll Mllllll Ii III Willl'l |m IIUW MUllllOllli lO OlMMl III!' imi|iiii'mmimiiU of mI ImmmI 411 wm iif ImihI </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Auricultural Experiment Station of Nebraaka Chemical Studitm on Silage.— The problem of how to make alfalfa silage hat* been studied in detail. Results indicate that alfalfa can be ensiled perfectly when mixed with other green crops, such as kaflr com or green rye. Organic Constituent* of Soil*. — Work on the effect of cer - tain toxic organic compounds on the growth of plants in the ■oil is nearly completed. Results have been obtained which tend to greatly minimize the importance of the soil toxin theory. Serum Production. — The last Legislature provided for the closing of the Serum Plant at the University Farm, and made an appropriation to develop investigation of animal diseases. Under this act, the Regents have secured Dr. L. Van Es, Dean of the Veterinary School of the North Dakota Agri - cultural College, as head of the Department of Animal Pa - thology and Hygiene. Doctor Van Es will take up his work at the Station July 1, 1918. Plans are being prepared for an animal disease labora - tory which will make possible a high type of investigation. It is hoped that this building will be completed during the year 1918. Temporary laboratories will be organized as needed before the new building is completed. Control of Injurious Insects. — During the year, experimen - tal work on the control of seriously injurious insects has been carried "on as in previous years, but more extensively than before, owing to the increased financial support for this work made by the Legislature of 1917. The ravages of wireworms in the newly planted cornfields of several counties of south - eastern Nebraska during May were investigated, and the studies then begun are yet being continued. The several injurious species concerned have been identified and much of their life-history has been worked out, so that an under - standing of the proper measures of controlling these pests is rapidly being reached. Later in the year, during July and August, attention was chiefly directed toward the control of injurious native grass - hoppers in several counties of western Nebraska. The most important result of these studies was the discovery that alfalfa meal is a satisfactory substitute for bran or middlings used as a base for poisoned grasshopper baits, and the working out of a formula which saves the wheat products and reduces the cost of the poisoned bait by fully one-half. A hopper- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirty-tint Annual Hf-ixni 13 dozer was also devised which cohU considerably less than the usual type and is equally efficient. The affliction of the red-tailed bot-fly which has appeared among the horses in western Nebraska during the past few years was investigated in a preliminary way, and further studies of this pest are now being carried on. Other work was done on the control of several minor field crop and gar - den pests. An entomological survey of the winter wheat crop of 1917-18 was begun on November 1st and is now nearly completed. It shows this crop to be remarkably free from the Hessian fly and other serious wheat pests. On the several definite projects in entomology, the largest amount of work has been done on the study of the life-his - tory of several common cutworms, as a basis for control measures against these pests. As usual, the nurseries of Nebraska have all been inspected during the year, as required by the State law, and all shipments of foreign nursery and greenhouse stock have also been inspected in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Plant Quarantine Act. Poultry Work. — The poultry plant established in 1915 has been developed, and lines of investigation are in progress. Much of the time of the poultry man is spent in giving assist - ance to the poultry interests of the State. TKCHMCAI, lNVKSTHiATIONS The following lines of technical investigation are in prog - ress at the Station. Some of these lines have been carried for a number of years. Adams Projects: No. 2, A Study of the Stem End Rot of the Irish Potato Tuber. No. 3, A Study of Leaf Curl, Leaf Roll, and Rosette and Related Diseases of the Potato Plant. No. 4, A Study of the Life History and Parasitism of Rhizoctonia as Related to Irish Potato Diseases. No. 5, The Study of Nummularia Discreta as the Cause of the Blister Canker of Apple. — Its Prevention and Control. No. 6, The Study of the Anatomy of the Potato Plant. No. 7, The Water Soluble Constituents of the Soils of the Transition Region. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 14 No. 8, A Study of the Chemical Factors Concerned in the Formation of Pigments in Certain Varieties of Corn. No. 9, A Study of the Formation and Persistence of Prussic Acid in Kafirs and Sweet Sorghums. No. 10, Methods of Determining Humus. No. 11, Corn Breeding Experiments. No. 12, Water Requirements of Crops. No. 13, Competition in Cereals. No. 14, Alfalfa Pollination by Insects. No. 15, Food Requirements of Growing Cattle. No. 16, Winterkilling Investigations. No. 17, Heredity Investigation. No. 62, Chemical Studies on Silage. No. 67, The Life-History of Wheat-Infesting Sawflies. No. 69, The Life-History of Several Common Cutworms. No. 72, Physiological Studies in the Formation of Silage. Hatch and State Projects: No. 18, Determination of Experimental Error. No. 19, Variety Testing, Breeding, Acclimatization, and Cultural Studies with Small Grains. No. 20, Classification of Oats Varieties. No. 21, Soy Bean Tests. No. 22, Crop Rotation and Fertilizer Experiments. No. 23, Cooperative Fertilizer Tests. No. 24, Soil Moisture Investigations. No. 25, Rodent Investigations. No. 26, Investigation and Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. No. 27, Treatment of Illinois or Blister Canker of Apple Trees. No. 28, Spraying Apples, Pears, Grapes, and Bush Fruits. No. 29, Pruning Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits. No. 30, Principles of Orchard Culture. No. 31, Hill Selection of Potatoes. No. 32, Home Production of Seed Tubers. No. 33, Fruit Breeding. No. 34, Corn Silage vs. Alfalfa Hay as Feeds for Milk Production. No. 35, Com Silage vs. Alfalfa Silage as Feeds for Milk Production. No. 36, A Study of the Soiling System under Nebraska Conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Thirty-first Annual Report 15 No. No. 37 A Cooperative Study of Dairying under Condi - tions of Western Nebraska. 38 A Study of the Underlying Factors Necessary for the Operation of a Successful Cooperative Creamery. No. 39 Factors Affecting the Efficiency of Hand Separa - tors and Causes of Variation in Cream Tests. Forage Crops for Hogs. No No. No No No No No No No 10 11 Fattening Cattle. Farm Survey. Farm Survey. Handling Silage. 12 13 11 15 Hog House Investigations. Draft of Wagons. 46, 17 Pump Irrigation. IS Nursery and Orchard and Nursery and Green - house Stock Inspection, under State Law. No. No No Serum Production. 49 63 The Organic Constituents of Soils. til Sweet Clover Hay vs. Alfalfa Hay as Feeds for Milk Production. No. No 65 Rations for Fattening Lambs. 66 A Study of the Efficiency of Various Types of Cream Cooling Tanks. No 68 The Relation of the Colloidal Properties of Glu - ten to Problems of Milling and Baking. No No No, No. No No 70 Plant Breeding. Lamb Feeding. 71 7:'. Farm Survey Based on Agricultural Census. Direct Marketing in Car Lots. 71 To Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1917 76 To Improve Dairy Cows by Grading up With Pure Bred Sires. No 77 Grasses and Grass Mixtures for Pasture Pur poses. No, No, No No 78 79 SO SI Rations for Fattening Sheep Rations for Fattening Hogs. Potato Selection for Seed Purposes. Tuber Line Selection of Potatoes for Increased Yields. No No S2 83 A Study of the Inheritance of Egg Production. The Essentials in a Ration for Baby Chicks. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 16 XOKTH I'LATTK Sl'KSTATION The North Platte Substation began its operations in 1904. Since that date the Substation has built up and equipped an efficient and substantial plant for carrying on experiments in methods of tillage, varieties of crops, and general farm practice adapted to central Nebraska. In the dates-of-seeding tests of spring grains, the early seedings proved more productive than later seedings. This applied to oats, wheat, and barley ,and confirmed the results of previous experiments. Forage Crops. — Several varieties of forage sorghum were sown both in drills and in cultivated plats. The best yields were secured from cultivated rows. Beans. — A comparative test of Navy and Pinto beans on table-land resulted in a yield of 6.3 bushels per acre of Pintos and a total failure of Navy beans. Pump Irrigation. — Altho the work of pump irrigation was unsatisfactory on account of inability to get the plant operated early enough in the season and many troubles incident to getting a new line of work under way, yet the results are quite encouraging. In a comparison of irrigated with unirrigated corn for silage, the nonirrigated corn produced 5 tons per acre, and the irrigated corn yielded 10 i/o tons per acre. The yield of grain was about 5 bushels per acre on the dry land and 50 bushels per acre on the irrigated land. A comparison of irrigation versus no irrigation for pota - toes where two irrigations were used gave a yield of 65.4 bushels per acre on dry land and 195 bushels per acre on irrigated land. Under irrigation, two acres of sugar beets yielded at the rate of 14.8 tons per acre ; mangel beets yielded at the rate of 26 tons per acre. In the garden tract, the following yields were secured from one-eighth acre plats: Potatoes, 250 bushels per acre; sugar beets, 21.9 tons per acre; Pinto beans, 24 bushels per acre; onions, 500 bushels per acre. WINTERING BROOD SOWS A ration of 3 parts finely cut alfalfa with 1 part ground corn, by weight, mixed and fed thru a self-feeder, has proved </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Thirty-first Annual Report 17 a quite satisfactory feed for mature brood sows during the winter. The use of self-waterers is also being tested. This has resulted, up to the present time, more in a saving of labor than in actual increase in pork produced. Dairy Herd. — A very creditable dairy herd is being developed. An experiment was conducted to determine the result of substituting finely cut alfalfa hay for bran in tht! usual dairy grain ration of 1 part oilmeal, 2 parts bran, and 4 parts com. There was no indication that bran was superior to alfalfa when fed under these conditions. THK VALKXTIXK Sl/HSTATIOX The leading lines of work conducted at the Valentine Sub - station are as follows: Forage Crops. — Corn, sorghums, Sudan grass, and alfalfa have been grown as forage crops at the Valentine Substation. Among these, corn has probably been most successful, and is depended upon almost altogether as a crop to be used for silage. Experiments with sweet clover and alfalfa showed that sweet clover is unlikely to suffer from too early seeding. The seedings completed before frost was out of the ground were entirely successful. The first seeding of sweet clover was done on April 7. Alfalfa seeded at this date was a failure, and no successful seeding of alfalfa was accomplished before May 10th, after the severe frosts were over. Successful seed - ings of alfalfa were made on light, sandy soil until the second week in June. No seeding of sweet clover was successful after the third week in April. Our experience indicated that early seeding of sweet clover is desirable but that alfalfa in this region should not be sown until the danger of frost is over, and in general should not be sown unless there is moisture in the ground sufficient for germination. Potatoes. — On unmulched, heavy soil, potatoes grown from seed raised under mulch showed an increase of 20 per cent over those from seed grown by ordinary methods. Beans. — Several varieties of beans were grown. Most of these were a failure on account of drouth. The Pinto bean seemed to stand the drouth better than other varieties. No other variety matured sufficiently to be harvested. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 18 THK SCOTTSBM hV SI IISTAT1OX The work of the Scottsbluff Experimental Substation car - ried on in cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture has continued along the same lines as formerly. Irrigation rotation work and dry land rotation and till - age work have been continued. Ail irrigated crops have been abundant this year. Alfalfa pasture with a supplementary corn ration has proved extremely profitable in growing hogs for market. Where hogs were fed 8,609 pounds of com, they produced 3,142 pounds of pork from one acre of alfalfa pasture and the supplementary grain ration. Hogging down com is practical and profitable. Alfalfa pasture in connection with com increases the gain. Larger gains were also made where tankage was fed as a supple - mentary ration. Sheep Feeding. — Ten lots of sheep are being fed at the Station, on different rations, to determine the value of by - products of the beet sugar factory when such products are fed with alfalfa hay. STATION STAKK Within the past year the following changes in the Station staff have taken place: Mr. J. A. Ratcliff, Assistant in Agronomy, resigned April 1, 1917, to take up farming. Mr. J. W. Calvin, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry, was granted leave of absence to enter the army, effective September 1, 1917. Mr. F. M. Colcord, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry, resigned September 1, 1917, to enter the Extension Service. Mr. L. B. Sturdevant, Assistant in Animal Pathology, resigned to enter the army, effective September 1, 1917. Mr. E. G. Woodward, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry, resigned September 1, 1917, to accept a position as Professor of Dairy Husbandry in the University of Nevada, Reno, Nevada. Mr. M. E. Dickson, Assistant Professor of Poultry Hus - bandry, resigned October 1, 1917, to engage in business. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Thirty-first Annual Report 19 Mr. Floyd Wambeam, Agricultural Editor, resigned Octo - ber 6, 1917, to enter the army. Mr. G. K. K. Link, Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology, was granted a leave of absence from November 1, 1917, to July 1, 1918, to assist the Bureau of Plant Industry of the United States Department of Agriculture in inspection work in plant diseases. Mr. H. G. Gould, Assistant in Agronomy, resigned Decem - ber 1. 1917, to enter the Extension Service. Mr. R. R. Spafford was appointed Assistant in Farm Man - agement, effective July, 1917. Mr. L. 0. Vose was appointed Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry, effective July 1, 1917. Mr. W. B. Nevens was appointed Assistant in Dairy Hus - bandry, effective September 1, 1917. Mr. R. P. Crawford was appointed Agricultural Editor, effective October 15, 1917. Mr. F. E. Mussehl was appointed Professor of Poultry Husbandry, effective October 20, 1917. Mr. H. W. Thurston, Jr., was appointed Assistant in Plant Physiology, effective November 1, 1917. Dr. L. Van Es was appointed head of the Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene, effective July 1, 1918. IMI'KOVKMEXTS Work on Agricultural Engineering Hall began in June, 1917, and it is hoped the building will be ready for use by September, 1918. This building is 180 feet long by 76 feet wide, two stories with basement, and contains a one-story annex 84 by 140 feet, for shops and laboratories. Plans are being drawn for a new veterinary building which will house the Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene. This building will cost from $60,000 to $100,000 and will fur - nish modern facilities for work in animal disease investi - gation. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 20 At the North Platte Station, the following improvements have been made: $3,860.00 At the North Platte Station, plans for a new horse barn have been drawn, at an estimated cost of $10,000. This ba'-n will be 100 feet long by 38 feet wide, with annexes for box stalls. The barn will be built of concrete, with grain and hay storage above. PlIHilCATIO-NS The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Thirtieth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor February 1, 1917. 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 160 (Volume XXIX, Article IV). Oats Inves - tigations. By T. A. Kiesselbach and J. A. Ratcliff. Accepted for publication March, 1917. Distributed November 15, 1917. 17,000 copies. Bulletin No. 161 (Volume XXX, Article I) (Popular Edi - tion of Research Bulletin No. 12). Methods of Controlling Blister Canker. By J. Ralph Cooper. Distributed December 15, 1917. 12,000 copies. Bulletin No. 162 (Volume XXX, Article II) (North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 18). Wintering Mature Brood Sows. By W. P. Snyder. Research Bulletin No. 11. Relation of Size of Seed and Sprout Value to the Yield of Small Grain Crops. By T. A. Kiesselbach and C. A. Helm. Accepted for publication April, 1917. Distributed December 1, 1917. 5,000 copies. Research Bulletin No. 12. Studies in the Etiology and Control of Blister Canker on Apple Trees. By J. Ralph Cooper. 5,000 copies. electric light plant J it silo house and silo Concrete root cellar, 18 by 22... Concreting hog corrals rrigation system — labor and ment, estimated )ne mile fencing I equip- 585.00 125.00 325.00 500.00 75.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Thirty-first Annual Report 21 Circular No. 3. Cooling Tanks and Milk Houses as Fac - tors in Cream Improvement. By J. H. Frandsen. Distrib - uted May 5, 1917. Reprinted November 1, 1917. 25,000 copies. Circular No. 4. Pork Production in Nebraska. By E. A. Burnett. Distributed May 5, 1917. 15,000 copies. Circular No. 5. From Car Door to Consumer. By H. C. Filley. Distributed January 1, 1918. 15,000 copies. \( k \ O\V I KIM i.\l KXTS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly news - papers, especially those papers located within the State, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Sta - tion by giving liberal space to experimental work reported and in every way facilitating the extension of useful agricul - tural knowledge. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 22 ANNUAL REPORT OF EXTENSION SERVICE The Extension Service is a joint organization of the Extension forces of the University of Nebraska College of Agriculture and the United States Department of Agriculture, and the work is carried on thruout the State in cooperation with local organizations of men and women and with the pub - lic school system. The main lines of activity in the Extension Service are as follows: Publications. Extension Specialists in Agriculture. Extension Specialists in Home Economics. County Agricultural Agent Work. Junior Extension Work. Home Demonstration Agent Work. The county agricultural agent work is carried on in coop - eration with county and local organizations of farmers, the home demonstration agent work in cooperation with county and local organizations of farm women and of town women, and the junior extension work in cooperation with the public school system. The work of the extension specialists is car - ried on in cooperation with these agencies. The customary policy has been continued in sending workers to the various communities. When workers are sent to a community for the purpose of organizing and promoting work new to that community, all expenses are paid by the State. However, after work is once organized in a community, all local expenses are taken care of by the local organizations. In sending exten - sion workers to these communities for special work, schedules are so made where possible that workers serve a number of communities in succession during a single trip out from head - quarters. In those cases where a community requests special services that cannot be fitted into a schedule, the community is called upon to pay traveling expenses from headquarters to the community and return. However, in the case of com - munities whose meetings can be fitted into a schedule, the State pays all traveling expenses and the community is called upon to pay only the purely local expenses. The State pays all salaries of regular workers. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thirty-first Annual Report xxiii During 1917 the following money was available for state- wide extension work: Federal Smith-Lever funds $38,575.71 State funds by appropriation 33,000.00 Apportionments by the United States Department of Agriculture 21,908.00 Total 193,483.71 This sum does not include the funds contributed by local communities for the local expenses of special meetings, nor the employment of county agricultural agents, home demon- stration agents, and supervisors of junior home project work. Neither does it include any Federal emergency money. The following statement shows the quantity of office work handled in the central extension offices during the year Personal letters typed 31,500 Pages typed 44,758 Circulars mailed 703,284 Mimeographed pages printed 1,708,757 Multigraphed pages printed 434,020 In the central extension offices are conducted the corre- spondence in connection with the general administrative work, the county agricultural agent work, the home dem- onstration agent work, the junior extension work, and the home economics specialists. A large proportion of the bulletins and circulars distributed in extension work are mailed from the extension offices. However, a considerable number of these are mailed out by the specialists from the offices of the various college departments and a great num- ber are distributed at local meetings thruout the State. Notwithstanding the fact that in the latter part of the year the Extension Service was provided with capacious quar- ters on the first floor of Agricultural Hall, having been given practically the whole of the floor, the close of the year finds the new quarters already almost outgrown. The extension offices are now divided into six principal parts: The main office, the county agent office, the home economics office, the junior extension office, the duplicating room, and the mailing room. The contact between the members of the Extension Serv- ice and the people of the State during the year may be seen from the following statistics : </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Class of Work Number Aggregate Attendance Farm and home visits 14,255 28,510 (estimated) As soon as it became evident that the United States was to take part in the world's war for democracy, the Nebraska Extension Service made its aid to the Government its first con - cern. Wherever suggestions on food production or conserva - tion could be obtained from the administration, steps were taken to put these suggestions into operation. When it became apparent in the early part of the season that there was likely to be a shortage of cans, the Extension Service gave special attention to methods of drying fruits and vegetables. The new method of drying was tried and found to be entirely successful. By this method sliced fruits and vegetables were placed upon wire screen trays in front of an electric fan, and air blown over them from 12 to 48 hours. This took out a sufficient amount of moisture from most products so that they could be safely stored for winter use. It was felt that this method, while valuable to those who had electric fans or who were able to purchase them, did not permit the poorer people of the towns and cities or the farmers of the country who did not have electricity available to dry their products. They must necessarily resort to the oven method, or to the sun method, both of which have dis - advantages. The Extension Service, therefore, developed a community drying plant, and the first one was established in Lincoln with funds which were contributed by the Lincoln Rotary Club and by interested citizens. The drying plant was operated by a community club organized for the purpose. The plant was wonderfully successful, and while it had a capacity of 144 trays, each 18 inches by 36 inches, it was not sufficiently large to take care of all of the products brought for drying. As a result of this community drying plant, the first one estab - lished in the United States, four other Nebraska communities I&gt;KYI\(&gt; Mil ITS AM) \ K&lt;iKTAI5I.KS Jemonstrations 1,719 lounty fair exhibits 7 itate fair food training lamp exhibits 9 )ther meetings 3,164 161,107 40,700 14,280 81,709 Total 326,306 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Thirty-first Anmial Report 25 established like plants as follows : University Place, Fremont, Omaha, South Omaha. In addition to this a number of towns in Iowa, Colorado, and other places put in plants made from the blue prints developed at the Extension Service. The reports of these plants are not all in, but they indicate that no plant was sufficiently large to care for all the vege - tables brought as soon as it was found what could be done by them. The indications are that more than 300 bushels of material were dried in each plant during the season. This is an enormous amount of food and had there been more plants at these places the dried products would have been greatly increased. The State Board of Agriculture had one of these drying plants made out of glass and placed it on exhibition at the State Fair. This was erected at the food training camp, and attracted a great deal of attention. Two people were kept in charge during the entire week and there was no place on the ground where a crowd could be found oftener than around this community drying plant. Quantities of circulars were distributed, and from the inquiries which have come in since the State Fair, many plants will be established in Nebraska towns. The community drying work in Nebraska has attracted nation-wide attention. Letters have been received asking for information from all over the United States. Practically every periodical has carried some mention of the work. The United States Department of Agriculture asked the Extension Service to write a farmers' bulletin on community driers for distribution thruout the country. This bulletin is No. 916, "A Successful Community Drying Plant." CorXTY KAIH KXHIIUTS In many respects the Agricultural Extension exhibit at county fairs had its most successful season in 1917. Many people saw the exhibit, and more people were interested in the facts brought to them from the Agricultural College and from successful farmers than during past seasons. The women's work was in charge of a woman demonstra - tor from the College of Agriculture, and during the time of day when people were on the grounds, she was busy explain - ing the community drying plants and new method of canning. Interest was developed in at least one county in the county </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Agricultural Experiment Station. of Nebraska 26 farm agent work, and in several communities in the drying plants. An interesting and useful fact for the enthusiastic fair manager to consider is that the purely agricultural fair made money even in spite of bad weather, while the fairs featuring side shows and amusement, altho getting larger crowds in some instances, lost money or at best little more than broke even. Aside from that essential fact, the fairs that were purely agricultural are serving a real purpose and will grow with the community. It is estimated that approximately 3,000 people saw the exhibits at the Antelope County Fair at Neligh. All of the farmers were very much interested, especially in the exhibits concerning storage of potatoes, many questions being asked regarding the experience of others in storing and keeping potatoes. On the last day of the fair a rainstorm broke and chilly cloudy weather prevailed during the rest of the sea - son with the exception of the last week. At the Dodge County Fair at Hooper about 2,000 inspected our exhibit. This is a purely agricultural fair and the Exten - sion exhibit was the most interesting spot on the grounds to most of those present. The car was delayed in getting to the Howard County Fair. The car was located by telephoning to railroad officials and rushed into St. Paul. Luckily the first day of the fair was called off on account of cold, wet weather, which gave plenty of time to have the exhibit complete for the opening. The attendance was estimated at 7,200. The weather was cold and rainy. This fair was well advertised and with favorable weather undoubtedly would have had larger exhibits and greater attendance. The last fair was the Garden County Fair at Lewellen. Four thousand and five hundred people inspected the exhibit. The exhibit was very popular in this western county and many farmers returned time and again to study the different facts and lessons brought to them. At the Dixon County Fair the exhibit was greeted with much interest. The "Agricultural Tent" was the meeting place for many people and the exhibit gave rise to many ques - tions and discussions. The canning and drying exhibits seemed to attract an extra amount of attention. During the three days the tent was open, the exhibit was visited by about 6,000 people. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Thirty-first Annual Report 27 Hardly as much interest was manifested at the Seward County Fair as at the other fairs. This was due to the peo - ple having already learned the lessons thru their county agent. Many had also seen parts of the exhibit before, but all were highly satisfied and found many things of interest to study. It is estimated that 9,000 people visited the exhibit at this place. At the Clay County Fair at Clay Center, the people were much interested in the exhibit and many visited the tent sev - eral times. This was mainly an agricultural fair and the sun - flower experiment showing amount of water used by sun - flower and corn caused much comment and wonderment. Approximately 9,000 people visited the tent and many expressed satisfaction in regard to the exhibit. Attendance at all fairs is as follows : Antelope County 3,000 Dodge County 2,000 Howard County 7,200 Garden County 4,500 Dixon County 6,000 Seward County 9,000 Clay County 9,000 Total attendance for season 40,700 1TBMCAT1OXS At the beginning of the war an information service was established known as "War Emergency Bulletins." lip to the close of the year there had been 24 such bulletins issued. They deal largely with the production and conservation of foods and food products. They are as follows : 1. A World Food Shortage. 2. St. Louis Conference on the Agricultural Situation. 3. Nebraska Towns and the World Foocl Shortage. 4. Bean Culture. 5. Potato Culture. 6. Prevention of Food Waste. 7. Food Production and Conservation. 8. Farm Machinery. 9. Planning an Economical Wardrobe 10. Spraying Potatoes for Insects and Diseases. 11. Economy in Buying. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 12. Economy in Shoes. 13. Drying Fruits and Vegetables. 14. Restrictive and Coercive Food Measures. 15. Controlling Insect Pests of the Garden. 16. Home Storage of Vegetables. 17. Grasshopper Control. 18. Whole Wheat Bread. 19. Substitutes for White Flour in Bread Making. 20. How to Substitute Other Foods for Meat. 21. Economy in the Use of Fats. 22. How Can I Make My Clothes Last Longer? 23. Saving Beans for Food and Seeding Purposes. 24. The Problem of Soft Corn. An increased number of regular Extension Bulletins also relate largely to war activities. 39. Pit, Semi-Pit, and Bank Silos. 40. Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska. 41. The Farm Inventory. 42. Vocational Education in Its Relation to School Gar - dening. 43. The School-Home Garden. 44. Every Cow on Her Own Merits. 45. Handling Silage. 46. Feeding Dairy Cows. 47. Farm Cheese-Making. 48. Well-Planned Meals. In accordance with instructions from the Government, im - mediate steps were taken to increase greatly the number of county agricultural agents, home demonstration agents, and junior extension workers. On September 1, emergency dis - trict agents were placed in charge of all territory not having county agents, to look after the work and to assist in organ - ization. In publicity work the year marked the firm establishment of two additional lines of activity. Whereas in the past the publicity of the institution had been confined to the Extension News Service, with an edition of approximately 2,000 copies a week, reaching every country paper in the State, and a few articles now and then contributed to the daily papers, for the first time a distinct service for the daily papers was added. During the latter part of the year this material was supplied regularly to the daily papers three times a week — Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday — carrying approximately 800 words each time. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Thirty-first Annual Report 29 The success which greeted the establishment of this daily service exceeded all expectations. It was developed from the miscellaneous collection of items to a service which was lib - erally used by the majority of the daily papers in the State. Very often syndicate material from this service occupies the most conspicuous places in both Omaha and Lincoln papers. Another branch of publicity was also established for the benefit of the farm papers. Short articles were supplied to this class of papers once a week. These articles were often written by members of the faculty. The material supplied to the country papers was continued as in the past. The success of the work in the country papers was even more striking than in the dailies. An analysis of 98 of those papers shows that 79 of them were carrying material of one sort or another which originated in the pub - licity office of the Extension Service. Thirty-two farm papers are now included on the farm paper list. The daily list embraces approximately 40 papers. The Extension News Service, which is designed in the main for country papers, reaches 565 papers within the State and 80 outside. The system of news distribution of the Extension Service was placed at the disposal of the State Council of Defense, and the State Labor Bureau. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 30 THE WORK OF EXTENSION SPECIALISTS IN AGRICULTURE ACiKONOMY Agronomy extension work has two phases, soils and crops. The latter phase may again be subdivided into cereal and forage crops. Each of these phases and sub-phases has sev - eral problems that are seriously confronting the farmers. Soil fertility is more important in many parts of the State than most people suppose. On the thin, glaciated, and eroded land of eastern Nebraska, organic matter and nitrogen are seriously lacking. Even on the rich, loose land of Thurston, Dakota, and Burt Counties, many hillsides show the need of nitrogen and organic matter. The same need is found in the rougher and more sandy sections of central Nebraska. The extension agronomists have organized and conducted demonstrations in the preservation and systematic application of barnyard manure, rotation with legumes, and commercial fertilizer. Erosion problems are becoming more and more serious as the land gets older and where the supply of organic mat - ter is not kept up. Demonstrations have been conducted to show the following methods of controlling erosion : (a) Seed - ing down to grasses and legumes, preferably stoloniferous grasses; (b) farming at right angles to slope; (c) deep plow - ing; (d) contour ditching; (e) filling ditches with brush, straw, trash, and by planting trees, etc. Methods demon - strated for controlling wind erosion were : (a) Keeping plenty of organic matter in the soil by planting legumes and grasses and by adding manure; (b) adding wet, strawy manure to stop blowing; (c) seeding in stubble instead of plowing; (d) keeping surface rough with a lister or cultivator; (e) dividing pastures and placing watering places in center of pasture, especially on sandy land. Many bad alkali spots have been observed and called to the attention of the extension agronomists. Control demon - strations have been conducted showing the following methods : (a) Drainage; (b) scraping alkali crust off on small patches; (c) deep plowing and thoroly mixing alkali to reduce the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Thirty-first Annual Report 31 strength of solution; (d) adding manure; (e) using alkali resistant plants. More acid soils are being found in Nebraska as the land grows older. One demonstration in liming for the correc - tion of acid conditions was organized. In the cereals work, special attention has been given to the proper selection of seed corn, the top dressing of winter wheat with manure and straw to reduce winterkilling, the planting of spring wheat, the treatment of western seed wheat for smut, the treatment of oats for smut, and the substitu - tion of barley on land that had been in wheat which was killed out during the winter. More inquiries and calls for help on pastures and pasture mixtures were received during this year than on any other subject. An effort has been made to meet the demand, and two pamphlets, one on pastures and pasture mixtures, and the other on seeding small seeded forage crops, have been distributed. Several demonstrations in building up old pas - tures and seeding of pasture mixtures have been conducted. Demonstrations have been conducted in the seeding of alfalfa and sweet clover for good stands. Considerable attention has been given to listing avail - able seed from all parts of the State. AXIMAIi Hl'SHANnUY The general work, conducted independent of the county agents, comprised short courses, institutes, county fairs, colt shows, banquets, miscellaneous meetings, and ewe buy - ing. The work at the meetings covered all the usual lines of selecting and managing cattle, sheep, hogs, and horses. Its effectiveness was in converse proportion to the breadth of subject matter covered. Orders for 9,000 head of ewes were received at the cen - tral office last summer. Tho many sheep were placed, there were more orders than ewes. The demand for breeding stock, especially purebreds, is increasing. With the advent of more valuable animals comes an increasing demand for information as to man - agement. It is the opinion of the extension animal hus - bandman that the practical things such as butchering, lambing, lamb docking, shearing, and judging demonstra- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska tions, while valuable in themselves, serve even a better pur - pose in making friends and gaining the farmers' trust, thus opening infinite possibilities for the management work. The work conducted in cooperation with the county agents may be divided into meat work, wool work, and management work. Meat Work. — "Butchering bees" were scheduled by the agents in various neighborhoods. The slaughtering was done one day and the cutting and curing the next. A surprising number of "short cuts" and easier methods were brought out by the men in attendance. A different system of handling these meat demonstrations has since been successfully tried out in Seward County. Each township appointed a repre - sentative to be present at the central or county meeting. Each man returned to this township and held a demonstration of his own. The results have proved to be more satisfactory and more permanent and the agent and extension animal hus - bandman were left free to cover more ground. Wool Work. — Shearing, wool tying, sacking and grading, a cooperative wool sale, shearing meetings at which the farmers did most of the shearing, and a demonstration show - ing the different grades of wool and methods of handling wool brought wool to market in a better condition and interested a number of new men in the sheep business. Some help was given in Gage County, where a successful cooperative sale netted local farmers 5 cents to 8 cents a pound above country prices. Management Work. — A central meeting was held where 600 ewes were lambing. Particular attention was paid to saving the youngsters. Seeing such a plant in successful operation put 1,600 ewes into one county last fall. Later meetings studied the growing out of the lamb, docking, etc. These did much to remove that fear of sheep which the unini - tiated farmer possesses. A number of pig-feeding demonstrations were planned to follow out the previous year's work. Loss of alfalfa and loss of labor stopped them before they were even started. DAIKY HISKAXDRY An effort has been made during this year to organize the dairy work in the State as completely as possible. In addi - tion to the Nebraska Dairymen's Association and the Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Thirty-first Anntial Report 33 Dairy Cattle Breeders' Association, which cooperate with the dairy extension department, dairymen's associations were organized in Adams, Fillmore, Pawnee, Gage, Lancaster, Sarpy, and Douglas Counties. Three automobile trips among dairymen have been con - ducted during the year. Such trips were found to be a very successful means of stimulating interest. Whenever possible, assistance has been given in selecting and purchasing dairy cattle. During the year three trips were made to Wisconsin for this purpose, and considerable attention has been given to this kind of work in the State. Results have been very satisfactory. Wherever selected cows have gone in carload lots, interest in dairying has been stim - ulated and there has been less tendency to continue milking inferior cows. Banks and creameries are anxious to cooperate. Bankers offer money at 5 per cent and encourage farmers to invest in cows. Lately, on account of the scarcity and the high price of good cows the mail order purchase of young heifer calves has been advised. Emphasis has also been placed on the very great importance of a good purebred bull in order that a larger number of dairy cattle of superior quality may be produced in the State, thus making it unnecessary to import cattle from other states. We have assisted in the purchase of six purebred Holstein bulls at a total cost of $900, eight purebred Holstein cows at a total cost of $1,450, and 295 head of grade cows at a total cost of $24,875. Extension specialists have attended a total of 50 meet - ings, at which the aggregate attendance was 6,879 people. They addressed 36 of these meetings, at which the aggregate attendance was 4,009 persons. There were in the State this year four small cow testing associations, that is, associations of about 200 cows each. The Central Nebraska and the Lancaster County Associations jointly employed a tester for full time. The Gage County and the Pawnee County Associations employed a tester in the same manner. While these associations maintain separate organizations for convenience in administration of affairs, the four really constitute but two associations of the usual size. This was the second year for the Gage County Associa - tion, which shows an increase of 38.6 pounds of fat per cow, an increase in income, at 40 cents a pound, of $15.44 per </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 34 cow. Another evidence of improvement is shown by the increased number of cows producing 300 pounds of butter fat. This number was increased from 30 to 73. One of the most noticeable single herd improvements was that of No. 10. The average production of this herd was increased 42 pounds per cow. Herd No. 13 showed an increase, resulting from better feeding and care alone, of 1,521 pounds of milk and 55.9 pounds of butter fat per cow. This having been the first year for the Pawnee County Association, a comparison like the above cannot be made here. Results in this county, however, are very encouraging and the cows made a very creditable showing. Of the 12o cows that remained in the association thruout the year, 5 produced over 400 pounds of butter fat in twelve months, 7 produced 350 pounds or more, and 18 produced 300 pounds or more. Of all the cows in the association the average pro - duction per cow for 12 months was 6,975 pounds of milk containing 262 pounds of butter fat. The Gage and Pawnee County Associations reorganized with an increased membership. Due to the fact that so much territory is included in the Central Nebraska-Lancaster County Association and also that most of the members have purebreds and are doing semiofficial work, these associations have not yet reorganized. Arrangements have been made, however, to do semiofficial work in the associations and to reorganize them within the next few months. Arrangements have been made for the testers to be pro - vided with cars and it is believed this will overcome the dif - ficulty of securing a sufficient number of cows in territory where herds are so far apart. The College of Agriculture is now offering a course of instructions for cow testers, but as yet no credit is given to students for cow testing associa - tion work. While the territory in which cooperative cow testing asso - ciations may be organized is very limited, emphasis has been placed on the importance of keeping individual records. In order to encourage this practice, record sheets have been fur - nished to those who will use them. It is endeavored to secure from farmers who use the record sheets such information as is desired concerning the herd. In communities where there are not enough cows for a cow testing association or when the herds are too small, it has been found very practicable to organize junior cow test- </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Thirty-first Annual Report 35 ing clubs. The members, under the direction of a competent local leader, keep a regular cow testing association record. These clubs should develop into cow testing associations. In a general way, interest in dairying is steadily increas - ing in Nebraska. In some instances large profits from sheep and steer feeding and good returns from grain farming tend to discourage temporarily the milking of cows. As a whole, however, the fact that dairying is the most dependable source of farm income is pretty generally realized and in cer - tain sections of the State dairying is already quite perma - nently established. Effort is being made to give special attention to represent - ative dairymen in different sections of the State, and as soon as advisable to organize the dairymen in communities. Spe - cial effort will be made during the coming year to extend work of this kind and make the mailing list as complete as possible so that the most effective work may be done. \(.i;k l l l i i; \i ENGINEERING The most important phases of the Extension work in agri - cultural engineering have been demonstrations in farm drain - age, farm tractors and machinery, and silos. Drainage is one of the most substantial means of increas - ing crop production. It brings uncultivated lands under cul - tivation and transforms areas of forage crop lands into human food producing lands. Too rapid a speeding up of produc - tion by going the limit of their productiveness on the farms of the State may have the effect of causing underproduction after the war. Increased production by means of drainage Is substantial. It is not a short-lived emergency increase, but one which will extend on thru the years. Each unit of land reclaimed adds to the world's supply of human food for not one year alone, but for a centuiy to come. The amount of land actually reclaimed in the demonstra - tions started by the extension agricultural engineer since the beginning of the war is 1,183 acres. This represents only the acreage included in the project. It does not represent drainage which resulted thru the influence of the project in the particular communities in which the projects were located. There is no definite way of checking this up, but there is posi - tive proof that these projects are being imitated. The land reclaimed in these projects alone would form quite an incre- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 36 ment of increased production. Allowing a 60-bushel increase in production (most of the land was fit only for prairie hay), there is a permanent increase of 70,980 bushels per year. Information on the subject has been given out thru nu- merous press articles and bulletins. Advice by letter or brief visits was given to 44 persons, 13 of whom installed systems with a total of over 800 acres reclaimed. Increased production is impossible with a great deficiency in man power without the aid of the tractor and tractor-farm - ing machinery. One of the great drawbacks of tractor farm - ing is the lack of knowledge relative to the operation of trac - tors. By means of special meetings, more than four thousand farmers have been reached with specific information on trac - tors. Special bulletins are issued during the summer to tractor owners who have attended meetings in the winter. Numerous letters of inquiry from tractor owners are answered by this section. The pit silo is proving a valuable means of conserving animal food. This is particularly true in the west. A model pit silo was installed at the State Fair and over 1,000 special bulletins were given to people particularly interested. A model pit silo was installed at the Maywood Fair and attracted a great deal of attention. One tour of inspection of pit silos has been held during the year. The following is a brief summary of the work handled by the extension agricultural engineer: Visits made to specialist .... 35 Visits made by specialist.. 51 Drainage 10 Farmsteads 14 Letters of information Gulleying 1 sent 290 Hog houses 4 Bulletins sent :v? Residences •? ■iii ;&gt; Sketches sent 20 Sanitation 1 No. of people to whom blue prints sent 96 Septic tank 1 Sheep shed 1 No. of people helped (other than thru pro - jects) 155 Storage tank 9 Terracing 1 Tractor farming 1 Projects started : Water systems •; ;&gt; Barns 5 Total number of projects Building plans o started 46 Community house 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Thirty- first Annual Report 37 KNTOMOUMJY Extension work in entomology did not begin until Octo - ber 1, 1917, when the Extension Service joined with the State Entomologist in the employment of an extension entomologist, 7/12 of his salary and expenses to be paid by the Extension Service and 5 12 by the State Entomologist. As October comes after the chief period of insect injury has passed, no extension work in the field was necessary during that month. In early November, however, a survey of Nebraska wheat fields was begun to determine the amount of infestation with the Hessian fly. It is necessary, in order to cope with this pest, to know approximately the amount of infestation from six months to a year in advance so that the amount of injury to be inspected may be anticipated and preventive meas - ures started if necessary. Up to December 1 the counties of Seward, Gage, Saline, Jefferson, Thayer, and Fillmore were surveyed and the percentage of infestation under wheat by the Hessian fly was definitely ascertained. KAKM MA.VMiKMKXT AND MARKKTIMi The farm management demonstration work was largely confined to the counties having agricultural agents. The cooperating farmers were assisted in keeping records of their farm business, and the records kept in 1916 were analyzed and returned. The most important marketing project carried on during the year of 1917 was in assisting the producer to deal direct with the consumer. Letters were sent to all merchants in Nebraska stating the advantage of buying direct from the producer and offering to furnish lists of orchardists and potato growers. The response from the merchants was good. Un - fortunately, so few growers had graded their potatoes that the county agents hesitated to recommend them, and direct selling was somewhat hampered. The orchardists who told us that they wished to sell direct had more orders than they could fill and wished the service continued the coming year. Elevator companies were helped to organize, to draft by - laws, and given instruction in short courses, and a four-day short course for elevator managers was held at the University Farm. The farmers of the State feel that the Agricultural Col - lege can be of the greatest assistance to them in the solving </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska of marketing problems. Inauguration of this work is, there - fore, a response to the often expressed wish of the farmers. The Extension Service realized that a shortage of labor was sure to come, and in cooperation with the Department of Agriculture placed a man in charge of the labor work early in the year. Later this man's office was moved to the State House to cooperate with the State Labor Commissioner and with a man from the United States Department of Labor. The plan was to have a labor representative in each locality, to have a county labor bureau in charge of the county agent, and to have a state labor bureau to keep in touch with the Government, which received reports from all states. It was thought that there would be a considerable amount of labor in each locality if it could be properly distributed, so this was the first effort of the labor specialist's work. His next effort was to redistribute surplus of labor from various sections. A number of people from the College of Agriculture donated their services in the organization of the local bureaus. Eleven student agents of the Burlington Railroad Company located about 125 such bureaus in the Burlington territory. Five members of the Extension Service spent one week and organized practically 40 local bureaus. Nine county agents organized 50 such bureaus. The activity of the bureaus has been determined by local labor shortage more than by any other factor. Probably 99 per cent of the bureaus were active when there was need for their work. Wherever there was a county agent there was a county bureau, and no county bureau was located in the State outside of the counties having agents, except in two instances. Wages finally settled at about $2.50 per day and board, and from $40 to $50 per month and board. More women and children than usual worked in the fields. There were few intances of crops being lost because of the shortage of labor. During May and June, 329 farm labor bureaus were located in 85 counties. Six temporary bureaus were located and used during the sand hill hay harvest. The placements for these bureaus were: December 832 Total 13,262 Probably 98 per cent of these placements were of farm labor. lay 548 une 1,083 uly 2,332 August 1,973 September .. &gt;ctober November ... 1,592 1,876 3,128 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Thirty-first Annual Report 39 HOItTll'l l,Tl ItK The efforts of the extension horticulturist during the year 1917 were largely directed to increasing the production of fruits in Nebraska orchards. The work comprised demon - strations in commercial orchard management, in home orchard management, in pruning, and in spraying. During the season of 1917, but one commercial orchard was used to demonstrate the value of good management. The work there was a continuation of the work started in 1916. In brief the methods followed were as follows: During the winter a pruning demonstration was given at the orchard, to which orchardists from the vicinity were invited. Methods of pruning the different varieties of apple trees and treat - ment of canker were shown. The owner finished the pruning according to the directions given. At spraying time another meeting was held at which this operation was described and demonstrated. The extension horticulturist then supervised the mixing of the spray material and the application of it to the trees. The owner kept accurate record of all expenses incurred. At harvest time another meeting was held to note and discuss the results of the work. The net proceeds this year were a little greater than for the year 1916, tho not as great as might have been. There developed unexpectedly a third brood of codling moth late in the season which was responsible for a greater per cent of cider apples than usual ; otherwise, the results were highly satisfactory. The home orchards in the State on the whole are in a sadly dilapidated and unproductive state because of neglect. Probably the best method of remedying this condition of af - fairs is by actually selecting neglected orchards, pruning and spraying them, and letting the results prove to the owner and the community that they can be made to pay. During the past year five home orchards were selected in which to carry on the demonstration : One in Gage County, three in Seward County, and one in Thurston County. The work was carried on in cooperation with the county agents of these counties. In late winter, pruning demonstrations were held at these places. Later, spraying demonstations were given and tRe orchards sprayed four times. At harvest time, meetings were held to discuss results. A record of all costs and receipts was kept so as to determine the exact value of the care given. The results shown by those cost accounts are a good indica- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 40 tion of the value of good orchard management. Checked trees that were left unsprayed showed an average of 65 per cent of unsound fruit, whereas the sprayed trees showed 85 per cent of sound fruit. The number of demonstration orchards must necessarily be small, since the time for applying the various sprays is short. During the winter months, considerable time can be given to demonstrations in pruning in communities that it would be impossible to reach with demonstration orchards. At these meetings the principles of pruning were explained and demonstrated. In addition, the need of spraying is em - phasized by charts, and methods are discussed for controlling orchard pests. During the year, 53 pruning demonstrations were given, attended by 300 farmers. Demonstrations in spraying were not numerous, as there is little time in which to give them, most of the extension horticulturist's time being taken up by actually spraying the demonstration orchards. Letters with return envelope were written to those peopic who attended demonstrations, but only a small number an - swered the inquiry. The answers showed that probably 40 pruned their orchards as a result of the demonstrations, and about 20 sprayed. One man near College View who owns about three acres of orchard was induced to prune and spray. His returns amounted to over $800. One man with whom the specialist cooperated in a demon - stration project in 1916 was informed of the advisability of leasing an orchard which in the two years immediately pre - ceding had yielded less than $500. He leased the orchard, and made it yield over 8,000 bushels of good fruit. During the course of the year some work has been done in seed potato selection, in cooperation with the county agents in the western part of the state. In addition, a potato improvement association was formed to improve the quality, the yield, the grades, and the marketing conditions. Another phase of this work is developing of a seed market for western Nebraska potatoes, but before this can be done, the growers of western Nebraska must be impressed with the need for growing better potatoes, free from disease, and then to grade them properly. The extension horticulturist spent three weeks in the counties of western Nebraska addressing farmers' meetings on the subjects of seed selection and the need for grading. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirty-first Annual Report 41 THE WORK OF EXTENSION SPECIALISTS IN HOME ECONOMICS CANNING The number of trained workers was so small that if they were to reach at once all of the people in the State with canning instructions, it was necessary to hold special train - ing schools. The latter part of May and the first of June, forty-five such training schools were held at thirty-three dif - ferent points in the State. Each school lasted for two days, and was in charge of a member of the home economics faculty from some one of the state schools. The normal schools cooperated in this work. The total attendance at these schools was 2,150. This includes only the women who came to all the meetings, who received instruction and made a pledge to teach the cold-pack method of canning to other people. Previous to the opening of these schools a series of con - ferences and schools were held with all of the home economics teachers, to teach them the method in all of its details. Sev - eral of these were held in Lincoln and others at the state nor - mal schools and the Curtis School of Agriculture. The mornings were devoted to laboratory work in which the women actually canned vegetables under direction of instructors. The afternoons were given over to discussions and demonstrations. Literature was distributed, and charts to be used were explained. After the schools were held, those receiving instruction gave demonstrations and individual instructions in their own communities. Proper literature was compiled and sent to them and a question and answer circular was made out from the inquiries regarding the cold-pack method of canning, so that the instructors would have practically every question that might be asked with its proper answer. The detailed sum - mary of the results of this work is not in at this time, but thousands of people received their first instruction in the method of cold-pack canning and the result was the saving of great quantities of wood which would otherwise have gone to waste. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska I&gt;KMO\KTlt.4TIO.\ A.M) KXHIIUTS At the Omaha Food Congress, representatives of the Extension Service had charge of the Home Economics exhibits. Meetings were held every day and demonstrations were in progress at all times. Booths giving graphic illus - trations of methods of saving food and methods of its proper preparation were attended by home economics workers. At the Epworth Assembly the first part of August the Extension Service tent was erected and daily demonstrations were given in canning and drying. Workers were in charge of the exhibit every day from 8 :30 in the morning until 7 :30 at night. Great quantities of literature on food conservation were distributed and the names of women taken who wished special help along various lines. At the State Fair the food conservation booths of the food training camp were in charge of the Extension Service. These booths presented the following conservation ideas: Child Welfare Conservation of Strength and Time in Housekeeping Wheat and Sugar Conservation Meat and Fat Conservation Home Methods of Preserving Food This took the time of twelve workers for one week. Care - ful estimate of the number of people visiting the booths showed that 17,000 people were reached. A home economics extension worker was sent to each of fifteen county fairs, and demonstrations in food conservation were given. At seven of these fairs the University exhibit tents were used. The number of women reached thru these county fairs was 7,000. TKACHKltS' IXSTITITKS Work was given at ten county teachers' institutes. In two cases a whole week's work was given. In seven cases two days only were given to food conservation, while in one case the representative remained only one day. At each one of these institutes the people were given a chance to obtain copies of the food emergency bulletins and were given talks on the importance of the conservation of food. One of tho most valuable features was the holding of individual confer - ences with rural teachers who were anxious to start the serv - ing of hot lunches. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Thirty-first Annual Report 43 WOJIK.VS SHOKT OOURMK8 The program for the women's work at short courses has been entirely changed in response to the suggestions given for food conservation. In many cases the old recipe sheets have been entirely discarded and new ones substituted advo - cating the use of substitute materials for wheat and sugar. A prominent place will be given at the short courses to war activities of women, such as Red Cross work, campaigns for liberty bonds, food purchase, and other lines of work in which the Government is especially interested. The women's ses - sions at farmers' institutes this year are all conservation pro - grams. IM.KIH.K ( AKI&gt; CAMI'AHiX In the first pledge card campaign the Extension Service sent out all of the pledge cards, and two or three of our workers devoted several weeks to organizing the State for the work. It was necessary for the University to pay for having the cards printed, as no funds were available from either the federal or the state government for this work. The time given for organizing the machinery was limited, and the workers were few, but in spite of that fact between 50,000 and 60,000 women signed the cards during the first campaign. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENT WORK By direct order from the Government, the State Extension Service, and the Farm Bureaus directing county agent work, the county agents immediately prepared their programs to help in every possible way in the production and conservation of the foods for the nation. Owing to the winterkilling of a large part of the wheat, the agents encouraged the sowing of spring wheat, and the Hour for many loaves of bread was made possible because the seed was located by the agents and distributed to farmers who needed it. Seed wheat surveys for the fall sowing were made by each agent and encouragement given toward increasing the acreage. Demonstrations were held in the proper methods of seeding in cornfields with small drills. Many wheat smut eradication meetings were held so that the next year's crop of wheat might be as free as possible from this disease and that the quality of grain for bread purposes might be in - creased as well as the yield. Because of the killing of the winter wheat a large acre - age was thrown upon the farmers' hands to be planted either to corn, spring wheat, oats, or some other crop. The county agents, together with workers from the Extension Service, located great quantities of seed of all kinds, including corn, spring wheat, sorghums of various kinds, oats, and beans. So far as possible the farmer was put in direct touch with the producer of these seeds. I«OTATOKS Because of the high price asked for potatoes, a special effort was made to increase the potato acreage. Sound and disease-free seed potatoes were located and brought to the counties by the county agents. The acreage of potatoes in Nebraska was tremendously increased because of extension activities. Aid was given during the entire summer in fight - ing insects and diseases, and a number of men were engaged during the fall helping in the marketing and storing of the potato crop. Special bulletins on planting, growing, harvest - ing, and storing potatoes were prepared and given wide dis - tribution. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Thirty-first Annual Report 45 MVK STOTK DISKASK CONTROL In the emergency work, special emphasis was given to the elimination, in so far as possible, of live stock diseases. This was especially true of hog cholera and diseases of similar nature. Hog cholera vaccination demonstrations were given by the county agents, and resulted directly in the vaccination of over 10,000 head of hogs. Many farmers who watched the vaccinations and saw the results of the demonstrations followed the example set by their neighbors. By cooperative work which is carried on by the Bureau of Animal Industry, veterinary inspectors have answered calls for the investiga - tion of sickness among hogs on over 1,500 farms, and have visited about 1,200 other farms, making a total of 2,700. General supervision has been given in the treatment of 16,000 hogs in 375 infected herds, and in the treatment of 45,000 hogs near cholera outbreaks. Hog cholera warning letters were sent to over 10,500 farmers notifying them of outbreaks in their vicinity. In addition to this hundreds of inquiries have been answered personally and by mail and numerous articles dealing with hog cholera control work disseminated. Blackleg control has been urged by all agents and the three or four western agents have brought about the vacci - nation of over 8,000 animals against this disease. HODKXT AXD IXHKtT I'KSTS The need of eliminating the destruction of crops by pocket gophers, prairie dogs, ground squirrels, and other pests has been emphasized. The agents in Gage, Seward, Madison, and Dakota Counties have organized gopher clubs covering a total of 2,000 farms. The work has been exceed - ingly successful in eliminating gophers from these areas. MAIthKTINi. Exchange bureaus are conducted by all county agents, the object of these being to find a market for all grain and live stock not normally taken care of and to eliminate in so far as possible all unnecessary friction and waste. The ex - changes have also given special attention to the redistribu - tion of second-hand machinery. This was brought about be - cause of the shortage of farm machinery and the great increase in prices incident to the war. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska The Potato Market News Service was established in the office of the agricultural agent in Alliance, Box Butte County, by the Office of Markets, U. S. Department of Agriculture. Daily reports of potato markets were sent to more than 2,000 growers. This has resulted in increasing the price paid the producers and lessening the price to consumers by help - ing to eliminate the uneconomic speculator. &lt;;k\ki:ai. The personal work of the nine county agricultural agents is summarized below: bought or sold thru exchange 38,046 Bushels of grain, seed, etc., bought and sold thru exchanges 61,306 Head of purebred live Demonstrations visited 377 Miles traveled by auto.60,419 Miles traveled by rail .19,529 Press articles written.. 675 Bulletins distributed. ... 6,117 Blackleg vaccinations. 15,072 stock introduced 55,557 Farm laborers placed... 665 Number of meetings held 1,247 Aggregate attendance. 19,326 JUNIOR KXTKXSIOX WORK The 1917 campaign for the promotion of agricultural extension work among the boys and girls was inaugurated by four regular workers with assistance from other workers as occasion would demand. Definitely outlined projects of work, embracing different lines of agricultural activity, were carried on. The work has been organized to include both town and rural boys and girls, the town work being largely confined to gardening and canning. In the work with towns, 46 active supervisors were employed during the summer months to oversee and direct the work. In the rural districts, enrollment was secured thru the cooperation of county agents, county superintendents, and rural teachers as well as thru correspondence direct between the individual boys and girls and the Extension Service. Hog cholera vaccina- tions 15,226 Head of live stock relephone calls 11,461 )ays in the field 1,672 )ays in the office 950 "alls on agent at head- quarters 13,464 Circular letters issued 36,464 J ersonal letters issued. 15,344 r arm visits made 3,314 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Thirty-first Annual Report xlvii The following are the home projects which were promoted during the year with the enrollment in each : From the reports obtained after deducting all overhead costs of supervision and cost of production, the net profit to the State totaled $46,851. In getting the interest awakened in this work among tho people of the State, junior institute's were held in as many counties as requested them. In such counties two workers spent four days and held a one-day meeting at four differ - ent rural schoolhouses, each in a different section of the county. Local arrangements were made by the county super - intendents. Special gatherings of teachers were addressed on the subject of junior extension work both at county insti - tutes and special teachers' meetings. In addition special talks were given when requests came from different sections of the State for them. In the towns interested in hiring paid supervisors, a series of three meet - ings was usually held, one with the grade children, one with the high school pupils, and a general meeting in the evening with the board of education present to take action regard - ing the proposition. After securing enrollment, a series of instructional circu - lars was ?ent from time to time as the requirements of the season demanded. Regular visits and correspondence were maintained with the different garden supervisors to keep in touch with the urban work. Several county agents gave per - sonal oversight to this work in their respective counties, and excellent results were obtained where this was done. With the outbreak of war and the calls for increased pro - duction and conservation of all surplus, the junior section of the Extension Service took active measures to cooperate as far as possible. Special efforts were put forth to secure addi - tional enrollments in the chicken raising and gardening proj - ects. The results of this effort were most gratifying. A patriotic appeal was made to all project members to increase their efforts toward getting larger yields and conserving all Enroll- Name of project ment 3gg producing 361 thicken raising 975 Horn growing 225 Potato growing 175 Total Name of project Pig raising Sewing Cooking Gardening 11,727 Enrol ; ment 319 1,350 2,500 5,822 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska xlviii surplus. In all garden towns special stress was laid on canning. Canning teams composed of two boys and two girls were organized and several such teams contested at the State Fair for the state championship. These teams gave demon - strations during the entire week of the fair, and the state champion team later contested at the inter-state fair at Sioux City with teams from Minnesota, South Dakota, and Iowa. Late in the summer the regular corps of workers was increased to seven and extensive preparations begun for con - ducting the work next year. The pig raising project was expanded to include a fall project as well as one in the sum - mer, and special effort was made to get a large enrollment in the egg producing project. A dairy calf raising project was started and the enrollment secured for work beginning December 1. With the campaign of the food administration for a reduc - tion in the amount of wheat flour to be used in making bread, a war bread project is being organized which will contain recipes for using the different wheat flour substitutes as rec - ommended by the food administration. This promises to be a popular project. In promoting the work for next year an extensive cam - paign has been inaugurated to install garden supervisors in the different towns of the State. As a preliminary, a garden survey is being planned for all towns in the State thru the cooperation of the superintendent of schools and the pupils. Furthermore, a special effort is being put forth to secure local leaders in different communities who will personally supervise the junior work among groups in the rural districts. In most instances teachers are doing this work. About 125 such leaders were secured during the fall months. As a further means of stimulating the rural work, the junior section is making plans for the placing of 25 or 30 county junior extension agents for service during the sum - mer months. The closest kind of cooperation exists between the Extension Service, the State Department of Public Instruction, and the State Board of Vocational Education in furthering agricultural education. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Thirty-first Annual Report 49 HOMH DKMONSTHATION AOKNTS Since the passage of the emergency food production law giving to the State of Nebraska some money for home dem - onstration agents, special effort has been made to organize various localities for county and urban agents. The close of the year finds two such county agents, one city agent, and nine district agents at work. The district agents are devot - ing their energies largely to the formation of county organ - izations for the permanent employment of county home demonstration agents. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska TI1K AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL .STATEMENT Financial Secretary. n . v i n ruiii/ RECEIPTS deceived by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1917, under the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, (Hatch fund) _ $15,000.00 EXPENDITURES Salaries _ _ _ _ _ Labor _ _ _ _ Publications _ Postage and stationery— _ _ _ _ Chemicals and laboratory supplies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies. Feeding stuffs Library _ Tools, machinery, and appliances. Scientific apparatus and specimens Live stock _. Traveling expenses _ _ $9,141.31 1,510.40 1,988.86 523.35 142.60 51.19 993.08 27.25 48.69 437.26 105.00 31.01 $15,000,00 $15,000,00 January 29, 1918. J. S. DALES, </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Thirty-first Annual Report 51 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued ADAMS FUND Financial Secretary. RECEIPTS Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1917, under the act of Congress approved March 16, 1906 (Adams fund) _ $15,000.00 EXPENDITURES Salaries — _ _ Labor _ _ _ _ _ _ Freight and express_ _ _ Chemicals and laboratory supplies- _ Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies _ Feeding stuffs _ _ __ Tools, machinery, and appliances. _ _ _ Furniture and fixtures— _ _ _ Scientific apparatus and sp«cimens_ _ Traveling expenses _ _ _ _ B u i Id i ngs and land _ _ _ $12,461.93 128.48 11.03 584.35 395.56 51.00 56.85 18.70 1.134.10 139.67 18.33 $15,000,00 $15,000,00 January 29, 1918. J. S. DALES, </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued SUPPLEMENTAL FUNDS RECEIPTS Moneys received by the University (State) treasurer from other sources than the United States, for the use and benefit of the Experi - ment Station and Substations, for the year ended June 30, 1917. Balance July 1, 1916, (corrected) $5,135.35 31,863.08 Sales of stock, produce, etc. EXPENDITURES Salaries Labor $4,1NX.6X 453.73 Publications 44.70 Postage and stationery Freight and express 250.29 333.97 Heat, light, water, and power_ _. Chemicals and laboratory supplies. Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies. Feeding stuffs _ 915.63 3,779.61 1,791.94 7,440.10 Library 140.03 892.18 Tools, machinery, and appliances Furniture and fixtures 197.35 Scientific apparatus and specimens Live stock .„ _ _ „ _ _ 1,096.17 2.864.95 Traveling expenses Contingent expenses Buildings and land Balance, June 30, 1917 410.69 153.47 1,988.93 10,056.01 $36,998.43 $36,998.43 January 29, 1918 J. S. DALES. Financial Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Thirty-first Annual Report 53 FINANCIAL STATEMENT — Continued APPROPRIATIONS BY THE STATE EXPERIMENTAL SUBSTATIONS Balances July 1, 1916, of legislative appropri - ation from the State general fund for the benefit of the Experimental Substations, for the two years ending March 31, 1917. North Platte _ _ $8,467.19 Scottsbluff _ _ 3,382.09 Valentine 2,799.89 Legislative appropriation for two years ending March 31, 1917, Expenditures, year ending June 30, 1917, for superintendence, supplies, labor, live stock, feed, seeds, machinery, tools, and bet - terment of the plants. North Platte ._ $15,305.64 Scottsbluff _ _ 4,902.13 Valentine _ _ _ 4,068.17 $24,275.94 Appropriations balances July 1, 1917, North Platte _ _ $23,086.55 Scottsbluff _ _ 2,279.96 Valentine _ _ _ 4,191.72 29,558.23 J14.649.17 North Platte _ _ _ $29,925.00 Scottsbluff ._ _ _ 3,800.00 Valentine _ _ _ 5,4 60.00 39,185.00 $53,834.17 $53,834.17 Balance, cash, July 1, 1916 $9,765.32 Receipts to June 30, 1917 29.087.28 Expenditures to June 30, 1917 _ $26,177.72 Balance, June 30, 1917 _ _ _ _ 12,674.88 $38,852.60 $38,852.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Concluded APPROPRIATIONS BY THE STATE— Concluded AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION Balance, July 1, 1916, of legislative appropri - ation from the State general fund for main - tenance of Agricultural Extension and Farmers' Institutes, for the two years end- ing March 31, 1917- _ _ _ $18,448.99 Legislative appropriation for two years ending March 31, 19 19 35,700.00 Expenditures, year ending June 30, 1917, for superintendence, clerical service, labor, lec - turers' and workers' services, expenses and printing __ _ _ _ _ J25.150.34 Appropriation balance _ _ 28,998.65 $54,148.99 $54,148.99 January 29, 1918. J. S. DALES, Financial Secretary. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>