<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Grand Island, Hall County, Nebraska BEING FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT —OF THE— Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Grand Island, Hall County, Nebraska BEING FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902 190! THE FR1MONT TaiBCHI Fftmotrr, Nib. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">• </seg>
            <seg id="p003">OFFICERS. A. V. Cole Commandant J. W. Bowen Adjutant H. L. Randall Surgeon Sarah E. Myers Matron. VISITING AND EXAMINING BOARD. John Reese President Sarah C. Sweet Secretary Robert S. Wilcox T. E. Hibbert Mrs. Belle C. Bolshuw </seg>
            <seg id="p004">• </seg>
            <seg id="p005">COMMANDANT'S REPORT. Headquarters Soldiers 1 and Sailors' Home, Grand Island, Nebr., Nov. 30, 1902. To His Excellency, the Governor, and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings: As commandant of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home at Grand Island, I have the honor to submit my report for the two years commencing December 1, 1900, and ending November 30, 1902. On assuming command of the Home February 1, 1901, I found that all of the funds appropriated by the legislature of 1S99 for the maintenance of this institution had been exhausted, the deficiency at that time amounting to $9,334.71, as shown by the records of the office. I With two months yet to elapse before the appropriation for ; next biennium would take effect, it placed the management no envious position. I mention these facts for the purpose of ling to your attention, as well as to the attention of the coming [islature, the necessity of making a more liberal appropria - n for the maintenance of this Home. On December 1, 1900, :re was a membership of 342. On November 30, 1902, there is a membership of 415, which shows an increase of seventy - •ee members, or 21 per cent; no doubt it has been presumed the past legislators that the old veterans, their wives and dows, were passing away so fast that the membership of the ldiers' Home would naturally decrease, but such is not the le; the older they get the more helpless they become, and it comes necessary for them to seek shelter in the Home that :y are justly entitled to. I Embodied in this report you will find my estimates for the ming biennium. I have been very conservative in making ;se estimates and I believe they are just. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">282 Land Commissioner's Report. (ESTIMATES.) Salary of commandant— Three thousand dollars t 3,000. (X&gt; Salary of adjutant— Eighteen hundred dollars 1,800.01) Salary of surgeon— Two thousand dollars 2,000. 0l&gt; Salary of matron — One thousand dollars 1,000.00 Salary of engineer— Fourteen hundred and forty dollars 1,440. in) Salary of night engineer — Nine hundred and sixty dollars 960. IN) Salary of farm manager — Nine hundred and sixty dollars 960.00 Salary of stenographer— Nine hundred and sixty dollars 960.00 For employes wages— Eighteen thousand dollars 18,000. 0i&gt; For maintenance and clothing — Sixty thousand dollars 60,000. (N) rfuel, engine oil, and repairs on steam plantr-Fifteen thous - and dollars 15,000.00 For drugs and instruments— Two thousand five hundred dollars 2,500. 00 For furniture and bedding — Two thousand dollars 2,000.00 For painting and repairs — Three thousand dollars. 3.000. 00 For stock and implements One thousand dollars 1,000.00 For sewerage— Five hundred dollars 500.00 For transportation— Two hundred dollars ..; 200. 0l&gt; For electric lights and repairs— Five hundred dollars f&gt;00.00 For visiting and examining board — One thousand dollars 1,000.00 For library— Three hundred dollars . . . 300 00 r express, telephone, telegraph and supplies — Seven hundred dollars 700.00 For laundry expenses— Three hundred dollars 300.00 For trees and improving grounds— Five hundred dollars M0.00 In addition to the above estimates, I wish to call your atten- tion to other improvements for the benefit of the Home, which I deem very essential; one of the most important, in my estima- tion, is a new building for the quartermaster and commissary supplies, the building now occupied as a commissary is an old wooden building, located in such close proximity to the main building that it is considered a fire trap. I therefore recommend that the wooden structure be removed and a good, substantial brick constructed in its place, sufficiently large to contain all the commissary and quartermaster stores; by doing this we can remove our clothing, furnishing goods, dress goods, etc., from the room they now occupy in the main building, which will give us an extra ward for members, the same being very much needed on account of the crowded condition of the Home at this time. I would recommend that an appropriation of at least </seg>
            <seg id="p007">oOIjUI bKo AND OAILOK.S XlOMIS* 283 ($4,000.00) four thousand dollars be made for the purpose of constructing the above named building. The old building now occupying the grounds can be removed to a suitable location and used by the farm hands and other employes as a sleeping room, and store room ; by doing this another room in the main building, now occupied by the farm hands, would be vacated. Permit me to call your attention to other very much needed mprovements, such as better fire protection, sewerage, and im - &gt;rovement of heating plant. I requested Joseph Burns, of Lin - oln, to make an estimate of the probable cost of improvements eferred to. Below I give you his report in full on the subject, le having given the matter a thorough investigation. BURNS' REPORT. !"I find it will cost to furnish your institution with a complete e protection for the main building, hospital, and cottages and irns, including three stand-pipes running from basement to of in the main building, with a lire plug on each floor, and ty feet of hose attached to each plug, to rest on brackets ways ready for instant use, and calls for 600 feet of hose in e main building. "You should have an 8-inch, cast iron pipe part of the way, nd 6-inch pipe the remainder of the line clear around the main milding and hospital, with eight double-nozzle tire hydrants et at various angles, and front and rear of the buildings; this will be connected with the fire force-pump, capable of throwing 00 gallons of water per minute against a pressure of 150 &gt;ounds to the square inch, the pump to be set in the engine oom and take the water from the stand-pipe and discharge it nder 150 pounds pressure on the fire. The outside hydrants o be set at least seventy-five feet from the building, so the heat n case of fire would not prevent operating them. You should lave at least 300 feet of standard fire hose, capable of standing pressure of 150 pounds to the square inch. then must have a line of four-inch cast iron pipe run - ig in the road west of the main building and north and south, protect the cottages, with five hydrants there at suitable dis- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">284 Land Commissioner s Iveport. tances to furnish the required protection; also run a main east with two hydrants, to protect the two buildings, also a line north to protect the barns, with a hydrant for each barn. This will cost $5,367.00, including new wells to replace those now in use that are worn out, and pumping sand cutting the pump cylin - ders, making the expense double what it should be to do the "To secure relief from the nuisance and threatened injunction from letting the sewerage run over the road and private ground, you must make a new channel similar to the one now in use, then build a dam at the lower end near the road to keep the sewerage on your own ground. When the new channel is fin - ished, turn the sewer into it, then pump out all the water or other refuse a pump will handle from the channel, letting it spread over the meadow; when all is out that a pump will han - dle, let it dry so that a team and scraper can clean it out, put - ting it as a fertilizer on the sandy ground. By using only one at a time and keeping it pumped out, a repetition of the present condition will not be possible. To do this work, provide a pumping plant to care for it in the future will cost approxi - mately $1,697.00. "Your boilers, to give the best results, should be raised and reset, the raising, resetting, and connecting up again I believe can be done for about $980.00; this includes new brick and new fire brick, which must be furnished to give a correct draft and get the best results from coal. "You ought to move the pumps and engine and dynamo from where they are now, as the dirt and grit wears the working &gt;arts; they should be moved in a new room. I would suggest lat the present laundry be given up for that, and a new room milt for a laundry away from the dirt of the engine room ; the ost of moving and building new foundations for dynamo, mmps, and engines would be about $425.00. The cost of small milding for a new laundry you can ascertain from some builder lere at the Island. I will say in conclusion, the changes 1 mention above seem absolutely necessary for the safety of the milding's and health of the inmates, and as there is no fire pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">285 tection now, should a fire occur when the water is low in the stand-pipe, it would not throw water to the top floor, much less the roof, and you have no method to work with, even with a full stand-pipe. "The new fire pump and pipe and hydrants included in the above give you as near an absolute fire protection as is possible to have. Joseph Burns." I recommend that seven thousand five hundred dollars ($7,500.03) be appropriated for the above purpose, and trust that the recommendation meet with your approval. The question of heating this institution has given me more worry than any other one thing. It seems to me that the amount of our coal bills are beyond all reason, and I am led to believe that the imperfect condition of our steam plant should be charged with the greater portion of this enormous extra expense. tin the matter of sewerage, no small amount of trouble has en given us; it is a nuisance as it is. Some provision should made for the accumulation from the sewerage pipes. I believe Mr. Burns' plan is a good one. Our present laundry is too small for the present membership of the Home; by building a new laundry room (the old one being next to the engine room) the old building could be used for the small engines and pumps now in the boiler rooms, thus protecting them from the dust and cinders of the boiler room. The roof of the main building is in very bad shape; all effort o patch it up so it would not leak have been fruitless. I am formed that it has leaked more or less ever since it was put n. I am of the opinion that the two towers built on said milding as ornaments are a damage to the roof and should be aken down, as the leaks are at the base of said towers. The oof on the old hospital is also in a leaky condition, caused by n immense rotunda built on top of the roof for show, the ame being covered with tin, which is decaying with rust, caus - ng the roof to leak badly. I would recommend that the use - ess ornament be removed from the roof. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">286 Land Commissioner s Report. The bath tubs used by the members in the main building are old, rusty iron. I have caused them to be dressed up with an enameled paint used for that purpose, but it proves to be of no account, wearing off in a short time. I recommend that the old tubs be removed and new ones substituted in their place. I further recommend that all buildings (including brick) be given at least two coats of paint; none of the brick buildings have ever been painted. I The new brick hospital is built of soft brick, the water oozes rough, thus damaging the wall. Two coats of paint would i of great benefit. The out-buildings are in poor shape; the most of them need repairing, especially the hog houses. The appropriation for paint and repairs was so limited that I was unable to make the necessary improvements. There is at the present time about two hundred acres of al - falfa on the farm, seventy acres of that amount was seeded this year; it is a first-class catch, having been cut twice this season. Alfalfa is the most profitable crop that can be produced on the place; it is excellent feed for cattle, horses and hogs. We win - tered thirteen brood sows on alfalfa hay last winter; fed them nothing else, and they came out in the spring in good, thrifty condition. We threshed from a part of our third crop, last year, 187 bushels of seed, which after seeding seventy acres brought $759.43, as shown by my cash statement. The hail storm which occurred July 4th, this year, damaged the Home very ma - terially; it not only caused an expense of $300.00 for window glass, but it damaged the roof to the engine house more than one hundred dollars; but the above were small matters when compared with the damage to the alfalfa crop; it destroyed the second cutting of alfalfa, or delayed the cutting for three weeks. In that way it was the means of destroying the seed crop, consequently I estimate the damage to hay and seed at ($2000.00) two thousand dollars. tWe have caused to be broken about seventy acres of new id for the purpose oP seeding the same to alfalfa next spring, t owing to failure of a seed crop this year, I would recommend </seg>
            <seg id="p011">287 that the new ground be cultivated into other grain until a seed crop is secured. Further along in this report you will find tabulated statements showing the amount of farm and garden products, as well as cattle, hogs, etc. The cattle are in splendid condition, also the hogs now on the farm. I The appropriation made by the legislature of 1901 for the ben - it of this institution was ($97,810.00) ninety seven thousand ght hundred and ten dollars; from reports on file in this office, find that the general government has paid into the treasury of ie state ($47,600.00) forty-seven thousand six hundred dollars, ius making the actual expense to the state for the maintenance : this Home ($50,210.00) fifty thousand two hundred and ten )llars for two years; thus you will see the old veterans of this ome cause to he paid into our state treasury nearly one-half of hat it costs to maintain, not only themselves, but also the wives id widows of their comrades. This is the third institution in is state, so far as membership is concerned, and for the above ason, I believe it is entitled to be recognized by the legislature r a more liberal appropriation. tl have attempted to make this report as brief as possible, and 1 1 desire to call your attention to the many needs of the in - tution. I In the management of the institution I have used my best ef - rts to economize without detriment to the men and women ider my charge, and in this I have been nobly assisted by Ad - tant General J. W. Bowen, Dr. H. L. Randall, the matron, ts. S. E. Myers, and all (other) subordinate officers, and I ke this opportunity to thank them for their faithful attention to eir respective duties, and to the Visiting and Examining oard I wish to extend my thanks ; harmony has prevailed at all nes between the management and the Board. tTo you, Governor, and the Board of Public Lands and Build - 's, I desire to express my sincere thanks for the courteous atment you have extended. Respectfully submitted, A. V. Cole, Commandant. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">From sale of hay 5.00 From sale of hides 18.37 rterial furnished A. C. JLederman Co. threshing alfalfa 28.08 From member's effect* 364.33 From premium on warrants^ 2 3-9* From sale of stock 164-45 From pay roll surplus 20.23 From miscellaneous sources I5-OO From sale of sacks 12.20 Found in unclaimed valise 5- 00 $ 664.47 $M°o-3S Iotal cash receipts to November 30, 1901 . . Total cash on hand from cash receipts • 1NANCIAL STATEME: f T FROM [ DEC. 1 1900, T&lt; NOV. 30, 1902. NAME OF FUNDS -a o. c B. S &lt;J x a oe tit 8 to 1 &amp; h x 5 z Officers' salaries Employes' wages Maintenance and clothing . Fuel, engine oil and re- pairs to steam plant . . . Drugs and instruments. . . . Furniture and bedding Stock and implements .... Sewerage Express, telephone, tele- graph and supplies Library Transportation Painting and repairs ( Visiting and Examining Board Electric lights and repairs Laundry expense Transplanting trees and improving grounds 1 mh.m 2182.65 1298.29 "i35;50 "3i!io "9!2O 16.54 $11960.00 15000.00 50000.00 12000.00 2000 00 1500.00 600.00 200.00 500.00 200.00 100.00 2000.00 $13580.00 17182.65 51298.29 12000.00 2000.00 1635.50 600.00 231.15 500 00 209.20 116.54 2000.00 $11586.66 14603.24 43594.00 11855 22 1894.74 895.24 611.70 139.50 522.78| 170.46 42.73 1964.78 $ 1993.34 2579.41 7704.29 144.7* 105. 2K 2S:S 1 800.00 300.00 250.00 800 00 300.00 250.00 793.56 154.06 95.04 - 22.00 400.00 422.00 312.85 109,5 •Deficit. CASH RECEIPTS AND DISBUJ 1900, TO NOV: ISEMEN1 SMBER 3) 'S FROM DECEMBER 1. ), 1902. December i, 1900 — Balance c; ,sh on ha nd $ 795.88 RECEIPTS FOR THE YEAR ENDING Ni 3VEMBER 30, 1901. From sale of old stoves $ 7.OO </seg>
            <seg id="p013">289 DISBURSEMENTS FOR THE YEAR ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1901 By L. A. Beltzer, commandant for December and January $ 39009 By A. V. Cole, commandant, paid employes 73.42 For food supplies 3235 For threshing alfalfa 187.50 Total $ 683 36 December 1, 1901 — Balance cash on hand from cash receipts $ 776 99 RECEIPTS FOR THE YEAR ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902. From sale of old wagon $ 5 00 From sale of hay 16.00 From sale of hides 121.97 From members' effects 93 47 From premium on warrants 40. 7 1 From sale of potato digger 7.00 From pay roll surplus 20.07 From miscellaneous sources I 9-°5 From sale of sacks 2 3-5&amp; From sale of alfalfa seed and sacks 766.23 Total cash receipts to Nov. 30., 1902 . $1,113.08 Total cash on hand from cash receipts $1,89007 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Land Commissioner's Report. 290 DISBURSEMENTS FOR THE YEAR ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902. For labor $ 329 89 For food supplio 327 75 For repairs 56.23 For building fenci 47-45 For hogs and pigs 183.50 For breaking prairii 99-75 For fire hose 11 3.40 For laundry supplies I 3&amp;S For roofing engine house J O5.55 For freight on flour 3I-5O For attorney's fees 25.00 For improvement of ground 45-OO For miscellaneous 15605 Total ' $1,534-9' Nov. 30, 1902 — Balance from cash receipts. $ 355-iS rounts in state warrants received to No - vember 30, 1902 $2,747.89 rount disbursed by 30,1902 vouchers to November 2,556-35 Balance on hand from warrants .... $ 191.54 Balance cash on hand Nov. 30, 1902 $ 546.69 VALUATION OF PROPERTY ON HAND NOVEMBER 30. 1H02 One hundred fifty-five head of cattle, of all ages, value . $3,490 00 Ten head horses, of all ages, value 480.00 One hundred thirty-seven head hogs, of all ages, value 880 00 Harness, robes, blankets, etc., valut- 81.00 Carriages, buggies and wagons, value 135-QO Mowers, hay rakes, stacking outfits and tools, valut . . . 129.10 Farm tools, value 40.00 Ice tools, value 1450 Clothing, groceries, flour, etc., value 1,050.00 Total $6,299.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">oOLDIERS AND oAILORS HOME. 291 (Hail storm July 4, 1902, destroyed all the garden stuff, and one crop of alfalfa hay, and all our ripening alfalfa seed.) GAINS AND LOSSKS FROM DECEMBER 1, 1900, TO NOVEMBER 30. 1902. AND DAILY AVERAGE PRESENT, AND PRESENT MEMBERSHIP. Male members present November 30, 1900 229 Female members present November 30, 1900 56 Total number 285 Male members absent November 30, 1900 50 Female members absent November 30, 1900 7 Total number 57 Total membership 342 Gain by admission lo November 30, 1902 — men 152 Gain by admission to November 30, 1902 — women 63 Total gain 215 Loss by death, men and women, to November 30, 1902 . 45 Loss by discharge, men and women, to November 30, 1902 95 Total loss 140 Net gain 75 EjU V7i&gt; i tic nuair, facuh ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902 1901 1902 Beef 860 lbs. ork 9,370 lbs. ilk 17,106 gals. Oate(inbdls) 18 tons Haifa bay 350 tons lfalfa straw 20 tons lfalfa seed 187 bus. Vairie hay 60 tons arden produce 'otatoes ■urnips 'urnips Onions S 51.60 589.55 2,052.60 90.00 2,275.00 360.00 937.50 360.00 433.53 13,734 lbs. 8,025 lbs. 19,711 gals. 400 tons 50 tons $ 888.M 521.63 2.SK.3. ta 250.00 47.00 MUM 40.00 30.00 37.50 1,200 bu. 200 bu. 300 bu. .-&gt;0bu. Value J. '$6,849.7* '$6,478.37 Total value of products for the two yei rs </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Land Commissioner s K-eport. 292 November 30, 1902 — men present 267 November 30, 1902 — women present 98 Total present 365 November 30, 1902 — men absent 46 November 30, 1902 — women absent 4 Total absent 50 Total membership 415 Daily average present from December 1, 1900, to No - vember 30, 1901 297 raily average present and absent from December 1, 1900, to November 30, 1901 372 Daily average present from December 1, 1901, to Novem - ber 30, 1902 331 3.V&gt; Daily average present and absent from December 1, 1901, to November 30, 190; 409 Average cost of daily rations for year ending November 3O» 19 01 *7 Average cost of clothing for year ending November 30, 1901 24.82 Average cost per capita for the year ending November 3O, 1901 185.46 Average cost of daily rations for the year ending No - vember 30, 1902 i6j4 Average cost of clothing for the year ending November 3O, 1902 17.06 Average cost per capita for year ending November 30, I 9O2 178.38 Eight men admitted have not reported. Five women admitted have not reported. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">293 MEDICAL DEPARTMENT. C»en. A. V. Cole, Commandant: Sir: — I have the honor to submit to you my report for e biennium ending November 30, 1902. There are at this time fifty-five men and twenty-five women carried on the hospital rolls and quartered in the hospital buildings. There are employed for the care of these, seven nurses: day — three male, one female; night — two male, one fe - male. There have been forty-five deaths since the last biennial re - port; forty since I took charge of the hospitals; seven occurred while they were on turlough, leaving thirty-three that died at the Home, of these one by suicide; eight were women. tTwo men and three women have been sent to the asylum, and o insane patients have died in the hospital since its manage - ;nt came into mv hands. February 1st, 1901, the date on which I look charge of the medical department, the morning hospital report shows that lere were fifty men and about twenty-three women in the sev - ral wards of the three hospitals connected with the Home. In ddition thereto there were several very sick in the cottages and much larger number of "outdoor" patients in the main build - ng, although the majority of them were able to visit the dis - pensary in quest of their medicine. One day I kept a record of orty-seven prescriptions made to those outside the hospitals. An epidemic disease of the respiratory organs prevailing at the me. But a very limited quantity of medical stores was turned over o me by my predecessor. Necessarily I had to order many emedies that were not specified in the contract for the first uarter of 1901, for which the contractor charged full retail rice, causing a heavy draught at once upon the appropriation made at that session of the legislature for this biennium, which was too small under ordinary circumstances to put this depart - ment in passable running condition. I was compelled to do without many necessaries to properly treat the sick and afflicted. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">294 With increasing age and its infirmities the membership of the Home forms, to a great extent, a community of invalids, and more medicine is issued to "outdoor" patients than to those in There was not then, and is not now, even a pocket case of in - struments with which to dress the minor surgical cases, much less, the graver ones. I was so cramped for funds that I have refrained from making purchases that are sadly needed. By the kindness of a medical friend I have been able to borrow instru - ments at different times, so that I have managed to get along in a parsimonious way. The appropriation by the forthcoming legislature should be liberal enough to enable the surgeon in charge to buy some of the necessities for the proper running of a hospital. For a modest supply of instruments and a few appliances for the proper care and treatment of patients, I would recommend $3000.00 (or at the very least $2500.00 is required) for the next biennium. I The greatly increased ratio of admission of members and their pidly increasing invalidism, from this time on, with the declin - g years of the veterans of the Civil War, will necessitate a uch closer attendance of the physician than in former years, he surgeon is required to live at the Home, who for a number years in the earlier history of the institution could live in the ty and do some outside practice, thereby making his profession munerative. 7 hat is now prevented by his almost constant ■esence needed at the Home. If "from any cause he is forced be absent from the institution, he must employ a physician in wn to answer all calls of emergency. For these and other asons that could be given, I think that the salary should be in - eased to $2500.00 for the biennium, which is but a paltry sum r an efficient physician. I would recommend that a carpet be put on the floor in the re - ception room of the new hospital. New matting is needed tor its halls, those now in use are utterly unfit, even dangerous, for the feeble paralytics and crippled patients to walk upon. Such is the condition of nearly all in this building. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">295 The range in the kitchen of the new hospital is too small by far for its use. It is but a six, while it should be a ten-hole range. The cook does the baking for this hospital, and the ca - pacity of the oven is inadequate for the present demands, there - fore I would recommend a change. t Certainly the defenders and saviors of the nation are as de - *ving of as good home comforts and medical attendance as any iss of citizens or wards in this commonwealth. Very respectfully yours, H. L. Randall, Surgeon. Grand Island, Nbbr., Nov. 30, 1902. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">4 I 0 c g&gt; • ■ g — 3 • C '• '■ p • gj ft g) fe § II I if a k i ? |-J ? gl?11. 1 1 ■*...** ■ * • • es ■ o -».iB ■ • j.-h • • a &gt;••-•■ -^ ■*. a •». • . c c .*- b . a jf ?Sg3?2SSSP£Ei5S?f23Eg^g;SS2:23J2i£S?P§ » 5 z ■ill mmmmmmm </seg>
            <seg id="p021">I I 4 3 1*1 1* o ■ en S u "= X g 3 - « 2 = g 5 -Q c c 1 X g 3 - V 2 3 0 5 JJ — . r * -~- . — salt 8 -!-! 3J?- 3j»S3— ooen t a £ 5o o Ca a 3. M S •j *j *■* s -* *-' ■ — "* *"* *"^ gj i" SSSgjS rill •^«.i s - III ■©«X— — i»~3T _, 3 C a « 1 3— i * X ■ a § — — — — T1TITI orT c4" i.'f -^ x" *J &gt; -» aT i I *- o • * C ." - * • — "" r J Z J 75 a a — 2^^« &lt; (tfoajrftf c 3S3B6 ■y . P — — i n - a E ll H 1 Z c^j — — — — O94M44O i r— r- i- t- it :o « 1 1 1 ** \\ i : : •&lt;4=&gt;^5 *» r^ o o rt o — o r^ r- t— i— o » • — i 9 a i i I I Z 2 5 IP I ■a a 0 ■ — • . • — « — -"*■ —" MPSVSSSS*? .."OQf ..I . . BeJtgeagas B § fl • «£^ - s +^~z -3'3~CSS33.S33 l5«S3 a3 33 X* Xi-s — i-ji-5&lt;&lt;&gt;-s'^50Z </seg>
            <seg id="p022">*9i Land Commissioner s Report. s IT 0 i l •e &gt;&gt; ST3 S «, ee 55 fill : ill iHliiIiilI hiJii M i ES-SSilfeSSSSSSl-SgtSfefECgfefeifc-Si ! -— &lt; *^ 3C iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii tf 4 , c * i»o§33 &gt; 2 5re§oaa3sS«|§c.'So*§oc.ci: | . : ; i \: . . I j j j , | \. . f 7^ : j i '■ ; : • »-^* ... (^..... ............. ; : ;■;■•• a •• t, ...■..•&gt;-.... -^ 8 f S££ 5CNKi-r-»ioo(SNHNtii*Ner-fHHHi-t-;i::i :- "" .- to j il e . MS *A £ &lt;* E &lt;&lt;&lt; ijiiiHiiiiiiiijiniiiiiiiij 2 : : •« : :oecri :::::■ : «/«•§ : :^&lt; :«* iiPIiiltfiiMlJ &lt;^%scssnnD3a333acQSC30QCQanaacccacssKcaa3 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">299 ♦a ■tS — ;£ ** ti — ** ** ■— — t£ tS — — &gt;»* yS .33 . . *^ . 72 *E3 iE "Es cS tE "SjS S -czE * iEE SiES sis j Ij— C «*^ ■*- S «C C — B A -* - *" "*• •*• •** ■*- B -*^ •*" E ■" — — "~ -~ ""~ -~ — IBliBSl?SIsI-«««ill|1iS8JiS|^f}«i - - *. ■ a*. ■ .«- • • • •&lt;►•*" • • c^ *- |HHrtHB H ».HH m -4-._,--rt-H-&lt;-^- 1 -lrt-H-H«-.H----- Zi-sSfc^S&gt;-si-»i-sQi- s &lt;j;-&lt;;o«^ 1 -5 &gt; -sD5CO-«6tiSS2^O 1 -s 1 -5OSi-si-9&lt;D 1 -s&lt; Q&lt;&lt;b^-J&lt; -Jd &lt;'J do fa &amp;Ja o* -J&lt; sc x, 'Jd n &amp; &amp;Toa"u &lt; &lt; « a: S 'J ssssssss^s^ss^-ss^x^s^iss^ss-s^S'j 1 -::- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">1 Q ■*"* *^ "5^ w w w w *^* E— E3 o- 0 - 3 - 0 £3 E 2 3E -° * S^ *■£ E&amp; B-* E -° ''•^ i * h %-2~z-z * h * * • ce «! *; ai-r ** «e— o— «s— i as— * be— §S3Fiel§SS§ciHllf»SllS1S§Sar§SI|£ ! I "s &lt; SJJSSII8SSSSS883SSJSSilS5SI8181SS i o •o ; i : ; : : : : : ; : ; ; ; ;::;;: : : * : ! ■ : : ; ; i : m | SfSSPS«SS«S«{e8?S*««86SB««**f&gt;«S3fl £ "• ,- &lt; • ■ : ■ 1 1 i I i • i Mx i ; i y : ; M ! ; ; ; I ; i ; : :« : : :^ : : : : : :§ : : : :-a&lt; : :^ : : : : :. : :"«» fiiittKIIifilKili </seg>
            <seg id="p025">301 Iiiiiilliiilllilililil?-iliiiirilillli liiallslllllll-sllllllilliW^MsJiii = r:-oi-K-M;:nii-jioi-i.'»it-or-'f-t-t;iict-it-t-s;ic-i- &lt; V m « : :"« ' :r\ " :oc li]*Si-fia j2i4l|rf5a l«-ldi e j s«4i jl" M — t-t.oo&lt;i)t.se330«»S5&lt;e«eo330o80oooooacd(e«e--x ■* •£ - r = SEB3S2sS 2g2S 323e3222=!S TSisj^:^- |BaBgg;aSg|igasg|-ggEgSSSsg|[!Egss2ss? — 25i2: CC:S i = - 3 — fc. = j; c = ,- ac = o = = = = -c_ :;:ii:; :: uS Btiss«Q«oiBo"fcdKd"&lt;s.'adQnDs'ii!&lt;o'c oftj &lt; d otfed &lt; &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p026">302 i- 5" ££ - 5 a? 1111 a 11 . iilll all ill ill § . a a— . — — i «e . — — c &lt;« ee oe o«— (ass u— * — — oe £— ce * o« B g* g g B g &amp;E- !! g£ S S 6 E fi S S-3 2 E g C e £ C S.g §&gt;B ! i i i » E ■ — &lt; 1 »-- fc S88SStS8 8 s § S e g S S S c S S 8 S S S 8 S S 8 8 &lt;C '&lt;*' 8 t S-; ?»M gt^f sf |l5"l S«|iililji 5l </seg>
            <seg id="p027">303 D*«S*a--i:i g . a .vex i; .;j;;i e.iiitiij, l °e3'3'5' o u' 3 "° .2 13 j» *o *o "O SS.JsS'Oo' 0 ■w_«'a"CT3t3'3-3-3 fi« S 6 S t £ S.2 g^'B |^&gt;g g g §■§ |.5&gt;1 B g- g |g &gt;-g g g g g g g Sj|2SSSS£SgS*gSSS*§sgS£S3S*§gSSSl5i5 *»Sx8SI»tSs»iJ*£?SJSx*£J**£J£»i*jilii ll^|s||^l!|M|i^ifi-?'l3^ssiiiifs5l •^ ' &lt; :~* - "5 i * .« 35 St. il li as fc « a^6 s .54|= §5 al Is t||.K S| a |ll!lll!illl!!lllllllj]lllll!fiil^i -*. &gt;■. --. -*. -\ --. -*. —. -*. — -J »J fc* *- *rf — — — ==-fl a'd" Jnf &lt; o"&lt; o &lt; -*«* a o o"ao*ca od ri &lt; bd &lt; &lt; - - h _' of &lt; rf = - e si =' £ Q SSSiSSSSSSSiSSS^SSS^gSt^SSSSPSSSSSJ r. ;-§.||z* -Xl \ : | : x </seg>
            <seg id="p028">304 t' 0 g &amp;£ E g I eil-1 El |g E g i|g I Eg tih% |g |E g = £ * £ S § £ S £ g £ 2 2 * £ S £ * * £ S s £ s £ g S* £ * S g t 3So2occ2o(too!SSotfoSSoo:2o2ois2oooBoB ! s I s •a I iliiillliiilllliliillilllillllll imziMimimmmiim % /■ * ES c S s fi -«g^«S?i^l|T:sr2^SPf.?:SSiSS?SPPSP^£-iz' I &lt; &lt; Ifl Illfl Fsliftiilii illlliHtlf II £ £ £ £ £ | £ £ i £ £ £ £ 3 SeSssS 3 g « 2gS 3 8 e'S bS e 3 ES = : : • • **&lt; "S ' "S '. '. '. '■ '• •■ • '• • • «- '■ '■ ' '.^ '.'.'. '. ■ '. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p029">305 « = 3Se!j BS SeSSesSS 2s3 e =S-g ES3S3SS2 c.2 g g BciS g|?Eggsegg |i:-i:-g^ 8 EgHgoEgggg-gg k «q"cq &lt; aa ?J «-,j af S c5« fan od fete 03 y ffldw o'JsJ rfri J -J Bfd -' -' M £P8£S3SS3£;!:£SES5£33?S33£5;S33£SSSP3L- j. &gt; m ...'.:: iii!II||lil3|ii!e4i!l!!fi^i!^-ir, S B E22S - {•§ g i3 § S 8.S3 S *5 § -5 5 S fil S-g E S?8 Si| S| </seg>
            <seg id="p030">s gxSSsSSE 32 «S3 2 sSS^ESSSB — -o -a "o -3 -o •« -2 •co'OTS'C_2'njcT3-a # aJ-3-s o'S'S cfl — — " « cfl c6 1' o -^ x "7 — ~- u cfi si -■ d aS s g i i 1 g g s ||g g| g g ht ht 2 S-I § it e a 3 § § &amp; § S S I * * S S S S § g I g S § § E S 3 5 S S i 1 E ■a &lt; iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii s s* ri if* 1 s ri -' Brf^ ?; -&lt; 3 "* '■'' s' If jS * :s sf rf rfrfrf 7 I I -= 5 ::::::::::: :J :! :::'::: !t ij : 0 E pi &lt; n* o M 4 &amp;.'^' PS 0 - - -=' rf«*rf!S d M tftftftf rf c jf SSgiSSSi'SSngSii'Si'gsgjyr-^S.?? — — — — 1 1 a — " ££ : : :o : : j : i^fcji ': ■** • g id i \ ': ! ! tii ilni Nllff Iliiliilf j s I * c c i = S «2 »£ s « j I iu.Sj; o «3 «£ *= J i 3 I </seg>
            <seg id="p031">307 THE WOMEN MEMBERS OF THE HOME. Anderton Susan Anthony Susan Allen Mary Ann Gelispie Mattie Gillet Valeria Geyer Sarah Glassford Sarah Henry Eliza Adams Elizabeth A. Abrams Hester Ames Etta Henderson MaryJ. Hagle Rosanna Brown Louisa Brown Elizabeth Bennet Margaret Hennet Kate Hughes Janie Hotes Sarah Hollowbaugh Emma J. Hunt Francis E. Barbee Melvina Burnett Charlotte Burns Mary E. Carlton Rebecca Coleman Sophia Colvert Mary Hall Phebe E. Henderson Elizabeth C. Jenkins Darthula Jackson Amanda Johnson Ellen Kirby Elizabeth J. Kinkead Sarah Landy Ellen Cumming Charlotte Coats Esther E. Chapman Anna M. Cooper Arcilla Lynch Johana Cole Elizabeth Dye Elizabeth Lapham Emeline Mouha Margaret Musser Henrietta Mullens Mary A. Dawson Louisa E Drake Sarah C. Darnell Sarah A. Deuel Nancy A. Emerson Priscilla Fry Agnes Mottinger Mrs M. E. Maine Eunice A. Moody Anna Me Anally Jane McKibben Eliza Norton Sallie A. Nail Sarah J. R etcher Wealthy A. ock Elvira French Laura C. Gray Mary Noell Louisa Olds Sarah A. Owens Carolina Orndroff Amanda Golway Olive Grove Mrs. A. L. Geis Eleanor </seg>
            <seg id="p032">308 i^AND V— OMMISSION ER S IVEPORT. Broken Bow, Neb., Dec. 4, 1902. To His Excellency, the Governor, and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Gentlemen: — In accordance with the laws of Nebraska governing Soldiers' and Sailors' Homes, the visiting and exam - ining board beg leave to make the following report, showing the condition of the Home and the substance of the proceedings had by the Board during the biennial period beginning Decem - .ber — , 1900, and closing November 30, 1902. We are sorry to announce the death on July 3, 1902, of our comrade Henry C. Russell, a member of this board. He was a valuable member, a good citizen and an honest man. I The board has made twenty-four visits during this time, eight which have been the regular quarterly meetings provided for r law. Sixteen have been auditing committee meetings, which immittee is composed of three membert of the board, who :amine all claims carefully before auditing vouchers. In Idition to auditing claims, this committee when composed of a ajority of the board, transact all business if an emergency hich could not be postponed until the regular quarterly Plant Mary Poor Louisa Painter Nancy Partridge Melissa Pierce Ruth T. W. Spink Charlotte J. Shipley Mary A. Tuffs Elizabeth Travis Anna M. West Elizabeth Pardo Martha Wilson Lizzie Phillips Mrs. E. J. Quick Mary E. Witting Rose Watson Louisa R. Kker Margaret :inhert Elizabeth Winslow Eugenia M Webster Francis Rowland Anna M. Rhodes Mattie E. Wolgamood Carolina Wolcott Catherine Reed Margaret Smith Sarah Smith Margaret Sturm Lucinda Wispal Hulda L. Young Margaret Young Sarah E. Yager Lottie </seg>
            <seg id="p033">oOLDIERS AND oAILORS nOME. 309 meeting without injury to the management of the Home. Also at each quarterly meeting we carefully inspect every department of the Home, hear all complaints that may be filed by any of the members or employes, dispose of the same and recommend such changes as we deem for the best interest of the institution. The board of purchase and supplies, on account of the meagre ppropriation have been compelled to purchase too cheap cloth - ng to keep within the appropriation. As the United States Government pays into the State Treasury the sum of one hun - red dollars per year for each soldier who is an inmate of these lomes, which is almost equal to one-half of the total cost of maintaining these defenders of our country and their wives, wid - ws and mothers, according to our judgment there should be a ufficient sum appropriated by the legislature so that there ould be a better quality of clothing purchased for the members. Two years ago it was said the membership of the Soldiers' Lomes had reached their limit, hence the appropriation need ot be increased, but we have seen the membership increase at us Home from 342 on December 1st, 1900, to 415 at the pres - nt time; and in our judgment the increase or demand for admis - on will be as great or greater in the next two years as in the &gt;ast. There is good reason for this, as our comrades are grow - ng older and less able to care for themselves, and their widows nd wives have nearly all reached the age, to-wit, fifty years, hich entitles them to admission provided they do not have the means of support or the physical ability to support themselves. We hope the present legislature will look, at this matter in its true light and do justice to the members of our Soldiers' homes. We find that the health of the members is good considering their age. There is the best feeling among the officers, mem - bers and employes in their intercourse with each other. All the officers are well qualified to fill the positions which they occupy, and are making every effort to administer the affairs of the Home so as to conserve the best interests of the state and the members. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">1-rfAND COMMISSIONER. S i\.EPORT* 310 As the details are fully reported and recommendations made n the report of the commandant, we deem it unnecessary to epeat the details and recommendations. We approve the ecommendations as to appropriations made by the command - ant, as we believe they are all needed and the Home is justly entitled to the amounts asked. Respectfully submitted, John Reese, President. Sarah C. Sweet, Secretary. R. S. Wilcox, T. E. Hibbert, Belle C. Bolshaw. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>