<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00054.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00054.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Secretary of State of the State of Nebraska for Twenty-Four Months ending November 30, 1924</title>
               <date value="1924-12-01">1924-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR TWENTY-FOUR MONTHS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1924 Charles W. Pool, Secretary of State TO THE GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Office of Secretary of State Lincoln, Nebraska December 1, 1924 ■ the Honorable, The Governor, Charles W. Bryan, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. Mv dear Governor I Conforming to the statutes of the Commonwealth, I have the honor resent herewith my report as Secretary of State for the State of ra.ska for the twenty—four months ending November 30, 1924. report contains an exhibit of the affairs of the office and the lod of conducting the same during the term now closing. tit further sets forth a statement of the number of corporations jrporating, qualifying, withdrawing or dissolving, the registration trade marks, the registration and renewal of brands, a classified ;ement of all moneys received by the office as fees, the amount of leys expended by this department, the granting of charters to chattel i organizations under the provisions of Chapter 204, Session Laws 1915, and a report of the Board of Pardons and Paroles. I In the interests of economy, we have abridged the report as much possible, eliminating several features that have heretofore been odied, which would increase the cost of publishing and are in them - es not of vital public interest. Respectfully submitted, CHARLES W. POOL Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">2 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE teath e.-itf SECRETARIES OF STATE TERRITORIAL ■ Thomas B. Cuming, August 23, 1854, to March 12, 185m. J. Sterling Morton, July 12, 1858, to May 6, 1861. Algernon S. Paddock, May 6, 1861, to Feb. 21, 1867. STATE i Thomas P. Kennard. from Feb. 21, lHtiT, to Jan. 10, 1871. Win. H. James, from Jan 10, 1871, to Jan. 12, 1873. Acting Governor, from June 2, 1871, to Jan. 13, 187c John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. Bruno Tzschuck, from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879. S. J. Alexander, from Jan. !». 1879, to Jan. 4, UML Resigned to fill unexpired term in Congress caused by the of James Laird. 11. Benjamin R. Cowdry, from Nov. 20, 1K89, to Jan. 8. LM1 Appointed by Governor Thayer to fill vacancy caused by tion of Gilbert L. Laws. John C. Allen, from Jan. I, MM, to Jan. 3, 1895 Joel A. Piper, from Jan. 3, 189f). to Jan. 7, 1897 William F. Porter, from Jan. 7, 1897, to Jan. 3, 1901. George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. 6, 19O'&gt;. A. Galusha, from Jan. 6, 1905, to Jan. 3, 1907 Geo. C. Junkin, from Jan. 3, 1907. to Jan. j, litll Addison Wait, from Jan. 5, 1911, to Jan. 7, 191i: Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 7, 1915, to Jan. 9, 1919. Darius M. Amsberry, from Jan. 9, 1919, to Jan. 4, 1923. Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 4, 1923. to__ 6. John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. 7. Bruno Tzschuck. from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879. 8. S. J. Alexander, from Jan. !», 1*79, to Jan. 4, ISKi. 9. Edward P. Roggen, from Jan 4, 1883. to Jan. 6, 1^7. 10. Gilbert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1XX7, to Nov. 20, 1889. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 3 STATE OFFICERS DURING BIENNIl'M Charles W Bryan, Governor Lincoln Fred G. Johnson, Lieutenant Governor Hasting.-* Charles W. Pool, Secretary of State Lincoln Geo. W. Marsh, Auditor Lincoln Dan Swanson, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings Fremont Charles D. Robinson, Treasurer Red Cloud O. S. Spillman, Attorney General Pierce Thorne A. Browne, Railway Commissioner Lincoln Charles A. Randall, Railway Commissioner Newman Grove H. G. Taylor. Railway Commissioner Central City John Matzen, State Superintendent Fremont I MTED STATES SENATORS George W. Norris McCook 1925-1931 R. B. Howell Omaha 1923-1929 CONGRESSMEN John H. Morehead Falls City First District Omaha__ Second District Willis G. Sears Edgar Howard __Columbus_ Third District M. O. McLaughlin York —Fourth District Ashton C. Shallenberger Alma Fifth District Scottsbluff Sixth District Robert G. Simmon \DMIMSTRATIVE BOARDS Of Hhifh the Secietary of S/ale is a Member I! iard of Equalization an I Assessment. Bnttrd of Educational Lands .ird Kun&lt;:.~. Board of Canvassers. Board of Pardons and Paroles. Board of Depository Bom OFFICE FORCE OF DEPARTMENT OF STATE Charles W. Pool, Secretary Lincoln Hugh L. Cooper, Deputy Tecumseh Charlotte R. Littlefield, Bookkeeper Lincoln Ruey B. Beach, Corporation Clerk Omaha Myrtle C. Bonner, Corporation Clerk Red Cloud Mabel Loveland, Correspondence Clerk Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE CORPORATION DEPARTMENT The table below sets forth the number of articles of incorporation amendments to articles of incorporation, appointment of agents, dis- solutions, etc. handled during the past twenty-four months: Domestic Corporations Total number of domestic corporations registered 3734 Number domestic corporations incorporated during biennium 37a Number domestic corporations filing amendments 273 Number domestic corporations voluntarily dissolving 321 Number of domestic corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes «9» Foreign Corporations Total number foreign corporations registered r&gt;12 Number foreign corporations i|ualified during biennium 12f&gt; Number amendments to appointments filed- 56 Number foreign corporations voluntarily withdrawing .",1 Number foreign corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes 102 Non-Profit Corporation* Total number non-profit corporations registered Number non-profit corporations incorporated during biennium Number non-profit corporations filing amendments Number non-profit corporation.- voluntarily dissolving Number non-profit corporations dissolved for non-payment taxes Grand total all corporations, domestic, foreign and non-profit. gaged in business at this date in Nebraska TRADE MARKS AND TRADE NAMES Total number of Trade Marks and Trade Names Number of Trade Marks and Trade Names filed during bienniu STOCK BRANDS This department is charged with the assignment and registration of brands used for the purpose of marking live stock, as by the statute - provided. The year 1922 was the year in which all stock brands were renewed. This renewal comes but once in five years. A summary of the business for the past twenty-four months is as follow Total number of brands registered 3*4H Number brands issued during biennium 74* Number brands renewed during bienuium .V27 FINANCIAL STATEMENT This office collects fees for filing articles of incorporation, corpora - tion permits, notary public commissions, registration of brands, certifi - cates of transcripts, trade marks, loan licenses under provisions of House Roll No. 44, Session Laws of 1915, etc. The following is a true and correct exhibit of moneys received during the past twenty-four months from all sources: </seg>
            <seg id="p006">RKPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE ■&gt; Total $ 23,239.26 ORGANIZATION OK LA FOLLETTE INDEPENDENT PARTY A new political party, the La Follette Independent Party, was or - ganized and the certificate of organization filed in this office August 2ti. 1!»24. INITIATIVE On July 3rd, 1924, there were filed in this office petitions request - ing that a proposed amendment to the Constitution of the State of Nebraska be submitted to the legal voters of the State for their ap - pro\al or rejection at the regular election to be held on Tuesday, November 4, A. D. 1&gt;»24. The number of signatures attached to these petitions were 44,000. Ballot Title Number 318-319 LOAN AGENCIES House Roll No. 41, Session Laws of 1915, provides for the licensing of loan agents or loan agencies, and is designed to regulate the loan - ing of money in small quantities upon chattel securities, salaries, etc. The bond to be given by the company is in the sum of $2,000.00 to be renewed and filed annually on March 1st. Under the provisions of this article, ten companies operated during the first year of the bi - ennium. and eight under the second year. The companies now operating Date licensed ELoan Company irantee Loan Company aha Loan Company -Omaha March 1, 1924 _0maha March 1, 192 t .Omaha March 1, 1924 Moneys Received Filing Articles of Incorporation and Amendments $ 33,685.7S Filing Appointments of Resident Agent 6,660.25 Non-Profit Corporation Permits 1,196.00 Domestic Corporation Permits 242.230.77 Foreign Corporation Permits 48,780.75 Notary Public Fees 4,672.00 Registration of Brands 1,382.54 Loan Company Licenses 1,020.00 Miscellaneous Fees 5,699.65 Total 1845,327.74 EXPENDITURES IHvember 1. 1922, to December 1, 1924 Salaries $ 11,253.32 Maintenance 4,902.6« Compiling and Printing Soldiers' Roster None Registering Brands 419.rt4 Initiative and Referendum 6,663.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE Peoples Loan Company- -Omaha March 1. 1924 -Omaha March 1, 1924 -Omaha March 1, 1924 Provident Loan Society (The)_ Rex Loan Company Tukey Mortgage Company Omaha Nov. 4, 1924 Farmers Loan &amp; Investment Company Lincoln March 1, 1921 These companies have been examined annually, as provided by law, and reports of examination are on file in this office Respectfully submitted. CHARLES W. POOL, Secretary of State BOARD OK PARDONS AND PAROLES Below is ,-hown a list of the number of applicants heard by the Board of Pardons and Paroles from the Penitentiary, Reformatory for Men and the Reformatory for Women, from December 1st, 1922, to December 1st, 1924: Total Number of cases in all heard fi4 Total Number of cases in all denied 17 Penitentiary Number of paroles granted Number of commutations grant* I Number of pardons granted- . Number of violators Number of violators returned k Number in custody ( waiting to b&lt; formatory for Men: Number of paroles granted Number of commutations granted Number of violators Number of violators returned- Number in custody (waiting to be returne Reformatory for Women: Number of discharges granted- bThis board is composed of the Governor, Attorney General and etary of State. The board meets th&lt;&gt; second Tuesday of each month ng the year, except in the month of August. The percentage of violations of paroles in Nebraska during thf past biennium is very low — 12.64 — or in other words less than thirteen ft of every hundred persons granted clemency have violated the con - ence reposed in them by the Board. This is a creditable showing compared with that of many other state?. Respectfully submitted, CHARLES W. POOL Secretary, Board of Pardons and Paroles. </seg> 
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>