<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska Tractor Tests 1920-1938</title>
               <date value="18??">January 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">¦ 'I. ' Bulletin 321 January, 1939 NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1938 ¦!¦¦'¦.'.". wavV Drawbar Test in Progress i ¦'¦.'.. • ; . .(: '¦¦..¦ ' :;¦" !¦ ¦' ' ..-..¦¦'¦. .'-''¦-' ¦'¦¦'¦¦ i . -, 1' ..¦'. i ¦ " ¦'-¦.¦"' ' v ' ! " The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln, Nebraska W. W. Burr, Director ! </seg>
         <seg id="p002">BOARD OF TRACTOR TEST ENGINEERS E. E. Bracket!, I. D. Wood, L. W. Hurlbut, C. W. Smith ENGINEER IN CHARGE OF TESTS Carlton L. Zink ASSISTANT IN CHARGE OF TESTS C. F. Adams CONTENTS Introduction 3 General Procedure and Rules 4 Belt tests 5 Drawbar tests 7 interpretation of Summary Sheet 9 Horsepower rating 10 Fuel economy 11 Horsepower 13 Drawbar horsepower 13 Belt horsepower 14 Drawbar Testing Equipment 17 Rubber Tire Tests 18 The Law 20 Tractor Specifications 23-45 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Nebraska Tractor Tests With the close o£ the testing season for 1938 came the end of the nineteenth year of tractor testing at the University of Nebraska. The num - bers of complete tests conducted and reported for these years are as follows: 1920 1921 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 65 15 5 I 12 10 8 12 15 7 16 1930 1931 1932 1933 1934 1935 1936 1937 1938 Total 10 14 12 : 9 11 17 28 jl9 19 ...304 This bulletin summarizes the results of 101 of these tests and includes data on all tractors reported by their manufacturers as on the market January 1,1939. If a tractor has been tested but is hot listed in this bulletin, the reader may safely assume that its manufacture has been discontinued. tractors tested are certified by their manufacturers as being stock - model machines, conforming to specifications filed with the application for test.lNo special or high-test fuels are used except in those cases where the manufacturer states in the application for test that they are necessary to insure satisfactory performance |of the engine. AH results shown on page 1 of tiie three-page reports are those actually attained in tests and are with - out correction or allowances fof friction, temperature, altitude, etc. Skilled operators employed by the University are in charge of the tractors when all testjresults are obtained. | I In the tests conducted from 1920 to and including the 1927 season, it was permissible to make carburetor settings for each individual load. Beginning with* 1928 the "one carburetor setting" was adopted and all results shown on reports of tests made from 1928 to 1934, inclusive, were obtained with the 'carburetor adjustment remaining unchanged throughout all parts of the 'complete test. A!s epjained on page 10, it was the practice from 1926 to 1936, inclusive, to determine the highest drawbar and belt rating per - missible under the rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers. The code as revised in 1(936 made no provisions for determining horsepower ratings. We use the same method outlined in the former code, however, in arriving at the calculated rating shown on the third page of the three-page test report andfin column three of the bulletin summary sheet. In determining the drawbar and belt ratings, runs! are made at a 100 per cent maximum car - buretor setting. The results of these runs did not appear in the test reports from 1928 to 1934 except in those cases where the "operating setting" was 100 (per cent. (See summary steet column 22 and page 6 of this bulletin.) Test reports issued I'm 1935-1938 inclusive, carried the 100 per cent in addition to the operating maximum test figures. The summary sheet issued witn this bulletin (No. 321) has been enlarged to include the results of testlß and test F (100 per cent: maximum belt and drawbar figures) on all current models of tractors testeli since March 1, 1930. i A three-page report of each test is issued soon after the test is com - pleted, and this bulletin is compiled from these reports. Copies of the original three-page reports are available at 5 cents perreport( on one trac- </seg>
         <seg id="p004">BOARD OF TRACTOR TEST ENGINEERS E. E. Brackett, I. D. Wood, L. W. Hurlbut, C. W. Smith ENGINEER IN CHARGE OF TESTS Carlton L. Z/nk ASSISTANT IN CHARGE OF TESTS C. F. Adams CONTENTS Introduction . . 3 General Procedure and Rules 4 Belt tests 5 Drawbar tests 7 Interpretation of Summary Sheet 9 Horsepower rating 10 Fuel economy 11 Horsepower 13 Drawbar horsepower 13 Belt horsepower 14 Drawbar Testing Equipment . 17 Rubber Tire Tests 18 The Law 20 Tractor Specifications 23-45 </seg>
         <seg id="p005"/>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 tor) from the Department of Agricultural Engineering, College o£ Agri - culture, Lincoln, Nebraska. By remitting $1.00 those desiring future re - ports without delay will receive for one year without further requests or other cost one copy of all reports or bulletins issued, referring to tractor tests; each one will be mailed as soon as possible after its release. GENERAL PROCEDURE AND RULES IN TESTING TRACTORS When a manufacturer wishes to test a new tractor, application forms are obtained from the Agricultural Engineering Department of the Uni - versity of Nebraska. These forms call for detailed specifications of the tractor to be tested. They are filled out and returned, together with a re - quest for the assignment of a testing date and check for $500.00 to cover the test fee. Dates for test are tentatively assigned in the order in which the application for test, specifications, and testing fee are received. The actual test date depends on the arrival of the tractor and suitable weather con - ditions. Tractors that are shipped by way of the C. R. I. &amp;t P. in Nebraska will be switched to the Agricultural College loading dock with minimum delay. It is assumed that the application for test is made by the tractor com - pany with the knowledge that it is not an experimental but an official per - formance test to be run under the tractor specifications submitted with the application and under the testing rules in force. One of the roles is that there shall be no revision of specifications after the test starts nor any change of parts or equipment except to make replacement for that which may be defective or broken. Experimentation desired by the manufacturer must be deferred until after the official test is completed and is then con - tingent on available time. All such experimental work is charged to the manufacturer on an hourly basis. Any data and results thus obtained--are for the information of the manufacturer and will not be includes! in the official report. \ A representative of the manufacturer should be present during the test. His duties include unloading tractor, installing wheel equipment or other accessories, operating the tractor during the "limber-up" run, making such adjustments as he may deem necessary before the test, making repairs when necessary during the test, and at the conclusion of the test disposing of the tractor. In addition to these duties, the manufacturer's representa - tive makes all decisions involving permissible choices or company policy relative to the current test which are not covered in the application for test. Before any tests are made the lubricating oil is drained from the crank - case and is replaced with new oil. This new oil is selected by the manu - facturer's representative from the brands generally available in Nebraska. It is of the viscosity specified in the application for)test and is^ purchased by the Tractor Testing Station in sealed containers. The oil is weighed and the weight per gallon at 60° F. is determined. All figures in the test report showing consumption of either oil, fuel, or water in gallons are based on the amounts used in pounds and the weight per gallon at 60° F. The fuel used is the lowest grade recommended by the manufacturer for use in the tractor being tested. For instance, if the application for test </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Nebraska Tractor Tests ,-¦¦" " state; that the tractor will operate on gasoline, kerosene, and distillate, distillate will be used. The gasoline used is of the lowest commercial grade available and in no case is a premium fuel used in an official test except in those cases where it is specified by the manufacturer as being essential to the successful operation of the engine. Fuels and lubricants are supplied by the University and charged jto the manufacturer at current prices. Test A.—The first run,is one made on the drawbar and is known as the "limber-up" run. The principal object of this test is to take out the stiffness likely to be found in a new machine and give an opportunity to check the condition of the tractor and ascertain if all the parts are working normally. The tractor is operated at approximately one-third rated load for four hours, two-thirds rated load for four hours, and full rated load for four hours. A reasonable amount of additional time is granted if de - sired; Each one of the forward gears is used for some i portion of this test. The I manufacturers' representative is responsible for the operation of the tractor during this test and may make such adjustments as he may feel are necessary, provided they dp not conflict with the specifications in the application for test. Adjustments that are permissible include setting the valve tappet clear - ancejand the gap of breaker points or spark plug points, adjusting the clutch, and making other adjustments of a similar nature. This shall not be interpreted to permit the installation.of new parts or accessories without having the same mentioned in the official report of the test. BELT TESTS ! ¦ The tractor testing engineer, then takes charge of the tractor and it is belted to the cradle-mounted General Electric dynamometer used in de - termining the belt horsepower. I Before any belt horsepower tests are run, the pop radiator tank is drilled to take an indicating thermometer, a fuel line is installed from tractor fuel system to the fuel-weighing equip - ment, and measurements are taken of the belt thickness and of the cir - cumference of both the engine and dynamometer pulleys. No allowances are made for belt losses. | Test B, 100% Maximum Belt Test—The engine is then run at full load until] it is thoroughly warmedjand has reached a condition of constant operating temperatures. All adjustments are made to secure maximum output from the engine at rated r.p.m. Rated crankshaft speed is that numl)er of revolutions per minute recommended by the manufacturer for normal operation. The governor is set to hold the throttle valve to the extreme open position, the spark is set to give the best results, the mani - fold Jieat control, if present, is set at the most favorable position, and the carburetor is carefully adjusted to that point at which an additional amount of. fuel: gives no increase but less fuel decreases the power output at the rated speed of the engine. After uniform operating conditions are, reached, this.test, known as the 100 per cent or rating maximum, is continued for two hours. The object of this test is to check or establish belt horsepower ratings. '.-. . ¦ .. , ' . ¦ : ¦ ¦ ';'..-.:. . ¦ , ¦ ' At ten-minute intervals readings are taken or observations made o£ engine belt pulley and brake speed, load on scale beam of dynamometer, </seg>
         <seg id="p008">NhBR-\sK\ Ac;riclltiral Experiment Station Bulletin 321 temperature of water in top tank of radiator, air temperature at a point approximately five feet in front of the center of the radiator, and amount in pounds of fuel used. Barometer readings are taken every hour. The water level in the radiator is measured at the beginning and at the end of the two-hour period, and the necessary amount of water is added to raise it to the same level as at the start of the two-hour test. Water, if used in the fuel mixture, is checked in the same manner. Results of this test are used in arriving at the "calculated" rating appearing on the third page of the three-page reports and in column 3 of the bulletin summary sheet. The manner in which this rating is deter - mined is explained on page 10. The observed maximum horsepower as determined in this initial belt test did not appear in the published report of each test nor on the summary sheet of the annual tractor test bulletin from 1928 to and including 1934 except in those cases where the manufacturer elected to use the 100 per cent or maximum power setting throughout the complete test. Test B has appeared on all of the individual test reports in 1935-1938 inclusive. The summary sheet of this bulletin (No. 321) has been revised to include Test B figures on all current models of tractors tested since March 1, 1930. On either the first or third page of the report and in column 22 of the summary sheet are figures indicating whether the carburetor setting used was 100 per cent or some lesser value. Test C, Operating Maximum Belt Test.—ln case the manufacturer wishes to use a carburetor adjustment leaner than the 100 per cent setting, a series of trial runs of 20 to 30 minutes at leaner settings are made and the manufacturer's representative is permitted to choose from these an "operating setting." This operating setting of the carburetor is used throughout the remainder of the test with the exception of the 100 per cent maximum drawbar test in rated gear (to determine the drawbar rating) when the adjustment used is the 100 per cent maximum power setting as obtained on the belt. The First run on this operating setting is a one-hour maximum power test known as the "operating maximum belt test." The object of this test is to determine the maximum power developed and the fuel consumption at a carburetor setting that is practical for field operations. The radiator cover, manifold heat control, and spark are set at the most favorable posi - tions, the engine is run until operating conditions have become stablized, and then readings are taken at ten-minute intervals over a one-hour period. Test D, Rated Load Belt Test.—The next belt test is of one-hour dura - tion and is known as the rated-load belt test. The object of this test is to determine whether the tractor will carry its rated load on the belt and to secure a record of fuel consumption and other operating data. The tractor is given, as nearly as possible, its rated load. The carburetor remains set at the operating setting. The governor is adjusted to maintain rated engine speed at rated load. Rated load is determined in one of two ways. If the tractor is rated by the manufacturer, sufficient load is applied to develop rated horse power at rated engine speed. In case the manufacturer either </seg>
         <seg id="p009">i Nebraska Tractor Tests not specify the rating of the tractor or elects to accept the "calculated" g, then rated load becomes 85 per cent of the corrected maximum as calculated from the results of the 100 per cent maximum belt test. Test E, Varying Load Belt Test— The last run on the belt is known as the varying-lpad test.; The jcarburetor setting and ignition timing are the same as in the rated-load test. The. object of this test is to show the governor control of the speed'and also fuel consumption when the load varies. It is comprised of. six twenty-minute runs made in the following order: The first is rated load, which is the same load as the one-hour rated loadl test just completed; in fact, if conditions are favorable, the rated and varying load tests are continuous and the last twenty minutes of the rated - load run are used for the first twenty of the varying-load test. This is fol - lowea by twenty minutes at no load. The minimum load is applied and the (power developed is approximately one horsepower. The next load applied is one-half of the rated-load torque arid this is followed by a maximum horsepower test in which enough load is applied on the dynamometer to pull the engine far enough under rated speed to insure an Extreme throttle opening. The last two runs are made at one-fourth and (three-fourths rated-load torque respectively. During the varying-load test the amount of heat applied to the intake manifold may be changed according to the load if an easily controlled manual adjustment, such as a lever operating from the drivers' seat, is pro - vided. An effort is made to maintain the recommended temperature of the cooling medium when possible, by regulating the amount of covering on me radiator in those cases where an adjustable cover is provided. These adjustments, we feel, require no more attention than may reasonably be expected from a careful operator. • End of Belt Test— When possible, the friction horsepower and the compression pressure at rated engine speed are checked at the end of the varying-load test. These figures do not appear in the report of the test but are useful in checking the mechanical condition of the engine before starting the drawbar test. . j;. ..'..- DRAWBAR TESTS : Test F. —The first drawbar, tests made are maximum horsepower runs at two carburetor settings, operating and 100 per cent,* The 100 per cent maximum test is made in one gear;only, that designated by the manu - facturer as most suitable for plowing or. ordinary farm work. It is com - morly known as "plow gear," "working gear" or "rated gear." The re - sult: of a test in this gear, with the carburetor adjusted at 100 per cent as fourd on the belt, are used to determine the "calculated" drawbar rating. The observed 100 per cent maximum drawbar horsepower is corrected to stankrd conditions, multiplied by 0.75, and the result is the "calculated" rating. This is explained in detail on page 10. The results of this rating maximum test have not appeared in the published report of each test nor in the summary sheet of the annual tractor test bulletin from 1928 to and including 1934 except in those cases where the manufacturer elected to use the 100 per cent or maximum power setting throughtout the complete </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 test. The summary sheet of this bulletin (No. 321) has been revised to in - clude Test F figures on all current models of tractors tested since March 1, 1930. The manufacturer's representative is permitted to select the tire, wheel, lug, and extension-rim equipment from that supplied on stock tractors or that regularly offered to the trade in Nebraska but at extra cost. The same tire or wheel and lug equipment must be used on all the drawbar tests. When drawbar tests are made on rubber tires, additional weight may be placed on the rear wheels or rear of the tractor. The total weight on the rear wheels is not to be in excess of die tire manufacturer's recom - mendations. In the case of the crawler tractors, a choice may be made in the type and width of track and the type and size of cleats, subject to the same restrictions as obtain for wheel tractors. The drawbar specifications as to dimensions and adjustments for height and point of attachment must be the same for all of the drawbar tests. They must also conform to the specifications in the application for test. Test G, Operating Maximum Drawbar Test. —Operating maximum drawbar tests are made in the forward gears, using the operating car - buretor setting selected and used on the operating belt tests. The object of these tests is to determine the maximum horsepower the tractor will develop in each forward gear with the carburetor adjusted at the operating setting with engine running at rated speed under the prevailing tempera ture and barometric conditions. After die tractor is thoroughly warmed and brought to a condition of constant operating temperature, at least two suitable drawbar runs are secured over a measured distance of 500 feet on the testing track. A suitable run is one in which the operating tem - peratures are normal, the throttle is open to the extreme position, the load is relatively constant, and the average engine speed is at or very close to that specified by the manufacturer. Very seldom is a pull used in which the variation from rated speed is more than one per cent and in each test in each gear an attempt is made to obtain an average number of revolu - tions per minute, which does not deviate from rated speed more than one-half of one per cent. Occasionally there is not sufficient traction with steel wheels to hold the engine speed down to the rated figure at wide - open dirottle without producing slippage of approximately 20 per cent or more. In such cases the throtde is closed to that point where the slippage is a reasonable amount or something less than 20 per cent. The method used in making maximum drawbar tests on rubber tires is explained in detail on page 18. Test H, Rated Load Drawbar Test.—The last run made on the draw - bar is the rated-load test. The duration of the test is ten hours' actual run - ning time (as nearly continuous as possible) with constant load. A record is made of the time and reason for each stop, and also of any adjustment or repairs made on the tractor. The object of this test is to determine whether the tractor can pull its rated load continuously and to secure a record of fuel consumption on drawbar work. The governor is adjusted to give rated speed of the engine with the tractor pulling rated load and in the gear recommended for plowing or ordinary farm work. The' car- </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Nebraska Tractor Tests buretor remains at the operating setting. Rated load is determined in one of two ways. If the tractor is rated by the manufacturer, sufficient load is applied to develop rated horsepower at rated engine speed in rated gear. In case the manufacturer either does not specify the rating of the tractor or elects to accept the "calculated" rating, then rated load becomes 75 per cent lof the corrected maximum as calculated from, the results of the 100 per cent maximum drawbar test in rated gear. ':' Once each hour during the rated-load drawbar test a chart is taken, by means of the graphic recording drawbar dynamometer, of the drawbar pullj observations are made of the time required to travel 500 feet, the revojutions, of the drive wheels over this same measured course, and the temprature of the air and cooling medium. From the chart and observa - tions, calculations are made for the drawbar pull; in pounds, the rate of travel in feet per minute anii miles per hour, the drawbar horsepower, the engine revolutions per minute, and the drive-wheel slippage in per - centage. The testing operator I maintains the load as nearly constant as possible and by following the progress of the test applies such a load as will be sufficient to develop horsepower "equal to or slightly in excess of ratec horsepower. END OF TESTS At the conclusion of the rated-load drawbar test the lubricating oil is drained from the crankcase and weighed, the specific gravity at 60° is determined, and the number of gallons drained is calculated. A record is kept| throughout the test of all oil added or drained. The test report shows the total number of gallons of riew oil put in the crankcase and the gallons of used oil drained. : . At this time the tractor is inspected. The manufacturer's representa - tive, when so directed by the engineer in charge, disassembles any part of the tractor, or its accessories in order to facilitate inspection. Particular attention is centered on such specifications as clearance volume, valve and port dimensions, bore and stroke, transmission, differential and belt-pulley reduction ratios, and the condition of such parts as valve heads and seats, spark plugs, magneto or distributor breaker points and fuel, oil, and water connections. During the drawbar tests, or on their completion, the tractor is driven to a government-inspected farm scale on the Agricultural College campus and weighed. The weight which appears in the test report is the observed weight plus the weight of the 'operator and the amount of fuel necessary to completely fill the fuel tank.' , When all of the tests have been completed and the inspection made, the engineer in charge may release the tractor to the manufacturer's repre - sentative or at his discretion may withhold the release until the test report is issued.' ¦ • ¦¦¦•'¦/ |- ¦• .¦ ' '•¦ ¦' - : ¦¦' . ' • ¦¦¦ I INtERPREtATION OF SUMMARY SHEET Name, CoL I.—The tractor |name as it appears in the body of the sum - mary report is the name by which it was known when the machine was tested. If it has been changed, the same has been noted below. </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 Horsepower Rating by Manufacturer, Col. 2.—This is a figure deter - mined by the manufacturer as being a reasonable output for the engine. The figure appearing first is the drawbar rating and the second is the belt rating. Horsepower Rating, Calculated, Col. 3.—For several years the A.S.A.E. and S.A.E. codes were quite generally accepted as the standard for tractor rating. These two groups, the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and Society of Automotive Engineers, revised their Tractor Test Code in 1936 and it no longer makes any provision for determining either belt or drawbar horsepower ratings. We have, however, in the Nebraska Tractor Tests continued to use the same method of determining belt and drawbar ratings as was formerly embodied in the A.S.A.E. and S.A.E. codes. These ratings are somewhat kss than the maximum horsepower output of the tractor in order that the operator may be sure of having a certain amount of reserve for emergencies. The belt horsepower rating is 85 per cent of the maximum corrected horse - power obtained by correcting the observed horsepower in Test B to stand - ard conditions (60° F. and 29.92" Hg). The drawbar horsepower rating is 75 per cent of the maximum cor - rected horsepower obtained by correcting the observed horsepower in Test F to standard conditions (60° F. and 29.92" Hg). The correction formula used is as follows: BHPc = BHPo X (Ps - Po) X V To H- Ts where BHPc = corrected brake horsepower BHPo = observed brake horsepower Po = observed barometric pressure in inches of mercury Ps = standard barometric pressure in inches of mercury To = observed absolute temperature in degrees Fahrenheit Ts = standard absolute temperature in degrees Fahrenheit The following is a typical application of the correction formula: Let us use Test 303 as an example. Looking at Test B on page 1 of the four - page report, we find that the BHPo = 25.45 horsepower Po = 28.740" of mercury Ps = 29.920" of mercury To = 81° F. 4-460° F. = 541° F. Ts = 60° F. + 460° F. = 520 oF. -g-UMO. V 1.0404 = 1.0200 The correction factor is 1.0411 X 1.0200 =1.062 Then BHPc = 25.45 X 1-062 = 27.03 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests The corrected brake horsepower is sometimes known as "sea level" horsepower, or the amount of horsepower developed under "standard conditions." | The "calculated" belt rating is obtained by multiplying the corrected horsdpower by 0.85. In this case the rating would be 27.03 X 0.85 = 22.98. Test F, 303, shows a maximum observed drawbar horsepower of 18.72, air temperature of 83° F. and barometer reading of 29.000". The correction factor is 1.054 and that multiplied by 18.72= 19.73 maximum corrected drawbar horsepower. The "calculated" drawbar rating is 19.73 X 0.75 = H.8(J..;- ¦ ¦-,-¦•. - . ;,¦ ..;.¦¦¦¦•¦ .'• ' '. . : : \jfeight as Tested, Col. 4.—This is the weight of the tractor and full fuel tank, full radiator, operator, and such attachments as are necessary in the testing procedure. The total weight of these attachments varies from 30 tol 40 pounds. \ ¦• kated R. P. M., Col. 7.—ln this column appears the speed recommend - ed by themanufacturer as the rated engine speed. In some instances a range of speeds may be recommended but for the purposes of this test it is necessary that some one rated speed be selected by the manufacturer. The manufacturer's specifications as to drawbar pull, rate of ground travel, pulley speed, and belt horsepower are all based on the rated engine speed. Fuel Used, Col. 9.—The manufacturer specifies the grade of fuel that may be used in a tractor. In jthe event that machines are sold to burn several grades of fuel, the lowest grade is used. High-test or special fuels are used only when specified by the manufacturer as being necessary to the successful operation of the engine. Oil, Cols. 10,11,12. —The vjiscosity of the lubricating oil used conforms to the manufacturer's specifications and the brand is one selected by the manufacturer's representative from those available in Nebraska. The gal - lons of oil placed in and drained from the motor are calculated figures obtained from observations of weight and the specific gravity of the new and used oil. ) Belt Horsepower, Cols. 14,23, 31.— 1n these columns are figures indicat - ing the horsepower delivered at the end of the belt under the conditions existing at the time of the test. See pages 13 to 17 for detailed explanation of horsepower. ¦:¦.. ' -¦ Average Engine Revolutions per Minute, Cols. 15, 24, 32, 74. —An at - tempt is made to maintain such loads and such governor adjustments on rated runs as will result in a deviation of not more than one per cent from rated speed. Fuel Economy Figures, Cols. 16,17,18, 25, 26, 27, 33, 34, 35,76, 77, 78.-rThe amount of fuel used is expressed in three ways. The first term is gallons per hour. Comparisoi s with other tractors as to relative economy are not readily made with this expression of fuel consumption because the amount of power developed is not included in the term. Two other expressions of fuel economy, horsepower hours per gallon and (pounds per horsepower hour, both allow direct comparison to* be made between two machines. A horsepower hour is the term applied to the arithmetical result of horsepower multiplied by time in hours. Ten horse- </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nlbraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 power hours might come from the development of ten horse power for one hour, lroin one horsepower to ten hours, from two and one-half horse - power for four hours, or from any other combination of horsepower and hours which, when multiplied together would equal ten. Then, if by the burning of a gallon of fuel one engine is able to develop eight horsepower hours and another burning the same amount of the same fuel will develop eleven horsepower hours, obviously the second engine has the better fuel economy. In other words, the larger the number of horsepower hours per gallon, the better the fuel economy. The third term, pounds per horsepower hour, expresses the amount of fuel used to develop one horsepower for one hour. The smaller this value, the better is the fuel economy. Pounds per horsepower hour may be readily converted into horsepower hours per gallon by dividing the weight of a gallon of the fuel used by the consumption in pounds per horsepower hour; or, conversely, dividing pounds per gallon by horsepower hours per gallon gives pounds per horsepower hour. Some like to compare tractors on the cost per horsepower hour basis. For instance, two tests might have been made on the same identical trac - tor, one on gasoline and the other on distillate. Let us assume these very reasonable figures: That on the operating maximum belt run, the distillate test shows 10.00 and the one on gasoline 9.00 horsepower hours per gallon. Then if distillate costs 10 cents per gallon and gasoline 14 cents per gallon, the cost per horseower hour for distillate would be 10 cents divided by 10 horsepower hours per gallon, or 1 cent per horsepower hour; and for gasoline, 14 cents divided by 9 horsepower hours per gallon or 1.56 cents per hourscpower hour. This fuel saving made possible by the use of low - grade fuel would be offset to some degree by the cost of the additional lubricating oil required when making the more frequent oil changes or - dinarily considered necessary when using the lower-grade fuels. Another controversial point is whether or not the use of distillate materially shortens the life of a tractor as compared with the service that can be obtained when using gasoline. We do not have a conclusive answer as to how much greater the maintenance cost would be, if any, when burning distillate in an engine designed for it than when using gasoline. Diluted lubricating oil, if clean, apparently does not produce the rapid wear once attributed to it. To burn low-grade fuel successfully, proper cooling medium and in - take manifold temperatures must be maintained. This may be readily done when operating at a steady load, but for intermittent operation, gasoline is unquestionably more satisfactory than distillate. The most favorable operation can be obtained from any fuel when used in an engine that is particularly designed for it. Water Used, Cols. 19, 28, 36, 79. —These figures indicate the amount of water used in the cooling system and, where water is used with the fuel mixture, include that also. Temperatures, Cols. 20, 21, 29, 30, 37, 38, 80, 81.—The atmospheric temperature as recorded is the average for the test. There may be consider- </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor Tests . . /|. . . j : : '- able variation of temperature from the, beginning to the end of the run, particularly on the ten-hour rated-load drawbar test. The cooling medium is maintained as nearly as possible at the temperature recommended by the manufacturer. Only such iccessorics as are standard equipment are used to maintain this regulation. j Carburetor Adjustmen for Percentage of Maximum, Col. 22.—A tractor is not ordinarily required! to develop its maximum horsepower. There is a point in the range of trie carburetor adjustment where the tractor will develop nearly its maximum horsepower arid still use considerably less fuel than it does at the pointy of maximum output. This point is determined by nrining- a series of be|t tests' at various carburetor settings. The manu - facturer's representative then selects some carburetor! adjustment as the operating setting. It is identified by dividing the horsepower obtained at this pomt —the point of operating.setting—by the: horsepower at the 100 per cent setting and multiplying the result by 100. This percentage figure appears in column 22. 1 I ¦yarying-Load Revolutions per Minute (High and Low), Cols. 39, 40.— These are the extremes of the crankshaft revolutions per minute for the varying load, testE, as obtained with the variation of load applied to the tractor. The figures are an indication of the governor control of the motor speed. . .:• . ¦. : ¦ •-•".¦-¦' -"• '¦ ¦¦'¦ ¦¦'••¦¦¦¦'.'- ¦•¦"'¦• Drawbar Horsepower, Cok. 42, 46, 50, 54, 58, 62, 66, 71.— 1n these columns are figures indicating the amount of horsepower delivered at the drawbar under the conditions existing at the time of test. See pages 13 to 17 for detailed explanation of horsepower. &gt; • Drawbar Pull, Cols. 43, 47,51,55, 5% 63, 67, 72.—These figures are the average pull exerted by the tractor under the described conditions. jililes per Hour, Cols. 44, 48, 52, 56, 60, 64, 68, 73.—These speeds are calculated from observations ofj the time required to travel, while pulling the described load, a distance of 500 feet. Slip of Drivers, per cent, Colls. 45; 49, 53, 57, 61, 65, 69, 75.—These are average slippage figures. The manner in which they are obtained is dis - cussed under "Drawbar Testing Equipment." HOTSEPO\TOR Horsepower is ia rate of doing work, and work is a force acting through a distance. For instance, a force of 150 pounds acting through.a,distance of 10 feet would do 1,500 foot pounds of work. However, unless we know the length of the time in which the work is done, we do not know how much power is developed. If,' in one case, the work is done in two minutes and in another only one minute is. required, then the amount of power developed is twice as great in the second instance as in the first. To develop one horsepower it \yould be necessary to do 33,000 foot pounds of wjork in one minute or 5:50 foot pounds in pne second.. Drawbar Horsepower.—Suppose we. wish to determine the drawbar horsepower required to pull a three-bottom plow three miles per hour. First, we shall have to assume that the draft per bottom is some value, let </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 us say 600 pounds. This, of course, will vary with the type and condition of soil, the depth and rate of plowing, and the condition and adjustment of the plow. If each bottom has a draft of 600 pounds, then the total pull required is 1,800 pounds. One mile per hour equals 88 feet per minute and three miles per hour equals 264 feet per minute. Then 1,800 pounds acting through a distance of 264 feet in one minute equals 475,000 foot pounds of work done per minute, and 475,000 divided by 33,000 equals 14.40 horsepower. If it were desired to pull the same number of pounds half as fast as before, then only 7.20 horsepower would be needed. If the rate of travel were twice as fast, or six miles per hour, then 28.80 horse - power would be required to pull the 1,800-pound load. The work done at the drawbar or on the belt is known as useful work. Non-useful work is done in moving the tractor, in flexing the belt about the pulleys, in slippage both of the drive wheels and of the belt, and in overcoming friction in gears and bearings. Improved gear and bearing design and materials, as well as reduction of tractor weight, have brought the useful drawbar horsepower of the modern tractor much closer to the belt horsepower than was true in the early models. Work also is done in overcoming the internal friction of the engine caused by piston-cylinder contact, connecting rod and main bearing friction, and the resistance of other moving parts. The use of rubber tires reduces the rolling resistance of a tractor, or in other words, less power is required to move the tractor over the ground than when steel wheels and lugs are used. This leaves more engine power available for useful work at the drawbar and accounts for the superior fuel economy of rubber over steel, particularly in the higher gears. Belt Horsepower.—The point of maximum available horsepower of an engine is at the flywheel. Few current tractors are designed, however, so that the belt pulley may be attached directly to the flywheel. The belt horsepower must pass through one set of gears and sometimes more before it is delivered to the belt. The belt horsepower figures shown in our re - ports are obtained after the power has been transmitted through the belt and the driven pulley and they represent the amount of power available for useful belt work. In an analysis of belt horsepower, there are the same factors—force, distance, and time —as in drawbar horsepower. Force is represented by the number of pounds of effective tension in the belt and the other two, distance and time, are the number of feet of belt travel per minute. The rate of belt travel will be controlled by the size and speed of the tractor belt pulley. For each revolution of the pulley the belt will be advanced a distance equal to the circumference of the pulley. Then, the revolutions per minute of the tractor belt pulley multiplied by the pulley circumference will equal the belt travel in feet per minute. This is assuming there will be no belt slippage. Actually the slippage will vary from 1 per cent to 5 per cent and with any given load will depend on the tightness of the belt as well as the size and condition of both pulleys and belt. With few exceptions the belt slippage on the official tests is held to 1 per cent or less. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Nebraska Tractor Tests While manufacturers have used a fairly uniform belt travel throughout their own line of equipment, belt speeds as found on the various makes range from 2,450 to 3,400 feet per minute. This often proves troublesome and I confusing to the operator, who may have a tractor made by one manufacturer and belt-driven machines purchased from one or more other concerns. : For instance, of two popular general-purpose-type tractors of the 2-3 plow size on the market, tractor A has a belt speed of 2,450 feet per minite and tractor B 3,300 feet per minute. Here is an example of what may and quite often does happen. Tractor A is used to operate an ensilage cutter which is designed to run at 650 r.p.m. If we divide the belt travel, 2,450, by 650, the result is the circumference of the cutter pulley, or 3.77 feet.) The circumference of a circle equals the diameter times 3.1416 or expressedin a formula: -. :.¦¦¦ . ¦¦¦/". , ': ¦'¦: C=;tD ' '¦¦'. ¦ ¦¦';' . -¦'].'.'' ¦ . ¦ . where C =circumference ;¦'-:.,. '¦ -¦¦ ¦ - ...: ¦.- jt=3.i4l6 -¦¦¦;. - .¦•.¦.•.¦-,¦ ;¦¦• D=diameter • Then it is also true that ' ¦¦¦¦'. \. ' .- ¦."¦¦" &#132;' '.'.. d=ca :. . ¦ . ¦• • Then 3.77 feet, the cutter; pulley circumference, divided by 3.1416 equals 1.20 feet, or, multiplied by 12, approximately 14 x/i inches. Either a 14-or a 15-inch pulley might be used on the cutter, although the smaller size would be preferable since it would run a little faster, and compensate for jelt slippage. . . Suppose now that, for one reason Or another, the operator wishes to use tractor B on the cutter and he does not change the cutter pulley to the proper size. If he selected a 14-inch cutter pulley for tractor A, then the circumference in feet is 14 X 3.1416 divided by 12, which equals 3.67 feet But tractor B's belt speed is 3,300 feet per minute and 3,300 divided by 3.67 equals 899 revolutions per minute, or an overspeed bf approxi - mately 250 revolutions. | The power needed to operate the fan represents quite an appreciable pan. of the total power requirements of an. ensilage cutter. An overspeed of 35 to 40 per cent would probably not affect the cutting mechanism a great deal, but the fan would consume from two to two and one-half times as much power as at the rated speed. This means that tractor B would be able to operate the cutter at only a fraction of its normal capacity,-since the excessive power requirements of the higher, fan speed would leave less power available to cut the ensilage. If the fan blast at 650J r.p.m. is sufficient to blcjw the ensilage into the silo, then power is wasted if the fan is run at a higher rate. . An alternative would be to reduce the tractor engine speed to about 70 to 75 per cent of its rated value; The cutter would then run at the proper speed but the engine power at this reduced speed would be so much less that the cutter could not be operated at normal capacity. The </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 logical thing to do would be to install on the cutter a 19- or 20-inch pulley, because 3,300 s- 650 = 5.08 feet and 5.08 X 12 -3.1416 =19.40 inches Proper pulley sizes are very important on many machines, in addition to ensilage cutters. Some ot those more sensitive to speed changes are the threshers, hullers, hammer grinders, and irrigation pumps. For instance, on one popular 6-inch horizontal centrifugal pump opera - ting against a 40-foot head, a speed change of 55 revolutions per minute, from 940 to 995, would produce 900 gallons per minute instead of 400, the horsepower required would rise from 7.5 to 12, and the pump efficiency from 54 to 76 per cent. By increasing the speed from 995 to 1065, the pump would deliver 1200 gallons per minute at a power requirement o£ 16.9 and the pump efficiency would drop to 72 per cent. The total speed change of 125 revolutions, 940 to 1065, would increase the pump discharge from 400 gallons per minute to 1200, and the power required would vary from 7.5 horsepower at the low speed to 16.9 at the higher figure. Variations in the amount of head against which the water must be pumped influence the power requirements. Other performance figures on this same 6-inch pump show that 1.45 horsepower will deliver 400 gallons per minute against a 10-foot head at a pump speed of 510 revolutions per minute and an efficiency of 70 per cent, while to pump the same amount of water against a head of 100 feet would require 24.7 horsepower, a pump speed of 1,485, and the efficiency would be 41 per cent. If when pumping against a 100-foot head the pump speed is increased only 40 revolutions per minute (1,485 to 1,525), the quantity of water discharged would go from 400 to 1200 gallons per minute, the power required from 24.7 to 39.0 horsepower, and the pump efficiency from 41 to 78 per cent. A 3-inch pump of this same type would deliver 400 gallons per minute against a 100 - -foot head at a power requirement of 14.5 and an efficiency o£ 70 per cent. These figures are not meant to confuse but rather to impress the pump irngator with the (act that there is some one "best combination" of pump size, pump speed, and power plant for each installation. The amount of draw-down or lowering of the water level produced by continuous pump - ing at the desired rate, the total head against which the pump will operate and a number of other details should be known before the pumping equip - ment is purchased. The Agricultural Engineering Department will be glad to receive inquiries relative to the selection of proper sizes and types of pumping equipment, the development of irrigation wells, and the pre - paration of land to be irrigated. Many tractor users who do not have a speed counter would find one very useful in checking the tractor pulley speed or the speed of the driven machine. While counters are available at a nominal figure, some operators prefer to use this simple method of checking pulley speed. A distinguish - ing mark, such as a streak of white paint, is made on the outer surface of the belt. Then the pulley in question is rotated by hand and the revolu- </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Nebraska Tractor Tests tions counted until the full length the belt has passed over the pulley. The mark on the belt moving at the relatively slow rate makes it possible to count the belt revolutions in one minute, as indicated on the second hand of a watch. The belt revolutions in one minute multiplied by the number of turns of the pulley per belt revolution gives a quick check on pulley sP«f" . :/¦ .¦:..' .1 " .'- :'" ''.".:¦''"' v . ¦ ¦¦ . ' A similar plan may be used to check engine speeds on drawbar work. The) number of turns on the engine necessary to produce one revolution of the drive wheel is determined for each gear. This may be readily done by Removing the spark plugs', carefully noting the relative position of some point on a drive wheel and some stationary part of the tractor chassis, placing the tractor in the desired gear, and counting the number of turns of the starting crank necessary to advance the tractor drive wheel one jcomplete revolution.: The iirive wheel revolutions per minute may be easily counted in the field.by jtying a rag to a spoke. This figure (drive wheel r.p.rn.) multiplied by the crarikshaft-to-drive-wheel ration previously dete -mined will give the engine speed. : : DRAWBAR TESTING EQUIPMENT Comments.—All of the. drawbar pull exerted by the tractor being tested is transmitted, by suitable equalizers and a hydraulic piston-cylinder mechanism called a draft unit; to the drawbar load. The pressure in the draft unit is carried through flexible metal tubing to the draft-recording instrument. The essential mechanism of this draft-recording unit is a gas - engine pressure indicator which has been so adapted to the requirements that it leaves on a special chart a continuous record of the drawbar pull of the tractor. From this chart, showing the pull in pounds, and from stop - watch readings showing the time of travel over a measured course, the horsepower developed is calculated. Rotary switches having ten contact points are.attached to each drive wheel and connected to magnetic counters which record to one-tenth of [one revolution the number of revolutions made over a measured distance. From these same readings are calculated the jaigine speed and the drive wheel or track slippage. In determining the slippage the tractor is driven without any drawbar load for a distance sufficient to give at least 10 revolutions of the drive wheels or crawler tracks. This distance is then accurately measured and is used as a basis for computing wheel slippage. The computations are as follows: The distance covered at no load is divided by the number of drive - wheel revolutions to obtain the number of feet advanced per revolution. Thd number of revolutions made in advancing 500 feet is recorded by the electric counters. This number multiplied by the feet of advance per revo - lution at ho load gives the distance the tractor would have traveled had there been no loss due to slippage. However, the tractor actually advances onlyj 500 feet. The difference between these two distances is divided by the former, and the answer multiplied by 100 is the percentage of slippage. (When speaking of rubber tire tests, some prefer to use the term, "travel reduction.") ? </seg>
         <seg id="p020">\IBR.\SK\ AguICLLTIRAL EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 321 Drawbar Loading Machines.—ln determining the drawbar horsepower of a tractor, it is necessary to provide a source of load which may be readily varied. One loading machine, which has been used in a large number of test since 1931, is built about a McCormick-Deering 15-30 tractor. A gear - type pump is mounted on the platform and driven by a roller chain from a special sproket which replaces the brake pulley. The discharge line of the pump is carried up and forward to valves mounted on the top of the radia - tor. These valves may be closed or opened to increase or decrease the amount of power absorbed by the pump. A return line from the lower radiator connection to the inlet opening of the pump completes the system. Additional load may be obtained by placing the tractor in gear and opera - ting the engine against compression without fuel or ignition. If a light load is desired, the tractor may be placed in gear, the fuel and ignition turned on, and the throttle set to give such assistance as will result in the desired load. The design of this equipment is not original except as improvements have been made from time to time. The International Harvester Com - pany had built two similar machines and at the time the Tractor Testing Station needed a new machine were able to furnish the plans and part of the special equipment necessary to make the conversion. Another loading machine built about a pneumatic-tired 15-30 Mc- Cormick-Deering tractor was first used in the 1936 testing season. The rear wheel equipment was changed to dual zero-pressure tires for the 1937 season. A four-speed transmission mounted in the power line from the tractor rear wheels to the gear-type pump permits the use of this machine at travel speeds up to approximately 25 miles per hour. Still another machine, a smaller one, has a range of load from about 200 pounds to 1,600 pounds and a possible top speed of 40 miles per hour. The essen - tial parts of this machine are the rear axle assembly and transmission from a heavy-type passenger car, a gear-type pump, a radiator and fan, a supply tank, and suitable controls. A close coupled four-wheeled vehicle, called the instrument car, is used to carry the recording instruments and an observer. A small gear pump mounted on this chassis, and driven by the rear wheels through a re - versed transmission, provides drawbar load for the very small tractors. RUBBER TIRE TESTS Starting with the 1934 season, supplementary tests on rubber tires, at no extra charge, were offered to manufacturers making drawbar tests on steel wheels and lugs. The first manufacturer to take advantage of this offer was Allis-Chalmers in test 223 on their model "WC" tractor. The routine drawbar tests were made on steel wheels and lugs. Then a four-hour fuel-economy run was made in third gear, after which the steel wheels were removed and rubber-tired wheels were mounted. For all rubber tire tests, the added weight per rear wheel has been such that the total weight on each rear tire did not exceed the tire manufacturer's recommendations. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Nebraska Tractor Tests These supplementary tests on rubber tires have consisted of operating maximum drawbar horsepower tests for each of the forward gears and fuel-economy runs of fdur hours each in second and third gears. jln the lower gears the traction developed by rubber tires and wheel weights, as ordinarily used, is not sufficient to transmit maximum engine horse power. To determine the maximum horsepower in each gear, a series of mns were made, sjartingl with the throttle partly closed so that the governor controlled the,engine speed and with sufficient load applied to produce a drive-wheel slippage of 5 to 6 per cent. Other runs were made wi :h increased load, But with the throttle openedj wider'to give rated en jine speed which, )of course, gave increased slippage. This balancing of throttle opening, engine speed, load, and slippage was carried to the point where either the engine was developing maximum power or the slippage was so great that the 1 horsepower was appreciably reduced, usually a slippage of 25 to 30 per cent. The horsepower was calculated for each of I the 500-foot tests/and such runs as produced the largest amount of power (and at the sane time keeping within one per cent of rated engine speed) were selected is representative of the operating maximum drawbar horsepower in that gear. I ' The following arbitrary method was used in arriving at a suitable horse - power to develop in :he fuel tests. The relationship between the rated and operating maximum horsepower on steel wheels in; rated gear was deter - mined. In test 223 this was 12.14 divided by 14.36 and multiplied by 100 which equals 845%\ | Carrying along the illustration in test 223, the amount of power that was desirable to develop in ithe second-gear fuel-economy run on rubber tires was obtained by multiplying the operating maximum horsepower in second gear on rubber, 14.19, by 84.5 per cent, which equals 1159. An examination of the test results' shows that 12.08 horsepower was the aver - age developed over the four-hour period. In the same manner, the desired hbrsepower figures for third gear on rubber (17.59 X 0.845 = 14.86) and for third gar on steel (1334 X 0.845 = 1157) were calculated for the fuel - economy tests. This method just outlined applies to tests 223, .237, 238, 249, 250, 282, 29,1, 292, 293, 294, 299, 303, 304 and 305. Tests 274, 275, 296, 297, 302, 308, 310, 311, 312 and 313 were conducted on rubber tires only. The drawbar tests made on these rubber-tired tractors were the same as normally would be made on| the steel-wheel equipment. In tests 306, 307 and 309 the drawbar ratings were determined on rubber tires and then supplementary tests were made on: steel wheels and lugs. The same procedure as outlined for test 223 was used except that the steel wheels and rubber tires were interchanged. .¦ ' :'¦¦¦¦:¦¦:'. THE LAW 'I. : " . ' ' Purpose of the Law.—The Nebraska Tractor Law, known as House Roll 85, 37th Session (Art. 10, paragraphs 5531-5543 inclusive, pages 1751 and 1752, Compiled Statutes of State of Nebraska, 1922), which became </seg>
         <seg id="p022"/>
         <seg id="p023"/>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 effective July 15, 1919, was enacted to encourage the manufacture and sale of improved types of tractors and to contribute to a more successful use of the tractor for farming. It was thought that the best method of accomplishing these objects would be to require a tractor of each model sold in the State to be tested at the State University and to have the results of these tests made public. Provisions of the Law.—Stated briefly, the provisions of the law are: That a stock tractor of each model sold in the State shall be tested and passed upon by a board of three engineers under State University management. That each company, dealer or individual offering a tractor for sale in Nebraska shall have a permit issued by the State Railway Commission. The permit for any model of tractor will be issued after a stock tractor of that model has been tested at the University and the performance of the tractor compared with the claims made for it by the manufacturer. That a service station with full supply of replacement parts for each model of tractor shall be maintained within the confines of the State and within reasonable shipping distance of customers. Nebraska Tractor Law. —Full text of the law as found in 75-901 to 911 inclusive, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, and revised by House Roll 526, 49th Session (1933) is as follows: Section 1. That on and after July 15, 1919, no tractor or traction com - pany shall be permitted to sell or dispose of any model or type of gas, gasoline, kerosene, distillate or other liquid fuel tractor engine in the state of Nebraska without first having said model tested and passed upon by a board of three competent engineers who are or shall be under the control of the state university management. Each and every tractor pre - sented to the State University management for testing, shall be a stock model and shall not be equipped with any special appliance or apparatus not regularly supplied to the trade. Any tractor not complying with the provisions of this section shall not be tested under this act, nor the results certified. Provided, no official tractor tests shall be conducted during the months of December, January and February. Applications for the test of a tractor shall be made to the testing board of engineers and shall be ac - companied by specifications of the tractor required by said board of engi - neers, and by the fee specified in Section 5535, Compiled Statutes of Ne - braska for 1922. If the application with specifications and fee is submitted during December, January, February or at any other time when the test can not be started at once, the State Railway Commission, with the ap - proval of the said board of engineers, may issue a temporary permit for the sale of tractors of the model specified in the application for test, the date on which said temporary permit shall terminate to be fixed by the said board of engineers. All temporary permits shall be conditioned upon such tractor as is covered thereby being tested at the earliest available date, and the tractor company to which a temporary permit has been issued shall submit a tractor for test which conforms to the specifications filed </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Nebraska Tractor Tests - . ¦ - ¦ ¦!¦ ¦ ¦ . ' - ¦ ~ \yit!i the application, said tractor to be delivered for test at any time specified by the board of engineers. Upon failure to do so, all such fees deposited by said companies shall be forfeited to the State of Nebraska, and in addition such companies shall be liable to the penalties prescribed by J3ection 5540, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922, and shall never thereafter be issued any temporary permit whatever.^ Provided, however, that air sales of tractors upon [which a temporary permit has been issued, shall be made subject to the final official test and approval of the model. Section 2. Such tests to consist of endurance, official rating of horse - povyer for continuous load, and consumption of fuel per hour or per acre of farm operations; the results of such tests to be open at all times to public inspection. . L ..':.' Section 3. The State University management after having duly tested any model of liquid fuel traction engine shall.certify die results to the State Railway Commission. Prior to the issuing of a i permit by said com - mission to any liquid fuel traction engine company to do business in the State of Nebraska, the official tests of the University shall be compared with the representations of the tractor company as to horsepower rating for not less than ten consecutive hours of continuous load, fuel used for developing such horsepower, and any other representation such company shall make, and in case any such representations shall be found false the State Railway Commission shall deny the company manufacturing or assembling such tractor, the right to do business in the State of Nebraska, except as hereinafter provided. : Section 4. Likewise, the State Railway Commission shall deny to any liquid fuel tractor company the right to do business in the State of Ne - braska which shall be found, on complaint of two or more bona fide cus - tomers residing within; the State, to fail to maintain an adequate service station with full supply of replacement parts within the confines of the State and within reasonable shipping distance of said customers. Section 5. Application to the State University management for test of a tractor shall be accompanied by a fee of five hundred dollars ($500.00) paid to the State University management as a partial reimbursement for the cost of such test. Payment; shall also be made upon presentation of the proper statement for costs of all fuel and oil consumed in making said test. 1 Section 6. Provided: further, that the failure of any model of tractor to come up to the representations of the company manufacturing or as - sembling same, shall not prevent said company from placing on the market, other models of tractors that Ido comply with specifications and ratings. Any model of tractor that fails in the official test to come up to the com - pany's own specifications, may be retested after alteration and remodeling. Each and every permit issued under this act shall specify the model or models included in such permit to sell. : Section 7. The report of the official tests herein provided shall be posted in the Agricultural Engineering Department of the State University and in such other places as may be designated by the State University man- </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 agement. The same shall be incorporated in the annual report o£ the State Railway Commission. Section 8. Provided, that no tractor company shall use the results of said tests in such manner as would cause it to appear that the State Uni - versity management intended to recommend the use of any given type or model of tractor in preference to any other type or model. It shall be unlawful for any tractor company operating in the State of Nebraska, to publish extracts from such official tests for advertising purposes, without publishing the entire report. Any infraction of the foregoing provisions shall result in the suspen - sion or denial to any company so offending the permission to do business in the State at the discretion of the State Railway Commission. Section 9. Tractors shall be tested by the State University management in the order in which they are presented for such tests, and no discrim - ination shall be made for or against any tractor company in any manner whatsoever. Complaints against the vaiolation of this provision shall be heard and adjudicated by the State Railway Commission. Section 10. After July 15, 1919, any gas, gasoline, kerosene, distillate or other liquid fuel tractor or traction company selling or offering for sale in the State of Nebraska or any automobile, implement or other company or individual operating in behalf of such tractor company or on their own behalf who shall after the date specified, sell or offer for sale in the State any model of liquid fuel tractor engine, without having in his possession a permit from the State Railway Commission to sell such model of tractor as he is offering for sale, the same shall be deemed guilty of a misde - meanor. On conviction such misdemeanor shall be punished by a fine of not less than $100.00 nor more than $500.00 for each offense in the discretion of the court. Section 11. The State Railway Commission shall have full authority to enforce the provisions of this act, both by denial of permit to do business in the State and by due process of law to compel compliance therewith. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">.-..-¦ Nebraska Tractor Tests TRACTOR SPECIFICATIONS The following tractors were reported by their manufacturers as being on the market January 1, 1938. The results of the tests are on the folded summary sheet. : ¦ Test No. 28. BEEMAN MODEL G 2-4, Bccman Tractor Company Minneapolis, Minnesota; June 22 to July 2, 1920. Heinze "AXI" magneto; Kingston "V" carburetor; Donaldson dry centrifugal-type airlcleaner; no governor. Engine '{vertical, L-hcad, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt puljey diameter 4 'A", width 3'A", rotates at engine speed. Chassis: two drive wheels in front, 2 caster wheels in rear;| own clutch, both external and internal expanding. Advertised speed .0.75 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Replaced carburetor.. Test No. 126. HUBER 20-40, Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; September 7; to 16, 1926. j Eisemann "GS4" magneto; Kingston "L 3" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" oil-spray - type air cleaner; Kingston fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley(diametcr 1514", width 8", rated speed 666 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2.47, high 3.48, reverse 1.94. Comments: During the rated brake test the fan belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. .. • ¦ -;.¦'•- j; - .'¦ . ¦ "¦"...' Test No. 135. HUBER SUPER FOUR 40-62, Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; May 17 to June 24| 1927. : lEisemann "G4" magneto; Ensign "A" carburetor; Pomona oil-spray-type air cleaner; Kingston fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1551", width 9'/t", rated speed 733 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive;TWin Disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2.00 to 2.50, high 3.00 to 3.50, reverse 1.75 to 2.25. Comments: During the rated drawbar test and after approximately 25 hours run - ning, ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced with new ones of the same make but did not remedy the trouble. The Stitt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were then replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was experienced. The left spindle arm sheared off, causing the front axle to bend somewhat; the axle and .spindle arm were replaced with new parts. The packing-gland nuts on the water (pump were tightened several times during the test The flexible oil tube leading to the clutch thrfiiv-out collar was leaking at the end of ¦.the] test. '.;¦ : ¦.-.'' ';¦ ,- ,|' ;¦¦',¦ _ ' ¦ '¦ :-¦ .. ¦ Test No. 142. McCORMICK-pEERING 10-20, International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October 3to 8, 1927. ....... lOwn-make "E4A" magneto; Ensign "R" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" Model 118 oujspray-iype air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 Vi", width 7", rated speed 661 r.pjn. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; own multiple dry disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2, intermediate 3, high 4, reverse 2.75. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. . Test No. 161. BAKER 43-67,' A. D. Baker Company, Swanton, Ohio, May 16 to 24J1929. .'. •' ¦ .- ;•..¦¦ ¦ (•¦-¦ :•¦¦ ¦¦-;•.. ; .¦ : ¦ ¦ ¦ Eisemann "G4" magneto; Strombcrg "M 4" carburetor; Pomona "Vortox" oil-nlter - type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crank - sh:ft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 ' A", width BV4", rated speed 774 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2.0 to| 2.5, high 3.0 to 3.5, reverse 2.5. I Comments: It was necessary to lock the gears in mesh during the high-gear max - imum and rated load drawbar tests. : </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 Test No. 167. CASE "C" 17-27, J. 1. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; August 12 to 19, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4ARS" magneto; Kingston "L 3" carburetor; own oil-filter-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-rype governor. Engine vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10!4", width bVi", rated speed 973 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear and chain drive; Twin Disc plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2.30. intermediate 3.28, high 4.50, reverse 2.59. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests, the clutch was adjusted. During the rated drawbar tcsr, the fuel line to the carburetor became clogged and was cleaned out. Test No. 168. HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36, The Hubcr Manufacturing Com - pany. Marion, Ohio; August 19 to 2-1, 1929. Eiscmann "GV4" magneto; Strombcrg "M 3" carburetor; Donaldson oiled-fibre-type air cleaner: Waukcsha fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 17", width B}4", rated speed 616 r.p.m. Chassis standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc dry-plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2.32, high 3.08, reverse 1.83. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 169. CASE "CC," J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; September 10 to 18, 1929. Robert Bosch "FLH" magneto; Kingston "LiV" carburetor; own oil-filter-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10K", width 6V2", rated speed 973 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear and chain drive; Twin Disc plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2.60, intermediate 3.72, high 5.H, reverse 2.95. Comments: It was necessary to raise the oil level in the transmission approximately one inch for the belt tests. Test No. 173. FORDSON "F" (Kerosene), Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michi - gan; March 11 to April 8, 1930. Robert Bosch "FU" 48R529 magneto; Kingston "MD2" carburetor; own water-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 9V4", width 6VI", rated speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; own multiplc-disc-typc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 1.75, intermediate 3.12, high 7.75, reverse 3.00. Comments; During the preliminary belt tests, the cylinder head gasket was replaced. The original governor spring was replaced by a heavier spring after the rated load belt test. Test No. 174. FORDSON "F" (Gasoline), Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Mich - igan; March 20 to April 10, 1930. Robert Bosch "FU"4BRS29 magneto; Zenith "INSF" carburetor; own water-type air cleaner; own fly-ball-type governor. Engine vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 9'A", width 6'A", rated speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; own multiple-disc-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour; low 2.12, intermediate 3.12, high 7.75, reverse 3.00. Comments: During the rated-load belt test, the water pump gland was tightened approximately one-fifdi turn. Test No. 184. EAGLE "6A," Eagle Manufacturing Company, Appleton, Wisconsin; October 21 to November 1, 1930. American Bosch "U6" magneto; Zenith "96ATO" carburetor; Pomona-Vortox oil - spray-type air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal-type governor. Engine vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 625 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc dry double-plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 2.50, intermediate 3.33, high 4.50, reverse 2.50. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 186. BATES STEEL MULE "35," Foote Bros. Gear and Machine Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois-, April 6 to 18, 1931. . American Bosch "U6" magneto; | Scheblcr "HDX" carburetor; Pomona-Vbrtox oil - spray;type air cleaner; Waukcsha centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 9", rated speed 920 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry-plate - type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: low 1.90, intermediate 2.85, high 3.80, reverse 2.65. , • Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. \ Test No. 187. BATES STEEL MULE "45," Foote Bros. Gear and Machine Com - pany, 1 Chicago, Illinois; April 8 to 28, 1931. American Bosch "U6" magneto; Schebler "HDX" carburetor; Pomona-Vortox oil - spray-type air cleaner; Waukesha centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 9", rated speed 920 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc dry double-plate dutch. Advertised speed's, miles per hour: low 1.92, intermediate 2.92, high 3.87, reverse 1.40. : I : Comments: After 15 hours of operation a leak was discovered at the connection between the oil line and the pressure gauge. The connection, was tightened and the leak stopped. Four quarts of oil had been added prior to this time. Test No. 193. ALLIS-CHALMERS "EX," Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; June 18 to 25, 1931. j, Fisemann "G4" magneto; Zenith "C6EV" carburetor; Donaldson and own centrif - ugal and oily-fibre-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 13", width i'A", rated speed 1,000 r.p.m. Chassis: standard, enclosed gear drive; own expanding - shoe^type dutch. Advertised speeds,|miles per hour: low 2.50,1 high 3.25, reverse 3.25. Comments: During the preliminary drawbar runs the head j gasket on cylinders No. 3 anil 4 was found to be leaking and replaced/ ; | Test No. 194. McCORMICK-DEERING INDUSTRIAL '20," International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois; July 20 to 27, 1931. Own "E4A" mageto; Zenith "CSFE" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, 'T'head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 15 Vt",\ width 7", rated speed 742 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; own single-plate-type clutch. Adver - tised; speeds, miles per hour: loiv 2.50, intermediate 3.50, high 5.00, reverse 3.00. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. . |, Test No. 198. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F 30," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; October! 9to 23, 1931. - .' Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "K5" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-nltcr-type air cleaner; owri centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14 Vt", width 7", rated speed 682 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; own dry single-plate-type. clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.00, second 2.75, third 3.25, fourth 3.75, reverse 2.50. Comments: The pin which holds the splined end of the steering rod in the splined sleeve sheared off twice, once during the limber-up run and again during the rated-load drawbar test. Each time the pin was replaced by another. Test No. 199. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor, International Harvester Com - pany, Chicago, Illinois; October 10) to 26, 1931. ) Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "K5" carburetor; own oil-washed, wire-filter type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley 'diameter 15V4 ".width 7", rated speed 682 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate, dry r disc-type clutch. Adver - tised speeds, miles per hour: low 1:75, intermediate 2.75, high 3.75, reverse 2.00. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 Test No. 200. ALLJS-CHALMERS MODEL "L," Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; March 17 to April 11, 1932. Eiscm.inn "GV(V magneto; two Zenith "C6EV" carburetors; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner: own ccntrifugal-typc governor. Engine six-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 20", width 15", rated speed SM)-12J2 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own double-disc-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.94, second 2.-15, third 3.05, fourth -1.10. fifth 5.20, sixth 6.47, reverse 1.45-3.0". Comments: During die rated load drawbar test, the fuel flow was restricted by a flake of solder partially covering the outlet in the bottom of the supply tank. The obstruction was blown away from the outlet and the test completed. Test No. 210. McCORMICK-DEERING "W 30," International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; July 26 to August 10, 1932. Own "E4A" magneto; Zenith "K5" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own ccntrifugal-typc governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 1514", width 7", rated speed 681 r.p.m. Chassis: standard: enclosed gear drive; own dry-disc single-plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second 3.25, third 3.75, reverse 2.75. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 215. ALUS-CHALMERS "X," Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; September 21 to October 4, 1933. Eiscmann "GL4" magneto; Zenith "C 6" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wtre-filter - type air cleaner; own ccntrifugal-typc governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 854", rated speed 1050 r.p.m. Chassis-, tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.08, second 3.10, third 4.50, reverse 2.39. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 216. ALLIS-CHALMERS "M," Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois: September 23 to October 9, 1933. Eisemann "GL4" magneto; Zenith "K5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter - type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width S'A", rated speed 960 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate-type dutch. Adver - tised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.23, second 3.20, third 4.15, fourth 5.82, reverse 2.55. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 219. MASSEY-HARRIS "3-4 PLOW," The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; October 24 to November 10, 1933. American Bosch "U4ED4" magneto; Kingston "L-3-L" carburetor; own oil-circu - lated-over-wool-type air cleaner; Kingston ccntrifugal-typc governor. Engine four - cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 19", width TVs", rated speed 525 r.p.m Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc dry single-plate-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second 3.25, third 4.00, reverse 2.50. Comments: During the preliminary belt tests, the spark plug in No. 1 cylinder was replaced with a new one. Test No. 220. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F-12" (Kerosene), Interna - tional Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 1 to 16, 1933. Own "F-4" magneto; own "A-10" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own ccntrifugal-typc governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12J4", width 6'A", rated speed 800 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry-disc-type clutch. Adver - tised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.00, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. Comments: During the belt tests the spark plug in No. 3 cylinder was replaced with a new one. On the rated-load drawbar test a bolt connecting the drawbar to the drawbar-adjusting plate was lost. This was replaced. </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Nebraska Tractor Tests Tat No. 222. JOHN DEERE GENERAL PURPOSE MODEL "A," John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; April 19 to 27, 1931 Flirbanks-Morse "DRV2A" magneto; Schebler "DLTX-8" carburetor; Vortex "2071 D" oil-washed wire-filter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder horizontal, "I" head, mounted. crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter 1213/16", width 7%", rated speed 975 r.p.m. '.Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; own 'disc-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.00, third 4.7si|fourth 6.25, reverse 3.50. Comments: During the drawbar tests grease leaked from the left end of the rear axle housing. The exhaust pipe to exhaust manifold connection became loose and was tightened during the maximum drawbar tests. Test No. 224. CATERPILLAR "R-5," Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; July |l 2 to 20, 1934. ' j . ¦ Eisemann "GT4" magneto; Ensign "Ked" carburetor; own, under Vortox patent, combination centrifugal, oil-and-mattcd-wire-type . air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width B &lt;A", rated speed 950 r.plm. Chassis: tracklayer, en - closed gear, drive, own single-plate dry-type, clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour; firstjl.9, second 2.8, third 3.6, fourth 5.1, reverse 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. ! . Test No. 226. CATERPILLAR "TWENTY-TWO" (Distillate), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; September 25 to October 9, 1934. Eisemann "CT4" magneto; Zenith "KSA" carburetor; own, under Vortox patent, combination centrifugal, oil-and-matied-wire-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft, lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10%", width 6'/:", rated speed 950 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - cWd gear drive, own single-plate, dry-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first|2!o, second 2.6, third 3.6, reverse 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. 'Test No. 228. CATERPILLAR "TWENTY-TWO" (Gasoline), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; October 17 to 30, 1934. ( Eiscmann "CT-4" magneto; Zenith "KSA" carburetor; own, under Vortox patent, combination centrifugal, oil-and-mattcd-wirc-typc air cleaner; own centrifugal-typd governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 10/2", width 6/2", rated speed 950 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, en - dosid gear drive, own single-plate dry-type clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.6, third 3.6, reverse 2.1. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. [Test No. 231. McCORMICK-DEERrNG "W-12" (Gasoline), International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 13 to 16, 1934. I / .¦.; • . 'Own "F4" magneto; own "aUO" carburetor; own oil-washed-wire-hlter-type air cleaner; own centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter BK", width 6/4 " , rated speed 787 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive, Rockford single-plate dry-disc-type clutch. Adver - tised speeds, miles per hour, first 2 25, second 2.75, third 3.75, reverse 2.25. jComments: At the end o£ the rated load drawbar test the manifold bolt, which holds the choke rod bracket, was found to be loose. , fTest No. 235. CLETRAC "40" DIESEL, The Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleve - land, Ohio; June 13 to 24, 1935. -&#132; -,' .-' American Bosch "APE6B7O ASOOS9I" fuel system; Vortox oil-washed, &gt;yire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal-type governor. Engine six-cylinder verdcal Diesel, I head, mounted crankshaft lengthWise; belt pulley diameter 13 , width 11 .rated fpecd 884 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; Long two-plate, dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: [first 1.8, second 3.0, third 4.3, reverse 2.2. Comments: No repairs nor ad iistmcnts. ¦ .'- ¦ :-.y¦.¦¦¦.'¦¦¦¦.¦ ::.¦;¦¦¦¦ ¦ ¦:¦''.'¦¦[¦'i /¦ •¦¦¦¦¦" </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 Test No. 236. JOHN DEERE "D", John Dccrc Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa: lunc 26 to July 2, 1935. Splitdorf ''246 T" magneto: Schcblcr "DLTX6" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed, screen-filler air cleaner: own. centrifugal-type governor. Engine two-cylinder horizontal, "I" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise; belt pulley diameter MVt", width 814", rated speed 900 r.p.m. Chassis: standard: enclosed gear and chain drive; own, double-disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.5, second 3.5, third 5, reverse 2. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 237. ALLIS-CHALMERS "U," Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee. Wisconsin: July 15 to August 5, 1(J35. Scintilla-Rcndix "C-T magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed, wirc - rilter air cleaner: own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise: belt pulley diameter 10", width 7 IA", rated speed 1094 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive: Rockford single-plate clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.33, third 5.0, fourth 10.0 (not recommended for steel wheels), reverse 2.67. Comments: On the limber-up run, it was found that of the two bolts which hold ihe left fender to the supporting saddle on the axle housing, one was lost and the other loose and &lt;vorn. Both bolts were replaced. On the maximum tests (steel), one of the same two bolts on the right fender was broken and the other loose. One was replaced and the other tightened. On the maximum drawbar tests (steel) it was observed that the brazed connection between the exhaust pipe and the exhaust pipe flange was broken. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS —SECOND AND THIRD GEARS „ , . , _ &#132; , sll P°n Fuel consumption Drawbar Speed Crankshaft drive ' HP. pull M.p.h. speed wheel- Gals. H.P./ns. Us. per Lbs. R.p.m. P.a. pcrhr. per gal. H.P. lir. STEEL WHEELS 19-35 1,891 3.84 1,202 3.29 2.825 6.85 1039 16.86 1,087 5.83 1,202 5.05 2.7-16 6.14 1.127 RUBBER TIRES Additional weight per rcjr wheel was 422 pounds. Rear tire size: 12.75" x 24". 16.47 1,845 3.35 1,201 9.61 2.079 792 0 882 22.72 1.680 5.07 1,200 9.10 2.650 8.57 0.815 Additional information available in test report. Test No. 238. ALLIS-CHALMERS "UC", Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Com - pany, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; July Irt to August 8, 1935. Bcndix-Scintilla "C-4" magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed, wire - filter air cleaner; own. ccntrifugal-typc governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise: belt pulley diameter 10", width 7'A", rated speed 1094 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle: enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.33, third 5.00, fourth 10.00 (not recommended for steel wheels), reverse 2.67. Comment!.: During the maximum drawbar tests on rubber tires, gear grease began to leak from the final drive. This continued to the end of the test (15 hours). Over the same period of time, grease leaked through the seal around the steering gear worm ¦.haft. </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Nebraska Tractor Tests FUEL ECONOMY T iSTS —SECOND AND THIRD GEARS Slip on Fuel consumption Drawbar Speed Crankshaft drive ! ' H.P. pull M.p./i. speed wheels Gals. HJ. hrs. Lbs. per Lbs. . i?.p.m. P.ct. 'per.hr. per gal. H.P.hr. STEEL WHEELS 18.90 1,808 3.92 1201 2.76 3.062 6.18 1.132 16.19 1,021 , 5.95 1202. 2.10 3.027 5.35 1.307 ¦".¦•'¦ "' RUBBER TIRES '..'.:¦ I Additional weight per rear u-liccl was 422 pounds. Rear tire size: 12.75" x 24". . 18.07 2,023 3.35 1U99 8.14 2.284 7.91 0.884 24.57 1,770 5.21 1{199 536 2.743 8.96 0.780 Additional information available in test report. . ¦ Test No. 239. ALLIS-CHALMERS "M", Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois; August T to 9, 1935. . | Bendix-Scintilla "C-4" magneto; Zenith "K-5" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed, wire - filter air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwiic; belt pulley diameter 12", width S'A", rated speed 960 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer] enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.23, second 3.20, third 4.15, fourth 1.83, reversV2.ss; '. " .-•/. • . .... •¦ :¦ " \". . Comments: No repairs or adjustments. . Test No. 242. CATERPILLAR DIESEL FORTY, Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria, Illinois; August 19 to September 9, 1935. ' . Own fuel system; Donaldson combination oil and wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, jcentrifugal-type governor. Engine three-cylinder, vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mount - ed crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width 814", rated speed 1000 r.p.ml Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate,' dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.0, second 2.9, third 3.8, fourth 5.4, reverse 2.2. ¦Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 243. CATERPILLAR DIESEL FORTY, Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; September 10 to 12, 1935. ¦ | Own fuel system; Donaldson combination oil and wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own.l centrifugal-type governor. Engine three-cylinder, vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 12", width B'A", rated speed 850 tp.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; own, single-plate, dry clutch. Adver - tised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7; second 2.5, third 3.2, fourth 4.6, reverse 1.9. Comments: No. repairs or adjustments. Test No. 246. McCORMICK-DEERING "WD-40", International Harvester Com - pany! Chicago, HUnbis; September 23 to 27, 1935. Own, "F-4" magneto (for starting only); own, "R" (modified) carburetor (for starting only); own ''PT4O" fuel system; Donaldson combination oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own. centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, Diesel, 'T' head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter. 16 ' A", widin 9", rated speed 588 r.p.m. Chassis: standard, enclosed gear drive; own single - platejdry disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.6, second 3.4, third 3.9, reverse 2.4. ¦ . ' . ' ¦;.)'.¦ :. ¦ ' . '¦' ''.'¦¦ Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 247. M-M TWIN CITY "KTA", Minneapolis-Molinc Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; October 2 to 9, 1935. , American Bosch "U4" magneto; Schebler "TTX-15" carburetor; Donaldson combin - ation) oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrindi air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type gov - ernor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 pulley diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.1, second 3.1. third 4.1, reverse 1.8. Comments: After the belt tests were begun it was observed that the pulley shaft housing and bearing were cracked. A new pulley unit was installed and all data shown in this report were taken after the replacement was made. The air cleaner stack broke off 'luring the preliminary drawbar tests. This was repaired by welding. The right hand tie-rod bolt started to work out during the rated load drawbar test. The cotter key which normally holds tin- bolt in place was lost. The bolt was put into proper position and keyed. Test No. 248. M-M TWIN CITY "MTA", Minncapolis-Molinc Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; October 2 to 17, 1935 . American Bosch "U4" magneto; Schcblcr "TTX 15" carburetor; Donaldson com - bination oil and centrifugal wire-screen labyrinth air cleaner; own, centrifugal-type governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise; belt pulley diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.1, second 3.1, third 4.1, reverse 1.8. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 249, M-M TWIN CITY "KTA" (HC), Minncapolis-Molinc Power Imple - ment Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; March 30 to April 10, 1936. American Dosch XT' magneto; Schcblcr "TTX 15" carburetor; Donaldson ejector and oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical. "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley diameter 14", face 7", rated speed 822 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive, Twin Disc single - plate clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.25, third 4.25, reverse 1.9. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS —SECOND AND THIRD GEARS Slip on p uc ] consumption Drawbar Speed Crankshaft drive YIP. pull M.p.h. speed wheels Gals. HJ'.hrs. Lbs. per Lbs. R.p.m. P.cl. perhr. per gal. H.P. hr. STEEL WHEELS 23.95 2,601 3.45 1,152 3.49 3.106 7.71 0.795 21.76 1.788 4.56 1,151 3.33 3.086 7.05 0.869 RUBBER TIRES Additional wciphr per rear wheel was 560 pounds. Rear tire size: 12.75" 124". 14.89 1,704 3.28 1,153 6.56 1.833 8.12 0.754 19.64 1,709 4.31 1,151 6.74 2.322 8.46 0.725 Additional information available in test report. Test No. 250. SILVER KING 3-WHEEL, Fate-Root-Heath Company, Plymouth, Ohio; March 23 to April 20, 1936. Fairbanks-Morse "RV-4" magneto; Zenith 193-'/i carburetor; Air Maze oil-washed screen-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: four-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter bVi", face 614", rated speed 1400 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive, Borg 8c Beck dry disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.35, third 5.5, fourth 14.5 (not recommended for steel wheels—up to 25 miles per hour according to motor speed), reverse 1.5. Comments: While making a preliminary belt test the mow over-heated. The radiator core, which was painted with aluminum paint and was not equipped with a shroud, was replaced by one unpaintcd and having a shroud. The aluminum paint was </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Nebraska Tractor Tests removed from the motor and the two-ground electrode type spark plugs were replaced by single-ground electrode plugs. All official test data were taken after these changes had [been made. At the end of the test it was found that insufficiently tightened cylinder head bolts had permitted water to leak from the cooling system into the second and third cylinders. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS—-SECOND AND THIRD GEARS I Slipon Fuel consumption Drawbar Speed Crankshaft drive . HP. pull M.p.h. speed wheels Galsl Hf.hr. Lbs. per Lbs.' . '. R.p.m. P.et. pcrhr. pergal. Hf.hr. STEEL WHEELS : &gt; 1Q.51 1,045 3,77 1,399 7.03 1.925' 5.46 1.128 .8.10 441 6.89 1,400 3.68 1.855 4.37 1.411 RUBBER TIRES J Additional weight per rear wheel was 402 pounds. Rear tire size: 9.00" x 24". 10.50 1,142 3.45 1,401 8.32 1.534 6.84 0.900 - -13.40 792 6.35 1,400 4.20 1.808 7.41 0.831 Additional information available in test report. I ¦ ... . • ¦ . ¦ ! ¦¦•¦.. Test No. 251. CASE RC, J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; April 7 to 16, 1936. ".¦¦"¦¦•: ...-...,.• ¦¦¦. . •; y" " American Bosch "MJB4A108" magneto; Zenith "193 54 "| carburetor; United oil - washed wire-filter air cleaner; Case Waukesha centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 10/ i", face 6'A", rated speed 991 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed chain drive, Twin Disc single plate clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.33, third 4.s,(reverse 2.5. ' , . .!. . ... Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 252. OLIVER HART^PARR ROW CROP 70 (HC), Oliver Farm Equip - ment Company, Charles City, Iowa; April 13 to 24, 1936. : American Bosch "MJ86A302" magneto; Zenith "12454 EX" carburetor; Donaldson ejector and oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; Handy centrifugal, governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12 3A", face 6'A", rated speed 774 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Borg &amp; Beck single-plate dry dutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.44, sec - ond]^, third 4.33, fourth 5.88, Reverse 2.44. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test the pin in the starting crank dropped out land lodged in the tractor framel The pin was replaced. On this same test a welded connection on the seat frame was broken. . : . Test No. 253. CATERPILLARI DIESEL RD-7 (61 H.P.—850 r.p.m.), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; May sto 15,. 1936. • 6wn fuel system; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical Diesel, "I' head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter IVA", face IVA", rated speed 753 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry dutch.; Advertised speeds, miles per (hour: first 1.6, second 2.4, third 3.4, fourth 4.7, reverse 1.9. Comments: The starting motor clutch was adjusted once during the test. Test No. 254. CATERKLtAR DIESEL RD-7 (69 H. P.-I-850 r.p.m.); Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; May 16 to 20, 1936. ; Own fuel system; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 13'/s", face 12' A", rated speed 753 r:p.m. Chassis: </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.6, second 2.4, third 3.4, fourth 4.7, reverse 1.9. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 255. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-7 (1,000 r.p.m.), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria. Illinois; May 21 to 25, 1936. Own fuel system; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 13 V, face 1214", rated speed 887 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.8, second 2.9, third 4.0, fourth 5.5, reverse 2.2. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 256. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-8 (850 r.p.m.), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria, Illinois; May 7 to 19, 1936. Own fuel system; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter HK", face 13", rated speed 720 r.p.m Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7, second 2.-), third 2.8, fourth 3.2, fifth 3.9, sixth 5.3, reverse 1.7 and 2.8. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 257. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-8 (1,000 r.p.m.), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Pcoria, Illinois; May 19 to 25, 1936. Own fuel system: Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter H l//', face 13", rated speed 847 r.pm. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: tirst 2.0, second 2.8, third i.i, fourth 3.8, fifth 4.6, sixth 6.2, reverse 2.0 and 3.3. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 259. CLETRAC BG, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; June 16 to July 10, 1936. Dclco-Rcmy "645 H" distributor; Tillotson "Y-8-C" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules ccnirifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley, diameter 12", face %'A", rated speed 1050 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry clutch. Advestiscd speeds, miles per hour: first 1.8, second 2.625, third 3.5, reverse 1.375. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test, the action of die external parts of the governor mechanism became sluggish. To restore proper action, the dust was washed from the parts and the cam of the cam-and-follower group was polished. Test No. 260. CLETRAC AG, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio, June 16 to 26, 1936. American Bosch '•MJB4A101" magneto; Tillotson "P-l-B" carburetor; Vortox oil - washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 10!4", face 8 1/:", rated speed 1166 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry dutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.625, third 3.75, reverse 1.375. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test the tractor stopped three times. The air temperature at the time of the first stop was 103" P., at the second 107" F., and at the third 110° F. The temperature of the fuel in the fuel tank at the tune of the first stop was 120° F. The initial boiling point of the fuel used was 136° F. These operating conditions indicate that the stops were due to vapor lock. Test No. 261. CLETRAC E, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; June 16 to July 9, 1936. </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Nebraska Tractor Tests American Bosch. "MJB4A101" magneto; Tillotson "P-l-B" carburetor; Vortox oil - washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 10!4", face 8 !4", rated speed 1000 r.p.m. Chaisis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.125, second 2.75, third 4.00, re - vcrsejl.62s. . . Comments: No repairs or adjusments. Test No. 262. CLETRAC FG, Cleveland Tractor Company Cleveland, Ohio; June 16 to July 16, 1936. I : i American Bosch "MJA6BIO2". magneto; Tillotson "YXIBX'[ carburetor; Vortox in - take | deflector and oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder, vertical'%" Head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 2414", face 15", rated speed 509 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive; Long two-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.5, third 4.3, reverse 2.1. | ' ' ': i' - bomments: No repairs or adjustments. I Test No. 263. CLETRAC FD, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; June 15 toj July 17, 1936. . | American Bosch "APE6BBOB3DOS9I" fu-1 system; Vortox intake deflector and oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted Crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 24/4", face 15", rated speed 535 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer, enclosed gear drive, Long two - plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.75, third 4.25, reverse 2.125. .'- "¦¦¦ .'. ¦ '.. -:; ¦.¦'¦..-¦¦ Comments: During the belt test, the fuel line to No. 6 cylinder cracked. This line was replaced with a new one. Test No. 265. MASSEY-HARRIS CHALLENGER, Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; August 10 to 18, 1936. j • . American Bosch "U4ED4VI" magneto; Kingston carburetor; own bil-circulated - over-jwool air cleaner; Handy centri :ugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "I" head) mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face 6 X", rated speed 831 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per? hour: first 2.4, second 3.3, third 4.1, fourth 8.5, reverse 3.0. ... '- . ¦ Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 266. MASSEY-HARRIS PACEMAKER, Masscy-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; August 10 to 19, 1936. ; American Bosch "U4ED4VI" magneto; Kingston carburetor; own oil-circulated - over-jwool air cleaner; Handy cenuifugal governor. Engine: 4 cylinder vertical, "I" headj mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face 6'A", rated speed 831 r.p.m. Chassis: standard: enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.4, second 3.3, third 4.1, fourth 8.5, reveree 3.0. Comments: No repairs or adjust: ncnts. . ; Test No. 267. OLIVER HART-PARR ROW CROP 70 KD, Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa; August 20 to 31, 1936. . , . American Bosch "MJ86A302" magneto; Zenith"l24J4 EX" carburetor; Donaldson ejector and oil-washed wire-screen filer air cleaner; Handy centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12%f', face 654", rated speed 774 r p.m; Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Borg &amp; Beck single-plate dry cultch. Advert sed speeds, miles per hour: first 2.44, second 3.32, third| 4.33, fourth 5.88, reverse 2.44 : Comments: Before any official belt data were obtained, the belt pulley bevel gear adjustment was checked. 1 It was fotnd that one bevel pinion. tooth was broken. This pinion was replaced with anew oiie. , \' </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 During the rated load drawbar test, the radiator temperature indicator became inoperative. Test No. 269. McCORMICK-DEERING WK-40 (1750 r.p.m.), International Har - vester Company, Chicago, Illinois: September 3 to 15, 1936. Own "F6" magneto; Zenith "50-AYI2" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter air desner: own centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 16H", face 9", rated speed 645 r.p.m. Chassis: standard: enclosed gear drive; own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.375, second 3.125, third 3.625, reverse 2.25. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 270. M-M TWIN CITY FTA, Minncapolis-Molinc Power Implement Company. Minneapolis. Minnesota; September 10 to 18, 1936. American Bosch "MJB4AIO2" magneto; Schcblcr "TTXI6" carburetor; Donaldson elector and oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: four cvlmder vertical. "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 16", lace 7':". rated speed foil r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour; 2.36, second 3.17, third -1.05. reverse 1.7-1. Comments: The water pump packing nut was tightened one-sixth turn before the rated load drawbar test was run. During this same test the steering column supiwrt set screw in the steering bracket and the steering bracket iell retainer became loose and a small amount of transmission oil worked out. Test No. 271. CATERPILLAR THIRTY (Distillate), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peom. Illinois: October 13 to 24, 1936. Eiscmann "CM--1" magneto; Zenith "KSA" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wire - screen filter air cleaner: own centrifugal governor. Engine; four cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face BV2", rated speed MO r.p.m. Chassis; tracklayer: enclosed gear drive: own single-plate dry clutch. Adu-rtiscd speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7, second 2.4, third 3.0, fourth 3.7, fifth 5.4, reverse 1.9. Comments: 'Hie water pump packing nut was tightened one-third turn before the rated load drawbar test was run. Test No. 272. CATERPILLAR THIRTY (Gasoline), Caterpillar Tractor Company, Tcoria. Illinois; October 15 to 23, 1936. The specifications arc the same as those under Test 271. The difference was in the fuel used. Comments: Corrosion caused the governor control rod to stick in the governor bottle during the rated load drawbar test. The corrosion was apparently due to con - densed crankcase vapor. Test No. 273. CATERPILLAR DIESEL RD-4, Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois; October H to 28, 193(1. Own fuel system; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face B'/:", rated speed 840 r.p.m. Chassis: iracklajcr; enclosed gear drive: own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.7. second 2.4, third 3.0, fourth 3.7, fifth 5.4, reverse 1.9. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 274. CO-OP No. 3, Duplex Machinery Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, October 22 to November 5, 1r»36.l r»36. Auto-lite "GAR46OB-C-5" generator; Zenith "124 Vi EX" carburetor; Donaldson twister prc-dcancr and oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; Pierce centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley. diameter 14", face SV. rated speed 754 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Nebraska Tractor Tests endo «d gear drive; Borg &amp; Beck single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour{ first 2.7, second 4.6, third 6.6,1 fourth 13.0, fifth 20.0, reverse 3.3. Rear tire size: 12.75"x28". - ¦ : ' ;¦..:¦¦"..¦¦ " ¦¦ ;¦¦-¦ ¦-¦_¦¦• Comments: The pressed steel web of the fibre belt pulley failed during the pre - liminary belt test after approximately^ two hours of operation. This pulley was replaced with la cast iron one of the same size. . : T&lt;at No. 275. CO-OP No. 2, Duplex Machinery Company, Battle Creek, Michigan, October 22 to November 10, 1936. . Aluto-litc "GAR46OB-C-5" generator; Zenith "124 Vi E" carburetor; Donaldson twister pre-cleaner and oil-washed wire-screen filter.air cleaner; Pierce centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise Belt pulley: diameter 14", face 8%", rated speed • 707 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive 1; Borg &amp; Beck single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.7, second 4.7, third 6.8, fourth 14.2, fifth 21.3, reverse 3.5. Rear tire size: 11.25" x 28".\. .\' ¦¦.-¦ ' ¦¦¦¦. ¦¦;'¦¦¦'. •¦'.¦¦ Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 276. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL F-20, International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; November 5 to 12, 1936. Own "F4" magneto; Zenith 'K-5" carburetor; .own oil-washed wire-filter air clcan|cr; own centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 14", face 6'A", rated speed 654 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles, per hour: first 2.25, second 2.75, third 3.2s,fourdi 3.75, reverse 2.75. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 277. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor TD-35, International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; April 5 to 27, 1937. Own "F-4" magneto (for starting only); own "C-12" carburetor (for starting only); own j fuel system; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centri - fugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 16JK ", face 9", rated speed 591 r.p.m. Chassis: track - layer]; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hourfe first 1.75, second 2.25, third 2 75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. _ Comments: During the preliminary drawbar tests and before any official drawbar testsjwerc made, kerosene was applied to the track link joints to relieve stiffness. Test No. 278. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor T-35 (Distillate), International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; April 19 to May 10, 1937. . _ Own "F-6" magneto; Zenith "K-5-/&gt; S" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wire - screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: six-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwisk Belt pulley: diameter 16' A", face 9", rated speed 619'r.p.m. Chassis:' tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles pcr'hourV first 1.75, second 2.2s,:third 2.75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00] reverse 2.25. V \ ;. . . „,.,., , Comments: During the preliminary drawbar tcstr and before any. official drawbar tcstsjwere made, kerosene was applied to the ttack link joints to relieve stiffness. Test No. 279. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor T-35 (Gasoline), International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois;' May 14 to June 4,1937. ¦-,:.' Own "F-6" magneto; Zenith "K-5-'/i"'S" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wire - screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder, vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 16%", face 9", rated speed 619 rpm Chassis: tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.25, third 2.75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. , . , Comments: No repairs or adjustments. : ¦-.:-..¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p040">NeBRASK \ AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 321 Test No. 280. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor T-40 (Distillate), International Harvester Company. Chicago, IlJinois; April 7 to 20. 1937- Own "}--l&gt;" magneto: Zenith "50-AYI2" carburetor; own oil-washed, wire-filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder, vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 16 J4 ", face 9", rated speed 619 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklau-r: enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.25, third 2.75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. Comments-. No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 281. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor T-40 (Gasoline), International Harvester Company, Chicago. Illinois; May -4 to M, 1937. Own "F-'&gt;" magneto; Zenith "50-AYI2" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner: own centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. licit pulley: diameter \(&gt;'A", face 9", rated speed 619 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer: enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.25, third 2.75, fourth 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. ("ornments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 282. FORDSON ALL-AROUND (Distillate), Ford Motor Company, Lim - ited, F.sscx, Dajicnham, England; May 17 to June 10, 1937. Amencan-liosch "U4ED3VI" magneto; Kingston (modified by Ford) carburetor; own water-wash air cleaner; Handy centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 9'A", face &amp;'A", rated speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; own multiple-plate (in oil) clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.92, second 2.91, third 5.13, re - verse 1.65. Gimmcnts: No repairs or ad|Uslmcnts. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS SKCOND AND THIRD GEARS Slip on Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive 11 P. pull Speed speed wheels Gall. H.P.hrs. Lbs. per Lbs. M.p.h. R.p.m. P.ct. P"'hr- P"S"1- H.P.hr. STEEL WHEELS 11.88 1,409 3.16 1,100 5.78 2.748 4.32 1.587 11.5 V 757 5.7-1 1.100 2.87 3.049 3.80 1.805 RUBBER TIRES Additional weight per rear wheel was 560 pounds, 100 pounds from. Rear tire size: 9.00" X 36". 16.71 2,198 2.H5 1,099 5.64 2.527 6.61 1.037 16.51 1,193 5.19 1,100 2.52 2.529 6.53 1.051 Test No. 283. OLIVER HART-PARR STANDARD 70 HC, Oliver Farm Equip - ment Company, Charles City, Iowa; June 14 to 22, 1937. American-Bosch "M)B6A-3.02" magneto; Zenith "124'/; EX" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wire-scrcen-filtcr air cleaner; Handy variable-speed, centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12!'/', face 7Vi", rated speed 774 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Borg &amp; Beck single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.44, second 3.32, third 4.33, fourth 5.88, reverse 2.44. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests a lug bolt was lost and the lug was broken. The lug was replaced with a new one. The remaining lug bolts were checked and most of them were tightened slightly. Test No. 284. OLIVER HART-PARR STANDARD 70 KD, Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa; June 24 to 30, 1937. </seg>
         <seg id="p041">Nebraska Tractor Tests ¦| . ¦ ¦ .- ¦¦¦ ' . .'.--, American Bosch "MJB6A-302" migncto; Zenith "12414 EX" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wirc-scrcen-filtcr air cleaner; Handy variable-speed, centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter \2'A", face 7*A", rated speed 774 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive: Borg &amp; Beck single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.44, second 3.32, third 4.33, fourth J5.88, reverse 2.44. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test the center steering shaft dropped out of the front steering arm. The shaft was put into place and the clamping bolt tightened. Test, No. 285. ALLIS-CHALMERS WK-O, Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; August 26 to Scpttmbcr 2, 1937. Mallory "MO-9OAT" ignition system; Dcco "PB-100-4" fuel system; United, oil - washed, steel-wool-filter air cleaner; own variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: four (cylinder, vertical, fuel injection, spark ignition, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face B'A", rated speed 1050 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; own single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour:! first 1.72, second 2.59, third 3J26, fourth 5.92, reverse 2.10. Comments: The fuel injectors were cleaned during the belt test. Test No. 286. ALLIS-CHALMERS SO, Allis-Chalmers Company, Milwaukee, Wis - consin; September 16 to 25, 1937. I : Mallory "MO-4 type 178" ignition system; Dcco "PB-100-5" fuel system; United, oil-washed, steel-wool-filter air cleaner; Pierce variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder, vertical, fuel injection, spark ignition, "I" head, mounted crank - shaftjlcngthwisc. Belt pulley: diameter \VA", face 10", rated speed 770 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour:.first 1.51, second 2.3J2, third 3.25, fourth 4.55, fifth 637, reverse 1.76. C&gt;mments: On the completion of the belt test, the water-pump gland nut was tightened one-third turn. | Test No. 287. ALLIS-CHALMERS L-O, Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; September 9 to 22j 1937. Mallory "MO-4 type 90" ignition system; Deco "PB-200-3" fuel system; United oil - wash steel-wool-filter air cleaner; own variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinccr, vertical, fuel injection, spa^k ignition, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: diameter 20", face 15", rated speed 580 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; own double-plate. dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first i.48, second 1.94, third 2.68, fourth 3.50, fifth 4.90, sixth 6.41, reverse 1.72 and ¦2.25.1 -• - -.••• : - ¦ \:: ; I\ ¦• ¦ ¦¦: . ¦:¦_ .• ¦ \ ¦ Comments: The fuel transfer pump pressure gauge failed during the maximum drawbar tests. It was replaced with another gauge. Test No. 288, CLETRAC BD, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; Sept - ember 16 to October 2, 1937. I . . . ¦ Bosch "PE6A65A4105506" fuel system; Vprtox oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner and A-C prc-cleancr; Bosch vacuum governor. Engine six cylinder, vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face B Yz", rated speed 1148 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; Long double-plate dry clutct. Advertised speeds, miles peri hour: first 1.8, second 2.625, third 3.50, reverse 1-325 : •-.-... _¦' ¦ _.- I •"•¦ ;, ¦¦; - :.,• :•,.; ¦¦¦¦:.•¦ Comments: No repairs or adjustments. T(3t No. 289. CLETRAC CG, Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio; Sept - ember 16 to October 4, 1937. Delco-Remy "642 W" distributor,; Tilloteon "Y-7-B" carburetor; Vortox oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner and A-C pre-clcaner; Hercules centrifugal governor. Engine: six cylinder, vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 13", face ; 1", rated speed 1017 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; Long double - plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first l f B7, second 3.05, third 4.44, revere 2.28. . ."._ ;' ' ' ¦-: . -•..: ' !. ': ", ..' ¦ Cjmmcnts: No repairs or adjustments. , </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 Test No. 290. M-M TWIN CITY ZT, Minncapolis-Molinc Power Implement Com - pany, Minneapolis. Minnesota; October 4 to 12, 1937. Fairbanks-Morse "RV-4" magneto: Schcblcr "TRXI2" carburetor; Donaldson oil - wasliai wire-filter air cleaner and prc-clcancr; own variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: lour cylinder, vertical, valves in block, horizontal over piston, mounted crank - shaft lengthwise. licit pulley: diameter 14", face 7", rated speed 786 r.p.m. Chassis: trioclc: enclosed gear drive: Twin Disc single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.18, second 2.62, third 3.13, fourth 4.57, fifth 14.3 (not recommended lor steel wheels), reverse 1.00. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 291. HUBER LC, Hubcr Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; October 11 to 28, 1937. American Bosch "MJB4A-112" magneto; Zenith "455" carburetor; Donaldson oil - washed wire-screcn-fiher air cleaner; Waukcsha centrifugal governor. Engine; fout cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 14", /'.ice 7'» ", rated speed 706 r.p. m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc sinjilc-nlatc dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.4, second 3.5, third ¦1.5. reverse 1.8. Comments: The line to the oil pressure gauge broke during the preliminary draw - bar k-st» and was replaced with a new one. Before the third-gear maximum run on steel was made, the hub bolts on one front wheel were tightened. During the third - gcir maximum run, the transmission slipped out of gear several times. After the third- quadrant slot was filed deeper to allow the transmission feeler plunger to scat, this trouble did not recur. The main fuel tank leaked at the lower front seam during the maximum drawbar tests. The tank was removed and both end seams were com - pletely rcsoldcrcd. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS SECOND AND THIRD CEARS S''P on Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive —. H.P. pull Speed speed wheels Gals. H.P.hrs. Lbs.per Lbs. M.f.h. R.p.m. P.ct. per hr. per gal. H.P.hr. STEEL WHEELS 25.34 2,122 4.12 1,200 4.45 3.207 7.28 0.952 20.47 1,416 5.42 1,201 4.07 2.999 6.83 1.015 RUBBER TIRES Addnion.il ueisht per rear wheel was 530 pounds. Rear tire size: 11.25" x 24". 21.43 2.387 3.37 1.200 9.33 2.848 7.52 0.921 24.90 2,0«r, 4.48 1,200 7.89 2.705 9.21 0.753 Test No. 292. HUBER B, Hubcr Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio; October 13 to November S, 1937. American Bosch "MIC4A-102" magneto; Zenith "TU4VP" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wire-screen-filter air cleaner; Pierce centrifugal fixed-speed governor, adjust - able from scat. Engine: four cylinder, vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley, diameter 10", face 6K", rated speed 990 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.2, second 3.2, third 4.3, fourth approximately 10.0, reverse 1.80. Comments: During the limber-up test a small leak developed in one end of the main fuel tank. The tank was removed and both ends completely rcsoidered. The ex - haust valves in cylinders 2 and 3 were reseated, refaced, and ground before running the steel-wheel drawbar test. The fuel line from the auxiliary tank to the fuel filter cracked at a flanged connec - tion. The broken end was cut off and the tube rcflanged. One skid-ring bolt on the left front wheel and two spoke-to-rim bolts on the right rear wheel were lost out and replaced. </seg>
         <seg id="p043">Nebraska Tractor Tests FUEL ECONOMY TESTS—SECOND AND THIRD GEARS Slipon Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive —'— '¦ pull Speed speed wheels Gals. H.P.firs. Lit. per H.?.. Us. M.p.h. R.p.m. P.ct. pcrhr. pergal. H.P.hr. ¦ STEEL WHEELS ¦ 1629 1,695 3.60 1,301 2.08 2.917 5.58 1.098 1570 1,231 4.78 1,299 2.00 2.860 5.49 1.117 '. RUBBER TIRES Additional weight per rear wKxl was 450 pounds. .Rear tire iize: 9.00" x 36". 1772 2,156 3.08 1,300 8.27 2.620 6.76 0.906 18 62 1,647 4.24 1,300 4.85 2.636 7.06 0.868 Test No. 293. MASSEV-hArRIS TWIN POWER CHALLENGER, Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin; October 25 to November 16, 1937. American-Bosch "MJB4A-306" magneto; Zenith "62-AX9" carburetor; Donaldson oil-Washed wire-screen-filter air cleaner; Kingston variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder, vertical, "I".head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 12", face 6'A", rated speed 832 and 969 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear [drive; Twin Disc single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.4, second 3.3, third 4.1, fourth 8.5, reverse 3.0. dornments: The air cleaner intake flange supporting the air cleaner stack broke loose from the top of the cleaner during) the maximum drawbar test. This cleaner was re - placed with a new one o£ later design. , FUEL ECONOMY TESTS—SECOND AND THIRD GEARS :. . ; ... I Slipon Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive: ¦— ¦ — pull Speed speed wheels ¦ Gals. HJ&gt;.hrs. Lbs.per K.P. Lbs.: M.p.h. . R.p.m. P.ct. ' perhr. pergal. H.P.hr. .¦.'.¦'¦ "JSTEEL WHEELS '¦ .. •/.•.•• 19 f 63 1,999 3.68 1,200 5.89 2.969 6.61 0.921 19.93 1,617 4.62 1,200 . 5.03 3.009 6.62 0.920 ¦ . . . ¦ RUBBER: TIRES . . Additional weight per rear wheel was 950 pounds. Rear, tire size: 11.25" x 36". 24.64 2,777 3.33 1,200 6.96 2.938 8.39 0.718 24.69 2,202 4.20 1,200 5.41 2.902 8.51 0.707 Test No. 294. MASSEY-HARMS TWIN POWER PACEMAKER, Masscy-Harris Cbm'pany, Racine, Wisconsin; Octolcr 25 to November 16, 1937. American-Bosch "MJB4A-306" magneto; Zenith "62-AX9" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed wirc-screcn-filtcr air demer; Kingston variable-speed centrifugal governor Engine: four cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diartieter 12", face 6*A", rated speed 832 and 969 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single-plate (Iry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.4, second 3.3, third 4.1, fourth 8.5, reverse 3.0. Comments: Before the drawbar tests were run, it was found that the top of the air cleaner was cracked at the point where the air cleaner stack was attached. This cleaner was [replaced with a new one of later design. ¦'&#132;.-. </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 fuel economy tests second and third gears ... „ , , , sl,'l? on Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive _ pull Speed speed wheels Gall. H.P.hrs. Lbs. per Hp Lbs. M.p.h. R.p. m . P.ct. pcrhr. per gal H£.hr. STEEL WHEELS 20.26 2,048 3.71 1,200 5.50 3.038 6.67 0.903 1'»92 1,617 1.62 1.200 5.03 3.009 6.62 0.920 RUBBER TIRES .AJJiiionjl uciflii per reir ulierl was 1,025 pounds. Rear tire size: 12.75"xM". 20.12 2.2.52 3.31 1,201 6.37 2.485 8.10 0.7-13 24.01 2.173 4.H 1,201 5.62 2.871 8.36 0.720 Test No. 295. JOHN DEERE G, John Dccre Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; November 15 to 19, 1937. Edison-Splinlorf "CD-2" magneto; Schcblcr "DLTX-24" carburetor; Donaldson oil - washed wirc-scrcen-filtcr air cleaner; own variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: two-cylinder, horizontal, "1" dead, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: diameter 12 1 ;/]&lt;&gt;". lace .S!i", raicd speed 9/5 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; own double-plate ,!ry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.25, second 3.25, third -4.25. fourth (&lt;, reverse 3. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No. 296. GRAHAM-BRADLEY 503.103, Graham-Paige Motors Corporation, Detroit. Michigan: April 6 to M, 1938. Dflfo-Remy "1101351" generator; Dclco-Rcmy 1110503 distributor; Schcblcr "TRX-15" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed, wirc-scrccn-filtcr air cleaner; Handy variable-speed, centrifugal governor. Engine: six-cylinder, vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. licit pulley: diameter 15", face 7%", rated speed 714 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Long single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.77, second 4.42, third 5.67, fourth 19.8, reverse 2.03. Comments: During the rated load drawbar test, the carburetor high-speed screw was momentarily opened approximately one turn and then closed the same amount to clear an apparent obstruction. Test No. 297. McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL F-M, International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois; April 19 to 27, 1938. Own "i'-T magneto; own "A-I0" carburetor; own oil-washed wire-filter air cleaner; own variable-speed, centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. licit puHcy: diameter 12'/»", face 6V4", rated speed 797 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.375, second 3.125, third 4.00, reverse 2.375. Comments: The pin which holds the splined end of the steering rod in the splined uniwrsal joint sheared off twice, once during the limber-up run and again during the rated load drawbar test. The cylindcr-head'to-radiator hose connection was tightened at the beginning of the drawbar test. Test No 298. McCORMICK-DEERING TracTracTor TD-40, International Harvester Company. Chicago, Illinois: April 20 to 30, 1938. Own "F-4" magneto (for starting only); own "C-12" carburetor (for starting only); own fuel system; Donaldson oil-washed wirc-scrccn filter air cleaner; own variable-speed, centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder vertical Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Ik-It pulley: diameter Ut%", face 9", rate speed 645 r.p.m. Chassis: track - layer: enclosed gear drive: Rockford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.75, second 2.25, third 2.75, fourdi 3.25, fifth 4.00, reverse 2.25. Comments. No repairs or adjustments. </seg>
         <seg id="p045">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 299. FORDSON ALL-AROUND (Gasoline), Ford Motor Company, Limit - ed, Essex, Dagcnham, England;. May 9to 20, 1938. ¦ v „ . Robert Bosch "FU4BRS29-T 1 magneto; Zenith "INST" carburetor; Handy pre - cleaner and oil-washed, wire-screen air cleaner; Handy variable-speed centrifugal gov - ernor Engine: four cylinder, vertical,! "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley, diameter 9&gt;A", face 6Vi", ra cd speed 1100 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; own multiple-plate (in oil) clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 1.92, second 2.91, third 5.13, reverse 1.61. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. PUEL ECONOMY TESTS —SECOND AND THIRD GEARS i Slip on Fuel consumption haft drive ¦ ¦ — ¦ pull Speed speed wheels Gals, H.V.hrs. Lbt.per H.P. Us. M.p.h. R.p.m. P.ct. perhr. per gal. H.P.hr. ¦ ¦ ¦ STEEL WHEELS / :' :; &gt; . ; 15.05 1,803 3.13 1,100 2.69 2.636 5.71 1.070 11.76 796 5.54 1.100 2.19 2.563 4.59 1.332 I RUBBER TIRES Added weisht per rear wheel (was 552 pounds. Rear tire lire: WWW. 17.93 2391 2.81 1,099 9.76 2.526 7.10 0.861 lS 1,315 5.20 1100 5.21 2.640 6.91. 0.884 Tot No 300 OLIVER ROW CROP 80 KD, Oliver Farm Equipment Company, n£e.o ; Schebler "TrX-18" carburetor; I^nald - son "pfe-deaner and oil-washed, wire screen filter air cleaner; own variable-speed, cen - ttUugll governor. Engine: four cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wisenßclt pulley: diameter 14 &gt;A", tice 7X", rtaed speed 731 rp.m. Chassis: tricyce; encloJed gear drive; Borg &amp; Beck single-plate dry clutch. Advertued speeds, m.les per hour: first 2.7, second 3.33, thircj 4.33, reverse 3.00. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. Test No 301 OLIVER STANpARD 80 KD, OVwcr-Faim Equipment Company, tt|Sffir mtgneto; Scheb.c, carburetor; Dongon prc-clcaner and oil-washed wire-screen filter air cleaner; own vamble-speed, centrifugal eovS. Engine: four cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. BeuTuley: toeter 145?', face 7 i", rated speed 731 r P m. Chas S .s: s^ndard, en, dosed gear drive-, Borg &amp; Beck sin'glc-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per tlal. oil leak developed between the : valve] cover and the cylinder head. . ¦¦¦: , ¦ ¦ T«t No 30Z. ALUS-CHALMERS B, Allis-Chalmcrs Manufacturing Company, mfc Si"6lA7" carburetor; Donaldson oil - wasS"e-screen filter air cleaner; Handy variable-speed ccmnfugal governor 3e four cylinder, vertical, "I" head/mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt puUey St r 8", face 514". rated speed 1050 r.p.m. Chassvs: standard, enclosed.sear dnve; R6ck'ford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second ¦'•"Immen'f DuringSriod bJtween Uie 100 per cent maximum^., tes, and the orKSrmTximVm belt test when ,i.o official readings were being uken, the fuel line •2£f3S auSy gasoline tank to the carburetor broke. This line W as replaced with a new.one. ' .;' ¦ I ' . : . . ¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 Test No. 303. ALLIS-CHALMERS WC (Distillate), Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; May 31 to June H, 1938. Fairbanks Morse "F.M.48" magneto; Zenith "124/2 TOP" carburetor; United oil - washed, wire-filter air cleaner; Kingston variable-speed, centrifugal governor. Engine: four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 9", face 6'A", rated speed 1170 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Rockford single-plate, dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second 3.50, third 4.75, fourth 9.00, reverse 2.00. Comments: During the drawbar tests a small oil leak developed at the governor speed control lever bearing in the governor housing and another around the shift lever pivot pin in the transmission cover. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS SECOND AND THIRD GEARS Slip on Fue l consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive pull Speed speed wheels Gals. H.P. hrs. Lbs. per HP. Lbs. M.p.li. R.p.m. P.ct. per hr. per gal. H.P.hr. STEEL WHEELS 14.81 1,447 3.84 1,301 4.29 " 1.944 7.62 0.904 12.92 944 5.13 1,301 3.55 1.973 6.55 1.052 RUBBER TIRES Additional weight per rear wheel was 425 pounds (cast iron), 285 pounds (calcium chloride) solution. Rear tire size: 11.25" I 24". 17.68 1,925 3.44 1,300 6.80 1.888 9.36 0.736 17.90 1,439 4.67 1,299 4.87 1.926 9.29 0.741 Test No. 304. ALLIS-CHALMERS WC (Gasoline), Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; June 2 to 16, 1938. Fairbanks Morse "F.M.48" magneto; Zenith "124 'A TOP" carburetor; United oil - washed wire-filter air cleaner; Kingston variable-speed, centrifugal governor. Engine: four cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 9", face 6'A", rated speed 1170 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Rock - ford single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.50, second 3.50, third 4.75, fourth 9.00, reverse 2.00. Comments: During the drawbar tests a small oil leak developed at the governor speed control lever bearing in the governor housing and another around the shift lever pivot pin in the transmission cover. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS SECOND AND THIRD GEARS Slip on p ue l consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive pull Speed speed wheels Gals. HJ'.hrs. Lbs. per HP. Lbs. M.p.h. R.p.m. P.ct. per hr. per gal. H.P./ir. STEEL WHEELS 17.67 1,727 3.84 1,300 0.28 2.173 8.13 0.758 17.00 1,226 5.20 1,300 0.04 2.223 7.65 0.805 RUBBER TIRES Additional weight per rear wheel was 425 pounds (cast iron), 285 pounds (calcium chloride) solution. Rear tire size: 11.25" x 24". 19.05 2,118 3.37 1,299 8.29 2.013 9.46 0.651 20.10 1,640 4.60 1,299 5.87 2.099 9.58 0.643 Test No. 305. JOHN DEERE B, John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; September 6 to 16, 1938. Wico "AP-477-B" magneto; Schebler "DLTXIO" carburetor; Donaldson oil-washed, wire-screen filter air cleaner; own centrifugal governor. Engine: two cylinder, "I" head, </seg>
         <seg id="p047">Nebraska Tractor Tests horizontal, mounted crankshaft crosswise. ISeitpuUey: diameter 10'/.", face 6". «»4 speed 1150 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle enclosed gear drive; .""/"M* ** «htch. Adverted speeds, miles per hour: first 2.33, second 3.00, third 4.00, fourth 5.25, '"oWnis- Before the drawbar ests were run, a leak was discovered at the fuel ttnk outlet flanpe soldered joint. This was repaired. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS—SECOND AND THIRD GEARS . ) Slip on Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive — : ¦¦ . • null Speed speed . wheels Gals. HJ.hrt. Lbt.pir H.E. Lbs. M.p.h. R!p.m. P.ct. perhr. per gal. H.P.hr. : • . STEEL WHEELS 10.84 1,228 3.31 !l 149 0.66 1.589 6.82 1.010 8.67 "38 4.41 1149 0.90 1.555 5.58 1.236 '¦ . RUBBER TIRES . : ". Additional -weight per rear wheel was 276 pounds. Rear lire size: 9.00" x 36". IV7C 1584 314 l!, 151 4-78 1.396 / 9.50 0.725 13J12 1,195 U2 i,149 3.70 1.451 : 9.04 0.762 Test No. 306. MASSEY-HARMS "101"S, Masscy-Harris Company, Racine, Wis - rtfit^fsw:™**. ator; Auto^ite I G. C,4402-l dis^ibutor; "TRX-22" carburetor; United oil-wished, crimped wire air cleaner; Handy centrifug '¦''lommen"? During the preliminary rubber tire tests an intermittent miss developed ill Nfo. 5 cylinder which was due to a defective spa* plug. The plug was replaced with 3 "Sinning the preliminary steel wheel drawbar tests .. piece of solder was fourid in and. removed from the fuy-tank-to-sediment-bowl connecnon. FUEL ECONOMY VESTS—SECOND AND THIRD OEABS Slip on Fuel consumption Dl3 ar Speed whSs O^^J.^ J.P. Lbs, M.p.h. R.p.m. P.ct. pcrhr. pcrgal. H.PM. RUBBER TIRES Addmcal «elEht per rear wheel, wa, 705 pound, («« irra ). 300 pound, water. Rear lire sue: 12.75 xM . ¦ ;^V^./^.s; j»"^;.:^.:ra;.-:!Sv STEEL WHEELS-. |Test No. 307. MASSEY-HARIUS "101" R, Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wis- Auto-Lite I. G. C,4402-l toibutor; Schebler </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 321 pulley: diameter 13 !4", face 6'A", rated speed 694 r.p.m. at J5OO, 833 r.p.m. at 1800. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; Borg 6t Beck dry disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 2.59, second 3.63, third 4.85, fourth 17.35 (1800 r.p.m.), reverse Comments: No repairs or adjustments. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS —SECOND AND THIRD GEARS P,,. X „ . . , Sl} p.on Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive _ pull Speed speed wheels Gait. H.P.hrs. Lbt.per HP. Lbs. M.p.i. R.p.m. Pxt. perhr. per gal. H.P.hr. RUBBER TIRES Additional weight per rear wheel wai 424 pounds can iron, 331 pounds water. Rrar tire lize: 11.25" I 36". 24.83 2,663 3.50 1,499 6.59 2.506 9.91 0.623 24.79 1,936 4.80 1,500 4.21 2.489 9.96 0.619 STEEL WHEELS 20.76 2,138 3.6-) 1,500 5.55 2.625 7.91 0782 20.33 1,520 5.01 1,499 2.80 2.643 7.69 0.80 J Test No. 308. CASE "R", J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; October 10 to 20, American Bosch "MJB-fAlOo"' magneto; Zenith "\9i'/i" carburetor; United oil - washed, crimped wire air cleaner; Waukesha-Case variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine four-cylinder, vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 10'/&gt;", face 6'A", rated speed 991 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear and chain drive; Twin Disc, single plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour (rubber tires): first 2.33, second 3.33, third 4.50, reverse 2.50. Comments: Throughout the complete test there was a slight grease leak at a welch plug in the front of. the transmission case cover. Test No. 309. CASE "L", J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin; October 10 to 24. 1938. Own magneto; Zenith "K-6-A" carburetor; own oil-washed, wire screen air cleaner; own variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: four-cylinder, vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 13", face Wt", rated speed 781 r.p.m. Chassis: standard, enclosed gear and chain drive; Twin Disc single disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour: first 3.52, second 4.48, third 5.58, reverse 3.78. Comments: After approximately 35 hours of operation the cooling medium tem - perature indicator ceased to function properly and was reading about 70 degrees higher than it should. FUEL ECONOMY TESTS SECOND AND THIRD GEARS _ , „ , , , sll P°n Fuel consumption Drawbar Crankshaft drive _ pull Speed speed wheels Gait. H.P.hrs. Lbs. per HP U»- M.p.h. R.p.m. P.ct. perhr. per gal H.P.hr. RUBBER TIRES Additional weight per rear wheel wal 471 pounds cast iron, 422 poundj water. Rear tire lize: 13.50" x 28". 32.11 2,768 4.35 1,100 5.77 3.198 10.05 0.688 32.05 2,186 5.50 1,099 4.45 3.245 9.88 0.700 STEEL WHEELS 25.74 2,657 3.63 1,098 3.62 3.240 7.94 0.870 23.62 1,921 4.61 1,099 2.02 3.224 7.33 0.943 </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 310. M-M TWIN CITY TJTS (Gasoline), Minneapolis-Moline Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; October 24 to November 16, 1938. Fairbanks-Morse "FM-4B" magneto; Schebler "TTX-1 7" carburetor; Donaldson oil - waihed, wire-screen air cleaner; own speed centrifugal governor. Engine: four - cylinder,: vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 1514*), face 7", rated speed 733 r.p'.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc tingle plate clutch. Advertised (speeds, miles per hour (rubber tires): fint 2.7, ieeond 3.5, third 4.7, fourth 6.2, fifth 20.2, reverse 1.3. Comments: While filling one oil the rear tires with water from a barrel carrying approximately 15 pounds air pressure, the valve stem came off the inner tube. A new item was vulcanized to the tube and it was used throughout the drawbar tests. Test No. 311. M-M TWIN CITY UTS (Distillate), Minneapolis-Moline Implement Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota; November 21 to 25, 1938. Fairbanks-Morse "FM4B" magneto; Schebler "TTX-17", carburetor; Donaldson oil - washed wire screen air cleaner; ownlvariable speed centrifugal governor. Engine: four - cylinder, vertical, "1" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 15J1T, face 7", rated speed 733 r.p'.m. Chassis: standard, enclosed gear drive; Twin Disc single plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour (rubber tires): first 2.7, second 3.5, third 4.7, fourth 6.2, fiflh 20.2, reverse 1.3. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. • Test No.' 312. JOHN DEERE "H", John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa; October 31 to November 10, 1938. I Eaison-Splitdorf "RM-2" magneto; Marvel-Schebler "DLTX-26" carburetor; United oil-washed, crimped wire air cleaner! own variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: two-cylinder, horizontal, "1" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: diameter 12' A'{, face V/i", rated speed 700 r.p.m. Chassis: tricycle; enclosed gear drive; own double disc clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour, (rubber tires): first 2.50, second 3.s(Uthird 5.75, reverse 1.75. | ¦¦'.: Comments: No repairs or adjustments. . Tat No. 313. JOHN DEERE I, John Deere Wagon Works-Moline Tractor Division of Deere &amp; Co, Molme, Illinois; November 14 to 16, 1938. Edison-Splitdorf "RM Series 03509" magneto; Marvel Schebler "TS-13" carburetor; United oil-washed, crimped wire air Jdeaner; Handy variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: two-cylinder vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: diameter 6'A", face 4'A", rated speed 1480 r.p.m. Chassis: standard; enclosed gear drive 1; Long CB-C single-plate dry clutch. Advertised speeds, miles per hour (rubber tires}: first 2.50, second 3.75, third 6.00, reverse 3.75. Comments: No repairs or adjustments. . . Te»t No. 3M. CATERPILLAR DIESEL D-8 (850 r.p.m.), Caterpillar Tractor Com - pany] Peoria, Illinois; November 28 io 30, 1938. Own fuel injection system; Donaldson oil-washed, wire-screen filter and collector prerdeaner air cleaner; own variable-speed centrifugal governor. Engine: six-cylinder vertical, Diesel, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise.; Belt pulley: diameter 1414", face 13", rated speed 719 r.p.m. Chassis: tracklayer; enclosed gear drive; own single - platJ dry crutch. Advertised speeds^ miles per hour: first 1.4, second 2.0, third 2.3, fourui 2.7, fifth 3.2, sixth 4.4, reverse 1.4-2.3. ; Comments: No repairs or adjustments. : </seg>
         <seg id="p050"/>
         <seg id="p051"/>
         <seg id="p052"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>