<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Norfolk State Hospital TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE NorfolkState Hospital TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908 BY G. A. YOUNG, M. D., SUPERINTENDENT 19M </seg>
            <seg id="p002">1&gt;"».\I\I' * ' I I I 13 !-• H l&lt;-\» 1 &gt; Jinkin. Secretary of State Secretary State Treasurer VttOrnev General KKSIDENT OFFICEBt Ym NO, M. I) A DtSBONQ, M. D. I.1.KV. M. I) SlKCLAI*. • ■ Superintendent of Nurses . Steward I RoHH Matron Lilui E. Baeki H M Eaton, CommiMioaer Public Lands and Buikbof ..President H Lawsom &lt;; Beian H&lt;&gt;\ William T. Thomiwon Superintendent . . . First Ass't Physician Second Ass't Physician </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Norfolk, Nkihi., Uk&lt; . 1. l!»u-- rD His Excellency, George Law son Sheldon. Governor of Nebraska: Dear Sir — I have the honor of submitting to you a report of the Norfolk State Hospital, covering the period from December 1. 1906 to November 30, 1908, inclusive. OFFICIAL CHAN (it At the date of the last biennial report. December 1. 1906, the administration of the hospital was conducted by the following officers: Dr. (i. A. Young, Superintendent, Dr. H. D. Singer. First Assistant Physician, and Mr. Alex Peters. Steward. During the biennium, the following changes have taken place; Dr. Singer resigned August 1"). 1907. to accept the position as Director of the • 'syehcrpathic Institute, of Illinois. He was succeeded by Di . W. Dishong, who, at that time, was officiating as Second Assist nt Physician and Pathologist. Mr. Alex Peters resigned April 1" 907, and was succeeded by Mr. Mont Robb. Dr. Ernest Kelle Homed the duties of Second Assistant Physician and Pathologist )eceml&gt;er Js, 1907, and Miss Helen C. Sinclair took up her wor superintendent of Nurses. January 1, 1007. Mrs. Lillia aker was appointed to the position of Matron. February 1. I90J MOVEMENT t&gt;F POPULATION i Owing to the fact that at the last legislature, the hospita Hastiifgs was changed to a receiving hospital, a redistrietin, the state was necessary. This Institution had been receiving tients from the counties north of the Platte. with the exeeptioi Douglas and Sarpy County. As the hospital was alread\ )\vded. and the prospect of relief by the erection of new building ..s not favorable, the district tributary to the Norfolk Hospita jj cut down, so that it contained twenty-five counties in the rtheast and north part of the state. The present populatioi the hospital is two hundred and eighty-three and the hospita crowded far in excess beyond what is proper for it. so far as gienic care of the patients is concerned. With the completioi </seg>
            <seg id="p004">164 of the new buildings now in the course of erection, there will be a &lt;itv of approximately four hundred and twenty-five patients. •i of the number of admissions during the year pn ing the redistricting of the state and the number admitted during following, show a reduction in the admissions for the i nearly one-third. I'pon the completion of the new buildings. I believe the Norfolk district should again be enlarged and the population of the hospital thereby be increased, in the - of a lower per capita cost of maintenain !At the iK'ginning of the biennium there were present in the NjMtal two hundred and nineteen patients. During the biennium i-ived two hundred and thirty-one patients. ve left the hospital as discharged, paroled, died, escaped, one hundred and sixty-seven patients, a percent - • of the admit mounting to seventy-two and a fraction. BMC in population, over the number present December lalfl sixty-four, or a percent of twenty-seven and a ction. The present populatUm of the hospital at the efc ■ biennium is two hundred and eightv-tlr A statistical table of the discharges, paroles, deaths, etc. will be found among the medical tables at the end of the report I'KIVIIM. VI I. HOSPITAL M A N \ &lt; . K M I. \ I 1'ignized that economic principles as well as charit - &gt;le underlie the management of the State Hospitals for the Insane, d in fad ipying the more prominent place. The quest ion insanity must \h&gt; studied with relation to the community at «'ll as with respect to the welfare of the individual insane tient The 1h&gt; no question but that the relative, as ■11 as tin i- number of the insane, is growing. The ratio the insane to the sane in this country varies from 1 :"2."&gt;0 to 1 :.")00. fair average for the entire country would approximate 1 :350. this state the ratio of the insane in the hospitals to the total potation approximates 1 :."&gt;(M). The los.s to the state and nation, : both in the actual cost of supporting the insane and the the inability of the insane to produce, reaches enormous This the last legislature appropriated mI.&lt;&gt;0 for the support of the insane during the past biennium. ition for maintenance alone is probably not less an 940.000.000.00. vearlv. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">165 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK F;u- more serious, however, than the monetary loss, u the nenaee to the average standards of general health and ability, )\ the mingling of the insane and the potentially, or near insane. rith the rest of the community. There is nothing more tragic in ur social life than the perpetuation of the insane constitution, by l-advimd marriages ami the production of morbid personalities. riminals, the insane, and the imbecile. The problem u not m inch the care of the present insane, as the determination of the ausal elements of insanity as found in the social habits, customs iid tendencies of our time. In this period, which is essentially that of constructs well as regulative government . the state hospitals should he regarded in the light of their opportunities for careful study of the intimate nature of insanity, as well as in their character of charitable and emedial institutions. From this aspect, it would appear that the ►olicy of frequent changes in the medical forces of our state hospitals - unfortunate, for it effectually discourages original and systematic vork upon the part of the resident physicians. I'nder this custom he consideration of salary looms large and the position is regarded is transitory. Statistics of value can he only obtained by the mployment of a uniform analytical system covering a number of cars, and it is needless to sa\ that the results will he of more value when the data are elicited by phyi than when the work has to he k change of state administration. partially to the medical personnel much to increase their efficiency. licians of experience in the work arned and relearne 1 with every The merit system applied im - of our state hospitals would do LA fruitful field for research lie it h reference to its constitution in the study of the insane mind ind tendencies before the onset f active insanity and after recovery from disease With the recent dvances in the science of psychology permitting of more accurate &gt;sycho-analvsis as exemplified by the studies of Jung. Rieklin, leuler, and Kreimd of the Zurich School, such a study would be ot only of general scientific interest, but would have a distinct &gt;earing upon pedagogic method and the developing science of )sychotherapy. It is my belief that the future will bring forward lucational methods for the prevention of insanity and psychiatry ill develop along the lines of diagnosis of the potentially insane mong the young and adolescent with employment of educational methods of mental orthopedy. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">166 One of the drawback! '&gt;f the present system of hospital admin istnttion is the amount of business detail which is forced upon tin superintendent. As a medical man. he finds but little time foi study and medical matters. He is unable to put the' time he would like to the supervision of the treatment of the patients and to the direction of and cooperation with the medical force o the ho.ipital The salary of the assistant physicians is such that iily the younger physicians of comparatively little little ice. who need active direction and help. ■t effective solution of the difficulty would probabl) lie in the establishment of a central psychiatrical laboratory whose head should direct and guide the medical work of the different and act in cooperation with their respective superin tendei I With reference to the immediate care of the individual insane e time has pone by when the insane have been committed to the Hospitals for the purpose of segregation only. It is recog ted that the initially sick persons, and every effort shoult made to promote their recovery. They may be. for broa&lt; ~es. divided into two large classes: the acutely insane, needinj tive medical treatment, and the chronic miring custodia re and occupation suitable to their mental condition. For the rmer specially constructed hospital buildings should l&gt;e employee i the same principles as general hospitals, for the latter home if cottages and surroundings. The actual administration of this hospital may be divide* •hree departments, to- wit: first, that having to do with the ledical work, and falling under the supervision of the physicians d. the nursing department, centralized in the Superintenden f Nurses, which has to do with the nursing work and general car f the patients: third, the business department, which com) ral business affairs of the Institution, such as the financia farm and stock, engineering, and the 'general hi ing. These three main departments have been kept mor ir'less distinct, and the report will in substance take up each on »f these separately. MKDK'AL WORK During the past ten years there has l&gt;een increased activity in the ranks of the physicians working among the insane. This has been due in part to the introduction in this country of the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">167 HoslMTAI, FOR INSANE, NORFOLK merit system into the State Hospitals for the Insane, and in part to the increased interest, which has been shown all over the world in the study of insanity and allied nervous diseases. Freed from the competition of general practice, it is necessary for the resident physicians, who are placed in charge of the insane, that they shall exert themselves to perform painstaking and conscientious work. by carefully studying their patients, and by keeping abreast of the recent advances in the science of psychiatry. It is being demon - strated more and more clearly, that by careful treatment a larger percentage of recoveries can be obtained than heretofore, and that the symptoms of chronic mental disease can be so ameliorated that the patient may be made useful, either in hospital life, or at home. The State Hospitals furnish a large field for research, and opportunities in this direction should not be neglected. To make the research of permanent benefit careful records of individual - should 1k&gt; kept. There has been installed at this hospital, a new system of records of the loose leaf type, with a vertical filing which will promote, and in fact, require, the careful individ - ualization of each case. A typewriter has been installed in the physician's offices, and all records have been made in typewriting by the use of a permanent black type. This system has entailed more work than the old. but the results have been very gratifying, in that the records will be complete, and will afford data in years to come for statistical compilation. The laboratory work has l&gt;een carried on as far as the meagre facilities now available will allow, and provision has been made in the new hospital building when completed, for a laboratory of the most approved type. Hydrotherapeutic measures have been carried into effect freely with very good results. Provision for the future has also l&gt;een made in the large hospital building for women, for the equipment of a hydrotherapeutic plant. I The medical work of the hospital grows in volume in propor - on as the principle of individualization of patients is carried into Tect. The amount of routine detail work is large, and takes up iuch of the physician's time, which might be more profitably &gt;ent. As a remedy I would suggest here the advisablity of an iterneship, on the same plan as is found in the general hospitals. hereby, recently graduated physicians might enter the service the State Hospital for the experience they could obtain. It mild be neeessarv to pay but a small salary, little, if any more, than </seg>
            <seg id="p008">168 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT that gives to one of the experienced nurses. This interneship should Iw of one year's duration, and could be placed either upon mpetitive, or an appointive basis The general health of the Institution has been very flood, there having t&gt;een no cases of contagious or infectious di&gt;&gt; contracted in the hospital. Attention should here be called to the necessity of providing dental treatment for our patients and a special fund should be appropriated for this purp&lt; M KSIN(. DEPARTMENT As indicated in the last report two years ago. a reorganization of our nursing force has Ween undertaken. The object of the inent was to replace the old attendant force by a body of trained nurses and trained attendants, who would be able to give the patients under their charge, the skilled care that their condition required. It was decided to entirely do away with the so called "tramp attendant '. who moves from one state hospital to another, rendering ice in no instance, and remaining but a months in each place. The whole nursing and attendant was placed in charge of a Superintendent of Nurses, who - as an administrative officer, and is responsible only to the Superintendent. A Training School for Nurses was established, which has develojx*d during the past two years, until it is now on a firm basis, and is affiliated with the Omaha Methodist Hospital, the ("larkson Hospital, of Omaha, and the Mercy Hospital, of Council Bluffs. la. It has a course of two and one-half years, six months of which is spent in one of the affiliated hospitals mentioned. The Superintendent of Nurses, Mist Sinclair has l&gt;een indefatigable in the promotion of this work, and much of its success has been due to her efforts. Negotiations are now in progress, which will • in a short time in the Training School being registered under -landards of the training schools of the state of New York. It has been our purpose and practice to obtain our pupil nurses from the northeast part of t' and admit only, candidates, who have worked in no other institution, and who possess the proper requirements of character and education. In this way we have been able to train our nurses according to our own ideas, and the result has been gratifying in an increased efficiency in the thoughtful and consider of the patients. It has taken much work on t! • .perintendent of Nurses, and also </seg>
            <seg id="p009">169 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK tthc pail of the physicians, in the way of instructions ami of tures. but the results have been profitable. In every hospital for the insane, the: four distinct asses of patients to he dealt with First, the recent acutely sane patients and the physically sick, who need the most careful nd considerate nursing. For the care of these patients just the une conditions are necessary as are found in the most complete general hospital. They arc essentially sick, and require skilled ursing. Second, we have the incurable, who are aged and infirm; iese also need special care and nursing by proficient nurses. 'hird. we have the chronically disturbed or violent patients, who (i not need the nursing that the hist class requires, hut should &gt;e under the supervision of a graduate trained nurse, assisted by rained attendants. Fourth, are the incurable cases, who are uiet and orderly, and are affected by various grades of dementia. 'hese patients represent mainly, terminal states, and from their inks are drawn the large number of working patients, that are wary for accomplishing the work in the different departments : the hospital, to-wit: farm, laundry, sewing-room and so on. 'he nursing force of the hospital should meet the various needs of with trained nurses for the sick and infirm, and trained ttendants for the quiet and demented &lt; A serious effort has been made during 'he past two yean to novide occupation on the ward for those patients, whose condition not allow them to he employed away from the ward. This ork has been embodied in an industrial class, which has ccomplished a great deal in the way of embroider}' and basket ork. While the movement has been on a small scale it is one uit should Ik- developed. The basket work among the male latients could be developed to supply the hospital needs. I have icen in communication witli the United States Department of griculture, which has promised to send a number of basket willow ittings of the l&gt;est variety, to plant in the marshy places of our asture. With proper care we shall be able to raise sufficient illows for this work, and I believe good results would be seen in n increased interest and diminished apathy on the part of the emented cases. These cases, if not given some form of occupation hich they can learn, will sit for hours upon the ward, staring lankly before them: whereas, by a certain amount of teaching. ley can become useful members of the hospital life. The industrial </seg>
            <seg id="p010">land commissioner's report 170 trk has l&gt;een in charge of the attendants, who are themselves eiving a course of instruction in the proper performance ot ■ir din I The nursing force has lieen working under many difficulties e chief one of which, has been poor living quartan. For tin development of an efficient and steady force of nurses ant tendants. it is desirable that special quarters should be furnishec r them, to which they may be able to retire after their work i&gt; »ne. and enjoy a privacy and quiet, which ifl now impossible le work of a trained nurse or attendant among the insane is. at arduous and wearing, and the hours are very long. I e hospital desires to keep the most efficient form of help in thu •partment. it is necessary that it should provide comfortablt -ing conditions, which young women engaged in this work have : jht to expect. For this purpose. I Mieve an appropriatioi ould be made sufficient to build a nurses" and attendants" home nough toaccommodateat least thirty-five to forty individuals BUSINESS DEPARTMENT FINANCIAL For the maintenance of the hospital, the sum of 170,500.0 WAS appropriated by the legislature of 1907. This sum was $5000.0 less than the amount established. The prospect! are. howevei that the Institution will pass through the fiscal biennium, endin April 1. 1900, without a deficiency. At the beginning of th biennium. cm account of the poorly equipped state of the hospita it w: tury to purchase a large amount of material in orde to bring up the different departments to their proper degree ( efficiency. The semi-annual per capita cost for the biennium ha shown a uniform da - is seen from the following figures ,i-annual j&gt;eriod $130.86; second semi-annual perio. $119.00; third semi-annual period $111.04: fourth semi-annu; period $ ( .t't.74. with the assistance of Mr. Kobb. the Stewart rigid economy has been practiced, but has not been allowed t interfere with the charitable purposes of the hospital. Purchase have been made on the principle that a good equipment is a pre requisite to an economical administrate </seg>
            <seg id="p011">171 HOSPITAL FOK INSANE, NORFOLK Tallies showing the condition of the different funds at the ■nt time and the estimates for the coming biennium are append- The estimates arc based upon an average population of four hundred at a weekly per capita cost of $4.00 KAKM \ N 1) STUCK The Institution farm, which is composed of three hundrei id twenty acres, has engaged much of our attention during the asi two years. Investigation made by boring auger holes a fferent placet over the farm have shown that much of the ground hich has been considered as worthless on account of its sand\ ature. is underlaid by a good day sub-soil. Other parts of the inn. where the soil has been fairly good, have been overtaxei &gt;y repeated crops of corn, so that the soil was no longer properh roduetive for grain crop LYYe believe that the farm is well adapted for forage purposes, d the fifty acres in front of the Institution have been entirely »wn in alfalfa, brome grass and clover. The pasture, which ha ecu giving very poor returns for the acreage fenced in. has bee ivided up, and this year a tract of forty acres was plowed up anc lanted at once into corn, with the ultimate purpose of sowing i it h tame pasture gra&gt;ses next year. The held will be thoroughly lanured during the coming winter, and put in good condition fo •wing next spring. It is proposed that additional tracts of th asture shall be treated in like manner, as soon as the first plo an be used for grazing. The hospital as it develops will need a lcreasingly large dairy herd, and this plan of replacing the nativ asture sod with tame grass will meet the requirements of th mspital for years to come. The hospital has rented a farm of on undred and forty acres, one mile to the northwest of the Institi on farm, from which a fair return has been derived. The soi lowever. is sandy and poor, and I believe that the interest- of th nstitution require the purchase of an additional one hundred an xty acres of good corn and grain land to supplement the forag roduee of the present hospital farm. If this is done, the hospit; an raise its own beef and pork, and it will not be necessary t mrchase corn or other grain for feeding purp&lt; The stock has done well during the past year, we having at the present time, two hundred and sixty-eight hogs and seventy- ed to the report </seg>
            <seg id="p012">172 LAM) ( OMMISSIONKKS HKi'ORT It cattle. Of this Bomber, thirty steers ami one hundred an&lt; hogs are U'ing fed for fattening purpose. The dairy hen l&gt;een improved by the acquisition of a thoroughbred Holsteii and two registered Holstein cows. We now have fourteei e Holstein heifers, which in time will materially improve th Meter of the herd. I Would suggest, however, that mor tered heifers be purchased, as at this time our milk Buppl; it sum'cient for the needs of the hospital. The health of th I her- optionally good. The dairy cows and calves were itly tested by the Department of Agriculture, for tuberculosis found to he free from the disease. The returns fron farm and garden have been very good, and have material]] 1 in reducing the per capita cost of the Institution. A detailei • of the produce received will he found among t he st atistica "he end of the report. The cow-yard has Keen improve* ■&gt; avation of eighteen inches of dirt, and the replacing o soil by broken brick and plaster from the ruins of the oh ling. This fit covered with cinders, and has resulted in ; p which is. always dry and clean, even after the heaviest rains LNew ml a new alfalfa hog pasture have been constructed, new chicken house with a capacity &lt;&gt;f seven hundred chickens * just !&gt;een completed. The old Inn &gt; l&gt;e replaced by a new horse am airy barn at iiossihle time. The horse barn now stand lirty feet from the new hospital building, and is in a very poo ir. I would recommend that a new barn be erects mmediately south of t he present hay barn, and that it \x&gt; of th&lt; &gt;roper size to accommodate the farm and driving horses, and ak&lt; quarters in the basement for the accommodation of the dair\ lerd. The fences about the hog and cow pens are very mucl •roken down, and should l&gt;e replaced by strong new board fences ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT At the iK'ginning of the biennium the electric light ami powe plant of the hospital was badly in need of reconstruction. Tin boilers and generators were both old. and in fact were pure: shortly after the hospital was built in 18.K7. The boilers whicl of five 48 H. 1'.. horizontal tubular units were worn out and lequate for the needs of the hospital. It was MM at ion of the department be undertaken, and tha </seg>
            <seg id="p013">173 it should \w placed upon an efficient ;tinl economical basis. 1'nder the appropriation furnished by the last legislature, two 150 H. P. Atlas water tube boilers were purchased and were installed by anuary 1st. of the present year. It was hoped that the work of istallation could have been finished during the summer, l&gt;ut wing to the fact that the boilers did not arrive until the latter tart of October, it was accessary to build an addition to the present toiler room for the accommodation of the new boilers, as the old toilers could not be placed out of commission until the new ones lad been erected. The boiler room, therefore, was enlarged by an addition of 30ft.x60 ft., and during the summer of 1906, an additional coal-bin of 3Oft.x30 ft., was added, so as to make the whole building symmetrical, and to give additional coal storage room. At the present time we are still using the old generators, which are of about 2"&gt; K. W. and 15 K. \Y. capacity, respectively. These generators are belted to two old. and badly worn Westing - house engines, and the plant is likely to break down any time. The pumping plant &lt;&gt;f the Institution is in good condition, except that the steam pumps connected with the wells are expensive in the amount of steam they consume. During the summer of 1907, it was found necessary to take up one of the eight inch wells, and deepen it about twenty feet. A seven foot stratum of coarse water-bearing gravel was found, with a result that we now have abundant water supply. The power of the laundry is obtained by a shaft, which is connected to a small "20 H. I\ engine in the engine room. It will be necessary to install a new generator and engine in place of the two old belt-connected dynamos and Westing - house engines, and I would recommend here the purchase &lt;&gt;f a 75 H. 1'.. direct connected Corliss engine and generator. This outfit will be sufficient for the needs of the Institution for many years to come, and I believe by its purchase we can dispense with rparate engines for the well and laundry. These should be run by motors (deriving their current from the central generator. By concentrating the power production in one large unit, a distinct saving can be made in the consumption of steam, and therefore coal, which is one of our largest items of expenditure. By the use of this system the central generator can lx&gt; run from ."&gt;:(&gt;&lt;) o'clock in the morning to 10:&lt;M) o'clock at night, and power can be obtained economically at any part of the Institution that it iired. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">174 I The contract for electric light service between the bospita id the Norfolk Electric Light and Power Company expirei ugust IS, l'.K)7. and was not renewed. It has since l&gt;een demon rated that considerable saving lias l&gt;een accomplished by ih MpitaJ making its own electric light ami using the exhaust steal r heating purposes. At the present time the Hospital is usin jht from the Norfolk Company's wires, between the hour MMI o'clock in the evening and 5:00 o'cl^K-k in the morning. Fo i vice we pay a price of l()c per K. W. hour, and the averag itisumption amounts to 5(K) K. W. hours |&gt;er month, or a nionthh 11 of $50. 00. As the Institution grows larger the expense fo is night service is likely to prove heavy, and 1 believe the sum rvice can be mure cheaply obtained when the new generate is )»een installed, by the use of a storage battery. I The battery which should be a «if capacity of at least '2\{ upere hours could !&gt;e charged during the day time while the loai i the generator was light, at a comparatively small cost, and a 1:00 o'clock could l&gt;e brought into use for night service. Sucl battery of a capacity large enough to la; t the Institution for tlu it'teen or twenty years would cost between $1500.00 am 1 K». and would save its cost in the course of the next sevei eight yea t\Ve annually pay between $400.00 and $500.00 for ice. Wit! e installation of the Corliss engine and generator mentioned. ; n ton ice plant could be installed for the sum of $1500.00, an&lt; uld 1m' operated by a motor. This would effect considerable ving as well as make the problem of summer refrigeration mud lisfaetorv. tin an institution of this nature, there should l&gt;e a system of -t keeping, which should accurately show the cost of running i different departments. By the installation of water meters &gt;rding indicators accurate data could l&gt;e obtained as to umption of steam, coal and water, and would be a great Ip in checking waste in this department. Much repair work has been done. All exposed steam pipes been carefully covered, and the arrangement of the stean in the engine room has l&gt;een changed to a more orderly am simple arrangement. A ventilation tunnel has been made l&gt;etween the general kitchen and the smoke stack to allow ventilation ii uinmer and to effect the removal of condensed steam fron </seg>
            <seg id="p015">175 HOSPITAL FOR I.NSANK. NORFOLK the steam cookers, in the winter. The engineering depart men lias l&gt;een in charge of Mr. A. I". Bauer, since August 1907, MM much is owing to his careful and able management. This depart inent has taken charge of the plumbing and heating work in th new buildings, and will lx» able to do the work at a saving of approx imately $o(H)0.00 helow the lowest price bid t&gt;y the plumbin contractors. In the case of the BtOTC room where the work ha been completed the cost has been SfiOO.OO where the lowest contrae bid was $12&lt;MI.&lt;H&gt;. MASON Wllllk During tlie past biennium there have been approximate! 0.000 square feet of cement sidewalk and flooring laid by th mspital mason. Of this 0000 feet has l&gt;een laid in the tunnels vhich before had either a dirt or a rough brick floor. Befor )lacing the floor in the tunnel back of the cottages, it was nece o lay 600 feet of S-in. sewer pipe to drain the basement of the cot I nd also to provide sewer facilities for the new cottage for mei ow in the course of erection. The mason has l&gt;een constantly at work, except during the wint&lt; lonths. and has l&gt;een able to train a working force of patients t ■ him. These patients have done all the mixing of the col and hauling the material, and have rendered it possible t omplete the work that has l&gt;eeii accomplished. Cement flooi lave been placed in the basement of the first cottage for womei nd this basement has lx&gt;en used for a general dining loom fi 'omen patients, allowing the use of the first floor rlining rooms i loth cottages for dormitories. Other work which has been don &gt;y the mason conrprises the new boiler room and coal bin at th &gt;st of $1000.00. foundation and cement floor for the chicken house unnel work for the new buildings and for the kitchen ventilation earn conduits and tunnels for the new hospital building, and ork for store room building. I The sand pit found one-half mile south of the buildings has rnished the sand for the cement and building work ;it ving to the hospital. HOUSE-KEEPING DEFAKTMKNT t Under the direction of the Matron the house-keeping department been systematically managed and a very literal dietary has n furnished for the patients. The garden produce has been </seg>
            <seg id="p016">176 LAM) COlilfI88IONER'8 KKI'ORT Ixiuntiful ami the large kitchen ha.- U*en very successful in putting u]&gt; vegetable* and pn for winter use OB the wards. For use during the present winter there will l&gt;e over :*.6&lt;M) gallons of corn, kraut, salted string lteans. canned tomatoes, etc.. for use upon the wards. A detailed table of the products of the garden, and the vegetables and fruit preserve* will be found among the statistical able* The laundry has Ihhmi equipped with a large 36x72-in. cylinde double compartment washer. Tlie steam dryer is of old style, bu stension of the power shafting through an intervening wall ; fan can be placed in the dryer, which will practically double ita capacity. It ial that a hot water meter If attached to the return pipe from the dryer to keep check upon the consumption &lt;&gt; steam and prevent W« The sewing room at this date remain.- in the old store room but with the completion of the store room building will move int&lt; new quarters. With the installation of the new power plant ic power machines should l&gt;e provided for the sewing room and remove the objection, that patient:- now have to working ii wing room. This could l&gt;e done for the sum of $4(M).(M). HOSPITAL (iHOl'NDS AND LAWN I At the beginning of the biennium the hospital grounds wer rewn with the ruin.- of the old building. Work has been constant!) proj loving the debris, leveling the grounds, making th placing sidewalks, and planting trees and shrubs. Tha le work of beautifying the grounds might proceed upon order! 1 ,\e were able to procure planting plans from the Horticul irist of the Department of Agriculture. These planting plan ill for the parking of the thirty or forty acres of ground in fron the hospital, and include the construction of new driveway id the formation of artistic and useful ihrubbery IkmIs. 1 ■If evident that l&gt;eautiful grounds about a hospital cannot othe MB have their own effect upon the minds of the patients residen : the hospital. The elevation and contour of the grounds lem lemselves readily to improvement, and if the care of the lawn i mtinued the result should !*■ very gratifying. THE NEW BUILDINUS The legislature of MM&gt;7 appropriated 102,000 00 for tin :urni.»hing of a hospital building for women, a col </seg>
            <seg id="p017">177 Em, and a store room ami employes' dormitory. The hospita ilding will probably l&gt;e ready for occupation by June of nex ;ir. and lias l&gt;een carefully planned for the special treat men 1 ■ acutely insane. The work has been done well, and when com ■ted it is safe In assume there will 1m- no more convenient doi fful bulling for the acutely insane in the west. The plans cal or the installation of a hydrotherapeutic plant, and the plumbing oik for the installation of this system has already been contracts or. An appropriation of $3,000.00 will Ik- necessary for this impose. There was no appropriation made at the last legislatun ir the construction of connecting tunnels between the pn wildings and those in the course of construction. This will probabh •quire the sum of 11,500.00. The appropriation for the new uiilding was insufficient to allow the installation of the marble ork called for in the specifications for the new building, anil tin larble work was. therefore, left out. This work comprises a tiling &gt;r the operating rooms, toilet rooms, and also the marble worl or the stairways. It will require $1 1 .(MX). (HI additional appropria on for itr completion. To complete the plumbing of the ne\ tuildings an additional appropriation of $:{.&lt;MM).(M) will also be needed s staled before, this work is done by the hospital engineerin &gt;rce. The lowest contract bid for this work was SI 1,000.01 'here was $3,500.00 available, and this amount will !«&gt; nece or the plumbing of the store room and the' roughing in work of th mspital building and cottage. The fixtures will approximat _'..")(MI.(H) in cost. IKII.IIIM; Kill! MEN At the present time the hospital is extremely crowded. ( )i le men's side, under ordinary circumstances, we have a capacit one hundred and thirty-five. We now have one hundred am ity-nine patients in these quarters; making a surplus of twenty our patients. The new cottage in the course of erection will hav capacity of only fifty patients, which gives us a margin of twenty x to accommodate the incoming male patients for the next thre ears, unless a fresh appropriation is made by the coming legislature would recommend that instead of a separate cottage l&gt;eing built lat the so-called west wing on the men's side l&gt;e extended on uindred feet to the west, and an L made there. This will male le buildings on both sides of the grounds symmetrical, and I believt SSITY OK NEW </seg>
            <seg id="p018">178 LAND 0OMMIS8IO NKK's REPORT will afford a cheaper method of construction than if a separate building were designed. For thk purpose ■ sum of $45,(XM).(M&gt; should Iw appropriated, and should afford additional room for nty-five more patients. ADDITIONAL IMPROVEMENTS NEEDED An extension to the present small greenhouse should. be mat p allow of cut flowers upon the wards in winter time and to gi\ Mini for the lidding plants required for the improved groum nd for the early garden vegetables. A new cellar is needed had! or vegetable storage purposes. The elevator leading from tl iitchen to the service tunnels is not large enough to hold a f&lt;XM ruck and is worn out. It should 1k&gt; replaced by an elevator i •uffioiently large size. The two cottage basements not yet floored and plastered should l»e improved and can then Ik- used for the industrial work. I The new driveways have l&gt;een carefully constructed with a d of broken brick, clay and cinders. and should be furnished with ment gutters to prevent washing. The central halls anil offices &lt;&gt;f the administration buildin; should Ik? painted, as the plaster is l&gt;eginning to show dark am ■oiled. The north walls must ba rendered damp proof l&gt;efore painting, by the removal of plaster and the application of Dehydra '(i the tile, followed by replastering. The smoke stack now ninety feet high should Ik 1 raised another thirty feet, for the purpose of increasing the draft, which now is deficient. This would cost the sum of $o(M).(H) but would pay for If in a verv short time. c ONCLU8ION The management of the hospital during the past two yean &gt;een characterized by |&gt;erfect harmony and coordinated work among its official force. This happy condition of affairs. I attribute entirely to Your Excellency's far sighted policy of allowing the Suj&gt;erintendents of the State Institutions u&gt; select their assistant i of merit alone, without interference by the spoils system of party politics. I cannot too earnestly express my appreciation of your support and aid and that of the Honorable Board of Public l.andr and Buildings. To the officers and employes of the hospital incere thanks are due. for their loyal and conscientious ■ ration. Respectfully submitted. (1. A. YotJNQ, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">179 FINANCIAL STATEMENT For Hiennhil Period Ending November 30, 1908. Appropriation Expended Balance Officers' salaries - *lti.(MMi (Ml $12,665 . 56 $3,334 II Officers' salaries - 116,000.00 112,665. 56 $3,334 M Employes' wage 37,000.00 M):2iV.l 67 6.7 Kinplovos' wa-r 37,000.00 :&lt;()._&gt;♦&gt;:; 67 ti.T Maintenance 70,500.00 56,646 16 13,8,' Maintenance 70,500.00 56446.1613,81 General repairs ll.ixxuMi 9,568. 8« 1,431.11 (ieneral repair- 11,000.00 9,568.89 1,431.11 Right of way for ade track. 500 (M) 500 no Kipht of way for ade track. 500 (M) 500 ()(• Boilers and remodelling Boilera and remodellinf; Boiler room :i.(MM&gt; (Ml 3,000 00 Boiler room :i.(MM&gt; (Ml .S.tKin on Hospital building for women 60,000.00 24,770 25 35.22 &gt;. 75 Hospital building for women 60,000.00 24,770 25 35,22 ». 75 Cottage for male patients 20,000 00 1,020 0018.980 00 Stove room and employes' dormitory d.ooo .on 3,636.81 2.361 19 Furnishing new buildings .ViMMI (Ml 3G1.30 It. '.(MM) (K) $141,932 til $X7.067 36 ESTIMATE l'i&gt;|{ ENSl'INti BIKNNUM Officers' salaries'* $18,600 (Mi Employes' wage* ' 50.000 (Mi Maintenance '.ki.ikmi (id Repairs and improvements 18.000 (Ml I'KKM VNEN 1 I M l'l{i&gt;\ KMK N I - New building for men $45,000.00 1 250 H. P. Water tulx&gt; boiler 4. (MM). 00 H. 1*. Direct connected Corliss engine and gener - ator 5,000.00 1 Nurses and Attendant's .home 12,000.00 1 — Horse and cow barn 7.."&gt;(MI 00 New farm land Ki.O(M) 00 Tunnels, new buildingt 1,500.00 Furnishing new buildings 5.000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">180 i. and commissioner's report STEWARD'S (ASH REPORT eipts and Disbursement! for the Biennial Period Receipts and Disbursement! for the Biennial IV Ending November 30th. 1" KK( Kl 1 RECEIPTS _'. To balance cash on hand _'. To bal h on hand 2 2, To B. W. A. Davis, difference in pay-roll To B. W. A. Davis, difference in pay-roll 3 I, To Max Yinger. sale old iron . To Max Yinger. sale old iron 11. To c. WoUschJeger, sale 1 boar pip 11 To C. Wollschleger. sale 1 bow pig To Kizzie Funk, difference in pay-roll 15 15. To Kizzie Funk, difference in pay-roll 15 1"). To Ltbbie Hammond, do To l.ihhie Hammond, do 1.'). To Edith Alfred, do lith Alfred, do 1.') », I« V. B. Nctheway. 573 lbs, bide* To V. B. Netbeway, 573 lbs. hid. Dec Dec. 22. To .!. V. Dedeiinaii. 1 hull To J. K. Dedermaii. 1 hull 1907 Jan. s. To Sarah Anderson, difference in pay-roll 10 &lt;&gt;0 Jan. s. To F. Hapsel. 1 boar pi| 10.00 To Hargreavee Mercantile Co., drayage Jan. 14. 1(1. IH) Jan. 14. To Nettie Poole, difference in pay-roll. T.i Baiter Coal &lt;fc Grain Co., 20 bom, 5860 Ibfl S») 30. 351.60 59 51 To Y. B. Net hew ay. \) hides 5. To Y. B. Netheway. 601 pounds tallow To Carrie Bryant, difference in pay-roll To 1). C. Regan, difference in pay-roll. (■ley l.awton. difference in pay-roll To Fritz Wendt. difference in pay-roll \nna Lynch, difference in pay-roll - igar City Cereal Mills. 44 pounds rye... To 11 - Mercantile Co.. N. W. freight . ■ train Co.. 1"&gt; hogs4320 pounds To Win. Ashley. 1 Mack horse To Y. B. Netheway. ."&gt; hide To V. B. Netheway, 319 pounds tallow irrk Meyer, difference in pay-roll To May Retail, difference in pay-roll To C. A N. \Y. Co. damage on groceries -•■or. Telephone Co.. hoard telephone men 25 54 14. ti 4.", 14. 1 tilt 14, ■2.12 Febr. 14. 7 74 14. 3.39 14. 15.65 Mch. 1. 1 26 4. 276 4 s 135.00 ■2(\ n."» Mch. 4. Mch. 6. Mch. 6. 13.55 12. '•s Mch. 12. Mch. 20. 2.95 4.20 Mch. 22. To Nebraska Telephone Co.. hone feeds Mch. 28, To Max Venger, old iron Mch. 22 1 . 7.") April. 17. To F. Braithway, board, 1 month </seg>
            <seg id="p021">181 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK 14.50 5.20 To Wilson Byerly, difference in pay-roll To Seeley Lawton, difference in pay-roll To May Regan difference in pay-roll To William Defratis, difference in pay-roll To J. Lawler, difference in pay-roll. To Anna Lynch, difference in pay-roll 10 Hi SI April 26, 1 1)1 April 26, 2 . 42 April 26, Mav 20, May 20, To Sam Jones, old furniture Mav 28 00 .Julv 4.20 Julv Julv To Alltert Bell, 68 pounds bra To Clarence Burke, board, 1 month Aug. Aug. Auk Sept 1 .(Ml Sent 20. 00 Sept .-, IN i 20. (Ml an. 11. an. 20. an. 24. an. 27. Vbr. 22 lch. 30, lch. M0 April 10 April 10 April 10 To H. 1). Martin. 1400 pounds coal To Clarence Burke, board. 2 mon To August Karo. 3!&gt;0 pounds hide- To C. Wollsehleger. 17 calves To Bolles &amp; Rogers. 744 pounds hides To Bolles A Rogers, 14.V&gt; pounds tallow To Standard Oil Co.. 6 bbls . 1 50 To Nebraska Telephone Co.. Meals tril. -i'J. To F. (iilmore. sale junk ril 22. To F. (lilinore. horse feed ril 23, To V. B. Netheway, :^J7 pound hid* ril 25, To Standard Oil Co., 5 bbb. ril 26. To Wilson Hyerly. difference in pay ■_&gt;.-&gt; L5.05 2.00 5.00 6.00 •J'.i. To Sam Jones, old tunmure lti. to L. Bcheniel, S50 pounds lard W, To V. B. Nethewav. »&gt;&lt;&gt; pound: hide 24, To I. Silkett, board B To All*&gt;it Kell. 68 pounds brass 20.00 20.33 2A, To Clarence Burke, hoard. I momn 28, To K. Von-8eggeni, board 7. To V. B. Netheway. 55 pound 3 hidi _'(). To L Scheuzt'l. lard 24. To Clarence Burke, board 1 n Iet. 10," ToR. F. Bruce, brick bftta [•t. 2t&gt;. To E. C Mohr, hoard. 1 month ov. 21, To Fred Bverly. 3 load: col ov. 21, To I. T. Cook, old iron, ov. 27. To R. W. Patterson, hoard. 4 weeks ov. 28, To Nebraska Telephone Co.. meals horse feed* ■ec. 19, To'R. 1). Martin, coal ec. 20, To August Karo, 211 pounds hide? nn. 11. To August Duncoe. hoard 20.00 14.00 To W. ('■■ Merten. "contractor" board A lod'ng </seg>
            <seg id="p022">182 land commissioner's hkport April 10, To W. (I. Merten. corn and hay . . . $20.33 ty 7. To 1. T. Cook, old iron 1 1 ,M y 7. To W. G. Morten, "contractor" hoard 4 lod'ng 229.35 &lt;t. To H. Goodwin, house rent 8.00 13, To Max Venger. old iron SO. 00 13, To Loui Seheniel, 326) pounds lard 22 s_' 13, To Loui Schenzel. 90 pounds hide 2 7n IS, To SunderUnd Bros. Co., 284 cement sacks. . . _'s 40 SO, To H. Goodwin, house real s 1111 June 1. To Loui Schenzel. 142 pounds hide- 7 si June 5, To Salter Coal ft drain Co., 30 hops. 7."&gt;l(l lbs. 375 50 June 17. To T. Whit more, hoard 8.00 July 3, To H. H. Wheeler, board 9 50 July 10, To Loui Schehsel, 502 pounds lard 1 1 44 Julv 11. To Clarence Burke, hoard 20 0(1 Julv 17. To E. L. Loucks, 3 old chain 2.00 Julv 20. To F. L. Wilhelm. house rent 2 00 July 20, To F. L. Wilhelm. 1500 pounds coal 3.75 July 24. To N. Netheway. 45 pounds hide 2 25 July 24. To \. Netheway, 385 pounds soap p*ea e July 24. !■ ie\vay. 121 \ pounds tallow 4.25 Julv 25. To Sunderland Bros. Co., 387 cement sacks :is 7n Julv 31, L. J. Slauter. 7 loads manure . 1 75 Julv 31, To Richard Peter. 2 loads manure 5(1 July 31, To Nebraska Telephone Co.. 9 meat 2 25- Aug. B, To T. Whit more, board 4.00 Aug. 21. To F. L. Wilhelm. house rent $2.50. cobs 75e 3.2S Aug. 21, To Herman Pribnow, 2 shoate 6.00 Aug. 24. To K. E. Holtgreen, board 10.00 Aug. 28, To T. D. Aldridge, board 3.00 4. To A. K. Bauer, horse feed 3.00 To Loui Sehenzel. 425 pounds lard 29.75 7. To K. E. Holtgreen. hoard 1(1. (Ml To Nebraska Telephone Co., 3 meal Sept. 11. To Irvin &amp; Melcher. 3(M) pounds lard 27.00 18, To V. B. Netheway, 95 pounds hidet 5.33 is. To Seeley Lawton. hoard 2 20 Sept. 18, To F. L. Wilhelm. house rent 2.50. Sept. 22. To F. E. Holtgreen. hoard 10.00 7. To F. E. Holtgreen. hoard 10.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">183 Oft. 14. To W. (1. Morten, "contractor" board A lod'ng *:V"&gt;0 iKt Oct. 29, To A. F. Bauer, horse feeds 3.00 Oct. 29, To Daily News office. H«&lt;&gt; pounds rap 7.80 Nov. 14. To (1. H. (mines, house rent 5.00 Nov. 19, To K. K. Holtgreen, hoard 30 im» Nov. 24. To A. F. Bauer, horse feed s no Oct. 9. To Mont Robb, Steward, repayment warrant.. 33.12 Total STEWARD'S CASH HKl'OKT DISBURSEMENTS l'.KKi Dec. s. By W. H. llasterman A Co., 50 pounds coffee 114.75 Dec. S. By Frank H. Heels, tuning piano 5 00 Dec. s. By K. D. Hammond, use potato digger &lt; ou Dec. 8, By l'aul Nordwig, repairing harnea Dec. 8, By Grand Union Tea Co., 50 pounds coffee 10.80 Dec 10. Bv Heeler Bros.. 1 shawl 2 l&gt;"&gt; Dec. 10. By Hoffman A Yiele. table felt. Dec. 16, By .1. C. Meyer. Y. S. veterinary service . I 50 Dec. 19, By Belter Bros., cotton blanket?. 5.94 Dec. 22. By \\ . ('. Alhman, tuning piano. 3 00 1907 .Ian. 5, By Henry Haase, 3 boxes cigars, patients, Xmas 6.00 Jan. 14, By Grand Union Tea Co., eoffe&lt; 16.00 .Ian. 24. By University of Nebraska, 1 Holstein bull ... 75.00 Jan. 28, By Charity C. Stubbe, Woman's Guild of Omaha .Ian. 29. By Cook Well Co., deep well pump repairs 11.20 Jan. 29. By Alex l'eters. Tele.. Telg., freight, voucher No. 20 34.11 Jan. 29. By Hurley Co.. toilet fixtures voucher No. 22 3.40 Jan. 29. By The Ailolph Levy Co.. thermometers, voucher No. 24 11.25 Jan. 29. By Huse Publishing Co.. advertisements, voucher No 25 14.61 Jan. 29. By Fremont Foundry Machine Co.. voucher a in' ji ami repr'tg cond. of boilers 17 ,'M) </seg>
            <seg id="p024">184 I &lt;. By Chicago Lumber Co., lumber, voucher No. 27 SloT.oo Jan. 2 ( .». By Asa K. Leonard, glue, voucher No. 28. ... 2 .00 Jan. 30, By American Journal of Nursing, sub 2.00 Jan. 90, By Beeler Bros., cotton batting 2.70 30, H\ State Journal Co., 1 Mipply record book 12.25 Febr. 2. Hv Iris Sniitli. services as attendant Febr. 2 . Hv Sarah And* attendant 1 50 Febr. 2, By J. R. Hayes, postage Btampa 10.00 2, By Jos. Hight. services as carpenter 2 50 Febr. 4. By Western I'nion Telg. Co., n 2 53 Fel». 8, By J. A. Jensen, painter, 24 hrs 9 60 Febr. S. Hv W. H. Clark, painter. 20 In. K.00 Febr. •». By Henry Marquardt, shelling corn 6.80 Febr. '.). By Christina Plohm, servia endunt 1.46 Febr. 12. Hv John Krantx, horse feeds. Norfolk Febr. 12, By H. C. Battler, diflf. purchased hoi 35,00 Febr. 12, By Traux, Greene Co.. restraint buckle: 3.02 Febr. 12. By Norfolk Plumbing Co., bath tubs k instal'ng 39 25 12. .My Bauach k Lomb Optical Co., surgical sup- plies 20.40 13, By J. R. 1! 10.00 Febr. 13, By James l.awler. freight &amp; expre 2.90 Febr. 14. By Crane Company, plumbing supplie: 55.06 Febr. 14. By Herman Pribnow, balance salary 48 Febr. 16, Hv James I. awlcr. express Febr. 21. By E. A. Hell, saw 7.00 Febr. 21. By C. 4 S. W. freight 1 2»i 21. By (i. F. l'ilger. coffee. 5.75 Febr. 27. . By C. S. Hays, alarm clock 125 Mch. 1. ByC. k. N. \Y. freight I 28 Mch. 1. Hv James Lawlei-. express 2.53 Mch. "). Hv Sarah Anderson, extra labor 1 oil Mch. "&gt;. Hv Charity ('. Stubbs. services employment 2 00 Mch. H. By Western I'nion Telegraph Co.. message 6.28 Mch. 6. By V. V. R. K. Co., freight J 0§ Mch. 11. By World Herald Publishing Co., a.lv 1.50 Mch. 19, *By A. Peters, freight Mch. 20. By Alex Peters, 3 yds. table fell 1.65 Mch. 20. By Alex Peters, ♦&gt; drawer pulls Mch. 21. Hv Delia Curry, service as waitress 1 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">185 Mch. 22. By Josephine Blum, services as usher Meh. 11. By Nehr. Telephone Co., rent telephones. Jan. Fehr. Mch HI 02 Mch. 22. By Nebr. Telephone Co.. toll*, Doc. Jan. Febr. Mch :(') H5 Mch. 1\). By I). ('. Regan, returning patient 3.00 Mch. 29, By Cleveland Press. 1 medical hook 8 00 Mch. 2'.t. By Chicago Lumber Co., lumber, voucher No. 29 Mch. 29, By Applegate Chemical Co.. I 1 , lbs. IndeL ink 8.00 Mch. 29, By Will H. Green, moulding, voucher No. 30 ."&gt; 95 Mch. 2&lt;t. By Crane Company, iron chain 28 95 Mch. 29, By A. B. Dick Co.. mimeograph, voucher No. 31 ■?■"&gt; oo Mch. 29, By Frank H. Beels. tuning piano 2 50 Mch. 29, By Hoffman &amp; Yiele. china ware 2.25 Mch. 29, By James C. Meyers, veterinary services 13.00 Mch. 30, By .1. R. Hayes, postage stamp- . . 15 0O Mch. M). By C. \Y. Craig. landscape plan- and topo- graphical map 100.00 Mch. 'M). By Aug. Pasewalk, wagon tongue 1 7."&gt; Mch. 30, By C. A. Kngen. aervio engineer. 26 85 Mch. M). By Placid Witten. services waitress 10.16 Mch. SO. By Laura Hill, services stenographer 1 1 29 Mch. 30, By K. H. Oury, services coachman 1"&gt; 81 Mch. 30, By Myrtle Mice, services night-cook t&gt; 7. Mch. :«). By H. H. Mueller, services night-watch 10 65 Mch. 30, By A. B. Colles. services florist 26.13 Mch. 30, By Fritz Wendt. services attendant 15.48 Mch. 'M). By A. L. Shannon, services attendant 9.68 Mch. 'M). By Theresa Curry, services nurse 10.45 Mch. 'M). By Gertrude I.indale. sei-vices usher 5 65 Mch. 30, By Sarah Anderson, services nurse 1 .50 Mch. 30, By Klsie Gaaaway, services laundreat 1 oo Mch. 30, By Nettie Poole, services nurse 8 s . Mch. M). By Herman Pasew&amp;lk, implements 122 50 Mch. M). By F. 0. Gaaeer, services attendant 2 50 Mch. 30, By H. K. Hardy. 3 scale Looks :i.(M&gt; Mch. M). By Grand Union Tea Co. coffee 5 25 Mch. 30, By Singer Sewing Machine Co. needles . 40 Mch. 30, By Helen White, services waitres- 4 14 Mch. 30, Hv Norfolk Lumber Co. lumber.. 69 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">I LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 186 Mch. 30, By ('. A. Young. M. I)., expense, business trips $78 11 Mch. SO, By V. P. R. R. Co. 4(K) pounds l&gt;eef 16.00 Mch. 10, By J. H. Hays, post office box rent 1.00 Mch. 30. By Western Union Telegraph Co. messages... 6.42 Mch. 30. By I). C. Bodkey. 20 bu. potatoes . 8.00 Mch. 30. By Huse Publishing Co., printing 22.53 Mch. 30. By Press Publishing Co. a&lt;lv 4(1 Mch. SO, By Cook Well Co. 6 leather cups 4.80 Mch. 30. By Vaughn's Seed Store, seeds &amp; implements. 37.15 Mch. 30, By Norfolk Lumber Co. gla- 10.06 April 1. By A. C. Yradenl&gt;erg. orchestra music 4.00 July 31, By World Herald PublishingCo.. advertisements 3.43 Aug. 12, By Journal of Nursing, advertisements 2.00 Aug. 12. By North Nebraska Kagle. advertisements 3.20 Aug. 12. By North Nebraska Journal, advertisement Aug. 12. By Neligh Register, advertisement &gt; 1.65 Aug. 12. By Plattsmoutli Journal, advertisements. .. 1 oil Aug. 12. By Lister Bros, advertisements l.(HI Sept. 2. By Worrell Mfg. Co. insect exterminator 50.00 Sept. 3. By Frank Benesh, 25 pounds chickens 3 75 10, By Asa K. Leonard, 42 tickets. Barnum and Bailey Circus 14.80 Sept. 11. By M. Smythe. orchestra music 2 SO Sept. 11. By Mrs. M. Smythe. orchestra music 2.50 Sept. 11. By A. C. Yradenl&gt;erg. orchestra music 2.00 Sept. 21. By W. Stransky. 16 pounds chickens 2.00 Oct. 1. By Ci. E. (iarretson. vaudeville performana 15.00 Oct. 4. By C. .1. Schroeder. phonographic entertainm't . 5.00 Oct. 7. By E. H. Ovry, express .1.80 Oct. 7. By Plattsmouth Journal, advertisements 2.34 Oct. 21. By J. P. Cooke Co. key tags 2.01 Nov. 15. By J. Yanalstine. carpenter. 25 hours 7.50 Nov. 15. By J- W. Shafer. carpenter. 33 hours *) M By John Friday, coffee pot 1.00 Nov. 25. By Loui Schenzel. 27 pounds turkey 4.05 Nov. 28, By M. Y. Avery. orchestra music 3.00 Dec. 2. By A. Degner. coffee pot 1.40 Dec. 2. By Hoffman &amp; Yiele, china dishes 15 30 Dec. 6. By W. S. (ioldie. advertisements 1.10 Dec. 6. By The Telegram Co. advertisement 1 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">187 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK Dee. 19, By H. Pub, 78 pound* 16.26 Dec. 19 ; By Rome Miller, 2 Hobtein cows. 200.00 Dec. 31, By A. B. Colles, business trip Lincoln. . :}.34 1908 .Ian. (i. By E. H. Oury. express 1 s5 Jan. 11. By World Herald Publishing Co., a.lv 1 BO .Ian. 13, By Geo. B. Christoph, playing cards 1 SO .Ian. 14. Bv C. \V. White. 4 chickens 1 20 .Ian. |5, By ('. P. Parish, apples, grape frail 1 25 .1 mi. 20, By Iivin &amp; Melcher. lamps 2 'M) Jan. 20, By L. J. Slauter. horse feeds. 3.50 Jan. '24. By Henry Bosch ('&lt;&gt;.. paint brushes 5.18 Jan. 27. By C. W. White, 4 doxen chickens 15.00 Fehr. 1. By H. A. Pasewalk, implements, voucher No. 1551 M) oil Febr. 1. By Chas. Schmiedeberg, separator washers 1.20 Febr. 6. By John Friday, hardware &lt; 45 Fehr. 6. By Albert Degner. zinc, gas stove I 1 80 Fehr. 11. By ('. 8. Hays. 1 doz. teaspoons, "Rogers". 3 90 Fehr. 17. By Ed Brueggennm. electric fixtures 4 55 F&gt;br. '22. Bv Hoffman &amp; Yiele. 2 mirrors 1 40 Fehr. 29. By Albert Degner, cooking utensils 1 40 Fehr. 29, By John Friday, cooking utensils 1 85 Mch. A. By &lt;i. A. Young. M. I), livery bin "Om*h»" 2.00 Men. 4. Bv Frank Benesh, 10 loads manure 1.50 Mch. 7. By A. Degner, coffee, pot 2.00 Mch. 7. Bv R. A. Bates, advertisement- 1 so Mch. &lt;». By Armour A Co., diff. on .'554 pounds turk 1 77 Mch. it. By F. L. Estabrook, 43 pounds turkeys 7 :U Mch. 20. Bv F. L. Estabrook, 4 dozen chickens 15 00 Mch. 20. By C. WoUschleger, 12 pounds honey .. 1.80 Mch. 23, By G. E. Stechert. medical books :i.% Mch. 30, By Norfolk Bargain Store, 80 pounds candy . 8.00 Mch. 31, By H. ('. Battler, wagon repair- 18.85 Mch. 31, By A. L. Killian Co., 12 wool blankets. . . 20 50 Mch. 31, By Hoffman* Yiele. 18 pillow- 9.00 April 4. By F. E. Oshorn. furniture 30 00 April 8, By Pie— Publishing Co., job work 3.75 April 8, By K. A. Armstrong. \ doz. rabbet ifaeetl 6.75 April 15. By H. ('. Battler, bal. on seed drill 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">188 LAND COMMISSIONKHS REPORT April "_'(». By &lt;ieu. B. Christoph, drugs, voucher No. 1552 $47 :i5 April 23, By Mrs. L ("locker. 7^ bushels potatoes • 2 55 April 24. By Adolph Hille. butter I roucher No. 1553.. .. 87 April 25. By Mrs. L (locker. l&gt;ai tei 7.10 April 25, By I). C Kegan. returning 2 patient. 9.00 April 27. By K. (i. Twes. :is bushels potatoes 13.30 April 28, By ImbM &lt; . Meyers, veterinary service 2.00 April 2K. By I.. (Mocker, potatoes 4 25 April 29, By Low * Carter, 1 bushel alfalfa i2 .00 April 29, By A. Low. 7\ lbs. white clover. 1 50 May 1. By Rev. C. Iffert. 10 bushek p. 3.50 May 1. By John Fuhrman. 501 bushels potatoet 17 ti.'i May 1. By Gub Tews, 17| bushek potatoes 6.10 May 4. My Hardington Herald, advertisement- 1 H May 7. By Sunderland Hoofing &amp; Supply Co.. check val\ t H 26 May 7. By Frank 1 1 25 May 7. By C. A. PiUjer, compressed yeast, bread 14 40 May 7. By Albert Degner. hardware .. 10.90 May 7. By Bauaeh A Lomb OpticalCo., oplical supplies May 7. By Irvin A: Melcher. groceries, fruit 17.30 7. By Asa K. Leonard, drugi 39 85 May 7. By Ed. Beemer. 29^ bushels potataeti 10.32 May *.t. By Carl Strate. 27 bushels potatoes 9.45 K\ Norfolk Lumber Co., fence posts, wire, lbr 44.70 18, By All&gt;ert Degner. 150 ft. rublier hose 23.25 4lay -IS. By C. &amp; N. \V. Agent, freight 4 62 May 21, By K. Mierhenrv. 10 bushels potatoes 3.60 May 22, By F. Pub, 30 dozen eggs .. 3.30 May 22. By V. Pub, 23) bushels potatoes May 22. By C. Knderely. 2~\ bushels potatoe 9.65 May 2t, By I). C. Hegan. returning patient 4.00 27. By Ed Brueggeinan. electrical fixture . 1 75 May 27 ; By H. Adair. difference in horse 5.00 30, By Lussky. White A Coolidge Co., hardware... 3.33 30, By Midland Taint &amp; GlawCo.,72 pkgs. kalkonia 20.00 May 30, By Illinois Leather Co., hair felt 3.49 By Irvin &amp; Melcher. groceries and fruit By L. Longenberg. 141 bushels potatoes 56 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">189 June 6. By Adolph Hille. butter and eggs s" May 6. By M. B. Cox. 31») bushels corn 18 June 11, By Faucet t. Carney, flmgrir f*o typewritei 6 June 11. By \V. Stramsky, seed corn Sept. 21, By The Macey Filing Co.. filing cabinet! Nov. \), Bv Mont Robb. Steward, voucher No. 1 33.13 Nov. 23, By W. (1. Merten. ■'contractor" add. labor and material furnished, raising foundation of and employes' dormitory 161 84 new store room J.-5.2WS it, Balance cash State Treasury Us 58 Balance cash Mont Robb, Steward Repayment vouchers Sect'y of State's office. 33 35 1 MM M.I HARDEN KKIMIICI Product 1907 l'tos Total Asparagus, bushels. Beans, bushels \ I 136 174 310 Beets, red. buslu Beets, sugar, bushels Cabbage, heads 45 SI MVM) 7.-&gt;&lt;&gt;o 10630 ."&gt;4 10(1 154 Carrots. Celery, bunches 103 2100 _'."&gt;n:; Corn, sweet, bushels 120 17."&gt; l'.»") Cauliflower 104 54 I5K &lt; 'ucumbers, bushels 54 14 Kgg Plant 10.-) 536 Endive, bushels If. 16 Lettuce, bushels. 47 77 124 Melons. Musk 50 Melons. Water 588 Onions, dozen bunches 1450 JUKI Onions, bushels 34 223 _ &gt; ")7 Parsnips, bushels 18 IN Parsley, dozen bunches 14 "21 Peas, bushels 4:-! </seg>
            <seg id="p030">190 I'eji; ! s4 120 204 1'eppers. red, bushels -1 21 l toes, bushels. .. 1 H 1 7 2§B6 4212 &lt;-et. bushels 80 BO 1'unipkin- KM) KM) lishes. bushels 36 2".t i&gt;4 Rhubarb, bushels 11 12 :« Rutabagas, bushels 1 1 fv, bushels 10 10 ish MH) KM) 400 Spinach, bushels 1 21 ard, bushels 1 26 ieen, bushels 16 131 14t&gt; Tomatoes, ripe, bushels 364 400 Turnips, bushek S(M) 19 si 1 .* FAHM KKI'DHT duct— litoT l'.tos T&lt;.tal n, bushels 2800 :i(HM) 5800 bushels 421 421 prairie, tons KM) ll'i 215 Millet, ton- 30 M Alfalfa, tons 15 15 M MATRONS KKI'ORT For Hiennial Period Ending Novenil&gt;er 30, 1908. PICKLES, ETC. Applet cami.-.i SO gallons Apple butter ( .l gallons Beans, salted MM) gallons Beets, pickled 182 gallons canned 10 q;. ip, tomato 150 gallons Chili sauce f] gallons Cham-Cham 48 gallons canned 104 quarts Coeumben, pickled 57 gallons Corn, tm 725 gallons </seg>
            <seg id="p031">191 urrants, canned Us quarts ucumben, salted :&gt;7"&gt; *mll«&gt;-iir- Dill pickles 7() gallons )ill pickles To gallons hitch pickles M&gt; &lt;rallon&gt; Dutch pickles 36 gallons Elderberry jam 7 quarts Elderberry jam 7 quarts rape batter. 1 12 qu irape juice Ki gallons Grape butter 1 12 quarts Grape marmalade 12 gallons Gooseberries, canned 40 quarts Jelly in glasses 12NN pi Jelly 43 gallons Mangoes, stuffed peppers 60 gallons Mince meat 70 gallon?- Piccalilli 1 i 5 gallons Pickles, watermelon 9 gallons Peaches, canned 44 quarts Peaches, preserved (i quarts Peaches, spiced 10 quarts Pears, spiced 14 quarts Plum butter 112 gallons Plum preserves 9 gallons Quince, preserves 16 quarts Raspberries, canned ti quarts Bauer kraut. 1250 gallons Strawberries, canned 59 quarts Tomatoes, canned. . "6:i gallons Tomatoes, preserved 280 gallons Tomatoes, mustard pickfe 1 1^ galk&gt;n g Tomatoes, sweet pickle 122 gallon Tomatoes, sour pickle. 15 gallon MATKKIAI. L'S E D I \ 3 K \V ING lit ii i M Bed ticking, yards Hunting, bleached, yards KM Buttons, agate, dozen 133 Buttons, pants, gross 6 Buttons, pearl, gross 10 Buttons, coat, grosi 1 Calico, yards 1461 Cotton batting, rolls 153 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">192 Canvas, yards 172 Canton flannel, bleached, yarda Canton flannel, unbleached. Crash toweling, unbleached. Darning cotton, halls 420 1140 1440 79 Diaper cloth, yards Deniin. blue, yards (iinghain. yards (ironnnets. t;i 70 498 »4 6 E dozen papen ■an twill, vards 11 417 Linen, table, yards Muslin, bleached, yards Muslin, unbleached. Napkins, table, dozen Needles, darning, dozen Needles, sewing, papers mio 1.-&gt;4U s 1 56 4o ing machine, papers Oilcloth, table, yards. 28 Pillow tubing, yard* Pins, pounds 824 Pins, pounds 4 re, pain 4 ting, unbleached, yards ting, bleached, yardt Tape. 1(KK) yard spools Threatl. cotton, dozen spools Thimbles, dozen Sheeting, unbleached, yards 2564 Sheeting, bleached, yards 1466 To.^n 1IUWI trmmA ..i i I. &gt; i:iu •) Window shade material. Holland, y ards 50 AKT1CI.KS MAM K ICTCBED Aprons, bleached, muslin 242 Aprons, kitchen and dining tool Aprons, rubber 271 12 Aprons, oilcloth s Hath hammock. can\ Hath hammock, laeii.. Hed pads, large and small Handages 12 74 4 Helts. black calico oilcloth. 39 126 Bibs, muslin 24 :&lt;(&gt;&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p033">193 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK Hibs. children's Broom covers Burial robei 39 24 14 Camisoles '.i Camisole strings andv bagi Candy hags 300 Chemise? 'hemises lothes bap 102 Clothes hags 1 ( 12 Curtains, wardrobe 'urtaini, wardrobe 14 14 Curtains, swiss tucked, pairs Curtains, muslin with border Curtains, transom 'urtains. swiss tucked, pairs 14 14 'urtains. muslin with border, pairs 20 20 P urs 'urtains. transom . . . 2 ■ ) Curtains, ruffled, pairs Drawers, canton flannel Dressing saciiues 'urtains. ruffled, pairs 77 i i )rawers. canton flannel. 147 147 •nn Baeqim 12 12 Dresses. eali&lt; Dresses, wool. . Dresser scart Furniture covers tresses, calico 71 71 M, wool. 1 1 uts 58 58 •'urniture covers 4 4 8 !"oinentation wrinpers ti ot water bottles covers on holders, dozen 20 Fomentation wringers Hot water hottles cover Iron holders, dozen. 20 Eifly strainers at tress cover? uff's can. jfly strainers § s • ) at tress covers - uff's canvas 3 A Eapkins. made of table linen apkins. hemmed apkins. made of table linen 120 120 apkins. hemmed % '.•♦i Xaj)kins. sanitary l.V&gt; Napkins, sanitary . Night gowns 155 Night gowns &lt;*6 96 Night shirts 294 Night shirts _'»I4 Operating gowns 1 2 12 Operating caps Pillow 993 i)93 Eano cover How ticks lilts 1 11 ■ )■) Hestrant bands ■ ) Edeboard covers. . leets, unbleached leets, bleached. . ■ &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p034">194 Shoe hags Eand covers rong suits raw ticks :,1 - t spenders, pair, ticking irt waists, calico 72 IX Skirts 35 Iahleclotli - able pad - owels. bath owels. dish . owels, hand owels. roller ■ rn strain' nder skill nder waists. . indow shades r rmppen. 14-.. 1 472 1635 440 118 20 £ 4 ■ MENDING Aprons, kitchen ■ I'M 6 Emkets d ticks lo 1 11« Cam s tl&gt;ags mfori 1 Curtains s 571 rr scarfs . 3 1 1 laekeU 119 Muffs, canvas Night shirts Overalls ' s </seg>
            <seg id="p035">HOSPITAL FOR INSANK. 195 NORFOLK TABLE NO. 1 Ob November 'M). 1906 the records of the hospital showed a population of 262 patients. V-\ lx»ing home on parole. Male Female Total 113 106 219 Remaining in hospital Nov. 'M). 11M)6. . . New cases from Nov. 30, '(Hi to Nov. 30 Pants 291 Pillow ticka _' Pillow cases ."&gt;() Hugs 15 Shirts '.ill Skirts 16 ShadM 25 Suspenders 12 Strong suits 40 Tablecloths 29 I'nderwaists 4 Under skirts s4 Wrappers, enlarged 1 1 AHTK IKS MANUrACTURKD POM PATIKNTs PROM PRIVATE MATERIAL Aprons, white It) Dresses, calico tiii 68, wool . . . . 2 sag sacques •") Drawer- 7 Night gowns 0 Shirt waists, calico. 1 1 Shirt waists, wool 1 Skirts, calico. 15 Under waists ti Wrappen OS . . 4:* s4 !_&gt;7 leturned from parole :\ 1 4 )ischarged new eMH 4s :V_» Ml Hseharged cases paroled previou i^«.. '(u; )fc IW </seg>
            <seg id="p036">196 Paroled 19 15 34 ped . - •&gt; SI 16 47 Deported 1 1 Transferred to Beatrice Institution. ... 1 1 Transferred to Lincoln hospital 2 2 Remaining in hospital Nov. 90, 1908.. . 168 128 •OtM of these was later transferred to Lincoln hospital. TABI.K N ADMISSION BY MONTHS l'.KKi Male Female Total 3 5s January § 5 13 10 6 16 h 11 5 16 April 6 8 14 6 4 10 June 9 2 11 July 7 2 9 August 5 3 s tember B 2 10 ,ber 3 1 4 imber 7 3 10 December 6 4 10 1906 January 4 3 7 February B 2 7 March 6 2 8 April .. 6 6 12 Urn? 5 4 9 June 5 2 7 July 6 4 10 August 5 5 September 4 6 10 October 5 4 9 ember 3 1 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">197 TABLE KO. COUNTIES KKUM WHICH ( oi'NTIKs FROM WHICH PATIKNTs VBB1 RKCBIVEB PATIENTS WERE RECEIVED Male Female Total Male Female Tot* Antelope s 1 \ Antelope s 2 10 Bonne Bonne 4 4 4 Box Butte 4 1 5 Box ButtC 1 1 Boyd. 4 6 10 Brown 4 1 Brown 4 1 Burt . I T Cedar 3 4 7 ( 'herrv Cheny. (• • &gt; I) 0 0 &lt;"heyenne 2 1 • Cheyenne 2 1 'i Colfax Colfax. 1 2 1 ('timing Cuining 10 ."&gt; 1 10 .-&gt; 15 TABLE NO. 3 TABLE NO. 3 Male Female Total Male Female Tola &lt;'iisttM- 4 titter 4 4 akota 2 1 awes (i 2 8 Dawei t&gt; 2 Dawson 1 3 1 Dawaoo 1 3 Dixon ti 2 Dodge 2 H 1 Douglas 1 ley l l Hamilton Holt . .') 4 I Howard 1 1 Keith Keya l'aha 2 1 3 Knox B 2 10 Lincoln 1 1 _' Madison 10 8 16 Merriek 2 1 Me PI i' Nance </seg>
            <seg id="p038">LAND COMMISSIONKH s HE PORT Pierce 10 ti _) t) 1 1 "i :&lt; 1 1 4 1 1 1 1 *i s A &lt; 1 ;:: 4 TAHl.K NO. 4 \NI) CIVIL CONDITION UK PATIENTS Male Female Sin. Marr'd Wid. Sin Marr'd Wid. Total 17 1 s 17 2 7 1 2 11 2 7 7, 10 2 \ A 4 I 21 B 40 13 6 2 1 si 4 1 7 17 45-50 7 7 2 :. :&lt; M :i 1 :i 1 4 :i 17 :i :&lt; :} 1 4 :i 17 U M 4 2 1 l :} n 2 :\ 2 H 1 11 2 1 2 2 7 I 12 6 LSI 5 1 1 85-90 1 i 2 Ilntnnnn in 1 1 1O \J i 1 I\ I 1 ' t \\ I 1 1 I I IMattc Rock ts HlufT Sheridan Sherman Sioux Stunton Thomai Thursnm V alley Hilton c Wheelei York </seg>
            <seg id="p039">199 TAB LI N mi r PATION &lt;&gt;F 1' ITIENTS Male Female Total ,t for nu. Book keeper stock 1 1 1 1 Carpenter t t 1 1 Eivil engineer oal miner 1 1 Domestic Drayman Farmer. s s 1 I 74 i 5 1 &lt; iardener 1 1 1 Hotel Keeper House work Harness maker Laborer 1 f.ti 66 ■) ■ ) 25 Milliner Eerchant one 1 ' ated Physician l'ugili 1 1 Ranchman 3 4 Railway service Student Store clerk 1 1 1 1 Store and saloon Stockman keeper 1 1 3 3 •&gt; teacher ramp ailor 2 1 1 1 1 Telegrapher Well digger 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">200 TABLE N&lt;&gt;. (i BIKTHPLACK OK PATIENT* Male Female Total Connecticut 1 1 t South 1 1 15 »•&gt; 4 15 Indiana Iowa. . . i 1 1 :: Kallr-a- &gt; Kentucky Michigan Mini Maryland Nebra 1 3 : 1 i i i 19 13 Hampshire ■ York 1 &gt; 3 i Korth Carolina hio 1 11 3 1 IVnnsylvania Vermont 3 ■) ! Virginia 1 4 ■ nsiii 4 linpton. 1). C linpton 1 1 1 Mas8achusett&gt; Not given 1 17 10 i L Foreign Horn — stria 3 Hohemia .da Denmark Kngland France 4 .) 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 ,; nany Ireland Ml 14 ■&gt; 3 : Italy ■» way den ■&gt; 6 1 2 Switzerland 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">201 Intoxication Psychoses (Alcoholic) Male Female Total 1. Delirium Tremens 1 1 2. Acute Hallucinosis ... A :{ A. Chronic Alcoholism . t&gt; t&gt; 4. Paranoic States 2 _' Exhaustion Psycho* 1. Collapse Delirium .... 2 2 2. Acute Confunonal Insanity 3 Paranoia 5 A s MENTAL DISK \SKS RKPRESKXTK.il Intoxication Psychoses (Alcoholic) Mule Female Total 1. Delirium Tremens 1 1 2. Acute Hallucinosis ... :i :&lt; A. Chronic Alcoholism (i 8 4. Paranoic States 2 "_' 1. Collapse Delirium 2 2 2. Acute Confusional Insanity A A Manic Depressive Group- 1. Maniacal State&gt; "t 13 22 2. Depressive State- 8 !(• -' . 'A. Mixed States 7 2 Dementia Praecox Group— 3. Paranoid 4 2 ti Paranoia . . •"» A Dementia Paralytica ... 7 1 8 Involution Psych* I . Melancholia 4 4 8 2. Senile Dementia ... 17 \A TABLE N&lt;&gt;. 7 MKNTAL DISKASKg REPRBSKSTKD .1. Polyneuritic (Kormakow) 1 1 .-&gt;. Polyneuritic (Koresakow) 1 l Exhaustion Psych 1. Hehephrenic :&lt;4 § 4_&gt; 2. Katatonic ~&gt; ■"&gt; 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">202 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ite&lt;l with organic brain disease — I. Huntington 's Chorea 1 i rebral Byphilii ... 1 1 3. Tumor ... 1 l Kpileptic Insanity 16 4 20 terical Insanity 1. Hysterical Somnambulism. .. 1 l Defective Mental Development — 1. Imbecility 7 I id Morbid Personalii . . 1 I ine . 1 ■ ) .5 TAH1.K NO. N ALLEGED • OK I NS WITY If ale Female Total 3 .i 10 10 2 2 Childbirth .) 6 6 able, 1 ■&gt; .; Epilepsy 7 2 0 1 neglect 4 4 ■ ) •&gt; 7 4 II 1 injury :i A Injury 1 1 111 health .. 1 a 6 e affair . . :{ \\ Masturbation 4 4 4 4 1 i ed ii.". 80 '.'.") heating s ration 1 1 work 1 2 3 Prize fighting ... 1 1 Religion j 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">203 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK 1 Sepsis &gt; tnility ock. ,) &gt; Syphilis. Tobacco liaciinc • ) 1 1 13 i I \H1.1 I Mil. I Of I' \ 1 I K Vl&gt; MHCH \ Hi. i Male Female Total 29 11 til 25 36 f&gt;l 10 C» Hi m P \TI ENTS DISTH \ H(.KD \ r Mlll.li \ n 1» I OND1 riON N r MHIH \ N 1» I ONDl II'IN Male Female Total 40 Recovered 2! i 1 1 Ucco'. Improved Unchanged I'nknowii Improved •_&gt;."» :;ii ..l 10 B 16 Unchanged i i Unknown SO. 10 r \iu i 1)1. \ 111 I V MONTHS Male Female Total 1 \ M H i 1 December 1907 ■&gt; January February 1 • &gt; March 4 ; April 4 May 2 1 June •&gt; Julv August Septembei - 1 I November 1*M»N • ) Eanuary Februarv •) April 1 1 May </seg>
            <seg id="p044">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 204 &gt; ■j 1 4 7 June 1 1 August 2 13 fciepteml&gt;er October. 1 • ) ■ ) inber ■ ) Iable no. 11 SE OF DEATH Male Female — Cause of death Mental &lt;lis&lt; Senile Dementia Brain Tumor sr i Hrain Tumor 1 Brain Tumor 1 Cancer Senile Dementia Senile Dementia 1 Cancer 1 Cerebral Hemorrhage Senile Dementia Cerebral Hemorrhage Senile Dementia liral Hemorrhage Epileptic Cerebral Hemorrhage Dementia Praeeox Cerebral Thrombosis Chronic Alcoholism liral Thrombosis Senile Dementia Cerebral Thrombosis Senile Dementia Cerebral Thrombosis Senile Dementia Cerebral Thrombosis Dementia Praecox i&gt;ral Thrombosis Senile Dementia Exhaustion Manic — Depressive 1 ! i i i i l i 21 | 1 1 Manic — Depressive Exhaustion Dementia Paralytics Exhaustion Manic — Depressive Exhaustion Korssakow's Psychoei Dementia Paralytics Dementia Paralytics 1 Exhaustion Chronic Myelitis 1 Exhaustion Melancholia 1 Exhaustion Manic — Depressive 1 Exhaustion Collapse Delirium 1 Exhaustion and scald Dementia Praecox Exhaustion Dementia Paralytics 1 General Peritonitis Dementia Paralytics Heart failure Exhaustion Psvchos&lt; 1 ; Exhaustion Psychose Organic Heart di- iile Dementia Exhaustion Exhaustion </seg>
            <seg id="p045">205 art disease Hank — Depressive art d Jenfle Dementia tuberculosis Chronic Alcoholism tuberculosis Melancholia Organic He 1 .). 1 tuberculosis Dementia Praecox 1 1 1 Melancholia Melancholia Senile Dementia Senile Dementia Senile Dementia Senile Dementia Senile Dementia Senility Senility Senility 1 1 1 Senility Senilitv 1 I 1 Septic intoxication Senile Dementia Status Kpilepticus f Epileptic Status Kpilepticus - Epileptic 2 1 1 1 Organic He Pulmonary 1 Pulmonary 1 Pulmonary Suicide Dementia Praecox Suicide Suicide 1 Suicide Manic — Depn 1 Tubercular empyema Dementia Praecox </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>