<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00010">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00010</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth AT BEATRICE TO THE Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings</title>
			            <date value="1904">1904</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-28</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

OP THE 

Nebraska Institution for Feeble 

Minded Youth 

AT 

BEATRICE 

TO THE 

Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings. 

DECEMBER 1. 1904. </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
Hon. John H. Mickey Govcrinu 

For Term Ending January 1, L90&amp; 

Hon. John H. Mickey Governor 

For Term Ending January 1, 1907. 

BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

For Term Ending January 1, 1905. 

t. Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Public Lands and 
Buildings President 

Hon. Geo. W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary 

Hon. Peter Mortensen State Treasurer 

Hon. Frank Prout Attorney General 

BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

For Term Ending January 1, 1907. 

Hon. Henry M. Eaton, Commissioner Public Lands and 
Buildings President 

Hon. Algernon Galusha, Secretary of State Secretary 

Hon. Peter Mortensen State Treasurer 

Hon. Norris Brown Attorney General </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
A. Johnson, M. D Superintendent 

Frank E. Osborn, M. D Pays! 

SCHOOL DEPARTMENT. 

Marie B. Armstrong Principal 

TEACHERS. 

Florence Hinkle. 
M. Belle Ebright 

Daisy Wardlaw. 
Eve. Burner. 

Jack O'Donnell, Band Instructor 

William Pollock Supervisor Boys' Department 

Ida A. Holt Supervisor Girls' Department 

W. 0. Alvord Supervisor Boys' Department, Hospital 

Nellie Alvord Supervisor Girls' Department, Hospital 

Nels Nelson In charge of Farm Department 

D. B. Gillespie. 

In charge of Carpenter and Brush Department 

Ed Enderline In charge of Bakery 

Amanda Sandahl In charge of Laundry 

AllilUIt; 1j. tlUUtfS Ill lilcirge OI DC n lUg XVUU11J </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
TABLE NO. 1. 

OVEMENT OF 

'opulation for thb year 
1902, and Ending Decembe 

IEGINI&lt; 
1, 190 

ING 

ecem 

i 
i 

I 

P enrolled at beginning of period 
admitted during the year 
returned from parole during the year 

161 
29 
4 

143 
27 
2 

304 
56 
6 

Number discharged during the year 
Number released on parole during the year 
Number died during the year 

6 
6 
7 

6 
4 
6 

12 
9 
13 

366 

. 

Number remaining at end of period, Dec. 1, 1903 

h-r- 

r» 

...:.. 

TABLE NO. 2. 

Movement of Population for thb Year 
1903, and Ending Decembe 

iegin: 
1, 19 

riNG 
14. 

ECKM 

S 
1 

! 

I 

Fr enrolled at beginning of period 
r admitted during the year 
r returned from parole during the year 

176 
28 
7 

156 
16 
5 

332 
44 
12 

Number discharged during the year 
Number released on parole during the year 
Number died during the year 

10 
5 
4 

9 
5 
7 

19 
10 
11 

388 

m 

Number remaining at end of period, Dec. 1, 1904 

TABLE NO. 3. 

I 
3 

I 

•3 
3 

Number of children in school department 
Number of children in custodial department 
Number of children in asylum department 

79 
40 
60 

84 
2T) 
60 

163 
65 
120 

Number of children admitted since organization . . 
Per capita cost from Dec. 1, 1902, to Dec. 1. 1903 
Per capita cost from Dec. 1, 1903, to Dec. 1, 1904 

S8-S 
</seg>

            <seg id="p005">
Hon. John H. Mickey, Governor of the State of Nebraska, and 

the Board of Public Lands and Buildings: 

§ accordance with the laws of the state of Nebraska, I 
y submit the Tenth Biennial Report of the Institution 
eeble-Minded Youth for the period ending November 30, 

(presenting this report it is gratifying to be able to show 
in all departments of the institution the progress has 
satisfactory, and that the institution more than ever 
gents the highest grade of proficiency in matters pertain&gt; 
the care, training, and treatment of the feeble minded. 

It is the expression of each person familiar with the affairs 
of the institution that at no time in its nearly twenty years' 
existence has it been a greater credit to the commonwealth of 
Nebraska than now. 

tring the present administration, the first and foren 
ivor on the part of the management has been to give the 
ren absolute protection, and it is the opinion of all 
its who have visited the institution that the place is safe, 
the children are all well cared for, and that they get 
y of good, nutritious food and sufficient clothing. 

At the beginning of the biennial period the number of inmates 
enrolled was 304, and at the end of the first year 332, 
an increase of 28. At the end of the second year, November 
30, 1904, the number of inmates enrolled was 348, an increase 
of 16 during the last year of this period. 

Had it not been for the fact that we are now very croA\ 
at our institution, all of the beds being occupied, and no room 
for additional beds, we would have admitted thirty more than 
we have during the last year, as we now have that numlx 
applications on file in our office, and all of the applicants are 
ready for admission. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
206 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

The health of the children has been remarkably good. We 
are again very glad, indeed, to be able to state that we have 
pawed through another biennial period without any epidemic 
of diseases, and that we have had very little sickness of any 
kind. Among the causes which have contributed to this end 
may be mentioned a water supply free from contamination, 
an abundance of milk from our own fine herd, vegetable* from 
our own garden, all of the food well seasoned and thoroughly 
•cooked, good ventilation and sanitary arrangements in the 
children's cottages and school rooms, and, not the least important, 
an abundance of out-of-door exercise. 

DIVISION OF POPULATION. 

The institution naturally falls into the following groups: 
(1) School, (2) Custodial, and (3) Asylum. 

The School division includes all of those children whose 
mental condition is susceptible of Improvement under proper 
school methods, the training given being on moral, mental, 
physical, and manual lines. 

Ee Custodial division includes those who have passed 
igh the school period, either in the institution or elsee, 
and who remain as permanent wards of the state. 

The Asylum division is made up of those with a low state 
of vitality, both mentally and physically. This class require 
-tant watch and care, both day and night, as they are entirely 
incompetent to care for themselves. 

SCHOOL DIVISION. 

Kiis institution was established by law to furnish the 
ds of education to that portion of the youth of the state 
provided for in any of it« educational institutions. See 
1 and 2, chap. 52, Session Laws of Nebraska, 1885. 

Er this purpose schoolrooms are provided and furnished 
special apparatus and an efficient corps of teachers 
tained. 

It is intended that each child admitted shall receive such 
degree of education as his enfeebled capabilities will permit, </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
207 

Braining given being on moral, mental, physical, and man 
ines. 

(here mental deficiency exists there exists, also, in most 
I, a deviation, as it were, from the average normal moral 
physical standards, and much time, patience, and pensen»e 
must be devoted to the improvement and correct i&lt;m 
iese deviations, and go hand in hand with the training 
arousing of the mental faculties. 

I r is not expected that any degree of what is known as 
higher education can be attained, but any progress, be it 
ever so little, is beneficial and will tend to lessen the burden 
of care and responsibility after the school age is passed, thus 
making each individual not only helpful to himself, but 
ful to others. To reach this object manual training is early 
introduced into the curriculum of all modern progressive institutions 
for feeble-minded children. 

fur method of instruction is based upon a modification of 
kindergarten idea as taught by Froebel. 

&lt; Mir school children are classified much as are the children 
in the lower grades of the common schools, with a regular 
from the lower to the higher; although much specialized 
effort must be made by the teacher for each individual. 


E pupil is in the schoolroom more than one-half of each 
the rest of the day being devoted to manual or industrial 
ing, physical drill, and out-of-doors recreation, thus seg 
healthy change and variety. 

In deciding upon the school exercises, we bear in mind the 
natural limitations of our pupils. Lessing says : "Education 
• an only develop and form, not create." We do not create a 
faculty, but we "draw out" what may not be evident at first, 
Imt, nevertheless, is there, and it is a question how much development 
is possible in each case. 

Ka class the feeble-minded have dull perceptions, feeble 
rs of attention, weak will power, uncertain memory, and 
tive judgment. 

It is useless to attempt to arouse these dormant faculties 
by forcing upon them the abstract truths of ready-made </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
208 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

knowledge. The child must be made to do, to see, to touch, 
to observe, to remember, and think. 

I r e utilize to the fullest extent the varied and attractive 
ipat ions and busy work which are so important a part of 
modern graphic methods of instruction for normal chil-1. 
Object teaching in its broadest sense is a prominent 
ure in our educational scheme. 

In the lower grades the pupils are taught form and color 
by means of sphere, cube, and cylinder, sticks, blocks, pictures, 
flowers, etc. ; to cut and paste, to perforate and sew, to 
form strokes on slate and blackboard preparatory to writing, 
to distinguish one object from two, to articulate distinctly, 
to speak words, phrases, and sentences, to sing simple songs 
,by ear, or form habits of attention and obedience, to obey 
commands, to keep time in marching, to keep step. In the 
higher grades the pupils are taught to read and write, to 
know something of arithmetic, geography, language, history, 
iand physiology, the value of money, to tell time, to do freehand 
drawing and crayon work, letter writing, and fancy 
needle work. 

tsarly all of our pupils receive daily systematic physical 
ing. Mental awakening generally follows as a direct reof 
increased physical development. The pupil must be 
ly attentive; he must quickly hear and understand; he 
promptly execute the command. It is a mental as well 
physical drill. 

Vocal music is taught in classes, and chorus singing comprises 
most of the work accomplished in this line. Our band 
ntly organized is doing well. Those capable are taught 
to read music by note. 

Krtain daily duties are assigned to each boy and girl, and 
8 duties are changed often enough to make each child 
liar with different kinds of work. 

Ke boys take great interest in both farm and garden. They 
, harrow, and cultivate, weed, hoe, and rake. Some asthe 
carpenter and engineer, while others do work of 
us kinds in kitchen, laundry, and ward. </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
209 

Iie girls do much of the sewing, mending, and darning for 
large household. They are taught to wash dishes, make 
, wash windows clean, and polish floors, sweep, dust, and 
1 and iron. 

Iar Sabbath devotional exercises have been both interestand 
instructive. In the morning at 9 o'clock, the entire 
iol assembles for Sunday school, and in the afternoon at 
i for an hour's devotion, which is made as non-sectarian 
ossible. The services are led by clergymen from town. 

Ethe work progresses in wisdom and righteousness, we 
hope that the education of all children, both normal and 
rmal, may be upon one plane, the right of every human 
I to receive the highest development attainable by him 
l individual. 

INSTITUTION FARM. 

One of the important and necessary places on the institution 
grounds is the farm. 

When we took charge of the institution, we had but f 
acres of ground in all, and nearly one-half of this was covered 
by the buildings, orchards, and lawns, there being at that 
time no pasture for our cows nor any hay land. We now 
have 225 acres of ground, a pasture consisting of forty -five 
acres of timothy and clover, also fifteen acres in timothy and 
clover for hay, and ten acres in alfalfa for hog pasture. 

Ee farm department with us means that department i 
1 the raising of fruit, vegetables, grain, hay, and the care 
ultry, hogs, cattle, and other stock. 

Kis our aim to raise just as much as possible of the prodnecessary 
for our own consumption, and, although we 
short of it, we are year by year adding to the amount 

We have during the year 1904 cultivated 160 acres of land, 
the work having been done by our own boys, with but one 
man hired to assist and oversee the work. The market value 
of the farm products raised is $3,665.95. If to the above be 
added the value of the milk, about 9,000 gallons produced by 

14 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
210 


¦own herd, the total value of farm products raised during 
j-ear would be more than f 5,000. 

REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS DONE. 

Iie work of beautifying the grounds that we began four 
3 ago has been continued during the past two years. Thus 
ave set out 500 shade and ornament trees, 150 fruit trees, 
ose bushes, a number of evergreens, and a lot of other 
bbery. A number of new flower beds have been laid out, 
? a little grading and sod laying has been done, and huns 
of loads of cinders have been placed on the drives; 1,352 
re feet of permanent sidewalk and 947 square feet of 
¦nt floor have been built during the biennium, and much 
r work done that has added very materially to the beauty 
e grounds and lawns. 

The schoolrooms and all of the children's dining rooms 
have been repaired, painted, or kalsomined. All of the halls, 
rooms, and dormitories in the girls' cottage, boys' old cot. 
and hospital have also been painted or kalsomined. 

Eie tin roof and all of the wood work on the main building 
boys' old cottage have been painted and much pointing 
een the bricks has been done. 

A new roof, glass, and rafters have been put on our greenhouse, 
and new benches built along the walls. 

A new addition, two stories high, has been built to our 
kitchen, and, although it is only about twenty-four feet 
square, it has relieved the crowded condition very much. 
Furthermore, the cooking for the officers and employes is now 
done in a separate room, something we could not do before, 
as we had but the one room in which to cook for everybody. 

A new cold storage building was put up last summer, but, 
as the legislature appropriated only half the money asked for, 
only part of the building is finished inside. It will require 
about $ 1,000 to complete this building, but we will then have 
sufficient room for many years. 

In June, 1903, the lightning struck our smokestack, causing 
damage that required an expenditure of ?250 for repair- </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
211 

Kring October, 1903, part of the walls of our blacksmith 
caved in. They were later rebuilt with brick and mortar 
expense of $200. 

Kring May, 1903, we built a hog house at an expense of 
We also built an addition to our cow barn, and reled 
the old cow barn, which cost in all f 290. 

Eie appropriation made by the last legislature has been 
:ient for the needs of the institution. The monthly allowhas 
been overdrawn in bu.t one fund, that for repairs 
improvements, and this is due to the fact that all of the 
e-mentioned improvements were paid for out of this fund. 

NEEDED OONSTUUCTIONS. 

A School Building. — In our biennial report of two years 
we made use of the following language : "As our present 
schoolrooms and assembly hall are too small to accommodate 
our school children, and also on account of the fact that our 
children have to walk two and three flights of stairs in order 
to get to them, I would recommend that a school building be 
provided. We now have a number of children whoareotherwise 
reasonably bright, but crippled to such an extent that they are 
unable to walk upstairs to the schoolrooms, and, therefore, they 
derive no benefit at all from our -schools. If we had a school 
building with most of the schoolrooms on the ground floor, 
and the assembly hall on the second floor, these crippled children 
could go to school, and the crowded condition that now 
exists would be overcome." The above being true two years 
ago, must impress every one with the fact that the condition 
is much more serious now, as we now have forty-four more 
children than we had two years ago. 

Girls' Cottage. — The one girls' cottage that we now have 
has been overcrowded for a long time, there being 130 girls 
there now. Nearly a year ago, in order to relieve the crowded 
condition of our girls' cottage, about twenty of the little girls 
were taken out and placed upstairs in our hospital building, 
where they are now occupying rooms intended for emergency 
sick rooms. The room thus left vacant in our girls' cottage 
has been filled up with new girls, so that we are now unable </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
212 


Ee any more new girls, although we have a number of apions 
on file. In view of the above facts, I would most 
stly recommend that the coming legislature appropriate 
K) for a new girls' cottage. 

I)ditional Water Supply. — The water supply at this intion, 
except drinking water taken from a well, has always 
defective. This water is secured from Bear creek and 
ped into the standpipe by means of a gasoline engine, 
water is always more or less muddy ; in fact, after a rain 
•comes so muddy that it is entirely unfit for laundry or 
ing purposes. I have had experienced men give their 
ion as to the best method of purifying this water, and 
all seem to agree that the only thing that can be done 
build two or three settling basins into which the water 
be pumped from the creek and then, after it has settled, 
ped into the standpipe. It will cost approximately $ 6,000 
ake this improvement. 

Kie question of an abundance of pure water, however, is 
ich vital importance to the institution that it merits full 
careful consideration, and I hope this matter can be ated 
to early next spring. 

EPEOVEMBNTS of Gbounds. — I have not asked for a special 
)priation for this purpose, for I believe we can do in the 
¦e as we have done in the past, use part of the money beng 
to the fund for repairs and improvements, for I cery 
believe that the money invested in improvements of 
rounds is well spent. 

fiave now briefly referred to the most important matters 
ting our institution, and trust that the necessary funds 
be provided, so that the recommendations can be carried 

I desire to extend my thanks to his excellency, Gov. J. H. 
Mickey, and to the Board of Public Lands and Buildings for 
the courtesies and acts of kindness which they have all shown 
me. I also wish to extend my sincere thanks to all employees 
for the faithful services they have rendered. 

Respectfully submitted, 

A. Johnson, Superintendent. </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
213 

INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

RECOMMENDATION FOB APPROPRIATION FOR PERMANENT 
IMPROVEMENTS. 

One fire-proof school building |25,000 00 

One fire-proof girls' cottage 25,000 00 

One new boiler 1,200 00 

Additional amount necessary to finish cold storage 1,000 00 

Additional water supply 6,000 00 

rIMATED APPROPRIATION FOR N. I. F. M. Y. APRIL 1, 1905, 
TO APRIL 1, 1907. 

For employees' wages f26 000 00 

For fuel and light 18,000 00 

For maintenance 35,000 00 

For repairs and improvements 3,500 00 

For furniture, bedding, and clothing 3,000 00 

For farm implements and vehicles 300 00 

For farm supplies and feed for stock 400 00 

Office supplies and postage 800 00 

Telegraph, telephone, and express 350 00 

Drugs and dispensary supplies 1,400 00 

Additional live stock 200 00 

School and industrial department 400 00 

Library and periodicals 200 00 

Amusement and music 300 00 

Chaplain's salary 200 00 

Superintendent's salary 5,000 00 

Physician's salary 2,400 00 

Teachers' salaries 5,000 00 

TABLE OF SCHOOL ATTAINMENTS. 

Reading. 

Read on chart 25 

Read in primer 16 

Read in first reader 18 

1 in second reader 13 

Read in third reader 15 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
214 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

Head in fourth reader 4 

Read in fifth reader 16 

Writing. 

Write a few words or letters IB 

Write from dictation 44 

Write from print 59 

Arithmetic. 

Combine numbers to five 32 

( 'ombine numbers to ten or more 54 

Work in addition 61 

Work in subtraction 58 

Work in multiplication 31 

Work in division 27 

Work in fractions 13 

Work in partnership 1 

U. S. Money. 

Know U. S. coins 75 

Know value of money to 25 cents 41 

m value of money to f 1 38 

Know value of money to $5 15 

Time. 

Know the hours M 

Can tell time to the minute 27 

Geography. 

Know something of location and direction 52 

Know something of local geography 35 

Know something of general geography 24 

Language. 

Know use of capital letters 48 

Know use of punctuation marks 42 

Know name words 38 

Know action words 38 

Know simple sentences 31 

Know compound sentences 5 

Know singular and plural forms 38 

Know use of the apostrophe 27 </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
215 

INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOtfTH. 

Know initial letters 

Write letters with assistance 

Write letters without assistance 1 v 

Drawing. 

Draw simple forms Tti 

Map drawing II 

&lt; 'rayon work and water colors 

Color 

Know only the primary colors 

Know both primary and secondary colors 

Can match compound shades 95 

Music. 

Sinn; simple tunes by ear 136 

l'lny in the band IT 

Gymnastics. 

i ute simple movements with apparatus 

History. 

Know something of U. S. history 

Physiology. 

Know something of elementary physiology 24 

Kindergarten work. 

Can do cardboard work 7 1 

Paper folding 65 

Paper weaving 60 

Paper cutting 

Use peg-boards methodically H 

Work with blocks and tablets 

INDUSTRIAL CLASS — HAND WOKK. 

Hemming. 


Tea towels 763 

Pillow cases 4 s 

Napkins 48 

Wash cloths 10 </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
216 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Hemstitching. 

Doilies 20 

Pablo napkins 13 

Towels 46 

Aprons 1 

Dresser scarfs 18 

Table covers 8 

Pillow cases 20 

Centerpieces 3 

Tray covers 13 

Dresser scarfs (cotton crash) 10 

Table scarfs (cotton crash ) 6 

Drawn icork. 

Center pieces 2 

Pillow cases 16 

Pillow shams 2 

Tray covers 6 

Dresser scarfs 4 

Dnncn icork and embroidery. 

Center pieces 2 

Tray covers 3 

Stand covers 2 

Table covers 1 

Pillow shams 2 

Doilies 4 

Dresser scarfs 1 

Embroidery. 

Center pieces 1 

Doilies 4 

Dresser scarfs 2 

Table covers 4 

Tray covers 1 

Pincushion covers 4 

Cross stitch. 

Child's gingham dress 1 

Gingham aprons 2 </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
217 

INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

Table covers 1 

Set collars and cuffs 1 

Pincushions 2 

Miscellaneous. 

Comforters 56 

Candy sacks , 64G 

Sofa pillow tops 18 

Handkerchief bags 1 

scarf-battenberg ends 1 

Mufflers 1- 

Dolls and animals 36 

SEWING BOOM. 

Articles made. 

Sheets 867 

Pillow cases 463 

Comforts 205 

Roller towels 124 

Bath towels 54° 

Curtains 18* 

Sash curtains 60 

Couch covers 10 

Pillow covers 21 

Aprons, sleeve 76 

Aprons 197 

Aprons, dining room 1*2 

Laundry bags 17 

Table cloths 39 

Iron holders 136 

Suspenders, pairs 234 

Bibs 430 

Straight jackets 5 

Napkins 72 

Dresses 760 

Waists 33 

Skirts 420 

v &gt;»+ </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
218 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 



set covers « - 

Under waists 4:? 

Bonnets 1 

Elastics, pairs "&gt; 11 

Sanitary napkins 


Drew skirts 6 


Night shirts 341 

king mittens &lt;&gt;&lt;• 

Mufflers 18 

Stand covers 6 

Mangel covers 1 

Mattress covers 34 


9. 



Mending work. 

Sheets 82 3 

Pillow cases 1(14 

.forts 19 

Spreads 109 

Blankets 12" 

Mattresses 88 

Straight jackets - t; 

Bath towels -'-• ' 

Roller towels 103 

Aprons, dining room 166 

Aprons, ward 117 

Aprons 2051 

B i b8 732 

Table cloths 53 

Napkins 12 

Laundry bags 3 


o </seg>


            <seg id="p019">
219 

INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH. 

Under shirts 

Night shirts !()»•&lt;) 

Drawers 42"&gt;T 

I'nder skirts 1643 

Under vests 1474 

Corset waists 80 

Dresses 

Night gowns 2n4ti 


Overcoats -4 

Suspenders 

Ties !tt 


Waists 133 

Jackets l.'U 

Chemise 

Hose supporters 37 



Handkerchiefs 3 

ARTICLES PREPARED FOR TABLE USE. 

Jelly, apple 310 glasses 

Jelly, grape 115 glasses 

Jelly, gooseberry 150 glasses 

Batter, apple 90 quarts 

Butter, peach 50 quarts 

UM^pi*npfi tftTYi 1 1 1 \ -10 e*i 1 1 oim 

Shirt waists 93 

Under waists HB 

C«a* 

Pantaloons 1562 

Bonnets 105 

Cloaks 108 

Hoods 4:{ 

Sanitary napkins </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
220 


Peaches, canned 44 quarts 

Tomatoes, canned 800 quarts 

Tomato catsup 32 quarts 

Tomato pickles 185 gallons 

Apple pickles 64 quarts 

Peach pickles 16 quarts 

Chili sauce 70 quarts 

Piccalilli 40 gallons 

Salted beans 25 gallons 

FARM PRODUCTS, ETC., FOB THE YEAB 1903 

3 

Wheat 428 bus. 

Rye 149 bus. 

Oats 673 bus. 

Corn 1000 bus. 

Potatoes 800 bus. 

Sweet potatoes 60 bus. 

Turnips 150 bus. 

Carrots 175 bus. 

Onions 50 bus. 

Beets 150 bus. 

Parsnips 100 bus. 

Tomatoes 50 bus. 

Hay 15 tons 

Millet 35 tons 

Cane 20 tons 

FARM PRODUCTS FOR THE YEAR 1904 

Wheat 329 bus. 

Rye 224 bus. 

Oats 720 bus. 

Corn 2200 bus. 

Hay 25 tons 

Millet 14 tons 

Cane 25 tons 

Hay 25 tons 

Grccu oots 15 tons </seg>


            <seg id="p021">
221 

Potatoes 1500 bus. 

Sweet potatoes 75 boa. 

Sweet com 150 bus. 

Tomatoas 540 bus. 

Onions 100 bus. 

Turnips 50 bua 

Parsnips 60 bus. 

Carrots 110 bus. 


Beans r 85 bus. 

Peas 65 bus. 

Radishes 85 bus. 

Cucumbers 75 bus. 

Cabbage 7000 heads 

Rhubarb 50 bus. 

Cauliflower 100 heads 

Eggplant 15 bus. 

Lettuce 50 bus. 

Spinach 80 bus. 

Pumpkins 4 doz. 

Squash 5 doz. 

Peaches 80 bus. 

Strawberries 25 gal </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>