<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ARTICLES OF INCORPORATION, BY-LAWS, AND ORDER OF BUSINESS of the NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION</title>
               <date value="1892">1892</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BY-LAWS, AND ORDER OF BUSINESS of the NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION Incorporated September 26, 1892. ta copy of the act of the Legislature granting aid to the Assot and legalizing the same as a State Institution. ARTICLES OF INCORPORATION. The State of Nebraska, i tKnow all men by these presents, That we, C. M. Lcwelling, Geo. W. rhout, John R. Megahan, Irving L. Lytnan, J. M. Armstrong, F. G. :, and Albert Lemen have associated ourselves together, and by these ;nts do associate ourselves together, for the purpose of forming and be - ing a corporation in the state of Nebraska, and do hereby adopt the wing ARTICLES OF INCORPORATION Article i . The name of such incorporation shall be the Nebraska State Poultry Association. Art. 2. The principal place of transacting its business shall be in the city of Lincoln, county of Lancaster, state of Nebraska. Art. 3. The nature of the business to be transacted by said corporation shall be the encouragement of the interests and promotion of improvements in the breeding and management of poultry, by means of exhibit! or the collection an 1 dissemination of reliable and practical information rela - tive to the utility breeds of poultry. I Art. 4. Tae amount of capital stock, authorized, of said association &gt; be two tho isand (2,000) dollars, which shall be divided into four hun (400) share of five (5) dollars each. Fifty per cent of each share of c shall be p id in cash at the time of issuing a certificate for the same, the fifty pe :ent remaining unpaid shall be due at the call of the board irectors, at ny time after six months from date of certificate. Art. 5. Eich share of stock shall entitle the owner thereof to one vote Vss. Lancaster County. ) </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 stock shall be owned by any one person. I Art. 6. The shares of any stockholder who shall neglect or refuse to into the treasury of this association such installments or sums of money thereon as may be called for by the board of directors as herein pro - d, within thirty days after notice of such call, shall, if the boar. ars so direct, be declared forfeited, and the same shall thereupon be for - d to the associal ; KRT. 7. The existence of this corporation shall commence September )2, and continue twei -ars from said date, unless soon* , or continued in accordance with law. I Art. 8. The amount of ability or indebtedness to which this corpora - is at any time to subject itself is hereby limited to fifty ( 50) per cent of aid up capital stock. Art. 9. The officers of this corporation shall consist of a President, Vice-President, Secretary, Treasurer, and Board of Directors. The Board of Directors shall consist of nine (g) members of the association, to-wit: the ent, Vice-President, Secretary, Treasurer, and five (5) others. The officers shall be elected by a majority vote, by ballot at the annual meeting of the stockholders, and shall serve one year, or until their successors have been elected and qualified. Vacancies in office occuring during the term, removal, or death of any of the above mentioned officers, shall be filled by the Board of Directors. L'ntil a regular election of officers the respective officers shall be as follows, to wit: President, C. M. hew Vice-President, Geo. \V. Osterhout; Secretary, John R. Megahan; Trea Wm. A. Armstrong; Board of Directors, C. M. Jewelling, Geo. \V John R. Megahan. Wm. A. Armstrong. B. C. Blowers, S. S. Borton, I. L. Lj'mau. H. R. C. Montgomery, and W. C. Brown. Art. 10. The business of this corporation shall be conducted in ac - cordance with the by-laws adopted by the corporation. In testimony whereof, we have hereunto set our hands this 25th da October, A. D. 1892 C. ML Lewei.i.' John R. Megahan, Irving L. Lyman, J. M. ARMSTR' ' F. G. Albert Li In presence of L. Meyer r State of Nebraska. ) Vss. caster County. ) On this 25th day of October, A D </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 r said counVy, personally came C. M. Lewelling, Geo. W. Osterhout, John R. Megahan, Irving L. Lyman, J. M. Armstrong, P. G. Yule, Albert Lemen, personally to ine known to be the identical persons whose name* are affixed to the above instrument as their act and nowledged the execution as their own free will and deed. Witness my hand and notarial seal at my office the day and year above [seal] L. Meyer, State oe Nebk Secretary's Office Received and filed for record this 15th day .her, A. D. i8&lt;,. recorded in book "L," Miscellaneous Incorporations, at page 455. BY-LAWS [Adopted by the Board of Directors, February 21, i Article 1. The President shall preside at all meetings, sign all war- upon the treasury, cast the deciding vote in case of a tie, call extra f the Board of Directors when requested in writing by five e members of the ass ful funct presiding officer of a deliberative b. Art. 2. The Vice- President shall perform all duties incident I office of President in the absence of the regular presiding officer. Art. 3. The Secretary shall conduct the general correspondence association, and have custody of the same, sha'l preserve all important let - ters received and a copy of the answer thereto, to be read at the met - the association, if requested, and keep the minutes of the Board of Directors; keep an account of all the expenses incurred by the correspon shall keep the minutes of the meetings of the stockholders of the assoc: and have charge of all the books and papers appertaining to his office shall also issue certificates of stock in the association , and shall have his books and papers open at all times for inspection of the Board of Dir and shall receive for all such services the sum of one hundr - per annum; said sum shall include clerical assistance; and give a bt the sum of one thousand ( 1,000) dollars, to be approved by the Board. Art. 4. The Treasurer shall have charge of all funds belonging to the association and pay all bills per order of the President. by the Secretary, as long as the association funds hold in hand. He shall keep his accounts in proper form for the inspection of the Board of Directors and shall give a bond to the President in the sum of two thousand ( 2,00 : CERS. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 lars. to be approved by the Board of Directors. He shall also make a report at the annual meeting of all the receipts and expenditures for the current year, and shall collect all moneys and assets due the association, keeping a correct account thereof, and shall receive for all services a salary of twenty - five dollars per annum. Art. 5. The Board of Directors will hold Special meetings at the call of five ( 5 ) or more of its members, five 15) of whom shall constitute a quorum. It shall control the affairs of the association at all times except when the stock holders are in session, attend to all printing, giving pub - licity to and secure suitable accommodation for all public exhibitions, appoint all judges; also provide suitable medals, diplomas, and such other awards as are advisable, and report its transactions at any meeting of the association. ANNUAL EXHIBIT Art. 6. The annual exhibit of the association shall be held in January of each year, beginning with the third Tuesday, on which day the annual meeting of the stockholders shall begin and continue in convention until the business of the association shall be concluded. The annual election of officers shall be held on Thursday evening of the same week, begining at 8 o'clock P. m. and said officers shall assume their respective duties on Fri - day next succeeding the annual meeting, when the Board of Directors shall meet, and all reports be audited, and accounts settled. All officers of this association shall hold their respective offices for one ( 1 ) year and until their successors are elected and inducted into office. SEMI-ANNUAL MEETING. art. 7. The semi-annual meeting of this association shall be held on Thursday of the week of the State Fair, on the Fair grounds. HOW AMENDED Art. 8. These by-laws may be amended by a majority vote of the stockholders when in regular convention. BOARD OF MANAGERS Art. 9. The Board of Directors shall also be the Board of Managers ORDER OF BUSINESS. Art. 10. Order of Business. — First, call to order; second, roll call; third, reading minutes of previous meeting; fourth, unfinished business; fifth, reports of officers: sixth, reports of special and other committees; seventh, communications and correspondence; eighth new business; ninth, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 r LEGISLATIVE ACT LEGALIZING THE NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION HOUSE ROLL NO. 388. r for an act legalizing the Nebraska State Poultry Association; to de - fine certain duties of said association; to make an annual appropria - tion therefor, and fixing a penalty fur the misappropriation of any of the money hereby granted. [Introduced by Mr. Casper, of Butler.] Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska: K Section i. That the regularly organized and incorporated society ,vn as the Nebraska State Poultry Association, whose articles of incor - tion are recorded in the office of the secretary of state, be and the same :reby legalized as a state institution. tSEC. 2. The Nebraska State Poultry Association shall hold a convention lally, on the third Tuesday in January, at such place in the state as the d of managers may select, for the purpose of gathering statistics and ising practical knowledge on subjects pertaining to the poultry interests le state, by addresses, papers, discussions, and such other means as the "d of managers may direct. I Sec. 3. The Secretary of said association shall preserve all papers read, take a stenographic report of all addresses and discussions at said an- I convention, and shall make a report of the same to the governor, to - ler with a full report of all business transacted, including an itemized ■merit of all expenditures of money, and shall publish in pamphlet form less than two thousand copies of said report, which shall be distributed irding to the laws governing the distribution of the reports of the e Board of Agriculture. SEC. 4. The sum of $1,000 is hereby annually appropriated out of any moneys in the state treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the use and benefit of said association, and the state auditor is hereby authorized to draw his warrant for the same upon presentation of proper vouchers therefor certified to by the President and Secretary of said association, said amount to be used only for defraying the expenses incurred in holding conventions, and in publishing and distributing reports and such other purposes as in the discretion of the board of managers shall best subserve the poultry in - terests of the state. I Sec. 5. If any officer or member of said association shall convert an v le moneys herein appropriated to his own use, or suffer the same to be or expended in any other way or manner or for any other purpose than signated by law, such officer or member shall be deemed guilty of em - lement, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by imprisonment le penitentiary not less than one nor more than three years. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 LIST OF MEMBERSHIP No. i. Gee. W. Osterhout, Bedford City, Va 2. C. M. Lewelling, Beaver City 3. Albert Letnen. Lincoln 4. Warren L. Mitchell, Table Rock 5 \V B. McDermott, Omaha 6. I. L. Lyman, Lincoln 7. R. Whithead, Lincoln 9. J. G. VVoolsy, Inknown 10. R. R. Ellinwood, Unknown 11. Raymond Stryker, Lincoln 12. H. C. Young, Lincoln 13. O. C. Smith, Lincoln 14. E. C. Bowers, Cripple Creek, Culo 15. J. D. Brubaker, Sidney 16. J. A. Howard, Edgar 17. C. C. Branson, Lincoln G. Palmer, Tobias 19. H. J. Smith, Lincoln S. Jennings, Lincoln 21. S. S. Borton, Beatrice 23. L. P. Harris, Clay Center 24. C. M. Lewelling, Beaver City 25. W. G. Gooden, Friend 1 26. H. C. McArthur, Washington, D. C. 1 J. &amp;H. Cirpinter \ I 28. Casper Dice, Roca 1 29. James Heaton, Lincoln 30. J. M. Armstrong, Greenwood 1 31. H. R. C. Montgomery, Omaha 32. Win. A. Armstrong, Greenwood 33. Ira A. Draper, Dawton 1 35. E. P. Mickel, Lincoln 1 36. T. E. Wheeler, Bennett 1 37. F. B. Denisthrop, Geneva ■ 38. M. M. Aaron, Roca ■ 39. H. S. Thomas, Omaha 1 40. L. P. Ludden. Lincoln 1 41. G. A. Ash mum. Louisville 1 42. F. T. Dean, Chicago, 111. 1 43. E. C. Worden, Columbus 1 44. J. F. Sietna, Columbus 1 45. M. H. Walker, I'nknown 1 Iwin Post, Waverly 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">-4 J *-*c . i ycrspschcr , (jr&amp;od Islsod i 49. Jacob Severns, Deceased 50. W. H. Chapman, Bee i i 51. J. W. Deary, Bloomington 52. Julis Boeck, Boulder, Colo 1 i 53. E. C. Hills, Lincoln Mrs. Anna M. Bunting, David City 57. A. S. Potter, I'nknown : 58. E. H. Eggert, Minden 59. Mrs. Minnie Chandler, I'nknown 1 60. W. A. Irvin, Wilber 1 16. Mrs. H. M. Crane, Bloomington 1 62. S. Rhodes, Ulysses 1 6j. J. S. Bishop, llysses ; 64. O. P. Dovel, Auburn 66. VVm. H. Harrison, Alda ■ 67. O. H. Kent, Auburn &gt; S. Brubaker, Lexington 1 69. Win. J. Palmer, Fremont 1 70. A. S. Godfrey, Lincoln 1 C W. Jester, Eagle 1 72. A. Gaiser, Tecumseh 7V A. N. Defoe, Tecumseh 1 74. W. H. Havens &amp; Son, Fremont 1 IE. O. Spencer, Lincoln Nellie Hawks, Friend Wm. Wilson, Normal 1 i 80. A. Cruikshank, Dorchester ■W. F. Cadogan, Omaha Chas. A. Cook, Salem 1 1 83. A. W. Saultbaugh, Auburn 1 IWm. M. Clark, Lincoln Abbott Bros. , Saltillo Geo. H. Lee, Omaha 1 1 I 88. Jennie K. Warner, Lincoln : 89. Mrs Nancy Watson, Lincoln 90. W. E. Mickel, Lincoln 1 91. W. H. Gardner, Fremont 92. E. A. Pegler, Lincoln 93. E. M. Martin, Fremont : 94. H. E. Lemmon, Falls City 96. Geo. O. Monroe, Omaha 1 97. Thos. H. Wade, Rising City 1 99. W. A. Taggert, Lincoln 1 100. Geo. A. Goodwin, Unknown 1 101. W. J. Scott, Omaha : 104. A. Sorenson, Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 io6. Magrane &amp; Co., Omaha ■ 107. Southwick &amp; Barclay, Friend 1 108. John Skinner, Spiker 1 109. F. W. Herpolsheimer, Denton 1 no. Frank C. Richards, Lincoln 1 III. G. W. Randall, Newman Grove 113. Mrs. Eleanor Odbert, Lincoln 114. J. W. Seabrook, University Place 1 1 1 115. F. W. Hudson, Saltillo 1 118. t- . F. Goodson, Unknown 1 119. Major J. T. Croft, Omaha 1 120. Fred E. Mockett, Lincoln 1 121. O. E. Gains. Unknown 1 122. Geo. Van Houton, Auburn 125. L. W. &amp; Scott Garroutte, Lincoln 1 126. E. A. Vanderlip, Bennett ! 127. L. L. Fisher, Geneva I 128. Lew W. Marshall, Lincoln 129. C. O. Harvey, Lincoln 1 130. G. Richards, Unknown 1 131. W. H. Bushell, David City 1 132. D. R. Leard, Shelby 1 133. A. S. Campbell, McCook 134. C. A. Chapin, Ulysses 1 135. F. L. Estnay, Deceased 1 137. R. L. Newton, Lincoln 138. Frank Patton, Surprise 1 139. Thos. K. Otis, Humphrey 1 140. A. M. Hendee, Unknown 1 141 . Ayiies &amp; Son Geneva J 142. C. B. Eckardt, Lincoln 1 143. A. Upton, Tobias 1 144. I. Payne, Lincoln 1 145. M. M. Fox, Geneva 1 146. J. G. Foster, Hoskins 1 147. Gallatin Ritter, Saltillo 1 148. Sam Gadd, Lincoln 1 149. H. H. Haines, Unknown 1 150. Gould &amp; Richardson, Lincoln 1 151. David Larson, Wahoo 1 152. D. S. Davis, Bennett . 1 153. Win. Foster, Saltillo 1 154. Chas. Ross, Omaha 1 155. C. E. Boogs, Lincoln 1 156. O. D. Talbert, Omaha 1 157. Aug. Seover, Edgar 1 158. Dr. O. C. Link, Lincoln 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 J • S ' D. D. Adams, Johnson M. H. Drollinger, Kenesaw J. C. Cordner, Lincoln 12: s H. J. F. Wert, Anburn H. J. Pegler, Palmyra 3 J. A. Alley, University Place Ray Winslow, Lincoln W S. Hillis, Omaha 5 James Glasgow, Deceased J. B. Brainerd &amp; Co. Cedar Bluffs J. A. Wheeler, Bennett Daniel Allen, Fremont A. C. Killian, Wah; J. B. Campbell, Hastings F. T. Wieuban, Madison Louis Jacobs, Wilber, Deceased Jno. A. Ling, Harvard D. H. Goodrich, Geneva Rob't Black, Raymond Mrs. A. B. Lathrop, Omaha John A. Landan Jr., Wahoo Dr. J. S. McCleary, Beatrice O. B. Fraser, North Beml W. L. Sprague, Wood River P. R. Longfellow, Deceased Cherney &amp; Kavan, North Bend J. C. Blackburn, Craig A. Granr Musson, Chicago, 111 C H. Roberts, Holdrege W. B. Fuerst, Battle Creek O. M. Tharp, Wahoo C. K. Olson, Unknown W. H. Powers, Lents, Org J. C. Kapser, Clay Center J. J. Brown, Normal Walter F. Savilk, Salem Geo. B. Galbraith, Jansen G. P. Whitman, Unknown Frank Scott, Surprise I E. Brien. Jansen L. C. Huntington, Omaha Wm. Miller, North Bend H. C. Witte, Lincoln Ray Winslow, Lincoln M. D. King. Minden Geo. P. Meesc, Itaca ! </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 208. A P. Hollenbeck, Lincoln 209. Jennie Birdsall, Greenwood 3 10. Amos Vogt, Unknown 211. Jas. Kay, David City 212. C. Rockhill, Harvard 213. J. W. Holstein, Herman 214. A. R. Carruth, Lincoln 215. T. L. Norval, Seward ji6. C. F. Hinman, Friend 217. C. M. Sanders, Friend 218. J. C. Morford, Beaver Crossing 219. D. Tipsword, Beaver Crossing 220. G. M. Whitford, Arlington 221. C. A. Blanchard, Friend : i i ■ i ■ ■ ; 222 G. B. Clary, Fairbury 223. A. B. Evans, Heartwell 224. J. E. Attaey, Fairfield 225. \V. S. Morlan, McCook 226. E. E. Greer, Cambridge 227. Kimball Bros., Beatrice 228. E. M. Coffin, Lincoln 229. E. E. Bowers, York 230. H. W. Lamphere, Scward 231. E. B. Day, Fremont 232. Anyon Kopac. Wells 233. Ida J. Buehler, Kenesaw 234. D. W. Evans, University Place 235. F. W. Brown, Lincoln 1 1 ■ 1 &gt; : 1 1 1 ■ 236. W. H. Lake, Hampton 237. E. E. Smith, Lincoln 238. Alice Hiatt, Bennett 239. V. A. Benway, Fairmont 240. J. Cook Johnson, Omaha 241. I. &amp; M. N. Connor, Ponca 242. H. E. Stien, Friend 1 1 1 ! 1 243. Dr. D. D. Potter, Seward 244. E. N. Crittenden, Lincoln 245. Emil Meduna, Wahoo 246. I. C. Stephens, Raymond 247. Hans Matherson, Scribner \V. Hall, David City 249. E. D. VanCourt, Nehaeka alien Cameron, Schuyler 251. Stephen Norton, Davey 252. Trester Supply Co., Lincoln 253. Cottle Bros., Edgar : 1 : ! : Carl Andra, Lincoln 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 &gt; 1 1 F. E. Brown, Syracuse I ■ rcutt, Lincoln I 258. Peter Jocohv, Aurora 1 259. E. H. Wilke, Lincoln 1 260. Geo. H. Dunham 261. James Craig, Wahoo 1 262. J. C. Seacrest, Lincoln I !rs. Henry Shrader, Wauneta r 264. G. A. Walker, Fairmont 1 266. C. E. Geneways, Aurora I W. Postle, Aurora 1 J. A. Johnson, Holdrege 268. J. A. Johnson, Holdrege 1 269. T. J. Cummins, Crab Orchard ebraska Farmer, Omaha 1 M M. Johnson, Clay Center I A. R. Smith, Lincoln 273. A. L. Clayburg, Lincoln I L. C. Foss, Lincoln W. I Camp, Cheney G. H. Terwilliger, Seward J. A. Rudge, Palmyra H. Terwilliger, Seward J. Lee, Frem 1 : J. Brown, Oseola I nter I 281. M. P. Jensen, Valpar 1- 1 282. ]. I. Lvell. Tecumseh J. J. Lyell, Tfcumseh 0. H. Green, Fremont 1 284. B. H. Dunn, Clay Center 1 285. F. B. Tipton, Seward 1 Karl Eager, Beaver Crossing 1 hil. Maurer, Beaver Cros- 1 Phil. Maurer, Beaver Cn- -nest Gibson, Mead 1 Mrs. J. G. Miller, Dunbar 1 2^ H. H. Campbell, Osceola 1 H. H. Campbell, Osceola 291. J. L. Smith, Cadams D. L. Brewen, Oldenbusch :.. B. Arnot, Johnson 295. Geo. Jackson, Cadamt 296. J. C. Day, Cadams .A. Simmons, Raymond 298. Mrs. Mattie Stufft, Lawrence C. H. Beethe, Elk Creek 1 too. Emma J Millett, Harris 301. J. W. Gibson, Norfolk Mrs. W. H. Kirkpatrick, Iniversity Place Paul C. Cook, Lincoln 304. HE. Bowman, Lawrence 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 305. C. M. Hulburt, Fairbury 306. Philip Benning, Lincoln 307. Schriver &amp; Mumaugh, Benson 308. G. E. Schrepf, Lincoln, R. F. D. 1 309. Geo. A. Hazelett, Weston I I I 1 1 310. Moll Bros., University Place 311. W. B. Swisher, Lincoln 312. Perry Strandberg, Davy 313. J. J. Eddy, Lincoln 1 : 1 314. A. E. Wagner, Lincoln 315. Geo. S. Root, Lincoln 316. A. A. Warner. Roca 318. Frank Staats, Lincoln 319. E. Y. Lawrence, York 320. Joe K. Hiltner, Lincoln 321. S. B. Henderson, Milford 322. David Foy, Beulab 1 1 : 1 323. E. E. Morrow, Blue Springs 324. E. H. Linn, Beatrice 1 325. F. R. Coon, David City 326. J. H. Creighton, Lincoln 327. J. H. Ed well, Havelock 328. A. D. Burhans, Lincoln 329. Henery C. Whitman, Lincoln 33°- J- J- Hamilton, Lincoln 331. Conrad Brehm, Harvard 332. Mr. &amp; Mrs. Miller. Kearney 333. Orville C. Jone«, York 1 1 1 1 I 1 : 1 334. Virgil E. Shirley, Harvard 335. W. W. Davis, Weeping Water 336. S. L. Salisbury, Lincoln 347. John L. Lehmen, Weeping Water 338. G. W. Hardin, Ulysses 1 1 1 ■ ■ 339. J. P. Hendy, Lincoln 340. E. B. Richardson, Ulysses 341. Hugh Compton. Wisner 342. John Levin, Wahoo 1 1 1 343. Win. S. Rhodes, Lincoln 344. A. H. Smith, Lincoln 345. Conard Reiutzel, Clay Center 346. C. R. Wilke, Lincoln 1 : 1 347. F. P. Gifford, Lincoln 348. J. M.Jamison, Valparaiso 349. M. S. Davis, Columbus 1 1 1 350. Jas. B. Hungate, Weeping Water 351. C. R. Jones, Lincoln 1 i 352. O. E. Imm, Milford 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 R. D. Muir, Milford I Mrs. F. E. Buzina, Lincoln L. E Mahan, Malcolm C. E. Knerr, Stromsbur W. J. Hildreth, Hildreth Adams, Weeping Water N. H. H. Lihby, Elk Creek J. F. Miller, Sutton : : i J. H. Craddock, Lincoln W. H. Swarthey, Columbus A. M. Hartley, Doniphan I 1 I C. K Weaver, Lincoln A. Wilson, Cheney S. W. Good, Lincoln : i Nebr. 1'oultrv Co., Clay Center J. H. Trough, Mitiden ■ i E. C. Clark. Weslon i Mrs. Chas. IvOwerv, Dunbar Chas. White, Aurora : i i Anna L. Pinkerton, Ha^- F. C. Dearduff, David C H. C. White, Beatrice i ! If cC ready, Lincoln C. E. Cherr\, Weeping Water \V. H. Stubbs, Bradshaw Will C. Hamilton, Plattsmouth : Oakwood White Egg Farm, Weeping Water Orville Compton, Lincoln ■ i W. A. Whitcomb, Friend W. H. Kennedy, Dorchester Wm. G Beha, Lincoln O. R. Mevers, Lincoln : • : M. Schlitz, Columbus H. R. Darnall, Germantown J. E. Fulmer, Columbus ■ ■ Otoe Egg and Poultry Farm, Nebraska City P. H. Gibson, Hampton i I W. A. Schwenck, So. Omaha : Loup Valley Poultry Farm, Columbus O. E. Henning, Wahoo ■ W. A. Schwenck, So. Omaha Frank H. Frease. Leigh : ■Unas. White, Aurora A. J. Kelpser, Weeping Water J. G. Gowrlay, Lincoln Anna L&gt;. Pinkerton, Ha^- </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015">Addresses Volume 1902 President L. P. Harris 4 C. H. Rhodes Geo. H. Gillis 9 Dr. J. W. Con way.. Dr. J. W. Conway Io Dr. A. T. Peters _. Dr. A. T. Peters „ Volume 1903 President Geo. \V. Osterhout ■ G. Lnitt. I7 T. J. Norval L. P. Ludden, Accepting I. L. Lyman, Dr. A. T. Peters , 9 I K T QOJ Dr. Peters _ 6 Mrs Emma J. Mellette g Gov. J. H. Mickey. _ _ , 9 Secretary E. C. Rewick jo T. J. Norval, Accepting- 26 L. P. Ludden " Volume 1905 Miss Smith... Dr. A. T. Peter- g C. M. Lewelling 9 T. J. NorTal, accepting E. B. Day, L. P. Ludden y, I. L&gt;. Lyman Amendments to Constitution, vol. [903 Annual Meetings 1902 volume 1902.. im 1903 '• 1903.. 5 1904 " 19. I9»5 " 1905... Article* of Incorporation following vol. 1905 1 Board Meetings I9Q8 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Commercial Club Omaha, vol.1904. 21 it Hastings " 1905 ig Delegate to A. P. A., vol. 1903 25 itio.n of Officers 1902 vol. i 2O 1903 vol. 1903 ,6 1904 vol. 1904 2 6 1905 vol. 1.. tion of the Board 1902 vol. 1902 _ 2O 1903 vol. 1903 , 9 I904 TOl. I904 .. jg I9O5 VOl. I9O5 yj ;al Remarks Volume 1902 L. L. Ludden . _ 11 and 15 ■I. Lewelling. 14 L. W. Garrotte. 14 and 16 mmaj. Mellett 15 and 18 M. L. Trester L. C. Foss ,8 Dr. A. T. Peters • ,8 Volume 1903 W. H. Haven 6 L. P. Ludden ... 6, 7, 24 I. L. Lyman Dr. A. T. Peters... C. M. Lewelling . . . Volume 1904 J. M Armstrong 7t 18, 19, 25 David Larson ij i x -j J. W. Seabrook 15,16 L. P. Ludden I5i 18, 19, 25 L. C. Fo9s 16 C. M. Lewelling ...16.17 T. J. Norval 16 W. H. Havens ... ,6 E. J. Pegler ... 18 Harris J. Cook Johnson . 22 Mr. Sherman 23 Albert Lemen 23 P. B. 1 lpton 23 G. H. Terwilliger 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 O. Cotnpton _ 26 P»ul Cook a6 Volume 1905 L. P. Ludden --19, *o, It, 24, 26, 28, 34 F. J. Benedict... 19, 2 J. Cook Johnson 19 Mr. Saddler ao G. H. Terwilliger I. L. Lytnan. 21,23 E. B. Day ... 22,26 T.J.Norval .. . 22,23,25,26,32,34 J. G. Gourley .. 22,25 Albert Lemen .. 27,28 O. Cotnpton 27 t Mrs. W. H. Kirkpatrick. .„«,. 28 E. E. Smith _ 33 Letter of Transmittai. 1902 vol. 1902 2 1903 " 1903 3 1904 ' 1904 3 1905 " 1905 3 List of Members ...- vppendix 6 Officers For 1902 " 1902 3 1903 " 1903 4 1904 " 1904 4 1905 " 1905 4 Resolutions 1903 vol. 1903 23 1905 " 1905 Report of Officers President 1902 Harris vol 1902 4 1903 Osterhout " 1903 1904 Norval ._ 11 Secretary 1902 Garroutte " 1902 .... 1903 Ludden " 1903 1904 '■ " 1904 11 1905 " " 19 Treasurer 1902 Lyman " 1902 8 19 *5 1904 " I9°4 '3 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Special Committee on St. Louis, vol. 1904 15 Semi Annual Meetings 1903 2 5 1904 31 Report of Committee 1905 Voting by Proxy Vol. 1905. </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>