<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00017.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00017.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FOURTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE DEPARTMENT OF BANKING SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE INCORPORATED, PRIVATE, AND SAVINGS BANKS OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR 1905 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE STATE BANKING BOARD JANUARY 20, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NG FOURTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE DEPARTMENT OF BANK nviM )NDIT1ON OF THE INCORPORATED. PRIVATE, AND SAVINGS HANKS OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR 1905 SUBMITTED TO THE GOVERNOR AND THE STATE BANKING BOARD JANUARY 20, 1906 E. ROYSE, Secretary LINCOLN. NEB DIUFF-COLLISI PBE11 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">DEPART.N! BANKING OF THE STATE OF NEBRASK BOARD HON K M SEARLE. JR HON PETER MORTENSKN HON NORRIS BROWN Auditor of Public Accounts, Pn si Trea Attorn- B ROYSE EXAMINERS C. H BEAUMONT, Madrid FRED WH1TTEMORE. Long Plr J f HALOBEMAN, Burchard E E. EMMETT. Arapahoe ADDISON WAIT. Chief Clerk MAl'DE H(KiE. Stenographer </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Likcolk, January 20, 1'toh". ( To Hit Excellency, John //. Mi Thf Honor ables A'. .1/. Snn-Ic, Jr., Auditor of Public Accounts, Peter Mortensen, State Treasut X orris Brown, Attorney General Membess or the State Banking Boabd Siks: — In compliance with the provisions of the Ban Act. I have the honor to submit herewith the fourteenth mini report of the Secretary of the St:ite Banking Board for the year 1905, showing the condition of the banks under your supervision on November !). 1905, f&gt;4&lt;&gt; in number; unmiaries (if the resources and liabilities of such hanks fipiled from reports submitted to the State Hanking ird in response to calls made by the Department during year; together with such information regarding faUn 'iverships, recommendations, etc., as seem contemplated the provisions of the law. Eliis report covers the period beginning November 10, L and ending November !», 1905. The period covered by 1 1 1 i &gt; characterized by phenomenal ; branches of husiness and con institutions under your supei s report has been especially growth and prosperity in all imeroe in Nebraska, and the rviaion have shared in these n by summaries and compari- Ispicious conditions, as show following. It is shown by a tabulation of the amount of bank capital, deposits and loans by counties, found elsewhere in this port, that the growth of state hanks has not been confined to any particular portion or portions of the state, but is general. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 KOIRTKKNTH ANN' ; t &gt; • I am pleased to report that during th.' calendar year 190! nk failure occurred in the state, ■ record which cannot but he a M&gt;arce of itisfaction to tli - pervising authorities and a credit to the management of tht intioiis under your sujk Under the proper heads. folio win j, Eitliin the period covered nks ineorpi -old to and i by this re] tort • rated. voluntary liquidation and qui Wanks have nationalized banks I. i incorporated and chart* '! • hanks have been reehartered. inks chartered had not commenced busine 1. Oxford — Commercial State Bank .... January 21, !!•&lt;• _'. Etandolph— Security State Bank May ;&gt;, 190 ::. Shelby— Bank of Shelby October 30, 1905 l"he Citizens Bank. . . .July 25, 1905 (i. Wilcox Tlie State B August 2L 1905 rvision. md in &lt;let;iil. I bes to Bubmit li'd bv other lcink Kvcn banks wen- placed in usiiit 4. Spalding— Spalding State Bank lanuary l'4. 1905 vember it. 1905. Three banks surrendered their charter* . never having opened for basinet I &gt;;m k suspended ;m&lt;l wn?- placed in the h;m&lt;ls of a ro- er. CHANGED FROM PRIVATE TO IX&lt; BANK8 DURING THE FEAB 1. I Bank of Eagle May 20, 1905 Humphrey- The Bank of Ottia hh.I Murpliy .lamiiiry .'!. 1905 Kimball— Bank of Kimhall March 27, 1905 STATE BANKS WHICH HAVE NATIONALIZED DUE- [NG THE FEAR. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THK TATE BANKING BOAKI 5 BANKS THAT HAVK SOLD TO AND BEEN Sl&lt; CEEDED BYOTHEB BANKS DUBING THK YF.AK &gt;Butt«- Bank of Hutte. sold to Bank of Boyd Comity Butte, March 7. 1905. I Fairfield— Bank of Fail-field, sold to Citizens Hank of FairfiekL March 7. L905. Naper— Citizens Bank, sold to Hank of Naper, October 20, 1906. Ieoll I'.ank of I'olk County, sold to First Nationa Bank of Osceola, October 3, 1905. Overtoil Alfalfa State Bank, sold to First Xationa I'.ank of Overton. October 21, 1905. Shelton -The Fanners Bank, sold to Shelton Hank. l&gt;t » Tobias— The People'- Bank, sold to Tobias Nati I'.ank. January 26, 1905. Ml 8. University Place- The Windom Bank, sold to the Firs! State Hank, June 28, 190 &gt; NE INTO VOLUNTARY IT BUSINESS DUB- fNKS WHICH IIAVF &lt;i LIQUIDATION AND Q VFAR Hank 1905 niercc lican Hank i uidv August 21, I April 26, 1905 Garrison — Hank of &lt;!ai rison 8. Madrid Hank of Madrid Jmw 30, 1905 Meadow Grove -The Farmers i Merchants State Bank -Tune 13, l!»'"&gt; 10. Odell— Bank of odell February l'4, 1!"'.") 11. Randolph- Randolph State Bank cember \2, 1!&gt;&lt;&gt;4 I National Bank, University Place. June 1. 19n."i. Wilsonville— Wilwraville Bank, sold to the Wilsonville Iix&lt;; Tin- Amei First I &gt;a tik of Ann Atkinson -Atkinson Stutt April 12, January 9, 1905 1 .uuiic Bank of Boone I Broken Bow Bank of Coi Emerson German-Americ Gandy— The Bank of Gan&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 NEW BANKS INCORPORATED AND CHARTERED lHHIXfi TIIK YFAK 1 Aiish-v- Farmers State Bank November 2!&gt;. 1904 I Arnold- The Farmers State Hank June 8, 1905 Beaver City- Bank of Beaver City. . .October 19, 4 Beaver Cn Citizens State Bank. . .July 31, 1905 i. Bethanv- First State Hank Kay 12. 1905 (i. Bladen State Bank of Bladen .... September 11. 1905 tBloomington The Franklin County Fannen Bank May 3, 1906 8 Blue Hill— The Commercial Bank August 8, 1905 IBoone The Boone State Bank May 20, Broken Bow Security State Bank Jme ■"&gt;, 1905 Burwell— BnrweU State Bank. kagmt 14. L905 Clariuon Farmers State Hank October 1!». 1905 10. Broken Bow Security State Bank. ...June ■"&gt;, 1905 11. Burwell— Bnrwell State Bank August 14. !!«•."• 1_'. Clarkson Fanners State Bank ...October 1!&gt;. 1905 13. Cozad— The Cozad State Bank \u-nist 8, 1905 ■ad state Bank \u-u&gt;t 14. Cotesfield First State Bank September 2."&gt;. 1905 ( «ite&gt;tield First State Bank September 25, I! 1 ""* 1."). Cornlea— Cocnlea State Hank January 24. 1905 State Bank January 24. 1905 Crab Orchard— Farmer* State Bank. .January •'!. 1905 16. Crab Orchard- Fanners State Bank. .January •'!. 1!»'"» 17. Creighton Citizens State Bank October lit. 1905 Creighton Citizens State Bank October lit. 1905 Decatur- Deeater State Bank February -1. 1! |(I "&gt; Decatur- Decatur State Bank February 21. 1905 Hate Bank of Deweese March 15, 1905 Dei State Bank nf Deweese March ir&gt;, I!" 1 "* Eddyville— The Farmer* State Rank . ' September 29, 1905 21. I Commercial State Bank Inly i'4. 1 Kricson Kru-un State I'.ank September 22, 1905 ter State I'.ank July 31. !!'••.") Funk— Funk State Bank. .February 24, 1905 Qandy -Gandy Bank June 12, a— Farmers* Merchants Bank.. April !&lt;•. 1905 fOothenbmrg- Fanners I Merchants Bank July 3, 1905 Grant— Commercial Bank of Grant June 21. 1!»&lt;»."&gt; Harbine -State Bank of Harbine .July 19, : Hardy Fanner- State Bank. June 12. !!•••:, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">' BA X KINU BOARD 7 Hastings — Bank of Commerce July 26, I!*".") Heartwell— Heartwell State Bank. September 18, 1905 33. Hendley— The Fanners State Bank. .August 8, L905 Holmesville- State Hank rune 30, 1905 Huntley State Bank of Huntley March 27, 1905 36. Keeoe — Fanners State Bank August 22. 1 Kramer- The Fanners Bank February 14. I Kramer Kramer State Bank. March 1(1. Lewellen — Bank of Lewellen October -7. 1 40. Loop City- I,oup City State Hank. . .January 41. Macon— Macon State Hank January 42. Mason City— First State Bank April 13, ! Meadow Grove The Farmers &amp; Merchant State Bank February 44. Meadow Drove Security Bank April 20, : 4.".. Merna— The Home Hank .July 20, I Murdock — Union State Hank June 30, 1905 47. Oeonto Farmers Hank July 31, 1905 4 s Orchard — Citizens State Hank Julv I!. V.K Orchard Farmers State Hank June Oshkosh Deuel Coutitv Hank November l'*. 1'.M'4 51. Overtoil -The Overton State Bank . September 13, r.»»."&gt; Y2. Pauline — Bank of Pauline November !». 1 53. Pool Siding- Pool Siding State Bank. . July 11. '} ."i4. Prairie Home — The Farmers Hank June 8, l'.ni.~&gt; Bockville— Rockville State Hank of Kock- ville, Nebraska June 29, 1905 Buskin — Farmers State Bank January 'A. 1905 Sargent- State Hank of Sargent June 8, 1905 58. Smithfield- -Farmers State Hank Yugust 14. 1905 Sumner— Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank... July lit, 1905 Taniov— The Tarnov State Bank March 4. 1905 61. Taylor— Bank of Taylor June 30, 1905 Thurston Thurston State Bank March 1(!. 1905 Trumbull — Farmers Exchange Hank .October li7. ti4 lehling — Farmers State Hank October &lt;i. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 FOURTEENTH ANNUAL KK.l'oliT UK THF 1905 HF S KD IR AR inn t. Wr.lon— The Bank of Wnlon Farm Verdon December 8, 1904 k Merchants Bank Januarv 19. 1905 I Wallace Citizens Security Bank. Wilooi — Exchange Bank Wilsonville — Wilsonville State Ba York German-American Bank.. IVATK BANKS BECHABTER] uritv Bank Annul 21, 1905 ank Jnlv 31, 1905 State Bank. . .June 28, 1905 1 (erman- American Bank Mm- 29 I'KIVATK BANKS h'FCHARTFKKD DlRIXii 'I TEAR YEAR. tOak irin t Company I lank. ..Fun* Bushville- Citizens Bank . Ma\ Oak — Tin -in A. Company I ;n Kusliville- Citizens Bank . May 1 4. BANKS rilAHTKRKI) IUT HAD NOT (OMMI NKs CHARTERED BUT HAD &gt; BUSINESS NOVEMBER X( BUSINESS NOVEMBER 9, 1905 r City Bank of Beaver City tBloomington The Franklin County Fannen B Clarkson — Farmers State Bank. ink ICoteafieM Fir&gt;t State Bank. Bricsoa Brieson State Bank. Kntina Commercial State Hank. Fairmont — Fairmont State Bant I.ewcllen Hank of Lewelkm. Pauline- Bank of Pauline. BTrumbull -Farmer* rehlins Fanner- State Ban Hank. BANKS WHICH HAVJ SUEEENDERED '1 \{ HAVING OPENED SINi IFF CHARTERS, XKVI FuR BF I Kramer The Fain Verdon The Bank of \'. lank. 'nlon. BANKS WHICH HAVE FAILED Dl'RINCJ THE VF O'Neill -Elkhorn Valley Bank ember 24, 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE BANKING BOAKD 9 SECRETARY OF Tilt Following is a statement of the condition of bv the Elkhorn its books at Valley Bank of O'Neill, Nebi the date the Examiner took i iska, as show n u $63,8 - Bills receivable Overdrafts 1,998.83 Banking house 3,500.00 Banking house 500.00 &gt; Furniture and fixtures 1.500.00 1.5D0.0O Furniture and fixtnf ( )thcr real estate. . . Dm from First Xnti Cash ( &gt;ther real estate 2.500.00 o 500.00 Dm from First National Hank. Sioux City 120.65 120.65 Cash 10 .10 Checks on other hanks 21.10 ( 'hecks on other bai Due from Merchant Expense 21.10 Due from Merchants National Bank, Omaha i Expense ii.27^.45 ,278.45 ■) Total 176,625.48 ,625.48 Total LIABII.I I Capital stock $15,00 *15 500.00 Capital stuck Surplus 1 •••' ' 1 Surplus Profits Profits 3,520-31 Time certificates of deposit 29,4' I Time certificates of Demand certificates Individual deposits. . Sundry accounts dm Demand certificates of deposit 485.00 Individual deposits 23,541 .33 Sundry accounts due 27-. 72 Due to Kountze Bros.. New Fork 14.63 niiic i&gt;..v.ii,i.. 2,500.00 Bills payable 309.26 Short and over. $76,625.48 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 RTEEJTTH ANMAI. KKPURT Of IHK Tin- following ii a statement of tli. found by the miner and the liabilities to be paid therefrom: Bills receivable $32,174.12 rdrafts ] ,998.83 Dae from Kountse P»n».. New Fork 104.23 Dae from Merchants National Hank. Omaha.... ").39 Due from First National Bank. Sioux City 120.65 Cash and checks 21.20 HuBber of banks reporting November 10. L904 515 Number of banks chartered but had not commenced Eusincss November lit. 1904 1 nber of banks organised since Nov&lt; inber 10, 1904. . 70 nber of banks discontinued November 10, 1904 *.. •■ 29 0 fcber of banks reporting November !•. 1905 546 ber of banks chartered but had not commenced business November 9, 1905 11 Banking house, furniture and fixture ... 5,000.00 ToU K),377.42 I.IABIU II KS Individual deposits 1 deposit _::.r)47.3o . .. 29,961.23 Sundry accounts due 272 . 72 Fs payable •aid drafts ... 2,500.00 206.67 Total 56,487.96 RECAPITULATION. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 I K BANKING BOARD ABSTRACT OF THE CONDITION OF THE INCORPORATED, PRIVATE NEBRASKA, AT AND SAVINGS BANKS OF THE STATE OF THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS FEBRUARY* TOTAL N 191 BER OF BANKS REPORTING RESC Other loans and discounts Overdraft Stocks, securities, judgments. Due from national, state and priva Banking house furni arc an I fixiui Other real esn • Current expenses anil t;iv Premium on bonds, etc Other assets Cash Total 1.1 AMI Capital stock paid in Surplus fund Undivided profits Dividends unpaid Deposits subject to check . . . Demand certificates of deposit Time certificates of deposit Due to banks and banker- Notes and bills rediscounted Bills payable Total -&gt; Loans on real estate securltj </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 FOURTEENTH ANNUAL RKPORT OF THK ABSTRACT OF THE CONDITION OF THE INCORPORATED. PRIVATE AND SAVINGS BANKS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA AT THE CLOSB OF BUSINESS MAY 29. 1905. TOTAL NUMBErt OF BANKS REPORTING RESOURCES Loans on real rarity * 5,77 loans and discounts 31,805.89( 478.80 iilfuwili. clain: 716,785 ud private banks and bank. "18.G2J Bank urniture and fixtur HI Other real 15.731 .4) Current txpenspg and taxes paid 507,640.44 4. "91 9i Total 81 LIABILITIES Capital stock paid in Surplus fund * 8 58 8 1 1 K hided i [lends 15 tk . . . ind certificales of deposit ticates of to banks and banket s and I 145 9 ;s 7&gt; 47/ 192,7 $5G 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">FARY OF THE STATE BANKIXli BOARD 13 ABSTRACT OF THE CONDITION OF THE INCORPORATED, PRIVATE AND SAVINGS BANKS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA AT THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS AUGUST 190 TOTAL NUM- BER OF BANKS REPORTINC RESOl RCES 32.118 Overdraft IS.C5 i laments, claim Dae from national, state and privae Banking house, furniture and fixture! Current expenses and taxes paid . etc 1) anl- and banker -83.87 17G.36 Cther real Premium on bonds, etc Other Cash Total LIABILI TIE :a Capital stock Surplus fund Dt posits subject to check Demand certificates of deposit Time certificates of deposit Due to banks and bankers Notes and bills rediscounted . . Bills rayable Total Loans on real estate security Other loans ani discount Undivided profit Dividends unpai&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p014">KOUKTKKJTTH ANNUAL KKl'dRT OF THE 14 ABSTRACT OF THE CONDITION OF THE INCORPORATED. PRIVATE AM) SATINOS BANKS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA AT THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS NOVEMBER 9. 19( BER OF BANKS REPORTING. 54C. TOTAL Nl'.M- RESOIRCES Eon real estate securi'y loans an:l discoun rafts Eks. securities, judgments, claims, from national, state and private It; king house, furniture and fixture: 1 1 estate Current expenses and t. Premium on bonds Total LIABIL JTIES Ktal stock lus fund Evided profits lends unpaid Deposits subject to check Demand certificates of deposit Time certificates of dei&gt;osit . . .) banks and bankers Noes and bills rediscounted . . Bills payable 14.G86.89G.14 1.110.253.82 ■ 87.4GO Total G2.853.G0l Gl leposits </seg>
            <seg id="p015">TARY OF THK STATK BANKING BOARD 15 rtACT OF REPORTS MADE TO THE COMPTROLLER OF THE CURRENCY, SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE NATIONAL BANKS IN THE STATE OF NEBRASKA (INCLUDING OMAHA AND LINCOLN) AT THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS ON THE 9th BANKS REPORT- DAY OF NOVEMBER, 1905 ING, 1G2. NUMBER OF RESOl RCES Loans and discounts Overdrafts $ 59,190,414.19 738,160.85 6,181,270.00 1,245,000.00 E. bonds to secure circulation . . bonds to secure deposit r bonds to secure U. S. deposi . bonds on hand . . 21,350.00 -13.82 Premium on U. S. bond 2,126,852.94 Bonds, securities, judgments, claims. t ite 2.227.900.31 ring house, furniture and fixtures r real estate and mortgages owns from other national banks from state and private banks an from approved reserve agents . Checks and other cash items . d 387,483.02 145.17 I ban H00.34 Exchanges 'or clearing house a of o"her national banks 10.58 408,553.00 Fractional pai er currtncy. nickels an Specie 1 cents Legal tender not Five per cent redemption fund Due from U. S. treasurer Tota LIABU I TIES Capital stock paid in Surplus fund Undivided profits less expenses . . National bank notes outstanding Due to other national banks .... Due to state banks and bankers Due to trust companies and saving Due to approved reserve agents Dividends unpaid 11,721,260.42 b; anks 357.97 Individual deposits subject to check U S. deposits 18.12 Deposits of U. S. disbursing officers Notes and bills rediscounted . 47.983.09 Bills payable 404 74 Reserved for taxes Other liabilities 91.2(11 !&lt;• $105,251. 252. 00 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 'KT (i&gt; THE Elate hanks reporting Norember !». 1905, and the lin capital, depontfl and loans and discounts represented B distributed among the sever*] counties of the state as B follows -* J County iCapitu I»epo Loans s. A. air- li 11(1 II * :we :5j. if. I -J.JO : •' 1 23.082.71 .\000.00 21.888 11 24.477.80 10.000 00 5 (KK).OO 250t KJ(O 10,843 47 S,4»»l imt.4'24 fir. 180.218H1 I (13 00 Ui7.500 0J 15O.000 00 105.000 00 815 ttS.ll 648,:,; Hamilton 719.066 58 605,241. 8a Hsrlan 710.425 88 557 «36 40 : 15.000.00 42.600H0 59.500 00 10.000 00 80.000 00 48.049.42 4 -:i7.O4 186,410.58 ... 5 888.989 35 Hooker. 1 3H.:«5.70 Howard I 521.021.01 i) 864.387 4* 87:i :&gt;44 I •;:■• 1 45.^ Id 1&lt;" « 3«:.!i Brown. 4 00.00 244.071 45 221.827.9M Buffalo. .(IHIOO l,091,9«l 44 7«3,8l Bun 7 11" 17 014,127 1b ■ Cm» ? I ss.55 100(1.00 MS.8M.U. :ti0» I .- 6«.i y ,181.49 46.000 0*&gt; 803.460. 1( .^0.15 16 589,086.98 14H.O00 464.76U.22 29. !)»«• 226,604 1 - ! 86. - 10 k74.tM.M 1.141 *6».O4 io ia : IK) 1.9x7. 709. -T. 1.341,886 9 30.000 00 j 1. 98,811 M I .■ ■■• $68,917! Krmnklin 100.000.00 853.144.4 -M8" 41.000.00 M0.S3-VM -'79,667.85 Kurii:.- 7 75 1 00 00 413.676.tt Gtfte 178.000.00 1N.3B3.73 i 10.000 00 T.SM.M </seg>
            <seg id="p017">SECRETAKY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 17 i -* X Loans County Capital Stock Deposits 7S 222.0001" 1.1'." Jefferson 102.5110 an.su «■_&gt; Johnson Kearney I07.M1 4U 100,307.27 92,794.27 KeyaPaha 4 Kimball. . . .' 17.01 (I (XI 'J43.OO0 IH) 1 386.0H6 'JO Knox 14 301. CH' La dc aster M8.817 90 Lincoln l.i.irnti :&gt;.ooo I'll 220,001 (K» a McPI, llO.IK'O r&gt;*7.63.-&gt; 5:! Merrick ... *&gt; (K) 15 000 419.993 15 Ni'iniilia. 353,491.84 Nuckolls s 871.715.24 8«7. 127.43 Pawnee ) 50,950.;*; Perkins 15.00(1 (HI IK) 2-.'7.(l»O.-l(l 1W.616.86 Kps .. ... 9 Pierce \HI 7».8M U MM.an.« Red Willow 104,000 (Ml Richardson 11 IM OB.M Saline I 9 'lli.W 4 mi Saunders.:. ....16 mi 174,50.08 - Bluff 8 14 Bewaril 3M7.379 57 Sheridan 6 161,740.56 Sherman 4 •J10.rt83.10 1 10.0CO 00 Stantou (0 (K) (X) 16 4' (101.772.27 Thayr 10 11.1- iSom:,- 1 Thnrston 1 HHI.OIKI 140.000 560,444 83 703, 90ti H-J BOti.MOK M 1.473.KH.38 Washington 9 1 702..- Wayne. 4 92,000 447,106.87 Webster I 8 Wheeler 974, V- 1O7.B00 00 Totals 646 $8,846,440.00 $50,157,335.20 $41.«68,868.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Comparative statement of deposits in all banks under Kpervision. including 2 to 1905, inclusive. banks in hands of Receivers, Irom the foregoing summaries it will he noted that the uder state supervision made four reports to the te Banking Board during the year, in which time the iber of banks in active operation increased 31. The ag - trate amount of resources has increased $10.!lf)S,lS6.49; i-in capital in. 2,040.00; loans inert general deposits increased £10,582452.06; notes and bills cediseoimted and bills payable have been i from &gt; 03 to $l&lt;&gt;:&gt;.770.33, a reduction of 0,056 While all this certainly giv n for congratulation, I regret to say that in some instances there is a tendency to overdo the banking business by the establishment of banks in communities already well provided, which mean&gt; ting competition sooner or later. However, I presume this must be determined in the 'hool of experience. • &gt;n June 26, 11*05, Mr. H. V. Temple, Receiver of the &gt;■ Bank of Gothenburg, filed his final report, a copy of which will be found under the head of Statements showing if Banks Placed in the Hands ol This i'EABS T"t»l deposits in banks placed in handi of recen Total deposits In all banks Number of depositors I - isn 1HM IX..:, i m 1MJ.T 18M lttOO 1901 1!«V4 •71,9 144. • 10 (Mi 10,915 81 ne 1T.2CH.4T6 14 lMP74.su:; 48 14.J' lO.-Ji Ji.lKO 14 Jl.tiW.lll U B ,{T SI,4S1,3H :u.4- llfi,484 1.-.3,I&gt;(I2 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">TABY OF THE STATE HANKING BOARD 19 * bank was placed in the hands of the receiver January 9, 1902, with total assets amounting to $51,682.36, and liabili - ties aggregating $34,438.13; the receiver paid all liabilities in full, except liabilities not proved, amounting to $418.70; paid the expenses of winding up the affairs of the bank, Kunting to $4,149.89, and had remaining in his hand amounting to $7,242.94. There has been a tendency in a few instances for bank chartered as commercial banks to receive savings depot also a few cases where banks chartered as savings bank rated to do a commercial business. In either instance wherever found, the department has enforced the law an&lt; compelled commercial banks to refrain from doing a sav inn bank business, and savings banks from doing a com mercial luisi' The Department is pleased to report that the banks un der state supervision, as a rule, comply with the provisioi of the Banking Act, giving the Department but little troi tbut some practices arc indulged in which, in my opinioi not only irregular, but unsound. There is a tendency &lt; the part of some banks, when demand for loans is pressing to issue certificates of deposit for borrowed moneV in orde to avoid showing a rediscount or bills payable. The pra. tice is certainly reprehensible and prohibited. Also thei is a disposition at times to earn its of a bank varioi kinds of stocks, which is not only unsound, but unauthorize and prohibited by the Department. RECOMMENDATIONS While the Banking Act of this state in the main proven very satisfactory, experience has shown that some needed amendments are required to make it effective. I'mler the present provisions banks under the supervision of this Department are required to pay for but one examination each year. Experience proves that it is sometimec sarv to make more than one examination each year in order </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 FOURTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE tthe requirements of the law enforced. This is usually B td the negligence or incompetence of the management the bank, and I would respectfully recommend an amend - ■iit providing that an examination fee shall be paid for lamination found J by the Department. lere is no reason why, in case- where the management nore than one examination necessary, that the work ould be done for nothing. I With regard to a surplus fund, under the present revenue w a hank is taxed on its capital, surplus and undivided uh"t&gt;. Thi.- provision of the law has a tendency to discour - ;e, on the part of banks, the building up of a surplus fund, rich is certainly i nard to the solvency of a bank, d the Department l&gt;elieves that it would be wise to only x the capital and surplus up to the point where the sur - per cent of the capital. This would have a y to encourage the building np of a Mirplus which uld not be but beneficial. It is further recommended that the present Banking be amended so that a bank may loan l'&lt;&gt; per cent of its capi - .nd surplus to any one individual, firm or corporation. capital, as now provided. In for each examiner by tlie last legis - jre was $1,200.00 for the biennium, making $600.00 each ir for expenses, which includes transportation. It must evident to the law-making body that this sum is entirely dequate unl&lt; \aminers accept free railroad ti •tation. If in the opinion of the next legislature the rail - id pass is an evil and should be abolished, the present aking Act should be amended and appropriation made ticient to cover the traveling expenses of the examiners, ich it is estimated would require an appropriation about lble the amount heretofore appropriated. My predecessor recommended that the word "bank" be denned by statute, and my experience bears him out in mak - ing the recommendation. The statute should provide that </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 the word "bank" or "banker" be used only by an indi - vidual, firm or corporation chartered to do a banking busi - j, and the word "'bank" or "banking" be specifically de - fined as doing any one or all of the following: Receiving deposit Paying check Buying and Belling exchange ■ Pursuing any one or all of the above as a business should constitute a bank or banking business and necessitate a proper authorization by the supervising authorities of the state. APPROPRIATION' KoR THK BEENNIUM, SHOWING AMOUNTS EXPENDED To JANUABY 1 1906, Balanct \X1&gt; BALANCES ON HAND Fary for Secretary.. &gt;4.n&lt;K).OO ount expended . . 1,499.94 Balance kary for Chief Cler* S2,400.00 ount expended I in lance firy for Stenographer ount expended 630.00 Balance •••.00 kary for Fonr liank Examinen. $14,400 lOUnt expended Balanee '0.00 t Office Expense -;l,500.00 uunt expended M 1.4^ Balance For Traveling expenses Four Bank Rxamine Balanee Old Appropriation $326.34 Appropriation 1,800.00 $5.1- inount expended . ' (i " </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Hon. Frank Jonvenat introduced a l)ill in the last legis lature which became a law July 1. 1905, requiring a fee of 'Hi to be paid to the state for each charter issued by the State Hanking Board. Since this law took effect there have been 4l' banks chartered op to January 1, 1906, for which the state received $1,050.00. Six hundred and sixty-three examinations were made dur- ing I!"*.") by the four state liank examiners, including build and loan associations, for which the state received in $10,92J Total expenses of Examiners, including salaries Leaving a surplus of 1, .'!.'!, .4^ Twenty-two special examinations were made during the . for which no fee could be charged under the present In conclusion. 1 beg to thank the members of the Statt Hanking Hoard for their wise counsel, courteous treatment and careful consideration of all matters brought to their at- tention. E\&gt; the bankers of the state I desire to express my appre - tion of their co-operation in accomplishing what attended the Department, by their conservative -iness methods and prompt compliance with instructions from the Department To the Examiners and Department force I acknow I sincere gratitude for their valuable services, faithful "ormance of every duty imposed upon them, and the very ient manner in which they have disposed of the vast amount of work entrusted to their can Very Respectfully submitted E. ROYSE, Secretary State Banking Board </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATEM ENTS rWING THE CONDITIONS OF BANKS PLACED IN THE HANDS OF RECEIVERS SUBSEQUENT TO JULY 1. 1901, REPORTING DE - CEMBER 31, 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 FOUBTEENTH ANNUAL BEPOBT OF THE l! — I = 5 OS© • ft - ■ C* is :§ : !i 8 ir : :P ■X O ■ . I6SI . — .O*-H* hi ■ H S X O S-" Ot- « ■&lt;* O t- O M ■*■ TC 3 X ?1 2 = ?J : 8 : o : S z " - 9BK » O T a If- t-x — c n — .- s*;:i- = tj — x 3 ~ ( - : — P8J o x s — : : — t-e» Si- is M Mi M I • 9 1 . : S : : - ■= a :• : : r t = : S « : ; t-i : 2- .1 S "O * - ■= — g z a gJ - -; 5 ill! * m a * « B * - - e S "5-=™ ■" a 2]jl S=-53 . _ ; f?.:iooi)»t 9»ox • • • Urn C*»C*t — — "'■" »-* O ® ---Ct C^INNC OXO t- w O «&amp;Ot^ ■"* i— r- r-OI - • 35 £-■-" 2 s *' : : : I * . : : • iJiiMill ;!; MM : : .'o- : : : :':'.: :::::: '. a : • : : : : : i ! ; !! ii 11 Mi MM : : "8 : : : i | : : : : '. I : j : : : if : :3 : 1 : - .= ■ ts ■ ■- ■&lt; • • S o • e •- ■ -i .. » 1 1 li 1 y : . cje : : ~ : :g : 1 1 iijjljs | I II : :^2 8 1 ° : 1 • : • -a -I s 5 fc -- J i : 5 ■•.*"■ = o : Iff* 1 3 -I il •! || i &amp;lli{! Si'i Hill) -££££ gjo I t = = 8=55 • e» : S </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 25 e -9BS : ! 2 2SS SSSSS 9 .©r. ■ « X • X *Q Cfi»2« *M X ?J O 3S3SS 8 « S |«" S : oo . 25 ; « 82 " 8 : " :W 8 s * &gt; ■ • ,3 ■ i X £ * T. * ii X ■ 5 - : : a g-S : •£ ■ r. . — — 1 I IliSjil i i I -His il • /* 2 ! : s f] g « : §| I Milt 1 X oJ z 18 JE-.-1 ;^l 5 U.-3 S :»; oo a £ — Z, « £ fl fr3 tl s s "'&amp;b«4« Si x 3! ? 5 as X s-ai-S&amp;a* £ § Ilk!*} i x !•* J S'S'ii.sS 1 ' 2-=.SS32 -.2 * «- » OC X SSfS " S 1 5SS £ 5SS £ :S§3S ■♦XX £ go-- - = " :3 «i| x&gt;--" 5 i a - : P j • : !— s i : ;1 ;= ; : : : ; i Jj ■ ■ — y s -i ■ : : : | ■ « • S I - H : *1 r 1 i ; 1:1 T3 &lt; fa .'a - .■=■-■ ■I ■»: 51 k S I i i ■i : r * '• 2- ! : : : il« * Si III! lilllill Z - " a a 2 2 2 U-i j. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">XXVI FOUBTBEKTB AXXl'AL REPORT OF THE I t jit j 5 : : : : - . . . JJMliJ: jj J S X z 3 S « * t- fill *O — iC &lt;— V¥K S£ : z 5 j. o :| 8 : • o ■ • 5 • ■ 1 * .. ; — : — Ml J — I |™"» B :.:r .:.:: ISg I: !| I ■ H fe = ■ • • I •• • • X loll : : : I : : \ ■ ■ ■ ■ \ '■ s : : : : : U|i !i --f. ■ W:\W\l \\ \-\ IP'S : : :•== : i " : : ' : |s Jl ; ; ■&gt;. l ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ | • • • : • — t- ■ • ■ s 5 ■ : 5 : : : : I . : : : : ! - £ &gt; 11 I I : &gt; : i I : i : : i = £ r : : : = S . : S i| • jf i ■ : : : = : : :gf; i | :S |:11 : 1 : : d — ■ .iff ■ .^J an » g ■ = ' " ' ' C i jig! 1| 1 I |li si ! jB ?SNi?il, ilii! lal II I Ilii i=l^ 2 °pll nSO -&lt;au 'sfa&amp;.&amp;.fr, oOh OO 'n MOO i I </seg>
            <seg id="p027">KCRKTARV OF THE STATE BAHIIHQ BOARD 27 SOS* *- o 3 so 5 o •* X O ■» O t- O S. . c r: • ■ . . .t- t ■ ■ as • • • 1 : : .55 : : — — i &lt; § o K O P 8 : : : . '."o '■ *j e • Ml i I ; ii.l: £ : : : :gS siHiss II a - ss : 9 ••*••• ■ • ft" : l s ■ : I 1 1{ if « » i &lt; u . . 5"" % g J5 o o- 1 Hll&amp; all "5 M^JI 8 1 It I 5 a iliilr §i H B | -a -S3 § 3« t § £*- ?^S 2 2 J §i£ ill I Is 3 s Z Id - K • • • 1 \ii 1 l-li i s a a e o o o • • -a * a o : ■ :•« : 3 : 1 :J : M . . . £ * - * a : i S : j ii. S ! J!li : I 5 a :sg :a : : I S.aZ"S --S : : » ifiiill » </seg>
            <seg id="p028">xxviii KTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE z- I s : :g^ . : » ; § istrs] I g ; :g= ;;;;i ill : s: if : s - a ; lg g IS iMMilM ri rf i s B *l ■:;F";F : : ; ; ;i : : : :-:":» * as S§ :S : ;S SS : i : §g i : S is gS : 3 S£ ■ T • •* S9 ■« x * h ra •* • • s $■*•••—•■ e • s • -« • I® '•S « • -8 e»« r-55 ; p • ■ B MS • ■ -S ■ ■ B ■&amp; S~ W - ■ ■ -I" ■ • Ob 93 -?■ — ~* f-S S- :|S : :S 5 '. : : S : : - i&lt; s- :■ : ;« tf ■ * * a 1 SS2 S23§5§;i : § i §i§ § cjg^f-e g : j -o : g = ?i § SSS £S xSor,:* : : •§ : Ssi 3 bb Tl I we* r- g ="'--"=£■" g" '■"«* g : : : : x « i s "i c s - 0 is ; : * *- jj» ;i«-- r. = -r = — — i «e« ■• o o ac Xfi^ tr S n-o« » ■ ■ cao — — •.£ x L ~ — •»■ — 5i ■• t- o •» £ « ■ • S3» S » §c ' S£S'^ I |i 2 " i s" 0 ' 5 ! : -' &lt;" | 5 £- £ " S 1^ V- &lt;- ■ . . S» Isil • i i -| i • I 1 1 ; i ! i I if MM Il^Oft SI I i | i i i • i ia I* j i j i j ij if J : j ! • I j -; 1 ? - z &lt; fc»i3 i L : ::■::::: J :| : • • ■ : j y i i £ : - = : 5 3! : k f : a '■- '■ T_ ijii^iii 5 Mi Q t. X J= pll 21} ilii'Hi fliligi lliillf iHliill riJJJlilll Jill 3-i 2 3 2E s| S = = = JE53 sow &lt;- ij££o££ co&lt; cootsco J - • r z _ ; : i £_£ : : *s III 1 £= : 5 S '-e— 3 5 "5 e :2 ■ ac ■ a :J ■ c . be . c : i • c </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SECKETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 29 © r- x © © «o *-&lt; t^ ?» 3S 35 'T *O jO» »o « »c © w a go © x *^ »c r- «5 © x *c »c r- to X — © *C -V C9 00 C 09 HH CD £J 4? » * a •"» s Xl r ill m ■■■'■• X X * H X oj). : :.£ &amp; r Z ■Sgfl i I^J 5 a Wti- ia 2 ~ :-E-Ss S si i "■5 5 £ = * = 8 3 J v- SsS.*' 1 £ * x— x . Uutl ii foe!*} i I X « s ■ sililil = a iiiii^ if 3 B 5555 So s § i (s ■ SaSSa^ 1 22 z x '3 s&lt;s «■&gt; m &lt;23 5? c-x «a . " i £' SS o • S ■ • ' "l 8" I*"' §j S «' : r I * CD .'t- u 1 s t P Z : : . 5 . - .... -5 ■ i::J : | : I * 1 : - I i 1 ! : &gt;r « &gt; r M u ■ u • • • ~ m ■ ; : ;l , : T. : : :■ : i. '• ■ -"S '9 ■ \ • X s ~ • • • a • • ■ UK I gb I i -aS «■ : « S-r 3 af 5 . i &amp; a : |ll I s-tl-s'JS. : il i II &gt; ItJIbMH f|siii&amp;l « O O w S — • -. m W 31 "" "" mil iisl i ii ££2 " U. '^. ii. J- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 KolRTEENTH ANNUAL RKPOBT OF THE S a ;§ s§ .-s x X « t- B i£ »« — : • • £ :S £ ■ §££ I £ • * S §£§ I | 5~i ? ;| h i ij I* : 2 ; S ' N ' S * I :::::*: S : E N § g &gt; £ V- * SSS : SI - (g * - El » • iKb -. ■ ie S £: — . at S§g£ ■•*■&lt; i - j •" « = = I • «' tfj ' 3D «' .' oT se o — • "MS- :t * sa : it isTH i '_- f; X — y 5. *- ®-r^— • • •«— o' = BE -" - '. 5 » -r x _ os . . -. ?* Mb SJ" 5 K S &amp; • = - : : : ■! ■* : « b »- 3C i z ! 5 £ : : : 5 z £ *■ ■ is *• *■ * &lt; 2: r i~ Ti tir 1 -*'-?! «; «- *- 2 eS'SSS -X-T aX t~MX - Ujh s «e ■ ■':.= :: :::::::: c : : : : : : s?i I : : : -::!:: : R I H a ■ I ; : "5 - -' I : ! : : : : : : : : : : : IP** T. : : : : : : : : : :■= \ : : : : ». .z k h 1 2 : : .::.:::: 1 ::: : s \\ \% \ ■ ; : ; :i ; : : ; ISJ , :l: -&lt; ; R ■ --E ...... a 3 : e - &lt; B» -i : i : T ~P.4* II iff = (I |1 f I . I i « : ? if 3 A x x C i!^H2 iifni *1|li«3 fiilli^'s i||iJ|il - ill I! i III i I|1Hi!l|| IllSi a ■ s: s 1 1 : </seg>
            <seg id="p031">;KTARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 31 §£g§§ 5 S :$ :Sll52 § 2»^« © • :::: I : I j j | j j j :; ! 1 !M !.||! j : ji j j X -a z -2 S.2 f jjjNlj Sjjiji : * 1 X 111 ~ ■ :&amp;* : . ■ \ • I Hm ! ■a . . "~t3 • • x 5 5&amp; e S « ajQ § iiifis ,§ j |1Ji i|| I s iiiififii! - : :■■*■ I 11 I « •■•*» ■ 1 lisllil I 1 :f}illl|l » a H8.SS T XX «.2 B --5?r-' xx SSssS S f|}|l| E 1 Jill II a a u a - as k. J3^335 «-« § &lt; 5SS £ : jS5§ I $Sz C &lt; * »■» 00 50 ■ O ™~ *~" t~ **' ' • 00 O zt r: 5: "' ■ ■ ' O *c OS ■ o •* w - ■ ■ r - x t^ ■ o * iqt-a • ■ so ad I io" o eV ! ' — ?-. C* ?i ■* »a m t- a £ — -- a ♦ tr M s 1 : ::§&amp;:::: : : ; s ; i s • i ;5 is ; • ; i : i z * : = 5 . it :J I i K z 0 2 1 i i ij • : 1 : : : :| :| : : I S ; : i k : : : : j I : * : : -&lt; 5 a r. I M { J 1 H] 1 r 3 &lt; X tZ~ ' I a : i H t J 1 S-S§ . = i.2Z- : : : : S £ X «- S£-2| mm i ifiiiiiiiiJ 5 wni 1* -3-3 §3 £-2 3 £ h aaaa-c p ? p p Hill 3&lt;S3a S 5^c £££ /. - 5. a &amp; x -= » &lt;M &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p032">xxxii FOURTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE I s CD s §:::§;; •■■••■■ ■ : i ;5 • ; ill S 2 • j S : j S5 : : : : %t : : ' : : g§ : x in ■ . . . « . = 5 S:;s; : : : " i : : • : : : : : 9 Si S 5 I K I * *■ 5 5 R s ■ - — . x X' \ i: s_ C X 3-8 PI u ■ hi 0 B5 ss la I 5gi2S s " if ;*l &lt;at 5" i I j j Ss SS :8 g§ : : ; : : :1 : : : : : 5_ ' '. '. '. i*. ' .' . '. '. I :::::: ~ : : : : : : : : : : : : : 1 : : ':':'■ . ... l| :: ;:: : ::'? : ; : :: _7" ' C ****** a '* ■•• I II I tie ; ;ic I I jl liilli liiJiiiiHiiiilii 111 il Iziiz illi l^llll ; i_ ; 5 ■ 5 H * j i </seg>
            <seg id="p033">IE BANKING BOARD 33 — S :£S S : 5 _ : U_J !_ - &gt; I 1 &gt; * &lt; ■- « : - c ■ u . •••••■• E *| •• 2 :8 = = -3 x oS B c a " "£ S, ~3l 8 * * Hhiit c .2 « 'S o S ** Ilfld —"to 8 ifiy a 1 if-ii i -a— r" iiii I asa s 2£2 s J I ■ s ■ I s I J i" »-• •» OB I B » i S : -Si ■ - o • '"S ID ' ■ |li ! ] ■.a g S= * gs o d d d « g j«^ o 53 jo |:| I : ;S 5: 11 S 5 5 — . . ill % : ; :;:°5i: ! 4 : : : • : • . : a : - : :sS :,;s :g ®-2cS « © 3 illlllifl ? .- o&lt;S o et « d ftS j ■£ e -3 — c 3 e 3 5 = a </seg>
            <seg id="p034">XXXIV KUKTKKNIH ANNUAL REPORT OF THh IBS S|S S 2? : 85 81 IS- 1 ■ I p . = p is « 3_&gt; : « • : . • : - © : i 1 ?■ i "1 B £ 2 : - i m I . I - I 5 : IS $5 5,T5J - Is set- V?i ;:' m^m :s- jj • » • » J S ' &gt;% I stslss sses-fcei; sg 2 ig _JL- * L : : :| . :| :.:: :: :t : : : : : c S . - K 5 ; •J — • • • j 1 I: if = [ of i ||l ; jiill !■ J i! iff! If J?!i III 1 I •-"? j d ii L \\%Qn lilli^lj «ijj s|l! * . « £ £s laaea ioPjoUtt s=-St ■=£ £2£2S «£ o S O a5=5£ I I </seg>
            <seg id="p035">BECBETABY OF THE STATE BANKING BOAKK 35 ■» § :3S?:§ SS !§ r 'S2S £ t- ■» — 5 i -55 oe" ! "* 0» ri i r jo^ion £ * S : » S • * 3 !►&gt; : :■* z f S s 8 : * i m ni X s T. S"?_5 2 _ ; S £ &lt; x s?' 5 So E I »-°S u •», S 1 Ill MKBf » ■a 5 S -« X s n !■: a '• c S u *. ?S;J H i &lt; X 13 «!9 2 55 El -T s5 c» S:i IO '* IM «• * unen 1 a ■ a Z 1:1 H SB 2:s M r. 0 - w § :3 x /&lt;■', s ? •I UK). ■III! L. L. U u&gt; 3 lift ! I i-iiiiilli iiilir is H w 5 1 • ■■■* '■ ■■'■■ &lt; i 1! i I 1 1=1 ■S T3 J2 £ ; Sr5S :-: = = S £2£ </seg>
          
            <seg id="p036">STATEMENTS SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE 546 INCORPORATED , PRI- VATE AND SAVINGS BANKS IN THE STATE OF NEBRASKA AT THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS NOVEMBER 9, 1905. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">2 \bie State Bank Ch r No. 804. (Incorporated .1! u President I J 1. E President ashler Mat 1. l-a ■ Vi ihler STA1 i- WENT, NOVEMBER RESOURCES MAI 1I-ITIES I »«■■ and discounts p i I a 1 M Overdrafts, secured and un cured 0 : proll 421.10 Stocks. securltief&gt;, ju.u-ni. n claims, «t ual il^p' H..i. ■!- 4.494.54 4.150. 4S ■ Banking house furnllur fixtures real * Mat. u Current «xi"-n&gt;«-« and tax paid . . 64 Duo r Premium on U S ar, : banks and bank and I: r Cash Items Bills pays Due from national. »t» ate bank* ai Currency Tula I ♦ 36,7:4.2» Adams rh. Stjtif Hank of Adams No. 1. (Incnri. I. B Hnv J W it, Kil .'. n r ■r L1AI ITI Lutn ■ : paid 1 I...d k. I </seg>
            <seg id="p038">3 ) aahler mt ('ashler ABILITIES • Id 17.11 Ian. I privat T ABII-ITIt ss x Ainsworth The Bank of Ainsworth Incorporated Chart r M President 1 C A- Ban Vice-President | J. M. Hanna IT A EMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 19 RESOIRCES xans and discount!) )verdrafts, secured (1 profit Individual dep&lt; Judgrmen Tax sale cert Warrants t'ertli B;ti f :penses and nd Premluir Due from na private bai - 1 and I II nk. 17 Ainsworth The Citiz.-ns St;it*&gt; Bank Incorporated r. J"U' President II: M V President j 1104. 083. &lt;&lt; &lt;*apltal stork paid in •', 000.0* rter N&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p039">4 FOURTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE la BII.ITIE i ILITII State Bank of Alexandr arter No. 4. (Incorporated) Prwider ■ MENT XoVEMBEF LI A |M apitai Surplus fui. 1.1M.O t'ndlvlded profits Dividend* unpaid i liflcat Banking houne furniture an fixtures i real estate nt expenses and tax _ paid .......... . Due to n 1.17S.99 I' urn on V- S. and oth bonds and s«curttics banki* and and t tt»- banks and bai 4 • la and $M Thf All.-n State Hank I 1 W Mel STAT y MENT, NOVEMBER LIA1 iii'j diKcoun Current •- &gt; and nt banks and hank Loans and discounts : rafts, secured and un» Stocks, securities, J*d» claims, *■■ Individual &gt;■ check Chart. N 'rated Stork*. — twlti— . judnrfw-nt claim*, ati Banking h flxtur. ■- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">SECKETABY OF THE STATE BAXKIXG BOARD 5 Alma The Hank of Alma harter No. 7. (Incorporated) Shallenb«-rK- r Prt-j'Ment A. A Billing- \--i-tant Cashier ■r,. S Klent M C. Shal \«sl*tant Cash STATEMENT. NOVEMBER ATKMENT. NOVEMBER 9. RKSOfRCES LIABIU1 LIABILITIES . . . .H4S.9t4.14 Capital Mock paid in I Surplus fund . . paid ■ rl prof ■ unpaid ■ ' to . U7.99K. P Ba iinkinK house furniture and and f flit rfc ks landing 264. 5 »P Ktl A K74.ll antl prti P anks an x-i ea and J3 Hills payat.) r private banks and bank- 45 117.90 3.746.65 tf ■ • |X14 ST4.15 AlniH Tli*' Marian County Hank The Harlan County Hank iarter N rporated) porated) TV'lHlam Gaslin I "r- &gt; i-K it T \S i shier • ATEMENT, NoVKMKi; RESOURCES I-IAHII.ITII I ur»- ■ Be :: at&lt; B. ur Prt-mium on }'. S. and t Ii sta bankers eichang Ipecie 'urrer 46fi &lt;•_ SI </seg>
            <seg id="p041">6 )F Mr ILITIE 44« 4 ■j 4 177,117.44 ft A r II.ITIE 4.64K M 43.1 4 d The Farmen Mid Merchants H; Charter No. 602. (Incorporated! ' B. \ . STATEMENT. NOVEMBEF LI A RESOl'RCF 111.67 ■ :al stock paid in | I^oan* and ■ ' ■d an Surplus fund 547.31 : proflu judpm unpaid Indiv idual dep Demand certiflcat Time certift rt tried checks Cashier's checks ou - and tax _ paid ....... Due to nat Due to state banks and ba jm on I*. S. an bond* and *t- . Notes and b 1 Bills i itlonal, state and nits and bankers . 4.40 •■ - and items of exchan 1 ■ J77.U7.44 Amherst Farmers State Bank X (Incorporated) A C Dan President A T I. Hart STAT MENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1 RCES LIAE I^oanit mnd discount S 760. S6 Capital stock paid in I Surplus fund . . . ; ndivided profits ■ Dividends unpaid judRme claims, etc Individual deposits subject check Demand certificates of Banki nit hou&gt;-- furniture an Time certificates of dep fixture) 1.000.00 Certified checks real estat* Cashier's checks outstand Due to national bank Current expenses and tax* _ P .id ...... Due to state and priv Premium on I*. S an'. bond* and securities banks and banker; and bills re-dlsoounted items Bills payable ' n m national, state and private banks and bankers . fiKT. and items of exchange 354.96 4,008.98 $ 847.10 Total Other tu«t.&lt; Banking house f urn n u I flxtur. The 'hart </seg>
            <seg id="p042">7 Anselmo The Anselm State Bank .orated t tt-r N. 1&gt;1 I STATEMENT. XOVEMBEI: LIABILITIES RESOURCES paid in ....»'. I ai&gt;it jnd 145 (« |.r. unj [&gt; 4,(81 01 B. and certiflca de .1 ■ks outsta r i P «c 1 bank dlscoun 'H 477.07 The Farm rs State Bant Ansley t Charter X&lt;r si 4. (Ineorporat E Naweomk PtmMi STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9 'ashler Ca»hl«r ITATEMENT. N( VEMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES LIABILITIES RESOIT LIABILITIE Loans and discounts 1^ ipital stock paid in IT. 504. M Loans and discounts l v ipital stock paid In IT. 504. M Overdrafts, secured and Surplus fund . . Surplus fund 13 I'ndivided profits !&gt;ll.M Dividends unpaid . . n'lividual deposits aubj* I'ndivided profits 911. N Dividends unpaid Bond.~ 15.38*. H Demand certlficav it 985.00 BankinK house furniture and Time certificate^ 530 00 100.00 Certified check sanding nationa M state and private Premium nn I" S and banks and bank Notes and hills : Cash it&gt; Bills payab private hanks and bankers . 9.8M.2C xi-P U $25,315 58 I Total ♦ 25.315. 5» </seg>
            <seg id="p043">8 KTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF TH i 11 I ; &lt; t Arapahoe The Arajiahoe State Bank Chart No. D45. (Incorporated r XtmoH Patr.-- - President - Thos II Patterson President STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RCE8 LI API I Loans and d Overdrafts. ( ■■»|.]lal stork M fun cured 1V474 led p Stocks, securitl •is unp* Individual check . Banking hoUM- furnltu fixtures "f dep Current expenses and tax paid Due to national bank 14!. OS Due to state and Premium on 1'. ■. ant bonds and &gt;*■■ uriti, - banks and hank ■-s and bill* 37 Bills payable . Item Dae from national, state an private banks and bankers 4.164 IT. i and items of exchan 427 19 1-sufu! p:t[ 441 Arcadia Mate Bank of Arcdadia dent O. II h '.1 H ■ 1 ATKMf XT. NOVEMBE1 -iahii.it Loans and d 431.00 Capital si ■ Surplus fund Storks, securities, judic claims, et. Banking house furniture and I ■ national banks tte an I and boads and securities banks and ba and bl M Bills payable ■ii national, state and ate banks and bankers 14 ;.n 47 Checks and lt&lt; 4 DO Gold and IT. 51 1141 61.64 I Total t- r No. i ] &lt; Incoi i It. '- . ■ id .., &lt;:■ [■■ -its subj remand certificates of &lt; icates of d--p« outsti real «t»te ■ and lax </seg>
            <seg id="p044">9 KCRETAKV OF THE TATE BANKING BOARD Arlington The Arlinct State Bank &gt;n iter N&lt; Incorporated) as F President H w Presid STATEMENT. XOVEMBKK HESOl'RCES LIABILITIES 446.97 I Capital stock paid in Surplus fund . . 383.99 Undivided pr 1.383.99 Undivided pi 100.00 pf-nst-s and ta Dividends unpai Individual dei&gt; k ta unpa Kin*: house furniture and : Demand otrtlfl 200.00 Demand certlftV Tim*- certificates of .1 meat ■ hecks ■ ■ --. hecks oui h..k- outntandl pa Premium »n V. S. and other to national banks to national banks Du*- to state and pri hanks and bank - and bills ate and ik&gt; and bank ,te n.l bills bankers . 41.4BS .56 Bills payabl 498.56 HilN payal 774.71 n«.91 Total .3 The Farme KrnuTs State Bank State Bank Arnold Inforporat I tK'orpora 1 1 r &gt; S I -. r . STATEMENT S N'T N 1 RESOURCES LJABILJ1 I-IAniLITlR 116.644 644 71 capital stock paid in Surplus fund . . profits . . 941. unpaid . . an k paid rd urtd and rplua fu 43 500.00 to national banks state and pri tlonal bank ate and private banks and bani^ 045.18 Hills pay.i: i 646 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">10 Cashier nt Cashier t 1 l 49.4 154,379.4 Ashland The Farm, rs and Merchants Bank Charter N (Incorporated Wlggenhom STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1 l.IABIMTI Loans and discounts . ■ paid .?t'd and uni&gt; Judum «im. ■r Banklnc hou«e f urn it ur- flimres ■ tisea and I ■ K ,.-,.i : The Hank o£ Anhton I M PolKk) IT Pr k T xnVEMBEF 8TATEMI N RCKS LIABILITY I^oann and dliwoun I rplu. fund :re&lt;! k«. seroiitles. Jud alms, etc Demand certlBcat ales &lt; r asstls Banking house fu Aztures nt ezpensee and tarn national ba iite ai Premium on U. s. an&gt;! bond* and securiii. - and bankers ind bills re-di Bills payat 'arjaras 4 4 • President ) - *enhorn . . . . Pre'sident E A Wiggenhorn, Jr.. A - 'in national, atl lie banks and ba f and Item- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">11 The Atlanta State Bank Atlanta Charter Xo. TIT (1 (Incorporated) ■ashler Fulk L. J tFulk ; STATEMENT. MOTB RESOl'RCES i and dUcouii $33.4S«. -'I rafts, secured and », securities. Judgn '" ms, etc In&lt; ,nt Cmahlar Vice-Pp W. B. Fu MBEH 9. 190o LIABILITIES RESOURCE: apital stock paid In t urplus fund Loans and Overdrafts, secured and u cured ndlvided profits 1 IK mis unpaid ks, securit Individual deposits subject to 35,181.71 Bonds ■ • ' Bond Demand certificates of deposit IS. 413. II Other assets Other assets .... ™ me certificates of d Banking house fu fixtures Banking house furnitur. fixtures * : '" ■"&gt;' J; e 4 Certified checks ashler's checks outstanding Other real estat Other real estate 1" national bank Current expenses and taxes paid Premium on U. S. and other Current expenses and taxes L)u paid Due to state and prlv banks and bank- Premium on O. S and other ' bonds and securities £ und bills re-discounted bonds and securiti Bills payab Cash Items ... Due from national, state and private banks and bankers ., 23,482.0 Cash Items I&gt;ue from national, state and private banks and bankers ., 2J.4S2.O5 Checks and Items of ex&lt; Checks and Items of exchange ' Currency 1.141.00 HI Curren Coin 1.401.04 1.401.04 IC1. 983.il Total »«1.983.i- Auburn The Xemali The Xemaha ( 'ounty Bank Auburn Charter No. 638. ( Charter N Incorporate A M. BMTXM ..President W . Tte*-PrwM«it Presid Wn snt Cashier Fred Lami" - Vice-Pt STATEMENT, XOVE: EMBER 9, 1905 STATEMENT, N :&gt;v LIABILITIES RESOUI: RESOURCE Loans and discou: ' C* Capital stock paid in I Surplus fund discour rafts, secure* Overdrafts, secured and cured 1 divided proflts ■d Stocks, securities. Dl claims, etc . - In Dividends unpaid url Individual deposits ms, etc Other assets . r* Demand certificates of Time certificates of d. I Banking house furniture and lUtures 8.S45.4- 45.4 'titled checks Cashiers checks outstandin Due to national banks Other real estate Current expens. paid tax Due to state and prlvat banks and bankers ii 3.440 Premium on t and bills ■ Hills pays)'; bonds and securit Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . 80,048 Checks and Items of exchange 3,848 1 4.508 4,092 Sp-, $182,703 24 »t 4 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p047">12 FOIRTEEXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Aurora The Aurora State Bank i Incorporate Thomp»on President ■r ■r RESO: FAKII t H. Mflrates of deposit lf.4U.SS nd pr N( i The Rank rter No 4f 1 XI M er TATKMENT. NOVE1IBE LIAHIUTI Jxian* and rt r B, 14 Banklnir hou r#irttrt^«t 1 »4 . 10 Kiwi '*iaif . . I Ann fln | /-•■»,&lt; • k. ■ i rniw. and JJ^ outstanding Due to n«tlon.l ba D«e to n.tlon.1 ba um on U. S and JlnvT . *!•*'! ?' 'n on I urn on U. S and taLnk^ l» and ««c«rii v«t. 5 ' and semrlt -. ' v~Zl— • 5 bond" and p. it*»t. an&lt; 3 bills re ~ and national. Mat- and * payabl &gt;m national'. »iai^ and Payabl private banks and liant and Items of exchange l#f le banks am] and ltem« of •■mum. ♦ 114. S74 furni of Avoca (Vrtiflc ' </seg>
            <seg id="p048">KC'RETARY OF THE •TATE BANKING BOARD 13 The Bank of Axtell iarter No. 21 Incorporated) 'a*h i»-r mi Cashier M ATEMENT, Si VKMKER 9. 1M ROES LIABIUTIK 44 apltal .stock paid In fl2.OO0.OO jrplus fund ik . ■693. «4 rtified ks outstandtn, ua l bank and private bills re-di»count« 'I'll** Haiu*n»tt Hank 1TATEMENT. NOV MHER », 19 SSOl'RCS LIABILITIES Hanking bowM furnltur. Tim. checks out - ■ I bank te and private and hankers payabl inka and hankers </seg>
            <seg id="p049">14 Bancroft itizens R Htik of Bancroft Char !■ Incorporate*] Rice er i • sldent ?-Pre«ident O. Arthur Ba Assistant Cashier si ATKMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 19C MEXT, NOVEMBER 9, 1 RESOURCES 1 Loans and discounts »Hl k paid In .&lt; ."do OC I142.SS9.D: f.plth •und Overdrafts, secured and un» cured fund a*4 Stock*, securities, Judcmer rlaims, etc lual •l.-i Banking house furniture and fixtures . . Other real estate landing urrent expenses and tax P»"J -••••■ ■ to nation! •07. «4 Due t bank* and in'I bi] Bills payable state ar - bonds and securities Item 1 m national, state and private banks and banker mi of exchanger 74 Total ■ Bank of Barii Barneston The liank (Incorporated rporate^ President I ■ i - -istant Cashier 1ENT, NOVEMBER 9, 19 TATEMENT, N&lt; :&gt;v EMBER 9, 19f I.I UAH1UTIES Loan* and di pltal erdrafi &gt;nd un ' und •• • Stocks, iwurit.fi*. judcr Banking ,r Mflcate: ,.»..! k bonds and t - m national, ntate and )&gt;anki and banker ■34 n hand Total tu T i ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p050">15 ■r 0 0 4 * 48.883.44 4 t The C oninitMvial Ntatt* Hank harter No. 723. (Incorporated Pr J M. H Munfrlt STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19C RESOURCES LI A BII.ITll 1 d stock pa cl in jrplu-* fund ured ided i mis unpaid mand c^rtiflcat f dejj jrf taaki and hmnker }T Hills pa Hartley The State Hank of Hartley arter Xc irated ATEMEXT. X&lt;&gt; - I.I A BII.ITIh •c]i pa H. Banking house fun it *[ u </seg>
            <seg id="p051">16 4 t Eassett The State Bank of B Chan. (Incorporated J Ii Brayton E L Brayton Pr«-sld nt H J TATKM EXT. N( &gt; V KM I '. K I . RCE8 LIABILITIES Loan* and &gt;'. 134,350.67 ! Capital Mock paid ir pltal ■( ■ ilrafts, secured and unse- Surplus t. ; judgmen -**. f»fruritit-s- judicm. ■ unpaid - unpaid claims, etc A Boo.i- B u.N Other «»- ■ ;■■■:.,, ; inn, .11 &gt;ther assets LH-man Banking hou»* rurnilure and Tim - flxlu-- - r real ratal' Banking hou*« furniture and fixtures ■rtiflfd - a] estat urrt-nr exp^ttifx and tax to national t nal banks paid binks and b ks anil ban bond* and *»-curiti.-&gt; \ . - Hm i hill* bond* ar ..n&lt;t hilt Bin- pi I Du** from national. Mate ar national. Mate and - banks and bant Xf.lt j • banks and bank 11 •■xrhantr ka and itemt* of exrha- 4 BlSMtt Th.' ('oniiiicrcial Bank Th« Commercial Hank Charter arter N (Incorpor M J Lipm nt - N( »v [ : IABH.TTIES Lo&gt;»ii and discout nd discount!* paid mrm4 am! m rdraftR, secured and ur Banking ho Other real estat ■al estate Current expenses and i-Ttrrent expenses ann 1 ' tate and z I hanks and hank«&gt;r&gt; banks and i ■asjdt and n n.i pa m natioMa! • banki&gt; and banker - and itfni- </seg>
            <seg id="p052">17 THE STATE BANKING BOABD SECBETARY &lt;&gt;K Battle Creek The Battle Creek Valley Bank arter No. 27. (Incorpor H. r Cashier President J H \V mt Cashier \V STATEMENT. NOVEMBER KESOI LIABILITIES Xizs - 4.91 D •i « Demand ctTttflrai ■ 11 Due to national banks l&gt;u I: 4» t :i 1181. 098 it Battle Creek The Citizens State Hank 606. (Incorporated) : w STATEMENT, NOVEMBER KCE8 LIABILITIES (S a 44 1 I r&gt; IT 91 »4 91.48 J- </seg>
            <seg id="p053">18 d Assist IABILITIES i .id lit it-i k bank 4 n anker r ABIIJ Bayard The Bank of Bayard Ch arter No. 28. (Incorporate F. Durnal Prealdcnt F. E. Steam -President STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1 RESOURCES 1 Loan« and dJi Overdrawn, set ured and un "■red Surplus fund Undivided proll Stocks, securities. Judgment claims, en Dividend unpa Individual dep&lt; Demand eertint Banking- housr furnit . fixtures ■ rtiflcate Certified check Other real estat Cashier's chec Current expenses and tax* _ P«*i Due to nationa 4 I Due to sta banks and I and b Cash item Bills j.ayal Due from i . private hank* and l&gt;« (1 r 82 | Tota Bazile Mills The Bank of Bazile Mills Charter No. 636. (Incorporat ■• banks and bank* Checks and .t*m* Total 137,480.01 Capital stock paid ir Prt-miun and oth bonds and &gt;■ private banka and banker* . 1,440 rhu-kx and II </seg>
            <seg id="p054">19 Beatrice The Union State Bank Charter No. So Incorporated) H. Penner Penner . . ■ H- M'T Jacob K A H Ki President .r Vice-president Assistant Cashier STATEMENT, N&lt; IX i MBER 9. 1905 LIABILITIES RESOURCES Loan* and discounts $147,7*2.35 Loans and discounts 1147,7(2.35 Capital stock paid In J30.000.0O apltal stock paid In 130.000. 00 Surplus fund 3. 000. 00 Surplus fund 3. 000. 00 Overdrafts, secured and unse- Overdrafts, secured and un 1I6.SS8.73 Other a Demand certificates of deposit 4, 559. 11 Banking house furniture and fixtures me certificates of deposit . . 39,791. 97 rtified checks iler's checks outstanding 1,183. SI real estat ue to national bank urrent exj 4t&gt;.11 Due to state and private tanks and bankers 18,442. TV Premium on V. S. and other .ind bills re-discounted Bills payable uri nkers 4.40 private ban ange 4.4 34' : • 219,998.17 The First State Bank Beaver City Incorporated) Charter N Presld Smi 1 ";t * ?; ler M Vice-President W. C, F. Lumley Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. N )\ EMBER 9, 19 RESOURCE LIABILITIES apital stock paid In 120. 000.0* und 5,00« i profit^ 4.431.07 d leads unpaid eck . .. 18S.020.1S • Demand certificates of deposit 49.413.S7 me certificates of deposit .. 30,943.47 Banking house furniture and lime cert fixtures i 'ashl- ending ■i taxes Due to national bank tnd private r r banker and Mils re-discounted Bills payat 4 cured 3,231.80 Undivided profits C.09t.tf ocks, securities. Judgments, Dividends unpaid •»».»• claims, warrants, etc .... 6,282.34 Individual deposits subject to ulual •: ieet to </seg>
            <seg id="p055">20 Beaver Crossing The State Bank of Beaver Crossing Charter No S3. (Incorporated President M W Wa T. H I ::; resident STATEMENT N LIABILITIES Lo*na and Ait- 4.443.04 Capital stuck paid Surplus fund . . . . • •t • • Jx rr/lrm.ft*, secured and ut cured • I I'ndivided profit Dividends unpai • • Stacks, mcu rlalms, et. Indlvldi h*r amt P Banking hou« fiirnni fl»tur- - 'ertined Ii Oth*r real eKiG Da* tr '•&lt;t tax* paid liu. banks Beaver Crossing The Citizens State Bank Charter No. 8 Incorp&lt; OVEMBER LIABILITIES -. - . Banking hou Bltu. Otl.er r 149. 63 Premiui *■ an tllf an payat sankfi and bank* i ■ k&gt; an Lo&amp;na and &lt;Ii-&lt; iftS, f*-' &gt;rplua fun </seg>
            <seg id="p056">21 . nt Cashier LIABILITIES "apital stock paid in . . . fund ,ck paid in S 1.-.2.00 91«.47 Dividend! unpaid Individual deposits Individual deposits saoject to , h..-k I2.4j!.1S i! 12.529. •» of depo 8.5SJ.4" landing banks ml bills r - vable ... A %te Bank ' (Incorporated) In q,, m , t President Ira E. WtlllaaH ...Cashier P C K™k \ ice-President Chas. E. M, , ! -tant Cashier Ira E. William- Chas. E. Mea-1 ATKMKNT. N VEM1 BHBKR I, LIAB1LITIE: LIABILITIES KESOl'RC ns and discounts $100.121. J3 Capital stock paid in $30.000. M Capital stock paid in . Surplus fund ... lrpius fund un Undivided profits . da unpaid Individual deposits subject Demand certificates of dep&lt; t deposit » Hanking house furniture and tel of deposit rheck out.«tandinc utstand x Due to state Ml banks and bank- nil private Premium on U. S. and other W__&gt;la nr.,i BAI'ltritfea Notes at discounted i securiti Bills pit ■ Due from id private banks and bank Checks and itema of exchange Cold and other coin 4.1»«.4O SI </seg>
            <seg id="p057">22 Cashier 0 47.41 4 0 Belden The Belden Bank Charter No. 498. (Incorporated Clark Knap resident Chan. L Be mark nt I. Beaty Asslstan STATEMENT MBER 9, 19( RESOURCES LIABILITIES 87 I Capital stock paid In S Overdrafts, secured and un cured Surplus fund nJivlded profits Stocks, securities. Judgmen claims, etc Dividends unpaid Individual deposits sub check Other assets Demand certificates of deposit ..'....." Time certificates of deposit . . 24, 1S7.M Banking house furniture and fixtures 4 Certified checks estate 951 II Cashier's checks outstand , Due to national banks . . . , Current expenses and taxes paid 1.0 Due to state and p banks and bankers . Premium on U. P. and other bonds and secur- Notes and bill Cash Items Bills payable m national, state and private banks and bankers . 6.465 Tl K. Andre President O. W. Andrews Vice-Presldeni Spencer Owen . . STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 19 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts f 7C Overdrafts, secured and urn Surplus fund cored ... «T0 47 Undivided profits Dividends unpaid Individual deposits su Stocks, securities, Judgment claims, etc check Other assets Demand certificates of deposit King house furniture and ures . Time certificates of deposit . . 1 »1 estat Current expenses and taxes — •-- - ~u*.*.ms UULBllUUiUI Due to national banks . . . SI Due to state and private banks and bankers Notes and bills re-dlscounted Premium on V. S. and other bonds and securities Cash Items Bills payable Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . 6.830 Ot 63 Checks and Items of exchange 342 Cut 4,338 i» 194.0 74 | Tot. Loans and discour . $ee 1&gt; Capital stock paid 00 Certifled checks Cashler'i checks outstanding </seg>
            <seg id="p058">23 The Bank of Bellwood Bellwood Charter No. (Incorporated) D. Bell President J Assistant Cashier Hattle I Yiee-Presldent asper S. B&lt; STATEMENT. N( )V F MBER 9, 1903 RESOURCES LIABILITIES •apital stock paid In 110,000. ** urplus fund • (63,940 icounts rdrafts, secured and unse ired S S« 961.99 Undivided profits Dividends unpaid ks, securities. Judgment Individual deposits subject to check 57,209. if Demand certificates of deposit 4-l.S5T.St Time certificates of deposit Kni house furniture and .». LtM.M Certified checks ashler's checks outstanding Due to national banks nses and tax Due to state and private banks and bankers 401! Premium on U. S. and url Bills payabl I- banks and bankers . 42, 194. SI nd items of exchange Oeo W W President President Ralph ashler -rant Cashier Le STATEMENT. N VEMBE1 LIABILITIES RESOURCE S49.156.49 'apital stock paid in I -.T.00.*4&gt; ured and irplus fund 1 ndivided profit Dividends unpaid Individual deposits subject to heck 3S.91J.H Demand certificates of deposit 11 Other a Time certificates of deposit . . 6.53K.M Banking house furniture and Certified check! fix 4.15C checks outstanding Due to national banks Current expenses ana tax paid 6 Due to state and priva banks and banker* Premiutai on I*. S. and other bonds and securities Notes and bills re-dls. Bills payabl Cash Items Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . 17 Checks and items of excTiangf 40 »76.r,is Notes and bills re-ilisoounted </seg>
            <seg id="p059">24 Benedict The Bank of Benedict Charter No 3 (Incorporate 1. Wlghtms President President s TATEMEXT. NC DVEMBEJ •L'RCB LIABILITIKS Low and discou Capital stock ] Surplus fund 1'ndivided profi Dividends unpa Individual depc IM«-rdraft», as* M-cur xt Due to national bank* ite and j ] ;im on banks Bills pay I 84.(2 44 647. 3» The Bank .f Benkelmai Charter No Incorpor* President W it. Wolf \ ice-President m. a. noil . . Cashier F R Walker Asslstant'caahler NT. NC )VE.MBER 9 RESOURCES LIABILITIES loans and d "4 pita] stock CG J ■ it depo k 71.124. •* nd certificates of deposit 10.700.0* Banking; house furmu. fixtures rtlflcates of de 14 Certified check real estate Cashiers checks outstanding 1.482.45 -it expenses and taxe Due to national bank 40. 5« Due to and p in on I', s. and bonds and secur banks and bankers Notes and bills re-dis. Bills payable Cash items 01 ■from national, state and fate banks and ha: 30 - and Items of exchange 1 f other banks, gold and ■ r certificates 00 1.911.25 $127.452. 01 ■ ■ d and mm claims, etc . </seg>
            <seg id="p060">25 The Citizens Bank Charter No. 40 rated) •W EKt ..President H. 11 Cashier .-*&gt;?£... '. i^.-Pr«md«nt , -tant CuhW Presld John P ATEMENT, N VEMBEI LIABILITIES RESOURCES l:;.uoo.o. I 1.3,-,. 00 SI nds unpaid k». ,-, ' Individual deposits subject 4.S04.»* » I17.M * »iher assets Banking house furniture and u Other real estate and taxes paid Mtl.M Premium on U. S ami '"ks and I and secur, Cash Items Bill* paya&gt;- Bil l&gt;ue from national private banks and bant Krom national ate banks and I... Checks and items of wxcTiangr id Items of *x Gold coin Currency and silver - «T3.0« r Tota) ltd i i &lt;■■■ TMal 10. 4» Bennington The Mangold i: Glandt Hank Charter No 41. (Incorporated) Mangold !hMV I Trf Axxlstant Ca»hl«r Mary Man ATEMENT, N VEMBER 9, 19 LIABILITIES Loans and dis.-oun' 1 Capital stock paid in tl ?-2»S'!2 Surplus fund . .. 4.300.04) rdra :ks, securiti unpaid subject to 68.737. 41 lm B Demand certificates of deposit T Banking house * Vurnitur- I Time certificates of deposit . . «1 urnit Ttlfled check Cashier's checks outstanding 17,919. &gt;• Other real Due to national bank urrent exj Ed and .nut ■»« »n d private i,,rr. nr, tt s and banks and bank. 141. M paid and in Premium on U. 8. and banks and bankers iU-rf. « n rt unii Notes and bills re-discnunted bonds and secur Bills payabl Cur from nation . private banks and bar •k. and item silver and currency Fractional coins |1«»,«4 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">26 BILITIB 4.524.04 lep •r 1LIT11 4 ank and pr kers . . di 5 The Bank of Benson Charter No. 803. (Incorporated Jan A H WulfT President &lt; - ha» A Tr»c President v STAT CT. NOVEMBEI LI A Loans and discounts Surplus fund Overdrafts, secured ar. Undivided prod Stocks, securities, ju.l Dividends unpaid Individual depos check Demand certlftcat Banklnc house furnltur fixtures Time certificate ertifled check 'ashler's check Due to national t expen 4 8. it I r* ue to state Pr. nnum on U. S. and oth bonds and serur ' — banks and b T Notes and Cuk items Bills payabl Krom national. Mate am ate banks and bsu b and Tin- Hank of Berlin President I President | I I Hillm \ STATF KMBEF LIA1 s profits ■ ■ nds unpaid ujai deposits sut I certificates of ti«T Bankfnc house furnitu rtlficates of d&lt; Ttifled check: - checks outstandi to national fa Due to state Kum on D. R. and other Is and securities banks and ban) Notes and bills r Bills payable ... Ca»h items Krom national, state and ate banks and banker* . ■ and itema of exchange 4 14 T I Tota 141.(41.31 Capital stock i Charter No 42 (Incorporated) Loans and •: &gt;*cured and 14 &lt; -i»i.it ;•: itock paid r».l «t.te \pen«ea and tax </seg>
            <seg id="p062">27 Bert rand The First State Bank (Incorporated) Cashier PreMd C C Gibbons ...President Vice-President Assistant Cashier )VEMBER 9. 1 STATEMENT, X LIABILITIE RESOURCES apital stock paid In II 8. 000.0* 194.411.08 Loans and discount Surplus fund K [rafts, secured and uns fd Undivided prc Dividends unpaid Stocks, securities. Judgment Individual deposits subject claims, etc 67 check Demand certificates of deposit T4,SS4.»» Other assets Time certificates of deposit r-ertlfled checks Banking house furniture and fixtures 00 checks outstanding Other real estate Due to national banks .... Due to state and prlva Current expenses and tax 1,047.94 banks and bankers 3i.M Premium on U. S. and other bonds and securities and bills re-dlscounted Cash Items 44 Bills payab Due from national, state anc private banks and bankers . 75.420.4 Checks and Items of exchange 785.3 M 18C.71S.7S The First State Bank Bethany (Incorporated Charter N R Fuller McCoy Pr Hur VIce-Presldent ,nt Cashier EMBER 9, 19'T. STATEMENT, NC :&gt;v RESOURCES LIABILITIES •5,000.00 113.17 'apital stock paid In urplus fund Loans and discount ured and unse T'ndlvided profits Dividends unpaid S. urltles, judgmen Individual deposits subject rr check 9.91.. M Demand certificates of deposit ;.02«.55 Time certificates of deposit . . 1.H0.7J Certified checks Ot.er a Fixtures 484.(0 Other real esta Cashiers checks outstanding Due to national banks Current expenses and tax _ P«'i •••• •••• -■••■ 416.44 Premium on 1' S and other bonds and securities Due to state and private banks and bankers Notes and bills re-discounted Bills payable » . . . Cash Items Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . 2,084 Checks and items of exchange 549 137.90 ll"8.79« Charter No. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">28 Tlif Exchange Bank of Bladen ■ ■rated) Charter Hall rashler •B Hall I'" 11 Casfcl« L Hall H" 11 • -i«tant CuhH -i«tant Cashlei STATKME NT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 ■!"RCh LIABILITI F I»an&gt; and dlscoum- *4« apltal stock paid lin.nnn 00 1 and u ■ I nda unp; rities, judsni i.il d?f] 4 Demand ■ ■ mfl. at o Banklnt- - - and tax* Due to Mat.- and p V- tier ,nker» 1,««9.J4 | 4 n hanc III SS8.&amp;: I Bladen Tha State Bank of Bladen The - tik of Bli Charter x &gt; Incorporated i Chart (Incnrj i ... ■. : ■TA1 XIHER 9. 1905. STATEMI NT. NOVKMHEI RESOT'I:' I.IABILI I.IABILITI U»n and discounts $11 080 55 Overdrn ured an 493 65 ft unpaid Stocks. securities. Judgments, unpaid . . . •eeurlties, judgn, .al deposits iu : ' n1ual deposits sul Otksr asx taa nf 4 Banklnir hous« furniture and :-.«8&gt;.M - real estate . . . ■ nses and lo national banks ndlr 231.41 Due to atate and I and other bonds and sc^utitle* and other banks and bankers banks and banker! bonds and securities i and bills re-dli and b Cash Items Bill* payalil&lt;- and and k- and hankers «,10&lt; * . » Ti *r • 3.170. 1J t.M I K3.S16 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">29 The Uhiir State Bank (Incorporated) Charter No. 4 President .\ Schmidt ■ashi-r \V Kr tnt Cashier A 1- II Vice-President STATEMENT, N AEMBER 9, 1 LIABILITIES RESOlKCr apltal stock paid in i • »• Loans and discounts *! verdrafls, secured and i, .. tu» :o.j«; 367.41 urt- unpaid ■s subject to 17O.7C1.OS U it 10.992.00 .lien ..f deposit . . 166, 030. is it 10.992.00 166, 030. 41 landing binding . . •r ■■■I private paid Prtmii nks and b;t:... nd bills re poyabl p f 4 6J The Banking I In hartor N ■ &gt;rateii • F. M. Cast«tter Presided Mrs. H M Castetter ....Vice-president 52SS TATEMEXT. XOVEMI RESOURCES I.IAHII.ITIES Loans and il ii Br ■ standing 1 nal banks nd f 15.401 N ' - .( Due from nation private banks a id item </seg>
            <seg id="p065">30 ilstant Cashier E oo « ■r * 4 ii 4 0 The Citizens State Bank Charter No. 797. (Incorporated) ■ H Mattlu.&gt;ni Maiil.i- President I). Z. Mummer li : ■ A STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 190 RESOURCES LIABILITI Loasjs and discount I 1.173.03 Capital stock paid In 150.004. M Overdrafts, secured and un» cured Surplus fund •t Undivided proflts (.100. &gt;• Stocks, securities. Judsment claims, etc . Dividends unpaid individual deposits subject to JO.080.00 check ■ «S,95«.li Demand certificates of deposit 15I.M 5£ heck Banklns house furniture and fixtures . . Time certificates of deposit . . 48,445. M «4.0t Certified checks ashler's checks outstand Current expenses and tax _P-«» Due to national bank. ■ and other bonds and securities Bills payable Dae from national. Mat* and M«.M IT '.it Hi Bil nickel* and 14 Bloomfield The Farmers and Merchant Bank Char r No. 48. (Incorporated) 8 Baunders Burro r 're: ident E. H. Ma President STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOURCES LIABILITII Loans and discoan t : and un Undivided pr judrir claimB, et - -ji- Hank. tig house fu: 'i t expenses and ta x ional banks Bills pays bonds and m national, Htate and - and items of exchange S al Due to state and pri banks and bankers . . ind bills re-dlscou .1 stock is fund nda unp ial del </seg>
            <seg id="p066">31 Bloomfield The Citizens State Bank Charter No. 538 (Incorporated) President F H. Crahan Wm. Barge . . Cashier Edward Renard G H Renard Vice-Prealdent ant CuhMr STATEMENT. N( )V EMBER 9. 19 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discount $S9 t 64« till apital stock pakl - "0.00 Surplus fund . . . il 00.00 I'ndivided profits Individual deposits nut) Banking house furniture and fixtures Time certificates of deposit . . 37 Certified ch» ■ 1'ashier's checks' outstanding . . &gt;ther real estat urrent expenses and tax Due to national banks 339.lt i Premium on I*. S and other bonds and securities banks and ba and bills mi Bills payable m national, state and private banks and bankers 4 ks and items of exchang Si SI 9 ". 1 ii &amp;1 Bloomington Blooming Charter No j B M H. Waldo M STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1 RES&lt;i LIABILITIES iscounts |149,04«.16 Capital stork paid assets I ■ Barking house furniture and ".98V. 70 r "S and taxes privat Bills payab nd ks and bankers . 35.294 k xt hang I200.C48 B rafts, secured and unst Jd s, securities, judgreient ms, etc assets . ■ ■ Dividends unpaid I&gt;emand certiflcat Due to state and pri i orated) Crafts, secured and unse- I ■d . . . 294.95 I !. securities. Judgi: inpaid ms, etc ... Individual deposits i assets </seg>
            <seg id="p067">32 r itant Cashier E t t « 4 a t4 Cashier Cashier 4 % 1.14 Blue HUl The Commercial Bank Charter No. 8«8. (Incorporated) M McBride Uoll President E. McBride VIce-President A STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES LJABILITI 1 •■»■ and discount I &gt;18.:» Capital stock paid in Overdrafts, secured and un&gt; cured Surplus fund Vndivlded profl Stocks, securities. Judgme claims, etc ■iual deposits sub Other asset i (Iflcat Banklnc house furniture ant; fixture* Time certificates of dep ertlfled check Other real estate 'ashier's checks outstandin Current expenses and taxe _ P«I&lt;J Due to national bank Due to state and pr Premium on U. S aj bonds and secur ■ . .ank&gt; and banker and bills re-discounted Cash Items Due from national, state an banks and bankers v hanice Currency Fractional silver, nickels an&lt; H«. 019.^0 I Tota Blue Springs The Blue Springs State Bank Charter N (Incorporated Black Vlce-Pr dent Bills i STATKMEXT. NOVKMBEB RESOUK LIABILITIE Lf.»n« and discoui . - , . iraft». neoured and ui n ... ■ Stork". IWUr - rabj'eci isisz r, h '"0.00 (&gt;rtin..,i checks ur P°»" X^L..™ ««*te ... I'ashJers checks outstand Current eipeiw and taxe* to national bank, •*_**^ TIT. 74 Due to state and t.riv Z?'? m °" C S aIld b « nl " and bankers m national, atate and it« banks and bankers . 22,119.81 and Items of rxchan*. ■ .:■■ end discounts CU. secured and un ■♦curi: h etc ' i&lt;ea«es and taxes I ■ bond* and seruritiF&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p068">33 The Boelus Si ate Bank r Nc Incorporated) Cashln taut Cashier Presid X ATEMENT. N"&lt; V EMBE1 LIABILITIES H'RCI mock paid in 110,000.0* fund ■ 10,000.0* $45.84 4,»7«.«* unpaid il deposit! subject to 25.37«.51 -it 2,114. 49 pmand i -It 2,114.4* .. 18.040.0* bank state and private 4 69. 4!i I nks and bankers :.«38.:4 re-discnunted Bills payable »7!,843.77 The Boom Baiil int Ca»hl«r ATEMENT, N&lt; VEMBER LIABILITIES J6.240.00 Surplus fum •i!:» dual d*T 8.424. T» 122 . 4ft M 46 59 1.S41.S7 iink </seg>
            <seg id="p069">34 r i 4 I 44 74 &lt; ii ii I lr • The State Bank of Bradshaw Bradshaw hart T llncorporat I i f Him— Ident T«- WlKhtman STATEMK XT. NOVEMBER ». 1» LIABILIT 1111 1 4.4« Oapltal stock paic f #■■■ and : Overdraft*. i*«-i-ure&lt;l and un end h fund • l profit 1- unpa Stocks. Mfur.'i-- ju-linnt-n aA*eta I iflratv Kins h'.u— furniiur. ■ f d«-j&gt; Current eip^ni* to national hanks p^d Premium on bonds and - banks and banker and hills r payabl ■ ale l«nk&gt; and ha '. 4 » liHiik of Brmdv The 11 ( Ii Charter N .1 H h I 'resident \\ W u 'r r NT N&lt; IVE1IBBR L1AKK.I • rdrafti&gt;. »&lt;- ( ured and ur U I • urr»r Premium or I'.i uk- and hank- ■ti natt&lt;*ri y.s and &gt;'MIlk* </seg>
            <seg id="p070">35 Brainard charter No. 6t. (Incorporated! K Smith ■ashler President A Mi'KnlK mt Caahler STATEMENT. NC )V EMBER MAHIUTIEi KKSlll Capital sti'rk paid $148.117. 88 Surplu ■« fund ured I'ndiviil- 1*1 M 17 Dividend* unpaid Individual ■■ SC.00 hankt-r 4 The Intimation al Stiit.- Hank Brewster Charter N s Iniiirpi&gt;rated) President President AIKMENT. NOVEHBI 1.IAB1LIT1E $24,477 50 I Capital Mock 1 1 and .. hurpiu- runa 86.53 I nili\ Mini iir..H Dividends unpaid ■ck «. Tim. nal bank Lank Bills pa 4 1.(0 yn The Hank of Brainard ■ Demand certificates of deposit Sf.Sll.ll Tim*' twrtMcataa ' 474 *• «&gt;rtln- &lt;*ashi&gt; i Due I" national bank Ht&amp;te ji t&gt;ank» and t&gt;ank.-rs ;m.l hills . Bills | Surplu- fund </seg>
            <seg id="p071">36 II. ITU Bridgeport Tin- Bridgeport Hank rter Xc Incorporated President Marl, President IT SIEXT, NOVEMBEF RESl .IA1 I^»«nv and di- jr.: pit. I s: Ovrrdmn- - olmli' m B.T..1- I'- man rtlflcatea Bank i: - Other r- paid national be Pr«-n; £. ah bonds ar, ' and bills re ■ i- bankr and bar Bridgeport Til,- Valley Bute Bank Chart Wo. 696. I i Homer K 1 A. lio TATF MENT. NOVEMBER 9. IS RESOURCE LI A HI l*tw and i; ■ Judc a banks and bank [•••n'l&gt; and I 'itlonal. sta ■ pri\ ■ r exet 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">37 The Bristow State Bank M« ;ment. n&lt; ABILITIES 2 17 IM.M 1 8.344 -SS U nk I &lt;l Exchange Banl The Amer Biistow IT. V KM UK It [WTKMK.NT. N LIABILITIES KESOIRCKS -i 'apit t nil 52.92 (I 40 landing other real estate ««.4O Ca Cvrrlm expense- and ta« 8 to national t.ank Ed interest ■-. 1.903.94 i n*- and private uuTon U. S and other smk..-* an*l banken e-di -^-r&gt;unt*d and securities " ' Bill" P a &gt;"» Bills 1 itate and r&gt;m national, state and urtvate banks and bankers . 1.(61. Of 1 nd J". </seg>
            <seg id="p073">38 » « S : 0 4 The Bank of Brock X a. 59. ilt&gt; M II.t IT •oVEMHKH IA U1I.ITIKS •• Capital ««1 Loans and d m.r.ir.- afif* un Surplus run ndrmrr . )»i 11. - Dtvtd«ndfl unpaid 0«l. 2i Individual i1pp&lt; ■ itankinit h..u- turrn - nxtur- I to natlnnal bank* plate and Charter No. 540. &lt; Incorporated) F..rd J at KimU-rliri« Pr»«ld»nt I K ■ Ass TATKMKNT NOVEMBER ». 19 MABILIT1E and discounts . $181 l and un»- Surplus fund 1.88 I'ndlvldi-d proSta. n KtiM-kn. aecurltl^H. judicmfnt 1 •] \ i'l.ri'1- unpaid ■Mil Dfmanil cerllfl'-ai- Tin. l-po«lt 00 Ortlflc: Banktnir houft* furniture and nutmandtn national hank* r»al »atat» i -ipenitMi and tax -late and prlv Premium m i- and twcuri* i ■ - hank* and t.ank.r ■nd hiiN r*-'dti»coant^d Duf from n«i tonal. «tat ■ 4 4.«4 BUI * pavahl Mf i-MTiki- aid Unkrr- C4 4 IS r\f\ RCE8 .9.03 i 'a. pi i m I Mtock paid Individual depo: </seg>
            <seg id="p074">39 State Hank Broken Bow The Security ( Incorporated arter N Jules Hau TATEMENT. N V KM HER 9. 19 LIABILITIE KCES k paid In »1 ■• Surplus fund iritles. judgments, Demand &lt;frtl(lf«te» of 'I ins linuxf furniture and ivrtifled checks .riding national banks nd tax itate and private hanks and banker - ind hills ' nd other urlti k» and bankers inge *0* $64.7 in Hank Bruning The &lt;i. mi (Incorporate.) Charter No. 61 Presld \V H "Si &gt; --.-tant rashlar Famuel Fill Prank Brow Vive-Pre»ident &gt;V EMBER », ITATEMENT. N LIABILITIES RESOURCES '"apital stock paid in $20,0©«.*J -.an* and dlarounta I77.91«.« rafts secured and un Surplus fund l.«21.1« 1 1'ndlvided profits red Banking house furniture and Individual deposits subject to 1&gt; check fixtures Demand certificates of deposit 22.57H.M ram national, mate and Time &lt;f deposit. . 22.49*. 77 private banks and bankers 16.S73.12 Checks anditemsof exchange 1.113.84 „..« J.0»2.00 Current «J Nickels ant 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">40 Bruno The Bruno State Bank Charter No &lt;M ( Incorporated) I President Asstfatant r«. W. J. Zeman an RESOURCES LIABILITIES MMM s E Surplus fund » r » d . ,■■■■ ««.«! Undivided profit inn house furniture and Individual depo flxtum . 2.000.0' »uojct Current (ipcuM and mand certlflcatMof d'e'p I&gt;, n*^, ■■ 529.00 and lime certillcatea of P r '&gt;»' 1«.I«».5T - «»■»« ,er,inc., es of d« hanka and hank-r- 16. Its °"«* ■ 4.458.28 t.tr.y S73.59I.O To In n n •» Brunswick Brunswick The Brunswick Bank Tlie Brunswick Bank Charter No. 697. (Incorporated) Charter N 697. (Incorporated) • l(&gt;lb«rt [ C Haltwri w Hammond Pr d A W Ha mm F. A. McCornark I — Prestd p . A. McComack \ --President M | ■ nt A STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905. STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 19 RESOURCES LIABILITIES RESOURCE LIABILITIES Loan&gt; and di «an. and diacounta f32.155.10 &lt;"apital stock paid In t&gt;2,lii 10 Capital stock paid In $( Undivided profits ooo oo .(ft.-, secured and un - •wured ********** •«■«»■«&gt; »nd un- Tndivlded profit! ... ,**tl? 1 "•"■■• 54«.»5 Individual deposits subject tanking house furniture and check ...._..". Kng house furniture and re» .... !4 64 000 90 Time certllicates of deposit .! 14 1.1 Current tip™™ and taz&lt; 90 D»« from national. Mate and privat* banks and bankers . 7. til. 14 Clwcks and item* of exchange 1,310 00 2,5S«.»5 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">41 Bank &lt;&gt;f Burchard Burchard Th. Bi Incorporate rter K&lt; ■J H P. i S&lt; iVEMBEI VKMBEK I.I. I.I A HI1.1TIB RESOURCE S5S.8S Capital I Sun 5 088. 2( Indtvided prnfli Individual Banking house furniture and 912 . 00 4 .850.00 Den Currents; &lt;* ' Premiums on I". S. and bondi. etc IM.M Due from nation private banks and .081.93 .3(0.13 -man American Bai No. 66. (Incorporate. resident " ; .1 K resident 3TA1 f MENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1 5NT. NOVEMBER 9, 19 ABILITIE LI LI RESOURCE J29. 309. 9» Capital stock paid in H 9.309.91 Capital plus fun&lt;l .02 Undivided pro n virtual dev dl ured and un Individual d Banking house furnltur 3S:.«4 2.347. IS check Demand certlfli 533.14 Time certiflcat fixtures Current expenses and taxe Demand certificates of deposit 2.4U.J* ,f deposit. . 10.2«J.»» paid Due from national, state and banks and banker 1.(13,22 35.(7 1 private banks and bankers. Checks and Items of exchange 4.530.(5 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">42 Tlh 4 &lt; T A It fir&gt;.000.M 430. M « 41 12.8t7.lt landlni; 1.140. 4* ■« Total The ( iti/.-ns Stat.- Bank STATEME :NT. NOVEMBER 9. 19 RESOfRfES LIABIIJT l-oan« and dlarouata |41 Overdrafta. »&lt;-rur»d and un- ««.«! I lapltal «ti&gt;rk paid In I'ndlvlded profits ♦ 47 II Individual drpoalta aut H.nkinr houac furnliurr and tatarvi ■ '•""&lt; Tlmi- i • TtKli'aira of Ae] 4»ft.OO "'ashlars checks outst - real •-■tat» Cmrrrnt expenaM and taxea national bank K. 144 14 14* . 00 items Kram national, state and ate banks and bankers (, 119.0? 0*2. C4 121.40 Checks and Items of exchange 1 Charter No. «9. &lt; Incorporated Will D Forties I • Jum Forbes \ioe-Prmldeni j a Mc'ljiuifhll W. W. Rob»n vi. f- President Burwell Tfce BarweU State Bank Incorporated) »Ballr&gt; STAi MUKMIIKI KESdl'H I I.IABIL1 Pmd dlao 1 I'apimi Maek paid in IT houw furnltur*- and I'm1tvid*-d profit Mtl.tt Individual drpoiilta «u MM and tax.-* 1 77 . 15 &gt;m national. Mat*- and If banka and hanker* 3.s«? I! and It. . n««- </seg>
            <seg id="p078">43 The Bank of oyd County &lt; Incorporated) nt H. A. Olerl. I Barnu 1'resid ATEMENT N( V EMBER ». 1905 LIABILITIES RESOCRCES $(6,439.13 ! u 570.45 I l"ndividt-a pr ii k lul it 6,1 4S :ud 45S xchan 4 J10S.S17 The Farmers an&lt; Merchants Bant rter N Preside 'anhlc ,nt Cashier M Vice- President VEMBER 9. 1906 ATEMENT. N LIABILITIES RESOURCE pital stock paid in $7,500.00 MM rdraft Surplus fund ndlvlded profit 41 flxtur Individual deposits sul I4.*M „, check Pus fr Id </seg>
            <seg id="p079">44 The ( 'aim State Kniik MUKH I.IAHIUTIKS 4 Total Tin' Seven Valleys Bank [ncorpi Win R. Bi STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905 LIABILITIES Surnlii Surplus f ""•';'"' I..ma,,,l »•».!« </seg>
            <seg id="p080">45 Callaway The Callawav Statf Bank Cuhler ;ant Cannier P INT NOVEMBER RCES LIABILITIES I3J.21O.1I ■ 1,500.00 863.12 IO.S75.t4 1.382. K 4 LairpoeJi The Bank of &lt; 'ampbell t^'ashier Pr nt I'ashier STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOURCES LIABILITIES 10,000.00 ! 1,315.90 04 ur 17.S47.91 1.0«7.4 if deposit 19.465.S8 deposit.. 2T.131 8--. ipe laif m nmtional, state and and bankers 4 exci: 4 IS </seg>
            <seg id="p081">46 mik IAB1LITIF I rt t it 1 ates of der f .1 4 ink ii » AHIMT1I' 41.034 Campbell Commercial State H The 'harter Nc Incorporated nl I H Chevali nt B M Chevall 'licvilirr BTAT KMENT. NOVKMREK S. 1 RCE8 I I na — and -i Capital raft*. »«-cur^d ;i ■ Surplus fund 14 11 ("ndlvlded pr. : taxr Individual de^ check Demand ■ . i r i n Tlm«- ctrtlflcat 1 nation; ££Z ind bll Carleton Tin* Citizens State Han t Heachjr Whlpkej M \\ I M Whipk. BTAT K MEXT, NOVEMBER 9. 1? Loans and di- secur jrplu Banking house, fui of d«F • bank» at 14 T </seg>
            <seg id="p082">47 k Cedar Bluffs The Bank of Cedar Bluffs "'hartt-r X i"-rated R H Knipp woirr . . F B Knapp .1 H. Mackpran tnt Cashier RCE8 LIABILITIES Loan* and dlst-ount- | I pital stock paid in $ 15.000 M Ov«rd rafts, Surplus fund 4.000. 00 I'ndlvided profits I.IM *' Banking hou: flxtu - Individual deposits suhj^rt tr 4'.t.l5!&gt; M urrtnl rip. rtiflcates of deposit . . 11;), jh jj tional. state and ks and banker' »M1I C!k 4 Cedar Bluffs The Farmers and Merchants Hank John K KESOrRCK LIABILITIK apital .stn.k paid in . . H",.".. Surplus fun ("ndivided p 3 ■ dividual ilf-p -.471 P» 1 I &gt;r*sM*at Vi. e-Pr*»ld«nt STATEMENT. N&lt; iVEHBEK heck l.lM* hmnic ■ STATEMENT, N&lt; IVEHBER Henry WVJi </seg>
            <seg id="p083">48 Cedar Rapids Tin* S. s. Hall«\ Company rated) nt A J I-indwtorm Assistant Cashier ■ LIABII.IT ■ iip drafi tnti un- us fund fled pr Eiiturf and Individual dep&lt; s Cedar Rapids lley Bank MABI1.1TIKS rdr. Bankiac ho fixture* 55 irr*nt 42 44 &gt;n. banks itcks and item M </seg>
            <seg id="p084">49 The Center State Bank rter No Incorporated) President I man E I. under Vice President Assistant Cashier \TKMENT. NOV EMBE1 LIABILITIES RESOL'R' KKSOURCE Loans and discounts 114.320.44 apital Stock paid In I 6.000 09 ndivlded profits 1.032.71 Overdrafts, secured and un - secured J42. 83 Overdrafts, secured and un Individual deposits subject to check »,OM.»1 Other assets 140.04 Other asset Banking house, furniture and ftxture. mIO.OO Banking house, furniture and Sl III I ■■■» Demand certificates of deposit S9.4I Time certificates of deposit.. 5.018.82 ftxturei Vrtlned checks 542.50 Other real estate Current expenses and taxes paid . «84.03 4 Cash items Due from national, state and private banks and bankers I Due from national, state and private banks and banker; -wk«* and iTi-ms of t X' hatl. Checks and items of fichantf 1,4 xihan. am. Cash l.«4 121.7:7.11 Total m,m.n $21,727.11 I Total City Bank Central City The Central Central City The Centr &gt;il president ident President President H Gra Assistant Cashier tTKMKNT. N&lt;&gt;V KMBEF LIABILITIES RESOURCES RESOURCES apital stock paid in i M f&gt;OO.«t Leans and discounts $118,107 .12 .cans and discounts $118,107.1 ■verdrafts. secured and un- it,-... 1 Overdral •' and un " .1 ••• ' Surplus fund ndlvided profits : J01.51 v.-d »•• Bankinff house, furniture and irM *■ ' Bankinff house, furniture and Individual deposits sut&gt; 84.13t.S4 Time certificates of deposit. 41.304. M 84.13t.S4 °ffF".* 1 *.'.''.'.'. and . tax " fixtures . ■ Current expenses and taxos ,.ji,l 1.876.4 it* and pi ks and bankers M Itar from national, state and private banks and bankers. 51.1 national, state and .ind items of exchange </seg>
            <seg id="p085">50 Oantral Olty The Farmers State Bank Charter No. It. (Incorporated) . Pre«id»nt J. W. Vlereic John Clav Cha» C McEndree vice President Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. XOV EMBER &gt;, 1 RB8OL'KCES LIABILITIES Lmm and dlaconnu |17t.«0«.28 ■ apltal stock paid In f 21, Surplus fund jft. s .-;.uoo.oo Overdrafta. secured and un- 6.000.00 secured ... 7«.lt Undivided profit* «.401.9] Individual deposits subject to Banking house, furniture and nxlures 3,000.00 check 70.f77.41 Current expenses and taxes paid 1.441. »0 Demand certificates of deposit 1,079.00 Time certificates of deposit .. 64.971. 5&lt; Dae from national, state and Due to state and private private banks and bankers. 17.1M.48 banks and bankers 14,117.71 Checks and Items of exchange 8:9.97 Cash 10,3*4.11 Total 1209.4*7. (« Total .$209,487 «0 Central City The Platte Valley State Bank Charter Incorporated K Scott . . K Has. President J. C t V'ice President Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9, 19 RESOURCES LIABILITIRs f tnmnt and discounts I13C704 apltal stock paid I Overdrafts, secured and un Surplus fund 270.it Undivided profl Banklnc house, furnltun Individual deposits su 1.500.00 k . . K.»77.M Demand certificates of deposit 1.104.(4 Cwrent expenses aad taxes -^ a :»0.8g I! II 4.(4 Time certificates of dep. 3S: Doe from national, state anil private banks and banker: 41' Checks and Items of exchange " tll!4T T4 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">51 Ceresco Tin 1 State Bank oi ,"jrated President H I.-n! Cashier Vice President Assistant Cash let STATEMENT, N( &gt;Y EMBER », IS' RESOURCE LIABILITIES I&gt; and discounts Irafts, secured ured . Loans and discounts I 38,(50. 05 I 38,(50.06 and an - 2*1.73 Capital stock paid in * 10. 000 . 00 Capital stock paid In * 10.000 «• Overdrafts, secured and un Surplus fund 800 . &lt;M&gt; Surplus fund 800 00 ured 2»1.7J Undivided profits 1.366.47 Undivided profits 1.3M.47 Banking; house, furniture and ing house, furniture and Individual deposits subject to check 43.771 71 Individual deposits subject to check 43,771 71 (Inures 2.500.00 urn . 2.500.00 Current expenses and tax nt expenses and taxes Demand certificates of deposit 17,411. 35 Demand certificates of deposit 17,411.34 745.29 Time certificates of deposit. 35.335 . 78 paid 745. 29 Time certificates of deposit. 35.335 7S Due from national, state and from national, state and rate banks and bankers. (3.121. &lt;t banks and bankers. 83.1 21. &lt;f 3.374.(5 3.374.15 Jl"- 8108.885.31 Chadron The Citize State Bank IIS rter No. I (Incorporated) A W Riekman J T May President •""ash ipf Vice President Assistant Cashlet STATEMENT, NC :&gt;v r MBER 9, 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts 1154.191.49 apltal stock paid in 120,000.00 rafts, secured and un Surplus fund 4,000.00 i 177.11 d profits MM. 41 Banking house, furniture and Individual deposits subject to 6.400 00 check 70.2U.35 uu 'urrent expenses and taxes Da 'tnand certificates of deposit 8.347.73 paid 1,393.17 Time certificates of deposit.. 7 1.785. €3 Checks and other cash Items 933.15 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers 15.855.11 Legal tender notes and cur- 3,500.00 870. « </seg>
            <seg id="p087">52 Assistant Cashier BILITIES d ir I II, J.O lubject to 14 A&gt;.sistar ■r 1LIT1 j ■ 20.017.41 &gt;f deposit. . 1.8&lt;:.7« Chambers The Chambers State Bank Chart •r N'o. «»7. (Incorporated) J C. MrOower vitrney President Edward Adam STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 19 RESOURCES LI A Loans and discounts » M,«T«.«T Capital stock pale Baaklnc house, furniture and fixtures Surplus fund Current expense* and taxes _ »•"» Individual deposit J«l . U check Due from national, state and private banks and bankers Time certificate Omrrency nickels and pennie I41.lt! 1 hapman State Hank Hamilton - 1 usser . . 1 •resident J K Hamilton 'resident STATE MENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES i.IAI Lmbk and .. Ssjrplus fund . Overdrafts, secured and un ■•cured profit Banking- house, fumit IIXtUT- I il Individual deposl »• check 'it exp«n*es and tax 407.41 Kfrom national, state ■ .I 11' 'O.W Undivided proflt t.'H.i* </seg>
            <seg id="p088">53 Chappell The Commerci rcial Bank ( Incorporated &gt; Hair B F Clayt, President H I ! Vice l'i Assistant Cashier TATKMENT. NC VKMKER • RESOI LIABILITIES n* and discounts S 64.31t.13 apltal stock paid In I 10.000. 00 Overdrafts, secured and un Surplus fund IJOU . 00 secured 1.311.11 Undivided profits 1.4M.M Other assets ... . «3t.4S Individual deposits subject to Banking house, furniture and check 57.414.1* fixtures 755.00 Demand certificates of deposit 29,465.9? Due from nat tons private banks and hank I 1100.347.13 $100,347 11 Chester The Farme rs Bank Charter No (Incorporated) Jame., Wil-.n President Robert Wilson. Jr Vice President Robert J. sfalowney. .Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NC IV EMBER 9. 190 RESOI' RCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts t 52. 129.il Capital stock paid in t 7.500 00 Overdrafts, secured and un Surplus fund 12.90(1 00 secured -35.49 rndlvlded profits 2.877. to Current expenses and taxe Individual deposits subject to paid 1.411.71 check 50.134. &gt;7 Cash items 3t.25 Demand certificates of deposit 17.989 41 Time certificates of deposit . 527.90 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers. 32. OSS. 21 Checks and items of exchunK*- S.S4 Currency 4 Current expenses and tax </seg>
            <seg id="p089">54 FOURTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE ■r F 4 ! • il 0 00 65 85 It 1.702.M 42.822. If The Clarkson State Bank arler No 9; (Incorporated I STATEMr ■VKMHKK &gt;. 190 MABIMTI Loans and diacounta . . Overdrafts, secured and un- Surplus fund Banking housi- furniture and ■xtures Du« from national, state and Timf t ■ Evate banks and bank - lea and items of exchange and silver, nick* b r mon* | 2.813 $16i The Farmers Bank of Clatonia harter Nc Wm Stein- Henry Alt- F 're» As: TATKME INT. NOVEMBER 9, 19 KESOrRCEt LIABILITIE Loans and diicoui, . 149 Overdrafts, secured and unse - "««&lt;1 I, Binkim house furniture and Surplus fund Ui.SI I-ndlvlded profit.. Individual deposits sub 454.40 Current expenses and taxes Demand certiflcatea of dep '»•*» Time certificates of deposit Caah items Bfrom national, state and ■rate banks and bankers . II, 257.41 359.00 55*. &lt;S Gold and sliver "resident I^ontrin 'resident Ka)nol&lt;! • 0« Capital stock p 40J.51 Individual depu JOO.00 check '50.05 ,&gt;f ata «' II '"ontlngent fun «»1. &lt; Incorporated ■ idem W i itdent 690.68 Capital </seg>
            <seg id="p090">55 Clay Center The Commercial State Bank Incorporated) J. L. Campbell H B. Campbell int Cashier EMBER 9, 1905 LIABILITIES 'apltal atock pa urplus fund . . IJO.OOi. 00 profits unpaid Individual nVj. check - 7 *&gt;•» *&gt;J Demand c Time cert deposit 14.465 . &lt;0 nal. state and and bankers . 4 ms of exchange 4.S r il 4 1147,459 1147,45*. 71 Clearwater The State Bank earwater Charter No. (29 ( I n corpora t ed ) I President H. M Stockwell Cashier Vice-Presldent Eugene A. Blakealey . . Assistant Cashier N. Seymour EMBER 9. 190 STATEMENT, NC ■)V RESOURCES LIABILITIES 'apital stock paid In M.000 »« Loans and discounts (55,581 i verdrafts. secured and unse- Surplus fund 5.000. •• ndivided profits 2.555.81 cured 812.19 Banking house furniture and Dividends unpaid fixtures 1,500.00 Individual deposits subject to check M.7M.1T Current expenses and taxes Demand certificates of deposit 90. •• paid 1. 021.11 Due from national, state and Time certificates of deposit . . 24,090. St Rvate banks and bankers . 5,984.92 cash on hand 3.&lt;4«.25 Certified checks Cashier's checks outstanding; If. If Due to national banks Due to atate and private banks and bankers Notes and bills re-discounted Bills payable </seg>
            <seg id="p091">56 The Bank of Cody Charter Incorporated) B. Spark. J A Spark President J F Whlttemo VIce-Pr Assistant Cashier STATEMKNI N&lt; JV EMBER 9. litiir. RESOURCES LIABILITIES I and discounts T1O.SS rafts, aecared and unse- Loans and discounts ■ 710.6S Capital stock paid In $10,000.00 Capital stock paid Id 110.000 00 urplus fund 1,000.00 Overdrafts, secured and un» Surplus fund 1,000.00 eared 1.962.24 1.M2.24 Undivided profits 11, 192. SO Undivided profits 11,192. SO Bsnking- house furniture and ng house furniture and Individual deposits subject to check 36.3OU. 42 Individual deposits subject to fixtures 1,788.34 irea . 1,788.34 check 36.30u.42 Demand certificates of deposit 1,300.00 Due from national, state and rom national, state and Demand certificates of deposit 1,300.00 Time certificates of deposit . . 6.642.50 Due to national banks 264.21 private banks and bankers . 30.507. 6u Cash 3.750.86 ate banks and bankers . 30.507. tu Time certificates of deposit . . 6,&lt;«2.50 Due to national banks 2(4.23 LTM.M H4.TU.W I Total 166.719 46 Coleridge The Coleridge State Bank 'harter No ■.•*", ( Incorporated &gt; F. A. McCornark J. W. Linkhsn President eo. I. Parker Vlce-Prealdent R Applegate Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. N&lt; &gt;V UMBER S, ISC RESOURCES UABILITIE Loans and discounts 1121. 104. »» Capital stock paid In J25.000.00 Surplus fund 6,e»0.00 Overdrafts, secured and un cured 2,16!. *« Undivided profits 10,121 »■■■•&gt;■«• house furniture and Current expenses and taxes Individual deposits subject to check SM4S.il P"Jd :.!74.«t Demand certificates of deposit 1.905.39 Time certificates of deposit . . 60.605.74 Cash!.' outstanding- 3.317.89 Cash lMtn&gt; 1*»!« Osm from national, state and private banks and bankers . 17,04&gt;.i4 l&gt;4».0« s*s»»e .578.'«» </seg>
            <seg id="p092">57 $107. »9S 74 T (H The State Bank of Colon 'harter M Incorporated) BJ. Kirch man Pranson . . President J. F. Bastar Assistant Cashier Vice-Presldent STATEMENT, N( )V EMBER 9, 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts (7«.4 apital stock paid in t7.M&gt;0.»« 1, 500.00 Overdrafts, secured and un* Surplus fund 580.60 Undivided profi 4.37S.14 cured Banking house furniture and Individualdeposits suhi 1.240 check ... 43,814.(4 fixturei Demand certificates of deposit Current expenses and taxes t,HUi ' - " p a ,d Time certificates of deposit . . (0,!9(.(J Coleridge The Coamereial State Bank Charter No. 899 (Incorporated) O*o A. Gray ...President V. G BridenhauKh Cashier T T Llnkhart Vice-Presldent Assistant Cashier STATK.MKXT XOVKMHI RESOURi I UABILI1 Loans and discounts $€3,682.41 Capital stock paid in i Overdrafts, secured and unse- Surplus fund . . cured 1.282.24 Undivided profit- Banking house furniture and Individual deposits subject to fixtures 6.000.00 check 14.854. »t Interest paid 3(5. Si Demand certificates of deposit 10.605.7* Current expenses and taxes Time certificates of deposit .. 37. 403. C? paid .... 888. «7 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . 11,417.4* Checks and Items of exchange 7S.57 G Id 1,)- 811ver, nickels and cents 724.54 Currency </seg>
            <seg id="p093">58 ♦ Columbus The Columbus State Bank Charter No 97 I Incorporated) M Brugser President ■ A ilark. c*.hl— Wm Bucher Vice-Pre.ldent V H A«si.tant Caahlw STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. It RESOIK LIABILITIES .•n.i dlwour k pald ,„ *a0 900»« Overdrafts, aeeured and unw- Surplus fund 4000 »• (.IM.tl Undivided proflts 947«M Stock., wcoritiea. judgment.. Individual deposits subject to ' claim., et. »«J.J 7 check ...7.;/; 114 «09 T7 Banking hou« furniture and Demand certlHcates of depo.lt 1MI« 14 Oth r rell e.t.t " "H !' Time certiflcate. of deposit .. 141.067.11 real e.t»te i. 44«.«2 Due to state and private "£f d n ' bank, and banker. 51.777. T4 Premium on V S. and m national, state and Tl ""' 1392. «18 4 «392.«18.4» Comstock The CoMtoek State Bank I TK&gt;rated) Robert 8 Stone President Tho» g Jark»n r,«hl» Peter Mirk!. Mce.Pre.ident AiXiiii SSZ STATEMENT, NOVEMBKK I II RESOl"RCES LIABILITIES Tl! rS. P- -•••••■" •£«■» C^iS"e.p^i- and t . 1M 1 ' 4 " 1S T.m.c.rtmcV.oid.po,,,:: SmiS paid . 1'3 «7 Premium on D S and other Due from national, state and prU-ate banks and bankers . 8,703. M Check* and Items of exchange 542 CO Gold, »l]ver and pennlrs 1.120 17 Cumncy l!24s'oo </seg>
            <seg id="p094">59 The Concord State Bank 'harter No, Incorporated) President A Paul Ca.h..r Annie Paul Assistant Cashier Vice-Presldent STATEMENT. N VEMBER 9, 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES *oans and discount $100.2(8 capital stock paid in 130,000.00 verdrafts, secured and unse 5,700.00 8,326.59 S36.08 t assets, interest paid on e C. I' Individual deposits subject to check 15.«4«.44 174.80 Banking bouse furniture and fixtures Demand certificates of deposit 16.861 1J Time certificates of deposit . . 47.01 2 1.114. 47 3.»39.29 &gt;ther real estat urrent expenses and taxe 418.48 and banks and bankers . 12,848 ms of exchang, n The Fan B nk of Cook arter N Incorporated) p n Pr- Assistant Cashier ITATEMENT. N&lt; \' MHER 9. 190 ■iRCE; LIABILITIES 117.500. 00 t paid in erdraft*. secured and u fun 9.50". 00 3.333 07 l,15i.71 ndlvided profits Banking house furniture and fixtures idividual deposits subject to r,9o.oo check 122,63!. »• Demand certificates of deposit 10.00S.57 Current expenses and taxes 1.138.31 me certificates of deposit.. 4.385 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . 57,750.11 8,087.17 ■■m nat 1123. 341. &gt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p095">60 1.-..1 il i »1 1.M1 o&lt; to 1«.«:7.4 lit 1 The ( lordoi Bank : morporated P H Tpdlk* ..President Hurbank O. Burbank - N I.IABILITIE I.. ,, i. - and « 1 1 ~ »l paid In I I Bank; irntturt- and ni eip€H«ei and laxe Premium on D. 8. and ..iher bondi and «■. uriti. • d»-ji. &lt;i Cart Items 4.18 itlonal. Ktate and private bank* and bankers . H A (Marke President J J Dlckfy Vlce-Prertdent \.»si STATEME NT XiiVEMKER 9. IS RESOURCES LIABIMTIE Loan&gt; and d |2t, Ovtrdraft*. x-cured and unse- DJ4.«» Capital stock paid In I'ndivided pronto 45 88 Individual deposits subject Banklnc house furniture and Sit urn check 043. »« Demand certificates of dep&lt; expenses and tales paid 1 Doe from national, state and Time certificates of deposit 245.10 private banks and bankers . 4 :.,i NOVEIiBKH 9. 1 ■ ■ t « SUb. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">61 Assistant Cuhlar Lotni and discounts »38. 306.6s apital stock paid in jrplus fund 110,000.0* ft. 1 *, secured and 470.00 rd 116.17 I'ndivided profits 6.7 30 ■rants 42.80 Individual deposits subject to check Banking: house furniture and 264.71 ,r tlflcates of deposit . 17,814.83 xpensea and ,,»,d ri m national, state and private banks and bankers . 91. «S and items of exc and silver S5 nder no |64M7«.M The Cowl os Bank I're mt Cashier ATEMENT. N VK.MiSKK 9, 19 RCEfl LIABILITIES Loan-* and diiu'ounts $-'. h paid in : »oo.oO ta, 4S profits lual d&lt; F7iand ' f: la rtiflt r </seg>
            <seg id="p097">62 C The Cozad State Bank Charter (Incorporated Pr-Hdent ■ Allen E E Cook Cuhlcr Vice-Presldent Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. Nt JV KMBKI RESOrRCE? LIABILITIES Loans and discounts 111. 21*. 41 fixtures . 1,04*. (5 Capital stock paid In Undivided profits J16.000.00 Current expenses and taxes paid IK Individual deposits subjec check ».47 Due from national, state and i!fl.-me.« of deposit private banks and bankers . 4. 711. ft Checks and Items of exchange 1.959.85 Cash 4 77C.52 Total |M.fM.tT I Tola 114. 554 Crab Orchard The Bank of Crab Orchard . (Im-orporat C L. Rothell President rank Rot Vice-President A Bailey Assi-tsnt Cashlet STATEMENT, NOV EMBER ». 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loems and discounts *3;.7(H.0« 'apltal stock paid In 115.000.00 urplu» fund 1.500.00 .ifts, secured and unse- 1.9S4.0* Banklnc boose furniture and ml deposits subject to fixtures 5. 000. 00 22,5tO.I* Current expense* paid .. and taxra 1.5:3.41 I ind certificates of deposit 10.248.JS ttinnal banks 1 .21 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . ;. 0C9.il "hecks and Items of exchance Ilt.t2 125 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">63 Crab Orchard The Fanner State Bank i :harter (Incorporated) n Bacon President H C Platt CubMr ice- President Assistant Cashier iTATEMENT. N( &gt;V EMBER 9, l»05. RESOURCES LIABILITIES 'apltal stock paid In 110,004.0* I«oans and discounts $18,973. 5S Overdrafts, secured and unse- ndivlded profits 1,101.04 .',00 . 811 1 ndlvldual deposits subject to ur Banking house furniture and fixtures . heck 14,0::. U l&gt; &gt;emand certificates of deposit 9St.37 'ashler's checks outstanding 717. S3 1.(00.00 Current expense* and taxes _paid ... 4 Dim from national, state and private banks and banker* and items of exchange (2i.903.87 Total *-'«. State Bank The Craig ■tor \"&lt; ■ .'rated President MrPherson Cashier VIce-Presldent Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NC JV ESIRER :« RESOURCES LIABILITIES apttal stock paid In |10.00«.»» ans and discounts |&lt;3,034 &gt;verdrafts, secured and unse - cured Surplus fund 2.040.00 Indlvided profit* . 510.0s Banking house furniture and Individual deposits subject to cherk . 45.Stt.02 fixture 0" Current expenses and taxes Premium on U. S. and other Demand certificate* of deposit 1S9.S5 Time certificates of deposit .. 21.0M.S0 Due to national banks 711.8* Cash items til Due from national, state and private banks and bankers . Checks and items of exchange urrenc i.r. </seg>
            <seg id="p099">64 HII.ITIr urplu* fund 4 I'ndivided profits . 744. M 'Ubjec posi 4.T4 |58.8«5.S4 : A ILITIB 4 &lt; The Farmers State Bank r Incorporated) President E. J. Martin -President HENT. NOVEMBER 9, IS I.I A i-rdraftn, secured and u ur-d Bankinr house furniture and Individual depof»i «»-«5 j M.7Z1.C - &lt;m national. Mate and ate hanks and baa tifi.ates of deposit 260.00 IH of deposit . . 17,»C4.»4 MT.(T:.(I , I'Hpital M...k paid in Crawford The Commercial State Bank (Incorporated) »t OK Eastman . •sident F L. Hall NOVEMBER 9, 1905. LIAT k pak » •« • niralt-. &gt;•■' ur.-d and un*«- Banking* house furniture and flxtu-- »-mand certificat* real estate nae« and taxes m national, private banks and bank </seg>
            <seg id="p100">65 Creighton The Security Bank of Creisrhton Incorporated) larter No. 4 President I F. K. Austin Cashier Vlc«-Presld Foster Assistant Cashier W H Butterneld ITATEMENT V MBKK RESOURCES LIABILITIES OS ''apital stock paid in $25, 000.04) iirplus fund 10.008.tf ; .- 1'ndivided profits . 8, 831. IS ndlvided profits 8.831. 2S Individual deposits subject to 13.33 check 109.82t.5l •dividual deposits subject to 109.82C.SS k -■mand certificates of deposit 3,730.00 ■ f deposit . . 99,603. •• state and private and certificates of deposit 3,730.00 certificates of deposit . . 99, 602.99 id bank . 5.43S. T4 *2(2,42I.4O rant Cashier MRER 9. IS LIABILITIES pltal stock paid in $25,000. •• urplus fund o.OOO.tf "ndivided profits 3.012.7* vidual deposits subject to heck •' tes of deposit ates of depos.* </seg>
            <seg id="p101">66 Creighton itizens State Bank ■rporated Frank r ! J F Greer IS STATEMENT. N&lt; VE1IBE1 RESOURCES LIABILITIE Lout and discounts . IS.tM.ll Capital Stock paid In 118.000 ♦• Banktnc house furniture and Individed profit! 45 taturex 1.414.20 Individual deposits subject to Current expense* and taxea - 2,125.7 taturex 1.414.20 Individual deposit! subject to !,125 paid 241.04 Time certificates of deposit . c Due from national. *tate and paid private banks and bankers . 12,903. 26 3.189.00 193.21 The Citizens State Bank Creston rpora nt B. T. FleminK Iraham I H W I.uedik Assist nt I T. Flemir STATEMENT. Nc RESOURCE I.IAHI1.ITIF vt-rdrafts. secured and uns 44 4 Banking house furniture and idual de[. k 14 ither real estat- &lt;00.00 Demand certificates of deposit 3,511.(0 expenses and taxes Time certificates of deposit lt.Mt.W ' real estate Ttincates of deposit pa.d I.I hi national, state and private banks and bankers . 6 Check* anil it^rns of exchange 22C.1U Currency 1.60 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">The Cri't. State Bank 117. (Incorporated Cashier H M President Harry W. Gasser nderson resident James O. ' Ml istant Cashier ATKMENT. NOV EMBK^ LIABILITIES k paid in J.'.O.ooo.OO Loan i. and discounts $384,787.83 ; Surplu- fund 40,000. •• I'ndivlded profiu 4.041.02 •07.09 ! Individual deposits subject to 118.134. IS f deposit 211.332.X King house furniture and Demand certificates of deposit 211,332. •• outstanding- 6 411.02 Due to national banks 2,915. ;• Kfrom national, state and Dav and private vate banks and bankers 106,731.44 banks and bankers 102. 722. it ashler A. C. Eisenhart Assistant Cashier LIABILITIES Capital stock paid In Undivided profits . . . $7,500.09 3,251. 1» Individaul deposits subject to 70,841.57 ates of deposit 4.521.11 i of deposit .. 10,754. tl ki outstanding 6.4KS ft </seg>
            <seg id="p103">68 T he State Bank of Curtis No. 113 (Incorporated Hag-adorn President .1 ■ U. Loans and discounts $77.»51.«7 : I'apilal - 57S.«I ! I Banklnc houH furniture and ,lual d. ur 9,291.4 4.500.00 » : n«es and taxes paid a hand and ex- 9. 'i T nM.ZM.4l 4.48 Dakota City Thr Bank &lt; The Bank of I &gt;akota City Owner Owner Caahlw Assistant Cashier resident -■ ■ President STATK.Vi EMBER 9, 19 RESOUR' RES«' LIABILITIES tMmnm and discounts $66,127. C5 Band discoui ■ $66.127. C5 ng house, furniture and Banking house, furniture and l.iOO.OO ■ nses and P»1&lt;1 LMt.11 m national, mate and private banks and bankers 11,4*1. M 377.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p104">69 Danbury The Bank of Danbnry Incorp. I r IT \TKMK.\T XOV1 M I.IAHI ! ,o ■ I 4 The Dannebrog Stati' Bank Dannebrog :.-nt T .1 Assistant &lt; STATEMENT. N'l iVEMBER LIABILITIES liCKS 'apttal Surplus fur ndivided prr Banking hou.-&lt;-. fwrnltun Individual h»i-k Demand certiftcat- Time certlti&gt; Duf banks' and tanl </seg>
            <seg id="p105">70 Davenport The Jennings State Bank Prenident w ~ A \V MBKl: Lnans and 141.44 » • The Farmers State Bank &lt;rv [■■-.-■ Hark - rafts &lt; and tir t&gt;- 34 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">71 &gt;n Hank The Dawa d&gt; M M K!l&gt;&gt;y Assistant Cashier 1 N. T Rll STATEMENT. N "v V LIABILITIES HRPF , paid in. 11)0. »t «4 1 pro Mial dej 7»41 &gt;4 . M ■J A I1S1.340.1I Daykin The Jeffer&gt;oi 'ounty Bank rporated) kitMr VicePr Hemenover ... Assistant (_a»nl«r Vice-f EMBER 9, 190 STATEMENT. NOV RESOURCES LIABILITIES ■ «ns and discounts »n.386.58 capital stock erdrafts. secured and un- Surplus fund r rdrafts. secured anc E?"- " eCU " a *" U UU " 55 , 2 indTvTded profit, 1.204.44 ng house' furniture and Individual ihjeet to id idivided profi 4.i:4. M k Demand certificates of deposit 3,44».4« x and ificates of deposit.. 21.914. 14 •d TS ii nation; jrlvate banks and bankers 16.758. 4i ■a </seg>
            <seg id="p107">72 ABILITI 168.4 Assistant Cashlar A.BILITII Id S 46 lubject to 48.70" 1« deposit 31.1 deposit. . 11.856 00 Decatur The Decatur State Bank (Incorporated H W. Buss-- . IT MRFF RESr. 6.46 ri P •Kind . . 14 Bunkii . tilture and Prtv f depo i 55.00 I i.n m.4i The st;it. • Hank of Deshler (Incorporated r RobI " Presid President STAT EMENT NOVEMBER 9, 19 RESOURCES LI LotH and d pital stock i) secured and •erur irplUH fund J4J.II Undivided profl Banking house furniture an fixtures dividual dep&lt; .heck </seg>
            <seg id="p108">73 State Bank of D*i Deweese Charter No 829 (In. F'n IT- ••■■ LIABILITIES k 1( i un . rndivided profits It Individual deposit Undivided pro S'.| I ..,,.. n t- check Demand certificate Time certificates i 4.677 Demand certlnc, tl d^P' » n it.- and 369.83 I2«.l $ ■ :. : The Farmers and .Merchants Bank he Farmers and Merchant* Bai De Witt Charter No. 643 (Incorporated) rated No. S4 . President President Ca.nl* Z22Z\ -,ant &gt;"h«« H namkros.i • Presld STATEMKNT NOVEMBEI: LI A LI A HI I.IT IKS 71 Capital stock paid in. * ' ****** |«E.48«.T1 I'apital stock pai Surplus fund 609.09 I'ndivlded profit- Surplus fund ur ■S «..» In^r idepo :" ».•« uri and Demand certlfl"»tes of deposit «*.M(.I ip 45 74 Dut- from nat private banks and banker- Checks and items of exchange </seg>
            <seg id="p109">74 1 De Witt De Witt The Home State Bank (Incorporated) A. Thomas Ca«hl« A. Thomtit C B Andtr- t \~ntant Cashier C B Anihrmn £ NT. NOVEMBER NT XOVKMMI KCKS l.IABIU LIABILITIES , paid In |10 000 00 ■ 1 and un- i Indlvlded profits ] ;:,i it 1 k paid In |10 000 00 ■ 'i and un- j I'ndlvtded proflta 1. T94.lt 177 M Imli vnliial deposits subject to 794. It - hous* furniture and 12,741. IT ■1.3"' Demand rertltlcaten of deposit 12!s30.4« ~ and tax. 14 'r»m national, state ai •it*- banks and l?* n l ■■■ paid in 10 0 and un- [ 4 ' 7 ur ur livldual .i.p. - hoiiK furniture and k t ~ rtifliatfs of depo-.it :,131 II and taies ricates of deno»lt and po iiank« and l.ank. "ok" and ltem« of ezrhan </seg>
            <seg id="p110">75 The Dixoo St;ite Bank • Incorporated) irated. Cashlw . Pres President Vice President Vice President R F De STATEMENT. NOVEMBER S. 1905. I.IABIIJ RESOURCES counts "* P ai&lt;i in *' palil unts ured ecured and un- ■ ■tided proflu .......... ied profits Jbjert to e furniture and ;•;••:.•.: I* ■tltieates of deposit 889. 7« locate* of deposit fiiturt iirrent lses'and U Time . .Ttiricate.-s of deposit 1 Due from ional. state and &lt;s and bank. $5«.589.(t The Farmers State Bank Dodge rated) d it Herman Hol«t&lt; t. m dent Will R- Hraba James !ant Cashier STATEMENT. NOVEMBER », 1905. STATEMENT. NOVEMBER OURCM 1 IJAliII.1 ui "■."*!" h ° USe ' Urn " Ure " d 4 180.O rl..p, .m nation*!, state and d bankers 4 ■x |303.941.«* </seg>
            <seg id="p111">76 Doniphan The Bank of Doniphan 1T«- .. - &gt; II Dorchester 'I'd.' Dorchester State Haul President rdr. and ui u M ■n nat i </seg>
            <seg id="p112">77 Douglas The Bank of Don* Marshall Mar The State Bank of Du Hois Du Bois utant Cash ATEMENT. NOVEMBER l.IAHII-ITIES RESO1 Hi it subject to 40.17J.9: dcpoait 30,701.14 I id a </seg>
            <seg id="p113">78 Dunbar The Dunbar State Bank harter N Incorporated w K President M ■ n STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9. l»u RESOURCE LIABILITIES nd discou fl»».4S .rafts, secured and Banking house furniture an xpenses and tax banks and bankers id discounts |: c k paid in 15,000.00 rdrafts. secured and u Kw, securt-a ana unit- t t()t 16.83 J \ nlu;i i deposits subject to house furniture and 9 50- fixture- 1.6C5.S9 Demand 1. a 485 11 expenses and taxes ot deDOSlt . 4.350 OS I rom national, state and tt* banks and bankers . &lt;nd items of exchange &lt;4 941 &lt;9 Dwight The Dwight State llmik (Incorporated) IW. Burte Sloiar \ , e-Presldem . . As Cashtel stant Cashlu KMENT. NOVI 1905. RESOUI;. LIABIL LITIE ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p114">79 KF B at c Eddyville .V Ri r I T The Bank of Eagle rter No 83». (I ■po rated t President Vice-President Mi I^nz Assistant Cashier TATKMENT, NOVE.MI E K 1 5URCB LIABILITIES ,1 stock paid In 120,000.00 II i and u ' Pro" subject to 37.190.41 rs 4 193. 12 193.123 Ir &gt;rj Assistant Cashier STATEMENT Ni IE I LIABILITIES iOURCES lid in ri profits . . . . J5.000.00 4,»89.tl ml ut 429.13 I In irnlture and I&gt;^ deposit 1.103.5* of deposit . . 2.0S6.35 19C 4 1J4 itate and and bankers . 9,(18.96 ind items of exchange «9.46 quarters. t &gt; liiates of deposit 15,9."6.42 16,&lt;50.0O [■he Eddyville State Bank jal deposits subject to </seg>
            <seg id="p115">80 Eddyville The Farmers .State Bank rporated PiwMmH As STATEMENT NOVEMBER LIABILITIES i k paid in $7,6 DUi«e fu: i profit dual dep&lt; heck 1,54 in:, ml I &lt; 4 - • Hank of Edgar ; -orated Wil Pre»l&lt;i Hart STATEMENT, NOVEMBER RCES LIABILITIES iid In i ' a aubj mturr- and el.- xpenaea anO laxrB lfi 1 3.4&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p116">81 lay County State Bank p "rated) . . . . President C. A \ oorhees Cashltr vice President F. A. Voorh«« Assistant Ca»hl«r C. A. \oorhees. . ..Vice President F. A. Voorhee». . STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905 ATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 19C LI A profits Individual deposl 4 | Demand rertiflcal [■ and 17.48 The Bank of Edi- The Bank of Edison (Incorporated) K.MKN </seg>
            <seg id="p117">82 The Kll&gt;a Stair Bank H., I&gt; MKNT MiVKMUKI. Kih MAKIMTIKS Ix&gt;»n« ud 14: I ■n national, mate and .inker* 19,4 4 Elein StHt.- Haul- ••. TT&gt;--idf n \\" rn I i (.11 d 4.0TO.U0 I tax' Tim paid ,«riK- antl 4 El an.! un- k:. i; m f urn I turt- and Individu;i 29.71C.0 nmem »nd I .ind certtflrat*-&gt; &gt;&gt;f d.j. »2t.21 Tim* 12,000. » </seg>
            <seg id="p118">83 Elk Creek The State Bank of Klk Creek No Itl ilnri.rp. SI ATEMENT N( IVBHBER RESOURCES I.IAH1I.IT1KS apital Mock p . $10, ar Surplus fund ndlvldsd pr,.ir -tanking house furniture and Individual J5.««» 111 f'urrcni &lt;ind taxes n&lt; '340. IS 4.37J.12 The State Hank of Elkhorn Elkhorn STATEMENT. Nl RCES LIABILITIB8 »-' »» tSS:S 48 | \ : deposit 11- 341.44 1.484 1.124 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">84 Elm Creek Th. Merchants Bank T. B Caahtcr Assiatant Cashier iTATEMEXT. XOV K 9, 1 LIABILITIES RCES ■ — and iii" ' »ep&lt; 1 Itt 11 d Da* from national. Mai ■r ban and it 74 4 Elmwood The Ameriean Exchange Bank k AKILITIES P [ir, 116 I 44 Da* fron bank* and ■ ■ and dltcoui IM.IOT.SS l and un- 1. 111. It ■ L and S=r </seg>
            <seg id="p120">85 Emerson The Farmt State Bank rs Incorporated • President &lt; *.«o H H ("ashler A distant t "ashler \TEMENT, N V FtCES I.IAHII.ITIES 120,000 00 4,000 00 14.13*. 14 ubjeet tc 4 1174 $174,050. »J The Farmers State Bank 'harter X Incorporated) David HaDP M Weil . . . . President I 'resident 6 Assistant Cashlsr E TATEMENT. N( \ EMHER 9, 1905 RESOURCES CIABILITIE $77.4 *oek paid Ln 111. 000. M nd 700.0* 1,256.00 fniiivi . 1,869. M individual dt 1U7.44O.4* Demand certificates of deposit 16.424.87 urrent expenses ant P«W irniing l'7m 00 Due from national, sts nks nnd banker: ■ hang&lt; 4.^^3.64 T 59.323 1» f depoait 77i.SO deposit 74, 152. SO I.M1.M </seg>
            <seg id="p121">86 AHH.rTI ( IABILITIE ! ■ 4 4 » The Ewing State Bank 1 m-orporated M T S \\* Hr: ITATI iVEMBEH Irfft and Surpl Hanklnc houe I dual (let k 714. 14 1 w illacc ik Co., Banker* H W MBER T\ I. 13 4 Banking \\&lt; from n 1M .ink« and I.; </seg>
            <seg id="p122">87 Exeter The Exeter State Bank rporated) u President ci \V Mppkrr \V ATEHENT. X VKMKKK RESOURCES 1AH1MTIES -&lt;k paid in III Surplus funil 4"0 i-d profits ! r dual deposits suti nd x.i Kt-mand c«*rtlflr.&gt; id ;tn'l 4 4.04 I'lie Harbine Bank porated) H r. Hoi TATKil V E MB1 HESOI-RCES .1 ABILITIES i Capital Surplus fun. Iiroflts R 47 It 174, 874 . S4 bank- x t </seg>
            <seg id="p123">88 Fairbury The Goodrich Hr )s. Banking C ;&gt;orated President -esident LIABILITIES Loans and diacoai ■ ■ ■. . tal stock paid In |C0 I ius fund 15 CU 2,541.03 Undivided proflta 541.03 4 7.500.00 Individual deposits subject to 500.00 Individual dep urn re and check 91 3.896.96 Demand certificates of deposit 70 3.S9C.9C Demand certl 4 ■ al estate 1. 00.60 Due to natlona 1.M0.60 Due to national bank I Due to state and private ■ n«e« and Due to state and prlvat 1,071.7* banks and bank, ri 4 ; l,07«.7» bank te and 40.771. «1 11 ,«M.M !&gt;4 I2S7.15S.85 TMa jTsT tJ Fairbury The Fairbury Savings Bank Charter No. 155 (Incorporated) :er No. Incorporated BE Goodr b President I. w Goodrich i Heanty M Bailey . Goodrlt President 1. \V Goodrkh Tn M Bailey Se. zz STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905. STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1 'I'RCE LIABILITIES LIABILITIES l«oan« and discounts I91.C4C I Capital stock paid In $25 3,300.00 | Surplus fund s Capital stock paid In I •Surplus fund nankins house furniture and fixtures ■e and Undivided profits 2 Undivided profits 558.40 Individual deposits subject to 40 raa national, state and private banks and bankers e and withdrawal 81 ankers Time certificates of deposit. . 12 4 »M 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">89 IJ46.4 * ant Cashier .0 34 4 I1T.VM3.4 63 4 ■ ■ ' nd private ... and bant 2»0.0» The F armers State Bank Fairmont dent Frank W. Sloan Pi Vice P B 1TATEMI N NOVEMBER 9, 19 RESOURCE I.IABILITIEi )verdra- I and un- Surplu- fund divided profits king house furniture and Individual deposits subject to ,...„. 00 check 9»,60« 3 Banking h 00 Demand certificates of deposit 86 nt expens 1 4 I! banks and bankers 11.871.11 ash Item: L»u- from national, state and private banks and bar- - ■porated dent Francis P. Putliti ... Am: SO Due to state and prlvat </seg>
            <seg id="p125">90 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">91 The State Hank Farnam v--!«t:int ' E M E N T X i &gt; V EMBER RCES liabilities Sit' . int Cashier RESOURCES LIABILITIES 1.610 [led profits* urt KlnK hnu.«f furniture and .,*. 1.666 "4 D.niaml i«rtl1cates of xjm ns nks k» J The Fariiani Bank Incorporated) President ST.V1 »'&lt; IVEMBER 9. 1 k paid i» mi </seg>
            <seg id="p127">92 Farwell The Fa™&gt; II State Bank T J I President Cashier Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. N&lt; IV EMBER 9, 1 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loan - • J ml un IKtNi Ml 806.40 Undivided prof] Individual depo Banking hou»e furniture and fixtures 00 check i and tax lif-mati' Time .ertiflcat I» t ■•■ and private hanks and bank* hange 1 1 Cut MM. 71 it. - 159.14 *ill«y The Btata Bank of Filley (Incorporated) (Incorporated " ' &gt;orcroM . I'r-sident Ear] Norcro»« lea* Earl Norer " ■ - N " rc r' -.-- ,1, . „ • " i resment Earl Norcross CashKr H H Ihm. ._ Um cZSSt STATEMENT. N ; 9. 19C IIEK 9. 19 ■ M0U1 LI RCES LIABILITIES Loan^ and dl«cour |U,043.«0 j Capital stock n!l!£.JV? d *"!*""-■ $16,043. «0 Capital stock paid in t red and un Overdraft., .rrured and un- ,, ius fund . «»&lt;-ured »J.46 i rndividrd profl Surplus fund - . l 704.34 Banking- house furniture and Individual Biturea mture. l.«58.37 Current txpenses and taxes .. manJ ill i il cert ■. i^ " 1 "°"' ■ na '•»•» ■ mand certlHcates of deposit 1; Due from national, state and private banks and bankers 37.S7J 01 Checks and Items of nrhancr 17.. J: IJ '1 and silver </seg>
            <seg id="p128">93 The Firth Bank Preside OuMa As»lstant I'astiler STATEMENT, NOVEMBER V. 19 UAHIMTIES RKSOIKCES Jl» and discounts $81,9*5.70 ! ■rdrafts, st-cured and un- dra ,1,995.7 1,4*9.; 11.3M.1I Indi ■ to </seg>
            <seg id="p129">94 IABILITIES 4 -I 4 44 Ft. Calhoun The Washington Countv Hank l.IAHILITIJ 4 r«ft k mi nai i' - and i.itt,. r\ &gt; From national. Man- a and l-.tiik. ' - ami it*-m* &lt;&gt;f &gt;x&lt;han urplufl fund ndiv |d« </seg>
            <seg id="p130">95 The Poster State Hank I ncirporatt-d t ! nl i-a.-h, STATEM EXT, N&lt; IV K.M BEH RCES I.IAHII.ITIKS apital ntock paid -.Si i profit* 1J3 Individual d&lt; xp. vheck « paid Tom nattonal. state ana ]ni&lt; 1)0 nkrr&gt;. 110. The Franklin Exchange Bank I nrorpi Pi !) .) Murr.iv \~-istant Cashier ATKMEXT XllVI HKSi HKCKS I.IABII.ITIKS K4.694.32 pai&lt;l In 11 fun.i I (Vi'M »■ rtlftt '114 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">96 Franklin The Franklin Stat.- Bank ■ Inrorpo ::;:;- M I.I A I r,lr ■Hi M 4 1104 Fremont The Securitj S Bank rporat€ UHEK &lt;H </seg>
            <seg id="p132">97 y Fremont The Home Savings Bank ii M as AT EM EXT. N V MBER 9. IS ROB LIABILITIES k paid 111 47 16 I n.l r» (4.832.44 uion of ...k It HI tiflCMl- 1 1341 r remoni r»u Kr. mont Trust and Savings Bank i Incorporated B. Sclu President Paul . Vice I'r- 'ashtor ATEMENT. N )V EMBER 9. 19 I E RC B 18 LIABILITIES urns $5 1 .930.00 Capital stock paid In »i:&gt; oun.oo Cndlvlded profit jr ■« Individual depoi lt» aubject u !U i heck S64 Demand of ilep. t nk. 174.34 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">98 Friend The Merchants and Farmers Bank President Z. Me H Hla. k MENT, NOVEMBER 9, 190i LIABILITIES I&gt; ur npital stock paid in jrplu* fund 1 tiled p Individual d ur&lt;- HankinK 6 heck uri Demand Due tc xi E: from na I* and banks ami The Funk liank Charter | Incorporated A. Franze 1 EMENT, N i\' EMBER 9. 1 LIABILIl'lKS I and $23.«73 . 1 ■••• » ;3&gt; paid In U IM.il ir«-d and un - ... M6.i&gt;- individual ilf us subject ired and un - "•■•- | Individual iV us subject 1 Mnd un " »,« ., L'ndivld* * p *" ' 8U - b " Individu s«M'urt? Bankinc house furniture and ing hou»e furniture ami ,•&gt;.*... l furniture and che ,. k «aOO» Demand cert: «o.o» ,. E«r- ■ ••«■•• Demand nt exp«iM«ff and taxes 4 1 IV* 77 V nt exp«iM«ff and taxes paid - m national Htate and e banks and bankers II Gold. - « 750.60 ■ and ,&amp;S3.4t US.27 </seg>
            <seg id="p134">99 The Gaml; Bank Gandy &gt;mleu t STATEMENT NOVEMBER LIABILITIES HESOURCES profit* p. 149.351 The Farmers ami Merehautx Bank Garrison KMF.NT. NOVEMBER 9. U05 LIABILITIES KF.SOURC •:•, 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">100 I &gt;, 1906 LIABILITI ml BILITII ' i/ciis Ban Wai W. H W. * STATEMENT NOVEMBER ! - :-ts 1 11.11 si &lt;1 I'll.- Geneva State 1 Geneva nt Frank V ATEMI MBER ■I'RCF l^otni and cured Hanking houx* fui i ' Indlvidu flxturr other l ••»&lt; « "urrent expfn pa.d ■ rom nation privmte banks and hankers 78. «1 11—01 Total 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p136">101 Goring H M \ -- -I M IABII.TIE 1 G6rin&lt;iiitown 1 he ( Jt*rniflntown Nt ;i 1 1 - 1 i;i n k r VT1SMKNT. NOVEMBE! The B;tnk of (lerinj; ATI'.M K"."l NOV1 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">102 The Commercial Bank of Gibbon No 174. (Incorporated) *±. m ?rr...-i^-2£Z -President » STATli iMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIE j£™: •° d di IU.825.80 Capital ,tock paid In . . I O«erdra , . ib fun led profl Furniture »i 'ultvidual dep&lt; 'urrent :»!&lt;■• MX and • 81 ii Total 151,142.51 - . 151, 142.51 ' Tolal The Exchange Bank The Exchange Bank (Incorporated) H Kirk w TATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES LIABILI TIE l^an. and °^S tu - serured ~" T P pISi fund Surplus fund • Undivided prc Banking hcu-- furnil . Individual d&lt;- t Current expenses an I rom nation private banks and bank* u </seg>
            <seg id="p138">103 The State Bank of Gilead No. 802. (Incorporated) Preside k Nelson Cashier Assistant Cuhkr Vice-President .1 STATEMENT. NOVEMI ER 9, 1905 ESOCRCES LIABILITIES 1 Loans and I I.Mt.M Capital stock paid In *5?2! !! ndlvlded protli- J, 1st II Banking house furniture and I ndlviaea proms ........... VL, "L 1.032.00 Individual "ject to , expense* and taxes .^^ - —,; 1^;JJ 13.501. 40 and tt m national, state and Time - • - • banker- .. $32,564.11 The Bank of Bromfield Charter No. «2 (Incorporated Glover ■n Vice-President BWva M Olover Assistant Cashlw ITATEMENT, NOVEMBEF 1 LIABILITIES F ESOURCES icfc paid In t i 000. •• IS6.060.04 apltal ;ount Surplus fund. Interest, ex - change and rents 8,«8«.7I fund. Interest. ex- r :ured and un» idivlded proBts 1M . SI dividual deposits subject to ies. judgments, ■u 4'J .8.853. SI a certificates of deposit 11.(41.71 I furniture and ■rtlflcates of deposit . . J5.34S *:, 4 and ta &gt;ue from national, state and private banks and bankers 40, 305. &lt; hand </seg>
            <seg id="p139">104 The Bank of Glenville . Brandt " IVKMUKI! 1 Goehner The Goehner State Bank Martin Mad- M 1^1 A HI I,1TI ■ - T </seg>
            <seg id="p140">105 The Sheridan County Bank Gordon RCES ABILITIES I Gothenburg The I Merchant* Bank r M Ml LIABILITII i </seg>
            <seg id="p141">106 The Bank of Graf Charter No 6»o (Incorporated President J. O Gra Graf 9. 190 RESCi IABILITIE9 127,034 H.M4 Ou 44 Indlvldu; • -» and tax »**m aux 33,834 2ft 676.33 Demand certificates of deposit 2 827 71 state and Time certificate n r A rnn J, i..L A ■■■■ •'•■« ix-mand certificates of deposit 2 827 71 .1. state and Tim. 7 4l» •« nd bank v '.4MB* 104 * Graf ton The Grafton State Bank ■ porate \*™ n A. S PmUa s 1'reeldi- illEXT N RESOIRCES LIABILFTIE Loan^ and di- 1 pita] 110.000. •* V ured irpiufi f 1.C4O.57 Undivided 4*6.97 Bankinc hou»e furniture and Individus flxtur check 6&lt; 'urrent expeni«es and tax Demand cert id posit 18,413. »s P»ld 1, 927 85 Time certificates of deposit .. 32«51 *« Due from national, state and 1.9 private banks and banV CTiecks and items of exchange 103 -.16 7«i- </seg>
            <seg id="p142">107 Grand Island The Grand Island Banking Company barter No Incorp' F President (! B. Be Vlce-Pre»ldent Ass: listant Cashier mpson ATKMKN II EIBK ' RCES LIABILITIES apltal stock paid In Sin urplus fund 3 ur Jed profits 16,643 71 I ids unpaid use furniture and vidual deposits subject to . . . 1 and certificates of deposit 2,351 Iflcates of di e banks and bankers 76. 21* .~r's checks outstanding I iank «.M 4 Island The Commercial State Bank Preslder ■r -tant Cashier (ABILITIES $ (•r 1 44 &gt;emand certificates of deposit 17,813. • 'rom national, state and Time certificate* of deposit .. 89,917.94 and bankers 122, 565. B7 Due to national banks 2,263.4 tchange 118.91 I' ind privat 121. 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">108 Grant The Commercial Bank of Gram \v TKMK •H Hank ■ t. </seg>
            <seg id="p144">Gresham The Farmers ami Merchants Hank i The Fanners and Merchants Hank Gr&lt;:na i. i |. nr iu H. M Harilin ATEMENT NOYEXBEB LIABILITIES 11% Surplus fund cl proB'i \ 1117.502.02 Demand certfflcat- ■ iiX. </seg>
            <seg id="p145">110 1 BIMTIt P laid in t 1 i I The Gross S\»w Ban! F M Wldner i F \v. W &lt;*. Kteka Aulitut \T NOVEMBER 9 l^f« and di ur idivid Indlv 371.10 check banking Im Demand 11 -■•m nallona Ivate i ks and **■ :• i and 4 Guide Reck The Bank of fiui.l.- Roc V President T EME.VT NOVEMBER Loan. an« •I3.09t.01 i-ii] »zzr ■S£ k 4.16 Due from ;ind id ban 344 It I1M.440 </seg>
            <seg id="p146">111 Empire Loan &amp; Trust Company H Presider Wm. H. Lamed Treasurer \ ice-Preslder Assistant Cashier mext x V EMBER 9. 1 LIABILITIES. Loans and discounts $11. 25.1. S9 apital stock paid In $ «.»S4 .934.52 Surplus funrt Undivided pi 1.3c Hi.17 Banking house furniture and fixtures Individual deposits subject to check . 17,109.41 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers. 13,194 check 17.10l-.43 .194.07 Demand ■ of de- Demand i if de posit .074.15 posit 3.80(91 .Time certifii :r -it... 6.433.9. 4.074.15 Time certificates of deposit. .. 6.4 fll.M4.4l t The llallain Bank Hallam r.ited &lt; &gt;r; realdent i John J Mey. &gt; ashler Gerhar .President j John J. Meyer resident j G. M. Ruhaak Assistant Cashier , H. Kuhaak. -tant Cashier EXT NOVEMBER 9, 1 VEMBER 9, 1 IKE NT X l.iABii.r l.IAHII.ITI k i Surplus Tund 421. M 471. ». ■ I'ndivlded ]n . 3.473.19 Banking hou«e furniture anil Individua -ubject Imh -ubject to Demand certificate* of deposit Na tT </seg>
            <seg id="p147">112 The Bank of Hampton Hampton TEMK !r«f o-., Harbine The State Hank of Harbine Inc .irp. Wr Wrinit ATKMKST NOVEMBER IAHI1.ITI jal d&lt; ..'..: </seg>
            <seg id="p148">113 The Hardy Bank Hardy lent Jas. H. Fs Lent « V.' H int Ca«hfer ATKMKNT NUVKMBt IABILITIES tack paid in $1 fund . Surplus fund Ided profit* Individual depost check . . and certifies' ■rtlncat it . . 4 14 S1I4 The Farmers State Bank Hardy ated Preside i 'reside JT1ES an B" k ", "' i.U1.U I rndTw™, 478 4 4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p149">114 Harnsburg The Banuer County Bank (Private r STATEMENT MBK1 Lc ital stock p rplus fund — Ir iled pr dividual depc • ifi *z k k&lt; ..its Harrison The Commercial Ban! Incorjj F \V W. II ATEM1 (EMI Loan, and Overdrafts &gt;ecu cm* Surplus HI Undivided p Individual de Storks, seeuritlet rlalma, • I ah *■ Bankine housf fu fixtures . depOM Current ezpenix 4.21C Due from natlo private banks &gt; an </seg>
            <seg id="p150">115 Hartington The Farmers State Bank :r No. 694. (Inc. Hi \Y 'ant ('ashler \I LIABILITIES k paid in J .i.nDO. «• uinl 1.000.00 a rolltn 5.80*. 11 ri ual deposits subject to Banking house furnltur fixtures . 5.2(3. »« nf de 8,291. 5« .4.379. »» ate banks and and private bank •M.M SI Si. 806 S3 Harvard The Union State Bank 1 tant c"hi"r ATEMEXT XOV MBER LIABILITIES paid In 125.000 0« plus fund 2.6."iO 00 4 ts (net) 1,721 R ■ subject to 64. '.*:.« U xtiflcates of de- 19.S12.42 Kfrom national, state and vate banks and bankers . at deposit... 7S.999 06 nd private banks S3. S3 i </seg>
            <seg id="p151">116 Harvard The Harvard State Bank Incorporated President F Kuenn Her mot M Well resident \V H Horwi Assistant Cashier Total cash on ha 64 and bankers Hastings Wm M. I. own , IT- I &lt;ia— and d nt fip ii banks k- and l^ k.r The B;mk of Commerc </seg>
            <seg id="p152">117 d Mechanics Bank Havelock Thi' FiirniiTs a Pre^iden K Fr Assistant Cashlar Viee-Preslden ATEMENT VEMBEI I.IABILITIE I 11 .» 15.000.0* 4 f 1,500.00 ed pr 2,«03.«7 to ;»r de 4 71 58.381 $1S».1«7 15 l'lif Farmers State Miint Hayes Center Banking house furniture and nxtur 1.41ft 0* d and » </seg>
            <seg id="p153">118 Bank » 8 « i k h ■r II 5. 000. 0» 4.000.0 IH 177.11 M Hay Spring* The F iirmers and Merchants ( Incort BT Taylor , Johansen ! 'lunim*-r A EMBER Lotai and discount - III,! I : . Capital « » paid in S rafts, Hcur plus fund ap SutplUS fU :. divided Banking houae fun dividual depc fliture* heck ■ t *-ip«nws and tax* ■rti ,,a,d rrom nations private hanks and ba 11 ei Tot .Northwestern State Ban Y Incorporated) fharles Wfston L«o J. Rrhlll President W B Mr-Qu. Mcuueei A EJIEXT NOVEMBER RKSC 1«— ■■ and discounts .;* Overdrafts, secured cored . profit Other a»«ft idual d*-pc Banking house furniture 4 Current expenses and taxc Kfrom national state a: rate banks and bankers Checks and Items of ex 3. 331 </seg>
            <seg id="p154">Stale Bank Heartwell The Henrtw 11 i b Barnhard Presid Job Assistant Cashier A R Vice- I STATEMENT NOV MBER 9. 1 ABILITIES :k paid 133 IS ded profit d and u (dual deposits subject to Ml !• ick Banking house furniture and mand certificates of de- De 510.00 posit "••!! me certificates of deposit. . . 5.000. •• urrent expenses and tax 24 Kfrom national, state and vate banks and bankers . 7.358.S7 I15.7J0.71 II County Bank The Thayer • rated) Charter S F M Wetherald President w D Galbrattr ant Cashier Bushnell VIce-Presldent n ITATEMENT N VEM I LIABILITIES RESOURCES Loan, and discount. 1141,854.39 Capital stock paid In $ '»•»»•.•§ .1 stock paid In $ 30,000. ♦• en. rdrafts secured and unse- Surplus fund ,'Sii'ii ,, 1.1(1.1* tndivided profits 1.89».#1 Surplus fund ndlvided profits 1.89».«1 „!„*, ... 4.300.00 Individual deposits subject to Individual deposits subject to check 88.410. «• Banking house 10,000.00 Due from national. »t*te and Demand certificates of de- banks and bankers. . 35.311.19 29.314. »4 po me certiflcates of deposit. . 48,317.4* and items of ex- lime CCrUUi:BLCn 111 uc K vo, t .. ..,.-.... Due to state and private banks and bankers S.tll.iT 8.50 65.00 8.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p155">120 r Assistant Cunla F 4 » i 4S3.M I69.9O«.1« 11.354.8 de 400.4* 496 .50 He mingf ord The First State Bank Incorporated) Barry Preside t K I President Anna M. Pierce STATEMENT NOVEMBER *. 19 I A BIT I 8 « k paid in I ~e» and taxes , in d certificates of d 'n naiional. state and bank« and bank&lt; K9.90C.14 Henderson The Bank of Henderson "harter N Incorporated ?■ i g*^ :•••• f*r STATEMENT NOVEMBER », IMi I.IABILITIE S Bankinic hoiiM furnmr pronis 1,731. 9( .il deposits subject to nl expends and taxc rtlflcatei »• posll "■ iflcal iflcatea of de ■ &gt;- and it* banks and ba 4" and it. 7«.0« 4 V Loan* and discount Banking hotu* furnitu I • I :;.; ,„ I-nan- and d\*r, . Overdraft., secured and ipital «to&lt;k paid [ n . j </seg>
            <seg id="p156">121 Henderson The Farmer* &amp; .Merchants Hank President J J. Kr&lt; President 1 i Neufe Kr int Cashier ME.VT NOVEMBER LIABILITIES SI iS:S U: ur JXC D jsfi.sl' The Farmers State Bank Hendley W T M Pre: Vlce-Pr« int Cashier STATEMENT NOVEMBER RCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts »li.09!i.98 Capital divided pro 47.32 I Individual dep. «Ml( Bank. urnitur 4 Demar l.«91.S4 1.3(t.X Current expe p.1.1 Due fr &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p157">122 Herman The Plateau Bank Prlvat Latta Rurdlc Istant Cuhltr TATEMENT XC VEMBEH 9. 19C t Loans and diKounti k paid In 120,000. •• • rdrafts, secured and . 1, €00.00 rured profits 1.509.14 Banking house furniture an 1,1 . . . M in national, state and 1 &lt;■ mum private banks and bank 334 00 . t deposit. . 50.846 k 3« 14« Hershey The Hank of Lincoln County Incorporated Marti- President \\ Vlre-Preslden ATEMENT N VEMBER UIABILITIB •: fund II M.M Individual de ■ urnitu ut heck 13. 770. IS Demand paid . . 504.31 ittional, ~isit and private banks and bankers. . l.i&gt;an* and discounts. . . $ -&gt;■» and tax f de- 5,010.00 &gt;oslt . 3,2 79.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p158">123 f Ilickman Hickuicin The Bank Charter N I rated) Presider int Cashlar J H Catron VFMBER 9. 190 STATEMENT N LIABILITIES RESOURCES n- and discount. I 75,0(3.98 j Capital »tock paid In |1 J t I!I - I2 ,0 00 King house furniture and Surplus fund J'?SI'JJ (40.00 ! Undivided profits . 3.105. li -urr. nt expenses ' and ' taxes Individual -Meet to ' DB l,j . 34*. 68 check 57.48».Ot -.-&gt;. i,=™. ' 650.00 Demand certificates of de - Demand A. Black Pre.1.1 • • • ; • Black .. President H s Klrkbrld, \-iatant CubMr W. Black . . .MENT Ml LIABILITIES paid in I 10,000. 0» I 1! &gt;flts ubject t (1,4(1.41 Banking house furnitu: J f de 71.(129 9! and tax deposit... ll,iO6 05 nd J159,»J4.(7 !1 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p159">126 The Security State Rank j 4fd ■ W H H \-*slstant ATEMI MBEK IABILITIES Loans and k paid Tdrafts. wcure ded pr Banking houM furni posits gut fltures _p*t ate banks Hooper The Dodge County Hank Lo«»« and d Bankmii hou Individual deposit! sable • 1 rx-mand ,f dep |...d depos m nun private bank* and ba Ohecka and it&lt; 6S.4O </seg>
            <seg id="p160">127 The Hoskins State Bank Hoskins ■porate President John I President Ca nt Cua MEXT Xt&gt;\ LIABILITIES iip J In fund 192.90 I'ndivided profits 4,210 ■1 Individual deposits subject to 31,3(9.11 ertincatds of of deposit . . 45, s ur It The Bank of Howe ...,.i,,, nt Ca»hler Prr LIABILITIES &gt;ck paid 2.000.00 1.708.01 VJ 1 , 1 " house furn! SIL"S profits fixture deposits sub :ji ;iii&lt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p161">128 Howells The Colfax County Bank Incorporated) F. F r n ■ nt A. Fi 74 p;l 4 P I 4 Howells The Howells St*te Bank -nt I Ka !&gt;«&gt;■■■ and d SET ."" -^ar- 1 » </seg>
            <seg id="p162">129 The Hubbard State Bank Hubbard irp&lt; EMENT NOVEMBER .■ABILITIES ock pa lal &gt;U-t i to 5. Hubbell The Hubbell Bank M M HER i A HI 1 I 4.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p163">130 Humboldt The State Bank -16 f Incorporate!! ■ LlAlill.I nal stock pa plu* fund , ur-d I.4C4.M d profit ]ndi\ i«Jua: 4 01 inri certifies it* and i Humphrey The Bank of Ottis A: .Murphy The Bank of on is A: .Murphy &gt;rpor I.IA Loans and Omrtafu, - ]ri) j - t Banking "JTrj" Kfm „,. lf deposit 48,028.1 mn ' Dm and private ! hanker- 1 504 4 - ■ 3« banks m hanfe H3.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p164">131 Huntley The St;it.' Bank of Huntley •rporated Cashier W Pri .nt Cashier A l)i ATEMENT X&lt; Kh LIABILITIES f tt.OOO.M I 1,171. It - subject t 146*2 Kl u '•"••!• d,po..« 434 f prr 933. S' ul banks J.500 0» and The Bank of Hyaimis Hyannis rter N W H Ninkl ant Cashtar \ mbei: ATEMENT N( liabilities paid In 115.000 00 10.0nil.iin rj.lu^ fun'l ■ t.-.l profl 4.731. It l«M"t tO 104.321.21 1,111 k </seg>
            <seg id="p165">132 Imperial Thi' Farmers mid Merchants Bank :XT N&lt; V iMmui and ' Overdraft*, cured KunkiriK I. axturt-K Due from privat*- hanks iin.l l.ai-k- Bank f f Inavalc T M l... B aii &gt; I armao RCES LIABILITIES 4 44 ■ r.nn n private l.. i </seg>
            <seg id="p166">133 Indianola I'h Stal Banl tnt Cashier MBE1 STATEMENT. NOV LIABILITIES RESOl'RCE Lou. and .■ ! " £»«&gt;"•' '"'1-i.ti nd nu Sl "i 1. -.0.1.00 furniture and &gt;'■ ' »1. 8J«. «J it 15.57*. 11 1.377.M 1155.513. «&gt; The Iinmm State Hank rpo rated I ■d. 'aslu&lt;T IF CSallaKlirr Pre«tdent £"?!" r DlrmlnFhim lit \--HtHnt Cashier I" \--Hlant .ashler Blrniinnham STATEMENT. NOV TKMKNT. NOVBMBE1 BMBEI I LIABILITIES I.IAHII.ITIES RESOIRCES Loan and .1 II $«.»••.•• . . $1 ' $•.•••.•• Surplus fuii'l It I'ndh i ...Ml MO ] Surplus fund 01 Km furnitur, Individual mii Indlvlda*] 1 1S.S44.*S ■v. 1 ertfficates or «ifpo»*it CC83.17 urrt^nt exp paid Dlie f private bank* and bank .rrenrv ... I.M4.K 121 I' </seg>
            <seg id="p167">134 IABILITII \ : A.BILITII 4(1 r Tl.. Fanners Slat,. Hank Q. r. Waener F Kinke STAT JIEXT, NOVEMBER 9, IS RESOURCES I t — »" and dlscoun l-ii.- Overdrafts, m-cup Surplu* fund I'ndivided pr uhI d&lt; Baakinc hou fixtures &lt;~*urr»-nt expend paid ■ \- Time cert 12 m natic : t&gt;ank' Currimy and »f,lrt Silver Him penn The Hank of Dakota Count &gt;rpora Ed T. Kearti. C M Kurn. v '■t EJ T. Kearr -President I.ee C. Kearne AT i MENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19C RESOURCE 1. 1 I*oao» and discount.- ,. $ O»«r«rm/ta. secured an Banklnir houne furr k Current expen Df-mand certifl D«e from n»i mna private banks and bank nMh on hand </seg>
            <seg id="p168">135 Kb rdr a liankii ,r urr.TH ex r Johnson J RE r u x IP bar ri The State Bank of Jansen orated) . Prestd -Prexid Assistant Cashier ATEMENT. NOVEMBER 1905. LIABILITIES SOURCES Loans and discounts (39.482.41 | Capital stock paid In $12.000. »• 6J3.60 .nd u 61 Individw 10.918. tl ing house furniture and 10,918. tl 3.300.00 Demand certificates of deposit 4.878. 2i deposit 1 30 ct-r 44.54 h 34 $53,691.97 I irmera Bank of Johnson rpo rated) President nson Vlce-Presld ant Cashier ATEMENT. NOVEMBEF 1 iABILITIES IOURCE itock paid In $15,000.0* I73.314.48 i ap: 9.500.00 urp fund .nd ur 0* Undl ided profits 1.73 1.734. U al deposits subject to 'urnttur Indi Idu ■ck M.MS.42 00 ch and tax Dem; . tate and and bankers 82 71 iichant: 49.0* 68.14 mi certificates of deposit 5,537.01 certificates of deposit .. 1«.15«.M </seg>
            <seg id="p169">136 Johnstown Th.- ( iti/i-ns Bank x 14 (Incorporated) Preald ■n* K. M Holt Hazel M Ho STATEMENT Nl VEMBER 9. 1 I.IARILITIE pital stock r n Surplus fund I'ndivided pro Individual dep* Bank i t I' pa 4 63 r 1 &amp; bank.- The Bank of Julian Incorporated President President M J t STATEMENT. N (V EMBER 9. 18 RCES LIABILITIES I.— ■■ and ■'■ Orerdrafta, secured and Batikinu li..u-&gt; furnitu. '-xpeniuM and Demand certlflcates of depc deposit p* 1 * «s°.o: posit Due from nation.. i.ank. and bank, r- D.4U.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p170">137 The Bank of Juniata Chart.: rated i . President President t x -istant Ca»hl STATKMKXT, NOVEMBER 9. STATEMENT NOVEMBER I.IAR LIABILITIES S94.74 Surplus fund . CO I I'm Individual Surplus fund . ,'76. «0 I'ndlvl Individual Demand oertlfiratr ifl I tW.Tl The Farmer-. Bank of Kearney . . .President \ t STATEMENT. NOVEMBr STATEMENT. NOVEMBEI: I I.I A I LIABILITIES ... , ■ •&gt;- \ &lt;*apital Itoek pal &lt; Surplus fund l.nOO . Ort 445.01 l'ndivided profl! inty nnul • Individual 'I Banking nous.- furniture and * *!"H. 2 fixtures "" Iwtnind certiflca' heck fixture Ttlflcate;* of deposit . 36,94 in national, state and ita banks iind banken 4: 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p171">138 42 #1 «I»-n-o and tax k MM 41 «,06«. It paid Draiin 1-..749 ■ck. ar 4 an eat** 600.00 Nirkeli and •■•-.• 10 Tlic Kenesaw Kxc Batik (Incorporated nt I H . STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 1905. RESOURCE LIABILITIES [nt! (6: 701.71 lid In 110,000.0* furniture and n.i 2. 000. 00 nitures 1.2S0.M 3.086.28 u*eu and tax- &gt; Individual deposits subject 730. S» I check 42.486. It m national, state and Demand certificates of deposit 27,931. M inka and banker- 41.b7J.lt Time certincates of deposit . . 26.275.01 and it-m- or fxrhan*- 1. 155.9* ■m»h i :i«4.72 </seg>
            <seg id="p172">139 Kennard The Farmers sad Merchant* Bank hler Preside -.-.atant Caxhler STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905 LIABILITIES RESOURCES paid in $1 * Iran.. -™ - ,.745.31 Indiv,. Ini house furniture and Individual d, . n nf f7 :;..«;: .;i Tim. m ■u i Kimball Th« Bank of Kimball Charter No. 831. (In . President L. W. Blckel Vice-Presldent C. W. Bi ki I STATEMENT XOVEMBK: RBSOURl LIABILITIES Loans and - ■ - I' uiJ ln * 17 a!U!! uv. rdrafts, seiured and unsr- Surplus fund rure{ | "r&gt; Undivided pronto 3, lianking hou&lt;r furnltur. Individual deposits subject to fixtures 65 Current Demand certificates or deposit 7oa.«i n.irt ,0.20 Time certificates of dtpoxlt .. lO.m.JI n </seg>
            <seg id="p173">140 The Kramer State Hank E M ipf BTATEMKNT NOVEMBER LIAB1I.ITIF Loans and &lt;1i « hOUK re» . . . MS and IAJ .Id The Farmers State Hank l'r. ~i.l.-r \V BTAT1 \IBER LIAB1LITIE 1- 1&gt;2.1* irr.m -ii« 4» •I.I lln&lt; ::«" 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p174">141 The Laurel State Bank T M LIABILITIES RESOURCES ,,oo •Xf S4fi ■111 4 m 00 42 &lt; The State Hank of Lawrenei m )NT, NOVEMBER RESOURCES RESO1 .1 15.401 71 1 46:. 45 4IS 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p175">142 Bank I 'ummir :~nt E. E. D« President J L,. Hortc AMI STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RCES LIABILITIES :...•.- ar Overt r»fts 4&gt; ■sss. "M d The Farmen hikI Merchants Baul i&gt;l M F. Rab R J MrX RESOl'KCES erdraf 1 1 -s.srs </seg>
            <seg id="p176">143 Leigh The -Maple Valle; Bank :&gt;rpo rated STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES 4ti I Lewiston The Hank of Lewiston r XT N&lt; LIAtSILITIK R( depos </seg>
            <seg id="p177">144 Lexington The Lexington Bank VI BE Ft RESOURCES LIABILITIES 1 Surplus fund I'ndlvi 4 4« &lt;■■ iti- Hank of Liberty I.IAHILITIE sti.c &gt;;4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p178">145 I'lif American SavingN Bant Lincoln r IAB1I.1 I IV RES&lt;i Farmers and Merchants ISaiiV Lincoln Alill.lTI </seg>
            <seg id="p179">146 Lindsay ■. TATE.MEXT LIABILITIES id I S urplus fund ur-d Bankln* to flituren pa,d k&gt; Lmdsav The Farm Merchants Bauk P E MrKllUp STATEMENT. NC LIABILITIES RESOURCES «--^»* and dlBcount^ Overdrafts, »ec ur?d anc Banking hou- furnit u - and tax • Demand e*rttflcmtes ot dep&gt; Time certificaits of deposit ,..id I-&lt; ical tender Due from national, state and private banks and bankers Checks and items of exchange S.254 Gold 1.4 The Lindsay State Bank 05 t'ndivided prod 70 Individual depo check N Ot man&lt;! ■ 1 .1 K IV KM HER 9. 19 I tal stock pa: ;nd . . . ided profits unpaid Individual check Uemand certlflrat n: </seg>
            <seg id="p180">147 The Fanners and Merchants Hank Linwood President En Vire-Presldent ATKMENT. NOVEMBER LIABILITIES RESOURCE i »:.» jrofl depo I4».tl 40 M 1-1 Tlie Lit.-hfielc State Hank Litchfleld P' W. T President Engl.ni. in VsslstMM Ca»hl«t Presid STATEMENT. N )VE.\: LIABIL1TIE RESOURCES urplus fu Jr Undivided Individual d iect tc BanklnK h k 11 r ■ i certirtc-a 1 ' t urrent &lt;-xt paid 47 ftBd tiona banks and bankr ha 4 34 I </seg>
            <seg id="p181">148 Lodge Pole riw People'* Hank Long Pine ■ mtv Bank 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p182">149 The Farmers State Bank : STATEMKN LIABILITIES 71 Tin- H;iiik of Lofton STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19C LIABILITIES RCES </seg>
            <seg id="p183">150 Louisville Illlt'l XTEMENT, XOVESIHKH I Loup City Bank NOVEMBER IABI I ur xp Dn« from national n </seg>
            <seg id="p184">151 The liiink of Lushton KMBKIi LIABILITIES ms . s ;ind ■&gt;f de- ll 4.S4».«t •■' • Tin- Bank of Lynch EMENT. N&lt; iVEMBEIt LIABILITIES ,id In fl dual dei flcat </seg>
            <seg id="p185">152 The I" ;i Valley Hunk III STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESO' LIABILITIES Individual .l.| The Farmers liHiik » 1 STATEMENT NOVEMBER RCES LIABILITIES nk </seg>
            <seg id="p186">153 McCook Tlie Citizens Hank IT w ATK.MKXT. NOVEMBER LIABILITIES P McCool Junction The Blue River Bank T STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1!" LIAB1 1 pr sll </seg>
            <seg id="p187">154 McCool Junction The Farmei Merchants Bai 1'reMdent r President \V iCMENT, NOVEMBER RESOURCES ur. 43 Hank ■at T B. 2 ATEMENT. NOVEMHEK UEPOi LIABILITIES a 138.44 lnd i.i rn 00 check 14.449 45 Dpmari'i 54».«7 | posit ... . 00 Timf of deposit . 7,274. IT </seg>
            <seg id="p188">155 utant STATEMEX MliEK LIABILITIES RESOURCE? n. Madison i' LIABILITIES M « 12 Deman'l d e " . 34. i:.«. 4S p«»it 43 i State Bank Phe Madison State Bai STATE.MEN I BER 9. 190 UESOURC • fun fled lual c </seg>
            <seg id="p189">156 Madrid 'I'ln- Madrid Exchange Banl \TEMEXT NOVI rhe Mavrnet State l?;mt TATKMKXT. NOVEMBEI ■ 'KCF k I &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p190">157 Malmo The Farmers and Merchants Hank Marquett F«ii </seg>
            <seg id="p191">158 Martmsburg Tin* Martinaburf linn! President M. I Mel ! Jeff* 3t»nt LIABILITIES and -ftK &gt; Mason City The .Mason City Banking ( 'barter X Inrorpera Mar STATl RESO1 LIABILITIES and di* &lt; 'a pii al - drafts. s« ( ur.-'i «n&lt;! Surplus I'n&lt;li\ U ndi\ idual dep real estate HT.14 U-mand •M.« po: and banks and bank- Mfl of </seg>
            <seg id="p192">159 a E 4t.II Jl M ■t Mason City The First State Bank * k LIABILITI RESOURCES pr x IJu a: The Maxwell State Bank Maxwell W H M P un&lt; KMh RESOURCES I.IAIHI.IT 94S.C8 ' I led prc .rdr Banking flxtur Current expen-.-- and taxes posit i.u» n.lrt mle •■«'«i«- 3.14 ip paid Due from na \"T NOVEMBER C7 Individual d»i - t to check 00 Demand certificai - </seg>
            <seg id="p193">160 Maywood The St.itc Ifnnk of Maw r IAMII.I The Bank of Mead </seg>
            <seg id="p194">161 Meadow Grove Meadow Gn '•■ Hi Meadow Grove The Security Bnnl Bunk I LIABILITIES RCES </seg>
            <seg id="p195">162 Memphis The Bank of Memphis Incorporated) I -it Ca*hi»r STATEMENT. NC VE.MBER 9. 19 RESOURCES LIABILITIES fioaiw and d f { &gt;pl Overdrafts cured .. urplus fund ■ i proft I* 00 Inc ■dividual deposits sufc check Banking house furnitu flitures 1,300 I demand certiflcat«a of d ime certiflcatea of depo Current expenses paid and taxes Time cert 1,020.29 I tti nalioi. and 11.(4*. 52 banks and bankers 11.S46 11 Checks and Items ■ 11.65 Merna Bank of Merna Charter No 6&lt;-4 harter Inrorpi f. F, I K W r J M Klmbertlai J II Km \ Ki STATEMENT. NOVEMBER STATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loan* and &lt;! 173.3; 1.94 i Capital ■ Loan» and (1 173,321. &gt;4 aplm Overdraft*, secured and unite- rplua f ■rdraft&gt; Surplus f ... 75. »« Indlvldei Undivided prol Individual del - Iioukc furniture and Indlvldua Bitur^. 100.00 heck ■ tional. Ktate and niand cer po^it 21.481.04 banks and bankers 35.550 54 2.SK.00 t.i2 </seg>
            <seg id="p196">163 The Home Ban! f M int CashMf IT STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 1 RESOURCES LIABILITIES »1 15 apital stack paid In »1C 8:5 ided profit: ;i6 Banking house fu fixtures 300 00 tdual deposits subject to 9.". nt expe Demand certlflcates of deposit J8S.8O 49 Due from nation private banks rhprk« and item nd bankers 14 03 4 134 « The Anchor Bank Merriman M Assistant STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 19 LIABILITIES RESOURCES , unt , 138.383.76 Capital stock paid in .... »l: id and uns&lt; plus fund \ id.*- d profit 4 house furniture^d ur rk 1UI flcates E.n, expenses and taxes Tim. ««««- o private banks and bankers 25.798.53 vtal cash on hand 2.2.1. 4C </seg>
            <seg id="p197">164 Milford flu' Nebraska State Hank i NT NOV IN- ABILITIES ord Farmers and Merchants Bank i ■-.OVEMBEK LIABILITII 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p198">165 The German Bank of Millanl : STATEMENT. NOVEMBER LIABILITIES I 4.. The First I4iiuk of Miller Hr - EMENT. NOVEMBER LIABI1 &gt;;i Fra </seg>
            <seg id="p199">166 The H Miler &gt;d : Madd Maddn; M ■ 4 Onrd rafts ■ Banklnc Milligam The Farmer? n\\&lt;\ Merchants Bank * In^orpors Prank w Sloan - imoui President Vlo&lt;"-Pr ATEMEXT. N VEMBEF RESOl'RCES LIABILITIES Isommm and d 144,379 Capital stock paid Surplus fund Overdraft cured Banking how furnitur* and flzturcs 2,500.00 * &lt; Current expen»ee and taxes Demand and time Of ■!■ :- paid 1 521 .18 Due from national, xtat*- and private banki and bankers &lt;.442 Chceki and itemi of cirliint' 4*8.93 I l"n&lt;iiMi]..l profits Individual ,500.00 check </seg>
            <seg id="p200">167 Minatare The Minatare Bank porated Pr • ATEMENT. N RESOURCES ABI1.ITIE 1».4» I 24 and taxe: -'.030.(3 t deposit . - 5,35». 74 id priv il h 84 |4I S4 The Minden Exchange Bank Minden Charter N Incorporated) President K Klngsley P. Kin K -id»nt Roblson ITATEMKNT N IV EMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES i.ns and dl^rou erdrafts, aecuri apitai slock paid In »30,000.0« Surplus fund S.24J.4* nd u: •03.11 ured • 6 Undivided pr Banking house furniture and fixtures Individual deposits subject to check 122.511. (4 80 Current expenses and Demand certificates of deposit 76.869 10 SO i.B ■ms :om national, state and private banks and bankers jll cash on hand 16.689.49 Check! and Items of exch </seg>
            <seg id="p201">168 Monowi The Monowi Slat.' Bank EM EN ifBEK I.U Banking • •Incorpora STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESO1 I.IAHIL.IJ I U *"■«£:■' " iture " d - MkOT rr«] t &lt;1 certi m» .-rtincaten of deposit 44 11.4.5.64 ,Zt PHV "' pii\ate banks anc 4s:, ..-,&lt; T. The K;mk of Monroe </seg>
            <seg id="p202">169 Moorefield The I MiMiivfielil i A HI I. IT 1 1 I 4 I Morse Bluff The Bank of Morse Bluff » « M \1 VTEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 1 I.IAI'.lI.lTIt plus fun </seg>
            <seg id="p203">170 Mount Clare The Mount Clare State Bank M President 2 M Y } ildent STATEMENT, N&lt; RESOURCES LIAB ILITIES and dlsronnti ... 1 J.365.17 1'apltal stock paid 0 id Surplus fund 424. 0» Undivided profl s urn da unpai 100.00 Individual dept exp paid check ii 341.22 Demand certiflcat* rt from natior private banks and bank 3,117 ■ 1 7 T he Bank of Mullen rt r Incorporated ■ I ■idem 4 STATE ME NT. NOVEMBER 9. 1 LIABI LITIES Loaai and di I and rplus fund irted p Kinc hou lndi\idual depc heck Current exp nd tax Time certlflc; r&gt;ue from national, state and private banks and ba n ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p204">171 Murdock The Hank of Murdock arter Incorporated) r: Prf!&gt;ld&lt; N&gt; - STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905. RESOfRCES LIABILITIES stock paid in II i fund rd Ml 1,001. Jl 1 dual deposits 21,175 «• and and tlm 11.877.14 paid »:i Murdock The Union State Bank Incorporated) g President F' S Crlnk V STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOfRCES LIABILITIES I In SurDlu&lt; fun i ' S 41 md taxes at deposit II 49.15 Tim. - of depi ;in&lt;i 4 4S »1 II </seg>
            <seg id="p205"/>
            <seg id="p206">173 i ,\ I AIM ["he \ State Ban) Naponee MEN I AIMI.ITIB &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p207">174 Nebraska City The Farmers Banl Incorporated l M £ tant STATEMENT NOVEMBEI RESOURCES LIABILITIES 1-oans and d 4 I and ur urpl 4 i Banking house furnnur Oiture. 2.749.50 k Due from national, state anc 1.8 Checks and items of exc 14.74 Certified check 13,160.00 I l .it*- and private urrenr 5.211. »4 It The Nehaw ka Bank rp M Stone . P Sheldon ' Vice-Presldent nt ■ «hlef STATEMENT, NOV EM HE I. RESOURCES LIABILITIES Lous and discounts 1135,778.00 Capital xtock paid Ir rdrafts, secured and 6:.». 14 : pn.tit- Bankins; hous. furniture and 4.121.61 dual ■!■ j urrt-nt tip nd tax k paid 45!.. 50 !■■ in.ttiil cert posit 13.93 lit . rasa national, state and Time private banks and bankers 27.4 7.161.11 </seg>
            <seg id="p208">175 Neligh Th.&gt; At as Bank Drpo rated) 0- Pr Payne Cashl« Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9, 19 MAHILITIE KKSOURCES and un fund H ture anc KT r a i: p« n*. - I2M.IM »( Tlif Commercial Bank Incorporated J K Parson Preald I J W Cashier int Cashier Vice-president STATEMENT. N&lt; EMBER 9. 1905 LIABILITIES RESOURCES _x&gt;ans and discount: &lt;68.»14 apltal stock paid in K5.000.00 Overdrafts, secured and unse - cured Surplus fund .... . 9,000.00 418.06 ndivided profits 2.679.34 ks. securities, judgments. dividual depo-. 50 36.(31. S2 10,500.00 Demand certiflcate» of deposit 25,042.74 Due to state and private Banking house furniture and fixtures Current expenses and taxes 00 banks and bankers 35.241.12 paid Premium on U. S. and other 944.98 and securlt 119 Due from national, state and itiual depo.sitx subi- ■ck . . 106,812.48 ind certiflcar a 7.74J.J5 _'is.»: </seg>
            <seg id="p209">176 The Hank of Wmaha : r ILITII 14.933.83 f.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p210">177 Newcastle The Newcastle State Bank rter N Incorporated* President President Cashier ant Cash Mr ATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 LIABILITIES (118,88. . 115,000. •• pr 842.lt Individual deu 41, 50&lt;lt B IBeatps of deposit 6,«9!.1» 41. H 44 Newman Grove The Newman Hate Hank ar ATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9 RESOURCES LIABILITIES m oo tM.M 841 subject t:\ </seg>
            <seg id="p211">178 nt Cashier ILITIE M4.*M l ILITIE il .I.JfUt 1 po It . . 1 nk 4 John I nt | A A. Qaii Duffle H»» 1 ■■■■.•■• Vxslstant i STATEMENT. NOVEMBEF RESOURCES LI A L&lt;a*aa and di»countx 11.41 I'apital stock pal ' &gt;i and un» Surplus fund 1,462.02 I'ni1viii--d pr.jtit Banking hou**- furniture and Ilitur* - Individual 2,2(2. OS check - and iaxi P«ld Tim»- rertincatt- 849.33 Due to national b; Dae from national. Mtate and private bank'' and banker' t.*lt.t&lt; I hani; 4»S 41 Newport The Rock County State Bank Char: ' Incorporated C M Thomp«&lt;i: STATEMENT N&lt; IV KM HER S. 190.-, RESOIH' LIA1 Loana and k I 111 " nid H..nkinn houiw furnmir.- a no paid 144 . banks and bankers 1.11 tl . . J4 Total . Newport The Newport State Hank Charter No. 644 (Incorporated; </seg>
            <seg id="p212">179 Nickerson The First Bank of Niekenon Nickerson Oiart- I artt-r -N'-i W -I founriKhi Prf-std^nt H .1. S W J &lt;\iurtriifht It. -i. lent H L M K'-fii'- Vice-President A \V Sprlch M Km. Vlee-Presld I A \V STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 190.V NOVEMBER 9. 190." ATEMENT RESOURCES LIABILITIES RESOl'RCI LIABILITIES »n« and discounts I17.i»«.»« j . k paid in . »^ and discounts MT.tM 9« I k |iai.l In &lt;»vrrdrafts. secured and unse- I ndiviiied profits cured 4l'O 58 lmlivhlual deposits «ul ured and unse- . Undivided pront~ l.(39.4&lt; 4 I'll BankinK h&lt;iu-&lt;t- furnlturf and nxlur- - (H Denial and 46 I Denial' Tim. 17 «'urr*-ni Tim - paid I&gt;u»- frnm nt I rival' 1 :,i&gt;7. It It IVS.7S9.4:; t Niobrara The Niohrara Valley Bank Niobrara The Niobrar I Valley Iiaiik rhartpr N'o L'sr. (Iacorpofmt«d) Incorporated artcr Nc y \.i--tt ■ -President Presld W. Chambi II. C. X.-I.«on . . nt ■nt Vlt-.'-Pr&lt;-sldfnt i M C N. ls..n Vire-Presid int Ca STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9 5VEMBER 9. 190.' RESOURCES LIABILITIES RESOURCES LIABILITIES and discountn $S«.8«7.JI Capital stock paid in II.IS.S67 k paid In li overdraft*, secured and unse- individt-d prnntx profits 3,248.39 I Individual deptwlt» subject t 3.248 39 furniture and Hunkin l&gt;emand certtflca: Time certiflcate.x of deposit . . M ■ III! &lt; I. state and private banks and bankers 18,040.41 tined cheeks xchanfee 4&lt;5 L&gt;ue to national banks 60. « »•_&gt; Due to state and private hanks and banker- 1.031 . 1 « </seg>
            <seg id="p213">180 Norden The Bank of Norden 1 1 H. W. Logan Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NC V EMIJEi LIAB1LITIE Banking boa fixture -in nalioi • banks 4 i ht-rks and it*-n m-r ■oin ■ foin »nd cent North Bend The ! Bank t" r Harvit \\ STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 19 HE SO LIABILITIES 1 ia«i and dl •afts, B 1 liank.nt I, 43.391.4 4 D«c from natior prlrale banK TihanK Oold and &lt;u- nit k. 1- and </seg>
            <seg id="p214">181 CM* Anlitint Cashier LIABILITIES t5.D99.O» 1.090 .00 S.tvt.SJ dual 'i ject to 38.l4i.ST iflcates of deposit 4.JS5.8I ates of deposit 5t0» 41 •5S.tSl.D4 North Platte The McDonald State Bank harter No. 647 Incorporated McDonald President W H McDonald Cashier Assistant Cashier EMBER 9. 1905. STATEMENT. NC V RCES I.IARII.ITIES Loans and discounts t231.029.t9 Capital Overdrafts, sei ured and amxa- Surplus fund Overdrafts, secured and un»- Surplus fund «.oo«.o» cured 1,878.79 | Undivided profits JJ.41J.Ji in* hou . furniture and Individual deposits subject to ,„, 17.000.00 ch. 115.591. 7t Banking hou ■ furr fixtures ■&lt;k Demand certificates of deposit 7.S1I.J4 Other real Time certificates of deposit 109.tIS.17 xpr pjjld 3,558.11 Due to state and private UK from national, state and banks and bankers 11,011 il paid e banks and bankers 84,04 Checks and items of exchar 2.044 » I II . *50.»M.»* fund 6.000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p215">182 IES i .r E ■P 1.019.4 The Scroggin &amp; Co. Bank *hart»r No SS4 'I'rivat ■ -■ roHKln A STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILIT Loan« and di- l.ital mock paid in Jl &gt;v«-rdrafts. i*»M-ur*-d and uns*-- i Surplus fund rur*d I Individed profits Banklnc haw furniture and Individual inj«-t t ««tu- l:.1(M).»0 ch«k . flxtur** m national. Matt and urmand icrtiflcates of drpoilt 1.7 .!«■ tanks and Lank. J.4 « im!h The Antelope County Bank | rat«(l \ ii Bo -Hldent W H M STATEME ;.VT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 IRCF LIABILTTI LottJiK and &lt;1 Banklnc h. ... I 445. J« Capital M Surplus fund l'ndi\ld*-d profi lndi\idual depositK nut flitur.-* &lt;'h«-fk urT«-nt . xp.ns.s and lax Demand certlfic Tim*- «-t-rtiflcate» of d«»t tram nations private banki and bankers 4 4 4' 4 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p216">183 The Oakdale Bank Oakdale "harter N" Incorporated Cashier President W. Park Payne President ITiestly VIce-President Assistant Ca»hl«r \V Priestly I) V N EMBER 9. 1905 STATEMENT. NOV LIABILITIES RESOURCE k paid In 113.000. •• t »v 1, 500.0* Surplus full' I'ndivid^d i ■d and tianking house furniture and Individual deposits subject to 42.341. *1 heck Time certificates of deposit . 47.947.«* and t from national, state and rate banks and banken 19.41'J ika and bankers 19.412.1 1107.821.24 J4 Total Merchants Bank Oakland The Farmers anil Prtvata) "harter N X.- VIce-President EMBER 9. 1905. LIABILITIES RESOURCES apital stock paid In $25.09*. •• $163,390. 71 nd discounts arplu* fund drafts, secured and un« ndivided pront 8.20$. J4 1.1 urt-d Individual deposits sut. i Banking house furniture and 1 74 Demand certificates of deposit J, 780. 48 Time oertlfieates of deposit . . 161.*»$.51 r items from national, state and tlvate banks and bankers 110.478.32 1 cash on hand 7.«23.31 _&lt;1 Vtce-Pl President il A U Neumann Su*l!!* r Presld. Neumann Assistant «^«hier STATEMENT. NOV futures *•*" urrent fipfnMi and ttiti n— Id l.««4 .Vk u.m. 153 </seg>
            <seg id="p217">184 1 « 8 T s Oakland The Bank of \. E. Wells &amp; Co charter No 89. (Private STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19 RESOURCES LIABILITIE L. k Hi Jr ured and BanktiK ubject to 34 • cured and 1 profl S.S94.68 rolliHtionp to be remitted S3 6 national,' state and kasjka and bankers 13,022.11 and items of exchange 2,(89.42 1,410. «0 Oold and sj 694.73 Loan« and discounl- t ■ ■"' paid in »T J73.644 _ The Oeoato State Bank Charter No. 722. (Incorporated) I '■■ • Robtnson . . \ K t- Pr«slden1 CM* Assistant Cash STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905. R [ESO 51F LIABII riES - house furniture and Bilur. expenses and taxes 2.953.37 1.301. 3i 2.427. tl Individual deposits subject to check 35,722.3 Demand certificates of deposit 1.915.* Time certificates of deposit . . 11,503.2 Due to national banks 1,333.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p218">185 10, 194. II t 4 «ie.l39.4 rant Cash i 100 00 1 t 4 Th€ K iriiii-rs Bank rporated r N Pre iid nt .1 V 1 fresid nt STATE.MEN NOVEMBER 9. 1 LIABILITIES RESOURCE k paid in }5.000 I discoun ured and u d profi 471 14J.93 Individual deposits subject t cured 149 Banking house furniture and li fixture -&lt; ; ■ . rtiflcates of deposi urniture and .if dep* IU 477 Current ;ind taxe&gt; paid 289.28 £ :a.«h items Due from national, state and private banks and bankers 4.064.87 unJ i d bankers 4.0C4 Currency 2.087.00 54.95 4 Total . »1«.13'.. I1S.1J'.' 4 Octavia Octavia The Octavia State Bank The Oct avia State Bank Chart- (Incorporated) arter Nc 1 ( Incorporated* P H ['iidikc I r ■'•'' « V esident K \ Hu Oeo Hahn *«M Id STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905. STATESIE." NT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES RESOURCE LIABILITIES Loans and discount- I ■'»' stotk P aid " capital stock paid In surplus fund Loans and d l Overdrafts, secured and un-e- burplus fund cure d 25.53 I nuivided proii Overdrafts, secured and u cured Undivided profit Individual dvpo Banking housW furniture and Individual nature* check ubject 4 4.23 check .4,550 i i deposit 5,099.1 Current expenses and r»emand certincatej ofdjjjoi paid 89S a'l Tim ; certificates of deposit 96.50 Tim? certificates of deposit . . 13,018 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers - and Items of exc « </seg>
            <seg id="p219">Cashier Cashier 1 ao !«» 00 45 14 191 14 Ml «&lt; ,7 M 107. It Cashier Cashier Assistant LIABILITIES (1 HankinK house furnitu' Mlur. - Demand 1" roin national bank 6 .If Tot»l JS8.9I3 S Ogalalla The Kxchmiy*' Hank 4 I Incorporated &gt; IT. -!.l J W. Welpton Wftherwai \ STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 19C SI Individual dtp.. situ subject to Banklnc h. 0" l&gt;*-man&gt;i of deposit Time e*»rtiflcates of deposit . . 1 gg C*ahl*r'« checks outstanding i t fxpenses and tax. prlvatr i.ank- and bai »( • 1.T4S 3.1*4 1107. K paid In 1'ndi Individual di-posita subject tc k RESOURCES LIABILITIES I*o«b» and discount* H'.Ut.II &lt;°apltal stock paid In Surplus fund 37h «T 1 adlvMad |ir»ni&gt; ■••*■ 1.400. no Individual deposits subject P»'&lt;l I.«57 II I TMul </seg>
            <seg id="p220">187 The First State Bank Ogalalla r Pit Incorporated ) SI. MarLfar Ca*.l.r Assistant Cashier Vice-Preside STATEMENT NOVEMBER .. 1905. RESOURCES ICES LIABILITIES LIABILITIES and discounts $20,674 ».■&gt; • T I II paid In k paid in $ 1".0«0 . •&gt;• id unsi- surplus fund 1.000. 188.85 i ndlvided profit." 2.8«1. tirplu* fund ... 1.000. ♦♦ rdrafts, secured and unne Ht-d profits S«l ure and Individual BbJ«ct to cktet 14.534. .lual" deposit!* sub: Banking house furniture and k 14.534.13 flxturei iirrent expenses and taxei A taxes -rtlncates of deposit 304. 2.106. OS Tim.- certificates of deposit . 3.520. ■rtlflcate* of deposit 304.00 tidcates of deposit 3.520.71 1( ate and itate an banks and bankers 3.941 bankers 3.941. n 1 -' ks and items of exchange 42 xchanire 42. 7» 1.0B4.0.. •73.34 HS4 IN. II Total $32.2:10 | The Bank of Ohiowa The Batik f Ohiowa Ohiowa &lt; mart.: i Inoirporatedl Incorporated riMlnl K J B* •■■ r Cash IT w. B limerick ■ tnt Tashler r.i rash STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905 EMBER 9. 190 ATEMENT. SOV RCES LIABILITIES LIABILITIES RESOURCES }i. paid in 11.1. 000 paid in I..&gt;ans and discount- " nd u Pl»" fund It I'ndlvlded profits l.JOS rplus fund 10.«"« M rdrafts. secured and ur I.MI H 411 I'ndivld. cured ture and ' i virtual depo»lt« subject to I check 50.97. Individual depositl subject t Hankin flxtur furnitui 35 k id taxes Kind certificate* nf deposit 33.3«4 33.10 Time certificates of deposit 50.J11 nd certificate" of deposit 33.3«4.15 urrent expenses and tax paid 1" from national, state and je from national, state anu private banks and bank ks and items of exchange *5.80 n </seg>
            <seg id="p221">188 The City Savings Bank (Incorporated Pr. A STATEMENT. NC JV EMBER 9. 1 LTACILITIE l^oan- anil Aftaeounta secured I ran pital stock jiakl In I I fund TOTUU ' hool. - Individ. Individual deposits on book 4 4 lateral loans i&gt;.-»t». collateral loans «9.741 . 1 7 3 ' 8O , Banking house furniture and Tin; ieposlt . l i&gt;.-»u. collateral loans «». 741 .17 of deposit Banking house furniture and leposlt 1 iiepo natures ft expenses and tun nses and taxes ! banks -n national, state I banks and bank m national, state and ■,ks and ba- .»nd Items . GaM an sT Omaha Omaha The ,1. L. JJraixi ns. Bankers The J. L. Brandt Incorporated ■ President Kmil Brand, i- Cashier H. Brandels &gt; .„ Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 19 iCRCI I-IABILITIE 112 Individual *»■*■ ::■:,).■■ II </seg>
            <seg id="p222">189 The Exehange Bank •ant Cashier STATEMENT NO 'RCES LIABILITIES 157. 7» 77,91*. M Oi chard The Orchar I I tank EMENT, SOVEMBE I!( 1)3" 01 s 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p223">190 |lf.«l Total IK Orchard The Citizens State Bank ( Incorporated . 'avidM&gt;ri nt Am tant Ca STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 190 RESOURCE- LIABILITIES l..ian- and di HSi.OM) ■ k paid ln&lt;iivid»*d profits $10.0 4 31 Individual d bject t Bankinic house furniture and k lo llltur. 1,0 &lt;urren,t expensea and taxes Time certificates of deposl ;ind iiill- rediscounted 4 pa 1 451 m national, state and U SIT private banks and bankers 2,202 and Items of exchange 1,021 1.24i&gt; nickel* and penr. is N on 66 Orchard The Farmers State Bank Charter No S43 (Inrorpormled I ID Thornton at s n TTm1»B Jr Oasl 1. Wattle. ! Assl.tant ' V,.| STATEMENT. KGVBMBBI RESOI'H I LIABILITIES luu lid dlmuou »13,5SS.4!&gt; Capital ntoek paid In jv«rdraft». -.&lt; ur.-.l and luld^d profit^ Individual drpOKlU subject l" Hankinc house furniture and nilur.^ (&gt;f deposit -urrent expenxs and taxes leposlt U.6J9 I***" uitlonal tianks Cl state and ■ banks and bankers 1.307.(2 44C.OO ". ;i . 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p224">191 The Ord Sta State Bank irter X.. Bit (Im Incorporated &gt; harter N President Vi nt A. Vincent Kok' A s Rogers And* STATE. ITEX1 RESOURCE LIABILITIES k paid in I jrofl 7.144.13 53.I!' subject and m.«»s.it&gt; . . .. 1 tlx and l&gt;i i- In tie from national. state and 15.548 n hanks and banker; ZS.577.4J and privat e«U ■ anil ilems of exrhanKe ,-1 banker; I msr i:i The Bank of The Bank f Orleans harter Ma 111 (I harter N t I ncorporated . lit H itti Cashier . VUr-Presldent \V Mean nwell. .Ir Assistant I ATEMENT. XOVE EMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCE LIABILITIES ;&lt;"-k paid in J. rrdraftK. secured and un.* ured r . . . . 1.747 Individual deposits subject to Banking house furniture and fixtures i Demand certificates of deposit M,*14.I1 Due from national, state i private banks and bant 14 and items of exc urren. * AZ n </seg>
            <seg id="p225">192 The Citizens State Bank rated) President \1 ice-Presldrm BTATEMENT. NOVEMBER xp. The Osceola Hank LIABILITI IS 84 ■ 16 It </seg>
            <seg id="p226">Oshkosh The Deucl County Bank urlt I. c Incorporated) T J. W. Wehc President C. H- Burk . . - Ca-sMer Vice-President J. H \Whn \--istant Cashier TA T EMENT NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIAE ILITIF 121, 506. 41 Capita] stock paid in II. ■ rdra 01 Individual di i Ranking 41 ttxtur 947.41 1,501 and private «13.70 hanks and I lt.il -r ks 144.141 144.141 53 Thp Farmen State Bank Osmond (Incorporated) porated) ... President i ashler President i 'ashler M F' v T.int iTEME.VT NOVEMBER 9. 1 A U MBER 9, 19 ll'RCES LIABILITIES LIAI ILITIES ■ (92 fapital stock paid In Ill t.92 Capital stock paid in $ and w Undivided profit ■ "&gt;.4« In.l to u 90. 4« I Iniii&gt; Judcw 270.51 Hrmand . niture and I4(.«l i taxc T: </seg>
            <seg id="p227">194 Osmond The Security State Bank (Incorporated) A J STATEMENT N ■V EMBER 9, 190 ABILITIES RESOURCE J-t'i.0S6 apilal at Surplus fuiu 4 ured CM Banking house' furnitur rotjs national, state an private banks and banker* IS .US S64.994 Overton The Overton State Bank Charter No. 876 (Incorporated EME.VT N"C V EMBER RESOURCE I-IABILITIES Loans and discounts $12. Ml r Bankinc; house furniture and Undivided p 44 fixtures »75.4f Individual depoatta sub check . nt expenses and tare: H.474 paid . . 180. JO Cub items 2.8&gt;0.0« Due from national, state and ua private banks and banker* 1 1.332.3* ash on hand 4.744. 10 E 3, (MO. 00 .heck ■••• and ta*e» Demand .. II I Darner I I &gt;arner PtmM Dfman-1 certificates of depc Time certificates -&gt;f deposit </seg>
            <seg id="p228">195 Oxford The Bank ank of Ox Inn I er N (Incorj Matthew H President nshi'-r Vice-Presid ATEMENT N V h MIIEH 9, 1906 RESOURCE LIABILITIES ««i" and discounts $12,407.15 Capital stock paid in rdrafts, secured and unse- surplus fund . . jred 4.57 Undivided proflta iking house furniture and Individual deposi ilividual deposits subject to Hitures ... check Undivided profit Individual depot 145.lt urities, Jud check Bukl Demand 943 certiflt ip. I- private banks and Iwrtin xpenses and taxes ,nd certificates of dep... ■ rtlfloates of dr(. </seg>
            <seg id="p229">196 The Frenchman Valley Bank Charter No Ml Incorporated) A J Vennum President R. J. Vennum S P Wnnum - -aldent Assistant Cashier STATEMENT NOVEMBER ». l»06 RESOURCES LIABILITIES «.t2 Individual deposits subject t 4 ■ expenses and tales •■ ■••■ ii-mati'i posit 14.001.17 it . . 5.425.00 ' incates of dt-p »4 l.rnai. banks and banK ■ ••h on hand |M.59t.5fc I Total The Palmer State Bank 'harter I Incorporated President H .! STATEMENT XOV t UIIEU 9. LIABILITIES RESOURCES Utu and diKrounts 148.042.88 "apltal stock paid Surplus fund . . . . i ■ ■. . rdr. - and un 1.331. 41 ur-d 25J.J Bankinff houxe furniture and futures 1,500.00 nxtures 4 6 i and nx Demand certificates of den - rtlficates of deposit paid r.3»6: 13.-. 18 ■ii national, state and ate banks and bankers 13 Checks and Items of exchange 318 ■ : nickels and [»i-n- 1.1(4 l...ans and di- M4.5J0.20 I'apltal - overdraft.. «-cor«l and tV"?. 1 ".^ I"" 1 . 4C1.S5 Undivided profl Hanking ho«w» furniture' and Individual depoi ,ii.ni»l. «tate and Undivided profits . Individual deposit* &gt;buject u </seg>
            <seg id="p230">197 Palmyra The Bank of Palmyra harter M Incorporated* President I. H. Matron. Jr Cashier J. H. Catron I Enyart Vice-Prestdent Bert I Hshi*-r STATEMENT NOV EMBER 9. 190 LIABILITIES RESOURCES Loans and discounts 168,444 apital stock paid in Slo.uOO.OA Surplus fund - 000.90 Overdrafts, secured and u cured 718.84 Undivided profit* 499.0: Individual deposits subject to Banking house furniture and fixtures 400.00 check 61.388.33 Demand certificates of deposit 8,428.44 Current expenses and tax€ paid 4 Time certificates nf deposit . . .'9.036.07 Special Due from national, stat private banks and bankers 37.121.54 - and Items of exchanpt' 806.95 Charles Marshall Samuel Tilton . . President John T M 'ashler Vice-President iiit cashier STATEMENT NOV EMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES LIABILITIES I70.5K.17 Loans and di apital stock paid l« ...... 110.000.00 irafis. secured and uns cur Surplui fund .. 3,000.0* iss.ns Undivided pronto 1,201.83 Kin* hou*e furniture and Individual di 3,300 11.(11. fl 747 in national, state and private banks and bankers 18 438.74 a and tax ru-mand certificate 4«.»8 </seg>
            <seg id="p231">198 1 4 1.74 I 4.104 4 IT4.4S 011.84 4 14 Papillion The Banking House &lt;if A. W. Clarke I'rtvate A W Oark Own ■r ATKkKNT MBER 9. IS LIABIL.ITIE Ixuns and d $88,545 1.21* 'al.ilal stock paid in Surplus fund s ; and un •S I'ndivided profits .... Individual Stocks, securities. Judgment 050 00 Banking house furniture and •xtwi Demand certificates of deposl •• Time certificates of deposit . 8,336 13, 7H &gt;ther real e«tat M.&gt; ?!-•-- and taxes paid 1,810 paid E (40.41 Ktate and .ind bankers 7J.11S.0S Total • »4 In4 47 ] Total . »2 Peru The (it ,\e Bank &lt;. Incorporated) Jacob Good President I Ellis E Good B. T. M.Adan \ ice-President | O. If. Good Assistant STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 1905 -OURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts $78,220.65 ! Capital stock paid In | Overdrafts, secured and unse- 10!. i: Bmnklnir home furniture and ublect to fii'u' 3.525.0" r-al estate •••.CO IVmand of deposit Current expenses and taxes to national banks ■ national, state and private banks and bankers 20.S91.29 To tm ' cash on hand 4 414 Ti </seg>
            <seg id="p232">199 176.295.95 Petersburg The Bank of Petersburg arter No. «31 President Cashier Vice-president Assistant Cashier STATEMENT N 3V EMBER 9, 190 RBSOURCE Loans and discounts Overdrafts, •* pital stock paid in 124,000.00 plus fund 4.800.00 idivided profits Banking: house furniture an fixtures Current expenses and taxe 4.S he fk .. 48.U5.S3 H4 pa,, Time certificates of deposit . . 45,883.81 'ash items m nati bankers 9.7C4 nd • tal (Incorporated) F. Jouvenat i*. W. Dimick LIABILITIES Individual &lt;i- :^ c t to Demand certificate-; ..f deposit Petersburg The Citizens State Bank Charter No. «21 (Incorporate*) President .7 J. I'ary Cashier n Mescher Vice-President C W. Schafer Assistant Cashier STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOUR' I LIABILITIES ti and discoui . 157.668. 20 1'apital stock paid In (11,200.00 lrafts, secured and unse- Surplus fund 178.00 ed 1,6*1.10 I'ndlvlded pronts 810.75 ing house furniture and Individual deposits subject to 2.123.01 check 22,734.08 nt expenses and . taxes Demand certificates of deposit 17«.95 Time certificates of deposit . . 39,124.11) from national, state and L-ate banks and bankers 10,662.31 i hand 3.957.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p233">200 Phillips The Bank of Phillips Charter No. 583 (Incorporated i President Vice-President Harry Peard Assistant Cashier STATEMENT NOV EMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts I35.S1S 'apital stock paid in |1 raftit, secured and udh Surplus fund eared 7,m Undivided pn Banking house furniture and Individual d idlvidual deposits subject to check 42.5«S Bxtures 2. 500. 00 Other real estate 990.00 Demand certlnc p, Current expenses and taxes Time certifl&lt;-ates of deposit . 8.8(5 paid 1.755.8* m national, state and inks and bankers 3C.746.4 ' other banks S88.317 : $88,317 Pickrell The Farn. Bank i Incorporated &gt; Presuit-ni Vice-President Assisian STATEMENT N \EMF1ER &gt;. 1 RE8OURCES IABILITIES Loan, and dlscou).' . »40.6S3.4o pital S in Overdrafts, secured and uns. Banking house furniture anc SUt futures . . 1.440.00 Demand Current expenses and tax* paid . 7U1.4S Time rertlflc 17 Hue from national, state anc Bvate banks and banker - 1.754 </seg>
            <seg id="p234">201 The Pierce State Bank Charter No. 331 (Incorporated) ..President I M Inheldrr ■ ■ ■ .CuW« Assistant Cashier H H Mohr Vit e-President STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCE LIABILITIES Loans and discounts $119,627. 4S Capital stock paid in »25.OOO.OO Overdrafts, scoured and unse- I Surplus fund 2,80*. •• 355.58 ' ndlvlded profits 4.210. 8» Banking hou«. furniture and Individual deposits subject to ■.mr.! 00 check 55,755. •» heck ftxtu 00 Due from national, state an Demand certificates of deposit 3,310.00 Time certificates of deposit . . 67.C52.97 private banks and bankers 15,042 ;.«4 $158,729.51 j Total . $158,729.51 unity Bank The Pieree ( rporated . .Fresiden kma &lt; 'ashler .VIce-President Eil I. J. : ■■■■' Ed 1. STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 1905 LIABILITIES Loans and discounts $153, 522.84 Capital stock paid In $25.00*. 0* Overdrafts, secured and unae- Surplus fund 5,000.00 cured .' 1,946.26 lndivided profit 6,941.10 Banking house furniture and Indlvi !uil deposits subject to 218 fixture urrent expenses and taxes f deposit 5.55«.«J _.!.« Sllf ft7 Tim, . 8S.78C.92 pa l&lt;l 3,482.97 Tim.- . 85.78«.92 Due fro k.r: </seg>
            <seg id="p235">202 &lt;- Plain view The Farm.rs Stato Bank Charter N Incorporated Halbert President atemj muet A BII.ITIE Loan* and discounts . ;.ital stock i plua fund ■ . nilirldrd nrofll ■ • ■ - . L'ndlTld Banking house furnltur.. and ■ .nlu.il dep. 1 Individual dep ' - ••■ 47.04 real e«tat. iflcates of deposit 6 111 to lash Itemf I14.il 1 .&lt;te» of d.-posit .. 9:!:io!«4 I&gt;u»' from natinna real estat. ■• banks and I,:, .te tank, and I TX.5! ni.oo 1181, 014 Plain view The Bank of Plainvicw Charter I ncorporatedt ..President I 7. H DeLaa Vice-President ASMiHtant Caithler STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 1 I.M ILITIS Lo«n« and d: II 20,578. 9« j Capital stock paid in $ Overdrafts, secured and unrte Surplus fund 1,718.1; Undivided profits 1.38 Banking house furniture and fixtures Individual &lt;1. posits subject t 1.S00.00 ' check «2.751.» Knt expenses and taiei " ■,,.,. Demand ctrtin-ates of deposit J.'ooo.O 1,141.44 Time cert ifl&lt;ut&gt;.i of deposit .. 64435. 1 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers 1.367.11 1.237.32 7.595.48 Checks and Items of • x. hanw. </seg>
            <seg id="p236">151,329.44 t51.32t.44 Platte Center The Platte ( !ounty Bank (Incorporated) arter No, 15 President P. F. Luchsinger Cashier W. P. Sehelp Assistant Cashier Vtce-President TATEMENT NC IVEMBKR i. 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES tm tork paid in 115.000. 00 i and un Surplus fund 2,000.00 Overdraft s:4 Undivided profits 4,4 Stocks, securities, judgment Individual ilepn-its subject to check 50.00 Demand certificate ; of deposit Banking house furniture and 4,030.00 flitur urrent expenses and tax&gt; II4.M paid Premium on U. S. and other I., .ml- and »ecuri: Du&lt;- from national, state and private banks and bankers 57.S70.44 Checks and items of exchange 1,368.25 4,312 1.024 sssr 1 I2.S6S. 1 of school district N 21 Plainview The Security State Bank rated) f^SSST m'cSSS STATEMENT NOVEMBER a. 1 RESOUR. I LIABILITIES I and discount. |35.79«.18 Capital .lock paid In ■M&gt;»&lt;&gt; rafts, secured and unse- " I ndiv.,1. ,1 prom .. 2.9M.IT t&lt; j 101.10 Indlvidu ct to ng house furniture and ["IJJ'm ir 5« 1, 500. 00 Time . • it expenses and taxes I ... 2.003.95 rom national, state and ate banks and bankers 5,«9».S5 s and items of exchange 1.031. (ft </seg>
            <seg id="p237">204 BILITIE! in I 1 ul 44 deposit 1 priva ker 31. «4 »342,794 BIHTIE S30.0D' I &gt;abject to 4 1 Plattsmouth The Bank of untv harter Incorporated i President T M I'm . i-resiaent l. M I'atterson Cashier Vice-president Assistant Cashier iTATEMEXT NOVEMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES LIA Irfia— ami 1 1 &gt; 16 Capital stock pa Surplus fund I'ndivfded profits Individual depo. 1 Overdrn? and un cured H5.28 »43 Banking house furniture an fixtures 1 check R.r.oo.of '2.1*!. ft Demand certiBca Time i«-rt i ' r real estat - and tax* to state hanks and bar 4 Cash Item L- 1 5 . 4 1 Bfrom national, state an vate banks and &lt;&gt;n hand ,i 28.5JC.4C 1C.S81.4C t34:.T94.«S Plattsmouth The 1'hittsmnuth State Bank mea-Prastdral STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 1805 RESOVK I LIA I-.«n« and discounts $5«,»»S.O8 Capita] stock [&gt;ai ■ &gt;v»rdraft«, •ecurrd and utlK- Ir.di iti Individual depoxii Banking hou*? furniture and "'""■" • 714. SO Demand •al»«tat&lt;- 11,08*. OS -iflcates. t'urreni axe« P»ld !,21J.«1 ra»h It. 72. 7« m national. Ktate and private banka and bankers 11.372.14 i C««" . 2.7»I.JJ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p238">205 Pleasant . Dale The First State Bank Incorporated) Charter No. Cashier H M President A F. Ackerman Vice-President Assistant Cashier EHENT N&lt; V E MHKR 9. 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES T^^ffM and discounts I37.M1 pital stock paid in $8,00«.»0 Surplus fund 1,200. 00 r.ir d and uns&lt; ndlvlded profits 1.201.01 Individual deposits subject to check 30.421.37 1 lemand certificates of deposit M nd tax a- from nan private bank ,i I5M93.07 i Pleasanton harter Nn Incorporated \ II aruuHf .Presideii Jrammer ishler immer lant Cashier TATKMKNT N IV EMBER 9. 190 UCES LIABILITIES apital slock paid In $10,000.00 furniture and Surplus fund 2.000.00 Hankln 1.200.00 I'ndlvided profits 371.44 nxtur&lt; Due from national, state and Individual deposits subject to private banks and bankers S3.2S8.10l check 40.425.07 check • •hecks and items of exchange 929.77 I Demand certificates of deposit 4.T 1.4(5.00 Time certificates of deposit . 13.442. SO 15.34 Fractiona rniture and ■rtiflcates of deposit . . 13,329.92 The l'leasanton State Hank </seg>
            
            <seg id="p239">206 Plymouth The Bank of Plymouth harter Km (Incorp W. Har.- President K 1. ■as. Vice-President .\ STATEMENT NO VEMBER 9. 1 RESOIHCE LIABILITIES ...an» and d $4!'.:.»9.4j Capital stock paid in S •rdraf t &gt; Surplus fu ndivided profl ured . . 1.1 1 4 Banking- houw furniture and niture. Individual nea and paid ,h Ite 4 ■ rom n private 4.713. 55 S.884 $72,504 Pool Siding The Pool Siding State Bank Chan. .-■•rated N Dim ; ri STATEMENT NOV EMBER 9. 190 LIABILIT Itomnm and d OSS. SI k paid in Overdraf'.^ cored Undivided profits Individual deposit Banking hi'i. fixtures rk 9,3.4. 7» Demand certificates of dep. rtificates of deposit ■ -s and tait- * prtvat&gt; 3,131 &lt;*h«iks and lt« &gt;ange 64 </seg>
            <seg id="p240">207 The Bank of I )ixon County 138. (Private) Halstead President EalstMd sident Will F. Mtki-- I i tant CaahUr TATEMENT N V EHBEf LIABILITIES lock paid in 1 Undivided profit.* I.ON.M 41 Dividends unpaid ss; OS Individual d- •ck . ind certlflcatfs t.f d.-po it 17 I223.U1.71 »;_ curity Hank of Ponea Hank of Ponca President O L. Wood President O I.. Wood . . Wm Au J. M O President M I Mellon . ''resident M I. Mellon .. ATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 1906. ATEMEXT N( MBER 9, 1905 ;S I.IABILIT LIABILITIES ... .1: JJO4.44 k paid i un3e - -urplus funil plus fund ' . 10.29«.0« Individual uJ &gt;'.l,839.ia n. Time tertificatcs of depo it flxtur lianks and bankers ks and b; 5 4111 </seg>
            <seg id="p241">208 C tant Cashier ■ 110,000. 00 t 19,5(1.1 1 1«5.1 41.11 llM.tM : 14 Prague The Farmers and Merchants Bank 'harter No 340. (Incorporated! Klrohmin President \V C Kirchmar, Yiee-Presldent | it. A Kirchman A STATEMENT NOVEMBER ». 1905 ■ LIABILITIE l.nan« and d S (83 2 J Capital stock paid in Surplus fund and un Banking; h..u-. furniture and nxtur* • Individual deposit! subj ■ck vpense* and tax« Demand certificat- p«M 'tincaten of deposl ,nd bankers Id and 1 Prairie Home The Farmers Bank charter \o 844. (Incorporated 11 K Frantl i A. M. Un ilman STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 18 RESOURCES LIABILITIE Lovbs and discounts I! 029.18 Capital stock paid in Undivided profits 400.00 Individual deposits subject check 571.3$. Demrnd certificates of dep 18.22 Time certificates of deposit Bankii ■ rniiure and -•-^ and tax* in national, state and .rid bankers &lt;•! 1,882.14 291. »« Undivided profit </seg>
            <seg id="p242">209 Preston The Fanners State Bauk M STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES JO I 45 Primrose The IViiiH STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOURCES I ABILITIES 4 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p243">210 Prosser STATEMENT NOVEMBER RESOURCES harter No. 341 (Pr STATEMENT NOVEMBER Loan* and discounts . . J . •-cured and Banking bouse furn fixtures expenses a in national, state and ■tte banks and bankers 44 The Prosser State Bank The Bank of Racran </seg>
            <seg id="p244">211 Bavenna The State Bank of Ravenna .rter No. 344. &lt;Incorj&gt; EM EN MBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES paid in fund . . a proflts it 4 $113,301 03 The Citizens State Hank Ravenna KM KNT. N' IV EMBER LIABILITIES RESOi I Surplus fund divided prof Individual dep. check n .9 N </seg>
            <seg id="p245">212 </seg>
            <seg id="p246">213 Red Cloud The People's Bank &lt;&gt;f Red Cloud P: STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOURCES LIABILITIES 41 STATEMENT. NOVEMBER LIABILITIES RESOURCES Republican City TTw Republi </seg>
            <seg id="p247">214 Or 4 Republican City The Commer Lai State Bank STATEMENT NO RESOURCE LIABILITIES Umudd M "■ il "took i lus func vided p and vidual depr check taxes md cert 43 Time cert P» and 'ate and pr banks and b; '..115. •&lt; 699.01 4.248.08 Reynold^ The Fiirint-rs I unk of Reynold i Incorporated Presiden ice-President ENT. N VEMBER 9, RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and 142.303.74 Ted and an 6T. ured Bankint I...U-- furniture and «,tur 00 Dm from national, state and hanks and bankers 14.(80.45 S7 </seg>
            <seg id="p248">215 Rising City The Rising City Bank arter N Incorporated) A Reiihenbacli President ■nt Issialam AT EM EN EMBEF RESOURCE LIABILITIES Loans and discoui ..pital stock paid in |20,000.0» Overdrafts, secured and ■ ; Surplus fund i -'71.39 Undivided pr- 3.16S. 83 Banking house furnitur- Individual deposits subject to fixtures r,.S00.00 check 56,007.1* Due from national banks .... L'."., 214. 63 Demand certifu-at-s of deposit 7 nd items of ■ ■ . t)0 Time certificates . 49,459.64 4 1141,178. 74 Rising City State Bank The Farmer Incorporated President Italpl .ashler President -tant Cashier STATEMENT. N( V KMBER 9. 19 LIABILITIES RESOURCES SI Banking house furniture and Sure 524. 49 Current expenses and I Ind: to ■ ,:.i,l l.«01.56 check . Due from national, stai- </seg>
            <seg id="p249">LIABILIT1KS 1 Rockville The Rockville State Bank of Rockville Nebraska I-IT1E </seg>
            <seg id="p250">217 The Hank of Rogers STATEMENT N' : 9. 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES rtit ! Roseland he K..s.-l;m&lt;l State Bank STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19C RCES LIABILITIES </seg>
            <seg id="p251">218 The Bank of Rulo {•orated) President \Y Vice-President EM EN RESO LIABILITIES ! pital II fund . 4 6C 4 M The Exchange Ban! Pri J Jwner Vice-Preslden MENT NOV h IABILITIES * Capital sto'k pa Undivided | 1 Individui check Stocks. , claims. 151. »1 Demand Time ce Bankinr house funm . fixtures 1,650.00 s and tax P.M • M. 4t ' ram nationa .ite banks a 4.72!. 45 MS. N » </seg>
            <seg id="p252">219 The Stockmen's Bank Rushville irporated) side ATEM LIABILITIES RESOURCES 1 il Trent expenses and tax€ Due from national, state and private banks and banker S14 ( "itizens Bank Rushville r No. 836. (Private) M . . . Owner President A.TEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 19 LIABILITIES RESOURCES B and 41 . i $8» </seg>
            <seg id="p253">220 The Ruskin State Bank ■ r M IABILITIB State Bank . STATEMENT. NOVEMBER », 19C LIABIL1TIE RESO: R 46 pa I 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p254">221 St Paul The St. Paul Slat.- Bank •d STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOURCES LIABILITIES St Paul The First State Hank STATEMENT. NO V KM BE It LIABILITIES RESOURCES paid in td pri </seg>
            <seg id="p255">222 The Bank of - Incorporated • ATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESO1 LIABILITIES nJ:: Sargent The State U.nik of Sargent TEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19C I-IAIIILITII Loans u erdraf : •,45 M Bankinr i tixturt-^ 1.338.4 ,.»,! 3,498.74 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p256">223 The farmers State Bank Saronville ATEMENl ER ». 190 t 4 Phe Banking Houie of F. b\M» Schuyler I, 190 check Bank • a.. </seg>
            <seg id="p257">224 Schuyler The Schuyler Saving! Hank STATEMENT, NOVEMBER LABILITIES and 104 The Rank of Scotia STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 19&lt;K RESO' LIABILITIES I&gt;a i hank* </seg>
            <seg id="p258">225 The Irritrators Bank Scotts Bluff -ashler J H Casselman ..President W H Johnson Vice-Presldent STATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9, 1905 LIABILITIES RESOURCES 701 ck paid in 110,000.00 until 000 . 00 . cured and unse- Surplus fund 857. IS Undivided profit: Banking house' furniture and Individual deposits subject to • * • nun 00 cheek 27.182. J» 18 Time i-.rtificates of deposit .. «,370.tT Mdn and 146.410.41 - 1 •&gt; State Ban* Scribner The Scribnc rporated A I' Hov Henry Sle President I'uul WupfMW Assistant I VEMBER 9, 1905 STATEMENT. N( LIABILITIES RESOURCES apital stock paid In |25,0O4).«« n.*'^™ h,,u,, furniture .nd Individual ,.,jectto Banking hooa. furniture and ,ww . . . 18,411.3* Emu n..us.- lu.ui.v..^ 38,411. 3« ZZ Time c?rtinoat -" ° f depo * u ■ • "•"'•" 1.40 4 .•a nl. state and Kfrom national, state ana M.ks and banker V i </seg>
            <seg id="p259">226 Scribner The Merchants and Farmers Bank IS. (Incorporated) 3 0 MllllKHtl . Pr. STATEMEN USER 9. 19C LIABILITIES Capltut surplu .k • Nebraska STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RCES LIABILITIES g leaa eip. DC.142.6S Individual Real «*«tat? on h 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p260">227 Sbelton The Meisner's Hank M I RCES Shelton The Shelton Hank STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOURCE.- I.I ABILITIES II fund ■d pr "9 4 49 Hi II </seg>
            <seg id="p261">228 * r IK IES S 4 4 il.-pcisit 401 4 The State Hank of Shickley Shickley ! ncorporated Tesident I ENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1900 BTATKM LIABILIT RESOI'RrE« Capital stock paid Surplus fund A H.,I,klllK urn Demand P Time certlflca A 1158,11" Tin- Farmers Slate Hank r N Inrorp- Cain i Hul .1 M STATEMEN T. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILIT Tf«m^« and discounts S King h(iu •■ furniture and I, Demand certiflc .-&gt; and tax pa.d rime certificates of der. . rtifled ch&lt; • IMS in national, state and private banks and bankers Total i ash on hand ■ I'ndivided profits Individual • !&gt;.)! k paid ind profits </seg>
            <seg id="p262">229 Tin' American Bank rtfr N Incorporated) J J Mclntosh Presid Kr.bt A Barlow Assistant Cashier E Taylor resident STATEMENT. N )VEMBER 9. 190S RESOURCES INABILITIES id discounts $140.59*. »5 [ &lt;"apltal stock paid in *t Due from national, state n'clu- fund iks and t mlivided prollti .H37.94 . and ltcm« of exchange $.870.17 Individual del d IS 43 .( .1 4 0 1182.607.40 Silver Creek The Silver Creek State Hank l'r Pi i ishler STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9, 1905 LIABILIIIE RESOURCE I : 119.91 furniture and k x 4 te and 4 JU.T'I it 2.47».»4 </seg>
            <seg id="p263">230 Smithfield Farnic •s State Hank • VEMBER 9 RESOURCES LIABILITIES P 1 1 Ir Demand k nk 1 II 1.831 he Snvd.T State Hank A Hamann nt H &lt;: M- * ■ - lit Cashi NOVEMBER 9, IOC STATEMENT RESOURCES LIABILITIES 163,941 draft .1 anil 1,14 1.118 4(10 and ta 4S.48 p..d 3S7 an«l ..!► bankx and bank. I •&lt; 14 ' .ifh on hand J« 4 Time cert iftrai*-* *&gt;f dt*i&gt; flxtur*« </seg>
            <seg id="p264">231 m caHhter i&gt; ■ "ashier itant Cashier 00 153.21 t 3S.793.8C lit 3.229.3 . . 1? South Omaha The South Omaha Saving! Bank W. Taliaff STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES 474 k paid plus f i prof idual dep&lt; n.I ml Efrom national, state and inks and bankers ks ami itt'ms of exchange ■ 113 ■ Spalding The Spalding City Bank charter Xo 713. (Incorporated) Sullivan -l.nt STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 190J. RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loana anil J&gt;»'d ln • • ■ • ■ ur«'d anil un &lt;*■- Surplus fund . L'ndlvlded pi-n Banking h.iu»&lt;- furniture and Individual abject flxtur*. - Current fip^nifi and taxe&gt;* I&gt;.-mand certificates of depoi paid M certillc»te» of deposit </seg>
            <seg id="p265">232 Spencer The Corn K B.-ii 1 1&lt; X( Incorporated John Fi ard Lynn Assistant Cashier STATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9, 190 RESOURCE LIABILITIES jubp and discouau |(0,2«76 ; Capital stork paid in J15.000.00 ured and m Surplus 3.550. 0J Indlvldu heck 17.3*4.44 xpen Demand pa.d From national. »ta&lt; n 3,7t0.2* liunge 1.S5S.S7 I* I7C.480 4^ Springfield Id The unty State Bank Idaon - - - President 11. ■ ■ .Cashier I' r .- ~ 1 1 1 ■ r : : W H- 1 • \ssistant Cashler W. M Satterflfld Vice-Presid STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 1905. STATEMENT. NOV f 1MBEI. ■ — IIIIBI I LIABILITIES LIABILITIES ■I'RCf Loam* and discounts $CS discounts ....... $*&gt;■ h paid in $18.00#.*# Surplus fund 2. 180. 0» rafts, secured and S4 Individed profits 1,892.44 fndivlded pn»ft u Bankins house furn flituren . &gt;use furniture and Individual deposits subject to .S5.00 check 30.19S.41 Individual deposits sub check . eatatc 1.211.72 Time &lt; 64.604.41 [ • al estate - outstanding 10.590. 3S paid 248 national, state and banks and banktrx 44.314 n hand 4.969.44 • 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p266">233 « Springfield The J. D. Spearman &amp; Co., Bankers Incorp nil's Bank Springview Stoekm President il Assistant Cashier ii I EMBER 9, 1905 STATEMENT, NOV RESOURCES LIABILITIES &gt;3.(&gt; Capital stock paid in $10.008. M I., Surplus fund . .. l.«0«.0« Pndlv. 3,87«.«2 Indiv '.i '.I .lei" I to «1.M ch. 53,7»7.5t Banking hou n furniture and j Dem: f deposit 1.804.1 f deposit 1.S06.15 ur lit 13.041 urrent uptisM and t utstandln* 281 state and private ban 1 , i and bankers 3,128.3 paid M Due fr l.r and Item </seg>
            <seg id="p267">234 BILITII t 4 t ILITIES &lt; 44.14 4 Spring-view The Sprinjrview State Bank •r Nc Incorporated '■' nt K V STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LI A pita] stock I'ndivided proti Individual dep&lt;: k xtate and nka and hank x 4« 4 Spungview The ('it ie Bank STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905. RESOURCES LIAE Ix&gt;an« and .pital .-■ ■ 'l profli :ual &lt;lep judgm - .i Banking hou«- furniture and Bills pa\ l.f em ar ran national, state and 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p268">235 St ami oid The Stamford B;mk i E Woo4 sldent W. X Clark Cuhle: ■aahi^r STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 190 uces lARII.ITIES apilal Surplus fund livi.L.l pn.fi rtill 11 J«4,IUK The Bank of Staplehurs* Staplehurst nit rmshler ATEMEXT NOVEMBER 9, 1905 LIABILITIES RESOURCES Surplus fund t'ndi\ i 1« Individual -3J.18 IVman&lt;t cf-rtirt 11. H ■tldcates or del JX.71J.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p269">236 Steele City The Exeh iinjrc Bank ;-orated) I'lapp President Assistant c'aabtor STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905 LIABILIT1E Lotus and d; :I2.14 Capital ■rdrafts, secured and u rplus fi M ITS Tndlvided pr Bar.kint house furniture and Individual dep&lt; Bxtur heck fxpen taxes Demand I&gt;o ,.a,, national, state an I.K- |4:,4&gt;l.f&gt; I T The Bank inauei F M STATEMENT. N VEMBER 9. 19C RESOURC I.I A III I. IT H apl d Banklnic "I 1 49 </seg>
            <seg id="p270">237 The State Bank arter N I m-oryorated Cashier n I W. H Vice-President .1 F .Ir Assistant Cashier Assistant Cashier I STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9 190o LIABILITIES RESOL RCES IHS.4JS.39 Capital stuck paid In I il t 11 1 4,578.14 Individu;i k II 1 Ideates of deposit tM.M il ■ k. 4 UM.4M «5 Sterling 1 be Farmers and Merchants Bank id * -President E. H. J nan STATEMENT. NOVEMBEF 9, 1905. LIABILITIES RESOt RCES apital k paid d i I it ■d Undivlde Individui profl •11 ii » I n of dep heck ■ ,1 1 itate and k ankers 45,47 </seg>
            <seg id="p271">238 Sterling The First State Bank n t Fr I1HKI1 I.IAHJI.ITIF Stockham The Stoekham State 15 NT. NOVEMBE] IAHIUTIES </seg>
            <seg id="p272">239 Stockville The Frontier County Bank i ln&lt; ..rporated) • d. ■ STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19C LIABILITIES on S4 rn 4.13 4 Strang The Union State Hank y \ STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES »1". 5r«v in k </seg>
            <seg id="p273">240 The Commercial Banking Co :»8. (Privat Vennun President F. A. Vennum M V STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9. 19 RESOURCES LIABILITIES i 'apltal Undlvidc Individual (1&lt; i •ok 4.6 4 Tota 4 Stromsburg The Fun Merchants Bank t'resident Nathan Wilson Vice-President Emil Olson . - . Assistant Ca,i Kl lent ■ han W i , . i 1'resident Kmil Olson I STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905. STATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES RESOURCES LIABILITIES LIABILITIES d dlecounu »' "* ld In » ccounts $17 k paid in $55.00 •cured and ■ '* 5.00 rdraf 5.57* . 04 •fits 5.57 and Individual dep. »e furnitur*- and Individual deposits subject to 43,01 heck 43.01S.14 Demand certificate* of deposit 4" I demand certificates of deposit 40,91 Time certificates of di 1,940. I* Time certificates of deposit . . 121,34 state and private pm :;, banks and bank- : . ] ■ 7 &lt;ind 7.45 l-t.24 787. 0J I </seg>
            <seg id="p274">241 Stromsburg The Stroiiishurir Bank Ira Banta Vice-President | C. V. Nelson Re TABILITIES k : surplus fund Ted Inilivlderl r,. p, The Citizen* Bnnk M Flann :i! .1 STATEMENT NOVEMBER !&gt;. 19C RESOURCES LIABILITIES plus fund ilivided profltH 010.91 k&gt; and hankers </seg>
            <seg id="p275">242 h i«tanl Ca LITIE *1 1 iut) of deposit 135 172.458 3 k Asslstan LITIES n 0 u S:8 T Security Bank 403. (Incorporated hs r President I V. L. Johnson President I R. W. Johnson ■ Maddox Maddox MENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1 STATE LIABI I-oann and discounts s 43.SOO.OS ' Capital stock paid Surplus fund Krafts, secured and uns * 00 . Undivided profits Individual deposits Banking; house furniture and fixtures 01 check Demand certificate: nt expenses and tax 1,111 .12 Lexington Bank Due from national, state and private bank* and bankers 22,942 .00 2.0(1.(7 172.458 The Farmers and Merchants Ban Charter No S(0. (Incorporated I ■ I. Gram P. Rowell .... President T H VIce-Presldent STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABI lam and discount (fi.ssi.af Capital stock paid drafts, secured and un^ Undivided profl 138.(1 Individual deposit check . Banking hou«e furniture ant fixtures Demand certin nt expenses and taxe 478.41 rom national, state anc ate bankit and bankeri lit. 41 &lt;4S,1 6S Total cash on hand </seg>
            <seg id="p276">243 Surprise The St e Bank lit harter X ■orpo rated) W. H. Greensllt Vire-Presid STATEMENT. NC V EMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCE; LIABILITIES (40, 566. 38 Capital stock paid In Jj.000.oo ured and unse- Surplus fund ided profits HanklnK hou-e furniture and Individual 1,150.00 check . . 43.532 01 xpensos and taxes Demand certinVates of deposit 12,969 (6 Time certiflci. Total cash on hand 43 Total Jv Total $86. 70 v&lt; :. Sutherland The Sutherlanc i State Bank &gt;r No, (Incorporated) H E. W Cashier .1 W. \\ E. M. Si Assistant Cashier J A. \V STATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9. 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES S26.j23.04 Capital stock paid In $5,000. 0« Surplus fund 450.00 ,1 ndlvided profits 1.407.6J il Individual deposits sub 1 check 31. i and taxi: Demand certificates of del Time certificates of deposit . S.902 i il 'ashler's checks outstanding banks and banker- </seg>
            <seg id="p277">&gt; 244 KTEKXTH ANNUAL BE] 'OUT OF THE Swanton The Hank (if Sw Hlltoll i porated TATEME.VT NOVEMBE R ». 1 RESO LIABILITIE ipita irplu: idivi ured nd W ur Bank: ;rniture and Illlur- I l&gt;. -m nationn Ml Th.. BankofSynu II Si barter No 4tts. ( lm '.rporat*-d Presi.l. Vlcc-Preiiideiit O. O Horn A ATEMENT. NOVEMBE R 9. 190 •l-RC LJABILITIE d fund . ■set 1ST profit and Banking I nd ■ck fixture 4.414.17 1 i CtTtifi' -al ■■«■ ■tlflcates of def 'urrent *-«|j nd taxes \&lt;a itate and pr p.,d 1.819.44 hanks A bank 85. 0 Bllla nd k- and bankers 11.4 'hecks i. M3 i!" 1.1 an 4,28(11 </seg>
            <seg id="p278">245 I1S1 Talmage The Bank of Talmat ■porated ) Ar H DamiiM STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES k ).a Surptui fund 40 l*ndi\i In.!!', nlual '!■ ,k k Drmantl rtrtlBo Time certificates of dt-poj*it.. 1 ;,nd ; I*U'- and private private hanks and binkw 36.49i.6O !'■&lt;&lt; II.TM.M 12 Table Rock The Stat.- Bank » Miller PthUmI Miller nl STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES msp- Surphn fin : ik hou ••■ furniture and Indl n - t t'lpcnsc- and I Kfrom nati-.nal. stat*&gt; and i Mil hanki-rs 41 i " </seg>
            <seg id="p279">246 The Farmers K xehanre lia.nl rporated Acting C« As STATEMENT N JVE MBER &gt;. 190 LIABILITIES ' ■ paid in . . | Itai ured and un 100.0" 104.14 furniture and ,917. »4 ,05S.73 n.l UK T 4:i.4 rt 3.S59 4».l I4&lt; tlonal cm The T«rnov State Bank Chart • Incorporated H M I IT ATEMK V f MBER &gt;, 1*05 1RCE LIABILITIES Loans and i .• Banking house furniture and penses and taxes m.'ind cer- deposit itlonal. Rtate and m national. Rtate and of d-p - and bant ;in&lt;l bills r-niiscounted </seg>
            <seg id="p280">247 Tekamah harter No. 413 (Incorporated ■S M. Spielmar r Wallace . . . . mt Cashier STATEMENT NC 'V I MBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES I ABILITIES mi- and discounts Jl_'l._'88 . 8f upltal stock paid in . red and un urplus fund s.ooo.00 4 I'ndivtded profits i\ise furniture and Individual deposits check . . . 00 Demand certificate- national, state and Time certificates of deposit . . 41. Due to national banks 4,315.49 private banks and bankers 3t.IM.T4 rl silver coin, nickels Due to state and private banks and bankers 74 00 »15.721.18 The Burt County State Bank President i H M. Hopewell Vice-President Taylor The Bank of Taylor 'ay. Charter No 85J (Incorporated) J M c.nrad President F B Palst Cashier I , . „ . Vi.e-President Aoiataot Cashier STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9. 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES tand discounts $10,(09.13 Capital stock p:iul in $5,000.04 . ured and unse- Lndivided proni 181. II i 4.48 Individual dey t to \g house furniture and check 8,757.30 res 1 . 1 1 B . 65 Demand certil t expenses and taxe« Time certificates of deposit.. 1.670.00 2«0.43 om national, state and ite banks and bankers 974.34 i and Items of exchange 249.78 ' </seg>
            <seg id="p281">248 Thayer Tlif Bank of Thayer m i XI I Thedford Th.&lt; Thedfon) Hnnk » IUnkltl ! "' ■■■■'• ■ • I M M&lt;M, ... h . , STATEMENT NOVEMBER H RESOURCES I LIABILITIES (la 15 000 i Individ,-,! proau 1 03« l.«»=.«J Individual i furniture and "unjeri m M.tT and II. ::'.«7 &gt;m national, utat** an,l e banks and bai </seg>
            <seg id="p282">249 Thurston The Thurston State Bank M STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 190.". RESOURCES LIABILITIES k I 4.'JI Demand otrtiti I • ' * The TiliU'ii State Hank ftcate* </seg>
            <seg id="p283">250 ■tant ('ashler a: 4 The Elkhorn Valley Bank 7 (Incorporated) President C. A Smltt President r O llakir Stuart E. Burnham V Rak EM EN HER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIAE ILITIES tana and &lt;1I ronnt SI 8,624.. 95 Capita wrdrafts. llfll and uns. Surplus fund Banking houw furniture an 4 S'M - and tax* «!• n: 1 IU.M MS 31 Tlu Citizens State Bank bwlck •»lck V I 'resident unemak 'resident H. K Xunemak STATE MENT. NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIAE ILITIES '-*-" and discount -afts, secured and unse - 1 Bank ins house furniture and t expensea and taxes Due from national, sta' private banks and bankers 13.093 ■ and Items of exchange 50 6.-4 i.m.oo 1.24*. 00 Curr.nry la and cent 99.12 199.92 i profi ! depo 'ii national, state and nken hange rated) $80.01».»S 1 Capital stock paid tad .... 6.000 do </seg>
            <seg id="p284">MvcrdrH ! Surplu* fun cured asl.M L'ndivii ndlvlded prolll Hanking bouse furniture and Individual 1.481.44 check . . und taxes Tim. ...id .. 274.31 Kfrom national, state and vat*- banks and bankers 17,353.43 IT 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p285">252 The First Hank 1 I. M.kIIiii \V II M STATEMENT. NOVEMBER RESOURCES LIABILITIES fund Bankln check * The Hank of Unadilla M E I)u(T STATEMENT, NOVEMBER RESOfnrKS RESOURCES Surplus 1 dividual ii.p. Bmrkinrt k&lt; atlonal ink* and ha 6«6 </seg>
            <seg id="p286">The Hank of Union \ STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 19C RESOURCES LIABILITIES 4» 4ii 174.47 Upland The 1 iiliiiid Banking Co. President? STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES $10,00*. M ir*tl ami in ' Surti 8.163 »7 40.00 I rhrrk 61.I2S I deposit 40, 71S.lt ture and ! Tim^ certifl . 2.S55.O* lalt 4 nd banks and banker \.hangc 4/144.45 II </seg>
            <seg id="p287">254 iWiler $ 44,477.11 J 4 4 The Merchants Bank 428. (Incorporated Charter N &lt;too. F Horlburt IT A nt Mamie Ttn - nt R F. Hurlburt Hurlburt . NOVEMBER », 1905 STATEME NT RESOURCE LIABILITIES I.mm and •' f Capital stork paid Banking boa r« and fixture* Individ t. check . ates of dep&lt; - and tax Kfrom national, and inks and bankers l"&gt; !K* 1 1 IT urr«-m 1111.177. U ' Total The I'tiia Hank rter N (Incorporated) Pn ut PR! H B' J ni Itay W Jon STAT I T MMER 9, 190 RESOURCE LIABILITIES T «»■■■ and discounts SI Ov«r4imft*. secured and ud» ■ ured 1 Bins' house furniture and una nt expenne* and tax« l&gt;--mand certificate.* of deposit 4 1 Time certificates of deposit . . 4 srarvs 4 II -1 071.11 Capital M»&lt;k paid (14.41 dual deposits Suci.Ou ■ . . i, sr = 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p288">255 TIES i o 1.83 4,03 10.17C. 4 $143,828 1 r ITIE i alentine State Bank Valentine Incorporated park Hntton 1 \V Stette NT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIAB1LI l,Aai»« and ill^tiunt- I verdrafu, secured and ur I'ndivided profit; Individual deposl Banking house furniture and fixtures , heck Due from national, state and Demand certlflca' private banks and bankers IT.lti.lt Time certlflcat- ' 1143.828. II I Total The Valley State Bank 6 (Incorporated! harter I I isident I F. C. Kenned 'r H. Norton \ * n STATEME NT, NOVEMBEI RESOURCE LIABII n pit tt I stock paid In jrpius fund </seg>
            <seg id="p289">256 I i &lt; I IS.IM.11 Valparaiso I'll. &lt;);ik Creek Valley Bank i Incorporated I K Peter TATl MENT. NOVEMBER A BIL1TIE l» rplus 41 1 k 05 Ts 41 nlpara -'ate Bank F STATE MENT. NOVEMBER 9. 1 RESOURCES LIAE ILITIE unl tal Mock p;. 1 and iirplus fund »2 i i.roHt~ Banki:,. irnitur*- and Bilur- I&gt;ivideniis unpi Individual 6 &gt;&gt;**• a heck 1«.«5 Demand certlflcat it* liankii and hankers Time certiBcai. It 44, &lt;4 IM.M </seg>
            <seg id="p290">257 SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD Verdel The Farnu State Bank rs rter N (Incorporated) President Kalph Oilman \Y Vlce-Presid mt Cashier TATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9, 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES 121.84 pital .stock paid in &lt; rid un&gt; ndivided profits Individual deposits subject Bankin urniture and heck 8.894 1 Demand certificates of deposit Current exp.nse* and P»'d rn national, state arrent n^ma and tax Time certificates of deposit 7^6.46 Cuhtar*! checks outstandinK l»s and Due to national barn 362 40 Due from national, state and national banks Due to state and private private banks and bankers 685.12 I»u. to state and private private banks and bankers 685.12 4 01.84 banks and bankers banks and bank- Cash 1,322.10 1 Total . 128,547. »7 Total 128.547 47 Verdigre The Knox County Bank Verdigre The Knox unity Bank Charter No 707 &lt; Incorporated) tmrter N ncorpo rated) D B. Welpton President j B. Stevenson Cash KWelpton A. Walk President B. Stevenson Cuhler Harry A. Walk \ ice-President | . \&lt;slstant Caah Vice-Pi &lt; Assistant Cuhler STATEMENT, NOVEMtfEK », 1805. STATEME.N1 EiltiKK 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans anil discounts S28.092.96 Capital stock paid in $10,000 lam and discounts 12 8.092.9* apital stock paid in $10,000.00 Overdraft*, secured and unse- Surplus fund 2,000. ured and un&lt; Surplus fund . 2,000.00 Undivided profits .. 2.897.75 401.83 I n.iivided profits 2,6»7. 401.81 Banking hou e furniture and Individual deposits subject to fixtures 3,281.61 check 2»,014 and taxes Demand certificates of deposit 444. paid 1.516.20 Time certificates of deposit . . 8,486, Banking hou e furniture and Individual deposits sub 3,281.(1 check 29,014. 11 lenses and tax Demand certificates of deposit 444.29 u. 1.516 Time certificates of deposit .. s, 486. 2a 1 • &lt;■ from national, state and banks and bankers 14,260.21 d il.-m- of exchange 150.21 3.250.00 1,6S».S4 </seg>
            <seg id="p291">258 Cash, itant CashlT ! 411. 1 13&lt;.611.0l $18 1.23J.4 t 15.658.73 Verdon The Verdon State Bank harter No. 433 i Incorporated President G. E. Hall J H Hall J F Cornell VIce-President E E. Bolejack Ass STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loam* and discounts 1110 Overdrafts, secured and unse- Bankinr hou»«- furniture and fixtures . . 4 Current expense* and lax*- - '"a.«h items &gt; apltal *tiH-k T'ndivlded profit!* &lt;■■ 50 Individual 11 heck 043 1? Demand I «47 r.oe «7 Da* from national, state and private banks and bankers 15 Til SI Total cub on hand J.72S.(S Total I13S.61I.08 I Total The Farmers and Merchants Bank Charter N 1 (Incorporated Auxier President I E. E. Ewlng M Helnxelman Vici -President ! F W Robb STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES LosM and discounts 110 Overdrafts, secured and unse- :31 ipltal stock paid In I'ndlvlded profits 07 I Individual deposits subject 119 R house furniture and expenaes and taxes m national. Mat.- and check 465 3S I Time certificates of deposit 20.711 38 64 ntm hank.- and bankers II Total canh on hand 4^ SSI 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p292">259 The Vesta State Bank Incorporated) D. M B. F'r Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9 1905 RESOl RCES LIABILITIES ns and discount |28.04«.Sl Capital t-- k paid in MO.OOO.i.o r,l 1 nd un ;&gt;lus fun' a 1 851.97 I'ndlvided profits Banking hou-e furniture and Individual deposits subject to " 1.77*. 11 Individual deposits subject K check 15.931.71 Demand certificates of deposit 4 I Time certificates of deposit . . fi ■ » </seg>
            <seg id="p293">260 ill * IES « 6 'P I A ssi IES * 1 4 t 8X-76 deposit 39,212.53 osit . . 32,530.90 The Farmers State Bank Wabash Charter No. 758 (Private) Thom» President J M Or^amT Vice-Presldent D. M. Thomtf STATEMENT N RESOURCES L.IABILIT 4 discount! $11.01)2.;" ! Capital «to&lt; k paid in I ndivtded profl drafts, secured and un 09 Individual dep. and check €.918.11 1, 635.00 Demand certificates of deposit 2.547.8S k flxtu Time certlflcat x 1.20 1, ... n ks 4*&gt; 4 1 Total $18,609.10 | Total o Waco The Farmers and Traders Bank Charter No. 806. ( Incorporated ) §, . President J. H. Fisher . AYiKhtmar I ice-President TATEMENT, NOVEMBER 8, 1905. RESOURCES LIABILIT I&lt;in»* and ■ $43, 808.41 Capital stock paid in Overdra' and udm- Surplus fund cured 52«.97 1'ndlvided profits Banking how furniture and Individual deposits sub flstur- . 1,860.00 check Current upt-nses and taxes Demand certificates of i paid ■ 542.68 Time certificates of dep Doe from national, state and private banks and bankers 58,561 . 49 : </seg>
            <seg id="p294">261 The Citizen State Bank (Incorporated) President t J. Picket H Lyle Henry Hast Vice-President I MBER 9. 1905 STATEMENT. N )V E RESOURCES LIABILITIES &gt; ■counts . . . . f pital stock urplus fund ur 46 4 xper 41 national, state and banks and bankers 54 tins of € rotal 8, 481. 10 I1M.4M.M Wakefield The Farmers mm Traders Bank arter No. 43 (Incorporated) D.M.i Cashier [■ n««*«n President Vlce-President H. Mathewson . . . .Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9, 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES f .i^m and discounts 155,553.19 apltal stock paid in J40.000.00 K. ured and u Surplus fund 10, 000. #4 Undivided profits 9,551.17 lo.ooo.o') ;;i Banking house furniture and fixtures Individual deposits subject to check 47,824 . 07 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers Demand certificates of deposit 22,508.17 Time certin. 51.071.4J 4 Checks and Items of exchange 121 Bills of other banks, nickels Bills payable . m.noo.00 and cents 4.094.48 nder nc Undivided profit* 4.200.97 Indtvidu k 57,871.15 id certiflcaT it 1.444.W Time certificates of deposit &lt;«.»«3.tl </seg>
            <seg id="p295">262 JTIES *16, Assistant Cannier .ITIES »1 f, posit 4 landing (1 prl -,, Wallace The Citi/' rity Bank Charter rS. (Incorporated) Htrprr Harper I VI. STATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 19 RESOURCES LIABIL T oasjs and di Hankini: hour furniture and III lure. and taxes «■««» ■ M I Individual deposit* subject t check 171. 14 Drmind certificates of deposit llt.270.CK | Tota Washington The Security State Bank "harter Incorporated) Waldron President W T. Waldr.»n 8TATEMENT. NOVEMBER ». l»05. RESOURCES liabil: :...:- and •])- . f I 471.1* Capital Mock paid in &gt;v«rdraft*. »*-cur«-d and unw cured 17.95 Backing nous* furniture and I 41 Demand certlflcat expemses and tax paid and inter* bi Time cttrtlllcates of d 4C I Cashier's ch&lt; ■ m national, state and private bank* and bankers Due to state and Jil.lt banks and banker: 051.15 I 1 $3,713. US Capua] stock paid in $;.."'■■■ I proflti . 121 tat* ai ..nk&gt; and t-ar.k. </seg>
            <seg id="p296">263 Waterbury The Waterhur State Bank v Incorporated) d President F. Smith Cashier McDonald Vice-Presldent W F Filley Assistant Cashier STATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES nd discounts JJ6.740.il apltal stock paid In 15.000.00 'cured and unse Surplus fund ... 125.00 Undivided profits 761. 57 il Banking house furniture and flxtut r expenses and taxes P-'I Individual .!• !•■« to 8.J30.61 Demand certificates of deposit 714.81 35 Time certificates of deposit . 17.813.80 »m national, state and private banks and bankers 894.08 i-h 1. 211. 01 $32,745.79 | Total 132.745. 7» Waterloo The Citizens State Bank (Incorporated 'arlton H Nr.y President H. B. Waldron Cashier James E. McGee Vice-President Assistant Cashier STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9. 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES .oans and discounts 158.352.(3 Capital stock paid in $10,000.0* [rafts, secured and unse 4.41 profits 1.717.94 rurniture and :ual deposits subject to fixture 3,300.00 32,643,29 746.99 Time (truncates of deposit . 12.076. »3 Cashier's checks outstanding 1 Due to state and private real estat urrent expenses and taxes 1.4S8.13 m national, state and private banks and banker banks and bankers 16,243 1,614.74 urren </seg>
            <seg id="p297">264 1 The WaunHa Falls Bank 71 iPrivat President F. T DImick 'a: Vire-Prr - ■ Irm F E licCallum Assistant Cashier STATEMENT NOVEMBER . . 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Mitchell Hunt President T. A. Anthony Vice- President Win. Berrldge :nt Win. Berridirt A» « STATEMENT NOVEMBER 9, 1906. RESOURCES LIABILITIES taaas and discount- paid In t Overdrafts, secured and unse - cured . . 1.1 fund ■ - I laJ depositH subject to 6 Banking house furniture and nitur— 17.7 check Other real estate 1.7 mud certificates of deposit 54 &lt;ie certificates of deposit. . . 148.22 Current cn^enses and taxes paid (.471 1.71 II I Cashier's checks outstanding 41 • Dae from national, state and piirate banks and banker* 30.27&lt; Total cash on hand &gt;,»•(. I 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p298">265 ial Bank The Commer '( (Incorporated) H. Renard ("ashlar Renard Assistant Ca«hl»r Vice-President 1 E. STATEMENT. NOV EMBER 9, 1905 LIABILITIES RESOURCES ck paid in J20.OO0.0O Loans and discounts $1 Overdrafts, secured and unse - cured 4 -Surplus fund ndivided profit 13,552.12 Banking house furniture and fixtures Individi. subject to 50.315. OS Time certificates of deposit 135.111 Other real Demand certificates of deposit 1.230. 00 Current expenses and taxes oald 2,8«3.8« Due to national banks pa Due to state and private banks and bankers 11,0 I • j- from national, state and »23«.506.01 1236.506.01 I Total Tota The Bank of Waverly Waverly arter No. 4 4 Incorporated) T. J. Beale Ca»hl». President N. H. Meeker Assistant Cashier Vice-Presldent EMBER 9, 1905 STATEMENT, NC 3V LIABILITIES RESOURCES apltal stock paid In $5.000. •« Loans and di-counts »!S,4I*.04 1. 000. 00 Surplus fund Overdrafts, secured and un»&lt; 1.630.48 40 t ndivided profit ured In. 11 virtual deposits subject to Banking house furniture and 45.71 ».»» 1.500.00 fixtures I rtificatei of deposit 1 Current expenses and tax 05 paid Due from national, sta private banks and bankers 52.943.33 r.ecks and items of exchange 206.04 1.425 urren Spent 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p299">266 I7S.000.00 1 I 4 1412.101.11 48. &lt;4 11.M1.T1 Wayne The Citizens Bank Charter N C. Hennry ..President Ami STATEMENT, NOVEMBER ». 1*05 RESOURCES INABILITIES Ji«&lt;"unts paid In Surplus fund r»ir;ift-. secured and un BankinK '■■■■! «- furniture and nmm and tax Tim** &lt;*-rtifliat - and P- 6 d privat bank* ami banker I'u. frum nut .rijil. ctalt- and .inker. gar- I -urr.no- The State Charter N Henri 1 As: A Chace STATEMENT RESOURCES LIABILITIES $158.8*1 ■ ■ &lt;1 and un» 94 ■nil." unpaid ... 25 Individual deposits sufc . ■ furniture and 7,€17 SI check urr^-ni ezpensaa and tax Demand certincates of deposit ite« of deposit . paid UH Kfrom national, state and rmim banks and bankers 46,5tS r's checks outstanding 6T. .ml Items of exchange 1S7 Gold 4.22S ' and silver 3.1S7 447. (Incorporated »33fi • lM.lf 000.00 4.11 1 .11 Total Bank of Wayne :m orporated) Pre»ld»nt NOVEMBER 9, 1905 S,S»1.«J lapltal stork pa 1.7*2. »4 on &lt;1 </seg>
            <seg id="p300">267 The Saline County Bank Western Than (Incorporated) President Frank Z» Cashier Assistant Cashier J. F. Blandtn Vice-President STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOl RCES LIABILITIES paid $30.0 U! .ml un Surplu t 100 1 Ills 6S7.65 I furnlt ure and deposits Bab 'rtiflcatrs of deposit L'0,071.36 it 1&gt;. 259.91 Time certificates of dej ur from national, state and Due to state and private private banks and bankers 25.353,69 banks and banker- Fractiona Weston h r. i President i Frank President II Frank K Ki iall ier dele, Jr. . .Assistant Cashier u STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9 1905. RESOL RCES LIABILITIES 140,579.96 Capital st paid in SI rafts, bi nd un Surplus fu :1 U0 is:!. IS Ind I ure and furr k 913.74 d taxes locates of depose rnnt exj tin 1 ks outatandinir 7.417.1 rom national, state and ks and bankers 6s. -'34 I 16 49« r 439. U </seg>
            <seg id="p301">268 0 5 63 0 West Point The Nebraska State Bank harter N 4 Incorporated) F W :ash STATEMENT ,!BER 9. 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES 1 ir&lt;w and discounts . . raft*, secured and 117:, 913 Capital fund 13' 1 ■oka, s. irm.ia Banking house furniture and ttmtur**. P- Current expanses* and tax*-.- rom national, state an at« bank- and ba.nker n» of ex 414 Is and cent Whitman The Whitman State Bank 'harter No Incorporated) ChU. 8 Hnyt Jr&gt;f»phlr. Hoy James Mann I TAT 1 N HER 9. 19 RESOURCE LIABILITIES $11,917 It k paid in ■ I'd profits , . . 110,000 Banking hou«e furniture and fixtures M,» 93 4-. Individual deposits subject to Current expenses* and taxes 18,395 paid Sll Time certificates of deposit Dim from national, state and private banks and bankers 14.744 T« Checks and change ■ ■■ 1.415 ■ 242. C8 400.00 000.00 Drnuid . .r IT. -idem m -Ident •J T </seg>
            <seg id="p302">269 The Bank of Wilber 'harter No. 64 Incorporated) W. Ribbl .President Bartos Cashier Martin Jan Vice-President J ph Howsik Assistant Cashier STATEMENT, N&lt; 1 E MBER 9. 1905 V LIABILITIES RESOURCES 162. 018.19 apltal stock paid in {20.000.00 ur-plu- fund 300.00 ided profl 4.921.27 idtvidui subject to I'Ulllr-Ill check 27.337.*! .u-i' furniture and •emand cert. t 7,809.33 me certificates of &lt;1 | :3,427.S5 fixtur and taxes , jai U 1,393.63 u and private banks and banker* 16,346.16 46 ".4 | TDtal I93.79C.S4 The Exchange Bank harter ! (Incorporated) W. Gishwiller President i D. C Vice-Presldent Chas. W. Lamlwrn . . Assistant Cashier E M Crannell STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES sans and discounts 118,845 Capital stock paid In $10,000.00 Undivided profits 1,202.75 rdrafts, secured and uns. ured 260.82 Individual deposits subject to Banking house furniture and 10,835-86 fixtures 3,333.33 Demand certificates of deposit 6,196.65 nt expenses and tax Time certificates of deposit.. 1,709.65 Notes and bills redlscounted . 2,506.25 paid JOS. 64 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers. 5,621.66 and items of exchange 920.43 3.000.00 Fractional 156.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p303">270 .»hi » LITIE S il f de f tan.] UITIES Wil«onville The Wilaonville State Bank I rlrc« . . President ( F. M- Pein Vic STATEMENT, NOVEMBER 9, l»05 RESOURCES LIABI .jnumm and discount* » 111.10 ' capital stork pi I'ndtvided profits ivrdraft*. .- &lt; -.ur»-d and ui 1,900.12 | Individual &gt;: Klas; nous* furniture and sjna l.ifto.OO I DemanM ITim^ rertiflcates of Cashier's checks ou i expense* and taxes -im nation* private hank- and I I ■■ J Jones xtoth Jones Iwsrd L ])r&lt; W. ("randall \ 8TATEMENT. NOVEMBER 9, 190E RESOI LIABI $4k,O4l •rdraft». wcurwl and 171.45 , , Kanklnic h«u«- furmiur.- and 1 p..d mm national Due to national ba l&gt;ank» and I ■ rin of firhince It. 94 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p304">271 Winside The Merchants State Bank fiarter No 4^&gt; Incorporated) E. French President h W Tucker "ashler -.edhair Vice-president nit Cashier STATEMENT NOV EMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIES Loans and discounts 1140,207.37 Capital stock paid In Surplus fund S drafts, secured and un 4.130.81 I'ndlvlded profit 4.H94.85 Banking hou*e furniture and Individual deposits rah check . . Time certificates of deposl Due to national banks... 43 Due from national, state and private banks and bankers 11.118.96 becks and items at fxrhange 1,103 o» 00 n&gt; Tot. T.)tal Wisner The Winter State Bank Charter Nc (Incorporated) H. D. Detl Presld H. A. t 'ashler Assistant Cashier STATEMENT, NOV EMBER », 1905. RESOURCES LIABILITIES pltal stock paid n irplus fund cured 477.21 I ■ .ats . :. ii\. 99 BankinK luiuie furniture and Individual deposits stil 58.184 Demand certiflcat*-- 1,440 1 1 in nation&amp;l private banks and bunker.'. 9,848.1 •ck.s and Items of exchs 4 Eire. . 8,300.00 nt t-jtp«-n-t-s and taxes 2,563. »0 xpensea and tax* 42 Time certiflc:! </seg>
            <seg id="p305">272 E '4 40.81 S ant Cashier :s »1 475. &lt; 36,105. 2&lt; t lit.. 3.895.3 Wolbach I'll,' Wolbaeh State Bank ncorporated arter President j C. W. Norton cashier \ &lt;■- President' Assistant Cashier President j C W. Norton STATKME NT. NOVEMBER », 1 RESOURCES LIABILITI Banking bou* furniture and I Individual ibjevt to ■&lt;k r real estate, building. I'emand cerlincat Time certificates of dep.. it... 7,34 »-"» 1 1.2&gt; 1 hand and from bank (■ S &gt;.5t Kt,&lt;M.ll The \Y km) Lake Bank Charter N T41 ( Incorporated President i A. U. Johnson Vice-President | W F Parker David Hanna T NOVEMBER 9, 1905 RESOURCES LIABILITIE linaM and i $32 i-urwi and 1 Surplus fund **•■»* Undivided pron Banking house furniture and Bitures I, expenses and taxes P»"l 1. I»u»r from national. Ktate and Individual depo its subject tO0. 00 check Demand certificates of dep ,179.12 Time certificates of depos private banks and bankers. 13, Checks and items of • xohangre Cm.h 1, ,7«.17 41.SH m.M I ins and di- |48,&gt;08.1(l paid in 1 rrdrafu, secured and unae- Surplus fund •57.17 t'ndivlded profits STATEMEN " Capital stock paid </seg>
            <seg id="p306">273 r • Wood River The Citizens State Bank (Incorporated) u \v M President Assistant Caahl STATEMENT, NOV EMBER 9, 1905 RCES LIABILITIES * cured 35.44 3,S«T.74 tanking lur. and 60.00 inkim dep k . . 66,095. 8« S46 4,173 $135,187 Wymore The Wymor State Bank A nil ■«..! I A Reuling Smitl u Cash! STATEMENT. NC \ EMBER 9, 190 RESOURCES LIABILITIES id &gt;verdrafta, m urea profits 114 Ranking house furniture and flxtur. ,.a,d Due to national bank i n id JST W. I- - P» id 1.710.91 Time certificates of .! J3,*U. eh Ihmand certifica Time certificates of d*\ </seg>
            <seg id="p307">274 iprman \merican Bank 'harter N'c 41 (Incorporated) Joshua Cox A, nl U W. Milt.ndi.rlf I enldent TATEMENT X&lt; V :mukh 9, 1905 RESOl !-I A HI LITIF !•■■■ and discounts $ : rafts, s. cured and un* 1.1 IS BanklnK liouw farniture and "ilnre. 4&lt; and taxes P«M 1.40 1 4.449.1 ie and private banks and banker - i 808.4 *S1.297.13 | Total The Hit nk of Yutan orated t I N 1 TATEMENT .\( V EHBEK Li. 190 LIABILITY I nmmm and discount »i3,«3 Overdrafts, secured and un Surplus fund I'ndlvidrd profit liankiriK house furniture and Individual deposits subject t 1.50 • ■ xjM-nscs and taxes 4 1.17 r. • rtiflcatt in national, state and private banks and bankers - checks outstanding. 1 and Items of exchange 19 ■a«h 1.01 3. H61 &lt;;»j.ital stu'k paid fn . . Indivlded profits . . . . Individual deposits sut I&gt;i-mand certifieat Time certificates of dej apital Stock paid In check cmand i </seg>
            <seg id="p308">General Index A fall State Banks, February all Statf Banks, May 29, all Stute Banks, August 25 all State Banks. November National Banks, Noveml.ei 190£ .xi 190 xh ! xiii 8. 1:10 ..xlv 19ii5 .xv xiv Krage Reserv ropriations xxi B Kks changed from Private to ks Nationalized 1 ated Banks ncorpor Banks sold to and succeeded by Banks gone into voluntary liqui Banks (incorporated) chartered Banks (chartered) but had not c Banks (Private) rechartered . . . ather L unks v 1; utiun v Banks which have surrendered arters. never havin opened viii . . .xvili xvi viii x xix o« •ommenced busu. u viii viii </seg>
            <seg id="p309">276 rEMKXTS. CONDITION [NCOHPOR.VTKD. PBIVATB AND SAY ING8 BAN i" \ The Abie State Hank Adan -late Bank of Adi Mirth, The Bank o; Ainsworth . POTtk, Citizens Sta'e Hank :,dria ~ate Bank Alma. The Bank of Alma Ii. The Harlan Counn Hank . The Farmers and Merchants Ha:. The Farn ■Imo. The Anselmo State Haul ey. The Farm- ; : lahoe. The Arapahtx dia. The State Bank of A read 1, igton. The Arlii ild. The Farmi • ,:. and. The Farmers and Merchants Baa) on. The Bank of Ashton l'l 1. Atlanta. The Atlanta Sate Bank . Auburn. The Nemaha County Bank i, The Aurora State Bank 1: El, The Bank of Avn. 1. The Bank of Axtell roft. The Bancroft Bank 12 Bancroft. The Citizen-- Hank of Banerof Barneston. The Bank of Barneston Barneston. The Commercial State Bank Bartley. The State Bank of Bartl. Bassett The State Bank of I: Basset t The Commercial Bank . . n i 16 EBaal le Creek. The Ban]. Uley Hani, ird. The Bank of Bayard IS Elle Mills. The Bank of Bazile Mil trice. The Union State Bank ver Ci\v. The First State Bank. is IS HI Ever Crossing. The State Bank of Beav. iig. The Citizens State Bank . The Ftate Bank of Bee iik 11 II Be*mer. The Beemer State Bank Beld&gt; :.td'-n Bank Bri^ra, -.ank of Belsrade </seg>
            <seg id="p310">277 Bellwood. The Bank of Bellwood Belvidere, The State Bank of Belvider Benedict, The Bank of Beiiedk Benkelman. The Bank of Benkelm an Bennet, The Citizens Bant Bennington, The Mangold &amp; Glandt Bank. Benson, The Bank of Benson Berlin, The Bank of Berlin M Erand, The First State Bank.... any. The First State Bank . . en. The State Bank of Bladen Bladen, The Exchange Bank of Bladen n Blair, The Blair State Bant Blair. The Banking House of A. Caatettei Blair. The Citizens State Bank Bloomfield, The Farmers and Merchants State Bank. 3i Bloomfield, The Ci'izeiis State Bank Bloomington, The Bloomington State Bank Blue Hill, The Commercial Bank Blue Springs, The Blue Springs State Bank The Boelus State Bank Boone. The Boone State Bank Bradshaw. The State Bank of Bradshaw... Brady, The Bank of Brady Brainard, The Bank of Brainard Brewster, The International State Banl. ■ Bridgeport. The Bridgepor Bank... Bridgeport. The Valley State Bank istow Sta' Bristow, The American Exchange Bank Brock. The Bank of Brock Broken Bow. The Broken Bow State Bank Broken Bow. The Security State Bank Bruning, The German Bank Bnino, The Bruno State Bank Brunswick, The Brunswick Bank Burchard. The Bank of Burchard 41 Burr, The German-American Bank 41 Burwell. The Burwell State Bank Butte. The Citizens State Bank Butte, The Bank of Boyd County 43 Byron. The Farmers and Merchants Bank 43 Cairo. The Cairo State Bank 44 Callaway. The Seven Valleys Bank 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p311">278 Cmllaway, Calla way State Bank Campbell, The Bank of Campbell Campbell, The Commercial State Bank ■■&gt;n. The Citizens State Bank Bluffs. Bank of Cedar Bluffs. . Cedar Bluffs. Farmers and Merchants Bank Cedar Rapids. The Cedar Valley Bank Cedar Rapids, The S. S. Hadley Com|. liter Stale Bank u 4.; :; 4» u ■ 1 City, The Central City Bank. ■1 City. The Farmers State Bank... il City, The Platte Val Bunk Ceresco, The State Bank of Ceresi ■■&gt; 4'.. ;: Eron. The Citizens State Bank., ibers. Chambers Stale Bank man. The Chapman State Bank pell. The Commercial Bank rmers Bank tson. The Clarkson State Bank nia. The Farmers Bank of Clatonia. . Center, The Commercial State Bant Clearwater, The State Bank of Cleai wat* r Cody, The Bank of Cody M ridge, The Coleridge State Bank.. ridge. The Commercial State Bank n. The State Bank of Colon :nbus. Columbus State Bank Comstork. The Comstock State Bank . ■ ird. The Concord State Bank... Cook, The Farmers Bank of Cook. . ova. The Cordova State Bank. . . . Cornlea. The Cornlea State Bank and. The Bank of Cortland . ... II U r, i hf Cowles Bank. . . id. The Cozad State Bank E Orchard. The Bank of Crab Orchard Orchard. The Farmers State Bank.. . The Craig State Bank N a E, The Farmers State Bank ford, The Commercial State Bank hton. The Security Bank : .-,.-, Ehton, The Bank of Creighton. hton. The I Bank on. The Citizens Stat. Bank H </seg>
            <seg id="p312">279 PiG« . The Crete State Bank 67 Culbertson, The Cnlbertson Bank 67 Curtis, The State Bank of Curtis 68 Dakota City, The Bank of Dako'a City 68 Danbury. The Bank of Danbury .Gil Dannebrog, The Dannebrog State Bank 69 iport. The Jennings State Bant Davey, The Farmers State Bank 70 Da wson. The Dawson Bank 71 Daykin, The Jefferson County Bank 71 Decatur, The Decatur State Bank 72 ler, The State Bank of Deshltr .. 72 Deweese. The State Bank of Deweese 73 D' Witt, The Farmers and Merchants Bank 73 DeWitt, The Home State Bank 74 Ulller, The Diller State Bank Dixon, The Dixon State Bank 75 Dodge, The Farmers State Bank .75 Doniphan, The Bank of Doniphan 7G Dorchester, The Dorchester Sate Bank 76 Douglas. The Bank of Douglas 77 Du Bois, The State Bank o: Du Bois 7 Dunbar, The Dunbar State Bank 78 Dwight, The Dwight State Bank 78 Eagle. The Bank of Eagle 79 Edriyville. The Eddy ville State Bauk 79 Eddyville, The Farmers State Bank 80 Edgar. The State Bank of Edgar 80 Edgar. The Clay County State Bank 81 Edison, The Bank of Edison 81 Elba. The Elba Sta'e Bank . . 82 Elgin. The Elgin State Bank 82 Elk Creek, The State Bank of Elk Creek 83 Elkhorn, The State Bank of Elkhorn 83 Elm Creek. The Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank 84 Elmwood, The American Exchange Bank . 84 Emerson. The Farmers State Bank .85 s, The Farmers State Bank .85 Ewing. The Ewing State Bank .86 r. Wallace &amp; Company Bankers .86 Exeter. The Exe'er State Bank .87 Fairbury. The Harbine Bank 87 Fairbury. The Goodrich Bros. Banking Co 88 Fairbury. The Fairbury Savings Bank ... .88 </seg>
            <seg id="p313">280 Fairfield, The Citizens Bank Enont, The Farm. Hank City, The Richardson County Bank City, The Falls City State Bank... am, The Farnam State Bank Farnam, The Farnam Bank E'ell, The Farwell State Bank, y, The State Bank of Filley. i, The Firth Bank Firth, The Citizens Bant Florence, The Bank of Florence LCalhoun, The Washington County Bank er, The Foster State Bank Franklin. The Franklin Exchange Bank Franklin, The Franklin State Bank Fremont, The Security Savings Bank Fremont, The Home Savings Bank Fremont, The Fremont Trust and Savii I, The Merchants and Farmers Bank... Funk, The Funk State Bank M K 17 ank. M Gandy. The Gandy Bank Garrison, The Farmers and Merchants Bank . a. The Citizens Bank N Geneva, The Geneva State Bank ng. The Bank of Gering... ::: Kantown, The Germantown State Bank in. The Commercial Bank Eon. The Exchange Bank id. The State Bank of Gilead . . ier, The Bank of Bromfield .... ville. The Bank of Glenville. . . . iner, The Goehner State Bank . . on. The Sheridan County Bank :::: 105 rnburj;. The Farmers and Merchants Bank The Bank of Graf Grafton, The Grafton State Bank. Ed Island, The Grand Island Banking Co. . d Island. The Commercial State Bank.... t, The Commercial Bank • y. The Greeley State Bank ins Enam, The Fanners and Merchants Bank, na, The Farmers and Merchants Bank s. The Gross State Bank ;;:: g~* ••i/irt t&gt;^sj^ir Tin ti lr c\f (^ 11 i (1 &lt; ■ "R/w*lr </seg>
            <seg id="p314">281 &gt;'ai;e Haigler, Empire Loan &amp; Trust Co Ill Hallain, The Hallam Bank Ill Hampton, The Bank of Hampton 112 Harbine, The State Bank of Harbine 112 Hardy, The Farmers State Bank .113 Hardy, The Hardy Bank 113 Harrisburg, The Banner County Bank 114 Harrison. The Commercial Bank ,...114 Hartington, The Farmers State Bank 115 Harvard. The Union State Bank 115 Harvard, The Harvard State Bank 116 Hastings, The Bank of Commerce 116 lock, The Farmers and Mechanics Bank 117 Hayes Center. The Farmers State Bank 117 Hay Springs, The Northwestern State Bank 118 Springs, The Farmers and Merchants Bank 118 Heartwell. The Heartwell State Bank 119 Hebron. The Thayer County Bank 119 Heminsford, The First State Bank 12" Henderson, The Bank of Henderson 120 Henderson. The Farmers and Merchants Bank 121 Hendley. The Farmers State Bank 121 Herman. The Plateau Bank 122 Hershey. The Bank of Lincoln County 122 Hickman. The Bank of Hickman 123 Hildreth. The Franklin County Bank of Hildreth 123 Holbrook. The Bank of Holbrook 124 Holmesville. The State Bank of Holmesville 124 Holstein, The First State Bank 125 Homer. The Homer State Bank .125 Homer, The Security State Bank 126 Hooper. The Dodge County Bank 126 Hoskins. The Hoskins State Bank 127 Howe. The Bank of Howe 127 Howells, The Colfax County Bank 128 Howells. The Howells State Bank 128 Hubbard. The Hubbard State Bank 129 Hubbell. The Hubbell Bank 129 Humboldt. The State Bank 130 Humphrey, The Bank of Ottis &amp; Murphy 130 Huntley. The State Bank of Huntley 131 Hyannis. The Bank of Hyannis 131 Imperial. The Farmers and Merchants Bank Inavale. Th«' Bank of Innvale </seg>
            <seg id="p315">282 Indianola, The State Bank Inman Tin Inman State Bank Ithaca, The Farmers State Bank Jackson, The Bank of Dakota Co Jansen, The State Bank of Jansen Johnson, The Farmers Bank of Johnson Johnstown, The Citizens Bank En. The Bank of Julian . . ita. The Bank of Juniata &gt;■&gt;. The Farmers Bank of Kearnt ;. Keen*- The Farmers State Bank Kenesaw, The Kenesaw Exchange Bunk... Kennard, The Farmers and Merchants Bank Kimball, The Bank of Kimball :S I Ener, The Kramer State Bank •el, The Farmers State Bank el. The Laurel State Bank The Sta'e Bank of Lawrence inon. The State Bank E&gt;. The Farmers and Merchants Bank 1, The Maple Valley State Bank ston. The Bank of Lewiston ii -:ton. The Lexington Bank &gt;. The Stan- Bank of Liberty I Merchants Bank. . in. The American Savings Bank Lindsay. The Farmers and Merchants Bank I Me Lindsay State Bank !« Kood, The Farmers and Merchan-.s Bank field, The Litchfield State Bank.. .:;; Lodge Pole. The Peoples Bank n* Long Pine. The Brown County Bank Loomis, The Farmers State Bank .... Lorton, The Bank of Lorton 14* .14« 149 Eiville. The Bank of Conn: The Loup City State Bank ton. The Bank of Lushton ... h. The Bank of Lynch.. s EThe Ponca Valley Bank The Farmers Bank .... k. The Citizens Bank McCool Junction. Thf j Hlue R' UMn a!, </seg>
            <seg id="p316">283 PACE Macon. The Macon State Bank 155 Madison, The Madison State Bank 155 Madrid. The Madrid Exchange Bank 156 Magnet, The Magnet State Bank 156 Malmo. The Farmers and Merchants Bank 157 Marquette, Farley's Bank 157 Marttnsburg. The Martinsburg State Bank 158 Mason City, The Mason City Banking Co 158 Mason City, The First State Bank 159 Maxwell. The Maxwell State Bank 159 May wood. The State Bank of May wood 160 Mead, The Bank of Mead 160 Meadow Grove. The Meadow Grove State Bank 161 Meadow Grove. The Security Bank 161 phis. The Bank of Memphis 162 Merna. The Bank of Merna 162 Merna, The Home Bank 163 i man. The Anchor Bank 163 Milford. The Nebraska State Bank 164 Milford. Farmers and Merchants State Bank 164 Millard. The German Bank of Millard 165 Miller, The First Bank of Miller 165 Miller. The Bank of Miller 166 Milligan. The Farmers and Merchants Bank 166 Minatare. The Minatare Bank 1G7 Minden. The Minden Exchange Bank 167 Monowi. The Monowi State Bank 168 Monroe. The Bank of Monroe 168 .•field. The Bank of Moorefleld 1C9 e Bluff. The Bank of Morse Bluff 169 Mount Clare. The Mount Clare State Bank 170 Mullen, The Bank of Mullen 170 Murdock. The Bank of Murdock 171 Murdock. The I'nion State Bank 171 Murray. The Murray State Bank .172 Naper. The Bank of Naper 172 Naper, The Peoples Bank 173 The Naponee State Bank . . 173 iska City. The Farmers Bank 174 Nehawka, The Nehawka Bank 174 Neligh. The Atlans Bank 175 Nelson. The Commercial Bank 175 ,ha, The Bank of Nemaha .176 Newcastle. The Farmers State Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p317">284 Pit I astle, The Newcastle State Bank 177 Newman Grove, The Newman Grove State Bank Newport. The Newport Stale Bank Eport. The Rock County State Bank. erson. The First Bank of Nickerson rara, The Niobrara Valley Bank . . . [en. The Bank of Norden... Eh Bend. The Farm* i mk. . . h I&gt;oup. The Farnu -: -lank., h Platte. The McDonald Stale Bank The Scroggin &amp; Co. Bank lale. The Antelope County Bank. . lale. The Oakdalc Bank Eand. The Farmers and Meielianis Ban) and. The Bank of A E Wells A: Oo to. The Oconto State Bank. . uteri Bank ia. The Octavia State Bank The Hit; :.• Ogalalla. The I Buk Ogalalla. The i Bank. va. The Bank of Ohiowa I Omaha. The J L Brandeis &amp; Sons. Banker |M City Savings Bank Ong, The Exchange Bank id. The Orchard State Bank. Orchard, The Farmers State Bank. Orchard, T 'ate Bank. Ord. The Ord State Bank 1S.1 I ins. The Bank of Orlean - ■ i e Bank . . . ola. The Osceola Bank ;osh. The Oeuel County Bank, ond. The Farm* ilank. ond. Th.- Seeuriu State Bank ton. The Overton State Bank, rd. The Bank of Oxford s Page. The Farmers Bank EThe Frenchman Valley Bank er The Palmer State Bank The Bank of Palmyra ma. The Bank of Panama Papillion. The Banking Hou- A. W. Clarke Pen, The Ota. P </seg>
            <seg id="p318">285 PA1. ». burg, The Citizens State Baal Phillips, The Bank of Phillips Pickrell, The Farm. Bank 6, The Pierce County Bank. e. The Pierce State Bank.... Plainview, The Farmers State Ba 1 I view. The Bank of Plainview view, The Security State Bank e Center, The Platte County Bank smouth. The Bank of Cass Count&gt; smou'h. The Platsmouth State Bank... ;ant Dale, The First State Bank, lanton. The Pleasanton State Ban louth. The Bank of Plymouth a. The Security Bank of Ponca a. The Bank of Dixon County Siding. The Pool Siding State Bank Prague, The Farmers and Merchants Bank Prairie Home, The Farmers Bank Mi Eton, The Farmers State Bank irose. The Primrose Stat ser, The Prosser State Bank, in, The Bank of Ragan K Ravenna, The Citizens State Ban! Ravenna, The State Bank of Rav nna Raymond. The Bank of Raymom K Cloud. The State Bank of Red Cloud Cloud, The Peoples Bank Republican City, The Republican C.ty Hank.. Republican City, The Commercial S ate Bank K. ynolds, The Farmers Bank of Reynolds. . Rising City, The Farmers State Bank . King City. The Rising City Bank erton. The Riverton State Bill tkville, The Rockville State Bank of Rockville ers, The Bank of Rogers Nebraska 217 tland. The Roseland Sta'e Bank The Bank of Rulo Rushville. The Exchange Bank.. Rushville. The Stockmens Bank . Rushvlle. The Citizens Bank.... fluskin. The Ruskin State Bank.. Rtiskin The Farmers State Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p319">286 A(,I 221 I Paul, The Si . Paul State Haul, Paul, The First State Bank . . m. The Bank of Salem.. 221 Sargent, The State Bank of Sargt-n Saronville, The Farmers State Bank Schuyler, The Banking House of t Schuyler. The Schuyler Savings Bank... Scotia. The Bank of Scotia 224 Hi Scotts Bluff. The Irrigators Bank.. Scribner, The Scribner State Bank. Kbntr, The Merchants and Farmers Bank ard. The Sate Bank of Nebraska. Bum, The Meisners Bank ton. The Shelton Bank Shickley. The State Bank of Shicklt ._* y Kbeit. The Farmers Slate Bank, ley. The American Bank 28 Silver Creek, The Silver Creek State Bank Smithfield, The Farmers Slate Bank Snyder, The Snyder State Bank Kb Omaha, The South Omaha Savings Bank ding. The Spalding City Bank Eicer, The Corn Exchange Bank Dgfield. The Sarpy Coun'y State Bank.... ngfield. The J. D. Spearman &amp; Co. Banke npview. The Stockman's Bank / 233 Egview, The Citizen's State Bank . . gview. The Springview State Bank ford, The Stamford Bank 234 234 Eehurst. The Bank of Staplehurst The Exchange Bank auer. The Bank of S^einauer... i. The State Bank 236 Sterling, The Farmers and Merchants Bank Sterling, The First State Bank Ekham. The Stockham State Bank. kville. The Frontier County Bank, ng. The Union State Bank tton. The Commercial Banking Co 240 Kmsburg. The Farmers and Merchants Bank m8burg. The Stromsburg Bank 240 L'41 241 Krt, The Citizens Bank . . ner. The Security Bank 241' Simmer. The Farmers and Merchants Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p320">287 Surprise, The State Bant Eerland, The Sutherland Stai lton, The Bank of Swanton cuse, The Bank of Syracuse e Rock, The State Bank... ink .244 Enage, The Bank of Talmagt lora, The Farmers Exchangt nov. The Tarnov State Bank lor. The Bank ji Taylor... 2 45 1 n; ink Etnah, The Hurt County Stat er, The Bank of Thayer. . ford. The Thedford Bank. 24X Thurston. The Thurston Stai 249 I lot. The Tilden State Bank... en, The Elkhorn Valley Bant ias, The Citizens State Bank, ron. The Collett State Bant mbull. The Bank of Trumbull The First Bank of I dilla, The Bank of Unadilla. . &gt;n, The Bank of I'nion ind, The Upland Banking Cc a. The Merchants Bank 251 251 254 254 I'tica. The Utica Bank t'ntine. The Valentine State Bank ey. The Valley State Bank rraiso. The Valparaiso State Bank., raiso. The Oak Creek Valley Bank y Verdel, The Farmers State Bank Verdifjre, The Knox County Bank V. nlon. The Verdon State Bank Wrilon. The Farmers and Merchan s Bant Bank |?inia. The Citizens S'ate Bank bash. The Farmers State Bank co. The Farmers and Traders Bank... hoo. The Citizens State Bank... kefleld, The Farmers and Traders Bank llace, The Citizens Security Bank shington. The Security State Bank ... (erbury, The Waterbury State Bank... terloo. The Citizens State Bank uneta. The Wauneta Falls Bank usa. The Farmers State Bank. 261 2i;i 2f,4 </seg>
            <seg id="p321">288 Wauaa, The Commercial Bank Waverly, The Bank of Waverl&gt; Wayne. Tl M Bank Wayne. The State Bank of Wayne. rn, The Saline County Bank.. Weston, The Weston Bank West Point, The Nebraska State Bank Whitman. The Whitman State Bank.. Wilber. The Bank of Wilber Wilcox, The Exchange Bank Wilsonville. The Wilsonville State Bank Winnetoon, The First State Bank -ide, The Merchants State Bank. &lt;r. The Wisi Bank. . ach, The Wolbach State Bank . Wood Lake. The Wood Lake Bank Wood River. The Citizens State Bank cire. The Wymore State Bank... York. The German-American Bank . . Yutan. The Bank of Yutan </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>