<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  CROP PRODUCTION IN WESTERN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XIX, Article II. CROP PRODUCTION IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. Report of Experimental Substation, North Platte, Nebraska. W. P. SNYDER, Superintendent. E. A. BURNETT, Director. FOLLOWING THE BINDER WITH THE DISK TO SAVE MOISTURE. Dimiinn Muci 11 MCI. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA V. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">The Farm . Character of Soil ritions at Beginning., ress in Improvements Land Farming Drought Resistant Crops Grains- Durum Wheat Winter Wheat Oats Barley Emm cr Proso Millet Corn Iual Forage Crops Cane ' Kafir Corn Dwarf Milo Millet Kie Grass fa Seed Distribution </seg>
            <seg id="p003">:rop production in western Nebraska. NUKNT EXPERIMENTAL SUBSTA VTTE, XEBEASKA people of the western half of the ■ cut nl station. .Many other people 1 iv - •nted lands, young nicu starting ill in the cities who desired to secure a emand. It was conceded that the Bx - tted at Lincoln could not deal with S the drier and higher parts of the State . In response to this public sentiment. Hire of l!Mi;i established an Experimeii - ■ located west of the lOUth meridian, 1 15,000 for the purchase of a farm and its nance. This station was placed under the &gt;ard .&gt;;' Regents of the Unhrenitj of Ne- the central experimental station lo- 1 to purchase a suitable far 920 acres of land lying three miles south ill I'latte. It conip; tioni -I and N f of sections lM) and 29, township \'A l'he people of North I'latte and vi. in - pun liase and operate this farm for iine-half of the purchase price. The ion of the University March 1, THE FAKM The farm ii a rectangular form, two miles lonjj; north nc and a half miles wide east and v. \b north line then- are 280 acres of level bench land which is from :'&gt;&lt;&gt; to 10 feet above "sheet" water. About 210 »."&gt;. AGK. EXP. STATION Or NKlSli. VOL. XIX. ART. II. UOMVTIOX. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 acres of this is under cultivation. South of this tilled land extends the South Side irrigation diteh, which sonic day may be of value to the farm. At present it is not in condition to carry water. The land to the south of the ditch rises thru a series of camons to the table-land, having an eleva - tiun of 3,000 tKt and lying 188 f&lt;vt above the bench land. About 160 acres of level land along the east line &lt;&gt;n the table is under cultivation. The "sheet" water is about :_'"_'•"&gt; K below the surface. The remainder &lt;&gt;f tin' 1.Jr_'0 acres ure land broken by canyons. Ihe soil is mainly derived from the loess formation. Tl llala formation (the so called '•magnesia beds'" or "mo beds'") is the soil forming material in spots, and moditit loess locally. The table-land is directly derived froi loess with very local modifications from the Ogallal: t bench land is alluvium derived chiefly from Ogallala formations which occur in the hig iOtild be properly termed a sandy loam. I till native to the tilled land, indicating a soil tl ly known as "hard land' in this part of the St CONDITIONS AT ltl The farm was formerly owned by several individuals. The only real attempt at progressive fanning was made by -Mr. 1'. 1». Drake who owned the larger part of the tract for two \&lt;ars preceding its purchase by the University. II nearly 100 acres to alfalfa, securing an excellent stand on all the land seeded. The other farm land was in a poor state of cultivation, much of it not having produced a profitable crop for many years owing to shiftless methods of farming. The buildings and nearly all the fences were in a very bad state of repair. Considerable mosey has been expended in cleaning the premises and repairing fences and getting the land in condition for experimental purposes. CHAKACTKU 01 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I ■&gt; »' 4b CflHYOM PASTURE 52 FIELD 48 43 43 47 E 44 « 41 -4-O FIELD FIELD A FIELD r&gt; 3 4 Map of Substation Farm. Letters represent fields and figures sub- fields under crop. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Fi l'KOI.KISS IN I.Ml'l Dwiag tlic year L904 only h absolutely necessary for condtu All the available money w;is nee \ lew necessary teams and tools wore pin crop was put in. and the work farm was began. As this station was established with a view of permanence that it might kelp to develop the agriculture of the country, it was deemed advisable to make only such improvements a* could be built substantially and be of use for many \ When the Legislative appropriation of |20,000 for the bten - nium of April 1, IMS, to April 1. litftT. becaae available. permanent buildings were erected. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">( I Foreman*! house and horse barn. Alfalfa in the foreground is decided upon m ar the center of the tilled land this place were built a Super - t of S3.500. and a baru for the \ ion. At ii a eo § houses have been built to te spring farrowing time ng the winter. There an one 30-acre alfalfa tield iiccoinmodate twenty-five sows and 150 hogi on experiments now seven 5 -a&lt; re alfalfa lots besides two 10- aud l."&gt;-acre K which are used for growiag forage for hojp. All these are fenced with 2()-inch woven wire. re old ranch house and stable are still in use tho unsuit - and long past the date of profitable repair. The ten earns at a cost of $2,300. A house was moved from another "ii on the farm and remodeled for the residence of the oreman, at a cost of f800. The old ranrli site was retained for the live stock and tin 1 lerdsman's residence. Three cattle sheds '2'2 feet \ tN feet ind one 22 f « -t ■ t x ~1 feet, with a water system and suitable orrals of 58-inch woven wire, have been completed. Two </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Crop Product ion in Wcttcrn Nebraska. nt i i &gt;n s i th r &gt;n list Es of barbed wire fence enclosing the farm and p been temporarily repaired. Five miles of pero&amp;n&lt; ■n wire fence lias been erected for hog pastures and ho cattle corrals. The tilled land lias been brought to a state of t lion &gt; . tivation and suitably plaited for experimental parpoc hundred acres is devoted to hog pasture experiments, • enty acres of which is in alfalfa. One hundred and twe - of bench land and ninety acres of high table are plat and used for crop experiments. MtY LAND FA1 x The important problem in dry land faruiin the moisture in the soil — distributing it thruo to grow a targe crop. Init some of it comes when in and in larger quantities than can be used and oftci can 1 K&gt; when most needed by the crop. The vast reservoir for storing the water unt t. By keeping the soil loose on top, wi from the soil so that all the water i In this way we save the water in tin the crop. Surface tillage is a means of trapping I face soil is made loose and the capillary connection on the loose surface and the firmer and moister soil bel woken, making it more difficult for the water in the &lt; reach the surface, where it is lost bv evaporation. ''. th of cultivation desirable in the formation of the I Ich will depend on the frequency of cultivation ami :&gt;unt of rainfall. During a long dry period a mulch th four inches thick is not too much. If a crust forms surface, water is lost rapidly by evaporation. If a cr ms under the mulch, it prevents the circulation of air soil and also favors the escape of the water. This cr Bt be broken by deeper cultivation. growth. The total annual precipitation is usually sufti&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p009">p Production in Wettern Nebraska. 9 ( r tilled to store the moisture of one season vp may be grown the next. The more ■ bettor this moisture is conserved. When s In-ing harvested, the disk should follow rouud may be plowed later in the fall harrow and soil packer. As soon as the i the .spring the ground should be made loose juld be kept in this condition all summer or next crop is seeded. The disk and harrow should s often as necessary to keep the surface loose. When not plowed in the fall, it will be necessary to i the spring and plow before July 15. Deep I the capacity of the soil to hold water. If ivcd to grow, the effect! of summer tilling art irface should never V allowed to become hard, me conditions as leaving a hole in the ter tank: it permit! the escape of the water. tuner-till land requires as much or more labor mil raising a corn crop. [fate packing is the finning of the soil beneath the This is not done to hold the moisture but to allow up within reach of the plant roots — to water to climb up, for water cannot go t a connected line along which to travel. I very loose and full of air spaces the line is vheu the soil has been packed, the air spaces \\ i out, the soil grains brought together, and a fine ide for the upward movement of the water. However, the tilling of the soil is not the sum total of dry land fanning. Drought resistant varieties, rotations, and fertility are also very important factors. The durum varieties of wheat are outyielding the common spring wheat by many bushels per acre, and the best varieties of winter wheat are in turn outyieldiug the durum. Kherson and other earlv varieties of oats are fast replacing the common varie- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Crop Production in Western Nebraska ties. Alfalfa is destined to produce a wonderful change in the West, hoth in its effect crop. Rotations often giv&lt; tillage or varieties. All the attention in a eotnprehensiv •&lt;tii Nebraska. upon the soil and as a forage as great increase in yield as factors should be given eqnal system of crop production for Mini cut i ISTAXT ill There arc several w'avs 11 which plants may "n Iight." Bome idaiits, such as durum wheat, seem to liax faculty of maturing grain with the use of less water tlia common varieties. Other grains, as Kherson oats, •art rather than resist drought by maturing before tli Kght comes. Some crops withstand drought isive root system that collects moisture fro of soil, and still others, as the Katii \ »rding their growth and wa its haring such rharaeteri supply of moisture is unce CKAI Durum Wheat.— Four vai been tested for three seasons. Tin the Kansas Branch Experimental Station thru Mr. M A Carleton of the United states Department of Agriculture. These four varieties, Kuhanka, fellow &lt; iliarnovka, Black Dob, and Velvet Don, have been considered among Um varieties of durum wheat. Kuhanka is considered especially strong in drought resistance During the past three MasoM ■ varieties have been tested along with a variety of vet Chaff, a common spring wheat grown near the Substation. The following table, No. I. gives the results &lt;&gt;f the t&lt; - </seg>
            <seg id="p011">I 11 I A verage .'i yean 10.6 18. B li 13.9 IT - ;i 17.9 1 crop of 1904 was haikd severely when in the shook. ■ieties of the durum wheats suffered alike. The local \ taying been cut just previous to the storm was still ml therefore did not shell as readily as the others. rop of 1005 was hailed on June 30. This reduced all greatly. While there is a considerable difference in • me durum variety over the others, yet in only (lid the lowest yielding durum variety produce n and rotation plats. In cooperation with the Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 tthan twice as much as the local wheat. Fating com lu i on the two years giving the fairest results, the Blacl and Velvet Don yielded higher than cither of the othe varieties. During a drier season it is probable tha ijanka would make a better showing. And for this r would not care to advise using either of the Dons to th lusion of the Kubanka, because a crop during a iln mch more to be desired than a slightly larger yield durinj et year. The failure of the local variety to give gi ds seems to have been due to the effect of dry wealliei h in 1904 and 190G there was but little rainfall durin; time the wheat was maturing. The local wheat niuturin; r than the durum was more affected by the drought. file highest yielding durum wheat in variety tea ons gave an average yield of 18.5 bushels per acr&lt; «t, 13.9 bushels per acre The common spring &lt; led 7.1' bushels {K-r acre, or C&gt;.7 bushels per acre less lowest yielding durum variety and 11.3 bushels pel tthan the highest yielding variety of age yield per acre during three year is 2 1-3 times the average yield of it. Erum varieties not only give higher yield more rust resistant than common variet [inter Wheat. — In the fall of 1M4, thirteen variei er wheat were sown on twenty -rive acres of summer &amp; land. Some of these were seeded at various nn ing, from two pecks to six pecks per acre. The grail sown at different times between Aug. 25 and Sept the grain made a good growth in the fall, covering th tad quite completely. The following spring was favor and the growth continued vigorous. During Jun erous heavy winds, accompanied by rain. lodged th y straw and by the latter part of Jaw ater par </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 &lt; Turkey lied wheat seeded Sept. 22 was It yielded thirty bushels per acre. Some ut with the mower am! some burned ivhen necessary, to clear it for the succeeding table that the loss could have been prevented the spring, but tin* location of the fields did Government No. 10474, was sown at the same wheat. The yield of the entire crop was 1,000 c. It did not gire any indication of being a for this region. It was harvested Aug. 11, Farkey Red wheat was harvested July 17. immer of 1905, an old tree planting of ten he tableland was plowed and the trees grubbed t and was kept in a fair condition of summer tillage irken it was sown to winter wheat of the Turkey Kharkof varieties. IMats a, b, and c on adjoining seeded to varieties received from the United States \&lt;rri( ulture after the larger field was sealed No 11 result of thi&gt; \ hi at, laob Date har- Yield per Area in acres v 12 42.13 4..U It 1.09 4-J.3 4."&gt; 51 13 41 it 2 44 :il 4.". u 94.9 .4.-. •■ M 31.1 i 1 shrunk h otlier plats ;n The soil on Plat ."&gt; was packed before seeding. Plats C, 7 and S are not comparable with the other plats, as the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 previous tillage of the land was not the same and the time of seeding was later. It will be noted that the Kb. variety yielded nore than the Tnrkej Bed in each instance. The yield of Plat 1 was reduced somewhat by cutting part of 0 green that the kernels shrunk. While the Ivkarkof ti the highest yield, it is noi deemed advisal)!e to di- Turkey Bed and grow only Kliarkof. The Turkey Red been tried during many seasons in Nebraska and lutfl «d a valuable and standard variety. The Kharkof should the wheat before Se]it. 15th or sufficiently strong growth in the fall, and then, if the rank, to pasture it down. If a reasonable gi cured in the fall and a dry Bpring follows, the to be light. Bte of Seeding. Providing t itions favorable, the rat Eany great effect on the yield. The light se&lt; ool sufficiently to make tiji for the deficiency ed. It is probable that in the thicker seeded of the weaker plants are killed in tin and thai in the end the number of grains reproducing then selves does not bear a very close relation to the numbe planted but a closer relationship with their distribution o distance from other grains in the soil. Beeding two peck or thirty pounds per acre gave practically the same \ where four or live picks of seed was used. Winter Wheat versus Durum Wheat. — Only a few t common spring wheat was the only kind grown in Nebraska. Winter wheat was confined to the south* corner of tin* State. The extension of the winter wheut Ih- nade to undergo a imnv &lt;-\ i i-iui&lt;-«l test In-fore being givei I ■&lt; vide distribution. Kinic of Seeding. Prom onr observation of the perfonn ■ of winter \\lic;lt during these seasons oil tile Sllbsl;|t iol farm and on adjoining farms, it would seem advisable ti </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 / 11 and northeastern sections of the placed spring wheat in these sections. ltd to secure moisture at seeding time, ■a is being constantly .extended to the s It lias many points of advantage where v y as it ripens earlier and is sooner out of the mer drought. In many sections of the State t Summer tilled land. Yield. 42 5 P r acr me very valuable for winter pasture, to this is one of the frequent causes of failure where a dry ng follows a dry winter. When the farmers come to ap - iate the value of summer tillage in storing moisture with eh to secure a stand in the fall and the very great advan - ? of early ripening, winter wheat will be grown to a •h greater extent than now. The durum wheats hold a very valuable place in western farm operations. They have practically displaced the vari- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 - of spring wheat which were grown in the western tions, and while not so valuable as the winter wheat where an be grown, they add another successful crop in the &lt;rn part of the State, producing a large aggregate yield of grain. Oats. — Oats have proved a very satisfactory crop. In l'.MM. a thirty-acre field was sown in plats of from two to live i l»ut owing to the unusually foul condition of the land the yield from most of the plats was of no value. The three plats containing the varieties were the least affected bj weeds. The local oats had the most favorable condition* in this resjM'ct. The yields for three years are given in Talile N,. III. Table III Variety Plat « M t&gt; IS Re&lt;l Sixty Day 4 Kherson. ti l'.tu ; 11 I i&gt;ks. Apr. lo Julj 2 Da&gt; 114 Re.l li:. 11 Earlv White Champion 116 Kherson' 117 Kherson ll'.» I 'Shrunk l&gt;ecause cut too green The local oat gave much the largest yield of straw, but was later in maturing and was badly damaged by rust. In </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 ( p Production in Western Nebraska the oat crop was damaged by hail on June 30th. The baring headed, were injured the most. irher var of l'.Mtt; was subjected to a long period of dry I uue and early in July. It will be noted that the rv I&gt;;iy o;its gave the highest yield, with Kherson follow - closely. Plata 117 ami 118 were cut too green to secure ats at Sextorp. Cheyenne county. High table. Sum tilled land. Yield, 72 bushels per acre. I lie heaviest yield. The yield of the local oats was only a trifle more thau half that of the Kherson or Sixty Day Oat. Texas l»ed gare a yield of 43.3 bushels per acre, 4 1-2 l.nshels less than the Sixty Day. The results of all the tests made during the three seasons place Kherson oats at the head of the list, with Sixty Day ■ .lose second, and Texas Red not far behind. Ehe local (»at is the kind that was grown in this locality n the Substation wa.s established. In every test, except- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 p I'rothiction in \\ ■ and the local not, the local variety yielded only about half as much as the Kherson, Sixty Day, ami Texas Bed vari&lt; Tho tin- highest yield of oats secured on the Substation farm i&gt; 52 bushels per acre on a five-acre tract, reliable staten report yields of T."&gt; bushels per acre of Kherson oats from seeil secured at the Substation. The following men hav&lt; grown oats from seed furnished by i H. 1). Lute, I'axton. 81 bushels per acre. Lewis Brott, Potter, 7."» bushels pet acre. Arthur Connor, North IMatte, 7."&gt; bushels pet acre. J. W. Rosenerants. Cozad. 82 bushels per acre. Bate of Seeding. — Owing to the unfavorable condyio ferred to, tests of rate of seeding have not given satis results. The one plat of Kherson ded at the i of 1 ])ecks per acre in 1906, yielded at the rate of IT had ripened, and matured quite naturally. T ts gave no results that were considered reliahl vki.ky. — During the season of 1904, the bear common in this locality, was tested with two Algerian ties, known as Heidi and Telli barlev. Neithei as large a yield as the local variety. The Heidi variety quite early in maturing but does not yield heavy enough warrant distribution. The Telli variety is quite late in ma turing and yields but little more than the Heidi. The yields are given in Table No. IV. The crop of !!•&lt;»."&gt; was greatly injured by hail. A whit hulless barley was added to the test. In 1906 a fairei obtained. The highest yield of common bearded barley in the variety test was 44.4 bushels per acre, of hulless lv». 4 (Gov. No. 12709), and of beardless 17.8. The hulless barley [ht acre, within less than one bushel of the yield of the hiiii ■st yielding plat. The stand of &lt;&gt;ats remained thin 8 &gt;ats were not affected so muck ;»s the thicker seeded plats t the lack of moisture. It continued to mow after th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p019">iiml from Mr. II. A. Carletoii of the United Department of Agriculture. It yielded 16.74 bushels in seed pon on the Substation the year I / ha i in i with the tMMEU. — Emuier, also known as speltz, has been grown three seasons, usually in comparison with barley. Tho this crop met with favor among the farmers when it was tirst brought into the country, there seems to be a reac - tion against it of late. The tests made here would indicate that it does not yield as heavily as barley, tho current re - port! would not confirm our results. In feeding value it has not been equal to barley. "»tcl,,r-" ,h™ V \pril 7-9 Jul\ 1- 40 I •• ft ■• ! 33.3 1 IB M 1 April 7 Auk 19 19 % I 5:5 - April 11 July 7 MA is 12.6 ■■ M ■' • 17 8 m the other plats, on account of the previou </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Tabi.k V. — Emm 7 i«i| \|.r S 11 129 i:« 132 Prom 2") ]&gt;er cei • YieM of Plat it nol \v Proso Millet. — Four varieties of Proso Millet, als as Iiroom Corn Millet and Hog Millet, wei in I'.*"! and 1966; also one variety in 1908. The yields wen- from IS io 20 bushels per aere. As a forage for 1 lo. to have any value above any ordinary kind ot . Rape gare evidence oi being much more satisfactory for ill puri)ose. Wkere so many other grains and forage crope c ■; &gt;\vn, Proso Millet will not be found very profitable u less under peculiar conditions. The varieties tested w Orenburg, Bed Voronesh, Black Voronesa and Gov. N &lt; oun. — Corn is one of the most important crops of wee Nebraska. Near the western border, only early maturing varieties gire any certainty of producing mature corn. Th&lt; - larj:e varieties like Silver Mine are liable not to become ma ture in normal years as far west as North Platte. Tin tat ion for better seed corn has influenced farmers in this </seg>
            <seg id="p021">rop Production in Nebraska. 21 ( tring in much Med from farther oast. This has vt tv serious results iu the past two seasons, but should have come as early as it lias other seasons the ; good corn from this seed would probably have small. It is highly probable that better results can be I'd by selecting an early maturing variety of medium hat has been grown under these conditions for some and developing it by careful selection. in n 1006 MX A Yi Husk, i7 1 47 I »-J 4 4(1 1 16.4 :.-i.-i I 17.4 1-J 4 Hi I ;;&gt; :; in '.i '.i ills of i wo years' tests on the Substation indicate &lt;'al lico is I lie best corn tested. The seed planted in 1905 it grown west of the center of the State. The yields ii are figured from the weights of the corn when shucked. pounds per bushel. We have no facilities for oWHl trying corn, therefore the yield as ghrca does not take into onsideration the unripe condition of the lanxe vari&gt; Eco and Pride of the North were fully mature. Sufficient have not been secured on methods of cultivation to war - publication. 1 An-:i Yii-1.1 , - ■rt in acres p^r 38 :: B2 16 I </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 ANNUAL FORAGK CHOPS The crop of 1904 was destroyed by hail. In 1905 cam- was planted in the following manner: i 1 t listed as corn is ordi - narily listed, BSing the same plate; (2 i drilled in double ro« - 7 inches apart, each pair of rows 35 inches from the next pair; i .'! i drilled in single rows :{."&gt; inches apart ; i ti drilled rain; (5) sowed broadcast. Kafir corn and dwarf milo were drilled in doable and in single rows. All seed sown in rows was cultivated. This test was duplicated in l!&gt;i)&lt;; and there was added a plat of dwarf milo drilled and a phi t &lt;&gt;f cane sown broadcast and harrowed twice after it was up. With the tests of both years there have been plats of corn of a few millets. Table No. VII ".ivcs the results of i u M Kind .... listt harrowed Milo drilled Silurian millet, drilled German millet drilled Proao millet . . drilled IJank. — Cane has been considered the forage crop for the lands of western Nebraska for many vears. The results these tests indicate that it has a just claim to such con - oration. In 1905 a 20-acre field of sod that was broken Kafir corn. . . . ■ni .... ;;;;■:;; . double row drilled . . double row drilled . double row drilled . single row drilled.. . . single row drilled. . single row ilrilk- 1 . . drilled . broadcast . ... 41 (I II 43 u </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 1 1 I" n v horoly disked and drilled to cane produced 4.25 tons of r acre. A 10-aere field treated in u similar manner )uly a slightly smaller yield. 1DUU wo years gives L'.tiOU pounds per KR heav- ;&gt;m cane drilled in pairs of rows than from that Dgie rows :i ii&lt; 1 1 ,:&gt;(»(&gt; iMiunds pet acre heavier tlian lat drilled thick. When we consider the labor of cul - &lt;' the rowed cane and the fact that it is coarser than towed thick, these results favor drilling cant- thickly i grain drill. However, there is but little doubt that in mis cane planted in such a way that it can be culti- II produce heavier than that not M tended. Th i &gt;f drilling the rows in pairs or singly for two years with Kafir corn and dwarf milo, gives l.ooo pounds per acre r yield from that rowed in pail •ited cane gave a light yield in 1905. This was due i stand caused by much of the cane being was of the two plats sowed broadcast, the one harrowed twice lei- the cane was up gave a slightly heavier yield. Kafiu ( Kafir corn has given nearly as heavy ton- tas cane. The forage is of excellent quality. Kafir corn given better results when planted in single rows, while ind milo have given better results when planted in pain ws. Kafir corn is considered more drought-resistant cane, and because of this character should be more dely grown than it is at present. EiAiif M ii.ti. — Dwarf milo, while giving good results, lias n no advantage over cane unless, as may be, the seed is r for feed. It yields from (KM) to 1,000 pounds per acre ■ forage than cane, and has a more woody stem. The yield acre has ranged from 3.13 to 4.71 tons. Eiu.KT. — The varieties grown in this locality under the e of German and Siberian have given nearly the same 1, the Siberian producing 200 pounds more per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 i Eer has vicldcd one-half as alfalfa, cue si ill ■tends rii Nebraska. much per acre as cum as th main foraei 1 croi r BttOMK CliASS I III i On Aug. 23, l!tU4, four plat ceded to brume • on tilled bench wen I were on well-tilled tableland, on out' on a hillside in a pasture. 1 cm the plais of tilled land and a ulv 16, r.mr,. the Srs4 tkree plat* T for the seed. The Yield of see Thick stands we thin stand on th were harvested i d thrashed from 1 157 pounds per vield would hav&lt; at «jiviii&lt;j the he Hi Ewas 260 pounds. Ton pounds, an e grass had been cut for hay the L5 lo .*! tons per acre. The pi had been in alfalfa prerioui Us Diu-iii" the season of l'.MMi il i ii I make a satisfactory growth. The led L5 tons of hav per acre. Tin never showed a thick stand, but r altho the cattle keep it picket t plats were seeded in the gprin 5. Ill almost every instance, fai the weeds made il advisable in ii !( wl them. in August, 1906, land from which a ed early was disked and seeded to but little rain during the fall, tin Ber rye came up. Some of this rye the field as soon as it had headed. \ \s 1 w; \ w The remainder rye was harvested and thrashed. The half of the tie which the rye was cut early, has much the better stand. Thi would indicate that anything in the nature of a nurs&lt; weeds or grain — should be cut down, that the grass may hav all the moisture. There are now on the farm about n seeded to broine grass. Our experience would indicate th </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Xcbraska. 25 \ i i the most important factors in the ran crops, but particularly when small, ,1s arc to be planted. For alfalfa M-nlial that the soil be in the proper ,1 bed should be deep, tine, firm, and moist. •■fi\ only by deep plowing and subsurface he soil plenty of time in which to settle. choosing a time of abundant rainfall. muot be made tinn after plowing, it will prove If the seed bed is not moist, sowing will prove discouraging. Too much attention can n to having the seed bed in the right condition. re several varieties of brome grass. Some of U 1 .. nisses and must be reseeded each year. BltMMM i perennial. When a stand is once secured, it re- the native gi It is very important that the cured. It can be bought from seed houses raising it, at from 8 to 10 cents per pound. ; ht seed such as that of brome grass, loses vitality rap - ; therefore the seed should be sown when fresh. ie usual custom is to sow l&gt;0 pounds per acre, broadcast and. The land is then harrowed twice with a common. II loot bed barrow. If good seed is sown during a moist tnd is assured, but if a few dry, hot days follow the stand is likely to be thin. advisable to sow when conditions of soil, seed, and are rieht, regardless of the month. Seed sown in have to contend with weeds during the rowth. This gives it such an advantagt t tields that if all other conditions are the same the a ill give much the better result To thicken the stand, the main requirement on the part of ! farmer is patience. Even if the plants are very small 1 far apart, they will cover the ground if given sufficient ie and moisture. To assist them, the weeds should be </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Crop Production in Wcattm Wbruska. mowed frequently. Sonic fields that were seeded in the fall of 1905, showed only a very thin stand during the summer of 1906, but when fall approached with an abundant rainfall, the plants spread rapidly and now a good stand is in evi - dence. Erome grass is primarily a pasture j^rass, rather than a &lt;_ r rass. As a iwrmaneiit hay gram adaptable for cultiva - uudcr our conditions lias not been found, the brome ■ is made to serve two purposes. Its chief value will Fig. 7. — Brome grass, June, 1906, from seedir r Bench land In- fur pasture, tho it may be cut as millet or timothy and used for hay. It will be found that this hay is quickly black cned by dew or rain and musts easily. In this wpoct it is very unlike the forage plants grown in this region. Broiue grass has the ability to withstand dry weather to an extent not equalled by any other tame graaa, It may </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 the native grasses in this characteristic. It starts grow - 1 the ipring about as early as rye and continues to grow ill winter has set in in earnest. On Dec. 1, 1906, [&gt;lats were green and inviting to stock. c grass has not been tested sufficiently in the West mt any prophecy as to its future place in our agricul- Opinioaa of those growing it vary. It relishes moisture growl best when we have the largest rainfall, yet it istands drought. It is the most promising perennial g WCstcin conditions yet introduced. It should be given a fair and thoro trial by every farmer and ranchman in west - ern Nebraska. It may yet prove valuable in reseeding the pastures in the sandhills. The brome gram is gradually taking possession of the plats of meadow fescue and orchard ntM8 seeded adjacent to it. ALFALFA About SO acres of bench land and 98 of table-laud were seeded to alfalfa in the spring of 1M2, by Mr. F. 15. Drake. Fig. 8.— Stacking alfalfa on high table-l»D«l. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Crop Production in Western Nebraska i i An excellent stand was secured on all the laii of the bench land is now tired for ho&lt;i pasture dnced three crop* of one too &lt;&gt;r more per acre each, during Msuns of HMU. 1905, and 1906. In the lots most heat pastured, the yield has noi been bo great. Daring the &lt;li time we have had in these three years, June and July, !'.•'•» the rainfall being less than two inches while the crop {rowing, this alfalfa gave one of the largest crops we h; ever cut. This indicates that the roots are getting moist i from the deeper soil anas not quickly affected by Tin- Held on the table is nearly l'&lt;mi the Wench, the elevation being about 3,000 ■ hi a level tract of ••hard"' ta it w with buffalo grass before being broken up. Tl produced from two to three crops each year, p par acre, depending entirely upon the precipitatii growth has always been sue! there would have been abnnd In the spring of 1904, tin seeded to "dry land" seed from Utah. 1 (•factory growth, and during the season of I'.mm had a kmg dry period, this alfalfa gav&lt; of producing more growth than alfalfa fn However, as the seeding was not don rate comparison could be made, the fall of 11M4. August i':{.l. a pla table was sown to alfalfa. This has given good re On May 10. IMS, cooperative work was begui w Bureau of Plant Industry of the United States Departmen &lt;&gt;f Agriculture to test the result of seed from various coui tries and states, and also the effect on the plant of inoculatin the seed. This test consists of 17 one tenth-acre plats the bench land and an equal number on the table-land. Bo from the following plac&lt; \vn : Montana, Kansas, I t;i </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 i irrigat' stern Nebraska, Mu - mis, (iennany, Poitou ami Provence, Afghanistan, Turkistan, Minnesota, M» Nebraska (not inoculated » aud com lent stands were secured ou all plats and table, with the exception of the plats Peru. The stand on these plats was very ill of the plants living in the fall winter - lier plats are growing nicely. Weights are amounts of hay cut on each plat, but this \ h « in progress long enough to warrant any veral plats on the bench gave a total yield ' more than four tons per acre. This alfalfa &gt;n mes, while that on the table was cut but me but not again until September, after the 1 started the crop growing again. i J s iia \ i \ determine some method that will make •d crop more successful. In this test, seed Ml Mi iown at different rates of seeding, art ire favorable, there is no difficulty in When com ed crop in western Nebraska. The table - nsidered best adapted to producing v \ farmer living on high table-land, more than 200 miles v. raised L50 bushels of excellent seed thi K. m 50 acres. We have not been successful in raising a ii d rop and has been secured at the first seeding on all A El Of the farm, excepting four plats where the seed was led loo deep and the two on which the Peruvian Med -own No farm crop is destined to play a greater part in the development of this region than alfalfa. Its feeding value forag.- crop for all kinds of stock has been proved re- ooperathre expertaenta was begaa in the </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 appreciated by only ;i few of the foremost alfalfa ami li Tlio our soil is rich in plant food, the alfalfa has a niai vclous effect in increasing its productivity. The physical con (lit ion of tlic soil undergoes a marked change when tin- a I falfa roots have grown in it for a tew years and then ha\ roiled and left their fertility for other crops. Grain sown in such soil starts out with a more vigorous growth thai sow n on adjoining land. The crop continues thriftier, b er leaved, larger, and darker green in color. On the Si tion farm, on land that had been in alfalfa followed bv corn. wheat gave more than four times ami oats more than t\\ as heavy yields as the same crops grown on the a&lt; fields which had previously been in corn during the p tlie other field grew alfalfa. Alfalfa has been growing in small fields lands for many years. Some lived thru the d the '90's and is doing well, l'oth on the •'hard "sandy" land, this crop is proving its adaptability. S fields are now scattered all over the state. On miles over table-land, seven fields were passed. Tli than 100 miles west of Kearney. These fields an tended and many more sown. Over nearly all th tin' soil is favorable. When the crop is once well establi and its roots deep in the soil, it will withstand any drought that has visited the country since settlement began. No field is too free from weed seed or too rich for alfalfa The best field on the farm is none too mod. One of tin worst enemies of alfalfa is the weeds that it must contend Ei during the first few months of its growth. Land to be ed to alfalfa should he given the most thoro preparation ihle. It should have been summer tilled the preceding year, or, in case this condition is not possible, corn land should give good results. This should be double disked and pcstcdly* J is vsilue in pork pr&lt; h I wet ion is ;is \ &lt; •! I m *i 11 . ITS. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 ( Kwed M soon as the soil is in a tillable condition in tin 1 ;. This treatment should be repeated at frequent inter- lic land is seeded. re should he exercised in purchasing to secure Kcd free adulterations and grown under the proper climatic con Some seed conies from fields in which noxious weeds t i ii&lt; 1 worthless clovers are growing with the alfalfa. Other Med is purposely adulterated with inexpensive seed similar tpearance, yet other seed is brought in from farther ■e the rainfall is greater, or from irrigated laud, or from art her south where the winters are mild. Crops from eed are liable to be killed for waut of moisture or by mperatorea in winter. To guard against impur&gt; I seed not adapted to our conditions, it is well to purchase ectly from the grower. If this cannot be done, goo I usually be secured thru any reliable dealer by demanding grown under the proper conditions and tree from other . and by paying a price that will command such seed. A fade is dear at any price. Such terms as '-fancy." •■prime," give no indication of where the see&lt;] was f how many kinds of seeds are mixed with tb« Efa seed. The best seed to sow in western Nebraska is grown on our tablelands without irrigation or grown what similar conditions. 1 It is customary to sow 120 pounds per acre broadcast or ra drill. If broadcast, it should be harrowed until the is firm; if drilled, the drill should bo run quite shallow. When a crust forms before the plants are up or when a wind is blowing and cutting off the young plants, it will prove profitable to break and roughen the surface with a harrow. The alfalfa plant needs all the moisture available; there fore a nurse crop should not be used. For the same reason fie Department of Botany. Agricultural Experiment Station. Lincoln aska. will test srra^s anil alfalfa sceil for paities sending a sample of seed the IMH of the ]&gt;artv from whom it was secureil The locality in which </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 19 during the seasoa. The cutter bar should be run ;i!»&gt;nt ■ inches hijih, as the i&gt;lanls ma\ be injured by being eul dose to the ground when young. When a heavy growth lfalfa or weeds is cut. it should be raked and hauled off. ag alfalfa is (jniie easily smothered. Alfalfa should t be pastured the tirst season, and should not be gp en when old. If a growth of six or more inch on (he land in the fall, the alfalfa will start several days ier in the spring. of oats and S bushels of wheat sold in 1905 &gt;o.. County the acreage e.f oats was i (Ml wheat more than 17"&gt; crown in 1906 fr&lt; man in UK).".. In 1904. 10 bushels of Kherson ,\ fanner Urine near the Substation. He v t the first season and sold nearly all of it for seed. II mates that 300 acres were grown from tl These are the partial results of seed secured by thr Twenty-five men have bought Kherson oats from th s station. This variety of oats is now the leading oat vicinity of the Substation, and is rapidly being intro u into the most western counties. The highest yield of Kherson oats reported was secured by KIT. D. Lute of Paxton. A 10 acre Held of irrigated land led 81 bushels per acre. .Mr. Lewis Brott of Bextorp, It DISTRIBUTION. It is the polk; of the Substation to dwtribui varieties of grain tli.it have proven superior to i-oiuinonh grown. Kherson oats and durum wli sent into many parts of the state. In some acreage grown from this ned is bo large thai liave become centres for further distribution. In Haves County more than loo acres of Khe .'."&gt; acres (tf (lnrnni wheat were crown in 1906 fr» </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Crop Production in Western Nebraska. 83 &gt;orts a yield of 72 bushels per acre of i^lis 40 pounds iht bushel. Tin - fallowed 15-acre field of bi^ti ■■hard* K i to irrigation. In IMS, Mr. I'.mtt f Kherson oats per acre. 906 there ware distributed :&gt;&lt;»o bushels of t wheat. Tin- reporta received to date in II inds have been secured in nearly every wing letters indicate the results coming from the of grain. Both of these farmers live on high llcolll, Nebr. \ In reply to yours of Sept. 19th will say, 1 have 1 that ."&gt; acres of macaroni wheat, and according line measure I had 148 1-2 bushels, but think by it will easily make :&gt;(( bushels. 1 had all mv wheat isne I threshed Signed Peter \i s Noltll I'latle. Xebf. Dear Sir Finished threshing about a month ago and will von the yields below i Haifa 1.-.0 bushels. 3 bushels seed per aere. 1." acres Kherson oats sown on hide and disked in Hill) bushels. 34.6 bush els pet acre. 15 acres Kherson oats, sum- mer cultivation 1080 bushels, 72 bushels per acre. Sextorp, Nebr., !&gt;&lt;•&lt;•. 1, 190ft. Bextorp, Nebr., Oct 17, L906. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 s 20 acres macaroni wheat 240 bushels, 12 bushel per acre. Have derided to M&gt;« 86 late next rammer. u&lt; ivs of alfalfa in 40-inch row Respectfully, sinifes for the seton f v l ,? epart " lent of -^culture, rendered v.)n«ble (Signed) L. Bm </seg>
            <seg id="p035">AGWCILTIRAL EXPERIMENT STATION OP NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD CARL I. ERNST, President, Omaha )RD, Falls City THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, B.Sc, Director I. S. DALES, M.Pii., Financial Secretary W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF Inimai Husbandry M., Animal Pathology Ki Ieald, Ph.D., Botany mtstry E. G. Montgomery, B.Sc, Field Crops F. G. Miller, M.K., Forestry G. K. Chatbikn. A.M., Higkwmy Engineering R. A. Kmkkson, B.Sc, Horticulture W. P. Snyder, M.S.. Superintendent Experimental Substation, North PUtU J. H. Gain, M.D.C., Associate in Animal Pathology A. F. Magdanz, Jr., A.B., Assistant in Animal Husbandry L. B. Sturdevant, A.M., Assistant in Animal Pathology Martin Nelson, M.S., Assistant in Field Crops. ¥. E. Denny, A.B., Assistant in Horticulture EL1SHA C. CALKINS, Kearney S. ALLEN, Lincoln G. WHITMORE, Valley &lt;VBBOTT, Columbus A. L. Hakckkr, B.Sc.A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bkiner, B.Sc, Entomology Erwin H. Barboir, Ph.D., Geology O. V. P. Stout, C.E., Irrigation /engineering G. A. Loveland, B.Sc, Meteorology Alvin Keyser, A.M., Soils </seg>
            <seg id="p036">The following bulletins of the Station may be had on request: No. 25 Detasseling Corn. No. 29, Cost of Farm Crops. No. 33 Meteorological Observations for 1893 No. 38'. Nebraska and the Beet Sugar Industry. Report of Dr. Max 11 rung, Halle, Germany. Translated from "Zeitschrift des Vereins fuer Ruebenzucker Industrie des DeuUchen Reichs." No. 39 Some Obstacles to Successful Fruit Growing No. 40, A Preliminary List of the Honey-Producing Plants No. 41 Water Supply in Nebraska. No. 42 Nebraska Weather Review for 189E Nebraska Weather and Clitnat No. 46 s No. 48 Windbreaks No. 49 Suggestions for Chicory Cult No. 50 Notes on Pruning ng-.V No. 51 Observations on the Co&lt; No. 52 Cornstalk Disease ■ 53, A Preliminary Report on Experiments with Forap 54. The Effect of Certain Methods of Soil Treatment I Crop. No. 55 Ornamental Planting No. 56 Methods of Tree Plantii ■ 58, Annual Forage Crops for Summer Pasture. 60, Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Heet in Nebraska. No. 70 Locusts or Grasshoppers No. 73 Experiments in the Culture of 1! 1 No. 77, Poisoning of Cattle by Common Sorghum and Kaf K No. 79 Experiments in Orchard Cultur No. 84 Pasture, Meadow, and Forage ( No. 85 Feeding Experiments with Catt No. 87 A Test of Calf Rations. Methods of Milk During Milking. Apple Scab and Cedar Rust. No. 88 No. 89 Winter Wheat. No. 90 Cattle Feeding Experiment No. 91 Experiments with Corn Cover-crops for Young Orchard No. 92 No. 93 Cattle Feeding Experiments No. 94 Fattening Pigs on Corn and Tankage. Crop Production in Western Nebraska. No. 95 No. 96 The Hessian Fly No. 97 Potato Experiments. (In pre No. 98, Spraying Demonstrations in Nebraska Apple Orchards fin press ) Press Bulletin No. 16. Alfalfa Experien r Bulletin No. 18. A Pig Feeding Experiment at the N( periment Station. Press Bulletin No. 19. The Hessian Fly Press Bulletin No. 20, Fattening Pigs and Wintering I Sow Alfalfa and a Grain Ration Press Bulletin No. 21, A Good Oat for Nebraska Press Bulletin No. 22. Malarial Fever in Horses PresB Bulletin No. 23, Ergot and Ergotism Press Bulletin No. 24. The Bleaching of Wheat Flour. Press Bulletin No. 25. The Seed of Cheat, Meadow Fescue and Brome Grass AddreSB AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION Lincoln. Nc br </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>