<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00046.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00046.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Consolidation of Rural Schools</title>
               <date value="1917-07">1917-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Consolidation of Rural Schools Play Activities Rural School • STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION LINCOLN W. H. CLEMMONS, State Superintendent ALICE FLORER, Assistant Superintendent Department of Rural Education </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONSOUOA J1ON OF RURAL SCHOOLS 5 INTRODUCTION Nebraska is comparatively a young state, but she has made rapid progress along educational lines. The Rural School Prob - lem is one of great interest and is now demanding the attention of a thinking and economical people. There is nothing too good for the rural child. The country - man is ready to meet all possible legitimate expense and the good work and feeling is manifest on every hand. This department is doing everything it can for Consolidation — the Rural High SchoJ. the Combination School and the One-Room School. Not only th. - physical conditions, such as sanitary school buildings, well-kept grounds, provided with necessary amusement-equipments are em - phasized, but the character, school efficiency and inspirational ac - tivities of the teachers are receiving the most careful consideration from this department. To build a great and lasting educational system, there must b. - umtx all along the lines. The country and town must come to - gether for one purpose — the betterment of the child, morally, in - ilustnallx and intellectually. Our people are getting together and arc rapidly solving the Rural School question and the time is not far distant when Nebraska will be able to place at the door of ever\ country boy and girl a splendid, advanced educational opportunity Miss Alice Florer, State Inspector of Rural Schools in Xc - braska has made a careful study of the Rural School question and incorporates herewith the results of the best experience of the nation. Facts are given at every instance to support the conclu - sions relative to Nebraska conditions. It is earnestly desired that all who receive this bulletin will read it carefully and pass it to his neighbor. The one thing the Department seeks is to get the school conditions and necessities properly before the people. Every advance step taken must of necessity have difficulties to surmount and criticisms to overcome. Our forefathers faced these same obstacles, but thev faulted not </seg>
            <seg id="p004">6 and today we have a nation, not faultless, but really directing the affairs of the world, ii'e must look ahead, build for the future, systematize our educational system for tiw tomorrow, withholding nothing from the child that zcill cause it to be a good American and useful citizen. To be educated does not mean to get rid of work, but it means to be able to do more and better work and shorten the time of operation. Our inheritance is a great state aboun ■ 1 i 1 1_-_» - in wealth and limitless possibilities. To make the most of these we must furnish a thinking people equal to the task before them. To accomplish this orr efforts must be well directed : needed edu - cational — facilities granted — active and incessant work on the part of all those vitally interested in the proper education of the rural VV. H. CLEMMONS State Si mountenden </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONSOLIDATION OF RURAL SCHOOLS 7 IMPROVEMENT IN RURAL SCHOOLS As we look back to the school house of pioneer days with its rude benches, old stove, open water pail, etc., we realize that there have been many changes and that the schools twenty-five years ago were quite an improvement over the pioneer school. But now that our civilization has progressed to the stage of automobiles, gas - oline engines, milk separators, gas lights, Victrolas and many other conveniences of the farms, we are not satisfied with the school housv f twenty-five years ago, nor are we satisfied with general condi- that surround such school houses ( &gt;ur dissatisfaction probably arises from the fact that we have learned by actual experience what environment will do for people : we have learned the value of unconscious influence in the child's education. The surroundings of home, school and social com- panions, dres , manners and general conversations all make an im - pression that is more effective and more lasting than even direct Rural School Play Activities </seg>
            <seg id="p006">8 ONE-ROOM SCHOOL To overcome many shortcomings that abound in the one-room rural sch&lt;xil, other states than ours have solved the problem by consolidation. It is true that there are parts of Nebraska where consolidations are impracticable because of physical conditions such as canons, roads, streams and distances. Some schools can consolidate with propriety : other schools can have rural high schools with propriety ; while there are yet other districts that can meet this problem by a combination or a two-room school. It is not desired on the part of the State Department to force these school conditions upon the people, but it is the desire to enlighten the people on the advantages to the child of school con - centration, and thus working together we will be able to givt- to the rural commonwealth the best possible advantages for the com - plete development of the rural child. In the one-room school every influence in the district must &gt;e brought about to bring the best possible conditions. With a good teacher, necessary equipment, including a modern, sanitary. &gt;roperly heated, properly lighted building, play ground apparatus and other conveniences good results can be secured in a one-room ■school, but the one-room school limits the possibility of reaching -■hove the eighth grade. If a district employs one teacher and that &gt;ne teacher does efficient work, she has everything to do that she •an possibly do to make thorough the common school subjects. On the other hand, the child is handicapped who attempts to -tudy high school subjects under the direction of a teacher who has all of the grades to teach no matter how efficient the teacher may &gt;e. It is an impossibility for the child to have as much of the eacher's time as it should have to accomplish the work it must do. The consolidated school facilitates and brings to the door of the country home an education that will enable the child to enter u|¥&gt;n his competitive life-w.&gt;rk, and at the same time, if he chooses, prepares him to take up college or university work. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">COSSOLIDATIOS OF RLRAL SCHOOLS 9 PURPOSE OF CONSOLIDATION. consolidation of rural schools is ;itional ad vantages. This system Fhe s^ria &gt;e of the the r\ child educ irst A well organized, well equipped and properly con ducted rural school. Second — Enough children in the classes to make the work interesting and vital. Third — Enough territory to make the district efficient, financially. 1 -'ourlli — Well-trained, efficient teachers, with an effective and agreeable division of labor. Fifth — Proper system of gradation and classification of pupils. Sixth — Longer recitation periods. Seventh — An enriched course of studv Eighth — High School advantages for every country boy and irirl. Nebraska and other states have found it impossible to secure K advantages in the one-room rural school. Consolidation Meeting in Gage County &gt;r&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p008">10 1 FIRST CONSOLIDATED SCHOOL The first consolidated school was estahlished in Massachu - setts. In planning for the first consolidated school, Massachusetts met with all the opposition Nebraska and other states are meeting with today, hut the same people who injected then are now its strongest supporters and warmest friends. INDIANA AND OHIO. We hear a great deal about the consolidated districts of In diana, Ohio and I'tah. SoBK people think our problems are similar but we find their conditions to be entirely different from our* They are more densely populated and their roads are piked o paved, which puts them in a different class from Nebraska. The could consolidate so much more easilv from the standpoint of dis tance and transportation NORTH DAKOTA schools of North Dakota. North Dakota has our problem and ever a more difficult one, Ixcause its population is very much more sparse than our;;, which makes longer transportation routes. N'ortl Dakota has four hundred otic consolidated schools. |"i\ ago they had one hundred fourtee* 1 . which demonstrates the fact that the schools have given tatisfactioa or this number would not have increased so rapidly. The inspector reports that thi increase during this time trebled the increase the preceding twenn NORTH DAKOTA LEGISLATURE 6 Five ylears ago the Legislature of North Dakota established »rtment to be organized and supervised by an officer known as State Inspector of Consolidated. Graded, and Rural Schools." Attention is respectfully called to the consolida </seg>
            <seg id="p009">CONSOLIDA TIOS OF RURAL SCHOOLS 11 It ■n h Ik n 1) t r also provided for an appropriation for this department. At the 1 of four rcan this appropriation was increased to make an mint four times the original siv.n ;iul designated that most of it ulil go lor consolidated schools. This has made it possible for Rural School Inspector to visit and supervise the schools of the ite and to raise the standards materially. This action dem - istrates the fact that the representative men of the State of Xorth ikota believe that a well-rounded, practical education for the boys nl skirls of the state is an asset, a resource, if you please, and they ink that, to the extent that they appropriate the money of the ite as an investment. What can be a better investment than one which brings in urn "Ciood Citizenship.'" Better schools make better boys and Is. which means better men and women and better citizenship. North Dakota reports the following benefits it has found as result of consolidation: i. Knrollment five years ago in consolidated schools. . . . s.(&gt;2^ Enrollment today in consolidated idtoob 24,210 Number doing high sch'H)l work five years ago 450 Number doing high school work today 2.455 X umber of eighth grade graduates trebled with twice the qualitv of work. Nine months term with 0,0 per cent attendance instead of ja months with fig per cent attendance. 8. Ketter high school privileges : ten times the number of coun - try pupils completing high school at one-fifteenth the cost to the individual pa*! on. &gt;. I tetter organization — a teacher with three grades and fif - teen classes daily instead of six grades with thirty classes. in. Fifteen visits per year by county superintendent instead of two or three. 11. Better civic and social opportunities. A good place for club, literary societies, social events, athletic contests, lec - tures and art exhibits. I !etter work in grades. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">12 Lin summing up the advantage-, we tin 1 the following fav.iralilt consolidation : 1. It increases the attendance, enrollment and makes attend ance More regular. 2. The older children are kept in school longer and it pr vii'.es for high school privilege* at urn-thin] the cost the district and one-nftrenth the cost to the patron compared with the old system. t, It makes possible the securing of better trained teacher improves industrial conditions in the coontn incl food road- and enhancing farm value-. 4. liittir training memms better wt&gt;rk eird 1 It conserve- tlie health of the children, gives an active con munitv interest and provides for all-cou tUllCtK 6. It gives ample time 1 a reduces tardiness and truano and makes super and better 7. It prevents drifting to the larger cities and k&lt; u vk r the neces : \\ \ ad benign i-irluences o and provides a general eliK'ational environment 8. l'roni every Mgk of inquiry consolidation is the one thi needful to brag so tlu rural o nimonvealth of Xehras 1 since it gives SO all an e(|iia! chance in the race of li ri Utes, distance for tirs apjiend the fallowing schedule co child to ri&lt;le. monthlx salary of each driver and Bomber of c'lildre in each wagon in one cnunty where consolidate. 11 has •TOVea BO l&gt;e successful : In this countv we find transnortation costs nine cent- per day |rt pupil: that there is no tardiness with transportation: attend ance is at its maximum. As farther enli^htment concenwi conMttdatians, we herewitl </seg>
            <seg id="p011">CONSOLIDATES OF RURAL SCHOOLS 13 CONTRACTS WITH DRIVER The driver ligm a contract which specifics his duties; he gives $300 bond tor the faithful discharge of his duties; maintains order the wagon both coming and going from s-rhool. This school transports 1(13 pupils: 100 pupils live close enough walk, making a total of -03 pupils in the school. Thus a higher ducation is brought directly to the home of the country child and ver\ advantage is given for country-life-cominunity-interests. TRANSPORTATION 1 hstanee for first Child Monthly Pay Nvakcr Children Route to Ride if Driver in Wagon -4 miles miles *3 50.00 -'5 4 4 miles 4O.0O -'4 miles 37-5° _•_&gt; miles 55-°o -'5 _»o 3 miles 44-oo &lt; \ vi. rage $45.11,) Total 163 wagons / Rural School Play Apparatus 4 miles :&gt;4&lt;,t.(&gt;o 2 ■lei 40.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">14 TIMELY SUGGESTIONS No institution worked out by human minds i&gt; perfect. If we waited to get a perfect system before it was put into practice, we vould make no progress. Everything in the line of invention &gt;r improvement of any kind lias come al&gt; nit gradually. Elect ricit\ and all of its uses as we know them today were not discovered vithoiu years of practice and application. Even a plan that ;i\ &gt;roaches per tec lion will fail in application in some localities. We enow, judging from our own observations of the application of the ilan of consolidation in other states, that the consolidated rural chool rs practicable. Progress means overcoming difficulties. Standing still means stagnation. The old must give place to newer and better things. The automobile lias and will solve the problem of fMld roads. Nc people in the state have a better right to demand good roada than the farmer who must transport the products of his farm several miles to market. This means that the transportation problem will sooner or later be solved most satisfactorily. Consequently the con veyance of the children who live three to five miles will be compara tively easy to overcome and this problem should not stand in the way of the child's better education. The wa\ to meet and overcome this difficulty is to put each mdiiidin.il shoulder to the whtel oi this educational development, pull and push together. A splendid school building, well equipped and well manned wit a live, active teaching force, is a valuable asset to any rural con munitv. The teachers' cottage should be modern, containing a parlor, sitting room, bed rooms, dining room, kitchen, laimdn and bath rijom. The architecture of the building should be a model for the entire community. The teacher who su|)ervises this school work should be a man or a woman who is in love with country-life and country-conditions, and who is a careful gardener, florist and cs|&gt;e - cially adapted to farm-life. A complete record should l&gt;e kept by each individual student and teacher covering all transactions — growing a product and mar- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">COSSOLIDATIO.X OF RLRAL SCHOOLS 15 keting the same. Hach girl student should Ix' required to keep an exact record of all meals served in the domestic science department and the cost of each article. These books must be kept as a part of the record of such rural schoi 1. Accurate records of ve^cab'.e production, dairying and poultry-raising will furnish a most va'.u able lesson in bookkeeping, thus making practical the e lucation received. Forty-six states have taken up the work of consolidation and everywhere that it has been tried, satisfaction prevails. Ver - mont expended in iyo8 $73,465.24 for consolidation. This was an increase of 100 per cent over that which was appropriated in 1903. Virginia increased its expenditure for the transportation of chi'.dre 1 $44,000 in five years. This is sufficient proof that consolidation is not inadvisable : rather the reverse, it speaks volrmes for the betterment of rura! children and community life. In the erection of suitable buildings, care and judgment should Ik- used. It is not necessary that you should pay double what a thng is actually worth. Build for the future and biild well, re - membering that it is not the first cost that makes the expense, bu tlie constant repairing and "adding to" that makes an expensive building. It is well, however, to proceed with this work well in formed and to act wisely as well as judiciously in every step taken If it is necessary to consult an architect, do it for the district jus the same as \ 011 would do it for your own private business — econoim. At all times the State Department should be consulted. M it is a part and parcel of its duty to assist in giving plans, speci - fications and suggestions along the lines of nuxlern school build - ing- and playground equipment, and this information can be had simply for the asking. In addition to reading this bulletin, feel free to consult with this department any time. The Rural Department is organized to promote the best interests of the boys and girls of Xebraskit. Let us co-operate with you and help you whenever and wherever you feel we can be of service. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">« </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CONSOLIDATION OF RURAL SCHOOLS 17 i &lt;. c I HOW TO PEOCEED TO CONSOLIDATE. Rend and become thoroughly jam liar wttk the Imm concerning olidation. Some districts should not attempt consolidation be- MM of roads, streams and other inconvenient conditions. Look ver the situation in your district and decide whether the Physical ditions will justify you in consolidating. Transportation Wagons Trumbull Consolidated School IF PHYSICAL CONDITIONS ARE RIGHT— Talk consolidation with every voter in the districts concerned. Talk ci&gt;ns&gt;l d.Uion wM your county superintendent. Hold a Meeting in each district and have a speaker who is posted i'ii consolidation Hold a mass meeting of the patrons of all districts concerned. MhI haze a speaker who beUtvet in the benefits that consolidation yrmg I isit consolidated districts and discuss the question with the patii'iis of these districts. These people have had the experience and will lx- glad to fjivc you information concerning their schools. Vote what is said in this bulletin about the planning and build- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">18 CONSOLIDATION OF RURAL SCHOOLS iii£ of a school-house. There were twenty-six consolidated schools in Nebraska pre - vious to January i, 1917. Eigktttm cf these sellouts were cot- Milidated previous to 1915. Thirteen additional consolidations haw been made since February. n&gt;ij. nuking a total in Nebraska ot thirty mime consolidated schools. The Fanners' I'nion, the Ctrwmgr and other organizations of Ne - braska are Ugnly in favor of consolidation of scli&lt; h &gt;1-. They art working hand-in-hand with the State Department of Education The following is the law governing consolidation in Ncl Sec. 4 A. Consolidation. — Districts located contiguous to eac other may unite and torn one consolidated district in the manne following : (a) The boards of directors in the district* affectei require their secretaries to give at least ten days notice time and place tor a meeting of the electors residing in t said districts whenever each of said district l&gt;oards shall to order such an election, or whenever a written request 1 fifth of the legal voters is presented to their respective hoi favor of uniting. Notice of such election shall be given 1&gt;&gt; written or printed notices in at least live public places in 1 said districts. At the meeting thiih called the electors sha bv ballot tor or against a consolidated zation said districts which vote in favor of consolidatiot which are adjoining and in which a majority of the electon are in favor of Bach consolidation. le organized as a consolidated school district. Th&lt; districts so consolidated shall notify the count) superintendent of the organization so affected, and the count) inptlinttlllh.nl shall make record of the fact and proceed to notify the county clerk and to alter the county school district map as directed b\ law. The county superintendent within ten days after the formation of said consolidated district shall call a meeting of the electors as provided by law for the organization of new districts. At said meetin gthe qualified electors shall proceed to elect a school board as provided by law. The consolidated c'istrict when organised shall </seg>
            <seg id="p017">CONSOL1DA T1ON OF RURAL SCHOOLS 19 ed for the government at schools &gt;c in existing high tchool .district may OM - it the the pfWMMMM oi this act, and dis - other may consolidate for the purpose of high school, cither as a separate school or as a lidatcd grade and high school tor such districts. board of am consolidated school district ride tor the comfortable transportation of pupils of said ed district living two or more miles from the school by the usual traveled road, in a safe and inclosed con- veyances, properly heated, and said district board i establish such rules and regulations as may be for carrying out the provisions of this act. At any liraal school district meeting in such district, it shall for the qualified voters therein by two-thirds vote to the provision for the district transportation of pupils and action shall be confirmed by the county superintendent satisfactory showing that individual arrangements have de for all necessary transportation of pupils without cost ( &gt;ne school district may be discontinued ami its territory to an adjoining consolidated school district upon a peti- (• ned by one-half of the legal voters of the district discon - rovided that a majority of the voters, attending the annual •■ a special meeting called by the board for that purpose, isolidated district vote in favor of annexing said territory. th, A consolidated district may lie formed under the provis - liis act any time during the year. Ml consolidated districts organized in accordance with i the provisions of this act and all school districts containing twenty - five sections or more which are now or may be hereafter organized and which provide for comfortable transportation of pupils liv - ing two or more miles from school and maintain suitable grounds and a two room school building and the necessary departments and equipment for teaching agriculture and home economics or other industrial and vocational subjects in addition to the regular </seg>
            <seg id="p018">20 COSSOLIDATIOS OF RURAL SCHCOLS course of study and employing teachers holding a certificate show ing their qualifications to teach said subject*, and in which said .ubjects are provided as a part i f the regular course in such in &gt;truction, shall be awarded an 1 paid from the state treasury from moneys not otherwise appropriated, the srin of $100 toward tin. huipment required, and the further sum oi $150 annually. ( f) All consolidated districts organized in accordance with the provisions of tilts act and all school districts containing twain live sections or mere which are now or may he hereafter organized and which provide for comfortable transportation of pupil&gt; living two or more miles from school and maintain suitable groondl an a three room building anil the necessary department an 1 equi] ment for teaching agriculture and home economics or othe and vocational subjects in addition to the regular cour and employing teachers holding certificates showing their qualil lions to teach said subjects, and in which said subjects are as a part of the regular course m such school c proval of the superintendent of pabhc instruction, shall Ik and paid from the state treasury, from ■MMCyi not otherv propriated. the sum of $150 toward the equipment re(|iiir further sum of $200 annuallv (g) All consolidated districts organized ii the provisions of this act and all school district five sections or more which are now or may Ik.- hereafte :e&lt; and which provide for comfortable transportati two or more miles from school and maintain suital and a four or more r&lt;H)in school building and the &lt;. |«rtments ami equipment for teaching agriculture and home econ omics or other suitable and vocational subjects in addition to regular course of study, and employing teachers holding certificates showing their qualifications to teach said subjects, and in which said subjects are provided as a part in the regular course in such schools, subject to the approval of the superintendent of public instruction, shall lie awarded and pail from the state treasun from moneys not otherwise appropriated the sum of $250 toward the equipment required and the further sum of $300 annualh </seg>
            <seg id="p019">COXSOLIDA T1ON OF RURAL SCHOOLS 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">22 CONSOLIDATION OF RURAL SCHOOLS HOW TO PROCEED TO ISSUE BONDS Chapter 8 Revised Statutes. Article / ///. Section 83. Nebraska School 1-aws. Read Carefully and Follow These Instructions Minutely I. N'o bonds shall lx- issued until the question has been Mb mittcd to the qualified electors of the district and three-fifths of al qualified electors of the district present, and voting on the questi"i shall declare by their vote in favor of issuing the same, at an elec tion called for the purpose. u|H&gt;n a notice given by the officers oi the district at least 20 days prior to such election. 2. All persons who are qualified to vote in a school distric meeting are entitled to vote n this proposition to issue lxmds when ever the question is property submitted. (Exception: Persons wli are transferred for school purpose&gt; may not vote on the issuanc of bonds in the district to which thev are transferred.) 3. No vote shall be ordered for issuing such bonds unless a pe tition shall be presented to the district board, asking for a rote for or against the issuance of bonds — to purchase a site for or build a school house or school houses or for furnishing the necessary furni - ture and apparatus for same or for all these purposes which pet tion shall be signed by at least one-third of the qualified voter - of such district. '^4. Bonds must not be issued to exceed five j&gt;er cent ( except in districts-having over one hundred ( 100) school children 1 at last assessment. 5. Bonds must not exceed five hundred (500) dollars in dis - tricts having less than twenty-five ( 25 ) children and not less than twelve (12) of school age. 6. Bonds must not exceed two thousand dollars ($2,000) when the number of children of school age is twenty-five 1 j; 1 or more, and less than fifty ( </seg>
            <seg id="p021">COSSOLIDATIOS OF RURAL SCHOOLS 23 I 1 1 c tit\ wh ec boi •I" not exceed five thousand ($5,000) dollars when hildren of school age in the district is fifty (50) K kin one hundred I 100) s t corrt|)leted assessment in districts having one lore children of school age. Kate of interest on 4 xceed six (6) per cent. KM) I c»r School Bondg and lHank bonds can be procure 1 ice "t the county superintendent who will purchase them hool supply house. Ilie officers of the school district must, before the issuance il-. make a written statement of all proceeding! relafve upon the issuance of such bonds and the notice of election. v ltd time of filing notice, questions of submission, result . a&gt; nf the vote, on the proportion together with a full f the assessed valuation, number of children of school 1 ling in the district, and total bonded indebtedness of the &lt; strict voting such bonds. Phis must l&gt;e certified to under oath by the proper school 1 of the district and be transmitted with the bonds proposed .tied to the State Auditor of public accounts. &gt;e pon examination, if the State Auditor finds that the en- lings conform to law, he shall record the statement and bonds in his office. No bonds shall be valid without a endorsed by the State Auditor, showing that such bonds 1 pursuant to law, the data filed in th»? office of State Au- he Iwsis of such certificate. 12. When the Auditor has registered the bonds he shall cer - the fact to the county clerk of the county in which the district mated and also to the proper officers of such school district. *e duty it shall Ik- to enter the same upon the proper school ■rd 13. If the State Auditor is not satisfied, he will return the s to the proper officers with a certificate to that effect. 14. It shall l&gt;e the duty of the county board to levy annually il all taxable property in each school district in such county, a tist mm exceed twelve ( 12) jkt cent of the a*- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">COXSOLIDA TIOS OF RURAL SCHOOLS 24 \ lax sufficient to pa\ interest accruing i.pon am bonds i&gt;sued b&gt; tmdk schuol district and to provide a sinking fund lor the final re demption of same, sucli levy to Ik* made with the annual count}' lev' and the taxes collected with Other taxes, and when collected sha. leniain in hands of count) Inmrt, a specific fund for the pa\ meat of the hw at maturity. It shall he the duty of the onrih clerk to furnish a copy of his register to the county treasurer. 15. Any money remaining m the hands of the cou.itv treasu e after interest has heen pail on such bonds, shall he placed by him a a sinking fund, and shall on order of school bokrd be invested: First — In redeeming lx&gt;nd t the school district issuing :h same : Second — In registered ban trict is located : of ihe counts in which th Third — In the bonds of tin. Fourth — In I*. S. lxmds ; tate of Nebraska 'rovided, such bonds sha chased at lowest market price, after twenty days' notice tion in at least one newspaper published and in general at the capital city of the state: the coal of advertising at r in be paid out of the sinking fund 16. When payments are due. the treasurer shall procure tor the amount, to be transmitted bj drawing hi&gt; own die Nome bank in Nebraska and lxith check and draft shall be &lt; d"rsed as to show exactly to what l)onds the Hinds shall lx- a — or at request of party holding or owning bonds, payment be made at office of countv treasurer. 17. The county treasurer shall Ik- liable on his official bond fo the faithful disbursement of all moneys so collected and received b him. 18. After all interest and principal have lx?en paid the count board shall notify the county treasurer to transfer remaining fund in his hands to the credit of the district to which they l&gt;elon£. ly. When all principal and bonds have been paid, coanty treas urer shall endorse and write '"Cancelled" together with date of pay ment, file it with county clerk who shall place the same on hi records of such school district. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">CONSOLIDATION* OF RURAL SCHOOLS 25 ivable outside the state, one-fourth of ■unty treasurer for expense attendant money in his hands remaining after n Nebraska having bonds which re- gal liability against the district and bearing y law to issue coupon bonds at a rate of :e \ 1 1 &gt; 1 per cent to be exchanged for bonds i ed. whenever such school district can affect such 1 exchange at a rate not exceeding dollar for dollar. \11 tn&gt;nil- issued under the provisions of this article must, e. contain a clause that the district issuing such bonds lie right t&gt; &gt; redeem them at the expiration of five years, the district does not have a census enrollment sufficient &gt;'&gt;nd&gt;. they may proceed according to 6743, Section 44 ition 45, Nebraska School Laws. 1 Department will be glad to furnish assistance to any lplating consolidation, where such is the wish of the lent, school board members or patrons. wish to promote this phase of educational work in we hope you will feel free to consult with us at any in help you \i.nE Florer \ssistant Superintendent State Inspector of Rural Schools. State 1) Lincoln, m of Education Nebraska July, IQI7 Yi'iir-; for "Hetter Schools </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>