<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA TWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA, PRESENTED TO THE GOVERNOR JANUARY 29, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">fWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT u ) Agricultural Experiment Station NEBRASKA RESEN e Governor Janizary 2'.i. HHJ8 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">III ral Experiment Station. \ ii. Georgt I.. Sheldon, Governor of Nebrutkm: lame witli the act of Congress approx e&lt;l Haick i of the general assembly of the State of March 31, L887, establishing and regulating stations. I have the honor herewith to submit the Annual Report of the Nebraska Agricultural K\ E. A. BrRNETT. Director. 29. UMIN GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE. Nebraska. Executive Department, Lincoln, January 29, 1908. A. Burnett, Director Nebrmtkm AfrieuMurml Experiment Station: Kir: I hereby a&lt; knowledge receipt of the Twenty-first Annual art &lt;&gt;f the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. Governor. r 1 1 1 : I'xiversity of Nebraska. Obobm Lawsox Sheldon, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">a IV THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF ["HE UNIVERSITY) 'hakles S. Allex, Lincoln, President Tern x Hok. William G. Whitmork, Valley Tern: XI Frederic k H. Aiikott. Aurora Term xp E. Vk ior G. Lyhikd. Falls Ci . Charles B. An i ii.iMi. Elsin. . y Tern xp Term exr J. S. Dales, Financial Secretary THE EXEC I T1VE COMMITTEE CHABI.K.x S. \l.l K\ E. Bf n.iamin Andrews THE ST ATION OFFICERS 1A. Burnett. B. S W. Marshall. . . THE WORKING STAFF H. R. Smith, B. S&lt; Ai A. T. Peters, D. V M. Ar Pkederic k D. Heai.d, Ph. I) F J. Alway, Ph. D Lawrence Bruneb. B. Sc E. G. Montgomery, B. S&lt; Frank J. Phillips, M. f Erwin H. Harbour, Ph. D G. R. Chatburn, A. M R. A. Emerson, B. S&lt; O. V. P Stout, C. E G. A. Lovei.am), B. Sc Alvin Keyser, A. M J. H. Gain, M. D. C Associate in Animal Pa A. P. Magdanz, Jk., A. B Assistant in Animal Husba L. B Sturdevant, A. M Assistant in Animal Pa Stella A. Hartzell, A. M Assistant in ( K. M. Little. B. Sc Assistant in Dairy H E. M. Little. B. Sc Assistant in Dairy Husband Martin Nelson, M. S Assistant in Field Cro P. E. Denny, A. B Assistant in Hort 8. W. Perin Farm Superintends I* By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska approv effect February 15, 1899, the State Treasurer became ex offlcio a of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1. A. L. Haecker. B. So. A W. P. Snydkr, M. S. .Superintendent Experimental Substation. N </seg>
            <seg id="p005">V iii iv Experiment*] work ig apple orchards xvli xperiments xvlll Potato experiment Cooperative experiments The North Platte Substation — Wheat Oats Barley Rye Corn Alfalfa Brome grass Annual forage crops Dry land farming Alkali soils Tree planting Orchard planting Growing hogs Cattle feeding North Plane Substation— A"heat xx iarlev xxl Alfalfa Brome grass xx " Annual forage crops xx " )rv land farming xx " Alkali soils rree planting xx '|! hard planting ( Growing hogs xxill ittle feeding xxlv ( The Station staff Station staff xxv Improvements mprovemen armers' Inst itutes xxvi Farmers' Institutes Publications it ions xxvii Station mail ma i« -leilgments xx ' x Acknowledgments 1 \l Statements — Hatch fund {■A Adams fund at ion moneys xxxii Other Station moneys State appropriations — Farmers' Institutes ... ■ation (North Platte)... ation i North Platte) xxxiii APPEN! APPENDIX. m Tomato Fki it ton Doanra i'.&lt;"7 Fki it Ron l)iKi\(. 1MT, With Till «W Contexts 1 NEW Form ok Sphn- ■ llfll Bpki •alunim The new form of $ph&lt;f phaeroptu matomm 34 Cultural characteristics 36 Inoculations 38 41 ons Extent of injury 42 Distinctions *' Species identity ■ &lt;3 Literature cited 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">VI ri Treatment kik i hi-: Smi ft 0* Winter Baki.ky- Introduction Description of the barley smuts The treatments carried out — (fll The formalin steep (6) The modified formalin steep (c) The hot-water treatment ... (rf) Corrosive sublimate steep . (e\ Copper sulphate steep ,n Arrangement of test plats Effect of treatment upon germination a nd vi Recommendations )f grow rHOLD in Maim i Syki !• — Introduction Historical Mition of the fiinsu^ Growth in cull u : Relation of growth ratiot Effect of concentration of suKar on Effect of form of nitrogen on Anah Literature cited Kt Hi Qbapu i n ■ )i Test or Hakm A fp Weed Poisoxinu in h Introduction Symptoms as hitherto The pastui' First attempt to indiu So. 1 . . Case of Horse No. Z. . Loco-eating history of Ho Symptoms of Horse No. . Post-mortem examination of H Case of Horse No. :l Loco-eating history of H mortem examination of Horse Ni Case of Horse No. 4 Loco-eating history of H" Symptoms of Horse No. 4 Post-mortem examination of Hoi Case of Horse No. 5 Case of Horse No &gt;; Summary — Loco-eating history Symptoms Post-mortem examination^ </seg>
            <seg id="p007">\ \ The w i\ 1 UtllW produ i v nto th tation mi i n th. Inction VII Xl'ERI MENTAL WciltK. ie Experiment Station for the cuiTent year lias which are technical and scientific in their endeavoring to discover scientific prineiptea which i bearing on practical farm proMenw; second, the ui of scientific principle! already worked nut. to the pra&lt; Is of the farmer. tigationa carried on under the Adams act are. a ilatioiis of Congress, confined to strictly scientific of the accumulation of knowledge which does not now which when worked out may have a beartag upon prac cultural tpiest ions. Tile other funds of the Kxpcriment sucli as the Hatch fund appropriated by the federal and slate appropriations, are available for the less lies of investigation which may have the most iin - 1 beneficial influence on the general farm practices of ork which this Station has done in the extension of the vheat area of the state has resulted in very jjreatly in areas of wheat, carrying: this extension first to the st. then to the northeastern section of the state, where on has increased more than 9,000,000 hushels in the last irs. and more recently extending winter wheat production northwest area of the state thru the work of the Sul&gt; ;it North TMatte. where the yields of winter wheat upon tilled land have exceeded the average yields of wheat astern counties of the state under the methods of pro in common at f investigation in tin' Experiment Station are of two </seg>
            <seg id="p008">VIII Ender the Adams fund, investigations have been carried on in bleaching of wheat tiours to determine whether the processes ■ in use by the millers have a deleterious effect on the health I persons consuming such flours, ted in Bulletin No. W2. The &gt; further being investigated to ?ngth of flour or those qualities 1 well formed loaf and make the Thew investigations ar&lt; eueral subject of wheat flours determine the cause of the which tend to produce a larg&lt; flour desirable from the stand point of the miller. Considerable controvei - among » titic men al the (present time as to the true cause of strengt flour, and until this can be determined it is impossible t&lt; tfiinine what qualities in wheat should be developed in ordi produce the iih.si desirable wheat from the niiller"s standp&lt; In connection with this work the Experiment Station is devi ing a large namher of strains or subvarietie: wheat with the expectation that the yield of son Tu E considerably exceed the yi&lt; mon use and that the i-hcm lof the Tlllkev I unpositM ■eptable will he such as to make it the m standpoint. I^he work of the Kxperiment Station in promoting tin (try of the state has l&gt;een large and efficient. Within tli • years, under the stimulus and advice of the Kxperimei n. more accurate and exact study of the improvement of corn i been made than in all the years which preceded. The agit the selection of better seed has resulted in giving very much ater attention to this important question. The discussion of I fertility, the rotation of crops, and of tillage to eat isture. have all tended to modify the practice of the »\ ■ mer and very greatly to improve the methods of the men who I previously given this subject special study. This invest iga a has tended to unify the general opinion regarding varieties t adapted to localities and to prove by careful investigation t certain varieties were superior to others which had nun nlv been grown. Five years' work naa been done to determine </seg>
            <seg id="p009">IX com were ix-st adapted to each of the f the state. The result of these investiga - 11 i he eastern section of the state, with t o\\ i men cooperating, the average yield of the best two each county for five years has been ."&gt;4 bushels per ige yield of all corn in the same counties bein. Tc The selected varieties produced an average of re nioi-c than the average of the county. This \i&lt; show that if food varieties are used and the dard of farming is brought up to that of the best ■ach neighborhood, an average increase of 15 to Jn ere would result. The state has l&gt;een divided in' 111 districts. ;n cording to a map shown herewith. The i|M»rative farmers assisting in this investigation have shown In Section 1. Reid's Yellow I&gt;ent gave l»est average yield for the \ears. IMS to l'.MX'. inclusive. Hogue's Yellow Dent Usi yield. These are l&gt;oth yellow varieties. The two promising white varieties were Nebraska White Prize and Silver Mine. Results obtained during the past three years, however, indicate that Chase's White Dent may W the best white variety. In Section 1. Reid's Yellow Dent has given best yield for rive ;irs. ami Mobile's Yellow I&gt;ent second best. The two liesf white ire Silver Mine and Nebraska White Prize. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">X Eii Section .'!. Hogoe'i Yellow Dent has give* best \ ield i den Knw BTCOBd l&gt;est. Silver Mine and Chase's While D to Ik' recommended for white varieties. In Seetiim 4. Qoldea How and Reid's Yellow I&gt;ent have gi\ Malta as yellow varieties, and Nebraska White Prize ; Silver Mine as white varieties, tho in main cases the two wl varieties have not matured well. Ku Section* ."&gt; and t&gt; we have not U-en able to secure sul irniation to determine certainly tlie varieties lust ad • A collection of native corns was made last \ear from I different farmers, and the work will I*- considerably extend) the future. At the North IMatte Station for the years 1906 1906, calico corn gave yields of .'!'.». :&gt; bushels and ~&gt;'2 bushel E lively, with an average of 4."i.t; bushels. Reid-H ded 'AUM and 47. S lmshels. with an average of 4.'! •roved LeUMBg yielded .'!7.1 bushels and 47.4 busln v. with au average of 4L'.4 bushels. Silver Mine, a ded 39.3 bushels and 52.2 bushels, with an aver; bushels. The calico corn above mentioned w tinue to hold a leading place anion t stern Nebraska, and the other varieties mention) change with more extensi\ Ilreeding work with corn at the central Station covering five re" investigation shows the average of such corn to be nine hels per acre more than the check plats from which thia a;inated, these check plats having been grows upon tlie land the same state of fertility and with the same conditions of a;;e as the corn which had been selected for increased yield 1 higher producing types. The final distribution of thr - ived varieties cannot but have a large beneficial effect upon corn-growing industry in the regions To which they are Ender the Adams fund investigations, we are studying the tion of leaf area to the water used in the growth of the corn it. It is proposed to determine by means of potometers the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">XI 1 \ i I. in nflu ler 1 i plieat alfalf f water used by different types of the corn plant, and letermine which type of plant is beet adapted to unlit ions, which has the greatest yield, and which the ihilit.v to withstand drought. It is l&gt;elieved that this i&lt;;ati&lt;&gt;n will determine what particular characterist rn plant enable it ti&gt; reach the highest development and •e the greatest yield under the conditions which exist in ate. When these fails have l&gt;een detenu ined. the develop •orn having the proper characteristics will materially he yield per acre and have an economic Waring upon oduction of tin nvcstigation of the soils of the state is in progress, to line roughly the different soil regions of the state as indi by the different geological formations from which these i'gions are derived. This line of investigation should l&gt;e &lt;nn - ;1 until accurate maps of these soil regions are availal&gt;j&gt; laraiter of the soil in the different regions of the state will me the character of the agriculture which is practiced. ghboring states to the east are spending large sums of v at the present time in working out these soil regions for respective states and have already found that the knowledge obtained has made it jtossible to operate the lands in the ent areas more profitably than could be done without this knowledge regarding the constituents of which the soil Je up. lited ex]&gt;eriinents have been earried on to determine the ace of commercial fertilizers upon the wheat crop in the sections of the state. These experiments so far indicate that which are declining in their productiveness are lacking in iren. but are not lacking in the other elements of plant food iry to a fertile soil. Nitrogen is readily supplied by the ap tion of barnyard manure, or by seeding lands down to gram, ll or clover, and permitting a rest from grain product ion period of years, after which these lands can again be used rowing grain with very greatly increased production. All </seg>
            <seg id="p012">XII I I I the investigation which lias been carried on relative to tl nap'iiit'iit of soils points conclusively to the fact th;it rotatk crops is necessary id secure t he largest ,\ iflds and the lar^.v itits from ilif land: that perioda &lt;&gt;f grain growing miisi I erspersed with periods during which the land is in iiininons crops like clover and alfalfa, and that the mail tenance of the fertility of the soil in anv region of high r land is the key to successful agrieultun Studies in soil tillage have sliown tliat water slum Ived or stored up in tl id. so thai it may l&gt;e used by ■ western section of T 1 1 ■ • rainfall of the growing matui-e ,1 crop. While timeh i ter. there is likely to Ik- a | &gt;p when soil water is deflcien when there is no crop the crop later on. l\i it is impossible to de] mis may supply an an period dining the grow at. If crop production into the region where it has n&lt; it will 1m- largely thru the int t liefoi-e lieel iductioi water in the soil before the crop - the crop dnriag the latter period of its ■.'row ciples apply to all agricultural region soil water is likely to occur in the regions fall, it is essential that our farmers understand tin of conserving soil water anil use those methods ins of most abundant rainfall. Such methods surance in crop production and mice understood can to the land without largely increasing the cost of farn tions. The relation of humus (total organic matter) in tin the storing up of water and plant food is one of the lending I in. of investigation in the Experiment Station A study of beef production has been made by this Station. t&gt; trniine how the crops which are grow* on the ordinary farm be utilized by cattle to produce the largest revenue. Bul- letins Nips. 7.V B5, 90, !••! and Hhi deal with the question of ec to BOppI.? lilt' w;i </seg>
            <seg id="p013">XIII i ii f P. r, I" production. Two hundred and ninety four cattle experiments, which have conclusively ,e character of the ration is an essential factor in odnciion: that economical rations containing the ins which are adapted to the use of the animals fed pie and may !&gt;e grown entirely npm a Nebraska farm. njr. the essential point in food nutrients is that l&gt;e a proper relation between what are known nstituents of the food anil the carbohydrate and fat of the food: in other words, hetwicii the albuminoid he food and the starches, sugar, fat and crude fiber MtA. These proportions do not need to Im* determined with atical accuracy, but can l&gt;e determined with sufficient ■y to give economical results by any farmer who under something of the nature and character of these different For example, there is a certain class of foods grvwm on i which will supply the protein requirements in fattening iods are. first, alfalfa hay; second, clover hay; ed h\ oats and bran as useful but not so economical foods ir present prices. This makes the range of protein foods he Nebraska farm extremely narrow, and, when these &gt;t In- supplied from the farm. ex|&gt;eriinents have shown Kiiomieal to purchase in the markets commercial which supply these protein requirements. The commercial • most commonly used are linseed meal, cottonseed-meal, and bly those protein foods which are the byproducts of the h factory. All of the exjieriments of our Station have iwrt that protein foods can be produced upon the farm in the in of alfalfa hay at alwut half the cost of such food constitu- s when purchased in the form of commercial foods. The iner who takes advantage of this knowledge and grows his itein upon the farm accomplishes the double result of making ft prorits upon his cattle feeding o|&gt;eration8 and of very ■atlv increasing the productiveness of his soil by the same ration. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">XIV It has been shown by exj&gt;eriments that more protein nutrients are supplied In alfalfa hay when it is used as the entire r MM of feeding steers than is necessary for their use. and that it is possible to utilize prairie hay. eon stover and unln corn which has liwi shocked at the proper ti - to Bake these forms of roughness very nmcli more valuable than tlie\ could l&gt;e made without the use of alfalfa hay in feeding o tions. {t has km shown that the use of alfalfa hay and corn - in connection with shelled corn will produce a liberal protit beef production where the use of prairie hay and shelled coin s given an actual loss in feeding operations. It has been shown that younger cattle, especially ca yearlings, are more dependent upon protein nutrients found alfalfa hay or linseed or cottonseed-meal than older cattle. : thai the farmer, when he attempts to feed calves or -. will find it more necessary to maintain the proper bala between protein and nonprotein food constituents than in ft ing older and mature cattle. In fattening pigs upon corn as the principal ration, it has found that the use of tankage, a byproduct of the packing li has increased tin- rate of gain and decreased the cost of prodin - tion where the percentage of tankage fed was about five per cent of the total ration; that a larger per cent of tankage did not greatly increase the rate of gain, and in some instances did in - crease the cost of gains to a point above the cost where corn alone wat fed. These experiments show, as do the experiments with cattle, that there should be a certain relation between the protein and nonprotein constituents of the food of any animal, and that it is as possible to increase these protein constituents beyond the point of profitable production as it is to limit them below the point of profitable production. In other words, it is necessary to know with some approximation what the requirement of the am mal is, and to supply these foods in the proportion which is needed by the animal fed. Pigs which are fed upon alfalfa pasture </seg>
            <seg id="p015">XV depeadmt upon protein in other food constituents as which do not have alfalfa pasture. The tests at the central ation. however, indicate that alfalfa pasture does not furnish tfticient amount of protein for economical production when makes the balance of the ration, but that mixed grains with fa pasture overcome the necessity for feeding tankage when can Ik- supplied at a lower rust. The results of experiments the western Station have indicated that corn and alfalfa hay tsuch nixed grains as corn, barley, sjK'ltz. and alfalfa hay nisli cheaper protein nutrients than were supplied in tankage. Ixperineati are in progress which are of very great interest It he breeder of pure bred stock, indicating that the strength of le in pigs may be very materially increased by the use of ikage. of ground Itonc. or of skim-milk fed with grain in grow- Tliree years' work has been done on this problem and • results have uniformlv shown a marked increase in the strength of bone where tankage or ground bone has been fed. Tins information is valuable localise the character of the feed um-iI in pork production tends strongly to produce a Injne of low tensile strength and a small percentage of mineral matter, while the heavy weights develojKHl in the young pig tend to produce animals which do not stand properly on their feet. The experiments above mentioned indicate that by proper methods of feeding and care in the selection of individuals for breeding purposes the tendency toward bad feet and legs may largely be overcome. t experiments at the western Station reported in Bulletin No. show that even in western Nebraska where alfalfa is abun - lt and grain of moderate price, liberal grain rations produce ger profit and more economical results than are secured by •wing hogs largely upon alfalfa pasture. These experiments licate that where alfalfa hay is fed and corn is valued at 35 its per bushel, barley is worth al&gt;out 24 cents per bushel and mer about 19 cents per bushel, four bushels of barley being lal in value to five bushels of enimer. It is not probable that </seg>
            <seg id="p016">XVI r t tecond experiment would exactly verify these figures, altlu should expect it to reasonably approximate these results. Ehe work of the Experiment Station in the care ;in«l nillgl it of dairy cattle has shown that the value of the individua ibers of the herd can only be determined by individual mill rl butter fat records. Such record* will show gnat varia the value of the different animals and will serve U the building up of an efficient herd. Cows vary from year to year in their butter fat produ The g°od cows in this herd have been inclined to give fa y.iv after year, while the poor ones have always been rela low. It has been found that as a rule the variation in mill in individual COW* from year to year is ilne to length of lad period and rest before freshen ing. A long period f;i\ ■ milk production. Tin liiih have given large annual have all been peraiateBt milkers ami have continued milki within four or six w tin- next calving tin A study of the coal of butter fat production baa ■out of milk and butter fat produced depends ii] dairy capacity of the animal and the amount and quality ration used. Cows of a decided dairy type will return th eat profit in milk and butter when fed to their full eapacit average cost of feeding a dairy cow as shown by tli&lt; about |30 per year, and the total value of butter fat of th tion herd is about $70 annually per cow: tearing an aver; about |40 for labor and profit in addition to the value &lt; skim-milk and the value of the calf. With the prices for forage and grain which have preva -.I the Experiment Station for the last four years, the cost of butte production can be reduced al&gt;out M per cent by the use of - as a part of the ration. This result is obtained by reducing th cost of feed and by materially increasing the average yield o butter for each cow thru the use of succulent feed during th winter season. The people of this state have been slow to adop the silo in the production of butter, from a feeling that tl </seg>
            <seg id="p017">XVII not tit into their method of dairying and that the original 8 too high. It has been found at the Station that even with If alfalfa hay. which is a most excellent ration for but - production. the cost of butter could be still further lowered the use of silage as a part of the ration. The Station is firmly tvinced that all dairymen milking twenty-five or more cows profitably incur the expense of a silo under such conditions now exist in eastern Nebraska. Fhe Experiment Station has published a bulletin on "The Fat ting of Cream."' which is being used as a standard method by Dairv and Food Commissioner of the state. SPRAYING APPLE ORCHARDS. E&gt;uring the summer of 1906, spraying demonstrations were ducted in six counties in Nebraska, the United States De - tment of Agriculture cooperating, the purpose of the work to control the apple scab and codling-moth and to deter- Ee whether the advantages of such spraying would pay the incurred. These demonstrations were continued during the tmt of 1907. with the result that a very superior quality nf it was produced upon the trees which were sprayed. Records le at the end of the season from the entire crop of 37 sprayed and 39 unsprayed ones in different orchards, including ob- mnrgtfai— on more than 110.000 fruits, showed 22 per cent of wormy apples on the sprayed trees and 46 per cent on the un - &gt;piayed ones. Of the sprayed fruits t! per cent and of the un - sprayed fruits 38 per cent were scabby. 1 Miring the fall, the foliage of the sprayed trees was much healthier than that of the unsprayed ones. In many cases from ."iii per cent to 75 per cent of the foliage of unsprayed trees was on the ground early in October and in some instances the trees were almost completely defoliated at that time. At the same Time the leaves of the sprayed trees were bright green and com - paratively free from fungus diseases. The crop was gathered from 20r&gt; sprayed trees and 71 un- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">XVIII I n .1 I i tyed trees. The average yield of the sprayed tree* wa els per tree aad of the ■■■prayed treea S.fl bushels per When sorted into merchantable and nnmercbantable fruit. s rent of the sprayed fruit and '_':! per een1 of tin* BMprayed fi unmerchantable. The total value jmt tree of the unspra fmit was fO.Sll and of the tprayed fruit #1.87. Tin- cost &lt;if tp ing was ill cenis per tree. The profit of the sprayed tree the nnspraved trees was 86 cents per tre&lt; POTATO EXPERIMI against cultivation have lieen carried on for a number Potatoes grown nndei- a mulch have been of poorer qua table purposes than those grown under cultivation, but superior for seed purposes. Medium-sized seed p quarter of a t niter, are superior to smaller - planted in hills so that the amount of seed equa bushels per a i re. Potatoes planted i inches ,1, yields than those planted either shallow' inches. The results of this work are reported in I The Station has receiitlv investigated the sul poisoning; in horses and • i a detailed its work in the appendix to this Report. The study of cornstalk disease has been e on in three counties of the state, in an effort prevalence of the disease, the methods of treatmei n v. w successful in lessening the loss. etc. The result of til w is reported in Press Bulletin No. 11. No information tend II nt the loss of rattle turned upon stalk fields has 1 veloped in this investigation. An investigation of the seed of cheat, meadow fescue, and bronie grass by the Station lias known that a large amount cheat seed is annually sold as either brotne grass or meadow fescue by persons who ignorant ly or otherwise have inisi resented the variety of seed for sale. Press Bulletin 23 deal with this subject. The Experiment Station is establishing Experiment! to determine the effeci &lt;&gt;f matching p </seg>
            <seg id="p019">XIX &gt;\ T I operation with the I'uited States Department of Agriculture, a ;ng laboratory, where all samples of grass seed and other nt to the Station will be examined free of cost. The : and quality of impurities in seed samples will be re orted, as well as the per rent of germination. The Station has recently investigated a new disease which s been somewhat prevalent in Nebraska and a number of other during the last few rears, known as the bud-rot of carna- This disease has l»een proved by the Station to be due to a Elite sj&gt;eeies of fungus. SporutrU-hum (inthophilum Peek, which dated with it. a new species of mite. Pediculoides dian- lus Wolcott, as a constant accompaniment. The disease the buds of carnations in various stages of maturity and he petals and other flower parts, interfering with the normal iij: of the flower. The disease is successfully treated by il care to remove from the greenhouse all material favoring pagation, by keeping the moisture down to the minimum ry for the healthy growth of the plants, and by picking id binning all th&lt; 1 portions of any plant. Ben d be gaac over at least every other day until the disease is mder control. The results of this investigation are pub Bulletin 10.1. x IPEBATIVE EX I'KKI M EXT Cooperative experimental are in progress with farmers of the in testing varieties of corn adapted to different regions, in xtending the winter wheat area of the state, in introducing rinter barley to determine its hardiness and production, and in praying demonstrations with apple orchards. In cooperation with the federal Department of Agriculture, xperiments are in progress to improve the quality and produc- !a of hard winter wheats, to introduce new crops into the ion. to control apple scab and codling-moth by spraying, to dy the effect of Ullage and rotations on crop production, to dy alkali-resistant crops, testing varieties of sweet corn, and the prosecution of the plant disease survey of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">XX n THE NORTH PLATO BCBSTATION. Wheat.— Systematic experiments have been carried on in tin growth of winter wheat, with tin- purpose of extending the wintei wheat arc a still farther to the west and north. Most of the wintii wheat grown mi the Station farm to date has been upon suiumei tilled land. In the summer of ISM, Turkey Red wheat prodncnl from SI liushels to M bushels per acre. The yield for tin UNIT upon high table land which had lx-en summer tilled varie. from 50 bushels to (in lnishels per acre. Nine acres of land m the bench or second bottom about 200 feet lower than tin I ile yielded about M bushels of ive in IMS, was plowed ; ,n to wheat, and produced 41 bushels per acre in l'.MlT. It WO in that the essential thing in successfully growing winter wh Lincoln County and farther • ire a good seed :h sufficient moisture to give a good fall growth. Spr ather conditions will, of course, have much influence on p, but if sullicient moisture has U-en stored in the soil in ice of sowing the crop, th- in insurance against wii 1 spring drought. In the region of the Substation farm, wl ra about Septemlwr l."ith upon land with plenty of n •sent has secured a sufficiently heavy fall growth. IkVhile winter wheat has lieen phenonienall -fill at th bstation. the durum wheats have given satisfactory \ jri, re greatly extended the wheat area of western Nebraska an&lt; item Colorado and Wyoming. The yields of durum wli ) Station farm have averaged about IS bushels per aire for th ■ee years of 1904. IMS, and IMS, while local wheat ' ne years on the same land yielded but 7.2 bushels. In 1M7 th ■Ids were, for durum. 17 to ."J."! bushels, and for local - ieat alniut the same. The cold, freezing weather in spring W* favorable to the durum variet: I Oats. — The oat crop has given fair yields where early varietie ive been raised. The Kherson oat has taken the lead at thi :ation. tho two other varieties have yielded nearly as well. Th eld of Kherson oats for three seasons. 1904, 1905. 1906. has beei </seg>
            <seg id="p021">XXI &lt; bushels, of Texas Red oats for the flame •in 2S hmhete t&lt;&gt; 43 bushels, of Sixty Day oats for the od from i'o bashela to 48 bushels. Haei.kv. — Bkrley lias beta quite universally successful as a : ain. and eniiner fairly successful. ■: Wye has given good yields and has furnished a m llent pasture for brood sows in winter and in early spring be- i ready to pasture. It has then gone on and pro- I iir yield of grain if not pastured too heavily in winter. Kxperiments with corn have shown that those vari&gt; have beta grown in the region are generally best adapted . even tho they have not been bred and selected for the 1 t\pes. Only the earlier of the introduced varieties will ii at this altitude. In 1M6 the live leading varieties pro d from 36 bushels to .'!!&gt; bushels j&gt;er acre. In 1906 the five varieties produced from 47 bushels to .12 bushels. Thive n &lt;' work would indicate that calico corn is the safest variety lie general farmer to raise in this region. There are doubt veral other satisfactory varieties of the smaller «ort. varieties, like Ilogue's Yellow Deal Silver Mine, and Hogne-Reid cross, have ripeaed in favorable seasons, but cannot lered safe varieties for this region re in progress with wheat, oats, barley, rye and &gt;rn to determine the most desirable rate of seeding, tim ■eding. preparatioa of the seed l&gt;ed. cultivation, and effect of ii the yield and quality of crop. mil Alfalfa. About UMi acres of alfalfa is growing on the Sul&gt; - ation farm, partly oa the table and partly on the bench land (second bottom land. The alfalfa on the bench has produced if crops of hay each year and in addition has pastured about lit pigs per acre thruout the growing season, giving yields not different from the high [triced lands in eastern Nebraska. • alfalfa on the table -land has varied greatly in yield, lapead - iiii seasonable rains. It has always produced one good crop about one ton of hay per acre, and a second crop, n </seg>
            <seg id="p022">XXII 1 w 1 111 1 cat i el heavy, some time during the mm When rainfall hai abundant in July, this second crop has COW on early and ■od yield, but where the rainfall has In-en scant in .Tnl following months the second CTOp has In-en very light, sh evidence t hat there was little or no reserve moisture in tl available for the growth of the plant altho there was sul to keep the plant alive until moisture for further growl ■applied. No difficulty has beta experienced in getting a of alfalfa !&gt;y tawing at the time the spring rains begin 01 thoiolv prepared. The station hopes to produce alfalfa si the tablelands and thus introduce a very profitable &lt;T&lt; tli is region. Brome Grass. The Subsiai lirome grant growing and has found standing climatic conditions perfectly v 1 makii It has not yet been lar Kich it has proved be»1 adapted Annual Forage ■ Vim titr com have given abundant yield. Win - drill, they make the tinesi anil ■■■■ produce more seed and aomewfa when planted in doable drills \\ .( the double rows and cultivated like corn. V from cane have varied from aboul two tons pe .is six or seven tons in the waaon of IIhiT. Lin have indicated that Katir corn is more palatabl cane. Im:y Land Farming.- The experiments in dry land t carried on by means of 93 tenth-acre plais on table-land work consists of rotations, methods of tillage, cultivatioi and manuring, in growing wheat, oats, barley, corn, am connection with this work accurate record* are kept tic conditions — precipitation, air and soil moisture an peratnre, evaporation, etc.. the United states Departm Agriculture cooperating. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">XXIII \ u i riod. pi rain Matin t on riic work in alkali iaveatigatioaa mti :i 5-acre tract of land toned by the United of Agriculture. Tlic objects sought arc the i In- relative resistance to alkali of various ropa, the development by selection of greater i in tin si-, tlic effect of a corrective such as (feet of cultivation anil of manure in prevent •licet of alkali, the United States Department The work in growing trees enibrao pacing, mixtures, pruning ami cultivation. Ten acre* ilanted on "bench" land, ten acres on "tables-land ami im;. In the spring of 10117 aliout UMI fruit 1 of hardy varieties of apple. peach, plum ami ese trees are being given tnoro cultivation to deter tardiness, production and adaptability to the w • ■tate. It is proposed in I'.iiiS to plant a number of ntal trees and shrubs to determine their suitability in western farms. Experiment! in growing hogs on alfalfa and produced in the region have l&gt;een in pi' blishnient of the Station. Tt has been shown that n ration is not most economical for growing uliar circumstances where alfalfa is abundant very high priced and where the market conditions s probable that two or more pounds of corn daily for lied pounds weight of hogs is more profitable than a ition. A heavier ration is desirable for the finishing ■oliably between three pounds daily per hundred and a ration animals, like brood sows, after weaning pigs will gain half pound p&lt; r day on alfalfa without grain. are cooperating. «ns. ihc United Statrs Department of Agrical- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">XXIV IV iv i Eo fattening hogs that have acceM to alfalfa hay. corn ts. barley at l!4 cents, and enimer at lit cents per busht ?n about equal results. I It has been shown that the i-ust per pound of gain is n ible criterion of profit. A cheap gain may lie so slow ; [profitable. Time, labor, investment and risk should lered when reckoning profits. Alfalfa in almost any form may lx- fed with profit to long as it does not make too large a proportion of the When cut and fed as one-quarter of the ration with grout it materially reduced the cost of gains and increased the t CaTTLI Fkkdim;. One lest has beta made to detern economical rations in wintering cattle, taking the weaning time and growing him until he is past two vt and ready for the feed lot. Five lots of calves \\&lt; • the fall of IMC and fed. Lot 1. alfalfa hay. Lot 2. praii Lot 3, cane; Lot 4. alfalfa and prairie hay: Lot 5, alfa cane. Two pounds of grain was fed daily to each calf the first winter. The gains made liv the calves fed alfa t alfalfa and either prairie hay of cane, were nor far from It" inds each in the low months. The gains on alfalfa ha\ re 71 pounds and on cane 4t! pounds for the same time. The inner gains following did not equalize these different it the lots did not go into the second winter with even weights. grain was fed the second winter, and the lots wen- eh that those receiving the poorest ration the first winter should eive the best ration the second winter. Again the second winter the large and the cheap gains were made on alfalfa ha either alone or combined with prairie hay or cane. Prairie ha and cane both gave a loss of weight during the winter and duoed the profit on cattle. IUilletin 105, or Substation Hull. NO. 3. will report this experiment. This test is being repeated at the present time, with on added to test the efficiency of prairie hay and cane as compared with the rations previously fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">XXV ) I I i 1 iMt n uj: fa nmlt for mstr i ud v of the effect of alfalfa on the growth rty weanling colts have been purchased and put i l&gt;e grown entirely on alfalfa hay and alfalfa on alfalfa hay aud prairie pasture, and still hay aud prairie pasture, to determine the i weight and the quality of the horses at maturit .. THE STATION STAFF. In- past year the following changes in the Station aken place: &gt;r P. &lt;!. Miller has resigned as Forester, and Pr&lt;&gt; I. Phillips has Im'cii employed, beginning September 1. M. Little has been added to the staff :i&gt; Assistant in la A. Hart/.ell has beeu made Assistant in Chemistrv. IMPROVKMENTS. Legislature appropriated fllMMMN) for improvements versity farm. This money is largely used for the d« agricultural education, but the Experiment Sta- its largely from the buildings and the equipment made under this appropriation. A new heating plant has I'leted. with two :!•"&gt;&lt;! horse [tower high pressure boilers. inildings on the University farm requiring heat have wen connected with this new system. A judging pavilion, offer- tor judging live stock and grain, is approaching n and will furnish two stock judging pavilions. MM urge class room for agricultural work, a seed judging labnra - ory, and a large seed room for the storage of grains to be used notional and experimental work. The Woman's Building has been practically completed for the • the department of Home IVonomies. furnishing dormitory facilities for sixty girls and class room and laboratory facilities for the School of Home Economics. V machine shed lias l&gt;een built to house the farm tools, and </seg>
            <seg id="p026">1 1 \ fit-r minor improvements have been Made, such ;is In ircr from the rniversiiy campus i&lt;i use ;ii tli&lt;' University prrnho— r and potting rooms have l&gt;een erected by tlu lioianist ami State Entomolo special appropriations to in\« B, under tilt' State Insect I'est and Plant IMseas hlislied by the last Legislature. The Department to logy in the Experiment Station has been furnished at the University farm. A milking machine ha~ md put in operation to determine its utility for dairyman. At the Sulisiation. since April. L907, the follow cattle barn with elevator and minder. *_'.Sll(l: n farm tools. $500; heating, plumbing and em's house and soil laboratory $900: wat plant. #4(MI; water system at west plant. *42."&gt; : : engine and freight, $800; 4- horse gasoline engine and *"_'&lt;wi: IIuIm'i- threshing machine. *7:!."i: fem lev same, f 1,000; approximate total cost, fll FARMERS NSTIT1 in Farmers' Institute work during the vear. One In thirty-six Institutes were held &lt;luriii«r the yeai 1907, and one hundred and seventy-five Institutes are schedul for the current year. Ten thousand dollars per annum was S] w propriated by the last Legislature for the bienniun n April 1. 1907. year, under the name of Organised Agriculture, the foil societies participating: The Association of Agricultural Si dents, the State Veterinary Medical Association, the l'olant China Breeders' Association, the Duroc-Jersei Breeders' Ass ist on ilu&gt; Station farn tifiate plain diseases nifiiis have U'cii made ;it approximately tli house iiiid suil laboratory, |2.2&lt;MI; Herdsman Several members &lt;if the Experimeni Station Various* agricultural societies meel ;it the l'nivt </seg>
            <seg id="p027">XXVII I H 1 I I ut Itate Board of Agriculture, the DairyawB'i Am Horticultural Bociety, state Poultr.v ktioa, Bee Keepers' Association, state Bwfaw Breeders' Ai Vmiieii's Departmeal of Organised Agrkaltare, Park and w ation, Improved Live Stock Breeders' Al and &lt;iirls' Agricultural Associations. Coin Improvers i. Bed Polled Breeder*' ASBOCiatioB, Fanners' Insti lit ion. Aberdeen- Aagm Breeders' Association. Short Breeders' Association. PUBLICATIONS. giving the result of investigation in the Experiment published in editions of from M,Mt to ML listributcd free of chnr&lt;re to any resident of the - (•plication. There is at the present time a regular mail hin the state of about L3,tM names. These are con Bg added to. and it is desired that all farmers who ed in the publications of this Station should ask to lpon this regain — &lt;H»g list. The publications of me those named in the last Annual Report are as ieth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor Kehru hit. -I capita. etin No. !••" .Substation Bulletin No. li I Vol. XIX. Air. rop Production in Western Nebraska. Report of Ex|&gt;eri ibstation. North Platte. Nebr. B.v W. I'. Snvder. Super . and E. A. Burnett. Dirertor. Distributed March 1^. bulletin No. !Mi i Vol. XIX. Art. III). Some Insects Injurious Wheat DariBg 1M6-1SM. B.v Lawrence Brunei- and Myron Swenk. Distributed March is. 1!M)7. L'D.lHtO copies. bulletin No. !»7 i Vol. XIX. Art. IV i. Potato Experiments. R. A. Emerson. Distributed April 13. 1907. 20.000 copies. bulletin No. M (Vol. XIX. Art. Vi. Spraying Demonstra us in Nebraska Apple Orchards. By R. A. Knierson. Distrib - ■d April in. 1907. l'ii.iiimi eopii IMHI icijiios </seg>
            <seg id="p028">XXVIII I I Bulletin No. M (Substation Bulletin No. 2) i Vol. XIX. Ai t). Growing Hogs in West. -in Nebraska. Ktywl of Expel &gt;ntal Substation. North Platte, Nehr. By W. 1". BaydV iperinteudent. it n&lt;l ]•:. A. Burnett. Director. Distributed .Iiu 117. ::il.l»IMI copies. Bulletin No. loo (Vol. XX. Art. I). Economical B »ns Beef Production. By 11. It. Smith. Distributed Sept&lt; I. Small Grains; 1'ait II. The Ise &lt;»f the Fanning M See.l Wheat and Seed Oats. Hv E. &lt;;. Montsomer Btilletin No. 111." (Substation Iiulletin No. 3) (Vol. VI). (innvirifr Tattle in Western Nebraska. Report i mental Substation. North I'lntte. Nebr. By W. P Superintendent, and E. A. Burnett. Director, l'.'.ik I'ress Bulletin No. 24. The Bleaching of Wheat F •T. Alwa.v. Distributed Febroarr l'ii. 1!M)7. :i.i&gt;tin ,-, Kl'.ulletin No. I'.".. The Seed of Cheat. Meadow F&lt; me Grass. By F. D. Heald. Distrihuted Febrnarv 00 copies. i&lt; 1JMI7 E'ss Bulletin No. 2C. The Fat Testing of (ream. I ker and E. M. Little. Distributed July is i&lt;»07 s. \. I .1.11(11 Press Bulletin No. l',. Losses from Cornstalk Diseast Ktilli'tin No. 1(14 (Vol. XX, Aim. V). 1 I!io7. -'.-..Odd copies. Bulletin No. 101 (Vol. XX. Art. II i. Part I. I&gt;air\ II. Record for Ten Years: Part II. Cost of Better Fat Product! I'.y A. L. Haecker. 1 &gt;isirilmiecl November is. I'.miT. copies. Bulletin No. 192 (Vol. XX. Ait. lid. The Effect &lt;&gt;f Bleaohi ■poa the Qualitv ..f Wheat Flour. Bv F. .1. Alwa.v. Dintribnt October 23, 1MT. 5,090 eopies. Bulletin No. 103 (Vol. XX. Art. IVi. The B«d-Ra tions. by F. I). Heald: A Mite AoeoaipanyiBg the Bad Rot Carnations. l, v Hubert H. Wolcott. Submitted for publicati October IT.. l'.toT. Distribnted Januarv m. v.mis. TtAKm e&lt;mii&gt;s </seg>
            <seg id="p029">XXIX A •&lt; I Nebraska, During tbe Winter of 1906-1 »07. My t- d A. T. Peter*. Distributed January 23, l!'" s and ninety-eight thousand bulletins and annual nted for distribution by the Experiment Station ti.l • I II, 1907. These publications 8TAT1ON .MA1I ived and sent out from the Experiment Station &gt; vear I'.miT as follows: 1m Sent First Cla u.scs postal*. Second Class. Til."! lbs. Third Cla 1,010 pounds Fourth Class. Ill' lbs. Free List lt;.::7n lbs. regular bulletiis. 1.365 lbs. press bulletins. \(i\V!.f.i&gt;i;mknts ral press, especially those papers located within Iniwii their appreciation of the work of the Kx &gt;rk reported and in every way facilitating the extension of ijrricultural knowledge ti We are indebted to the Thirtieth Session of the Nebraska Leg- ratal work at the North Platte Station and for the further inipment and nsaintenance of all the agricultural work in the IHVITNlT \ printed for ilistniuit i-iii- ending December .092,000 printed ]i:i&lt;rt 5,285 letters. by fiivinj: liberal ■pace ti&gt; the experimental atnic for its appreciatkn of the work of the Experiment Sta hi. ;is txpuwcd by increased appropriations for the experi </seg>
            <seg id="p030">TIIH AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT Eved by th&lt;- i surer the L'nitH,! - nstalli r ended Jr ss approved Ma allmer rr Puhlications Eage and stationer\ ght and exi Chemical supplies Seeds, plants and sundry sup] Feeding stuffs tls, implements and machin niture and fixtures ry Eintific apparatus veling expenses tingent expenses </seg>
            <seg id="p031">a 11 from the treasurer (ailment for the fiscal EXPENDITURES T under supplemental act March K, 1&lt;t"&lt;; i .Vlams a tiinf r </seg>
            <seg id="p032">XXXII V SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT KhlElI Moneys received by the state treasure sources than the United States, for benefit of the Experiment Station an for the year ended July 31, I Balance Jul&gt; Sales of stock, produ from oth ar Substat XPE rr E;e and stationery ht and ex; ical supplies . . . . Kb, plants and sundry supplies ing stuffs . Ks, implements and machinery liture and fixtures Scientific apparatus Live stock Eveling expenses . . ldings and land . . Mice, July 31, 1907 t </seg>
            <seg id="p033">\ .1 a iut a STATE APPROPRIATIONS FARMERS' INSTITUTES )6, of state general fund $5,368 16 al fund appropriation of 1907 for the xpenses, printing, general supplies $7,451 SI priation balance November 30, 1907 17,916 55 $25,368 16 $25,368 16 SUBSTATION (North Platte) Etl fund appropriation of 1907, for the years ending March 31, 1909 $25,000 00 to November 30, 1907, for superin - abor, live stock, feed, seeds, tools. neral supplies, and permanent im- $16,162 10 Appropriation balance November 30, 1907 8.837 90 $25,000 00 $25,000 00 J. S. DALES. Financial Secretary. ars ending March 31, 1909 20,000 00 ures to November 30, 1907, for superin- ■e. clerical services, labor, lecturers' serv- </seg>
            <seg id="p034"/>
            <seg id="p035">SOME TOMATO FRUIT ROTS DURING 1907. BY VENTS WORRELL POOL </seg>
            <seg id="p036">FAOE Introduction Fungus character Fick-Rot" (Alternana fast to (C*E) Jones &amp; 0 Observed symptoms Appressoria Isolations and a Cultural chara Isolations and inoculations 4 Description of the funpi; Syn Historical etic Cultural cham a a i His rmttami* on the Tomato fr History Symptoms Isolations and inoculatic Vegetative characters of 1 ■a * fungus Cultural characters ■Ripe Rot" or Anthracr }' Tomato — Symptoms Historical etiology io D« </seg>
            <seg id="p037">II n.l Th urfa f N A oOMli I UMA 1 U rivUlI KO I 5 DURLrsCj JtO7. V VENt'8 WoRRKI.I. 1'iMii.t 1NTKOIHCTION. m of the tomato [Lycoptrtietm esculent urn &gt; Ix't'ii known and described. Altho many coniinon doubt, have the power of rotting the overripe fruit, the ■; still limited which are able to grow upon the green or pelllU which are herein descril&gt;ed were studied during the 1907. No entirely unknown organisms were found. w characters of those which are more or less Htii observed which it might 1m- well to add to It known of these fruit rots i tomatoes which were used in the inocula - te "Dwarf Champion," "Stone" an&lt;l a special called Magnua" which was one of the potato-leaved varieties. if Champion" as a nile did not yield so readily as the tin}; organisms, even under laboratory condi BSEBVED SVMITHMS. ripe fruit examined had the diseased spot at the blossom lightly wrinkled and dark brown to almost black in color. illapsed flattened area extended almost across the upper •f the fruit. (PI. I. tig. 4.i The underlying tissues of ibmitted as a thesis for the degree of Master of Arts, University raska. 190X. ant in Plant Pathology "BLACK ROT." nia faadculata (CftE) -Jones &amp; Orout. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">4 I I 1 t.u I lecolii III liiElit the older portions were extremely hardened in places, tin rening cavities being tilled with flnffy fungus mycelit microscopical examination of the tissues revealed a dei ination of very dark, almost black hyphae in the older while brownish colored filaments extended into the ram healtli.v tissues. Sections made of such tissue taken from art iticiall\ spots revealed something of the nature of the patholog ditiou. The tough, hard portion* are made up &lt;&gt;f a aggregate of swollen, almost spherical cells: some of t rather thick walled, dearly pigniented and stand out relief in the midst of the snrronnding brown colored on II. Hjr. T.i The transition from this portion to the nei&lt; cavity (PI. II. li^. St. tilled with a lightly woven mass nary filaments, is very abrupt. No cellular strmtni-i ISOLATIONS AN • ilucose agar planted plate culture the diseased tissue, resulted in a per I ItiriKiiio. Inoculations were madt tained in this wav. Five davs after I the ripe fruit, the rotted area measured meter. In ten davs to two weeks the ri rotted and collapsed thru one-third their el \ t*ue was hard, leathery and blackened, risen every particular. No change or growth took place in the green fru (ilucose agar planted plate cultures made from tht lotted by the artificial inoculation of the fungus, prodnc cultures which were identical with the tirst isolation! III. Kg. !». i I'KSCRIPTloN !&gt;!•■ THE II Mil K Fertile hyphae. at tirst hyaline to lijrht In-own, later In rk brown to almost Mack. Sterile tilaments alwavs tinguishable. sinh utmcture being found &lt;&gt;n </seg>
            <seg id="p039">I i I mi 1 a &lt; ill Ml I t « McAlpilie' repor 7 nni' I ran [ihae. which wet « J t-oul to the fun n on the tomat fonidiophorefi \\ hen mature, dark tt H 14 microns l»v 4-."i microns. &lt; onidia i short side branch several ronidia. Them side chains are char frequently. Mature lie. | PI. II. ti-. conidia and hvphae ISTOKICAI. KTIOI.O'^ . nt" has l&gt;eeii known and descrilied. various liven to the causal organism. Xotwithstatid fuiifjns probablv has In-en observed when this 1 In* disease has been noted. 'iiniitii t'ke. was first 1 reported as occurring i in South Carolina in 1883. hater Galloway 1 ise "Black Hot." jjivinj; as the causal organ e. and h ii xa tin in snliuii Mart, lie states that glWl and ripe frail was readily effected 1 &gt;&gt; &lt;isjn,i in in spores under the skin." 1/. xnlmii ither writers as the causal organism. n 1S!m; 7 -found that the funjius which caoM on the rotting fruit was an Altirimrin. and 1 this fangna did not cause the rot. for p«m d with upon* from a pure culture from the ii a moist chamber until thev ripeaed without he rot. and cultures made from toaMton just rould not vield the Aftiriitniii." ted a tomato rot from N. S. Wales caused In The description agreei with tluit of the one in with the pxreptioa of the color of the neutral to gravish. 'inhitii I'JkK is the name given by Joan I us which was found growing as a saprophyte us li\ lti-i'n inii Tons, witli tlnw to six two limuitiulinal septa. Apical cell rnwii. often producing They include ms kvhoiivims ilarrotporium </seg>
            <seg id="p040">6 1/ i I' 11 V trturum T'k., )/. faxru-ulntum C&amp;E, .1/. tomato Cke. and i/rft« C&amp;E. The description and illustration given :tL t of the fungus under consideration. The two doubtless identical. Altcnxirin faxriruUitu (CJkE a rot of the frtm fruit hut do* Jones k &lt; i rout do produce a pronounced de&lt;a\ the ripe, duplicating in an artificial infection the original Itl; hard, leathery condition of the tissues. CLTIRAI. c IIAK ■ &lt;&gt;n :; per cent glucose agar | I 10): At tirst the growth is light colored, almost white, fluffy; later it dark gray with medium much darkened. Not an abund duetion of ronidia. Kn tomato agar i .'! §r. agar to 100 ec toaMto juice) ato or corn meal: Very similar to the preceding Ei steamed carrot or banana: Growth heavy, fluf n. Mycelium blackish green where the surface lied. SjK&gt;re production, but not abundant. En steamed potato: ilrowth light gray with places. Potato darkened beneath growth. My 'y but clinging mat-like to the surface. No spore RHl/.OCTOM 1 ON Till'. TOMATO HISTORY In the Florida station report 5 for 1936 an account is given occurrence of the potato Rhi&amp;octomiu upon the tomato fn le tomatoes which touch the ground are fre&lt;|iientl\ more i covered by the fruiting membrane of the fungus, which m ir appearance. So long as the tomato is green and the s tains uninjured, the fruit remains sound: however, if the si i ripe fruit is ruptured in any way. the fungus soon destn producing a brown rot. • • • The size and shape of res and the structure of the hvphae agree qaite well w </seg>
            <seg id="p041">7 t wth. T radiat mannei le fill jfter it li '. This is the only description found of a omato fruit. SYMPTOMS. xamincd showed nu rupture iu the external naked eye. The diseased area was plaiuly dis- the chocolate-colored, slightly wrinkled epidcr - aatioa of the underlying tissues revealed the and numerous somewhat darkened filaments Is in all directions. Nu conidia or fruiting id have yet l&gt;eeu observed. It has not yet ben her this Rhizodomm is Cortieiwm vmgwm BftC, upon the potato ATloNS AND INOCULATION ire of the fungus was obtained by the planted Green tomatoes only were used in the first - Three days after infection the discolored areas of inoculation measured one half inch in di - more days the older external hyphae had ted mycelial growth, while the new filaments almost around the entire fruit surface. In ten weeks the tomatoes were completely rotted. ind series green and rij&gt;e fruits were used. B the time of infection, the green specimens were ut. The tissues remained firm but were changed to brown and emitted a toadstool-like odor, which is stie of new growths of the fungus. The ripe tomatoes much the same appearance with the exception of a ftening of the tissues and a heavier external mycelial rhis growth is very iK'culiar and characteristic in its imaged filaments spreading in a clinging, mat like (PI. VIII. fig. -1-1.' i:iis spreads thru the green fruit readily as the ripe is ome gained an entrance. Its power to enter the </seg>
            <seg id="p042">8 \ vet been il \ f /, ire somcv lei ppeai us coloi v Under browned th thru the onbroken epidermis has nut ■ ited. VEliETATIVE I'HARACTKRS OK THE PI The fnnjrus ajjrees with the dearriptionB ;eneral.' ; ~ especially in the following details EThe young branche* are inclined to th« wth nf the parent stem, and the former rowed or constricted where united witli th ri mil : later the growth dark* srlerotia are formed. « '&lt; i. ii-iiii :i I : In twu da\s mycelisil grtiwtli over loin nieal i-ake. with a Iiull\ white tiny i dark brown selemtia with a denied central p I PI. III. fig. Hi. i • '•impost: A slight growth which sunn dis Steamed potato: In twent\ tuiir boon fun liuicters in diameter, thin Mycelium, potato n\er a great portion uf its expowd wurfa&lt;*e. Later typica selerotia arc foi-mcd &lt; ilucosc ajrar : At tirst mycelium thin, tpn pi'udiieini; selerutia similar tn preceding. Sti'Wnl ichiJIIu: Similar In |p|(&lt;cilii "\iinng hyphae hw Ktrongh v;triwlate Inn nniformlv granular and iihht deepl.t colored mm to bave oi-rurred wore nearly at ri^hi ; !i.v|.li :l .'." i PI. IV, tin. ll-l The iiiiiiKTinis Hclerutiu 1 1 ti ■&lt; I n&lt; &lt; &lt;l i I'l. III. lip of cldsclv sc|p|;i1c Iiv|iIi;ic. The it-lls w livpluu' iii;i\ be \civ irregular in shape and il •His nuir 1m- of a lighter brown ami vary litil up al si Btraighi hyj»h»e i I'l. l\'. ftg. Il'i. : ivpliac arc very easily broken up. each •-«■! I Itf forming a new growth. 1*1 III UAI. I HAB T&lt;iiiiat&lt;i iigiir: ai tiisi. white, matted m </seg>
            <seg id="p043">9 1 h « 1 t Mycelium identical with that upon potato. Rhteoctonia-like, the filaments w liioi-t li other, while along their length ir lengths mi lined. KOT" ol{ AXTHRACXOHE OF Till: TOMATO VMI'IUM mav varv from small, sunken, smooth larker in color than the surrounding health* x and dotted with the small fruit maw n entire side of the fruit. A great nian\ have a characteristic which is verv noticeable. mi rinjjs. These are plainly shown in Plate ionrenti-ii-ill\ arranged spot the acervuli ier in circles, while a portion of Brier Menial evidence of disease intervene*. Thi tiied in the first photograph taken of this ter.' In Plate I. figure •!. the diseased area homogeneous surface with the acervuli at on I \ a slight conation is noted. In lions and inoculations made, it was ill— I ml ; kept in the light developed this 7.011a t ion while ie dark formed an even, continuous growth. No •Id observation* were made, however, as to the position of the various fruits with reference to sunlight and shade, altho this probably the cause of the appearance or nonappearanre of nil mji 1-1 111 The deeper t is th an imiuem rn led as soon ; ervuli are oolv sues of the anthracnose spots are alwavs tilled ;e BBnbcr of spores. These commence to be ■; the tangos has grown for a day or two. The found after the growth has continued for somt hum l/frnjn rxiri Chest et uiiirus. to large roughened antui, brows to ;\\ </seg>
            <seg id="p044">10 i-.l urn v 7 i 1 he ri{ while in C. h HISTORICAL ETIOLOGY. (Uucusporium pkomoUe$ was first described by Sac prodaciag a rot of rijK' tow ton In 1884 Arthur 21 reported the same fungus as "rap epidermis and producing great ammbera &lt; &gt;f spores 01 of the protruding mycelium. In 1891 rhester" fouud that a fungus which caused a nose of the tomato was a CoUetotrichum, and tx-lii of tomatoes with what was apparently O. I'll in at first a pinkish stroma without setae hut wli turned darker and developed pet The spore measurements an niui microns. Ii L8M Mis- Btooeman 1 * i.'i V(S :| brief descriptioi (Hoses. She states that "the colonies of the s are quite different. The Qloeo*porium 'dded beneath the epidermis, the short eon tin projecting beyond the host. In the Colletotric acervuli are erumpent and the setae are sotneti k spherical perithecialliki' hodies are formed w setae. These so far as lias vet been determine conidia formed freely on the mycelium do noi e heaps." ail Eof the tomato by Halsted 1 - i: in 1895 aad IMI 14 lie names the fungus CoUetotrickmm pkotnt B 1B in 190n pives the nanie of the anthra. id Ches. be ;i new specie! Darned ii &gt;'. lyroperaici. In 1 s! &gt;•_• "the fungus which in lsid was clearly a Colleto the abundant development of setae was in \su~2 withou mid to all appearances a Oloeoaporium." In 1893 lihn (ix)Kiriuiii phomoHea Sacc. is report jf the fungua it seems to bear a relation to ag 0oM&gt;" in 1 s!i.~&gt; reported a "pimply rut of the he &lt;li&lt;l not name the &lt;;ius;il or-r;i nisin. tin- ]&gt;h trription of t In- disease agree with that of </seg>
            <seg id="p045">11 i nid i I'MI tv 1 1 M.I 1 i i w mad ho thev ie new "v ped. lh( l.ien produ &gt; have existed ;is to the proper naming of However, conclusions drawn from these itions point to the occurrence of two anthrac - tomato. one produced by QUiMftrimm Pho- and one bj Colletotrickmm Ipeopeniei (Mies. The ■acteriaed bj an iinl&gt;edded acervulus without s. er forms an em in pent acervulus with or without FUN0U8 CHARACTERS ;i measure 10 IS microns kmg by _'..".".."&gt; microns wide, lewliat less than that given in the original descrip size of setae and acervuli agree. In a •"! ]&gt;er cent I 1-10) culture at 26 »'.. tlie fungus spores germinate urs. In 1^ to "_'4 hours an abundance of primary ifoduced. Tkej are formed by tlie pinching off of the the simple eonidiopliores. which process requires ii three -fourths of an hour (PI. IV. tig. 13). The remain in clusters around the hyphal end but into the surrounding medium. Their formation it determined by the usual banging drop method. pf spore production is evidently followed by the •during the quantities of conidia found in the al culture media. JOBBg colonies are white to When examined microscopically an abundance of lidia are found. Later the colony commences to and around the central or older portion. The two or three times their usual diameter, become &lt; spherical in sha(&gt;e (PL IV. tip. 14), form many 1 take on a dark brown color. If an examination is ■w if any conidia are found in this darkened portion, ■cur abundantly near the ed«re of the colony where wth continues. As these darkened masses are de- conidia format ion ceases. The spores which have .1 germinate and now into i new mycelium. The the anthracsoM spot i I'l. V. tifi. IB). </seg>
            <seg id="p046">12 \ i n i n latter, due to lark uf nutrition, does not produce upon EThe blackened imi gradua • or less spherical anil somew h;ii may or Mr imi produce setae. El t times, especially in freshly is&lt; &gt;! ps precede the formation of the n to Im- the tvnical aceivulus will led cultures, sniitl I' Mark aggregation I nder natural conditions, tin xan na i ion iinlhraciiose spot which li;is not abundant production of priiiuir duced ;icer\ \ n w Kulllie milliner ax lhal \&gt; consist of parallel bear the setae and PI \ fer are identical i idia. As these net flingUS I issue till dually continues u \ r- couidia also dittap|iear. fall scattering elsew here. ii At times these blackened Ik 'I spot from the time the epidermis is i-ii i such a case few typical acervuli ;ire i dark aggregations are identical with tl cultures. They g€i urinate readily. pr» when placed under favotiilde i-ondition tho 'oduciui Al'l'ltKSSOIil A I The appress&lt;iria i IM. VII, ti}. r . 18) ;is found in this gpeciec al lM)dien. siihmiI Ii in outline or with knol» like project! rk brown, and contain a few large oil drops. They. :tr&lt; rialdy the first objects to come into focus when a III o|i preparation is examined. Certain hyphae seem to «. ' towards the cover jjlass and when it is reached, thru l.v heap iif&gt; until tlit confluent. Thcv arc I;H' ;lll&lt;l spin Ix-cuiiit's older, pink iicerru r attain linn iiiiirs iiinii the i p i I 'I. VI. fig. LOi. The at little or no evidence wan f&lt; tiptim leVt'liipi </seg>
            <seg id="p047">13 x \\ i I le t uiiyrns w ited plate nu nail, su heiwise. these attachment i»rgant&lt; are uniting drop of water and incubated at rcssoria w itliin iwu da\s. No s|&gt;ores were id dav, when a vcrv few were found. The increased ulightlv up to tlie tifth day. was no appreciable change. the same method and conditions, ronidia ! pet- cent jjlucose ajrar i 1th han^in^ drop i t went \ four lionrs an immense Dumber "f lined but no appressoria were distinguishable. y, however, appressoria were developed in ilian in the preceding culture. In l&gt;oih i ivere formed without reference to the surround sscria were formed in the latter culture a greater luvreluil growth was made, thus mil need for greater attachment. Since adverse mse a greater production of these funned are for the purpuse of tiding the i ii in and H« luted" for other s|M'&lt;ies. that iiini |iroduces only a Dieager supplv of pare water yields few spores and manv dark ihe tendenrv that Haiwelbring mentions, "the &gt;\\s in a nutrient medium commences to form lint before this is formed the livpha grows out repeal the process." in this way fornii pollen hyphal cells, i PI. VII. fi^r. l'-».^ AI'lliNS AMI INimI LATION as repeatedly isolated in pure cultures liv the ■thod. l'xactly the same cultures were obtained lotli. sunken spots, as seen in T'late I. figure 1'. |i|»;ii' prohable. in this s|M'iics ai lcnst. tliiii favorable period. HaxtielbriniJ 1 * found for </seg>
            <seg id="p048">14 i f as from well developed spots ing. 3) which had produ abundance of acervuli. These cultures were used indi nately in the inoculations. Four days after infection the diseased area measured fourth inch in diameter on the average. This was true of green and ripe tomatoes. No acervuli were formed at tl but an internal examination gave evidence of an almndan Corn-meal: At first mycelium grayish green, not membi but rising slightly above the medium: colony edge pink, sh into white. Later when mycelial growth is carefu away, the characteristic small heaps or acervuli may U the medium. Potato: Mycelium pink, edged with whit)' and covering nted closely. Acervuli next medium hidden by the llaiftons growtl Carrot: Growth resembling that upon the potato. Banana: Mycelium at first fluffy, later, in month-old culture medium shrunken, black, covered with a roughened heap acervuli. mation of the primary spurts. The spots increased in extent slowly even under ide.nl eond tinns. In two weeks' time, or longer, the size of the div area had iaerawed bat little: the acerrvli had made their a] pearnnee. however, u small pinkish heaps. These gradual 1 increased in density ami color, eventually becoming black ii of cells, setae and qw us. Tomato ajjar : Caltnrea cme week old. &lt;irowth he pact, membrane like, pink with an abundant production i Bpores. Later growth roughened with the Mack masses ol vnli scattered over the surt Stewed tomato: At first mycelial growth clinging I of medium, brownish pink. Later, surface blackened maases of acervuli. Three per cent glucose agax (H 10) : The fungus pn sjune aiiiteai-ance as upon tomato agar. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">15 i r f S \ I\ I f 1/ SI , SYMPTOMS. ms which ripened in one garden under ttetrn - inly sound and healthv . the external surface plump with mi evidence of internal softened wevtr. upon putting into the fmits. a fourth to mie inner tissues was found to l&gt;e darkened and shriveled. ken. greenish black tissue was usually located i&gt;f the fruit, in the cavities around the seeds. The tissues were usually healthy and tirni. &lt;rivin«r the nial appearance externally (PI. 1. tij;. 5). The •e|ieatedly exainined bat no evidence of the presence I lament! was found. Tlie exaininatiniis were not however, on account of the dry. collapsed condition. ISOLATIONS AMI 1 N(M T 1.AT1ON S. ised tissue were at various tin ultures. lmt no onstant results were obtained. llle of the variOUfl poured plate series, similar bacterial colonies developed around the itiun in the planted plates and in the Berk n such abundance that it was thought then usal organisms. Pure cultures were obtained ami ide into both green and ripe tomatoes, lmt no in- imilar appearance developed. From a pure culture of this fun- inoculations were made into the jireen and ri|&gt;e fruits-. After three or four days, the funjrus liypliae had penetrated the rarronnding tissues to the extent of one fourth to one half inch. The growth occurred the same upon the green and ripe speci - mens. The liypliae also grew externally in tufts, which were made up of numerous fascicles, which in turn produced a j;ivat ilnindaiice of conidia. ■equently observed. ;it various times placed in ylu- n resulted. one series of poured |il;ites. numerous funjjus colonies of </seg>
            <seg id="p050">16 i i i i t Isolations from the artificially rotted fruits yielded the inal fungus. fvidenth this fungus could character* &lt;&gt;f the disease produce a roi "f the tissues. did not resemble the original twa.v. The diseased tissu&lt; In 1 \ darkened and rather treating with instead of a of the artificial mi were \\ater\ in appearance, stron treeing with the drv. dark gr to Mark tissui' of the original. For tliis reason the fungus j vimi a specific name. Altho the connection between funjrns and the specific disease is not known, it is a genuine fr ich is described. The conidia germinate in a few In &gt;ni ( glucose agar i " l"i culture, and in twen kinds of conidia are formed, nii'i The microconidia are borne apon very short eo hardly man than a side growth of the cell iPl. IX The conidia are formed by the simp) They remain clustered around the hyphal spores are massed together, when the pai microns wide by 4-14 microns long The inacroconidia are produced in a similar fash i ends of long condiophores i PI. IX. ti^s. 23-27), the latter pert bearing microconidia upon short side branches. From the ber of eonidia whose growth was continuously observed K) became nniseptate and then only just before germinat k jilace. When plain ajrar was used in the place of glue njmr. the conidia were much smaller and e monlv one t septate, reseinhliii}; somewhat the typical Fusarium spore. The niacroconidia coninionly measure :'. .'i microns by !• germinating tubea have produced mm abnndan form mom Conidia are nonseptate. o\ </seg>
            <seg id="p051">17 / HISTORICAL. mentions a blackening of the tomato fruit tissues i.v Im- hm externally as well as internally. The disease 1 most frequently nn the early fruits of rapidly growing Ets but continued to appear thruout the season. The remark - feature of this rot is the total absence of fungus hyphae i i lit* tissues of the fruits in the early stages of the disease." - the only report found in which reference is made to this \r condition of the tomato fruit. tLTLRAL CHARACTERS. Growth rather fluffy, white, with a shade of der wed tomato: Growth fluffy, white with a pinkish tinge. •n meal : Growth fluffy, white with a tinge of lavender. edium changed to a purple which is very characteristic. QIqcom agar: At first culture is pare white, later becoming e at the edjje of the medium. The lavender pigment does xti'tid into the hyphae but remains in the medium. to: Growth clings to surface, rising but slightlv above it. .v na : Mycelium compart, fluffy, soon tilling tube. / / SARI I 1/ MiL I \ / MART. SYMPTOMS. The outside of the fruit presents an unliroken epidermis. The diseased area is recognized by a wrinkled area, somewhat darker red in color than the surrounding epidermis. The underlying ■s are of a lighter color, shrunken and filled with fungus filaments. The central jK&gt;rtion of the diseased area is compact, dry and can be lifted out as a •core." The tissue around this shows dark red, softened areas, which upon examination reveal a great hyphal development. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">18 H ll I ( u i t i ISOLATIONS AMI INOCI I. ATKINS. fPi-din the pare cultures obtained by tin- nasal Method, inoc us wfic made into the ripe ami green tomatoes. In thro e daya the rotted area am the ripe fruits ateaawed from i If to one incli in surface tliaim trr. and extended one third i • entire fruit. The hvphae grew externally in tufts, w I \\ The fnngUfl seems to have Very little effect DpOB til -I fruits, penetrating the tissues Inn slightly. Howerei celiam is able to grow sufficiently to produce a tuft of x h.vphae. which attain a slight growth and then become d in:sii:ii'iio\ The ronidia germinate in a few hout ( culture media. In twentv-four hours a del formed lint no spores are produced mil for two or three da\s. The con id I'onidiophores which may lie simple or I like effect with their side liranches. and terminal hranchc 1!4 44 microns liv 2.5-5 niicrons. No niicroronidia I served. I I'l. X.I IIISToKK A I. KT The fungus under considt ration doulitless is the sain loway- lias described. The illustrations of the two fun&lt;. 1" to the same species. Callow ay also found that /'. aolan Wi not penetrate the green fruit altho it so readily produced decay of the ripe. Ehi« last year a bulletin" has been issued which descriU jrus i t'uxa riii in xolani Mart, i which was aide to produce a ■e a of even the small jrreen fruits, blackening the tissues in a pecv va,v. This characteristic antl the manner of spore prodnct jwiiiit to another species rather than to the one under consid tion. produced an immense number &lt;&gt;f nickle-shaped sport in very rliaraciensiic. ilic rooidioplx The conidia arc tickle-shaped, time to ti </seg>
            <seg id="p053">19 I 1 li kee, f vent ■i I n \v;is grown opoD tomato itfjar. stewed tomato. «sc agar, potato, carrot and hanana. witli similar The nircelial growth is Huffy, cottony, varying from e to white with a pinkish cast. After a few days ar I'UKVALKNTi: OF THK ROTS. xperiiueni Station plat and two home garden wen .1 rvation. iraonoM or "ripe rot" of the tomato was found upon uf the later tomatoes which ripened in the plat of the t Station, rendering the fruits practically worthless. 1 not occur in the two other jiardens. ar blackened condition produced by f'umiriuin &gt;\&lt;. fully one half of the earliest fruits which ripened home gardens, as shown by the number* of tosMtoea ut open and found to 1m* in this condition. w uned in greater or less abundance daring rt of the season. The loss was not estimated as nn vailahle as to the amounts of fruit there would he ■ occurred. PREVENTIVE MEASURES. he tomato rots, like the majority of all ]&gt;lant diseases, can not ield in check to any great degree after they are once estal&gt; ed. Preventive measures applied in time, however, should the loss of fruits at a minimum. he measures here recommended are gleaned from the reports liffereni experiment stations where experiment! for the pec - don of tomato disease have been carried on thru several sue- lve seasons he work of llalsted was carried on thru seven successive aea- Some of the results obtained may Ik' rammed up as fol- roduetion of conidia upon all media. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">20 1 Tomatoes may grow ;mmi thrive upon the same html year Biter year, with the employment of proper sanitary measuirs. Am compared, however, with tomatoes grows upon land under rota tion. the fruit is inferior in o,uality anil quantity, and is nodi more liable to rot. Plants which have an upright position with smooth, thick skinned fruits, as the "Dwarf Champion," an- freer from dil than the trailing thin skinned varieties. "Stone." The training of the vines wax not found advisable. t't is advocated by others-' that "ain system of training which dws free access of air and sun to the fruits and holds plants &gt;\e the gromd, decreases the rut. However, liranches must Ik - iched out. &lt;&gt;r the trellis liecoines an iuterminaltle in. iage." E unitary measures should l&gt;e emjiloyed at all tin ;. decayed fruit should Ik- removed and burnt, and a lication of Bordeaux mixture should lie gives ever ks during the growing season. Ehe Department of Agriculture* 1 as far back as 1889 giv&lt; rincing evidence of the iH-netit of efficient spra\ Section 1 Bordeaux in 2 No treHtiiir Ammoniac* Acknowledgments are due I&gt;r. F. 1&gt;. Heald. Botanist of tht Station. f&lt;ir his kindly help and advice given at all times, ami Mr. W. H. Hein. Field Assistant, for specimens collected. Bordeaux mixture of the formula &lt;&gt;-4 ."in or 5-4-60 should I* </seg>
            <seg id="p055">21 w • im":;i i I \rtln I 4. Callow Fie. 1 howing (i« Pi thrarnosf Fi with a lioiu i.iisuockai'HY /.':::i ( . l- \iiii. Bep. Florida Exp. Sta.. 1906:44 and Stewart: Ball. Cornell Exp. Sta.. isii. 1901. Bull. Colorado Exp. Sta.. .&lt;»/. 1!&gt;l&gt;4. •: Ann. Bep. Del. F.x)». Sta.. ', : til*. ls!U Ann. Hep. Del. Exp. Sta.. .7: so. 1892. Ann. Rep. Del Kxp. Sta.. 0:111-115. 18» Hass.ll.iin-: Bot &lt;ia/-.. )2 : i:{5-14l'. 1!MM;. lialstcd: Ann. Rep. N. J. Exp. Sta.. /.{:.!(»:!. ls'.lj. Beach: Itull. \. V. A&gt;;r. Kxp. Sta.. tt5:M6*. 1897. Tomato fruit showing the very immature, smooth, an - spots which have produced but slight indentations. Two tomato fruits showing large anthrarnose spots logeiii'iins arrangement of the aeervuli. Rep. ..f Chief of Bee. Veg. Path., 1888: :U4 Jone« &amp; Groat : Mull, of Torr. Hot. Club. .&gt;', : -jr.7. is:»7. .M.Ah.iitc: \*r. &lt;;.■,/.. of N. S. Walt's. ? : :!U4. ISM. c.l.l.: Agr. (in/.. N. S. Wnl.'s. 8:868-9. ls'.C. ll.ilsi. :l «l: Ann. Rep. N. J. Ex\&gt;. St;i.. f«:2M. 1896 Ann. Hep. N. J. Kxp. St;i.. r7:33&amp; 18M. Ann. Sep. N. I. Exp. St;i.. S|:54C-T. 1903, Rolfs: Ann. \U-\&gt;. Florida Exp. Bta., 1905:45. Tech. Ball. Mass. Exp. St;i.. .&lt;. INT. Ill 1..: Mi.-h.-lia. 2:640. If : Ann. K.'j.. X. Y. Bsp. Sta.. 9:38. 1- nn : Bot. &lt;l:t7... it: 74 and O."&gt;. l - .iii.l l...&lt;leman: BalL Toriiel! Exp. Sfa.. .&lt;. J . 1S!H. it: Ann. Rep. I', s. Dept. Agr, 188»: 4 is. EXPLANATION OF PLATB8. Plate I. Tomatu fruir with lar&lt;;e niatnrc anthrainose gpo flnitc zonatinn rings. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">22 llapsed learaii I 1 1 I round &lt; / Illldel rujitui tae and Fig. 4. Toniato fruit with portion blackened ami liv Altrnwria fatcicuUtta. Fiji. ."&gt;. Tomato fruit snowing normal external ap] with collapsed internal darkened lissur caused by Futai Plat.' II E'ifi. 8. Mtiriiiiriii faacieufata showing method of ion tioii. Fijr. i. Section thru portion of tomato tissue hardene&lt; 1 Hi rum in rut anil showing ilic intensely dark in i brown colored cloaelv massed ones. 'i^. 8. An adjoining cavitr lilted with filamentB. fiuin an artiflciallv infeoted tin Fig. in. Silrri.tia form /,' rake. l'lati- l\ fig. ll!. Sclcrutia hvphae with short. Fij:. 13. Time developnieni of primal E'ijr. 14. An aggregation of enlarged, sphcriial. vac wn ceils, the forerunner &lt;&gt;f the blackened mass iticial cultures and occasional natural infections /» isiii. Date V. IFi&lt;r. IS. A section thru a typical acervulus of ('. ///&lt; owing; the fungus hyjihae and primary conidia in tin ing; tissue and the parallel arranged fimirus tilaments \l The epidermis of the tomato fruit and bearing se fondarv conidia. Fig. It. Glucose agar cnl rt. 11. Immature RhiziH'touia \\\\ and peculiar romtriction ai the &lt; i ichinii ///co/(( rx'ui. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">ui. vulu placed 1 t. S 1 \ A I I ( 7 Plate VI. mi thru a Mackowd ■paerlud heap &lt;&gt;f C. hf fimjrus cells have completely replaced tile tissue li'in thru an acervulus whicli is jit&gt;t ffflWH m\ if by the blackened fuii&lt;Mis cells. Plate VII pitssiiria of C. Igcopcraivi fanned in a •'! per cent • I'M culture. lnetinies before an ap].ressorimn was coinpletek ■ ha grew out and attempted t&lt;« repeal the prom* egnlar chain of h.vphal cells. Plate VIII • niato fruit artiticiall.v infected with F iismiu m &gt;p. oniato fruit artiticall.v infected with F. solan i. ■ niato fruit artificially infected with Rkizoctomim. ['late IX. Plate X. development &lt;&gt;f Macroronidia &lt;&gt;f Futrn rirnw ap. clcvclnpiiifiit of niii -roruniiliii of Fuxiniinn s\&lt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">24 IM.ATK </seg>
            <seg id="p059">25 PLATE II ./m r </seg>
            <seg id="p060">26 PLATE III </seg>
            <seg id="p061">« ■&gt;■ </seg>
            <seg id="p062">28 PLATE \ 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">■ PLATE VI 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">30 12 • / / p • * / \ f ♦•• r *? 1 i v*- ■ %• N </seg>
            <seg id="p065">31 PLATE VIII. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">32 Agricultural Expirinn nt Station of Xrbnixkn I- PLATE IX </seg>
            <seg id="p067">33 PLATE X </seg>
            <seg id="p068">34 A NEW FORM OF SPHAEROPSIS ON APPLES. BY LEVA BELLE WALKER. Two forms of 8phaerop#ia have been observed whi&lt; pable of producing a severe black rot of the apple. The n ■copic appearance of the rota is very much the same. The cipaJ differencea in the two forms are in the size of the sp size and thickness of the pycnidiam, and tli ostiole in the new form. Tin- new form als more vigorous mi producer In this discussion tin- typical Sphaero form and the differences and p Itlul an- respectively considered &gt;/'// 1 H Hol- ls 1/ l/.OA' Sphaeroptit tualorum !Vck is the well known f causes the Mack rot of apples. It lias been very f and it is onlv necessary to reft Peck 1 described the fungus to the |uili|ii-at uul cave diaei tions of the spores, prcnidia ami appearance &lt;&gt;f the app &gt; Considerable work has Keen done to show the identity of ngus with .][(icn&gt;i&gt;lttnini nit/lonnn- ami Sphaeroptit rkoint l'addock 4 proved the identity of the fnn&lt;:iis earning the Mark rot and the canker of apples and also made a lar&lt;;e number of cross inoculations with Spkseroptis inaltintni and other S/ihrn ropges which show that the size of the spores varies with the host and not with the species. He gives no work on the pyonidial Delacroix 5 gives a review of previous work and some original "Assistant in the Department of Botany, T'nivergity of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p069">35 on the pvcnidial form. Be shows illustrations of cankered pvcnidia from cankered limbs, spores, etc., but re quite diagrammatic. oUS lustrations are Kinne I good description of the fungus and illustra- | M» 1 2 Fig. 1. — Section of Sphaeropsis malorum liycnidium taken from a green apple mummy, illustrating typical pycnidia with oval spores. Spores from the same apple. tions of spores aud of rotting apples; and most of the Experi - ment Station publications mention the disease, giving cuts of rotted apples, cankered limbs, etc.. for the macroscopic recogni - tion of the disease. Where the minute structure is spoken of at </seg>
            <seg id="p070">36 i i u whit wn or &lt; ::: nil. mention is made of the oval or egg-shaped spores and th ln-itad ostiole of the pycnidia. I^ngyear 7 gives a detailed drawing of a pycnidium and sjmh and a brief, very careful description of the fungus and of th diseases caused by it. One form of the 8pkaerop*i* ander consideration agn fectlv witli this description. Stevens' and others mention its attacks upon green fruit. T has been observed very commonly by the writer, as main ereei apples mummied by the fungus are found daring the w In sections of such apples the fungus filament! do tint jienetrate deeply into the tissues of the apph All who have given careful studv to the fungus found oval or egg-shaped spores 20-25 microna by io-ii microns and conical pycnidiuni with an ontiole corresponding w THE NEW FdK.M UK sl'H \I.H Tlie new form of Sphaentp lagly. It was first isolated from ai black rot in tlie fall of 1906, and h other similar apples. In ever\ emi have been observed. &lt; i LTL'BAI IIARAi TK1 The fungus has been grows upon all the eon media (glucose agar. glycerine agar. plain agnr. I^'MT gelatin, Pasteur's solution, corn-meal, potato, etc.). Ii it has produced the same type of growth, but ih&lt; grow been most vigorous upon glucose agar. potato, and pon Tin* growth is cottony and at first of h slightly grayish color. Soon near the surface of the piedium the fungus t\ begin to turn dark and tlie culture assumes a dark hrn blackish hue wiieh viewed from the under surface. The spreads rapidh thru aerial Inuliu and all be coat d e extreme surface hyphae alone remaining a light gray description, i Kijjs. 1 ;nul </seg>
            <seg id="p071">37 \ IS T/ 3 t3 — Enlarged cells found in filaments of the new form as seen in hanging drops. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">38 i i i f '. The fungus hyphae are normally aboat M microns in d ameter, lmt often, in examining the apple tissue in which t fungus was growing, very much enlarged cells were obai Haute iIlgCLi tar ■ short time and then placed in damp chamber. Two apples were placed in the same one of which was simply punctured, while tht lated with the hyphae of the fangn The inoculated apples began to rot around the in spot in a few days and the rot spread rery rapidly thr entire apple. The rotting was much the same as for 8pkm\ maiorum, but more rapid. The apples at first turned brow i blackish discoloration under the skin. Gradually tit darker and became much wrinkled and shrunken black man Examinations of the decayed tissue and of sections of the r&gt; parts seem to indicate that the growth of the fungus is la intercellular. No definite exj&gt;eriiiients were carried on to determine the i 1 of infection of the apples, but it seems evident that the fun filaments have the power of penetrating the epidermis of tt appl. . as the check applet would become infected at the point contact if allowed to touch the inoculated apples after they 1 came badlv rotted. Similar cells were obtained in great numbers in hanging droj made of glucose agar. I'astciir's solution, etc This peculi;i formation is shown in figure .!. The walls of these en, cells are slightly thicker and the contest! very much moi granular. Upon none of the media used have pycnidia ever been foun&lt; Imt sclcrntiiiinlike bodiei bling pycnidia wen- often d&lt; veloped. IMMTI.ATIoNs. Kejx&gt;ated inoculations were tried in apples, and in ever? eat the black rot was developed. The applet used wen- irai wiappc in absorbent cotton wet with a L-1000 solution of eorr </seg>
            <seg id="p073">■i/firxt Annual Report. 39 s A % Oi 5 Fig. 4. — Section of the new form of Xphaeropsis pycnidium. Flo. 5. — Same as Fip. 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">40 t. 7. — Detail of the spore-l, earing surface of . * — t" pores of the new form of jiyi-nidiun </seg>
            <seg id="p075">41 The pycuidia begin to form very in the apple and can l&gt;e easily soon after the rot has spread seen just under the surface epidermis. They gradually force their way thru the Eand appear as rough black e pycnidia many sderotia-likt apple. These resemble the pyc • can only be detected by the spots ou the apple. B« - masses of hyphae form upon nidia so closely that the differ - lid of the microsco)M'. Serial seel inns of several hundred of these pycuidia taken rom various inoculations, from different cultures, wen raph showing si&gt;ha /ism mummy and a check appl low ihe exact form .it ion of the pycnidia. but in no twaa an ostiole found. Instead of an ostiole the pycnidiuin almost ahvavs verv much thicker on the outer surface than I the inner. Figures 4. 5 and t'» sliow typical pycnidia. Dark \vn one celled spores were found in the pycnidia. but the res were much longer than the spores described for S/thuf rof*i$ iiinloniiii. The average spores were about 28-30 microns long and 10-12 microns wide, while many spores were as much microns long. The very smallest spore found w . microns long. Figure 7 shows the detail of the spore-ln-aring surface, and figure S. mature spores from fresh material. I INS. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">42 thinking that possibly the slightly abnormal &lt;•&lt; nditioni ip chamber might affect the pycnidial form, sections in a w. Jle of storage apples and of mummies wintered in the 1 were affected with the Maek rot. The same pycnidial : observed in all the apples that had pyenidia with res, while in those having the typical egg shaped sport lole was always very conspicuous. In a few wn apple niuiiiinies the pyenidia containing long sports \\ E little thicker on the outer surface and it seemeil possi t an ostiole might exist, but in examining dozens &lt;&gt;• ie were found. I So far as it has been observed the long spored form - be a much more vigorous grower and to do much more damagt in has been descril&gt;ed for Spkaeropait mmlorum. I In one orchard reported near Blair, Washington County. ;i rge per cent of the apples rotted on the trees from the attack the fungus. EPhe fungus penetrates the tissues of the apple so rapidly that entire apple is rotted before the pyenidia begin to ap ich does not seem to be the case with 8pkmmop$it imilnnnn. Fie;. uhaeropsis mummy, showing pycnidia. The size of the pycnidia varied very greatly in the rv I shown by figures 1. 4. ."&gt; and 6. as both forms a: under the same magnification. KXTKNT OF INJI'RY. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">I I n 1" .Ins i with lions between the two fungi can be briefly summed p\v Sphaeroptis maUtrum New Form. 25 x 12 microns 15 x 10 microns 33 x 10 microns 23 x 10 microns 19-20 i 10-12 microns 27-31 x 10-12 microns r of pycnidia 169-223 microns 300-600 microns ameter of pyt UJ9-225 microns 150-375 microns Very abundant development None Broad, always present None found Thin Thick Thick SPECIES IDENTITY. her the kmg-apored form should be considered a mem or a form of 8fhmerofm» malorum is not determined. xaniiuing applet roiled by Bphmeroptit, none of the typical lia and iporet were found till very recently. These • upon very small greet apple mummies. All the other ma - examined was from ripe or half grown apples. Jock* from his experiment! in cross inoculations with ■ (includes that the size of the spore varies with the he spore size varies with the host, it seems possible that iore size mijiht vary when jtrown upon green and mature And if the spore size varies with the host it would seem probable that the pyrnKHam also might vary. Whether true or not can only t&gt;e determined by further experiments cultures and inoculations. DISTINCTIONS. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">44 i 1. I'crk: Ann. Bep. N. V. State Musciiin. .? / : 96. 2. Stewart. Rolfs an.l Mall: Hull. N. V. A&lt;:i\ Bx| ISM Sta.. I'M 331. 1900. 3. OViara: Science. N. S.. ft: 434-435. IMS. 4. I'lKhlock: U.ill. N. Y. Agr. Kxp. Sta.. /I».):1T9 206. lsit'.t r Delacroix: Ball. Sue. Mv&lt; 19(«. France. /.'&gt; : 1 141 : :i.-&gt;n (». Kinncv : Ann. Hep. HIkmIi 19219 Sta.. I 7. Loagjear: Special Hull. Mi IMi. b. \gr. Coll. Ex[ LITKRATlKi: &lt;ITKI&gt;. land Kx|p. Sr </seg>
            <seg id="p079">45 SEED TREATMENT FOR THE SMUTS OF WINTER BARLEY. AM) IX COOPERATION WITH THE DEPARTMENT OF FIELD CROPS. INTRODUCTION. {Vinter barley has been {frown on the Exiieriment Station plats* •ing the past three jean and has given a high yield, altho it i lxt'ii badly infected with smut. The plat grown in ISM twed 10 per cent of smut as determined hv actual count, while IMM the count gave 15 jkt cent. The per cent of smut shown a count does not indicate the exact j&gt;er cent of lows by redue - n of yield, lint is generally somewhat greater than the per cent Einci' wed treatment of barley for smuts has not been an i orv as in some other cereals it was deemed advisable to com r some of the different methods and to try a number of modi tions. The results of the treatments will be given in the fol lowing pages description of the barley s.mits. Barley is affected by two different species of smuts: the • &lt;/ smut and the mated xnutt. Both of these smuts were present in the field in the season of 1906. The covered smut i ( xtihif/o hnrilci il'ers. i Kell. and Sw.i was present in slightly larger amount than the naked smut {Ustilcujn nmUi (Jens.) Kell. and Sw. i The differences in the external appearances of the two species arc shown in the accompanying cuts i figs. 2 and S). In the covered smut the entire head is destroyed and the smut masses which take the place of the kernels are covered at first with the more or less transparent basal parts of the glumes </seg>
            <seg id="p080">46 ifig. 2 1. In tke.voaager itegea of tin- disease the awns still j and th«»v may remain till ham t time, althn in inanv ase r 1 - — A bundle of smutted heads for comparison with two norma heads. I... are broken off (If. 2). while the thin membrane enclosing tli. Bmut masses may be more or less rapt wed, exposing the purple Mack spui-e niilss. s . tij;. 2). I'mler the influence «.f heiivv \viml&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p081">47 A i vail under Nebraska conditions, some of the spore - at become exposed may !»■ considerably dissipated heads have somewhat the appearanee of the heads he other species (tig. S). Heads of barley affected with the cove red smut. smutted plants all heads produced from a single stool nia.\ tniay not lie smutted, hut in case any heads are free from smut ■y ate frequently reduced in size, and in many cases are less n half the size of normal heads from unsmutted plants. The in her of smutted and unsmutted heads in affected stools is </seg>
            <seg id="p082">48 —Heads of barley affected with th </seg>
            <seg id="p083">49 wing counts which may be considered fairly No. of heads free No. smutted heads. from smut. 10 4 4 ii 4 •&gt; lie naked sunn the entire heads are also destroyed but ive an entirely different appearance from heads affected ■ covered smut i tig. 3). When the head is just emerging the leaf-sheath the smut-masses are covered with a thin me, but this membrane soon becomes ruptured and the asses are rapidly dissipated. The awns never develop. the dissipation of the spore-masses the naked central ■ bead is all that remains at harvest time, and even this ;ntlj broken off at its junction with the stem. The steins roduce smutted heads are frequently three to six inches D the normal ones, and consequently are easily THE TREATMENTS CARRIED OUT. rhe different kinds of seed treatment used were the following i The formalin steep. — Four different strengths of formalin ion were employed : Plat 2. 1 pint to 10 gallons water Plat 3. 1 pint to IS gallons water Plat 4. 1 pint to 211 gallons water Plat ."&gt;. 1 pint to 25 gallons water Ed to lie treated was placed in a coarse sack and sub - ged in the solution for ten minutes and then removed and wed to drain to remove the excess of the solution. It was Ei emptied in a heap and covered with wet sacks for two hours, r which it was spread out to dry. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">50 i lii Tin modified formalin xl I*. The seed nsed for 1' first soaked in coM water for four hours and then sei the wet sack for eight hours longer. At tin- end of tli was treated with formalin solution. 1 pint to ■"&gt;»; &lt;;all&lt; the same method as employed for the normal treatmei tin- normal treatment ici Tin hot-water treatment The seed used for PI given the common hot-water treatment in r&lt;dd water and set awav in the we to 130 1". for five minutes and th nil Ciirmsin siihlimnli xtiiii iusive sublimate were naed : Plat !'. 3 jiaits i oiT&lt;!si\ !■ snlilii l'lat 10, 14 parts corrosive suli The wed was snaked for tiftei i e i f 'upper xnljiliii were employed, tin while the second mav U- E'lat 11. The seed was mm 1*4 gallons of water i for 12 lo gallon*) for five minute: f. I'lat lli. The seed was soaked Eper solution il pound to 18 ed by the niinutes in lime w usual manner. I All of the seed treated was dried sufficient in ami prevent beating and was stored in s time of seedinj. irratKfement nf Test I'lul The treated seed was sown in twentieth h drills running north and south, and three check w;i* then warmed bj submerging in water ;it lltt ;: few minute*, after which it w;is immersed in then spread on1 i&lt;&gt; drj urt- plats will &gt;r control plai </seg>
            <seg id="p085">51 N 1 were used, tin- location of which is shown iu fc |-l-?l!Ji l 5 T. - X z &lt;• per cent of germination &lt;raa teaaeaed by all of the treat Fu;. 4 — Qu&amp;drat frame, enclosing one square yard, with I wires at regular intervals. nation was reduced to 40 per cent by formalin lid. anil to "•&gt; r cent by 1-15. The \ \&lt;n&gt;r of was also very milch sened. and the appearance of I'lat No. '2 was very poor when (mined on October 8, 1906. Not oaljr were the plants smaller I HI 11 12 13 Treatment I \nm Germination ami Vigor &lt;&gt;j Orotctk s ewployed except in tin- hot water treated seed wliiili cil a perfect &lt;;ei-iiii nation as runt lasted with !&gt;T \*-v eent for IDtrpated seed nse&lt;l in the check plats. The per rent &lt;&gt;t </seg>
            <seg id="p086">52 \ i i It the stand sliowed less thiin half the iiiiitilwr of plants in the other plats. The amount of seed used on the diflei its was made to accord as nearly ;is practical with the germ n per cent, m that the rate of seeding varied from two to f shels per acre. In order to determine to what extent the i seeding employed gave a uniform and equal stand in the di t plats, careful counts were made on October 8th. For purpose ■ qnftdrat frame i tig. 4 employed, and the figures given each plat. The following tahli records for germination, rate o enclosing one iqaan re the result of three will give the summ; seeding, number of id vield Tw V. 1 Untreated I Formalin 1 to 10 Formalin 1 to 15. Formalin 1 to 80. Formalin 1 to 25 Formalin &lt; modified Untreated * Hot water ■ Corrosive sublimate 3-1000 Corrosive sublimate 1 • 1000 CuSo, i normal i ■ Cu^o, (modified Untreated Che per cent of smut was detf number of smutted and tin rained for each plat by com matted heads in three com Flls running the entire length of each plat. The total num heads counted for each drill varied from 2£20 to :!.:!75. s believed that this method would give a much more aecnr iniate of the per cent of smut than either the staked quad the quadrat frame method, which are better adapted for •qua re yard, per ceni of sin </seg>
            <seg id="p087">53 1 &lt; r. 1 eld conditions. The average yield for the control bushels, while the yields for treated plats i 77.1'n luislu'ls. or an increase in yield per i IMat 2, in which the treatment injured The cent and rigor of growth, to 19.58 bushels in • the highest vitld. is employed were more effective in preventing the hail the naked smut. The relative efficiency is Table II noted from this table that both of the copper I d (Plata 11 and li'i were entirely effective in pre - vered smut, while the naked snmt was reduced to more than a half of one per cent. The formaliu t ployed for Plat ."&gt; il pint to i2."&gt; gallon*) was equally ve and entirely prevented the covered snint. while the per if naked smut was the least obtained in any of the phi i| MEXDATION8. he experiments show that barley smuts can be very greatly ened by the us&lt;" of the seed treatments employed. Of ihese itments there may be recommended, as ahovt equally effective: Formalin rteep, nsing 1 pint to 2Q-2S gallons of water The hot water treatment. The copper sulphate steep. win"; Ullilt f n^keil smut Per ct. covered smut. 30 iKi 1 f&gt;7 1 144 (I 95.6 M ii 100 (I !i7 'J 4 4 10.0 24.20 ii Ti't; 1 a 2 IH H 80 :f7.n 7.") ii laid 100.0 0.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">54 n THE MOLD OF MAPLE SYRUP. tin- work of E^achenhagea and Rruhne. stales that t per cent of grape »ugar for the growth of fungi lies betwi per cent lint that sonic fnn«;i can tolerate as hij;h a eent PmieHlimm glaucum, laperffillux niger and oth arc able to grow in solutions so concentrated thai their equivalent to -'is per cent sodium nitrate, or 4."i jmt eeni | nitrate, which inns! prodnce an osmotic preaaui ii equal n&gt; 157 at spheres. The idea is expressed thai fun&lt; "i"-' ■" ' ' 'I' 11 ""' ' ■■&lt;• iur« i" e\ pressed iimi Iiilij;i v witlistiiiid iso tonic tolationa of different non-toxic suIisimh BY r. l&gt;. HKAI.ll AM&gt; \l:M&gt; W. POOL. I\ THolH CTION. [luring 1 1n • |&gt;;im few vc;^s a mold has frequently be* growing upon various brands of maple syrup after the exposed in various container! to the air of the bonaebt weeks or more, and even in the original container amount of the syrup had been removed. The mold ?. r e pored to Ik- present iii pare culture and its alum apparent Qeculiaritie* of nutrition led to the followinj HISTORICAL. Thru the rest aii Ins &lt;it i:sehenha^eli. liruhne. and has been demons! rated that smne fungi are capable • in very concentrated solutions of neutral, toxic, or nut siam-es baring a high osmotic equivalent. Thiefe in in' the effect of concentration of medium upon the temper: iinuiii grew Pen ici Ilium on solutions containing per cent of grape BOgar, and on a medii xrataining : glycerin. Aaperfillus was growa on medium contain cent glucose or J.". per cent glycerin. I'fetl'er. 1 in re </seg>
            <seg id="p089">55 oncentrated solutions ■ matter «if turgor Raciborski* found tli;it Aapergillua glmmemt and a iilu could now nil saturated solutions of sodium i chloride, or cane sugar, while Torn hi sj&gt;. p«l unrated solution of lithium chloride. Concentra- had but littlt &gt; -* yrup mold upon maple syrup Natural Krowth of ivhile the cells were reduced in size and shortened. .l*/« it/iltnx how normal color in the more concentrated solutions I That some fBBg] are aide to tolerate a strong solution of a toxic siilistame is evident from the work of Uostrup.' According to this writer. I't iiirilliuin ijhnu inn and a Tuniln sjwcies were found v r iii«in^. r in a solution containing 14 per cent of copper sulphate. effect upon the color of Tomtm </seg>
            <seg id="p090">56 r \- DESCRIPTION I' THE Fl'XUl Ehe syrup mold ii]miii its natural substratum produce* a t htly powdery growth which either •preach quite unifoi Fig. 2. — Appearance of syrup mold on glued in agar ai •&gt; ;a plain agar slant eulturf over the surface or produces distinct h stellnte c-olonie*. Th hi' jonag giwvth is of a pah- brown color, turning; slightly dark with ape i fljr. 1 ). The spores ate spherical or sometimes sli-jlit elon«i;it&lt;'&lt;l. •_!&gt; micron* in diameter or 2.9 by 4 microns, and ai </seg>
            <seg id="p091">1 &lt;) i- r i ir r 1 D abundance from eJoagated club-shaped conidiophores it her dense tufts or acervuli. The spores are borne in •m the chains break up. upon mounting, into isolated ■d groapa of two, three or four. The root hvphae ei- Bg Mow the a.ervuli into the medium are septate and color while the ■aore-prodaciag branches and spores an of a k\ In-own cultures of the syrup mold were examined by Prof. C. H. md pronounced a new species of Toniln closely related to / xurrhun 1,,,-tix (Mid.. T from which it differs in the average nd color of the spores and the ultimate branchlets and in •sen, e of the delicate prickles. penes may appropriately lie named Tondm suclunina QBOWTH IN CULTUEBS. &gt;yrup mold was easily isolated from its natural growth maple syrup since in all of the earlier studies it was the nold present. For purposes of isolation, 3 per cent glucose I'M was employed and the first subcultures made showed he mold was unable to grow upon plain agar to any extent i. indicating that it was not able to use jieptone as a source bon. In this reaped it differs from many other fungi' grow well with peptone as the only source of carl..m. i&gt;tb cane sugar and grape sugar present the carbon in a tsily assimilable form. The growth upon some common ndicated in the following table: </seg>
            <seg id="p092">58 1 Medium. Culture. Temper Fine appear - ance of growt Eitent of growt atur.- Streak M None N Streak. I» N N Streak Few small wh ipore pn *% Gluooae agar - 10&gt; Streak la hocolate brown, tuml with abundant spore I lor J* Glucose agar ( + 10) Streak u ■w I a&lt; la wha m;orf 3% Glucose agar (+1 IS «■* Glj'cerln agar (+Wj Streak Potato Irish Potato ttwmt Piat L Tin- preference uf the Mold for *u ■howa in ihc altnvc table, risce only a slight growth . |&gt;l:iin ;i}r;ir at the ead of l!l davs. ami also sin.-,- the . mm li slower on gtyeerla mgue than nptw gtacoM agar ]MMuliarit.v was also shown 1&gt;\ th&lt;- quick germination dant growth on iweel potato, and the slow liatfted m Irish potato. The growth of the hngw was Blightlv retarded q the togai m.ilia l»y subject ing it to the teaperatwe of the laboratory re Mferatar (18 C). This would indicate thai ijTop would moid at refrigerator teaperatare, ami the experisaeota carried out show that such is the rase, only a retarding of the moldiii" takin" place. K'he fuii};us prodmes a characteristic growth in plate culture*, ■ superficial colonies are at first white, distinctly circular in line, later taming lirown with the formation of spores ami Eagar +■ »g»r(+10&gt; agar ■ »ln </seg>
            <seg id="p093">59 lecoming decidedly truncate pulvinate. They never increMe iii&gt;;iii\ in si/.f. varying from one-twelfth to one-eighth inch in The deep colonies i-cni;iin small and colorless i tig. 3) raster nf well developed figurex which repuwnt colonies is shown in the acconi sections of apt colonies. The network of hvphae. while compact, parallel hvphae which the colony exhibit* a liery shows a region of t ::. — Appearance of superficial ami deep colonies of the syrup mold. Glucose agar culture. III! iteh emls in the spore -producing brandies i tigs. 4 and ft) The gemination of the spores and the growth of the hvphae was ohnerred in pure hangingdrop cultures. The growth from a ■ingle spore is shown in figure t! from the Ix-ginning of gerinina tion to the formation of the first s|M»res. A much branched, spar - ingly septate mycelium is produced with chains of globular ■pore* RELATION OF GROWTH TO CONCENTBAT1ON oh" SUGAR. Bn order to determine the maximum concentration of sugar ich would permit the growth of the mold, a series of cultures </seg>
            <seg id="p094">60 4 Fio. 4. — Horizontal section of an agar plate colony Fig. 5.— Vertical section of an agar plate colony. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">61 7 ,&lt; I. V /- c ■^ 6. — Germination of spores and formation of hyphae from hanging - drop cultures. A. Early stages in germination. B. The growth from a single spore. S The original spore. SC. The first spore hain \v B \\ e^, </seg>
            <seg id="p096">62 f Biade usiiij; tin* normal Pasteur's solution, which contai iciit of caiic sujrai-. as a stock solution ami im-rcasin nun of sugar to obtain the differai eonceatratioos. Tli ini: forma la fur I'asteur's Bolotion was employed: Cane su«ar srams Ammoniiim tartrai firani;- -&lt;ium phosphati Calcium phosphatf .Magnesium sulpha Water (distilled i . The cultures were m tuf the medium wan eni|i cadi Itask was mailr li\ Eltc Culture to each It ■fciinii. The result ih I'&lt; Hicillium i&gt; riv&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p097">•/ y- first Annual Report. 63 1I«T * a h ay II. thin hi ' surfa h sma : days, w tiny 3 day mai: 7 :olonl RVV Mni.l rrnicillium. Flrat appear- Extent of growth ance. 8 day 24 hours. ■ ilays. rowth at bottom of flask and a few sur - face colonies. Surface coyered whh heavy folded green- ish growth Tday Surface colonies some - what larger. fairly nu- erous 7 days Colonies n ume rous, light brown scum over en - tire surface. 7 days 2 days I davs on Entire surfaoe covered Surface W Large, green, fo'ded rown with worm-like covered makeovers surface growth day I U»JB. n Surface covered with completely merged colon! days d urface covered. Colo nies larger. - 'lays « days Surface '. Surface covered with covered c re a my, somewhat wlththln folded maw. growth 6 days. Entire surface covered growth piled up t) days Entire surface covered Colonies separate slightly spreading s days 2 days 7 days. mies few- Mold covers entire sun Slight Growth whlte.sBOOtb - g rowth ly covering surface. Inth face; growth thin rown lution. :i days. float- Surface covered with rowth Growth white, sllght- slight, i y folded; micro - thin, scope showing bo white. spores. thin, spreading, light brown growth I days 6 days. 12 days. » dot- Entire surface covered G r o w t h No practlcaldlfference whit- with spreading light slight, from 6 days. slight, from c. .lays. brown growth !i days. white Entire surface dotted rface. with light brown colo- nies. Colonies flat. spreadlng. No growth. Colony used for Inoculation then placed in gl. agar tube Good growth In 7 days. 15 days. white Surface covered with light brown growth- Colonies tbln, spread- int. no depth. Eitent of growth. « days. 12 days. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">64 It may 1m- noted from the above table thai tin- gro ■yrnp mold ni slower Rod less prom&gt;unced in 1 of siijjiii- than in the higher concentrations, while tl nut completely inhibited until ■ concentration of &gt;' not completely inhibited until n concentration of Wl \h reached. The character &lt;&gt;f growth upon the ros leached. The eh;l rader of "l-owlh Upon the court-lit r:l I i&lt; Migar from 80-75 per cent simulates vert crawly i slljjar from (iO-7."&gt; per cent simulates \cr\ closely I In- jjro Hpontaneona molding and in the pare nil tare m spoiii;iuei&gt;us molding! and in the pare culture on which was parried mil for coinpuriMon. I'vnirUUu which was carried mil for com unisoti. / common booae mold, did not at all in 75 per common house mold, did not grow in any of the maple Kvrupti which wen- tested. The inhibition of growth l&gt;.\ Mil per &lt;-eni su^ar u i mold and by 7."&gt; per ceni for I'ctiiri Ilium is prol to the high oMiiotir value of the solution. The hv&lt; sure in the cell-Hap i»f the hyphae growing ii|m&gt;ii 7."i sure in the cell sap su^ar inusl 1m- equivalent in slij;hilv over •"&gt;&lt;• aim is known that 1'rnii-illiuni ijluHcum and some oil capable of growing in sol ui inns mi i-oncent rated th; Illivalelll lo 4.") |&gt;er i-ent |i&lt; il ;l &gt;si Mill IMllMlc tM|iii\alent to 4-~i pci res. hence the iullilii ar is pi'nl&gt;alil\ due t plien s. hence the inhibition of growth \\\ the hi^ Kiigar is probabh due io low per eent of water av than to the lii^li immotic value. In a series of cnltnre* in l*a«tenr'n k«»Iiii i tin to the high osmotic valu* I n a series of cult ures in 1' was sulistituteil for cane xngsii was substituted for i-aiie migar. the Tomla w all eoneeniratioiis from I.Vmi per cent. The mi pel all concentrations from l."isn pci allowed only a few scattered colonies to develop also that the inhibition of growth is not due i&lt;&gt; the of the aUgar. since glncoae has neailv double the of cane Mgar. In mder lo grow in (Ml per cen of cane ftugar. In order to grow in mi ii livphae would l&gt;e obliged to develop an internal osi hvphae would Ite obliged to develop an equal to inn aiuiosphere pqnal to loo atmosphere**. It was inipossilile to determine the optimiini It was impossible to determine the optimum Hiigttr conct nation for the growth of the syrup mold l&gt;y ocnla \ ocular oliscn ilone. An examination of the cultures indicated that th mum c enti-ation was between -tit and ."in per cent closer estimate could lie made. Tin- optimum concentration \\ </seg>
            <seg id="p099">•/ 65 series of cultures in Krleninever Hawks in will was removed it the fiiil of wren days, carefully I lie migar and then dried to constant weight determination given in tlie following tabk ' of i/mitth ltion 1 ;ir i-'ram: Solutii mar n.218 gram .11 ion " .^Kl gram ii :hi Solution 4" ;ar grams Of •I in ii in ition ir 0.2 Kram uar i' sram h —Growth of the syrup mold on Pasteur's solution '■training 4J per cent can«» sugar. II niav Ik- noted from lliis table that the greatest growth re - ed in the 48 per cent solution, while the culture attained a Her weight in 56 per cent of Mgmr than in l."&gt;. 25. Of •"{•") pet nt concentrations. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">EFFECT OF CONCENTRATION OK SUGAR ON SPORE SIX. Eriic concentration of sugar to which the Torula wa cultures in Pasteur's solution had little effect upon t her spores or hvphae. The following table gi\ i exp IV rlts from a large iiuiiiIkt Pasteur's Solution. cane sugar cane sugar cane sugar cane sugar. 75% cane sugar Canada sap results from a large number of measurements : of measurements Pasteur's Solutiov Hyphw • ane sugar "1 micron nicroi ••"&gt; microns 2.58 micror microns 2.58 microi ■ane sugar microns 2.58 mi ane sugar •ane sugar . ..3.H2 microns 2.58 micror M microns 2.58 microt M microi. nicror "ii micron microns 2.58 micror microns 2.58 micror cane sugar 'I, micron microi Canada sai mi EFFECT OF FORM )K NITROGEN ON GROW! A series of cultures was •arried out to test the form of nitrogen on the cfe aracter of the growth used also for lomparis titnted in l'astcui mold, and PeniciUium was lowing substances were sub&gt; tmionium tartrate: iKNO I jiotassiuin nitrate iinoiiiuni nitrate, ami iKcii potassium rblorid&lt; given in the appended table: N 28- C Strip Mol Media. First appearance. B ™£\ Variations in Pasteur's solution: 1. KNi ."&gt; days Euted for Surface dotted with 4 tar- small whitish eolo - :e. nies. No hang-. jw NH,NO B days. 8 day substituted Colonies light brown. Color does not^Growth for NH| surface coTered, di- become dark tartrate ameter '.^ of colonies brown trate solut on 30% P'asteur's so lution ■ KC1 6 days. 10 days 5 day Surface covered with Growth n-ry ThiriM-um o row thin » hite nontypical growth. thin The result shows that lsed to l tited extent as a source of nitrogen, but that it rer than ammonium tartrate. The growth in | iiiii-h ammonium nitrate can Id </seg>
            <seg id="p101">67 in nitrate TBUPB." AN A LI - determine whether the molding of the different (1 Ei of syrup was due to the low sugar content, a number of known commercial brands were obtained for analysis. e samples, which were in either tin or glass containers and (for 28 to 4."i cents each, have been given a sample number. manufacturer's name is recorded with the sample number he records but will not be repeated in this article. The unt of reducing sugars and sucrose in each sample was de - lined as recorded in the following table: 2&gt; C. Sample Reducing Sucrose in m i Time required for mold Number. su .^rs in m c(? Total sugar. to CO ver surface after 1(K ' inoculation. It may be seen from the above table that none of the syrups analyzed contained a sufficient sugar content to prevent the growth of the Torulo. but it may be noted that the samples which contained the highest total sugar molded more slowly. Some experiments were carried out to determine the effect of increasing the sugar content upon the molding. For example, by increasing the total sugar content of sample number 3 to 76 per cent by addition of cane sugar, the growth of the Torula was very nearly inhibited, only a very slight growth resulting. The nished by Dr. F. J. Alway I maple. . I maple i maple. i mapl' i maple. r maple. . . i maple. 1 mapi 2 32 7 io 4.04 - :«; i 38 1 74 13.61 57.36 59 !&gt;2 59 30 38 32 40.27 52.70 51 25 51 45 59 67.12 63 34 6fi (il 35 .vr.oe 55 99 65.06 11 days. 12 days. 15 days. 14 days (few colonies only 15 days. 12 days. 11 days. 11 days. 13 days. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">t Agricultural Experiment Station (if \ &lt; III Hsl, per ifiu of su&lt;;ai" which will prevent or inhibit the growth Tmiiln lies between 7."&gt; and Wl per cent isee table, \&gt;. S4| : Ih-i r i is evident thai tin* market articles should !&gt;»• made inon t (rated than is tin- cominoD practi&lt;*e. If the ivrupn are iiiciitl\ concentrate*! little t»r no growth nf uioM is liki (H-ciir KAII E!l Eipr.ifter I &gt;itwerta1 i Pf.-tl.i-: l'llaii/..n . Kaiiliuiski : I'.u \ 8. Naseli: l!..t. Mil 1 Ewhenluiijen : Kintius* d. l^munjien vci Srliiiiinu'l|iil/.c. lss!l i Lci|&gt;zi^ci- I&gt;i Kruline: Zopfw lii-iirn^tn /.. I'hvuiol. h. Mo Thiclc : hie T«'iiiiK*ratnriireiiZfii dn- Sih Mil 471. Ref. It.. i. &lt; »i. l{«isini|&gt; : Km. Titlsski 7. SjiicmiiIii : Kvlloije I'n !». I'f.llrl-: l'll;lli/.rli|.li </seg>
            <seg id="p103">7 69 A ROT OF GRAPES DUE TO PESTAL0ZZ1A VVICOLA SPEGAZ. P.Y V. A. WOLF.* l&gt;&lt;- (trap** that were broaght into the laborntorv at the Kxperinieni Station iti Heptcmher, 1 !m»7. were covered iiiiiIm rlcss l&gt;lack pustules protruding from the epidermis, •oscopic examination showed that the sports were those haracteri/.e the j;enus Peatalozzia of l'&lt; xtnliizziii have been descrilied as occin -riny; in tlie vineyards of France and [fair. 1 The one. tltniiii,iii Kpegax.. forms the larger, mote niiiner Its |&gt;ustults are irrejiulai- in sluip*- and the ciinei have two hairs, one arising from the vertex and the r pnwtnlfM and its fusifoim iiporea bear three haira The Nehraska Bperinena a^i-ee in size and character with /'&lt; xtiilit;;iu nr'nuhi Hpegax. No reronl has mi,,, In was tiisi reported in September, 1S77. hv heioff very dVati active among the vinevardi mar i. \elietia. Vim Thiiimi!. 1 who hist desirilx-d llns \ts the « hararteri/.ation as follows: "The s|.ore&gt; or mostly spindle sha|&gt;ed. tive celled: the three middh \e In-own, slightly constricted at the points of septa 1 -eiieially provided with gattae. Both end cells are as in other species of I', xttilutziu. and more or less coui- he len«rth of the spore is :{.") microns, the breadth siti mi At the basal end is a crooked hyaline stalk of uniform and Plant Dispas.&gt; Iliirean sit!*-. Th«* other, Pentaloxzut nriii&gt;ht Hmni lie |d-c\ 'ions occiirri-ih c uf t his s|K'&lt;ics in Atfiil «. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">70 thickness 25-30 microm long and 1 micron broad, while upper end are found three characteristic hairs or setae wh h a colorless. 8-10 microns in length and 1 micron in thickne In hanging drop-cultures, in which the medium was i ■gar with ■ reaction 10, these spores were found to germ readih and to produce hyphae from all the dark wh in the Bpecies on rotting rtrawberr known to germinate. Not onh was a single tube fm several from each cell seemed to In- more tvpical and of the intense rigor of the s| • r&lt; In order 1o detenu illations were made on two separate bunches of grap&lt; chambers. In one cat fungus wire used, and in th&lt; A sterile needle was used to puncture the grape inoculum thru the puncture into the interiot All the noticeable effect in t: A emlar depreasioat occurred at the points of inocu u time numerous pustules In in inoculated grapes. At the mil' tin veloped ill the pure culture of the fangUS 88 gTOWl w agar with the reaction lo. The only definite™ formation was that it was restricted t I it promiscuously over the hyphal surf;: l'ortions of grapes showing spore-producing pus bedded in paraffin. Sections of the pustules did not show tare as one would expert to tind in the Melanconiat &gt;\ ■ilozzia belongs. Mai hai pyenidia an lacking in this group. Von Tuoeuf shows Pettaioaszi4 ka 7 a prey of coniferous seedlings, as causing the epidermis ruptured, while from the flat surface beneath the rupturei le, dennis the conidia are borne. Frank thai the spot Pestulozzia are liberated thru the ostiole-like break it I epidermis, which is in accord with Von Tuheufs descri] tio. Shear 5 in his work on the of the oranbem describe! </seg>
            <seg id="p105">71 fora very similar to those already mentioned. None u a pvcnidial structure for Pestalozzin. </seg>
            <seg id="p106">72 /, Vrniil Ten u I real amoii Iii the section* of Pegtaiozzia urii-oki the true i ppidemial w:ills and expanding above them into a pseudo paiendn inn. A relatively narrow ostiole is led il Igore •*&gt;. yet in all we tind that a definite i-onceptacl l&gt;y the false tissue within which the spore* ale formed Since it is so evident that this is typically a true | forming fungus, we must slightly inodifv our vii its dassitication. Either it is not one of the 1/ else the generic description is m&gt;t adequate unit so as to include the range of types from th« which tile spores are formed beneittfa the epidi pseudo paremhvma. to the one which forms a w ell iletiin w iuin. The latter would s( KAI I Yam Tliiiiuen: l*ilae des VVein»t&lt;H-ke&gt; Massee: Text l»&lt;» k of Funyi. :: &lt; .C.. I! IX'on Tulx'uf and Smith: [Hnetlii Frank: Krankheiten der l'tlanzen. Shear: Mull. I'.ureau of I'lani ludu in KXI'I.WA T|o\ Fi}j. 1. Spores show inj; the ti\ Ii" liasal hyaline, and the upper hyaline with th&gt;« Pfajt. -. Spores which have germinated from h Phj. •'!. The middle cell alone has not germinated I tli three and the other with two hyphae. Fig. 4. All the dark cells have germinated. Fiil. 5. Showing the prcnidinm in sei tion. the of pseudo parenchyma, the remaining niter wall of epideru and the lar^e cells of grape tissue beneath tic was easilv &lt;iei istrated. Tilt- well detined pveiiidium pi ides t Ill-ll tilt- ruptured epidermis, porting up the mil pan-iicliMiiiiluus tissue thru which lhc spuics pit if &lt;tMM the pyraidia were laore tt;ii ami &lt;&gt;|«'ii than il iiiin. l lie latter would s« cm il&gt; |MM-Ii;i|»s Im- iMsit-st ;UTOiii|ilislic&lt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p107">73 I I 1 1 I A STRENGTH TEST OF HARNESS LEATHER V IJEORliE It HATBfHN. i usi. new. with ■ hame tnj;. attacked l&gt;y ami I keye. was placed in the testin&lt;; it |&gt;|&gt;1 i«^4l at the end of the hame ordinary buckle and ■ &lt;•&lt;&gt;&lt; lie anil force runt inuously H. and at the cockeye &lt;\ until the failure of the tag. which red by tearing the leather taroagh the luu-kle hole at ». \\&lt;&gt; lests were made, each of which failed in the same manner. rst Test HMiti pounds 14111) pounds Failure began l&gt;y teariag at Maximum loading attained .r..nd Test : Failure begaa at Maximum loading 1 inn pounds 157(1 pounds Vverain lt»."&gt;ii pounds 14S.1 pounds Beginning of failure Maximum loading . Since the tractive force necessar n earth road which is in fairly ounds per ton. four tuj;s of this iclnding the weight of the wagon jr to haul a loaded wairon on •rood condition is al&gt;out Hmi character would haul a load of ■ HO &gt;r with a factor of safety of ten. which is not any too large, the I | huh tag is capalile of safely aavHag o.04 — that is. practi allv t&gt; tons On a macadam road this load could \te doubled, and on a brick lavement i|uadrupled. Die results were ;is follows: = 59.4 tons </seg>
            <seg id="p108">74 LOCO WEED POISONING IN HORSES. BY A. T. PETERS AND L. B. STL'RDEVANT. INTRODUCTION In .Inlv. I'.mh;. the Department of Animal Pathology of iversity of Nebraska Im-j;mii an experiment with loco w soning in horaaa nt Imperial, Nearaaka. The work • •ried on with the cooperatioi of the Bsreaa of Plant Indiu the United states Department &lt;&gt;f Agriculture and with istancc also of the citizens of &lt;'has«' COUty, Nebraska. Dvighi .Marsh of the Itureau of Plant Industry had alre :un his investigations oa the loco weed early in 1905, at 1 1 « lorado. and was thus in a position to aid us very material Ei advice from time to time saved us without doubt fr ions mistakes For the animals used in the experin the use of tlie lair grounds at Imperial, we are w» to the Chase county citizens The thousands of dollars lost annualh western part of this state on account of loco weed pofe* in horses, cattle, and sheep was mflcieni reason for startii experiment. The sunnner of 1906 seemed to he a most opportm time for this research, since the ltureau of Plant Industry ha already begun investigations al&lt;m&gt;: this line, and we could pro! hj their past experience. SYMPTOMS AS HITHERTO DESCRIBED The symptoms of loco weed poisoning as described in 1901 1&gt; V. K. Chestnut and E. V. Wilcox in Hulletin No. L't; of th Department of Agriculture, Division of Botany, from which w take the liberty of quoting, were as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p109">75 be most characteristic are those of cerebral origiu. in peculiar irregularities in gait and action, which apared to a drunken condition in men. Sheep ami affected by this disease are commonly said to l&gt;e ■d. The cerebral disturbance may consist in an riurnit'iit of the function of the special senses, or in improperly ilated motor impulses which produce a more or less pro 1 im-oordiiiiitioii of muscular movement. Sight is fre- 1OI11K quently impaired. In some cases the animal soon becomes totally Mind. This condition is reached more often in acute cases than of loco disease. More frequently the animal incorrectly or makes errors in judgment of si objects. These errors in judgment of ocular pereep- ire a common occurrence and are often so pronounced as • •me ludicrous. A locoed horse upon l&gt;eing driven up to ■ may either attempt to jump over the crossbar, which is y placed at the height of about IT) feet, or may lower his usiia nun feat- of striking it. Simple experiments indicate that beep and horses in a locoed condition frequently mistake ■ss tilings for dangerous enemies. In horses which are &lt;1 with the chronic form of loco disease one has abundant unity to observe many peculiar and senseless actions which &gt; i dently due to cerebral disease. Locoed horses are often v both draft and driving purposes. Such horses may travel in a perfectly normal manner for days at a time. \V I &gt; I' k They frequently, however, run away or are attacked with kicking tits without any apparent external cause. &lt; &gt;l&gt;servations made SB 1,,.,-s. which are only slightly locoed indicate that they do at become frightened by purely imaginary objects. This t lines fright would seem, however, to be none the less real, since such ■ often tremble or become covered with a cold sweat after these imaginary daagen are passed. r-Tlie sense of hearing is frequently affected in locoed animals. is easily demonstrated by simple experiments. The response various sounds and noises is not alwavs in accordance with the </seg>
            <seg id="p110">76 character or volume of the sound. At times si n. I ■ in li 1«-&lt;1. while iit other tiim ;l slight noise of ill in lei- may produce fright. Tlie locoed animals ;ire often nii;ilili to judjre correctly the direction from which sounds nil Irregularities of the muscular movements of locoed hi may assume a variety of forms. The animal iua\ mil 1 its head in an extended or otherwise unnatural position. In whih he aichrd carriage of the hack is to be noticed with aw w ward movements of ihe le&lt;;s. Trembling is n fieuueii characteristic of the locoed animal. 'Phis niav lie contii the le^s. es|teciall.v to the klK r max him muscles, and occurs in a ui&lt; t pronounced nianni have experienced. fright which the animal ma observed of locoed horses that even when thev are al forward with conHidenible pi \ backing THE \&gt;Ai TIRF The pastures used and the laud all unbroken raw prairie. The most Imtc for feed wns Igiit/ttftim glaurum. since it jtrew in in many places. &gt;'&lt;•//&lt; tliutiiai tlux /until nhil nx and •ilii/oxtaili/iti were also very p lent if i oligoatmchgm were also \crv plentiful and mdil.t &lt; ffodnmim juihki was paten abnai :is readily ;;s tin- y was grow lag in large nnabrni twrywttere. t'hartwk I green foxtail) was pern occasioiiallv ;*?- was als&lt; was growing in large number* everym-hei t iilnihtiili x. One spccit s of Aristida w.i I uhiiloiilrx. (&gt;]]&lt;■ s|i&lt;ci&lt; s &lt;if Aiixtiilu was fairly alx not eaten after it had developed the ■■stirki-is." which t not eaten after ii had developed the -sti. w wished to avoid. Among the wreds not eaten bv the wished to avoid. Among the weed* not eai eiiiiiinonei- were I'snnil-u c-oilina, 1'xnrnhii arffophl/lla i Mifininitxa . and Hfiplopoppvn ttpinuloxuft, while A nth mi* we folia and Polygon urn ramoaiasinwm were not mixiiirfolifi and Polygon urn niinoxixxinuuii wct-e im s&lt;ilxo&lt;i tntftu i Htissian tliistlei was not ronimon Imt Sirlsoa tnii/iix i Russian thistlei was not common hul w fairly readily in the jjieen state. Attrngalwi inollix woolly loco weed) was fairly abundant over most of the i broken prairie. </seg>
            <seg id="p111">/ 77 .\ V) I I i I w hen t i hi'lil to ( i \ horse w r a few TEMPT TO INDUCT LOOO-EATIN(; HABIT ■intent wiis started on Jnl.v in. ISM, with tare* Kilpatrick Brothers' ranrli. located nine miles south ■rial. Tluse had Ih-cii shipped in from Wyoming winter ami were rather wild Imt supposed to I..- n. They were in fair Mesh. Three other horses wctc lose above mentioned and an effort was made to se horses to acquire the loco habit by running in a iere loco weed was rominon. e first the animals were corralled at night and then. morning, turned into the small pasture, whieh was Her lhan a jrood sized lot. containing two or three was with the hope that they would snap at the larger tiding the loco weed in order to ajairkly satisfv their «1 argeat pangs of hunger. This plan. howev. •e sueet ssful in cattle, where the inimeiise size of the nandfl a spaee tilling food l.tl&lt;linlixnii&lt;i jiiinrii i the It could Ik- noticed, how rush like Lifffodetmim) w;is nrlv morning than later in fairly large weed and tills than anv of the jjras- the personal equation is too large for us to haae al conclusions mi the feeding habits of a half-doarn I'his much, however, was plain, that when the - short, hunger will compel many hornet to eat this « Ii coiih'rins the ohservations of the ranchmen who slate habit is frequently formed in the early spring or late the pram is short. It is advisable to give a small graia horses turned mil to pasture too earlv or kept in it n the fall so that their extreme hunger will not lead ■at the loco weed. This custom is practiced l».v a few in the western part of the state and with goad results, ihich. by reason of the short jrrass. nibbles loco wed days, when transferred to good pistnre persists in the sidcr;il»lv oftff I in llic ( | &lt; !■ I &gt;;l I » I \ Iwciiusr it is ■ ii ilic same grazing linn </seg>
            <seg id="p112">78 h f th h. loco-eating habit ouly for the tirst day or part of it. If i pelled to eat loco for a longer tine, the habit persists loi and may become permanent as we shall show. A very wet will freqnently produce a large number of locoed aaimala da t entire summer, probably bee ulent then and they get int &gt;s is abundant at that time. mse the loco plant is unusi the toco-eating habit \ En July 28th we abandoned ng habit by corralling at n the following morninj the attempt to induci ight and turning the l&gt;egan "breaking" tli into the habit one at a time by shutting them up in the feeding them for a few da\ with the picked weed A.SE Of HORSE NO Forse No. 1 was a black ti ;en her hip by a fall on was now healed, so that being turned into the pi y. nearly two yen he ice the preceding w t did not interfere w litre when she was t: July 10, 1906. she snapped at a loco plant getting a mouthful of the weed, wb acquired the loco-eating habit, but only after into it. and is not further mentioned in this ex diil not die from the effects of the CASE OF HORSE N Horse No. 2 was a black gelding, about with a weak and lax fetlock joint on the left hind caused him considerable difficult v in using the piece of dried loco weed in the pasture on July 21st but did not ••at loco afterward until specially fed in the com I.OCO EAT1XO IIISTOUV OF HORSE SI Starting with No. 2 on July 28th. he was left in the eo and at 4 P. M. on the day following was fed five pound picked loco weed, which he ate readily. On July 30th and night following he ate 10 pounds of the picked weed, and on </seg>
            <seg id="p113">cntyfinst Annual Keport. 79 \ i : ii I Hi- was then turned into the small pasture when he was offend 2| pounds of picked weed vt'iv fresh and which he did not eat until P. M. Be was left in the corral over night, and da.v ate ti pounds of the weed in the forenoon and he afternoon, and was turned into the small pasture 1'. M. ( &gt;n August I'd he was corralled all day. eatii weed in the forenoon and ."&gt; pounds in the after- 1 iving about 1 pound uneaten. He was turned into the isture at night. On the 3d he was corralled all day and tied into the small pasture at night, eating 9 pounds of ked loco in the forenoon and 4 pounds in the afternoon. » &gt;n isi tth he was corralled all day and the night following. [g U pounds of loco. Four pounds more, which was a little was offered him at ti P. M. hut was left till the next day. it was washed to remove the dirt and was eaten during ie forenoon. During the afternoon of August 5th he ate ." muds of loco and was turned into the small pasture at I II. with access to 5 pounds more loco, which was all eaten the next morning. On August tith he ate 13 pounds more of loco during the forenoon and on being corralled ate most pounds placed there for another animal. He was turned the small pasture for the night and left there during the day wing, when he ate readily 5 pounds of loco in the forenoon ."i. 1 , in the afternoon. On August 8th. while still in the mall pasture, he ate 6 pounds of loco in the forenoon and ."&gt; "Hinds in the evening and the following morning. The total mount of picked loco weed eaten from July 2flth to August 8th (was Iltf pounds. During all this time the few loco ii ts growing in the small pasture had remained untouched. August !tth he was found waiting at the place where he Eilly received this loco ration and was driven out into the er pasture. On the way over he ate the first loco plant he e to. walked bv the second, ate the third, and then walked </seg>
            <seg id="p114">80 \ Kr several more without paying any attention ! time on lit- was fed with picked toco at ii ntci'va [•regularly bc&lt;-auw of the difficult just when it was wanted. We had n wav of mi accurately the amount of weed eaten 01 the prairie or it i fed. We alw hut weighed the picked weed w; to jrive all the horses on this experiment gram at freqw \als. sin,., there is very little nutritive ttle nutiit mate] and the horses which do not have ili«' loco and the horses which do no ive tin except when forced to by hunger. From August 8th to A iv. -pi when forced to l&gt;.\ hanger. From Kith, no picked loco m led. From An Kith, no picked loco was f d. Fron \ 13th elusive. 87 pounds of picked loco was elusive. 87 pounds of picked loco « was an average of about &lt;&gt;] poundi per .1 w as an average of ah to li 1 poanda per day. It wns impomil to li 1 pounds per da w; i-:iti&lt;m always the same, owinj; to the &lt;litl ration alwavs the same, on picked weed jusi when it was wanted and picked weed just when it was wanted and the furtht in keeping it fresh. These were overcome in keeping it fresh. These w&lt; the loco in water or sprinkling with wate w in the shade and covered with a wet clotl in the shade and covered with a w \ to September 16th he was herded on tin- pi to September 15th he was herded and received no picked and received no picked loco except 1 1 poo \c and 7th. From September 15th and 7th. From September 15th to 21rt pounds of picked loco, an average of 9 pounds of picked loco, an ivera September Ufitli he was fed in pounds of September I'Cith he was fed Id pound pounds, on the 28th 6 pounds, and ws pounds, on the 28th 6 pounds, and was foi ing of September 29th. The total amoai iag of September 29th. The total amon sinned by this hone was rji'i' pounds sinned by this horse was rjl'l' pounds. T eaten (•&gt;!' days before death occurred. eaten Cii' days before death occurred SYMPTOMS OF HOK« VMPTOM The symptoms exhibited by Horse No. i' a Tin. symptoms exhibited by Horse No. 2 as follows: On July Kith a diffuse swell as follows: On Julv Kith a diffuse s\\ im iiiiiiii the niasseter muscle was first noticed OB the masseter muscle was first noticed on the left lower jaw. The animal on this morning lower jaw. The animal on this morning tried rorral as tho after loco, pa tine nearly ev u </seg>
            <seg id="p115">81 nd walking five or six feet out of his way to On August 11th. wheu driven to the water id clear around it before drinking. He ate a little ftiuch was being saved for another animal, before •cd. He ate growing loco plants greedily. pM swelling was now i August 11th) on both sides of xlfiiding to the angle of the mouth on either side. Horse No. 2. showing the "hanging" head not s«i promineot. On August I'lie tilst I f swelling wa he swelling had disappeared. On August 14th the animal iidily in addition to that eaten he was offered picked loco twice i pounds of picked loco n e grazing. On August loth mt left most of it to go and look for the other horses. On \ugust Kith some enlargement of the lymphatic glands of the wit jaw was first noticed. This enlargement continued till the </seg>
            <seg id="p116">82 Igricultural Experiment station \ h time of Ins death. On this date lie circled clear aro water tank and hesitated before drinking. lit- \\a leak. At this time lie Ix-jran to show a more irritable dis] tlian formerly, biting at the other horses, ea] iallv when N the aorrel filly, happened in nibble at a pile of picked lo weed where he was eating. picket weed occasionally, he a when he saw her eatiag ai his allowed one of the larger In picked toco without resenting attendant went to drive him fright and trotted away in the eave drivi Ausp pil (M 1 ii t i f. wl 1 water lie Ii '1 and at the same time lifting his fore feet verv high a the characteristic loose knee action w carpal joint. water pail by first squealing and when the animal tried a second time to drink. A tived at the fair grounds toward evenin expecting a ration of picked loco but watered and when we left he whinnied to notice us and show interest whenever we cai • leased from this time on and the animal becan than before. He frequently wanted also to sto| where lie had Immmi fed with picked loco. Stu marked at this time also, the hone standing per many minutes at a lime. Despite tins stupidiM hibited signs of uneasiness, starting to walk many any object whatever in view, sometimes stopping times continuing to walk aimlessly in a straight the fence. A group of locoed animals will follow a straight line and follow a fence from corner to p down the other side for many minutes or even hon n in oi In Alrliii lie would wins returned i I jillc off N. On Augusi 22 No. - drovi ippearance of the eye« w;is tirst do </seg>
            <seg id="p117">83 tin the lirst time lie allowed one of the it at the same loco pile with him. On tK'inj: ih a rope be showed great excitement, the muscles of It i- and thigh quivered almonnaH.v and he struck out tnd wildly with his left fore leg. While trotting i fore and hind legs unusually high, flexion at the htened from in front while walking iii led gate, which bad to !«■ opened widely t&gt; now Ki thru, lie now ate every loco plant which he came across. lile drinking in the afternoon lie leaned forward against tin especially the right, very imuli ()n rorralling him at night he Kter tank, with his fort 1 feet lind their normal position. red at the place where he w is nsuallv fetl with loco weed. ihtr extreme. On Aogoal 'J4th be walked riiiht </seg>
            <seg id="p118">84 &lt; I &gt; of loco weed and then back t&lt;&gt; it again. This nervous or "an (•(induct of the animal increased from this time on. Tin would do one thing for awhile and then suddenly leave th start something else. It was the same way with his feeding in one place for a short time, then walking to mho a distance of twenty or thirty feet from the first in an way. On being driven to water be was very 1 X( some sacks of loco weed that had in front of the water lank and rapidlv w before them. Later be tried io climb over the pipe, « from the windmill to the water tank, lmt pm around to walk out from between the two. tin Aog would eat loco weed from one's hand. He answered of another horse in a near-by pasture and walked that animal was. He now walked (i frightened twice, once by some hoys who w frequently failed to show fright when expect it or on the other hand showed general he was frightened more often and I normal animal. On August 27th he a day. hastening from one plant to another. Once, wl the phalanges] joints of his left fore leg remained llexei half minute before he put any weight on ihei straightened them. The up-and-down motion of his head excessive while walking. He came up to the wrilei loco weed perhaps, and from this time on he became tarn ■ver. On August 20th all the animals drifted on a Ian of wild wheat grass and would not leave it until driven on* August 30th they left the wheat grass in the afternoon to for loco weed. On August Itlst he would tun us whistle. On September 1st he started for a sn ' JI1 Allans I _■ i Hi lit* wus 4'(iUstttiiTi ( \ I'll 1 1 it I tt Lt «t\V;i v t !&lt; &gt; ! n f li« for more than ;i couple &lt;&gt;f minm li.v a sunflower moving in the wind. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">85 i\ ,\ w • n the Ih i. |m Tliaps. in strike him, l&gt;ut the On September :&gt;d and thereafter, the horses woaM wheat gram and on being driven off would (&gt;ne of tliciu. however, toward the last. wheat uiass to look for loco. All of them Is slightly lower than normal homes and turd owh \ _' was by nature inclined to stumlde. hut this ten pparently nmch increased l&gt;\ the inrtuence of the also the case in the others. On September 4th he \injr down on the prairie in the afternoon, and on selv frightened lie arose at once, getting up like a hind lejjs tirst. The hind lejrs are apparently i the fore leys by the loco weed. i iber 5th the animals were driven under a huge white i ck letters on it. They never seemed to notice it at ,\ were driven under it several times taring the linns one of them would shy at the gate which • side hut that was all. Ilmse No. 2 &lt;&gt;n September water tank after drinking hut immediately returned ijiain. This was unusual hut constituted one of his nervousness. By this time there was prominently tendency t&lt;&gt; follow a road, a ditch, a railroad •. a buggy, or one of the other horses or even to a straight line for many rods on the prairie appar it reference to any particular end in view. In fol me lie would almost always go right bv an open ould persist in following a road or another horse inj; BtnhbomneM at times, it being a hard matter go in any other direction. At other times, however. d wander away, usually in search of loco, and remain I day. walking very slowly and standing still by turns. n with the other hones would agaii show the tendency t&lt;&gt; ii het them. The other animals from now on were less kindh </seg>
            <seg id="p120">1 I" 1 m 1. but 80 Agricultural Experiment station of At Xebrask disposed toward him. Occasionally he would show stnbboii also in wanting to remain out on the prairie when it was tin him to 1m' driven home. His tendency to stumble was mort iiounced at this time than ever. He would frequently fall t kniH-s. regaiaiag liis feet in a lively hut very awkward ma In crossing a railroad track or furrow he would raise hi&gt; slowly and very high. This was especially true of his fore &lt; &gt;n September 14th he was tirst obatmd to void hi without extruding the penis from the foreskin. Half ■ later the pemifl was extruded. At this time lie walked r a couple of pails of water and had to be driven !&gt;ack \&gt; when he drank a considerable quantity. He neighed buggy started away leaving him alone on the prairie. T day he came hack to tin- fair grounds of his own acCOT wn a&lt; E'ks at the angle of the mouth appeared to lie &gt; m this time on the head was rallied somew nally. On the Kith he came in answer w\ • n or eight rods. On beiac gi\ f ruing lie made an awkward lunge forward fore feet hut hacking off suddenly as douht he suddenly for the moment lost &lt; I the later stages of loco poisoning the animals frequently catch themselves from falling. Sometimes they do fall i 1 then follows the awkward, hard struggle to again gel ■ir feet. Most of their motions are "jerky." Kven when 1 ■ir hind feet, they bring them up suddenly and rather netimes almost to the belly. As an instance of this Ins control the muscles well, may be cited the almost con idency to understep or overstep especially with the fore e former results in stumbling, but the latter does not ■ animal much inconvenience. tOn September 17th the horse would not come when cat let ighed. altho not looking in our direction. He would n&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p121">87 rl n "11 h. mud top, I.at, hand ou this day Imt would back away, the muscles being at the MUM time distinctly risible iwa.v while cornered along the fence he acted as tho inili the latter. He seemed to be able to back up only le greatest difficulty. At the loco pile he raised and ex forward his left hind leg several times. This was perhaps symptom of nervousness. He was taken down by i to a patch of loco but wandered back in the p\V! an hour to the road leading by the fair grounds. 18th the muscles of the animal's legs quivered ntly whenever he was touched or driven. He neighed OB ig us. When confronted along the fence, he reared ap and ver backwards. Be apparently could not back up at all. niggled for a couple of seconds before regaining his feet, ind legs were up a little before the fore legs. He neighed at anie within twenty or thirty feet of one of the other bo ie liith of September while out on the prairie Oa this day etiis of the animal was extruded before urination. A rail lin passed within thirty yards of him but he didn't seem •ightened. only trotting away slowly for tifteen or twenn When the attendant stopped driving him for a while he clear around and went back in the opposite direction for e but soon commenced going one way and then another n of his nose (|uivered while drinking water. This •tom remained from this time on. The faeces beiag usualh and somewhat dry were now still darker than ever. On ng to ■ deep rut he looked down into it before attempting s. His weight was found to be 466 pounds on Septenilter On September 21st. while stepping off the scales down to L'round. a distance of L| feet, the horse fell into a near-by hole and floundered around for a couple of minutes, only ping to rest, and finally pushed himself out by meai tiind legs, getting up oa his fore legs a second afterward, r lie was startled by tlie sneezing of a bystander. He </seg>
            <seg id="p122">Agricultural Expi rim 88 V, freq«entlv would leave the circling around to it again in a small circle &lt;&gt;f per ha] feet in diameter. He rked Iris bead apward once sudd Init without any apparent can mn without any apparent cause. &lt; »n i une horse corner of tin- lot in which lit- was contim d. he walked coiner of the lot iii which lie was confined, lie \\ Iked where they were and stayed for several ninates. lie now where they w,!,. mid stayed tor ■event I minutes, lie now « almost constantly ami slowly, somet imes. however, stam almost eoiistantly and slowly, sometimes, however, stand teeth still for several minutes at a time. He caughi from fnllin&lt;; once. Several times he lifted his right li from falling oace. Several times he lifted his 1 I ■lowly for &lt;; or 7 inches. Be did the same thing again slowly for i; or 7 inches. He did the same thing ihe day lint tins time the aetioti was due probably to l h&lt;- dav lint this time the a m was iluf pro tation of a sunflower which was touching his foot. tation of a sunflower which was touching his foot. () leather 22d, he coaM not be induced to drink out of a tember _:M. he coaM not he induced to drink out of a n would walk right over it. He was scared Inn slight! would walk rijjlit over it. II u automobile. &lt; &gt;n this day for the lirst time we could automobile. Ob this day for the lirst time we could hands on him without his walking away. He was turn hands on him without his walking awav. He was iuiikm daring that afternoon to shift for himself and look for during that afternoon to shif ol the prairie, dace the Chase couaty fair had tesapon the prairie, since the Chase count v ii him of his qaarters. II.- was aot found next daj search. Perhaps he had wandered into some cornfield. found late in the afternoon of September 24th. seven mil found late in the afternoon of S home. l,\ the side of the railroad track. Alter being home. 1,\ the side of the railroad VI slowly and with dillieulty for half of the distance towar slowly and with difficulty for half he lialked and started to go around the driver and bad opposite direction. He was stoj,, H d with a whip and opposite direction. He was stopped \\ whirled around slowly to his right about a dozen tim circle on the same spot and then stood still with both circle on the same spot and then and hind le;.'s widely apart, the right from ih,. left. and hind le^-s widely apart, the righ U it was attempted to turn him about !&gt;y whipping it was attempted to turn him about by whipping his i reared up on his hind lejxs. striking out quickly with and fell, not attempting to rise at once. This 1; reared up on his hind legs, striking out imicklv with 1 and fell, not attempting to rise a unusual, as he always, heretofore, had tried to get tip unusual, as he always, heretofore, had tried ately upon falling. It was now late in the evening ni wafer was obtained from a neighboring firm house </seg>
            <seg id="p123">89 he water the animal was upon its feet. He out of the water pail when driven up to it but stop and drink out of the mud puddles on the I'd over one pail and upset it. Another pail of placed under liis nose and lifted until the ips. when he drank all right. The penis was No. 1 after leing frightened from in front while walking Thi hows the poor control over and near a corne \truded to urinate. He wa left on the prairie for the night, tired out and it was now dark. • same place the next morning. not drink when driven up to ght. lie nibbled at the handle pparentlv sniked at some _ to be completely tw.is found in verv nearly the t ember 25th. when he would water pail even in broad daylif li_ r c' of the pail mid a| </seg>
            <seg id="p124">90 \ 1 t I II he w 1 n v &gt; I in the water could be lifted t&lt;&gt; his lips, so he was driven to i farmhouse where he finally walked up lo a tank of w drank for a loag time, after hesitating at every new s sound, especial!? ai a mud puddle l&gt;\ ilie side of il The urine was voided without extruding the penis. Ob I me he wanted to stop L r iuj; was Fioagk to keep ivard liiimi' at the righi altho he knew the plai ne road straight ahead idling the fair grounds at evi Blag at seven oYI walk, hut in tin- wmii the animal over to the whipping his nose, win 1 did not attempt at &lt; inii eat eve|-\ weed, liur him on a slow walk. He did corner until we compelled e well. He would have fc if he had Imm-ii left to Inn k when we called to him direction to find us. h I'll we attempted II II ver back war lice to rise So tin I teed l&gt;y his nose and he began ea wevei . in a couple «&gt;f minutes later. Ill the forenoon uf September lllitl have escaped from the sin pa south of the pasture feme. He was all Boratehi barbed wire. He was driven I He had eaten verv little loco the night &lt; "I to the corral he took a mouthful This {.Mass was full of stickers and w animals. It waa of a grayish appears n&lt; it is hardly possible that the horse n especially after getting it into his m switch his tail much and was fairlv covered with flit picked loco was placed in the corral for him. He wo weed in his month, hegin rbewine it am) then walk ai hf was placed in the small | siill. with IicikI slijihth hanging carried it along in his mouth wh </seg>
            <seg id="p125">liuiiiiil Repoi t. 91 1 x i w ii. 1 I I hin lent w Eely sej standi ie same time, forgetting to chew after a mi u : in walk. The penis was nut extruded t"&gt; 1 i "instantly, the fore and hind legs both In-iug rt. the right from the left. This latter tend - with loco poisoning is noticed only late in the le would stop at the loco pile only long enough t" 1 the weed. Sometimes he would eat t lit- weed, hut ifti-r chewing for a time while walking, lie would kg and later drop the half-chewed mouthful, appar ■cident. or as tho he had forgotten it. never picking 1 dropped, continuing to walk all the time and return loco pile a minute later for another weed, only to go line performance, lie would turn to one side in order alking into the attendant. afternoon of the Sttk he walked along the fei would frequently stop, stand still for many minutes Mid shut his eyes. He would, however, open In - liis ears when we made a little noise. On this day he keel over backwards as he had done formerly on U-ing the head with a cap but would move his head or ahead, never backing up to get away. He would om one's hand only when cornered along the feme. ive or abnormal secretion was running from the ver onto his cheek. His hair was rougher than ever. cular day. as the horse switched his tail against could hear sparks, apparently electrical, the hair standing out erratically and part of it clinging to mber L'Tth he drank water only when it was lifted ■-. When a pail of water was p laced on the ground he would walk right over it. sometimes striking it by it h his feet. His fore feet and hind feet were rather orated, tin- right from the left, lioth while walking ng. This *hci\vs how much control over the limbs was </seg>
            <seg id="p126">A a ! lost, lie neighed at Keing us, but it was when we ta - -i .-. k to him. His stupor was such that many things failed his attention. There seemed to be nothing inherently wro uses. Weeds and dirt in his inane and scrati body showed tliat lie had been iluwn. On tin- 28th he would eat from our hands, lit- • stand still until a pail of water could be bronghi to h after we had finally succeeded in doing this, be drank He paid no attention to the sneezing of a man twent and oesophagus of the alimentary canal w&lt; frous membrane of the fundie portion of the stomach was erv dnrk. red color, and almost black in places. The stom I empty. A few bots were attached to its wall. Bots « r&gt; found in the duodennm for the tirst eight or ten inches, m these beinp attached to the wall. The sinnll intestine \ * The animal was now very much emaciated. His him plaeed rather far back ami widely apart while he va still. A little blood was dripping from his aoatrita eathing a hissing ■oand. His bom was swolli in had a «!«■&lt; i&lt;]&lt;«l droop laterally. The stradd leg! was si ill worse mi this day. both while standing „,, &lt;»n the morning &lt; &gt; f September 29th the animal in the corral, lie was lying "ii his left side, the standing angle with the body. No rigor moi exeept a very little in ..ne hind leg, altbo il this time. The liyht eye was half u|&gt;en ation was pronounced. His coal of hair \\;i- POST MOB &lt; »n pod lnorteni examination of this animal, the org rotation were found to be normal. The respiratory oi also normal, exeept for a small amount of an in the nares and some froth in the trachea. The inte tarbinated bones was greatly congested. The montl n Mill </seg>
            <seg id="p127">93 I i w a I l i w \ i I, Colored I in] ni innl reason. ( 1 1 li for a very large amount of yellowish, •rhtly frothy limi-us. Kxtcrnally on the olon, there were several placet where the &lt;■ enlarged. The contents of the great ami ipartenly normal. In the tirst half of the was found a large imiiiiIkt of small nemut&lt; The liver was normal. Tlie urinary The bladder contained I or .". mw argam mentioned so far were slightly lighter nal in postmortem examinations. The brain however, were both congested. A cherry-red. organized exudate was found in great abundance in ooe, i. e.. bet ween the dura mater and the vertebrae enclosing the neural canal, all along (ASK OF HORSE NO. s a sorrel yearling illy which had previoush hut had sufficiently recovered so that the R ere with bernit. She nibbled at loco weed on and again during the forenoon of the 24th pasture, btrt not in the late afternoon or '&gt;n IXO HISTORY OK 1IOII-I s few months TOtnger than Horse No. :! abort s niuch slower and lazier Imt not so much 1 1 «_r down in pasture. there had been picked by mistake a few |x&gt;unds xrti i&gt;liniless loi-o weed or crazy weed. i loco vetch i. This weed was tirst found four rial. It was deemed advisable to feed tli i and Horse No. ."! was selected, altho for no &gt;n being corralled at &lt;! o'clock in the evening t any of the Armgtthu Immherii and did not niulit which followed. On the next dav. how </seg>
            <seg id="p128">94 ii i n \ he at ten hiii": to \ r or •ix In ml I o'clock in the evening and was allowed to run at that hour. During; the next few (lavs sin- did not was driven over to when- another animal was eat lino. The latter, it was thought, would eat more of the other horses was there for company. Horse \&lt; to nibble at the pile of loeo Imt was driven awa\ times by the l&gt;i t i n jr of the other animal. The sain happened in the evening and again on the followh August llttli we received some more picked stem the corral at ."! o'clock in the afternoon and day she was fed witli this weed and ate. Imt no pounds of it. leaving main the weed at that season of ill w dry. &lt;&gt;n August 21st. before 6 o'clock in the afti which time she was taken oat of the corral and small pasture i. she had eaten f;i \ni()(iUux htinbirti upon being driv ral times. She returned to the w K! of the other horses eating picki ly be due to imitation. &lt; &gt;n An corral from 12 M. until i I'. M. and during ill readily 4 pouda of Armgmlhii lambc.-ti. On the to i-at picked loco at the same pile with Inn permitting it for the first time, and was corral She was left in the corral for the list of the da following and ate readily during this time !i pom Anif/allux lainbrrti. eating a plant from the hand of E', whom she followed about for a while as tho whil out of the corral, certainly not wanting either wai ce she had both. We were now out of \niqalhi 1 picked no more of it afterward since it ronld no in t. mi being N'ft in ili&lt;* corral, sin- air u jm m n&lt; 1 i Axti(i(j(ilux MoUisaimut). Ob the morning of Xagu i Anu/tilliix lamberti\. Hone No. 3 w </seg>
            <seg id="p129">95 y ,\ l'i we offered her, at '&gt; I'. M., .» pounds "f wuoll\ loco weed), which she . was otiered i pound* but 2 pounds n the following day. Bhe would now mds for the tirst time. On the -7th this horse ■ked loco, getting about 1 pound of it. She bow This was the last picked WOolV except 1 pound on September &lt;i. of Aragalhu lamberti eaten on August 14th was uduce the loco-eating habit. From August 2Ota • ive she was fed 21 pounds of steinless loco above On August -J."th she ate ."i pounds, on the 2tth Vu^u.st 20th, this animal received :i::j pounds »f up to the time of her death. September 9th, 11) dajl i veiv short and rapid etUH for loco i&gt;oisoning in be explained only on the ground that she tniount of loco in the pasture and possibly to the of her age, her small size, and possibly to her lazy disposition showed narked stupidity on August 27th. She would ; at quite a distance behind the other horses while on She would eat scarcely anything but would siand mites at a time witti eyes half closed and with ltlv. At such times she could 1m- aroused bv me loco, which she would eat from one's hand. ,vn accord she would l«'&lt;;in grafting on loco and ut in a half -minute or so would relapse again into her Utitude. Her other symptoms agreed in general with xhibited by the horse just described above, so that it will neeeMari to (tire them in detail. She always, however 1 more laziness and stupidity. lorning of August -&lt;&gt; slit- ate :'&gt;i poudi the 27th 1 poud of Aitrmgmlm* moUUsimtu r.li. receiviag 1 pwwd also on Bcpteaihcr •«tli. </seg>
            <seg id="p130">(Mi August :.".i the herd boj found her lying on the part way up with her fore l»^s under her body. II j;ct her ap even by whipping and by palling npw tail. At in A. M. sin- was ap ;iik1 grazing with tlu - ji«&gt;in&gt; from the front side of Iwth forefeet at the I fetlocks. Oa September 4. on walking into ;i te% 1-1)111 w ■he did not look iit tin-in closi-lv ttut walked alien feet very high and showing | r control over them. &lt; &gt;n 5th, while getting her onto a platform which wa above the ground, it wa lie a time, and plan- them on the raised place, aft « walked onto it all right. &lt; &gt;n Se) w 8 A. M., but down at noon. A man who hap tried in make her "el tin bv whipping her oi failed to do In only a few particulars animal differ from those of Horse X Eoiiiiiial ciivity ■bowed much congeal ■ slniiiac-li dill not show anv COngei M lining tin- cardiac portion i&gt;f t |&gt;}K'd off. The stomach and inicsi The stomach did not show anv coi of millet, which, however, the animal had lni-n us&lt; occasionally. Fotir specimens of Agcarig were fotim jejnnam as well as two tapeworm slight excess of mucus present in the tiist ti\ \ jejnnam. Externallv on the wider, longitudinal, ligamenton hand of the tttCW were two spots cadi an ind diameter, where the blood vessels were enlarged and engo Tin' spleen was blnisb-black in its middle third, its caudal end was bright red, while the other end was dark blue. Tin- spleen weighed about half si pound. Tin- other organs were like ih ,.f Horse No. 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p131">V 97 \ ( 1 Ii. 11 ID CASE OF HORSE NO. 4 ill. Horse No. 4. :i pot-bellied black yearling gelding Mr. Frank .MH'lain. was added to the experiment, was rather wild and had a noticeable tendency to rough places in the road. Me was a little older than either of the animals just described. His stumble greatly increased as the experiment pro- I 1 . M. on August LV&gt;th he was corralled and offered 1 i&gt;f picked Attngahu molli$*imu$ (woolly loco wn eing adhered to in hmakiag in this aniinal. He be - irly well and the weed was all eaten on the follow - when he ate 4 pounds more. In the afternoon of 26th ar 5:30 he was fed 11 pounds of loco, which he On August 27th all the animals were herded on 1 Xo. 4 ate a good deal of loco in the forenoon but ii the afternoon. Four pounds of picked loco was four of the horses in this experiment while in the corral day. The loco eating habit had now been formed b h received practically no more picked loco weed until d except 14 pounds on September tith and 7th. On Id we began feeding large amounts, since it seemed lat another month of grazing without additional feed- would not kill the animal. From October l\d to 14th n which latter date he died, he ate 11M&gt; pounds of . varying from 1 pound to 45 pounds per day, re- verage of nearly is pounds jK.-r day during this time. YMPTOMS or HORSE NO. 4 •n September 23d, on escaping from pasture at the fair tinds. he started on a swift walk down the usual road toward prairie where the loco grew, but stopj&gt;ed and came back hearing the neighing of one of the other horses, which he wered. From this time on until the time of his death, on EATING HI8TORY OF HORSE NO. 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p132">98 October 14. he showed practically all of the symptoms N«i. i'. with some nore pronounced symptoms whiel II.. specially mentioned. I He balked occasionally and could then lipping. He slaved vcr\ clow to anothe rciallv on on i-asion after having bees all dav. when he pressed so closely agail 11a lv agaiD sidi other animal as if afraid of li mu - at him. He lifted his led higher than horses in crossing the rails of the railroad tr more frequently, and fell as a result of this of i in 11. the other horses. In the f relioon .. I Uctobel I back until he stumbled and a Ee one trial to gel up. then did not t lltcs. After this rest he sun. riled ; u he started straight toward h inc. ( ii iich lav on the ground he balked, nt ahead slowly, lifting his feet l: step over them lmt not looking dowi ne to where the fence had been prev t lmt the posts, he cautiously preai one side for an instant as tbo fearing II there. On getting out into the opei ge pasture where Horse No. 1 was in in tho corral all dav. When the two in loudly and loag. He pressed close to tli thu afraid of losing her. When she won Id turn would tl\ POST MORTEM KXAMIXATIO Ehe post-mortem examination of Hot r»ns prartienlly identical with those sparent jelly like and organiied exu Xo. I revi horse No Tl down tin* road along tin- railroad Vpusli ajiainst him by acciil&lt;-nt. hi instant. late in tin- extra-dor </seg>
            <seg id="p133">99 I pa Shallenl lint was 1 ut havii mentioned be dorsal and em brighter, almost a dark gion. The dura mater in the cervical n serous ri 11 i«l. The stomacli was enormously ireed, ilie orgai with its contents weighing The mucous membrane of the cardiac portion pped off, while that in the faadic portion 1 ted, amounting; to an inflammation. The pyloric lained an exo ssive amount of mucus. This excess pned through the duodenuni. jejunum and the first ileiiin. tile last portion of this last organ containing eed. which was not found iu any amount in thi intestines. In the tirsi jart of the ileum there were estodea (dead when found i. These were unusually is. one of them measuring ;»o cm. Three specimens cad when found i were preaeni near the junction of with the ileum. irregularly over the small intestines and great smaller arteries were somewliat enlarged and jular patches, each from two to four square i contained practically no nematodes and was 1. appearing like normal colon contents. The full of loco weed, with a very slight i hea contained no froth. The pericardial fluid eased in amount and had a slight reddish ting*. ans llian those mentioned were all normal or in appearance CASK OF HORSE NO Horse Xo. .-.. a iwo year old liay jreldinjr iM-lonjjinjr to Mr. 0. lerger, was ahw added to the experiment at this time. turned to the owner on request September 16th with developed the loco-eating habit, and will not again l«' in this article. nl waa i&gt;f a Imrt' color in the Mcral. he dona] region, becoming clit'ii- </seg>
            <seg id="p134">100 ri If Wll 1 \ el-cd in, i I i ( 1 I it. and w ite readi I v l pound le all d Qgine t&lt;&gt; M OF HORSE NO I Horse No. &lt;i. :ui Iron-gray yearling gelding !»■ low. was adiliil to the experiment on July Utth s crippled with a broken bameraa on the left i ited badly and caused severe lameness. On ill ■ neck, below the inane, was a small tumor, not n. A s:'&lt;-oncl tumor was present between the • nose, jusi below the level of the eve. This ani o weed on Julv 23d only, when tl,. d th&lt; was practically gone. He was allowed to i date, since his crippled condition made to take him over to the large pasture a On August ilih we ]iul him in the cor picked loco weed, which he refused to corral that night. During the next da \\ {fairly readily i:;j ( pounds of picked I and the night following be ate v ml ■■eaten. on the '••th he was in the I the resi of the time in the small pa le or no grass. On August llitli lie •wed to run at large, when lie ate readi i weed placed in front of him. The nex ked loco placed before him. so he v w till pasture, where he liegan eating it at once. &lt; of the eight given him being left on the mor August 12th lie finished 8 pounds in the p n turned out to run at large in the evening owing while at large he ate 4 pounds of pick* August 14th he was missed in the afternoon evening of the next day as he was coming « ti field. He was offered loco, which he would n&lt; Ei put into the corral for the night, where he nds of the weed. On the Kith he ate about one rl but showed symptoms of colic, lying on hi </seg>
            <seg id="p135">rtill lead many horses to eat loco weed when th« it. especially in the early spring or in the late fall wet seasons when the grass is not short, probablv weed is then more succulent. A small grain mtion hort will usually lie sufficient to Weep the from forming the loco eating habit. After a horse has ■o for a time, this habit becomes permanent iu most permanently formed in Horse No. 2 after 1 is pounds ■d woolly loco weed [Attrmgmliu mollixximus) had been nd probably long before this time. This animal lived after the picked loco was first fed and consumed a 1 of :V2-2 pounds of this besides that eaten in pasture and on he prairie six pounds of picked Arm§mfhu Immkmrti istemless loco weed or crazy weed, also known as Colorado loco vetch) on August 14th was not sufficient to induce the loco habit in Horse No. :{. We began to feed her with this weed again on the 20th. The caused by the churning abool of the intestinal eoal listimilv beard. Hut littk pis was present, not enough ta ice noticeable distension of the al&gt;doinen. Tlie corral tpened toward evening, when he was gim water froTii a hut he did not. perhaps coald not. walk out alt ho the '-ate tied open all night. On the day following he drank mmm ■ in the morning luit could not in the evening, tying some thai night. lopsv of this animal on Aujjust 18th revealed niostlv | I|,S\ • lirst half and apparently corn leaves in the last half of - reat rolon. while ; xcess of imi.iis was found alonj: the colon, heath was due. in all probaliilitv. to colic induced i unusually large amount of corn havrs. to which the 1 1 was unaccustomed. tUM.MARY. LOCO-BATING HISTORY. ■o: </seg>
            <seg id="p136">102 ll md I x u ha i remai • ico-eating habit was this time permanently induced in •It after iM. 1 , pouds &lt;&gt;f picked ArofUvt kmherti imuda &lt;&gt;f picked woolly loco weed i ittrmgmttu mo id beta eaten. TIk' animal died lit days after the lii ccd had been fed, if we except the t&gt; pounds of iiilxrli on August 14th. After the loco-eating habit dnced in this animal, one pound only of picked wi ii-d was led. practically all being eaten while grazii prairie. I The loeocaiini: habit was perntanen d\ 5 ponnda of \atragalu* mollissitm \e da\ s. The total am on Ks animal was l'l'1 ', pounds. Th ;t of this was fed. KThe lirst indication pointing b loss of flesh. The animal I value. Iniw condition is the loco-eating habit. Tin at almost every opportunity. I'istinct irregular bw&lt; side of the lower jaw as well us mi the place behind Up. These swellings persist for ;i day or two and tinot enlargement of the lynphatic gland ■pace of the lower jow just in front of the throa mem. This condition persists. The quivering of the mi • specially of the limbs, together with inaccui movements of these, are 1m-si noticed when the h They can 1m- broaghj out very cleail.x by frighten in or teasin&lt;r the animal The usual habits of a normal horse are preserved t ■ble degree in this condition. Their nwmon for i ■stiff knee" ;ils(&gt; nptom of inn or less bilaterally symmetrical appeal nil times at irregular intervals bul \\ </seg>
            <seg id="p137">103 7 t probably unimpaired TWy will usually return after l;i\ or two when thev have wandered several miles from home. . show very plainly their love of company and their in - lislike of being alone. They exhibit signs of fright when- would hardly exped them and on the other hand they fail &gt; show these in many cases where they could l&gt;e reasonably \ locoed horse on being frightened while in a corner and trying away. This shows poor control over the fore legs and inability n looked for. In fractal they are more often and more severely frightened than would be the ease in a normal animal. We can - not agree with the opinion formerly held by some that a locoed animal becomes frightened at imaginary objects analogously with "ghosts" or "snakes' in the human subject. A locoed horse Kf. omes very tame as the condition progresses. Periods of </seg>
            <seg id="p138">104 Agricultural Erpt Stati // 1 id hin ta from f if one it stupor lasting for many minutes or evrn bears, wh mal stands perfectly still with eyes half dosed and place where lie docs not want ally slow. or. as it is sometimes interpreted, then lie will frequently run into things before no will soon righl himself when he is thus aroused from he will fr stupor. When feeding in a cert it. turning to the right and describing a snu again to the same place. Hi mistakt objects for loco weeds until a closer inspection closure many times A locoed horse exhibits manv gvmpton lar control. His walking is slow same time moving «p and down to an exaggera While standing still, his head hangs lower than is raises his feet slowly and very high in stepping ove his wav. Flexion seems to W more difficult tli Eere is an increasing tendency to stumble. The a ng down gets up like a cow on the hind legs first ■s are not so much affected in the horse. A slight t ■ feet to \h' placed too widely apart, especially th ! right from the left, is noticeable in the last s lease. The bone has occasionally to catch himself ile merely standing still. He cannot back up but in^. are intemipted temporarily by aimless walking ;il other nervous, "uneasy" net ions. The irritable ilisji Kt displayed when the animal is with other horei ■ must in evidence when lie is led or driven re where lie does not want t&lt;&gt; go. A locoed hone is 1 nist;ik&lt;\ In liis dreamlike Btnpidity also he forgets I It' lies. He will blindly and pven stubbornly follow a f( &gt;r another hone, or go ahead in a straight line foi tance witlmui any apparent end in view. A fir&lt;ni]i nf "locoea" in a corral will frequently f&lt;&gt; rtlc and follow the feace from corner to corner an </seg>
            <seg id="p139">105 n i liel path i i I n 1 t rns of respn turhinated ' handlers, and neral condit ppearing norm ntestllies extel ii an ociasii will rear up and fall over backwards. instead &lt;&gt;f rearing up this way he will simply when anyone tries to make him back up by |is will quiver exceaaiyely while the horse ippean BOBCwhai glassy from an • arise in late stages of the condition is voided xtrusion of the penis, which is sometimes extruded a MORTEM EXAMINATIONS. new finding! of the Uepartment of Agriculture l at SogO, Colorado, were continued by us. &lt; ««n - ilogy of loco weed poiaoning. I when found dead were lying on the left it right angles with the body as they are when ling. The alidomeu was nut so soon distended n the hone. There was ao rigor mortis rery little in one hind leg. The hair was wry uinial in evert caae was verv greatly emaciated. t of ainlMT colored fluid was coming from the was a sei-o sangiiinous exudate of the mucous nasal chanilters. particularly that covering the The eye next to the ground was closed, the half open. rculation were normal. The heart was urn- 1 weight and the valves were all cnmitetent. A of the pericardia] fluid could l&gt;e noted. The ration were also normal except for congestion of Imuics. with the exudate mentioned in the perhaps a slight excess of pleural fluid. The &gt;n of the abdominal cavity was good, the organs lal or slightly pale. Here and there, along the nally. or on the parietal peritoneum, might be traal small, slightly congested patch. The ali- </seg>
            <seg id="p140">i i 1M Agricultural Experiment station &lt;&gt;\ .\&lt;iin iiientarv canal was normal ;is far ;is the stomach. \\ luti lining coat of the cardiac itortion of tin- mucous menil could 1«' easily stripped off, the fundic i&gt;r second pori very badly congested amounting to an inflammatory p and the priori c or third portion of the organ was rover a fery jjreat excess of mucus coining do doubt from gestion of the fnii&lt;lus. Tliis excess of mucus, ultho not i was found all along the remainder of the alimentary i was tiiiiinl all along i hi- remainder of tin- uliiuentai were also many bota which had conie from the stoma Horse So. :'. ili&lt;l not show the congestion Inn the liniu Horse No. :', iliil not show tin cardiac portion could lie easily snippe cardiac portion could be easih stripped off. The diseasi animal ran an acute course, which perhaps explains thi animal ran an acute com h wcr&lt;- present in the stomach but many of then were were present in the stomacl nit ma from i he wall and man.v more were found loose in the ii from the wall and maiiv moi 1 1&lt; Were foun contents. The stomach contests. The stomach contents were very small in nts \vt V( except in the case of Horse N&lt;&gt;. 4. where the organ was em •x&lt;( pt in the case of Ho &lt; A here tl distended liv loco weed, the StOU distended liy loco weed, the stomach with its contents ' pounds. The contents looked normal save for il ■js 1 , pounds. The coin, excess uf mucus. excess uf mucus. The intestinal contents appeared ii" The intestinal contents ap|* mucus. In the case uf Horse Nn. 2 the mucus was pi mucus. In the case of Ilortu N the small intestines in a veiv excessive amount, there l&gt; tlie small intestines in a ver\ x or no other intestinal contents. In character this ruu or no other intestinal conten tenacious, yellowish white and slighth frothy. The gligl tenacious, yellowish white and slight of munis persisted thrnoul the large and small colons of mucus persist! d thruoul th lai rt'ctuni. hut the contents were otherwise normal. rectum, but the contents wei .t The spleen in one case was normal, in another i The spleen ill one case w nun greenish cast, and in still another. Horse No. :!. it wa greenish cast, and in still another, lloi No red in its posterior third, bluish-black in its middle. red in its posterior third, bluish blacl Ihmiij; dark Idue. The kidneys were not ii were also the other abdominal organ The greatest change of all was not n the nervous This showed much congestion thruout. The extra-dura 1 of the spinal canal was distended very greatlv liv a trans] </seg>
            <seg id="p141">n I'll Hi. -i nerv Illl i mi. Mini vei lie ilnt re than which was atguiaed, hariag ■ cherry-red tinv Mood vessels riinnin&lt;: thru it in iiu-roti exud ite extended t«&gt; the foramen magnum either periosteum or dura lint clung cut to their origin, since it ran thru ami at between the anterior and posterior nerve mil was thus held in place 1&gt;\ these. It was at the cervical region. In this region the \ deep red. In-coming much lighter, almost ill region, while in the luinhar rejiion it was a buff color or an oranjrepink. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>