<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Great Formulas and Standardization</title>
               <date value="1924-11">1924-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">£yy^ [tC*U </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Classificciion of Ice Cream 3 FORMULAS Plain or Philadelphia Ice Cream French Neapolitan Ice Cream Simple Flavors — Custards — Vanilla 5 Custard Using Flour 9 Caramel 5 Custard Using Cornstarch 9 Maple 5 Coffee 5 Parfaits — Chocolate 6 Walnut 9 Custard Flavor 6 Vanilla 9 Malted Milk 6 Strawberry 10 Fruit Ice Cream — Puddings — Berry 6 Nesselrode 10 Tutti-Frutti 6 English Plum 10 Cherry 7 Fruit 10 Pineapple 7 Manhattan 11 Orange or Lemon 7 Peach or Apricot : 7 Fancy Ice Cream Banana 7 Mousse — Strawberry .: 11 Nut Ice Cream — Maple 11 Black or English Walnut 8 Pistachio or Almond 8 Bisque— Maple or Caramel Nut 8 Macaroon 12 Filbert, Pecan or Peanut 8 Maple or Caramel 12 Peanut Butter 8 French Fruit Salad 12 Sherbets and Ices Fancy Sherbets — Commercial Sherbet — °™ n 8 e 12 Lemon 14 Pineapple 13 Commercial Sherbet — Pineapple 13 Grape or Loganberry 13 Ices and Punches— Souffles— ruffi.es— Lemon 14 Pineapple 13 Lacto Pineapple Ice 15 Grape 14 Fruit Punch 15 Standardization of Ice Cream Mixes 15 Methods lg Table for determining the butterfat factor of milk and cream 22 Helpful Suggestions 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization BY H. P. DAVIS. P. A. DOWNS AND BENJAMIN MASUROVSKY ICE cream is the name ordinarily used to designate a variety of frozen products most of which contain cream or milk. In common usage, therefore, the term ice cream is applied to almost any frozen dessert. The federal pure food regulations and the state food laws or regulations usually define ice cream as a frozen product containing cream, sugar, flavoring, and a stabilizer. Frozen products commonly are classified according to the ingredients or the method of manufacture or both. CLASSIFICATION OF ICE CREAM I. PLAIN ICE CREAM This product is made of creams of different richness, sugar, flavor, and with or without a stabilizer. Eggs are seldom used and the materials are not cooked. Pasteurization of the in - gredients is not considered as cooking. Plain ice cream is sometimes called Philadelphia or New York ice cream, of which the following are common kinds : Simple Flavors: Vanilla, chocolate, caramel, coffee, mint, maple, etc. Fruit: Strawberry, pineapple, cherry, raspberry, etc. The fruits used may be fresh, canned, or preserved. Nut: Walnut, almond, pistachio, peanut, etc. II. FRENCH OR NEAPOLITAN ICE CREAM Such ice cream is made from cream, sugar, eggs, flavor, and usually a stabilizer. The ingredients are made into a custard, which is commonly cooked and cooled before being put into the freezer. In other words, it is a frozen custard. As French ice creams freeze with little whipping, a smaller swell or overrun is obtained than in plain ice cream. Neapolitan is considered by some manufacturers to be a frozen custard The authors desire to express their appreciation of the assistance given by Mr. E. O. Anderson and Mr. E. L. Reichart of the Department of Dairy Husbandry. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 203 packed in brick form with layers of different flavors. The varieties belonging to this group are : Custard: A simple custard usually flavored with vanilla. Par fait: A heavy custard that has the beaten whites of eggs added just before freezing. Pudding: A heavy custard usually highly flavored with candied fruits, nuts, spices, etc. III. FANCY ICE CREAMS This class includes various combinations of frozen desserts. Mousse: Frozen whipped cream sweetened and flavored. Bisque: Mixture of egg yolks, whipped cream, sugar, and flavors. Sometimes a bisque ice cream is made by incorporat - ing macaroons, marshmallows, or sponge cake in plain ice cream. Glace: Whipped cream, egg whites, sugar, and flavor IV. SHERBETS AND ICES Ices are made from water, sugar, flavor, and with or with - out a stabilizer. Sherbets differ from ices in that they are made of milk and in addition may contain whites of eggs. Sherbet: Composed of skim or whole milk, sugar, flavor, stabilizer, and egg whites. Souffle: A milk sherbet in which the yolks of eggs are in - cluded. Lacto: A frozen, flavored sour milk. Commercial Sherbet: Composed of half skim milk and water, sugar, flavor, and stabilizer. Ices or Punches: A frozen mixture of water, sugar, and flavor. Granites are frozen with little agitation and frappes are semi-solid. FORMULAS There are innumerable recipes for making the various frozen products. Those included are typical of the different kinds and are recommended. Many factories add vanilla to all mixes, using it as a base for other flavors. It is under - stood that in all these formulas the quantities of extracts, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 5 flavors, nuts, fruits, etc., depend upon many things. Un - fortunately all extracts and flavors are not of the same strength so that the ice cream maker will have to depend up - on his own judgment as to the exact quantities required. In the use of fruits and nuts there is also a great variation in individual tastes, which must be considered. A vanilla mix used for ice cream of other flavors should not be colored. Salt is often added to bring out the flavor of ice cream. The usual quantity is one half teaspoon for five gallons of mix. Flavors and colors are usually added to the mix just before freezing. Fruits, nuts, macaroons, etc., are commonly added to the partly frozen cream either just before the ice cream is drawn from the freezer or stirred in just after removal. I. PLAIN OR PHILADELPHIA ICE CREAM The mixes of plain ice cream will be discussed in some de - tail under methods of standardization. The following for - mulas are based upon 10 gallons of finished ice cream when approximately 100 per cent overrun is obtained. The un - flavored or basic mix can be made up of various ingredients and of different percentages of fat, sugar, and other solids. Select a suitable basic mix and to that make the additions necessary for the other kinds of ice cream. See section on standardization. ■See Circular 22, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. a mi Vanilla Unflavored or basic mix Vanilla extract 5 to 5 Mi gallons (45-50 lbs.) 1 to 4 oz. as desired Caramel Vanilla mix Caramel flavor Color 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) 2 to 4 ounces as desired Maple Vanilla mix Maple flavor Color 5 to 5Vz gallons (45-50 lbs.) 1 to 3 ounces as desired Coffee Vanilla mix Coffee extract ' Color 5 to 5 M. gallons (45-50 lbs.) 4 to 8 ounces as desired </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 203 6 Chocolate Vanilla mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Chocolate syrup 1 or paste to taste or from 2 to 4 quarts or 2 lbs. of milk chocolate shaved and stirred into frozen ice cream. Usually a fruit ice cream is made by the addition of fruit and either an extract or a flavor, or both, to a basic mix either just before or just after freezing. Various combinations of fruit may be used and several recipes are suggested below: Berry Strawberry, Raspberry, Loganberry, Blackberry, etc. Vanilla or unflavored mix Crushed berries (cold pack if 5 to 5V4 gallons (45-50 lbs.) possible) 1 to 2 quarts Fruit flavor none to 4 ounces none to Vi ounce as desired Citric acid — 50 % solution Color If fresh fruit is used, omit the acid. The flavor, extract, color, and citric acid should be added during freezing. Fresh berries should be prepared and allowed to stand after sugaring until all the sugar is dis - solved. Berries should be added either just before or just after draw- Tutti-Frutti Vanilla mix 5 to 5 Ms gallons (45-50 lbs.) Chopped maraschino cherries 1 quart Orange and pineapple pieces Strawberries (cold pack) 1 quart 1 quart Nuts may be added — English walnuts, chopped fine 1 to 2 pounds Tutti-frutti flavor 2 to 4 ounces Rum flavor^ if desired Color if desired Mix the fruits and stir in the chopped nuts. Add the mixture either just before or just after drawing. ■See Circular 22. Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. 'Artificial flavor. Custard Flavor 'anilla mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs. 'ustard flavor 1 to 3 ounces Malted Milk ' anilla mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs. falted milk (powdered) 3 pounds (Add malted milk just before drawing from freezer.) </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 7 Cherry Vanilla or unflavored mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Cherries — chopped maraschino or V 1 to 2 quarts Cherries preserved Cherry flavor 1 to 3 ounces 1 to 3 ounces Citric acid — 50 % solution none to 1 ounce with preserved cherries Color— red as desired Add fruit and flavor as described under berry ice creams. Pineapple Vanilla or unflavored mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Preserved pineapple |l to 2 quarts or Crushed pineapple Citric acid — 50 % solution none to 1 ounce Color — yellow as desired Add fruit and flavor as described. Orange or Lemon Vanilla or unflavored mix Extract of lemon or orange 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) 1% to 2 ounces Emulsion of lemon or orange to taste Color — yellow if desire if desired Peach or Apricot Vanilla or unflavored mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Dried fruit soaked and chopped 5 lbs. or Canned fruit chopped 2 quarts or Fresh fruit mashed 4 quarts of peaches or 2 quarts of apricots Extract 1 to 2 ounces Color if desired Fresh fruit should be cut fine and mixed with sugar and allowed to stand for several hours. Dried fruit should be soaked overnight in just enough water to cover fruit and then chopped fine before adding to the ice cream. Add as described. Banana Vanilla or unflavored mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) 4 to 6 lbs. or about 2 to 3 dozen Banana pulp rubbed into sugar bananas Banana flavor Color if desired 1 to 2 ounces Peel bananas and grind the banana fruit pulp in meat chopper or similar device. Mix well with about two pounds of sugar. Add to ice cream immediately after drawing. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NUT ICE CREAM Other nuts may be substituted in place of those mentioned if desired. Black Walnut or English Walnut Vanilla mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Black walnut meats chopped 1 to 2 pounds or English walnut meats chopped 1 to 2 pounds Walnut flavor, either black or English 2 to 3 ounces The nuts can be chopped fine by grinding the nut meats in a meat chopper. Add to the ice cream mix just after removing it from the freezer. Pistachio or Almond Vanilla mix I to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Pistachio nuts or almonds (blanched and chopped fine) 1 lb. Pistachio flavor or almond flavor I to 5 ounces Color — light green for pistachio Maple Nut or Caramel Nut Vanilla mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) English walnuts or other nuts chopped fine 1 to 2 lbs. Maple or caramel flavor 1 to 3 ounces Filbert, Pecan, or Peanut Vanilla mix 5 to 5Vi gallons (45-50 lbs.) 1-2 lbs. Filberts or pecans — peanuts blanched — chopped fine Peanut Butter Vanilla mix Peanut butter 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) 4 to 6 lbs. Warm peanut butter and add to batch in freezer. II. FRENCH OR NEAPOLITAN ICE CREAM (cooked) No basic recipes can be given for this class of ice cream, as various materials are used. There are many variations but only a few of the better recipes are given. The high cost of this type of ice cream generally limits its manufacture to special occasions. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 9 CUSTARDS Custard Using Flour Milk 26.87 lbs.— 12% quarts Cream — 30% 5.23 lbs. — 2% quarts Eggs 2 dozen Sugar 6.25 lbs. Flour 4 ounces — 16 tablespoons Vanilla 2 to 4 ounces Heat the milk in a double boiler or steam kettle. Moisten the flour with a little cold milk and work into a paste without lumps. When the milk is hot add the flour and stir until it begins to thicken. Beat the eggs and sugar together until light and add them to the hot milk. Cook 10 to 15 minutes or until it thickens. Cream— 25% 40 lbs. — 4.75 gallons Eggs 8 dozen Sugar 12 lbs. Vanilla 2 to 4 ounces Walnut — English walnuts chopped fine 4 pounds Separate the egg yolks and beat until smooth. Add sugar and ber.t again. Then add to the cream and cook in a double boiler or steani kettle at 180° F. for 15 minutes. Cool, add the balance of the mix except the egg whites, and freeze. Just before freezing is completed add the beaten egg whites. Eggs 8 dozen Vanilla 4 ounces Add the sugar to the separated yolks after they have been well beaten. Beat this mixture until the sugar is dissolved. Beat the whites until stiff and stir into the yolks and sugar. Mix with the cream and cook in double boiler or steam kettle at a temperature of 180° F. for 15 minutes. Cool to 40° F., add vanilla, and freeze. Vanilla Parfait Cream — 20% 40 lbs. — 4.75 gallons Sugar 10 lbs. Custard Using Cornstarch Milk 32.25 lbs.— 15 quarts Sugar 7.50 lbs. Eggs 5 dozen Cornstarch 7.5 ounces — 30 tablespoons Vanilla 2 to 4 ounces Other flavors such as chocolate, coffee, and strawberry may be sui stituted for vanilla. PARFAITS Walnut Parfait </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Strawberry Parfait Cream— 28% 40 lbs.— 4.75 gallons Eggs 8 dozen Strawberries — cold pack 2 quarts or fresh Vanilla 2 to 4 ounces Beat the whole eggs together, add to mix, cook as above, and freeze; or the whites may be beaten separately if desired and added after the mix is frozen. PUDDINGS Puddings are heavy custards, highly flavored with the addition of fruits or other materials. The cost makes the manufacture of these impracticable except for special purposes. Ne88elrode Pudding Cook the egg yolks with the cream. Beat the whites and add when partly frozen. English Plum Pudding Ground cloves 1 tablespoon Cook the egg yolks with the cream and add the beaten whites when partly frozen. Fruit Pudding Cream — 25% 32 lbs. — 3.75 gallons Whole condensed milk (sweetened) 8 lbs. Sugar 8 lbs. Gelatine dissolved in part of 8 lbs. cream 5 ounces Chopped cherries 2 lbs. Chopped raisins 2 lbs. Flavor delicately with rum or sherry flavor. 1 Cook egg yolks, cream, and sugar as described above. ■Artificial flavors. .ream — 28 % tegs English walnuts — chopped line bandied cherries chopped bandied fruits chopped 32 lbs.— 3.f 10 lbs. 10 dozen 4 lbs. 3 lbs. 3 lbs. 4 lbs. a a. _ a _. 8 gal Ions Cream— 25% Cocoa or chocolate Chopped fruits that do not pulp Chopped seeded raisins Chopped dates Chopped walnut meats Ground cinnamon Ground ginger 32 lbs,— 3.8 gall 8 dozen 12 lbs. 3 lbs. 5 lbs. 2 lbs. 3 lbs. 4 lbs. 4 tablespoons 1 tablespoon lions </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Mousse — A mousse is flavored and sweetened whipped cream frozen without agitation. The cream used must be of such richness as to whip readily and stiff enough to allow the addition of the flavoring material without destroying the body. The overrun will be much less than in plain ice cream. Typical examples are given below. Strawberry Mousse Cream — 40% 33.2 lbs. — 4 gallons Strawberry juice 1.5 gallons Sugar 8 lbs. Gelatine 4 ounces. Mix the sugar and gelatine dry, dissolve in a small amount of boil - ing water, and add to the fruit juice. Chill and stir the mixture as it begins to thicken. Whip the cream until stiff and stir it carefully or fold it into the fruit juice. Place in molds or other containers and set in the freezing room to harden. Maple Mousse Cream — 40% 49.8 lbs.— 6 gallons Sugar . 8 lbs. Gelatine 4 ounces Maple flavor 1 to 3 ounces Mix gelatine dry with sugar, add just enough water to wet sugar and heat until gelatine has dissolved. Whip cream until stiff and add slowly to the cooled sugar syrup. Flavor and harden as directed above. Bisque — This type of ice cream consists of adding to any of the different vanilla mixes some form of bread or cake products. Those most commonly used are macaroons, broken lady fingers, sponge cake, sugar wafers, grape nuts, or similar material. While the bisque is generally made by adding one of the above materials to a Neapolitan or French ice cream mix, it can be made with the uncooked mix which should have a fairly high percentage of fat in it. The addition of Manhattan Pudding Cream — 30% 25.11 lbs. — 3 gallons Orange juice 2 quarts Lemon juice 1 pint Chopped walnut meats 4 lbs. Chopped pecan meats 4 lbs. Chopped cherries and assorted fruits 4 lbs. Cook egg yolks, cream, and sugar as described above. III. FANCY ICE CREAMS </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 203 12 approximately 5 pounds of any of the bread products or 2 pounds of grape nuts is generally sufficient. Macaroon Bisque Vanilla mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Almond macaroons chopped or ground 5 lbs. Almond flavor to taste Custard flavor 1 to 3 ounces The macaroons may be added to the ice cream mix either in the freezer or after the cream is drawn from the freezer. When other bread products are used the almond flavor may be omitted. Shredded cocoanut may be added if desired. Maple or Caramel Bisque Vanilla mix 5 to 5% gallons (45-50 lbs.) Grape nuts 2 lbs. Maple or caramel flavor 1 to 4 ounces The grape nuts are added either just before or just after the ice cream is removed from the freezer. French Fruit Salad Cream — 40% 8 lbs. Mayonnaise dressing 1% pints Canned pears 1 quart Canned peaches 1 quart Canned apricots 1" quart Maraschino cherries 1 quart Vinegar to taste Whip cream until stiff and add slowly to mixture of fruits. Fresh fruit may be used if desired. Put in molds and harden as above. This recipe makes 3 gallons. IV. SHERBETS AND ICES Fancy Sherbets — For sherbets the formulas as given under commercial sherbets may be used, substituting milk for the water. Either skim or whole milk may be used, depending on the type of product desired. Ee beaten whites of 2 dozen eggs when added to the partially frozen improves the quality of the product, and if used, the amount of is reduced to 4 ounces. Orange Sherbet lilk 51.6 lbs.— 6 gallons •range juice 6 quarts or 'rushed orange and pineapple pieces 2 quarts Mtric acid — £0% solution 8 to 12 ounces (range extract 3 to 6 ounces iugar 20 lbs. lum (vegetable) 8 ounces </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 13 Milk 51.6 lbs. — 6 gallons Grape or loganberry juice 2 quarts Sugar 20 lbs. Grape or loganberry extract (true fruit) 6 ounces Gum (vegetable) 8 ounces Egg whites may be used as directed above. Other fruits and flavors may be used in these formulas. Cold pack fruits such as strawberries, apricots, and peaches can be used in place of fresh fruit. Souffle — A souffle is a milk sherbet in which the whole egg is used without cooking. Pineapple Souffle Milk 51.6 lbs.— 6 gallons Pineapple (canned and grated) 1 gallon Sugar 12.0 lbs. Eggs 10 dozen Gum (vegetable) 4 to 6 ounces Beat the egg yolks and part of the sugar to a creamy consistency. Add this to the milk. Dissolve the gum by heating in a small amount of milk and mix with the rest. Add the pineapple and freeze. When partly frozen add the beaten whites. Any fruit or combination of fruits can be used in place of pineapple. Lacto* — The original formulas for lacto contained eggs but today eggs are commonly omitted. Various flavors such as cherry, orange, and mint may be substituted for the flavor given below. The amount of sugar will have to be varied to suit the fruit used. The lacto milk is simply a good starter, such as is used in butter or cheese making. Either whole or skim milk starter may be used. •Iowa Station Bulletin No. 140. Ptneappl &gt;le Sherbet Uilk Sugar jemon juice or Citric acid — 50% solution Crushed pineapple Sum (vegetable) Egg whites may be used as above Prepare as with orange sherbet. 51.6 lbs. — 6 gallon; 20 lbs. 1 quart 6 ounces 2 quarts 8 ounces Grape or Logi tanberry Sherbet </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Mix in the order named and freeze as usual. Pineapple, loganberry, or other fruits can be used in making other kinds of lacto. Commercial Sherbet — This sherbet is made of half skim milk and water, sugar, flavor, and stabilizer. For a stabilizer usually a vegetable gum is used. The following is a repre - sentative formula of the common commercial sherbets placed on the market. Lemon Sherbet Skim milk Water 30 lbs. — 3.5 gallons 30 lbs. — 3.75 gallons 20 lbs. Citric acid — 50% solution Lemon extract 10 to 16 ounces 4 to 6 ounces 8 ounces Gum (vegetable) Ices and Punches — Ice or punch is simply frozen water which has been sweetened and flavored. The punches differ from the ices in that they are flavored more like a punch with rum, wine flavors,' or spices. These frozen products do not stand well unless a stabilizer is used to keep them from crys - tallizing. For a stabilizer either gelatine or one of the many preparations on the market can be used. If gelatine is used it may be added to the mixture and allowed to jelly before be - ing frozen. The formula given for lemon may be used for any fruit flavor by the addition of fruit or suitable flavors and citric acid. •ape Lacto Lacto milk (starter) Sugar Gum (vegetable) Grape juice Lemon juice 51.6 lbs. — 6 gallons 20 lbs. 6 to 8 ounces 2 quarts 3 pints Lemon Ice Water Water 50.04 lbs.— 6 gallons Sugar . 20 lbs. Gelatine 4 ounces Lemon juice 4 quarts or Water 66.72 lbs. — 8 gallons Sugar 27 lbs. Citric acid — 50% solution 8 ounces Salt Vi ounce Lemon extract 3 ounces Dissolve gelatine and sugar in water by heating. Allow to cool pref- erably overnight and freeze, adding lemon juice when partly frozen. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Uniformity is essential in the manufacture of any food pro - duct. High quality establishes the reputation of the product, and uniformity maintains it. In a product composed of ingredients which vary in com - position, uniformity is essential. Business reasons dictate that the quality of a product should be maintained at as low a cost as possible. The Federal Government has regulations re - garding the ingredients that may be used in ice cream, and most of the states have either regulations or laws governing the percentage of butterfat, — several have requirements gov - erning total solids and quantity of stabilizer. For all these reasons it is essential that the manufacturer know how to control the composition of the mix, which requires standard - ization. Milk, cream, and other dairy products require the greatest attention in standardization because the minimum butterfat requirement of any state must be complied with. Standardization is based on the mathematical principle of alligation. This may be denned as a rule relating to the solu - tion of problems concerning the compounding or mixing of different ingredients or ingredients of different qualities or values. The rule is named from the method of connecting to - gether the terms by certain ligature-like signs. Alligation is of ■Artificial flavors. Pineapple lee Water 50.04 lbs. — 6 gallons Sugar 20 lbs. Lemon juice 1 quart Grated pineapple 2 quarts Gelatine 4 ounces or Water 66.7 lbs. — 8 gallons Sugar 26 lbs. Grated pineapple 2 quarts Citric acid — 50% solution 4 to 5 ounces Pineapple extract 2 to 3 ounces Fruit Punch Water 50.04 lbs. — 6 gallons Sugar 20 lbs. Lemon juice 1 pint Orange juice 1 quart Grape juice 1 quart Gelatine 4 ounces Rum or claret flavor 1 to taste. Prepare as for lemon. STANDARDIZATION OF ICE CREAM MIXE </seg>
            <seg id="p016">two kinds, medial and alternate; the medial, teaching the method of finding the price or quality of a mixture of several simple ingredients whose prices and qualities are known; the alternate, teaching the amount of each of several simple in - fredients, whose prices or qualities are known, which will be required to make a mixture of given price or quality. METHODS OF STANDARDIZATION In dairy practice the principles of alligation are applied to problems by means of a square, called from its author Pear - son's* square. At first it was used to standardize dairy pro - ducts for butterfat and total solids. Later, however, various modifications of this method have been devised. Since there is a great variety of dairy products which go to make up the ice cream mix, it becomes essential to devise a method which will facilitate the standardization of any ice cream mix. For this purpose the specialization method has been found satis - factory. The principles underlying this method are illus - trated in the following problems. Specialization Method — The object of this method is to divide the ingredients into two groups, one of which includes Kthe dairy products and the other the remaining ingre- Problem I Prepare an ice cream mix of the following composition: 14% butter - fat, 13% sugar, 36.5% total solids, 9% milk solids-not-fat (serum sol - ids), 0.5% gelatine, and 0.5% vanilla. Given: Cream testing 35% butterfat; skim milk containing 9% milk solids-not-fat; powdered skim milk containing 95% milk solids-not-fat; gelatine; pure cane or beet sugar, containing approximately 100% sol - ids; vanilla. Solution — Step I. Determine the quantity of non-dairy ingredients which enter 100 lbs. of mix — (10% gal.) Sugar 13 lbs. Gelatine 0.5 lb. Vanilla 0.5 lb. Total 14.0 lbs. Step II. Calculate the composition of the dairy portion of the 100 lb. mix. 1. 100 lbs. (total weight of mix) — 14 lbs. (weight of non-dairy in - gredients) = 86 lbs. (weight of dairy products in mix). •R. A. Pe»rson. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 17 2. Determine the butterfat factor for 35% cream, or the pounds of 35% cream necessary to ftwnish 1 lb. of butterfat. 3. Determine the quantity of 35% cream necessary to furnish 14 lbs. of butterfat. of mix. 4. Determine the quantity of skim milk and skim milk powder to be added to the cream to furnish 86 lbs. of dairy products in the mix. 5. Determine the milk solids-not-fat contained in 40.04 lbs. of 35% cream. a. Cream being considered as a mixture of skim milk and butter - fat, therefore: 40.04 lbs. of cream — 14 lbs. of fat = 26.04 lbs. of skim milk in the cream. b. Skim milk contains 9% of milk solids-not-fat, consequently: 26.04 lbs. of skim milk x 0.09 = 2.34 lbs. of milk solids-not-fat con - tained in the skim milk of the cream. 6. Calculate the quantity of milk solids-not-fat to be supplied by the skim milk and the skim milk powder. Since 9% or 9 lbs. of milk solids-not-fat is required, according to the formula, therefore: 7. Using 45.96 lbs. of skim milk and skim milk powder as determined in Step 4, calculate the average percentage of milk solids-not-fat neces - sary to supply 6.66 lbs. of milk solids-not-fat. 8. Standardize the skim milk and skim milk powder using Pearson's square method in order to determine the proportions of skim milk and skim milk powder to be used in a mixture of the same testing 14.48% milk solids-not-fat. Subtract diagonally the smaller from the greater. Skim milk 80.52 parts of skim Skim milk pow - der (milk solids 95%) 5.48 parts of skim milk powder 86.00 total parts •See table on pmge 22. 100-^35 = 2.86 (the butterfat factor).* 14 X 2.86 = 40.04 lbs. of 35% cream to furnish the butterfat for 100 lbs. 86—40.04 = 45.96 lbs. 9—2.34 = 6.66 lbs. 6.66 X 100 ' = 14.48 % 45.96 (milk solids 9% ) milk </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 203 9. To obtain the relative proportion of skim milk to skim milk powder, divide 80.52 by 5.48 = 14.69. The proportion, therefore, is 14.69 parts of skim milk to 1 part of skim milk powder. In other words, there is a total number of parts of 10. 'Determine the pounds of skim milk and skim milk powder, re- spectively, in the 45.96 lbs. (See Step 4.) a. 45.96-h15.69 = 2.93 lbs. for each part. b. Since the skim milk bears 14.69 parts of the proportion, there - fore: c. Since the skim milk powder bears one part of the proportion, therefore : Step III. Tabulate the mix as follows: Quantity Ingredients Sugar Butter- Milk Solids Total fat not fat Solids lbs. lbs. lbs. lbs. 40.04 lbs. 35% cream 14.00 2.34 16.34 Dairy [ 43.03 lbs. skim milk. Ingre- i [43.03 X .09 (9%)] 3.87 3.87 dients | 2.93 lbs. skim powder [ [2.93 X. 95 (95%)] 2.78 2.78 13.00 lbs. sugar.... Dairy 0.50 lb. gelatine... dients { 0.50 lb. vanilla. 13.00 13.00 .50 100.00 lbs. mix 13.00 14.00 8.99 36.49 Problem II. It is required to prepare 100 lbs. of mix of the following composition: 14% butter fat 11% milk solids-not-fat 13% sugar 38.5% total solids 0.5% gelatine 0.5% vanilla Given: Cream testing 25% butterfat; sweetened condensed skim milk containing 30% solids-not-fat and 40% sugar; gelatine, vanilla and Solution. — Step I. Determine the amount of non-dairy ingredients which enter per 100 lbs. of ice cream mix. Gelatine 0.5 lb. Sugar 13 lbs. Vanilla 0.5 lbs. Total 14.0 lbs. •Using the straight proportion we obtain: 80.52 parts of skim milk: 86 total parts : : X parts of skim milk is to 45.96 of total parts desired. lbs. of skim milk=2.93 lbs. of skim milk powder. 14.69 + 1 = 15.69 2.93x14.69 = 43.03 lbs. of skim milk. 2.93 X 1 = 2.93 lbs. of skim milk, Therefore, X = 80.52X45.96=43,08 lbs. of skim milk, and 45.96 lbs. — 43.03 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 19 Step II. Calculate the composition of the dairy part of 100 pounds ice cream mix. 1. 100—14 = 86 lbs. 2. Determine the butterfat factor for 25% cream. In other words, the pounds of 25% cream necessary to furnish one pound of butterfat. 2. Determine the butterfat factor for 25% cream. Ii tunds of 25% cream necessary to furnish one pound 100 --25 = 4. 3. Compute the quantity of 25% cream necessary to furnish 14 lbs. of butterfat. 3. Compute the quantity of 25% cream necessary butterfat. 14x4 = 56 lbs. of 25% cream will provide the required amount of 14x4 = 56 lbs. of 25% cream will provide the reqi butterfat for every 100 lbs. of mi butterfat for every 100 lbs. of mix. 4. Determine the amount of solids-not-fat contained in 56 lbs. of 25% cream : 4. Determine the amount of solids-not-fat contained earn: a. 56 — 14 = 42 lbs. of skim milk. b. 42 X. 09 = 3.78 lba. of solids-not-fat. 5. Calculate the amount of milk solids-not-fat to be supplied by the sweetened condensed milk. 5. Calculate the amount of milk solids-not-fat to b veetened condensed milk. Since 11% or 11 lbs. of milk solids-not-fat is reqi Since 11% or 11 lbs. of milk solids-not-fat is required in this mix, therefore : leref ore : 11—3.78=7.22 lbs. solids-not-fat. 6. Compute the amount of sweetened condensed skim milk required to furnish 7.22 lbs. of milk solids-not-fat. 6. Compute the amount of sweetened condensed si furnish 7.22 lbs. of milk solids-not-fat. a. Determine the milk solids-not-fat factor for i. densed skim milk. In other words, the pounds densed skim milk to furnish one pound of ir a. Determine the milk solids-not-fat factor for the sweetened con - densed skim milk. In other words, the pounds of sweetened con - densed skim milk to furnish one pound of milk solids-not-fat: 100 -h 30 = 3.33 b. 7.22 x 3.33 =: 24.04 lbs. of sweetened condensed skim milk. 7. Calculate the amount of sugar present in 24.04 pounds of sweetened b. 7.22x3.33 -.- 24.04 lbs. of sweetened condensed 7. Calculate the amount of sugar present in 24.04 pa condensed skim milk. mdensed skim milk. 24.04 X. 40 = 9.61 lbs. of sugar. Step III. How much cane sugar is it necessary to i Step III. How much cane sugar is it necessary to add to this mix to comply with the set requirements? imply with the set requirements? 13. — 9.61 = 3.39 lbs. of cane sugar. Step IV. Tabulate the mix as follows: Quantity Ingredients Sugar Butter- I Step IV. Tabulate the mix as follows: Quantity Ingredients Sugar Butter- Milk Solids- Total fat not-fat Solids fat lbs. lbs. lbs. lbs. lbs. lbs. Dairy f 56 lbs. 25% cream 14.00 Ingre- ■! 24.04 lbs. sweetened dients [ cond. skim milk 9.61 Dairy f 56 lbs. 25% cream 14.00 3.78 17.78 Ingre- \ 24.04 lbs. sweetened dients I cond. skim milk 9.61 7.22 16.83 Non- f3.39 lbs. sugar 3.39 3.39 Dairy \ 0.5 lb. gelatine 0.50 Ingredients ( 0.5 lb. vanilla Non- [3.39 lbs. sugar 3.39 Dairy j 0.5 lb. gelatine 0.50 [ngredients | 0.5 lb. vanilla "84.43 lbs. mix 13.00 14.00 Step V. Determine the quantity of water necessary 84.43 lbs. mix 13.00 14.00 11.00 38.50 Step V. Determine the quantity of water necessary to dilute the con - densed sweetened skim and to make up every 100 lbs. of ice cream mix. ansed sweetened skim and to make up every 100 lbs. 100 — 84.43 = 15.57 lbs. of water. Problem III Prepare an ice cream mix of the following composition: 14% butter - fat, 13% sugar, 9.5% milk solids-not-fat, 37% total solids, 0.5% gel - atine and 0.5% vanilla. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 203 Given: Cream testing 20% butterfat; condensed skim milk contain - ing 277c milk solids-not-fat; gelatine, sugar and vanilla. Solution — Step I. Determine the amount of non-dairy ingredients which enter per 100 lbs. of ice cream mix. Sugar 13. lbs. Gelatine 0.5 lb. Vanilla 0.5 lb. Total 14.0 lbs. Step II. Calculate the composition of the dairy part of 100 lbs. ice cream mix. 2. Determine the butterfat factor for 20% cream; in other words the pounds of 20% cream necessary to furnish one pound of butterfat. 3. Compute the quantity of 20% cream necessary to furnish 14 lbs. of butterfat. 14x5 — 70 lbs. of 20% cream will provide the required amount of butterfat for every 100 lbs. of mix. 4. Determine the amount of solids-not-fat contained in 70 lbs. of 20% cream. a. 70 — 14 = 56 lbs. of skim milk in the cream. b. 56x.09= 5.04 lbs. of solids-not-fat. 5. Calculate the amount of solids-not-fat to be supplied by the con - densed skim milk. 6. Compute the amount of condensed skim milk required to furnish 4.46 lbs. of solids-not-fat. a. Determine the solids-not-fat factor for the condensed skim milk. In other words, the pounds of condensed skim milk to furnish one pound of milk solids-not-fat. Step III. Tabulate the mix as follows: Quantity Ingredients Sugar Butter- Milk Solids- Total fat not-fat Solids lbs. lbs. lbs. lbs. Dairy f 70.0 lbs. 20% cream 14.00 5.04 19.04 Ingre- \ 16.5 lbs. condensed dients I skim milk 4.46 4.46 Non 13.0 lbs. sugar 13.00 13.00 Dairy \ 0.51b. gelatine 0.50 4.46 4.46 13.00 0.50 Ingre- \ 0.5 lbs. vanilla dients 100.5 lbs. mix 13.00 14.00 9.5 37.00 Problem IV Prepare an ice cream mix of the following composition: 14% butter - fat, 13% sugar, 0.5 gelatine, 10% milk solids-not-fat, 37.5% total solids, and 0.5% vanilla. 1. 100—14 = 86 lbs. 100-:- 20 = 5 9.50 — 5.04 = 4.46 lbs. of solids-not-fat. 100-^27 = 3.7 b. 4.46x3.7 = 16.5 lbs. of condensed skim milk. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 21 Given: Unsalted butter containing 84% butterfat; powdered skim milk testing 95% solids; sugar, gelatine, vanilla, and water. Solution — Step I. Determine the amount of non-dairy ingredients (ex- cluding the water) which enter per 100 lbs. of mix. Sugar 13 lbs. Gelatine 0.5 lb. Vanilla 0.5 lb. Total 14.0 lbs. Step II. Calculate the composition of the dairy part of 100 lbs. ice cream mix diluted with the water. 2. Determine the butterfat factor for the unsalted butter; in other words, the pounds of unsalted butter necessary to furnish 1 lb. of butter - fat. 100-^84 = 1.19, the butterfat factor or the pounds of unsalted butter needed to furnish 1 lb. of butterfat. 3. Calculate the quantity of unsalted butter necessary to furnish 14 lbs. of butterfat. 4. Compute the amount of powdered skim milk necessary to furnish 10 lbs. of solids-not-fat. a. Determine the solids-not-fat factor for the powdered skim milk; in other words, the pounds of powdered skim milk necessary to furnish one pound of milk solids-not-fat. b. 10x1.05 = 10.5 lbs. of powdered skim milk which will provide the required amount of milk solids-not-fat. Step III. How much water is required to make up 100 lbs. of this ice cream mix? 1. 16.66 lbs. of butter 10.50 lbs. of powdered skim milk 13.00 lbs. of sugar 0.50 lb. of gelatine 0.50 lb. vanilla 41.16 lbs. Step IV. Tabulate the mix as calculated. Quantity Ingredients Sugar Butter- Milk Solids- Total fat not-fat Solids lbs. lbs. lbs. lbs. Dairy f 16.66 lbs. butter 14.00 14.00 Ingred- \ 10.50 lbs. powdered ients skim milk 10.00 10.00 f 13.00 lbs. sugar 13.00 13.00 Non- 0.501b. gelatine 0.50 Dairy i 0.50 lb. vanilla 0.50 1b. vanilla Ingredi- \ 58.84 lbs. water ents [ 100.00 lbs. mix 13.00 14.00 10.00 37.50 1. 100—14 = 86 lbs. (including the water). 14x1.19 = 16.66 lbs. of unsalted butter. 100 --95 = 1.05 2. 100 — 41.16 = 58.84 lbs. of water. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 203 BUTTERFAT FACTOR To facilitate the finding of the butterfat factor of creams the following table has been arranged for reference : THE BUTTERFAT FACTOR* FOR THE VARIOUS PERCENTAGES OF BUTTERFAT It is of utmost importance to bear in mind the fact that whenever several sources of butterfat are on hand it is best to simplify the computation of the entire ice cream mix by standardizing the sources of butterfat to a desirable richness of the single source of butterfat to be used later in the stand - ardization of the entire ice cream mix. For instance, if you have on hand whole milk testing 5% butterfat, cream testing 20% butterfat, and cream testing 40% butterfat, reduce these three sources of various percent - ages of butterfat to one source, say, testing &amp;0y ( butterfat. This is accomplished by Pearson's square method as follows: Step I. Construct two squares as follows: 'The butterfat factor of a Riven dairy product is obtained by dividing 100 by the percentage of butterfat contained in the article under consideration. I Per cent 3lT~ 3.5 4.0 4.5 5.0 5.5 6.0 6.5 7.0 7.5 8.0 8.5 9.0 9.5 10.0 10.5 11.0 11.5 12.0 12.5 13.0 13.5 14.0 Factor | Per cent j Factor I Per cent j Factor [Per cent | Factor 33.33 1475 &amp;I9 26.0 3.85 37.5 2.67 28.56 15.0 6.67 26.5 3.77 38.0 2.63 25.00 15.5 6.45 27.0 3.70 38.5 2.60 22.22 16.0 6.25 27.5 3.64 39.0 2.57 20.00 16.5 6.06 28.0 3.57 39.5 2.53 18.18 17.0 5.88 28.5 3.51 40.0 2.50 16.67 17.5 5.71 29.0 ; 3.45 ] 40.5 j 2.47 15.38 18.0 5.55 29.5 3.39 41.0 2.44 14.28 18.5 5.40 30.0 3.33 41.5 2.41 13.33 19.0 5.26 30.5 3.28 42.0 2.38 12.50 19.5 5.15 31.0 3.23 42.5 2.35 11.76 20.0 5.00 31.5 3.18 43.0 2.33 11.11 20.5 4.87 32.0 3.13 43.5 2.30 10.52 21.0 4.76 32.5 3.08 44.0 2.27 10.00 21.5 4.65 33.0 3.03 44.5 2.25 9.52 22.0 4.55 33.5 2.99 45.0 2.22 9.09 22.5 4.44 34.0 2.94 45.5 2.20 8.69 23.0 4.35 34.5 2.90 46.0 2.18 8.33 23.5 4.25 35.0 2.86 46.5 2.15 8.00 24.0 4.17 35.5 2.82 47.0 2.13 7.69 24.5 4.08 36.0 2.78 47.5 2.11 7.41 25.0 4.00 36.5 2.74 48.0 2.08 7.14 25.5 3.92 37.0 2.70 48.5 1 2.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Ice Cream Formulas and Standardization 23 Which means that for every 10 parts of whole milk testing 5% butterfat you must take 10 parts of cream testing 20% butter - fat and (25+10=) 35 parts of 40% cream. 20 10 30 ■40 10 Step II. Check: 10x.05= 0.5 lb. of butterfat. 10x.20= 2.0 lbs. of butterfat. 35 x. 40 = 14.0 lbs. of butterfat. 10 lbs. of 5% milk contains 10 lbs. 20% cream contains 35 lbs. 40% cream contains 55 lbs. of this mixture 16.5 x 100 16.5 lbs. of butterfat or 55 It is also important to know the content of milk solids-not - fat (serum solids) of the condensed milk products as well as of the cream which go to make up the ice cream mix. For this purpose make tests not only for the determination of butter - fat but also for the total solids of a given dairy ingredient. Then subtract from the total solids the percentage of butterfat and the result will represent the milk solids-not-fat.* With these precautions in mind and the specialization method as presented and illustrated in this circular, the dif - ficulties confronted in the standardization of ice cream mixes are minimized to a great degree and a working basis is given for practical computation of ice cream mixes. •For average analysis of the various dairy products which enter the ice cream mix, see Experiment Station Circular 22, "Ice Cream Ingredients," prepared in the Department of Dairy Husbandry, University of Nebraska. [5M] = 30% butterfat. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>