<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ALFALFA IN NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1927-07">1927-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 222 July, 1927 ALFALFA IN NEBRASKA T. A. KIESSBLBACH AND ARTHUR ANDERSON IH H^S^a^^a^l a^B Premature loss of alfalfa stands Is often due to the use of unhardy ' varieties or strains THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, Directot </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS PfIJT(? Introduction „ Varieties and seed sources. . Description of varieties 4 Common - Cossack &#132; Grimm - Baltic g Canadian Variegated 7 Sand Lucern Peruvian „ Turkestan 7 Variety test _ Variation m winter hardiness. g Comparative yields 9 Plant characteristics 10 Source of seed test with Common alfalfa 10 Variation m winter hardiness 10 Comparative yields jo Plant characteristics 13 Seed to plant 13 Securing and maintaining a productive field of alfalfa 13 Adapted seed jo Purity and viability of seed . J4 Seeding practices 14 The seedbed ir Manner of seeding and use of a nurse crop. 15 Seed inoculation ,r , 10 Time of seeding 1/* Rate of seeding j- Management the first year.. i 7 Special seeding practices for sandy soils.. 18 Care of an established alfalfa meadow jg Cultivation of alfalfa 29 The use of top dressings on alfalfa 19 Harvesting alfalfa 20 Effect of the time of cutting upon the yield and quality of hayL 20 Yield of hay per acre 9. Proportion of leaves 21 Yield of seed per acre 21 Chemical composition of hay 21 Yield of feed constituents 09 Composition of first, second, and third cuttings * 22 Curing alfalfa hay "". 24 Feeding value of alfalfa hay £0 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">ALFALFA IN NEBRASKA T. A. KIESSELBACH AND ARTHUR ANDERSON The introduction of alfalfa into.Nebraska was a noteworthy contribution leading to a more efficient diversified agriculture. By far the most successful feeding operations include a ■ liberal portion of this forage m the ration. No combination of crops could be better suited for the extensive production of livestock than alfalfa, sweet clover, and corn, all of which do comparatively well m much of the state. The yield of alfalfa ordinarily exceeds that of all other legumes that may be grown for hay. Furthermore, except m regions of rather extreme moisture shortage, this crop has exceptional value m the rota - tion by virtue of improving the productivity of the soil. • As may be seen m the accompanying map, Fig. 1 alfalfa is grown more extensively m eastern than m western Ne - braska, cue largely to more favorable moisture conditions. Nevertheless, the subirrigated valleys and irrigated districts • farther west are well suited to this crop. Practically all soil m the cultivated areas of the state is naturally favorable for its production. Nebraska now ranks first among all states m the acreage ?noc i ' annual crop during the s " year P eri od 1921 - -1925 has averaged slightly over 1,200,000 acres, which is approximately one-eighth of that grown m the United States me acreage has increased more than 6-fold during the past 25 years, and it is now Nebraska's most important hay crop. Altho alfalfa was brought into California from South America as early as 1850, it was not tried m Nebraska until 1875, and was first given serious consideration here m about 1890 , J a ?. pea -* s J hat a material increase m the present acreage would be highly desirable m striving toward a more balanced agriculture. With a better understanding of the comparative value of varieties and seed-sources and of cultural practices T p ?Fu ln ™ curin B. and c a"n&amp; for the stand, an increase should be rather easily achieved. It is primarily the purpose of this bulletin 1 to report in - vestigations concerning the relation of variety, source of S f if a w various cultural practices, to the yield and quality ox HliHlici liciy. ' This bulletin is larsrely abstracted from Research Bulletin 36 of the HJ.hr..!,. A K r.cultural Experiment Station, altho some additional data are included. Nebri " ka </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 varieties and seed sources Recent tests at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station have disclosed that the winter survival and produc-' tivity of alfalfa meadows may be greatly influenced by the seed that is planted. Alfalfa should not be thought of merely as " alfalfa." There are distinct varieties of this crop which differ in their adaptation fully as much as do varieties of the grain crops. The effect of seed source within a variety may also be of great importance in the adaptation of alfalfa, es - pecially as to its winter hardiness. It is believed that much of the winterkilling in recent years has been due to widespread sowing of unhardy seed imported from foreign countries or from southern districts of the United States. While there may be exceptions, it is safest to plant only seed which has been produced for at least several seed generations under as severe climatic conditions as pre - vail where it is to be sown. DESCRIPTION OF VARIETIES Altho alfalfa varies materially in productivity and winter hardiness it is difficult and often impossible to identify the I i [ f~~| | I = f = ~] l Ii NEBRASKA I 1 J i i . i ! ■ ; i 1 ' j "'' " s~44-.-. •' 'm-^mlMv^^M Tft. W0Z4 __ r. .. .r.'. Li_t.___. ___-^«J. ».. • .ft'i'V r •bl77F._fep^^Mgft i p i i 1 1 1 [_\ I 1 Ml FlG " ,n^_' A1 l?* fa &lt;_ Jistr _ bution - Each dot represents 1,000 acres grown in 19^5. No effort has been made to show the distribution within the county. Data taken from Nebraska Agricultural Statistics for 1925 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Alfalfa in Nebraska variety or origin by the appearance of its seed or of the growth in the field. The so-called Common or smooth purple flowered alfalfa is most extensively grown. It is rather vari - able according to seed source in response to differences in en - vironmental conditions. Due to rather similar appearance, it is often impossible to distinguish Common alfalfa from • varieties of the Turkestan and non-hardy groups. In contrast with these purple flowered alfalfas, there is another important commercial group known as variegated, which is characterized by decided variation in flower color. While the purple. flower predominates, light colors including greenish or yellowish tints and even some pure white and yellow make up a considerable per cent of the total. The variegated varieties are commonly regarded as of hybrid origin, resulting from a natural cross between the purple flowered Common and an extremely hardy yellow flowered sort which grows wild in Europe but is of no economic im - portance here. The history and chief characteristics of 8 important varieties included in the Nebraska Experiment Station tests may be described as follows : Common. Much of the Common alfalfa grown in this coun - try has originated from that introduced into California from South America. This evidently consisted of a mixture of types differing especially in winter hardiness. When grown for several seed generations in this country under various climatic conditions, so-called regional strains have developed thru the principle of the survival of the fittest. The more severe the conditions under which the crop has been grown, the greater has been the elimination of the unhardy plant types which the variety contained; Thus southern grown alfalfa is commonly less winter hardy than northern grown and intermediate hardiness may be expected at intervening . points. Seed of foreign origin has likewise shown similar or even greater variation in this respect. Common alfalfa as previously stated is characterized by its purple flowers and relatively smooth leaves and stems as com- - pared with the more hairy Peruvian. Aside from hardiness there is little difference in the agronomic value of most of the regional strains as long as stands are comparable. A strain of Spanish origin has been the only one to appear materially less productive. Regional strains do not differ appreciably in feed value or palatability. Cossack alfalfa had its origin in a small quantity of seed introduced in 1907 by the United States Department of Agri - culture from Russia. This variety differs from Common in flower color, having variegated blossoms which include purple, white, yellow, and many intermediate shades. Cossack alfalfa </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 is generally recognized as somewhat more winter hardv than the best northern strains of the Common. When stands are comparable it is usually not thought of as being superior in yield to Common, altho in the Nebraska tests it has vielded somewhat more, and has surpassed all other varieties in this of g _u * " ■ H testing is desired t0 establish the question No material difference from the Common variety has been noted in feed value or growth habits. Having been grown appear toSE* '" the n ° rth ' n ° distinct regioml s ' rain " JS T , he ,? r if in of } h j s . va «ety is generally traced to a Sil -, afal r Seeded !"_ Carver Count y- Minnesota, in 1858 by Wendehn Grimm with seed brought from Germany. Seed harvested from plants which survived these rigorous conditions served as the foundation stock for this variety !_. su PT or "ardiness of Grimm alfalfa over that of Common came to be recognized. This has resulted in a rather wide - spread use thruout the northern states where it is todav the most popular variety grown. Grimm alfalfa resembles Cossack rather closelv in appear - ance, both varieties having variegated blossoms. In plats h fl .f e nf a rL h. Nebraska Experiment Station, approximatelv naif ot the blossoms of each variety resembled those of the Common variety and the other half were more or less varS been \J*°a "^f .. differ , ences fr0m the Comm ™ alfalfa have been noted in feeding value, palatability, coarseness, propor! tion of leaves, protein content, branching tendencv. or root and crown development Grimm alfalfa has proved some what more hardy than the Common in these tests. In yield of forage and other agronomic characteristics it has proved fully equal to the best of Common alfalfa secured from 20 different sources. Aside from the Common, seed of the Grimm variety is more readily available than that of anv oS variety adapted to Nebraska conditions. Its seed producing wilf .,..,W ? y ! nCre ?u Sin S and ft would seem that Grimm will ultimately replace the Common to a large extent wher - should .?»?,.. - nJ . ry is serious " Increased * eed Production should result in lowering its price which is now relativelv m ° re * jUStifying its use as a ioi^e variety Baltic very closely resembles Grimm and Cossack in all particulars and cannot be distinguished from them. In feed - abou^*?™" 0 "" 0 Va ' Ue theS6 V3rietieS may be regar *- d as The history of Baltic alfalfa is not known prior to 1906 when ,t was named after the town of Baltic, South. Dakota near which it was first grown. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Alfalfa in Nebraska Canadian Variegated closely resembles Grimm, Cossack, and Baltic as to flower color and habits of growth and is generally regarded as intermediate between this group of varieties and northern grown Common alfalfa in the matter of hardiness. In the Nebraska tests it has thinned out slightly more than the hardier strains of Common but has been equally productive. This variety is said to have been intro - duced from France into Ontario, Canada, where it has been grown for many years, and where most of the available seed is now produced. Sand Lucern is a variegated alfalfa which closely resembles in appearance the Grimm and other variegated varieties. It varies in hardiness according to acclimatization and source of seed. The regional strain of this variety grown in the Ne - braska tests has proved very susceptible to cold. This com - parison serves a valuable purpose in showing that all varie - gated alfalfa is not hardy, and that it is important to have authentic information concerning variety and source of seed. Peruvian alfalfa is very important in the extreme southern United States where it surpasses all other varieties. It was first introduced from Peru by the United States Department of Agriculture- in 1899. It is not adapted in Nebraska be - cause of extreme lack of winter resistance. Under favorable conditions a satisfactory stand may be maintained here for a year or two but is invariably followed by a complete loss whereas adapted varieties may be uninjured. True Peruvian alfalfa may be recognized from Common alfalfa in the field by the greater hairiness of its stems and leaves. Turkestan alfalfa resembles the Common variety in ap - pearance and its identification is not always possible. This name is now applied to all alfalfa of Turkestan origin. The original importations were thought to be hardy, due to the adverse conditions under which they had been grown for many seed generations. Within recent years, however, the importations have included miscellaneous lots of seed much of which has been produced under relatively favorable con - ditions, so that now Turkestan is generally considered in - ferior. The imported Turkestan seed can usually be dis - tinguished by the presence of seed of the Russian knapweed. VARIETY TEST • The 8 varieties which have just been described were in - cluded in a comparative variety test at the Nebraska Agri - cultural Experiment Station. Seed of all except the Common was secured from the office of Forage Crop Investigations of the United States Department of Agriculture and was true to name. The Common variety was obtained from a farmer in west central Nebraska. These alfalfas were seeded without - " - ' ■ ' . - . ' " </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 a nurse crop in May, 1922, at the rate of 20 pounds per acre. Good stands were secured and the variations in stand which have occurred may be largely credited to a difference in winter resistance. Such deterioration has ranged from very light to complete loss of stand. Variation in winter liardiness. The first winterkilling was apparent among these varieties following the third winter, 1924-1925, when Peruvian (cover page) was almost com - pletely lost and Turkestan and Sand Lucern were slightly thinned. During the fourth winter, 1925-1926, at least a slight loss of stand was observed on all plats while a few suffered rather severe damage. Sand Lucern (Fig. 2), altho a variegated alfalfa, was very decidedly affected, while Com - mon, Turkestan, and Canadian Variegated showed a little more loss of stand than Cossack, Grimm, and Baltic. Further winterkilling has occurred during the fifth winter, 1926-1927. This was again especially marked with the Sand Lucern and somewhat more noticeable with the Common and Canadian" Variegated than with the other varieties. Stand survival in April, 1927, was estimated as follows: Common 72 per cent, Fig. 2. — Canadian Variegated alfalfa on the left, Sand Lucern in the center, and Common alfalfa on the right. Seeded May 16, 1922, and photographed September 2, 1926. The stand of Sand Lucern was materially thinned during the winter of 1924-1925 and the following winters. The weeds in the foreground of the Sand Lucern plat have been pulled in order to show the actual stand of alfalfa in con - trast with the adjacent plats. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Alfalfa in Nebraska Cossack 89, Baltic 85, Grimm 83, Canadian Variegated 69, band Lucern 13, and Turkestan 81 per cent. With the ex - ception of Sand. Lucern proportionate decreases in yield are not expected since fairly satisfactory stands still remain. In fa 1 seedings made in 1924 and 1925, these varieties gave re - sults similar to those from the older field plats Comparative yields. In comparison (Fig. 3) with Nebras- . ka Common alfalfa which averaged 4.47 tons of hay per acre annually during the 4-year period, 1923-1926, Cossack yielded l»r 9 J°A S d* B ? ltlC I" 97 , t0 . ns&gt; Grimm 4 - 72 tons - Canadian Varie - gated 4.66 tons, Sand Lucern 4.05 tons, and Turkestan 4 16 tons per acre. During the first 2 years of the test before Peruvian winterkilled, it gave no indication of being superior . m yield to Common. p Founds im — — \\wrwm : Fig. 3.— Comparative hay yields' of alfalfa varieties, 1923-1926, to - gether with the proportionate yields of leaves and stems, 1923-1925. - The 3 most desirable variegated varieties, Cossack, Grimm and Baltic, averaged 10 per cent more in yield than the Com - mon. This, coupled with the evidence of somewhat superior winter hardiness and practical equality in all other respects suggests special merit in this group for Nebraska conditions' The more extensive use of one or more of these variegated </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 varieties becomes largely a question of seed supply and com - parative seed cost. The total seed producing acreage of these sorts is relatively small, and, due to a special demand, their seed cost is rather high. Because of inability to distinguish between the seeds of these various varieties, a special trade has developed in seed certified as to origin and trueness to name. Such certified seed, altho now approximately twice as expensive as Common alfalfa, is the only extensive reliable commercial source. Plant characteristics. The most striking difference ob - served in the appearance of these varieties was that of flower color. The Cossack, Baltic, Grimm, Canadian Variegated, and Sand Lucern, tho not distinguishable from each other, could be recognized as a group by the varied blossom colors, where - as the Common, Turkestan, and Peruvian have rather uni - formly purple blossoms. Varietal differences in proportion of leaves, height, coarseness of stem, and chemical composi - tion were not marked. The Turkestan averaged a few days later in maturity at each cutting, and made much less growth after the removal of the last cutting in the fall. A comparative study was made of the crowns and roots of Common, Grimm, and Cossack alfalfas. Approximately 300 3-year old plants of each variety taken from the foregoing variety test plats were measured. Tho considerable variation in crown and root type occurred within all the varieties no varietal differences were found of sufficient magnitude to aid in identification. SOURCE OF SEED TEST WITH COMMON ALFALFA For the purpose of observing the effects of acclimatization upon this variety, seed was obtained from 20 different sources and was grown comparatively at the Nebraska Experiment Station. Such lots of seed are generally spoken of as re - gional strains. These strains included 15 of domestic and 5 of foreign origin. The domestic seed was obtained from each of the states extending from North Dakota and Montana on the north, to Texas and New Mexico on the south. Of these, 2 were from central Nebraska (Dawson County) where they were thought locally to have special merit, one was from west central Nebraska (Lincoln County), and 2 came from ex - treme western Nebraska where they had been produced re - spectively under dry land and irrigated conditions. Both dry land and irrigated seed was included from Wyoming. The results secured during the 6-year period, 1922-1927, may be summarized as follows: Variation in winter hardiness. No appreciable winterkill - ing was observed during the first 2 winters with the alfalfa from any of the 20 sources. The following winter, 1924-1925, </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Alfalfa in Nebraska the Argentine (Fig. 4), Spanish, and Italian strains suffered material loss of stand and proved least hardy. Further winterkilling which affected all strains in varying degrees occurred during the next season, 1925-1926. The Argentine, bpanish, and Italian strains again showed material loss while the strains from Texas, Oklahoma, New Mexico, and southern Colorado were thinned appreciably more than those originat - ing farther north, thereby showing only intermediate winter resistance. Additional winterkilling was observed following the fifth winter, 1926-1927. It was again most striking with those strains that showed the greatest losses during the pre - vious winters. Stand survival estimates (Table 1) in April, i* ii ra "2 e 2 n from 18 Per cent for the Argentine and Spanish : alfalfas to 88 per cent for one of the strains from central Nebraska (Dawson County). A new series of field plats seeded in 1925 to Common and Grimm alfalfa from various sources has also shown striking results in respect to winterkilling. In the spring of 1927, tallowing the- second winter, less than one-fourth stand re - mained of Common alfalfa from Argentina, Italy, Southern _fc " a_____: ' -a** '••___ ______ _______________! ._______! B**o _ &lt;_______&gt;- - fci____j MPl'JW ____fffi*T_i bImBoE. -Kfl KPHI -P- I^B _ff*^D ____Jtt___fcjK365^8 S5_&gt;. * KWfl |H _■____■ ____ Fig. 4.— Argentine seed of Common alfalfa at left and Nebraska Common at right, seeded May 16, 1922. The Argentine seed has proved unhardy for Nebraska conditions, winterkilling severely in the Winter of 1924-1925 and the following winters. Photographed May 25, 1925. ' </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Tari.E 1. — Comparative yields and stand xureival of regional utrainx of Common alfalfa, IHJJ-t!iJ7. Strain Yield of hay ' per acre with 15 per cent moisture content \ Stand j£j" survival CO 1923 i 1924 1925 l.*26 5 Average I 1927 3 &gt; Tons Rcla- Tons JRela- Tons Rela- Tons Rela- Tons Rela-j jg tive ! tive tive tive tive- | Per cent j, West Central Nebraska 4.70 100 7.18 \ 1(10 4.90 100 1.69 100 4.63 '' 100 I 75 M Russian 5.14 108 7.31 I 102 5.:12 109 1.08 99 4.86 I 105 | C&gt;8 !_ Italian 5.30 111 ' 7.:10 I 102 3.31 68 1.20 71 4.28 I 92 | 19 W Provence 4.71 !U&gt; 6.«7 | Id 4.83 99 1.33 79 4.39 ; 95 77 2 Spanish 3.45 ' 72 4.87 68 3.40 fi» 1.09 64 j 3.20 69 18 g Argentine 5.02 105 I 7.36 103 I 2.78 57 1.09 64 I 4;06 | 88 18 __ North Dakota 4.69 ' 99 I 7.33 102 I 4.84 99 ! 1.59 I 94 I 4.61 100 75 South Dakota ; 4.90 I 103 I 7.28 101 | 4.98 j 102 | 1.70 101 4.72 102 80 Central Nebraska (Dawson Co.) 4.70 I 100 ! 6.90 96 4.73 I 97 ; 1.65 | 98 4.51 97 75 % Central Nebraska (Dawson To.)' j 5.04 106 6.98 97 5.09 I 104 ! 1.66 ! 98 1 4.69 101 88 &gt; West Nebr. Dry Land I 5.19 109 7.59 106 I 5.15 I 105 1.57 I 93 4.88 105 80 g West Nebr. Irrigated 5.21 109 7.56 I 105 5.02 | 102 I 1.51 89 j 4.83 104 75 g Kansas :...'. I 5.34 112 7.53 ! 105 ! 4.87 ! 99 j 1.71 101 4.86 105 80 Z Oklahoma ! 4.27 90 7.15 I 100 I 5.61 I 114 1.60 95 4.66 101 50 Texas I 4.29 i 90 I 7.17 100 I 5.59 I 114 ! 1.54 I 91 4.65 100 53 2 Montana, Dry Land I 4.83 I 101 I 7.12 99 ! 5.13 I 105 I 1.50 89 4.65 100 73 g Wyoming. J)r'y Land ! 4.73 99 ; 7.38 103 ! 5.12 | 104 1.43 85 4.67 101 70 £ Wyoming, Irrigated ! 5.02 105 I 6.65 93 i 5.07 I 103 1.60 95 | 4.59 99 83 3 Colorado, Dry Land I 4.65 I 98 ! 0.87 ! 96 I 4.72 I 96 1.30 I 77 4.39 95 67 B New Mexico. Irrigated „ „.„.„„„... 5.30 1 HI | 7.53 \~YM~\f.M I 99 I 1.34 I 79 I 4.76 I 103 54 'The last &lt;-iittiii K s of lliiliun. Spanish, ami Aivulim- in l!l_li nn.l nf all strains in l'.»i!li eontained varyini; amounts of weeds whn»e JjJ pi-rrenlUK. was tli-t I'rniiiu-tl from samples, ami llu- hay yields ar. 1 here reported cm u weed- free htt-sis. 1^ - ('nlt-nlnted rrinu tin- 4-year average yields. ■ Estimated stand survival on April 20. I!&gt;_7. as averaKed fur tin- dtijdielile plats. •Crown in Dawson County as Turkestan. In these tests it could not lie illsUnituished from Common alfalfa. 'The decided reduction in yield in 11120 was due to the depletion of sulisoil moisture. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Alfalfa in Nebraska California, and Arizona. Common alfalfa from Utah and Idaho had stands of 80 per cent as compared with 85 per cent for Kansas and Nebraska strains. On the other hand Grimm alfalfa from 9 sources and Cossack from one source have come thru with very uniform and almost perfect stands. Comparative yields. The 4-year average yields (Table 1) of the Common alfalfa from various sources ranged from 3 20 tons of hay per acre for the Spanish to 4.88 tons for one of the western Nebraska strains. The 3 alfalfas which winterkilled most and yielded least were Argentine, Spanish, and Italian. Aside from these the yield differences to date have not been very significant. The variation in the yield of the alfalfa from the 5 different Nebraska sources was practically as great as that for the other regional strains. Plant characteristics. Differences in the appearance of the regional strains used in these tests were not striking. The Argentine, Spanish, and French alfalfas appeared somewhat lighter green in color. The Russian, Argentine, Italian, and- French were slower to start growth after cutting and made a somewhat shorter growth after the removal of the last cutting in the fall. In contrast, the strain from Spain was quicker to start after cutting and usually made more late fall growth. The Spanish and French alfalfa made somewhat shorter growth per cutting than the others. securing and maintaining a productive field of - ALFALFA SEED TO PLANT Adapted seed. The three most important requirements of good seed are purity, viability, and winter hardiness of the plants produced. The foregoing tests have shown the use of an adapted strain or variety to be of extreme importance. Domestic production has not met the demand for alfalfa seed, with the result that large quantities are imported annually. Much of this forejgn seed is not adapted for general use in the United States. TT ec fnt federal seed legislation and rulings made by the United States Department of Agriculture which require the staining of all imported alfalfa and red clover seed should prove a valuable safeguard to the purchaser. The color of the stain and the percentage of seed that must be stained in each container varies with the source of the seed and its adaptability. The law requires : (1) that red clover imported from Italy and alfalfa seed from Africa and Turkestan be stained red because of their general inadaptation to this country. As a matter of precaution, seed of unknown origin must also be stained red. (2) Due to inadaptation in the middle and northern states, alfalfa from South America must </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 be stained orange-red (effective July 2, 1927). (3) Canadian seed must be stained violet, and (4) all other imported seed must be stained green. All green stained seed is questionable for use in Nebraska since in certain cases seed now classed in this grobp has been found unadapted. On the other hand, violet stained seed may ordinarily be regarded as suitable for this statef The staining requirements of this law apply bnly to im - ported seed. Seed produced in this country also varies in hardiness with the severity of climatic conditions linder which it has become acclimated. As a general principle only seed should be planted which is known to have been grown several seed generations under conditions as least as severe, as those where it is sown. Purity and viability of seed. The buying of low grade seed is seldom justified because of weed seed, inert material, or low germination. Clean fields may become foul with weeds thru the use of impure seed. High and prompt viability is desirable because it results in uniform germination and better stands. Scarification is generally believed to be helpful to any alfalfa seed which contains a large amount of hard seed that is slow to germinate because of retarded moisture ab - sorption. The Nebraska Seed Law requires, in part, tha. all alfalfa seed offered for sale within Nebraska, in quantities of 10 pounds or more, must bear a label specifying, (1) the ap - proximate percentage by weight of purity, (2) the approxi - mate total percentage by weight of weed seed, and in case of certain noxious weeds (small-flowered morning glory, wild mustard, quack grass, wild oats, and all species of dodder) * present in excess of 1 seed in 5 grams, the name and approxi - mate number of such seed per ounce, (3) the presence of seed of Canada thistle (it is made illegal to offer for sale or dis - tribution agricultural seed containing more than one seed of the Canadian thistle to the 5 grams), and (4) the approxi - mate percentage of germination. The law further provides for free purity and germination tests to any citizen of the state. Such tests may be secured by sending small representative samples to the State Seed Laboratory, State Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebraska. When buying alfalfa seed its purity and germination should be noted and its quality and price judged accordingly. SEEDING PRACTICES The relation of various seeding practices to the likelihood of securing a satisfactory stand of alfalfa and the mainten - ance of such a stand when once secured has long been under observation in this state and certain conclusions seem justi - j </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Alfalfa in Nebraska fled. Special practices for sandy soils are discussed sep - arately on page 18. The seedbed. A high state of soil fertility aids in establish - ing a stand of alfalfa on any type of soil and is favorable for the production of large yields of forage. On soils which are not subject to severe blowing, thoroly prepared, finely pulver - ized, compact, moist seedbeds are most conducive to securing a stand. Tillage operations and crop rotations should be planned with this in mind. Early plowing followed by suf - ficient disking, harrowing, and possibly rolling to control weed growth and compact the soil is usually desirable. Under ex - ceptionally favorable moisture and weed-free ' conditions, alfalfa may be drilled in late summer directly into small grain stubble, with mere disking or without any treatment. This is especially true of the rather light soils of central and western Nebraska. Almost any seeding or cultural practice will prove successful when weather and soil -conditions are favorable. Except under conditions of irrigation or favorable proximity to the ground water table, seeding on land previously in alfalfa is generally inadvisable because of the probable de - pletion of subsoil moisture. Manner of seeding and use of a nurse crop. Except under extremely favorable conditions, drilling is more successful than broadcasting. It insures more uniform covering in moist soil and more prompt and uniform germination. The drilling should be very shallow, not to exceed 1 inch other - wise it may be impossible for the seedling to get up thru the covering. This is especially true in case of dashing rains which may cover it still deeper. Broadcast seed is usually covered by a harrow. Seeding alone without a nurse crop is in most cases the most dependable practice for securing a stand. The use of a small grain nurse crop with spring seeding is fairly successful in some localities and especially in the ex - treme eastern counties. Thin stands of winter wheat follow - ing severe winterkilling often, prove to be good nurse crops. Short-strawed, early maturing varieties of oats and barley, seeded at half the normal rate, make good modified nurse crops. Mowing the small grains for hay in the early milk stage or even earlier. is desirable if the season becomes very dry, or the nurse crop becomes excessively rank in growth. Seed inoculation. Alfalfa plants are enabled to produce such a large yield of high protein forage only because of the atmospheric nitrogen gathering properties of bacteria which dwell on their root systems. These bacteria form the charac - teristic nodules found on the finer roots of inoculated plants. The occurrence of nodules is evidence that these bacteria are present. Careful excavation of typical roots is necessary to . determine their presence. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 Most Nebraska soil is naturally very favorable for the de - velopment of these bacteria and artificial inoculation has sel - dom been found necessary. It has been concluded from vari - ous co-operative tests with farmers as well as by tests on the Experiment Station Farm, that artificial inoculation is essen - tial only in restricted regions of unusually acid soil and per - haps in a few isolated localities where alfalfa has not been previously grown. Soils too acid for nodule formation must be limed before alfalfa may be successfully grown. Such land is very limited in this state. The trial of seed inoculation is recommended for localities where failures to secure a pro - ductive stand cannot be accounted for otherwise. Such artificial inoculation may be accomplished bv the use of commercial cultures which are always accompanied bv directions for their application, or by some soil method A simple form of this latter method is to scatter 2 or 3 bushels of soil per acre from a healthy well established field of alfalfa or sweet clover upon the land at time of seeding. This soil which naturally contains the desired bacteria, should be worked into the ground with a harrow, disk, or drill immedi - ately after it is scattered. Time of seeding. Seeding should be done onlv when weather and soil conditions are favorable. It may preferablv be done either in the spring or the early fall in eastern Nebraska and in the spring or the early summer in central and western Ne - braska. Fall seeding in eastern Nebraska can be advantageously done between August 10 and September 1. If conditions are lavorable tor prompt germination and continued fall growth there is seldom danger of winterkilling, provided seed of a hardy strain or variety is planted. Chances of winterkilling are increased with more delayed seeding which is not generally recommended, altho successful stands are sometimes secured as late as September 15 in the southeastern portion of the If seeding is to be done in the spring, April is considered L«°n fi, m0 ? th in . e , astern Nebraska, the exact time depending upon the favorableness of conditions. Seeding seems most successful during May and early June in central and western Nebraska, preceded by tillage planned to conserve moisture, kill weeds, and compact the seed bed. In those regions where fall seeding following a small grain crop is successful the land will produce almost as much hay the following year as if seeded the preceding spring. Spring seeded alf alf a seldom proves a profitable crop during the first to 3 .-' _?_- mUS . ofte \ b u e C »PP«&lt;» several times the first season to check weed growth. If conditions are favorable and if </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Alfalfa in. Nebraska there is but little competition from weeds one or two light cuttings of fair quality hay may be secured. Cutting in this case should be delayed until the crop is fairly mature. Rate of seeding. The number of alfalfa plants necessary for maximum production and the rate of seeding required to se - cure this stand varies with conditions. There are enough • seed in the average pound of alfalfa when distributed uni - formly over an acre to produce 5 or 6 plants per square foot if all the seed grow when planted. Stands resulting from excessively thin seeding are invariably more or less uneven, more subject to ingress of weeds, and usually produce a hav of lower quality. Fifteen pounds of good seed per acre may be regarded as a standard seeding rate and more than this seldom seems advisable. Ten pounds may produce good even stands when conditions are extremely favorable but the use of a somewhat larger amount of seed will increase the chances of securing such a stand under average conditions. With age the stand gradually becomes thinner and the surviving plants grow . larger. Thus a field with an initial stand of 100 seedlings per square foot may be reduced to half a dozen plants per square foot within a few years, and yet be very productive. Tests comparing Grimm and Common alfalfa at various seeding rates would not seem to justify the statement some - times made that Grimm may be seeded at a thinner rate due to a more branching type of plant. No marked varietal dif - ferences in this respect have been found. Management the first year. Ordinarily the weed growth proves a serious factor the first season following spring seed - ing without a nurse crop and the question arises as to how • the situation may be best handled. If the weed growth be - comes quite heavy the most feasible plan appears to be clip - ping in order to avoid the loss of the alfalfa seedlings due to weed competition. Under exceptional conditions 2 or 3 or even more clippings may be necessary. These clippings should be made rather high and if possible during cool, damp weather. If for any reason the clipped growth was permitted to become very heavy, it should be removed, tho this extra labor can usually be avoided by timely work. It has sometimes been recommended that the new field should be undipped thruout the first season, to be followed by burning over or raking off the following spring. This prac - tice should be governed largely by local conditions. Whenever the weed growth becomes so heavy that there is danger of smothering out the less vigorous alfalfa plants, it should be clipped. In the Nebraska Experiment Station tests of this practice the .weed growth has been so great in 2 years out of </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 4 as to kill out the alfalfa when left undipped during the season. Late summer or early fall seeding seldom needs further attention and fair yields of relatively weed-free hay may be expected the following season. Special seeding practices for sandy soils. On light sandy soil that is subject to severe blowing when in a bare tilled condition, a number of special practices have come into use in connection with the seeding of alfalfa, which are designed to reduce such tendencies. These are briefly described as fol - lows: 1. Seeding may be done directly into small grain stubble in the early fall, if comparatively weed free, without further preparation. 2. Where fall seeding is permissible a peck of oats to the acre may be seeded with the alfalfa. These make a rapid growth and serve to hold the soil. Fall frosts kill the oats and prevent excessive growth. 3. Some farmers sow a crop of millet early in June and seed alfalfa directly into the millet stubble after harvest if moisture conditions are favorable. 4. On sandy soils in northern Nebraska the ground is sometimes listed late in May or early in June the same as if corn were planted. Cultivate the field twice thereafter the same as for corn to level the ground and destroy weeds. Then harrow crosswise about the middle of July at which time the soil moisture conditions are commonly favorable and the ground free from weeds, smooth and well packed. These soil conditions are all regarded as very important. The seed is drilled not to exceed 1 inch deep immediately after the first good rain following the middle of July. The winds are less severe after this date and annual weeds are less bothersome. The early seeding results in sufficient growth to afford winter protection and hold the soil. CARE OF AN ESTABLISHED ALFALFA MEADOW Premature thinning of alfalfa may be due to a number of causes. Some of these may be controlled in a large measure by proper cultural practices such as: (1) the use of seed of a hardy sort, (2) the leaving of considerable fall growth as winter protection, and (3) the avoidance of frequent cutting in very immature stages. Unavoidable losses of stand are frequently due to drought and cold beyond the endurance of the crop. Bacterial wilt disease (Aplanobacter insidiosum McCulloch) has recently come to be regarded by some workers as a factor in the pre - mature thinning of stands and merits further investigation. Experiment Station tests have indicated the symptoms of this </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Alfalfa in Nebraska disease to be most prevalent in those plats seeded to non - hardy sorts in which winter injury has been severe Disking or otherwise cultivating an alfalfa field in an effort to - .mcken the stand seldom proves effective. When fields have become so badly thinned as to be unprofitable they should be plowed up rather than attempting to restore them thru tillage practices or reseeding. ■ Cultivation of alfalfa. Tillage of an established stand of alfalfa has been frequently advocated as a means of stimulat - ing growth of the. crop, destroying weeds, and conserving moisture. A series of comparative tests was conducted dur - ing the period 1921 to 1925 to determine the effects upon yield from cultivation by means of a disk harrow, a spring tooth harrow (alfalfa renovator), and an ordinary smoothing ™„^ treatments were located in a field of well-estab - lished alfalfa seeded in 1918 and having an almost perfect and uniform stand. Production from 1922 to 1925 was rela - tively low due to moisture shortage. This condition was in - tensified by the rainfall being below normal much of the time and by the heavy production of hay during 1919-1921 As a 4-year average, 1921-1924, the plats receiving no cultivation averaged 3.39 tons per acre. In comparison, 3 different disk harrow treatments averaged 3.22 tons, the 3 spring tooth harrow treatments averaged 3.31 tons, and the ordinary harrow treatment 3.37 tons. No manner of tillaee increased the production. «"«se When all of the plats were harvested uniformly in 1925 without further treatment, there was no marked difference in yield except that where spring tooth harrow cultivation fol - tilTed late 7 CUttmg yi6ld W8S ° nly 81 Per cent of the un^ The use oj 'top dressings on alfalfa. It is generally recog - nized that alfalfa hay cannot be produced profitably on soils too low in their lime and sulphur content and in general fer - tility. Alfalfa will not thrive on acid soils. Sulphur is a necessary plant food element and alfalfa has a high sulnhur requirement A test was begun in 1921, wherein gypsum (calcium sulphate), sulphur (flowers of sulphur), lime and sulphur in combination, lime alone, and barnyard manure were applied as top dressings in commonly recommended amounts to alf alf a growing on the Experiment Station Farm The applications were made in duplicate in the spring of l«fci on a well-established stand of alfalfa in the same field where the cultivation tests just described were made. Gypsum was applied at the rate of 400 pounds per acre, sulphur alone as well as in conjunction with lime was applied at the rate of 200 pounds per acre, while 2 tons crushed limestone and 8 tons of barnyard manure were used. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 The 4-year averages show practically no difference in the yields from the untreated, the gypsum, or the sulphur and lime treated plats. These results indicate that there is suf - ficient lime and sulphur in this soil for alfalfa production. It seems probable, however, that favorable response from lime application should result in limited areas having rather acid soil. The application of barnyard manure increased the yield of alfalfa hay 13 per cent over the plats receiving no treat - ment. harvesting alfalfa EFFECT OF THE TIME OF CUTTING UPON THE YIELD AND QUALITY OF HAY The yield and quality of hay and the permanency of stand may be materially influenced by the stage of maturity at which the crop is harvested. Under average Nebraska con - ditions the best practice is to harvest the hay when in the one-tenth to half-bloom stage. A test bearing upon this sub - ject was made under the same conditions as the tillage and top dressing experiments just reported. These yields were also affected to some extent by the abnormal growth condi - tions resulting from a moisture shortage during the period 1922 to 1924. Continuous harvesting of alfalfa at 8 stages of maturity was practiced. The tests were made in duplicate field plats during 1921 to 1924. Five of these stages of maturity were determined by the state of bloom as follows: Pre-bloom, initial bloom, one - tenth bloom, one-half bloom, and full bloom. In a sixth prac - tice the second cutting was left each year to mature a seed crop while the other cuttings were made at the normal or new growth stage. The yields as reported are inclusive of all cuttings. A seventh or new growth stage, also designated as " normal " or " check " in these tests, was determined by the rather definite appearance of new growth or shoots at the crown. Ordinarily this stage fell between the tenth and half - bloom stages, but several times it preceded or followed them. An eighth or modified new growth stage was included, com - parable to the other new growth stage except that the second cutting was harvested each year when the first blooms ap - peared. Frequently under Nebraska conditions the second cutting of alfalfa and the small grain crop are ready for harvest at the same time, and this test was planned to indi - cate the effect of cutting the second crop of alfalfa early so as not to interfere with the small grain harvest. All of these specified maturity stages were adhered to as nearly as condi - tions permitted. Owing to irregularity in blooming and growth associated with season and weather, some of the cut- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Alfalfa in Nebraska tings were at times more or less arbitrary. Any appreciable growth at the end of the season was harvested regardless of maturity and was included in the yield. ■tiJi el c\ °f lmy per acre - As an avera ge for the 4-year period, 1921-1924, the following acre yields were obtained for the various stages of maturity: Pre-bloom'3.00 tons; initial bloom 3.04 tons; one-tenth bloom 3.35 tons; one-half bloom 3 43 tons; full bloom 3.19 tons; seed stage 2.82 tons; new growth stage 3.51 tons; and the modified new growth stage 3.34 tons per acre. The one-tenth and one-half bloom and new growth stages averaged 14 per cent higher yield than the pre-bloom and initial-bloom stages. The full bloom stage yielded 6 per cent more than the pre-bloom, whereas the seed stage yielded 6 per cent less. These data indicate that under eastern Nebraska conditions the maximum annual yield may be secured if har - vested from the tenth to half-bloom stages. It appears that no serious damage to stand or yield results from an occasional cutting as early as the initial bloom stage. As a 3-year average in an earlier test, 1915-1917, hay har - vested at one-fourth bloom yielded decidedly more than hay cut in the pre-bud stage or when very mature. There was a marked weakening of plants and thinning of stand where the alfalfa was cut too frequently. Proportion of leaves. The proportion of leaves at harvest was found to be closely correlated with maturity. As a 4-year average for all cuttings the pre-bloom, initial bloom, one-tenth bloom, one-half bloom, full-bloom, seed, and new growth stages consisted of 57.3, 56.6, 55.8, 53.2, 49.4, 33.3, and 52.8 per cent leaves respectively. This was an extreme difference of 24 0 per cent and a variation of 7.9 per cent among the stages ordinarily harvested for hay. Yield of seed per acre. Under Nebraska conditions the sec - ond cutting is usually considered the most desirable to leave for seed production. It will ordinarily blossom and set seed pods more freely than the first cutting whereas later cuttings seldom mature seed. Leaving the second cutting for seed in these tests has reduced the forage yield materially as well as resulting in feed of lower quality. There was measurable seed production during this test in only 1 year out of 4, the seed plats yielding at the rate of 1.2 bushels per acre in 1921. It is recognized that seed production in eastern Nebraska is relatively uncertain as compared with the central and western portion of the state. Chemical composition of liay. Fodder analyses were made of the leaves and stems from all cuttings of alfalfa harvested for hay at 6 stages of maturity during the 4-year period, </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 1921-1924. The composition of the whole hay has been calcu - lated from that of the leaves and stems. As a 4-year average, there was a rather gradual reduction in the ash content of the hay of 1.88 per cent from the pre - bloom stage to the full-bloom stage. The protein percentages were as follows: Pre-bloom 21.98, initial bloom 20.03, one - tenth bloom 19.24, one-half bloom 18.84, full bloom 18.13, and new growth stage 18.38 per cent. The decrease in protein content of 3.85 per cent between extremes was rather parallel with increased maturity of the plant and was accompanied by an increase in crude fiber content of 5.69 per cent. NO con - sistent variation was found in the percentage of nitrogen-free extract or fat. When all the analyses are averaged for the 4-year period, it is found that the stems compared with the leaves contained 75 per cent as much ash, 43 per cent as much protein, 249 per cent as much fiber, 90 per cent as much nitrogen-free extract, and 46 per cent as much fat. Yield of feed constituents. The 4-year average annual acre yields of moisture-free hay, leaves, and stems together with their yields of feed constituents are shown graphically in Fig. 5, for each of the 6 maturity stages. The average an - nual acre yields of protein for the various stages were : Pre - bloom 0.552 ton, initial bloom 0.515 ton, one-tenth bloom 0.541 ton, one-half bloom 0.535 ton) full bloom 0.482 ton, and new growth stage 0.546 ton. The proportion of this total protein that was borne in the leaves ranged from 75 per cent in the least mature stages to 70 per cent in the full bloom stage. From the combined standpoints of acre yields of hay and feed constituents, quality of hay and permanency of stand, it would seem that harvesting alfalfa at approximately the new - growth stage should prove the most desirable practice. This stage usually occurs under average Nebraska conditions dur - ing the period from one-tenth to one-half bloom and for practical purposes harvesting may ordinarily extend over this period without materially affecting results, using either the new-growth or bloom development as an index. A modifica - tion of this practice to fit local conditions may often prove desirable but frequent cutting of alfalfa in more immature stages should be avoided. COMPOSITION OF FIRST, SECOND, AND THIRD CUTTINGS It is of interest to compare the physical and chemical com - position of successive cuttings of the hay. Such data have been averaged during the 4-year period, 1921-1924, for hay cut at the 6 stages of maturity (pre-bloom, initial bloom, one - tenth bloom, one-half bloom, full bloom, and new-growth) pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Alfalfa in Nebraska Pou_fc_ . __ COM — : SSOO -&amp;| || 1| Pre- Initial i/jo [few Vl Full bloom gloom bloom growth bloom bloom A3h=m Protein=M Fiber^M N-free E*t*m tat=m FlG ;t__r^ 0 - S i U A e . ree ac l e f e l ds of ha y &lt; left &gt;, leaves (center), and *___? f r A ght) _ f ? r ? aC \S* th ? stages of maturity designated at the _. _L°n f ft Cha S- t0get i* er with their Proportionate content of ash, 192W92. „ ' n,tr0gen - free extract - andf at- Average for 4 years, viously reported. The first, second, and third cuttings con - sisted, respectively, of 48.7, 56.4, and 58.1 per cent leaves There was a slight increase, 1.07 per cent, in the protein con- - tent of the hay from the first to the third cutting </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 As an average of the 7 varieties tested during the 3-year period, 1923-1925, the proportion of leaves was 39.7, 43.7, and 54.9 per cent, respectively, for the first, second, and third cuttings. Corresponding protein contents were 16.84 18.58, and 19.99 per cent. Averaging both of the above experiments the first, second, and third cuttings consisted of 44, 50, and 56 per cent leaves and contained 17.9, 19.2, and 20.0 per cent protein, respec - tively. Being more leafy, finer stemmed, and higher in protein, the later cuttings would seem to have the higher feeding value. CURING ALFALFA HAY The most successful alfalfa hay curing practices take into consideration the importance of retaining the leaves, green color, and sweetness of the forage. The leaves constitute ap - proximately half of the tonnage and contain practically three - fourths of all of the protein of a good grade of hay. Pro - longed exposure to the weather after cutting results in undue shattering of leaves and bleaching. Rain is especially in - jurious to quality. Such harmful effects of undue exposure can be most effectively avoided thru the use of combined swath and windrow curing and placing in the stack or mow just as soon as sufficiently dry. The moisture content of alfalfa at time of cutting is ap - proximately 70 per cent. This must be reduced thru curing to somewhere between 20 and 30 per cent in order that the hay may be stored without danger of decay or mustiness. The atmospheric forces which aid in the curing of hay are the same as those concerned in the evaporation of water from any moist object. The rate of drying naturally varies with the temperature, relative humidity, wind movement, and sun - shine. As a rule hay in the curing process loses water most rapidly when spread out thin. Thus less time is required to cure it in the swath than when raked into a windrow or cock. Complete curing in the swath, however, usually results in unnecessary loss of leaves by shattering. Such loss, which often amounts to as much as 20 or 30 per cent of the leaves, may be largely prevented by timely raking and prompt storage of the hay when cured. Ordinarily the hay should not be raked until it has become at least well wilted and in no case should the raking be delayed until the leaves become brittle. Comparative tests of various practices indicate that such a combination of swath and windrow curing will often permit stacking a day earlier than if raked at once after cutting. This is important since unnecessary delay before stacking may result in serious damage from unfavorable weather condi - tions. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Alfalfa in Nebraska ■ In the case of heavy dews or showers, partially cured hay is better off in the windrow than in the swath, because hay that is wet with external moisture is especially subject to V.ieaching when exposed to the sun. This should be taken into consideration when planning the work. Under favorable con - ditions hay may be cut in the forenoon, raked during the afternoon, and stacked the next day. Another desirable prac - tice is to cut late in the afternoon, rake the following day when sufficiently dry and stack as soon as cured. Since freshly cut hay is bleached but little by exposure to dew, this plan has the advantage of a longer curing period. Brown hay results from stacking before sufficiently cured. Such hay has a satisfactory feeding value and is relished by stock but it is difficult to secure a brown hay of uniformly good quality and there is considerable loss of substance due to the excessive heating in the stack. The market value is also greatly lessened. , FEEDING VALUE OF ALFALFA HAY It is generally recognized that alfalfa hay is superior to grass hay in feeding value and palatability. Good quality hay harvested at the proper stage of maturity is readily eaten by all classes of livestock. Experiments have shown alfalfa hay to be a desirable roughage for growing, winter - ing, breeding, and fattening, stock as well as for dairy animals. Hay crops may be grouped into 2 general classes, legume or nitrogenous and grass or carbohydrate. The chief dis - tinguishing character is the. difference in the relative propor - tion of the protein and carbohydrate or the nitrogen-free ex - tract content. Sorghum, Sudan grass, and all other forage plants belonging to the grass family are relatively high in carbohydrates, whereas legumes such as alfalfa and the clovers are comparatively high in protein. This difference may be readily seen by a comparison of sorghum and Sudan grass hay with alfalfa hay grown under comparable conditions on the Experiment Station Farm, the yield and analyses of which are reported for the 4-year period, 1921 - 1924, in Table 2. On a moisture-free basis the protein and nitrogen-free ex - tract contents of the alfalfa hay were 18.38 and 40.14 per cent, respectively, compared with 5.37 and 52.52 per cent as an average for sorghum and Sudan grass. Differences in ash, fiber, and fat contents were not marked. Moisture-free acre yields of the hay, protein, and nitrogen-free extract were 2.978, 0.546, and 1.175 tons, respectively, for the alfalfa com - pared with 3.561, 0.196, and 1.878 tons per acre as an average for sorghum and Sudan grass. ■ - .■ </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 222 It is well known that such analyses of the feed constituents are not absolute indexes of the nutrient value of the feed in question. They do, however, permit closer comparative* evaluations of different feeds. The relative food values of these 2 classes of forage have likewise been well established thru extensive and varied feeding tests. Table 2. — Relative yield and chemical composition of typical leguminous and non-leg iiminons forage plants ' — U-year average 1921-192U. Yield of ! Fodder analyses on a moisture-free basis lhliyl&gt;e . r | | I Nitro- I ~ " Cr °P ;. "percent Ash | Crude I Crude gen-free Fat j moi»ture ' protein I fiber extract icontent I | Tons ! Per cent ; Per cent) Per cent| Per cent Per cent Amber sorghum.... 4.72 7.16 j 4.88 I 29.58 56.12 2.26 Sudan grass 3.66 8.38 \ 5.85 I 34.84 I 48.92 2.01 Alfalfa ____..____..__.&lt;__ 3.51 9.71 18.38 i 29.08 ( 40.14 | 2.69 Yield per acre on a moisture-free basis - Crop | Nitro- I Hay Ash Crude | Crude gen-free Fat i protein \ fiber extract | Tons Tons Tons | Tons | Tons ; Tons I ! I Amber sorghum... 4.010 0.290 0.197 I 1.191 j 2.241 i 0.091 Sudan grass 3.112 0.262 0.194; 1.078 | 1.514 0.064 Alfalfa 2.978 0.289 0.546 ' 0.885 1.175 I 0.083 Si : i - 1 Analyses reported for sorghum and Sudan _rass are for forage harvested in the soft dough stage while those for alfalfa are averages of all cuttings made at a" normal stage of maturity. These crops were grown in adjacent fields. - The annual yields were calculated from the composition and yield of each cutting. Due to its high market and feeding value, rational feeding of alfalfa hay should be practiced at all times. Undue waste in feeding and overfeeding should be avoided. Alfalfa is more than a maintenance ration and when fed alone may result in an uneconomical use of protein due to its narrow nutritive ratio. This should be borne in mind when feeding a rela - tively fine or immature hay which is especially high in pro - tein. Experiments at the North Platte Substation, published in Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin No. 105, have shown that mixed feed consisting of one-half alfalfa and one-half prairie hay or one-half alfalfa and one-half cane gave approximately the same results as a full feed of alfalfa in wintering cattle. Alfalfa harvested in the earlier stages of maturity makes a more palatable hay, and has a somewhat higher protein con - tent and feeding value than alfalfa harvested in more mature </seg>
            <seg id="p027">■ ■• ■ Alfalfa in Nebraska stages. It does not follow, however, that the cutting of alfalfa in comparatively immature stages should be generally prac - ticed. The coarser hay or that harvested approximately when in full bloom is more desirable for horses than that harvested more immaturely since it is less laxative. On the other hand, the finer and more immature hay is desirable for feeding to hogs, sheep, and calves. The extensive harvesting of alfalfa in very immature stages, or earlier than one-tenth bloom, in order to increase the protein content and feeding value of the hay, is uneconomical. The cost of harvesting is increased due to the more frequent cuttings and as has been shown the acre yields of hay are materially lower than for alfalfa harvested when in one-tenth to one-half bloom. Furthermore, the continued harvesting of alfalfa in very im - mature stages results in premature thinning of the stand. As has been indicated, the proportion of leaves and protein content ordinarily become somewhat higher and the forage finer from the first to the last cutting of the season. The "hay from these later cuttings is thus more palatable and for most stock may be considered as having a somewhat higher feeding value than an equal amount of hay from the earlier cuttings. Alfalfa is also used to a considerable extent as a pasture crop. Prom the standpoints of palatability, feed value, and carrying capacity it is unexcelled. Grazing before the stand has become well established and pasturing continuously and closely results in rapid thinning of stand. Due to their ex - tremely close grazing, horses and sheep are more apt to in - jure the plants than are cattle and hogs. Frequent losses from bloat may be experienced where cattle and sheep are pastured on alfalfa. Since sweet clover is decidedly less dangerous in this respect it is replacing alfalfa to a marked extent as pasture for cattle and sheep. Without question alfalfa is the most desirable hog pasture. Hogs thrive on it, either as a sole or- supplementary growing or maintenance ration and as a supplementary fattening ration. Under proper management and otherwise favorable conditions a field of alfalfa may be retained as hog pasture for several years. I10H1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>