<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Local Prices of Farm Products in Nebraska, 1895-1932</title>
               <date value="1933-07">1933-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 284 JulyJ 1933 Local Prices of Farm Products in Nebraska, 1895-1932 H. C. FILLEY AND ARTHUR M. HAUKE Department of Rural Economics Mi I I i i I I II " 200 V&gt;^l 200 RwHEAT , 7J W 174 isc 14 \ i» . MLj\ !,„ 15 l«0O I»O5 I»IO ItU l»20 l»2i IK&gt;O 1832 Average annual prices paid to Nebraska farmers for wheat, corn, and oats fer bushelj; 1895-1932 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS ' Page Prices and Purchasing Power 3 Prices and Farm Business Planning 4 Price Cycles and Long Time Trends " .." 5 Uses of Price Information 5 Scope of Study. 6 Sources of Data 7 Division of State into Areas 9 Price Relatives _ 9 Index Numbers j JO Method of Determining Purchasing Power of Farm Products 12 Prices Paid Farmers for Specified Products £ 13 Wheat ......""...... 13 Corn 15 Oats ' 17 Hogs 19 Butter and Butterfat 20 Eggs _ 21 Potatoes 23 The Purchasing Power of Nebraska Farm Products 24 Wheat 24 Corn ' 26 Oats &#132;27 Hogs ; "" 29 Butter and Butterfat 31 Eggs ™..."..™.".r.1 34 Potatoes •_ , 3g Conclusions 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Local Prices of Farm Products m Nebraska, 1895-1932 H. C. PILLEY AND ARTHUR M. HAUKE The farmer, as a business man, is interested primarily m profits; and profits m farmink, as m other productive in - dustries, are not determined solely by the price at which tho products are sold, but by the relationship which exists be - tween the prices of the products sold and the expenses of production. Farmers must buy equipment and materials, and must provide laoor. They must pay rent, or take into account the capital invested m land and m improvements. EW if a farmer uses only family labor and thus avoids hiring other help, the labor is nevertheless an important item m the cost of production because the amount that the labor of the farmer and other members of his family would have earned had they been engaged m some alternative enter - prise must be regarded as a cost. Farmers are prosperous when the amount received for the product is considerably more than the "out of pocket" or actual money costs of production. They are receiving a satisfactory return upon their investment, relatively] high wages for their labor, and some reward for their risk and managerial ability. PRICES AND PURCHASING POWER Farm prosperity cannot be measured by comparing the prices of farm products at any given time with the prices of the same or similar products at some preceding period. Production costs may have varied either more or less; than the price of the products. For example, lifty cents a bushel for wheat m April, 1896, was a higher price relative to cost of production than fifty cents per bushel m April, 1931, even though the hours of labor required to produce a bushel of wheat decreased very materially between 1896 and 1931. It is of historical interest to know that eggs, butter, hogs, corn, cattle, and various other farm products sold at lower average prices from 1893 to 1896 thlan m 1930, but these prices of themselves prove nothing con - cerning the relative prosperity of the farmers durint the two periods. We must compare the price of farm products with the price of the things that farmers buy m order to get an accurate conception of relative prosperity. The price of farm products measured m dollars and cents is of much less importance to the farmer who is out of debii than is the purchasing power of those products measured m terms of farm equipment, clothing, furniture, and groceries. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 The farmer who must meet heavy debt and interest pay - ments is ordinarily more interested in the price of the products that he sells than in the price of the new goods that he might purchase. The debtor cannot entirely over - look purchasing power because a part of his income must be used to meet current living and operating expenses. prices and farm business planning When the price of a farm product is relatively high — that is, when a product sells at a considerable margin over cost of production — farmers tend to increase the produc - tion of that particular product. This usually results in larger quantities being sent to market, and the larger offerings are almost inevitably followed by a decline in price, because buyers will not purchase the larger offerings unless the price is lowered or the demand is increased. Conversely, when prices are low, compared with cost of production, the tendency is for some of the producers to go out of business or at least to decrease production, thereby decreasing the supply, with a resultant increase in price. Adjustment of production to demand-supply conditions always lags behind price adjustment. Price also exerts an influence upon the rate at which farm products are marketed. When the price of wheat, for example, is very low at threshing time there is a ten - dency for farmers to delay sale in the hope that prices will advance. Fat hogs and cattle are sometimes held on feed for weeks while the owners wait for an advance in price. There is also seasonal fluctuation in the prices of most farm products, the prices being lowest when the largest quantities are ready for market and highest when the accumulated costs of storage are largest. Wheat, for ex - ample, during the past 40 years has averaged about 10 cents per bushel lower in November than in the following May. Few persons wish to hold wheat until May, not only because of the cost of holding but because of the specu - lative risk due to unforeseen price changes. Plans for the production of most farm products must be made several months, and sometimes a year or more, be - fore the products can be sold. Once the crops are planted or the livestock is bred it is difficult for the farmer to in - crease or decrease production. His problem is less simple than that of the manufacturer who may close down a part or all of his plant upon short notice. While the fluctuations in prices of farm products from day to day, week to week, and month to month are of considerable importance to the farmer, the trend of prices over a period of years may have an even greater influence upon his profits. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 price cycles and long time trends The production and consequently the price of many farm products tend to run in cyccles. If the production of a product such as hogs increases for two or three yearsj the price ordinarily declines. The price decline is followed by a decrease in production. When the number of hogs coming to market decreases, the price increases and in turn stimulates production. We have also a long-time price trend, which is de - pendent, on the one hand, primarily upon the volume of money in circulation and the rapidity with which it circu - lates; it is dependent on the other hand, upon the volume of trade. Increasing the amount of money or substitutes for money, or increasing the rapidity of circulation, tends to increase prices, whereas increasing the volume of busi - ness transactions which must be carried on with a given volume of money tends to lower prices. The prices of most commodities, for example, were much higher from 1922 to 1930 than they were during the last decade of the nineteenth century. This is doubtless because the amount of money in circulation per capita, the use of substituted for money such as checks, and the rate of circulation have in - creased more rapidly than has the volume of goods to be bought and sold. The long-time price trend of any one product may vary materially from the average price trend of all commodities because of a variation in the efficiency of production. Some products, of which lumber is one, are materially higher in price than a century ago. Other products, wheat for ex - ample, are lower, primarily because of increased efficiency of production. The extension and contraction of credit influence prices in the same way as do extension and con - traction of money. uses of price information Considerable data have been assembled in recent years upon the prices paid for the principal farm produces at terminal markets. Much less data are available upon the prices actually paid to farmers at local points, although the value of local price data is probably greater than the value of terminal-market data. Among the uses of such information, the following are probably the most im - portant : 1. It supplies data for making a comparison of prices in different areas of the state. 2. It gives specific information upon price trends. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 3. It provides tables of actual prices. Such tables are essential to a study of cyclical changes. 4. It furnishes accurate information upon the prices which farmers actually receive. Terminal-market prices, on the other hand, do not always give an accurate reflection of what the farmer is receiving for his products. For ex - ample, the local-shipping price of corn in a considerable portion of Nebraska in a good crop year is ordinarily the price at Omaha or Kansas City, less transportation and handling charges. In a year when the corn crop is short, the price at the local shipping points is sometimes the Omaha or Kansas City price, plus transportation and handling charges. Changes in transportation costs and handling charges are ordinarily reflected in the margin between local prices and terminal-market prices. When - ever changes in these costs occur, the relationship between these two sets of prices changes. Important changes have taken place during the past fifty years. 5. From specific data on prices paid to farmers and from a table giving the index numbers of wholesale prices of all commodities, it is possible to compute the monthly and yearly purchasing power of each farm product. scope of study This study is necessarily limited to those products for which it was possible to secure fairly complete price data for a considerable number of years. The products for which data were secured are corn, wheat, oats, hogs, butter and butterfat, eggs, and potatoes. This list includes the major farm products of Nebraska except cattle and hay. Unfortunately farm prices could not be secured for any grade or class of cattle, because the sources from which the other prices were obtained seldom quoted any price for cattle, and when a price was quoted the class, weight, and condition were not specified. Hay prices were quoted by grades only at terminal markets, and the stand - ards for grades changed during the period under con - sideration. . _ .. As a matter of course, many more price quotations are available for recent years than for earlier periods. While it is possible to obtain a few quotations dating back to the early vears of statehood, not enough could be obtained in the earlier settled regions to be fully representative, while none were available for the areas settled later. No data older than 1895 are presented. This is, however, a suf - ficiently long period to include the lowest prices paid during the depression which followed the panic of 189d, and makes possible a comparison of the purchasing power </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Local Prices op Farm Products, 1895-1932 of farm products during that period of depression with the purchasing power during the depressions of more recent years. sources of data Local prices of farm products may be compiled from the account books of buyers and from the files of local news - papers which have published price quotations with some degree of regularity. Fortunately the Nebraska State His - torical Society has fairly complete files of most of the news - papers which have been published in Nebraska. 1 In [fact the Historical Society has the files of many papers wfuch have discontinued publication. This simplifies the collect - ing of data, since it is not necessary to visit the various newspaper offices in all parts of the state. 2 The task of going through the papers and collecting the prices is largely mechanical. One possible defect in the published prices is that a busy editor may sometimes have permitted quotations to stand for more than one week. Occasionally it is not possible to tell whether a specific price was a wholesale buying price or a retail selling price. This occurred more often with potatoes than with any other commodity. Although the published prices may not always reflect the exact prices paid to farmers, the trends and fluctuations are almost identical with those of prices obtained from other sources. Because of the very general interest in prices and price trends, which was one of the results of the depression of the middle nineties, the United States Department of Agri - culture has gradually broadened its activities to include the collection of considerable price data. Data for the principal Nebraska products have been collected since about 1908, and have been published annually under the title, Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, by the United States Department of Agriculture and the Nebraska State De - partment of Agriculture, in co-operation. The published figures are averages compiled from the reports of several hundred crop reporters who represent every portion of the state. A comparison of the price data contained in these re - ports with those published in newspapers reveals no yride discrepancy. The averages from the two sources are in fact almost identical. 1 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 187 gives data upon prices paid for corn, wheat, and oats at Columbus, Nebraska, from 187T to 1922. 'The authors are indebted to A. E. Sheldon, Director of the Nebraska State His - torical Society, for placing tho newspaper files at their disposal. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 Since the federal and state statistics are averages of a larger number of quotations than could be secured from newspapers, it has seemed advisable to use them for the years for which they are available. The prices in this bulletin for the years 1895 to 1909 are taken from news - papers and from 1910 to 1932 from federal and state statistics, except for butterfat, which are entirely from the newspapers until the end of 1920 and in part from news - papers for 1921 and 1922. As a preliminary step to compiling the newspaper price data the state was divided into four areas as shown in Figure 1. Three newspapers which published price quota - tions were selected for each area except Area 4, for which only one paper with a fairly complete record was available. The papers selected were as follows : AREA 1 The Wayne Herald, Wayne The Albion News, Albion The Tekamah Journal, Tekamah AREA 2 The Nebraska Signal, Geneva The Tecumseh Chieftian, Tecumseh The Blue Valley Blade, Seward AREA 3 The Grand Island Independent, Grand Island The Ord Quiz, Ord The Holdrege Citizen, Holdrege AREA 4 The Rushville Citizen, Rushville ....J*"" I t . t . . . S\ * I«"HT3k "XTr-i^ f*y I • ■•»• • o 1 1 ?! i__J? r^ W\ 1 }' . f 5*t5\ «^. 1 . i p.. .»Lo....i/i ...... t». &gt; /■ —^yf\^ AZ&amp;. •"" / l«*"«"l J \ 1— « — *-r TMtnaffi li ' |— ( [ \ I I ««»ti. ________ ...iiL t — Z ' S^~ "^ — «-|',1n« - |"""- YzZAZ _, y/b _______ iffi^A KXim Oj 4i«l»« IUMAIO H»Vt V* »O««IIW»«0 7" * **' I — j — fe^L r _i_jioj^_L___w__./ 7rrr\ eases »«»t»[»o»Tii»l __? jf ,♦* »•»•»»•» Jt —sins _~__\ I ? f V** &amp;»j an- _ - ■_- -Jtg w __B5a»r.H ••■•» jr j__. &gt;»•"» / /- y Tx r"*' 0 !/*^! ["""P^x^. Fig. 1. — Areas into which the state was divided for tabulating newspaper price data. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 The chief criterion used in selecting the newspapers was the completeness of the record of local prices. The loca - tion of a paper within any one of the four areas was a matter of secondary consideration. The price series in a paper was not always continuous. Some of the issues were missing and the price quotations were often omitted for weeks or months at a time. When this occurred, the omissions were filled in from files of other papers in the same town or nearby towns. After the weekly prices from each of the papers selected (and any prices from supplementary papers) were] com - piled, the monthly average price for each commodity was calculated. The monthly prices for each commodity as obtained from a given paper were then averaged with the monthly prices obtained from other papers in the same area in order to secure the average monthly price for each com - modity in each area. THE DIVISION OF STATE INTO AREAS As has been previously explained, the state was divided into four areas and the data for each area were tabulated separately. While prices varied somewhat from area to area, these variations were not large enough to warrant publishing the separate tables for each area. Wherever any very wide price variation occurred, it is mentioned in the discussion. In general, prices averaged somewhat higher in eastern Nebraska than in western Nebraska, primarily be - cause of the additional distance the products must be transported to reach eastern markets. There were some ex - ceptions to this general rule. Some of these exceptions are mentioned in the discussions which accompany the tables. For Areas 1, 2, and 3, it was possible to obtain data for the years 1895 to 1931. In Area 4, which includes the northwestern part of the state and which was settled some - what later, it was impossible to obtain data for yeark pre - ceding 1906, and for 1906 and for several years thereafter they could be obtained from only one paper. Price quota - tions in this paper were not always complete and as a re - sult there are some gaps in the data. The state averages for the years 1895 to 1905 are therefore of necessity aver - ages for only three of the four areas. PRICE RELATIVES In order to determine the rate at which the price of any commodity rises or falls, the average price for some period, such as a year or for a series of years, may be taken as a base. If the price at any other time is divided by the price for the base period, the quotient will show the percentage </seg>
            <seg id="p010">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 284 that the price for the time selected is of the price for the base period. For example, the average farm price of wheat in Nebraska for the five-year period, 1910-14, was 81 cents per bushel. The average price in 1932 was 33 cents. Dividing 33 by 81 gives .41. The price in 1932 was, therefore, 41 per cent of the price in the base period. If, then, we assign to the average price of wheat in 1910-14 the value of 100, the price of wheat in 1932 relative to it is 41. Such numbers are called price relatives. Since the prices of most farm products vary somewhat with the season, the average price for some one month in each year of a given period makes a better base with which to compare prices for the same month in other years than does an average yearly price. The average December farm price of wheat in Nebraska for the five years, 1910-14, was 82 cents per bushel. The average price in December, 1932, was 27 cents, which is 33 per cent of the average December price for the five years used as a base. The price relative of wheat for December, 1932, is therefore 33. In this study the price relative of each commodity for each month in each area was computed according to the plan just described. The tables for the various products therefore give not only the average monthly price of each product, but indicate the ratio between that price and the average price in the corresponding months of the years 1910-14. INDEX NUMBERS Changes in price levels — that is, in the purchasing power uf money — are indicated statistically by the use of index numbers. The average prices of a considerable number of commodities during some one year or for a term of years are taken as a base and are always given the value of 100. If the purchasing power of money decreases — that is, if prices go up — the index number will rise above 100, but if prices go down the index number will fall below 100. The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States De - partment of Labor is undoubtedly assembling more infor - mation upon general commodity prices than is any other organization in the United States. Its "all commodities" price index is at present (1933) based on the wholesale prices of 784 commodities. When the index was first con - structed a somewhat smaller number of articles was used, but the list was, nevertheless, large enough to be repre - sentative. The indexes were prepared quarterly for the years 1890-99 but have been published monthly since January, 1900. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 11 The Bureau of Labor Statistics 3 originally used the 10 - -year period, 1890-99, as a base. This base was afterward changed to 1913 and more recently to 1926. Computations necessary to place the index on the 1910-14 base havef been made by the Department of Farm Management. Cornell University, Ithaca, New York. 4 All index numbers used m this bulletin are therefore the index numbers prepared by Cornell University, based on the index numbers ox the Bureau of Labor Statistics. These index numbers are given m Table 1. Table 1. — Index numbers of wholesale prices of all corimod - ities, based on variable group weights * (1910-U=lv6) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Eec. Ay. 1895 68 69 69 72 78 7* 78 72 72 72 72 171 71 1896 70 69 69 68 67 66 66 66 66 08 70 fro 68 1897 68 68 68 67 66 66 66 69 71 70 70 F0 68 1898 70 71 71 71 76 71 70 70 70 70 70 J\ 71 1899 71 78 78 74 74 75 76 77 80 81 82 S3 77 1900 83 84 84 84 82 81 82 81 82 81 81 iO 82 1901 81 80 80 79 79 79 80 81 82 82 83 34 81 1902 83 83 83 84 85 86 86 85 86 92 89 )0 86 1903 91 91 88 88 86 86 86 86 87 86 85 35 87 1904 87 89 88 87 85 85 85 86 87 87 89 39 87 1905 89 89 88 88 87 87 87 88 87 87 88 89 88 1906 89 89 89 89 90 90 87 89 90 92 93 D 4 90 1907 93 95 94 94 96 97 97 97 97 98 94 32 95 1908 91 90 90 91 91 91 02 92 92 93 94 35 92 1909 94 95 95 97 98 9D 99 100 101 103 104 IDS 99 1910 104 104 106 107 105 104 104 108 162 99 97 97 103 1911 97 94 95 92 92 92 93 96 97 97 96 35 95 1912 96 97 99 102 102 101 101 102 103 103 103 102 101 1913 103 102 102 102 101 101 102 102 103 103 102 101 102 1914 100 100 99 99 98 98 99 101 108 99 99 B 8 99 1916 99 100 100 100 101 100 101 100 100 103 105 IDS 101 1916 112 115 117 119 121 121 122 124 127 138 142 145 125 1917 149 153 167 167 176 178 180 182 180 178 179 180 172 1918 183 179 185 187 187 188 193 196 201 199 199 199 191 1919 196 199 192 194 198 198 206 211 206 207 211 220 202 1920 23C 229 282 242 244 248 242 236 227 211 195 176 226 1921 167 158 160 144 141 136 136 187 186 137 138 1)6 143 1922 134 136 136 136 140 141 145 144 145 146 147 147 141 1923 149 151 153 152 149 147 144 143 146 145 144 143 147 1924 146 146 144 142 140 189 140 142 142 143 145 113 143 1925 150 152 162 149 148 160 162 152 151 161 153 151 151 1926 151 149 147 147 147 147 146 145 146 145 144 113 146 1927 141 140 188 187 138 187 188 139 141 141 141 111 139 1928 141 140 189 141 142 141 142 143 144 141 - 140 110 141 1920 140 139 140 139 188 189 141 141 140 189 187 116 189 1930 135 134 182 181 180 127 123 123 123 121 119 116 126 1981 114 112 111 109 107 105 105 105 104 103 103 100 107 1982 98 97 96 96 94 93 94 95 95 94 93 Bl 95 'Farm Economics. College of Agriculture. Ithaca, N. V. : No. 72, Sept 1931, p. 1587; No. 74, Febr. 1982, p. 1634; No. 80, May 1983, p. 1869. •Monthly Labor Review, Bureau of Labor Statistics, U. S. Department o:f Labor, Vols. 1 to 85. . Mitchell, Wesley C, Bulletin 284; Bureau of Labor Statistics, U. S. Department of Labor. * Farm Economics, Collesfe of Agriculture, Ithaca, New York. No. 72, ]&gt;. 1,587 ; No. 74, p. 1.681; No. 80, p. 1,869. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 12 METHOD OF DETERMINING PURCHASING POWER OF FARM PRODUCTS In order to determine the purchasing power of any com - modity, it is necessary to know the price relative of that commodity and the index number of all commodities, or of some group of commodities that are to be purchased. In order to determine the purchasing power of Nebraska wheat m December, 1932, for example, we compare the price relative of wheat for the month with the index num - ber of all commodities for the same time. The price rela - tive of wheat (Table 9) was 33, and the wholesale-com - modities index was 91 (Table 1). The purchasing power of wheat was, therefore, 36 per cent of pre-war (33 divided by 91 — .36, or 36 per cent). Wholesale prices are used because they are more nearly uniform than retail prices. The wholesale-price index is not, however, an absolutely representative index of the price that the Nebraska consumer pays. The more im - portant reasons for this are as follows : 1. The average margin added by retailers is not uniform over long periods. It has been wider m recent years than before the World War. 2. The relationship existing between the average whole - sale price m Nebraska and the average wholesale price m the United States may be altered by changes m freight costs and other handling charges. 3. The "all commodities" wholesale-price index includes various farm products as well as manufactured goods. The farmer is selling farm products and not buying them. When the price of farm products falls to a lower level relatively than the price of manufactured goods, the all - commodities index reaches a lower level than would an index based on the price of manufactured goods. Under such conditions farm products have less purchasing power than the statistics indicate. This is true at the present time (March, 1933), and has been true continuously since the autumn of 1920. The wholesale-price index is used, therefore, not because it is absolutely representative of consumer buying power, but because it is the most nearly representative of any data readily available. The reader should bear m mind that the true purchasing power may vary, and probably often does yary several points from the figure given. The trends shown m this bulletin are, however, correct. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Local Prices op Farm Products, 1895-1932 13 Table 2. — Wheat : Average monthly price m cents -per bushel received by producers m Nebraska, 1895-1932 \ Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. ijec Ay. 1805 45 44 46 49 48 54 52 49 SS 41 41 41 46 1896 42 46 60 48 48 42 89 37 37 48 64 59 46 1897 69 68 69 69 61 67 65 65 73 67 70 71 63 1898 68 72 76 76 95 75 59 53 49 48 48 48 64 1899 51 61 51 63 64 66 63 52 61 49 48 49 52 1900 47 48 48 49 48 64 67 54 65 55 52 52 52 1901 53 56 66 63 65 53 49 52 52 52 63 57 63 1902 61 60 68 57 59 58 57 54 63 60 50 50 56 1903 51 62 62 68 54 57 59 60 60 58 65 56 66 1904 66 65 71 72 70 71 71 81 90 94 92 88 77 1905 90 94 90 83 77 82 74 68 66 67 69 68 77 , 1906 65 64 69 62 64 64 69 54 54 56 56 58 60 1907 58 58 58 68 70 75 74 72 81. 86 80 34 71 1908 £2 82 82 82 83 83 80 78 80 82 84 84 82 1909 85 90 94 100 108 110 100 88 85 86 88 91 94 1910 93 92 92 92 90 86 86 88 86 S3 80 80 87 1911 80 78 74 76 76 76 74 76 82 88 88 88 80 1912 90 90 91 95 98 96 88 78 76 76 72 70 85 1918 72 74 74 74 76 76 73 72 72 72 71 72 73 1914 73 74 74 75 76 74 69 78 88 £9 94 100 80 1916 116 129 131 134 134 114 98 96 88 84 84 90 108 1916 100 99 92 92 92 86 93 116 135 160 160 155 114 1917 158 166 176 222 254 238 238 231 204 194 194 194 206 1918 194 196 198 198 198 199 200 200 200 199 198 108 198 1919 200 202 204 214 221 216 205 196 196 198 200 213 205 1920 226 221 220 283 243 246 226 210 206 184 151 135 209 1921 138 137 180 116 114 112 98 92 94 89 82 84 107 1922 89 102 110 109 108 99 91 86 84 89 95 98 97 1923 96 95 98 102 100 92 80 78 84 87 85 84 90 1924 87 88 90 88 85 87 94 105 102 120 122 33 100 1925 161 162 165 129 142 142 132 147 140 133 139 50 144 1926 156 152 143 139 137 138 117 117 114 119 121 20 131 1927 119 118 117 113 118 126 120 116 112 110 107 .12 115 1928 111 111 116 121 136 127 112 87 88 93 92 94 107 1929 93 100 100 95 84 83 97 104 106 104 95 00 97 1930 102 95 84 86 80 81 63 67 63 68 61 54 74 1931 54 54 54 55 56 44 28 31 32 30 45 39 44 1932 40 39 39 36 36 33 28 32 31 29 28 1 27 33 PRICES PAID FARMERS FOR SPECIFIED PRODUCTS WHEAT Table 2 gives the average monthly wheat-price quota - tions at country points from January, 1895, to December, 1932. This commodity averaged lower m price m October than m any other month and averaged highest ir May. The average monthly price range for the period is much less striking than the variation m the average yearly price. Wheat was low m price m 1895 and 1896 because of abundant world harvests, world-wide depression, and a low price level. The price increased from 37 cents m October, 1896, to 71 centa m December, 1897, primarily because of decreased world production m 1896 and a greater decrease m 1897. The 1898 world wheat crop was large and as a result the price fell from 95 cents a bushel m May, 1898, to 51 cents m January, 1899. The price ranged from 50 to 60 cents per bushel until February, 1904, when it started to rise because of a short world crop. It averaged 94 cents a bushel m October. During 1906 the price of wheat fell to </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 14 54 cents, the major cause of the drop being a new peak m production. Production fell again m 1907. The price went up to nearly 90 cents and remained between 70 and 90 cents per bushel until 1914. During the period from 1907 to 1913, world production increased nearly 500,000,000 bushels, but demand increased and prices remained at a fairly satisfactory level. Prices rose rapidly during the later months of 1914, primarily because of the outbreak of the World War. The price increase was aided by a slight decrease m world wheat production. The 1915 wheat crop was the largest ever produced. Prices receded somewhat but rose again the next year. The 1916 world crop was smaller than the 1915 crop by about 750,000,000 bushels. The 1917 crop was smaller than the 1916 crop. The average price quoted by country elevators m Nebraska m May, 1917, was $2.54. The United States government then established a minimum price on wheat, which was to all intents and purposes a maximum price. As a result of the stabilization program, the price of wheat remained relatively stable until all re - strictions were removed m the spring of 1920. Table 2 re - cords an average price of $2.43 for May, 1920. The world crop was large, deflation set m, and the price of wheat fell rapidly. It was only 92 cents per bushel m August, 1921, and ranged from 80 cents to $1.00 per bushel during the major part of the time until August, 1924, when it started to rise because of a decrease m the world crop. The de - mand for wheat continued strong until the late autumn of 1929 and large crops of wheat entered into consumption. The price fell during 1930 and 1931. The July, 1932, country-elevator prices averaged only 28 cents^ a bushel for the state. Some of the causes for the decline were as follows : 1. Large world crops. ..'.]. , 2. A world-wide depression, which decreased consump - tive demand. 3. International trade restrictions. 4. A decrease m the world price level. This decrease is attributed to several factors, among which the follow - ing are generally regarded to be most important : (a) Failure of the world supply of monetary gold to increase as fast as the needs of business de - manded. „ _ (b) Increased demand for gold by European nations which were striving to build up gold reserves. (c) The end of the "easy money" policy, which ex - isted m the United States from 1922 to 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 15 Nebraska wheat prices are not uniform throughout the state. The average prices m the three areas for data for the 38 years are available were as follows: Area 1, 93 cents; Area 2, 95 cents; Area 3, 92 cents; avWage price for the state, 93.3 cents. Wheat quotations m Area 4 m recent years have averaged about 2.5 cents below those of Area 3. The November, 1930, averages of the freight rates from Omaha, Nebraska, to each of the towns used as basic, points for data were as follows: Area 1, 8.1 cents per bushel; Area 2, 9.0 cents; Area 3, 9.8 cents; and Area 4, 11.8 cents. Except as influenced by other factors the price would be about one cent higher m Area 1 than m Area 2, about one cent higher m Area 2 than m Area 3, and about 2 cents higher m Area 3 than m Area 4. Other factors than transportation rates to Omaha have influenced the relative prices of wheat m the areas. Wheat is not an important crop m the major part of Area 1. [There is a tendency for wheat m Areas 2 and 3 to move to Gulf ports for export, and this has doubtless had an appreciable effect on price. CORN Table 3 gives the average monthly price quotations at the country points from which data were secured from January, 1895, to December, 1932. These average msnthly prices varied from a low of 10 cents per bushel m January, February, and March, 1897, to a high of $1.70 per aushel m June, 1920. The percentage variation m the pijice ot corn from year to year has been wider than the percentage variation m the price of wheat. The explanation for this difference m variation is very simple. Wheat is a world food crop. Our surplus is sold on the world market, and the domestic price m Nebraska is ordinarily the world price as reflected by the Liverpool, England, market, less transportation and handling charges. Corn, on the other hand, is a feed crop. The production m the United States is usually not less than three-fifths of the world production. Net exports since 1895 have aver - aged only about 2.6 per cent of our total production kind m recent years have been almost negligible. Since we [export but little corn when the crop is abundant, and import but little m short-crop seasons, it naturally follows that a change m domestic yield has a greater effect on price than it has on a crop like wheat that is widely grown and enters m a large way into international trade. Corn prices were high m the first seven months of 1895 m spite of the depression, because of the short crop o:t 1894. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 16 Table 3. — Corn: Average monthly price m cents per bushel received by producers m Nebraska, 18 95-1 932 Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. At. 1895 45 46 45 46 47 46 45 40 27 21 16 16 87 1896 14 15 17 15 15 18 IS 18 11 12 12 11 IS 1897 10 10 10 11 12 12 14 16 18 15 15 16 13 1898 15 17 18 19 23 22 21 21 19 21 21 23 20 1899 25 25 24 24 24 24 23 20 21 21 21 21 23 1900 22 28 27 28 28 29 80 28 29 29 26 26 27 1901 81 28 29 32 34 S3 87 47 49 49 53 56 40 1902 56 61 60 49 52 49 60 45 45 42 S3 29 46 1908 27 27 27 27 29 32 86 36 36 30 27 27 80 1904 28 88 35 39 41 37 88 40 39 39 83 31 36 1905 81 34 86 85 37 38 41 40 40 37 84 SO 86 1906 30 29 29 82 85 36 88 86 85 84 82 80 88 1907 29 29 29 80 87 40 40 42 48 49 42 42 88 1908 47 49 62 64 68 62 64 66 64 68 62 50 66 1909 50 62 64 56 60 62 60 67 56 53 50 51 65 1910 63 68 62 49 48 50 62 63 60 44 88 86 48 1911 36 86 36 88 42 46 52 66 66 59 68 54 47 1912 66 67 69 66 72 72 69 68 65 67 44 88 60 1918 40 42 44 46 49 62 66 64 72 70 66 64 56 1914 68 61 62 64 66 66 64 67 68 63 56 64 63 1915 60 64 64 64 64 64 66 67 64 57 60 50 61 1916 64 65 55 68 60 63 68 72 73 76 78 78 66 1917 80 85 96 122 142 148 178 181 166 161 185 122 184 1918 124 184 140 136 140 142 146 152 151 134 125 IS4 188 1919 182 126 184 148 166 160 172 176 154 180 122 124 144 1920 127 126 130 143 166 163 143 127 106 72 61 42 116 1921 40 88 88 86 86 88 88 34 80 26 25 28 84 1922 29 86 41 41 43 44 44 45 44 48 66 58 44 1928 68 68 60 66 74 74 72 70 70 70 62 62 65 1924 56 60 60 61 61 65 87 92 94 94 87 100 76 1925 107 105 101 88 96 98 95 93 84 69 67 61 89 1926 62 68 65 55 68 60 63 75 74 74 70 70 64 1927 67 66 64 65 73 84 87 89 84 75 62 66 74i 1928 64 68 75 80 90 83 87 80 83 79 72 70 78 1929 78 78 78 76 75 78 81 85 87 81 70 67 77 1930 66 65 60 65 64 66 68 77 79 69 62 62 65 1931 47 42 41 41 40 38 40 88 86 29 37 86 39 1932 85 82 81 28 26 26 26 26 22 16 13 13 24 Prices were very low m the early months of 1897, following excellent crops m 1895 and 1896. Prices rose sharply following the short crops of 1901 and 1913. They also rose during the World War, as did other prices, and collapsed during the post-war deflation. Since most corn is used for feed, high meat prices are followed by an increase m the demand for corn, which m turn influences the price of corn. Conversely, low meat prices are followed by low corn prices, because meat pro - duction is decreased when feed is high m price m relation to the price of the finished product. Very cheap corn has been followed invariably by an increase m pork production and very high prices by a decrease. The average prices m the areas, except m Area 4, for the 38 years were as follows: Area 1, 57 cents; Area 2, 58 cents; Area 3, 61 cents; average for state, 58.7 cents. When we compare area prices m different periods, the variations are far from uniform. For the first 10 years, 1895-1904, the average prices were as follows: Area 1, </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 17 27.7 cents; Area 2, 29.9 cents; and Area 3, 28.4 centsj For the 10 years 1923-32, the average prices were as follows: Area 1, 66.9 cents; Area 2, 65.2 cents; Area 3, 66.2 cents; and Area 4, 63.2 cents. The price differential between eastern Nebraska and western Nebraska varies more from year to year for corn than for wheat. This is accounted for m major part by the influence of local demand and local supply upon price. Whenever the corn crop was good m western Nebraska m the early years of the period for which statistics are pre - sented, the price was several cents lower than ir the eastern part of the state. The average price m Area 3in 1898, for example, was 18 cents and m Area 2 was 22 cents. Corn yielded well m Area 3in 1898 and the sv rplus was shipped to other markets. On the other hand, when - ever the crop m southwestern Nebraska is insufficient to supply domestic need, and more corn is shipped into the region than is shipped out, the price rises. For example, m 1895 the average price of corn m Area 3 was 41 cents and m Area 2 was 35 cents. In December, 1926, the aver - age price of corn m Area 1 was 67 cents, m Area 2 it was 71 cents, and m Area 3 it was 80 cents. In recent years there has been a material movement of corn from central and western Nebraska to the Pacific states. Much corn has also moved into the feeding I areas of the North Platte valley and to other western areas where corn production is insufficient to meet consumption heeds. This western movement of corn has been sufficient m some years to consume the surplus of the western part of the state and raise the price as high as that m central Nebraska, or higher. This occurred m the fall of 1932, because jot" the combined effects of a small crop and a good demand from local feeders and western shippers. In the 1895-1904 period, country elevators quoted a higher price for corn m Area 2 than m Area 1. In the 1923-32 period, corn-price quotations were higher m Area 1 than m Area 2. During the years intervening between these two periods hog production and cattle feeding m northeastern Nebraska increased until m many localities insufficient corn was ordinarily produced to supply the local demand. The local price at these deficit points during a part of the year is, therefore, the price of corn at the nearest corn-surplus market plus transportation and hand - ling costs. QATs The lowest average oat prices m Nebraska during the past 38 years, according to the data secured and presented </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 18 Table 4. — Oats: Average monthly price m cents per bushel received by producers m Nebraska, 1895-1932 Year Jan. Feb. liar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 1895 81 29 81 81 81 81 21 16 12 IS 12 12 22 1896 12 12 18 18 12 1111 12 11 11 11 11 11 1897 11 11 1111 11 11 12 12 18 18 14 14 12 1898 16 18 19 20 28 21 17 17 16 18 20 21 18 1899 22 28 22 23 28 21 19 16 16 17 18 19 20 1900 19 19 19 21 20 19 20 17 18 18 18 20 19 1901 20 21 21 22 23 24 26 30 80 32 34 38 27 1902 89 88 38 36 87 86 85 28 25 24 22 24 32 1903 25 26 25 25 26 28 27 26 27 27 25 26 26 1904 28 82 82 32 82 32 80 27 25 23 23 23 28 1905 28 24 24 23 24 24 24 20 20 21 22 23 28 1906 24 24 24 25 26 28 28 24 23 24 25 26 26 1907 28 80 82 32 85 36 34 85 40 40 35 39 35 1908 41 41 42 44 44 44 48 42 41 40 40 41 42 1909 42 42 44 46 49 60 46 38 34 35 35 36 41 1910 88 40 40 38 36 86 86 34 82 30 28 28 85 1911 20 28 28 26 28 81 35 36 38 40 42 42 83 1912 44 46 49 52 52 50 44 34 30 30 30 30 41 1918 80 80 31 32 34 36 36 38 39 88 38 38 85 1914 88 87 37 37 88 36 33 34 89 40 40 41 38 1915 44 46 48 48 48 44 42 S9 34 30 80 32 40 1916 36 87 86 87 86 36 35 36 38 41 44 46 88 1917 49 61 53 60 64 62 64 58 50 62 56 64 67 1918 70 75 78 78 74 70 66 68 64 64 64 65 69 1919 64 60 60 64 66 66 68 68 64 62 63 68 65 1920 72 74 78 85 92 96 80 62 56 48 40 38 69 1921 36 34 33 30 28 29 26 23 22 22 21 20 27 1922 24 27 28 28 29 80 30 28 27 30 84 35 29 1923 86 36 88 40 42 88 84 31 32 34 34 35 36 1924 86 39 41 40 40 41 45 42 41 43 43 47 42 1925 51 51 61 43 44 44 48 39 86 36 36 36 43 1926 88 88 38 38 89 38 39 41 40 41 40 41 39 1927 48 45 45 45 47 49 45 41 39 40 40 42 43 1928 48 45 48 50 63 64 49 32 34 37 88 39 44 1929 41 44 44 44 42 41 40 87 39 89 38 38 40 1930 87 87 36 37 35 34 27 SO 31 29 27 27 82 1931 27 27 27 27 25 24 20 19 20 20 23 23 24 1932 28 24 25 24 23 21 15 12 12 10 10 10 17 m Table 4, occurred m the last seven months of 1896 and the first six months of 1897. During 12 of these 18 months the average price was only 11 cents per bushel. The general trend m the price of oats was upward from the latter part of 1897 until May, 1920. A short crop was usually followed by a noticeable increase m price, and a large crop by a decrease m price. The price rose rapidly during the war years and declined even more rapidly fol - lowing the collapse of the post-war boom. The average price quoted for oats for the 10 years, 1896 - -1905, was 21.4 cents m Area 1, 21.8 cents m Area 2, and 22 cents m Area 3. During the 10 years, 1923-32, the average prices were as follows: Area 1, 34.8 cents; Area 2, 35-8 cents; Area 3, 38.1 cents; and Area 4, 34.7 cents. The higher prices m Areas 2 and 3 during the past 10 years were due primarily to short crops of oats. For example, m 1926 oats were a short crop m Area 3, and the price aver - aged 49 cents. In Area 1, where oat yields were good, the price was only 42 cents. In 1931 the average price quoted for each area was 22 cents. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 19 HOGS Monthly and yearly averages of hog prices are given m Table 5. A study of the table indicates that hog prices as a general thing are lower m December and January than m the late summer and early autumn. The average yearly prices also indicate that prices were low m the early years of the period studied, and rose gradually until the World War, when they practically doubled within two years. The average hog-price quotations for 1932 were lower than for any preceding year of the 38 for which prices are pre - sented. The tables for the different areas show fluctuations due to market development. The price of hogs during the years 1895-1904 averaged $4.26 m Area 1, $4.27 inTArea 2, and $4.12 m Area 3. During the 10 years, 1923-32, the price averaged $8.38 m Area 1, $8.22 m Area 2, and $8.30 m Area 3. The increase m price m Area 1 as compared with Area 2 is undoubtedly due m major part to the de - velopment of the packing industry m Sioux City, which has Table 5. — Hogs: Average monthly price m dollars per 100 pounds received by producers m Nebraska, 1895-1932 Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 1895 8.74 8.41 8.61 4.05 8.99 8.90 4.10 8.97 8.73 3^87 3.14 "" S.loO 3.67 1896 3.18 3.65 8.48 8.14 2.76 2.63 2.60 2.47 2.48 2.60 2.94 2.80 2.89 1897 2.E4 2.86 3.28 3.39 8.26 2.96 2.86 3.21 3.55 3.20 2.96 2J89 3.10 1898 3.03 3.82 8.41 8.36 8.73 8.57 3.28 3.44 3.30 3.20 8.11 8.03 3.32 1899 3.18 3.21 8.19 3.29 3.23 8.26 8.49 3.80 8.87 3.89 8.60 3.48 3.46 1900 4.00 4.28 4.89 4.82 4.71 4.60 4.57 4.63 4.67 4.49 4.27 4.37 4.48 1901 4.55 4.79 5.02 6.33 6.22 6.34 5.25 5.31 5.94 5.63 ' 5.12 5.54 5.25 1902 6.67 5.52 5.63 6.57 6.54 6.65 7.01 6.49 6.62 6.35 5.72 5.57 6.18 1903 5.84 6.20 6.57 6.68 5.99 6.35 4.92 4.75 5.11 6.05 4.80 3.90 5.40 1904 4.22 4.47 4.61 4.42 4.18 4.45 4.59 4.36 4.89 4.74 4.34 4.22 4.46 1906 4.15 4.23 4.46 4.82 4.74 4.73 4.91 5.21 4.86 4.48 4.30 4.34 4.60 1906 4.73 5.24 6.64 5.73 6.73 6.84 5.87 6.53 5.37 5.68 6.47 5.57 6.53 1907 5.87 6.35 6.10 5.93 6.84 5.66 5.87 6.41 6.34 5.43 4.14 3.94 6.44 1908 3.79 3.74 4.10 4.97 4.86 4.90 6.44 6.68 6.93 6.28 COS 4.94 4.89 1909 5.23 5.43 6.73 6.10 6.28 6.40 6.78 6.69 6.91 6.94 6.98 7.44 6.41 1910 7.80 7.90 9.20 9.80 8.40 8.50 7.80 7.40 8.30 7.80 7.20 6.70 8.02 1911 7.10 6.60 6.20 5.60 6.80 6.40 5.70 6.50 6.30 5.80 5.70 5.50 5.98 1912 5.60 5.50 5.80 7.00 7.00 6.80 6.70 7.20 7.60 8.00 7.10 6.80 6.76 1913 6.60 7.20 7.80 8.20 7.60 7.80 B.OC 7.60 7.40 7.60 7.10 6.100 7.48 1914 7.40 7.70 7.80 7.90 7.60 7.40 7.90 8.20 8.00 7.00 6.90 G. 40 7.52 1915 6.80 6.00 6.00 6.80 6.70 6.70 6.60 6.20 6.50 7.80 6.10 680 6.38 1916 6.20 7.20 8.60 8.60 8.90 8.60 8.90 8.90 9.60 8.80 8.90 9.00 8.50 1917 9.60 11.00 13.70 15.00 14.90 14.50 14.30 15.50 16.80 16.90 15.90 16.20 14.52 1918 15.30 15.10 16.80 16.90 16.10 15.60 16.00 17.60 18.30 16.90 16.00 IG.IO 16.22 1919 16.10 16.10 17.00 18.80 19.10 18.90 20.40 20.00 14.90 13.40 13.20 12 20 16.68 1920 13.20 13.20 13.20 12.80 12.80 18.00 13.40 13.40 13.90 13.30 11.20 800 12.62 1921 8.00 7.90 8.70 7.00. 7.30 6.60 7.90 8.20 6.30 6.20 5.70 550 7.11 1922 6.80 8.40 8.90 9.00 9.10 9.20 8.80 7.70 7.50 7.60 7.10 700 8.04 1923 7.40 7.20 7.00 7.00 6.60 5.60 6.00 6.30 7.60 6.70 6.00 680 6.59 1924 610 6.00 6.80 6.30 6.80 6.10 6.30 8.20 8.80 9.30 8.30 810 7.18 1925 910 9.50 12.20 11.80 10.70 10.80 12.30 12.30 11.00 10.80 10.10 980 10.87 1926 10.70 11.80 11.50 11.00 11.70 12.90 12.40 11.20 11.80 11.80 11.00 10 70 11.64 1927 10.70 10.90 10.60' 10.10 8.80 7.90 8.20 8.70 9.60 9.50 8.60 780 9.51 1928 7.40 7.20 7.20 7.60 8.80 8.60 9.70 9.90 11.50 9.30 8.30 7-20 8.56 1929 800 8.90 10.20 10.40 9.90 9.80 10.40 10.20 9.20 . 8.70 8.10 8.20 9.33 1930 860 9.40 9.50 9.00 8.80 9.00 8.00 8.30 9.30 8.60 7.90 7.10 8.62 1931 690 6.80 6.60 6.60 5.90 5.30 5.90 6.90 5.00 4.30 3.90 3.30 5.49 1932 3.30 3.00 3.60 3.20 2.40 2.30 4.10 3.86 3.45 2.80 2.65 2.30 3.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 20 decreased the distance which northern Nebraska hog pro - ducers must ship, and the development of shipment by truck, which has given more satisfactory short haul service. The increase m relative price m Area 3 is apparently due m major part to the demand of western markets for light hogs. The Pacific coast does not produce enough hogs to supply the demand for fresh pork and the western half of Nebraska is one of the nearest sources of supply. BUTTER AND BUTTERFAT Table 6is a composite table. The price of country butver is quoted for the years 1895-1919 and the price of butter - fat for the years 1920-32. The reason for presenting the quotations for these two closely related commodities m one table is that statistics were not available for either for the entire period. During the early years no quotations were Table 6. — Butter and Butterfat: Average monthly price m cents per pound received by producers m Nebraska, 1895 - --1932 Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aub. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 18S5 IB 14 12 12 13 11 11 1111 13 11 15 12 1896 14 10 11 10 9 b 8 10 10 11 11 12 10 1897 12 12 10 11 10 9 9 10 10 13 13 14 11 1898 14 12 12 1111 11 10 12 18 14 15 15 12 1899 18 18 12 12 11 11 11 12 18 16 16 16 13 1900 16 16 16 18 13 13 14 15 16 16 16 15 15 1901 15 14 13 13 12 13 13 13 14 14 15 15 14 1902 15 16 IT 18 16 16 15 14 14 17 18 19 16 1903 18 15 14 14 14 14 14 13 14 16 17 17 15 1904 15 16 14 15 14 12 12 12 13 15 15 16 14 1905 17 19 19 18 17 15 14 15 15 17 18 19 17 1906 18 17 17 16 14 13 13 14 15 18 18 19 16 1907 19 21 21 20 18 15 15 16 17 20 19 20 18 1908 2C, 21 20 19 18 18 18 18 18 19 21 24 20 1909 28 21 20 21 21 20 20 20 22 24 26 26 22 1910 26 24 24 24 22 22 22 23 28 25 26 26 24 1911 21 18 16 16 17 16 17 18 18 22 24 26 19 1912 27 25 24 24 23 20 20 20 22 24 27 27 24 1918 26 24 25 26 25 24 28 24 25 26 27 26 25 1914 26 22 22 19 20 20 20 22 25 25 26 26 23 1915 27 25 24 23 22 22 22 22 22 23 25 28 24 1916 27 28 29 29 26 25 25 27 27 30 33 33 28 1917 82 82 82 37 34 34 84 36 40 41 42 44 37 1918 45 46 42 40 88 37 40 40 48 54 55 60 45 1919 62 45 55 58 68 60 60 54 66 65 69 71 58 BUTTERFAT 1920 59 66 59 50 64 52 52 50 54 52 51 39 53 1921 42 84 36 37 24 21 28 31 32 32 37 35 32 1922 23 28 27 28 28 29 29 25 28 28 31 36 28 1928 43 41 SO 46 86 82 80 34 40 39 45 47 39 1924 EG 45 42 34 32 33 82 28 29 29 31 36 35 1925 83 31 35 35 34 34 34 37 37 37 43 43 36 1926 38 37 37 35 34 34 83 33 36 40 40 42 37 1927 41 42 44 44 88 87 36 35 37 40 42 44 40 1928 46 48 45 48 41 42 40 40 43 43 44 46 48 1929 44 44 48 45 44 42 41 41 42 42 37 84 42 1930 28 81 31 35 32 26 27 33 37 S3 80 24 81 1931 28 20 26 23 17 17 18 22 25 29 25 24 22 1932 20 16 17 14 18 12 12 17 16 16 16 19 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 21 published for butterfat and during the later years the papers did not quote the price offered for butter. During a part of the period most of the papers quoted prices for both butter and butterfat. The lowest average price quoted for either product was 8 cents for butter m June and July, 1896. The highest average quotation was 7L cents for butterfat m December, 1919. During the years 1895-1904 the average prices quoted for butter were as follows: Area 1, 12.8 cents; Area 2, 14.2 cents; Area 3, 13 cents. During the last 10 years the prices for butterfat averaged as follows : Area jl , 34.4 cents; Area 2, 33.9 cents; Area 3, 34.0 cents; and Area 4, 34.1 cents. These prices indicate that prices quoted for butiier and butterfat vary less widely over the state than do the prices quoted for many other farm products. The individual papers, however, showed considerable variation within a given area. Butterfat prices are apparently less stable over the state as a whole than the preceding averages in - dicate. EGGS The trend of egg prices was upward for the years 1895 - -1916, with the low points of 6 cents m June, 1896; June, July, and August, 1897; and July, 1898. The average farm price did not rise above 30 cents a dozen durug any month until November, 1916, when it stood at 31 cents. The total spread m nearly 21 years was only 24 cents. During the World War the price of eggs rose materially. The highest average price for any month was 61 cents m December, 1919. The yearly price cycle is indicated clearly m Table 7. Eggs are lowest m price m late spring and early summer and highest m price m late fall and early winter. The average price quoted for eggs for the 38-yeai| period was 19.3 cents m Area 1; 19.9 cents m Area 2; aid 19.3 cents m Area 3. During the first 10 years of the period, the average prices m these three areas were 11.4 cents, 11.9 cents, and 12.1 cents, respectively. During! the 10 years from 1923 to 1932 the average prices secured for the four areas (newspaper data) were as follows: Area 1, 24.1 cents; Area 2, 22.6 cents; Area 3, 21.6 cents; and Area 4, 22.5 cents. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 22 Table 7. — Eggs: Average monthly price m cents per dozen received by producers m Nebraska, 189 5-19 32 Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jnnc July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 1895 16 16 12 9 10 8 8 8 9 12 15 15 11 1896 IS 9.8 8 7 6 7 7 8 12 14 15 9 1897 18 12 9 8 7 6 6 6 9 9 18 16 9 1898 14 10 8 7 7 7 6 7 8 12 IB 17 10 1899 16 18 12 10 10 10 9 8 10 13 14 15 12 1900 14 10 ' 9 8 9 8 7 8 10 18 16 18 11 1901 16 . 14 12 11 9 8 7 8 10 IS 16 18 12 1902 17 18 IS 12 12 12 12 IS 13 17 17 20 15 190S 18 IS 12 11 11 10 10 10 13 16 19 22 14 1904 19 21 13 13 14 12 12 13 15 15 20 21 16 1905 20 23 14 14 18 12 10 12 18 16 19 21 16 1906 18 IS 1111 12 12 12 13 14 17 21 24 15 1907 20 19 14 12 12 11 11 11 14 17 20 21 15 1908 20 17 12 11 12 12 12 12 14 17 23 27 16 1909 24 21 16 16 16 16 16 16 18 20 24 27 19 1910 28 24 18 17 17 16 14 14 17 20 24 26 20 1911 22 16 14 12 12 12 12 13 15 18 23 26 16 1912 27 24 20 16 16 14 14 14 16 20 24 24 19 1913 22 20 16 15 15 14 13 13 16 21 28 SO 19 1914 28 22 19 15 15 15 15 16 20 20 23 27 20 1915 27 22 16 16 15 14 IS 14 17 20 26 27 19 1916 25 25 15 17 17 17 17 17 20 27 31 35 21 1917 SS 82 23 28 29 28 25 26 32 84 SG 40 31 1918 42 42 29 28 28 24 27 29 33 3D 45 55 85 1919 50 80 SI 84 37 31 80 33 84 46 66 66 40 1920 52 42 86 34 85 SI 81 36 42 47 65 68 42 1921 49 25 24 18 15 16 20 23 23 32 42 42 27 1922 23 27 16 18 18 16 16 14 19 25 34 41 22 1928 SO 25 21 20 18 17 16 17 22 26 37 36 23 1924 29 28 17 17 17 18 19 21 26 29 37 43 26 1926 43 29 22 22 22 28 24 25 24 29 39 39 29 1926 SI 28 21 24 24 23 22 22 26 31 36 40 27 1927 80 25 19 17 17 24 17 17 22 29 32 .14 24 1928 SI 24 21 21 23 21 22 22 25 27 81 36 26 1929 27 28 24 21 22 23 23 24 26 30 36 38 27 1930 31 27 18 19 16 15 13 13 18 18 24 20 19 1931 16 9 16 14 10 10 10 11 12 16 21 28 14 1932 14 10 7 8 9 7 8 11 13 19 22 25 13 Eggs have dropped more m price from December to Janu - ary m recent years, not only m cents per dozen but m per cent of December price, than m the earlier years for which data are presented. This change is a result of improve - ments m poultry and egg production. Chickens are better housed than formerly, and a larger proportion are fed a well balanced ration. Hens that are warmly housed and fed an egg producing ration will lay many more eggs dur - ing the winter months than hens that do not have proper care. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Local Prices op Farm Products, 1895-1932 23 POTATOES Potato price data were secured from Areas 2 and 3 only. The price variation for potatoes between areas was. wider than for any other product studied. One reason for this is that the price quotations from Area 3 were m major part terminal-market prices, less transportation and handling. The price quotations m Area 2 were to a considerable ex - tent the prices which farmers received for potatoes sold m competition with potatoes shipped m from western Ne - braska and other potato-surplus areas. Table 8. — Potatoes: Average monthly price m cen^ts per bushel received by producers m Nebraska, 1895-19^32 Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 1895 82 86 86 83 83 80 55 42 83 83 31 35 61 1896 82 83 36 82 83 S3 35 29 26 23 24 28 30 1897 32 81 32 83 37 42 44 44 46 63 55 55 42 1898 54 61 51 61 49 61 55 50 47 42 87 37 49 1899 87 43 63 86 89 78 65 28 24 31 23 20 48 1900 21 21 21 19 19 25 38 31 40 46 50 51 32 1901 59 61 62 60 65 81 110 120 117 113 103 106 88 1902 110 112 115 116 180 121 62 41 35 30 26 26 77 1903 29 SO 30 28 27 83 64 54 68 73 62 60 46 1904 64 68 76 84 93 112 67 45 28 26 24 26 59 1905 27 31 29 27 26 45 59 46 89 34 36 37 36 1906 88 42 44 40 38 51 64 67 65 49 48 49 49 1907 61 64 64 65 74 89 97 75 77 72 77 69 72 1908 69 71 71 74 78 87 90 69 54 51 47 47 66 1909 68 62 68 78 S3 94 86 72 70 64 60 60 72 1910 62 64 63 66 50 58 78 92 98 94 86 84 74 1911 82 82 84 92 100 162 208 175 114 96 90 95 114 1912 100 114 128 142 162 148 122 86 66 64 60 63 101 1913 66 66 62 53 62 66 74 86 84 78 76 80 67 1914 82 83 89 92 91 108 118 95 82 66 56 58 85 1915 64 69 66 64 68 75 82 72 57 46 41 60 64 1916 67 82 87 88 88 92 96 96 96 110 136 154 100 1917 156 192 288 276 298 293 239 166 186 114 106 10S 193 1918 104 113 118 102 92 124 162 168 166 124 114 124 125 1919 128 180 124 116 122 148 194 226 216 191 188 182 164 8K SS ?ol » £ !S SS £ 52 111 !S S ig SS i 4 S 4i V *S 10 55 T* II II SI B S 1! S R ?I II 8 ?7 $ 11? 1?9 J2 I ill 189 At 1926 215 224 220 240 286 210 210 160 146 140 160 170 194 1927 170 170 160 165 174 220 235 160 110 76 76 80 149 I 8 H 8 £ iS iS 1?5 iS 12$ II € € x i To " 9 °o *s s "« "o s s s m \lll 53 55 52 5J 58 65 60 46 34 27 27 31 46 THE PURCHASING POWER OF NEBRASKA FARM PRODUCTS WHEAT Table 9 gives the monthly price relatives of wheat for the years 1895-1932, based on the average monthlY prices for the years 1910-14. Table 10 gives the purchasing power of wheat m Nebraska for each month from January, 1895 to December, 1932. The data contained m Table 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 24 for the years 1916-32 are presented graphically m Figure 2. The effect of the commodity-price level upon purchasing power is clearly indicated. The price relative of wheat m December, 1895, was 50 and the purchasing power was 70 ; the price relative m December, 1921, was 102 but the pur - chasing power was only 75. The lowest purchasing power of wheat during the period discussed m this bulletin and m fact the lowest purchasing power for any time for which Nebraska records are avail - able B was m July, 1931, when a bushel of wheat would buy only 34 per cent as much of "all commodities" as m the five-year period preceding the war. The purchasing power m terms of "commodities purchased by farmers" was some - what smaller than m terms of "all commodities". The farm purchasing power of wheat did not exceed 50 per cent of pre-war m any month of 1932. TABLE 9. — Wheat: Price relatives by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-14=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nuv. Dec. Ay. 1895 56 54 67 59 58 6G 67 62 47 50 51 50 57 1896 61 57 62 58 68 61 60 47 46 69 67 72 57 1897 72 71 73 72 74 70 70 83 90 82 86 86 77 1898 88 88 93 92 114 92 76 68 61 59 59 58 79 1899 62 63 63 64 65 69 68 66 63 60 69 60 64 1900 58 69 69 59 68 66 73 69 68 68 64 63 64 1901 65 68 68 64 66 66 63 66 64 64 65 69 66 1902 76 74 72 69 71 71 78 69 66 61 62 61 69 1903 62 64 64 64 65 70 76 76 74 71 68 68 69 1904 69 80 88 87 84 87 91 103 111 115 114 107 95 1905 110 115 111 101 93 100 95 87 82 82 85 83 95 1906 80 79 73 75 77 78 76 69 67 69 69 71 74 1907 71 71 72 70 84 92 96 92 100 106 99 102 88 1908 100 100 101 99 100 102 10S 99 99 101 104 102 101 1909 104 110 116 121 130 135 128 112 105 106 109 111 116 1910 114 113 114 112 108 105 110 112 106 102 99 98 107 1911 98 96 91 92 92 93 95 97 101 108 109 107 99 1912 110 110 112 115 118 118 113 99 94 92 89 85 104 1913 88 91 91 90 90 93 94 92 89 S8 88 88 90 1914 89 91 91 91 92 91 88 99 109 109 116 122 99 1915 142 168 162 163 161 140 126 122 109 103 104 110 133 1916 122 121 114 112 111 106 119 148 167 184 197 189 141 1917 194 208 217 269 306 292 305 294 252 238 239 236 254 1918 238 240 244 240 238 244 256 265 247 244 244 241 244 1919 245 247 252 260 266 263 263 250 242 243 247 260 263 1920 277 270 271 283 298 301 290 268 254 226 186 165 258 1921 170 163 160 141 137 137 126 117 116 109 101 102 132 1922 109 126 136 132 130 121 117 110 104 109 117 119 120 1923 118 116 121 124 120 113 103 99 104 107 106 102 111 1924 107 108 111 107 102 107 120 134 126 147 150 162 123 1925 185 198 191 166 171 174 169 187 173 163 172 183 177 1926 191 186 176 169 165 169 160 149 141 146 149 146 162 1927 146 144 144 187 142 163 164 147 138 135 132 136 142 1928 136 186 143 147 164 166 144 111 109 114 114 115 132 1929 114 122 123 115 101 102 124 133 181 128 117 122 120 1930 125 116 104 104 96 99 81 85 78 71 63 66 91 1931 66 66 67 67 68 54 36 40 40 37 56 48 54 1932 49 48 48 44 43 40 36 41 38 36 84 33 41 * H. C. Filley and E. A. Frerichs, Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 187. p. 28. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Local Prices op Farm Products, 1895-1932 25 ITSI [-7 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 I&lt;™ l\ WjHEAT uo ULX- — &gt;so A-^-%^ IK S^L J*_l_» „ )\fpl : \rk~ V \ as : « im an »i&gt; Kit iko imi mv mi hrn Ml m* imt nil iin mo »)i na Fig. 2. — The purchasing power of wheat, corn, and oats m Nebraska, (1910-14=100). Table 10. — Wheat: Purchasing power by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-14=100) [ Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 1895 80 78 83 82 79 89 92 86 65 69 71 70 80 1896 73 83 90 85 87 77 76 71 70 87 96 103 84 1897 JO6 104 107 107 112 106 106 120 127 117 123 123 113 1898 119 124 131 130 150 180 109 97 87 84 84 82 111 1899 87 86 86 86 88 92 89 86 79 74 72 72 83 1900 70 70 70 70 71 81 89 85 83 84 79 79 78 1901 80 85 86 81 84 82 72 82 78 78 78 82 81 19d2 90 89 87 82 83 83 85 81 77 66 70 68 80 1903 68 70 73 73 76 81 88 88 70 83 80 80 79 1904 79 90 100 100 99 102 107 120 128 132 128 120 109 1905 124 129 126 115 107 115 109 99 94 94 97 93 108 1906 90 89 82 84 86 87 87 78 74 75 74 76 82 1907 76 76 77 74 88 96 98 95 103 108 96 111 92 1908 110 111 112 109 110 112 112 108 108 109 111 107 110 1909 111 116 122 125 133 186 129 112 104 103 105 106 117 1910 110 109 108 106 103 101 106 109 104 103 102 101 104 1911 101 102 96 100 100 101 102 101 104 111 114 113 104 1912 116 118 118 118 116 112 98 97 91 89 86 83 103 1913 85 89 89 88 92 93 92 90 86 85 86 87 88 1914 89 91 92 92 94 93 89 98 106 110 117 124 100 1915 143 158 162 163 159 140 126 122 109 100 99 102 132 1916 109 105 97 94 92 87 98 119 124 138 139 ISO 118 1917 180 188 138 161 174 164 169 162 140 184 134 131 148 1918 180 134 182 128 127 130 183 130 123 123 128 121 128 1919 125 130 181 134 134 133 128 118 117 117 117 118 126 m? % \\i is *s v lit v 'it »a v ?i s * \lll n ?? *8 II fl B ?2 6 6 9 7? 74 IS ! ft 1924 74 74 77 75 73 77 83 94 89 103 103 109 86 1925 123 130 126 105 116 116 111 123 116 108 112 121 117 1926 126 126 120 115 112 115 103 103 97 101 10S 102 111 1927 104 103 104 100 103 112 112 106 98 96 94 96 102 1928 96 97 103 104 116 111 101 78 76 81 81 82 94 1929 fcl 88 88 83 73 73 88 94 94 92 86 90 86 1930 V 3 87 79 74 74 78 66 69 63 59 53 67 72 1931 58 59 60 61 64 51 34 38 38 36 54 48 50 1932 60 49 60 46 46 43 88 43 40 38 37 36 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 26 THE PURCHASING POWER OF CORN The price relative of corn for each month of the 38-year period, 1895-1932, is given m Table 11. The average price quoted for the corresponding months m the five-year period, 1910-14, is used as a base for each month. The purchasing power for each month of the period is given m Table 12 and for the later years of the period is presented graphically m Figure 2. The fact that the price relative of corn is higher than the "all commodities" index m any given year, such as 1913, is not proof that corn was a profitable crop that year. In order to determine the profitableness of corn at any time we must know the cost of production. The purchas - ing power gives, of course, some indication of profitableness because there is a direct relationship between cost of pro - duction and the general price level of commodities. On the other hand, the purchasing power of corn may be very high, but because of crop failure the farmer may be buying corn instead of selling. Table 11. — Corn: Price relatives by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-14=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 18SS 91 92 80 87 8G E0 77 6S 43 86 31 32 68 1896 28 80 81 28 27 28 22 21 18 20 23 22 21 1897 20 20 20 21 22 21 21 26 29 26 29 32 21 1898 SO 81 86 86 12 88 36 81 81 86 10 IT 87 1899 60 50 17 16 IS 12 89 S3 81 36 40 43 42 1900 11 16 63 63 61 51 61 16 17 19 50 53 19 1901 62 56 67 61 61 58 68 76 79 81 101 114 73 1902 Ul 102 99 93 91 86 86 73 72 72 63 49 81 1903 51 ' 51 53 51 62 56 62 59 58 51 52 55 55 1901 56 66 69 71 71 65 65 65 63 67 63 63 66 1905 62 68 71 67 67 66 70 65 61 63 65 61 66 1906 60 68 67 61 63 63 65 59 56 58 61 61 60 1907 58 58 57 57 67 70 68 68 77 81 80 85 70 1908 95 98 103 103 106 108 110 106 103 99 99 102 102 1909 101 101 107 106 108 108 103 93 88 90 95 101 101 1910 107 106 103 93 87 87 89 86 SO 75 72 73 88 1911 78 72 71 72 76 80 89 89 90 101 111 110 86 1912 113 111 117 125 130 126 118 111 101 97 81 77 110 1918 81 81 87 87 88 91 91 101 JIG 119 126 130 101 1911 127 122 128 122 119 115 110 109 109 107 107 110 115 1915 121 129 126 122 116 112 113 109 103 97 95 102 112 1916 109 110 109 110 108 110 116 117 117 ISO 119 158 121 1917 161 171 190 232 256 259 805 295 ■ 267 276 258 248 246 1918 260 269 277 258 253 218 250 217 213 229 238 272 253 1919 266 258 266 281 282 280 291 285 218 222 233 252 261 1920 256 258 257 272 282 285 216 207 170 123 97 85 212 1921 81 76 76 68 65 66 65 65 48 14 48 C 7 62 1922 68 72 81 78 78 77 76 73 71 82 107 118 81 1923 117 116 119 125 181 129 128 111 113 119 118 106 119 1921 118 120 119 116 110 111 119 160 151 160 166 203 189 1925 216 211 200 167 173 171 163 151 185 118 128 124 163 1926 126 116 109 101 105 105 108 122 119 126 134 142 117 1927 185 188 126 121 182 117 119 115 135 128 118 134 135 1928 129 137 118 152 162 161 119 180 138 135 137 142 113 1929 117 157 161 111 135 186 139 138 140 188 134 136 111 19S0 ISB 181 119 121 116 115 108 125 127 118 99 106 119 1931 95 81 81 78 72 66 68 62 56 19 71 73 71 1932 71 61 61 53 17 45 45 42 35 26 25 26 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 27 The corn crop was an almost total failure m the major portion of southern Nebraska m 1913. Because of the small yield, the per-bushel cost of production was high. Even at the high price, the corn, if sold, would not have returned cost of production. Little could be sold, as most farmers not only needed for feed all that they raised but were compelled to purchase corn shipped m from other regions. Table 12. — Corn: Purchasing power by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-14 = 100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Ausr- Sept. Oct. Nov. JDec. Ay. 1898 132 133 129 121 116 108 105 90 60 60 43 45 96 1896 40 43 49 41 40 85 83 82 27 29 S3 31 35 1897 29 29 29 31 88 82 86 38 41 41 41 46 35 1898 43 48 61 61 65 64 51 49 44 61 67 66 52 1899 70 68 64 62 68 66 61 43 42 44 49 62 66 1900 53 65 63 63 62 63 62 67 67 60 62 66 60 1901 77 70 71 77 77 73 72 94 96 102 122 136 90 1902 IS4 123 119 111 111 100 100 86 84 78 71 66 98 8S S ?4 78 II 87 76 3 8- 3 8 8 8 8 Mil 67 S li 8 S 70 6 ?5° li li II It II ion? &lt;tt 61 61 61 70 72 70 70 79 86 86 93 74 1908 104 109 114 118 116 119 120 116 112 97 105 107 111 Hit 107 110 118 109 110 109 104 93 87 78 91 99 102 1910 103 102 97 87 83 84 86 83 78 76 74 75 85 1911 75 77 76 78 83 87 96 93 93 106 116 116 91 1912 111 118 118 123 127 125 117 109 101 94 82 75 109 £ JI x?? iH 121 iil lit Hi ffi iS I Hi *S "5 "89 J K '8 T 2 II 105 109 H ! \i S! SS &amp; £ S IS % Wi lit S? &amp; i li II II 1 1 II I j 1 ll% 3 . li Li, 0% of, 79 g2 106 106 106 112 114 187 97 4 T J J 8 x fl T* i 9 4 S I? SJ ii Z ilUlUUllili THE PURCHASING POWER OF OATS Table 13 gives price relatives for oats, and Table 14 jrives the purchasing power. These tables are constructed m the same manner as the tables giving the price relatives and purchasing power of wheat and corn. Figure^ 2 pre - sents the purchasing power graphically for the years 1916-32. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 28 Table 13. — Oats: Price relatives by months, Nebraska, 1895-1982 (1910-14=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Av. JS?5 S! 80 84 8i 82 82 57 45 34 87 34 33 61 J886 34 33 36 85 82 29 30 84 81 81 31 31 31 «?I .1 S0 80 80 29 29 83 34 37 87 39 39 83 Jfgf « 60 61 64 61 82 46 48 45 61 56 69 49 jaSO 62 64 69 62 61 32 52 45 46 48 61 53 64 J2S? li I. 61 B7 68 B0 " « Sl 61 51 56 62 1901 67 68 67 69 61 68 71 85 84 90 96 106 74 1902 111 106 103 97 98 96 95 80 70 67 62 67 88 1903 71 72 68 68 69 74 78 74 76 76 70 73 71 1904 80 88 86 66 85 85 82 77 70 65 65 64 77 1905 65 66 66 62 64 63 65 67 56 59 62 64 63 1906 68 66 66 68 69 74 76 68 65 67 70 73 69 1907 80 83 86 86 93 93 92 99 112 112 98 109 96 1908 116 118 114 119 117 116 117 119 115 112 112 115 116 1909 119 116 119 124 180 132 122 105 96 68 98 101 113 1910 108 110 108 103 96 95 98 97 90 84 79 78 96 1911 74 77 76 70 "74 82 96 102 107 112 118 117 . 91 1912 126 127 182 141 138 132 120 97 84 84 84 34 113 1913 85 83 84 86 SO 95 98 108 110 107 107 106 96 1914 108 102 100 100 101 95 90 97 110 112 112 115 104 1915 126 127 180 ISO 128 116 114 111 96 84 84 89 110 1916 102 102 97 100 96 95 95 102 107 115 124 128 105 1917 139 141 148 162 170 164 174 165 140 146 157 179 157 1918 199 207 210 210 197 185 179 179 180 180 180 182 190 1919 182 166 162 178 176 175 185 193 180 174 177 190 178 1920 205 204 211 230 245 264 217 176 167 135 112 106 189 1921 102 94 89 81 74 77 71 65 62 62 69 56 74 1922 68 75 76 76 77 79 82 80 76 84 96 98 80 1923 162 99 108 108 112 101 92 88 90 96 96 98 99 1924 102 108 111 108 106 108 122 119 115 121 121 131 115 1925 146 141 188 116 117 116 117 111 101 101 101 101 118 1926 108 106 103 103 104 101 109 116 112 115 112 115 107 1927 122 124 122 122 125 130 122 116 110 112 112 117 118 1928 322 124 130 185 141 148 133 Sl 96 104 107 109 121 1S29 116 122 119 119 112 108 109 105 110 110 107 106 110 1980 105 102 97 100 93 90 73 85 87 81 7C 75 88 1931 77 75 78 73 66 63 54 64 66 66 65 64 66 1932 64 66 67 65 61 66 41 34 84 28 28 28 48 The price relative of oats in 1908 was 115 and the aver - age purchasing power was 125, which was the highest of any year included in the study. In 1920 the price relative was 189 but the purchasing power was only 84. The aver - age price of oats at Nebraska country shipping points during the last three months of 1932 was 10 cents per bushel and the price relative, was only 28. The lowest pur - chasing power of oats in Nebraska for which we have a record was in October and November, 1932, when it was only 29. The purchasing power increased to 31 in Decem - ber because of a slight decrease in the "all commodities" price index. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 29 Table 14. — Oats: Purchasing power by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-14=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Pec Ay. 1895 328 116 122 117 112 111 78 62 47 61 47 46 86 1896 49 48 SI 61 48 44 45 62 47 46 44 44 46 1897 46 44 44 45 44 44 60 49 62 63 66 66 49 1898 64 70 72 76 80 46 66 69 64 73 80 83 69 1899 B 7 88 81 84 82 43 68 68 66 69 62 64 70 1900 65 62 61 68 65 62 66 59 62 63 63 70 63 1901 70 72 71 76 77 80 82 106 102 HO 116 126 91 1902 134 127 124 115 116 110 110 94 81 73 70 74 102 1903 78 79 77 77 80 86 85 86 87 88 82 86 82 1904 '92 99 98 99 100 100 96 90 80 75 73 72 89 1906 73 74 74 70 74 72 76 65 64 68 70 72 72 1906 76 74 78 76 77 82 87 76 72 73 75 [78 77 1967 86 87 92 92 97 96 95 102 116 114 104 \IS 101 1908 127 125 127 131 129 127 127 129 125 120 119 121 125 1909 127 122 125 128 133 133 128 105 95 95 94 96 114 1910 104 106 102 96 91 91 94 94 88 85 81 80 93 illi 76 82 80 76 80 89 102 106 110 116 123 123 96 1912 130 131 188 138 135 131 119 95 82 82 82 82 112 1913 83 81 82 84 89 94 96 106 107 104 105 106 94 1914 108 102 101 101 103 97 96 96 107 113 US 117 105 1915 126 127 108 103 127 116 113 111 96 |2 80 82 109 1916 91 89 83 84 79 78 102 82 84 86 87 88 84 1917 93 92 91 97 97 92 97 91 78 82 88 99 91 ioi R Ifla 116 114 112 105 98 93 91 90 90 90 91 99 1919 93 87 84 89 89 88 90 91 87 84 84 86 88 iSIS 89 §9 'Si 96 100 106 90 76 69 64 57 60 84 SS l\ 55 I? I! S 5 66 8 66 ilii % ?! ?? ?J ft ?! U I II it il SS lo 11 1 1 1 1 1.1 Ii I ■ 1 . 1 | I 8 I 11 8 I 8 8 \\ 1931 68 67 66 67 62 60 51 61 64 64 63 64 62 J932 65 68 70 68 65 71 44 36 36 29 29 31 51 THE PURCHASING POWER OF HOGS The price relatives of hogs are given m Table 15 and the purchasing power of hogs m Table 16. Figure 3 shows the price relatives of corn and hogs and the "all commodities price index, by months, for the years 1916-32. Hogs are profitable when the price of hogs is relatively higher than the price of corn. Nearly all hog producers secured a profit on their hogs m 1922, even though the price of hogs averaged only $8.04. Hogs did notlhave a high purchasing power, but because corn was relatively cheaper than hogs the feeding of corn to hogs wad profit - able. Most hog producers would have secured a greater profit from selling corn m 1917 than they received from feeding the corn to hogs and selling the hogs. Hogs were high m price and had a satisfactory purchasing pp\fer, but corn was so high that most hog producers received very little for their labor and some received nothing. Hogs were low m price m 1896, the price relative for the year averaging only 40. Their average purchasing power </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 30 Table 15. — Hogs: Price relatives by months, Nebraska, 1895-1982 (1910-U=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jane July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 1895 64 40 49 63 66 64 67 64 60 47 44 46 61 1896 46 62 47 41 88 87 86 83 88 36 41 43 40 1897 41 41 45 44 46 41 40 48 47 44 42 45 43 1898 44 48 46 44 62 60 46 47 44 44 46 47 46 1899 46 46 43 43 46 46 48 61 61 64 61 64 48 1900 68 61 60 63 66 64 68 63 62 62 64 68 63 1901 66 69 68 70 73 74 78 72 79 78 81 86 73 1902 82 79 77 84 91 98 97 88 88 R8 82 86 86 1908 86 89 89 88 83 74 68 64 68 70 59 62 76 1904 61 64 63 58 68 62 64 69 66 66 62 65 62 1905 60 61 61 68 66 66 68 71 66 62 63 67 64 1906 69 76 77 76 80 81 81 75 71 79 80 86 77 1907 86 91 88 78 81 77 74 73 71 76 61 61 76 1908 55 54 66 65 68 68 75 77 79 73 74 76 68 1909 76 78 78 80 87 39 94 91 92 96 103 115 90 1910 118 113 126 122 117 118 108 100 110 108 106 104 112 1911 103 95 84 74 74 75 79 88 84 80 84 85 84 1912 81 79 79 92 97 95 93 98 101 111 104 105 95 1918 96 103 106 108 106 109 111 103 98 104 104 107 105 1914 107 110 106 104 106 108 109 111 106 97 101 99 106 1915 91 86 82 83 93 93 91 84 86 101 90 90 89 1916 90 108 116 118 124 118 123 121 128 122 131 139 119 1917 189 168 186 197 207 202 198 210 223 234 234 251 203 1918 222 216 216 209 224 217 222 238 248 234 285 249 227 1919 2SB 281 281 247 266 268 283 271 198 186 194 189 233 1920 191 189 179 168 178 181 186 182 186 184 165 124 176 1921 116 113 118 92 102 92 109 111 84 86 84 85 99 1922 91 120 121 118 127 128 122 104 100 104 104 103 112 1823 107 103 96 92 92 77 83 86 101 93 88 90 92 1924 88 86 86 83 88 86 87 111 110 129 122 125 100 1925 182 186 166 166 149 150 170 167 146 150 148 152 152 1926 156 169 166 145 168 180 172 162 167 168 162 166 161 1927 165 166 144 183 122 110 114 118 126 187 126 121 180 1928 107 103 98 100 122 120 184 134 153 129 122 111 120 1929 116 128 189 187 138 186 144 138 122 120 119 127 131 1980 126 185 129 118 122 125 111 112 124 118 116 110 121 1931 100 90 90 87 82 74 82 80 66 60 57 51 77 1932 48 43 48 42 83 82 67 51 46 89 39 35 43 "i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — ' r* :zlaakz^zzzzzzzbz: ' Z342Z %,— - --„ : 9£» o I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I Ia . mt 17 1« 1» 10 11 12 -2S ?« ■" ?• ~n « ?0 JO 31 J2 Pig. 3. — Price relatives of corn and hogs and index numbers of the wholesale price of all commodities (1910-14 = 100). </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Local Prices op Farm Products, 1895-1932 31 Table 16. — Hogs: Purchasing power by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 {1910-U = 100) \ Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Auk. Sept. Oct. Nov. pec. Ay. 1895 78 71 71 74 77 73 78 75 69 65 61 65 72 1896 C 6 76 68 60 57 56 55 50 60 63 59 61 69 1897 60 60 66 66 68 62 61 62 66 63 60 64 63 1898 63 68 65 62 68 70 64 67 63 63 64 66 65 1899 CC 63 59 68 61 60 63 66 64 67 62 65 62 1900 70 73 71 75 60 79 77 78 76 77 79 85 77 1901 82 86 85 89 92 04 84 89 96 95 98 102 90 1902 09 ' 95 93 100 107 108 118 103 102 96 92 96 100 1903 U3 98 101 100 97 86 79 74 78 81 69 73 86 1904 70 72 72 67 68 78 75 69 75 62 74 70 71 1908 67 69 69 72 76 76 78 81 76 71 72 76 73 1906 78 84 87 84 89 90 93 84 79 86 86 92 86 1907 91 96 88 83 84 79 76 75 73 77 66 77 80 1908 60 60 62 71 76 75 82 84 86 78 79 80 74 1909 81 82 82 82 89 90 95 91 91 94 99 110 91 1910 109 109 118 114 111 118 104 97 108 109 109 107 109 1911 106 101 88 80 80 82 85 92 87 82 88 [90 88 1912 84 81 80 90 96 94 92 96 98 108 101 103 94 1913 98 101 104 106 106 108 109 101 95 101 102 JO6 103 1914 107 110 107 105 108 105 110 110 103 98 102 101 106 1915 92 86 82 83 92 03 90 84 86 98 86 83 88 1916 SO 90 99 95 102 98 102 98 101 92 92 96 95 ill? 93 103 118 118 118 118 110 115 124 131 131 139 119 1918 121 121 116 112 120 116 115 121 121 118 118 125 119 1919 119 122 120 127 184 188 137 128 96 90 92 86 116 1920 R3 83 77 69 73 74 77 77 81 87 85 70 78 1921 69 74 79 64 72 68 80 81 62 63 61 62 69 1922 C? 88 89 8* 91 91 84 72 69 72 71 73 79 1923 72 68 62 60 62 62 68 69 69 64 61 63 63 1924 61 59 60 58 68 61 62 78 77 90 84 84 70 S3 ill ,S 111 V 33 Ml SS 3S £ iS i 1 1 VZ Hi J 74 Tl S II i°s II 9*4 ill II S S 2 i S II »S SI To S Ji 8 8 S 8 III? 88 80 81 80 77 70 78 76 63 68 55 51 72 1932 49 44 60 44 85 34 61 54 48 41 42 38 45 for the year was 59 and for two months, August and Sep - tember, was only 50. Prices averaged nearly as low m 1932 as m 1896. The price relative for the year was 43, and for June was only 32, which was one point lower than was reached m 1896. The average purchasing power of hogs m 1932 was 45. In only three months, March, July, and August, did it rise to 50 or above. The all-time low was 34 m June. THE PURCHASING POWER OF BUTTER AND BUTTERFAT The price relatives for butter (1896-1920) and for butter - fat (1921-32) and the purchasing power, computed, m the same way as for the products previously discussed, are pre - sented m Tables 17 and 18. The purchasing power of butter for the years 1895-1914 and 1915-32 are shown graphically The lowest butter or butterfat price quoted m the 38 - --year period was 8 cents per pound m June and Juljf, 1896. The price relative at that time was 39 and the purchasing </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 32 M0 I — I — I — I — I — I — l — l — I — I — i — i — i — i — i — i — r — i — i — i — imo ItKMft * ■" y^ -/ — V «o Sioe — , -4 J _^ JL. __, t ______ ______ „,„§ * _ BM-WM \ *l r* gj* sss "5» »» — iw!* * m* ItZO 192s ,910 UM Fig. 4.— Purchasing power of butter (1895-1919) and butterfat (1920-32) in Nebraska. The years 1895-1914 are compared with the years 1915-32 (1910-14=100). Table 17. — Butter and Butterfat: Price relatives by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-1^=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jure July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Av. 1895 60 62 64 66 61 64 64 61 49 63 54 57 55 1896 56 44 49 46 42 39 39 47 44 45 42 46 44 Mil il ll 4S 61 " ** ** « ** 68 bi 63 48 Mil ll ll l*. 61 61 54 *° 66 fi 7 ST 58 57 54 1899 52 68 64 56 61 54 64 66 67 66 61 61 56 1900 64 71 72 60 61 64 69 70 71 66 61 57 65 1901 60 62 69 60 66 64 64 61 62 67 63 67 61 1902 60 71 77 83 75 78 74 65 62 70 69 72 70 1903 72 66 63 66 65 69 69 61 62 66 65 65 65 1904 60 66 63 69 65 69 69 66 67 61 58 61 61 1905 68 84 86 83 79 74 69 70 66 70 69 72 74 1906 72 76 77 74 65 64 64 65 66 74 69 72 70 1907 76 93 95 98 84 74 74 76 75 82 73 76 80 1908 80 93 90 88 84 88 88 84 80 78 81 92 87 1909 92 98 90 97 98 98 98 98 97 98 100 99 96 1910 104 106 108 111 103 108 108 107 102 102 100 99 104 1911 84 80 72 74 79 78 83 84 80 90 92 99 83 1912 108 111 108 111 107 98 98 93 92 98 104 103 104 1918 100 106 118 116 117 118 118 112 111 106 104 99 109 1914 104 07 99 88 98 98 98 103 111 102 100 99 100 1915 108 111 108 106 103 108 108 103 97 94 96 107 104 1916 108 124 181 184 121 123 123 126 119 123 127 126 123 1917 128 142 144 171 159 167 167 168 177 168 161 168 161 1918 180 204 189 185 178 181 196 187 212 221 211 229 197 1919 248 199 248 269 271 245 245 £62 248 266 265 271 252 BUTTERFAT 1920 236 248 266 273 252 266 255 234 239 213 196 149 231 1921 168 160 162 171 112 103 137 145 142 131 142 134 141 1922 62 124 122 ISO 131 142 142 117 124 115 119 137 125 1923 172 181 176 213 168 167 147 159 177 160 173 179 172 1924 200 199 189 167 150 162 157 181 128 118 119 137 154 1925 182 187 158 162 159 167 167 173 164 152 165 164 168 1926 162 164 167 162 159 167 162 154 169 164 154 160 161 1927 164 186 198 204 178 181 176 164 164 164 162 168 175 1928 184 190 203 199 192 206 196 187 190 176 169 176 188 1929 176 195 216 208 206 206 201 192 186 172 142 130 183 1980 112 137 140 162 150 127 182 154 164 135 115 92 185 1931 92 89 117 106 79 83 88 103 111 119. 96 92 97 1932 80 71 77 65 61 59 69 79 71 66 62 72 69 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Local Prices, of Farm Products, 1895-1932 33 Table 18. — Butter and Butterfat: Purchasing power by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-14=100) \ Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Juno July Aue. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Ay. 1895 87 90 78 78 83 7» 74 71 68 74 75 80 77 1896 80 64 71 68 68 60 69 71 67 66 60 66 65 1897 71 78 66 76 71 67 67 68 62 76 71 76 71 1898 80 75 76 72 67 76 70 80 81 81 88 80 76 1899 78 78 74 76 60 72 71 78 71 81 74 74 73 1900 77 84 86 71 74 79 84 86 87 81 76 71 79 1901 74 77 74 76 71 81 80 75 76 69 78 68 75 1902 72 86 98 99 88 91 86 76 72 76 77 80 82 1903 79 73 72 74 76 80 80 71 71 77 76 76 75 1904 60 74 72 79 76 69 69 65 65 70 65 68 70 1905 76 94 98 94 91 86 79 80 76 80 78 81 84 1906 81 84 86 83 72 71 74 73 78 80 74 76 78 ISO? 82 98 101 99 87 76 76 77 77 84 78 88 84 1908 88 103 100 97 92 97 96 91 87 84 81 97 94 1909 98 98 95 100 100 99 99 93 96 95 96 94 97 1910 100 102 102 104 98 104 104 104 100 108 103 102 101 1911 87 86 76 80 86 85 89 87 82 93 96 101 87 \l\l 112 114 109 109 105 97 97 91 94 96 101 101 103 mis 97 104 111 114 116 117 111 110 108 103 102 98 107 \l\\ 104 97 100 89 96 100 99 102 108 103 101 101 100 1915 109 111 108 106 102 108 107 103 97 91 91 99 103 1916 96 108 112 113 100 102 101 102 94 92 89 87 99 mi? 86 98 92 102 90 94 98 92 98 94 90 93 94 \l\l 98 114 102 102 99 95 102 96 105 111 106 116 103 loil 125 105 129 189 137 124 119 119 120 128 126 123 125 BUTTERFAT 1920 103 108 115 113 103 105 105 99 105 101 101 8E 102 1921 101 98 108 119 79 76 101 106 104 96 103 98 99 19*2 69 91 90 96 94 101 98 81 86 79 81 93 88 1923 115 120 116 140 113 107 102 111 121 110 120 126 116 100 l liS IRfi 131 111 107 117 112 92 90 82 82 93 108 \lli 88 90 104 109 107 lil 110 114 109 101 108 109 105 1926 101 110 114 110 108 114 112 106 109 103 107 112 110 1927 116 133 143 149 129 132 127 118 116 116 116 :19 125 1928 180 186 146 141 135 146 138 181 132 126 121 126 133 1929 126 140 164 149 149 148 143 186 133 124 104 96 182 lliS " 1M iO6 124 115 100 107 125 183 112 97 79 107 •toQi fet m lOK 97 74 79 84 08 107 115 uo «~ »i |||| g| ™ M II 65 63 5 83 75 70 67 | 70 72 power was 59. The average price of butterfat m June and July, 1932, was only 12 cents, which was the lowest average price paid for either butter or butterfat since the sutnmer of 1904. The price relative of butterfat m June and July was 59 and the purchasing power was 63. &gt;_ . | . A comparison of the present price of butterfat with the price m 1897 gives little information concerning the com - parative profits from dairying m the two periods. The price which a farmer receives for a pound of butterfat is of less importance to him than is the amount of gctods for which he can exchange a pound of butterfat. prices were low m 1932 not only because they were lower than they were from 1921 to 1931, but because a pound of butterfat would buy less of the things that families pur - chase than at any preceding time m the period covered by this study except the years 1896, 1897, and 1904. The average purchasing power of butterfat for the year was 12. Butterfat had a higher average purchasing power, for the </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 34 years 1921-31, as compared with the five pre-war years, than any other commodity included in this study. This was doubtless due in part to the increased use of milk as a beverage. The per-capita consumption for beverage pur - poses increased from 42.4 gallons in 1917 to nearly 60 gallons in 1929. It dropped to 57 gallons in 1931. THE PURCHASING POWER OF EGGS When eggs were 6 cents per dozen in June, 1896 and 1897, the monthly price relative was 42 and the purchasing power was 64 (Tables 19 and 20). The high point in egg prices was reached in December, 1919, when the average price received by farmers was 66 cents. The price relative was 248 and the purchasing power was 113. Eggs had their greatest purchasing power in December, 1920, although the price relative at that time was 30 points lower than in December, 1919. In March, 1932, farmers received on the average only 7 cents per dozen for their eggs. The price relative was 40 and the purchasing power was 42, which is the lowest of any time during the 38 years. The reason why the purchasing power of 7-cent Table 19.— Eggs: Price relatives by months, Nebraska, Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aujc. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Av. 1896 63 76 69 60 67 66 59 68 64 61 61 KR ki 1896 51 42 46 53 47 42 61 61 48 61 67 ll bJ 1897 61 67 52 53 47 42 44 48 64 Sg fl so sS 1898 65 47 46 47 47 49 44 61 48 61 61 64 M 1899 68 61 69 67 67 70 66 68 60 66 67 66 ll 1900 65 47 52 63 60 66 51 68 60 66 66 RS M 1901 63 66 69 78 60 66 51 68 60 66 66 68 ll 1902 67 85 76 80 80 86 88 94 77 86 70 75 80 1908 71 61 69 73 73 70 74 72 77 81 78 88 ?2 1904 76 99 76 87 93 85 88 94 89 76 82 79 85 1905 79 108 80 93 87 b5 74 87 77 76 78 79 86 1906 71 61 68 78 80 86 88 94 83 86 86 90 io 1907 79 90 80 80 80 77 81 80 83 86 82 79 Io 1908 70 80 69 73 80 85 88 87 88 II 94 ill |2 1909 94 99 92 107 107 118 118 116 107 101 98 101 102 ?o}? 4? HI 42 118 118 103 "* "1 „1 98 98 106 1911 87 76 80 80 B0 85 88 94 89 91 94 98 rr 1912 106 118 IIS 107 107 99 108 101 SI ill 98 90 lit 1918 87 94 92 100 100 09 96 94 95 106 115 113 101 1914 110 104 109 100 100 106 110 109 119 101 94 101 1.1 1916 106 104 92 100 100 99 96 101 101 101 107 101 ioi 1916 98 118 86 118 118 120 126 128 119 186 127 182 117 Mil Mi J„ Ml Ml 19S m 18t 188 »• 172 148 „5 ill 1918 165 198 167 187 187 169 199 210 196 197 184 207 187 1919 196 141 178 226 246 218 220 289 202 232 229 248 218 1920 204 198 206 226 283 218 223 261 250 237 226 218 223 1921 198 118 188 120 100 118 147 167 187 162 172 168 144 1922 91 127 92 120 120 118 118 101 113 126 189 154 11? 1928 118 118 121 188 120 120 118 128 181 131 162 185 128 MU Mi Ml .11 118 118 127 "° 1M "» "« "2 ill „S 1925 169 187 126 147 147 162 176 181 143 146 160 147 164 1926 122 108 120 160 160 162 161 159 154 166 147 160 144 1927 118 118 109 118 118 169 126 128 131 141 181 128 127 1928 122 118 120 140 163 148 162 169 149 136 127 186 185 1929 106 182 188 140 146 162 169 174 154 161 147 142 144 1980 122 127 108 127 107 106 96 94 107 91 98 76 108 1931 68 42 92 93 67 70 74 80 71 76 86 86 76 1982 65 47 40 64 60 49 69 80 77 96 90 94 67 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Local Prices op Farm Products, 1895-1932 35 i4M— l — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — I — | — I — I — I — r~~i 4o 120 IJO MS- 932 £ &gt; k As **' \ s w^. V •» tol ' 1 1 1 1 1 L — l 1 ' 1 1 1 I I J 1 I I . - J«o «l I I — I — I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I ll~l« MM 1000 I*os I»K&gt; 191* I»U I*2o IKS I*3o I*l4 FIG. 5. — Purchasing power of eggs m Nebraska. The years; 1895 - -1914 are compared with the years 1915-32 (1910-14=100). eggs was materially less m 1932 than of 6-cent eggs m 1896 and 1897 is explained by the relatively higher level of commodity prices m the later years. Figure 5 shows the purchasing power of eggs for the years 1895-1914 and 1915-32. Table 20. — Eggs: Purchasing power by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-U=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. | Dec. Ay. 1895 91 109 100 88 92 76 81 81 75 ■ 85 85 79 86 1896 78 61 67 78 70 64 77 77 78 90 81 80 74 1897 75 84 ' 76 79 71 64 67 62 76 64 76 86 71 IS9B 79 66 65 66 62 69 63 73 69 87 87 90 74 1899 S3 84 95 91 91 88 87 75 75 81 70 67 83 1900 66 66 62 63 73 69 62 72 73 81 81 85 71 1901 78 82 86 92 76 71 64 72 73 81 80 81 79 1902 81 102 90 95 94 99 102 110 90 93 79 83 93 1903 78 67 78 8a 85 81 86 84 88 94 91 98 85 1904 . 86 111 85 100 109 100 103 109 102 87 92 . 89 98 1905 89 121 91 106 100 98 85 99 88 87 89 89 96 1906 80 69 71 82 89 94 101 106 92 93 92 96 89 1907 8B 95 85 85 88 79 88 82 86 88 87 97 84 1908 87 89 77 80 88 98 96 96 90 92 100 106 93 1909 100 104 97 110 109 114 119 116 106 88 94 96 102 1910 106 109 97 106 108 109 99 98 99 102 101 101 103 1911 90 80 84 87 87 92 95 98 92 94 98 103 91 1912 110 116 116 106 106 98 102 99 92 98 96 88 101 1913 84 92 90 98 99 98 94 92 92 103 113 112 99 1914 110 104 110 101 102 108 111 108 116 102 95 103 107 1916 107 104 92 100 99 99 95 101 101 98 102 94 100 1916 88 103 78 95 93 99 102 99 94 102 89 91 94 1917 87 99 84 112 110 111 102 103 106 97 83 83 96 lfliß 90 111 90 100 100 90 103 107 98 99 92 104 98 Ul9 100 76 II 117 MS 110 107 118 98 112 109 US 106 i aon so «A R0 04 95 90 94 HI HO 112 115 124 99 1921 116 77 92 88 71 83 108 122 101 118 126 116 101 1922 68 98 68 88 86 80 81 70 78 87 95 105 83 1 ™ ? 2 S i B of i?! 1| ill IS A,S 1 i ' ill 7 , U li I? Si 18 iol ni m i« ™ II II ** Z i hi *8 1! '8 a ?? x l li 1* </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 36 THE PURCHASING POWER OF POTATOES Potatoes have fluctuated more in price and purchasing power than any of the other products studied. The price relatives (Table 21) vary from 27 in August, 1896 to 558 in May, 1920. On the latter date the purchasing power of potatoes (Table 22) was 227; in October, 1932, it was only 37. The lowest average purchasing power for any year was 44 in 1900, although potatoes averaged two cents per bushel higher that year than in 1896. The principal reason for the wider variation in potato prices than for cereals is the greater perishability of the product. Cereals are carried over from season to season. The abundant harvest of one year is used to supply the deficit caused by the short crop of some succeeding year. Potatoes cannot be carried in storage from year to year and, therefore, the size of the crop is more fully reflected in the price. TABLE 21. — Potatoes: Price relatives by months, Nebraska, 1895-1932 (1910-14=100) Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Auir. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Av. 1895 107 108 103 95 93 77 46 89 87 42 48 47 69 1S96 42 41 48 37 37 32 29 27 29 80 34 38 34 1897 42 39 88 88 42 40 37 41 52 68 77 74 48 1898 71 64 61 68 65 58 46 47 53 54 52 60 56 1899 48 54 64 99 100 75 55 26 27 40 32 27 64 1900 27 26 26 22 21 24 82 29 45 69 70 69 86 1901 77 76 76 69 73 78 92 112 182 146 144 143 100 1902 144 140 188 188 146 116 52 88 39 39 35 85 87 1903 88 88 86 32 30 32 54 61 65 94 87 81 62 1904 84 86 91 96 104 107 66 42 32 83 84 35 67 1905 85 89 86 31 29 43 50 43 44 44 36 60 41 1906 60 58 53 46 43 49 64 63 62 63 67 66 66 1907 67 68 77 75 83 86 82 70 ' 87 93 107 93 82 1908 90 89 85 85 82 83 76 65 61 66 66 63 76 1909 76 78 82 90 99 90 72 67 79 82 84 81 82 1910 81 80 76 64 56 56 66 86 110 121 120 113 84 1911 107 103 101 106 112 146 175 164 128 124 126 128 129 1912 181 143 164 163 171 142 103 81 74 70 70 72 115 1913 78 70 63 61 68 64 62 81 95 100 106 108 76 1914 107 104 107 106 102 103 95 89 92 85 78 78 96 1915 84 86 79 74 76 72 69 67 64 69 67 81 78 1916 88 103 105 101 99 88 81 90 108 142 190 208 114 1917 204 240 286 317 835 281 201 156 162 147 148 146 219 1918 186 142 142 117 103 119 136 157 176 160 169 168 142 1919 168 163 149 188 137 142 163 212 243 246 262 246 186 1920 272 823 846 449 658 608 875 257 206 166 152 162 824 1921 148 188 125 121 115 103 108 120 140 160 168 167 131 1922 156 166 163 186 117 101 79 76 74 67 67 65 104 1923 66 68 65 67 62 61 76 92 106 104 105 112 81 1924 111 118 102 100 95 86 109 112 83 80 80 85 97 1925 90 93 88 82 76 74 150 147 184 158 262 265 182 1926 281 281 264 276 264 201 176 150 163 180 223 230 220 1927 223 213 192 190 195 211 197 140 124 97 105 108 169 1928 105 107 108 109 107 91 80 66 68 64 70 68 86 1929 72 75 60 52 51 63 84 103 129 148 161 162 98 1930 ' 157 150 150 149 157 158 126 103 124 129 119 101 135 1931 92 94 96 103 101 81 101 108 60 64 63 68 90 1932 69 69 63 69 60 62 50 43 88 36 38 42 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Local Prices of Farm Products, 1895-1932 37 TABLE 22. — Potatoes: Purchasing power by months, Nebras - ka, 1895-1932 (1910-14 = 100) | Year Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Auk. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. Av. 1896 165 156 149 132 127 104 63 64 51 68 60 66 97 1896 60 59 62 64 55 48 44 41 44 44 49 54 50 1897 62 67 56 57 64 61 56 59 73 97 110 106 . 71 1898 101 90 86 82 72 82 66 67 76 - 77 74 70 79 1899 68 74 88 134 135 100 72 84 34 49 39 33 70 1900 S3 81 30 26 26 30 39 86 55 78 86 86 44 1901 95 96 94 87 92 S9 106 138 161 178 174 170 124 1902 178 169 166 158 172 136 60 46 46 42 39 39 101 1903 42 42 41 36 35 37 63 59 75 109 102 95 60 1904 96 96 103 110 122 126 66 49 31 46 38 39 77 1906 67 69 69 72 76 76 78 49 61 51 41 67 47 1906 66 60 60 62 48 55 62 71 69 68 72 70 62 1907 72 72 82 80 86 88 86 72 00 95 114 112 86 1908 90 89 94 93 80 91 83 60 66 71 70 .166 92 1909 81 82 86 93 82 91 73 67 78 93 99 110 83 1910 78 77 72 60 53 54 63 83 108 122 124 117 82 1911 110 110 106 115 122 169 188 171 132 128 131 135 ' 186 1912 137 147 166 160 168 141 102 79 72 68 68 71 114 1913 71 69 62 60 67 63 61 79 92 97 104 107 76 1914 107 104 108 107 104 105 96 88 80 86 79 80 97 1915 85 86 79 74 75 72 68 67 64 67 64 75 72 1916 79 90 90 85 82 73 66 73 85 107 134 143 91 1917 137 167 182 190 190 158 112 86 84 83 83 j 81 127 1918 74 79 77 63 55 63 70 80 88 80 80 184 74 1919 86 86 78 69 69 72 79 100 118 119 124 112 92 1920 118 141 149 186 229 209 165 109 91 79 78 i 92 143 1921 89 87 83 84 82 76 79 88 103 117 122 115 93 1922 116 121 120 100 84 72 64 63. 51 46 46 144 74 1923 44 46 42 44 42 41 52 64. 78 72 73 178 65 1924 77 77 71 70 68 62 78 79 58 66 55 . 67 69 1925 60 61 58 55 51 49 99 97 89 106 171 169 87 1926 186 189 180 188 180 137 121 103 112 124 166 161 151 1927 168 162 139 189 141 164 148 101 88 69 74 77 122 1928 74 76 78 77 76 66 66 46 47 45 60 [49 61 1929 112 64 43 37 37 88 60 73 92 106 118 119 67 1930 116 112 114 106 121 124 102 84 101 107 100 , 87 107 1931 81 84 86 94 94 96 96 103 87 62 61 68 84 1932 70 71 66 59 64 67 53 45 40 37 41 46 65 CONCLUSIONS Tables 2 to 8 show that the prices of the products for which information was collected have dropped rapidly since 1929, and averaged lower in 1932 than during any preceding year in the present century. During the later months of the year some of the prices were nearly as low as during the depression years of 1895-97, and for oats they were lower. j The prices of most manufactured goods declined less be - tween 1929 and the close of 1932 than did those ojf farm products. The index number of the wholesale price of all commodities was 91 per cent of pre-war in December, 1932. This index included farm products, which were veryj low in price and lowered the "all commodity" index. The index of the wholesale prices of non-agricultural commodities was slightly higher than pre-war at the end of 1932.J Since the costs of transportation and handling have risen since 1914, retail costs are higher relatively than wholesale costs </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 284 38 as compared with pre-war. The U. S. Bureau of Agricul - tural Economics estimated that m December, 1932, the prices paid by farmers for commodities bought at retail were 106 per cent of pre-war. As has been previously stated, farmers are usually leas interested m the price that they receive for products than m the amount of goods which can be purchased with a given amount of farm products. The price of either farm products or manufactured goods is of less importance to farmers than the relationship existing between prices. The fact that farm products have fallen lower relatively than manufactured goods has decreased the purchasing power of farmers. The tables which report purchasing power show that Nebraska farm products as a group had not only less purchasing power m 1932 than m any other year since the opening of the World War but less than m any of the depression years of the middle nineties. The purchasing power of farm products can be increased either by an increase m the price of the products sold or by a decrease m the price of the goods purchased. As a matter of course, a combination of these two methods would be satisfactory. Because of the large volume of debts which were incurred at a higher price level, it will be more satis - factory if the purchasing power is increased by an increase m the price of farm products. This has an added advantage because of the friction incident to a reduction m many fixed charges such as railway rates. Every Nebraskan should recognize that the prosperity of the state depends upon the amount of desirable goods that can be purchased with our surplus products. We may be prosperous at a high price level or a low price level, but we cannot be prosperous unless the products of our farms can purchase more than the most meager of necessities. [SM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>