<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00051.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00051.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Statement of the Auditor of Public Accounts of the State of Nebraska Showing the Appropriations Made and Moneys Expended by the Forty-Second Session of the Legislature</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATEMENT OF THE AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS of THE STATE OF NEBRASKA Showing the Appropriations Made and Moneys Expended BY THE FORTY-SECOND SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE Convened January 2 and Adjourned May 2, 1923 TO AND INCLUDING MAY 19, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">KIM KM OI \1 KIIOK OF l'l BI.IC ACCOUNTS --Auditor Deputy Auditor \ 11 « 1 ■ i i 1 1 &gt;i Division Accountant Tieas. Kxamine ■ Treas. Kxaminer -Fund Bookkeeper Stenographer Warrant Division \t Warrant Clerk Warrant Recorder Bond 1) Examii EQUALIZATION AMI ASSESSMENT Governor Auditor State Treasurer Bookkeeper </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 STATEMENT OF THK Statement No. 2 Sumirarv of Legislative Appi'»priatior and Expenditures Page A. Sa'aries &amp; Mileage— M»rrbe e B. Salaries — Officers and Kmploves of .Senate I 2 C. Salaries &amp; Mil &gt;ag -Members of H&lt; I). Salarie- -Officers &amp; Employes of Hou-p Page 2 E. Ex a* F. Telephone &amp; Te'egrap «&lt; 2 G. Expense&gt; Printing Page 2 H. Expenses — Blank Books &amp; Supplies - Page 2 ( 2 I. Expenses — Miscellaneous __Page 3 Auditors Certificate Page TABLE OF CONTENTS Statement No. 1 Appropriation Bills 1 A. Emergency Appropriations available during the fiscal year endinir June 30, 1923 1 B. Biennial Appropriations for the hiennium July 1, 1923 to June 30. 1928 1 I'. Nominal Appropriations .. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 5 STATEMENT NO. 1 APPROPRIATIONS MADE BY THE 42nd LEGISLATURE H. R. A. Emergency Appropriations Legislative Salaries $ 117,000.00 &gt;8 Legislative Expense 78,800.00 Printing House &amp; Senate Journal 15,000.00 Relief of Mrs. McComber and Mrs. Rogers 10,000.00 4!» Relief of Lieut. Gov. P. A. Barrows 1,801.69 Relief of Peerls &amp; James Taylor 5,000.00 Purchase, Propogation, Preservation &amp; Distribution of pheasant, quail &amp; partridges (Game &amp; Fish).. 15,000.00 Misc. Claims and Deficiencies 49,610.39 $ 287,212.08 Kmernency Appropriation If. lor the biennium July 1, 1923 to June 30, 1925: »t- tradication of scabies (Dept. of Agric.) $ 10,000.00 •ir, Refund of Paving Tax S. S. Home, Burkett 119.70 Refund of Paving Tax S. S. Home, Burkett. 24 Instruction of Deaf Children (Supt.) 5,000.00 Instruction of Deaf Children (Supt.) .25 Education of Dependent Children (Board of Control) 14,000.00 Education of Dependent Children (Board of Control) 14,000.00 J30 Purchasing &amp; Improving lakes and swamps for the purpose of sinking wells to keep said lakes from freezing (Fish &amp; Game&gt; 50,000.00 ?0 Purchasing &amp; Improving lakes and swamps for the purpose of sinking wells to keep said lakes from freezing (Fish &amp; Game&gt; 50,000.00 ■6b Kradication of Bovine Tuberculosis 285,000.00 72 Salaries &amp; Maintenance 19,680,060.66 19 Officers Salaries 860,140.00 Officers Salarie *20,904,320.36 Kirn ni urn — Governmental Cost C. Nominal Appropriations .ccurdance with Art. 3, Section 22 and 25 of the Constitution, being appropriations which do not increase the expenses of the state or the amount Revenue to be provided; contained in H. R. Sections 35 to 38 (See Statement No. 1 C&gt;.-$ 3,461,000.00 Recapitulation : Emergency Appropriations available during the biennium ending June 30, 1923, Statement No. 1 A $ 287,212.08 For the Biennium, July 1, 1923 to June 30, 1925 Statement 1 B $20,904,320.36 Total Governmental Cost Appropria tions 921,191,532.44 Nominal Appropriations, Statement 3,461,000.00 1 C $24,652,532.44 Granil Total </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 STATEMENT OF THE STATEMENT NO. 1A. Emergent-! Appropriation* Detailed Statement showing ueiaiieci statement showing the appropriations made by Legislature passed with the emergency clause and thus availa the Fiscal year ending June 30, 1 H. R. For What Purpose Appropriated Account Amount Total No. Appro- Appro priated priation Legislative Department 57 Legislative Salaries— 42 58 Legislative Expenses — 4 58 Printing House &amp; Sena Executive Department 349 Relief of Lt. Governor Barrow 717 Premium on Bond of Lt. Gover 717 Premium on B I'nder Direction of Slate Supt 717 Instruction of deaf children Code Dt-parimenl- Department of A 534 Pure &amp; I&gt; Department of Public Work. 717 Enterprise P: 717 Geo. E. John M Sundry Appropriation 313 Relief of Mis. McC« R. 411 Relief of Pearl a 717 Refund of Taxes 717 Claims &amp; Judgeir resurve 717 Miscellaneous Relief B Hoard of Control Prisoners in 717 Tuition of Stato W; 717 Premium on Bo 717 Boanl and Maintenam </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 7 IB \ppropriution&gt; m ( \ r M V Inder Direction of H. R. 672 56 La R. 672 55 Re\var&lt; Secretary of State H. R. 71!&gt; 60 Sa H.R. 71!i 61 Sa U. R. 672 (1-2 Sa BIENNIAL APPROPRIATIONS the 42nd Legislature to cover Governmental r the Biennium July 1, 1923 to June 30, 1925. Indicate* Capital Outla&gt; ) LEGISLATIVE DEPARTMENT Amount Amount Appropriated Appropriation enta] Ex jlar 2.000.00 S 2,000.00 JI'DICIARY DEPARTMENTS ] 96,690.00 upreme 105,000.00 10,000.00 Court Rt 12,000.00 13,000.00 Repo 20.000.00 Kx EXECUTIVE DEPARTM e N is 13.KKO.00 15,000.00 5,280.00 7,900.00 ?c'v to Goverr W ,200.00 t. rnor's ( 500.00 improvements, repair etc. for Governor s man 10,000.00 nil erou 60,500.00 Governor 60,000.00 w Enforcement 500.00 war Reporter 8,000.00 &lt;1 Wa^es 54,340.00 e (Clerk's office) 7,000.00 e &lt; Reporter's 350.00 3,000.0(1 * 10,000.00 562,500.00 350,000.00 192,500.00 Depart $ 772,190.00 46,230.00 ilary of Sec'y of State 10,000.00 alary of Deputy 5,280.00 ilaries ami WaRes 12,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 STATEMENT OF THE Apgr. Amount Total ■'cNo. Appropriated Appropriation H. R. 672 63 Maintenance 4,750.00 H. R. 672 64 Printing roster of ex-soldiers 4,000.00 H. R. 672 66 Administration of initiative and referendum laws 10,000.00 State Auditor 54,840.00 H. R. 719 70 Salary of Auditor 10,000 00 H. R. 719 71 Salary of Deputy 5,280.00 H. R. 672 72 Salaries and Wages 29,560 00 H.R.672 73 Maintenance 9,000.00 H. R. 672 74 For expense of accountant- and examiners. All mon- eys received for the an- nual audit of the Metro- politan Water District of Omaha, estimated _ 1, 000.00 State Treasurer 31,920.00 H. R. 719 80 Salary of Treasurer 10,000 00 H. R. 719 81 Salary of Deputy 5,28000 H. R. 672 82 Salaries and Wage.- . 14,140 00 H.R.672 83 Maintenance 2 500 00 Attorney General :»7,375.00 H. R. 719 90 Salary Attorney Genera! 10,000.00 H. R. 672 91 Salaries and Wages 49,875.00 H.R.672 92 Maintenance (office* 2,500.00 H.R.672 !)3 Prosecutions 30,000.00 H. R. 672 94 Cost and judgments 5,000.0*1 Superintendent of Public Instructions si 660.00 H. R. 719 100 Salary State Supt. 10,000.00 H. R. 719 101 Salary of Deputy-.. 5,280.00 H.R.672 102 Salaries and Wages 36,670.00 H. R. 672 103 Readers of Examination and extra help 9,700.00 H.R.672 104 Maintenance 20,000.00 Under Direction of State Superintendent. 345,000.00 H.R.672 105 Fixed charges — aid to school.-. 110,000.00 H.R.672 106 Normal Training 210,000.00 H. R. 672 108 For inspection of high schools 20,000.00 H. R. 524 109 For instruction of deaf chil- dren 5,000.00 Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings 38,080.00 H. R. 719 110 Salary Land Commissioner 10,000.00 H. R. 719 111 Salary of Deputy 5,280.00 H.R.672 112 Salaries and Wages 16,800.00 H.R.672 113 Maintenance 2,000.00 H.R.672 114 Capital outlay (solar transit and equipment) "1,100.00 H.R.672 115 Compiling and printing Blue Book 3,500.00 (Total Executive Depart ments) 800,075.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 9 CIVIl ADMINISTRATIVE CODE DEPARTMENTS Appr. Amount Total aic No. Appropriated Appropriation Ifepartment of Agriculture __ 1,077,740.00 H R. 672 121 For the use of the Bureau of Is, Drugs, and Oil and Bureau of Markets and Marketing all moneys col ay said Bureaus of the ■tment of Agriculture ie bienmum ending June 30, 1925, or so much may be needed for tenance and support bureaus together with Bureaus together with expended balance on :pended balance on le 30, 1923, estimate 589,000.00 }0, 1923, estimate :&gt;8it,000.00 of A IT al Industry ry and wages, estimate. I 1 8,000.1)0 ■u estima enance, estimated ince, estimated 20,000.00 ion of Bovine tuber- Bov ne tube iis 285,000.00 ion of Scabies. 10,000 00 .md Fish h i and Wages— 8,740.00 w 8,740.00 12,000.00 ince 12,000.00 tion, preservation and Proposition, preservation •ibution 85,000.00 -..000.00 ng and improving mproving d swamps for the r t\ of sinking wells to wells t( il lakes from freezing *5O,OOO.O0 and Wages 20.000.0C Ml.OOu.OO l.oO Finance 20,000.00 5.000.00 V ance 5,000.0(1 and wages l2,000.0C Labor 22.500.00 I 12,000.00 5,000.00 ance 5,000.0( ry expenses of the the expense rd of Mediation l,000.0&lt; I! 1 .000.00 llniMnn of Free Employment 1. R. 672 154 Salaries and wages 3,000.00 I. R. 672 156 Maintenance 1,500.00 Department of Public Welfare 156,954.00 Bureau of Health, Child Hygiene and Social Hygiene H. R. 672 162 Salaries and Wages 45,000.00 H.R. 672 163 Maintenance 23,000.00 Federal Social Hygiene, Maternity and Infancy H.R. 672 168 All moneys received from Federal Government, es- timated 36,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">lotal Appropriation m I 10 STATEMENT OF THE \ppr. Amount a|c No. Appropriated Bureau of Child Welfare NWMi.Oi 4.500.0C Bur.au of Examining Boards H. R. 672 173 For the Bure; Exami Department of I'ublic Works State \id Koad Administrat H. R. 672 181 Sala H. R. 672 182 M Knad Maintenance and Administr H. H. ';:•_' lsii Motor \Htiiole .\! Special Funds H. R. ii--&gt; ISO II. R H. R Federal Funds H. R. 1.72 104 Department of Trade and Commerct H. R H. R. 672 202 M Bureau of Banking H. R. (572 203 Sal H. R. H72 204 M H. R. 672 204b Si I'L Bureau of Insurance H. R. 672 205 Sal: H. R. 672 171 Salaries and watf H. R. 672 172 Maintenance Division of Athletio H. R. 672 174 Mai Bun .u of Irrigation H.R.672 183 Sala H. R. t;:-j 1st Mail H. R. 672 206 Maint H. R. fi72 207 Expei </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 11 Appr cN.i I nuni*si &gt;,p I i:«ui I Amount Total Appropriated Appropriation urit ,000.00 ,200.00 re 1» rventi 15,000.00 3,000.00 10.000.00 M Department SI, 781, 227.4 48,000.00 ;5,029 ,227.48 INDKV DEPART MEN I S 23,300.00 HIT 10,000.00 6,700.00 6,600.00 Tax Wa mnussior m&lt; 159,400.00 nt i Natio liuar rtmi Adjutar t General it A.lj. Ge 8,000.00 :.,4oo.oii Assista 130,000.00 ■ipi Certifi- 1,000.00 15,000.00 125,280.00 nil ion Railway Commis- 30,000.00 5,280.00 50,000.00 10,000.00 tar\ ae anc ,1 elp. traveling ex ate investi 80,000.00 115,500.00 &gt;nal Lands and Fund suppl mil it. 2,000.00 15,000.00 .-\ xpense reappraisir u light, power andengine lie 27,500.00 provements &amp; repairs to CaDitol 4,500.00 Capitc 3,500.00 Ma inter nt and moving 5,000.00 iTi </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 STATEMENT OF THK Total Appropriation t Capitol Commission from the Capitol Fund H. R. 672 270 Special levy for 1923-4, to MlSCELLANEOrs APPROPRIATIONS State Board of Agriculture H. R. 672 320 Premiums 4,000.0 H. R. 672 321 Meetings of organized agri- gether with any unex- Total Sundry ilepartir culture 3,000.00 H. R. 672 322 Maintenance &amp; storn- sewers *r&gt;0,000.0&lt; Appr. •|e No. Amount Appropriated H. R. 672 258 H. R. 672 259 H. R. 672 260 Relief of ex-soldiers, to be expended under provision Chap. 40, Session Laws of 1921 25,000.t)0 Relief of Spanish War Veter- erans and dependents 10,000.00 Publishing reports 500.00 penderi balance, etc.. etc. 5,048.7i Public Library I om mission H. R. 672 280 Salaries and wages H. R. 672 281 Maintenance H. R.672 282 Binding H. R. 672 283 Book* H. R.672 284 Institutional Librarie- 0,000.0( 3,00fl.0( l,000.0&lt; 4,000.0' n.000.0&lt; Boartl ol Vocational Education H. R.672 290 Salaries am! wa| H. R. 672 291 Maintenance H. R. 672 2!'2 State aid vocational educa- tion U.OOO.ii' in H. R. 672 293 All moneys received ;"ron the federal gfovernmen for the vocational educa tion daring the bien nium, etc. H. R. 672 2;i4 Inuu.-trial Re-education - — H. R. 672 295 All moneys received fron federal government fo S6.0O0 i) L'5.000.0 industrial re-etlucfctio: during the biennium end ing June 30, 1925. esti mate . Board of Pardons and Parole.- H. R. .'"2 300 Salaries and wages H. R. 672 302 Maintenance _ 10,000.0 5.000.( urn ii State Park Board H. R. '"'72 M12 Maintenance Morton Park 10.000.(1 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 13 H. R. 872 32/t Publishing reports and pro- motion activities cultural Societie: of Agri- State Hi-ti&gt;riral Society H. R H. R. 672 325 Maintena (irand Army of the Republic H. R Maintenanc KDl'C \TIONAI hra 1 in Morri Kurtau Normal SchiMil* t4&gt; vise herein specified, for the Normal Schools as follow H. R. 672 430 Chadron State Normal- H R. 672 440 Kearney State Normal- H R. 672 450 Peru State Normal H. R. 672 460 Wayne State Normal— H. R. 672 42«i Use of Normal BoanL 258,000 00 348,000.00 280,000.00 305,000.00 5.000.00 All expenditures for eiluca tional purposes unless other- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">1 ITATEMENT OF THE pur. mount ■ itui . r \n. pproprintcd Appropriation I. R C72 4-'l F&lt; ci no formal Sel n. L'ash and Maintenance Funds il i 1 H R «7-' 441 rhadron N'i id H. R. &lt;iT-' 4 VI Chadion Ni i- H. R. fi7'2 4r&gt;l Keaniex Norn H R KT&gt; lh-2 Kearnev N li H R «7S 4til Peru N H R (172 472 Wavne I ChariUhlf and I'mal Inslilution- H. R K72 500 Ceneral Maintaii riation. A I ikI it itt urn :iml lin.Ui HR719 502 Salarv Three &gt; rack 1- mil H R R79 For each insti other cash receij ine the bienniu June 30, 192 with bal. e; H R (!7-&gt; 4H-2 Pom N H.R. 672 471 Wayne Nora estimate Board H. R. 71i» 503 Salary of Sec H R R72 504 Salaries and ively all inst </seg>
            <seg id="p015">•UBLI A ■OUNTS 1: Amount Total Appropriated Appropriatiur App N Nebraska InMitution for Keeble Minded — Beatric .000.00 loo no </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 STATEMKNT OF THK lutal Appropriation Vppr. Amount aeNo. Appropriated 1R. 672 581 Cash Fuml ___ R.672 "i82 General repair lfi.iHMi.OO Stale Penitentiary — Lincoln H. R.672 r.yi Cash Fun. H. R. 672 -&gt;!'2 General rf (M Handc.att I urnilure &lt; onipain I State Penitentiary H. R.672 59fl Cash Ku Nebraska Industrial Homt H. R. 67:! ."&gt;OOK Apportion Milford t ipproi H. R HIM Rj Soldier-.' and Sailor?-' Homt — Milford H. R. &lt;i7 \ 1 H. R. (17 H. R. 8T Ft U. R. f I" H. R. «72 821 ' ash Fun( H. R. f.7 Norfolk Stale Hospital— Norfolk H. R. &lt;!72 500N Apjiortionmer appropriat H. R.672 631 La*h Fund H. R.672 »&gt;32 (leneral repairs H. R. 672 633 One new builditiR lO.IMlO Nebraska School For Deaf— Omaha H. R. 672 5(&gt;0P A pportionment from Maint appropriation tR. 672 641 Cash Fund — R. f.72 642 General repair *.IMX).O&lt; Slate R«formatory for Women — York H. R. 672 .iOOR Apportionment from Maint appropriation £R. 672 661 Cash Fund — R. 672 652 General repairs *4,(»00.00 H. R. ti7'2 . r )00J Apportionment from Maint appropriation H. R. 672 &lt;&gt;(VJ ( Nebra-Ka S. '11(1111 t«r Blind — Nt </seg>
            <seg id="p017">AUDITOR OK PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 17 Amount Total \ppr. a c No. Appropriated Appropriation Nebraska Home for Dependent Children — Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 STATEMENT OF THK AT1ONS the Constitut f the Sta U' o&lt; STATEMENT NO. !C. NOMINAL AI'I'KOI'KI In accordance with Article 3, Section 22 and 25 of being appropriations which do not increase the exper or the amount of Revenue to be provided. i I lJ«ard of Public l-a!id&gt; and Buildi H.R nc&lt;* i»Li* mii ri .^i Finance Department ■ H. R. 672 700 Revolving Cash Fund, esti mateil Department of Public W«tfci H. R. 672 710 State Equipment and Mater ial Fund, estimated Board of Control H. R. &lt;w2 720 Handcraft Furniture Co, fCa.oh Fund &gt; of manu facturinir end of State Penitentiary, est. TRIST Fl XDS I'nder Direction of Stale Superintendent H. R.672 800 Temporal j School Fund 1 No appropriation by thi H. R. t;72 &gt;&lt;H) Forest Reserve Recei;&gt;l&gt; from Federal ( 1 Nil appi opi iation 1&gt;\ th Department ot Trade and Commerce H. R. &gt;&gt;72 820 The rci-eim- duiinti tin- bien </seg>
            <seg id="p019">&gt;ITOR OF PUBLU ACCOUNTS \l 19 RKAI'PROI'RI A1EI) V ppr Amount Total Appropriated Appropriation \m 2.000,000.00 the State 192; t n . 2,000,000.00 $3,461,000.00 &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p020">STATEMENT OF THK ■ STATEMENT NO. 2 Showing the Expenditures of the Forty-second Se.-.&gt;i&lt;n\ of the Ne braska State Legislature: Salaries — Members of Senate Mileage — Members of Senate Salaries — Officers of Senate Salaries — Employes of Senate A. .*2rt,400.0ti 2 A. !)41.60 2 B. «,424.0O Total Appropriations Expended up to May 1! « Unexpended Balance Acct. No Unexpended Balance Acct. No. Unexpended Balance Acct. No. « OOO.Oi *:&lt;*.: Salaries — Employes of Senate 2 B. »,825.50 i.:- Total for Senate Salaries — Members of Hou&gt;e 2 C. Mileage — Members of Hou&gt;p 2 C. Salaries — Officers of House 2 D. Salaries — Employes of House 2 D. 80,000.00 2.842.0&lt;i 4,320.00 14.231.31 Total for House Expense* — Postage - E. Telephone &amp; Telegraph 2 F. I'rintinjf - 2 (i. Blank Books &amp; Supplies 2 H. MiscellaiifMiu- 2 I. !.72:Uo 236.74 15,83a.8ft 3,552 4!i 3,01 ».(W Total Sundry Expense.-- _ Total Expenditure.- up to May UM923 APPROPRIATIONS Account No. 1, H. K. 1 ' 1921 &gt; For Expenses of beginning legislature i Acct. No. 1 H. R. 58 Expenses of legislatu;. Acct. No. 2 H. R. 57 Salaries of Me-nber&gt; and Officers Acct. No " H. K. 87 Printing House ami Senate n </seg>
            <seg id="p021">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 21 Statement No. 2A OF THE SENATE the mileage and per diem paid by war - unts on the General Fund to members Legislature of the S*ate of Nebraska. Amount »er diem No. of Amount Miles of Mileage Total Paid xoo.oo *76 37.60 837.60 X0O.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 son.oo •6 !».6O 809.6(1 11)8 19.80 819.80 200 20.00 820.00 43fi 43.60 843.60 112 11.20 811.20 112 11.20 811.20 250 25.00 825.00 91.40 891.40 106 10.60 810.60 592 59.20 859.20 284 28.40 828.40 194 19.40 819.40 694 (59.40 869.40 112 11.20 811.20 58 5.80 805.80 mi 266 26.60 826.60 824 82.40 882.40 35.20 835.20 27.20 827.20 800.00 800.(10 442 44.20 844.20 J24 32.40 832.40 112 11.20 811.20 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 .800.00 800.00 800.00 112 11.20 811.20 498 49.80 849.80 136 13.60 813.60 460 46.00 846.00 266 26.60 826.60 104 10.40 810.40 24 2.40 802.40 306 30.60 830.60 184 18.40 818.40 28,400.00 !&gt;41.60 941.60 &gt;7 .341.60 27,341.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">■&gt;■&gt; STATEMENT OF THF Statement No. 2 B. OFFICERS OF SENATE In Whum I'aid No. of Days Amount Lieut. Governor, Fred G. Johnson Secretary, Clyde W. Barnard 1st Asst. Secretary, H. E. Wright 2nd Attt Secretary, F. E. McFarl Chaplain, A. A. Cressman 1 14 day- (hi $10.0(1 114 days @$ 8.00 104 (lavs &lt;S) $ 8.00 104 days @ % 5.00 520.00 59 days @ % 5.00 295.00 Sergeantat aims. A. D. McGinnis Asst. Sergeant-at-arms, W. F. Jor Postmaster, Jerry Wilhelm 104 davs @ $ 5.00 520.00 IK EMPLOYEES Secretary's Office Stenographer, Mrs. M. M. Me Bookkeeper, Mrs. M. S. McRe Stenographer, Maude Hoge Stenographer. Hattie Binder Stenographer, Henrietta Ham Stenographer. Mildred Darrov Mimeographer, Anna Mills Stenographer. Laura Mayer 44 da Senate Page, Edward Conne Page, Cecil Parson.- Page, Barnard Orr Pacre. Ravmond Buff Bill K.Him Chief Bill Clerk, W. H. lioi Bill Clerk, George Cathroe Bill Clerk. W. C. Gilham Bill Clerk, Wm. Cain Bill Clerk, F. B. SmitV Engrossing Room Chief Er.g. &amp; Enroll. Clerk. Ali Stenographer, Ruth Askine Stenographer, Ella Nelson Clerk to Lieut. Governor Stenographer, Georgia Ragsdak Janitors Harry Bradley J. C. St. Clair 134 davs fa 15 days &lt;® $ 4 Statement No. 2 B. )F SEN ATI Stenographer, W. H. Wine Stenographer. Kay Forbes </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS Statement No. 2 ( MKMBKKS OK THK HOI SK. Amount No. of Amount Total per diem Miles of Mileage Paid In \\ hum I'ai \ K \ M \\ 10 11.00 811.00 0 875.60 7.00 807.00 800.00 TJ»; 12.60 812.60 800.00 40 812.40 gn i" 10 Jll 841.6 KOO.I 2.40 832. si 14.00 844.( •a 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 600 60.00 860.00 800.00 280 28.00 828.00 800.00 168 16.80 816.80 800.00 480 48.00 848.00 800.00 184 18.40 818.40 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 54 5.40 805.40 800.00 S36 83.60 883.60 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 306 30.60 830.60 8C0.00 104 10.40 810.40 800.00 TOO 70.00 870.00 800.00 260 26.00 826.00 800.00 254 25.40 825.40 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 110 11.00 18.40 818.4C 4C.00 846.0C U.00 811.0C 14.60 814.6( .S0.80 830.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 STATEMENT OF THK Amount No. of Amount Total To Whom i'aid per diem Miles of Mileage Paid Kemper, E. L., Aurora 800.00 158 15.80 815.80 Kendall, J. F., Ponca 800.00 360 36.00 836.00 Keyes, Albert M., Holbrook 800.00 392 39.20 839.20 Lamb, Elmer J., Tecumseh 800.00 96 9.60 809.60 Lundy, James W., Sargent 800.00 372 37.20 837.20 Mathers, A. N., Gering 800.00 860 86.00 886.00 McCain, Wm. S., Stapleton 800.00 528 52.80 852.80 Miner, Chas., Ravenna 800.00 270 27.00 827.00 Mears, Grant S., Wayne 800.00 326 32.60 832.6(1 Mears, Grant S., Wayne 800.00 326 32.60 832.6' Mitchell, W. R., Wahoo 800.00 60 6.00 806.00 Mitchell, W. R., Wahoo 800.00 60 6.00 806.00 Moore, Wm.. Brownville 800.00 150 15.00 815.00 Moore, Win., Brownvilie 800.00 150 15.00 815.00 Morgan, John, York 800.00 120 12.00 812.00 Neff, P. B., BloomfieM -.800.00 428 42.80 842.80 Nelson, N. M., Pierce 800.00 296 29.6(&gt; 829.60 North, L. R.. Bridgeport __800.00 806 80.60 880.60 O'Gara. W. H.. Laurel 800.00 330 33.00 *:«.0" O'Malley, Ceo. W., Greeley 800.00 284 28.40 Orr, Chas. \V\, Lyons 800.00 190 19.00 819.00 Orr, Chas. \\\, L Osterrrran, Theo., Central City 800.00 194 19.40 819.40 Osterman, Theo., Cen Otteman, Geo. F., Hooper 800.00 140 14.00 814.00 Otteman, Geo. F., Hooper Parkinson, W. T., Pawnee City__ 800.00 140 14.00 814.00 Parkinson, W. T., Pawnee ( Peterson, Ernest, Axtell 800.00 294 29.40 Pollard, J. M.. Riverton __ .800.00 304 30.40 $30.40 yuinn, J K.. Elkhorn 800.00 150 15.00 Raasch, Ohed. Norfolk 800.00 274 27.40 Raasch, Olicil. Nf Reece. Chas. S., Simeon 800.00 682 68.20 Regan, R. C, Columbus 800.00 138 13.80 « 13.80 Reynolds. Scott, North Platte 800.00 510 61.00 Rourke, Jas. P., Grand Island 800.00 206 20.60 820.60 Schneringer, M. E., Callc Schneringer, M. E., Calloway 250.00 422 42.20 292.20 Smiley, Erie B., Seward 800.00 54 5.40 805.40 Smilev, Erie B., Se Smith, Ed A., Omaha Smith, Ed A., Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 xllOO Staats. Geo. F., Fremont 800.00 100 10.00 810.00 Stibal, Thomas, Schuvler Stibal, Thomas, Schuyler 800.00 148 14.80 814.80 Strehlow, Robt.. Omaha hOO.OO 110 11.00 811.00 Strehlow, Robt.. Omaha Svoboda, C. V., St. Paul 800.00 246 24.60 824 60 Svoboda, C. V.. St. Paul 46 Thatcher, A. B., Butte 800.00 494 49.40 848.40 Thatcher, A. B., Butte_. 800.00 Thomassen, John, Alda 800.00 210 21.00 821.00 Thomassen, John, Alda Timme, Herman C, Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Timme, Herman C, Omaha Vance, R. R., Hastings 800.00 194 19.40 819.40 Vance, R. R., Hastings 800.00 Ward, J. K., Arcadia 800.00 334 33.40 833.40 Ward, J. K., Arcadia 800.00 334 Wells, Frank S., Fairbury 800.00 128 12.80 812.80 Wells, Frank S., Fairbury 800.00 128 12.80 812'8O Whitehead. E. J., Holdrege 800.00 316 31.60 831.60 80 Whitehead. E. J., Holdrege 800.00 316 31.60 831.60 Wilson, Ralph P., Lincoln __800.00 Wilson, Ralph P., Lincoln 800.00 800.00 Wilson, Everett P., Chadron 800.00 916 91.60 89L60 Wingett. Wm., Walthill 800.00 216 21.60 82L60 Wise, John S., Hamlet 800.00 528 52*80 852*80 Wood, W. F., Haigler 800.00 602 60.20 860*20 Yochum, Chas. L., Talmage 800.00 124 12.40 812*40 Yochum, L. G., Ashland 800.00 52 5.20 805*20 80,000.00 2,842.00 2,842.00 82,842.00 82,842.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 25 Statement No. 2 D. OFFICERS OF HOUSE To Whom Paid No. of l»a&gt; - Amount Chief Clerk, Frank P. Corrick 104 days @ $10.00 Asst. Chief Clerk, T. W. Bass 104 days @ $ 8.00 Second Asst. Chief, Frances Sturmer 111 days (ff* % 8.00 Chaplain, J. G. Standard 104 days @ $ 5.00 Sergeant-at-arm.s Geo. Bivens 104 days (ffi $ 5.00 Asst. Serjeant-at-arms, W. W. Cole 104 days @$ 5.00 1,040.00 832.00 888.00 520.00 520.00 520.00 4,320.00 Statement No. 2 D. EMPLOYEES OF HOUSE Chief Clerk's Office Stenographer. M. L. Hamilton % days @ $ 5.00 480.00 8 days @ $ 6.00 48.00 Back pay 96.00 624.00 Si grapher, Kstella Athey 95 days &lt;W $ 5.00 475.00 8 days @ $ 6.00 48.00 Back pay 95.00 618.00 Stenographer, Zelma Arts 79 days @ $ 5.00 395.00 8 days @ $ 6.00 48.00 Back Pay 79\00 522.00 Stenographer. France.- Daly 66 days @ $ 5.00 330.00 8 days @ $ 6.00 48.00 Back Pay 65.00 443.00 Proof Reader. I. H. Rickel 10 days @ $ 4.00 40.00 89 days @ $ 5.00 445.00 174 hrs. 108.22 593.22 Proof Reader. F. G. Simmon.- 101 days @ $ 5.00 505.00 177 hours 110.09 615.0!) Messenger, C A. Crawford !I6 days &lt;fi&gt; $ 4.00 384.00 8 days @ $ 5.00 40.00 Back pay 96.00 520.00 House Postmaster, D. E. McNichol 104 days @ $ 4.00 416.00 9 days @ $ 5.00 45.00 Back pay 101.00 562.00 Mail Carrier, Ellis Coder 111 days @ $ 4.00 444.00 10 days @$ 5.00 50.00 Back pay 109.00 603.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 STATEMENT OF THl ay.- (a $ 5.00 4 P i5.0( 8 days &lt;ff $ fi.00 48.00 Back pay !»5.00 !U days @ $ 5.00 455.00 8 Back pay Clerk. Committee to investigate L'ni. Finances, Ethel Soderberg 14 days (n $ ."&gt; Clerk £ Bookkeeper, Nelle East 62 days &lt;« s 5 44 days (&lt;i I t; 2H4.OI Bookkeeper, F. M. Stapl l'aye. Barton Crawford Chief Clerk— W. D. Percival Stenographer — Ruby Daharsh Back pay Stenographer, Segrid Anders Stenographer, Grace Erskii l'ane. Barton (raw!. Pajre. Bruce Bell Pajje. Donald Thoma Pasre. Ben Gadcl Com. Clerk. C. B. Kl Stenographer — Olive Ridgell </seg>
            <seg id="p027">t&gt;ITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS Janitor* 95 .lays (a) $ 4.00 380.00 8 days &lt;K&gt; $ 5.00 40.00 Back pay "J5.00 515.00 !&gt;5days @ $ 4.00 380.00 9 days &lt;a&gt; $ 5.00 45.00 .00 380.00 ® $ 5.00 45.00 Back pay 95.00 520.00 Back ps i)5.00 520.00 $14,231.31 14,231.31 \TEMEN TEMENT 2 K. POSTAGE K. POSTAGE Dale nl \ Amount of Vntount of Warrant Warrant To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant rt hom and for What Account Issued Warrant P. Corrick, &gt;uimps $ 100.00 100.00 Barnard, stamps 32.00 32.00 Corrick, stamps 100.00 100.00 Barnard, stamps 36.95 36.95 E. E. Coder, P .0. E Coder, P .0. Box 2.15 2.15 Barnard, stamps . 35.00 35.00 :t tarn). P. Corrick, stamps 200.00 Krank P. Corrick, start 200.00 I Barnard, stamps 45.00 45.00 ii Barnard, stamps 40.00 Barnard, stair 40.00 Corrick, stamps __ 100.00 rick, stami 100.00 Barnard, stamps 50.00 50.00 tamp McClay, P. M. stamps (House* 200.00 McClay, P. M. stamps &lt; Hous -'00.00 Barnard, stamps 50.00 50.00 Barnard, stamps 50.00 Barnard, stamps 50.00 50.00 tamp McClay. P. M., postage ( House i 200.00 W. L. McClay, P. M.. po.-tage » House i 200.00 Barnard, postage 50.00 McClay. P. M., stamps (House) 102.00 Barnard, stamps 50.00 McClay, P. M., stamps i House ■ 200.00 u M.. stamps i.Hou.-e) 102.00 50.0(1 McClay, I'. M., stamp- i House i 200.00 Barnard, postage 20.00 20.00 Barnard, postage . - 10.00 s 1,72:!. 10 Statement No. 2 I'. No. 2 I ki.ki'hom: &amp; EPHONE &amp; TELKGRAPH TELKGRAPH U rn Union § 3.!»5 Western I in Union, Senate 2.31 2.31 n Tel. &amp; Tel. Co., House 101.05 Co., House 101.05 n Tel. &amp; Tel. Co.. Senate to Apr. 1__ 73.60 late to Apr. 1__ 73.60 Western I 3.75 Tel. &amp; 1 Co., Senate for April 21.00 UH Tel. &amp; T( Co., House for April 28.00 legrams 3.08 $ 236.74 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 STATEMENT OF THK Statement No. 2 G PRINTING AND PRINTED MATTER Date of No. of Vniount of Warrant Warrant Warrant To Whom and for What Account Issued 1923 Jan. 9 G-26760 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Journals $ 392.00 27137 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals 243.04 13 27285 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Records 211.60 18 27420 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 188.10 20 27812 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Journals 211.96 22 27815 Kline Pub. Co., House Rolls 388.08 24 27937 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 255.42 25 28158 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals 238.78 27 28411 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 144.89 29 28473 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals 199.98 28474 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals &amp; Rolls.. «47.7 Feb. 1 28684 F. E. Bricka, 5,000 Amendment Slips 16.50 28796 Acme Printing Co., Roll Calls 55.60 28797 Acme Printing Co., Roll Call Blanks 9.60 28851 Kline Pub. Co., Senate File •&gt; 3 28852 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals &amp; H. R. 841.4 9 29078 Kline Pub. Co., House Rolls 532.62 29108 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Journals 208.E 10 29186 Acme Printing Co., Receipts for Senate 14 29257 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals IB 29271 Beacon Press, House Rosters 16 29514 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 312.84 29515 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 293.04 19 29630 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 20 29716 Kline Pub. Co., House Rolls ,J 29717 Kline Pub. Co., House Rolls 489.06 21 29809 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 146 29993 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals. .06 29994 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Journals 208.W 30254 Kline Pub. Co., House Rolls__ 30256 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files. MM Mar. 1 30390 Kline Pub. Co., House Journals &amp; H. R._ i&gt;6: 8 30531 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 23.76 9 30646 Kline Pub. Co., House Rolls !*08.72 30653 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 206.00 13 30873 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 27.72 15 30961 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal :170.13 30962 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 31.68 17 31015 Beacon Press, Rosters 24.50 31016 F. E. Bricka, Amendments 16.00 23 31351 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 447.64 27 31484 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 288.65 31754 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 55.44 28 31925 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 206.00 31946 Kline Pub. Co., House Rolls 284.36 Apr. 2 32032 Acme Printing Co., Blanks 17.50 6 32240 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 209.75 32345 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 242.46 10 32490 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Journal 208.75 13 32726 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 217.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 29 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 267.2*2 32933 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 219.41 32934 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 206.00 13170 Claflin Ptg. Co., Printing ..—____ 173.50 3315 Claflin Ptg. Co., Senate Laws 42.50 J3388 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 138.36 i3391 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files ■ 43.56 ■63 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 211.76 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 150.12 laflin Ptg. Co., Printing House Roll 193.90 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 84.83 Kline Pub. Co., Senate Files 73.20 Kline Pub. Co., House Journal 126.75 43W Claflin Ptg. Co., Printing H. R. 362.50 $15,835.88 Statement No. 2 H. TA'IIONERY, BLANK BOOKS &amp; SUPPLIES Date ol No. of Amount of Warrant Warrant To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant 1H23 ItiHHi Beacon Pies.-. Desk card*--- S 12.00 !6911 Latsch Bros., Legal paper 16.50 Capital Bindery, Blank books, etc 105.25 7404 Capital Bindery, Blank books.— 105.25 8309 Revolving Fund, Supplies 56.90 «375 Latsch Bros., Supplies 111.40 8653 Beacon Press, Cards 31.75 '8686 Capital Bindery, Binders 12.00 8847 Jacob North &amp; Co., Envelopes &amp; Letterheads 39.00 8981 Revolving Fund, Supplies 159.85 8988 Tucker-Shean, supplies 22.05 19111 Jacob North &amp; Co., voucher books 88.50 29113 Tucker-Shean, supplies 14.85 29114 A. G. Chapman, Lineatime 14.00 29187 N. C. Leary Co., Letterheads 313.30 29248 Latsch Bros., supplies 13!oO 29265 Wekesser Ptg. Co., envelopes 24.85 2C257 George Bros., supp ies 70.65 29268 S. C. Huffman &amp; Co., filing boxes 2.48 29274 Latsch Bros., office supplies 48.60 29512 George Bros., supples 33.45 29806 Franklin Press, envelopes 43.60 2 29808 George Bros., stationery 906.8;l Mai 1 3U255 Frannlin rTCM, seal and letterheads 7.16 7.16 50389 Schwarz Paper Co., supplies 11.10 .5053!) N. C. Leary &amp; Co., stationery 109.66 30335 Latsch Bros., supplies 15.56 30(514 Revolving Fund, supplies 106.20 30654 Latsch Bros., supplies 17.60 31056 Jacob North &amp; Co., books 85.00 31057 Revolving Fund, supplies 94.70 31058 George Bros., letterheads 19.95 31350 Latsch Bros., supplies 1.00 1.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 STATEMKNT OF THE 31756 Tucker-Shean. supplies . 31757 Rudjre &amp; Guenzel, Misc. 31758 Beacon Press, rtationerj 31759 Capital Bindery, string; Apr. 6 31761 George Bros., supplies 32279 Revolving: Fund, supplie 32432 George Bros., stationery Revolving Fund, House 12 32663 Latsch Bros.. House sup 17 32814 N. C. Leary Co.. lettern 23 33172 Capital Bindery, 100 co&lt; 33385 Beacon Press, cards 33390 Latsch Bros., office supp 27 33558 Capital Bindery, covers «172 Capital Bindery, If 33385 Beacon Press, can 33390 Latsch Bi May 1 33790 Capital Bindery, tape. .. 33838 Revolving Fund, office 10 34215 Revolving Fund. House 15 34430 Tucker-Shean. office su 18 34543 Latsch Bros., office sup May 1 33790 Capital Bindery, tap* 33838 R nir 10 34215 Rev ii 15 34430 Tuc 18 34543 Lat Statement No. utcnuwit N MISCELLANEI MISCE1XANEOI Date of No. of Date of No. of Warrant Warrant To Whom and for \\ I 1923 Wai rant Warrant Id Whom and for What Ac 1923 Jan. 18 G-27-121 C. 11. Prey Floral Co.. 27422 Enterprise Elec. Co., Vo 27423 Miller &amp; Paine, flag 22 27833 C. E. Allen, floral tribi 28308 L. C. Smith Typewritei 27 28374 Miller A Paine, flag 2!) 28652 Hardy Furniture Co., ii Jan. 18 ( 7422 Enterprise i 8308 L. ( 8374 Mil Feb. 1 28683 A. (i.' Chapman. Lineati 3 2*S7s Mason Wheeler, Commi Mason Wh Phras( Phrase., and Correl ti 28979 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, pail. - 28980 Schwarz Paper Co., pa] Rudee &amp; Pai 8980 it 29107 Remington Typcw riter &lt; 29110 Remington Typewriter 291 12 L. C. Smith &amp; Bros., v, 19107 Remit '9110 Remin 29112 L. C. Smith &amp; 13 29249 Lincoln Fixtui 13 2924!» Lincoln Fixture &amp; Supp 15 29270 Enterprise Elec. Co., lai 29273 Eiche Floral Co.. spra; 1(&gt; 20513 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, incK 16 29513 Ruder &amp; G 20 29718 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, inciil 29719 Underwood Typewriter 20 2971N Rudjre &amp; Guenzel, incidt 29719 Underwood 7 27 30257 L. C. Smith &amp; Bros., t&gt;| 30329 Peoples Grocery, soap "0330 Benj. Hearson, auto hi 30257 L. C. Sm 21 29807 Calvin A. Er Mar. 3 30420 L. C. Smith &amp; Bros., typewrit 8 30532 Fred G. Johnson, exp. to St. F 30534 Hardv Fu </seg>
            <seg id="p031">UDIT )R OK PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 31 &amp; (iuenzel, cheesecloth 2.50 rite&gt; Co.. rent 10.00 Wheeler, assisting A. P. C. committee 100.00 &amp; Bros., typewriter rent 20.00 \ 29.75 &amp; Seal Co., rubber stamps 20.35 pans, etc 2.25 6.00 10.00 51.25 10.00 Dr. Hall 10.00 100.00 ICf wall 2.40 &amp; Glass Co., incidentals 1.55 iltv Co.. negatives 9.00 &amp; (iuenzel, merchandise it.30 16.00 Behrens, examining state institutions 13.68 !'u institutions.. 13.68 I mini i \\ Gcoil, examining stat institutions., 13.68 te institutions 13.68 xumnu W. H lllian, examining state institutions.. 13.68 i Paper Co., sweeping compound 4.50 impound 4.50 Smith &amp; Bros., typewriter rent 20.00 &amp; Bros., typewrite rent 20.00 Hughes, flowers 4.70 4.70 w Stapleton, investigating com. to Omaha 8.53 tfton Typewriter Co., rent 5.00 iSc Guenzel, cheesecloth 2.50 2.50 Wheeler, legal a.lvice 100.00 100.00 Minor, visiting state institutions 22.83 stitutions 22.83 tate institutions 22.83 n 1 1 titutions 3.48 ing state n 8.00 institutions 6.96 king state t n itutions 7.00 visiting &gt;tat isiting insti' institutions 19.58 tions 12.10 .timcnv 5(55.00 Wl Col )n Arrang. &amp; 128.00 apitol Inv. Com. 177.24 ,\ ( . I Typewriter Co.. rent 4.00 M. Pollard, investigating ftate institutions 3.48 Laundry Co., towels Jan \pr. 18.00 ;ten Typewriter Co., rent 5.00 Barnard, compiling and preparing nate Journal 200.00 Barnard, comparing and providing ginal Journal for Secretary of State 600.00 $ 3,014.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">\ Account re tr ment ■t W. MAF STATE OF NKBRASh Office of the Auditor of Public It is hereby certified that the fore appropriations made and the moneys &gt;n xp Session of the Legislature of the tate N the nineteenth day of May, 1925 sppt and to whom and for what paid of the constitution. IN TESTIMONY WHERE01 affixed my official seal this twenty-tirst day of Ma t i SEAL Attest FRANK B. HONZA. Dei </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>