<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00030</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION SHORT COURSES</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">rzr:^ THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebraska, U. S. A. AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION SHORT COURSES By H. J. Grami.ich Ladies' Class at Farnam Short Course. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C. W. Pugsley, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS History in Nebraska 3 Purpose of the Short Course 3 Men's Department 4 Ladies' Department 5 Arrangements with Town School Officials 6 Length of Short Course 6 Admission Charges 6 Tickets and Ribbons 7 Approximate Cost 7 Requirements to Secure Short Course 9 How to Secure a Short Course 9 Ticket Pledge for Short Course 10 Guarantors' Pledge for Short Course 10 Necessity of Cooperation 10 Advertising 11 Officers and Committees 11 Exhibits and Premiums 12 Entertainment of Speakers 13 Room for Domestic Science Work 13 Stock Judging Room 13 Results to be Expected from the Short Course 13 Specifications for Raised Seats 14 Extension Bulletins 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">iihort Courses are comparatively new in Nebraska. Many people not understand just what they are and how they are managed. :ordingly in this booklet an endeavor will be made to give a few ts pertaining to securing, promoting and managing them in com - nities. The aim will be to present the subject matter so as to the officers and committees in making their arrangements and &gt; to give prospective ticket buyers an idea of what they are to jive and why an admission charge is necessary. History in Nebraska Eiort Courses are commonly termed "One Week Schools of Agri - ire and Domestic Science", altho some call them "Fanners' tute Schools". The first one of these schools held in Nebraska at Pawnee City in the winter of 1907-08. Up to the date of this ng, twenty-eight have been held in Nebraska, nine of which : held during the season just closing. Besides these regular Short Courses a large number of Junior Short Courses, under the direction of the County Superintendents, have been held in the past four years. The Short Course is no longer an experiment. It has proven itself to be upon solid footing. With but few exceptions, every Short Course so far held has paid all local expenses by the sale of tickets and other minor sources of Purpose of the Short Course The Short Course is not installed in a community to teach the people how to farm and keep house. Most people were taught how to do these things prior to reaching their maturity. Neither does it give "fool-proof advice" as pessimists sometimes say. Instead it brings forth the results of years of experimental work conducted by our Experiment Station at Lincoln and its Sub-stations scattered over the state. I he Short Course instructors are constantly rubbing elbows with tical farmers. They glean ideas and new methods at each stop. 1 result their work is practical. It is the aim of the Extension artment to reach the youth of the land at these Short Courses 'ell as their fathers and mothers. Get the boy more interested lore of the farm problems. Let him try his hand at judging i, splicing hay ropes and doing similar feats. Likewise, let the attend the cooking school with her mother and see ladies cook- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 ing many splendid dishes and explaining and demonstrating while they work. A week's schooling of this sort will do much towards causing daughters to look upon housekeeping, and cooking in par - ticular, as an art rather than drudgery fit only for their good moth - ers to do and way below the dignity of their own dainty hands. I Short Course {s not a Farmers' Institute, altho it supplements fe in the Department feel that the Short Course, for money ded by us and by the local people, accomplishes a great deal than the Farmers' Institute. The instructors come and stay jhout the week. You get acquainted with them and feel at :t liberty to ask questions and enter discussions at any time : Institute the speaker talks rapidly for forty minutes, opens a inute discussion, then grasps his grip and runs for the train, g you wondering whether he knew what he was talking about s merely a living graphophone. Men's Department In the men's department classes begin each day at 10 a. m. Two hours are then devoted to lectures on practical farm subjects and to exercise in rope work including the making of various knots, hitches, splices, etc. The afternoons are devoted to crop lectures and stock judging. Raised seats are arranged in some well lighted building which can be kept heated. Lectures on the unsoundness of horses and similar subjects occupy a portion of the time. In judging the A class of three yearling Belgian colts used at Farnam Short Course. It is essential to get uniform groups of animals for the stock judging work. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 stock, classes of three or four animals are used and students are permitted to come down and go over them carefully. A meat cutting demonstration is given one afternoon to show where the various commercial cuts are made on the carcass and their relative value. This has a practical and close bearing on the stock judging work done during the week. Corn, grain and grass seed judging occupies a portion of the afternoon sessions. Detecting common weed seeds, treating grains for common diseases, preparing seed-beds and such subjects are included in this work. Where practicable a plow - setting demonstration is given on one afternoon. Among other sub - jects which may be discussed during the week are some of the following: Alfalfa, silos, winter wheat, farm weeds, horticulture insects, soils, crop rotations, dairying, cream separators and various Eie Short Course is not a prolonged Institute, but it is a School griculture giving in brief some of the work taught at our State cultural School to a class of people whose work and time will permit their attending the Lincoln school. Of the subjects ;ioned above only a portion are handled at a first year Short se and others at later courses if such are held. Ladies' Department §the Domestic Science Department the week is spent with lec - ; upon cooking, home nursing, sewing and other home problems, lemented by demonstrations. The cooking demonstrations and res occupy the bulk of the time and doubtless are of the most ral interest and importance. Many practical recipes are used lg the week's work and the prepared dishes are passed about Arrangement of equipment in Domestic Science Room at Utica Short Course. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 in charge of this work are the best which can be secured, and their efficiency and work can best be judged by the strong demand for their return to towns which have already held a Short Course. As with the men's work the practical side is put foremost. Arrangements with Town School Officials (should be so arranged that the students of the local high &gt;1, or at least those in the Agriculture and Domestic Science , can attend the Short Course. A very satisfactory arrangement have these students attend the forenoon sessions each day from 12. The forenoon work is adaptable to both men and boys, : the ladies' work is likewise adaptable to the school girls. Fore - sessions are oftentimes not as well attended by men and women e those of the afternoons. A special class in stock judging can ven the boys each morning from o to 10. In some towns the school officials do not feel that they can spare the entire week's time from the pupils' regular work, and in such cases the above scheme works out admirably. Sometimes the afternoon attendance of men and women cramps the rooms for space without the presence of the school boys and girls. Pupils from rural districts who are about to finish the eighth grade, or have finished it, should be urged to come in for the week. Length of the Short Course I be opening session is held Monday evening and the closing ses - either Friday afternoon or Friday evening. The Monday ing session is advertised as a general opening meeting and re - ion, and no charge of admission is made for same. State speak - are furnished for the evening session supplemented by local it in the form of quartets, recitations, music, and similar nura - . Four consecutive days are about as long as most farmers can way from their work. This with either four or five evening rtainments constitutes the Short Course. Admission Charges Pi meet the necessary expenses of a Short Course, tickets of ad - on must be sold. While the Department at Lincoln cannot late the exact amount to be charged, we prefer that one dollar le rate for men, and fifty cents for women. This admits them I day and evening sessions. We do not recommend charging a more than is absolutely necessary to defray local expenses. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 If the week's work is not worth the prices mentioned above it surely is not worth putting on at all, and so small an amount as that should keep no one from attending. The money raised locally is only used in the town where the Short Course is held. The Exten - sion Department pays speakers' salaries, expenses on trains arvl furnishes equipment. There are too many towns demanding Short Courses for the Department to be able to pay local expenses. Then again, if a town cannot raise sufficient money to meet local ex - penses we feel that there is not enough interest to guarantee a large attendance at the Short Course. Irate per day can fie fixed for single admissions. This should rge enough to encourage the sale of full week tickets. Twenty cents is generally charged for admission to each evening ses - , providing the party does not have a season ticket. Rates for ol children are generally half the rate for adults. School boards stimes buy tickets for their children. Commercial clubs have •ed to pay all expenses to get a Short Course to their town. We ot favor this because people will take more interest and attend ons more regularly if they have some money invested in the ect. We encourage cooperation in the entire community — in it is a necessity for a successful Short Course. Tickets and Ribbons Tickets should be printed and sold to those who guaranteed to take them and to all others possible, at least a month prior to the Short Course. Upon these tickets should appear the name of the Short Course, town in which held, dates and whether for men, ladies or school children. A week or so before the Short Course opens, ribbons should be printed. Upon these should appear the same wording as on the tickets, and use riblxins of different colors for each department. These ribbons should be at least an inch wide and seven inches long. The day the Short Course opens have a doorkeeper to take up tickets and pin ribboni on parties holding same. The ribbons are a great help. They will help advertise the Short Course and will obviate a good deal of bother watching doors, and furthermore will remove temptation from those who might at - tempt to gain admission without paying. When a party wishes a one-day ticket have your doorkeeper collect and give a receipt. Approximate Cost The local people will have to look after all expenses incurred in town. This will include buying of groceries and supplies for the ladies' department, renting halls and barns, equipping a stock judg - ing room with raised seats, hotel bill of speakers, printing of all </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 advertising including a uooklet containing complete program and premium list, and various other incidentals which may occur. Also the hiring of a lady to wash dishes and help during the week in the women's department. A town should have at least $250 in sight before contracting for a Short Course. An average expense of the Courses held this past winter, aside from premiums offered by merchants, runs about $200. Following is an itemized bill of the expenses at a recent Short Course. Newman Grove, Nebraska February 3 to 7, 191 3 Hall rent. Domestic Science Room $ 12.50 Juelson Bros., Mdse 1 .35 C. H. Morian, Meat 2.65 E. \V. Hallgren, Mdse 75 Conrad Erickson, Mdse 14 .75 Witt Bros., Mdse 3.25 Axel Nelson, Mdse 40 Mrs. Ed Johnson, Milk .48 Mrs. Julis Torgeson, Mdse 1 .50 J. M. Strand, Cream 1 .25 Chas. Letheby, Flour 1.10 Mrs. Christiana Johnson, Labor S.00 Mrs. Rustad, Labor « &gt;.oo Mrs. Johnson, I^abor &lt;Voo Thomassen Bakery, Mdse 40 Board for Speakers 3--5O Printing and Advertising 5-M5 Gutru &amp; Juelson, Mdse 4.20 N. G. Milling Co., Lumber, etc 12.80 Opera House 1 8 00 Total $180.33 "A balance of over sixty dollars is left to apply on next year's r r j j meeting. This is doing remarkably well for the first attempt. Those who had charge of the enterprise have reason to feel mighty well satisfied with their efforts." — (Clipping from "Newman Grove Reporter".) Practically all points are able to meet expenses by ticket money providing, of course, that the ticket selling is pushed. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Requirements to Secure Short Course {Complete harmony between town and community. Complete confidence of the people in their officers. Harmony among all officers. rA good record of Farmers' Institutes held in years preceding. Available buildings in town which will be suitable for follow- ing purposes : a. Domestic Science Demonstrations. This room not to be molested for other purposes from Monday morning until Friday night. b. Hall for men's forenoon and afternoon sessions and large enough to accommodate combined audience at night. c. Stock judging room, well lighted and heated. d. Exhibit room. KA pledge sheet containing names of one hundred men agree - to take tickets at one dollar each and one hundred women at fifty :s each, or names of sufficient men and women guaranteeing to : one or more tickets to bring the total of each up to one hundred. 7. Names of ten or more reliable men guaranteeing to make good any deficit which might occur in financing the Short Course. This is to assure the Department of Agricultural Extension at Lincoln that all bills incurred will be met. K Duplicates of such guarantee sheets as are mentioned above to be sent to the Department of Agricultural Extension before lite promise of Short Course is made. 9. Publication of a complete report of all expenditures and receipts in local paper after Course is over. Such a statement must be submitted to this office at the close of a Course. How to Secure a Short Course if you have requirements 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 and are desirous of uring a Short Course, the first step is to get a supply of this letin from the Lincoln office and distribute them among the &gt;ple of your community. We will furnish these bulletins free, ter the people have had time to read the bulletin over carefully, cure pledge sheets and some day when many people are in n have each officer take one of the sheets and canvass as many possible. It would be well to have five or six sheets at least. f e the pledgors to understand that the money will not need to be d unless the Short Course is secured. Sheets headed as below 1 be sent upon application. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 J ICKET i LLIXiE FOR J&gt;HORT COl/RSE We, the undersigned, agree to purchase the number of Short Course tickets set opposite our names, said Short Course to be held in during the winter of 1913-14. Men's tickets one dollar each. Ladies' fifty cents. Men's Indies' Name Address Tickets Tickets John Brown Upland 2 1 1 J. R. Smith Upland 1 Mr-. White Minden 1 CiiAK.wTORs' Pledge for Short Con We, the undersigned, jointly and severally agree to make goof 1 . any deficit which might occur in financing a Short Course in during the winter of 10.13-14. Xanie Address Occupation J. R. White Farmer Tom Brown Implement Dealer James Brown \u000cneer Of the twenty-eight Short Courses held up to date in Nebraska, . -- o — —g- r not to exceed three have drawn uyton this deficit pledge and they drew very lightly. A duplicate of each pledge sheet must be sent to the Department of Agricultural Extension, Lincoln, Nebraska. Necessity of Cooperation Where there is a lack of unity between town and country people ___ — j — — __..-- _ 4 j- , we find it very hard to hold a well attended, successful Short Course. While the Course is primarily along agricultural lines, yet its sphere is for the betterment of the entire community. It is well to have some of the officers residing in the town or at least some of the committee chairmen. The secretary should either live in town or close by, because of the nature of his duties. After a course has been secured everyone should lay aside petty grievances and boost. Count on sending the state speakers away with the report that y&lt; mr o _ ( _ _^ -~i — - - — , town put up the best attendance and interest of the season. There will be no graft connected with the Course. Instances have hap- pened where men who were supposed to be "boosters" have turned "turtle" just because their man was not at the head of the Course. The only compensation any officer or committee can hope to get is the satisfaction of knowing that their efforts helped to make the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Advertising The Short Course should be thoroughly advertised over the county and adjoining territory. Farmers and their wives from neighboring communities should be especially invited to come and stay for the entire week. A committee would do well to secure a list of available rooming places for such parties as might wish to do tin- Letterheads might be printed announcing date. Officers and Committees Kere should be a president, vice president, secretary and treas- There should also l)e a committee composed of from one to members for each of the following : i. Advertising and Program Printing. Finance and Ticket Selling. ,V Premium. To solicit and apportion premiums. 4. Live Stock. To secure stock for judging. — _ — _ — _ - _ j o o Equipment. To arrange for buildings, seats, stock stalls, do - ic science room. etc. The ladies should have their auxiliary officer* and be represented on all committees except No. 4. The financing and ticket selling committees should by all means work together. In appointing committees, especially the chairman of each, the president should be very sure to get parties whom he knows will WORK. Officers of the Farnam Short Course. Two successful courses have been </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Exhibits and Premiums Knerallv Short Courses do not offer as many prizes for exhibits stitutes. The amount allowed for these is, of course, left en - with the local committee. Women as a rule do not have to bake much during the week. It is well to give prizes for of the following: i. The man, woman, or child selling the most tickets. 2. The party coming the greatest distance. 3. The boy judging stock the best. 4. The boy who ties rope the best. 5. Grains, silage, cooking, sewing, fancy work and other things as in the past. K offering premiums remember that the Short Course is primarily 100I and the student should receive the prize rather than the r or possessor of some worthy article, fowl or stock. Merchants are generally willing to offer certain articles in their stores for prizes. Holdrege this year had over $400 in prizes. Other towns have had less than $50 and still had successful Courses. Domestic Science Exhibit at Newman Grove Short Course. Over seventy cakes were displayed. The railing in foreground makes more room for rr &gt;mmittpps to wnrlc </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Entertainment of Speakers. If the hotel is reasonably good the speakers would prefer to stay there, as it is hard for them to always be prompt for meals, and they then can have a room that they feel is their own, to which they can come at any time without inconveniencing the owner. The recep - tion committee should make reservations for the speakers and see that they are met at the train, or at least notified where to go. Room for Domf.stic Science Work Iiis should be amply large to handle a maximum crowd, well ed and heated. It should be a room which will not need to be sted for other purposes during the entire week. A lodge room isatisfactory for that reason, unless all lodge meetings can be x&gt;ned. In this room platforms and tables will be necessary, to - er with full equipment for the demonstrations. A list of articles ssary for equipping this room will be furnished prior to the t Course. Stock Judging Room tis often difficult to secure a suitable room for this. There are absolute essentials for this room at a winter Short Course, first is ample light, even with all doors shut, and the second is imcnt with stoves or other means of heating. Ample light is isary to see the stock properly, while the room must have the removed as the classes sometimes remain there two hours at a Plans and specifications for bleacher supports are given on an - other page. Sixteen foot planks are generally used for seats. These should lap about a foot where they join ends. There should be three supports for each length of plank. Figure eighteen inches space per person and you can estimate the room needed for your class. These raised seats are absolutely necessary to enable the students to see the stock right. An unused garage often serves the purpose well. Vacant store buildings answer well, and livery barns may do if they are amply lighted when the doors are closed. Results to Re Expected from the Short Course E would be hard to say just what results should be expected from Short Course. We hope they may be many. As a rule if one ires of people who have attended Short Courses in other towns, find that they feel well repaid for the time and money expended, ses a long way towards putting a town on the map if the Short </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 l-Oursc people go away Doosting und newspapers comment iavorablv over the state. The influence of this Short Course is far-reaching. Below is a picture of Frank Carver. This boy, for that is all he is today as he is not yet eighteen years old, attended a Short Course at Cambridge. Nebraska, the last week in January, 1910. A large cattle judging contest was held for men and boys. Nine groups of cattle, including Red Polls. Herefords, Angus and Shorthorns, were judged. In figuring up scores the writer found this boy an easv winner of first prize. That evening Frank said that he thought he would come to the State Agricultural School as soon as he could arrange to do so. I^ast fall he entered the school. In January he entered the annual horse and cattle judging contest held at the State Farm. Breeders of fancy stock from all over the state were Frank Carver, a boy who received his first agricultural training at a SI </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 (contest, besides a large number of advanced students. Frank fth in the horse judging, in which contest a class of ten draft were placed and another of five Shetland ponies. In the judging he won eighth on placing a class of ten head. Un - dly the Cambridge Short Course started this boy to thinking utilizing every opportunity to secure an education. ' Side view of support for raised seats in stock judging room. The dotted lines at top might previ represent banisters where the seats are not against a wall. This an accident. Drawing furnished thro courtesy of Agricul- prevent tunl Engineering </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Back view of support for stock judging seats. The l"x6"s make the sup- ports firm and safe. Extension Bulletins Bulletins on Crop and Annual Production, and on methods of organizing Farmers' Institutes, Boys' and Girls' Clubs, Short Courses and County Farm Demonstration work will be sent free upon request. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>