<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  ECONOMICAL RATIONS IN BEEF PRODUCTION.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Nebraska. IH'ULETIX AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RASKA ii.umb XX. Article I. DNOMICAL RATIONS IN BEEF PRODUCTION. By H. R. Smith Ski'Tkmbek 11, 19UT fft Qfe/ RT I.OIN OF JAMES IMPROVER breeds). International Live I)r Fed and exhibited by \ sity of Ncbrsuka. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">\ Introduction Plan of Experiments Prairie Hay versus Alfalfa The Use of Corn-stover with Corn and A Feeding Corn-fodder Corn and Prairie Hay versus Corn. L rein Concentrates i Wheat I meal) Compared LJnseed-meal (a Protein Concent r Roughage) Prairie Hay versus Corn-stover Heavy versus Light Feed of Corn with A The MOt-1907 Experiments Financial Statement </seg>
            <seg id="p003">&gt; i ECONOMICAL RATIONS IN BEEF PRODUCTION. BY II. K. SMITH. Uion of methods In which beef production ■e profitable is one of the important problem! estigation ;it tin- Nebraska Experiment Sta - icccnt yean the attractive pricei offered for uarkeis of the world have led many stockmen of discontinue their cattle feeding operations and lop direct to elevator companies for shipment. turned their attention to pork and mutton pro iave riiat beef values have not kept pace with th&gt; • upward trend of recent years is not denied. Nor said that the market quotations for corn-fed beef as attractive as the prices offered for finished pork !i during the past few years. Nevertheless, rattle l!l its place, and the industry will Ik- regarded with ivor as we learn to more fully appreciate the im - i-attle in their relation to the economic mat ir laud ally every farm in the State where grain crops own and sold direct to the elevator for a sn. the soil is much below the productive capacii\ rnis where crop rotation and stock feeding id iced. Pork production, good so far as it § uk to the land fertilising material taken from profitable as it has been during these year- in should not be carried on to the entire exclusion &gt;f meat production. The occasional de I an entire herd of swine by the ravages of cholera of he considered, but as an argument for a givatev i ter y of live stock on the farm it does not carry the weight ne great argument, viz., the economical conversion of h u 100, AGR. EXP. STATION of NEBS. Vol.. XX. AKT. I </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 noHiual Ration* in Beef Production. t r a larger part of the vast quantity of roughage grown ou everj farm as by-products to grain into some marketable commod - ity. Cattle and sheep feeding not only make possible the utilization of such material, but these ruminants, requiring much bulk as they do, also encourage tlie growth of more clover and alfalfa iu the crop rotation, thus pwiU'fing the fertility of the land, ('at tie are not only able to conMUne bulky material in quantity, but they are also able to t; in its crude form, less costly, therefore, than if labor is ex pended in its preparation. During the years of low-priced corn, cattle feeding \va profitable under almost any system of feeding, but condition having changed, methods must be varied to meet the mw »ii nation. Beef lias always been a luxury, and we can hardl, expect its rise in value to be commensurate with thai of con and other cereals used in the human dietary. When it i» collies excessively Ugh ill price the consumers use less lnc;i and more of other foods which, tho less palatable, are nun cheaper and can serve as substitutes. In beef production, a Ber forms of industry, competition forces (H-ononiical methods, and it is left for t beef more cheaply rather than to diaconti cattle because of higher priced grain. If cattle feeding, aside from its beneficial tainiug or restoring soil fertility, is still a profitable industry in states farther east — as it is when properly conducted farmers of Nebraska are situated to make it doubly - virtue of the natural conditions which favor the industry lure, viz., lower priced corn than any other state in the Union the possibilities of alfalfa and clover culture, notably tin former, favorable markets and shipping facilities, and a &lt;li mate of relatively low humidity in winter which permits out door feeding. It would be unreasonable to expect cattle t&lt; return every year without fail prices for corn above what might have been received at the elevator. The instability &lt;&gt;| the average stock market would hardly permit it. But fol </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 / after year with careful buyiiig and the exercise lie management of tattle, particularly with refer- leetion and use of foods, fair profits are to be n N raska. relatively speaking, is a uewly settled State, the u half being occupied by farmers who have been giving )f their attention to the growing and selling of grain. &lt;&gt;t at all surprising, therefore, to find that as the need k on the farm is felt mistakes will be made and what have been profits are really losses. That the Experi Station might be brought in closer touch with actual us as they exist in this State, the writer in the early : of L903 visited a large number of feed lots to learn rations were in common use. In this investigation it mind that by far the largest number were fattening n corn and prairie hay, tho some were making use of ane or millet as a substitute for prairie hay. In the ntral and western portions of the State corn and al- » were being fed, while a number in the Missouri River its were feeding clover. The use of oil-meal and eotton- 1 il was confined to a few men who feed on an extensiv • d who buy practically all their grain. From the on- us made it would be conservative to sav that unbal- I rations were being fed on two-thirds of the farms vi&lt;- That our farmers might have a practical demonstration i • greater possibilities of a system of cattle feeding which ore nearly in harmony with Nature's laws with re- (be character of tho food as opposed to a system which m entirelv the animal's physiological requirements, tho •s of experiments herein described were conducted under lit ions precisely as they may lx&gt; found on many farms in State. PLAN OF EXPERIMENTS. The steers selected for all experiments were grown under range conditions, having had no grain previous to their pur- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">EIIh-v were ehoaen for uniformity in age, qua ;ts ni-arh ;is it was poauble to secure it. V\ hen l into lota &lt;&gt;f ten steer* each was made previous i imental feeding, an effort was pat forth io n Till lots represeniai ive of the entire herd sn tlia would have the advantage of another in weight, ilition or age. This would make the several lots h. II another. EJvery feed was carefully weighed, no credit bein given for any course ronghnefw left in racks and afterwards thrown out for bedding. This waste was charge to the r! iust as tho it liad been consumed. From what has been ahnvo it may lie assumed that the differences in ir;tins as re ported in tho tables to follow ai d bv the rations, at gle winter's experiment comparable, Inn inn the lois fed on winter with those fed another winter. In other words, ill reader is not to compare the feed record of 1904 &lt;(."&gt; wiili th feed record of !!•&lt;»."» tit; or any other year. Grade Herefor yearlings from Cherry County, Nebraska, were fed in \\^y-'&lt; »&gt;l: Grade Shorthorn two-year-old« from North Park r.ido. in l'.MU 15; Grade Shorthorn and Hereford two oi.is from Bock County, Nebraska, in 1905 (•&lt;;. and G Aliens two-year-olds from Sioux County, Nebraska, in 0i. All lots in evei-v e\|M-riin&lt; nt were provided with having large open doors on the south side to permit the - to l;o in and out at will, none having horns. The yards small l&gt;ut of sutlicient size to permit of some exerciw 1 . A cattle were given water morning and night and sail was ke| before them at all times. Each lot was fed for a preliminar period of approximately three weeks before the r the experiment were begun in order that all know how to pal grain and furthermore have time to l E adapt themselves to their respective rations. The initi; hts of the different lots as tabulated are an average &lt; four weighings made on successive days jusi before waterin in the norning. This is done to reduce as much as posaihl the element of error often caused bv a fill larger one dav tha </seg>
            <seg id="p007">/ 7 i i I ■xl i largely so as it was possible to make the several lots veil experiment average uniform in quality ami gain- iparity. It is out of the question to eliminate entirely •ror which might be caused by individual differences in gaining capacity of steers even by feeding in lots of ten i. It is for the purj)ose of making the conclusions more iilile that the same ex]&gt;eriments are being continued thru I'KAIKIK HAY VERSIS ALFALFA twiug is a comparison of the feeding value of native hay as it grows in Nebraska, and alfalfa, each seiag as a roughness to supplement heavy corn feeding: and prairie hay versus corn and alfalfa steers Average '03. to Ian . 05, to Nov., UV for lime. '04, July, 05,— Feb., '(Hi. 3 years. 24 weeks. 24 weeks. 12 weeks. ISnaL Shellrd |*-d S ?2f Con and r " pram, alfalfa J '.' and , . pram. 1 . VI 1 1 -'d 2.06 1 4* | 11 14:io 15.SU 17 90 18.60 '.(.47 9.47 13 89 14 4ti 7o B.20 15 12 21 ».9U !) 10.50 7.70 B.52 8.14 7 s7 4 (Ml 4 70 5 Hi 4.08 15.1H 10.75 - Profit 1'rotit Loss I'nilit Loss I'n.fit Loss t'rurit ♦».«« fl.13 *2.Hfi to. 0B 13.56 10.27 I Snapped corn is the ear within the husk or shuck. The figures in table are its shelled corn equivalent. » computing profits all items of expense were included except the f feeding which is customarily figured as an offset to manure made. ssion of three &lt;&gt;r more years. Vearling Two-year-old Two -y tar-old stters steers steers SOI. 00806. 00!»2«. 00981 U0M5 i»Mi77.0O 901 .(M&gt; 17.00 12.40 14 71 12.18 -^.tia 15 :$5 18 #6 (14 18.23 *&lt;: x'.i $8 7B 15.49 $8.32! W.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 i IV &gt; It is never safe to accept as definite (he conclusions draw from a single experiment, but when we have, dunii"- a su. cession of three years, tlie niai-ketl contrast in daily .f production, and net profits in favor of alfalfa a pared with prairie hay which the above table indicates, thei would seem to be little room to doubt the superiority of a fill fa when each is fed with corn alone. There may 1&gt;&lt; eral reasons for this. Perhaps tirst in importance is th x that alfalfa is a legume, having, like clover and i*owpea power to take nitrogen from the air. storing it with n cellular structure in the form of proteids, which niatei needed by the animal in the formation of lean titwii n Itone. Alfalfa in itself contains more protein than tl a\ age fattening animal require**, an excess sntiicieni pensate for that lacking in corn, the two togethei making a balanced ration for fattening cattle. I like corn, lacks protein and when fed singly 01 do not supply enough of that nutrient to meet pi requirements. This is best shown by exauiin i lean formers i of each food and the w h carbohydrates i starches, etc. ) and \ latter producing animal fat and IkxIv heat. \Vh proximately a well-balanced ratioi year-old steer is indicated by the line havit seven pounds of carbohydrates and fats. It will how closely the ration corn and alfalfa — two pound former to one of the latter — approaches this proportion. In fact, we are not sure lint that 1 :7.3 is just as suitable as 1 for an average two-year-old steer. The corn and prairie h: combination, however, is decidedly larking in protein, which is no &lt;louht one of the chief causes of its failure as an nomical ration. iii jr chart, the black lines reprewentin ratio 1:7, by wliicli is meant out' |h&gt;iiik </seg>
            <seg id="p009">iUi'i 7 u •»-i Hut the composition of a food is not the only factor which icrniincs its value Alfalfa is very ninth more Kinked u prairie hay and it is less difficult to masticate. Steen a dcil for the largest putwible t'OUHUiiiptioo of grain can be induced to eat a little more coin with alfalfa than prairie hay. Betennining the cost of producing loo pounds of gain, and prairie hay were figured at *)&gt;.(&gt;&lt;) each per ton for the three years. Corn was X\ cents per bushel in LM3, :{'•' cents in 1904, and ."{."&gt; cents in 1!)!)."). It is unfair to make com - parative values of a roughage like alfalfa, which balance! well with corn alone, and one like prairie hay which dix^s not, hut when thus fed as in these three experiments, the alfalfa returned values ranging from (10.88 to *1."&gt;.7I) par ton as Bired with prairie hay at Sft.00. The ex]&gt;eriments show, er. that we can not afford to feed prairie hay at fU.iMI 'This chart is based on the average composition and digestibility of the foods indicated as determined at numerous places. The nutritive ratio is found by multiplying the digestible fats by 2%. adding this to the digestible carlxihydrates and dividing the sum by the digestible protein. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Economical Rations in Beef Production. per ion even if we include in the profits all pork nade from droppings, as was done in these computations; at least we &lt;an not afford to do so if corn alone makes up the grain ra - tion. Referring to the net profits per head M given in the table it is of interest to know that the net advance of selling over cost price for the twenty-four weeks period* was |1.30 per hundred on the corn and prairie hay steers in LM8 and fO.78 in 1904, while the advance on the alfalfa steers was |1.68 per hundred in 1903 and fl.00 in 1904. The larger ad vain e received for the alfalfa steers was no doubt due to tin - higher finish made by those steers. It is apparent that profits can he made by feeding corn and alfalfa even tln&gt; the selling price of the cattle does not greatly exceed tin price. In these experiments the feeding of alfalfa at $t».(&gt;0 per ton with corn nude this grain bring, when converted into beef, 51 cents per bushel in 1903. 44 cents in 1904. and tin cents in 1MB. It would take a larger advance than our mar kets usually afford to make corn and prairie hav profitable at the prices for corn and cattle which have prevailed during the past few years. Clover was not fed in this series of experiments, but cause it is similar to alfalfa in composition, tho somewhat lower in protein, it would not be unreasonable to exjwet gains on corn and clover; and experiments made in other states show favorable results for this combination of f With any other form of roughness with the exception of cow pea hay, which is also a legume, we would hardly expec isfactory gains unless some protein concentrate is fed with THE TTSE OF CORN-STOVER WITH CORN AND ALFALFA. From the experiments already described it is apparent that a ration of corn and alfalfa is capable of producing large and profitable gains, enough so to make corn bring more in the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Ik upon which it grew. Do not these stalks growi iu irge quantity «&gt;n our con laud pattern sufficient nu make it worth while to harvest them for deed- Left standing in the field they become woody in fill only as winter forage for stock cattle ami value being estimated at from 25 cents to *l.no rice not to exceed ~&gt;0 cents {mt ton. When cut locks immediately after the corn rijM'ns they iv tin fairly green, retain in the leaves the nutritive pro[&gt;erties Rack for feeding corn fodder or stover iiich they possessed when harvested and are much relished en by cattle on a full grain feed. For the purpose of se - ring data upon the above question two experiments were mlucted in which the ration corn and alfalfa was compared th corn, alfalfa and stover i stalks without the earsi. Th. - &gt;ver was fed unshredded in racks provided with vertical shits only wide enough apart to permit the steers to enter E heads, thus preventing the stalks from being pulled out trampled under f&lt;x&gt;t. The coarse butts refused, approx elv 40 per cent of the stalks fed, were thrown out for </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 1 I. i 1 h r I i bedding purposes bat charged to the steers ;1 s feed roma Tlie stover was fed each morninu in order that the stn mijrht have the entire day to work over the stalks, and i alfalfa was fed only at ni-rht to those lots receiving stov Following is tin- record of the steers— ten two-year-olds each lot — fed as indicated : rge initial weigl nds 4! 4 Average gain per day. j li K grain fed per day. pound roogkneM fed per day, pounds I rain consumed per pound i &gt;f pounds of gain, p ninds Total food consumed per pound 4 The tahle shows that in the first experiment eqaal pan alfalfa and stover produced a slightly larger daily gain th; alfalfa fed as the sole roughness with shelled corn. In t second exiM-riinent, when mapped corn was used, the reven was true. A ration consisting of corn and alfalfa is often t&lt; laxative, especially with the later cuttings of alfalfa. In t first experiment it is very probable that the stover lessen the tendency to scour, while in the second experiment t| presence of husk and col, served the same purpose. The may have Imvii also some advantage in having stover wit ilfalfa for variety. In this connection it may !.&lt;■ said th; Roughness consumed per j. &gt;f 100 pounds of gain |&lt;t.8» *&lt;i.4H io.4!&lt; *.", n| f &gt;t i pn.nt per head including ix.rk. r3.32 *;i . .-&gt;»&gt; $4.ao * ['ABLE I alfalfa versta corn, al/alla and a . n"&gt;. to Nov., '06, ti July, '06, Ian., '(Mi, -&gt;\ weeks. 18 »■ exi A l&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p013">liswcr these purposes, hut prairie hay ordi- niiicli as alfalfa, so there is hut little advan it. In both the experiments tabulated above, rn-stover at si'. .10 per ton as half the roughness lie tost of gains — in the tirst 40 cent* per hundred, id 48 cents. The stover proved to l&gt;e actually h 93.55 per ton witli mapped conn ami $4.1(i per ton with ed corn, worth :{!! cents per hushel, as compared with fa fe&lt;l alone at $i\.W pet ton. Nehraska produced last , in round cumbers, eight milliou tons of corn-stover. If 'ourth of this amount could have heen converted into bringing hut ¥-•&lt;*&gt;&lt;&gt; jht ton as fed from the shock ins tea 1 .")(» cents in the stalk fields, four millions of dollars could ire been added to our earnings, and no losses from cornstalk asc would have come from feeding the stalks thus Ejection that is usually raised against the practice of ng and shocking corn for feeding purposes is the lahoi volved in husking it from the shock. The fact that a great rn mav he fed to cattle in the stalk unhusked is en v overlooked. In a 1905-06 experiment one lot of ten year-old steers was fed corn fodder for a period of twelve weeks in comparison with the same amount of snapped corn and stover fed another lot. Two-thirds of all the corn given the one lot was attached to the stalk, the remainder consist ing of shelled corn fed at night. Charging four cents per hushel for husking, the cost of gains was the same in both ts. In 1906-07 this comparison was again made and half ill the corn fed was attached to the stalk. Here again the I of production was practically the same, being only 10 cents per hundred less for mapped corn. The feeding of corn on the stalk in the morning with shelled corn and alfalfa hay at night is proving to he a very economical system of lun-f production, and it may he continued thruout the entire pe- FEEDING n»UX FO1&gt;1&gt;EK I KNTIKE PLANT). </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Fie. 2 Ha Fig. 3. Building bottom of round stack for spring feeding of bundles should be flatwise with all heads touching </seg>
            <seg id="p015">icai Rations in Beef Production. t 15 itacking the bundle* near the feed yards for use in urinter. For such purposes con which has been drilled thicker than usual is West becaaae the cars arc loaae - nailer, tho it should nor be planted so thickly that the corn will be reduced. By feeding corn fodder m be stalk and vet are put to no extra labor basking it let corn can be cut with a harvester and put in the shock Bier than if can he picked and cribbed, inasmuch as three iritfa a team and harvester can cut and shock seven m ay. Records from the Farm Department of this Kxp»-ri Station show that it costs $1.1S jmt acre to cut and corn, which figure does not allow for wear and tear on Hiachine. Three cents per hushel should cover the creating corn with a machine and patting it in shocks. hich form it nay he fed direct to the cattle. nltX AND IitAIKIK MAY VERSl'8 CORN. LINSEED-MEAL AND PRAIRIE HAY. On manv farms alfalfa or clover is not available in sufti plant it v to form even half of the roughness supplied ing cattle. Under these circumstances the use of ommercial proteia concentrate would seem desirable. In rder that this might be gi?ca a practical test, three expert- merits were conducted in which the ration corn and prairi" hay was fed with and without the protein concentrate lin - meal (oil-meal). The latter food was made hut 10 jmt cent of the grain ration because of its hijrh protein content and relative cost. Tn this experiment, as in all other t i|Hll—a1l Ibed in this bulletin, ten steers were fed iii each lot. F&lt;&gt;r the purpose of making the results more easily comprehended by the reader, the tablet are made to show the aTerage record fur each steer by lot. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 motnical Rations in lin f Production Tabi.k III.— Corn and prairie hay versus corn, limsted metti on i / i Ian., u.-.. to r Dec., 'OB, t. \vrray |une. "4, - luly. '(&gt;■&gt;.— April. (Hi. the tl lune.'lM, 24 weeks .'1 weeks. B weeks experir •J4 v.i I weeks. B weeks experin !"L. I 1 Av. initial vU. per 801.00 799. 0OI92fl.OU834.0U IHt.M II87.M W7.00I _ .&lt;iit per d;i\. - |.88 l.tl I.i"i - 10 1 -'■; 2.53 l ."&gt;l .rain fell per . ll»s 14.80 19.40 17. W 18.40 19.10 J4 »Ki 17.10 Av. initial vst. per KOI iki 790.00 INI !C(4 IKI in per (lav iin feil ptr ! 1 in 411 111 A\. liav (eil pef A\. liay fed per il.i\ . ll&gt;s - ro hi c .i..'*p 5. si • nsunied per Ib. o( gain, H&gt;s . . - nned per ll&gt;...( gain, lha 10. SO 8.10 si .vj ».(M 15.10 0.77 ' Ila\ i nisumecl per 4 «ain. lbs . . . r,.:»i 4.6U 5 19 l.iW ~hI consumed per Ib. of gain, Ihs 17 imp \-j 70 14 71 1:1 :■,&lt;; m iX per KM) lbs. of i W . 27 j I rotit Of l"ss bead including p«irk fmni (Imp- Profit Profit Loss Profit pin^s »ii.:1m 94.7(1 11.18 11.00 *&lt;i I HI 1" lla\ i nisuineil | I train, lbs IikhI consumed per Id. of gain, Iba *- pork from drop- Profit Profit L«ss I'mtit Luss $ii.:1m #4 7&lt;&gt; #1 .18 i\ mi #n ■ - Nutritive ratio 1:10.41:8 I: lO.sjl - Thiii linsfcd-iiK-iil is capable &lt;»f supplying \\li;ii corn Nutritive ratio 1:111 4 1:8 1:10.2 prairie aaj links is readily appareni when we in »t &lt; narked incmue in daily gains effwted by iis use. Kach the steers feil litise&lt;-&lt;l-ineal took on a mow thrifty a|&gt;| aure. as indicated \&gt;\ the coat of hair a few weeks aft**! experiments were began. They ate their grain with u r i relish and when on full feed consumed somewhat more grain which of course partly accounts for the increased gains. Tin was especially noticeable in the short period of heavy feiHlinj; in 1906-06 when the steers were crowded with thruout that entire period, the oil-meal steers takin pounds of grail per day in excess of the lot not receirin n ii. |\r.,t'| , •■ | &gt; 1 tin* t \\~ \ i i \\'\ * v 1 1 1 1 1 *» )'\iH'i'iiiH'iils \\ 1 1 ( ■ 1 1 1 h 1 1 1 1 lot </seg>
            <seg id="p017">I 17 v kept on the mm amount of grain per day for three months, the linseed-Meal steers, particularly njis iii i!»o:{ 04, gave niucb larger gains. It will !&gt;&lt;• ' tliat much less grata was reqaired to make a pound nil year, the average for the three years l*-iug 21 Phis is equivalent to saying that four i&gt;ounds in with linseed-meal produced as much Ixvf as rive fi without liaaeed-BMaL With torn averaging :&gt;•"&gt;. 7 &gt;rv inishei and Masrrd aril S2&amp;33 per ton for the taree the cost of producing one pound of gain was id. 7 per less by the use of the Hnartd mral The experiment* v the urgent need of some protein concentrate with corn prairie hay, provided its cost is not too great. Had the ige cost of the linseed-Meal been $45.66 or more per ton he three years, there would have Ix-en no advantage in I'ttdTKIX CONCENTRATES (OMl'AKKD. Having shown the importance of aaing w it h corn and prai- iy a small quantity of some protein concentrate, in this nseed-iiieal, we next compare three protein foods corn- only sold in Nebraska, viz., wheat bran, linseed-meal and •ttonseed nieal. (iluten feed, a by-product in the manufac- starch, glucose, etc.. from corn, would have been fo- lded in these tests if the cost of freight from eastern fac- tories were not such as to make the price of this food prohibitive for stock fee&lt;lin&lt;; purposes here. Just as soon as starch and glncose are manufactured in quantity in thi&gt; lion, glnten fe&lt;-d will no doubt become a formidable competi - tor of the protein foods mentioned. Owing to the lower pro - tein content of wheat bran, this food was made '2'2 per cent of the grain ration, whereas Hnsrcd mr al and cottonseed-meal wen- each made 10 per cent of the grain ration. It will he noted in the table to follow that the basic part of each ration in the tirst experiment was corn and prairie hay, while in the second it was corn and corn-stover. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 momical Rations in Href Production Tahlk IV. li'ht'tit t'ltiu In both of these experiments bran gives a much small) dailv gain than either linseed- or cottonseed-meal. In order to furnish the desired amount of protein, it was neci fti-d from rive to six pounds per dav to each steer, which ijuantitv of this fo&lt;Ml, rather laxative in its effects, caused the steers to scour both winters. Several steers in the I. ran lot became more or less rheumatic or still'. This wa&gt; also observed both winters, but it was more pronounced in tin second trial. No doubt these difficulties were partly reapoo sible for the unsatisfactory gam* on corn and bran, as nt </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 r lots were similarly affected. The bran put on the mar odav its apparently less valuable than formerly, no doubt high crude tiber content due to modern methods in Biug which effect a more complete extraction of the e portions of the wheat kernel. K! cottonseed-meal is slightly higher in protein than meal, the latter gave the larger gains in both these cuts, tho the difference was not great. The cattle did it the mixture of corn and cottonseed-meal with the relish that was conspicuous when the ration corn and d -meal was placed before them, and this no doubt fur- lishcs one explanation of the superiority of linseed-meal in ■rodm-ing not only larger daily gains but also larger gains rom the same weight of food. The feeds used in the §nt xperimeut cost as follows : corn 35 cents per bushel, bran $15.00 per ton, liuseed-meal $32.00 per ton, and cotton - meal $32. 00 per ton. Those used in the second experiment is follows : eon .50 cents per bushel, bran $18.00 per ton, ■d meal $29.50 per ton, cottonseed-meal $27.75 per ton. and stover $2.50 per ton. The prices given for commercial - are on the basis of car lots f. o. b. Lincoln. At the above prices it will be noted that the cost of producing one pound of gain was much greater with bran than either of the other protein foods. In the tirst experiment the linseed-nnal proved to be three times as valuable as bran. The different 't - was tvtn greater in the second experiment. It would not be wise, however, to place any relative values upon these foods until after further tests are made. In examining the above table it is interesting to note that the gains made in the second rrprrimmt. where corn-stovr was used as the roughness, compared favorably with tho* Bade in the tirst experiment, on prairie hay. We can not, however, formulate' any estimate of the relative values of the two forms of roughness from the above table, because the tirst experiment was of only eight weeks' duration, during the finishing period, while the second test lasted twenty </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Economical Ration* in Reef Production i i 1 weeks, practically tlic entire fattening period. Partbermoi grade Shorthorns were used in tlie first experiment and irra Angus in tlie second. 1.1XSKK1) -MICA I. (A PROTEIN CONCENTRATE I COMPARED WITH ALFALFA I A PKOTF.IN K4 »1 "« ! 1 1 A« ;t The two experiments with protein concentrates conduct to date faror the use of linseed-meal as a food supplements o com when the roughnest orn-stovei-. The question o supply sufficient protein Ifalfa, dispensing with tin M- al»le to secure just as uake it possible to utilize consists of either prairie hav now arises, would it lie possi by making half of the rouzhn use of the concentrate, and satisfactory liains? This « a ereal deal of stover or in Cost of UN) ll&gt;s of gain in 1 Valve "f i» &gt;rk pnidUced ai product for 100 lbs of frain im steers us) Nrt COS! of food per UN) jhd Nit profit per head including |M.rk produced from droppings 1 4:! Nutritive ratio tv and iit the same time oliviate the necessity of parch) c ((iinniercial food. Two experiment* in which the ra Roughage consumed per steer per day, ll&gt;s ('■rain consumed per l)&gt; of His Rougliage consumed per 1 1 &gt;. ■ &gt;f jjain.ltis Total fiHid consumed fur 1 ll&gt; of gain, lbs </seg>
            <seg id="p021">/. 21 daily gains, the linseed-meal seems to have vjint i In- first experiment with prairie hay, and i in tin- second experiment with corn stover. An iin of two pounds per da; for u entire fattening ordinarily considered good. Tin- -rains niiiili- oa rations in the two experiments reported are taonftm .u r nitif\ -iiiji. particularly the average jrains made for a 1 &lt;&gt;f twenty weeks in tin- second experiment Tin- fait one lot of ten two year-old ■teen gained '2..VA ponnda |mt ila.v for a |m-Hoi1 of tivi- niontlis with unshredded ovi-r for roaghneM ami no hay of any kind, is added of tin- high feeding mine of this by-prodnd so com- onl.v wasted in Ni-l»raska. While tin- linseed-meal ration shows its superiority over • alfalfa combination in making larger daily gains dnring '■ experiment, tin- use of alfalfa without linseed-meal made tlv in both. Tin- alfalfa-fed ateen in th xperimenl sold for tin- same price per hnndred as the 1 nical steers. In the second experiment the alfalfa sold for (5.65 per hundred, while the linaeed-meal Id for sr.r.o the same day, which difference may ha\&lt; due to the quality of the individuals at the beginning of •st and not to the feed. Brorn coating .■&gt;.'» cents per bushel and prairie hay - . the alfalfa hay proved to Im- worth ¥1:5.11 per ton in mm with linseed-meal mating *:{i'.o&lt;&gt; per ton. In the ond experiment, with com worth :?t; cents per bushel and v.r valued at |2.50 per ton, the alfalfa returned a value of 113.12 per ton in comparison with linaeed-meal at $29.50. Prom these ugureH it is apparcni that alfalfa possesses a high value as a source of protein. The experiment* furthermore Rugged that a relatively small quantity of this hay will sup - ply sufficient protein to insure good gains on two-year-old steers, and that this can lie produced on the farm niinli cheaper than it can be purchased on the market in the form of linseed-nieal or some other protein concentrate. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Eoomtmiomi Rations in Beef Production I'KAIRIK HAY VERSUS CORN-STOVER. In the comparison of Unmed-meal and alfalfa, first when used with corn and prairie hay. and second with corn and stover, the reader is not to draw any conclusions as to ih&gt; - relative values of prairie hay and stover, Uecause they wen - fed during different years under dissimilar conditions. 1"«&gt;I lowing is a direct comparison of these two forms of rough ness, one year with linseed-meal supplementing the corn, an other year with alfalfa forming half the roughnem with each. iind a third comparison with each roughness fed with cot I All! 24 wet per steer, pounds i»i tie gain |» per d.iv, pounds ! !•! 1 '• per steer per day, pounds l.Y4u i^c consumed per pound of gain, pounds . 8.10 IMI Phen balanced rations were fed. the protein being fur - ed in one experiment bj the use of linseed -meal and in other hy alfalfa hay, the corn-stover made a favoraMe showing with prairie hay. proving to be worth in the first |4.23 per ton and in the second $5.17 jmt ton compared with ■ He grain consun Bper day, |»«un&lt;l- consumed per Kige consumed per ;i of gain, pounds hkI consumed per i of gain, pounds. . of food for ltMl is of gain e ratio -UK I r-».7(l $6.82 lira *6.(»9 10.-17 1 •"&gt;. 1 7 J.V47 1 1 44 #."&gt;.nl 15.16 1:11 s i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Et 23 ■ hay at $»».(H) per ton. lu the third comparison, with protein food, the stover returned a value of but f2.77 Kred with prairie hay at fO.OO, whirh smaller value is m attributable to the lower protein content of stover. \s already stated, not more than (50 per cent of the stow &lt; ■barged to the steers fed in these ex[&gt;eriments was consumed. &lt;■ remainder consisting of refuse butts which had to be rown out for bedding. The stover actually consume! \oiild seeaa to possess a feeding value quite the equal of prai - se hay. Inasmuch as corn-stover contains only »&gt;0 per rent rtter, while prairie hay is approximately M per cent, it seem conservative to say also that the dry matter of entire cornstalk with ear detached, cut immediately after corn ripens and properly cured in the shook, is equal to dry matter of prairie hay. RELATIVE ECONOMY OK A HEAVY AND LIGHT RATION OP CORN. ■ experiments so far conducted and re]M&gt;rted in these indicate that beef can be produced most economically Nebraska by the use of corn, alfalfa, and corn-stover. It would seem proper to next determine, if possible, what pro - portion of corn to such roughness is most economical. Porn lias ruled high in price during the past few years, while rough of all kinds has remained relatively low in value until the last year when hay has been abnormally high In'cause the dry weather which prevailed thruout the country during th- - early part of the summer caused a shortage in this crop, the effect of which will no doubt be but temporary. The pet hauling and shipping hay and other bulky fe&lt;&gt;d is such as to make it seem probable that the price of roughness on our He* braska farms, many of them situated some distance from stations, will not advance with corn in the fntnre. Reef rat - tle in the West are ordinarily fed all the grain they will con - sume, very commonly by the nse of self-feeders, having before </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 i i them what roogh feed is needed i&lt;» satisfy the ( ravin, bulk. The latter is often of very inferior quality, perhaps i stack of wheat straw, and a very limited quantity is con suined. That a -rood quality of roughness can he made t - take the place of a part of the coin is shown by the following single experiment conducted the past winter: Table Wl.—Hmvy versus light fe,d ot corn with alfalfa and com Nor., "06, to No&gt; Apr., (17. Ma\ ■&gt;A » '* k Av. initial wt. per steer Nov. 14 ,ain per steer, 5 iims 4 Loftt.lt. _Hin per steer per day pain consumed per -tc ramed per st oinsumed for ta .11 Value &lt;&gt;f i»irk produced ax a by-product for KM of gain on steers .' Net cost of f&lt;KKi per KHl lbs. of gain. Profit per steer, including [xirk pr droppings Nutritive ratio The steers on the light ration of corn were never given to exceed fourteen pounds of corn per day, the average daily ration for the twenty-four weeks being 13.89 pounds, while the full-fed steers were given as high as 24 pounds per day, an average of 2&amp;J8 pounds for the period of twenty weeks fi-d. The light fed steers consumed ;is much more rovghnem as the heavy fed steers consumed more corn. Pis interesting to note that the ten steers on the lighl ration made the same gain in six months (24 weeks i the heavy led steers made in five months i I'll weeks). ijlht fed steers were equally well finished with the extra Av roughage consumed f Av cost .if 1UU lbs. of gair </seg>
            <seg id="p025">/ 25 ng and .sold at $."&gt;.."»(» jmm- hundred, the top of tin South Omaha market May 14, "07, when there was a heavy rattle. The lieavv led tattle sold for fo.t&gt;«~&gt; April lGth nth previous, when the market was I'tt cents per him died higher, as found by averaging the selling price of the top hundred steers April Kith and the same nuinlHT .May 14th. In computing the net protits in the above table, both lot.s !•&lt;• figured at s."&gt;.:t,s j M -r handred net, the price received for • heavy fed cattle on home weights at the close of the ex- periment. At last winter's (*§6-*§7) prices on fi-eds, viz., shelled corn 36 cents per bushel, snapped corn :{."&gt; cents, al- fa hay VS.00 per ton, ami stover 4'2.7&gt;() per ton, the heavy I steers produced gains ;it a net cost (deducting pork from droppings i of ¥."&gt;.4C&gt; per hundred compared with $5.(&gt;^ for the lighi led steers. Had the alfalfa hay cost $5.00 per tou instead of $8.00 — and alfalfa in the stack on the average farm of Ne - braska does not usually command a figure greater than $3.00 Rnet protits per steer would have Ixi-u the same in both This would have Ix-en true also if the corn had cost M per bushel instead of Ho cents, figuring the alfalfa at This experiment emphasise* further the value of al - as a Ix-ef producer, and it ojx-ns a new and important for future investigation. The record made by the light ed cattle was no accident, as another lot in a corn fodder \|&gt;&lt;riineut made very nearly as large gains on the same grain ration. No conclusions, however, are to be drawn until after further tests along this line are made. As a single exjx-ri - inent it suggests the possibility of producing Ix-ef most cm c nominally on what approaches a full grain feed when corn is low in price and alfalfa high. When corn is high and alfalfa l«&gt;w. something more like half a full feed of grain would make IxM'f production more profitable even tho more time is re - quired to finish the cattle. .Fudging from the results of the above experiment, it is probable that the most economical proportion of grain to hay under average conditions will be found somewhere between a half feed and a full feed of grain. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Ping definite, however, will be known until after several are made in which different quantities of grain are fed. rent quantities of grain are led. THE 1906-07 EXPERIMENTS The sixty steers used in last winter's experiments wen - purchased in October, llMMi, from Mr. .lames Cook of A_ Sioux County, Net*. They were high grade Angus two-year - olds selected from a herd uumln'riug about two hundred, all reared under rauge conditions, having had. previous to their purchase, nothing but grass supplemented with native ha\ during the winter mouths. They were in what would !&gt;&lt;■ con- Fig 4. Angus steers as they appeared on the range when purcba Photo by Morrill Geological Expedition. sidered good grass tiesh when purchased, and no doubt would have sold at top values for feeder steers had they been sent to market. These steers cost $4.00 per kindred at the rant li and were weighed after having been yarded twenty-four hours without feed and water. The stwrs were shipped during the time of the severe October snowstorm and the shrinkage was very heavy. This shrinkage with the freight across the State </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 and the expense of three weeks" preliminary feeding made tin steers cost net Nov. 14th, on the initial weights of the experi incut. 4..X cents per hundred as given in tlie Financial State inent to follow. (11 steers were yarded at the Experiment Station iiii. -&gt;'&lt;. &gt;, and given a liberal feed &lt;if hay and but little grain. ag to the fact that they had never been fed grain it was ■ssary to sprinkle corn-meal over the hay in order t&lt;&gt; get u started. They immediately acquired a fondues corn-meal and a few days later for shelled and napped corn, the feed iK'inj,' increased from one pound of meal per steer the first day to four pounds of shelled and snapped corn per day liy the end of the first week. Nov. I'd. l&gt;\ Nov. 14th. wln-n the records of the experiment were begun, the steers in Lot? l! and 3 were each receiving i\8 pounds of snapped «•&lt; the Morning and (&gt; pounds of the mixture of shelled col linseed- or cottonseed-meal at night, the equivalent pounds of grain per day. Owing to the balky charac liran, which formed about one-fourth of that ration, was purposely given a little larger feed of grain to ma in quantity of corn correspond more nearly to that fed I. and 3, which received linseed- and cottonseed-meal, forming but 1(1 per cent of the daily grain ration. On Dee. li'th the ten steers in Lot 1 received 14(1 pounds of snapped corn in the morning and S4 |H&gt;unds of shelled corn ami ."&gt; pounds of bran at ni&lt;rht. The ten in Lot l! received 1 16 pounds snapped corn in the morning and sit pounds shelled corn and 22 ]M&lt;unds of linseed-meal at night. Lot 3 received the same ra - tion except that cottonseed-meal was substituted for Iiii meal. On that date, therefore, each steer in Lots i! and 3 was receiving the equivalent of llt.s pounds of shelled corn and L'.L' pounds of the linseed- or cot tonseed-meal. while each steer in Lot 1 received the equivalent of lit. 3 pounds of shelled coin E pounds of bran. Lot 4 was fed the same quantity a&lt; and 3, the grain being corn alone. These four lots ven all the grain they would consume during the last </seg>
            <seg id="p029">t 29 &lt; acli steer |mt day. Lots ."» ami ♦&gt; were never iu- 1 beyond 14 pound* of con jh*i- day. They rw— iii 1 noic ronghneaa, however, as their record indieai results of one ex]ieriinent with these steers in which liran. linseed-meal and cottonseed-meal were compared dished on page 18 of this Imlletin for parpom of com- ftith the previous winter's test in which the same feeds The records of Letts 4 ami .1 are published on pajct n the experiment entitled "Light versus Heavy drain &gt;n." the steers in Lot 4 having ben fed heavily on grata riod of five months and those in Lot ."&gt; very moder- • six months. The steers in Lot &lt;;. the financial state f which follows, were also fed six months on the same \ n y of grain supplied Lot 5. Dnriag the first two the steers in Lot ti were fed a large part of their corn .11 on e stalk as corn-fodder to serve as a comparison with Loi snapped corn, while dariag the last three months they d ground corn for a comparison with shelled corn fed thai •Hod to the steers of Lot ."». The results of the corn 111 ■r versus Knapped corn experiment and the shelled corn is c -oni -meal experiment will not Im- published until next when the records for a series of three years will Ik- com ..let It may lie stated at this writing that the records to date indicate that grinding corn for cattle does not pay when then- are pijjs behind to consume the undigested corn in the droppings The data obtained in the other experiment dur - ing two years show no particular advantage in favor of de - taching the ears from stalks supplied fattening steers. How - ever, all conclusions concerning this will l&gt;c deferred nntil more data are at hand. In the following Financial State - ment of the sixty steers there is included a small item for cane liay which was substituted for corn-stover during the closing day* of the experiment after the supply of stover had Ix-en inoiiilis of the experiment, an avenge of abovt 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 * ft </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 u </seg>
            <seg id="p033">inil Ration* in Beef Production 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 omical Rations in Beef J'roduction. ; </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Econmmieml Rut inn* ,,i ll&gt;&lt;f Production 1906 1907 !»• •« i s t j. 4 t FINANCIAL STATEMENT. Lot 1, on corn, wheat bran, and corm-stovw To 10 steers, weight 9.737 lbs., at |4.U par cwt net, f. o. b. Lincoln $H at 35 cents per bu ($11,112;, per cwt 1 To 7.465 lbs. of bran at $18 per ton To 11.05H lbs. of cornstov To 1 430 lbs. of cane at $3 r at $L'.5O per ton '0 per ton To interest on $445.',«; for ;, mo. ai 1; per cm 11 13 Apr. 3 By M steers, weight 12.2i&gt;7 lbs., ai t cwt. net. Lincoln By Wl lbs. pork at 1 By loss on ten on ea t' Lot 2. on corn, lin 1 Nov. 14 To 10 steers, weight »,7«7 lb&gt;., at $4 cwt net, f. o. b. Line 1 To 22,685 lbs. shelled rn at bu. ($0,643 per cwt. 1 To 8,51(1 lbs. snapped corn ( at 35 cents per bu. ($0.62 To 3,183 lbs. of oil-meal at $ To 11,050 lbs. of corn-stover at $ To interest on $447.33 for 5 1110. a To profit on ten steers (pork in Apr. 3 By 10 steers, weight 13,01-3 lbs., at $5 cwt net. Lincoln By 683 lbs. pork at 6' t cents net (Profit on each steer. $1 To 21.140 lbs. shelled corn at 3ii rents per bu. ($0,643 per cwt.) ! To 8,5n; lbs snapped corn («,J62 lbs of corn) To 1.470 lbs. of cane at $3.5o per t&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 rn. cottonseed-meal, and corn-stover. weight 9.887 lbs., at $4.58 per $452 83 Lincoln shelled corn at 36 cents per bu. 144 31 cwt lbs. of corn) snapped corn It ■nts per bu. ($0,625 per cwt. ) 39 71 cottonseed-meal at $27.75 per ton 44 01 . of stalks at $2.50 per ton 13 81 ■1 tf cane at $3.50 per ton &lt; .:._ H for E mo. at fi per cent. . 11 32 &gt;tit on ten steers (pork included) 13 lfi 13 lfi steers, weight 12.843 lbs. at *5-23 per wt. net. Lincoln ♦"' .i... - nl £ I . *.*»nt&lt; net 4'.* 91 pork at 6V 4 cents net $721 60 $721 60 (Profit on each steer. $1.32.) 4. on corn, alfalfa hay and coru-stover rs. weight 9,787 lbs., at $4.58 per wt. net, f. o. I). Lincoln $448 25 lbs. shelled corn at 36 cents per bu. (fO.MS per cwt.) 160 99 \,tU lbs. snapped corn («.221 7 lbs. of corni at H cents per bu. ($0,625 per cwt.).. 38 89 ..rnstovei at $2 50 per ton 7 18 tOC lbs. alfalfa at $8 per ton 28 82 28 82 alfalfa at $8 per ton ro 71". lbs. cane at $3.f&gt;o per ton 1 25 ane at $3.50 per ton 1 25 To interest on $448.25 for 5 mo. at 6 per cent 11 21 ereat on $448.25 for 5 mo. at 6 per cent 11 21 fit on ten steers I pork included) 6:! 80 ro profit on ten steers (pork included) «3 80 63 80 By lo steers, weight 13.170 lbs., at $5.38 per cwt. net. Lincoln By 829.4 lbs. pork at «', cents net </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ii *-&amp;i &amp;» on shelled com. snapped corn (light alfalfa 1906 Nov. 14 To 10 steers, weight 9,777 lbs., at $4.58 p. 41 115 48 To 7,210 lbs. snapped torn I at 35 cents per bu. (fO 13 w To 9,392 lbs. of corn-stover at 12.50 ner ton 11 To ls.t;:;;, lbs. of alfalfa at $8 To 2.3-io lbs. of can. To interest on $447. 79 for To profit on ti 1907 May 1 My 10 t cwt. net. Lincoln By 7W.J lbs tMirk 1'r Lot C, on shelled corn at 35 cents per bu. &lt;$im 710 lbs. of corn-meal at 7 To 2.350 lbs. of cane at $3.50 per t To interest on $449.44 for 6 mo. at To profit on ten steers (pork inolu&lt; t $ $7 (Profit on each steer. $0.71 ■The profit per head would have been $4.61 had this lot a market equally as good as that four weeks previous when the f four lots were sold. The profits on Lot 6 would also have been erea on such a market or the market four weeks later when the quotatii were 50 cents per hundred higher for this class of cattle cwt. net, f. o. b. Lincoln. To 17,960 lbs. shelled pom at ($0,643 per cwt.) Nov. 14 To 1" cwt. net. f. o. b. Lir helled ($0,643 per cwt.l To 7,212 lbs. snapped To 9,352 lbs of corn-stover at $2 To 18.620 lbs. of alfalfa at $8 per i 1907 May 1 By 10 steers, weight 13,10(1 lbs. at $ cwt. net, LJneoln By 387.8 lbs. pork at 6V4 cents net </seg>
            <seg id="p039">/;. 39 M'KKIMKNTS li coin alone to fattening cattle rv gains and very little or :n&lt; in-il rorn-siovei- with alfalfa and corn. iodine larger gains, will make the gains of its low market value, thereby imieas- &gt;ver corn ami alfalfa alone. only prairie liay as roughness to fattening :er and more profitable gains can be made if possibly some other protein concentrate i all quantity rather than feeding corn alone. of two experiments indicati that linseed ne valuable than cottonseed-meal and much ii wheat bran for supplementing corn when luiv or e(»in-sto\ •r. is made at lea u -stover, good n no alfalfa ii t half of the roughness w ith ijaiiis may !»• made ami at •d, the protein being In other words, it is pos- in on i he farm market in tlie form of some commercial over cut immediately after the ears ripen ami iks possesses a value fully two-thirds as great as The part usually consumed, viz.. the leaves and n of stalk, is quite the equal of prairie hav pound h i- i&gt;oiind 8. The results of a single experiment in which but little &gt;re than half a full feed of corn was supplied two lots &lt;&gt;f of hay in finishing cattle for market than is ordinarily rn alone gives large ami profitable I iihmI. In other wonts, it is pos- e farm iii a price nim-h below what iii-iiinir sti its sii^jrrsi tin- piwsiltilit y of makiiitr :&gt; Ull </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Economical Rations in Uivj I'ro C'"de aud at less tout, especially where hay is ivla 1 corn high in price. I From a commercial point of view the ivsuits of this &gt;■ n'rics of experiments ,n&lt;&gt; to show that cattle feeding w ide profitable when discretion is used in the selection for the ration. &lt; »n the average farm in Nebraska whe and hay command figures below Lincoln i&gt;i-i - e cattle arc undisturbed by frequent weighings whi&lt; •iinciital feeding necessitates, the profits can be mm E greater than those report) II make our corn bring to the elevator eompanie d cattle is not far in ad\ ly of these experiments. e growing of alfalfa am ■d in ili is bulletin. Good f more as beef than when even t ho the selling pr Ktfce maintenance and increase of land fert r for this mode &lt;&gt;f selling a larger part of i ■crop. The cattle industry di in this State than has been a \&lt;k.\(i\vi.i:im;mi ■Howledgmeni is here made to Mr. Joseph !■'. I ental Feeder in the Department, for his can in weighing and feeding all rations, and to A \. F. M danz. Jr.. anil ('. \V. Bine for valnal Bee of &lt;nst price as was The importance of mai clover as agencies contri </seg>
            
            <seg id="p041">OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD UNVCNSiTv) nt, Omaha )KE, Vallcv ABBOTT, Aurora |RD, Falls Citv THE STATION OFFICERS r, B.Sc .. Director M Ph.. Financial Secretary ■ttive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF initmal Husbandry Annual Pal' PH.D., Botany ■tttistrv A.. Hairy Husbandry E*4omoiegj Field Crops »N, A.M., Highway Engineering N Hoiticulturt K . Irrigation Engineering Veteoroi Supt-rin/endtnt Experimental Substation, North Ptattt ilc- in Auintml Pathology XtsxitmtU in Animal Husbandry s ■rdevant, A.M., Assistant in Animal Pathology ml in Field Croft A.Ii , Assistant in Horticulturt </seg>
            <seg id="p042">X ■x </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>