<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Oats Investigations</title>
               <date value="1917-11-15">1917-11-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 160 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OP THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA Volume XXIX, Article IV OATS INVESTIGATIONS By T. A. Kiesselbach and J. A. Ratcliff Accepted for Publication, March, 1917 Distributed November 15, 1917 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, President, Omaha HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Vice-president, Falls City HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln HONORABLE HARRY D. LANDIS, Seward THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc., Director C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary 'FLOYD WAMBEAM, B. Sc., Bulletin Editor THE WORKING STAFF F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Agronomy T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Agronomy H. J. GRAMLICH, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology M. H. SWENK, A. M., Entomology H. C. Filley, A. M., Farm Management R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine James A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell J L. L. ZoOK, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte •J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry 4 G. K. K. Link, Ph. D., Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology Erwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy H. G. Gould, Assistant in Agronomy &gt;E. G. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry W. B. N evens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry R. R. Spafford, A. M., Assistant in Farm Management J. R. Cooper, A. M., Astsistant in Horticulture 1 Resigned 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. 'Granted leave of absence for military service 'Granted leave of absence </seg>
            <seg id="p004">CONTENTS Summary Importance of the Oats Crop Adaptation and Varieties Improvement of Oats by Breeding IRRIGATED VS. UnIRRIGATED OATS FOR SEED Effect of Grading on Seed Value of Oats Equal Weights vs. Equal Numbers of Large Rate of Planting Relative Yields of Oats and Other Crops General Notes on Oats Growing Soil Fertility The Seed Bed Choice of Seed Preparation of Seed Seeding Harvesting Substitute Crops for Oats 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SUMMARY 1. Oats rank third in importance of the grain crops grown in Nebraska. More than 2,000,000 acres were grown during each of the last 12 years. 2. For most parts of the State, oats are less profitable than other grain crops and are frequently grown at a loss. 3. Because of special adaptation for a cool climate, oats are more nearly commercially profitable in northeastern Nebraska. 4. Variety tests extending over a period of 15 years show conclusively that early varieties are better adapted and yield more in this State than late varieties. In a 12-year test, the average yield of three early varieties was 11.1 bushels (or 22 per cent) superior to the average yield of four late varieties. There was an average difference of 8 days in time of ripening. The best early variety, Burt, yielded 20 per cent more than the best late variety, Swedish Select. In a 6-year test, four early varieties averaged 42 per cent greater yield than ten late varieties. There was again an 8-day difference in time of ripening. The best early variety, Burt, yielded 23 per cent more than the best late variety, Swedish Select. Practically all oats varieties grown in the United States were compared for growth and seed production during the period 1910 to 1916. None have given promise of superiority over the group of early varieties which have been thoroly compared in the field variety tests. 5. Forty strains of Kherson oats, originating from 750 head selections, have been tested 6 years in the nursery, while 10 of these have also been grown 4 years in field plats. A white Kherson strain known as "Nebraska No. 21" was increased in 1916 for distribution among farmers. This strain averaged 9 per cent higher yield than the original Kherson in the nursery and 15 per cent higher in the field plats. In this 4-year average, the yields of Nebraska No. 21, original Kherson, Burt, and Texas Red have been respectively 61.9, 54.1, 64.5, and 62.3 bushels per acre. 6. During a 5-year period, seed of both Kherson and Swedish Select oats varieties, which had been grown for many years under irrigation in western Nebraska, yielded slightly more than un - irrigated seed grown in eastern Nebraska. This suggests that seed oats of suitable varieties grown under irrigation can be used with safety for dry land planting. 7. As an average for 12 years, the heaviest one-fourth Kher - son seed oats as separated by a fanning mill has yielded 0.74 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 bushel better than the lightest one-fourth seed, and 0.83 bushel better than the original unselected seed. . In a similar 8-year test with American Banner oats — a late variety — the heavy seed has yielded 1.44 bushels less than the light seed. During 4 years, the original unselected seed was com - pared with the heavy and light selections, and for this period the heavy seed yielded 3.70 bushels less and the unselected seed 1.63 bushels less than the lightest seed. 8. When distinct grades of hand-selected large and small seeds were planted during 5 years in equal numbers at a rate normal for the large seed, the large yielded 13 per cent more than the small. However, when equal weights of seed were planted at a rate normal for the large seed, both grades yielded equally and practically the same as the original unselected seed. 9. Rate-planting tests extending over a period of 12 years indicate that there may be a rather wide range in planting rate without materially affecting the yield per acre. However, the data suggest that varieties of the Kherson type should be drilled 10 to 12 pecks per acre, while those of the Swedish Select type yield best when planted 12 pecks per acre. Somewhat lower rates are recommended for central and western Nebraska because of less favorable moisture conditions. 10. During the 16-year period, 1902 to 1916, the relative yields of oats, corn, and winter wheat have been 53, 58, and 36 bushels, respectively. During the 8-year period, 1909 to 1916, oats, corn, winter wheat, and spring wheat have yielded 52, 48, 36, and 19 bushels per acre, respectively. Calculated in pounds, these yields of oats, corn, winter wheat, and spring wheat were respectively 1664, 2576, 2160, and 1140 pounds per acre. Allow - ing 30 per cent for hull, the net grain yield of oats equalled 1165 pounds. 11. Profit or loss from oats growing is often determined by the cultural practices followed. The oats crop responds readily to increased soil fertility and careful seed bed preparation. Early seeding and treatment for smut are desirable. 12. In a 4-year test, 1907 to 1910, the yields from Kherson oats, Oderbrucker barley, Tennessee winter barley, and Turkey Red winter wheat have been respectively 51.2, 42.9, 29.3, and 41.2 bushels, or 1638, 2059, 1406, and 2472 pounds per acre. Allow - ing 30 per cent for hull in oats and 15 per cent lor hull in barley, these respective grain yields were 1147, 1750, 1195, and 2472 pounds per acre. Barley is the highest-producing spring crop which may be substituted for oats. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Oats Investigations 7 OATS INVESTIGATIONS T. A. KIESSELBACH AND J. A. RATCLIFF IMPORTANCE OF THE OATS CROP The relative importance of oats and other grain crops grown in Nebraska is shown in table 1, which is compiled from the 1916 annual report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture. Oats are third in importance of the grain crops — more than 2,000,000 acres having been grown during each of the past 12 years. The approximate average annual acreages of corn, wheat, oats, rye, and barley during the last 9 years have been respectively 6.5, 3.1, 2.2, 0.12, and 0.1 million acres. The large acreage devoted to oats does not signify that this is a relatively profitable crop. The relative production and acre income for the principal grain crops grown in Nebraska are shown in tables 2 and 3. The price per bushel is the average price as given by the State Board of Agriculture during 27 years. The yields, as compiled from the 1916 annual report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture, are given in table 1. The grain yields for corn, wheat, and oats have been 24.9, 16.9, and 27.0 bushels per acre as an average for the 27 years, 1890 to 1916, while the average acre incomes have been, respectively, $10.46, $11.66, and $7.29. During the last 9 years, 1908 to 1916, the yields of corn, wheat, and oats have been 25.7, 17.9, and 27.6 bushels per acre, and the respective acre incomes have been $14.70 $16.11, and $9.66. In table 3 are given the yields and acre incomes for corn, wheat, and oats during the 15-year period, 1902 to 1916, for the Nebraska Experiment Station at Lincoln and for Lancaster County, the county in which the Station is located. The average yields of corn, wheat, and oats at the Station have been respec - tively 57.2, 36.2, and 56.0 bushels per acre, while the County yields have been 26.5, 21.3, and 23.0 bushels per acre. The average acre incomes for corn, wheat, and oats have been $29.17, $29.32, and $17.92 at the Station, and $13.52, $17.25, and $7.36 in the County. Altho the acre cost of growing oats is some - what less than for wheat and corn, this lower cost will not offset the lower acre income. Hence, oats are a relatively unprofitable crop. Acknowledgment ia made to Dr. T. L. Lyo.i. now of Cornell Unlvmlty, (or data ucurad prior to 1W7 and to Prof. E O. Montgomery, il«&gt; now of Cornell Unlverelty, for daia Mcurrd between 1907 and 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 naska A gricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 60 i! tt^JOOOOO9)O0&gt; tD VO9)OU3OU3t«(0 b~ 3 18 E- « if !_Z_ I II |__ •oSSJSj^S^SS^ S to r35225gggs § S88S8?SSS?8"8f 8" HHHH »H »H »-l »-i |»esooe«ON oo ONot^totousooo o « to us io us &gt;a id to c-^ t-^ uj tc i^ us t^ — to t-^ t-^ to oo »2 — i5S — 22°2 m o&gt;cou5»t-ioo»oco q&gt; 5 ■ I I ! i 1 !L__ l_ i ii ; — 3 ec °0 O 00 Oi IO VC •*• 00 O5 ©-*«WiCMe5e5&lt;©-§ S Q S !C^ ia0 N **" oo t~ vo oo to &amp; eS o" •5 H « 2fe S^R^^^oo^T oo co io o to t- oo cm co &lt;i B5 I J I — i 1 — - I •—I ! 9 3s I _, £ £ 2 J; £ ■* °9. o&gt; 2 s oo to t- to &lt;&gt; S t- co eo to 8 •.'".*.*. ls . e l* N . ls . *i e^oitot-cotooooco S •&lt; S £1 S3 2 *~ 25 °° °* 1 " H °&gt; -* N &gt;O US t&gt; N Oi ■§ §1 W HHHMriHririM »h .-JeJeJeJ'eJeicJeJe'j' si vOtooooous©© us to oo ■* o t- oo t- co oo to si "* ~ « •-&lt; to w N N NN-MNnnnN 5j •« eg 5 II J , I L^ |__ S m q t-_&lt;e «■« »Nt-_ ■* a&gt;ooiooco&lt;£-3«e»o6 §3 o?2S?2 HNN » of 'S'^mtDomcioto to •*2SS5; m t; t0 "* 10 - 1 «oi&gt;o-.mt2t-:Soo S 0i00_-«N0lo&gt;o -» n oo io-H in ij S S &lt;N ■^" to co t* » t-^ itf &lt;o&lt;D*au$&lt;oto&lt;£&lt;Q&lt;£ to l_ I ± __, i ii | — I i — ril — — — : — : — I :::::: : • 2;5222J2!£?££S£ o»2«Nco^iotpt- ssss|S|ss llslsssisls I </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Oats Investigations 9 •05 Tno^ooncgoOMie 00 p "§&lt;g| 22 fsisissssissss g| a §3 « N | 5 I =5 -§ o to go to to sS a. «9SI&lt;«I-ai9N 7 :? ■3 v c w *^ °° t~ 1 7 T) s — i jT~ " ■oj •§ N t- us oo © m to oo •U « u l^^P M — — 1 JS oiAtoujHo^ion n ■ M odei I * &lt;c ©^" t^'^ ttcli ' JJM -^ I tf _ _ — ■*» WO1-HM5O— Tf © ■S I MNNnnneonn co ei • ■ s ? &lt;5 i 5 riTiMr:r:r:^r:r; I to -a- gSSSSSSSSS ~5~S~ H w o» w — oo us o&gt; w a&gt; os o&gt; a ™ «M rt (*i K_ »rt »-» «■. M t, £ -a -a — m .JS °5 °? 1°J ** °i * 'T "? "? Sit - ; I M m 00 ff) U5 Oi OS b~ CO 00 CO • fe. rT S JS "5 "5 — CC — f IM t- -" * MMNMNMNMN g ! ! 1_J ! ! ■_ t s h g . a &lt; * « Jo*ooo«oo« t-_ « ■ "* E- 1 o £ h a »*&gt;o n e t&gt;"o o a ?i" oo c_l oa Jl to v as ~ t^ -^ c»5 os -^ N to 3 I " w .'*. l '?. ? l c t 00 .'4 o l t^. "i ■ s ;;;;;!;;:;»■ &gt; i </seg>
            <seg id="p010">at the Nebraska Experiment Station and in Lancaster County, 1 in which county the Station is located. Average, 1902 to 1916 Yield per acre Acre income Crop Price Lancaster Experiment County Station per Lancaster Experiment bushel County Station Cents Bushels Bushels Dollars Dollars 13.52 29.17 17.25 29.32 Corn 57.2 Winter wheat Oats 36.2 56.0 ■The County yields have been compiled from the annual reports of the Nebraska Bureau of Crop Statistics and of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture. Thruout the greater part of the State oats are grown with far less profit and more frequent actual loss than either corn or winter wheat. The reason for growing oats is primarily to supply the individual farmer's requirements for a favorite horse feed. In 51 26.5 81 21.3 32 23.0 7.36 17.92 0 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bullet in 160 'able 2 — Production and acre incomes for corn, whet in the State of Nebraska, 1890 to 1916* it, and oats Average price per bushel Yield per acre Crop Acre income Ceni* Bushels DoOan NINE- YEAR PERIOD. 1890 TO 1898 28.0 54.0 16.3 20.5 14.7 24.9 5.74 7.94 4.06 Corn Winter wheat Oats NINE- YEAR PERIOD, 1899 TO 1907 39.3 64.0 28.3 28.6 18.1 28.5 11.24 11.58 8.07 Corn Winter wheat Oats NINE- YEAR PERIOD, 1908 TO 1916 57.2 90.0 35.0 25.7 17.9 27.6 14.70 16.11 9.66 Corn Winter wheat Oats 27-YEAR PERIOD, 1890 TO 1916 42.0 69.0 27.0 24.9 16.9 27.0 10.46 11.66 7.29 Corn Winter wheat Oats I I I 'Compiled from the 1916 annual report of the Nebraska Si ite Board of A| piculture. Table 3 — Relative yields and &lt; icre incomes j rr corn, wh eat, and oats </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Oats Investigations 11 eastern Nebraska, oats are grown to facilitate a change in the rotation from corn to winter wheat. The organization of labor on many farms also requires that a portion of the land be sown to some small grain crop in the spring. Of all the spring-sown small grain crops, oats appear to be most practical for the average farm, except in southwestern Nebraska, where barley is held in higher favor. The superior feeding value of the straw is a special inducement to grow oats rather than other spring-sown grains. As an average for 27 years for the entire State, the approxi - mate yields of corn, wheat, oats, rye, and barley have been 24.9, 16.9, 27.0, 16.6, and 22.0 bushels per acre. The actual production of crops differing in weight per bushel can be compared more directly in pounds than in bushels per acre. Grains enclosed in a hull which has very little food value, such as oats and barley, may also be compared with hull-less grain to best advantage by their relative yields free from hull. Allowing 30 per cent for hull in oats and 15 per cent hull for barley, the net yields of grain for the above five crops have been, respectively, 1394, 1014, 605, 930, and 898 pounds per acre. The distribution of the spring-sown small grain crops in Nebraska is shown in figures 1, 2, and 3. Because of the large acreage and because of the relatively low yield and small profit from oats, this crop seems to offer a good field for investigation. Fig. 1 — Distribution of oats in 1916, one dot for each 1,000 acres grown. Compiled from the 1916 annual report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 Fig. 2 — Distribution of spring wheat in 1916, one dot for each 1,000 acres grown. Compiled from the 1916 annual report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture Fig. 3 — Distribution of barley in 1916, one dot for each 1,000 acres grown. Compiled from the 1916 annual report of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture ADAPTATION AND VARIETIES In order that a crop shall produce successfully, it is essential that the environmental conditions fit the needs of the crop. For example, cotton and rice are not grown in this State because environmental conditions are unsuited. On the other hand, corn and winter wheat are especially well adapted to a large part of the State. In general, oats stand between these two classes of </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Oats Investigations 13 crops in adaptation to Nebraska climatic conditions. While being grown extensively in this State, production is confined to a very limited number of varieties, and even these seldom reach their maximum development, because of the unfavorable environment. This crop is best suited to a cool growing season such as exists in the northern states, Canada, England, and Scotland, and it suffers severely when exposed to intense heat during the fruiting period. In the greater part of Nebraska, the oats crop must usually endure a period of dry, hot weather just before harvest. Therefore, because of a consistently cooler climate, the northern half of the State is more favorable to oats culture than is the southern half, and profitable commercial oats growing is quite largely confined to this section, with the most extensive production in the northeastern part. Fig. 4 — General view of oats variety test plats (1916) Recognizing the general lack of adaptation of oats to Nebraska conditions, the Experiment Station early undertook to determine the type of oats best suited here. Variety tests indicated that extreme earliness would permit the crop to ripen with less danger from heat and drouth and less likelihood of rust and lodging. In the search for early oats suited to Nebraska conditions, the now well-known Kherson variety was introduced from Kherson, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 Russia, and first tested by T. L. Lyon, of the Nebraska Station, in 1898. Further tests by the Experiment Station and extensive cooperative trials indicated that this variety was superior to any other which had been grown in the State. It quickly came into general use and has been adopted as the standard variety in Nebraska, except in the more favored oats districts where later varieties are still grown extensively. More extended variety tests, reported upon by E. G. Mont - gomery in 1910 and continued to the present time, indicate con - clusively that the principle of earliness in cats is very important. The early varieties develop rapidly and reach the fruiting stage 6 to 12 days earlier than do the late ones. This stage, for the early varieties, is reached about the middle of June in eastern Nebraska, and at this time the weather is usually favorable for crop growth. About the Fourth of July, however, as the early oats are ripening, the weather normally becomes hotter and the ground drier. The late varieties at this time are just in their prime and under these conditions are unable to fill well, because of premature ripening. Thus, it usually happens that the early varieties are able to grow and mature under the more favorable conditions. It is the ability to escape the heat and drouth of summer that results in larger yields. Tables 4 and 5 contain the results for two groups of repre - sentative early and late varieties which been tested for yield during 12 consecutive years, 1905—1916. Station seed from the preceding crop has been planted each year. These tests, as well as other variety tests which follow, have been made mostly in duplicate or triplicate in plats varying from 1/15 to 1/30 acre in size. Altho systematically distributed check plats of Kherson oats have been grown, they have seldom been used to correct the yields of intervening plats. The small and large seeded varieties have been drilled respec - tively at the rates of 10 and 12 pecks per acre with a press drill. This was done in order to sow a somewhat similar number of seeds per acre. During this 12-year period, 1905 to 1916, the early varieties averaged 11.1 bushels greater yield per acre than did the later group. There was an average difference of 8 days in time of ripening between the two groups, and 5 inches difference in height of crop. The three early varieties are each clearly superior to any of the later oats. The Burt, Texas Red, and Kherson yielded respectively 61.3, 57.7, and 53.9 bushels per acre. It is evident that the Kherson has been surpassed by both Burt and Texas Red in this test. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Oats Investigations 15 ? 1 is !||| II 0 CONm 2 a^^fi tt ?'° c^ c^ S oowtcti -- r r 00 t- *-* I I !2 a^^ 0 ? e i"? c ! 1^: ®°;* - _ I'H^iiato nnnn iinN 2 a 1^^ 1^ «3 te«o 95 at •00«-&lt;1&gt; Qtaqeo ■WCOINTli | us ioo | uinN I OS r»^ t-^ U3 00 «O 00 *O Oi t&gt; t-^ O5 .-■ nnnn ecu c s &amp; G i i Oi 00 W 00 U3 N OS oit~d — "^cn-vm -^fcoeoco con rt "JtHOSD lO&gt;OTfiO IOU5 1 8 § 3 = °™ 2 cssSSS — 1~ o «s t^ QO T* V CO «&gt; t- ono&lt;o •* Tf aid — t- •&gt;» S •OIOIO 33 •»■«■■* iflo^io t^ -^j m d ~~ oj oo codec coeciNeM ttco — « "-IcO^"-** OONtOCO O100&gt; "■»■ ■"»■ CC •*• -^"^f 3 I 1 ■ . . </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 «3iaio«e usTf-w* |2«^ Z a a I «— «C U3Xf"^ X t*- &lt;-&gt; O *t* C*» ■* to o&gt; t- — — &lt; i — - - a, xt^ous t- -^ t- O5 N CTJ CO 00 N p t* us co ec t-t-O« ■^« oo ■** 1 1 — *S 8 "3 O od v co eo cc 8 I ' o-.ooo i^?" 5 o ■S 2 TT Tf ?C I O I 2222 S 2°° bl? ' 00 •— &lt;&lt;G lOt-CDCO C30CD 333 3333 33 : J. |^ - - - c c c 3 3 3 01 0) 0) 0) 0) 0) c c c c c c 3 3 3 3 3 3 Hj» t}» ■&lt;}• ir a. a D.O. a.o. I 2 y life 5 S Sugg's I.I : || : Hi &gt; &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Oats Investigations 17 Tables 6 and 7 contain the results obtained from all varieties tested in field plats thruout the last 6 years. These may again be divided into early and late groups, differing 6 days in length of growing period and 4 inches in height of plants. The early varieties averaged 16.7 bushels greater yield than the late group. In this 6-year period, the Burt, Texas Red, and June varieties surpassed the Kherson 7.3, 6.1, and 1.2 bushels per acre, respec - tively. Under favorable climatic conditions, the difference in time of ripening between the two groups would be greater. The Nebraska climate promotes premature ripening of late varieties. The yields are given in table 8 for all varieties of oats which have been tested in the field plats for a period of at least 4 con - secutive years during the period, 1902 to 1916. Many other varieties have been grown for a shorter period, but the results are not included in the table, because of the brief duration of the tests. Fig. 5 — Early versus late varieties of oats. From left to right: Lincoln Kherson, Swedish Select Since the varieties were not all grown during identically the same years, the customary mean yields for all varieties tested would not be comparable. To overcome this, Kherson was selected as a standard, and the other varieties were compared with it for the years in which they were grown, the relation being </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 :o Agr, cultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 ¥ i j^aoa oo -h oo o» eo t^ us ~« &lt;e »h SSSSS SS5S3Sc???S?3S SS2 0) 5O SfHNB CO kO COCO HAOAIO CC »— ?! "5 JhOAOI M«Ot-O-01M«00 C^ 00 COCCCOCOCOCOC4COCOC4 lO ~ M - 5 | 2 b : ei ? t 7°* X, 3&lt;Ot-C-&lt;0 t^*! * © t~ O5 CO ■-« U3 CO OO ©t*-CO i CO 00 -^1 -^1 CO as «c -^o co I » a ChCftOCOUSOOt^OOCOlO O(C-T '/ tdco'ojoncots^icouj us t^ t^ U3C4M " | E rt u ; i '&gt;NO NN1D-HN t-COO&gt;t--CO 00TOIO 1 S aeo-fl'ccec -&gt;iicc eo m com cocoSSjn «to : : : : :::::::::: : : : | " • • • ■ . a I M M| I M if M M ; ii\\ &gt;* I ::::■-::: I ' ■ * * ■ g i a* m » ' ' ' C C *C ' '5 *" : : : &gt;§ : : ; s - '■ '■ '■ '■ &gt; &gt; '■ I ► S : : sis* '&amp;.'■■'■*' :l - IN Sjfi ji^ss; Hi | H </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Oats Investigations 19 2i,» -t-woa) ao — • t-^ co x »o « oi co »o cc ai «e ■* ■*• n if n m cc co^ eo *5co«-« I S S .2 S is o Et T3^^ 5 32.82 2.* S|S : : : •3 h B "5C-&gt;C« . 5 0) 3 X_t- — -X 5 - 1 o aoc4 ec t-* — a&gt;r:«^j — t- — loos o t-_ t-_ ©_ x ■&lt;» c-_ o oo lOffitt _J c 3 Co-^3&gt;« K tNNMN 2* |r" rt wooxxxxxx ex — o b£«« B &lt; kO US ud n "a &gt;5 CO CO CO CO T)&gt; CO ■* COCO -c I 2 £ =-8 - ~5 Is T~ g°lfe ,5««00QO — C0-«-h*h©(NCMO1CO CO-HM &lt;M CM 94 CM C4 CM 94 O) N OJ M N eft 35 3i as as 3i s: si as o* aoo) » o t'jS 00 00 ?D CD *-» CC TO 09 CO CO t» CO \ i^^ ■ 3333 3333333333 33 • •^^^'^'^ "-&gt; &gt;-s *^ »-8 «-9 •-» »^ *-7 »-a i-^ "^&gt;-» . 1 Q J- 5 ■ -. •-. -1-1 v « v a* §e s c 3 3 3 ■-»TT-» O«NNCg^N«-HM • MNMNMMNMNN «N ■ EEEEBESBEB SB 3333333333 33 l -»T^TT-jT-a"T-. T-» I oooo *— t »-t .—1 i— ( Q.Q. a. a. &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt; =. =. - — — ~~ — =.=. — — ! ■~* ■ • ■ ""j sg n SI 05 • -E-S § g e-g B B H c « »2fe UJ=£3§kEc.£iog3etotE &gt; &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 jNtoeo »»«■; . ©CO t-; t- — « ■ 00 *-• 00 etc «i- so | •-. — ..; . -. © | «3cet-co ;t- •ocm-* cm NM CMCM CM OO on : q sow • aico'so | |_«S8 j_ j3 cpcM ri CMCM CMCMCM i ■OlOSC O oi ** ■ ■ os oo t-^ ~. i a 3 1 I a I ■o i I I I t- mANA 00 ■ Csl « O)Ut&gt; O I * ) '*^"O ;■* ; mm ; MN« ■ w* I ■ ■ . . : ' ■ r~ : . CONN *J INN MMN • ■« -- f; o; co ! XNoi-toni; : : fmic^driw NOsiiovNe .... ~ . '. : : ; ! r I-NMNN NMNMNNM • t-; t-; N 0) US ! NOJhiOhWO '.'.'.'..'. O '■'aoooxoooo &lt;o t- 1- J^ t- oc 10 •&lt;re*meim NNNNccNn m i • ■ : : : ~:~. • oio^fo ! ! io«nio '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. HHMH • ■ C4HHH I a*-. 0 .*. '■'■'■ ::::::::::::: | jaJ5S?3 ; :::::::::::: ■ M M N» i I iJilif il i i i I H M Hig MJI :*l i M M $ &lt;=S ■«• s* • ■* ■ &gt; c*. — USi-it- jlrfsi liiHIptiitf </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Oats Investigations 21 •^2 2"-;CO 1 «i;Mt-;N i U5 CO t-; IO CO &gt;-&gt; Cft ■*; » e» CO •-; OJ ►^•&gt;© CC CO Cft CO t- *-* O t- CO t- CC ■W ■* CO 4 -* CO 5 CO S ij CO SS" „__ I ■■gg £§££g£gS3S?g£S : : : T! 2 fe"- 1 «« • • • « a, . : : O) - 1 g ■ — , i ■ ■ ■ a 1 "*** ■ e i"^ &lt;O"» ' -coco ' ' ' | 2 «jg£ : :«g 3g : :&lt;g° jgjggggg : : : *N « tCOJ-NIM NN MM MNNMNM I '.'.'. I ■ a — — : i ■ ■ ■ •£ S t * i -q"Q ; ;»"i cow ; coco ;com*McowcJ 1 ' "§ t-M NN NO NCJ C4MC4C4C4OJ • • ■ H« 1 ' " - ' ... 1 I I S ! I ! 1 t&gt;3 a — : 1 ■ ■ ■ £1 31 »2~ torn ot-' ■ aim ■ h w uj « x w 2 * 2 w ' ■ w w cow ! ! co co '. co co co co co co I ! ! ! s " T— r- i L___ § • ** Oi ' - ■_ ■ ? * o "^ ■ Tf-^' ; !^^ ; -^ -^^ -^&lt;^&gt; -^ La I ' ' ... b &amp; — 1 — ... . ... H ; l— • 1 z -- h r- ; — - ..** * " ' ... I ... t- eo ■ ■ co eo co co ■ coco ■ co co co co 00 co ■ ■ ■ . c a | 1 _^ l^j : 1 ■ ■ • •W3»O ! NO OJt&gt;; ! !&lt;O^H ! t&gt;; l&gt;; CO OS t-; «? ! ! ', £»2^ 2S^ was usco'oi^od^ — ■*^00^« • "COCO "^CO ■ COCO CONCOCOCMCM • • ■ 0) : • .. • ■_ • - ... ; ; — ; 00 eo ■ coco coco ■ coco ■ co co co cm co co • ■ ■ ; :t&gt;. : aoo&gt; ; !oiw ieooi^ooo : ; ; ; ca i — '■ '. * : : • ... . . . , 1 fc- CO ■ CO ■ COCO ■ COCO ■ CO CO CO CO CO ■ I . . . ' I ■ • ■__ • I • ■ ■ :::::: : : :fc? it's : : : : : 88 : 1 N N Niij M :'r Nj \ || a |3^1tig J: i||l.lli : 8llSII gg Q </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 expressed in per cent of the Kherson yield. The relative stand ing, therefore, of each variety as compared with Kherson is given in the next to the last column, and the corresponding relative yield in bushels per acre is shown in the last column. Burt, Texas Red, and June again are superior to Kherson oats. The Burt yield is 15 per cent superior to the Kherson, 29 per cent superior to the best late variety, and 93 per cent better than the poorest late variety. The average superiority of the six early varieties is 13 bushels over the late group. Fig. 6 — Kherson oats Fig. 7 — Swedish Select oata In 1910, 789 lots of seed were obtained for classification studies from the various experiment stations and seed houses, which included practically all the oats varieties grown in this country. These have been grown for 6 years in nursery plats and have afforded an opportunity for careful examination and observa - tion regarding characteristics of growth and seed production </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Oats Investigations 23 under Nebraska conditions. None of these varieties have given promise of being superior to the best already grown in the variety yield tests. A number of representative types of oats are shown in figures 6 to 10. Figure 6 is a typical head of Kherson oats. This type of head is also characteristic of all early varieties grown in this State. It is commonly known as the "true" or "spreading" panicle. Kherson has for many years been the standard variety of oats for a large part of Nebraska. Fig. 8 — Canadian oats Fig. 9— White Russian oats A typical head of Swedish Select oats is shown in figure 7. This is a medium-late variety and is grown rather extensively in parts of the State. In growth habit, it is representative of the small group of late varieties indicated in tables 4 to 9. This is the same type of panicle as that in figure 6, but is larger and more spreading. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 Fig._ll— Various types of oats spikelets </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Oats Investigations 25 Figure 8 shows a typical head of Canadian oats. This variety has very large, coarse straw and is very late in maturing. It represents a type that is not at all suited to Nebraska conditions. While the large, plump seed of this or similar varieties imported from the northern states and Canada are very attractive, no attempts should be made to grow them here. White Russian oats, shown in figure 9, is of the "side panicle" type which is characteristic of a few late varieties grown chiefly in the cooler and more humid sections of the country. Such oats are frequently classified as side oats, in contrast with the true panicle oats. No early varieties of this type have thus far been found to be adapted to Nebraska conditions. Figure 10 is a head of hull-less or "naked" oats. This type of oats differs from the common varieties chiefly in two respects: (1) The hull, or flowering glume, does not adhere to the grain; (2) the spikelet contains from 3 to 10 grains, instead of 1 to 3. Varieties of this type are not suited to Nebraska conditions. Different types of oats spikelets are shown in figure 11 as follows: (1) Spikelet 2-grained, 2-awned, with long hairs at base of grain and on the hull; (2) spikelet 2-grained, 2-awned, with basal hairs; (3) spikelet 3-grained, 3-awned, with basal hairs; (4) spikelet 2-grained, 1-awned, with no basal hairs; (5) spikelet 1-grained, 1-awned, with no basal hairs; (6) spikelet 2-grained, awnless, with no basal hairs; (7) spikelet 1-grained, awnless, with no basal hairs; (8) spikelet 3 (or more) grained, awnless, with no basal hairs. Figure 12 shows two typical plants grown from seed bearing the same name. The seed for No. 1 came from Deleware, that for No. 2 came from Utah. This is plainly a case of confusion of variety names. Such cases are rather frequent, and they suggest that care is necessary in purchasing seed oats in order to make sure that the desired variety is being obtained. Two very distinct types of growth habit are also illustrated by these two plants. IMPROVEMENT OF OATS BY BREEDING Varieties, as commonly grown, have a rather uniform appear - ance, altho close analysis may show the presence of a number of more or less distinct types of oats. These types may be quite distinct and may or may not have practical importance. Again, they may be similar in appearance and the difference ascertained only thru careful yield tests after having been isolated from the general variety. Since oats are, at best, a poorly adapted crop for Nebraska conditions, an attempt to select and multiply strains somewhat </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 better adapted than the bulk of the original variety is attended with considerable promise. Such an attempt has been made by the Nebraska Experiment Station and has apparently met with a certain measure of success. Fig. 12 — Two distinct varieties of oats bearing the same name Since Kherson oats was the most commonly grown variety in the State and possessed many desirable characters, this variety was chosen as a foundation for improvement. Seven hundred and fifty individual oat heads were selected at random in 1907 from a field of Kherson oats originating from an 1896 importation from Russia. In selecting these heads, the chief considerations </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Oats Investigations 27 wire that they should conform to the general Kherson type of head and contain not less than 50 seeds. In 1908, fifty seeds from each head were planted in individual 2-foot rows spaced 10 inches apart. This approximated the usual rate of planting under field conditions. Fig. 13 — Method of testing individual head selections ot Kherson oats the first year. Seven hundred fifty initial selections were made Based upon the 1908 results, 300 strains were discarded because they appeared to have slightly weaker straw. Of the remaining strains, the 265 giving the highest yields were tested in 1909. They were planted at the normal rate in duplicate 12.5-foot nursery rows, with a check plat of the original seed after every tenth row. Following this test, all except the 75 most promising strains were eliminated. These were planted in 1910 in 12.5-foot nursery rows — the entire series being repeated ten times. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 In 1911 the number of strains was further reduced to forty all of which have been grown at the normal rate of planting during the 6 years, 1911 to 1916, in 16-foot nursery plats contain - ing 5 rows spaced 10 inches apart (figure 14.) The plats have been systematically repeated six to eight times each year with checks of the original seed planted after every fifth strain. Beginning with 1915, the two outer rows of each plat have been discarded, and the yield determined for the three center rows only. Fig. 14 — Oats nursery containing 40 strains of Kherson oats repeated 8 times in 5-row nursery blocks. The outer rows of each block are discarded at harvest. Strain No. 35 in center The strain numbers by which these 40 strains are known originate in the 1910 ranking for yield. They were numbered from 1 to 40 according to their rank. The results for the last 6 years follow in tables 9 and 10. In the 6-year nursery test, 25 strains have yielded better than the original seed, while 15 strains have yielded less. The best two strains have yielded nearly 5 bushels better. While the grain of the original Kherson oats is chiefly yellow, it is interesting to note that the two highest ranking strains, Nos. 5 and 21, are light </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Oats Investigations 29 yellow and white respectively. Since strain No. 21 is white and has yielded only 0.18 bushel less per acre than No. 5, and appears equally meritorious in other regards, this strain may be considered as the most worthy of increase and dissemination. Table 9 — Yield test of forty Kherson oats strains grown in nursery , 1911 to 1916 Yield per acre Strain No. 1911 1912 1913 i riginal 5 21 33 11 22 30 16 27 17 1 IS 4 I .-) a to 23 7 88 39 29 12 13 25 15 14 32 2 8 19 40 20 26 24 37 31 28 36 34 35 Bushels Bushels 40.07 27.84 44.79 28.47 44.02 28.15 | 39.66 31.12 I 44.79 25.50 41.91 25.32 41.42 25.77 38.04 28.92 46.73 28.78 40.92 30.62 40.29 27.21 39.98 27.52 38.04 28.69 46.00 28.56 42.32 27.48 40.74 24.51 38.58 26.04 45.10 28.02 42.18 26.40 40.34 29.73 37.91 29.28 38.85 25.18 39.62 28.51 41.33 28.06 43.48 29.14 40.29 28.74 37.95 28.92 38.13 28.15 44.07 27.84 40.56 24.91 38.18 24.42 37.10 26.04 40.16 25.86 37.42 29.00 42.54 28.38 36.83 29.55 37.69 24.96 42.94 25.27 36.02 26.89 38.63 30.40 23.65 20.51 Bushel 68.40 75.60 | 67.64 ! 71.14 '■ 67.37 71.95 68.04 65.07 68.40 66.70 66.51 66.51 70.56 68.22 71.81 62.38 60.22 68.63 64.26 65.92 63.95 67.68 71.24 65.07 69.80 61.57 65.84 60.94 68.31 61.48 63.90 62.47 61.88 65.30 64.08 63.59 63.72 60.98 59.40 51.17 41.24 1914 Bushels 56.21 58.62 66.51 60.98 59.32 58.78 i 62.87 ! 56.08 61.48 62.34 62.63 59.68 60.90 60.22 61.09 63.32 63.28 59.90 61.44 57.10 58.42 60.72 59.54 56.88 60.94 61.07 58.10 59.50 57.63 58.02 59.14 51.73 61.48 57.38 57.96 53.88 58.46 58.10 52.44 38.49 48.71 1915 Bushels 51.12 56.96 63.10 55.24 57.26 52.69 55.61 66.55 53.14 52.76 56.14 59.88 59.14 55.77 54.34 60.94 52.76 49.10 54.79 54.41 56.96 56.06 49.02 55.54 48.64 54.34 51.34 50.14 46.39 52.76 60.64 52.54 50.74 50.37 46.92 46.17 44.15 38.82 48.12 26.23 32.08 1916 Average Bushels Bushels 72.10 52.62 81.01 57.57 74.95 57.39 79.60 56.29 81.70 55.99 85.14 55.96 81.48 55.86 80.12 55.79 73.68 55.37 78.55 55.31 77.20 54.99 76.14 54.95 72.33 54.94 68.50 54.54 69.85 54.48 74.65 54.42 85.15 54.34 74.05 54.13 74.80 53.98 75.47 53.83 76.23 53.79 74.13 53.77 74.13 53.68 74.36 53.54 68.50 53.42 72.78 53.13 73.38 52.59 78.25 52.52 70.38 52.44 75.62 52.22 66.78 52.18 81.02 51.82 70.68 51.80 69.25 51.45 63.86 50.62 70.83 50.14 71.73 50.12 72.78 49.81 66.93 48.30 59.21 40.69 60.78 37.83 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 TABLE 10 — Description of forty Kherson oats strains grown in nursery. Average, 1911 to 1916 Date Date Date ! Length ' Length Height Amount Strain No. Color of grain of of of of growing of fruiting of of ripening period period plants lodging planting heading Dnu* Dayt I Ineket \Per cent Original. . Yellow April 6 June 14 5 I Medium yellow .. April 6 June 13 21 White April 6 June 15 33 White April 6 June 13 II White April 6 June 14 22 ' Medium yellow .. April 6 June 14 SO Yellow April 6 June 16 IS Yellow April S June 14 27 Medium white... April 6 June 16 17 Medium yellow. . April 6 June 14 1 Medium white ... April 6 June 16 18 Medium yellow . . April 6 June 15 4 Yellow April 6 June 16 t. Medium yellow . . April 6 June 14 April 6 June 15 1 Yellow 9 Medium white... April 6 June 16 10 Yellow April 6 June 16 23 Yellow April 6 June 14 T.. Medium white ... April 6 June 15 April 6 June 16 88 Yellow SS Yellow April 6 June 16 29 Medium yellow.. April 6 June 14 1* Yellow April 6 June 15 IS Medium yellow . . April 6 June 1 5 25 Yellow April 6 June 15 16 Yellow April 6 June 16 14 Medium yellow .. April 6 June 16 82 i Medium white ... April 6 June 14 2 Medium yellow. . April 6 , June 14 April 6 June 14 8 ' Yellow 19. ...... Reddish white. . April 6 June 16 40 Medium yellow . . April 6 | June 14 20 Yellow. April 6 I June 17 M White April 6 I June 13 24! ..... .\ Medium yellow.. April 6 June 14 87 Yellow April 6 June 15 81 Yellow April 6 June 13 B. ...... Medium yellow. . April 6 June 16 86 Yellow ! April 6 | June 17 84 White April 6 ! June 19 U White April 6 June 20 April 6 June 20 Six of the 40 strains were distinctly white oats, but there was no apparent difference in the grain in other respects. The two distinctly later ripening strains were far inferior in yield, which correlation has also been found to exist for oats varieties. Twelve of the Kherson oats strains have been tested 3 to 4 years in field plats in a manner similar to the variety tests described earlier. (Figure 15.) The results are given in tables 11 and 12. Strain No. 21, white Kherson oats, ranked first in yield, whereas it was second in the nursery. Its yield was 7.8 bushels per acre greater than the original Kherson as an average for the 4-year period. Strain No. 5 has been grown only 3 years in field plats, during which time it has yielded 3.3 July 8 July 7 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 9 July 8 July 9 July 7 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 7 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 8 July 7 July 8 . July 8 July 8 [ July 8 I July 7 . July 8 1 July 7 I July 9 July 8 July 8 . July 8 July 8 July 8 July 9 July 10 July 11 i»3 M 93 93 93 93 93 M 93 93 91 93 94 92 93 93 93 M N 93 93 93 93 93 92 93 93 93 M 92 93 92 91 93 93 93 93 93 94 95 96 24 24 23 25 24 24 22 24 22 24 23 23 23 23 23 22 22 23 23 22 22 24 23 23 22 22 22 24 24 23 22 23 22 25 24 23 25 22 22 21 21 I 3S.1 ! 33.9 33.1 33.5 31.9 32.7 33.5 33.5 34.3 33.1 33.9 33.5 I 33.9 I ! 31.9 32.7 33.9 32.7 31.9 | 33.9 32.7 33.1 32.3 ' 33.1 , 32.7 ! 31.9 33.1 32.3 31.6 32.3 32.3 32.3 32.3 34.9 31.9 31.9 32.7 33.1 32.7 33.5 33.1 S7.4 17 17 17 17 II 17 17 17 17 17 17 17 17 20 17 17 17 17 20 17 17 17 II 18 17 19 IK 17 17 17 17 19 17 18 19 17 17 17 17 17 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Oats Investigations 31 bushels per acre more than the original Kherson and 2.6 bushels less than strain No. 21. During the last two years, however, strain No. 5 has taken the lead and is apparently equal in yielding power to No. 21, as is indicated by the nursery record. Fig. 15— Method of testing Kherson oats strains in field plate. (1916.) The plats are the width of a grain drill and are harvested with one swath of the binder. From left to right: Strains Nos. 19, 35, 5 Table 11— Yield test of Kherson oats strains grown in field plats, 1913 to 1916 Yield per acre Strain Number 1913 1914 1915 1916 Average iriginal a'.'.'. 15. 25 . 6. . . 33 27. . . 38. . 35 4. .. 6... 19... Bushels 44.4 58.0 61.0 51.8 62.1 64.1 58.5 50.8 62.1 33.9 61.0 Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels 58.9 29.9 83.0 54.1 71.7 32.4 85.4 61.9 67.3 27.7 85.9 60.5 50.4 26.5 77.3 51.5 64.2 30.7 83.9 60.2 63.2 24.4 81.6 58.3 63.7 35.7 86.1 61.0 67.1 31.7 81.9 57.9 64.9 31.9 81.1 60.0 53.0 22.8 76.7 46.6 67.8 30.5 80.3 59.9 65.2 33.3 83.3 50.1 21.4 74.8 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 Table 12 — Description of Kherson oats strains grown in field plats Average, 1913 to 1916 Date I Length i Length Height Amount Date Date Strain No. Color of grain of of of of growing of fruiting of of ripening period period plants lodging planting heading Dai' i Dms Ii,c&gt;trx \Prr rent Original Yellow April 9 June 16 21 White April 9 June 1 2:1 Yellow April 9 June 16 IS ; Yellow April 9 June 18 tt Yellow April 9 June 16 C. Medium yellow April 9 June 16 IS White April 9 June 16 April 9 June 16 27 Medium white . . April 9 June 1 38 i Yellow April 9 June 1 April 9 June 1 S5 White April 9 June 22 4 Yellow April 9 June 1 Fig. 16 — Ten-acre field of Nebraska No. 21 white Kherson oats, which yielded at the rate of 78.5 bushels an acre in 1916. As an average for 4 years, it has surpassed the original Kherson, from which it was selected, 7.8 bushels an acre The consistent superiority in yield of strain No. 21 in the field plats as well as in the nursery indicates a marked improve - ment over_the original Kherson from which it was selected. Iuly 10 ! luly 10 Iuly 9 luly 10 luly 9 luly 9 I luly 10 , luly 10 luly 10 luly 14 lulv 10 92 92 91 92 91 91 92 92 92 96 92 24 23 23 22 23 23 24 23 23 22 23 39.4 | 40.2 I 39.4 40.9 39.0 38.6 39.0 40.6 39.4 42.9 39.8 21 24 27 38 23 25 25 25 25 25 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Oats Investigations 33 The white color would also give it an added value on the general market. Figure 16 shows a 10-acre increase field of this strain No. 21 grown in 1916. It yielded at the rate of 78.2 bushels per acre. The seed was distributed to farmers during the early spring of 1917, under the name of Nebraska No. 21 oats. Table 13 gives the relative yields of Burt, Texas Red, Kherson strain No. 21, and the original Kherson oats. Table 13 — Relative yields of the three highest yielding varieties and strain No. 21. Average, 1913 to 1916 The data in table 13 indicate a very important improvement over the original Kherson oats. However, two varieties — Burt and Texas Red — have been found to exceed the yield of strain No. 21 by 2.6 bushels and 0.4 bushel respectively. This suggests that variety tests may be at least as important as crop breeding. An attempt to select a superior strain from Burt oats will be started in 1917. Unless a superior strain of Burt is found, both Burt and Kherson strain No. 21 may be regarded as practically equal. The superiority of Burt over common Kherson is, how - ever, somewhat more definitely established than is that of Kher - son strain No. 21, because of the much greater duration of the comparative yit.d tests. IRRIGATED VERSUS UNIRRIGATED OATS FOR SEED In occasional years, such as 1911, farmers on unirrigated land have had difficulty in securing seed (grown without irrigation), which they believed satisfactory. An investigation was started in 1912 to determine whether it would be safe for the eastern Nebraska farmers to secure seed oats grown under irrigation in western Nebraska. Seed of both Kherson and Swedish Select oats grown for many years under irrigation in Scotts Bluff County, Nebraska, was secured during each of the last 5 years and compared at the Experiment Station at Lincoln with locally-grown seed of the Variety Color Yield per acre Kherson Oats No. 21 ... iriginal Kherson iurt 'exas Red White Yellow Reddish yellow . . Red Bushels 61.9 54.1 64.5 62.3 i J </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 34 same varieties. Each season the plats were repeated two to three times. The results are given in table 14. During the 5-year period, the seed of both varieties grown under irrigation has rather consistently outyielded the seed of home-grown unirrigated oats. The average difference has been TABLE 14 — Yields from irrigated and unirrigated seed oats, 1912 to Select oats. The investigation suggests that irrigated seed oats grown in western Nebraska may be substituted for unirrigated seed of the same variety in eastern Nebraska. These varieties have not changed their growth habits as the result of being grown under irrigation for many years. EFFECT OF GRADING ON SEED VALUE OF OATS An experiment was started in 1905 to determine the effect of continuous grading upon the seed value of Kherson oats. A similar test with American Banner, a later-maturing variety, was started in 1909. The tests have been made each year in duplicate, on plats 1-30 to 1-15 acre in size, and all seeding was done with a press drill. For all Kherson grades, the rate of seeding was 10 pecks per acre. For the American Banner, the rate was 12 pecks. In the first year of the tests, the oats were divided into grades by means of directing the seed into an upward moving air blast. The lighter seed was carried over, while the heavier seed fell down and out at the bottom of the machine. By this means the heaviest one-fourth and the lightest one-fourth of the seed were secured in separate lots for comparison with the original seed. Each year since, the lightest one-fourth seed has been secured from the crop previously grown from the lightest one-fourth seed. Similarly, the heaviest one-fourth seed has been secured from the Yield per acre Variety and previous 1 1 1 treatment 1912 1913 1914 1915 1916 1915 1916 Average Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Cherson, unirrigated 41.9 43.1 57.5 29.5 65.9 Cherson, irrigated 45.1 57.6 58.4 30.7 63.1 Iwedish Select, unirrigated 23.6 32.9 46.7 27.0 37.6 Swedish Select, irrigated 25.6 38.7 49.4 31.0 39.3 Bushels 47.6 51.0 33.6 36.8 I t.4 bushels per acre for Kherson and 3.2 bushels for the S Jelect oats. The investigation suggests that irrigated sei Iwedish ed oats </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Oats Investigations 35 ■/■ OS ■K.OOlOt- 5 -3 -S ■*•"»■•«": &lt;2 • --■aot-r- 3-. oj a 5 — acoooo fiSo-jie n °5 cc N a 3 . — ■&lt;). t- to » — ?eper^ 1 - 0 -*. so * • • ■~- a. 5 *-« =s .r w «5-55^i i ■o S I rnSotrt: n 3- _MO!B »1"O N £ S -^ g 1 - 2 t§ s 3SS N S »-&lt;»9« S &lt;&amp; 0 ."*. i-t *■* 05 (SS 000001 •*5" 35O&gt;0O V S 9-99« ►-5 ««» *l -IS3S S 8 (Ss^sjo M 3- •r-. K a 5 iji ? I ; Ht *« a III 119 S sll .-&lt; S fill ? a m OK3lZ Ei OBJ e E s v • • • S~-*«&gt;* slaaszss li 2 I j i i| i?i I)! 3 - — ■ ~ COO US *H -^CO SO CO 5 Oi t— 4 "j§S33 E I ■^ i-h CO »*5 CO c IT? 05 IS I f 5 l I ►J^' co com </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 1 ! ae -- a. i =; ■7. HJ e S 5 Is-rpt- e 3 "I'm 1 * 5 &gt;- &lt;q = T3 ot-n _ioot- 3 ~«Nm aSE-yt- -NNN =c C-, 2 ! S- ; SSS | N E s-s s« =5 a. * ° a-* JR« T|&gt;» 2 ! S^ tt ! M ffl« ?.li "S s a, k ISIO -. I 1 •-,5 ~ a, •— . z 2 Ji — -oon § 2 I 8^ :~« I IS5J :g§ I N a a NN 7. =: a. "^» 1 L i 111 I 1 111 1 sJli ■ s i 4 1 sill - 1 1?1 | h :b"S| i 1 III X ■o «Hit B l.a £ «« « i S5« OK 3 i ? H 1 H |=^s &gt; &gt;&gt; 9 — C4 C4 G! : ■ v • 2 S^SS? | 2 I|^S§§ _ i 00 fri i M S »_ f 35 3*&gt;^oio a. K 1.8 2 '1~ :=&gt;=&gt; .£■1 2 1 1- as </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Oats Investigations 37 crop previously grown from the heaviest one-fourth seed. This has given an opportunity for an accumulative effect of the use of the fanning mill. As a standard for determining the increase or decrease in yield from the two grades, a crop from the original unselected seed has been grown each season along with that from the selected seed. The results for the two varieties are given in tables 15 to 18. As an average for 12 years, the heaviest one-fourth Kherson oats seed yielded 0.77 bushel better than the unselected seed, while the light seed yielded 0.09 bushel better. This difference is slight and may be regarded as within the limits of experimental error. The use of the fanning mill had very little effect upon the quality of the crop harvested. In the 8-year test with American Banner oats, which is a rel - atively late and unadapted variety, only the light and heavy seed were compared during the first 4 years, while the unselected Fig. 17 — Test plats of light and heavy American Banner seed oats. (1916.) Left to right: Unselected seed, heaviest one-fourth, lightest one-fourth seed planted seed was included after 1912. As an 8-year average the light seed has yielded 1.44 bushels more than the heavy. t)uring the last four years, the heavy seed has yielded 2.07 bushels less and the light seed has yielded 1.63 bushels more than the unselected </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 seed. This variety appears to have been a mixture of strains, before the original separation was made. These were oAsuch a character that they have been separated by the fanning mill. On an average for the last 5 years, the crop from the light seed has ripened 2 days earlier than that from the heavy seed. The lighter weight of the seed planted has evidently been associated with earliness and higher yield in this case. The crop harvested, however, has had slightly greater weight per bushel from the light seed. These experiments indicate that little practical improvement in the yield of oats may be effected by planting only the heavy grade of seed as may be obtained from the use of a fanning mill. In general, the fanning mill is not a grain breeder. Its practical use consists largely in removing trash and weed seed when present in the seed. EQUAL WEIGHTS VERSUS EQUAL NUMBERS OF LARGE AND SMALL OATS SEED During 5 years, 1912 to 1916, large and small hand-selected seeds of Kherson oats have been compared for yield at the normal rate of planting. The plan has been to plant the grades in both equal numbers and equal weights at an optimum rate for the large seeds. The various rates have been grown in series of nursery plats repeated ten times. The results are given in table 19. When planted in equal numbers, the small seed yielded only 89 per cent as much as the large, while both grades yielded equally when equal weights of seed were used. The difference of 2 per cent in yield between the two grades and the unselected seed is within the limits of experimental error. Planting equal weights of the different grades corresponds more nearly to what would happen in farm practice than does planting equal numbers. RATE OF PLANTING Rate-planting tests with oats have beep made since 1903. Since the various rates have not all been tested thruout the entire period, the results have been grouped in a number of tables (tables 20 to 24) according to the duration of the test. Well - cleaned oats have been drilled each year in duplicate or triplicate plats of 1-30 to 1-15 acre area. In a 12-year comparison of 8 and 16 pecks of Kherson oats per acre, the 16 pecks have given a 2.1-bushel greater yield and a 0.1-bushel greater net return. By net return is meant the yield per acre less the amount of seed planted. During a 9-year period, 8 and 16 pecks per acre have yielded respectively 4.2 and 8.2 bushels more than a 4-peck seeding, while the net returns have been 3.2 and 5.2 bushels greater. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Oats Investigations 39 In an 8-year comparison, 8, 10, 12, and 16 pecks of Kherson oats per acre have yielded respectively 61.9, 61.6, 62.4, and 63.4 bushels, while the net returns were 59.9, 59.1, 59.4, and 59.4 bushels. Table 19 — Yields from equal numbers versus equal weights of large and small seed of Kherson oats, 1912 to 1916 1 Equal numbers of seed Equal weights of seed Seed per acre Seed per acre Yield Yield Kind of Number I Weight | per Number I Weight per seed planted acre acre Pounds Bushels Pounds Bushels (1) I (2) I (3) I (4) (5) I (6) I (7) YEAR 1912 Large 1 1,319,868 j 73 25.4 I 1,319,868 I 73 25.4 Small 1,319,868 50 23.8 1,897,729 73 23.6 Unselected . . . . | | | | 1,633,500 I 73 24.7 YEAR 1913 Large I 1,319,868 I 64 71.5 | 1,319,868 I 64 71.5 Small 1,319,868 34 55.1 2,450,250 64 76.3 Unselected .... | | I I 1,767,447 | 64 72.0 YEAR 1914 Large I 1,319,868 I 55 26.5 I 1,319,868 I 55 26.5 Small 1,319,868 35 27.0 2,100,681 55 24.7 Unselected 1,653,102 55 25.0 YEAR 1915 Large 11,306,800 1 65 34.0 11,306,800 1 65 34.0 Small 1,306,800 35 33.3 2,479,653 65 38.2 Unselected | | 1,731,510 65 36.0 YEAR 1916 Large I 1,306,800 I 61 73.8 ! 1,306,800 I 61 73.3 Small 1,306,800 28 65.5 2,868,426 61 67.9 Unselected .... I | | I 2,041,875 | 61 68.8 FIVE YEAR AVERAGE Lane 1,314,641 64 46.1 1,314,641 64 46.1 Small 1,314,641 36 40.9 2,359,348 64 46.1 tt l *._ j i t/ic &lt;on . ■ ac n Unselected 1,765,487 64 45.3 'The teat* were made in sititfle ro* plats iii \tt\l a. id 1J13 and in 3-row blocks in 1914, 1915 and 19*6. Results are based on the center row of three-row blocks. All testa were replicated ten times each year, except the unselected seed, which was repeated 30 times. During the 4-year period, 1913 to 1916, Kherson oats were grown at six rates of seeding, namely, 4, 8, 10, 12, 14, and 16 pecks per acre. The average yields for these rates were respec- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 !..p 1-3 e E SB-g S££ *• on ■3 JS©noi 3 4 1! -8?53? S 2!5&lt;5»&lt;» =: = Tf IO«&gt; *. 3U340101O « 60 s s I If I n. liii ?- 5§ 4? I s 1 - « *&lt; a &lt; _ 5. • ■ B j OOtO ! « ■-i Si jjeiw 2 »«» 2 aaSJSs 2 »»» | 2 2 &lt;5g£ 1,3 a^ | | 2J*33 i * s ■§ |3 -S ? § »*.*. =- 2 «=SS "o" « g _■ m -w | 2 S52SS 2 3sS 1 S a^^ E&lt; 2 tt)SS 2 &lt;*££ 1 §3SS as i iocici •i 3t-00» i — 1 — 2 |SSS r 5 S 2 5553 I —3— - - os oc co cc n I -T— 53 2 SSSS h * &lt; os x t»oote f_ rt SCOTT &lt;S aa 2 S35§ * g [|O3&lt;OT|I^I ■&lt; "3 ■5 2 SSSSS | « or os wasTJoo 00 I 1 2 SSSSS I — "o 2 e i"""&gt; T ': o&gt; ■» os ;u)iods j ? - (g-oS-w 1 7^ &gt;^ os 2«»-^c&gt; -h a«ont&gt;oio I — ; 2 |£ggg W so O &lt; 2 S§gS§g E-i _J5 2 SSSSS &lt;4 z =5 I — z ~&amp; os wustoooj 2 B I oe os 2«oo«c&gt; rt SUSTfUSlO S3 2 3S88S 0Q 2 1 t </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Oats Investigations 41 tively 55.4, 56.7, 60.2, 60.6, 61.2, and 62.9 bushels per acre. The respective net returns were 54.4, 54.7, 57.7, 57.6, 57.7, and 58.9 bushels per acre. Both the maximum yield and maximum net return were secured from the 4-bushel rate of seeding. The yield was distinctly better from a 10-peck than from a lighter rate, while the differences between the 10 pecks and the higher rates were very slight. TABLE 23— Rate of planting Kherson oats, 1913 to 1916 All of the data suggest that there may be a rather wide range in rate of planting oats without a material effect upon the net returns per acre. However, each of the four preceding tables indicates that 16 pecks per acre have yielded more than 8 pecks, and the net return is also shown to be greater in three tables. The most practical rate for Kherson oats would seem to be 10 to 12 pecks per acre for conditions comparable with those at the Experiment Station. Under similar conditions, the large seeded varieties, such as Swedish Select, should be planted not thinner than 12 pecks. These rates conform to present general farm practice in eastern Nebraska. It is customary to seed less in central and western Nebraska because of a more probable short- lei per acre per acre 1913 1914 1915 1916 Average | Net return Peeka Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels Bushels 4 52.2 58.0 35.7 75.7 55.4 54.4 8 55.2 59.7 29.6 82.2 56.7 54.7 L0 56.1 65.5 34.7 84.6 60.2 57.7 12 50.6 66.4 40.3 85.1 60.6 57.6 14 51.5 67.9 39.4 85.8 61.2 57.7 16 49.4 69.1 40.3 92.6 62.9 58.9 Table 24 — Rote of planting Swedish Select oats, 191 S to 1916 iel per acre Rate per acre 1913 1914 1915 1916 Average Net return Peek* 4 8 10 12 L4 16 1 Bushels 22.1 30.3 29.6 29.1 28.9 27.5 Bushels 37.9 43.4 42.8 45.1 46.8 43.7 Bushels 23.5 21.1 27.2 29.3 27.2 25.8 Bushels 50.1 59.7 63.1 67.5 70.3 73.8 Bushels 33.4 38.6 40.7 42.8 43.3 42.6 Bushels 32.4 36.6 38.2 39.8 39.8 38.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 age of soil moisture. With Swedish Select oats (table 24), which is a larger grain type, identical net returns were secured during a 4-year period from 12 and 14 peck seedings, while the yields were lower for both lighter and heavier rates. RELATIVE YIELDS OF OATS AND OTHER CROPS AT THE NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION The relative yields for corn, winter wheat and oats, during the 15-year period, 1902 to 1916, are given in table 25. The relative yields for these crops together with spring wheat are also shown for the 8-year period, 1909 to 1915. Table 25 — Relative yields of oats and other crops at the Nebraska Experiment Station, 1902 to 1915 Kherson Hogue's Yellow ; Turkey Red i Spring GENERAL NOTES ON OATS GROWING 1 Soil Fertility — One reason for the unsatisfactory yiejds of oats in recent years in eastern Nebraska is the lessened available fertility, due to continuous grain cropping without a legume, such as alfalfa or clover, in the rotation. Oats also respond favorably to an occasional light application of manure. Increased available fertility and more thoro seed bed preparation add Year oats Dent corn winter wheat i wheat 1902 1903 1904 :. 1905 1906 1907 1908 Bushels : 42 68 55 83 36 :: S Bushels 75 75 82 72 66 66 55 Bushels Bushels 33 32 18 21 62 52 38 7-year average 1909 1910 1911 1912 1913 1914 1915 1916 55 77 67~ 42 38 37 45 68 33 85 67 41 58 43 4S 8 5:i 75 H2 -iT- 27 18 48 30 51 16 9 14 50 17 34 17 30 16 38 22 8-year average 15-year average 52 53 48 5* I ! : 36 j 19 36 ~i </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Oats Investigations 43 materially to the yield and profit from growing oats. This fact is illustrated in table 3, in which the yield and the acre income of oats on the Experiment Station farm are compared with the average yield and acre income for Lancaster County. The differences are largely a matter of soil fertility and tillage methods. Early varieties of oats grow on reasonably productive soils with - out serious lodging. 2 The Seed Bed — In general, oats should be planted upon cornstalk land. The seed bed should be prepared either by thoro double-disking and harrowing, or by shallow plowing followed by thoro disking and harrowing. Early preparation is desirable. A comparison of different methods of seed bed preparation and of crop sequence has been made by the Experimental Sub - station at North Platte, during a period of 8 years, 1907 to 1914. The results are given in table 26. Slightly lower yields Table 26 — Yield of oats, spring wheat, and barley from different seed bed preparation and crop sequences. Average, 1907 to 191 U l ■Compiled from Ncbrmrkm North Platte Substation Bulletin No. IT. are indicated for oats, barley, and spring wheat from disking than from either spring or fall plowing. The lower cost of seed bed preparation by disking makes this method somewhat more profit - able, however. " f I Previous crop Yield per acre I-T-: — I Yield per acre Preparation of seedbed Spring Oats wheat Barley Oats Spring wheat Barley Fall plowed Corn Oats Wheat Spring wheat Barley Average Bushels Bushels Bushels 12.0 20.7 11.1 11.7 . 17.1 . 15.4 17.1 17.7 11.6 Spring plowed DUked [ Corn Oats Wheat - Spring wheat Barley Sorghum Average Corn 19.6 10.2 16.3 9.6 15.9 12.2 . 19.4 15.8 16.5 10.1 18.5 10.6 15.9 17.9 10.4 13.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 In eastern Nebraska, shallow plowing and thoro double-disk - ing are regarded as equally profitable. However, where a large acreage is to be seeded, disking will prove most practical, since the land can be prepared more quickly, thus permitting earlier seeding. 3 Choice of Seed— Early varieties give best results in the average year thruout most of the State. Nebraska No. 21 oats and Burt oats surpass other varieties but are not yet available in large amounts commercially. The common Kherson oats is the best variety that may be secured in large quantities at the present time. Local conditions of soil and climate may, however, make the planting of other varieties desirable. While Kherson and the other early oats are suited especially to fertile soil and to general Nebraska conditions, it may be advisable to select a larger and later variety for the poorer soils of the northern part of the State. 4 Preparation of Seed — Grading or fanning the seed need be practiced only to remove weed seeds and trash when these are present, and in occasional years to remove immature seeds. Treatment to prevent smut is desirable, unless it is positively known that the field in which the seed had been grown was free from smut. The smut is carried over from one crop to the next on the exterior of the seed. This may be prevented by the form - alin treatment as follows: Add commercial formalin (40 per cent solution of formaldehyde) to water in the proportion of 1 pound to 40 gallons of water. If made too strong, the viability of the seed will be impaired. Pile the seed upon a granary floor or similar place. Apply the formalin solution at the rate of about 3 quarts to 1 bushel of seed. During the application the pile should be thoroly scooped in order to dampen all the seed. Then cover the seed with empty bags or blankets for several hours or over night. Uncover and spread the oats out thin, and dry rapidly, stirring them occasionally. Replacing them in bags or other con - tainers infested with oats smut should be avoided. Infected sacks may be used after being dipped into the formaldehyde solution and dried. It may be necessary to adjust the rate of planting to allow for swelling of the seed caused by the moisture. If sown with an end-gate seeder, the oats need not be dried before seeding, altho with a grain drill this is necessary since damp oats do not feed well thru a drill. 5 Seeding — Oats may be sown either broadcast or with a drill. The customary farm practice in eastern Nebraska is to seed oats and other spring small grain crops broadcast. Whether this practice can be followed with profit, however, depends largely upon soil and climatic conditions, while drilling is a more standard method and can always be used safely. Table 27 contains yields </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Oats Investigations 45 Table 27 — Yields from drilled and broadcast oats, spring wheat, barley, emmer, and winter wheat. Four-year average 1 North Platte data (4-year average) (4-yr. av.) Method of planting Spring I . ~ Winter n Winter Oats w heat Barley Emmer wheat' &lt;&gt;*** w h ea t Bushels Bushels Bushels I Bushels I Bushels Bushels Bushels Drilled 40.1 16.3 16.5 35.0 20.6 57.9 38.2 Broadcast 31.4 10.5 9.2 26.1 9.7 58.8 38.2 Increase fromdrilling 8.7 5.8 7.3 8.9 10.9 —.9 .0 ■Data compiled from Nebraska North Platte Substation Bulletin No. 12, were secured in 1908, 1909, 1911 and 1913. The data compiled from Nebraska Bulleli.i No. 104 were secured in 1900. 1903, 1905 and 1906. Three-year average. secured both at North Platte and Lincoln, for the two methods of seeding. Drilling has proved much superior under the conditions at North Platte, whereas the yields were approximately equal for the two methods at Lincoln. It is reasonable that drilling should be relatively more favorable in the central and western parts of the State where soil moisture conditions are commonly less favorable for early growth. Oats planted with a press drill are placed uniformly in a more moist and more compact soil than is the case with broadcasting, and this gives a more certain and uniform germination. These considerations are not so important under the more favorable moisture conditions of eastern Nebraska. The better the seed bed preparation and the more favorable the soil moisture conditions, the smaller will be the difference in yield between drilled and broadcast oats. The most satisfactory rate of planting small seeded varieties is 2.5 to 3 bushels per acre for eastern Nebraska. Three bushels per acre is a very satisfactory rate for varieties having large seeds. These amounts may be somewhat reduced in central and western Nebraska, because of less favorable moisture conditions. 6 Harvesting — If the oats straw is to be used for feed, the crop should be harvested a day or two before being fully ripe, and while the straw is still slightly green. In order to insure the best quality of grain and the highest feeding value of the straw, the crop should be stacked as soon as the oats are dried out after cutting and shocking. The shape of the shock is also of more or less importance. If the oats straw is green when harvested or if large weeds are abundant or if the weather is not favorable for drying, the long type of shock is best. Otherwise, the ordinary round shock is satisfactory. The long shocks should usually be built north and south as this protects the bundles somewhat from </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 heavy rains, and exposes both sides of the shock to the sun and wind. Another important factor is to carefully stack the straw pile, as oat straw makes very good feed. SUBSTITUTE CROPS FOR OATS Spring Wheat — Spring wheat and spring barley are the two most satisfactory substitute crops for oats. Spring wheat should commonly be seeded before oats, and as early as the soil can be worked in the spring. The most satisfactory practice is to drill in fall plowed land or on disked corn ground. The usual rate of seeding is 6 pecks per acre for the eastern part of the state and 4 pecks for the western part. This crop is poorly adapted to the climatic conditions of the greater part of Nebraska because of late maturity, and it is far more subject to drouth, heat, rust, and chinch bugs than is winter wheat. At Lincoln spring wheat has produced approximately only half as great yields as winter wheat. Table 28 contains the results with eight varieties of spring wheat tested from 3 to 6 years in duplicate 1/30-acre field plats. The spring wheat varieties now grown in this State under the names of Swedish, Scotch Fife, and Early Java are probably the best suited for the greater portion of the State. Altho Marquis wheat, imported in 1911 from Canada, has given a slightly higher yield at the Experiment Station, the quality of grain has been somewhat inferior because of excessive shriveling with consequent light weight per bushel. The 6-year average for the three highest yielding varieties of spring wheat has been 17.1 bushels or 1,026 pounds per acre, as compared with 55.5 bushels or 1,776 pounds for Kherson oats.. Barley — Experience has taught that varieties of the bearded 6-row type of spring barley yield most in our climate. The common 6-row barley, Oderbrucker, Odessa, and Manchurian are of this type. Barley is not so easily damaged by heat and dry weather as are oats, and for this reason it is customary to seed this crop immediately after oats planting. The method of seed bed prepa - ration and of planting are essentially the same as for oats and spring wheat. The ordinary rate of seeding in eastern Nebraska is about 2 bushels per acre. The rate recommended for the drier sections of the state is 1.5 to 2 bushels. The relative yields of barley, oats, and several other small grain crops during the 4-year period, 1907 to 1910, are given in table 29. Kherson oats yielded 20 per cent less grain than Oder - brucker barley, while Turkey Red winter wheat yielded 20 per </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Oats Investigations 47 ■■c -- - — 1 » 3iO "WM ■» 3 o 00 -^ O tC O « 00 « 9- = S 5 I. If. I 3-. •esnoos I a § S o&gt; 5 «VO4OOt - *5 3 i 10 •7: 05 a 1 "5 _^o -^o 00 S3 :5S :SS » !»os I T-H W Jootc 3 *h 1-1 «5 I: &lt;? IlII « ?5 5 - 2 :5 I ;1 : i : sen 6 1 •« ■3 3_g?lfe* 0 !r hafc* 5** &amp;• x. a) 5r a* s,. a* a- Illllli £.2 £.= a 5.2 ! en .mo i- 3SO O'* ■» oj *~* jj i-t t- to oo t*- oo f-j *-; fc3 « ao oi t&gt; «&gt; i&gt; t-^ «o oi ui en a-i : «9&gt; : « 8.2 -s go 25 2! °- *i '~"~ l *T "*! "I "i 2 *~ S (35 oo id t-^ id •* •fll id ■* i~ oi o&gt; § « ~ ■» =| ~ »8 .2 g oo « SW»« ' -00 * S.0. 0 S3 1«jt^^: : : : : :^i «e g - c 2 ~ I""" ; ; ; ; r I 1^ — . . . . . &amp; 2 |S23 : : : : :SS ~~ :::::: •$ "-" S«J&lt;o "o * — KtOlO '.'.'.'.'. .00 » _ — . en &amp; sis s * * * °* *&gt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 160 cent more. Altho barley gives a greater grain yield, oats straw has a greater value than barley straw, and the crop is also much more pleasant to handle during harvest and threshing. The oats grain also has a special feeding value for horses. Winter Oats — Winter oats have proved unhardy and in most seasons have entirely winterkilled. Winter Barley — Winter barley also lacks in hardiness, and for this reason it is an unsafe and unsatisfactory crop. In those years when it survives the winter, it ripens two weeks earlier than common barley and yields considerably more. The development of a hardy strain of winter barley would doubtless be a valuable achievement. In 1910, only 220 plants survived on a $ acre plat of winter barley. It was thought that these plants had perhaps survived because of special hardiness. Consequently, they were harvested individually and planted in separate nursery rows for the purpose of further selection for hardiness. A good growth was secured in the fall, but every plant winterkilled. Sufficient seed had been retained from each plant for seeding a second time in the fall of 1911. This again entirely winterkilled. Winter Emmer — This crop has proved to be less hardy than Turkey Red winter wheat and its value in Nebraska is doubtful. The method of planting is the same as for winter wheat, except the rate of planting, which should be about 2 bushels per acre. [6-18-17— 17M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>