<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Winter Wheat in Western Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1922-02">1922-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 February, 192: Bulletin IT 1 Winter Wheat in Western Nebraska I.. L. ZOOK Bulletin No. 2S of the North Platte Experimental Substation 1' Snyder. Superintendent K A. Burnett. Director WINTER WHEAT FOLLOWING CORN SORTH PI ATTE EXPERIMENTAL SUBSTATION M.KKl LTl KAL KXPEK1MENT STATION THE INIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LTNCOTA' </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS {"4 Summary Introduction Climatic Condition* Plan and Scope of Invert ipationK Seed Bed Preparation Experimental Results Manner of Comparing Brauli Continuous Cropping of Winter Wl Winter Wheat Following Corn. }&gt; Continuous Cropping versa- Kotatioi Winter Wheat Follo\vin«r Kumner Tillage ill ( ... u Summer Tillage vcimis Continue Winter Wheat i rit|&gt;|ni Summer Tillage versus Rotation v Growing Winter Wheat 1 &lt; (Jreen Manuring for Winter Wh Effect of Different Cropping Systems mi S Comparisons &lt;»f Winter Wheat Ynrietie- M(Mn1 III Sources of J)ai;i </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY 1. In l&gt;oth acreage and product ion, winter wheat is one of ending crops for a large section of western Nebraska. '2. Experimental results with winter wheat are presented from four stations: North Platte and Scottsbluff, Nebraska; Akron. Colorado; and Ardmore. South Dakota. :i. The chief limiting factor in crop production in western Nebraska is insufficient and variable rainfall. Winter wheat, by making the greater part bf its growth during the period of irreatest average rainfall and before the time of greatest evapo - ration losses, adapts itself lietter than many other crops to the and efficient use of the moisture available. 1. Comparisons are made of four tillage practices: (a) inuous cropping to winter wheat. (b"&gt; Winter wheat alter- ag with corn, (e) Winter wheat on summer tilled ground. Winter wheat on land upon which rye or peas had been ■ lowed under for green manure. Lowest average yields per acre, at all stations, were se - oin continuous cropping. Good yields of wheat, following corn, have been secured stations. CoaaWleriiig the value of the corn crop and the low cost uction. the most profitable yields of wheat have been blowing corn. The highest yields per acre have been those following \1 three of four stations less total wheat has been pro need by summer tilling half of the land than by continuous popping of all the land to wheat. 10. Allowing for sax ings in seed, and for savings in seeding md harvesting costs from summer tilling, the average profits roin simiiner tilling and continuous cropping to wheat have ieen about equal. 11. Higher yields per acre of xvinter wheat have been se - .ured after summer tillage than after corn; but allowing for the value of the corn produced, the most economical yields have been those following corn. 12. Averaging the results from all tests at all stations, in i-omparing the yield of wheat produced by summer tillage with </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Kxi-krimknt Station Rii.i.kttn 17!' I I r that produced by wheat following corn, each additional bush*' produced under summer tillage cost an equivalent of 4.9 bushel of corn produced under the corn-wheat rotation. 18. Plowing under rye or peas for preen manure failed t increase average yields over ihose following summer tillage, an proved to be the least profitable of the methods under trial. 14. The average soil moisture content in the spring \va greater following summer tillage than following either corn &lt;&lt; »»at, and greater following corn than following wheat. Thes erences are the chief MOW of yield variations between th various methods. IS. In tests of winter wlieal vaiict h-s at North IMattc an Akron. the most |&gt;ri)inisiny variety luis 1 n Kanrerl </seg>
            <seg id="p005">WINTER WHEAT IN WESTERN NEBRASKA L. L. ZOOK 1 INTRODUCTION Of the approximately three and one-third million acres used for the growing of wheat annually in the State of Nebraska, about one and one-half million acres or nearly two-fifths of the total is included in the 37 counties which lie west of the 99th meridian. 5 The ratio of the winter wheat to the spring wheat aereaf.'.' in this territory is a little less than four to one. The corn acreage is about 150 per cent of the winter wheat acreage. With this exception the winter wheat acreage exceeds that of any other single crop, and more than exceeds the combined acreage of spring wheat, rye, barley, and oats. In the sand hill region which occupies a large section of western Nebraska, rye is mart largely grown than wheat. West and north of the sand hill region spring wheat still predominates over winter wheat in acreage ami production. In the territory between the sand nills and the south line of the State and west to include the three south counties of the panhandle, the normal winter wheat crop occupies over one million acres and is exceeded by the corn crop by only about 20 per cent. In Deuel and Cheyenne coun - ties the present winter wheat acreage is over three times that of corn. The position occupied by winter wheat in western Nebraska has been gained within a period of 25 years. At the beginning of this time the crop was but little grown. Its culture is now well established. It is likely that it will supplant spring wheat in still greater areas. Its culture has been particularly successful on new land, and in some newly developed areas it has been and is almost the only crop grown. Continuous cropping has usually resulted in diminishing yields and in the older sections the prac - tice has given way to the introduction of other crops and the adoption to some extent of rotation methods. Experimental re - sults from continuous cropping, rotating with corn, alternating with fallow, and the effects of plowing under peas or rye for green manure are presented in this bulletin. SOURCES OF DATA The experimental results with winter wheat reported in thin bulletin are from four stations. The locations of these arc ■Agronomist, University of Nebraska Experimental Substation. North Platte. Ne - braska; Physiologist. Offlee of Dry Land Agriculture. Bureau of Plant Industry. United States Department of Agriculture. •Compiled from Nebraska State Board of Agriculture Bulletin. No. 274. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nkbraska Exi'kkimkxt Station Bulletin 17'.' shown iii Figure 1. They are near tin 1 towns of North 1 Scottsbluff. Nebraska; Akron, Colorado; ;m&lt;l Anb Dakota. The stations outside of tin- S Dakota. The stations outside of the State are M el conditions repretnted »re nimilar to thus,, of ady within the Stat«-. At tlic two Nebraska stationx the work I cooperatively between the Nebraska Experim&lt; the Office of Dry Land Agriculture of the I ) incut of Agriculture. The utationx ;it Al i Ardmore. South Dakota, arc o| lied hv the ( it! Agriculture. The data from tl thru the courtesy of the official in chart men in char-re of the stations 'Members of the staff of the Offici- of Dry-Land Agriculture who have contributed to this bulletin by the supplying of (hi tions are E. C. Chilcott. Acrirulturist in Charge, and John S. Cole. Agriculturist Washington. D. C. ; Clarence Harris. SrottsblufT. Nebraska : J F. Brandon. Akron Colorado ; and F. L. Kelso. Ardmore. South Dakota. The following men have been ir charge of the work at the various stations at some time during its mh; W W Kami W. M. Osborn. Nnrth Platte. Nebraska: M. Pfaender. J. H. Jacol son. and enbrug. ScottsblufT, Nebraska : O. J. Grace. Akron, Colorado. Acknowledgment is also made to J. A. Clark, of the Office of Cereal Investiga tions. Bureau of Plant Industry, for the supplying of varietal data from the Akron </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Winter Wheat in Western Nebraska 7 CLIMATIC CONDITIONS chief factor limiting (.Top production in the western Nebraska is the limited and varying amount of annual d its uncertain seasonal distribution. In the case of actor of uncertain winter survival is an im- ,\ Winterkilling in this section is usually associated moisture conditions and seldom occurs when ire favorable. A high winter survival is isual result of sufficient moisture in the fall to give the start, followed by sufficient winter and spring tat ion to prevent soil blowing. Under these conditions of ow temperatWM usually do not cause injury. Mid, severe winterkilling usually occurs during winters, regardless of whether the prevailing tempera low or high. lieating the limits of average annual precipitation rvals are shown on the map. Figure 1. From irs that the average annual rainfall for the western ate range* from 21 to '2'2 inches in the extrem* ictwrrn 15 and lli inches in the extreme southwest, normal monthly and annual rainfall for each station, as he longest record available at a near-by \Yealn«»r station: the average monthly and annual rainfall at for the years of the winter wheat experiments re- monthly and annual records for the lowest and years at each station are shown in Table 1. The average d total evaporation for the six months from April to naive, at eaea station for the period of the ex meiits reported, monthly and total evaporation for the high- the total precipitation for the correspond- lie ratio of total evaporation to precipitation Tab! \ itmdy of these data shows that the winter months an precipitation, and that there is a pro - inir advances until the highest point is lirementa of the crop are slight during the winter, and early spring. From the time the plants begin t from thf first to the third week &lt;&gt;f May, the iilirements of tht rop are very heavy. Without a plentiful supply of moisture during this period either from niins or from previous storage in the soil, good yields cannot be prqjaeed. This is the time of the year of highest normal rain- fall in western Nebraska. Table 2 indicates that it is also before the time of highest evaporation. The ratio between </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nki'.raska Kxi'khimkm Station Bii.i.ktin 17h 8 II 7 I* M a •S&amp;5 to** Use I g 00 CO 00 CM C WO i&lt;f«5 &lt; -«l»- II _e __ 5* I ON 03 t- jl jj II «O05 5C C S3 —• O 3C O". O (j o. usoi o-^; I-H g 3 1 »■* -t i Eh « ioco WO I ►H C Ji c,| ( - — • l-j I] CO O5 &gt;» || ew I o^ S a| «•• «« - k 511 I fc2 •&lt; MM M si S3 qij _o O CO P&lt;*N ■g ■»» -30 | fa "' ' I ! -» I : ; ~ I A ji. I "* « &gt;o&lt;o g 1 -I 2 I s E it I! If II iOKD — CO 'I t ~. kO . ! II t- 1~ i o m II — | — II t-; ua o a-. ■ ' II O t~ — io '' I II £ SI X X» O O ~ rr t- m : H- TC? — 00 ■■ ?i ri •"* I 3". t- as "3 I ri r i -^ — ■ a o tc ,' — -r — rr — ■■£ o cc i- x &gt;n -'I ' t- t- s re t-;M IOO || !o ' ' ' 1 3 ; ; i ! ■&amp; 22 | ' g ~~ GO :? Eg — « 3 3 is .§.§ Illl : icoc I xu ii &lt;c t = — • ON Bt- I «e us co 3&gt; n ox in so Olt- O«5 ISO 1O-* lO'* IOCS | ■VO «5«S g t-^h us Q r? co mm fc COOJ OO "t~ 1O00 OX S| ■*— X Tl t-» SKoo oso -wo 5 ■^•7^ iflf i! ?C IO O CD [^ men x ~i ajai c-;cvi " -In » ' wi M j S§ 1 83 j §g 3§3 n 7i en 3-. t- I oi- i § O_ i - ~J ~ ,| &lt;O — — t- JJ c-4 — c-i csioi I — -h I t^ 9S 30 || rc Tl t- O i ? ci-H ?i^ co?j K 1 = X 9 ?1 || so &lt;£ -; ?j i I ! ore t~oo! iooo cr-3; on ejn I oio — io j ': 3 ■ — '* no at- o j&gt; • JIT — O 3!«5 So 3 ~* o — • *r n x oc -£ J s 32 i2g I sa ss g - ' ' " ' i I I ■ 2 ,y i i — O-* 1 g ■ , oe 2 ; : g 22 •&lt; ■ ff 22 i J f3 E J ii ' it s:s i?. s:s ' ;: 2 : * is f ( z :| ill - 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Wjmkk Whk.vi is Westkrn Nebraska 9 JOUBJldl.MJli uon^odBAa S2g jg£§ il g«g I g^gi X las-mtiv SS3 2SS i SS3 i| 2§5 «*s , to-a ma-9 xooS t^^"00 t-M« M » M ■*«O50;| «&gt;»M ,; TOTrrs j5 uat~o: ow^! uitJua V. H M as at — t- t- a&gt; us ij w * us r~ oo id z a: t- »W • wt-US 'i t-x«O »3&gt;iO 2IS2E'! 2E«f:' P??» o5»i5 ~3of? S»r, 5S3 tO-W IOIOt» «&gt;t-»O 1 COt-IO /■ P 5C e s &gt;&gt; ? X R t 3&gt; Ol I — 35 31 _" 9191 "2 : E e :hs : B a | :Eg -s5 5 :■ 2 Ul mrnM m I "83 Illl 111! Ill &lt;^s ba3 «? -: &lt;=: &lt;*&gt;"?=&gt;!! *■**■: ,i °&gt;^^ jjb^j ci^^i oJW-^ rj&lt;o— I |j d^ri i l.i. U.I ui &lt;m t^ ■*» ai so Nt-^ai S§£ 53= ,; ££S £»£ macs «o — oo ooosus 3&gt;t-se x&gt; &lt;o « «=►-:« "*'? : * »»?? </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 • ' Kit K A .** K A fj \I r.HI MF.NT i*l II *r. I IN 1 1 «* r oration and precipitation is lower than in later months summer, and the precipitation is therefore of niaxiini value to the erop. Total failure of winter wheel from lad moisture daring the growing season is of rare occurrence. On the other hand, a shortage of moisture with consequent tion of yield is of frequent occurrence. The normal preei| tion is barely sufficient to produce a full erop and t are very rare when upland soils bearing winter v completely exhausted of available moisture l&gt;y harvest tim At all stations tin- precipitation of the maximum jreai been more than double that of the minimum year. \ in evaporation are only slightly xtn-nn oration tends to tie high when precipitation is low, the ra between evaporation and precip v to year. The BTerage seasonal evaporation I three times the average seasonal nrecipitatio The minimum ratio has been 'J.nii at North l'latte and 1 the other stations. At Rcottsbluff in 1919 "&gt;.4'i tunes the precipitation. A ti occurred when the evaporation was more than fow tir precipitation. It appear*, then fails to survive the winter, ai account of moisture limitations, winter wheat amonir the crops lust adapted Wlirask PLAN AND SCOPE OF INVESTIGATIONS Investigations of the problem carried on along the same general lin t which the results with winter wheat ai letin. The standard crops are grown in rota lengths and l&gt;y different methods of preparation ni of continuous cropping. In this bulletin the rotations are noi discussed as units, and the results with other crops are given only for comparison with winter wheat or where they are defi nitely related to the production of winter wheat. The effects of tillage practices or the influence of previous crops are given consideration only for the season which immediately precedes the growing of winter wheat. The plats at all the stations are one-tenth acre in size Their dimensions are 2 by S rods. The plats are separated by cultivated alleys about 4 feet in width. The arrangement of rotations at the North Platte station, and the location of winter wheat plats for 1920 are shown in Figure '2. Where winter wheat </seg>
            <seg id="p011">WlXTKK WllKAT IN WksTKRN NEBRASKA 11 ntation with other crops the crop by which it is •Tow preceded in the rotation is ;ilso shown. The arrangement of other stations is sufficiently similar to that at North I'latte so that tin' diagram will serve to illustrate the plan PL A TTE PROJECT HELD 49. A VI STL n m is t » ( At North Platte, winter wheat has l&gt;eeu grown on 25 plats or !* years; at Akron, on 17 plats for 11 years; at Seottsbluff, on !t ]&gt;lats for !&gt; years; and at Ardmore, on 12 plats for 8 years. The ivsults reported aggregate '.M station years and involve an aggregate of 599 plat years. Results of winter wheat varietal t«ata at North Platte and a comparison between Kharkov and Kanred wheat at Akron are also given. The present study of tillage practices with winter wheat is confined chiefly to comparisons of four methods. These are: 1. Winter wheat grown continuously. At North Platte, winter wheat yields from three rotations in which the crop follows oats are grouped with the yields of plats continuously cropped to wheat. As the average yields after oats and from continuous cropping of wheat are about the same, this arrangement does not materially affect results, g. Winter wheat following corn. In some cases the two crops alternate in two-year rotations. In : , : •i l» | Id L B K &gt; m m r A g D « IT . 1 I* 1 ji- t' M| ' : I. »-«^ I ' t w "^1 If"" I Ig '•— » J •_ n '•— " 1c ■■■ " I p-— » ■„ c o_ f •■«" U 1 lT = » If" ■ K* L' M' II' 0' P r '•- . F n [ • VrtUI 1 .9.TIU ' " \ Wi r- ■ 7- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 .&gt; KBRASKA KXPKRIMENT STATION Bl'LLETIX Ii9 ' other cases wheat follows corn in rotations of greater Imgtl 3. Winter wheat alternating witii summer tillage or following summer tillage in longer rotations. 4. Winter wheat follow ui&lt; rye or peas plowed under for green manure in rotations of four year length in which the other crops are corn and oats. SEED BED PREPARATION At North Platte two of the plats following oats art- pr. pared for winter wheat seeding by disking only. The oth oats plat is disked and fall plowed. Of the plats whu wiiit.-r wheat continuously, two aiv early fall plowed an.l -r — m — - — ~ — — j -~ plowed and another late fall plowed. At the latter two | the third plat is plowed and rabaoiled and the foartl prepared by early listing and 1 veling the lai before seeding. At North Platte where wheat has followed w small grain, small increases liav resulted fr Disked stubble has also produced yields lomewha those secured on pl*wed ground. 1 Similar resul secured at the other three stations. At Hays, K ever, where the rainfall is greater and the season longer there is time for a more effective fallow betwei fall seeding, marked iwitM suited from early plowing ai in winter w stubble land. In parts of western Nebraska, wher Platte and Hays are about equal, it is lit from early and late plowing somewhat intermedia we those secured at the two stations could be ex present study all plats following wheat or other grouped together, for each station, irrespective ( 1 seed bed preparation. (Where wheat follows corn the land has been in most case pared by disking after the corn was cut and removed, li le cases the wheat was seeded between the rows with a on ■se drill before the corn was cut. In all cases the cornstalk re removed from the ground either before or after seedinc this method has had no advantage over the others in a win cover which would hold snow. ■ 'Winter Wheat Seed-Bed Preparation. Nebraska Experimental Station Bullet r Bein» published as "Methods of Grow in* Winter Wheat at Han. Kansas." U. S Department of Agriculture Bulletin by John S. Cole and A. L. HalUted. tfall plowed. At Scottsbluff. Akron, and Ardinorc. tme &lt; plats which fiww winter wheat ciintinuously is early fa </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Wintkr Wheat in Western Nebraska 13 The fallow- or summer tilled plats were given sufficient cul - vation thru the season to keep down weed growth. This is isually accomplished by one or two spring or early summer Ifckiagt, and one plowing about midsummer, followed bv one era*] harrowintrs bcfate seeding time. Occasionally, when plowing has boon somewhat early and heavv rains had oc- the disk after plowing or even a second plow- tig has been necessary to keep down weed growth and to pre - &gt;are a pood seed bed. The green manure crops are plowed under about the time mrtly before the seed is sufficiently well formed to germi- iate. At North Platte and Akron this is usually by June 15 or rye. and 15 to 20 days later for peas. At the other stations ime is a little later. After plowinpr, these plats are treated MM as the fallow plats: that is, they arc (riven sufficient n to keep down weed growth. EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS Fhe annual and average yields in bushels per acre from of the cropping systems for the terms of years during li the work has been in progress at each station are shown \v Table 3. Yields from single plats of winter wheat following atoes and weedy fallow at North Platte are also shown. Graphic comparisons of the yields secured from each of the four methods at the different stations are shown in Figures 3 to 6 inclusive. The average yields from each method at each sta- are shown in Figure 7. The largest differences in yields at all stations are those ■d by seasonal variations. The maximum yield from anv nethod at any station has been at least four times the minimum field. In the 37 station years represented, the average yield from all methods has been below 10 bushels per acre 13 times and above 20 bushels per acre 12 times. The fluctuations are not as great from some methods as from others, but the same tendency for wide vield differences to occur from vear to year is apparent in all. fhe fluctuations resulting from seasonal variations must be recognized as normal conditions and it is not to be expected that they can be overcome in extreme cases by any method or system of tillage. The effects of cultural treatments are most apparent in those years when normal or average conditions are approached. Following unfavorable winter conditions or pro - longed drouth during the growing season, total failure or very low yields result from all methods. Under extremely favorable </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Kxi-kki mkm Station Bii.i.ktix 17'.» Sc — CCtOiO — H — it- lOt-ON 5C t-t-SOO i &gt; lOOJ — N t- 00 90 "'- I N« t- — — — — — M N — £ •2 £ 1 * t( ;"?^9 a&lt; !|«|| 1 o&lt;»«o&gt;!eii! l of&gt;«o&lt;o!— rejiase* I t- "S §&gt; £ X 25 ?;??!*: H «■"• fr&gt; i "* H « ■»!-*-« id » -«;n — — mo a; ;e — ri ri x; ■«■ 3-. 3: in 1- 10x1010 -1 -^ « b r. &lt; 15 2 ft m — -MM - -MM- - — MW — — MN— 0) *•■ 5; n x io Co ~ ~ te naNxi te = i =■. 1 - — i-«xe n § • f » K ••5555 •• * I * S" » HeiiV ri II -&lt;r ad o -w t-^ §" ~ * k i *!' fl : t ~ x . "■ *! '- — ~ ~ ~* • xa: — tc S r: — tc^ ec « a.S3 2£f;?S-- 9 u ''o-»-« : K««jtox c -6-In - 2 1 rr:;i;.-r - ?1 -m -j _ ~, _ -, ~ ri ?i ~ ~ ~ - v 2 ■* °S xonc«x te x t- o — ic -r •§ S --=o t -^ sfssaa ?i ==== = * 01 tc X to h- *r 3:^t^cc xiot'tc m V 5 •* « j? 3J -t r? «|lO&gt;&lt;Ma t- 1 — ' c x 1- 1- I ;;;; - _2_ ■838-" s|88$g = 1[ »t2SJ= 2 j ; &gt;. P j: tt t- ~ t» lot- j- O» " J£ J? s: -t r? n ~ — m as t- i — ' c x i- i-:«ccc; c = !r i C § ? »- * l-a 5 °— J 1 ' — - 3 a i Z -&lt; t "■ e i 5 &lt; ? 9-«- g l ! it I s ii - ii - it H 5 BI .?£ f • fc 6 J g fi i-2 f Ijllll jili ill lii c - ■ i g 1 * p a &lt; /. &lt;• Bn t^q»o^i -^ a: r^ a: o x cc cc 3i </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 WlNTKK WllKAT IN WkSTKRN XkHRASKA NORTH PLflTTE N€BR j 71 »lifiit from four cropping systems at to l^-'H UU-illMVe. Ncl.r.. Ill usture cuiulitions good yit'ltls result fn.m all methods. Under rniiil eonditiona of &gt;li-rlitly deficient moisture, intermittent drouth. »ti-.. dittereiicts in yield ilue to t praetieea are frequently quite pronounced. MANNER OF COMPARING RESULTS The profit or loss from any method ohviously depends upon the relations whieh exist hetw.Vn cost of produetion. yields, and crop values. On aeeount of the wide fillet nations whieh hav: - eeeurred in eo«ta of produetion and erop values in reeent years. no attempt is Bade in the present study to MBga definite values to those factor*. The different methods are compared, primarily on the basis of relative yields. Those methods are considered most profitable whieh have produeed the highest average yields or produced the highest yields the greatest number of times after taking into consideration the differences in the amount of land involved, seed costs, and the relative values of wheat and anv other crops grown. 1915 fib lit! Ifl8 1919 1920 OWING SVHEAT OR OAT5 Hv£RA6L 0f£Pl/1T4 CORN " " 1 * SUMMER TILLAGE " 4 Gl?££tt A/M/VUBE CflOPS " " 2 " difference! in jrield due t&lt;. .linVn-nc.-s in t-ultural </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nk.HRASKA Kxi'KltlMKM STATION Bl 1.1.KT1X 170 - -Compar;iti\f .mr I Thus in n— paring Um eoatinuous cropping growing of wlieat in alternation with suimi lod is considered most profitable which ha : wheat eonsiderinp the total ;irr;t involved a n ences in seeding and harvesting MSta In comparing the growing of wheat alter A mer tillage and the growing of wheat alternating wit Inmer tillage method in order 'ield of wlieat sufficiently largt make up for the value of the to yield a profit must p r than the yield followin corn prodoeed. Ijhe green manure practice in order to be profitable n tluce yields sufficiently large to make up for the loss of tl [ while the green manure crop is beinjr jrrown and to cov( other costs involved. LEach practice is discussed separately and detailed eompan made between them in the following pages of this bulletin CONTINUOUS CROPPING OF WINTER WHEAT tThe growing of any one crop continuously on the saim nd for an extended period is generally regarded as a poor tice. It is a matter of common observation that large yields </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Win IKK Whk.vi in Western Nebraska 17 at from four cropptng systems \. at wheat iirr M'l-nrt'd on land immediately after the sod i* brokea and that there is a tendency for the yields of the sui-- eeeding i-r(i|&gt;s to decrease. This is commonly attributed to de - creased fertility. In humid sections this is without doubt the chief cause. In regions of limited rainfall another factor plays an important part. This is the amount of soil moisture availa - ble for plant growth. In western Nebraska this si-ems to be the chief factor limiting wheat yields where the crop is &lt;rro\vn con - tinuously, or where wheat follows other small prain. Ak shown in Table ;{, and in Figure 7, the continuous crop - ping, or wheat following wheat Method, lias •riven the lowest average yield of any of the four methods under trial at the four stations. At North PlattC the !l-year average following wheat or oats is 4.'{ bushels per acre less than that following corn, and 6.0 bushels less than That following summer tillage. At Akron the 11 year avenge following wheat is 4.&lt;i bushels per acre less than from wheat following corn and 9.7 bushels per acre less </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Billetin 179 18 than from that following suinniiT tillage. At Seottabluff tin 9-j-ear average following wheat is 1:1 buahda j&gt;«-r men Im thai that following corn anil 1"J.."&gt; bushels per men Vem than that fol lowing summer tillage. At Ardmore the "year average follow ingr wheat is ."&gt; Imshcls pet acre I«H than that following con and 7.9 bushels per acre less than th.it following summer tillage In a total of 35 comparisons, excluding the years of lotal failure of all methods at Ardmorc. the yields of wheat follow ing wheat or oats have exceeded the yields following corn only five times, and the yields following summer tillage only oner The latter ease was at North Plattc in lflS when the crop fol lowing summer tillage was very hadly lodjred. The yields following winter wheat or oats have been less than half of those following summer tillage lti times, and more than half 19 times. The yields of wheat following wheat have averaged 78 per cent at North Plattc. 71 per cent at Akron, 47 per cent at Scottsbluff, and 7ti per cent at Ardmore, of the yields following corn, and 72, ."&gt;4. ."i4. and 67 per cent of the yields following summer tillajrc at the four stations, respectively. f\ RDMORE so 6UiHlLS PER ACHE 35 JO rkd- "5 i* r 1 — I -i *^H I i m : ■ ■ M_ zo mm #■4 : IS t I ji |i H I :: = It — u Q ~i 1 I I:: I i rl ' j J 1 1 H/J /**/4 1*15 IJlo 11(1 &gt;♦»( )■?/&lt;) /9.?0 [ I WH f»T FOIL 0WIN6 VVME/IT ■ikfRlUSC C E§£3J •■ " CORN ■^^ " 5(JWM[RTIU«6C UUUUU1U " O»f[N M««UBt CHOPS « PLin 3 2 FlC 6.- - ( omparative a] vie </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Wixtkk Wheat is \\'k-iki:n Nkhkaska 19 Fig. 7. — Comparative average yiekls of winter wheat from four cropping systems at four stations The relative economy of the continuous cropping and sum - mer tillage methods will be discussed more fully under the heading of. "Winter Wheat following Summer Tillage 1 ' and "Summer Tillage vs. Continuous Cropping"; while the effects of continuous cropping upon soil moisture will be taken up </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Hi i.i.etiji 179 20 under the heading. "Effects of Different Cropping System? upon Soil Moisture." WINTER WHEAT FOLLOWING CORN The practice of growing winter wheat after corn is a com mon one in much of the winter wheat growing territory in the western part of Nebraska. Corn in this part of the State makes a shorter stalk growth than it does farther east. The stalks m uplands usually stand up well enough so that wheat can b&lt; drilled between the rows without much injury to the sore. Where corn is kept free from weeds, seeding between the rows is one of the most satisfactory and economical methods of ieed ing winter wheat. t Winter wheat yields have averaged materially higher at til 1 stations where the crop follows corn than where it follow* at or other small grain. The average yields following eoru e been less than those following summer tillage at all sta s. The differences are not great, however; and MMtderiag value of the corn crop, the practice of growing wheat in rnation with corn is more profitable than that of growing at in alternation with summer tillage. The avenge yield jwinp corn has been above that following green manure at stations and below that following green manure at th&lt; other two stations. In the 35 comparisons at the four statioi I tie 3, the yields of winter wheat following corn have beei ater than those following wheat or other small fimia '&gt;0 es and greater than those following summer tillage 7 tines. North Platte the average wheat yield following corn has n 128 per cent of that fallowing wheat, and !»li per cent of t following summer tillage. At Akron the percentages be en the same methods were, respectively. 140 and 7t&gt; : at ttsbluff, 211 and 72; and at Ardmore. 132 and 88. A&gt; pr&gt; - jsly stated, the experimental yields here reported are for the &gt;t part from seedings made after the corn was removed. In cases the stalks were removed during the fall either before after seeding. The increases in yield secured from this hod over those of wheat following wheat and the favorable wing made in comparison with summer tillage are therefore due to increased winter protection and better holding of w by the cornstalks. The differences in yield are thought to due largely to differences in soil moisture, but the moisture erences are due to causes other than catching and holding of W. These differences will he more fullv discussed tinder the </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Wivm; Whkat in Wesikkn Nkbka»k\ 21 heading. • KftVet of Different Moisture." Cropping Systems on Soil CONTIMOIS CHOPPING OF WINTER WHEAT VER818 ROTATION WITH CO«N Whether wheat should he grown eontinuously on the same ground or rotated with eon depends upon the effect of each crop upon the other and whether under the system of farming employed it is possihle to keep a balance in acreage between the The so called "tractor" system of wheat farming, exten - sively used in some parts of western Nebraska, does not lend itself readily to the gumJBg of intertilled crops. It is essen - tially a one crop system, and is well adapted to bringing large acreages quickly under cultivation. It works to the advantage of those non-resident operators who wish to spend a minimum time upon the land, and thus do not wisli to lie ineumbercd with the care of live stock and those things which are necessary in making the farm a place of permanent residence. In those ■MM where all or a major part of the acreage is used for the irrowin&lt;r of wheat, the practice of summer tilling seems to be about the only relief from continuous cropping. On the other hand, where diversified farming is practiced. he question of whether the crops grown shall be rotated or frrown eontinuously is larjrely one of returns to be expected from either method. It would ordinarily be expected that on an acre of land more wheat would be produced by planting all of the land t&lt;&gt; wheat than by planting only half of the land to wheat and the other half to corn. In the experiments here reported this has been true in the greater number of cases, but not in ali. 01 the :{."&gt; station years, the wheat produced on the full acre where wheiit follows wheat exceeded that produced on the half acre where wheat followed corn 24 times, but failed to exceed it 11 times. The it-year average yield of wheat following wheat, at N'orth Platte. is 15.4 bushels per acre. The average yield where wheat followed corn is 19.7 bushels per acre. Since in the rota - tion of corn and wheat only one-half of the land would be in wheat each year, the acre yield of wheat following corn should be divided by two. which gives 9.9 bushels as an average yield on the one-half acre. Therefore, the acre yield of wheat follow - ing wheat exceeded the half-acre yield of wheat following corn bv an average of 5.5 bushels. In the same manner at Akron the 11-year average shows 3.4 bushels more wheat from an acre of wheat following </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Km'kkimkxt Station Hi i.i.ktin Ii'.i I it than was obtained from a half-acre of wheat following At Ardmore, the 7-year average is ."&gt;.:} bushels more at on an acre of wheat following wheat tlum on a half firn wing corn. At 8eottsbluff, the 9-jtmt average half-acre 1 of wheat following corn was actually M bushel more than acre yield following wheat. The average results from the stations for the :{."&gt; crop years show an average annual I of 3.5 bushels more wheat on an acre where wheat follows it than was obtained from a half-acre of wheat following t Since more wheat was usually produced on an acre eon ously cropped to wheat than on tilt' half acre when the land divided between corn and wheat, the value of the corn pro - ?d in the corn-wheat rotation must at least equal the value he additional wheat in continuous cropping, if the returns i the two acres are to be equal. In other words, the raise he corn produced on the half-acre must make up the differ- I 1 in the wheat yield. The annual average acre yield of eorn &gt;wing wheat or other small gram, at tile different stations. liown in Table 5. Dividing the yields by L*. irives the a\'er - half-acre yields of It..") bushels for North Platte. ti.7 for on. 11.6 for Seottshluff. it. 2 bushels for Ardmore and an aver of 9.0 bushels for tin- combined :!."&gt; station years. Compar these half-acre yields of corn with the additional wheat [red by devoting all the land to wheat fives 1.7 bushels of l for each additional bushel of wheat at North Platte, or a 0 of 1 to 1.7. For Akron the ratio is 1 to 2: for Seottsbluff i 0 to 11.0: for Ardmore it is 1 to 1.7. and it is 1 to I'.ti foi stations. In other words, for each bushel of wheat lost b- w totinjr half of the land to eorn, there was produced 1.7 bust of corn at North Platte, '2.0 bushels at Akron, 11.0 bushels t ttsbhiff, 1.7 bushels at Ardmore. and an average of "_'. bushels for all stations. The average farm price per bushel. December 1 I Bureau of Crop Estimates for Nebraska for the 10-year 10d from 1910 to 1910. inclusive, is $1.24 far wheat 'and f4 for corn. On the basis of these prices and the yields se ed in these experiments, average gross returns from an acre wheat continuously cropped compare with those from a half e each of wheat and corn in rotation as follows: .$19.10 to .24 at North Platte. $14.2li to $14.H8 at Akron. |8JI to .67 at Scottsbluff, $19.47 to $UM at Ardmore, and $ir&gt;.00 to .03 for all stations. There is, then, a decided margin in gross returns in favor of rotating wheat and corn over those from continuous cropping </seg>
            <seg id="p023">WlNTKR WllKAT IN Wf&gt;TK»N Nk.BKA-.KA 23 it inn' sTat ion and about equal returns from the two methods at three stations. These returns have been figured on the basis of pram alone. In the case of the wheat-corn rotation, the corn Fodder is also of considerable value where live stock enters into system of farming used. Cost of production as well as gross returns also must be u consideration in determining the relative economy of the thods. Per acre production costs are determined largely amount of work done on the land. In these experiments •cist of growing wheat in rotation with corn lias been less that of continuous cropping of wheat, because for the plowing has been done each year in the greater number In general farm practice, where wheat is drilled between •urn rows no cost of seed bed preparation, previous to drill - is involved. The earn also in a corn-wheat rotation is grown at a low It is usually listed in the wheat stubble after one or two If carefully done at the proper time, two or three in this part of the State, usually keep corn suffi- tly free from weeds so that wheat can be drilled between rows iii the fall without difficulty. It is thus possible to .v the corn crop with but 4 to 6 inexpensive operations. Where wheat alone is grown, cost of seed bed preparation pctiils upon the method employed. Drilling directly into the ibble without previous working of the land can be done at less expense than drilling in cornstalks under the rotation in. Other methods of preparation, such as single or double ng. listing and leveling the ridges, or plowing and packing. preparation costs according to the manner in which they lone and the frequency of their use. As a rule, however. vork is necessary to keep down weed growth and prepare factory seed bed following wheat than following corn. Considering the somewhat higher value of grain produced v rotating wheat and corn, the additional value of stalks or fodder for carrying live stock, the somewhat lower cost of pro - duction, and the better distribution of labor made possible by its use. this system, on tlie whole, seems to be both more profita - ble and more satisfactory than that of growing wheat continu - ously. WINTER WHEAT FOLLOWING SUMMER TILLAGE With the exception of green manuring at North Platte, summer tillage has produced the highest average yields per ncre of all methods at all stations. In the 35 comparisons </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nkhhaska Knpkkiment Station Hi i.i.etix 17 shown in Table 3, the highest yield has followed summer tilluy;' 24 times. The wheat yield following summer tillage lias been exceeded by that following green maiiurt' 7 times, by that fol lowing corn 7 times, by that following wheat only aaee. As a means of increasing per acre yields, summer tillage is the most effective method under trial. The high yields following summei tillage have not been the most profitable in the greatest number of cases, however. I Alternate cropping and summer tilling involves the Im i use of half of the land each year, and makes necessary ti: of twice as much land as is eropped. By summer tillin f of the {rround. only half as much seed is necessary. Alsi y half as mueli area need be covered in seeding and harves With these exceptions the costs of maintaining eroppe I uncropped areas are much the same. On this basis, if pqni aunts of grain are to be produced by the two systems, tl acre yields from summer tillage must be twice those froi tinuous cropping fess one-half the seed used per acre. To \ [ally profitable with continuous cropping, the yields inn imer tillage must be great enough to make up for the lot the unoccupied land after making allowances for the saving in seed, seeding, and harvesting SIMMER TILLAGE VERSl 8 C0NTIM01 8 CROPPING TO WINTER WHEAT In comparing alternate summer tillage with i cropping, allowance must be made for the loss of one-half land under the summer tillage method. Table 4 shows yearly and average half-acre yields following summer tilla&lt;. comparison with acre yields from continuous cropping, and yearly and average train or loss from summer tillage at ea&lt; the four stations. The minus ugn indicates a loss I At North Platte. summer tillage failed in 6 years out of J double the per acre yield from continuous cropping, and the ■rape half-acre yield from summer tillage is 4.7 bushels pei e less than the average acre yields from continuous cropping Counting the year of total failure of all methods from drouth, at Ardmore summer tillage failed to increase production in 5 out of 7 years and the average half-acre yield from summei tillage is 3.9 bushels per acre less than the acre yield from eon tinuous cropping. At Akron, summer tillage produced a gain 5 times and a loss 6 times out of 11 years, and the half-acre average yield from summer tillage is .9 bushel less than the acre yield from continuous cropping. This difference in yield is not siifncientU large to be of significance. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Winter w iikat in Western Nebraska 25 i auiddojo snonuiiuoo ii -fi : t ~:-r a ; i o'o=i"-* l » -• mojj sp[dtA ajoy ' [§ m** &lt;-ie« 1-1 j3b|[u Jdiuuins i- r:xo»3i»&lt;o«x t- Z 2ui.iionoj spiauC wdb-jibh V « </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nf.BK\S!&lt;\ ExnBIMKKl STATION Hi l.l.KTIN 1 ( !• At Scottsbluff. rammer tillage prodaeed a gain in ."&gt; out of b years and Tlu 1 average half tit yield from mm« tillatrt f bushels per acre more than tliat from qq» tUMMHH Cropping In the •{•") comparisons from all the stations, the half-aeri yield following summer tillage exceed* the acre yield from con tinilOUS cropping It) times ami fails to exceed it !!• times. Tl average gain of tli.&gt; l(i cases in which increases resulted from summer tillage is 4:2 bushels per acre. The average loss ft-a.ses in which increases did not occur is G.:i bmmeia per ae The average losses have therefore exceeded tlie avera gains in these cases by 'J.I bushels per acre. The average \al of two bushels of wheat probably about equals the living seed and cultural operations from the summer tillage met On this basis the average gain* from the Ifi cases in which sum mer tillage prodaeed the highe»t yield about equal the a\ losses from the !!• cases in which the yields of summer t fell below those from continuous cropping. Also, by apphll correction of two bushels to the summer tillage yiek comparisons divide themselves as follows; l(i cases in \vl gain of two or more bushels per acre resulted from sumii tillage, 12 cases in which a loss tf two or more bushel and 7 cases in which the differences are not suftii be of significance. The results seem to indicate that, in western Nebr small average differences in production can be ex| the summer tillage and continuous cropping pra A any particular case, however. The fact should not be lost siu'l of that material {rains have resulted from ramm some vcars at all stations. As shown in Tablt gram of Figure 7. mum tillage with the exeeptioi manuring at North l'latte has been tile most rhods in increasing average per acre yields at all Summer tillage makes its poorest relative show hos years when precipitation is above normal and good secured from continuously cropped lands. Thus in l!ll-~&gt;. an ex eeasively wet year, summer tillage made ■ decidedly | low ing in comparison with continuous cropping at North 1'lat Akron, and Ardniore. In 191fi. when there was ■ good earr over of soil moisture from 1915 even in continuously croppf land, summer tillage again showed at a disadvantage at North Platte and Ardmore. 1912 and 1!&gt;14 were years of heavier than normal precipitation during the growing season at Akron. 19'20. the only year in which summer tillage showed at a dis- »*'— v, * .' .- — - •■ ... advantage at all stations, was a year of excess precipitation at a!_'&lt;'^ made up of widely different results CilllllOt In </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Winter Wheat in Western N'kbraska 27 \s ■ meam of increasing production in dry years summer tillage is nf great value. In those sections of western Nebraska where winter wheat is the predominating crop, sum- practiced to some extent until systems of mer tilling w ure adopted which make use of larger acreages of ■lips SIMMER TILLAGE VEKS1 S ROTATION WITH CORN IN GROWING WINTER WHEAT Iii comparing the profits of the two practices of glwwiBg winter wheat, in one of which the erop follows summer tillage ther of which it follows corn, several factors must ! n consideration. These are. the amount of wheat gained by summer tilling, the amount of corn grown by the other practise, ;md the relative values of the two crops. Table •"&gt; shows: the yearly and average gains or losses in lels of wheat per aere at each station from growing winter h wheat after summer tillage as compared with growing it after •orn : tin- yearly iind average corn yields; and the ratio in bushels pi-r acre of wheat gained by the one method to bushels •orn raised by the other. The gains or losses in wheat yields wn are the differences between the yields following summer lace and those following corn, as shown in Table B. The corn yields given are from plats on which corn follows wheat or oats at North l'latte, and on which it follows winter or spring wheat it the other stations. The corn yields are the averages from 18 plats «it North Platte, 10 plats at Akron, 9 plats at Scottsbluff, md 13 plats at Ardmore. The yearly variations, both in the relative yields of wheat both methods and in the yields of corn, have been great. ii the yields of wheat following summer tillage as com- pared with that following corn occurred in 6 of the 3-i station years when either crop was produced. These are indicated by the minus sil'ii in the table. Maximum gains were 7.1 bushels per acre at North Platte, 1SJ bushels at Akron, 14.6 bushels at Sri.tts.MufT. and 13.6 bushels at Ardmore. Corn yields have varied from a minimum yield of 6M bushels per acre at Scotts- hluff and total failures at all the other stations to maximum vii'hls c.f 4:?."&gt; bushels per acre at North Platte, 40.9 bushels at Scottsbluff. IBjO bushels at Ardmore, and 35.3 bushels at Akron. Since there is no apparent relation between the pain in wheat from summer tillage and the size of the corn yield and both are subject to wide yearly variations, very large fluetua- tions naturally occur in the ratios of one to the other. Thus in some of the years when there was a loss In th" </seg>
            <seg id="p028">1 NEBRASKA EXI'KRIMENT STATION Rll.I.ETIN 17!' 28 fc. •«*. )8O[ UJO.) * © . 18O[UJO0 o-5e , JO s[dqsnqTjo siuaaj ui peuiB3 v «j iO 50 ' « &lt;0 = 5 I M }Bau.« jojiaqsnq ipsa jo 1803 fc • »- V £ OS ] f '■ ■' ' -v 5 &amp;, ifl^te &gt;J S la i . n«- T4 n — O s ■- -Q &lt; UJ03 3UL*0U0J ppiX J3A0 «=u5««;«;t- a-. ,»3Bi[iJ Jeuiums 8ui .MO|i»j jcaq.w £ °S8 "—•••••jtrf ej ft .S unjiM m kdwhX ui .&gt;SKr»J.1UI -t t- ] -r jajurw }o spjaiX u; es^aaouj J8O[ UJOO sieqsnq jo suuai ui paureS * "^ fc }° t' WX X'WW N ?■! — g" « U. }«au.« jo jaqsnq qJBa jo 1803 I 1 s - 1 — ~, _ i ■&lt;^. O UJOO 8Ut.«O||OJ p[&lt;M.{ JdAO U — 5 O UJOO 8Ut.«O||OJ pI-MA J.1AO r:ixnico 3C 3C 5 "I " . aa«iip jaiuiuhs aui.Yvojioj jBeq.w ..flE[[u Jaiuiuhs Sui.wohoj jBai^w in ~ k — ' d -r «c o ~S _~ jaiuiA\ jo spi^iX ui ascaioui . "5 J9O1 UJOO V 5 J° sjaqsnq jo suijaj ui psui«8 a *&gt; jBai^M jo iei|sna \\o*d JO JSOJ i V Z jajut.w jo spi^iX ui ascajouj JSt)| UJOO ;o s[aqsnq jo suijaj ui paui«8 j ■«!-; -» )«e^.« jo jaqsnq l^o«a JO JSOJ S ■ T1 /. '^ V Z -. I g woo ]o pieiA ! |i S ? "* uaoo aui.wo|ioj ppiX J3AO $ § * a3B|l!l jauiuins SJuimohoj )Baq.« . &lt;s !- jajuLw jo spiaiX ui aesajour 5 s- 5 - 5 wat^cji-ti^iri usC* ? -j, -2 "* HJOO aui.WOUOJ p\8lX WAO "| M ; * a2B|i!) jauiuins 8ui.»o[ioj isaqw £ ~ t^ — ' — si t- 1~ « ■» ui e jajuLvi jo Ep(a;X ui aesajouj r **^- jsoi tuoo _ V . I t^ t«.aii m in uncnri nn«j in imi s ** *s 1 1 S J° B l a M sn( l 1° SUJ J d: J ui paum8 "5 . c p jsaqM jo jaqsnq qDBa jo jsoj I • &lt;SiS ft- UJOJ J° PH!A IBaqw jo |aqsnq q3Ba jo jsoj Irft.-- t t5 « _^ ft. 5J.S 1 |3 g s — — ■, J _LJ L_ **S « UJOO 8ui-VkO(10J piaiX J3AO « t- J-. 1- 1- t «O) «-; «S § cu O a3BH!J jauiuins auiMo[]oj iBaqM ■»tcNi^X'at- ; ri i-S «Mt-X' J3}uim jo spjdiX ui sseajoui IS :i &lt; 2S£h23122«22 o </seg>
            <seg id="p029">\\l\IIK WllKVl IN II ESTKRN NkHKASK\ 29 .ving summer tillage as compared with those .vheat following corn, the corn vields were good. In these cases tht atter Method lias both the gain in wheat and the corn yield to r vears when the gains of wheat from were small the corn yields were good, so that umn lined, in the most extreme cases, represents of porn at Ardmore in 1915, 48. '.I bushels at North Plata in 1!V_&gt;(). SI. 7 bushels at Akron in 1910. and 7.7 bushels at Seottshluff in 1912. The extremes in the other direc v gains of 6.7 of wheat at Xorth Platte I' 1913 anil (Mi at Akron in 1016, and total failure* of corn at the corresponding years: a gain of 13.8 bushels gain in wheat of 13.1 bushels and a com yield of 9.4 ml Ardmore in 1919 nwi'si average gain in wheat following summer tillage it following corn at any station was 1.7 bushels per North Platte. The average corn yield was. 19.0 bushels &lt;■. s&lt;&gt; that each bushel of wheat grained by summer tillage tits mi the average a loss in possible eorn production of ihels. At Ardiuore the average gain of wheat from sum - age was 'J.!&lt; bushels pet acre. The average corn yield l ."&gt; bushels. Thf average bushel of wheat gained there m-si'iits an average loss of (i.4 bushels of corn. At Akron •age gain of wheat following summer tillage was 5.1 per acre, the average corn yield was 13.5 bushels per west at any station. The average bushels of wheat umnier tillage therefore represents an average loss rn. which is also less than that at any other The greatest average gain per acre from growing wheat ifter summer tillage was 5.3 bushels at Scottsbluff. The high- &gt;rn vield secured was also at this station. This r er acre and an average bushel of wheat ■presents an average loss of 4.2 bushels of ■on Omitting 1!»14 at Ardmore when the crops were destroyed by hail, including 1913 when the failure was due to drouth, and combining the msulls from the four stations, the average gain of wheat from summer tillage for the :{•"&gt; station years is 3.6 bushels per acre. The average eorn yield for the same time was 17.7 bushels per acre. The average bushel of wheat gained by summer tillage therefore cost 4.9 bushels in possible corn pro- duction. Tt is probable that this is about the average ratio to be expected under general farm conditions in western Nebraska. The average December 1 farm prices in Nebraska as given by yield of 8.1 bushels at Keottshluff in 1914: </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 NkUHVSKV F.XI'K.lilMKNT STATION BtTIXBTIM 178 tiureau of Crop Estimates, for the 10-year period 1910 to inclusive, were $1.24 per bushel for wheat ami 74 cents for On the basis of these priees and the average ratio seeured ir&lt; in these experiments between the wheat fused by summer tillage and the corn pained by alternating wheat with corn, it appears that summer tillage is the less profitable of the two methods. It should be borne in mind, however, that the average is not what can be expected in any one year. Summer tilla£ has been profitable at all statioi in some years both green manuring has been the least effective of the i under trial. The yields following greea manure crops havf averaged lew than those following Rummer tillage at all stations except Xorth Platte. At rliis statioi ige inereast yield has been only .6 bathe! per acre, which is insufficient to pay for the seed of the &lt;rreen inanun- eropa and the eost of seed ing: them. At Akron and Ardmore the ■T«fg« yields following jrreen manure crops have been less than those following com. The averape yield follo\vin&lt;r &lt;rreen — ■■!! has been more than double that of wheat after wheat at Si'Ottsbluft onlv. At this station the average yield was 4.3 bushels less per acre than that following summer tillape. which indicates that moisture rather than fertility was the limiting factor. In so far as the condi - tions at these stations represent general conditions in western panson with continuous cropping of wheat and in eompai with growing wheat in alternation witli corn. While its u&gt; I recommended fur lartre scale operation* when' diversi nintr can be practiced, it has an undoubted vatae far eei rial purpos,- As has be«M shown in previous Suhsta liciitions and reported later in this bulletin, rammer til been the most efficient method tried of ■taring BOistur sulisoil. As all insurance against failure or serious in in eding crops from drouth it h;is not ben altogether fill. l)ut ii has ln'cii tlie most effective of any method d. Where tractor or other typea of farmiiiir ar.&lt; praet ch do not lend themselves readily to the frrowing of ii PI crops, summer tillage aerrefl as ■ means of clearing weeds, and of controlling insect pesti and plant diaet h freijuently follow the growing of one crop eoBtinuo) GREEN MANURING FOR WINTER WHEAT Green manuring lias for its purpoae the maintenance o; creasinf; of fertility. In wesiern Xfliraska this remains as siihordiiiate to soil moisture as ■ limit t mr factor in crop ]&gt;ro tion. As a means of producing economical violds of wl </seg>
            <seg id="p031">KSTKKN NEBR.VSKA 31 ii. tin- (rowing of green manure crops to increase wheat at the present time. EFFECT OF DIFFERENT CROPPING SYSTEMS ON SOIL MOISTURE listure studies have beca made at each of tin- results with winter wheat are A p«rt of thCM from the North Platte the spring, following wheat, corn, and 17 /&gt;^r cent mmer tillage, at \vrth PlatU, Xcfrr., /y/.* to i9io inclusive </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Kxperiment Station Bulletin 17 station are here reported for the purpose of bringing out mor&gt; clearly some of the reasons for the occurrence of yield varia tions between different cropping or tillage practi So moisture determinations at all stations have shown that as a general rule the moisture content in the spring is considerably higher in land that has been summer tilled than in land that has been cropped the previous immml Also that the moistun content is higher following corn than following prain crops. I Figure 8 shows the ptnortaffl of Matm in the upper iwi :, second two feet, and third two feet of soil, in the sprill! Mriag summer tillage, corn, and wheat at Xorth Platte froa 2 to 1920, inclusive. The determinations were made fron iples taken dwi»g the latter part of April or early in May erminations wen- inside for eaefc foot section, but the In I second, third and fourth, and fifth and sixth foot section combined for the present study. The percentages indicate! the chart are the IWnm of determinations made in dupli cate on each of two plats (The amount of moisture in dry land soil in the is upon the amount left over from the pnviou amount and nature of the precipitation which h, e the crop of the previous jresr was removed, ll feet the effect of the latter is usually the great* »r levels the effect of the previous year's tfeatllli I greater importance. A rather uniform moisture spring would then lie expected ill tllP upper two all plats, irrespective of the previous crop or I Ea- -howu on Figan 8, the moisture content *i one crop or treatment is not consistently hijrh after the others. The lack of uniformity betw ferent methods is due in part to difference* in tim In both 1913 and 1917 the first samples were tak. plats, and rains interrupted tin- work before the : wheat and fallow plats were taken. This account w deviations of the corn sequence from the others, at this dej those years. tin the second and third two-foot sections, the lines repre ting the moisture percentages of the different methods, with exception, remain separate for the entire period. Followiiii.' lmer tillage, the average moisture eont/nt in the spring has er been below 14 per cent in the 3d an&lt;T4th feet, and below per cent only once in the 5th and 6th feet. Following corn percentages of moisture in the Id and 4th feet have varied the different years from 9.5 to 16. and in the 5th and 6th t from 12 to 17. Following wheat the moisture percentages </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Wl.NTKR \\ HE.\T IX WESTERN NEBRASKA 33 ml 4th feet have varied from 7.5 to 15.5, and in the roin 7.2 to 15. These soils arc dry as far as available water for plant rned when the moisture content falls below 7 to 9 per cent. It is apparent, then, that in the spring following wheat there is usuallv verv little available moisture below the w iverapre moisture content of the 3d, 4th, 5th, and 6th he 9-year period has been equivalent to 1.3 inches of has ;rrown wheat the previous year than in rod that has grown eon. and '.\M inches less than that in n summer tilled. UTCMe of an inch or more of rain or its equivalent oisture may be of very great value in carrying the Irouth. er t-« been shown that moisture penetration, following much more rapid in soils which are somewhat moist n those which are perfectly dry. 1 On this account to be less loss by run-off and evaporation of rain or snow from land that has grown corn or that has been tilled than from dry stubble land. The differences in ■oujrht to the crop as a result of the previous treat - p thus account in a large measure for the differences l&gt;y the different methods from year to year. COMPARISONS OF WINTER WHEAT VARIETIES nited number of winter wheat varieties have 1 at North Platte since 1906. Two varieties, Tur Kharkov, have been grown for the entire period have been &lt;rro\vn for from one to nine years. variety for the years it was grown are \ Table 6. In 1917 the crop was a total failure on ae- winterkillinir. The yields of Table 6 are summarized n Table 7. In the first column of Table 7 is given the 15-year rage yieldi of Turkev Red and Kharkov. Altho there has been considerable variation between these two varieties in dif - ferent years, their averages for the entire period are practically the same. In the second column a 3-year comparison of Turkey Red, Kharkov, and Beloglina is given, for the years 1907 to 1909. These were unusually favorable years, and high yields were • "*-"~ ..~-~ «—,-—.-— — j — j j — o — ~ — secured from each variety. The average yield of Beloglina was a little over 2 bushels per acre below the other varieties and it was dropped from the tests. 'Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin No. S. pace* »4-»7. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Fll — ■■■■ Station Bulletin 17i» 3 i § SS p* zl ~? ~? ■V k fe ac *~ O «5 Cvi rJ s« wrr © g»«t&gt; M —i M— M B- ¥ ti :i?iMr:Nr rj n -m 7-j -m -m i X /: ■t XXX x i - 1 10 •» . ?J f.«aZ'jZZ'vZZ!&lt;Z 00 t- » w — c&lt;i m »C1 5e5c5 x ;c -i = S. «d 6 6~ ~ 6 o J^Z^ZZgZZ-oZ ■T s^^.t^j: 3-=-= c^ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">WlNTK.i: \» 1IKAT IN \\k.»TKK\ .\tllli\&gt;KV 35 I ".\BI.I i of winter wheat rarietitu &lt;&gt;n xummer Worth I'lutti' for citrio'ix /itrioih from 8-Year 6-Year age, :i-Year average, average, 4-Year 1921, average, 1910-1918, 1915-1921, average. 19D7-19O9 1917 1917 1918-1921 omitted omitted Bushels per acre Kl Xebr. N 25.4 24.0 30.8 28.0 N 30.3 Kar nun at tin- table jiivt-s a comparison between Kharkov. Nebraska No. 287, and Ghirka, for the l!tl&lt;! to litlS, with 1917 omitted. Nebraska Xu. )\vh in 1912, and the average of other varieties iiir is used iii computing its S-year average. During; Turkey Red produced an averasre of .•"&gt; bushel per acre Kharkov. 1.8 bushel* more than Nebraska No. 287 more than Ghirka . Kharkov, and Nebraska No. 28, for the ti-year period 1921, inclusive, with 1!&gt;17 omitted. In this comparison. nda 1:2 bushels per acre above Turkey Red. \ Kharkov. Reference to Table (&gt; shows trains in 1915 and 1919. In both n tlw other varieties. Nebraska No. 28 is from a Her than Turkey Red. lias a short stiff Red and ;ilso Bomewhat inferior in milling quality 1 stiffness of straw make it superior to s rurkey Ked fur certain special conditions, it is likely that under average conditions these advantages will be offset by the in- ferior qualities mentioned and that little can be gained from its use in western Nebraska The fifth column of the table shows a comparison between Turkey Red. Kharkov. NYhraska No. '2$, and Kaured, for the 52.9 27.2 29.6 26.3 52.7 26.7 29.3 27.2 50.4 ii in ii of the table &lt;rives a cc&gt;iii|iarison of Till ,iiii of Wl)i-ask;i No. 28 oyit the othor vas considerable lodging and considerabk liros. It is slijrlitly less winter hiirdy </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nkhkaska Exi'kriment Station Bulletin 179 1 dlH 04 US 00 •&lt;* Ml tflOKOl Til NiS ! « si QCtOuJM SJ SJ OMX D — Mr; X 1 r. s Z N -?&lt;: x -: /: /. K JC «K&gt;* -r. X •ON s^?: r"?4s Zh $m S fcl c t: &lt; c « cjnoo I ■* || o&gt;i- x O X t-' X X M- X — '• 80 ri ?4 ra ri m — n J </seg>
            <seg id="p037">U INTER W'lIK \ I N \\ KMK.KN VbMUMI \ :t7 Kharkov is !l hush&lt;&gt;l per nen above Turkey Red. and Nebraska NO. L'S is 1.7 bushels per MTC above Turkey Red. The yield of Kanred. which is the highest of any variety, is 4.0 bushels per aere above Turkev Kt'd. Keferenee to Table H shows that Kan- Itjielded Turkev Hed each year durinjr which it ha^ &lt;. r ro\vn fxci'pt tlir first. No other variety except Nebraska Ko. -* lia&gt; oiityii-ldi-,1 Turkey Red by so larpe a marfriu as did Kanretl in l!»l!t und 1920. Unlike Nebraska No. 28, Kanred has cater winter hardiness and greater rust re e. In years when these factors are of importance it will •s&gt; oiii\ ield Turkey Red by a considerable margin. ween Kanred and Kharkov at Akron. Colo. At each of aecs the tests were eondueted on both summer tilled and lbble land. The data on the tests of varieties at Akron irnisheil by courtesy of the Office of Cereal Investigation I . S. Department of Agriculture. At North Platte following enrn the 4-year average yield oi itlifrhtly above that of Kanred. With this exceptioi the leading variety in all lour tests. At Akron tin :\ 'erenee between Kanred and Kharkov is much jrreater than North Platte. This is probably due to the faet that winter iiiportant far-tor at Akron than at North M I lnl&gt; in 1921, inclusive. In tliis compttrutoii eh niiiki' it inferior to Turkey Red. Its superi hi Table 8, n 4-year comparison is jriven between Knnred. \liarknv. Turkfv Hod. him! NVIira.ska No. 28 at North Platte. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>