<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Girls' Industrial School for Juvenile Delinquents AT GENEVA, NEBRASKA FOR THE Biennium Ending November 30, 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">OF THE AT GENEVA, NEBRASKA FOR THE Bicnnium Ending November 30, 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Board of Public Lands and Buildings Hon. E. B. Cowles K George C. Junkin Lawson C. Brian. Wm. T. Thompson Attorney Gen. nil Officers and Employes tj. McMahon Hannah Kell. Louise Shaffer Mary A McMahon Emma L. Meier Anna Mackenzie Nan McMahon Fannie Saininis 3 Cuzick Matron ...Family Manager, "A" Family ...Family Manager, "B" Family Sewing Teacher Cooking Teacher Enmi Land Commissioner ivtary of S .Treasurer Superintendent Secretary Laundry </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT i &lt;&gt; iiis r^xct*. !i * . ?^iicii lcn Dcr^cr, iiiti 1 members 01 the State Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings. In accordance with law the Tenth Biennial Report of the r Industrial School is presented for your consideration. It affords me pleasure to refer to the improved conditions i tid advancement attained. A loving Providence so gen enmslv good to the girls daring the period just closed, is entitled to the lasting gratitude of the entire school. His smile has seemed st upon our work. His blessings manifested in Bk care of afflicted, and by the giving of perfect health to each and every one of our reasonably large population. The general improvement of the school as auspiciously begun some yean ago has steadily progressed, the improvements made are indeed conspicuous, and I believe the Institution stands to-day r&gt;mplete and in as good condition as is possible to make it. In its first years before its practicability and usefulness had been demonstrated, liberal appropriations were not made, per- manent betterment did not seem to have been considered, and the inmates had been confined to the bare necessities of life. For six years the present management has had the generous support of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, and with their heart operation, and the consideration of our Legislators, what baa accomplished was made possible. History of Repair and Improvements. We now have a clean comfortable building, the steam heating plant which caused considerable annoyance ou account of no out - let for the condensation, has been greatly improved by making it a double-pipe system, and placing where need demanded, la radiators, so that uniform heat may be distributed throughout the building. The conservatory completely equipped with steam coil, attached to ceiling, and giving us a nice place for the accom - modation of hot-house plants. Storm windows made for all north, east and west windows. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT The new laundry building was ready for occupancy January 5, 1909, and has been one of the most needed improvements made. This building has one large wash room, an ironing room and metal dry room, a modern and convenient store room with large basement floor, giving us ample accommodation for all supplies purchased quarterly for the Institution. Above is a comfortable cottage of four rooms, steam heated and having all modern con - veniences. Under this building is a fair sized cistern. Kk splendid new barn replaces the old one, and this includes ifortable department for the cows fitted with iron stanchions, nt floors and drains. New hog shed, chicken house, and nt walks laid to the barn. In the main building a new lavatory, closet and hath was put in for the use of the teachers, and the hospital has been entirely remodeled: a new neat floor laid, and opening made into a smaller wing which is completely equipped with hath, toilet, lavatory, hot and cold water. We are now ahle to keep this department perfectly sanitary, and is converted into a room of convenience and comfort for the sick. ■ The second veranda has been screened for a sleeping p all buildings have been freshly painted with two coat work. I We are now rebuilding the boiler house which was partially royed by the tornado, and expect to have this complet - first of the year. School and Domestic Work. Educational departments are conducted by yoong w who have had experience in Public school work, hold State I ficates and are State Normal Graduates. Under their untiring effort the advancement made by the pupils is gratifying, and promotion has been made on merit, not for the sake of equalizing enrollment. This feature of our work is now very satisfactory. I The Domestic Departments are managed by compitent teach - especially adapted to. and capable of imparting knowledge le art of sewing, needle-work, cooking, house and laundry i. In these departments a lack of training is noticeable in girls, and every effort is made to teach them the work so ral and necessary for every young woman, and to place them 1 a plane of usefulness and independence. Each is greatlv </seg>
            <seg id="p005">INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, GENEVA benefited thereby, and the change wrought in the girls is re markable. The usefulness of the school is being more greatly acknowl - edged and responsibilities upon the management are becoming greater. The appropriations asked for, are carefully considered, and must be made to meet the requirements of the institution. ■ Nebraska can afford to care for her wards, and "Forward" continue to be our motto. Needs of the Institution Kith all due care exercised I find the cost of maintenance what higher, and this is due to a general advance in the ! of all commodities. It will require for suitable mainteance support for the next two years: Maintenanc $30,(X Matron's salary Salary of two Family Managers 2,400 00 Respectfully and obediently yours, I yh \ j \f('\I\TI()V Kintr children in hom&lt; lir and inmprovemen 1,000 00 2,500 00 Employes' \va 6,000 00 rintendents ? salary 3,000 00 1,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT TABLE KO. 1 Appropriations for the Biennium i la, 1 e %%£ sources NOV^ ) for Total Kx I w ' nd - I Hal. K ';l &gt;a . ir ,.(1 - and lm- TABLE &gt;0. 2 Repairs and Improvements. On hand Appropri- Used from 30 ; ated Employees" Total expended Balance $8000.00 | 10.00 18732.80 fti4.V!.t)4 879.10 Itla- i , •WW.SWI 5800.00W t&gt;76ti.N0j* 5HOO.OOIO2 I 9M«.H0 .ges 907.52 0000.00 '.!h»7..",l» 5802.00 ll(4.s.| tenanee 2&lt;»3.44 2O5OO.O0 Ii)7ii.i.44 hv.i\- 4444. sr, tig &lt; hiki- in hom.-&gt; 4!i.(&gt;s lmmiii) 1OM.0H H52.31J03 - •+«&gt;. 77 1909 Wages </seg>
            <seg id="p007">E. J. Assenmaker 26 50 Wm. Bowers 13 50 George Hansen.. .. 13 00 Chas. Stewart 62 50 dish for old grey team 100 00 Cash for hogs: 2410 lbs., $7 40 cwt _ 178 35 560 lbs., $6 75 cwt 37 80 2050 lbs., $5 50 cwt 112 75 Cash for calves 14 36 Cash for 9 loads of cinders, $0.50 each... 4 50 Total amount of cash received ____$818 22 Table No. 3. Cost per capita for total expenditures and currennt support during the biennium : Officers' salaries _... $ 5,800 00 Kloyes' wages 0.172 69 itenance 16,318 59 Placing children in homes 9"i. Total number of inmates present Nov. 80, 1 Total number of inmates received since 41 Total number returned from parole 13 Total number cared for during biennium 112 Total number paroled during biennium 59 Total number present, Nov. 30, 1910 53 112 Cost per capital _ $252.17 Table No. 4. Cash Statement. Received On hand November 30, 1908 &lt;254 96 Received for board : I) </seg>
            <seg id="p008">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Paid Out Rev. Thos. Griffiths $ 15 75 Rev. C. M. Shepherd 11 25 Rev. Arthur Cash 9 00 Rev. Chas. A. Becker 18 00 Rosenquist &amp; Nicholas 75 27 Alexander &amp; Son 63 85 December, 1908, Incidentals 116 17 January, 1910, Incidentals ... 106 20 April, 1910, Incidentals 34 72 May, 1910, Incidentals 129 49 June, 1910, Incidentals 70 80 Julv, 1910, Incidentals 37 81 August, 1910, Incidentals 44 66 Total amount of cash paid out .$732 97 Balance of cash on hand November 30. 1910 *s;, 25 PHYSICIAN'S REPORT Miss Lyda J. McMahon, Supt., Girls' Industrial School, Geneva, Nebraska. Dear Madam : — I am pleased to report that in the last bien - nium we have had but very little sickness of a severe grade, and no accident of importance. Were it not for the two epidemics of Scarlet fever, one occuring in December 1908, the other in Jan - uary 1910, the report from this department would be meagre in - deed. The first case being that of a little girl, who had, unknown to the Superintendent, been exposed in her home and was taken sick in a day or two after entering the school, and as a result oth - ers, of course were exposed. By the hearty co-operation of the management and instructors, rigid isolation of the sick was estab - lished and maintained with the result that the number becoming afflicted was limited to four, all of whom made good recoveries. The later epidemic, January, 1910, was traced to a little girl re- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">eeiving an infected doll sent by a friend, she and other little girls who played with the doll were stricken with Scarlet fever at about the same time. Two other playmates caught the disease from them, but we were able to prevent further spread of the contagion, and those afflicted suffered with only a mild type of the disease. t Improvements have been made in the hospital wing, and e the last report we have access to a lavatory, closet, and bath acent to the hospital proper. But there is one thing of which are still in need, a sterilizer, so that towels, instruments, dress - &gt; etc., can be readily sterilized and hot and cold steril v. ays at hand. Only by these rigid aseptic measures can the : results with those unfortunate children, infected before com- ing here, be hoped for I On the whole my relations with the school in the last two •s has been most pleasant and I trust effective. Thanks for earnest and efficient assistancel have received from every one lected with the Institution. Geneva Nebr., November, 30, 1910. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>