<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Suggestive Programs for Special Day Exercises Issued by the Department of Public Instruction For the Use of the Schools of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1901">1901</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Suggestive Programs for Special Day Exercises Issued by (he I Department of Public Instruction For the Use of the Schools of Nebraska WILLIAM K. FO WLER State Superintendent LINCOLN State Journal Company, Printers 1901 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">By Way of Introduction Department of Public Instruction, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 1, 1901. 2b the Teacher* of Nebraska : This department takes pleasure in presenting to you these suggestive ex - ercises for Special Day programs, in the hope that they may prove a material and valuable aid in making more interesting to the school children of our beloved state these holidays and anniversaries. May these exercises lighten your labors, brighten their work, enliven your school, and impress upon the minds of all patriotic sentiments. We beg no one's pardon for asking the schools to observe the anniver - saries of the birth of Lincoln and of Washington ; the children will thank us for including a day to be devoted to the study of their poet and his verses ; Ne - braskans generally are proud of the origin of Arbor Day and of its founder, their distinguished fellow citizen, the Hon. J. Sterling Morton; the agricul - turists of our state are interested in the preservation of our insectivorous birds, and all are interested in the care and increase of the native birds of Nebraska; the observance of Memorial Day grows sweeter, brighter, and better with the passing years; Library Day is growing constantly in im - portance and value in our schools and in the rural communities ; Thanksgiving Day is a part of our national history, and Nebraska's bountiful- harvests cause her to rejoice with her sister states; and Christmas Day is a fitting close to the commemoration of special days, containing in a large measure the children's hopes, their elders' reminiscences, and the common religion of all, with " peace on earth, good will to men." Teach patriotism; teach love of beautiful characters, of kindly sentiments, and of nature ; teach appreciation of pure literature ; teach thankfulness for the bounty bestowed by the great giver of all good ; and teach peace and goodwill, self-sacrifice and all charitableness. The future destiny of this nation must be worked out in the homes and the schools of the land. This instruction need not displace the multiplication table and the art of correct spelling, but it must have a place. Use these exercises judiciously. Do not adopt them in whole, but adapt them in part. Use what is best suited to your needs. Local conditions and requirements vary. Consult the authorities and texts referred to. You may find there something better suited to your peculiar necessities. Remember this publication is for the ensuing two years, the biennium 1901 and 1902. It should remain the property of the schoolroom for that length of time, as a teacher's desk copy. Prepare your programs for these special days, alternating music, recita - tions, special exercises, etc., and assigning parts, and then publish them in a local or county newspaper. Send printed or written invitations to your patrons to attend the exercises. Do not attempt to observe all these special days each year, but bring in every one during the next two years. With high hopes and best wishes for a continued successful observance of these special days, I am Sincerely yours, William K. Fowler, Superintendent. (2) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A.31 1*1.^' l M , .^ * </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Lincoln's Boyhood and Youth ' T^HE Statesman or the military hero born and reared in a log cabin is a X familiar figure in American history; but we may search in vain among our celebrities for one whose origin and early life equalled Abraham Lincoln's in wretchedness Hard work was his early lot. When a mere boy he had to help in supporting the family, either on his father's clearing, or hired out to other farmers to plough, or dig ditches, or chop wood, or drive ox teams; occasionally also to " tend the baby " when the farmer's wife was otherwise engaged. He could regard it as an advancement to a higher sphere of activity when he obtained work in a " cross-roads store," where he amused his customers by his talk over the counter; for he soon distinguished himself among the backwoods folk as one who had something to say worth listening to. Every printed page that fell into his hands he would greedily devour, and his family and friends watched him with wonder, as the uncouth boy, after his daily work, crouched in a corner of the log cabin or outside under a tree, absorbed in a book while munching his supper of corn bread. In this manner he began to gather some knowledge, and sometimes he would astonish the girls with such startling remarks as that the earth was moving around the sun, and not the sun around the earth, and they marveled where " Abe " could have got such queer notions. Soon he also felt the impulse to write; not only making extracts from books he wished to remember, but also com - posing little essays of his own. First he sketched these with charcoal on a wooden shovel scraped white with a drawing knife, or on basswood shingles. Then he transferred them to paper, which was a scarce commodity in the Lincoln household care to cut his expressions close, so that they might not cover too much space, a style-forming method greatly to be commended. Seeing boys put a burning coal on the back of a wood turtle, he was moved to write on cruelty to animals. Seeing men intoxicated with whiskey, he wrote on temperance. In verse-making, too, he tried himself, and in satire on persons offensive to him or others. Also political thoughts he put on paper, and some of his pieces were even deemed good enough for publication in the county weekly. Thus he won a neighborhood reputation, as a clever young man, which he increased by his performances as a speaker, not seldom drawing upon himself the dissatisfaction of bis employers by mounting a stump in the field and keeping the farm hands from their work by little speeches in a jocose and sometimes also a serious vein. At the rude social frolics of the settlement he became an important person, telling funny stories and mimicking the itinerant preachers All this made him a favorite in backwoods society, although in some things he appeared a little odd to his friends. Far more than any of them, he was given not only to reading, but to fits of abstraction, to quiet musincr with himself, and also to scrange spells of melancholy, from which he often would pass in a moment to rollicking out - bursts of droll humor. But, on the whole, he was one of the people among (3) incoln Day FEBRUARY 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES whom he lived; in appearance, perhaps, a little more uncouth than the most of them, a very tall, rawboned youth, with large features, dark shriveled skin, and rebellious hair; his arms and legs long, out of proportion; clad in deer - skin trousers, which from frequent exposure to the rain had shrunk so as to sit tightly on his limbs, leaving several inches of bluish skin exposed between their lower end and the heavy tan -colored shoes; the nether garment held usually by only one suspender, that was strung over a coarse home made shirt ; the head covered in winter with a coonskin cap, in summer with a rough straw hat of uncertain shape, without a band.— Carl Schurz. (Published 6y special permission of Houghton, Mifflin &amp; Co.) # # The Death of Lincoln OSLOW to smite and swift to spare. Gentle and merciful and just ! Who, in the fear of God, didst bear The sword of power, a nation's trust ! In sorrow by thy bier we stand, Amid the awe that hushes all, And speak the anguish of a land That shook with horror at thy fall. Thy task is done ; the bond are free ; We bear thee to an honored grave, Whose proudest monument shall be The broken fetters of the slave. Pure was thy life ; its bloody close Hath placed thee with the sons of light, Among the noblest host of those Who perished in the cause of Right. — William Cullen Bryant. # # The Hard-Work Plan FROM the lowest depths of poverty To the highest heights of fame, From obscureness of position To a bright and shining name; From the mass of human beings, Who compose the common clan, You can earn your way to greatness By the Hard- Work Plan. Twas the key to Lincoln's progress, Twas the route to Webster's fame ; And Garfield, by this method, To distinction laid his claim; And all earth's noblest heroes, Since this old world first began, Have earned their way to honor By the Hard-Work Plan. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">5 Lincoln Exercise FIRST CHILD. PLEASE listen, dear friends, while little ones tell Of Abraham Lincoln we all love so well. He was born in Kentucky ninety -one years ago, The twelfth of February, this much I know. SECOND CHILD. His home a log cabin, his parents were poor, Many trials and hardships he had to endure ; He had not, as we have, good teachers, and few Were the books from which most of his knowledge he drew. THIRD CHILD. O, sad was his heart when his dear mother died, And no preacher to pray the lone mourner beside. Poor lad! he was only nine years that sad day, When in the dark grave she was hidden away. FOURTH CHILD. His heart was so tender, I know he was kind, For when the poor doggie was crying behind, He waded the dark, muddy stream, and the cur Took up in his strong arms and carried him o'er. FIFTH CHILD. I know he was honest, he never could bear To wrong any one in the least, if aware ; Have you heard how he walked three long miles ere he slept, To return the change which he unwittingly kept ? 8IXTH CHILD. So manly, so humble, so noble, so brave, The foe of the bully, the friend of the slave. No wonder the hearts of the people he won, Who made him the President, March — '61. SEVENTH CHILD. September, eighteen hundred and sixty-two, Throughout all the world how the glad tidings flew! When Lincoln proclaimed the poor slaves' liberty, And said all in bondage hereafter were free. EIOHTH CHILD. For freedom he labored, for freedom he died, For weak ones, and helpless, like Him crucified ; How the heart of the nation with sorrow did swell, When he by the hand of the murderer fell. NINTH CHILD. About Abr'am Lincoln, this one thing I know, He will long be remembered by high and by low, A great object lesson— that one humble-born May rise and the highest position adorn. — Annie W. Woodruff, in Teachers' World. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 6 The Name of Lincoln THERE'S a name that brings a picture Of a man great souled and grand ; One whose deeds on History's pages, Carved in bold relief shall stand. There's a name that brings a picture Of a time when blood was shed, When the boom of cannon sounded And the star of War was red. There's a name that brings a picture Of a shackled race set free, Brought from out the ban of bondage To the joys of liberty. There's a name that brings a picture Of a nation bowed in woe, For the hand of an assassin Laid a noble spirit low. "Ti8 the name of martyred Lincoln Calls these pictures from the past, And that name with the Immortals Shall endure while earth shall last. — Susie M. Beat, in Teachers' World. * * A King WE talked of kings, little Ned and I, As we sat in the firelight's glow ; Of Alfred the Great, in days gone by, And his kingdom of long ago. Of Norman William, who, brave and stern, His armies to victory led. Then, after a pause : "At school we learn Of another great man," said Ned. "And this one was good to the oppressed, He was gentle, and brave, and so Wasn't he greateF than all the rest ? 'Twas Abraham Lincoln, you know." "Was Lincoln a king? " I asked him then, And in waiting for his reply A long procession of noble men Seemed to pass in the firelight by. When, " No," came slowly from little Ned, And thoughtfully ; then with a start, " He wasn't a king — outside," he said, " But I think he was — in his heart." —Ella Matthews Bangs, in St. Nicholas </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 Readings i «&lt;*TpHE Old World and the New, from sea to sea, A Utter one voice of sympathy and shame! Sore heart, so stopped when it at last beat high, Sad life, cut short just as its triumph came." II Peace! Let the sad procession go, While cannon boom and bells toll slow. And go, thou sacred ear, Bearing our woe afar. — R. H. Stoddard. Ill "Rest, noble martyr; rest in peace Rest with the true and brave, Who, like thee, fell in freedom's cause The nation's life to save." IV Thy name shall live while time endures, And men shall say of thee, "He saved his country from its foes, And bade the slave be free." V O God ! before whom we in tears, Our fallen chief deplore ; Grant that the cause for which he died, May live forevermore. —Gurley. * * " The First American" GREAT captains, with their drums and guns, Disturb our judgment for the hour, But at last silence comes; These all are gone, and, standing like a tower, Our children shall behold his fame, The kindly-earnest, brave, foreseeing man, Sagacious, patient, dreading praise, not blame, New birth of our new soil, the first American. — From LoweWs '■'■Commemoration Ode. # * Lincoln as a Military Hero WHEN the Black Hawk war broke out, young Lincoln helped to raise a company of volunteers and was chosen its captain. The company afterward disbanded, but young Lincoln, determined to serve in the campaign, enlisted as a private, and lived a soldier's life for the next three months. Referring to this experience in a congressional speech in after years, Mr. Lincoln said : " By the way, Mr. Speaker, did you know I was a military </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES hero? Yes, sir, in the days of the Black Hawk war, I fought, bled, and came away. Speaking of General Cass' career, reminds me of my own. I was not at Stillman's defeat, but I was about as near it as Cass to Hull's surrender; and, like him, I saw the place very soon afterward. It is quite certain I did not break my sword, for I had none to break ; but I bent a musket pretty badly on one occasion. If Cass broke his sword, the idea is, he broke it in desperation ; I bent the musket by accident. If Cass went in advance of me in picking whortleberries, I guess I surpassed him in charging upon the wild onions. If he saw any live, fighting Indians, it was more than I did, but I had a good many bloody battles with the mosquitoes; and although I never fainted, from loss of blood, I can truly say, I was often very hungry." a a Lincoln's Method of Study (After his Cooper Union speech, February 27, 1880, Mr. Lincoln visited, among other places, Norwich, Conn. The following is his answer to a question of Mr. Gulliver, in the railway train on his way back to New York :) "WTJTELL, as to education, the newspapers are correct; I never went to school Jfw more than six months in my life. But, as you say, this must be a product of culture in some form. I have been putting the question you ask me to myself, while you have been talking. I can say this, that among ray earliest recollections, I remember how, when a mere child, I used to get irritated when anybody talked to me in a way I could not understand. I don't think I ever got angry at anything else in my life. But that always disturbed my temper, and has ever since. I can remember going to my little bedroom, after hearing the neighbors talk of an evening with my father, and spending no small part of the night walking up and down, and trying to make out what was the exact meaning of some of their, to me, dark sayings. I could not sleep, though I often tried to when I got on such a hunt after an idea, until I had caught it; and when I thought I had got it, I was not satis - fied until I would repeat it over and over, until I had put it in language plain enough, as I thought, for any boy to comprehend. This was a kind of passion with me, and it has stuck by me; for I am never easy now when I am hand - ling a thought, till I have bounded it north, and bounded it south, and bounded it east, and bounded it west. Perhaps that accounts for the characteristic you observe in my speeches, though I never put the two things together before. Oh, yes! I "read law," as the phrase is— that is, I became a lawyer's clerk in Springfield, and copied tedious documents and picked up what I could of law in the intervals of other work. But your question reminds me of a bit of education I had, which I am bound in honesty to mention. In the course of my law reading, I constantly came upon the word demonstrate. I thought at first that I understood its meaning, but soon became satisfied that I did not. I said to myself, "What do I mean when I demonstrate more than when I reason or prove t How does demonstration differ from any other proof?" I consulted Webster's Dictionary. That told of "certain proof," "proof beyond the possibility of doubt ; " but I could form no idea what sort of proof that was. I thought a great many things were proved beyond a possi - bility of doubt, without recourse to any such extraordinary process of reason - ing as I understood "demonstration " to be. I consulted all the dictionaries and books of reference I could find, but with no better results. You might as well have defined blue to a blind man. At last I said, " Lincoln, you can never make a lawyer if you do not understand what demonstrate means;" and I left my situation at Springfield, went home to my father's house and stayed there till I could give any proposition in the six books of Euclid at sight. I then found out what " demonstrate " means, and went back to my law-studies. — From u Words of Abraham Lincoln," published by the Western Publishing House, Chicago. </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">9 Lincoln and the Dying Soldier Boy ONE day in May, 1863, while the great war was raging between the North and the South, President Lincoln paid a visit to one of the military hos- pitals, says an exchange. He had spoken many cheering words of sympathy to the wounded as he proceeded through the various wards, and now he was at the bedside of a Vermont boy of about sixteen years of age, who lay there mortally wounded. Taking the dying boy's thin, white hands in his own, the President said, in a tender tone : "Well, my poor boy, what can I do for you ? " The young fellow looked up into the President's kindly face and asked : "Won't you write to my mother for me ? " "That I will," answered Mr. Lincoln ; and calling for a pen, ink, and paper, he seated himself by the side of the bed and wrote from the boy's dic - tation. It was a long letter, but the President betrayed no sign of weariness. When it was finished, he rose, saying: " I will post this as soon as I get back to my office. Now, is there any - thing else I can do for you ? " The boy looked up appealingly to the President. "Won't you stay with me?'" he asked. — I do want to hold on to your hand." Mr. Lincoln understood the boy's meaning. The appeal was too strong for him to resist; so he sat down by his side and took hold of his hand. For two hours the President sat there patiently as though he had been the boy's father. When the end came he bent over and folded the thin hands over his breast. As he did so, he burst into tears, and when, soon afterward, he left the hospital, they were still streaming down his cheeks. — From "Best Lincoln Stories," by permission of James E. Gallaher &amp; Co. 0 0 Lincoln's Famous Speech (At Gettysburg, November 19, 1883.) TJV5URSCORE and seven years ago our fathers brought forth upon this JT continent a new nation, conceived in liberty, and dedicated to the propo - sition that all men are created equal. Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation, or any nation so conceived and so dedi - cated, can long endure. We are met on a great battle-field of that war. We hare come to dedicate a portion of that field as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live. It is altogether fitting and proper that we should do this. But in a larger sense we cannot dedicate, we cannot consecrate, we cannot hallow this ground. The brave men, living and dead, who struggled here, have consecrated it far above our power to add or detract. The world will little note, nor long remember what we say here, but it can never forget what they did here. It is for us, the living, rather to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have thus far so nobly advanced. It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the great task remaining before us, that from these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion; that we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain; that this nation, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom, and that government of the people, by the people, and for the people, shall not perish from the earth. COMMENT ON THIS SPEECH. On November 19, 1863, two orators met on the memorable field of Get - tysburg. One was gifted in oratory, learned in schools and from books ; the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">10 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES other was skilled in the 'witchery of speech' as gathered from the river, the forest, and the plain. Both spoke. The speech of one lies dumb and mean - ingless, unread and unremembered, while the speech of the other, rooted in the memory of man, and oft repeated, will live with the literature of the race, growing grander and sweeter in pathos and in beauty as the years shall gather around and about it. One was a brain effort, the other was a heart effort. One spoke words that were heard, the other words that were felt. One was art, the other genius. One was Edward Everett, the gifted scholar of New England, the other was Abraham Lincoln, the gifted railsplitter of the west. —Judge Tenney. EVERETT'S LETTER ON SAME. The day after the delivery of these two speeches, Edward Everett wrote Mr. Lincoln as follows: "My dear Lincoln: Could I flatter myself with the thought that I came as near the central idea of the occasion yesterday in three hours as you did in three minutes, I would be a happy man." The re - ply was characteristic of Mr. Lincoln. He wrote: "My dear Everett: Yours on our Gettysburg speeches at hand. It would not do for Edward Everett to make a short speech or Abraham Lincoln a long one. Yours, A. Lincoln." # * Lincoln's First Speech in the Supreme Court (The case being called, Mr. Lincoln appeared for the appellant, and according to Judge Treat, spoke as follows:) YOUR HONOR:— This is the first case I have ever had in this court, and I have examined it with great care. As the court will perceive by looking at the abstract of the record, the only question in the case is one of authority. I have not been able to find any authority sustaining my side of the case, but I have found several cases directly in point on the other side. I will now give the citations and then submit the case. — Published by per - mission of Rhodes &amp; McClure. * * First Talk with Friends After Receiving Tel - egram of His First Nomination (This telegram was received In the Journal office at Springfield. Immediately everybody wanted to shake his hand, and so long as he was willing, they continued to congratutate him.) GENTLEMEN:— (with a twinkle in his eye)— You had better come up and shake my hand while you can ; honors elevate some men, you know. . . . Well, gentlemen, there is a little short woman at our house, who is probably more interested in this dispatch than I am ; and if you will excuse me, I will take it up and let her see it. — Published by permission of Rhodes &lt;£- McClure. a a Washington and Lincoln Compared THE greatest names in American history are Washington and Lincoln. One is forever associated with the independence of the states and forma- tion of the Federal Union; the other with universal freedom and the preservation of the Union. Washington enforced the Declaration of Inde - pendence as against England; Lincoln proclaimed its fulfillment not only to </seg>
            <seg id="p013">11 a downtrodden race in America, but to all people for all time who may seek the protection of our flag. These illustrious men achieved grander results for mankind within a single century, from 1775 to 1865, than any other men ever accomplished in all the years since first the flight of time began. Washington engaged in no ordinary revolution; with him it was not who should rule, but what should rule. He drew his sword not for a change of rulers upon an established throne, but to establish a new government which should acknowledge no throne but the tribune of the people. Lincoln accepted war to save the Union, the safeguard of our liberties, and re-estab - lish it on "indestructible foundations" as forever "one and indivisible." To quote his own grand words: Now we are contending "that this nation under God shall have a new birth of freedom, and that government of the people, by the people, for the people, shall not perish from the earth." Each lived to accomplish his appointed task. Each received the un - bounded gratitude of the people of his time and each is held in great and ever-increasing reverence by posterity. The fame of each will never die; it will grow with the ages, because it is based upon imperishable service to humanity; not to the people of a single generation or country, but to the whole human family, wherever scattered, forever.— W illiam McKinley, in Porter's Life of McKinley, by permission of the N. G. Hamilton Publishing Co., Cleveland. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Washington IN his person, Washington was six feet high, and rather slender. His limbs were long; his hands were uncommonly large, his chest broad and full, his head was exactly round, and the hair brown in manhood, but gray at fifty ; his forehead rather low and retreating ; the nose large and massy, the mouth wide and firm, the chin square and heavy, the cheeks full and ruddy in early life. His eyes were blue and handsome, but not quick or nervous. He required spectacles to read with at fifty. He was one or the best riders in the United States, but, like some other good riders, awkward and shambling in his walk. He was stately in his bearing, reserved, distant, and apparently haughty. Shy among women, he was not a great talker in any company, but a care - ful observer and listener. He read the natural temper of men, but not always aright. He seldom smiled. He did not laugh with his face, but in his body, and, while calm above, below the diaphragm his laughter was copious and earnest. Like many grave persons he was fond of jokes and loved humorous stories. He had negro story-tellers to regale him with fun and anecdotes at Mt. Vemon He was not critical about his food, but fond of tea. He took beer or cider at dinner, and occasionally wine. He hated drunkenness, gam - ing, and tobacco. He had a hearty love of farming and of private life. There was nothing of the politician in him, — no particle of cunning. He was one of the most industrious of men. Not an elegant or accurate writer, he yet took great pains with style, and after the revolution carefully corrected the letters he had written in the time of the French war, more than thirty years before. He was no orator. He never made a speech. The public papers were drafted for him, and he read them when the occasion came. It has been said Washington was not a great soldier; but certainly he created an army out of the roughest materials, out-generaled all that Britain could send against him, and in the midst of poverty and distress, organized victory. He was not brilliant and rapid. He was slow, defensive, victorious. He made "an empty bag stand upright," which Franklin says is "hard." Some men command the world, or hold its admiration by their ideas or their intellect. Washington had neither original ideas nor a deeply cultured mind. He commanded by his integrity, by his justice. He loved power by instinct, and strong government by reflective choice. Twice he was made dictator, with absolute power, and never abused the awful and despotic trust. The monarchic soldiers and civilians would make him king. He trampled on their offer and went back to his fields of corn at Mt. Vernon. Washington is the first man of his type : when will there be another ! As yet the American Rhetoricians do not dare tell half his excellence ; but the people should not complain. — Theodore Parker, in "Our Country in Poetry and Proae." {By permission of The American Book Company.) (12) </seg>
            <seg id="p015">GEORGE WASHINGTON. From the Baldwin Primer, published by the American Book Co </seg>
            <seg id="p016">13 Birthday of Washington (May be sung to America. FIRST PIPIL. WELCOME, thou festal mom! Never be passed in scorn Thy rising sun. Thou day forever bright With Freedom's holy light, That gave the world the sight Of Washington. SECOND PUPIL. Unshaken 'mid the storm, Behold that noble form — That peerless one, With his protecting hand, Like Freedom's angel, stand, The guardian of our land, Our Washington. THIRD PUPIL. Traced there in lines of light, Where all pure rays unite, Obscured by none ; Brightest on history's page, Of any clime or age, As chieftain, man or sage, Stands Washington. FOURTH PUPIL. Name at which tyrants pale, And their proud legions quail, Their boasting done; While Freedom lilts her head, No longer filled with dread, Her sons to victory led By Washington . CLASS IN CONCERT. Now the true patriot see, The foremost of the free, The victory won. In Freedom's presence bow, While sweetly smiling now She wreathes the spotless brow Of Washington. Then, with each coming year, Whenever shall appear That natal sun, Will we attest the w orth Of one true man to earth And celebrate the birth Of Washington. — George Rowland, </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Acrostic for Washington's Birthday Note. — If recited by ten small children they might have letters covered with different colored tissue paper, or with evergreen, laurel, or boxwood, if obtainable. VV-hy are we gathered here today, A-nd what would our friends all have us say ? g-urely a hero our theme should be, H-onored his name, on land, and sea |-nquire thou the name of our hero true? N-oble, courageous, a patriot too, C -uiding through trial our " Ship of State." X-ru'y h' 8 name we can all call great. Q-'er this broad country, each daughter and son, N-ow welcomes the name— George Washington. — Louise M. Byrnes, in The Teachers' World. 0 a A " New Physical Culture " Exercise for Washington's Birthday Commands — 1. Recited — 2. 1. At-tention. 2. George Washington always gave individual attention to the calls of duty. 1. Po-sition. 2. Washington always made the best of any position in which he might be placed. 1. Heels-raise. 2. His very presence would always raise the spirits of his army, and his voice would inspire them with courage. 1. Heels-sink. 2. Nor would his own spirits sink, for his trust in God was unbounded. 1. Hips-firm. 2. Yes, his firm, unwavering trust in God was what sustained him during the darkest hours of the Revolution. 1. Po-sition. 2. His position as commander of the Revolutionary army was one of grave responsibility, but ably and successfully did he fill it. 1. Feet-close. 2. At the close of the war he retired to his home, Mt. Vernon, after having bid farewell to his beloved army. 1. Feet-open. 2. His grand character and noble life cannot fail to open to us a lofty stand - ard of courage and patriotism. 1. Heads backward-bend. 2. Let us then backward bend our thoughts to-day towards the memory of this great man who still " Lives in the hearts of his countrymen." 1. Heads upward-raise. 2. At the same time let us uptoard raise our thankful hearts to our Heavenly Father for having sent us in our hour of need this " Father of His Country." — Washington. Salute-right (or left), face-march. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">15 George Washington (The following exercise may be given by sixteen pupils. Each pupil has a large pasteboard letter hung about the neck. The letters are covered with gilt paper, turned and displayed at the beginning of the verse as it is recited. The letters in order spell "George Washington.") General Washington's name we praise, In tributes now our voices raise. Earnest and true, he was noble and good; I'd be like Washington— that I would! Obedient always — a manly boy; His playmates he did not annoy. Right in word, in act, in deed; In classes he would always lead. Good and thoughtful, always kind, Such boys make friends we always find. Eager to learn he improved each hour. This gave to him great strength and power. Wisdom he sought, and in this land, No greater general could command. Alert and quick to do his work ; A duty he would never shirk. Strong in body and strong in mind, No greater general can we find. Happy to do for his country and men, He bravely fought for freedom then. Illustrious soldier, statesman, friend, Our country '8 cause he did defend. Noble in thought, in action sure, Great suffering he did endure. Great was the work of this soldier's life; He conquered the foe in the bitter strife. True to his country, as president, he Ruled his people in "the land of the free." Obedient still to duty's command, He loved our own, free native land. Noted, obedient, great and grand, Did ever a greater man live in our land? (The first four boys recite In concert the following, form - ing a circle at the appropriate words.) Four brave little laddies, Wearing loyal badges. In a row together, standing hand in hand ; Make a manly circle, Join hands all together, So one link we've fastened of a loyal band. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">16 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES THE NEXT FOUR GIRLS RECITE : Four true little lassies, From the world's great masses, In a row together, standing hand in hand; Swing into a circle, Join both lads and lassies, So two links we've fastened of a loyal band. (Aa the two groups come together, four hands meet and cross, thus uniting the two circles.) THE NEXT FOUR REPEAT : We four make a circle, Join each hand to hand ; And a third link we have fastened of our loyal band. Battlefields may lie Before us by and by, But strong we'll be to fight in freedom's land. THE LAST FOUR REPEAT : Four more little lassies From our brightest classes, In a row together, standing hand in hand ; Make a loving circle, Join we to the others, So four links are fastened in our loyal band. ALL REPEAT Four strong links for greatness In our chain to-day, Strong and good as Washington's brave loyal band. Strong, obedient, tender, Our love together render, For Washington's great goodness and our own fair native land. ALL SING TO THE TUNE OF "LIGHTLY ROW." Gayly sing, gayly sing, Washington's great fame we bring. Joyfully, joyfully, Sing his praise to-day. May our lives be good and great, And we armed for any fate, Joyfully, joyfully, Sing his praise to-day. (At the beginning of the last four lines, the groups sepa - rate and march out) — The Helper. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">MOUNT VERNON. Copyright 1S9X by A. W. Elton &amp; Co., Botton. From a carbon photo«raph:f rom a negative directly from original, published by A. W. Elson 6b Co., Boston. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">17 coat sleere tall oat and For Two Boys One boy should be dressed as an old soldier — soldier's uniform, and right hanging empty at his side. The other coy is dressed as an old man - spectacles, cane. OLD MAN. ■Y"OU were at Valley Forge, old friend? SOLDIER. Aye, aye, sir, that I was, Fighting for love and freedom, My country and Liberty's laws. I got a ball right here, sir, And that at Bunker Hill; Ah, man! 'twas seven long years for us, Those battles I see still. OLD MAN. And you were at Trenton, soldier ? SOLDIER. Aye, stranger, on that day, The fight was long and bitter Ere the English foe gave way. OLD MAN. You fought under Washington, soldier ? 8OLDIER. Yes, stranger; we would tread Through cold and fire and battle And follow where he led. OLD MAN. And he was a right good General ? SOLDIER. Ah ! that he was. To me There never lived a greater, His equal ne'er could be. OLD man. You've lost an arm, brave comrade? SOLDIER. Yes, sir; my loss is gain, For I gave that right arm gladly And did not mind the pain. For independence I gave it, For the flag I love so true, And had they needed this arm I'd have given it gladly, too. OLD MAN. Ah, you have honor, soldier. - SOLDIER. Men make me a hero now, But many a hero ne'er was crowned With laurel on his brow. •) </seg>
            <seg id="p022">18 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES A hero dies for his country, The earth knows not his name, But angels kind watch o'er him, In Heaven they know his name. And all deeds brave and loyal Are recognized in Heaven ; And the crown of love is granted Whose life, for love, was given. This may be followed by singing by the school: "Battle Hymn of the Republic." — The Helper. 0 0 Dialogue Costumes. — Two girls may be dressed quaintly in white caps, white kerchiefs, full skirts, hair done up with high-back combs, spectacles, etc. BEinfc, imir uuiif up wnii iu^u-uul-k uumuB, ajwumcieg, etc. Two boys representing the men of Washington's time, may wear knee breeches, old - fashioned coats trimmed with silver or gold lace if possible, three-cornered hats trimmed with same lace. Deep lace ruffles on the sleeves and shirt bosom, wigs, buckles at the knees and on the shoes. Two ladles are knitting and sewing. A bell rings. MRS. A.— Who can that be ? (Goes to door.) Enter two gentlemen. I'm so glad to see you both; please be seated. Mr. A. — Thank you. (Removes his hat as he comes forward.) Have you seen Washington to-day? Mrs. B. — He passed the house on horseback not more than an hour ago. Mr. B. - We are sorry. We hope he will accept a third term as president. He is a kingly man. Mr. A. — Indeed he is. He was born, you know, the year I was, in seven - teen thirty-two. We played together. He had no sisters, but two older brothers. A fine, manly fellow Washington was; fond of athletic sports. He could pitch the heaviest bar of all of us. He was strong. Mr. B. — At school he would divide the boys into two armies, the French and the Americans. We fought our battles with corn-stalks. Mrs. A.— Yes; he is so kind and true that every one loves him. He was a good pupil in school. He learned very fast. He began to be great right there in the school room at Bridges' Creek. Mr. B. — I used to see him often when he was surveying, measuring off great plantations and planning roads, walls, and fences. One day I called on him when it was bitter cold. He had slept on a bed of leaves that night and was then doing his own cooking. Mrs. B. — What a brave soldier he has been! I was glad enough to see the English army go home after seven years of that bitter war, and leave our country free to make her own laws. My brother , you know, was one who froze to death in crossing the Delaware in the snow and sleet. But we must not think about our own sorrows. Here, gentlemen, let me give you a cup of tea. (Offers cups of tea.) Mr. A.— I'll say " yes " to-day, but I should say " no " most decidedly if this were seventy-three and this tea of yours what the English wanted us to buy. How that tea did go into the Boston Harbor! How indignant we all were ! Mrs. A. — We had reason to be. Such oppression and suffering was a gross injustice. Mr. B.— Well, we shall have to ride on to Mt. Vernon if we wish to see our Washington. Mrs. A. — It's a grand old place with its lawns, porches, and large, airy rooms. Mr. B. — Yes, and I am thinking Washington would far rather retire in quiet there than take hold of this government a third term. Good-day, ladies. —The Helper. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 19 An Estimate of Washington TEV3R many years I hare studied minutely the career of Washington, and M. with every step the greatness of the man has grown upon me, for analy- sis has failed to discover the act of his life which, under the conditions of the time, I could unhesitatingly pronounce to have been an error. Such has been my experience, and although my deductions may be wrong, they at least have been carefully and slowly made. I see in Washington a great soldier who fought a trying war to a successful end impossible without him; a great statesman who did more than all other men to lay the foundations of a repub - lic which has endured in prosperity for more than a century. I find in him a marvelous judgment which was never at fault, a penetrating vision which be - held the future of America when it was dim to other eyes, a great intellectual force, a will of iron, an unyielding grasp of facts, and an unequaled strength of patriotic purpose. I see in him too, a pure and high-minded gentleman of dauntless courage and stainless honor, simple and stately of manner, kind and generous of heart. Such he was in truth. The historian and the biographer may fail to do him justice, but the instinct of mankind will not fail. The real hero needs not books to give him worshipers. George Washington will al - ways receive the love and reverence of men because they see embodied in him the noblest possibilities of humanity. — Henry Cabot Lodge in "American Statesmen Series." By permission of Houghton, Mifflin &amp; Co. 0 0 Washington NIAGARA stands alone, unrivaled among the cataracts of earth, and man might as well attempt to create it, as by pen or pencil to give an ade- quate description of it. Thus Washington stands so unrivaled in the combinations of his life, character, and career, — as fortunate as he was great and as good as he was great and fortunate, — that one might as well under - take to create as describe him. I shall not attempt it, but this I may say, that the more I read history, the more I study biography, the more I contemplate human nature and aim to form correct moral estimates of men, the more the character of Washington, in its glorious beauty, in the august sublimity of its splendid combinations, looms up before my imaginations, my feelings, and my judgment, as the grandest to be found in the authentic records of our race, save those records, short and simple, that contain the glorious gospel of the Son of God. Does any one maintain that in the raising up of such a man to be the leader of our fathers in their revolutionary struggle, to be the model, guide, and inspiration, in all coming time, to the new development and progress which humanity is to make on this continent, he sees nothing wonderfully providential? That in all this struggle, he finds no special token of the benignant purpose of the Almighty in regard to the interests of liberty and humanity in this land?' I can only answer, that I envy not the coldness or skepticism of his heart. Such a man is wanting in the great element of faith, —faith in the invisible, the spiritual, the eternal, — which has ever been one of the noblest attributes of the noblest minds. Most persons will recognize, and delight to recognize, the hand of God in that glorious revolutionary struggle of our fathers, whose importance can never diminish and the memory of which can never die. It was the first stern conflict between the despotism of the Old World and the liberty of the New. In that conflict, liberty triumphed, lifting up our country "from impending servitude to acknowledged independence,'' and that riumph should stand before us today as "the Lord's doing, marvelous in our eyes," a testimony to his gracious purpose to promote the interests and pro - cess of humanity in our land and throughout the world. — Samuel K. Lathrop, n Franklin Fifth Reader. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">20 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES The Character and Career of Washington WHEN reflecting upon the character and career of Washington, the mind becomes impressed with a degree of solemn awe and reverence which is inspired by the contemplation of no other human being. We seem to be gazing upward to that Olympus on which he now serenely sits, as upon the form of one who belongs to that majestic race of beings to whom the ancient Greeks and Romans ascribed qualities and honors almost divine — to some modern Achilles, Hercules, or Theseus. Other distinguished men inspire us with a noble, but with a much less profound and impressive, senti - ment. Frederick the Great excites our admiration for his superior strategic skill as a warrior. William Pitt and Hamilton extort our applause for the splendor of their stately and resistless eloquence. We commend Marlborough and Wellington for their uniform and singular success on the battle-field. We admire Metternich and Talleyrand for the profundity and intricacy of their state-craft. We at once praise and pity Napoleon for the grandeur and the insanity both of his intellect and his ambition. But to Washington alone, of all illustrious men, do we ascribe the full perfection of heroism ; and him only do we contemplate with a reverence and admiration which are unmixed with the slightest alloy of censure, untarnished by the least sentiment of detraction. Of him alone can we say that his various qualities were precisely such, and so proportioned and balanced, as under the peculiar circumstances of the case, all wise and good men would wish them to have been. In a word, Washington was a masterpiece of human excellence on whom no improve - ment could scarcely have been effected, even by that great creative power which first called him into existence. — Samuel M. Schmucker, in "■Life and Times of Alexander Hamilton." a a What Washington Stands For NO MAN ever stood for so much to his country and to mankind as George Washington. Hamilton, Jefferson and Adams, Madison and Jay, each represented some of the elements forming the Union. Wash - ington embodied them all. They fell at times under popular disapproval, were burned in effigy, were stoned, but he with unerring judgment was always the leader of the people. Milton said of Cromwell that " war made him great, peace greater." The superiority of Washington's character and genius were more conspicuous in the formation of our government and in putting it on in - destructible foundations than in leading armies to victory and conquering the independence of his country. " The union in any event," is the central thought of his farewell address, and all the years of his grand life were de - voted to its preservation. He fought as a youth with Braddock and in the capture of Fort Duquesne for the protection of the whole country. As eom - mander-in-chief of the continental army, his commission was from the con - gress of the united colonies. He inspired the movement for the Republic, was the president and dominant spirit of the convention which framed its con - stitution, and its president for eight years, and guided its course until satis - fied that moving safely along the broad highway of time it would be surely ascending toward the first place among the nations of the world, the asylum of the oppressed, the home of the free. Do his countrymen exaggerate his virtues ? Listen to Guizot, the his - torian of civilization: "Washington did the two greatest things which in politics it is permitted to man to attempt. He maintained by peace the inde - pendence of his country, which he conquered by war. He founded a free government in the name of the principles of order and by re-establishing their sway." Hear Lord Erskins, the famous of English advocates: " You are </seg>
            <seg id="p025">21 the only being for whom I have an awful reverence." Remember the tribute of Charles James Fox, the greatest parliamentary orator who ever swayed the British house of commons: " Illustrious man, before whom all borrowed greatness sinks into insignificance." Contemplate the character of Lord Brougham, pre-eminent for two generations in every department of human activity and thought, and then impress upon the memories of your children his deliberate judgment: "Until time shall be no more will a test of the progress which our race has made in wisdom and virtue be derived from the veneration paid to the immortal name of Washington." Chatham, who, with Clive, conquered an empire in the east, died broken - hearted at the loss of the empire in the west by follies which even his power and eloquence could not prevent. Pitt saw the vast creations of his diplomacy shattered at Austerlitz and fell murmuring: "My country! how I love my country! " Napoleon caused a noble tribute to Washington to be read at the head of his armies, but, unable to rise to Washington's greatness, witnessed the vast structure erected by conquest and cemented by blood, to minister to his own ambition and pride, crumble into fragments, and an exile and a pris - oner, he breathed his last babbling of battle fields and carnage. Washington, with his finger upon his pulse, felt the presence of death and calmly reviewing the past and forecasting the future answered to the summons of the grim mes - senger, " It is well," and, as his mighty soul ascended to God, the land was deluged with tears and the world united in his eulogy. Blot out from the page of history the names of all the great actors of his time in the drama of nations and preserve the name of Washington, and the century will be re - nowned. -Chauncey M. Depew, on the One- Hundredth Anniversary of the Founding of Our Government. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Henry Wadsworth Longfellow A Grammar School Exercise Arranged by A. C. Scammell. Motto for the Day: "/ Will Be Eminent in Something." Song by the School— "Psalm of Life." Reading selections from "The Building of the Ship." Quotations from Longfellow's writings. first pupil. % When the wanderer, lonely, friendless, In foreign harbors shall behold That flag unfurled, Twill be as a friendly hand Stretched out from his native land, Filling his heart with memories sweet and endless.— .Patriotism. SECOND PUPIL, Though the mills of God grind slowly, Yet they grind exceeding small. Though with patience he stands waiting, With exactness grinds he all. — Retribution THIRD PUPIL. Intelligence and courtesy, Not always are combined. Often in a wooden house, A golden room we find. — Art and Tact FOURTH PUPIL. When by night the frogs are croaking, Kindle but a torch's fire, Ha! how soon they all are silent! Thus Truth silences the liar. — Truth. , FIFTH PUPIL. Live I, so live I, To my Lord heartily, To my Prince faithfully, To my Neighbor honestly, Die I, so die I. — Law of Life. SIXTH PUPIL. Henry Wadsworth Longfellow was born in Portland. Me., "The Forest City," on the 27th of February, 1807. He died March 24, 1882, at Cambridge, Massachusetts. (22) 1^ ongf ellow Day A fflft FEBRUARY 27 j[ </seg>
            <seg id="p027">From Pollard's Advanced Reader, published by the Western Publishing House, Chicago. HENRY W. LONGFELLOW. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Zi SEVENTH PUPIL. When he was fourteen, he entered Bowdoin College. While there he wrote to his father, "I will be eminent in something. I have a most voracious appetite for knowledge. To its acquisition, I will sacrifice everything." EIGHTH PUPIL. At the age of nineteen, he was appointed Professor of Modem Languages at Bowdoin College. To prepare for this position, he spent three years in study in Europe. NINTH PUPIL. At 27, he accepted a professorship in Harvard University. He made his home in Cambridge, in the "Old Craigie House," which had been the home of Washington, when he took command of the army. TENTH PUPIL . Among his lifelong friends were Sumner, Prescott, Hawthorne, Emerson, Agassiz, and Lowell. ELEVENTH PUPIL. He was a descendant of the John Alden and Priscilla Mullens, whose lives he wove into the beautiful Puritan romance, "The Courtship of Miles Stand - ish." TWELFTH PUPIL. Reading — Selections from "Courtship of Miles Standish." THIRTEENTH PUPIL. Two other loved American poems are "Evangeline" and "Hiawatha." FOURTEENTH PUPIL. Reading — Selections from "Evangeline." Singing -"The Arrow and the Song." FIFTEENTH PUPIL. He was early fond of reading. His favorite book was the Sketch Book of Washington Irving. He enjoyed only the best books of the best authors. Yet he wrote to his mother, "There is no book in which I read with so much in - terest and profit as one of your letters." SIXTEENTH PUPIL Longfellow was the poet of every-day life. He is one of our most popu - lar poets. SEVENTEENTH PUPIL. All common things, each day's events, That with the hour begin and end, Our pleasures and our discontents, Are rounds by which we may ascend EIGHTEENTH PUPIL. Honor to those whose words or deeds, Thus help us in our daily needs. And by their overflow, Raise us from what is low. NINETEENTH PUPIL. He loved children, and was loved by them. He is called the poet of childhood. TWENTIETH PUPIL. Recitation— "Come to Me, O Ye Children." </seg>
            <seg id="p029">24 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES TWENTY-FIRST PUPIL. He wrote his first verses at the age of thirteen. They appeared in the local paper. He was grieved to hear the criticism, " That poetry is very stiff. Besides, it is borrowed, every word." TWENTY-SECOND PUPIL. The heights by great men reached and kept, Were not attained by sudden flight; But they, while their companions slept, Were toiling upward in the night. TWENTY-THIRD PUPIL. Recitation—" Excelsior." TWENTY-FOURTH PUPIL. Among the world's favorite poems are his, -"The Village Blacksmith," "The Old Clock on the Stairs," "Paul Revere's Ride," "The Beleaguered City," and " The Footsteps of Angels." Recitation by School—" The Old Clock on the Stairs. TWENTY-FIFTH PUPIL. Recitation—" Paul Revere's Ride." TWENTY-SIXTH PUPIL. After visiting the Arsenal at Springfield, Mass., he wrote — Were half th power that fills " the world with terror," Were hal the wealth bestowed on camps and courts, Given to redeem the human mind from error, There were no need of arsenals and forts. TWENTY-SEVENTH PUPIL. He had a generous nature. Nobody was ever turned away from his home with a heavy heart. " When I cannot help the one who comes to me in trouble," he said, " I always keep him to dinner, and try to send him away in good spirits." TWENTY-EIGHTH PUPIL. A schoolgirl, a stranger, wrote for an original poem. " I could not writ** it," said Mr. Longfellow, " but I tried to say ' no so softly, that she would think it better than ' yes '." TWEVTY-NINTH PUPIL. In the height of his fame, when the great of Europe and America came to his house, he could take time to go to the Police Court, to get the fines of a poor German woman remitted for stealing some apples. THIRTIETH PUPIL. When so busy with work that he rose at five o'clock in the morning, he could take time to send off seventy-five autographs, because he could make people happy by so doing. THIRTY -FIRST PUPIL. Where'er a noble deed is wrought, Where'er is spoken a noble thought, Our hearts in glad surprise, To higher levels rise. THIRTY-SECOND PUPIL. His later years were brightened by many proofs of the children's affec - tion. THIRTY-THIRD PUPIL. When he was seventy-two, a lovely present came from the school children of Cambridge, an arm-chair made from wood of the horse-chestnut tree, under </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THE LONGFELLOW HOUSE, CAMBRIDGE. From the Children'! Second Reader, Cyr, published by Ginn &lt;t Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES ■ which the Village Blacksmith stood. The poem written for them was given to every child who came to see and sit in the chair. THIRTY-FOURTH PUPIL. Recitation— "The Children's Hour." THIRTY-FIFTH PUPIL. Themext year, fifteen thousand children of Cincinnati, celebrated the poet's birthday with recitations from his poems and si aging of his songs. He wrote them to live up to the best that is in them, so that their monument might be that of Euripides. THIRTY-SIXTH PUPIL. "This monument does not make thee famous, O Euripides, but thoumak - est the monument famous." THIRTY-SEVENTH PUPIL. His marble image stands in Westmister Abbey, in the Poet's Corner; but, better still, he lives in the hearts of the people of two hemispheres. THIRTY-EIGHTH PUPIL. His songs have power to quiet, The restless pulse of care. And come like the benediction, That follows after prayer. Close with volunteer stories gleaned from the poet's life. — The Teachers 1 World. a a The Building of the Ship (Extract.) THOU, too, sail on, O Ship of State! Sail on, O Union, strong and great! Humanity with all its fears, With all its hope of future years, Is hanging breathless on thy fate ! We know what Master laid thy keel, What workman wrought thy ribs of steel, Who made each mast, and sail, and rope, What anvils rang, what hammers beat, In what a forge, and what a heat Were shaped the anchors of thy hope! Kear not each sudden sound and shock, 'is of the wave and not the rock ; "is but the flapping of a sail, nd not a rent made by the gale ! l spite of rock and tempest's roar, In spite of false lights on the shore, Sail on, nor fear to breast the sea, Our hearts, our hopes, are all with thee, Ou hearts, our hopes, our prayers, our tears, Our faith triumphant o'er our fears Are all with thee; are all with thee. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">26 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Children COME to me, 0 ye children ! For I hear you at your play, And the questions that perplexed me Hare vanished quite away. Ye open the eastern windows, That look towards the sun, Where the thoughts are singing swallows And the brooks of morning run. In your hearts are the birds and sunshine, In your thoughts the brooklets flow, But in mine is the wind of autumn And the first fall of the snow. Ah, what would the world be to us If the children were no more? We should dread the desert behind us Worse than the dark before. What the leaves are to the forest With light and air for food, Ere their sweet and tender juices Hare been hardened into wood, That to the world are children ; Through them it feels the glow Of a brighter and sunnier climate Than reaches the trunks below. Come to me, O ye children ! And whisper in my ear What the birds and the winds are singing In your sunny atmosphere. For what are all our contrivings, And the wisdom of our books, When compared with your caresses, And the gladness of your looks? Ye are better than all the ballads That ever were sung or said, For ye are the living poems And all the rest are dead. 0 0 The Children's Hour BETWEEN the dark and the daylight, When the night is beginning to lower, Comes a pause in the day's occupations, That is known as the Children's Hour. I hear in the chamber above me The patter of little feet, The sound of a door that is opened, And voices soft and sweet. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 27 From my study I 8ee in the lamplight, Descending the broad hall stair, Grave Alice and laughing Allegra, And Edith with golden hair. A whisper, and then a silence : Yet I know by their merry eyes They are plotting and planning together To take me by surprise. A sudden rush from the stairway, A sudden raid from the hall ! By three doors left unguarded They enter my castle wall ! They climb up into ray turret O'er the arms and back of my chair; If I try to escape they surround me ; They seem to be everywhere. They almost devour me with kisses, Their arras about me entwine, Till I think of the Bishop of Bingen In his Manse-Tower on the Rhine. Do you think, 0 blue-eyed banditti, Because you have scaled the wall, Such an old mustache as I am *Is not a match for you all ! I have you fast in my fortress, And will not let you depart, But put you down into the dungeon In the round-tower of my heart. And there I will keep you forever, Yes, forever and a day. Till the walls shall crumble to ruin, And moulder in dust away. * # The Arrow and the Song I SHOT an arrow into the air, It fell to earth, I knew not where; For, so swift it flew, the sight Could not follow it in its flight. I breathed a song into the air, It fell to earth, I knew not where; For who has sight so keen and strong, That it can follow the flight of a song ? Long, long afterward, in an oak I found the arrow still unbroke ; And the song, from beginning to end I found again in the heart of a friend. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">28 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES The Old Clock on the Stairs SOMEWHAT back from the village street Stands the old fashioned country-seat. Across its antique portico Tall poplar- trees their shadows throw; And from its station in the hall An ancient timepiece says to all, — " Forever -never 1 Never — forever ! " Half-way up the stairs it stands, And points and beckons with its hands, From its case of massive oak, Like a monk, who, under his cloak, Crosses himself and sighs, alas ! With sorrowful voice to all who pass, " Forever — never ! Never — forever ! " By day its voice is low and light; But in the silent dead of night, Distinct as a passing footstep's fall, It echoes along the vacant hall, Along the ceiling, along the floor, And seems to say at each chamber door, — " Forever — never ! Never — forever ! " Through days of sorrow and of mirth, Through days of death and days of birth, Through every swift vicissitude Of changeful time, unchanged it stood, And as if, like God, it all things saw, It calmly repeats those words of awe, — ■ " Forever — never ! Never — forever ! " In that mansion used to be Free-hearted hospitality; His great fires up the chimney roared, The stranger feasted at his board; But like the skeleton at the feast, That warning timepiece never ceased,— " Forever — never ! Never— forever ! " There groups of merry children played. There youths and maidens dreaming strayed ; O precious hours ! O golden prime, And affluence of love and time ! Even as a miser counts his gold, Those hours the ancient timepiece told, — " Forever — never ! Never — forever ! " From that chamber, clothed in white, The bride came forth on her wedding night; There, in that silent room below, The dead lay in his shroud of snow; </seg>
            <seg id="p035">THE CHILDREN'S CHAIR. From the Children'! Second Reader, Cyr, published by Ginn &lt;fc Co </seg>
            <seg id="p036">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 29 To th February 2" Longfellow. And in the hush that followed the prayer, Was heard the old clock on the stair, — " Forever— never ! Never — forever ! " All are scattered now and fled, Some are married, some are dead ; And when I ask, with throbs of pain, "Ah ! when shall they all meet again?" As in the days long since gone by, The ancient timepiece makes reply, — " Forever — never ! Never — forever ! " a a From My Arm-Chair children of Cambridge, who presented to me, on my seventy-second birthday 1*79. this chair made from the wood of the Village Blacksmith's chestnut tree.- AM I a king, that I should call my own This splendid ebon throne? Or by what reason or what right divine, Can I proclaim it mine ? Only, perhaps, by right divine of song It may to me belong; Only because the spreading chestnut tree Of old was sung by me. Well I remember it in all its prime, When in the summer-time The affluent foliage of its branches made A cavern of cool shade. There, by the blacksmith's forge, beside the street, Its blossoms white and sweet Enticed the bees, until it seemed alive And murmured like a hive. And when the winds of autumn, with a shout Tossed its great arms about, The shining chestnuts, bursting from the sheath, Dropped to the ground beneath. And now some fragments of its branches bare, Shaped as a stately chair, Have by my hearthstone found a home at last And whisper of the past. The Danish king could not in all his pride Repel the ocean tide; But seated in this chair I can in rhyme, Roll back the tide of time. I see again, as one in vision sees, The blossoms and the bees, And hear the children's voices shout and call, And the brown chestnuts fall. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">30 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Co holds a I see the smithy with its fires aglow, I hear the bellows blow, And the shrill hammers on the anvil beat The iron white with heat ! And thus, dear children, have ye made for me This day a jubilee, And to my more than three-score years and ten Brought back my youth again. The heart hath its own memory, like tne mind, And in it are enshrined, The precious keepsakes, into which is wrought The giver's loving thought. Only your love and your remembrance could Give life to this dead wood, And make these branches, leafless now so long, Blossom again in song. — From the Children's Second Reader, Cyr, published by Ginn &lt;&amp; 0 a A Longfellow- Exercise (Each pupil learns one of the following stanzas from Longfellow's poems and large letter, printed on cardboard, in front of him and repeats his Terse.) LIFE is real ! life is earnest ! And the grave is not its goal. "Dust thou art, to dust returnest," Was not spoken of the soul. O STAR of strength 1 I see thee stand And smile upon my pain ; Thou beckonest me with thy mailed hand, And I am strong again. NOTHING useless is or low, Each thing in its place is best ; And what seems but idle show Strengthens and supports the rest. COD sent his singers upon earth, With songs of sadness and of mirth That they might touch the hearts of men, And bring them back to heaven. FOR, like strains of martial music, Their mighty thoughts suggest Life's endless toil and endeavor, And to-night I long for rest. EACH heart has its haunted chamber Where the silent moonlight falls ; On the floor are mysterious footsteps ; There are whispers along the walls. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">31 LABOR with what zeal we will Something 1 still remains undone, Something uncompleted still Waits the rising of the sun. LIVES of great men all remind us We can make our lives sublime, And, departing, leave behind us Foot-prints on the sands of time. O. FEAR not in a world like this, And thou shalt know ere long, — Know how sublime a thing it is To suffer and be strong. WE speak of friends and their fortunes And of what they did and said, Till the dead alone seem living And the living alone seem dead. — Arranged by D. C. Murphy, in The Moderator, </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Executive Cbamber, Xincoln, Hcbraefca. proclamation b? tbe Governor: C^*HE observance of Arbor Day has contributed in the I (j\ past in no small degree to the growth and improve- ment of Nebraska's forestry and foliage. It has transformed vast expanses of prairie into picturesque wood - land, increasing the landscape beauty of the state and making it more desirable for those seeking opportunities for invest - ment, and affording comfort and pleasure for those already here. This practice, which has added so much beauty and value to the state in the past, should not only be maintained in the future, but should be enlarged upon to the greatest practical extent. On each recurring Arbor Day every citizen of Nebraska should add at least one tree to our forestry and foliage, which shall serve the double purpose of being both commemorative and beneficial— commemorative of the mental genius of our distinguished citizen, Hon. J. Sterling Morton, author of Arbor Day, and beneficial in the way of increased comfort and value. By authority vested in me by law I therefore do hereby proclaim and designate Monday, April 22, 1901, as Arbor Day, and I earnestly request of the citizens of this State and all school children, to observe this oscasion by the planting of trees and beautifying shrubbery. In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto subscribed my name and caused to be affixed the Great Seal of the State of Nebraska. Done at Lincoln, the capital of the State of Nebraska, this fourth day of February, in the Year of Our Lord, 1901. Governor, CHARLES H. DIETRICH Attest GEO. W. MARSH, Secretary of State </seg>
            <seg id="p040">HOX. J. STERLING MORTON, OF NEBRASKA, THE FOfNDER OF ARBOR DAY. From hi» lalett photograph, taken especially for thi» Publication. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">THE erasure of forests and groves from the lands of the United States is nearing completion. All over the globe hillsides, valleys, and plains are being rapidly denuded. The consumption of forest products increases each day. During the last twenty-five years the vast pine forests of Michi - gan, Wisconsin, and Minnesota have vanished from view. The ax and the saw no longer find destructive employment within the dense forests of those states. Every twenty-four hours the American people consume the wood products of more than 25,000 acres of forests and groves. In view of these stupendous and startling facts, it behooves all citizens, especially teachers, to try to find a way of preventing entire forest denudation of the globe. The esthetic side of arboriculture has been illuminated in the schools and the literature of the country on every Arbor Day since 1872, when that anniversary began its beneficent career. Therefore, the opportunity for the utilitarian in tree-planting and tree-conserving has arrived. The wood - lands still left to us must be conserved. Waste places must be reafforested. Every intelligent American farmer must plant a reasonable area of his lands in forest trees. He must also carefully prune and care for whatsoever he may have left to him of woodlands. At the risk of parading a personal experience, to be characterized as egotism by critics, I briefly give the narrative of my own care of native for - ests and of the planted trees at Arbor Lodge. In June, 1856, 1 became a squatter upon a quarter section of land now known as Arbor Lodge. Out of 160 acres then claimed there were between 50 and 60 acres of brush and indigenous forest trees. Carefully the brush along the ravines and creek was cleaned out. The better shaped young trees were properly pruned. The old and decaying trees were cut down for fuel. For 45 years the trees upon the area named, together with trees planted and trimmed in orchards and in rows along drives, have furnished abundant fuel for domestic purposes and likewise thousands of fence posts for use about the place. The quarter section of land was selected because I thought that the timber growing upon it would in time more than pay the price I gave for it, which was $650 for the squatter's right to take the land and become a pre - emptor, and then $200 more in gold, or $1.25 an acre, paid to the Government of the United States for a clear title, when the land office opened at Omaha in April, 1857. During these 45 years ( now nearly 46 years), it is within bounds to say that, with the furnace, range, and open fire grates, there has been consumed each year $200 worth of fuel. This makes an income from the original patch of native timber, which has been properly conserved, of $9,000. And it is most agreeable to my judgment as to the possibilities of our native growths, to state with great satisfaction, that there is more good timber in that grove to - day than there was when I first saw it. In cutting out I have always first taken the dwarfed, maimed, or decaying trees of all varieties, and secondly, the pig-nut hickory. My experience proves that by careful and judicious management, a few acres of woodlands may be perpetuated as fuel-and-post-producers generation after generation. Planted groves may be made very useful and cause rough and untillable lands to become among the most profitable on the place. Seven to ten acres, 3 (33) RBOR DAY APRIL 2 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">34 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES planted in rows running north and south, four feet apart — the first row being of cottonwood, the next row of black walnuts, white oaks and shellbark hickory, and the third row of maple or box elder (or, better still, of catalpa speciosa ) will make through the right sort of thinning-out process, within five years from their planting, sufficient fuel for an ordinary household. All groves should be planted in rows running north and south. The hard - woods must be planted between the rows of soft woods which are generally rapidly growing trees. Thus the swiftly growing trees become nurses for the slowly growing nut-bearing trees between the rows. All trees reach upward for light, and when they are shaded from the eastern sun in the morning and the ■western in the afternoon, they make a much more rapid and vigorous up - right growth than when they stand out in the open plain surrounded by sun - light all day. These hints are thrown out hastily, as the Honorable Superintendent of Public Instruction, Mr. W. K. Fowler, well knows, because of a hurry-up telephone message received from him this afternoon. My intent is, if possible, to arouse practical men and women to the vast importance of forest conserva - tion and arboriculture in Nebraska and everywhere throughout the United States. J. Sterling Morton. Arbor Lodge, Nebraska City, Neb., January 29, 1901 a a Why Do We Observe Arbor Day? IN OUR relatively new country this question may arise. In the same line we may ask : Why did Alexander the Great plant with his own hands hundreds of trees in nearly every province of Russia in Europe ? Why did Charles II plant with his own hands nearly every tree in the avenue at Windsor? Why did George III have such a mania for tree planting ? Why did Queen Victoria personally superintend the planting of over 5,000 trees near London, and at places she visited ? Why has the Prince of Wales planted on public occasions so many trees at home and abroad ? Why are so many great arboretums and parks of vast extent maintained in all parts of Europe ? Why is every tree labeled with botanic and common name in public gardens, parks, and even public avenues ? Why are the elements of forestry and horticulture taught in the common schools of Germany? Why are so many forestry schools supported in every part of continental Europe? In all cases the purpose is to create a public sentiment favorable to tree planting, and to familiarize the people with the best species and varieties of trees and the best modes and methods of planting and managing them. During the past century the rulers and educators of Europe, from the king down to the common school teacher, have kept before the people these few primary facts in regard to trees, that our commerce, home shelters, furniture, machines, landscape effects, depend upon tree planting and forest preservation. Only this constant education of the masses would permit the maintenance of the rigid forest laws of nearly all continental Europe. It has been said that the Europeans may disagree on questions of politics, religion, etc., but on the forestry question, from prince to peasant, they agree that at least 33 J per cent of the entire area of the country must be kept in timber blocks properly distributed for economic nans and climatic effect. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">35 This public education also renders possible the system of fruit trees by the roadside, the beautiful little park and flower garden at the railway station, and tree and shrub groupings and effects everywhere, such as we cannot reach with our present public sentiment. To us this work is new. With a forest wealth in extent and number of valuable species not excelled on the earth, the first moves in the occupation of the continent have been in the way of wasteful forest destruction. But a new era is dawning. • In many ways that cannot here be enumer - ated we have commenced the good work which a century of growth has made nearly complete in parts of Europe. — J. L. Budd, Amet, Iowa. a a Springtime Air— "Auld Lang Syne." THE winter storms have passed away And springtime now is here With sunshine smiling all around, And heavens blue and clear. The gifts of Nature brighten earth, And make her garden gay ; They give a cheery greeting bright On this, the Arbor Day. The birds with gladsome voices sing Each its melodious lay, And music swells each little throat On this, the Arbor Day. The trees put forth their greenest leaves On this, the Arbor Day, And welcome now the chosen tree Which we shall plant to-day. — Ellen Beauchamp. a a The Gourd and the Palm (A Perstin Fable.) tCLTOW old art thou?" said a boastful gourd, JlJL As o'er the palm tree's crest it poured Its spreading leaves and tendrils fine, And hung a bloom in the morning's shine. "A hundred years!" the palm tree sighed; "And I," the saucy gourd replied, "Am at the most a hundred hours, Yet overtop thee in the bowers!" Through all the palm tree's leaves there went A tremor of self-content. " I live my life," it whispering said, " See what I see, and count the dead ; And every year, of all I've known, A gourd above my head has grown, And made a boast like thine to-day: Yet here /stand — but where are theyt" —Light* to Literature, by Rand, McXally &amp; Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">36 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES &gt; A Useful Gift ONE day wee Willie and his dog Sprawled on the nursery floor. He had a florist's catalogue, And turned the pages o'er. Till all at once he gave a spring, " Hurrah ! " he cried with joy; " Mamma, here's just the very thing To give your little boy ! " For when we fellows go to school, We lose our things, you know ; And in that vestibule They do get mixed up so. " And as you often say you can't Take care of 'em for me, Why don't you buy a rubber plant And an umbrella tree ? " — Caroline Wells, in St. Nicholas. 0 a When the Green Gits Bach in the Trees r IN the spring when the green gits back in the trees, And the sun comes out and stays, And your boots pull on with a good tight squeeze, And you think of your barefoot days; When you ort to work and you want to not, And you and your wife agrees It's time to spade up the garden lot- When the green gits back on the trees. Well, work is the least of my idees When the green, you know, gits back on the trees. When the green gits back in the trees, and bees Is a-buzzin' aroun' agin, In that kind of a " Lazy -go-as-you-please" Old gait they hum roun' in; When the ground's all bald where the hayrick stood And the crick's riz, and the breeze Coaxes the bloom in the old dogwood, And the green gits back in the trees— I like, I say, in such scenes as these, The time when the green gits back in the trees. When the whole tail feathers o' winter time Is all pulled out and gone, And the sap it thaws and begins to climb, And the sweat it starts out on A feller's forrerd, a-gittin' down At the old spring on his knees — I kind o' like jes' a loaferin' roun' When the green gits back in the trees— Jes' a-potterin' roun' as I-durn-please, When the green, you know, gits back in the trees. — James Whitcomb Riley. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SPECIAL. DAY EXERCISES 37 Motion Song— The Trees' Story BY THE PRIMARY CLASS Tune— "Comtn' Thro' the Rye. THE trees lift up their branches tall; Their leaves dance in the breeze; "Oh, ho!'' they sing, "for what care we? We're living at our ease." But presently the woodman conies, With axes sharp and bright, And choosing him a tall pine tree, He works with all his might. "Oh, see! the tree is falling now," It lies upon the ground ; The axes cut off each twig and bough, And round it chains are bound. Two horses pull the tree along Until a stream they find, On which the tree floats to the mill, Where waits the miller kind. He lays the log before the saw, And back and fourth it goes, Until the mill is full of boards That lie in long white rows. And then the children's father buys Shingles and beams and planks, To build his house for which we must Give tree and woodman thanks. — Grace Butterfield , in Little Men and Women. * * Song of Dedication Air— "Columbia, the Gem of the Ocean." THE tree we are planting this May day Is chosen with tenderest care; May beauty adorn it hereafter, And clothe it with usefulness rare. May green leaves appearing each springtime Be leaves of a fair book of fame, And spread to the breezes the story Extolling the new-given name. The tree is an emblem of greatness, As, springing from one tiny seed, It mounts ever upward and onward An emblem of greatness, indeed ! The birds sing the praises to others, The winds carry swiftly the tale, The tree is the monarch of forest, Of hill, valley, greenwood, and dale Ellen Beauchamp. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">38 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES The Heart of the Tree WHAT does he plant who plants a tree ? He plants a friend of sun and sky; Heplants the flag of breezes free; The shaft of beauty towering high; He plants a home to heaven anigh For song and mother-croon of bird In hushed and happy twilight heard — The treble of heaven's harmony — These things he plants who plants a tree. What does he plant who plants a tree ? He plants cool shade and tender rain, The seed and bud of days to be, And years that fade and flush again He plan ts the glory of the plain; He plants the forest's heritage; The harvest of a coming age ; The joy that unborn eyes shall see— These things he plants who plants a tree. What does he plant who plants a tree ? He plants, in sap and leaf and wood, In love of home and loyalty And far-cast thought of civic good — His blessing on the neighborhood Who in the hollow of this hand Holds all the growth of all our land— A nation's growth from sea to sea Stirs in his heart who plants a tree. — Henry C. Bunner, in The Century. 0 0 Italian Tree Day r'ALIANS appreciate a good thing if it is American. Our Arbor day, which has been a grand success in nearly every state in the Union, is being adopted by them with even more official enthusiasm than with us. The minister of public instruction, Professor Baccelli, has established " Tree Day," and the first ceremony was honored by the presence of the queen and upwards of 7,000 children took a part. These exercises were of so much importance that the London Times' special correspondent telegraphed this to the leading English paper: " Rome, November 21. " The interesting ceremony known as the ' Festa degli alberi,' or ' tree day,' took place this morning in the presence of Queen Margherita on the Via Latina. Some 7,000 children from various Roman schools took part in the ceremony, which consisted chiefly in planting a large number of young trees. 'Tree day' has been organized by Professor Baccelli, minister of public instruction, in order to instil into the minds of Italian children reverence tor, and a sense of the value of trees, and to stimulate the replanting of trees throughout Italy. Professor Baccelli deserves hearty congratulations upon his public -spirited initiative." Such interchange of educational ideas can but do much to bring nations into sympathetic activities and unify their domestic purposes.— Journal of Education. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">SPECIAL. DAY EXERCISES 39 A Little Planter DOWN by the wall where the lilacs grow, Digging away with a garden hoe, Toiling as busily as he can — Eagr and earnest, dear little man ! Spoon and shingle are lying by, With a bit of evergreen, long since dry. "What are you doing, dear?" I ask. Ted for an instant stops his task, Glances up with a sunny smile, Dimpling his rosy cheeks the while; " Why, it's Arbor Day, you see, And I'm planting a next year's Christmas tree; For last year, auntie, Johnny Dunn Didn't have even the smallest one, And I almost cried, he felt so bad, When I told him 'bout the splendid one we had ; And I thought if I planted this one here, And watered it every day this year, It would grow real fast — I think it might ; ( His blue eyes filled with eager light ; i And I'm sure 'twill be, though very small, A great deal better than nothing at all." Then something suddenly comes between My eyes and the bit of withered green, As I kiss the face of our Teddy boy, Bright and glowing with giving's joy, And Johnny Dunn, it is plain to see, Will have his next year's Christmas tree. a a Planting Trees For four little boys FREDDY. IF we are all to choose and say What trees we'd like to plant to-day, Seems to me None can be Half so good as a Christmas tree! For surely even a baby knows That's where the nicest candy grows, Candy on a Christmas tree — That's what pleases me! CHARLEY. Planted out 'twould never bear — But after all why should we care ? The richest thing Is what we bring From sugar maples in the spring. So, now I'll set a Maple here, For feast and frolic every year Sugar from a maple tree — That's what pleases me ! </seg>
            <seg id="p048">40 • WILLIE. Sweets are good most any day, But as for trees, I'm bound to say, A shag -bark tall Is best of all When once the nuts begin to fall. And so a Hickory tree I'll set And piles of nuts and fun I'll get. Nuts from a hickory tree — That's what pleases me ! JOHNNY. I shall plant an apple tree, That's the best of all for me; And each kind To suit my mind On this one with grafts I'll bind. Ripe or green, the whole year through, Pie or dumpling, bake or stew, Every way I like 'em best, And I'll treat the rest! — Eudora S. Bumstead. 0 a Part Recitation with Motions (BY THE LITTLE ONES.) ALL. Fingers tapping desks.) Patter, patter comes the rain, Over hill and over plain. FIRST ROW OF PUPILS. Clasp hands in front, false them gradually, till fall circle is formed Higher, higher climbs the sun, Now our spring is just begun. SECOND ROW. Motion as if scattering Beeds in aisles.) Scatter, scatter seeds once more, Now that winter days are o'er. THIRD ROW. Both hands on desks raised gradually to full length, all rows same motion Upward, upward into light Creep the shoots, tall and upright. FOURTH ROW. Motion: arms still raised, swaying from right to left. Boughs are swaying to and fro, As the breezes come and go. FIFTH ROW. (Arms lowered gradually to desks; fingers moving to represent fluttering blossoms Blossoms sweet with perfume rare, Flutter down through soft warm air. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">A WOODLAND SCENE. From the Children'! Fourth Reader, Cyr, Ginn &amp; Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 11 SIXTH ROW. (Hands raised as in the act of catching ) Now catch the fruit of red and yellow, In the fall when ripe and mellow. ALL. Hands gently clasped as If guarding the seed. We guard the seed to plant next year, That fruit for all may then appear. — Journal of Education. 0 0 Arbor Day Exercises Decorations. — Secure stencils of the Charter Oak, Washington Elm, and California Giants. Draw in colors upon the board a border or branch of oak and acorns, or pine and cones. Upon rustic fruit-stands place ferns or palms. Hanging baskets of vines at the win - dows add to the beauty of the room. Arbor Day Song THE breezes of spring wave the tree-tops The flowers so sweet bloom again, O, joyfully birds sing of springtime, While flying o'er mountain and glen. Chorus : Sing here, sing there, Sing of the springtime to-day, to-day. Sing here, sing there, Sing of the springtime to-day. O, glorious country of freedom ! Our lives we will make pure and sweet Thou givest to us this bright springtime With hearts full of love we now greet. Chorus. Then shout for the oak in the Northland, And answer, O South, with the palm. And we who inherit this Union Sing gaily our Nation's great psalm. Chorus. Suggestive Poems Bryant.— Inscriptions for the Entrance to a Wood, A Forest Hymn, Among the Trees, Autumn Woods, A Winter Piece, The Planting of the Apple Tree. Holmes. — Spring, Under the Washington Elm, Spring has Come. Longfellow. —An April Day, Spring, The Hemlock Tree, Selections from Hiawatha's Sailing. Lowell.— To a Pine Tree, The Oak. The Birch Tree, Sunthin' in the Pastoral Line (beginning, " First comes the blackbirds," ending, " Barb'ry droops its strings o' golden flowers " ), The Maple. Whittier. — Funeral Tree of Sokosis, April, The Pine Tree, A Dream of Summer, The Mayflowers, The First Flowers. Air, " My Bonnie." </seg>
            <seg id="p051">42 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Historic Trees (Exercise for nine pupils.) FIRST PUPIL. We sing of trees, historic, old, That swayed before the breeze; No trees in our broad land have seen More memorable deeds than these. The Charter Oak SECOND PUPIL. A Royal Charter was obtained In sixteen sixty-two; The Colonies of Connecticut A bond of union drew. When Andros came with sixty men The Charter to revoke, Brave Captain Wadsworth hid it safe Within the Charter Oak. —R. C. Adam* THIRD PUPIL. They love their land because it is their own, And scorn to give aught other reason why; Would shake hands with a king upon his throne And think it kindness to his majesty. Fits- Greene Halleck Elm at Philadelphia FOURTH PUPIL. Penn, a treaty with Indians made, 'Neath a spacious, tall elm tree, "While sun, moon, and stars endure, In peace we'll live with thee." These were the words of the Indian chief, In sixteen-eighty-three. In Philadelphia this chartered right Was made 'neath a tall elm tree. FIFTH PUPIL. Long as thine Art shall love true love, Long as thy Science truth shall know, Long as thine Eagle harms no dove, Long as thy Law by law shall grow, Long as thy God is God above, Thy brother every man below— So long, dear Land of all my love, Thy name shall shine, thy fame shall glow. — Sidney Lanier. 8ECTH PUPIL. I speak of the elm at Cambridge, Where Washington took command ; And that vast army true and brave, Now liberty for our land. With muskets clean and courage true, In seventeen seventy-five, Our men marched valiantly to fight, For Liberty each did strive. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">"Special day exercises 43 SEVENTH PUPIL. When the battle is won, And the land from traitors free, Our children shall tell of the strife begun, When liberty's second April sun Was bright on our brave old tree. —Holme* The Apple Tree of Appomattox EIGHTH PUPIL The Army of North Virginia Was yielded by Robert Lee In eighteen hundred sixty-five Near the famous apple tree. Near Appomattox's old Court-House, Arms, artillery, all, Was ceded to Grant that April day With slavery's great downfall. NINTH PUPIL. The change for Which he prayed and sought, In that sharp agony was wrought; No partial interest draws its alien line Twixt North and South, the cypress and the pine. The sword was sheathed; in April's sun Lay green the fields by Freedom won, And several sections, weary of debates, Joined hands at last and were United States. — WhiMer ALL REPEAT: Hurrah for the oak, the apple and elm! Hurrah for all these trees! No trees in our broad land have seen More stirring deeds than these. 'All sing to air " Battle Hymn of the Republic." The beauty of the stately trees We sing aloud to-day. These stirring deeds of history In loving hearts shall stay. For peace and love and Union Evermore we now will pray, As we go marching on ! Glory! glory! hallelujah! Glory! glory! hallelujah! Glory! glory! hallelujah! His truth is marching on! —Ella M. Powers </seg>
            <seg id="p053">44 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Drill [ The following may be given by six girls. Each wears a crown made of colored leaves (cut from paper). Around her waist she wears a bright scarf of scrim (of the color of the crown) . In her hand each carries a branch of laurel. J of the color of the FIRST PUPIL. Green crown and sash.) A STATELY elm with leaves of green, O'er-spreading far on high Its canopy of fresh spring leaves, All hail the elm 1 I cry. SECOND PUPIL. (Crown of pink and pink sash.) I'd crown the peach with blossom pink And fruit so luscious sweet; Bending low the pale pink buds Of the peach tree, I would greet. THIRD PUPIL. (Crown of white and white sash. A crown for the cherry blossom pure, With its little petals, white ; A pure white carpet nature dons : "Tis a rare and happy sight. FOURTH PUPIL. (Red crown and sash.) The early maples in the swamp, So bright, so red are they, My eye delights to gaze on these Throughout the fresh spring day. FIFTH PUPIL. (Gray crown and sash.) And I the catkins seek and love With early buds of gray ; Each silvery bud this new-born spring, Seems dearer every day. SIXTH PUPIL. (Yellow crown and sash.) The leaves of yellow birch I like, All fluttering in the breeze, Turning, twisting, chasing fast And quivering as they please. ALL REPEAT. We have a crown for every tree, And beg each tree to stay; Our boughs, unchanging as our hearts, All wave this Arbor Day. Music, ''Marching through Georgia." Branches wave and the six girls march around In a circle, each depositing her bough on a rustic flower-stand. Sashes (which have been tied about the waist but loosely) are untied and grasped In the hands about six inches from the ends. All stand In line. Music changes to " Hail Columbia." 1. Sash held in front horizont - ally, arms' length. 2. Sash held against waist horizontally. Repeat four times. 3. Sash held above the head at arms' length horizontally. 4. Sash resting on head, held horizontally Repeat four times. 5. Hold sash perpendicularly at right side. 6. Sash raised horizontally above head. Repeat four times. 7. Sash held perpendicularly at left side. 8. Sash raised horizontally at left side. Repeat four times. Repeat the same motions while kneeling. Repeat first movement, followed by the third, four times. Repeat second movement, followed by the fourth, four times. Repeat fifth movement, followed by the seventh, four times. Repeat sixth movement, followed by eighth, four times. All rise, passing out to music. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES V. What We Owe Trees * •¥XID you ever stop to think how much we owe to trees ? Let us see. MJ You have learned in school that trees purify the air by taking out of it teases which are hurtful to man, and also that they purify the springs of water at their roots; consequently you understand why it is that terrible fevers have so often followed the cutting down of forests in a new country. But do you know, too, that the health-giving quality of trees is only one of their many virtues? Not the least of these is the prevention of floods, and the drouths which follow floods. You will wonder how this is. Now you know that if you hang out a piece of wet cloth in the sun and wind it will become quickly dry. The water in it has evaporated. So it is with the open spaces where there are no trees. And the moisture which has all at once been absorbed by the air is discharged in torrents instead of in gentle rains, as would be th ecase if there were trees and it was absorbed gradually. Here again comes in the question of health, for floods and drouths are as hurtful to man as the soil which suffers from them. A way in which trees help us greatly, which is not often thought of, is, by preventing so great extremes of heat and cold as there would otherwise be. Your geographies tell you how the ocean equalizes the climate of places upon it. It is upon the same principle that trees modify climate, though in a lesser degree. Their effect upon desert land should be spoken of as well. It has been ound that, where trees have been planted to keep off the winds of the ocean rom such land, in a short time crops could be raised. This is because the inds take up moisture very quickly. When they cease to blow, therefore, r blow less hard, the rainfall is increased. Indeed, it has been thought that ven the terrible Sahara desert itself, might be made fertile by planting trees, t is known that springs of water in the oases disappear if the trees are for any reason destroyed, and also that new springs appear in the spots where ley have been made to grow. None, perhaps, can appreciate so fully their loveliness and charm as those who have crossed the desert plains of the great West. How the passengers on the overland train crowd about the little plats of grass (carefully guarded by iron fences), where trees are growing, while such exclamations as "Oh! don't they look good?" "How it rests one to see those trees!" "I never appreciated trees before ! " are heard on every side. Now of their use as homes for birds and animals. See that nest on the top bough ? Hear those robins twittering from the leafy sprays above our heads, while from bough to bough dart the nimble squirrels, peering at us with sharp eyes as much as to say,—" 0. you poor people, you have to be shut up in boards and bricks and roofings. You are to be pitied ! Don't you envy us, and wish you were as free as we ? " And the woodpecker taps, taps away on the old trunk industriously getting his dinner. Ah, these, our lesser brothers and sisters, would be bereft indeed were they deprived of their leafy habitations I— Eleanor Root. 0 0 Carl Morton's Orchard *¥*HE death of Carl Morton, which has caused so much sympathy to go out M. from the people of Nebraska to his bereaved father, recalls the beauti - ful incident recently recorded by J. Sterling Morton in the Conservative ronce reprinted in these columns. It was entitled " His Orchard ": It was a bright, balmy morning in April more than a quarter of a century ago. The sun was nursing the young grass into verdure, and the prairie was just beginning to put off its winter coat of sombre colorings. Tranquil skies </seg>
            <seg id="p055">46 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES and morning mists were redolent at Arbor Lodge of the coming resurrection of the foliage and flowers that died the autumn before. All about the cottage home there was hope and peace; and everywhere the signs of woman's watoh - ful love and tidy care, when suddenly, toned with affectionate solicitude, rang out: "Carl, Carl! " but no answer came. Down stairs, up stairs, at the barn, even in the well, everywhere, the mother's voice called anxiously, again and again. But the silence, menacing and frightening, was unbroken by an an - swer from the lost boy. At last, however, he was found behind a smoke house, busily digging in the ground with a small spade, though only five years of age, and he said: " I'm too busy to talk. I'm planting an orchard," and sure enough he had set out a tiny seedling apple tree, a small cottonwood, and a little elm. The delighted mother clasped him in her arms, kissed him and said: "This orchard must not be destroyed." And so now " I hear the muffled tramp of years Come stealing up the slopes of Time; They bear a train of smiles and tears Of burning hopes and dreams sublime." The child's orchard is more than thirty years of age. The cottonwood is a giant now, and its vibrant foliage talks, summer after summer, in the even - ing breeze with human-like voice, and tells its life story to the graceful, sway - ing elm near by, while the gnarled and scrubby little apple tree, shaped, as to its head, like a despondent toadstool, stands in dual shade, and bears small sweet apples, year after year, in all humility. But that orchard must not be destroyed. It was established by the youngest tree planter who ever planted in this tree planter's state, and for his sake and the memory of the sweet soul who nursed and loved him, it lives and grows, one cottonwood, one apple tree, one elm. " But O, for the touch of a vanished hand, And the sound of a voice that is still." The memories that live and bloom in trees, that whisper of the loved and lost in summer leaves, are as imperishable as the seasons of the year — im - mortal as the love of a mother.— Nebraska State Journal. a a An Arbor Day Symposium WE submit herewith the views of many of the state superintendents of our beloved country on the subject of Arbor Day, written expressly for this publication by request of the state superintendent of Nebraska. The ingenious teacher can use these expressions in an exercise, representing a Congress of these states, with each state represented by a pupil who shall express the views of the superintendent of his state. Nebraska's representa - tive may act as chairman, reading the Governor's proclamation, or come in in alphabetical order, using a part of the Hon. J. Sterling Morton's excellent letter. a a Arkansas ««*T*HE groves were God's first temples," and, to the lover of nature, A nothing is more restful, more suggestive of that quiet dignity, and power, and grandeur that should mark the highest type of human kind than a brotherhood of venerable trees. In the springtime, when the woodland sprites are clothing the forests in vernal foliage, and the life-bearing current is forcing its way through trunk, </seg>
            <seg id="p056">and branch, and twig, they tell of the glorious dawn of nope that springs from the source eternal and kindles anew in every aspiring breast the desire to do and dare and rise triumphant from the ashes of defeat. In summer, when sun, and wind, and storm, have added new strength and beauty to their growth, they show forth the power that unity and steadfast purpose have in developing, by slow degrees, all that is best and noblest in our being. When autumn colors, by unseen artists used, have tinged their leafy garb with most varied and attractive hues, and boughs are bending 'neath the fruit - age of which the early blossoms gave fair promise, in voiceless, yet eloquent appeal, they urge that man shall strive to be rich in yield of fruit as fair, when western suns mark his declining years. When winter, cheerless and sombre, wraps their forms and leaves them bereft of all that erstwhile made them so rich in beauty and so freighted with the wealth of yet ungathered harvests, they bid us learn of them ; so that, when, earth's labor over, we, too, shall stand stripped of all that wealth, or worth, or beauty gave, ready to be ushered into the great beyond, others shall gather inspiration from our labors, now ended, and life's highest aim to them shall be to bless and benefit the time and place that know them. J. J. DOYNE. 0 0 Colorado TTOW much of our enjoyment of nature and our appreciation of its beauty, 1JL how much of the universal exhilaration in the abounding life of spring, are due to the trees it would be impossible to estimate. Let us not neglect the cultivation of the esthetic and moral perceptions of the subject, while impressing the practical. A great, refining, ennobling influence is brought into a child's life with an enthusiasm for planting, tending, and watching the growth of flowers, vines, and trees, and sympathetic inspiration to such work on the teacher's part can hardly fail to communicate this enthusiasm. Mrs. Helen L. Grenfell. 0 0 Illinois WHY not have a small tree nursery connected with your school ? Get per - mission of the directors to fence off a corner of the school grounds for that purpose. Prepare the ground with intelligent care. Plant seeds of the elm, maple, wild cherry, oak, and walnut as soon as they ripen. Sow thickly. Thin them out when necessary. Cultivate them as you would a garden. Study them as they are growing. This is the way to know, and one way to learn to love trees. By-and-byyou can supply young trees for "Arbor Day" to all the neighborhood. Plant trees, and protect their growth. You will thereby increase the wealth of the State and reform and ennoble the lives of her children. " Plant; Life does the rest! " Your Arbor Day will not be a complete festival if you forget the birds and flowers. If the groves were " God s first temples," the birds must surely have been the first choristers, and the good "Autocrat " said that " The Amen! of Nature is always a flower." Plant flowers, then, and teach th*&gt; children tocare for them, and to welcome and protect those most sensitive and beautiful of all nature's children, the singing birds. Make your Arbor Day Festival instructive, inspiring, ennobling, and follow it up by a more intelli - gent and loving study of Nature in all her varied forms. You can do the State no higher service. Alfred Batliss. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">48 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Indiana THE observance of Arbor Day in the schools of the country is partly the result of a conviction that in the education of children something more than a knowledge of the text-books is necessary. Nature is a wonder - ful worker, and no one can watch her and learn of her ways without realizing that she has much to teach that cannot be found in books. The time was when it was thought that all education came through the study of books, but now it is almost universally recognized that one may know a great deal of books and yet have missed some of the best things in education. Too many people go through the monotony of their daily occupations without seeing the beauty that not only brings cheer but gives wisdom. Such persons do not know how to aid nature in keeping the world beautiful, but often retard her by doing injury to trees, plants, and shrubs. They are unconscious of the power that lies in a lovely flower, a stately tree, or a graceful vine, to influ - ence life and mold character. Arbor Day has come again to remind us that we can do much to make the scenes about us more attractive. If we all make an effort to place trees, shrubs, and plants into the school grounds, it will be only a few years until some of the yards which are now desolate will be transformed into places which all will admire. When we have done our part, and the branches of the trees begin to spread themselves, even a very little, the birds will come, and when they are sure that they can stay with safety, nests will be built. In at least one school yard in the United States squirrels play on the same ground with the children with no fear of harm. It is hoped that you will take an in - terest in the planting of trees, and that you will then trVto encourage the birds to build their nests near the school house. Frank L. Jones. a a Indian Territory *V*HE average Indian possesses a high regard for trees. He may be said JL to reverence them. He never destroys them except as he finds it neces- sary to use them. Neither does he look with favor upon the action of the white man who relentlessly destroys the trees to make room for crops. The noble red man sees in such acts the destruction of his hunting grounds. In his journeys, the Indian uses certain trees as guide posts ana they are frequently used instead of corner stones, to define the boundaries of their claims or tracts of land. The Indian considers trees as living, growing beings, and when the avaricious white man destroys his forests, he feels lone - some — feels that some of his dear friends and associates are gone. Yes, indeed, the Indian is heartily in favor of your Arbor Day movement and hopes that the time will soon come when every paleface who cuts or destroys a tree will be required to plant another in its stead. John D. Benedict. a a Iowa WOULD you rear a monument more noble than marble and more endur - ing than granite? Plant a tree that may furnish shade for the weary or fruit for the hungry in future years. "Heaven and earth will help»him who plants a tree; And his work its own reward shall be. May the spirit of Arbor Day pervade the entire year, and may we all be stronger in heart and purpose for its proper observance. Richard C. Barrett. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 1-J Kansas &lt; ARBOR DAY should be appropriately observed by the schools. Children should be taught to plant trees upon the schoolhouse grounds, and at- tention should be called to the many beautiful lessons that nature teaches us. The schoolhouse grounds and the immediate surroundings should be made as inviting as possible. It requires but very little effort to do this. Unfortunately many schoolhouse grounds are bleak, and barren, and without a tree or bush. Such conditions should not be allowed to exist. A few trees not only afford shade for the pupils, but give relief to the landscape. Nature's beauties are God's imperishable gifts to the children of men. I firmly believe that we should not only encourage the children to plant trees on Arbor Day, but we should teach them to care for them in order that they may "grow and grow all the summer day." Frank Nelson. a a Maine PHYSICAL surroundings are either a means of grace or the efficient cause of degradation. Groves were God's first temples, and trees are God's greatest silent teachers. What the local community does for the local school is worth more than all ihat can be done for the school by the State. Our interest depends largely upon our efforts and sacrifices. We have talked too much about the school; the schools will be better when we do enough for them so that we talk about my school. W. W. Stetson. a a Maryland NEBRASKA is the mother of Arbor Day. She can with peculiar appro - priateness celebrate its next observance by rendering a program which is more than local in its make-up, and which will arouse national inter - est. Maryland schools share the spirit so manifest in Nebraska to increase the usefulnsss of Arbor Day celebrations. Aside from any consideration of their beauty and comfort, the trees of our schoolhouse grounds are factors which enter into the healthfulness of the school locality. It is a well-known fact that the tree feeds upon the gases and poisonous matter exhaled from the human lungs. They rob the air of these impurities and make it fit for our pupils' use. We should protect them and increase their number if for no other reason than from the health standpoint. We can hardly dissociate from the care of the tree, the protection of our birds. The school children must take up and carry on this important work also. M. B. Stephens. a a Michigan THE planting of trees on Arbor Day should be, and is an exercise of vast importance, not only from an economical point of view, but in the stimulating of a spirit of patriotism shown by the earnest thoughtful - ness for the generations to follow; but it should be remembered that there is more virtue in keeping a tree alive after it has been planted, than in the first planting. If pupils in our public school are allowed to neglect a plant re - quiring attention, water to drink, food to nourish it, they are learning lessons which dull the sensibilities and lower the moral standard, the effect of which will be felt throughout life. I am most heartily in sympathy with, and am glad to encourage your plan. Delos Fall. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">50 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES » Missouri THOUSANDS of rural schools in Missouri are located on beautiful blue grass lawns, shaded by hardy native forest trees. Many school premises are on bleak prairies, unprotected from heat or storm. Our children are naturally lovers of nature, and are learning, in regular school lessons, to beautify school grounds. Missouri has an association of boys and girls known as "Vine, Vegetable, and Flower Growers." As results of this movement, both school and home premises have been greatly ornamented by growing vines on porches, fences, walls, and stumps; many waste places, more particularly at home, have been converted into gardens, and nice crisp vegetables put on the market by chil - dren ten and twelve years old ; potted plants adorn the windows of schools and homes in fall and winter, and their yards in spring and summer. W. T. Carrington. # * New Jersey To the School Children of Nebraska: I AM glad that through the courtesy of your state superintendent, I am to have a word to say to you on Arbor Day. The importance of this day is now so generally recognized that it is observed in the schools of nearly every state and territory in the Union, and you have learned to look forward to it with increasing interest and pleasure. The trees are indeed most valu - able to us. Throughout the year they bring us kindly ministries. Though indebted to the trees for so much, it seems to me that while caring for them we should also have a thought for those who are both their friends and ours. I am sure you will agree with me in thinking that the birds are just as near and dear to us as the trees, and that it is also our duty to do all that we can to protect them. They not only appeal to what is best in us and serve to strengthen our love of the good and beautiful, but add much to the brightness and cheer of our daily life. They also help us all they can in our warfare against the insect pests which do more or less harm to about every - thing that grows upon the lawn, the farm, or in the garden. When the birds are such good friends of ours, what a strange and unnatural thing it is for any of us to be enemies of theirs ! How cruel for any of us to rob or tear down a nest built with so much labor and care ! To destroy the home in which they expected to rear their little ones and which is just as dear to them as our homes are to us ! How wicked for anyone with sling-shot, toy rifle, or firearms to kill them ! To take the one glad, free, precious life to them given ! What a shallow and heartless vanity to wear the feathers, the wings, and sometimes the entire plumage of our most beautiful and useful birds as ornaments. Those who do so, not only advertise their approval of their merciless slaughter, but furnish its direct cause. Those who make the demand are more than equal partners in guilt with the hunters, who provide the pitiful supply. " Ah ! life, and joy, and song, depend upon it, Are costly trimmings for a woman's bonnet. " If the wholesale destruction of our feathe'-ed friends is to continue, the time will soon come when you will no longer be waked by bird-song in the morning, and when you shall stroll through the fields and woods the bright and happy form of life which gives them their greatest charm will be absent. I have however great hopes for the birds, if all the boys and girls in our public schools shall take a proper interest in them and learn to appreciate their beauty and usefulness. This would give these most beautiful, innocent, </seg>
            <seg id="p060">51 and helpless of God's creatures at least one champion and friend in nearly every home. As your state was the first to establish Arbor Day, I hope it may also be the first to require the observance of Bird Day in connection with it. ' With best wishes for the welfare of both the birds and yourselves, and also for the success of your exercises on Arbor Day. C. J. Baiter. 41 &lt;* Pennsylvania THE benefits which result from Arbor Day are easily shown. The obser - vance of this day has led to the planting of millions of trees. It has made the rising generation familiar with the uses and the charms of our forests. It has drawn attention to the value of trees for shade, for fruit, and for the arts. Very many of the pupils of our public schools have learned how the reckless and wanton destruction of forests may ruin, and has ruined, some of the richest countries on earth. They have learned that coal and water are the chief sources of the mechanical power which lies at the basis of our industrial prosperity. They have been taught that the vegetable growth in geological ages was transformed into the coal, which is so useful in the warming of our houses, in the preparation of our food, in the lighting of our cities, and in the running of our machinery. They have been taught the rela - tion of trees to our water supply, without which neither man, nor his crops, nor his beasts of burden can survive. They have been taught that a sufficient flow of water can only be preserved by preserving the forests on our hillsides and mountain tops, and that the roots of the trees help to hide it away in the depths of the earth until it is needed. Nathan C. Schaeffer. * # South Carolina ARBOR DAY is becoming more and more a part of the school exercises in our state. Our foremost teachers devote much time to it, imbued with the idea of the preservation of our forestry and the stimulation of a de - votion to trees and shrubbery. We are not very far advanced so far as results are concerned, for it is only within the past few years that we have been pay - ing attention to Arbor Day, yet some good has been done and the idea is growing. John J. McMahan. # * Wisconsin THE observance of Arbor and Bird Day in the public schools has grown out of the conviction of the people that in the education of children something more is necessary than a knowledge of books. This day comes just when the birds, following close upon the heels of the retreating winter, seem in their glad notes to be exulting over the defeat of the forces of the frost king, and the breaking of the icy fetters with which he has bound the earth. At the same time they are sounding paeans of joy, over nature's new birth as shown in purling brooks, leaping rivers, and rippled lakes, smiling in the face of the springtime sun, like the smile of childhood responsive to the mother's loving glance and caressing touch ; as shown by the emerald green of grassy fields and leafy woods, and the unfolding flowers which, like gems of beauty, dot hillside, plain, and valley, bursting into lifr under the magic touch of spring. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">B SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES As the spring is the time of awakening life, the advance herald of the full rounded year, the budding promise of later fruitage, so the observance of Arbor and Bird Day in the schools should be the occasion for the awakening thoughts, ideals, and interests which shall unfold and ripen into deeper rev - erence for life in its myriad forms, into wider sympathies, into gentler man - ners, into love of nature's beauties, and into nobler character. As the spring - time is but the promise, the beginning of what the later year is to realize', as it must be followed by the heat and by the refreshing rains of summer, and by the cool of autumn, so the exercises in the school on Arbor and Bird Day should be but the promise, the beginning of what is to be realized in the child's development throughout the year. The lessons and suggestions of this day are but the seeds which need for their unfolding, development, and final fruitage, the life-giving rain and glow - ing warmth of intelligent, persistent effort by the enthusiastic, nature-loving, child-loving teacher in an appeal to the emotional nature of the child, fol - lowed later by the cool reasoning which justifies this appeal. L. D. Harvey 4 * New YorR ARBOR DAY celebrations are instituted not to glory over things achieved, but to consider and take heart for the achievement of things we have neglected; to create and stimulate proper sentiment regarding our duties as true citizens in one particular direction, namely: To secure an enlightened consideration and treatment of trees and forests. To the man who bases his action on mere reasoning of cause and effect, who sees that the enormous drain on our forest resources must soon exhaust the virgin supplies, that the denudation of hills and mountains leads to uncer - tain water stages, to deterioration of agricultural lands, who realizes the great economic importance of a rational use of our forest resources, to him the idea of remedying the evil by Arbor Day celebrations appears indeed inadequate. But the world is not moved as much by knowledge and reason as we are apt to think. Our conduct, even in our individual lives, falls short of fulfill - ing the dictates of knowledge and reasoning. Much less does our progress in corporate capacity as communities and states depend solely on these attributes of the mind. The great mass is moved by emotion rather than by reason, by the heart rather than by the head, by sentiment rather than Dy argument. Hence, reforms which appeal directly to our sentiments are comparatively easily accomplished, and even reform movements of an economic nature, such as the forestry movement, instead of appealing only to the judgment, will find it advantageous to stir up the emotions, the interests of the heart, to educate proper sentiment which leads to action. It is for this purpose, I take it, that Arbor Days are instituted, namely, to stimulate our sentiment on behalf of a higher civilization, of better things, to arouse our feelings against existing abuses, and to create an appreciation for tree-growth, be it from an economic point of view or that of beauty. It is a day designated to take your mind and heart away from the busy life, the narrow horizon between brick walls, into the forest, to contemplate its fate, to consider its needs, to arouse in you a sentiment which will lead you to active co-operation in reforming our present treatment of the same. There are two points of view from which we may look upon the forestry movement; the one which the thinking lumberman and forest owner would or should take, considering only the perpetuation of supplies of useful material which the forest resources yield; and the other, a broader one, which the statesman and every patriotic citizen is bound to take in addition, namely, </seg>
            <seg id="p062">53 considering the role which the forest plays as a factor in our civilization, as a general condition of our country, which, if altered in an irrational manner, invariably leads to the misery of the whole community. The fact that forest destruction has a most detrimental effect upon the flow of our rivers, upon the conditions of our agricultural lands, upon climate and health to some extent, makes the forestry question one of general inter - est to the community, and the fact that these influences upon other cultural conditions can rarely, if ever, concern the private forest owner who is inter - ested only in the profit which he can draw from his property, makes it neces - sary for the community itself, or its agent, the state, to look out for its own interests, present and future. For the state alone is as long-lived as the forest; the individual lives for to-day, the community may even outlive the old Sequoias, and hence must guard the conditions of its future welfare. There are many questions, commercial, financial, municipal, which agitate the public mind, that if left alone either adjust themselves, or whose adjustment can be deferred without detriment. Whether the tariff be high or low, whether gold or silver be the standard, whether we have a large ship - ping fleet, or let the English carry our goods, these are all matters which we can decide at any time, and any evil consequences resulting from a mistaken policy can be rectified in a few years. But whether the fertile lands are turned into deserts, forests into waste places, brooks into torrents, rivers changed from means of intercourse and power into means of destruction and desolation, these are questions of much more immediate importance, which must be considered and solved at the proper time. As slowly as the evils of forest destruction become apparent, just so slowly only can they be repaired, and often they become irremediable. Delay in adjusting private and communal interests in the forest-cover invariably lead to disaster. All European nations have learned this lesson. They know that to leave the mountain forest unreservedly to the exercise of private property rights is bound to bring misfortune, not only to the moun - tains, but to the plains below, to the country in general. Miserable farms, with more than half their agricultural soil lost by ero - sion, furtowed and gullied and washed, all in consequence of irrational clear - ing of mountains and hillsides, are found in al! parts of the Union, and especially in the Southern and Middle States; and in the Prairie States it is now so well known that a shelter belt against the constant drying winds is a welcome protection, that no advocacy for planting it should be needed. But while these protective featuies of a forest -cover are not to be under - rated, it has also become plain that supplies of wood material, this most essential factor of our civilization next to food crops, are waning; that the natural forests show signs of exhaustion and that a new crop must be started and fostered. Arbor Days should be used to impress this fact upon the minds of those who celebrate them. The need of wood supplies is, indeed, more essential than the beauty, adornment, and shelter which trees give. Trees must be cut as well as replanted; and to be able to cut them in the future, more must be planted in the present, more of the young crop, and a better kind of crop than nature, unassisted, is apt to grow, must be allowed to take the place of the old crop when it has been used. As farmers are needed to produce food crops, so foresters are called for. to produce wood crops, to celebrate, not Arbor Days, but Arbor Weeks ana Arbor Months, to devote themselves to the reproductien as well as the rat - ional harvesting of wood crops. New York State has made a beginning in that direction by instituting a State College of Forestry, where all the technical details of the raising, treat - ment, and rational harvest of tree crops and the manner of managing forest properties for wood and revenue production are taught. And, that there should be not only preaching, but practicing, a large tract of forest land has been set aside, where the manner of harvesting the old crop and of starting the new crop is being demonstrated. Last spring's "Arbor Weeks" have </seg>
            <seg id="p063">54 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES resulted on this tract in the planting of 95 acres of burnt over slash to pine and spruce, and the coming spring's "Arbor Weeks" will see 250 acres of ground from which the old, over mature wood has been removed so replanted; and on an another 250 acres the young, volunteer growth will be allowed to preserve the forest by replacing the harvest of old trees. Thus Arbor Day, the beautifu. festival, which is to inculcate apprecia - tion of tree growth, has already borne practical economic results. B. E. Fernow, Director New York State College of Forestry, Cornell University, Ithaca. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Bird Trades THE swallow is a mason, And underneath the eaves He builds a nest and plasters it With mud and hay and leaves. Of all the weavers that I know, The oriole is the best; High on the branches of the tree She hangs her cozy nest. The woodpecker is hard at work— A carpenter is he — And you may hear him hammering His nest high up a tree. Some little birds are miners ; Some build upon the ground ; And busy little tailors too, Among the birds are found. — Lincoln Literary Collection. {By permission of The American Book Co.) * * Our Little Martyrs SHALL we care when nesting-time Brings no birds from any clime ; Not a voice or ruby wing, Not a single nest to swing, Midst the reeds, or higher up, Like a dainty fairy cup; Not a single little friend, All the way, as footsteps wend Here and there through every clime, Not a bird at any time ? Does it matter ? Do we care What the feathers women wear Cost the world ? Must all birds die ? May they never, nt.ver fly Safely thiough their native air ? Slaughter meets them everywhere. Scorned be the hands that touch such spoil ! Let women pity and recoil Prom traffic barbarous and grave, And quickly strive the birds to save. — George Klingle. (56) 0 I R D •* DAY M A Y 1 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">From Margaret Miller't " My Saturday Bird Clan," by perminion of D. C. Heath A- Co .56 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 57 My Robin WHEN I was a child, beside our door, In a green and spreading sycamore, There sung each morning, with note as clear As a crystal brook, and full of cheer, A Robin. I watched his plumage in childish glee, And fancied he sang his song for me; And the melody lingers in heart and brain, Making me often a child again — My Robin. I look for his coming in early spring, When the crocus opens, and maples bring Their crimson tassels to kiss the breeze, And the sunshine dallies with new-leaved trees, My Robin. I hear him sing as the sun goes down, And the stars come out o'er the silent town ; But there's never a harsh or mournful note, Thafc wells afresh from the warbler's throat, My Robin. And I learn a lesson of hope and cheer That carries me on from year to year; To sing in the shadow as in the sun, Doing my part till the work is done, — My Robin. —Sarah K. Bolton # # Lost— Three Little Robins OH, where is the boy, dressed in jacket of gray, Who climbed up a tree in the orchard today And carried my three little birdies away? They hardly were dressed, When he took from the nest My three little robins and left me distressed. O wrens! have you seen, in your travels today, A very small boy, dressed in jacket of gray, Who carried my three little robins away? He had light colored hair, And his feet were both bare, And he was most cruel to me, I declare. O butterfly! stop just one moment, I pray; Have you seen a boy dressed in jacket of gray, Who carried my three little birdies away? Prom his pretty blue eyes One might think he was wise, But he must be wicked for one of his size. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">58 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES O boy with blue eyes, dressed in jacket of gray! If you will bring back my three robins today, With sweetest of music the gift I'll repay; I'll sing all day long My merriest song. And I will forgive you this terrible wrong. Bobolink ! did you see my birdies and me, How happy we were on the old apple tree, Until I was robbed of my young, as you see? Oh, how can I sing, Unless he will bring My three robins back, to sleep under my wing ? — Lincoln Literary Collection. (By permission of The American Book Company.) * 4&gt; Birds' Nests THE skylark's nest among the gnm And waving corn is found ; The robin's on a shady bank, With oak leaves strewn around. The wren builds in an ivied thorn Or old and ruined wall ; The mossy nest, so covered in, You scarce can see at all. The martins build their nest of clay, In rows beneath the eaves ; While silvery lichens, moss, and hair The chaffinch interweaves. Tho cuckoo makes no nest at all, But through the wood she strays, Until she finds one snug and warm, And there her eggs she lays. The sparrow has a nest of hay, With feathers warmly lined ; The ring-dove's careless nest of sticks On lofty trees we find. Rooks build together in a wood, And often disagree ; The owl will build inside a barn Or in a hollow tree. The blackbird's nest of grass and mud, In bush and bank is found ; The lapwing's darkly spotted eggs Are laid upon the ground. The magpie's nest is girt with thorns In leafless tree or hedge ; The wild duck and the water-hen Build by the water's edge. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 59 Birds build their nests from year to year, According to their kind,— Some very neat and beautiful, Some easily designed. The habits of each little bird, And all its patient skill, Are surely taught by God himself And ordered by his will. — Lincoln Literary Collection. (By permission of The American Book Co * * A Lesson From the Sparrows I AWAKENED one morning early, The great city slept near by, And the first faint coming of daylight Flushed pink in the eastern sky. The cool, sweet breeze stirred gently, The trees had revived again, And they lifted their green, wet branches Refreshed with the cool night rain. Earth lay in a calm, still waiting Before it awoke to toil, And the new day breathed its blessing On the children of the soil . As the dawn grew clear and stronger And the rosy east grew bright, I thought of the hearts that still wished for The silence and peace of the night, — Hearts that were faint in life's battle, That had lost their faith and trust, That saw not the glory of living, But dragged out their lives in the dust. And lo ! as the sun rose brighter, From under the eaves ( heard The first faint twitter of rapture From the heart of a little bird ! And another and then another Caught up the joyful lay, And louder swelled the chorus As they greeted the new-born day. They were only the Father's sparrows, But they knew His tender care, For they fall not to earth without Him, Or flit in the sunlit air ! And I thought if we would but remember The same Lord guides our days, We, too, would greet each new morning With a paean of joyful praise ! -Selected. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 60 A Nest in a PocKet A LITTLE bird went to and fro, In spring, the nesting season, And sought for shelter high and low, Until, for some queer reason, She flew into a granary, Where, on a nail suspended, The farmer's coat she chanced to see, And then her search was ended. The grain was heaped up to the loft ; There not a creature met her; The coat had hollows deep and soft — Could anything be better? And where it hung, how safe it was, Without a breeze to rock it! Come, busy little beak and claws, Build quick inside a pocket! Three speckled eggs soon warmly lay Beneath the happy sitter; Three little birds - oh, joy!— one day Began to chirp and twitter. And then— ah, can you guess the tale? — The farmer came one morning, And took the coat down from the nail Without a word of warning! Poor little frightened motherling— Out of her nest she fluttered, And each unfledged, small, downy thing Its terror piping uttered. The good man started back aghast, But merry was his wonder When, in the pocket, he at last Found such unlooked-for plunder. rie put the coat back carefully : "'Tis well I have another; You need not be afraid of me, You bright-eyed little mother. I know just how you feel, poor thing, For I have youngsters, bless you! There — stop your foolish fluttering— Here no one shall distress you. Then cheerfully he walked away To tell his wife about it- How in the coat the nestlings lay, And he must do without it. She smiled, and said she knew he could, And so, all unmolested, The mother birdie and her brood Safe in the pocket rested, Till all the little wings were set In proper flying feather; And then there was a nest to let, For off they flocked together. The farmer keeps it still to show And says that he's the debtor; His coat is none the worse, you know, While he's— a little better. —lights to </seg>
            <seg id="p070">r^ i*a\ i i ■ m | j f\ i p^ ■** r\\_/ 1.^^ Ci?^ 61 Bird Game (Half of the children are to be birds, and each ia to hare a name — orioles, swallows, robins, etc. The other children take the part of boys and girls asking questions. All ioin in CHILDREN. WHAT must you do this summer day, Summer day, summer day? Up in the trees in the sunshine gay, What must you do, little birdies? BIRDS. Build our nests on the elm tree bough, Elm tree bough! elm tree bough! See how fast we are working now, 1 Building our nests, little children. CHORUS. Twittering, twittering, sweet and low, Twittering, twittering, as we go, Hark to the song of the birdies! Fluttering, 2 fluttering, to and fro, Fluttering, fluttering, swift or slow, See the dear little birdies! CHILDREN. What is the song you sing so sweet, Sing so sweet, sing so sweet? What are the words you all repeat , Merry and glad, little birdies? BIRDS. Twee! twee! twee! we are singing sweet, Tweet! tweet! tweet! tweet! tweet! tweet! Love is the song we all repeat ; Love is our song, little children CHILDREN. What will you do when the day is done, Day is done, day is done? What will you do in the setting sun? What will you do, little birdies? BIRDS. Fold our wings and sweetly rest,' Sweetly rest, sweetly rest. Sleep so safe in each tiny nest,' That's what we'll do, little children. CHILDREN. Where will you go when tne summer goes, Summer goes, summer goes? Where will you go when the north wind blows? Where will you go, little birdies? BIRDS. Spread our wings 5 and away we'll fly, Away -we'll fly, away we'll fly, Spread our wings and away we'll fly, Away to the South, little children. — 8elect«d. 1. Waving motion with both hands. 2. Hands above the head waving to and fro. 3. Hands folded like folded wings. 4. Hands held in shape of nest. 5. Flying motion, arms outspread. —Primary Education, June, 1886. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">62 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES I Used to Kill Birds I USED to kill birds in my boyhood, Bluebirds and robins and wrens, I hunted them up in the mountains, I hunted them down in the glens I never thought it was sinful — I did it only for fun — And I had rare sport in the forest With the poor little birds and my gun. But one beautiful day in the springtime I spied a brown bird in a tree, Merrily swinging and chirping, As happy as bird could be ; And, raising my gun in a twinkling, I fired, and my aim was too true ; For a moment the little thing fluttered, Then off to the bushes it flew. I followed it quickly and softly, And there to my sorrow I found, Right close to its nest full of young ones, The little bird dead on the ground ! Poor birdies ! For food they were calling ; But now they could never be fed, For the kind mother-bird who had loved them Was lying there bleeding and dead. I picked up the bird in my anguish, I stroked the wee motherly thing That could never more feed its dear young ones, Nor dart through the air on swift wing. And I made a firm vow at that moment, When my heart with such sorrow was stirred, That never again in my life-time Would I shoot a poor innocent bird ! # * FranKlin's Birds' Nest WE present herewith an illustration of a home-made bird's nest, now in the office of the state superintendent. Mr. Lew Franklin of Lincoln, Nebraska, has suggested that the cultivation of gourds be encouraged, and the gourds be utilized for birds' nests. Boys may be as easily interested in the manufacture of birds' nests as in their destruction. The illustration above represents an old-fashioned, long-handled gourd, swung between two branches of a tree that extend one above the other; an opening about the size of a half-dollar is cut into one side just above the center for the entrance and exit of the bird. Two discs are used; one is screwed to the bottom of the globular part of the gourd and to a block within it, and the other is slipped down over the neck. The upper disc affords some shelter from the rain and storms, and both furnish resting places for the birds. Some wool, cotton batting, straws, strings, etc., may be seen protruding from the opening of the nest and lying loosely about on the discs. The gourd is swung between two branches as some protection from the cats. Boys should be taught to act as foes and not as allies of the cats in these matters. The cultivation of the gourd commenced in Asia and Africa long before the dawn of history. They were used for water bottles and for dishes. The </seg>
            <seg id="p072">franklin's bird's ibt </seg>
            <seg id="p073">63 small, pear-shaped ones were used for ornaments, and others were used for lanterns. The French people used the seeds to flavor soups. Gourds were indigenous to the American plains. In the early history of America, they were used for the sake of economy; one was always at the spring or well for drinking purposes; larger ones were used for dipping boiling water, small grain, soft soap, apple butter, etc. Small ones were and still are used to place in stocking heels or toes when the stocking is required to be darned. We hope to see an immediate increase in the cultivation of gourds for use as birds' nests. Djear Love shall reign from East to West, And shall bring Peace from North to South; The timid bird shall build her nest In the grim and silent cannon's mouth. a a Ten Things We May Do to Help Bird Life FIRST— Set out about our homes and school grounds trees, shrubs, and other plants most valuable to attract birds and furnish them food from their fruits, berries, or seeds. Second - Scatter crumbs and grains where the birds can get them. Third -Place shallow dishes of water at convenient heights for the birds to drink and bathe. Fourth — Place nesting material in their way at the time of nest building. Fifth— Where cats are kept, train them to keep away from nesting regions. Sixth— Watch for opportunities to help and protect the fledgelings until able to fly. Thousands of young birds every year leave their nests a day 1 or two before their wing's are quite strong and fall an easy prey to cats or other enemies. We can place them in a cage near the nest, and often the old birds will continue to feed them. If not, they should be fed and watered regularly about every hour during daylight until they become able to feed themselves. Caged birds should be liberated as soon as it is evident that they cannot be made happy and contented in captivity. Seventh — Provide bird houses and sheltered nooks for the nests. Dr. Hodge says the proper size for a bird house is six inches square floor space and eight inches high. A single opening near the top should be made two inches in diameter for most birds, although for wrens, chickadees, and the smaller birds, one inch is sufficient and will serve to keep out the English Sjarrow. Houses may be made with several compartments of these propor - ons. U Eighth— Arrange safe places of shelter about our houses and barns, in er to save as many birds as possible during the storms. Ninth — Refuse to wear birds and their plumage that is obtained by slaughter. If you must wear feathers, remember that made wings, quills, and ostrich plumes cost no bird its life. The wings are made from the feathers of fowls used for food. Tenth— If you have a bird to tame, place it in a clean cage, supply it with water and food for the first day, being careful not to frighten it. By the morning of the second day, when all the food in the cage haa been eaten or removed, offer it suitable food on the end of a slender wand, perhaps several eet long at first, and gently approach until the morsel is in reach of his bill. f he takes it, try another, moving up a little closer. If not, let his appetite harpen a little, or get a longer stick. By this method and a little patience iny young bird can, in three days, be tamed to take things from your hand.— Colorado "Arbor Day Notes." </seg>
            <seg id="p074">64 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES ■ Topography of Bohemian Waxwing 1 Upper Mandible. 2 Culmen. 3 Nostril. 4 Forehead. 5 Lores. « Superciliary Stripe. 7 Crown. H Crest. 9 Occiput. 10 Auriculars or Ear Coverts 11 Nape. 12 Interscapular Region. 13 Back. 14 Scapulars. 15 Tertials. 1« Rump. 17 Upper Tail Coverts. 18 Tail Feathers. 19 First Primary. 20 Primaries. 21 Tarsus. 22 Hind Toe. 23 Outer Toe. 24 Middle Toe. 25 Inner Toe. 2(i Abdomen or Belly 27 Secondaries. 2S Side. 20 Greater Wing Coverts. 30 Middle Wing Coverts 31 Breast. 32 Lesser Wing Coverts. 33 Carpal Joint. 34 Jugulum. 30 Throat. % Chin. 37 Gape. 38 Lower Mandible. TYPES OF BILLS AND FEET. 39 Strongly hooked bill of Hawk. 40 Falcate bill of Mexican Crossbill. 41 Tubular nostril of Fulmar Petrel. 42 Raptorial foot of Long Eared Owl. 43 Locate foot of Pied Billed Grebe. 44 Palmate foot of Duck. 45 Totipalmate foot of Cormorant. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">' 65 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">66 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES A Key to the Higher Groups of North American Birds A. Birds with toes connected by web or membrane. b All four toes so connected. — Pelicans and Cormorants, bb Only three toes so connected, or with feet lobed. c Nostrils tubular. — Petrels, Albatrosses, etc. cc Nostrils not tubular. d Bill either turned up or down. e Bill turned up, bird less than two feet long. — Avocet. ee Bill turned down, bird more than two feet long. -Flamingo. dd Bill neither turned up nor down, variously formed, e Feet webbed. / Wings long, extending beyond tip of tail. — Gulls, Terns. ff Wings short, not extending to tip of tail. g Legs attached to body normally; bill serrated. — Ducks and Geese. gg Legs attached to rear of body; bill not serrated. — Loons and Grebes, ee Feet lobed. / Tail very small, nearly absent. — Grebes. ff Tail present, well developed. g Bill strong, in color white. — Coots. gg Bill slender, in color black. — I'halaropes. AA. Birds with webbing between toes very slight or absent. b Bill strongly hooked. c Colors bright, fruit eaters. - Parrots , etc. cc Colors not bright, flesh-eaters. — Eagles, Hawks, and OwU. bb Bill not strongly hooked. c Hind toe small or absent, if present elevated. d Lower portion of thigh not feathered. e Bill slender, hind toe small or absent.— Plovers, Hand- pipers, etc. ee EilT not so slender, hind toe larger.^Oan«8, Rails, and Gallinules. dd Lower portion of thigh feathered. — Grouse, Quail, and Turkey. cc [Hind toe well developed. d [Base of upper mandible with a soft swollen structure. — IHgeons, Doves, etc. dd [Base of upper mandible without soft swollen structure. e [Toes 2 in front and 2 behind, or else 2 in front and 1 behind. / Tail feathers stiff, bill chisel-like. — Woodpeckers. ff Tail feathers not stiff, bill not chisel-like.— ( uckoos. ee [Toes 3 in front and 1 behind. / Feet small and weak. g Toes more or less grown together. h Bill small and weak. — Svoaliows. hh Bill long and strong. — Kingfishers. gg Toes not grown together. h Bill long and slender, colors bright.— Hum- mingbirds. hh Bill short, colors dull. — Nighthawks, Svrifts, etc. ff Feet larger and stronger. — Crows, Jays, Blackbirds, Shrikes, Sparrows, Wrens, Thrushes, Warblers, etc. —J. 8. Hunter. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">67 The Bluebird TE^EW, indeed, must be the boys and girls, who are not acquainted with this P beautiful harbinger of spring, and who do not look forward to its coming with the greatest eagerness. When he first comes, in the sunny days of March, his song is exceedingly gay and cheerful, as he sits on the topmost twig of a leafless tree, pouring out his little heart in the gladness of his return. In a few days, with the arrival of his more sober spouse, nest hunting begins and when a satisfactory site is chosen, work commences in earn' Although the birds are quite abundant about our towns, and even oil in the early spring, they are forced by the hordes of English Sparrows to seek their summer homes in the country where these pests do not venture in such numbers. So we must seek them in some box in a friendly farmer's barnyard or in a deserted woodpecker's hole in a quiet shady grove or garden fence post. After cleaning out the cavity a soft loose nest of dried grass is built within, and usually lined with a few feathers picked up about the barn - yard. Then the fragile, sky-blue eggs are laid, one each day until four or five are deposited in the nest. During the time of these labors the male en - tertains his mate by frequent snatches of song. Often he, will bring a choice bit oi grass or a feather or perhaps a fat juicy worm and turn them over to her with many chirps and twitterings. After aoout fifteen days of patient incubation by the male and female in turn the queer, naked misshapen little creatures break from their shells and open their gaping mouths for food. Now comes the trying time for the parent birds; to obtain food for their young and to guard them from harm until they can care for themselves. The male has very lit.ie time for singing now, but joins the female in the hurried search for worms to fill the hungry little mouths. It seems as if they are never satisfied, but their growth is very rapid and before long black pin - feathers appear on the wings, head, back and where the tail will be. These soon develop into strong coarse feathers, whose shafts are surrounded by soft grayish down, which gradually disappears as the birds become strong enough to fly and partially take care of themselves. Two broods are raised in a summer and if the spring be very early even three, so you see there is little wonder that as summer wanes, saddened by the approach of grim old winter, and worn by the labor of feeding so many hungry mouths during the summer months, their song grows plaintive and sad. ' Still they linger with us through sunny September and crisp October, delaying their departure as long as possible, as if regretting to leave the places which are doubtless filled with happy memories for them. At last with a sad farewell song they launch into the air and begin their long flight to the sunny Southland where perhaps the boys and girls are looking for them as eagerly as we did in the early spring. M. A. Carriker, Jr. a a What Our Birds Eat in Summer BY ACTUAL observation 221 distinct kinds of birds are known to regularly raise their young in Nebraska, while 60 others may do so occasionally. The nesting of all these birds within the state is very significant since it is during the growth of the young that a large amount of very highly nutri - tious food is required. From the standpoint of the farmer and fruitgrower this fact is of theutmo8t importance, because most young birds are fed almost en - tirely on an insect diet during the time spent in the nest and for a short time afterwards. The same can also be said of many of the birds that leave the nest as soon as hatched. Therefore during the growth of the young birds the quantity of such food which is gathered by the parent birds over the entire </seg>
            <seg id="p078">68 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES state must be relatively enormous. Taking as a basis for our estimations the figures given in my leaflet entitled "A plea for the protection of our birds" -we would have about 75,000,000 birds or approximately 35,000,000 to 40,000,000 pairs that nest here. Should each pair of this large number rear four young there would be required a sufficient food supply for from 140,000,000, to 160, 000,000 young birds alone. If, as we suggested in that paper, a single bird eats on an average 25 insects per day, the enormous number of four billions of insects or 35,000 bushels of 120,000 insects would be required each day to feed the young birds alone. But young birds need much more food than do old ones, therefore we should at least double this quantity for the young birds. Then to this must be added that required by the parent birds while taking care of the young. Again estimating as above, the grand total of 86,000 bushels or 107 car loads of 20 tons each would be the required amount of insect food for our Nebraska birds during a single day, allowing 50 pounds for the weight of a bushel. — Lawrence Bruner, University of Nebraska. a a Birds in Their Relation to Man THE birds form a carefully organized army which is intrusted with the great task of policing the earth. They come and go on the " wings of the four winds" that they may the more readily perform their allotted tasks. Each species by nature has been assigned its special portion of this great work, hence the various ways that different birds work and the widely dissimilar haunts frequented by them. It is by this means that the God of the universe has provided for the maintenance of an equilibrium in nature. Birds can be useful to man in many ways. They can benefit him by carry - ing the seeds of various plants from place to place so as to assist him in establishing new groves in which to find shelter from the cold of winter and a refuge from the broiling noonday sun in summer. They plant various shrubs by the wayside that spring up and later are laden with luscious fruit. They also carry the spawn of fishes and small crustaceans among their feathers into new waters, and feed upon the countless seeds of weeds that are scattered broadcast over the face of the earth . Some kinds live almost exclusively on insects, while others hunt out the small rodents that would, if left to them - selves, destroy great quantities of grain and other vegetation. Still other birds benefit mankind by acting as scavengers in the removal of putrid and other offensive matter which would endanger our health. In addition to all these varied direct benefits which are brought about by the presence of birds, man is further indebted to these creatures for the cheer which their gay music, bright plumage, and pleasing manners bring to him. But we can go even further when summing up the benefits that man may derive from the birds. A great many kinds provide him with excellent food, and downy pillows, while others furnish sport and pleasure to a large number of men and boys who seem to require a certain kind of entertainment while accompanied with dog and gun. Dead birds, when embalmed as mummies and attached to the headgear worn by some girls and women, are also claimed to cause mueh happiness in the world. It would be ridiculous, on the other hand, for me to assert here that no injury ever results from the presence of birds on the farm or in the orchard. Quite a number of different species are continually stepping over to the wrong side of the "ledger," as it were, and committing depredations of various kinds which, if considered alone, would render the perpetrators liable to severe punishment — in some cases even unto death. Some of the crimes that can be charged to the feathered tribe are cherry and berry stealing, grape puncturing, apple pecking, corn pulling, grain eating, the unintentional carry - ing from place to place of some kinds of scale insects that happen to crawl on </seg>
            <seg id="p079">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 69 their legs and feet, the possible spreading of hog cholera by crows and buz - zards, the robbing of the poultry yard, and lastly some birds are accused of making noises that awaken us from our slumbers in the morning. A few of these crimes are genuine and are to be deplored, while others are more imaginary than real. A few of them could be prevented in part or altogether, while others might be diminished if we were inclined to take the trouble to do it. After all that can be said pro and con, concerning the usefulness of birds in general, there remains no doubt in the minds of thinking people as to the value of these creatures. It is only the vicious, biased, and thoughtless per - sons who continue ruthlessly to destroy birds indiscriminately without first pausing to consider whether or not it is a proper thing to do, whether it is right or wrong:. During the early days of the settlement of a country when the pioneer breaks up the virgin soil and sows his seeds, the fowls of the air come from the " four quarters of the globe" and devour that which is sown before it is covered. At this time great caution must be exercised in handling the matter or later on even more and greater calamities will visit the tiller of the soil. When the birds come to eat the seeds as they are being put into the ground, scare them away, and presently they will return to attack the insects that otherwise would destroy the growing plants. — Lawrence Bruner, University of Nebraska. 0 0 The Nesting of Our Birds ■*¥THERE a bird nests, there i3 its home, and though most of our feathered W friends are driven southward in the fall by scarcity of food and to escape the rigorous northern winter, among the first evidences of the spring are the returning birds, pressing northward again in defiance of even snow and ice, toward the home they left a few short months before. Almost before it is reached the courtship begins and soon follows the choosing of mates, the selection of a location, the construction of a nest and the begin - ning of incubation. The location, chosen with the greatest care and after due deliberation, may even later be deserted and the nest removed if after its beginning dan - gers appear to threaten the safety of the young. Its nature is as varied as the nature of the various birds themselves; but instinct, moulded by the ex - perience of the previous generations, leads each to choose that which best serves its purpose. Floating on the water at the margin of a pond is the soaked and soggy raft of the Grebe, slung in the cat-tails and rushes above the cosy ball of the Long-billed Marsh Wren or the basket of the Red-winged Blackbird, while in a little hollow in the sand are arranged the eggs of the Sandpiper, protected by their color from all but knowing eyes, and still farther back in the trackless meadow those of the Duck are hidden in the grass. Out on the wind-swept prairie the nest of the Shore-lark is sunken beside some clod, and the eggs of the Nighthawk in lieu of any nest at all rest directly on the ground, while in the thicket under the shelter of the trees the Warbler builds her dainty cradle side by side with the clumsy heap of twigs collected by the Thrasher. Safe in a tunnel in a bank the Kingfisher and the Bank Swallow hide their pure white eggs, and in cavities in trees, hidden also from the light, are the ivory treasures of the Woodpecker. The Hawk, scorning con - cealment or protection, places his platform high in a towering tree, the Heron his in some secluded swamp, but at the tip of a swaying limb by the roadside the purse of the Baltimore Oriole is safer than either from the foe. Many birds delight in man's society and haunt the barn, the shed, the porch, the trees and shrubbery about the house, and even enter chimneys to rear their young. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">70 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES In choice of materials the bird is guided by the necessities arising from the location of its nest, the time of year when made, and the physical abilities of the bird, mud, moss, grass, sticks, cloth, twine, hair, and fur all coming handy on occasion, while to the Chimney Swift its own saliva serves as glue. Some of our birds are hatched before the end of winter, and poorly would the young of the owl in its coat of heavy down fare in the warmth of the later days of spring. The young of most birds hatched thus early in the sea - son, and those of waterbirds, which need protection from the dampness, are downy, while those which later, fed on the insects, enjoy the warmth of sum - mer days are naked when they leave the egg. During this period, as a rule, both birds share equally the labor, but there are not wanting lazy dandies, as even the lovable Bluebird, that spend their time on song and toilet when their domestic spouse toils to collect mate - rial for their home. On the other hand, there are strong-minded females, among the phalaropes, who pose as the representative of the household while their dull-colored mates perform the family duties. In most cases the male has sufficient gallantry to bring his sitting mate an occasional tidbit, or even to relieve her while she goes for exercise or in search of food, but among the Ducks are shameless Drakes who go off in a crowd to enjoy themselves, leav - ing their families to fare as best they may. The eggs are brooded for a time the length of which is in proportion to their size, the female Humming-bird sitting but ten days, some of our largest birds three or even four weeks. The love of birds for nest and eggs is slight at first, but rapidly increases, and reaches its full strength with the hatching of the young, which are the objects of tenderest solicitude. When hatched, the young of waterbirds and fowls— Quail, Grouse, and Prairie Chicken— are able at once to swim or run about, but the care of the parents is required by most young birds for many weeks, and it is usual if but one brood is reared in a season, for the family to remain together till the com - ing of the fall brings round again the time when all leave on the fall migra - tion.— Robert H. Wolcott, University of Nebraska. ? </seg>
            <seg id="p081">oostrr publish bp Craiw &amp; Co., lloprka. l&amp;anoas. A star for every State, a State for every star.— Winthrop. Ye who love the Republic, remember the claim Ye owe to her fortunes, ye owe to her name. To her years of prosperity past and in store, A hundred behind you, a thousand before. 'Tis the schoolhouse stands by the flag. Let the Nation stand by the school ; 'Tis the school-bell that rings for our Liberty old, ' Tis the schoolboy whose ballot will rule. The blue arch above us is Liberty's dome, The green fields beneath us, Equality's home. But the schoolroom to-day is humanity's friend, — Let the people the flag and the schoolhouse defend 'Tis the schoolhouse stands by the flag, Let the Nation stand by the school ; 'Tis the school-bell that rings for our Liberty old, 'Tie the schoolboy whose ballot shall rule. Buttbkworth on "The Schoolhouse Stands by the Flag Patriotic Quotations. We join ourselves to no party that does not carry the flag and keep step to the lisic of the Union. — Rcpus Choatk. tst our object be our country, our whole country, and nothing but our country. ntel Webster. If any one attempts to haul down the American flag, shoot him on the spot. — </seg>
            <seg id="p082">TIME only enhances the lasting value and demonstrates anew the true significance of these inspiring observances. Whatever may be the char- acter of its temporary problems, this liberty loving nation is not and never can be forgetful of the immortal heroes of the civil war. The debt of gratitude which we owe to the nation's defenders can never be repaid, either by this or future generations; yet the acknowledged gift of the obligation each year, in various forms and in a multitude of places throughout this broad land, purifies our ideas and brings us all together in sympathy of sentiment and unity of purpose. Generations come and go and the issues for which they fought and died soon pass into history. But the living principles of undertakings worthily accomplished, for an unselfish purpose, abide forever and guide us to a nobler destiny and still greater achievements as a nation. — President McKinley. a a What Can the Children Do ? FIRST CHILD. WHAT can the little children do, When Decoration Day is here, To show their love for soldiers brave Who, fighting for their country, gave The life that was to them so dear ? SECOND CHILD. We'll bring the lovely flowers of spring That in the fields and gardens grow, And on the soldiers' graves to-day Our garlands we will gladly lay, Our loving thoughts of them to show. THIRD CHILD. We'll raise aloft the " stars and stripes" On this Memorial Day, to show We honor those who for it bled. Some now are living, many dead, For this was many years ago. FOURTH CHILD. We'll sing our patriotic songs; We'll truly sing with heart and voice, And to our country we'll be true, And honor our " red, white, and blue," And in our freedom we'll rejoice. — Laura F. Armitage in Journal of Education. (71) </seg>
            <seg id="p083">72 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Which General? Sometimes mamma calls me " general I wish I knew which one ; But I always try to tell the truth, So I hope it's Washington. But when I tell my papa that, He laughs loud as he can, And says if she calls me "general," She must mean Sheridan, Because whenever she wants me, And I am out at play, I nearly always seem to be 1 Bout " twenty miles away." — Kate W. Hamilton 0 0 Our Flag MART. *W*ELL me, who can, about our flag, JL With its red, and white, and blue ? How came it to have so many stars, And of pretty stripes so few ? JOHN. The thirteen stripes are for thirteen states That first into the Union came ; For each new state we have added a star. But have kept the stripes the same. BESSIE. The number has now reached forty-five ! So here's an example for you : Take " the old thirteen" from forty-five. And how many states are new? CHARLES. Thirteen from forty-five ? Let's see Well, three from five leaves two, And one from four leaves three ■ there'll be, Of new states, — thirty-two. ALL m CONCERT. And these all reach from East to West, To both the ocean shores ; And over all the proud flag waves, And the Bird of Freedom soars ! </seg>
            <seg id="p084">73 Each A Memorial Gift (For four pupils. &gt; FROM woodland and field, In this bright month of May, What flowers can we bring For Memorial Day? 2 (dressed in red, holding columbine).— I am sweet columbine, And I nod my gay head As I offer you freely My blossoms of red. S (dressed In white, holding daisies).— I'm a tall, slender daisy, With my petals of white. Take a few of my blossoms, Their faces are bright. 4 (dressed In blue, holding violets) .— We violets sweet, Though half hid in the grass, If you search you may find us, My dear little lass. 1 (taking the bouquets and holding them up) . — What more can we wish Than the red, white, and blue Of nature's sweet flowers For the brave and the true? Nellie G. Jerome # # Four Soldier Boys This short exercise may be giren by fonr little boys with soldiers' caps and capes bears a small flag. All march in to drum beats, and stand in line. FIRST SOLDIER. AN HONEST soldier I would be And serve my country, grand and free. I'll fight for truth, be good and great, I'll bravely march and fear no fate. ALL (W A VINO FLAGS). " Hurrah ! Hurrah ! Wave, flags, wave ! Wave for the soldier who is true and brave ! SECOND SOLDIER. A loving soldier I would be, And serve my country, grand and free. Loving God and loving man, I'll always do the best I can. ALL. Hurrah ! Hurrah I Ware, flags, wave ! Wave for this country and our soldiers brave t </seg>
            <seg id="p085">74 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES THIRD SOLDIER. A soldier brave I'll try to be, And serve my country grand and free. In dangers I'll be brave and true; This for my country I will do. ALL. Hurrah ! Hurrah ! Wave, flaps, wave ! Wave for the country and our soldiers brave ! FOURTH SOLDIER. The best of soldiers we will be, And serve our country, grand and free Honest, loving, brave, and true, O, much for our country we can do ! ALL (MARCHING OUT). Hurrah ! Hurrah ! Wave, flags, wave ! Wave for the country and our soldiers brave! # # Meaning of the Colors FIRST PUPIL. RED, from the leaves of the autumn woods, Of our frost-kissed northern hills; Red, to show that patriot blood Is beating now in a hurrying flood In the hearts of American men. SECOND PUPIL. White, from the fields of stainless drift, On our wide western plains; White, to show that as pure as snow, We believe the Christ light yet shall glow, In the souls of American men. THIRD PUPIL. Blue, from the arch of the winter sky, O'er our fatherland outspread; Blue, to show that as wide as heaven, Shall justice to all mankind be given, At the hands of American men. ALL TOGETHER. Red, white, and blue, and the light of stars, Through our holy colors shine ; Love, truth, and justice, virtues three, That shall bloom in the land of liberty, In the homes of American men. </seg>
            <seg id="p086"/>
            <seg id="p087">farfciOIAi* DAY EXERCISES 75 " I'm Only a Regular " Jj* L CANET : The battle was over. In the midst of the dead and dying JUs were two New York volunteers and a soldier of the regular army, lying there suffering in the burning sun. Suddenly the regular saw an opportunity to get a canteen from a dead Spanish sharpshooter. "With diffi - culty he crawled the 300 yards necessary to reach the water. But instead of quenching his own thirst, wounded as he was, he painfully dragged himself back to his comrades, and died lifting the canteen to their lips. " I'm only a regular," he said, " you fellow3 have folks at home waiting for you." # # A Tribute to Our Army THE following is part of the farewell address issued by the Spanish soldiers before their embarkation for Spain at the end of the Spanish - American war. It is a tribute of appreciation to our army for com - plying with the instincts of a humane nation in their fighting: Soldiers of the American army: We would not be fulfilling our duty as well-born men, in whose breasts live gratitude and courtesy, should we embark for our beloved Spain without sending to you our most cordial and sincere good wishes and farewell. We fought you with .ardor, with all our strength, endeavoring to gain the victory, but without the slightest rancor or hate towards the American nation. We have been vanquished by you (so our generals and chiefs judged in signing the capitulation), but our surrender and the bloody battles preceding it have left in our souls no place for resentment against the men who fought U3 so nobly and valiantly. You fought and acted in compliance with the same call of duty as we, for we all but represent the power of our respective states. You fought us as men, face to face, and with great courage. You have given honorable burial to the dead of the vanquished; have cured their wounded with great humanity; have respected and cared for your prisoners and their comfort, and, lastly, to us, whose condition was terrible, you have given freely of food, of your stock of medicines, and you have honored us with distinction and courtesy, for after the fighting the two armies mingled with the utmost harmony. With this high sentiment of appreciation from us all, there remains but to express our farewell, and with the greatest sincerity we wish you all hap - piness and health in this land, which will no longer belong to our dear Spain, but will be yours, who have conquered it by force and watered it with blood. * * The Southern Soldier YOU of the North have had drawn for you with a master's hand the pic - ture of your returning armies. You have heard how, in the pomp and circumstance of war, they came back to you, marching with proud and victorious tread, reading their glory in a nation's eyes. Will you bear with me while I tell you of another army that sought its home at the close of the late war — an army that marched home in defeat and not in victory, in pathos and not in splendor? Let me picture to you the footsore confederate soldier, as, buttoning up in his faded gray jacket the parole which was to bear testimony to his children of his fidelity and faith, he turned his face southward from Appomattox in April, 1866. Think of him as ragged, half starved, heavy-hearted, enfeebled by want and wounds; having fought to exhaustion, he surrenders his gun, </seg>
            <seg id="p088">76 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES wrings the hands of his comrades in silence, and lifting his tear-stained and pallid face for the last time to the graves that dot the old Virginia hills, pulls his gray cap over his brow and begins the slow and painful journey. What does he find — let me ask you who went to your homes eager to find in the wel - come you had justly earned, full payment for four years' sacrifice— what does he find when having followed the battle -stained cross against overwhelming odds, dreading death not half so much as surrender, he reaches the home he left so prosperous and beautiful? He finds his house in ruins, his farm devastated, his slaves free, his stock killed, his barns empty, his trade destroyed, his money worthless; his social system, feudal in its magnificence, swept away; his people without law or legal status, his comrades slain, and the burdens of others heavy on his shoul - ders. Crushed by defeat, his very traditions are gone ; without money, credit, material, or training; and beside all this, confronted with the gravest prob - lem that ever met human intelligence — the establishing of a status for the vast body of his liberated slaves. What does he do— this hero in gray with a heart of gold? Does he sit down in sullenness and despair? Not for a day. Surely God who had strip - ped him of his prosperity, inspired him in his adversity. As ruin was never so overwhelming, never was restoration swifter. The soldier stepped from the trenches into the furrow; horses that had charged federal guns marched before the plough, and fields that ran red with blood in April were green with the harvest in June. Never was nobler duty confided to human hands than the uplifting and upbuilding of the prostrate and bleeding south, misguided perhaps, but beautiful in her suffering. In the record of her social, indust - rial, and political evolution, we await with confidence the verdict of the world. — Henry Grady. From SUckney's Fifth Reader by permission of Qinn &amp; Co. # * Remember the Maine— A Beautiful Tribute to its Noble Dead Delivered In House of Representatives, March 21, 1896, by Hon. Robert G. Cousins, Iowa. NO HUMAN speech can add anything to the silent gratitude, the speech - less reverence, already given by a great and grateful nation to its dead defenders and to their living kin. No act of congress providing for their needs can make a restitution for their sacrifice. Human nature does, in human ways, its best, and still feels deep in debt. Expressions of condolence have come from every country and from every clime, and every nerve of steel and ocean cable has carried on electric breath the sweetest, tenderest words of sympathy for that gallant crew who manned the Maine. But no human recompense can reach them. Humanity and time remain their everlasting debtors. It was a brave and strong and splendid crew. They were a part of the blood and bone and sinew of our land. Two of them were from my native state of Iowa. Some were only recently at the United States Naval Academy, wiere they had so often heard the morning and the evening salutation to the flag, that flag which had been interwoven with the dearest memories of their lives, that had colored all their friendships with the lasting blue of true fidelity. But whether they came from naval school or civil life, from one state or another, they called each other comrade— that gem of human lan - guage which sometimes means but a little less than love and a little more than friendship, that gentle salutation of the human heart which lives in all the languages of man, that winds and turns and runs through all the joys and sorrows of the human race, through deed and thought and dream, through song and toil and battlefield. No foe had ever challenged them. The world can never know how brave they arere. They never knew defeat; they never shall. "While at their posts of duty, sleep lured them into the abyss; then death unlocked their slrmber- </seg>
            <seg id="p089">77 7 ing eyes but for an instant to behold its dreadful carnival, most of them just when life was full of hope, and all its tides were at their highest, grandest flow ; just when the early sunbeams were falling on the steeps of fame and flooding all life's landscape far out into the dreamy, distant horizon; just at that age when all the nymphs were making diadems and garlands, waving laurel wreaths before the eyes of young and eager nature — just then, when death seemed most unnatural. Hovering above the dark waters of that mysterious harbor of Havana, the black-winged vulture watches for the dead, while over it, and over all, there is the eagle's piercing eye sternly watching for the truth. Whether the appropriation carried by this resolution shall be ultimately charged to fate or to some foe shall soon appear. Meanwhile a patient and a patriotic people, enlightened by the lessons of our history, remembering the woes of war, both to the vanquished and victorious, are ready for the truth and ready for their duty. " The tumult and the shouting dies — The captains and the kings depart — Still stands thine ancient sacrifice, An humble and a contrite heart. Lord God of Hosts, be with us yet. Lest we forget — lest we forget." # * Welcome to Company G of the "Fighting First" MR. PRESIDENT, Ladies, and Gentlemen: On behalf of the Local Ex - ecutive Committee, I have the honor to pronounce the sentiment which thrills the heart and electrifies the soul of every man, woman, and child in this vast multitude, Welcome! Welcome! A thousand times welcome to the brave boys of Company G, of the " Fighting First." These hundreds of human faces, glowing with sympathy and joy, " In this spacious temple of the firmament," turn reverently to heaven and proclaim their gratitude unto a kind providence for being permitted to grasp the hands of these heroes in welcome home. * Hail , Sons of Columbia ! Fortunate , fortunate men ! With what measure of devotion will you not thank God for the circumstances of your extraordi - nary lives ? You are connected with two hemispheres. You have carried a victorious banner twenty thousand miles. Heaven saw fit to ordain that the electric spark of Liberty should be conducted through you, from the New World to the Old. " Strongholds of Tyrants you did greet, In the cause of freedom, you did meet To strike for the oppressed. You hoisted the flag that knows no stain, You waved defiance unto Spain, And the battle cry, ' Remember the Maine,' Was heard around the world." Sons of Nebraska mothers, the events of this day bring to our minds that April day, 1898. That day you parted with those you loved to enlist in the army of freedom. That was a day that tried our souls. The child gave its father, the maiden her lever, the wife her husband, and the mother her son to the cause of humanity. Under flaunting flags, you hurried to our Capital City to await orders. You then crossed the prairies, climbed the mountains, and sailed the seas, prepared to do and to die for the eternal right. The gory fields, the hospitals of pain, weary marches under a tropical sun, guard duty in the awful storm, the whistle of the Mauser bullet, "The </seg>
            <seg id="p090">78 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES roar and shriek of the bursting shell," the gallant charge and the triumphant shout are a part of your thrilling experiences. With what delight we hailed your letters from far-away Luzon! How eagerly we sought the press dispatches after each tattle, to see if any of Com - pany G had fallen. How we have longed for you to be mustered out; and now you come back to us, "marching with proud and victorious tread, reading your glory in a Nation's eyes." But alas! you are not all here, Walker, Hague, Spivey, Forby, Stotsen - burg! Our eyes seek for them in vain amidst this brave band. They have answered the roll call on high, and live only to their country, in her grateful remembrance, and their own bright example. "Let us not too much grieve that they have met the common fate of men." They lived long enough to know that their work had been nobly done. The sky on which they closed their eyes was cloudless. The record they left those near and dear to them was above reproach. They wrought wiser than they knew. They are at rest. Monuments and eulogy are indeed due such heroic dead. "Human beings are composed not of reason only, but of sentiment as well, and that is neither wasted nor misapplied which is appropriated for the pur - pose of giving direction to sentiments, and opening proper springs of feeling in the heart." Let the ceremonies of this day proclaim the importance of the achievements of Company G and other patriotic sons of the First Ne - braska. Let mothers teach the full meaning of this welcome to the children at home. Let the memories of this occasion stand as a mighty Gibraltar against those days of criticism and disaster, which, as they come om all nations, must be expected to come on us also. Let desponding patriotism turn her eyes to this heroic picture, and be assured that the foundations of our national power still stand firm, and that the gates of hell shall not prevail against us. Again, heroes of Company G, we welcome you. We welcome you for what you hare done; more than that, we welcome you for what you are. We welcome you as friends of liberty and humanity; we welcome you as those who have made Old Glory the flag of the seas. We welcome you as defend - ers of the greatest, the grandest, and the best government on the face of the earth. Sons of Columbia ! "You who with gallant Dewey fought, And counted human life as naught, If, at such priceless cost it brought A birthright for the free," — we welcome you Sons of Nebraska Mothers! "You who crushed out tyranny, Set fellow-men from thraldom free, And ended the tyrant's sway," — We welcome you! In the name of liberty, in« the name of humanity, under a flag- without a stain — we welcome you! —Elizabeth Stultz, of Geneva, on the return home of Company G of tlie first Nebraska. * 4&gt; The Essence of Patriotism THE essence of patriotism lies in a willingness to sacrifice for one's country, just as true greatness finds expression, not in blessings enjoyed, but in good bestowed. Read the words inscribed on the monuments reared by loving hands to the heroes of the past; they do not speak of wealth inherited, or honors bought, or of hours in leisure spent, but of service done. Twenty years, forty years, a life or life's most precious blood he yielded up for the welfare of his fellows — this is the simple story which proves that it is now, and ever has been more blessed to give than to receive. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">79 • Th e . officer was a patriot when he gave his ability to his country and risked his name and fame upon the fortunes of war; the private soldier was a patriot when he took his place in the ranks and offered his body as a bul - wark to protect the flag; the wife was a patriot when she bade her husband farewell and gathered about her the little brood over which she must exer - cise both a mother's and a father's care; and if there can be degrees in patriotism, the mother stood first among the patriots when she gave to the nation her sons, the divinely appointed support of her declining years, and as she brushed the tears away, thanked God that he had given her the strength to rear strong and courageous sons for the battlefield.— IT. J. Bryan. * * Col. Ingersoll's Remarkable Vision (One of the most eloquent extracts In the English Language. Published by permission of Rhodes 4 McClure.) THE past, as it were, rises before me like a dream. Again we are in the great struggle for national life. We hear the sound of preparation — the music of boisterous drums — the silver voices of heroic bugles. We see the thousands of assemblages and hear the appeals of orators. We see the pale cheeks of women and the flushed faces of men; and in those assemblages we see all the dead whose dust we have covered with flowers. We lose sight of them no more. We are with them when they enlist in the great army of free - dom. We see them part with those they love. Some are walking for the last time in quiet woody places with the maidens they adore. We hear the whis - perings of the sweet vows of eternal love as they lingeringly part forever. -Others are bending over cradles, kissing babes that are asleep. Some are receiving the blessings of old men. Some are parting with mothers who hold them and press them to their hearts again and again, and say nothing; and some are talking with wives and endeavoring with brave words spoken in the old tones to drive away the awful fear. We see them part. We see the wife standing in the door with the babe in her arms — standing in the sunlight sobbing— at the turn of the road a hand waves — she answers by holding high in her loving hands the child. He is gone, and forever. We see them all as they march proudly away under the flaunting flags, keeping time to the wild, grand music of war — marching down the streets of the great cities— through the town and across the prairies — down to the fields of glory, to do and to die for the eternal right. We go with them one and all. We are by their side on all the gory fields, in all the hospitals of pain — on all the weary marches. We stand guard with them in the wild storm and under the quiet stars. We are with them in ravines running with blood, in the furrows of old fields. We are with them between contending hosts, unable to move, wild with thirst, the life ebbing slowly away among the withered leaves. We see them pierced by balls and torn with shells in the trenches of forts, and in the whirlwind of the charge, where men become iron with nerves of steel. We are with them in the prisons of hatred and famine, but human speech can never tell what they endured. We are at home when the news comes that they are dead. We see the maiden in the shadow of her sorrow. We see the silvered head of the old man bowed with the last grief. The past rises before us, and we see four millions of human beings gov - erned by the lash — we see them bound hand and foot — we hear the strokes of cruel whips— we see the hounds tracking women through tangled swamps. We see babes sold from the breasts of mothers. Cruelty unspeakable ! Out-, .rage infinite! </seg>
            <seg id="p092">80 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Four million bodies in chains — four million souls in fetters. All the sacred relations of wife, mother, father, and child trampled beneath the bru - tal feet of might. And all this was done under our own beautiful banner of the free. The past rises before us. We hear the roar and shriek of the burning shell. The broken fetters fall. There heroes died. We look. Instead of slaves, we see men and women and children. The wand of progress touches the auction-block, the slave-pen, and the whipping-post, and we see homes and firesides, and school-houses and books, and where all was want and crime, and cruelty and fear, we see the faces of the free. These heroes are dead. They died for liberty — they died for us. They are at rest. They sleep in the land they made free, under the flag they ren - dered stainless, under the solemn pines, the sad hemlocks, the tearful willows, the embracing vines. They sleep beneath the shadows of the clouds, careless alike of sunshine or storm, each in the windowless palace of rest. Earth may run red with other wars — they are at peace. In the midst of battle in the roar of conflict, they found the serenity of death. I have one sentiment for the soldiers living and dead— cheers for the living and tears for the dead. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">"KISS ME.' Courteiy of G. P. Brown &lt;fc Co., publithers of Brown* Famout Pictures, Beverly, KM. </seg>
            <seg id="p094">Public Schools and Education AN open school-house, free to all, evidences the highest type of advance civilization. It is the gateway to progress, prosperity, and honor, and the best security for the liberties and independence of the people. It is the strongest rock of the foundation, the most enduring stone of the temple of liberty, our surest stay in every storm, our present safety, our future hope, aye the very citadel of our influence and power. It is better than garrisons and guns, than forts and fleets. An educated people, governed by true moral principle, can never take a backward step, nor be dispossessed of their citizenship and liberties. Permanently engrafted upon the policy and legislation of the state, it i&gt; free to all; to it all are invited and welcome, without money and without price. It is supported with boundless generosity by the people of the state, open to the children of the humblest citizen or exiled sojoumer within our gates, as freely and ungrudgingly as to the native born or the children of the most opulent. Within its jurisdiction all distinctions, social, political, and religious, are banished; all differeftees hushed, all barriers removed. It recognizes neither party nor church, creed, condition, nor station, but free as the air we breathe, its bounties and benefits fall in equal measure upon all. These advantages should be sacredly cherished, never lightly regarded. The time to enjoy them is in youth; no other time is so opportune. If neg - lected then, they are reasonably certain to remain forever unimproved. We have no time to wait in this short, hurrying life. The early years are the golden ones for preparation; not a moment should be squandered. It might be otherwise could we realize the sentiment of the old rhyme : Could a man be secure That his days would endure As of old, for a thousand long years, What things he might know, What deeds might he do, What reap and what sow, And all without hurry and care! But it is all otherwise ordained; " our brief span " admits of no idleness, no loitering by the way. The to-morrows are too full to be crowded with the yesterdays. We must move on and forward. We must learn that every day is a new day, with its own distinctive and commanding duties, and cannot atone for the yesterdays unimproved. To-morrow's tent must be pitched in new fields; to-morrow s thought in advance of yesterday's. We must keep up or be crowded out. You can afford to appear here in any department, from the primary to the high school, poorly dressed, if your necessities require. You can face the sharp and sometimes humiliating contrast with your better dressed classmate, for be assured that attention to your studies, thought and industry in your work, and a hearty realization of your advantages and duties, will remove these differences in a few years. With your growth and progress, your patched and shabby clothes will be wholly forgotten, or if recollected, 6 (81) </seg>
            <seg id="p095">t Zd SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES remembered only to your honor, and your independence will stand as an example worthy of emulation by the struggling boys who are to follow you. The poor and shabbily clad boy, with a clean face and clear head, seeking and appreciating the advantages of the public school, will win his way against all opposition. His future is assured. The want of the time is manly men, men of character, culture and courage, of faith and sincerity; the exalted manhood which forges its way to the front by force of its own merits. Self earned stations are the best and most secure; self -earned reputations the most lasting. What you have fairly acquired by your own brain and con - science and mind belongs to you. It is your throne from which you cannot be misplaced; your scepter, which you alone have a right to wield. It is your priceless possession. A man may get rich in a day or an hour by the quick turn of a fortunate speculation, but the only wealth which lasts and wears is that which builds steadily up through honesty, industry, and sacrifice. — Wm. McKinley, in Porter 1 » Life ofMcKinley. * # The Council of the Boohs ONE day the books in council met To crown the greatest one. The laurel wreath was all prepared, The Council was begun. The Dictionary took the floor In ponderous volumes two: " I hold the wisdom of the world, Pray give me what is due." Then came the Cyclopedia ; His volumes were two score. " I've twenty words for one of yours, Now which deserves it more ? " The novels said, "We please the world." The essays, "We instruct." Said Robert's Rules, " Clubs are the things, I show how to conduct." Shakespeare, in Russia leather dressed, Spoke eloquently, too. The books nodded their wise old heads And wondered what to do. A little gay First Reader came With photographs galore, And colored pictures on each page — " What could you ask foi more ? " " I teach the babies how to read, They learn it without trying. That I'm entitled to the crown Surely there's no denying." Then came a curious battered thing For such grand company; The Horn Book from the museum shelf With A and B and C. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p096">fePECIA-L DAi EXEivC/IdEo 83 For shame it could not lift its head, It looked upon the ground, But a great thunder of applause Rose from the circle round. They took the laurel from the shelf And crowned the Horn Book king. " For we are all your followers," Said the grand books in the ring. —Bertha E. Bush. 0 a A Life Lesson THERE! little girl; don't cry! They have broken your doll, I know; And your tea-set blue, And your play-house, too, Are things of the long ago ; But childish troubles will soon pass by, — There! little girl; don't cry! There! little girl; don't cry! They have broken your slate, I know! And the glad, wild days Of your school-girl days Are things of the long ago ; But life and love will soon come by, — There! little girl; don't cry! There! little girl; don't cry! They have broken your heart, I know; And the rainbow gleams Of your youthful dreams Are things of the long ago; But heaven holds all for which you sigh, — There! little girl; don't cry! — James Whitcomb Riley, in " Child Rhymes," Copyrighted. ( By permission The Bowen- Merrill Company. ) a 0 The Most Appropriate Gift A GOOD book is the most appropriate gift that friendship can make. It ill never changes, it never grows unfashionable or old. It is soured by no I neglect, it is jealous of no rival ; but always its clean, clear pages are idy to amuse, interest, and instruct. The voice that speaks the thought may mge or grow still forever, the heart that prompted the kindly and cheering rd may grow cold and forgetful ; but the page that mirrors it is changeless, thful, immortal. The book that records the incarnation of divine love, is d's best gift to man, and the books which are filled with kindly thought and lerous sympathy, are the bejt gifts of friend to friend. — Royal ftith of Life </seg>
            <seg id="p097">81 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES The Influence of Boohs THE influence of books upon man is remarkable; they make the man. You may judge a man more truly by the books and papers that he reads than by the company which he keeps, for his associates are often, in a manner, imposed upon him; but his reading is the result of choice, and a man who chooses a certain class of books and papers unconsciously becomes more colored in their views, more rooted in their opinions, and the mind be - comes fettered to their views. All the life and feeling of a young girl is fascinated by some glowing love romance, is colored and shaped by the page she reads. If it be false, and weak, and foolish, she will be false, and weak, and foolish, too; but if it be true, and tender, and inspiring, then something of its truth, and tenderness, and inspiration will grow into her soul and become a part of her very self. The boy who reads deeds of manliness, of bravery, and noble daring, feels the spirit of emulation grow within him, and the seed is planted which will bring forth fruit of heroic endeavor and exalted life . —Royal Path of Life. a a The Best Society in the World THE best society in the world is that which lives in books. No taint of vulgarity attaches to it, no petty strife for place or power disturbs its harmony, no falsehood stains its perfect truth; and those who move habitually in these associations find a strength which is the more controlling because moulded by genius into forms of grace and refinement. There is a certain monotony in daily life, and those whose aims are high, but who lack the inherent strength to stand true to them amid adverse in - fluences, gradually drop out of the ever-thinking ranks of the aspiring. They are conquered by routine and disheartened by the discipline and labor that guard the prizes of life. Even to the strongest there are hours of weak - ness and weariness. To the weak and to the strong, in their times of weak - ness, books are inspiring friends and teachers. Against the feebleness of individual efforts they proclaim the victory of faith and patience, and out of the uncertainty and discouragement of one day's work, they prophesy the fuller and richer life, that grows strong and deep through conflict, sets itself more and more in harmony with the noblest aims, and is at last crowned with honor and power. — Royal Path of Life. 0 0 The Value of College Training REV. Dr. J. P. John, ex-president of the De Pauw University, a wise, en - terprising, and skilful educator, says : " Is it worth while for the wood- man to stop an hour in the morning to grind his axe? He may be in a great haste to reach the scene of his daily work, but the greater his hurry, the longer he can afford to tarry at the grindstone. He may greatly desire to see the chips fly, but they will fly all the more rapidly when he comes an hour late with a sharp axe. He may hope to accomplish an unusually large day's work, but he will chop more wood in the one hour at the grindstone than he would have done in two hours with a blunt axe. A nine-hour day with a keen instrument is longer than a ten-hour day with a dull one. "Why should a young man at eighteen hurry into his life work with a dull, untempered, intellectual blade? Let him stop four or five years at the college grindstone. The 'expectation of life' for a man of eighteen is a little over forty years; that is he has a mathematical prospect of living until he is </seg>
            <seg id="p098"/>
            <seg id="p099">1U..., A FASCINATINU TALK. Taken from Mrs. Wilson's interesting book, " Picture Study in Elementary Schools, A Manual for Teachers, Part II," published by The Macmillan Company. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">■ fifty-eight years old. Shall he work forty years with a dull instrument and with the odds against him, or shall he halt for five years at the beginning in order to get ready, and then work thirty-five years with a keen blade, and with the odds in his favor? Which is the longer life to a young man just en - tering upon his vocation — forty more years on a low plane with contracted horizon, narrow opportunity, and small capacity, or thirty-five more years on a high plane with extended horizon, wide opportunity, and ever increasing capacity? Thirty-five may be more than forty. Thirty-five hours on an ex - press train means a greater distance than forty hours on a log wagon. The college graduate at twenty-three lives longer in his remaining thirty-five years from commencement day than does his fellow who hastens into business at eighteen in the forty years that yet possibly remain to him. ■ Let the young men and women of this generation stop and get well ready before plunging upon a career at which they have but one chance." a 0 Quotations QWEET are the uses of adversity, &lt;O Which, like the toad, ugly and venomous, Wears yet a precious jewel in his head ; And this, our life exempt from public haunt, Finds tongues in trees, books in running brooks, Sermons in stones, and good in everything. — Shakespeare. A little philosophy inclineth a man's mind to atheism, but depth in phil - osophy bringeth men's minds about to religion.— Bacon. A cheerful temper, joined with innocence, will make beauty attractive, knowledge delightful, and wit good-natured. It will lighten sickness, poverty, and affliction, convert ignorance into an amiable simplicity, and render de - formity itself agreeable. — Addison. Oh, wad some power the giftie gie us To see oursels as ithers see us! It wad frae mony a blunder free us And foolish notion. What airs in dress and gait wad lea' us, And e'en devotion. —Burns. Might I give counsel to any young hearer, I would say to him : Try to frequent the company of your betters. In books and life, that is the most wholesome society; learn to admire rightly; the great pleasure of life is that. Note what great men admire; they admired great things; narrow spirits ad - mire basely, and worship meanly. — Thackeray. Knowledge is of two kinds : We know the subject ourselves, or we know where we can find information upon it. — Johnson. Reading without purpose is sauntering, not exercise. More is got from one book on which the thought settles, for a definite end in knowledge, than from libraries skimmed over by a wandering eye. A cottage flower gives honey to the bee, — a king's garden none to the butterfly. — Lytton. </seg>
            <seg id="p101">WJ SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES The Study of Pictures To Teacher* Who Are Interested in Pictures and Picture Study: We're made so that we love First when we see them painted, things we have passed Perhaps a hundred times nor cared to see; God uses us to help each other so, Lending our minds out. — Robert Browning. Children delight in pictures. Every child-lover knows how intently and with what delight the baby's eyes gaze upon the pages of the beloved picture book, long before the words which describe the picture can be spoken or even understood by the young student. The childish chatter is an attempt to ex - press the delight in the treasure and the thoughts suggested by the picture. As the child grows older, pictures continue to be a source of pleasure. He names the familiar objects, talks about them, asks questions about them. Thus he unconsciously grows in the power to see and to tell what he sees, taught by the many willing helpers who turn the pages of his book and inter - pret its pictures. We have been slow in our school work to follow the teaching of children's experience. Although we have always known and always recognized the child's interest in pictures, we have not used them in the school room to the extent that they might have been used, nor in such a manner as to yield the greatest advantage. The writer remembers a class of children in whose hands were placed some new readers beautifully illustrated with full -page pictures. The new books which had just been brought into the room, were given to the children with the brief direction, " Turn to page 85 and begin reading at the top of the page." " Theirs not to reason why, Theirs not to make reply." The obedient fingers turned to the page indicated, and the curious eyes were allowed no moment to linger over the pages which tempted them with their fascinating pictures. Yet here was the "Delectable Land," which might have been opened to them to their lasting advantage. Here the children's interest was assured, and no artificial incentive needed to be pre - sented. Another class, under similar conditions, had a different experience. " Here are new books," the teacher said to the children. " You will en - joy reading these stories, I know. But you will find pictures in them as well as stories. Before we read, let us look at the pictures and enjoy them." The children eagerly opened the books. They found, as a frontispiece, a copy of Rosa Bonheur's " Norman Sire." The children talked about the picture, "compared the horse with horses that they knew, admired the noble head, the fine eyes. As they turned the pages or their books, they found other pictures of animals, " The Lions at Home," and "Coming from the Pair." Their comments were free, their questions ready. Nobody thought of the picture as a picture. The conver - sation centered about lions and horses only, and expressed the children's interest in animals. It was the teacher who called the attention of the children to the name written underneath the first picture, " Rosa Bonheur." This they inferred, must be the name of the one who made the picture. The teacher then explained that the pictures in the book were copied from photographs of the original pictures which the artist painted. If the children were to see the painting they would find it colored and much larger than the copies. Looking again with a new interest at the other pictures, the children dis - covered the same name written below them. " Did Rosa Bonheur paint this picture, too?" "And this?" " Did she paint any others? "" Does she paint </seg>
            <seg id="p102">a now?" These questions answered, the children asked, "Who painted the picture of the little girl tending the baby?" "Is this the painter's name under the picture ?" "Yes, Meyer Von Bremen. On this page you will find another picture of his." The children found the picture of " The Pet Canary," and talked earnestly about it. " I like that picture. I wonder if it is the same little girl?" "What queer chairs ?" "What a funny window." "This girl has been knitting, too." The teacher threw some light upon the German exterior, explaining that this was a picture of a home in the country where the artist lived. Then she questioned, " What did Meyer Von Bremen paint for you ?" "Children," was the ready response. "And what did Rosa Bonheur paint ? " "Animals," came quite as readily. " Do the pictures tell you anything about the artists?" The children hesitated. "You remember, 'The Children's Hour'?" sug - gested the teacher. " You thought that Mr. Longfellow wrote about children," — "Because he loved children." volunteered a child, as the teacher paused. " I should think Meyer Von Bremen liked children, too," observed another thoughtfully. "And Rosa Bonheur must like animals," added a third. They turned again to the pictures, and decided, after some discussion, that Rosa Bonheur not only loved animals, but was able to make us love them better by her painting. Such study has a legitimate place in the school curriculum. Happily, it is now emphasized in some degree in the drawing. It should also appear in connection with the reading. The picture is intended to throw light upon the lesson which is illustrated. The children should be taught to read the picture as well as the story. Fortunately the abundance of cheap good reprints, and the careful illus - tration of text -books, place the means for such study within the reach of every teacher and pupil. It will not be long before the picture will take its proper place with the song and the poem as a factor in elementary education. — Ex - tracts from an article on '■'■The Study of Pictures," by Sarah Louise Arnold, in "Reading: How to Teach it," by Dermission of Silver, Hurdett and Com - pany. a 0 Practical Suggestions (Taken from Mrs. Wilson's excellent little books on Picture Study In Elementary Schools Numbers land II, to which teachers are referred for further information.) A GOOD background for pictures and bits of statuary is essential. For - tunately, in modern school houses the walls are most frequently painted a cream color, which not only harmonizes well with the usually yellow woodwork, but also sets off t.ie pictures to the greatest advantage. With regard to the pictures, two externals are essential: First, that they shall be large; and second, that they shall be suitably framed. It is a great temptation to buy four small pictures rather than one large one. If you are buying for your own room, then perhaps the choice could be defended. But in a school room, which isa place forstudy, for work, the dignity which eomes from the size counts for more than variety. Then, too, the children remain in the room but a year at most. Let them carry away with them the deep abiding remembrance of a few large pictures well hung. Framing. — Plain moulding with no ornate projections to catch the dust and worry the eye is a safe choice. Very wide mats and frames are out of place in the schoolroom. The usual rule forcolor is that the frame should cor - respond with the middle tone of the picture. In the long run unexpensive oak, ash, or birch frames will be the most satisfactory. ekBIly '}i U1M II naill' ~» Will ut; liic luuat oauoioi/iui j» . Small pictures have their value, and should be given from time to time a temporary place on the walls. When, for instance, the children are studying the early colonial history of our own country, what could be better than a line, </seg>
            <seg id="p103">t* SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES or two lines, on a level with the children's eyes, of the series of the pictures which so graphically illustrate the conditions and facts of the settlement of Massachusetts, viz., the series by Boughton, and the corresponding pictures by Weir and Rothennel ? An excellent way to keep them permanently is to paste partout them. Materials. — Ptts»e partrwt paper, which comes in all colors, gummed, put up in small rolls; photographic mounts the size desired; glass of a size to correspond with the mounts; bottle of library paste; and gummed suspen - sion eyes or rings. With these materials proceed as follows: Cut away neatly all the white margin, or if preferred leave a white margin of less than one-eighth of an inch in width; place the trimmed picture in the middle of the mount and secure it there by applying paste to the corners or upper edge of picture ; paste the paste partout paper for one-half its width to the edge of the glass, whicn has Deen thoroughly cleaned; place the mounted picture, face down, on glass and paste free edges of paper to back of mount; on the middle of the back glue the suspension eyes or ring. — Jennie B. Adams, Department Stenographer. Calendars.— This is an excellent way to use the smaller pictures. The calendar pads cost but a few cents. "Rembrandt mounts," 8x10 inches, make the most convenient mount. On each of these paste an appropriate picture. Below the picture fasten the leaf for the month on the calendar. After pressing the mounts — always an essential when paste is used — eyelet them and fasten them together. A most effective Millet calendar may be made in this way : — Use a por - trait of Millet for the cover mount, then for each month choose the following appropriate pictures: — January, Girl Spinning. February, Woman Churning. March, Labor. April, Potato Planting. May, The Sower. June, Going to Work. July, The Gleaners. August, The Angelus. September, The Rainbow. October, Feeding the Hens. November, The Wood-Chopper. December, Mother and Child. For a like purpose, the pictures of Rosa Bonheur, Breton, Dupre, Corot, lend themselves with equal appropriateness to the change of seasons. Equally interesting calendars may be made from the pictures of Botticelli, Raphael, Rubens, Van Dyck, Velasquez, Murillo, Rembrandt, Sir Joshua Reynolds, and Burne-Jones, to mention the better known and more popular artists only. Course. — To those who prefer to make their own course, I would sug - gest a picture for each month, selecting always something appropriate to the season ; for example, a scene reminiscent of vacation sights, or a summer picture from another land. Perhaps for those who have left their mothers for the first time, a Madonna, or to put them even more at ease, a picture of some of their pets at home, would be suitable for September. For October, show them a harvest picture. November may be celebrated with one of Boughton's reminders of the Pilgrims and Thanksgiving, or with something suggestive of preparation for winter. In December come the Madonnas. Then devote the winter months to the study of the old masters. With the end of winter comes appropriately enough the study of some of the modern masters. In the spring take up the study of some of the outdoor scenes which belong to this season, while in the summer months suitable outdoor scenes, or, better still, pictures of summer in distant lands. — Picture Study in Elementary Schools, by Mrs. L. L. Wilson. {By permission of The MacmiUan Oo.) </seg>
            <seg id="p104">Punting by Me jrer voa Brana (i«) PAY TOLL HERE! </seg>
            <seg id="p105">From Baldwin** Primer. Copyright, 18M, by America* Book Company. PmiMif^ by A- Lei THE END OF THE DAY The birdie has gone to its nest, And baby must go to her bed, For the sun has sunk down in the west In curtains of purple and red. Yes, this is the end of the day ; The lambs are asleep in the dew; So baby must leave off her play, And go to her little bed too. -Airowmou.. 122 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">A Thanksgiving Hymn. CAN a little child like me, Thank the Father fittingly? Yes, oh yes! be good and true, Patient, kind in all you do; Love the Lord and do your part, Learn to say with all your heart : ■ Father, we thank Thee ! Father, we thank Thee! Father in Heaven we thank Thee! For the fruits upon the tree, For the birds that sing of Thee, For the earth in beauty drest. Father, mother, and the rest, For Thy precious loving care, For Thy bounty everywhere, Father, we thank Thee! Father, we thank Thee! Father in Heaven we thank Thee! — Mary Mape* Dodge. 0 a Praise God PRAISE God for wheat, so white and sweet, Of which we make our bread ! Praise Him for yellow corn with which His waiting world is fed! Praise God for fish and flesh and fowl He gave to roan for food ! Praise God for every creature which He made and called it good! Praise God for winter's store of ice, Praise God for summer's heat! Praise God for fruit trees bearing seed, " To you it is for meat! " Praise God for all the bounty By which the world is fed! Praise God, ye children all, to whom He gives your daily bread ! —Selected. (89) 0 hanksgiving NOVEMBER 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">90 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Little Paul's Thanksgiving THEY tossed him and they squeezed him, And they kissed him one and all; They said, "You blessed, blessed boy ! " And "Darling little Paul !" But they didn't (jive him turkey, Nor any pumpkin pie, And when the nuts and gTapes went round They slyly passed him by. But he didn't seem to mind it, For in the sweetest way He sat and sucked his little thumb His first Thanksgiving day. Selected. * * A Little Boy's Dream THANKSGIVING night I had a fright. I thought I heard it said That turkey dear was coming near, But hadn't any head ! Thanksgiving night, oh, awful sight ! I thought the turkey came, And then he said, "Who stole my head ? I'd like to know your name." Thanksgiving night no more delight Take I in turkeys bold, For then it seems they come in dreams And make your flesh turn cold. — Laura Rountree Smith. * # When the Frost is on the PunKin the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock, T» And you hear the kyouck and gobble of the struttin' turkey-cock And the clackin' of the guineys and the cluckin' of the hens, And the rooster's hallylooyer as he tiptoes on the fence ; O, it's then's the times a feller is a feelin' at his best, With the risin' sun to greet him from a night of peaceful rest, As he leaves the house bareheaded and goes out to feed the stock When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock. They's something kindo' hearty like about the atmusfere When the heat of summer's over and the coolin' fall is here — Of course we miss the flowers and the blossoms on the trees, And the mumble of the hummin'-birds and buzzin' of the bees; But the air's so appetizin'; and the landscape through the haze Of a crisp and sunny morning of the early autumn days Is a pictur' that no painter has the colorin' to mock- When the frost ir on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock. </seg>
            <seg id="p108"/>
            <seg id="p109">or tiL&gt; 1 A.L* UA i t. A. tirCL/l^ij^) 91 The husky rusty rustle of the tossels of the corn, And the raspin of the tangled leaves as golden as the morn; The stubble in the furries kindo' lonesome -like, but still A-preachin' sermons to us of the barns they growed to fill ; The strawstack in the medder, and the reaper in the shed; The hosses in theyr stalls below— the clover overhead! — O, it sets my heart a clickin' like the tickin' of a clock, When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock! Then your apples all is gethered, and the ones a feller keep&gt; Is poured around the cellar floor in red and yeller heaps; And your eider-makin's over, and your wimmern-folks is through With theyr mince and apple-butter and theyr souse and , »oo! I don't know how to tell it — but ef sich a thing could be As the angels wantin' boardin', and they'd call around on m&lt;- I'd want to 'commodate 'em — all the whole-indurin' flock — When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock. — James WhitcombRiley,in " Neighborly Poems,' 1 '' copyrighted . By permission of Bowen-Merrill O # # A Thanksgiving Dialogue (A ragged little boy, a street wait, enters stagf and recites M indicated. He should be a fair reciter, able to be heard by all.) BOY. THEY call this Thanksgiving, A day to be glad ; But how can I keep it, A poor, hungry lad ? I sleep in a cellar, I live on the street; How can I be thankful, I've nothing to eat ? He sits down on a box as If on the street, when along comes a little girl dressed for the street and carrying a package. FIRST GIRL. A happy Thanksgiving To you, little man. Each one should be thankful The best that he can. BOY. You're kind, little lady, But tell me, I pray, Why I should be thankful On this happy day ? FIRST GIRL. I'm going to visit A blind little friend ; Suppose this poor blind boy Your eyes you would lend. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">92 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES He can't see his parents, The beautiful light; He sits sad and lonely In one starless night. BOY. Pass on little stranger, I can't spare my eyes; I've one gift of value Which I ought to prize. She passes on, ) SECOND GIRL. (Enters stage, dressed (or calling ) Good morning! glad morning! Why are you so sad ? Today is Thanksgiving, When all should be glad. BOY. I've only one blessing Which I've learned to prize; Although I am wretched I'm glad for my eyes. SECOND GIRL. I'm going to visit A lame little boy; He can't walk a step, Yet his heart's full of joy. He once sold the papers, The best on the street; Until the cars caught him And crushed both his feet. He lives in Black alley ; His parents are dead ; A cripple, he's thankful; But you hang your head. BOY. I, too, am the quickest On foot, the boys say: For seeing and walking, I'm thankful today. (Second girl passes on.) THIRD GIRL. (Enters stage and carries a basket and bundle My poor little stranger, Why are you so sad? Today is Thanksgiving, When all should be glad. BOY. I'm thankful this morning, For eyes and for feet; No more, for I suffer For something to eat. I'm poverty's orphan, You're wealth's child, I know — Pray what do you carry, And where may you go? </seg>
            <seg id="p111">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 93 THIRD GIRL. I have here a dinner, Some books, and a toy For poor Billy Mason, A deaf ai\d dumb boy. He wants to hear music, And talk like the boys; He lives in lone silence, So few are his joys. Third girl passes on.) BOY. (Rising and speaking in an earnest manner My eyes are my diamonds, My feet are true friends', My ears bring me music, My speech comfort lends. Though hungry and ragged On this happy day, I'll brace up and hustle; The will makes the way. That boy should be thankful, Though poor and distressed, Who has all the powers With which I am blessed. I'll earn what is needful, No longer repine ; Though poor yet I'm favored, With powers divine. I know if I labor And live the right way, I'll always be thankful On this happy day. He retires ■T. B. Weaver, in School Education a a A Patriotic Thanksgiving Exercise. This exercise may be given by six pupils; two dressed as Indians, two as Negroes, and two as Puritans. The Indian* may dress in brown blankets trimmed with bands of yellow, a gay-colored fringe around the bottom, leggins, beaded moccasins. Their bead-dress may oe a band of red card board, on the inside of which are sewn long, stiff feathers. Bits of gold, silver, and tin may adorn the front of their blankets. Their faces may be painted in streaks of brown and red. (Water colors are harmless.) Bow and arrows should be hung over the back of each, and each may carry a tomahawk. The two Pilgrims may be dressed in long cloaks or capes and broad - rlmmed hats, and may carry guns over their shoulders. The two Negroes should color their faces with burnt cork , wear checked trousers and gay neckties. Each has a flag. The six march in to the roll of a drum. FIRST INDIAN. I THINK of the days when with swift-footed step Through the wilderness wild I bounded. I think of the chiefs, our Indian dance, As our songs through the forests resounded. </seg>
            <seg id="p112">94 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES I have stood in many a bloody war, With warriors dying about me, Strong I've stood by the burning stake, Whence the bravest would never flee. In fighting, in hunting, in fishing — al!, I have joyed in the face of danger; But ah ! we were driven and crushed and killed By the white and merciless stranger. SECOND INDIAN. I will go to my tent and lie down in despair; I will paint me with black and sever my hair; I will sit on the shore where the hurricane blows And reveal to the God of the Tempest my woes ; I will weep for a season on bitterness fed, For my kindred are gone to the hills of the dead ; But they died not of hunger, or lingering decay; The steel of the white man hath swept chem away. —Selected, FIRST PURITAN. 0, see what wonders meet our eyes! Another land, and other skies! Columbian hills have met our view! Adieu! Old England's shores, adieu! Here, at length, our feet shall rest, Hearts be free, and homes be blest. — Vpham. SECOND PURITAN. Great God! we thank Thee for this home, This bounteous birth-land of the free; Where wanderers from afar may come And breathe the air of liberty! Still may her flowers untrammeled spring, Her harvests wave, her cities rise : And yet, till time shall fold her wing, Remain Earth's loveliest paradise ! — Pabodie, FIRST NEGRO. Guided by our country's laws, For truth, and right and suffering man Be ours to strive in Freedom's cause, As Christians may, as freemen cant Still pouring on unwilling ears That truth oppression only fears. — Whittier. SECOND NEGRO. Rail on, then, "brethren of the South," Ye shall not hear the truth the less; No seal is on the Yankee's mouth, No fetter on the Yankee's press ! From our Green Mountains to the sea, One voice shall thunder, We are free? —WhitHer. ALL REPEAT. By our altars, pure and free, By our Law's deep-rooted tree, By the past dead memory, By our Washington ; </seg>
            <seg id="p113">95 By our common parent tongue, By our hopes, bright, buoyant, young, By the tide of country strong, We will still be one. "Fathers ! have ye bled in vain? Ages ! must ye droop again ? Maker ! shall we rashly stain Blessings sent by Thee ?" No! receive our solemn vow, While before thy throne we bow, Even to maintain as now, "Union, liberty." — Selected America" should then be sung as it Is sung at Hampton Institute, Va. WHITES, NEGROES, AND INDIANS SING My country, 'tis of thee, Sweet land of liberty, Of thee I sing. INDIANS. Land where my fathers died, PURITANS. Land of the pilgrim's pride, NEGROES. From every mountain side, Let Freedom ring INDIANS ALONE SING THE SECOND STANZA. My native country, thee, Land of the noble free, Thy name I love. I love thy rocks and rills, Thy woods and templed hills, My heart with rapture thrills Like that above. NEGROES SING THE THIRD STANZA. Let music swell the breeze And ring from all the trees Sweet freedom's song. Let mortal tongues awake, Let all that breathe partake, Let rocks their silence break, The sound prolong. WHOLE SCHOOL AND ALL JOIN IN SINGINO LAST STANZA. (School rises.) Our fathers' God, to thee, Author of liberty, To thee we sing. Long may our land be bright With freedom's holy light ; Protect us by thy might, Great God, our King. —Ella Marie Poteen. </seg>
            <seg id="p114">96 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Landing of the Pilgrims THE breaking waves dashed high On a stern and rock-bound coast, And the woods against a stormy sky Their giant branches tossed ; And the heavy night hung dark The hills and waters o'er, When a band of exiles moored their bark On the wild New England shore. Not as the conqueror comes, They, the true-hearted, came, Not with the roll of the stirring drums, And the trumpet that sings of fame. Not as the flying come, In silence, and in fear. They shook the depths of the desert's gloom With their hymns of lofty cheer. Amid the storm they sang, . And the stars heard and the sea ; And the sounding aisles of the dim woods lung To the anthem of the free. The ocean eagle soared From his nest by the white waves' foam, And the rocking pines of the forest roared : This was their welcome home. There were men with hoary hair Amid that pilgrim band ; Why had they come to wither there, Away from their childhood's land? There was woman's fearless eye, Lit by her deep love's truth ; There was manhood's brow serenely high And the fiery heart of youth. What sought they thus afar ? Bright jewels of the mine ? The wealth of seas, the spoils of war ? They sought a faith's pure shrine! Ay, call it holy ground, The soil where first they trod! They have left unstained what there they found! Freedom to worship God ! — Mrs. Hemans. </seg>
            <seg id="p115">CHRISTMAS IS COMING. From the Finch Primer, by permission of Ginn * Co., Chicago. To Prevent a Mistake When Santa comes down the chimney With his heavy pack of toys, How does he know which stockings are girls', And which belong to boys ? Suppose he should fill boys' stockings With tea-sets and dolls — Oh, my! — And should give tops, guns, and marbles to girls! Wouldn't there be a cry? It's no use to borrow trouble At this time so full of joy, But I'll pin this note on my stocking's toe: " Dear Santa, I'm a boy." — Laura F. Armitage. (97) 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">98 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES A Christinas Eve Thought IF Santa Claus should stumble, As he climbs the chimney tall With all this ice upon it, I'm afraid he'd get a fall And smash himself to pieces — To say nothing of the toys! Dear me, what sorrow that would bring To all the girls and boys ! So I am going to write a note And pin it to the gate— I'll write it large so he can see, No matter if it's late, — And say, "Dear Santa Claus, don't try To climb the roof to-night, . But walk right in, the door's unlocked, The nursery's on the right! " ■St. Nicholas. a a Hang Up the Children's Stockings HANG up the children's stockings, And ring the happy chimes, For peace and love shall reign on earth In merry Christmas time— Mementos of that other morn In Bethlehem where Christ was born. Some homes in every nation, In city or in town, Still keep the dear old customs The past has handed down, And celebrate them year by year, Aa Christmas crowns the world with cheer. In English homes, 'neath mistletoe, They sing the Christmas song. While o'er the Yule-log's rugged side The bright flames creep along, And scarlet holly berries glow Among the green boughs bending low. We decorate the branches Of Christmas trees with cheer, An emblem of thanksgiving For all the fruitful year. And Santa Claus brings dolls and drums, To glad expectant little ones. 0, day the best and dearest Of all the seasons, bring The hope of every Christian heart, The birthday of our King; The one glad day of joy and mirth, When God's best gift was sent to earth. -Selected. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">oPECIAL* DAY EXERCISES 99 Christmas Joy (Tune: " There's a Good Time Coming, Help It On.") THERE'S a gladness all around, Christmas joy! There's a gladness all around, Christmas joy! Smiles can easily be found, Mirth and happiness abound, Christmas joy, Christmas joy, Christmas joy, joy, joy 1 There's a bustle through the street, Christmas joy! There's a bustle through the street, Christmas joy! Bundles, bundles do we meet, Laughing crowds and tripping feet , Christmas joy, Christmas joy, Christmas joy, joy, joy! Savory odors fill the air, Christmas joy! Savory odors fill the air, Christmas joy! Busy housewives everywhere For their friends a feast prepare, Christmas joy, Christmas joy, Christniar joy, joy, joy ! 0 * A Feel in the Christmas Air THEY'S a kind o' feel in the air, to me, When the Chris'mas time sets in, That's about as much of a mystery As ever I've run agin! Fer instunce, now, whilse I gain in weight An' gineral health, I swear There's a goneness somers I can't quite state — A kind o' feel in the air. They's a feel in the Chris'mas air goes right To the spot where a man lives at! It gives a feller an appetite — There ain t no doubt about that! And yit, they's somepin' — I don't know what — That follows me here and there, And ha'nts and worries and spares me not — A kind o' feel in the air. Is it the racket the children raise? W'y, no .'-God bless 'em!— no.' Is it the eyes and cheeks ablaze— Like my own wuz, long ago? — Is it the bleat o' the whistle and beat O' the little toy-drum and blare O' the horn?— No! no!— it's jest the sweet— The sad-sweet feel in the air. — James Whitcomb Riley. </seg>
            <seg id="p118">100 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES SANTA CLAUS IS COMING From the Finch Primer, by permiisiun of Ginn &lt;fc Co. A Christmas Gift This short dialogue may be given by two pupils', a boy and a girl. The girl should hare an old doll In her arms, the boy should carry an old drum with (he head broken. GIRL. This doll Kris Kringle brought last year, Gone is one eye, her hair, her ear; And now some new ones he must bring, The kind that walk and talk and sing. BOY. Here is a drum I had last year, You see it sounds now very queer; I left it out once in the rain, I've begged for other new drums in vain. GIRL. (Seating herself at a table.) Let's write a letter to Santa Claus, Telling him what to bring, because It must be hard to bring, you see, The very things we want; Dear me! (Girl reaching for paper, Ink, and pen, writes. Presently she reads :) " I'll have a hundred wax dolls when you come, And please bring a nice, rich sounding drum; Bring hundreds of books and games, a store, And a thousand candies and lots more." The letter is done and now we'll away And mail it to him right off to-day. BOY. I guess he'll think 'tis very shocking, To expect so much in one small stocking. —Ella M. Powers, in the Intelligence. </seg>
            <seg id="p119">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 101 Christmas Fairies (Enter two small boys— Queen's pages, saying in concert: "Hearye! Hear ye! Hear ye! The court or the Christmas Fairies Is about to assemble. Make way for the Queen of the Fairies !" They arrange chair for throne, foot -stool, etc., then stand one on each side of throne at back. Enter Queen and two maids of honor; Queen takes place and maids stand one near each page. Pages and maids say in concert:) Gentle Christmas Fairy Queen, Here thy Maids and Pages stand. Touch us with thy wand so green, We'll obey thy least command. (Queen rises and touches first maid with her sceptre and says:) Good- Will, do all the boys and girls in the world still remember and love you ? Good-Will— Nearly all are my friends. Some poor children hare never heard about Good- Will, and they quarrel and sometimes hurt one another and hare bad wishes. But I am going about all over the world as quickly as I can, teaching them what a good fairy "Good Will " is and how happy I can make them. (Queen touches second maid, saying:) Your name is Peace. Do you make people peaceful at Christmastime? k Peace — Yes, and all the year. I keep little girls quiet and good and p them from being afraid, and I make the little boys play their games lout quarreling. First Page. — Your majesty, the other Christmas Fairies^ire coming. Enter First Fairy. Queen — Welcome to our fairy court, Sprite. Where hare you been and t have you done. First Fairy (girl) — I am the fairy of Christmas Beauty. I have gone through the world with my holly and mistletoe and evergreen. I have helped to trim the churches; I have hung wreaths in the windows; I have helped the flowers to bloom. But, best of all, I touched a little girl's thoughts and she began to think of the poor little girl around the corner who had no beauty in her home. Then I led the little girl down the dark street and smiled upon her while she put flowers in the window and hung evergreens over the fire- Second Page— Another fairy comes. (Enter Second Fairy (boy) says:) kHail, Christmas Queen. I have worked through all the year to fill boys' •ts with Christmas feeling, and now it is Christmas time and I am happy, the good boys are waiting for Santa Claus, and they are all going to do ething to make Christmas happy for someone else. Pages— Who comes here ? (Enter two fairies— boy and girl. They say In concert :) Oh, Queen and Fairies, if you could have seen what we hare seen! All— What was it? The Gnu, — Oh, such happy children! Hundreds and hundreds of them! The Boy — And we helped to make them happy. The Girl — Yes, we whispered to them about Christmas and Santa Claus. The Boy — And stockings and candy. The Girl — And they will be up early Christmas morning and they'll play — The Boy — And skate and coast. </seg>
            <seg id="p120">102 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES The Girl — And I helped hundreds of little girls to remember how glad their busy fingers could make some one, and they are dressing dolls and mak - ing aprons and warm hoods and — Oh, the whole world is happy. It is Christ - mas time! The Boy — And bo many boys are saving their pennies to buy skates and mittens for poorer boys. We have worked well this year. (All the Fairies recite In concert:) "Everywhere, everywhere, Christmas to-night. Christmas in lands of the fir tree and pine, Christmas in lands of the palm tree and vine, Christmas where snow-peaks stand solemn and white, Christmas where corn fields lie sunny and bright I Christmas where children are hopeful and gay, Christmas where old men are patient and gray, Christinas where peace, like a dove in his flight, Broods o'er brave men in the thick of the fight, Everywhere, everywhere, Christmas to-night! For the Christ-child who comes is the master of all, — No palace too great and no cottage too small." (Enter last Fairy as if In great hurry. He rushes to his place without stopping to bow to the Queen as the others have done. He says :) I know I'm late, but have been working very hard. Queen— Where have you been? Last Fairy— Helping Santa Claus. Oh how we have worked ! There were the dolls and drums and skates and books and dolls' carriages and toy engines and boats and wagons and candy and oranges and nuts and warm mittens and pop-corn and toy furniture and — and— Oh, so many things all to be packed in that little sleigh; and the reindeer to harness and — Oh, there will be some happy children tomorrow ! All— Welcome to dear old Christmas. (All sing with school any suitable Christmas song. At end of song Queen leaves throne and followed by Maids, Pages, and Fairies in procession, walks from room.) — Helen Morris Sedgewick. 0 a A Christmas Exercise Scene:— An ordinary room or schoolroom. Teacher seated beside a desk; children dancing about the room singing. Tune:—" Rock-a-Bye Baby.' DANCE we together, happy and gay, Cheerily singing of Christmas Day. Backward and forward, then to and fro, That is the way the children must go. Little care we, though loud the winds blow, Skies may be gray and fast fall the snow. Put away books, be merry and free, Christmas is coming! Hurrah, say we! TEACHER. So you think Christmas is coming ? CHILDREN. Of course we do, it's almost here, And Santa Claus, too, is drawing near. We can almost hear the jingling of bells That of his coming always tells. </seg>
            <seg id="p121">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 103 TEACHER. And what will you do at Christmas, My dear little girls and boys ? CHILDREN. Be merry as birda the livelong day, Have candy and lots cf toys. TEACHER. My dears, do you think that the wisest way, — Is that all you will do on Christmas Day ? CHILDREN. We will speak the truth, whatever we do, And try to be honest, brave, and true. Thoughtful for others, patient alway. That's what we will do upon Christmas Day. TEACHER. That I am sure is a better plan, Be kind and do all the good you can. (Knocking outside; sound of bells and some one singing.) Tune:—" Oh, Hare You Heard Geography Sung ? " Here I come knocking now at your door, Now at your door, now at your door; Here I come knocking now at your door, While Christmas bells are a-ringing. CHILDREN. Who is there ? (Door opens and Santa Claus puts In his head.) SANTA CLAUS. I am Mr. Santa Claus, Only come to call. Here's a lot of Christmas things, You can have them all. (Puts his pack on the threshold.) CHILDREN. Thank you, Mr. Santa Claus, You are welcome here. Please step in a moment, sir, And pass the time of year. We are only boys and girls Keeping Christmas Day, And we're always glad whene'er We see you come this way. SANTA CLAUS. Nay, I must not wait for you, I have far to go. Over Afric's burning sands, Russia's steppes of snow. With my reindeer, like a bird, Through the air I fly. Time is up— now little folks, I am off — good bye. (Goes away singing while the bells ring, until the sound la lost In the distance.) </seg>
            <seg id="p122">104 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES , Tune:—" The Spanish Cayaller." Oh, farewell, farewell! I can no longer stay For I must away o er the snow, dears The short winter's day Will soon speed away. Remember and be true where you go, dears. (Children join hands and dance around, reciting:) Old Santa Claus has gone To other lands afar, But 0, he's left such loads of toys, Hurrah! Hurrah! Hurrah! (Knock at the door; enter child, bearing a Christmas tree.) CHILD. Here's a little Christmas tree, All with toys 'tis laden. Pretty gifts old Santa Claus Brought for each wee maiden. BOYS. (Beginning to cry.) For the girls, O, dear! O, dear! Where then, are our toys ? TEACHER. Don't you fear, good Santa Claus Won't forget the boys. Just outside, I'm sure I see, Trumpet, fife, and drum, Hoops and marbles, skates and sleds, Each one will have some. (Enter children ringing small bells.) We are little Christmas bells. Don't you hear us ringing ? (Enter Carol singers.) CAROL SINGERS. We are merry Christmas Waifs. You shall hear us sing. (They sing " Beautiful Christmas Time.") (Written for Teacher 1 s World and adapted for this program by Department of Public Instruction.) Beautiful Christmas Time. Adapted to the tune "Hail Columbia." Beautiful this, our Christmas time, Beautiful bells, with silv'ry chime, Beautiful words are these we say, Beautiful words are these we say, — Jesus, our King, is born today, Jesus our King is born. Beautiful angels came of old, Sang to the shepherds near their fold; Beautiful story told to them, Beautiful story told to them, — Jesus is born in Bethlehem, Is born in Bethlehem. </seg>
            <seg id="p123">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 105 Beautiful songs they sing today, Sweeter by far than earthly lay ; Join in the chorus, all who sing, Join in the chorus, all who sing, — Joy to the world, our Lord is King, Joy, our Lord is King! — From Sunshine Melodies. Enter several children dressed to represent pop - corn and nuts. Pop-corn wears yellow and white and has a string of pop-corn around his neck; nuts wear brown. POP-CORNS. We are little pop -corns, and When around the fire Christmas Eve, you're sitting all, No one can jump higher. NUTS. We are Christmas nuts so brown, That the boys are bringing. Crack us while the merry girls Christmas songs are singing. CHILDREN. Don't you think we well may be, Happy, glad, and gay, When so many things we have For our Christmas Day? TEACHER. Yes, my little children ; and Thank the One in heaven, Who, from out His boundless love, Christ's birthday has given. CHILDREN. Won't you tell the story, pray, Of that first glad Christmas Day? TEACHER. Yes, I'll tell it. CHILDREN. Now? TEACHER. Nay, wait, Someone stands outside the gate. Don't you hear their voices ring? 'Tis a Christmas song they sing. (Voices outside singing.) Tune:— "What a Friend We Have in Jesus." We are coming, we are coming, Where our bright rays all may see, We are coming, we are coming, Now to grace your Christmas tree. For we know that God is saying, As each ray doth shimmer down, That a Babe for you, dear children, Now is born in Bethlehem town. (Enter several children. They wear buff dresses and a band of gilt paper about their foreheads, with one star In the center.) </seg>
            <seg id="p124">106 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES CHILDREN. Who are you? STARS. Don't you know us? Then, on some starry night, Look upward to the heavens, You will see us shining bright. Our homes are in the ether ; We are stars that gem the sky ; And we come to you, dear children, From that blus dome up on high. We've come to tell unto you, How once, when he looked down, Upon the humble dwellings In ancient Bethelem town, We saw where, in a stable, All cradled in the hay, Within a lowly manger, The Baby Jesus lay. FIRST STAR. I saw out on the hillsides, The wondering shepherds, bowed Before the heavenly choir, A shining, glorious crowd. SECOND STAR. Their ladder reached the heavens And loud their voices rang, As to the awe-struck shepherds, The heavenly chorus sang. "Peace, peace on earth," they chanted, "Good will, good will," and then, "Glad tidings we are bringing, Unto the sons of men." THIRD STAR. I shone within the stable, And there the shepherds saw, Before that Baby bending, In mute, adoring awe. FOURTH STAR. Far off, across the desert, From their distant Eastern home, With balm and myrrh and spices, I saw three Wise Men come. FIFTH STAR. Twas I who went before them, Through all the weary way, And shone above the stable, Where the little Christ-child lay. SIXTH STAR. And when the Wise Men found Him, Led by a guiding star, I saw the precious jewels They brought Him from afar. </seg>
            <seg id="p125">SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES 107 TOGETHER. Then when the Babe they'd worshipped,— Each Wise Man, well content, Back to the Eastern country, By another pathway went. This is the precious story, So old, yet ever new, And we have come, dear children, To tell it unto you. (Tune: "Lightly Row." ALL SINO. Prom the starry realms of space, We have come a weary way, To help the little children keep A merry Christmas Day. CHORUS. We are shining, shining for you, Shining for you, little children dear, For Christmas Day is ever the best, The best of all the year. CHILDREN RECITE. O, little stare that came to earth, To tell us of the Christ-child's birth, We welcome you and, hand in hand, Together a united band, Let us so gaily march along And wake the echoes with a song; And while to heaven the chorus swells, Loud let us ring the Christmas bells. (They join hands and march two by two around the stage, ringing bells and singing Christmas Welcome.) The The Christmas Welcome Tune: " Tramp, Tramp, Tramp." When the summer time is passed and the harvest housed at last, And the woods are standing bare and brown and sere, When the frost is sharp at night, and the days are short and bright, Comes the gladdest, merriest time of all the year. CHORUS. Shout, boys, shout the hearty welcome! Greet old Christmas with a roar! He has met us with good cheer for this many a merry year, And we hope he'll meet us all for many more. Then away with every cloud that our pleasure might enshroud, And away with every word and look unkind; Let old quarrels all be healed and old friendships closer sealed, And our lives with sweeter, purer ties entwined. Since we know the blessed power of this happy Christmas hour, We will keep its holy spell upon our heart, That each evil thing within that would tempt us into sin, May forever from our peaceful souls depart. —Lizzie M. Hadley, in Song Knapsack. </seg>
            <seg id="p126">108 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES a 1 1 £ 6 R 5 3 s {A new collection of words and melodittfor the various occasions in daily school life by John Hyatt Brewer and Frederic Reddall. Published by Maynard, Merrill i Company, t9, SI, and », £o*l Nineteenth Street, New Fork.) Eft II m Fl i 'Wj W i it f nji l|ft*Jf III fr^-S 2 ffiL ■"■■ s;- F+ff r * r « * ■•■.♦y Iffl ■-;;, -2 B^ j-_ |k ] f i . # II m 4! JCt tffl i » ■I liU|L 4j fi ?w -to i *.?L 1 3 if if *f W li-:F fir it WI-RMffl s v; i "'is -•« S diW wrf 1 d,'k A SPECIMEN PAGE FROM 8ONO8 OP THE YEAR. </seg>
            <seg id="p127">109 Christmas ONE thousand years of the world's existence rolled painfully and wearily along, and no Christ. Two thousand years and no Christ. Three thou- sand years and no Christ. Four thousand years and no Christ. But the slow century, and the slow year, and the slow month, and the slow nour at last arrived. The world had had matins or concerts in the morning, and vespers or concerts in the evening, but now it is to have a concert at mid - night. The black window shutters of a December night were thrown open, and some of the best singers of the world, where they all sing, stood there, and putting back the drapery of cloud, chanted a peace anthem, until the echoes of hill and valley applauded and encored the hallelujah chorus. At last the world has a Christ, and just the Christ it needs. Come, let us go into that Christmas scene as though we had never before worshiped at the manger. Here is a Madonna worth looking at. I wonder not that the most frequent name in all lands and in all Christian centuries is Mary. And there are Marys in palaces and Marys in cabins, and although German and French, and Italian, and Spanish, and English pronounce it differently, they are all namesakes of the one whom we find on a bed of straw with her pale face against the soft cheek of Christ in the night of the nativity. All the great painters have tried on canvas to present Mary and her child, and the incidents of that most famous night of the world's history. Raphael, in three different masterpieces, celebrated them. Tintoret and Gurrlandjo surpassed themselves in the adoration of the Magi. Correggio needed to do no more than his Madonna to become immortal. The Madonna of the Lily, by Leonardo da Vinci, will kindle the admiration of all ages. Murillo never won greater triumph by his pencil than in his presentation of the Holy Family. But all the galleries of Dresden are forgotten when I think of the small room of that gallery containing that Sistine Madonna. Yet all of them were copies of St. Matthew's Madonna and Luke's Madonna of the Old Book, which he had put into our hands when we were infants, and that we hope to have under our heads when we die. Behold in this Bible scene, how, on that Christmas night, God honored -childhood. Christ might have made his first visit to our world in a cloud, as he will descend on his next visit in a cloud. In what a chariot of illuminated vapor he might have rolled down the sky, escorted by mounted cavalry, with lightning or drawn sword. Elijah had a carriage of fire to take him up; why not Jesus a carriage of fire to fetch him down ? Or, over the arched bridge of a rainbow, the Lord might have descended. Our Christ might have had his mortality built up on earth out of the dust of a garden, as was Adam, in full manhood, at the start, without the introductory feebleness of infancy. No, No ! Childhood was to be honored by that event. He must have a child's light limbs, and a child's dimpled hand, and a child's beaming eye, and a child's flaxen hair, and babyhood was to be honored for all time to come, and a cradle was to mean more than a grave. Mighty God ! May the reflection of that one child's face be seen in all infantile faces. Enough have those fathers and mothers on hand if they have a child in the house. A throne, a ■crown, a scepter, a kingdom under charge. Be careful how you strike him across the head, jarring the brain. What you say to him will be centennial and millennial, and one hundred years, and one thousand years will not stop the echo and re-echo. Men, women, nations, all earth, and all Heaven, behold the child ! Is there any velvet so soft as a child's cheek ? Is there any sky so blue as a ■child's eye ? Is there any music so sweet as the child's voice ? Is there any plume so wavy as a child s hair ? Behold also that on that Christinas night, God honored motherhood. Two angels on their wings might have brought an infant Savior, to Bethlehem without Mary's being there at all. When the villagers, on the morning of December 25 awoke, by divine arrangement, and in some unexplained way, </seg>
            <seg id="p128">110 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES the child Jesus might have been found in some comfortable home of the vil - lage. But, No, No ! Motherhood for all time was to be consecrated, and one of the tenderest relations was to be the maternal relation, and one of the sweet - est words, "mother." In all ages, God has honored good motherhood: John Wesley had a good mother, Samuel Budgett had a good mother, St. Bernard had a good mother, Doddridge a good mother, Walter Scott a good mother, Benjamin West a good mother. In a great audience, most of whom were Christians, I asked that all those who had been blessed of Christian mothers arise, and almost the entire assembly stood up. Don't you see how import - ant it is that all motherhood be consecrated ? Why did Titian, the Italian artist, when he sketched the Madonna, make it an Italian face ? Why did Rubens, the German artist, in his Madonna, make it a German face ? Why did Joshua Reynolds, the English artist, in his Madonna, make it an Eng - lish face ? Why did Murillo, the Spanish artist, in his Madonna, make it a Spanish face ? I never heard, but I think they took their own mothers as the type of Mary, the mother of Christ. When you hear some one in sermon or oration speak in the abstract of a good, faithful, honest mother, your eyes fill with tears, while you say to yourself, that was my mother. The first word a child utters is apt to be "mother," and the old man in his dying dreams, calls "Mother! Mother!" It matters not whether she was brought up in the surroundings of the city, and in an affluent home, and was dressed appropriately with reference to the demands of modem life, or whether she wore the old-time cap and great, round spectacles, and apron of her own make and knit your socks with her own needles, seated by the broad fireplace, with a great black log ablaze on a winter night. It matters not how many wrinkles crossed and re-crossed her face, or how much her shoul - ders stooped with the burdens of a long life, if you painted a Madonna, hers would be the face. What a gentle hand she had when we were sick, and what a voice to soothe, and was there any one who could so fill up a room with peace, and purity, and light? And what a sad day that was when we came home and she could greet us not, for her lips were still forever. Come back, mother, this Christmas day, and take your old place, and, as ten, or twenty, or fifty years ago, come and open the Old Bible you used to read, and kneel in the same place where you used to pray, and look upon us as of old when you wished us a merry Christmas or a happy New Year. But no! That would not be fair to call you back. You had troubles enough, and aches enough, and bereavements enough while you were here. Tarry by the throne, mother, till we join you there, your prayers all answered, and in the eternal homestead of our God we shall again keep Christmas jubilee together. But speak from your thrones, all you glorified mothers, and say to all these, your sons and daughters, words of love, words of warning, words of cheer. They need your voice, for they have traveled far and with many a heart-break since you left them, and you do well to call from the heights of Heaven to the val - leys of the earth. Hail, enthroned ancestry! We are coming. Keep a place right beside you at the banquet. " Slow-footed years! More swiftly run Into the goal of that unsetting sun. Homesick we are for thee, Calm land beyond the sea." — Rev. T. DeWitt Talmage. </seg>
            <seg id="p129">111 Reference* for Special Days Abraham Lincoln Baldwin's Story of Abraham Lincoln for Young Readers.— Werner School Book Co., Chicago. John. Burns of Gettysburg, The Little Drummer, Jennie M' Neal, Little Giffen, in Ballads of American Bravery. — Silver, Burdett it Co., Chicago. The Soldier's Reprieve, in Our Country in Poem and Prose. — American Book Co., Chicago. The Words of Abraham Lincoln.— Western Publishing House, Chicago. Best Lincoln Stories. — James E. Gallaher it Co., Chicago. Lincoln's Speeches.— Rhodes &amp; McClure, Chicago. Morse's Life of Lincoln. — Houghton, Mifflin &lt;fc Co., Boston. George Washington _ Baldwin's Story of George Washington for Young Readers. — Werner School Book Co., Chicago. The Rising of '76, Independence Bell, At Valley Forge, Our Country in Poem and Prose.— The American Book Co., Chicago. Washington's Rules of Conduct and Farewell Address. — Ainsworth tt Co., Chicago. Irving's Life of Washington.— A. L. Burt, New York. Henry Cabot Lodge's Life of Washington. — Houghton, Mifflin &amp; Co., Boston. Exercises for Washington's Birthday, Dick's Festival Reciter. — Dick &amp; Fitzgerald, New York. How to Celebrate Washington's Birthday in the School Room. — E. L Kellogg &amp; Co., New York. Henry W. Longfellow A Longfellow Program. — American Journal of Education, St. Louis. A Longfellow Day.— Published in The Helper, by School Education Co., Minneapolis, Minn. Program for Longfellow Day.— Published in The Teachers' World, by Bemis Publishing Co., New York. How to Celebrate Longfellow's Birthday in the School Room.— E. L. Kellogg &lt;fc Co., New York. Arbor Day To a Pine, The Oak, The Birch Tree.— Lowell. Forest Hymn, Planting of the Apple Tree. — Bryant. ■ The Sycamores, The Trailing Arbutus, The Lumberman, The Palm Tree. — Whittier. The Builders, Hiawatha's Sailing, Description of Forests in Evangeline. — Longfellow. Under The Washington Elm, The Last Leaf .— Holmes. Arbor Day Songs and Exercises.— Dick &amp; Fitzgerald, New York. How to Celebrate Arbor Day in the School Room. — E. L. Kellogg 4 Co., New York. Arbor Day, Edited and Compiled by Hon. Robert W. Furnas, dedicated to Hon. J. Sterling Morton, Author of Arbor Day. — State Journal Co., Lin - coln, Nebraska. Arbor Day: Its History and Observance. — N. H. Eggleston, Government Printing Office, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p130">112 SPECIAL DAY EXERCISES Bird Day The Birds of Killingsworth, The Herons of Elmwood, The Legend of the Crossbill. — Longfellow. Our Friends in Feathers and Fur,' Nature's Reader. — American Book Co., Chicago. Our Feathered Friends, Margaret Miller's Saturday Bird Class. — D. C. Heath &amp; Co., Chicago. Birds Before Uncle Sam.— The Macmillan Co., New York. Memorial Day Patriotic Quotations.— The Whitaker &amp; Ray Publishing Co., San Fran - cisco. Our Country in Poem and Prose. — American Book Co., Chicago. Patriotism in Prose and Verse. — Educational Publishing Co., Topeka, Kansas. Ballads of American Bravery. — Silver, Burdett A Co., Chicago. A Memorial Day Exercise.— Dick &amp; Fitzgerald, New York. The Broom Drill, The Fan Drill, The School of the Soldier.— E. L. Kel- logg &amp; Co., New York. Library Day Little Boy Blue,Wynken, BKnken &amp; Nod, Pittypat and Tippytoe. — Eugene Field. Child-Rhymes by James Whitcomb Riley. — The Bowen-Merrill Com - pany, Indianapolis. Dick's Comic and Dialect Recitations. — Dick &amp; Fitzgerald, New York. Authors' Days.— E. L. Kellogg* Co., New York. Thanksgiving Thanksgiving Exercises. — Dick &amp; Fitzgerald, New York. How to Celebrate Thanksgiving in the School Room. — E. L. Kellogg &amp; Co., New York. Christinas Long Afore I Knowed Who Santy Claus Wuz.— Riley. Jest ' Fore Christmas, The Peace of Christmas Time, Christmas Treas - ures.— Field. A Christmas Entertainment. — Dick &amp; Fitzgerald, New York. A Visit from St. Nicholas.— Fourth Reader of Stepping Stones to Lit - erature. The Christmas Angel, A Christmas Star, The Christmas Dolls, in Prose and Verse. — American Book Co., Chicago. How to Celebrate Christmas in the School-Room. — E. L. Kellogg &amp; Co., New York. For All Days Special Day Programs.— Published by the Department of Public Instruc - tion, Lincoln, Nebraska, in former years. </seg>
            <seg id="p131">* page Introduction. Lincoln Day . Michigan 3-U P-nn&lt;vlvania arolina ■ Lincoln's Boyhood and Youth ... 3 Death of Lincoln I The Hard Work Plan — 1 Lincoln Exercise New York s The Name of Lincoln g A King ... 6 Bird Day Bird T Readings Our Little Martvr My Robin . The First Americar Lincoln As a Military H«r&lt; Lincoln's Method of Study Lout— Three Little Robin Birds' \ - Lincoln and tht- Dying Soldier Bo it Lincoln's Famous Speech » ■OB from the Sparrow - ' in a Focket Comment on Everett's Letter on Same Bird (jam Lincoln's First Speech in Court Lincoln's First Speech in Supreme Court i" Supreme ! 10 Kill Birds Fran. First Talk with Friends After Receiving Ten Things we may do • Telegram of HIr First Nomination. . 1" First Talk with Friends After Receiving Telegram of His First Nomination I Washington and Lincoln Compared in A K Washington and Lincoln Compared !•&gt; Washington Day 12-21 Tne'^lii^Bird"^ The B. Washingrton Day 12-21 Washington U Wh&lt;i Kat in Sunim Washington 12 Birthday of Washington U £,?£ n x h " lr ReUtion to™lT Washington's Birthday ... It Memorial Day Wha- inir Birds Kat in Birthday of Washington M Birds in Th-ir Relattoi The Nesting of Our Br Acrostic For Washington's Birthday New Physical Culture Exercise 'for Memorial Day Washington's Birthday ... 14 Mem George Washington. George Washington I", ForTwoH'u- *J. hu ' For Two Boys ... H Dialog- &gt; ,. "J! " ra ' Dialogu 18 An Estimate of Washington 19 )u .. a * , , . &lt; )ur Flag An Estimate of Washington 19 Washington * Memorial Oil' A Memorial Gift . . Four Soldier Boys Washington . .19 Character and Career of Washington . . Four **■'•',*??■.• Character and Career of Washington . . 20 What Washington Stands For What Washington Stands For 20 " ': I •■ In: ■• I'm ilar". A Tnl Longfellow Day ■ongfellow Day 22-31 \ Tr A Grammar School Exercise 22 Th.- - .... The Building of the Ship !"&gt; Kem Rem-mh.-r . ■ I Children 28 Children The Children's Hour 28 The Children's Hour 28 ■ ing PI 1 The Arrow and the Song . 27 ing Fir»t ' The Arrow and th- Song The Old Clock on th.' stairs 28 Th. i The Old Clock ■ The Essence of Patriot! I ol. Ingersoll's Remark From My Arm-Chair .. ... 29 Remarkable V From My Arm-^hair . . A Longfellow Km - .30 ij brary Du A Longfellow Exer - ... 30 Library Day Arbor Day xbor Day rj-VI Public Schools and Education I Education M Proclamation by the Governor :e The ( oun.il of the B. r From J. Sterling Morton A Lil Proclamation by the Governor of the Book: iling Morton. ■ M Wliy Do We Observe Arbor Day? The ' Why Do We Observe Arbor Day? N Springtime H The l Springtiir M The Gourd and the Palm ... 35 Tne Gourd and the Palm A Useful ciit! ■ Tratnin A Useful Gift . . . . . -1 When the Green (jits Back in the Trees 36 Otiotatu.:.- When the Green (Jits Hack in the T Motlon Song— The Trees' Story 37 Motion Song— The Tree. Song of Dedication. Practical Sugge.' Song of Dedication 37 Pf. of Ti he Trw 2 Thanksgiving The Heart of the Tree ■ Tbankssrivingr Italian Tree Day 38 \ Thanksgiving Hvmn A Little Planter 39 PratM &lt; ;&lt;xl A Little Planter 30 ■ Planting Trees » LJttle Paul's Tha Planting Trees 39 '• Part Recitation with Motions 10 Part Recitation with Motions. Ill •« Arbor Day Exerci~ 41 wh-' Arbor Day Exercise ... 11 ,n Arbor Day Song 41 \ Thanksgiving Dial' Arbor Day Song II AThanksgiv ■ _• ■ Suggestive Poems 11 Sugg 'stive Poems 41 p^,. Patriot Historic Trees 42 Landing of the^sT: II Landing oi ' Drill 11 What We Owe Tree,. It Christmas Christmas What We Owe Tree- ■ Carl Morton's Orchard. T ° p . '^"' h , Carl Morton's Orchard . 45 •&gt;• An Arbor Dav SvmDOeium 48-54 Thought... An Arbor Day Symposium 4«-54 » kings M Arkansas 46 Colorado 47 », ' ■ Illinois 47 Indiana 48 A Chri-tma-' ■ I" Christmas Fairies l"l Indian Territory ■ A Christmas Exercise M Iowa 48 Carol 1O Kansas » Christmas io&gt; Maine 49 Maryland References for Special Days 1 11-11 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">PA( i 1 lair 1 4 w. XT 1 I'M ILLUSTRATIONS 41 PAGE Bird and Its Par' The Children and thp F 12 Battle of Manila Bay . 1? "KissMf" Abraham Lincoln Lincoln's Early Home George Washington . Mount Vernon Henry W. Longfellow Spring The Longfellow House, C'ambridgi Children's Chair A Fascinating Talf 29 PayTollHere The End of the Day . . 41 John Alden and Priscil 56 Christmas is Coming . Santa Claus is Coming Hon. J. Sterling Morten A Woodland Scene My Saturdav Bird Class Franklin's Birds' Nest. . </seg>
            <seg id="p133"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>