<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00093.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0093.0001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Public Documents of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">1940-1942</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1940-11142 ¦i. ¦¦¦¦¦-. ¦¦• . VOLUME! </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">; ; ':V ¦' ; ¦¦'¦..;,'.:'¦.''.¦:;''¦ VOLUME l^l.- : -1. Governor's Message ; , ' ;. J^ ¦|': R. L. Cochran, Retiring, 1941. j;; &gt; ¦¦¦, '¦_ .';. Dwight P. Griswold, Inaugural, 1941. 2. Secretary of State, Biennial Report,l94o-1942. 3. Auditor of Public Accounts, Biennial Report, 1940-1942. a. Appropriation, etc., 55th Legislative Session. 1941. ; |i 4[.Treasurer, Biennial Report, 1940-1942. ;:; .'5. Department of Public Instruction, Biennial Report, 1941-1942. j 6. Board of Educational Lands and Funds, Biennial Report, 1940-1942. : \ 7. Tax Commissioner, Annual Reports, 1942,1942. .:..' j". . ¦¦.¦'-'.' ¦ '¦'¦' . . :'••;••¦'." . :*:¦:' ¦¦'¦'¦ • ¦".' .'."¦¦ .¦¦'.¦•• .¦.'¦' ii ¦ V. ¦'..¦¦.'.¦ ¦'¦'¦¦ *; 8. Department of Insurance. Annual Reports, 1941,1942. </seg>
         <seg id="p004"/>
         <seg id="p005">&amp; L fiOfiplfl Delivered to the? Fifty-Fifth Session of the Legislature of Nebraska # January 9*h, I9&lt;H </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Governor R. L. Cochran's Farewell Message To the Members of the Fifty-Fifth Session of the Legislature of Nebraska January 9th, 1941 Mr. President and Members of the Legislature of Nebraska: The Constitution of the State of Nebraska contemplates the submission of budget recommendations by the retiring Governor. This was submitted on January Bth, 1940. Under our Constitution the chief executive is also required to pre - sent to the Legislature a review of activities during the past two years, conditions at the present time and recommenda - tions for the future. In view of the fact that the past two years have seen but a continuation of the conditions of the previous four years, my observations and recommendations are conditioned by this entire six year period. There is every indication that my worthy successor will be confronted by much the same conditionjLthat confronted me and he will face much the same problems that I faced. He will be met by the same pressure groups and perhaps new ones, however improbable that may seem. I am sure, too, that veteran members of the Legislature are most familiar with the process of pressure and the new members will not long escape the close and cordial attention of those whose in - terests in their own eyes transcend all other considerations. Each group will favor economical-government until it comes to the particular cause this group represents. May I predict, Mr. Governor, and members of the Legislature, that repre - sentatives of the educational field who ask you for greater appropriations will applaud any economies you may accom - plish in reducing expenditures for other purposes. May I pre - dict, too, that those seeking more for old age assistance will think nobly of your efforts in reducing public expenditures for highways and other agencies. It follows, too, that those who would speed up the highway building program will give you just credit for effecting economies in the assistance program and in other state activities. The odd thing about all of this is that, for instance, those who most ardently advocate a reduction in highway expenditures will perhaps be the first asking for a highway project. 2 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">I ¦¦'¦.'"• • ' ¦'¦" •:¦.":¦¦¦'".¦¦- -¦•¦;': ' ; . " I am describing a condition and not a theory. I merely cite this to you to counsel you that as you consider the ques - tion of appropriations, which is the most important function of the Legislature, you will find, and must keep in mind, that everyone is for lower appropriations, lower taxes, except for his own pet activity. We cannot change human nature but we can be guided by it. | I have submitted a budget to this honorable legislative body in which I have attempted to appraise as a whole the needs of the people and the ability of our people to pay for those needs. j We must think in terms of majority instead of minority interest. We must think in terms not only of the state's needs but also in terms of our ability to supply those needs. We must think, too, of the decline in physicial valuation of prop - erty for assessment purposes from three and one-third billion dollars in 1921 to one billion, nine hundred millionMollars in 1940. We must think in terms of the reduction in farm in - come of more than 50% during the past ten years. We must think in terms of our dependence, to a considerable extent, during the past seven years on the federal government. A realistic view forces us to conclude that had we hot had the benefits of this federal policy, our decline in population would have reached into the hundreds of thousands instead of a mere sixty-four thousand. "¦!'¦"" ' -;. "¦.•"¦' v.-¦'.•' :¦.¦ ' " "'.'' : t: ','.-¦.-¦ ¦'.-..¦ '.:'':¦'..'•¦.'¦' -..-.-¦. '¦.. ¦ ! As your Governor for the past six years, I bring thess things to your minds as a proper review of the past, as a possible guide to the future. In making appropriations for state needs, whether it be for the state university, normal schools, charitable and penal institutions, state assistance, highways or any other purpose, the sound judgment of our people would have, us determine appropriations on this basis of what we can afford. They would not have us fix our appropriations on the basis of the standards of other states, with vastly larger resources. Rather would our people have us make appropriations on the basis of Nebraska's resources. " PLANNING BOARD This board was established by an act of the Legislature four years ago, one of its purposes being to study and report on the building needs for the next ten years. At that time we had in mind the construction and maintenance of addi- 3 </seg>
         <seg id="p008">tional buildings for education purposes and for charitable and penal institutions. I think this board has done a splendid job along the lines of reporting on these needs and of improv - ing the maintenance of existing buildings. Since 1937; when this law was passed, we have had four additional years of drouth. Frankly, gentlemen, it is now a question in my mind not of whether we can build and maintain additional build - ings but whether we can maintain existing buildings. If more buildings are constructed, it will be necessary to increase the property tax burden. The only alternative, in my judgment, would be to depart from our time-tested and may I say time - honored system of avoiding new forms of taxes and at the same time achieving reductions in the property tax burden. Has anything happened to warrant our departure from this policy? I do not think so. The farmers who cannot build new barns or even paint their old ones would have to pay for any new buildings and their future maintenance. The report of the board on a building program will be valuable in assisting future legislatures to determine priority of construction in the event that our income and our physical valuation of property return to a level where the people can afford not only new construction but even more important to maintain additional buildings. Certain it is that the big prob - lem of today is to maintain existing buildings. Let us not for - get that durng our more prosperous years we had fewer state buildings to maintain than now. This board has rendered an outstanding service in their survey of Nebraska resources and also in their survey of the educational needs of Nebraska. This latter survey, covering higher education as well as secondary education was found necessary by the board so that they could intelligently report on a ten-year building program for institutions of higher learning. In arriving at their conclusions with reference to building needs, the board thought exclusively of needs. I am thinking, too, of ability to pay for those needs. I believe that the board has done its work well. I believe, too, that it should be discontinued as a state activity and recommend the repeal of the law creating the board. "' IMPROVEMENTS AT STATE CHARITABLE AND PENAL INSTITUTIONS Because of the. improvements made during the past six years not only has congestion been decreased in the state 4 </seg>
         <seg id="p009">I mental hospitals, but also the list of those held in counties j awaiting admittance has been practically eliminated. ' &gt; ®? ?***? a »° when I became Governor, the total number of patients in state mental hospitals was 4,957. The total number today is 5,638. At the end of this biennium, within the next six months an additional capacity of 667 will be available. This means that during the',six years of which I speak the capacity of our state mental hospitals has been in - creased by the grand total of 1,348 beds. In addition this construction program has also made it possible to give proper facilities for 356 patients who previously had been sleeping on floors, in basement rooms and in other places not suitable for occupancy. This has been not alone a humanitarian program. It has I been a program of sound economics. It has been a program under which the taxpayers as a whole save by spending • money. The savings result by providing facilities at state in- I stitutions at greatly reduced per patient cost under the cost of holding patients in the counties in private institutions, or county ]ails. Briefly, it is a building program which not alone improves living conditions and treatment of the patients but will reduce the total burden of the taxpayer as well, consider - lng state and county taxes as a whole. I do not wish to imply that all construction work neces - sary for the institutions under the State Board of Control ' has been accomplished. I merely wish to say that in my bud - &gt;get because of present, economic conditions in the state I have |lunited my recommendations to actual emergencies such as i provisions for sewage disposal at the Beatrice Feeble-Minded Institution and for a new boiler at the Norfolk institution. ! In addition, attention is called to improved methods of treatment at state mental hospitals. Attention is also called to , greatly improved purchasing methods with tests made of commodities purchased. The population at the penal institutions has declined very considerably during recent years. The number of inmates at the men's reformatory is 194 at present, being less than one half of the peak number of 426. The population of the penitentiary is 150 less than the peak number of 981. With the facilities now available at the Genoa state farm, it is suggested that study and consideration be given to elim- 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p010">¦sll ' If 1 1 • ination of the reformatory for men. It is estimated that \\ j $50,000.00 per biennium could be saved by such an elimination. h Consolidation of the schools for the Wind and the deaf is a. also a matter for consideration, perhaps to be accomplished \\ sometime in the future. il, SOCIAL SECURITY I We are expending now $8,000,000.00 per year for old ill age assistance, aid to dependent and crippled children and to "Hi the blind. The state revenue supporting these activities comes l| from beer and liquor taxes, the $2.00 head tax for those be- ii tween 21 and 50 years of age, from estate taxes and from ¦¦••"'.!» one cent gasoline tax. The law applying one cent of gasoline tax to state assistance expires under its own provisions on July Ist, 1941.1 recommend the re-enactment of this law. jf The principle of applying the provisions of the Social / Security law having to do with retirement pay has been a I' matter of public discussion as to its application to public em - ployees. I think the principle is sound and that eventually the j[ state should make provision for retirement pay of state em - ployees. The facts are that one state agency, the Board of h Regents of the University, has already announced such a pro- 'I i gram for their teaching staff. To me it is inequitable and un- ii just for the state to pick one class for retirement pay to the "J neglect of all others and particularly when the group so pre- I ferred represents the highest income brackets. I do not believe that any administrative agency should establish such a | policy without authorization from the Legislature. I do believe I. that if and when such a policy is established by legislative ;l action, first consideration should be given to the low-salaried : employees, rather than to those whose employment at higher !l salaries over a long period of years should make it possible j for them to provide for security in old age. j STATE TREASURY i The prevailing overdraft in the general fund of the 1 state treasury started approximately three years ago and was I caused by three things: I 1. In 1937, the legislature allocated revenue from beer I and liquor taxes to the state assistance fund. Previ- 1 ously such revenue had been allocated to the general m fund of the state treasury. The amount so transferred M by the Legislature in 1937 from the general fund to ¦ 6 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">—¦»*- '.-^^f.J — . fc-*»* * - .»» -^^^^ M »»^».......»»1»-»»»»»»»»-»»»»»»»»»»»»»'''''J'M'''J*f'********J*i**************l**************************** _^| : ¦——. ¦111, M ..,nw„ ii.TTI . . m. \[ the state assistance fund was approximately Mi': $1,300,000.00. The Legislature made no provision to WW replenish the general fund and consequently this It.-' large deficiency resulting from this transfer to the M state assistance fund had to be absorbed out of proper - pi ty tax collections accruing to the general fund. M 2. The Legislature of 1937 in the appropriation bill appro- II priated unexpended balances instead of allowing such M ) unexpended balances to revert to the general fund, as 8j". j had been the practice throughout the history of the g- ¦;¦;. j,. '¦ :' state. 13. Due to greatly reduced crop production as a result of drouth during these years, tax delinquencies have increased materially. Despite these handicaps in maintaining a general fund balance, collections have been made of taxes which have ac - j:rued to the general fund to the extent that for the fiscal year July Ist, 1939 to July Ist, 1940, the revenue which ac - crued to the state general fund totalled $6,232,830.86, where - ias the expenditures from this fund for the same period to - talled $5,697,152.67, the receipts for the year exceeding the expenditures by $535,678.19. In the month of December, 1938, the net general fund overdraft reached $1,042,737.26, its largest amount. By July Ist, 1940, the overdraft had been wiped out, with a small balance remaining. Owing to the usual slackening off of tax collections during the last six months of the year, the net general fund overdraft amounted to $192,971.17 on December 31,1940. However, it is. expected that with receipts in January, 1941, the overdraft will entirely disappear. ! Fortunately a provision of the statute enacted in 1915 authorizes the state treasurer to carry as cash items out of any balances in the treasury, state warrants drawn against the fund in which there are inadequate receipts to meet the same. Because of this provision and the fact that there were ample proceeds in other funds in the office of the state trea - surer, it has not been necessary to register warrants or pay . interest on any sums whatsoever because of the general fund :/\ overdraft. 7 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS As chairman of this board, I am happy to report that the affairs of this board are in the best condition that they have been for many years. This was made possible by elimination of the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings and as a result of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds ac - tualy assuming complete control of the matters entrusted to it. On September 19, 1939, the board reorganized its staff and selected a chief clerk to be in charge of the entire office, under the direction of the board. At the same time the num - ber of the staff was reduced. By this arrangement, there was at all times one person in charge of the office responsible to the board. The efficiencies resulting from this become most obvious by the following: First, in 1940, every acre of school land subject to lease was placed under lease for the first time in the history of the state. Second, a number of small isolated tracts consisting of a few acres here and there, on which the state had received no rental for years, have been favorably disposed of. Third, collections from July, 1939, to July, 1940; were in - creased in excess of $125,000.00, over the previous year. The collections during the last half of 1940 amount to more than the collections for a full year back in the boom years of 1917 and 1918, even though there is considerably less land now due to the fact much has been deeded since that time. Fourth, in the past two years the expense of operating the office has been grealy reduced. The past several years have been difficult years in which to invest money. Due to the loose system which pre - vailed prior to the time when the board had complete control as a board, large delinquencies in lease rental and sales con - tract collections grew to approximately $1,500,000.00., It is our opinion that at least one-third of this amount can be;collected with proper legal procedure. It is further the opinion of the board that a full time field man should be retained by the board to supervise leasing of school lands, collection of rentals and permanent fund investments. ' 8 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">; l .-'.'¦ *"' ¦ '¦"-". . ' ¦'¦'*' '¦'-''. ¦:/ ¦¦:¦¦'" '.'".'¦¦ ; ¦": -'¦ ¦'!"¦ '--: TAXATION*'..:. ¦ I In 1939, I called the attention of the Legislature to the fact that the intangible tax law passed in 1921 was in the light of experience almost a failure. I emphasized in my mes - sage to the Legislature the need for putting teeth into this law jwhich would provide for its effective operation by placing tens of millions of dollars of intangible property that is now escap - ing taxation on the taxrolls. I give one example to show the extent to which intangible property escapes taxation. During the past year, an estate filed for probate in a Ne - braska county was valued at between $900,000 and $1,000,000. A large part of this estate was invested in securi - ties. 'The amount returned for taxation in 1940 was $100.00' in cash and $11,000.00 in stocks. The estate was filed for pro - bate prior to December Ist of the year in which the assess - ment was made and as a result, the county assessor of that particular county checked the assests with the tax return and added approximately $16,000.00 in cash to the original return and more than $600,000.00 in stocks and bonds, the tax accruing to the county as a result of his action totaling nearly $5,000.00. Here is a typical case where almost $600,000 owned by one individual had been escaping taxation for years. i Two years ago I recommended, too, that a study be made i'to determine and enact a method to place personal property ion the tax rolls on a basis of equality with real property to the end that property.'of all kinds be taxed on a more equitable basis. j The Legislature of 1939 failed to act on either one of these ! recommendations. The Legislative Council during the past Inearly two years likewise failed to deal positively with either 'one of these problems of such great importance to the tax - ¦ payers./ ¦ I again recommend to this body definite action along the same line as I recommended two years ago. This becomes even ' more of a problem now in the light of the reduction in the assessed valuation of real estate in Nebraska which took place i in 1940 and the resultant greater difficulty in raising revenue 'for state and local purposes. '"':;:¦' -l-.:':. HIGBWAYS ! Our pay-as-we-go plan for highways permits us either to expand our program at any legislative session or to contract it We have 3,887 miles of paved road, 3,718 miles of gravel 9 </seg>
         <seg id="p014">road and 413 miles of unsurfaced roads in the state and federal highway system. Your attention is invited to the fact that of the total miles of paved roads amounting to 3,887 miles, 2,215 miles have been paved during the last six years. In other words, during the period I have served as your Governor, ap - proximately 60% of our present paved roads have been con - structed. All highways in Nebraska having a daily traffic of 500 or more vehicles have been paved except approximately 76 miles. It should be of interest to you to know that during this biennium approximately two million dollars of federal aid for highways went unused because of inability to match these funds. I recommend that we should discontinue one of two prac - tices, either that of reducing state revenue for highways or that of taking over more county highways for state construc - tion and maintenance. The State Highway Department has made a survey show - ing highway use and distribution of revenue collected from highway users. I recommend that you give this study careful consideration so that highway users shall pay for the use of the highways, builded and maintained by the state, in propor - tion to the use thereof. IRRIGATION I recommend to this legislative body that legislation be enacted to give every possible assistance to the development of irrigation and the conservation of our water resources. I will mention one act specifically which has to do with pump irrigation. At the present moment it seems necessary that a state law be passed granting a similar measure of state control over pump irrigation as is now granted by law over stream irriga - tion. This appears to be necessary as a condition precedent to receiving any federal financing on long term basis at low rates of interest for the development of pump irrigation. Any needed legislation to advance what has been accom - plished over a period of years with reference to the develop - ment of the Republican River Valley should have the earnest and considerate attention of this body. This includes the ratifi- 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">the commissioners of the three states, Colorado, Kansas and cation of a compact which it is expected will be submitted by 'Nebraska, during your session. J Irrigation from streams in Nebraska has had an import - ant part in the development of several sections of our state. jThe principal section is that area adjacent to the North Platte and Platte Rivers lying between the Wyoming-Nebraska line and Kearney. For the most part this area was developed under the protection of our state Constitution and state laws which set up the principle that first in use of water was first in right. In other words, the person or group who constructed an irri - gation project in accordance with the laws of the state and made a continuous use of water each year estabUshed a prior right over those who came after with similar developments. The statutes of Nebraska clearly define the methods of admin - istration by the state to guarantee that these rights not be violated. ¦'.'.'¦ ..'¦'¦,•''¦ •: Each session of the Legislature makes appropriations to the Department of Roads and Irrigation for the purpose of admimstering the irrigation laws of this state in accordance with priority of rights. For many years we have seen these irights in effect violated by court action. We have seen in' effect water being taken away from a senior appropriator and given to a junior appropriator through injunction process—-all in violation of Our state Constitution and of our irrigation stat - utes. I would call your attention to the fact that this invasion by the judiciary of administrative functions always comes during the irrigation season at a time when the need for or - derly administration is most pressing and important. The rec - ord of the past shows that these temporary injunctions have been granted in every case where asked for. The record of the past shows, too, that the cases are never brought to trial. As soon as the emergency is over, during which the water has been diverted from the rightful user to one not entitled to the water, the case is dismissed and court action is suspended. Next year a similar emergency arises and a similar practice is followed and the judiciary again lends itself to this tacit agreement for the defeat of the laws of this state. Almost $200,000 has been appropriated to protect the j water appropriators of Nebraska as against the claims of Wy - oming and Colorado. My budget recommendation is for the expenditure of $30,000 during the next biennium to continue this defense of our citizens' rights. Yet, we find while fight- 11 </seg>
         <seg id="p016">mg against the invasion of priority rights on the part of other states, we permit the invasion of those rights within our own state by judicial nullification of law by injunction. This situation is intolerable and demands action at this. session of the Legislature to correct it. I recommend that it be corrected by one of the two following methods: First, the passage of legislation providing that no judge can issue an injunction except by requiring the posting of a bond in an amount sufficient to protect senior appropriators against damages that may be determined upon trial, and the amount of such bond to be computed upon the basis of a rea - sonable valuation of each acre foot of water diverted as a re - sult of the injunction. It is further recommended that legisla - tion be passed requiring a hearing on such injunction be held within twenty-four hours after application is made for such injunction. Or, second — provision by legislation that only District Judges can hear such injunction cases, and that the bound - aries of the judicial districts be so changed that all the irri - gated territory affected by the watershed I have discussed will fall within the boundaries of but one judicial district. I believe that my first recommendation is the better but certain it is that one of these two should be provided by legis - lation during this session. INSURANCE DEPARTMENT The past six years saw the culmination of the promotion stage of the insurance business in Nebraska. Like other busi - ness, there had to be a reaction to unsound promotion and a cleaning up of those companies which failed to achieve a stable financial basis. During these six years, companies have been reinsured, have been dissolved by court order and mergers have been effected with minimum loss to policyholders as far as Nebraska companies are concerned. And, during this six year period no general remedial legislation of the insurance code was effected but at this time the experience gained has crystalized around a few changes that were to have been con - sidered by the last Legislature, but failed to have their atten - tion. The general insurance situation as it affects Nebraska policyholders is one for which satisfaction may be expressed. Since 1913, changes in the insurance business have been such 12 </seg>
         <seg id="p017">¦-¦•---- -¦¦-¦«. I, ¦ — 1 n —rtn —¦rrn******T*******r***************************************************************r*********BWl**************"*'***~*^^ !¦'¦.:¦ ¦"-;¦." ;¦¦;-¦. ;; : . ¦-¦"'{¦. ;. ¦ ;,¦ . . , that some basic remedial legislation is necessary, particularly jin -the .field of casualty underwriting which was of very small volume in 1913 when the insurance code was enacted, but which has since grown to a considerable volume. (while the public looks upon the department as having wide discretionary power and sometimes questions are raised why greater control has not been exercised by the state, the fact remains that the department's authority is limited by statute and court decisions. It is entirely possible that the general administration of insurance in Nebraska might be en - hanced and carried on more efficiently with the passage of legislation under which the department would be given more authority and be less subject to restrictions now imposed upon the part of the courts. DEPARTMENT OF BANKING - In the six years just ended, only eight going state banks have been placed in receivership, and in three of the last four of these, the Department of Banking has been able to pay all claims of depositors in full. The 1933 revision of the bank - ing laws, providing for liquidation of failed banks by the de - partment as statutory receiver, has resulted in substantial savings to the depositors in |the banks that have failed since that time. Including the banks that closed in 1933 and 1934, the department has liquidated about one hundred banks under the 1933 law, and that law has satisfactorily met every test to which it has been subjected with reference to banks closed ¦ since it came into effect. However, the record of all bank receiverships in this state during the past six years is not as desirable as it should be. In 1935 the retiring superintendent of the Banking Depart - ment remained the judicial receiver of about 250 state banks which had closed prior to the 1933 change in the law-—some of them many, many years prior to 1933. Believing all deposi - tors in failed banks were entitled to equal protection under the law, we tried every means at our disposal, including court ac - tion, to require the closing up of those old judicial receiver - ships, or their transfer to the Department of Banking, but the Supreme Court, in the Hoskins State Bank case, held that the Legislature had not authorized the department to act as judi - cial receiver, and the judicial receiver above mentioned, I am advised, still maintains an office in Lincoln with a full-time attorney and at least two other full-time employees. For six i years now the depositors of those banks in judicial receiver- 13 </seg>
         <seg id="p018"/>
         <seg id="p019"/>
         <seg id="p020">ship have been burdened with the expense of salaries of this receiver and his employees, bond premiums, rent, and other items that could have been saved entirely, or considerably re - duced, had those old receiverships been turned over to the Banking Department. The depositors are unable to understand this situation and to realize that under the present laws the Governor and the Banking Department have no control over these old judicial receiverships, and they continually com - plain to us about the delay and expense and small returns to them. I recommend that the Legislature, at an early date, give consideration to the adoption of appropriate measures to end this confusion and waste. MERIT SYSTEM CHANGES \ During the past few years, merit system laws have been passed in connection with state-federal agencies—unemploy- ment insurance, employment service and state assistance. In most respects these laws have been satisfactory. However, we have had experience that shows need for amendments to our law permitting the discharge of undesirable employees. My theory is that appointment on so-called merit without a con - tinuous exhibition of such merit does not make for efficiency. I can see, too, the danger that in the future the tail may wag the dog. These changes should be made only after consulta - tion with and in collaboration with the federal agencies with which these agencies work. LEGISLATIVE COUNCIL I recommend the repeal of the law providing for the Le - gislative Council. The records disclose that it has not under - taken a study of or stated a position on subjects worthy of its attention such as amendments to the intangible tax law, or amendments needed to improve the method of making assess - ments of personal property, or of the educational survey sub - mitted by the State Planning Board. The record likewise discloses that where recommenda - tions were made by the Legislative Council for legislation to the 1939 session, the Legislature paid little or no attention to such recommendations. I cannot see in its action thus far anything to justify its continuance. 14 </seg>
         <seg id="p021">if I MAINTENANCE OF, CONSTITUTIONAL GOVERNMENT If I. ¦ Section 6of Article IV of the Constitution of Nebraska || provides that: "The supreme executive power shall be vested m in the Governor, who shall take care that the laws be faith - m fully executed and the[affairs of the state efficiently and eec- M nomically administered." B '.-' This provision is entirely consistent with the sound and I fundamental concept of division of power between the execu- I tive, legislative and judicial branches which characterizes our I democratic form of government. It is vital that tim separation i of powers and functions be maintained. At least, it is neces- I sary that, if any chanf es be made, they be made by the people with full knowledge as the provisions for amending our Con - stitution require, and not indirectly through legislative . iction. ¦ \-.\. . :. : )''.; I call your attention to the fact that there is a tendency to invade the power and functions of the chief executive by legislative enactments setting up administrative agencies over which the chief executive has hmited authority to discharge i the responsibility given him by the Constitution. There has been manifested, also, /a- tendency on the part of the Legisla - ture to create legislative agencies with functions purely ad - ministrative in character. This is clearly in Iconflict with the Constitution and can - ¦¦'¦'•¦¦ not but have harmful jconsequences. Our form of government requires that responsibility for the conduct of public affairs be clearly fixed and |properly balanced between the three branches of government in order that public officials be held properly accountable. Responsibility contemplates the neces - sary authority for the discharge of responsibility. CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENTS I recommend the submission by this body of a constitu - tional amendment providing for appointment by the Governor of the attorney general. Certain it is that the Governor being charged with the responsibility that he is under our Constitu - tion and our statutes is entitled to a legal advisor of his own choosing. ( ¦¦'•¦.¦.-.,- ¦. -.¦¦•¦'" v.'-'r.; ; I also recommend the submission of a constitutional amendment providing for appointment by the Governor of members of the State Railway Commission. The work of this department is largely of a technical nature and can be best 15 </seg>
         <seg id="p022">t administered by those with the proper background of training 1 I and experience. Selection by appointment would provide | greater assurance of obtaining properly qualified members. f ji In both of these cases I think that provision should be I y made for confirmation of the Governor's appointments by the • 1 ;j Legislature. -\% 'j CONCLUSION ;: j| i In this message it has been my purpose to give you }! whatever benefit there can be derived from my observations ¦•-.' |1 | and conclusions based upon my three terms as your Governor. )'• Because of this experience, during a period of stress un - equalled in our state's history, no one recognizes more than I I the seriousness of the problems which confront you, as they 1 ;¦ have confronted us during the past six years. I lam happy to see among you many with whom it has .'¦¦.'•• been my privilege to work in previous sessions. In leaving the office of Governor, may I express to you my appreciation for I j your cooperation that has prevailed and the courtesies you 1! have extended me. I '.:¦;;¦¦¦¦' ,j Let me say, too, that I leave the office of Governor with j the happy feeling that my successor is worthy of the trust, | | confidence and responsibility reposed in him. I have known j i him in an official way when he was a member of the State j Senate and I occupied an administrative position. Our associ - ations at that time, my close association with him in many ;; other ways, and my knowledge of his talents all impress me with the thought that he will give a full measure of devotion - to the duties of the office of Governor. I bespeak for him your cooperation and support in the interest of all Nebraska. Respectfully submitted, 1 R. L. COCHRAN, Governor. , REPORT OF MONEY Received by the Governor During the Biennium Ended January 9th, 1941 I SOURCE I Fees for Warehouse Licenses $ 52.00 I j Fees for Extradition Warrants 40.00 « ! Federal Aid for Soldiers' Home 26,879.53 1 Total $26,971.53 M 16 </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>