<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS TO THE GOVERNOR AND LEGISLATURE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS TO THE GOVERNOR AND LEGISLATURE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA For the Biennium Ending November 30. 1914 Silas A. Holcomb, Chairman, Sixth Congressional District Second Congressional District Howard Kennedy, First Congressional District Henry Gerdes, Leo Matthews, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF NAME OF INSTITUTIONS AND BOARDS CONTROLLED NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH BEATRICE, NEBRASKA GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL GENEVA, NEBRASKA NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME BURKETT, NEBRASKA ASYLUM FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL KEARNEY, NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS KEARNEY, NEBRASKA NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL LINCOLN, NEBRASKA STATE PENITENTIARY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME MILFORD, NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME MILFORD, NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA NORFOLK, NEBRASKA NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF OMAHA, NEBRASKA NEBRASKA REFORMATORY UN LOCATED HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS LINCOLN, NEBRASKA ADVISORY BOARD LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 3 REPORT OF BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS TO THE GOVERNOR AND LEGISLATURE: The constitutional amendment and the law enacted by the legislature in pursuance thereof creating a Board of Commissioners of State Institutions provides for the as - sumption of the duties imposed upon the Board on July 1st, 1913. By your appointment, as Governor, and con - firmation by the senate, the Board as at present consti - tuted, qualified and entered upon the discharge of its du - ties at the time stated in the law. Our first report, there - fore, will not cover the entire biennial period, and, in so far as our activities generally are concerned, covers only that period of time between July 1st, 1913, when we first began our work, and November 30th of the present year, the time of the expiration of the biennial period. For convenience, however, and in order to make our report thorough and complete with respect to our financial transactions, it has been thought best to cover the period beginning April 1st, 1913, when the appropriations for the present biennium became available, it being easily de - termined the amounts of the expenditures from these vari - ous appropriations made by others from April 1st, 1913, until the law under which we operate became effective. Fifteen different state institutions came under the con - trol and management of the Board, one of which, however, the Home for Dependent Children, was not taken charge of by us until May 1st, 1914, nor does the above include a reformatory for first offenders, the establishment and lo - cation of which was provided for by the last legislature and an appropriation made to carry the same into effect. On November 30th, 1914, there was a total present inmate population in these fifteen institutions of 4,521. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF There were also on that date inmates who were out on parole to the number of 718, making a total inmate popula - tion of 5,239. The total number of officers and employees aggregated 721, making a total population of 5,960. At the beginning of the period, from the best information obtainable, we find that the total inmate population pres - ent was 4,223 ; that there were on parole at that time 476, making a total population at the beginning of the period 4,699. It is thus disclosed that the increase in inmate population of these several institutions amounts to ap - proximately 12 per cent during the biennial period. The several institutions under the control of the Board may be grouped or classified somewhat as follows : Educa - tional, such as the schools for blind and deaf at Nebraska City and at Omaha ; Educational and Corrective, as are the industrial schools for boys and girls at Kearney and at Ge - neva ; Educational and Reformatory, such as the Nebraska industrial home at Milford and the reformatory for first offenders, when established; Charitable, such as the sol - diers' and sailors' homes at Burkett and at Milford, and the hospital for tuberculous patients at Kearney ; Educa - tional and Charitable, as the institution for feeble-minded at Beatrice, orthopedic hospital and home for dependent children at Lincoln ; For the Care and Restoration of the Mentally Unsound, such as the hospitals for the insane, of which there are three, located respectively at Lincoln. Ingleside and Norfolk ; Penal and Reformatory, the same being the Nebraska state prison located at Lincoln. The scope of the work being as diversified as it is shown to be by the foregoing, will give some idea of the immense amount of detail that is absolutely essential in carrying on suc - cessfully the work of management and government of these several different public activities. Conditions confronting the Board at the beginning of its work seemed to require that its first efforts should be especially directed to the subject of systematizing, stand - ardizing and rendering uniform, as much as circumstances would permit, the business operations and affairs of these fifteen different institutions. To accomplish the desired object a uniform system, in so far as was practicable, of </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 5 keeping the accounts, showing receipts and expenditures, vouchering for claims against the state for supplies fur - nished and labor performed, and arranging a classification of the different supplies required for the support and main - tenance of the different institutions was worked out and followed in the conduct of the business. In so far as could be done all supplies furnished were standardized in order that the same could be obtained in larger quantities and at more favorable prices and then distributed to the differ - ent institutions according to their several needs and re - quirements. Substantially all supplies have been pur - chased upon public notice and competitive bidding. In the purchase of supplies it has been the policy of the Board to regard quality as a predominating factor and to purchase only such as were of good quality and best calculated tu serve the purpose for which obtained, paying therefor what the article was fairly worth rather than to engage in an effort to buy solely with reference to the cheapness of the thing purchased. In carrying out this policy it has been our constant effort to specify and describe and to re - quire samples to the end that misunderstandings as to the quality of the article to be furnished would be eliminated and to endeavor in all cases to have successful bidders fur - nish the quantity, quality and kind of article on which the bid was made and accepted. We are convinced that this policy has borne good fruit and that in the long run the purchases as made and the expenditures required therefor have resulted in the state securing a better article for less money than otherwise would be the case. In making expenditures for general repairs, stability, durability and permanency have been the general objects kept in view even though more money is required therefor, rather than to make repairs of a temporary and evanescent character at a lesser expense. In the construction of new buildings we have given much thought to the uses and pur - poses for which the structures are erected, rendering them as nearly perfectly adapted for the anticipated use as is possible under the circumstances. Strength, durability, solidity and pleasing outlines in the appearance have con - stantly been kept in view rather than the adoption of </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF architectural ornateness; that is, utility is the main object which we have kept in view rather than ornamentation. All new buildings save the kitchen, dining-room and hos - pital building at the penitentiary have been constructed under contract with competent and responsible contractors after the thorough preparation of plans and specifications by architects of standing and character. The new build - ing at the penitentiary was constructed under the direc - tion of a foreman by skilled mechanics where that was necessary, aided by the use of prison labor in so far as it could be utilized to advantage. While the business and financial part of the work has received our best attention, consideration and judgment we have not in the discharge of our duties lost sight of the fact that other equally important factors were to be recog - nized and considered if we are to attain that degree of suc - cess in the general work to be done that ought to be striven for, and to fully carry out the object of the law providing for the maintenance of these public institutions. The prop - er care, treatment, and attention, which should be given to the different inmates of these several institutions have re - ceived equally careful thought and consideration at our hands in an effort, wherever possible, to improve condi - tions, provide proper care for those who remain and restore to society as many as can be made fit to become useful and helpful in the ordinary walks of life. With the view of keeping ourselves fully informed as to conditions and the situation with respect to the care and treatment of the different wards of the state, aside from the several personal visits which are made from time to time by the members of the Board in a body and more frequently by some only of the different members, we have prepared and require submission to us at stated times cer - tain forms of reports relating to the admission of inmates to the several institutions, to their care while in the cus - tody of the state and to their discharge when that is done. From the information received and the data found in these several reports much valuable information is ob - tained from which it is hoped after the covering of a rea - sonable period of time conclusions may be reached with </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 7 some degree of assurance of their correctness as to the causes contributing to the abnormal condition necessitat - ing the admission of the inmate into the institution and also as to possibilities of what may be done in order to prevent a like condition in others in the hope that as time progresses, the cause may be removed and the number of admissions thereby diminished rather than to constantly increase as seems to be the present tendency. By these means we also keep in close touch with the methods and manner of the care and treatment accorded the inmates while in charge of the institution. Briefly, with respect to the information above alluded to, forms have been prepared upon which reports are to be made of the admission of each individual in each one of the different state institutions under our control. These ad - mission cards, when transmitted to this office, show gen - erally the name and residence of the individual, his or her age, civil condition, cause or causes for admission, con - dition at the time of admission, treatment prescribed, changes of treatment, improvement or lack of improve - ment as the case may be. Reports are also required of a statistical nature showing why admitted, personal history, age, nativity, education, previous occupation, civil condi - tion, habits previous to admission, heredity, environment, former existence of same condition, attack or abnormality and other similar information from which ideas can be gathered as to the causes leading to the condition in which the patient is found to be at the time of entry into the cus - tody of the state. Reports are also required as to all pa - roles and discharges and the reasons therefor, with a brief history or record of the patient while in the institution ; result of institutional care and the length of time while in the institution. Similar reports are required as to all surgical operations; as to the use of mechaniral restraint and as to the infliction of punishment of any kind upon any of the inmates of these different institutions. Monthly reports are also required showing the movement of popu - lation of the different institutions, those present, those ad - mitted during the period, returned from parole or escape, those discharged or paroled or died, and the total number </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF present at the beginning and at the end of the period. Also like information with respect to officers and employes is required and the reasons given as to the discharge of all employes. It is also required that a monthly report be made as to the health of the population of the institution, such report in a general way to show those who are sick not requiring hospital treatment, those who require hospital treatment or surgical operations, the total number of sick or injured and the duration thereof. This information is re - quired both as to inmates and as to employes. A further monthly report is required showing the employment, in - cluding school attendance, of the population of the differ - ent institutions and also as to the employment of the paid employes and the total number of hours of employment of each. The above is a general outline of the nature, extent and scope of the work which we have sought to harmonize and render as near uniform as practicable with reference to all of the different institutions. The Board has been especially concerned with respect to the question of the adoption of measures, methods and means whereby it is hoped to improve and bring about conditions having for their object a reduction in the per - centage of the state's population of those who are for one reason or another found incapable of caring for themselves and are or have become dependent, delinquent or defective in some respect to the extent that it is essential that the custodial power of the state must be invoked and they segregated and kept under restraint and control because of the burden and danger to society were they permitted to be at large. Progress along these lines is necessarily slow and to intelligently mark out a path of action and progress requires not alone months or years but possibly a genera - tion before the highest degree of success which may be reasonably hoped for can be obtained. The object above referred to generally is entered upon more in detail hereafter as it relates to conditions in certain of the different institutions under our charge. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH The conditions prevailing and the work being done at the institution for the feeble-minded at Beatrice during the period we have had charge of the institution have been reasonably satisfactory. The physical condition in the way of buildings and improvements and other arrangements for the care of the inmates is good. Much in the way of repair and improvement has been done during the past biennium. A visit to the institution and personal touch with the work being done for these unfortunates will im - press one with the necessity and importance of making ade - quate provision for the future. The report of the superin - tendent is referred to for a more detailed statement of the local situation as it affects this institution. Some further improvements seem quite essential at this institution in order that the work may be carried on satis - factorily. The population of the institution has increased to the point where its capacity is taxed to the limit. The demand for additional admissions is steady and will con - tinue from time to time as the state grows in population. With a view of relieving the congested condition and mak - ing suitable provisions for future admissions the Board deems it quite important that an additional building should be constructed which may be used as a school building and as an auditorium and which they have estimated to cost $40,000.00. With this additional building other por - tions of the buildings now existing and used for the same purpose can be vacated, remodeled and changed into room for housing additional inmates, thus providing for a nor - mal increase in population for the coming biennium. There also should be constructed, and we have so recommended, a dairy barn and silo at an approximate cost of $5,000.00 ; also an ice plant to cost about $3,000.00. It should also be noted here that the inmate population of this institu - tion is such that additional land to that now owned by the state could be used to good advantage for pasturage and to raise the ordinary crops and furnish employment for the inmates. Being unable, however, to obtain any definite information as to the purchase of additional land available </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF for this purpose and of the consideration required to be paid for such land, we have withheld our recommendation to you and to the legislature until such time as we may obtain definite and specific information with regard thereto and to feel that as a business proposition the proposed ex - penditure for such purpose is wise and judicious. With respect to the objects to be attained and the purpose for which the institution for feeble-minded is maintained, we desire to submit for the serious consideration of the Gov - ernor and the legislature the following observations which peculiarly affect society in its treatment of this class of wards of the state. The inmate population has now grown to the number of 470 and including those who are out on parole, 495, and, as above stated, has about reached the limit of its capacity. Besides those now in the institution there are very many feeble-minded persons in the three hospitals for the insane. During the past biennium there were committed to the hospital at Lincoln 25 of these "de - velopmental defectives" ; to the hospital at Norfolk 22 ; and to the hospital at Ingleside 20. During the same period the accessions to the institute at Beatrice were 161. These 228 persons were all placed in these several institutions by reason of their mental defects. But in addition to these there are no doubt many other feeble-minded persons in other state institutions to which they have been admitted for other reasons. For example, a recent application of the Binet-Simon intelligence tests to inmates of the Nebraska Industrial Home at Milford gave the following results: The average age of the thirty-eight young women ex - amined was 19.7 years. Of this number only six passed the test applicable to children of 15 years. These were re - corded as not retarded. Of the number examined nearly three-fourths (73.4 per cent.) were mentally under 12 years of age; nearly one-half (47.2 per cent.) were mentally under 10 years of age ; and two were mentally but 5 years of age. Similar tests, if applied to our population in the in - dustrial schools and in the penitentiary would unquestion - ably reveal others who are feeble-minded and who ought not to be returned to society. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 11 Feeble-mindedness is known to be chiefly a matter of heredity. It seems, therefore, inexcusable folly to permit a feeble-minded person to become a parent. In this respect the high-grade feeble-minded is the greater menace to so - ciety, for often the mental deficiency is accompanied by physical attractiveness and charm with but little self-con - trol or self-restraint. The feeble-minded girl is especially in need of protection. The statistics concerning the Mil - ford Home — and they confirm the results of similar inves - tigations elsewhere — corroborate this statement. The only effective measures to meet these conditions are segregation and sterilization ; but in our state neither of these may be applied except as a voluntary proceeding on the part of the legal guardian of the feeble-minded person. Aside from the limited jurisdiction of the juvenile court in such cases, the only judicial proceeding provided by our statutes is a hearing in the county court in the case of an indigent feeble-minded individual, this proceeding being merely for the purpose of fixing the liability of the county for the clothing of such indigent. It is not a proceeding by which a feeble-minded person may be committed to nor de - tained in the institute against the desire of the parent or guardian. In this respect our laws are similar to those of many other states. By some, however, the inadequacy of the statutes to meet the necessities of the situation has been recognized and New York and Pennsylvania have recently enacted laws to supply this lack. The substance of these late enactments is that provision is made for a hearing by the court upon the issue whether the subject of the in - quiry be feeble-minded and if so adjudged, an order of commitment is entered, placing him in the proper institu - tion. In this way both the rights of the individual and of society are safe-guarded and the community is enabled to seclude those who cannot safely be allowed to mingle freely with their fellows. We, therefore, recommend that a statute, similar to those above mentioned, be enacted by this state to provide that admission to the institution for feeble-minded be by or - der of commitment entered by the county court of the proper </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF county, after due hearing and finding upon a petition filed by the husband, wife, parent, guardian or other person standing in loco parentis to the alleged feeble-minded per - son, or by the superintendents, managers or trustees of any institution having such person in charge, or by the county commissioners, county attorney, superintendent or prin - cipal of schools, or a probation officer of the county in which such alleged feeble-minded person shall reside. There are some who might become in a large measure self-supporting and might safely be allowed to live with their families or relatives were it not for the probability of their transmitting their defects to their offspring. This consideration applies likewise to certain types or individual cases of the insane. The only way to safeguard society in these instances is the sterilization of these individuals as a condition of their being permitted to live outside of an institution. It is noteworthy that Dr. W. S. Fast, Dr. B. F. Williams and Dr. M. W. Baxter, out of their wide experience with these cases, all recommend such a course. We think that a law should be enacted authorizing the asexualization of such persons with the consent of their near relatives and of the persons themselves so far as they may be capable of comprehending and assenting to such operations, as a condition of their return to society. Such a course would permit the crowded coriditions of these institutions to be somewhat relieved. GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL The population at this institution has grown until it now reaches one hundred. These, together with officers and employees, have been housed in one building which is fast becoming inadequate to provide suitable facilities for the work to be carried on at such an institution. The last legislature made an appropriation for a new building which is now under course of construction and which will soon be completed. When this new building is finished and furnished the necessary room and facilities for properly </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THK BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 13 caring for all of the inmate population of this institution will be ample, not only for the present but for years to come. Conditions on the whole are satisfactory. The young girls who are in the custody of the state in this institu - tion appear to be happy and contented and to be making appreciable and satisfactory progress in reaching higher standards morally, educationally and industrially. Life at this institution is so ordered and directed under the man - agement of the superintendent that all have mutual respect, regard and affection for each other, and all enter actively and enthusiastically into the life of the institution. Dis - content, expressions of dissatisfaction, and efforts to es - cape are scarcely heard of. Those leaving the institution uniformly speak with the utmost feeling of the helpful character of the work of the institution and of the benefits derived by them during the time they remained there. The education of the young girls in the custody of this institution is given all possible attention, a suitable number of teachers well equipped for the work being at all times engaged in school work and in the training and improving of the mind and character of those for whose benefit the institution is maintained. Many useful lines of industry and pursuits peculiarly adapted to the work of young women are systematically carried on at all times with the object in view that when these young people leave the in - stitution they will be fully equipped and capable of being useful and helpful members of society for the remainder of their lives. There are, of course, opportunities for improvement in different ways. These always exist where honest en - deavor is being made to reach high standards in the laud - able effort of fitting one to be a worthy member of society, and these opportunities when presented will be grasped and taken advantage of from time to time in the further pro - gress of the work of this institution. The Delinquent Girl The superintendent in her biennial report makes a sug - gestion which is worthy of consideration and in our opinion </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF could be adopted with benefit to the inmates, namely, that the age when a girl attains her majority should be 21 years instead of 18 years, as at present. A boy does not become of age until he is 21. There seems to us no good reason why a girl should be freed from parental authority at 18. As a matter of fact, a girl is quite as much in need of protection and of control be - tween the ages of 18 and 21 as between 15 and 18, if not more so. If, for any reason, a girl becomes wayward or delin - quent and in need of custodial care and training with the re - sult that she be placed in the industrial school, it is impor - tant that she may be retained in such institution for a suf - ficient length of time that the tendency to waywardness be overcome and that she be confirmed in a right disposition and character. To require her discharge at a most critical period in her life and before the full benefits of the dis - cipline and training of the institution can be received is a mistake and may prove a misfortune not only to those im - mediately concerned but to society at large. In this connection we also call attention to the fact that the institution for girls at Geneva is an educational and not a penal institution. It receives many girls who are dependent or neglected children and who are not de - linquent. The corresponding school for boys at Kearney is officially designated as "The State Industrial School." The institution for girls, however, is designated in our statutes as the "Girls Industrial School for Juvenile De - linquents." In order that the corporate title may more accurately describe the institution we recommend that the statutes (Sec. 7382 Rev. St. Neb. 1913) be amended by striking therefrom the words "for Juvenile Delinquents" wherever the same appears so that the official name of the school may be "Girls' Industrial School." </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 15 SOLDIERS' HOMES The two Soldiers' Homes, one at Burkett and the other at Milford, are both crowded to their capacity especially during the colder period of the year. During the warmer months many of the veterans leave the institutions on pa - role and the congested condition is thus materially re - lieved. The normal capacity at Burkett is about 450 and yet at this time it has an inmate population of nearly 500. At Milford the capacity is limited to about 125. We are. however, at this institution constructing a new hospital building which, when completed, will increase the capacity of that institution to about 200. At Burkett the buildings are not in a good state of repair and much has been done during the last eighteen months in repairing and painting and otherwise improving the condition of the buildings and their equipments. The sanitary arrangements and facil - ities are poor and it is quite difficult to keep conditions in this respect as satisfactory as should be the case. In the way of plumbing, wiring and heating much has been done to better prevailing conditions and much is yet to be done before conditions are as they should be. Some remodeling has been done, the most noteworthv of which is the alteration and rebuilding of the laundry building and its equipment with modern and improved machinery. It is the sense of the Board that for the coming bi - ennium it would be wise to direct all efforts in the way of expenditure, outside of maintenance, to further repairing and improving the buildings and equipments now existing rather than to undertake to increase the capacity by the construction of any new building of importance. It is believed that with the increased capacity, pro - visions for which are being made at Milford, and improve - ments in the way of repairs at both places and especially at Burkett, we will be enabled to properly provide for the care and support during the coming biennium of all of the veterans and their wives and widows who are or will be seeking admission into these institutions. While we do not speak with the fullest information and probably are </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK not as well qualified to form a correct opinion as others who have given more study to the subject, it occurs to us that the demand for admission to these two institutions has almost, if not entirely, reached its maximum and that in the future the applications for admission will be less numerous than now or heretofore. It has been our constant effort and endeavor to provide adequately for the comfort and enjoyment and well-being of those entitled to admission in the way of shelter, cloth - ing, board and other comforts and conveniences that will contribute to the peace and happiness of the old soldiers during their declining years. Soldiers' Pensions Under the law of this state the pensions which are re - ceived by the veterans who are members or applicants for membership in the Soldiers' Home may not be used by the state nor taken into consideration by it ; that is to say, al - though a veteran may be receiving a pension of thirty dollars ($30.00) or more per month, which pension was given him by the government for the purpose of assisting in his support, he must be by the state provided with food, lodging and clothing the same as though he had no income of his own. We take it that the purpose of these Homes is to af - ford a comfortable support and maintenance for those who have served their country in the army or navy and who are in need of such support, and for only those who are in need of such support. We think, therefore, that the present law should be modified so that the amount received in the way of pen - sion may be taken into account by the Board so that, for example, clothing need not be furnished to one who is abundantly able to supply himself, and we think such a modification of the law, which would in no wise impose any hardship upon the veterans, would be gratifying to their self-respect as well as relieve the state of unneces - sary expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OK COMMISSIONERS 17 HOSPITALS FOR THE INSANE Of the total inmate population of 5,239 in the several institutions under the control of the Board, 2,460 or nearly one-half belong to the three hospitals for the insane located respectively at Lincoln, Ingleside and Norfolk. Notwith - standing that during the past biennium by the erection of new buildings, especially at Lincoln, the capacity for hous - ing patients has been materially increased, yet the demand for new admissions has been so constant that each of the institutions mentioned is at the present time taxed to its full capacity and especially is this the case at the Lincoln hospital, where the situation has become acute by reason of the over-crowded condition and the inability of the man - agement to receive new patients, applications for which are constantly being made. To relieve the over-crowded condition and provide capacity for the constantly increas - ing number of this class of wards of the state, this Board has deemed it not only wise but an actual duty, ow - ing by the state to these helpless people, to make provisions for additional room and to that end in our estimates of needed appropriations for the coming biennium we have asked for sums to provide two new buildings at the Lin - coln hospital and one at the Norfolk hospital. The situa - tion is such that it is believed that the erection of two new buildings at the Lincoln hospital for the use of untidy pa - tients, or possibly one building for this especial purpose, and one for dipsomaniacs or employees, which need not be of a very costly character, will, for the time being, serve present purposes and relieve in a measure the congested condition now existing. By the removal of this class of patients to the contemplated building or buildings and pro - viding new quarters for dipsomaniacs, room will be pro - vided for others who may be seeking admission, and thereby, in a limited way, enable us to meet the reasonable demands upon the institution for the coming two years. At Norfolk there is now being constructed and soon will be finished, an addition or annex to one of the main buildings, which will furnish housing room for approximately 75 additional patients. We have, in our recommendation of needed ap- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF propriations asked for the further sum of $60,000.00 for the erection and furnishing of an additional building at Norfolk for the housing of female patients of a capacity to accommodate approximately 100 new patients. With the additional room thus provided for the state could ac - commodate and care for approximately 250 patients in addition to the present population. In providing for the enlargement of the institution of this character the Board is of the opinion that it would be in the interest of economy and an improved administration of the affairs of these in - stitutions to make provisions for an increased population at Norfolk, which now has only 480, and at Lincoln, which has 778, rather than to further increase the capacity at Ingleside, which at the present time cares for a population of 1,202. By the adoption of such a policy the population of these three institutions will be brought nearer together which, in our judgment, would result in a more economical administration than would be the case if the disparity in the number of patients at each of the institutions were maintained at relatively the same ratio as the present. Reasons of this character have led us to recommend that provision be made for increased capacity at Lincoln and Norfolk, leaving Ingleside as it now stands for the next two years at least. While the erection of new buildings year after year will, no doubt, be necessary in order to keep pace with the demands of an increasing population, it is also quite evident that more consideration should be given to the causes which unceasingly create the conditions which supply this unending stream of patients. It is conceded that many persons become insane from causes which are preventable. Heredity, alcoholism and venereal diseases are large factors in the problem and these are all preventable causes. A systematic dissemination of information on these topics presented in untechnical lan - guage; the prompt treatment of cases in the early stages of the disease; a following-up system by which paroled patients may be kept in touch with the hospital and changes of treatment suggested where necessary; the compulsory segregation or sterilization in proper cases of insane per- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 19 sons who might otherwise become parents — these are meas - ures which are prophylatic in character and in our judg - ment should be adopted with a view to prevent or at least lessen the inroads of insanity. In this connection we also indorse the suggestion of Dr. W. D. Guttery of the Hospital at Norfolk, that a statute be enacted providing that every luetic person should be quar - antined and that physicians be required under severe pen - alty to report to the Department of Health all cases of syphilitic infection coming under their observation. The expense to the tax-payers of the state incident to the proper care and treatment of these unfortunates is necessarily very large. To those who are without means this care should be freely and ungrudgingly given, but there seems to be no sufficient reason why those who are able to pay the expense of such care should be supported by the state. In many places the estates of such patients are re - quired to bear this burden. We accordingly recommend that in all cases where the patient or the person, if any, legally liable for his main - tenance is possessed of an estate or income sufficient to meet the expense of his care and treatment without depriv - ing of necessary support those, if any, dependent upon such patient, the guardian of such patient or the person legally liable for his support be required to pay to the superintendent of the hospital in which he is a patient, quarterly during his stay in such hospital, a sum to be fixed by the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions in an amount as nearly as may be equal to the per capita cost of maintaining such hospital, said sum to be a claim against such estate or person and collectable in the same way as other claims. Dipsomaniacs As pointed out in the report of Dr. B. F. Williams, the present method of treating dipsomaniacs and drug-habitues is far from satisfactory and largely fails to accomplish the desired results. We do not believe the problem has yet reached such proportions in this state that a new and dis - tinct institution is required, but we believe and recommend </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF that an appropriate building located apart from other buildings and from other patients be provided and that the patients be given plenty of work, preferably out-of-doors and be made to conform with the requirements of a strict discipline. We think that the typical police court offender who is absolutely lacking in any purpose or desire to reform should not be received by this institution, but should be committed to a municipal work-house or farm for misdemeanants or some such institution. We also strongly recommend the enactment of a law stringently regulating the sale of narcotic drugs and se - verely punishing the offender who violates its provisions. STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL Notwithstanding the population of this school has in - creased from 173 at the beginning of the biennial period to 203 at the close, the buildings and equipment afford ample facilities for the proper care, training and education of the youth who are placed therein. To our minds there are yet a number of grave problems to be solved as to the best method of caring for and educating these youthful wards of the state in order to best fit them for a life of usefulness when they leave the institution. There is, of course, the exercise of more or less restraint by those in authority over the liberty of action of these boys while in custodial care. Just what degree of liberty and freedom may be accorded consistent with the proper government of the institution and in securing the best results has not yet been worked out to our entire satisfaction. How far these young boys may be trusted and confidence reposed in them without its being abused and how heartily and gener - ally they will respond to a system of government placing them upon honor rather than being held under forcible restraint, are problems which we hope to gradually work out in a way that will bring about more contentment and love for the life of the school and more nearly fit them for useful citizenship. We hope to evolve a system of dis- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 21 cipline and management that will develop self-reliance, strengthen them morally and better enable them to over - come the weakness and waywardness which have led to their being placed in the institution. Efforts are constantly being made for improvement; for the better education of these boys and young men and especially to instruct them along useful lines of industry ; and to fit them for different trades and occupations. Much is being done in an indus - trial way, farm operations being conducted on a large and extensive scale, including not only the raising of crops of various kinds but also engaging in dairying and stock raising. All of these activities are found to afford useful and healthful employment during the greater portion of the year. The school rooms are not neglected and are kept open the year 'round and presided over by competent in - structors who devote all necessary time to the educational advancement of the boys according to their ability to re - ceive instruction and needs therefor. Trades departments are also maintained at this insti - tution such as printing, tailoring, engineering, carpenter - ing, boot and shoe making and other like industries. During the past biennium much in the way of re - pairs and improvements has been done at this institution. The principal improvement has been in the installation of a conduit system of steam heating which has been found to greatly improve conditions in this respect and to effec - tuate a material saving in the coal consumption. A new farm machinery building has been constructed and one of the walls of the main or administration building torn down and rebuilt to overcome a defective condition that had be - come dangerous. Most of the buildings have been repainted and refinished on the inside; also new porches constructed on several buildings, included in which is a large porch now being built on the main or administration building. Many other improvements of a minor character have also been made. While some further repairs and improvements are required, it is believed that at the present time all of the buildings are in fairly good condition and much im - proved over what they were at the beginning of the biennial period. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS An average of about 25 patients has been cared for at the Hospital for Tuberculous. The results of the treatment given to the patients at this institution are somewhat un - certain. It has been difficult to keep track of those who have improved to the point of being able to leave the in - stitution and as to whether their health continued to im - prove or whether the disease terminated fatally. It is quite true that a great many — in fact too many — do not seek admission to this institution until far ad - vanced in the stages of the disease under which they are suffering and when it is almost hopeless to expect either benefit or recovery. The result is, the rate of mortality is greater than otherwise would be the case. It is to be hoped that physicians and others interested in the proper treatment of those suffering from tuberculous ailment would more keenly appreciate the importance and neces - sity of early, persistent and systematic treatment and care, if recovery or arresting the further progress of the disease is to be reasonably hoped for. Provisions were made by the last legislature for the erection of a hospital at this institution which, when com - pleted, will increase the capacity from what it is at present, about 30 or 32, to in the neighborhood of 80 or 90. Only preliminary consideration has been given the subject of the erection of this building — no actual work having been, at yet, begun. This building will be shortly erected and thus better facilities and enlarged opportunities will be given for the treatment of patients who are entitled to admission therein. It is also found that some further im - provements should be made in order that the work may be carried on effectively and with proper facilities and to this end we have recommended an appropriation for some additional buildings, the chief of which are a residence for the superintendent and a power house with a laundry building in connection and proper equipment therefor. When these are completed this institution will be well fitted to carry out its mission and afford special treatment and care for those whose benefit it is maintained. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS ■&gt; ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL There has been treated at this institution during the biennium a total of 690. The average of those present for treatment is about 100. The surgical operations required and necessary in order to relieve the crippled and deformed are in many cases of a serious and delicate character. The results obtained appear to be satisfactory. Of the total number treated 279 have been discharged as cured, 258 im - proved, 30 unimproved and 16 have died. A new building especially adapted for the surgical part of the work performed in such an institution and to furnish additional wards for the patients is now nearing completion which, when finished and furnished, will afford greatly improved capacity and facilities for the prosecu - tion of the work to be carried on and will, we are con - strained to say, make this one of the leading institututions of this character in the entire country. In addition to the surgical and professional care and treatment bestowed upon the inmates of this institution, there is being conducted continually a school for the instruc - tion of these unfortunate young people during their stay at this institution. They are also trained in useful lines of industry suitable to their ages and capabilities. This educational work has been systematized and is carried on methodically under the direction of a corps of teachers and it may be confidently stated that with these oppor - tunities for the improvement of the mind and body, the children in this institution during their stay there are looked after in all ways calculated to alleviate and improve their unfortunate condition. With the completion of the new building referred to and its proper equipment, this institution will be prepared and fitted to carry forward its work in the future more successfully than heretofore. Under the statute covering admission to the Ortho - pedic Hospital it is required that the applicant be exam - ined by the county physician of the county in which he resides and that the result of each examination be reported Recommendations </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF in detail to the Board, which, on approval of the applica - tion, issues to such county physician an entrance permit for such patient. This procedure is circuitous and burden - some and has been somewhat departed from in practice. We suggest that this provision of the statute be changed and that the examination of the applicant be made by any legally qualified practitioner of medicine in the state of Nebraska ; that his report of such examination together with a complete history of the case be forwarded to the superintendent of the Hospital ; that the application con - tain a detailed statement of the financial condition of the applicant, or his parents, or guardians, and be accompa - nied by a certificate by some reputable citizen of the com - munity who is personally acquainted with the facts, verify - ing such statements. If from such report and statements it is the judgment of the physician or surgeon in charge of the hospital that there is a reasonable chance for the appli - cant to be benefited by the proposed medical or surgical treatment, and it appears that the applicant, or his parents, or guardians are financially unable to provide the necessary medical or surgical treatment, the application may be ap - proved and a permit to enter the hospital issued. STATE PENITENTIARY During the biennium much progress has been made at this institution. Among other things, cell houses have been overhauled, freshly painted and their old roofs re - placed with new ; sanitary bathing facilities have been pro - vided ; a modern and properly equipped dining-room, kitch - en and bakery has been erected, with an adequate hospital upstairs, including sleeping porch for tuberculous pris - oners; the prison yard has ben cleansed and beautified; and additional lights have been supplied both outside and inside the buildings. The measure to secure the physical well-being of the men — clean, wholesome, sanitary housing and food and the utter casting out of the "dope" traffic — have been accom - panied by measures directed to their mental and moral </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 25 improvement. The work of the chaplains has been sec - onded, the prison staff improved, the library encouraged, the prison school reorganized and strengthened, opportun - ity for healthful out-of-door exercise afforded and a grad - ual extension of privileges granted to those who show themselves trustworthy. Prison Labor One of the most important matters in connection with the administration of a prison is the employment of the inmates. The average inmate population of our peniten - tiary for the year ending November 30, 1914, was 349. Of these about 100 were given employment in connection with the administration of the prison, in doing work in the kitchen and dining-room, in the cell-houses, the boiler - house, the laundry, the yard, the barn, the farm, the gar - den, etc. There remained, therefore, about 250 persons to be otherwise employed. For many years the system of contract labor has been in force in this state. When this Board entered upon its duties there were two such contracts outstanding, one with the Lee Broom and Duster Company and the other with the Handcraft Furniture Company. Of these contracts the former has already expired and the latter will end next June. The two industries together employed practically all of the men who were capable of working and whose serv - ices were not necessary to the prison itself. The system of contract labor was abolished by the legislature in 1913 and it was provided that upon the expiration of the con - tracts then in force, the old order should terminate. The statute further provided that the warden should employ such convicts as are necessary in the manufacture of all clothing, shoes and furniture for use in the prison and other state institutions and such other articles used by the state institutions that it is possible to manufacture, and that he might manufacture for sale any article not manu - factured in the state and that would not compete with in - dustries already established. It was also provided that the warden should procure machinery, prepare shop rooms and employ such persons as might be necessary to instruct the </seg>
            <seg id="p026">■Iti FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF convicts in such manufacture, but no appropriation was made to carry into effect these provisions. It is quite essential that the inmates — not alone of the penitentiary but of all of our state institutions — be em - ployed so far as their physical and mental condition will warrant. In the institution for feeble-minded and in the several hospitals for the insane there are many inmates who can and do labor efficiently to the advantage of the state and to the benefit of their own physical and mental well-being. At the boys' industrial school there is a con - siderable number of active, energetic boys who are being instructed in various lines of useful effort. Among the industries of the institution are a shoe shop and a tailor shop where the shoes and the clothing of the population are made. In this institution and in the school for the deaf, instruction is given in cabinet-making, among other things, and some articles of furniture are made at these institu - tions for their own use. It seems to us that in providing necessary employment for the prisoners in the penitentiary care should be taken not to interfere with the operations and employments al - ready in use in other state institutions where the proper employment of the inmates is really as essential as in the penitentiary. Some machinery has been purchased and installed by the warden and the making of furniture for state use has been begun on a small scale. Some articles of furniture have been supplied to the Board from this shop and a num - ber of pieces are in course of construction for the school for the blind, but the number who can be furnished em - ployment in this way is very small. After giving this serious problem much consideration, we are of the opinion that to restrict the products of prison labor to the state use would be impracticable ; that the de - mands of the state institutions would not be sufficient to keep employed the number of persons available for such employment; or would result in the accumulation of a large supply of articles for which there would be no de - mand; or would involve the establishment of a large num - ber of industries, and their equipment with machinery and </seg>
            <seg id="p027">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 27 instructors at great expense, and for a very small out-put. This Board heartily approves the action of the legis - lature in doing away with contract labor in the prison and believes that the system of letting to individuals the labor of prisoners is fundamentally wrong in principle. We also believe that whatever may be the case in other states, in Nebraska it will be impracticable to employ our prisoners in the manufacture of articles for state use only. The only alternative is to manufacture articles both for state use and for sale. The present statute limits the manu - facture of articles for sale to articles not manufactured in the state and not competing with industries already estab - lished. These limitations are so comprehensive that there is almost no field of manufacture left open to the state, and they seem to us inconsistent with the broader purpose of such employment. If a term of imprisonment is to accomplish any good result it must be by making the prisoner more fit to live in society ; it must at least equip him with habits of in - dustry and the ability to earn a livelihood. From this point of view it would seem that it is the duty of the state to employ its convicts at some kind of work in which they may find employment when they are again returned to society, rather than to employ them in lines of service or manufacture in which they cannot find employment when they are restored to the community. To discharge a man from prison with ten dollars in money and with skill ac - quired for an industry not found in the state outside, and then expect him to be a self-supporting, law-abiding citizen seems to us somewhat of a mockery. The sort of industry which should be provided in the prison is not only one in which the discharged man may find employment after his release, but one which requires much manual labor and comparatively little machinery — work which requires some attention on the part of the laborer so that his mind may be occupied and stimulated. In this connection we refer to the appropriation of $35,000.00 made by the legislature for the purpose of con - structing and equipping at the state penitentiary the neces - sary buildings and machinery for the manufacture of bind- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ing twine. We have given this matter considerable thought and two of the members of the Board, Messrs. Gerdes and Kennedy, with Warden Fenton, visited the Kansas State Penitentiary at Lansing especially to investigate the bind - ing twine industry in that institution. We find that suit - ably to construct and equip such a plant will require a much larger sum than that appropriated and not less than $100,000.00; and that in addition thereto it will be neces - sary to have a working capital or revolving fund of at least $150,000.00, making a total initial investment of $250, - 000.00; that the manufacture of binding twine is largely the work of machinery and that the element of manual labor and of mental effort is small ; that the margin between the cost of the raw material and the price of the manu - factured article is small and the risk of loss, great; that the sales season is short; and that there is a considerable speculative element in the business. Our conclusion is that, viewed both as a business prop - osition and as a matter of prison administration, taking into consideration the employment of the men as a dis - ciplinary and reformative measure, the manufacture of binding twine in Nebraska is neither desirable nor prac - ticable. This Board has in mind certain sorts of wholesome em - ployment which will require a maximum of hand labor and a minimum of machinery and of working capital, and rec - ommends that the statutes of this state be amended so that it shall not be required that all clothing, shoes and furni - ture for use in other state institutions be manufactured by the penitentiary to the detriment of the labor of the in - mates of such other insttutions, nor that the manufacture of articles for sale by the penitentiary be restricted to articles not manufactured in the state and not competing with industries already established. The removal of these limitations, it seems to us, is absolutely necessary in order to provide proper employment for the prisoners, and will not subject outside industries to unfair or improper com - petition. The removal of a man from the avenues of ordi - nary occupation to an occupation conducted within prison walls will not increase competition, and if the articles man- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 29 ufactured by him are placed upon the market for sale they can only compete on their merits with articles manufac - tured outside, and against such competition no one may rightfully complain. The provision of the statute by which the warden was authorized to contract with any county, city or village in the state for prison labor for building or repairing roads or highways, has not been called into use. The county commissioners of Lancaster county entered into some nego - tiations with the Board for the employment of a few men, but deemed the terms fixed by the statute too burdensome to make their use of the prison labor profitable to the county. Compensation of Prisoners The matter of giving some compensation to the pris - oners as an incentive to greater industry and to the exer - cise of better care and more skill and as a means of pro - viding some measure of assistance to those who are depend - ent upon them, as proposed in the legislation enacted on the subject by the last legislature, could not be carried out be - cause no appropriation was made from which to meet the cost. We believe that the principle upon which such legis - lation is based is a sound one and are of the opinion that the amount of such compensation should be fixed by the Board and the warden, and its payment provided for out of a fund created by the earnings of the men, such com - pensation, however, not to be restricted to those who are engaged in remunerative employment but to be available as well to those who work directly for the state but whose efforts do not result in any income to the state. The mat - ter of compensating prisoners is in a more or leas ex - perimental stage. The compensation should be large enough to afford a real incentive to the man but not so large as unduly to burden the state. The amount, we think, should not be inflexibly fixed by statute but should be left to the determination of the prison administration so that it may be adjusted as experience and surrounding circum - stances may require. In the employment of prisoners by the state itself, it </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF is contemplated, of course, that the earnings of the pris - oners shall be paid into the cash fund of the institution to be used in the carrying on of business, the compensation of prisoners and the maintenance of the penitentiary. In the past the sums earned by prison contract labor have not gone into the institution cash fund as in other in - stitutions and as other earnings of the penitentiary have gone, but these sums have been deposited with the State Treasurer to the credit of the general fund. These earn - ings during the period from April 1, 1913, to December 1, 1914, amounted to $43,351.85. In addition the penitentiary has furnished the electric current used to light the Governor's mansion and that used for power and light by the state house and grounds and by the orthopedic hospital. For these purposes there has been furnished in round numbers an aggregate of 342,000 K. W. H. during the biennium, which, at the rate of 3'/)C per K. W. H., represents an earning of $11,970.00, or $5,985.00 per annum, for which the penitentiary has re - ceived no compensation whatever. These demands upon the power plant have resulted in overtaxing its capacity and recently it has been necessary to obtain from a commercial company the power for oper - ating the elevator in the capitol building. The new build - ing now in course of construction at the orthopedic hos - pital will further increase the demands upon this plant. The engines are of an obsolete type, wasteful of fuel and in constant need of repair and must soon be replaced. A somewhat similar state of affairs exists at the Ne - braska Hospital for the Insane at Lincoln, where the great - ly increased demands upon the power plant, incident to the erection and occupancy of the new buildings, have over - burdened the equipment and have made it necessary either to enlarge the power plant there or to procure current elsewhere. After a careful consideration of the problem, we are of the opinion that the power plant at the penitentiary should be enlarged and equipped with adequate and efficient ma - chinery to manufacture and supply the necessary electric current for its own use, for the use of the capitol and the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 31 Governor's mansion, the orthopedic hospital and the hos - pital for the insane. We believe that such a reorganization of the penitentiary plant will be of advantage to the state both by effecting greater economy and a reduced cost of production, and by affording employment to a somewhat larger number of prisoners. In order to meet these several demands including that of the hospital for the insane, the enlarged plant from the beginning be required to furnish other institutions approxi - mately 217,000 K. W. H. per annum which, at the rate of 31/iC per K. W. H., would represent an annual earning ca - pacity of $11,095.00. We further believe that the several institutions and departments of the state to which current is furnished should be required to pay to the penitentiary the reasonable value of such current. We have had a competent engineer estimate the prob - able cost of these changes and find the same to be approxi - mately $18,000.00 We, therefore, ask an appropriation for this purpose in the amount mentioned. The earning capacity of the prison is thus shown to be considerable, and we believe that by the elimination of the contractor's profits, will be materially increased. It will require, however, both money and time to estab - lish the prison industries upon a producing basis. Build - ings must be prepared, machinery bought and installed, raw material purchased, manufacture begun and a mar - ket for the finished product found before earnings can be expected to flow in. After giving careful consideration to the matter we are of the opinion that not less than $100, - 000.00 will be required for this purpose. We, therefore, ask an appropriation of $100,000.00 to establish, equip and maintain in the state penitentiary such industries as, in the opinion of the Board of Commission - ers of State Institutions and the Warden, may be best suited to the needs of that institution. The Paroled Man There is no more crucial period in the life of a prisoner than that of his return to society. It is then that the se - verest test is made both of the man himself and of the penal </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF system whose finished product he is. The restraints, the strict discipline, the daily routine, the compulsion of au - thority, the constant oversight and the dependence upon the state for food, shelter and clothing are alike and at once removed and the prisoner goes forth to mingle again with a community which looks at him askance, which in a gen - eral way wishes him well but is very reluctant individually to lend him assistance or encouragement and in which he must make his way solely by his own efforts and without the helpful guidance of any supervising authority. To assist the out-going prisoner in this critical time the system of parole has been established so that for a period before his final discharge he may be placed under a qualified supervision and kept in touch with the prison authorities by regular reports and with a certainty of a return within its walls should he fail to make good. But to make the parole effective there should be provided as a part of the penitentiary staff a parole officer who should be a man familiar with the prisoner, acquainted with his weaknesses and capabilities, a man of sympathy, of wise counsel, of firm purpose and of discriminating judgment, who would visit the prisoner at his home, consult with his employer, investigate his associates and his manner of spending his idle hours, and, in a word, extend over the man an oversight and a friendly supervision that would further reduce the number of failures. We concur heartily in the recommendation of the war - den that such an officer be employed and that a salary be provided adequate to secure a man of the character and qualifications necessary to such an important position. The Indeterminate Sentence In this state there is in force a qualified form of inde - terminate sentence, that is, the man convicted of a felony (except in a few cases) is sentenced not to a fixed number of years of imprisonment but to be imprisoned for a period extending between the minimum and maximum penalty pre - scribed for the offense. This is certainly much better than the old system of fixed sentences, but in our opinion it does not go far enough. We are of the opinion that all persons </seg>
            <seg id="p033">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS ■i who have been convicted of a felony, except possibly a few of the higher grades, should be sentenced to imprisonment without any limitation of minimum or maximum. If the purpose of imprisonment in the penitentiary is the protection of society, the prevention of crime and the reformation of the individual, then certainly the imprisonment of one who, on account of his violation of the laws of the state, has been separated from his fel - lows, should continue so long as his attitude towards society would make his return to the community dangerous, be that period one year or seven, or for life. The man who, at the expiration of a maximum sentence is as much a thief as he was at the beginning, is as dangerous to society as he was then and ought not to be permitted to return to the community and again ply his illicit trade. On the other hand, one who is manifestly so impressed and chastened by a short period of incarceration that it is evident he can again take his place in the community with credit to himself and with safety to society ought not to be held in prison merely that the time fixed by an arbitrary minimum established without reference to the individual and without any logical basis, should elapse. Certainly the reformative work of the prison which is after all the most important, would be rendered most efficient if the prisoner understood that after having been convicted and sentenced his stay within the confines of the prison was dependent wholly upon himself ; that it was incumbent upon him to earn his parole and ultimate discharge ; and to satisfy a compet - ent examining board of his purpose and ability again to take his place as a law-abiding, self-respecting citizen of the com - munity. It seems to us that this form of sentence is the only logical system. It has the support of those who have given the subject most attention — not only the theorists but the men who administer prisons and sit upon boards of parole. Such a law would involve a radical change in our penal system, but we are of the opinion that such a change ought to be made and is necessary to the greatest progress. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME Although in a quiet way, the mission of this institu - tion is being effectively performed. The average number cared for, including children born in the institution, is about 65. The stay of each person entering the insti - tution for shelter and care is for a period of one year. The objects sought to be attained are the finding of good homes for the little waifs thus coming into the world, also helping, encouraging and strengthening the mothers so that when they again go into the world they may be strong enough to overcome the faults and weaknesses of the past, leading to their downfall. From the information at hand it should be said that much is being accomplished in this direction. It is reported that a large percentage of those who enter the institution under such adverse conditions, by the helpful aid, assistance, wise training and counsel given them during their stay, emerge therefrom stronger and better, thus enabling them to rise above and over - come like misdeeds in the future. The capacity of the institution is sufficient to meet all present requirements; it, however, is found advisable to engage in much work in the way of repairs and improve - ment in order to properly preserve the buildings already constructed and make some needed changes with the view of making them better fitted to serve the purposes and needs of the institution. During the past biennium the laundry building caught fire and was totally destroyed. A new building was immediately constructed and equipped out of the repairs and improvement fund, which serves not only as a laundry but also as a store-house, with rooms for residential purposes in the second story. Other improve - ments have been made, a part of which consisted in re - laying the steam pipes in a well insulated conduit of split tiling, thereby greatly adding to the efficiency of the heat - ing plant and effectuating a notable saving in the consump - tion of coal. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 35 INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND The biennial report of the superintendent of the Inti - tute for the Blind discloses the interesting fact that during the past twenty years blindness, happily, has decreased. It appears that there are in the school today only about sixty per cent, of the number who were in attendance there eighteen years ago. The average attendance during the past year was 56. Of the total enrollment only 17.4 per cent, are wholly blind ; 82.6 per cent, have partial vision but not sufficient to enable them to pursue their studies in the public schools, and hence are eligible to receive the benefits of the institute. During the period six pupils were graduated from the regular high school course. The training given to the pupils of this institution is both literary and industrial, but it is all educational. The institution should be regarded as a part of the public school system of the state and should be denominated a school, not an "Institute." We concur in the recommendation of the superintend - ent that the name of the institution be changed to "Ne - braska School for the Blind." NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF During the biennium, besides the construction of the new primary building, not yet completed, much has been done in repairing the older buildings, remodeling school rooms and generally improving the physical condition of the plant. The average attendance of pupils during the past year has been 163. Sixteen have graduated during the bi - ennium. The education of the deaf is a subject upon which there sems to be a rather wide divergence of opinion. The parti - sans of the "combined" method and those of the purely oral method are equally earnest and aggressive. Four years ago a law was enacted in this state provid- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ing that all children thereafter admitted to the school and all children not advanced beyond three years in the course under methods then in use be taught by the oral method "to the exclusion of the deaf alphabet and sign language, unless incapacitated by mental defects or malformation of the vocal organs". This law has been the object of bitter attack and of heated defense. The members of this Board make no claim to expert knowledge of the pedagogical aspects of the subject, and the suggestions which we have to offer deal with the practical rather than the technical view. Incidentally, it seems to us rather unwise for a legis - lative body to prescribe by inflexible statute an exclusive method of instruction in any school. Conceding the greater desirability of the oral method and its wide applicability in practice, it occurs to us that in a given case a child might be unable to acquire speech or lip-reading to a profitable degree and yet might not be men - tally defective by the Binet scale nor physically mal-formed, and might be capable of receiving a fair education through silent methods. The chief objection to the law as it stands, however, is that it makes no provision for the choice or wish of the parent. A parent might wish his child to receive in - struction in the manual method after the child had received five or six years training by the oral method, or a parent might prefer his child to take the manual method exclus - ively. We do not see any good reason why the legislature or the school authorities should deny such a parent this election. There will probably always be in the institution manual classes in which such pupils might be taught. According to the report of the superintendent about 85 per cent, of the pupils received since this law went into effect and now in school are in oral classes, and 15 per cent, are in manual classes. The deaf are not becoming more numerous, pro - portionately, and there is not in this state a sufficient num - ber to justify the creation of a separate school for either class. We accordingly recommend that the statute (Sec. 7218 Rev. St. Neb. 1913) be amended by substitution for the words "to the exclusion of the deaf alphabet and sign Ian- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 37 guage, unless incapacitated by mental defects or malforma - tion of the vocal organs," the words "unless it appears to the superintendent, after trial, that such child cannot ac - quire speech or lip-reading to a profitable degree, or unless the parent or guardian of such child request in writing that such child be taught by some other method." We further recommend the repeal of Sec. 7219 of the Rev. St. Neb. 1913, providing for certain payments by the state to parents or guardians who send their wards to oral schools in other states. Under this provision of law the state last year contributed the sum of $612.00 toward the expenses of two pupils in the Clarke School for the Deaf at Northampton, Massachusetts. HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN This institution came under the control of the Board by reason of an opinion of the attorney general to the effect that its management, government and control under the constitutional amendment belonged to this Board rather than to an independent organization under which it had been managed before. The principal object is to receive, temporarily, dependent children, who, for one reason or an - other, have no proper homes and who are not given proper care and training by those in whose charge they are found. Also to find permanent homes for all such children with those who may be so situated as to give them good homes and all that goes with home life, good moral training and education, thus giving these unfortunate children, in so far as is possible, the advantages and benefits of the average home life of the state. In carrying out the objects of the statute and while finding homes for those thus placed in the custody of the state, there has been kept under the di - rect and immediate control of the officers of the Home an average of about 55, varying in age from the infant child to those of twelve and fourteen years. It has been the policy, heretofore prevailing in the con - duct of this institution, to find among residents in and near this city places for their keeping and boarding, for which </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF the state has been paying $3.00 or more per week until such time as they can be placed either permanently or in trial homes with the view of being adopted as permanent members of the family where placed. The unanimous judg - ment of this board is that such a policy is unwise and more expensive than should be the case. While it is true, in a measure only, that these children, during the time they are thus being boarded out, have some of the benefits of home life, it is also equally true according to our experience and observation that there is an element of commercialism in all such transactions, the result of which generally is to give the least of service in the way of care, attention, food and shelter for the money paid therefore. In a general way the person thus employed to board one of these children has need of the money, and this necessity alone results in the undertaking. These temporary homes thus provided are in many cases poorly suited for the proper care of the chil - dren thus placed therein. We therefore recommend a change of policy and favor the construction of a building for the proper housing and care of these children coming into the custody of the state until permanent homes can be found for them. An examination of the grounds and buildings in the city where the Orthopedic Hospital is lo - cated convinces us that such a structure can be erected there and the work of caring for these children be car - ried on in conjunction with the work of the hospital and yet each kept separate and as a separate institution, and that such a method would result in greater economy and more effective means of carrying out the objects of of the statute. By the expenditure of $2,500.00 the state can secure three additional lots adjoining those now owned by it which will give ample room for a site for this pro - posed structure. It is to be borne in mind at all times that these chil - dren are to be kept in the custody of the state only so long as is absolutely necessary until a home can be found for them and then placed in such homes. This latter is the home life that we feel they should enjoy rather than a temporary home while being boarded — a few here and a few there — and scattered over a wide area of country until </seg>
            <seg id="p039">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 39 such permanent homes can be found for them. In this con - nection we call attention to the superintendent's report on this same subject. In the statute covering admission to the Home for Dependent Children it is provided that the Board may at its discretion care for children temporarily; that in such cases the Board shall require payment for the case of such children from their legal guardians whenever there exists the ability to pay for such care; and that in case the legal guardians are unable to pay at least two dollars per week for the care of these children, then they can be received by the Board only when committed by county boards, and in such cases the county must pay for the care of such children the sum of $2.00 per week or such portion thereof as the legal guardians cannot pay. Past experience has shown that the sum of two dol - lars, per week is not sufficient to pay for the care of such children ; that the board and lodging of the children has cost the state a minimum of three dollars per week; and that clothing, medical attention and other attention and other expenses have been furnished at an additional cost to the state. We recommend that this provision of the statute be amended so that in the case of children who are received and cared for temporarily, their legal guardians or the counties of their residence be required to pay a sum to be fixed by this Board in an amount equal, as nearly as may be, to the actual per capita cost of maintaining these chil - dren. In the revised statutes of 1913 there is some ambiguity as to the name which should be applied to this department. We recommend that the statute be amended and that the organization be designated "The Nebraska Home for De - pendent Children." NEBRASKA REFORMATORY The small prison population of the state, with its mil - lion and a quarter inhabitants, as compared with the prison population of other states is a matter of congratulation and </seg>
            <seg id="p040">■40 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF mutual felicitation. The improved conditions now prevail - ing at the Nebraska prison and a wise and judicious exer - cise of the provisions of the parole law have kept the popu - lation of this institution reduced to the minimum, and have afforded opportunities for the release of those who have been confined there for brief periods of time and who have proven themselves worthy and entitled to consideration and clemency. The last legislature in its wisdom provided for further reform and improvement in the administration of the penal laws of the state by the establishment of a reformatory for first-offenders, it being provided in the act that such an institution should be established and open to all male per - sons between the ages of 16 and 30, who for the first time had been convicted of a felony and, by the trial judge, sen - tenced to confinement at such institution. An appropria - tion in the sum of $150,000.00 was made by the legisla - ture for the purpose of carrying into effect the provisions of the act. The general demands made upon us at the time we began the discharge of our duties in the organiza - tion and government of all the institutions coming under our control, and especially in an effort to aid in the further improvement of the affairs connected with the manage - ment of the state prison, which had theretofore been begun by you as Governor aided and assisted by the present War - den, it being our especial desire to facilitate the work thus begun in every way possible, suggested to us the wisdom of deferring action with respect to the establishment of a reformatory until a later period, and for reasons of this character, nothing was done by us during the remainder of the year 1913, in this connection save to obtain all pos - sible information we were able to in order to be fully ad - vised and informed as to all matters pertaining to the es - tablishment, future work, and usefulness of such an in - stitution. Early in the year now drawing to a close we began a systematic effort looking to the carrying out of the pro - visions of the legislature and as a part of the general scope of this particular work thus engaged in, and having our attention called thereto by different localities, a majority </seg>
            <seg id="p041">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 41 of the members of the Board visited a large number of localities with the view of examining the local situation and informing themselves fully as to the advisability, avail - ability and respective merits of the different places thus visited and proposed sites examined as a suitable location for such an institution. The Board visited some sixteen different parts of the State, making at each an examina - tion of one or more places with especial reference to the advantages offered and the desirability and wisdom of lo - cating the proposed reformatory at such place. These visits and examinations were made from time to time as opportunity therefor presented itself, and covering a per - iod of some eight or ten months. Much valuable informa - tion regarding the subject was thus obtained, and the Board now feels quite familiar with the local situation and differing conditions existing in many parts of the State with respect to the establishment of such an institution. Much valuable data was collected during these visits and much information and many suggestions regarding the subject generally were obtained from many other sources. The Board has kept in view at all times the main pur - poses and objects of an institution of this kind as expressed by the legislature ( and has regarded and now regards out - of-door work and especially the pursuit of agriculture in all its varied branches as being best suited for offering healthy, wholesome, and useful employment to those who might become inmates of this institution, and of affording opportunities for reformation, training and improvement in character and for their return to society better fitted to engage in useful employment and to become law-abiding, self-supporting citizens. We have also been greatly impressed with the advan - tage of having in connection with land for agricultural purposes, facilities for obtaining the raw material used in the manufacture of certain kinds of building material, especially that of brick and its related products. The legislature intended and we have felt the wisdom and advisability of obtaining, as a site for this proposed reformatory at least 640 acres of land to be used princi - pally for agricultural purposes, and also, if possible, some </seg>
            <seg id="p042">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 42 clay or shale bearing land, suitable for brick making, etc. The purchase of the required amount of land will necessi - tate the expenditure of $80,000.00 to $90,000.00 of the appropriation made. Possibly $100,000.00 will be required in order to obtain the best site which may be found avail - able for this purpose. It is our judgment that upon the acquisition of the re - quired amount of land and the fixing of the exact location for the reformatory, the development of the institution should be very carefully entered upon, beginning in a small way and gradually increasing the capacity until we have reached the probable maximum demand for the caring of those who will become inmates therein ; also that much of the work in the way of building, improving the real estate, and developing the institution should be done by the in - mates sentenced to confinement therein ; that only where skilled help is required which the State does not have at its command, and only when material is required that the State cannot manufacture itself, should there be expense and outlay in the way of both labor and material. It oc - curs to us that the buildings first constructed should be such as to serve a permanent, useful purpose but in the first instance to provide for the immediate wants of the institution in the way of housing inmates, officers, and employes, and sheltering live stock; that gradually, there - after, other and more permanent buildings especially adapted for a particular purpose should be constructed, the first ones erected being put to other uses as rapidly as those of a permanent character are completed, and it is to be borne in mind, however, that from the very incep - tion of the work, the future demands should be always kept in view and the buildings and improvements construc - ted in such a way that later on by extensions and addi - tions, enlargements may be made in conformity with a pre-arranged plan and outline, and thus in time develop the institution into a complete well-arranged and sym - metrical group of buildings and improvements, which 3hall met the lasting needs and demands of the institution. By a gradual process of development of this charcter, it is believed that accommodations may be provided for all those </seg>
            <seg id="p043">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 43 who will probably become inmates therein from time to time, they be given useful work, and the growth and de - velopment of the institution will keep pace with the in - creased demand in harmony with the growth of the state. After the expenditure of the amount required for the necessary land upon which the institution is to be located, it is believed that the remainder of the appropriation will provide for the necessary buildings to be constructed dur - ing the present biennium, and that the construction during the present biennium, and that the construction of such buildings will provide for the housing and employment of those who will be placed therein during the remainder of this period and that by the development of the institution gradually as above outlined, more in the way of economy can be accomplished than otherwise. It will be essential, of course, upon the establishment of the reformatory to have provisions made for the officers and employees necessary to man the institution; for their support and maintenance as well as that of the inmates, and for the purchasing of machinery for the manufacture of brick, if we are to engage in such work ; for the pur - chase of live stock and the equipment of the farm with farm machinery ; all of which, in our judgment, will re - quire the expenditure during the coming biennium of at least $50,000.00 in addition to the sum already appropri - ated. In brief, the above is an outline of what has been done and what, in our judgment, should be done in the fu - ture in the location, establishment and development of a reformatory such as is contemplated by the statute. If our views are concurred in by you as Governor and by the legislature, we respectfully suggest and recommend the wisdom of re-appropriating, so that the same may be available during the entire coming biennial period, the $150,000.00 heretofore appropriated, it being provided that none of the old appropriations should be used, and the further sum of $50,000.00 for the purpose last above men - tioned. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICIAL VISITS TO INSTITUTIONS We append to and present herewith a tabulated state - ment of visits to the different institutions of the entire membership of the Board and also by the different mem - bers thereof from time to time. It is proper, perhaps, in this connection to call attention to the fact that in the aggregate these several visits have consumed a great deal of the time of the members of the Board as a part of the general work in which it is engaged. It is our conviction, however, that the information gained by these personal visits fully justifies the time and expense required there - for. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 45 Holcomb, Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes 1914, Feb. 26 April 28 June 16,17 Holcomb, Gerdes, Gerdes Kennedy July 11 Aug. 7 Gerdes Oct. 28, 29 Holcomb, Gerdes. Gerdes Kennedy Nov. 10 2:i Gerdes Hospital for the In - sane of Nebraska, Norfolk. 1913, Aug. 6, 7 Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb. Gerdes, Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy n i»r i Dec. 13 Kennedy 1914, Feb. 4, 5 Mar. 3 Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy May 19, 20 June 10, 11 Holcomb, Gerdes Gerdes Kennedy June 23 July 28,29 Sept. 17,18 Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, 1913, Aug. 20,21 Dec. 23 Kennedy 1914, Feb. 20, 21 Beatrice April 8 Gerdes r&gt; i__ Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy 28 May 29 June 27 July 17 Aug. 25 Oct. 22 Nov. 6 Holcomb, Gerdes, Gerdes Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy 17,18 /ISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS (July 1, 1913 — November 30, 1914.) INSTITUTION DATE OF VISIT BY WHOM MADE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln. Asylum for the In- sane of Nebraska, Ingleside. 1913, July 18 30 Aug. 25 Sept. 8, 9 20 Dec. 30 1914, Feb. 3 6 Mar. 5 31 May 8 27 June 6 30 July 4 Aug. 2 Sept. 11 23 Oct 24 31 Nov. 20 1913, Aug. 29,30 Oct. 24 Dec. 13 Gerdes, Kennedy j Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Hclcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Kenedy Kenedy Gerdes, Kenedy Gerdes Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS. (July 1, 1913— November 30, 1914.) INSTITUTION DATE OF VISIT BY WHOM MADE State Penitentiary, Lincoln. 1913, July 16 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Sept. 16 Oct. 24 27 Nov. 3, 4 Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Geries. Kennedy 21 Kennedy Kennedy Kennedy 26 Feb. 1 Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy April 12 May 6 June 7 Gerdes Kennedy Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes State Industrial School, Kearney. Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes May 12, 13 June 17, 18 Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes Girls' Industrial School, Geneva. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes Sept. 30 Kennedy Kennedy Oct. 20, 21 Holcomb Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes. Kennedy Nebraska School for the Deaf, Kennedy Kennedy Omaha Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Dec. 29 1914, Jan. 20 8 Mar. 1 21 20 July 24 Aujr. 20 Sept. 23 Oct 24 25 1913, Aug. 28 Oct. 23 Dec. 12 1914, Feb. 24. 25,26 April 29 Aug. 8 Oct. 29, 30 Nov. 11 24 1913, Aug. 14 Oct. 25 Dec. 19 1914, Feb. 27 April 27 June 12 July 21,22 Aug. 6 27,28 1913 Aug. 8 Sept. 6 Nov. 15 Dec. 17, 18 1914, Feb. 2 April 1, 2 28 June 10 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 47 VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS. (July 1, 1913 — November 30, i9i4. ) INSTITUTION DATE OF VISIT BY WHOM MADE Nebraska School for the Deaf — (Con - tinued). June 24 June 27 Aug. 18 Gerdes Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy 1914, Sept. 16 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Sept. 25 Nov. 12 Gerdes, Kennedy r: erdes. Kennedy Kennedy Institute for the 1913, Aug. 12 Nov. 14 Dec. 18 Blind, Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Nebraska City. 1914, Feb. 19 Kennedy April 29 Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy June 9, 10 Aug. 21 Oct. 23 Nov. 22 Gcrdes Kennedy Kennedy Hospital for Tuber - culous, Kearney. 1913, Aug. 28 Gerdes Kennedy Gerdes Oct 23 Dec. 12 Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy 1914, Feb. 25 April 30 May 13 June 18 July 9 Aug. 8 Oct. 30 Nov. 11 Nov. 24 Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln. 1913, Aug. 2 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy Sept. 17 Nov. 8 30 Dec. 27 Holcorob. Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy 1914, Feb. 28 April 15 May 18 Gerdes Kennedy Kennedy • June 12 * July 20 Holcomb. Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Sept. 23 Oct 15 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy 19 Nov. 2 Gerdes Kennedy Kennedy 24 Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy Nebraska Soldiers' &amp; Sailors' Home, Home, Burkett 1913, Aug. 27 Sept 19 Oct 22 Dec. 11 Gerdes Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy 1914, Feb. 24 Mar. 11 Gerdes April 24, 25 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy May 13 June 17 Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy July 8 Gerdes Sept. 2, 3 Kennedy </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS. (July 1, 1913 — November 30, 1914.) INSTITUTION DATE OF VISIT BY WHOM MADE Sept. 29 Gerdes Oct. 29 Holcomb, Gerdes, oerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Kennedy Soldiers' &amp; Sailors' Home, Mil ford. 1913, July 25 Oct 21 :;o Oerdes Dec. 9 Holcomb, Gerdes, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Gerdes Kennedy 1914, Feb. 9, 10 April 22 June 29 Kennedy July Sept. 8 uerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes 26 Oct. 9 20 Nov. 5 Holcomb, Gerdes Kennedy Kennedy 2:i Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford. 1913, July 25 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Oct. 21 30 Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb. Gerdes, Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes, Kennedy Dec. 9 Kennedy 1914, Feb. 10 April 21 June 29 July 5 Aug. 16 Nov. 5 Kennedy Kennedy Holcomb, Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy 2:! Hclcomb, Gerdes Kennedy Home frr Dependent 1914, May 4 Kennedy 11 Children, Lincoln. (Jurisdiction taken Aug. 6, 7 Kennedy May 1, 1914.) </seg>
            <seg id="p049">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS ■Jit ESTIMATES OF EXPENDITURES REQUIRED DURING THE COMING BIENNIAL PERIOD We present herewith a statement showing the needs and requirements of the different institutions in the way of ap - propriations to meet necessary expenditures during the bi - ennium beginning April 1st, 1915, and ending March 31st, 1917. In the estimate presented we have grouped or classified the expenses to be met and provided for into what we have denominated "Ordinary Expenses" and "Extraordinary Ex - penses," the latter including disbursements for the construc - tion of new buildings or permanent additions to present ones together with other permanent and lasting improvements and the purchase of land, the items of which are specifically stated. In the class denominated "Ordinary Expenses" is included all other expenses connected with the management, control, maintenance and support of these several institu - tions. It is deemed advisable by us to keep separate the ex - penditures made for permanent and lasting improvements, new structures, the purchase of land, etc., from the gen - eral disbursements made from day to day of current ex - penses and which in the main are common to all institu - tions. As a part of the estimates of ordinary expenditures we present an analysis or detailed statement of the different items and purposes of expenditures going to make up the sum total of all the ordinary expenditures of each institu - tion. While these detailed statements determine approxi - mately the different amounts required for the different purposes mentioned they cannot in the nature of things be made certain and accurate for the reason that it is im - possible to determine in advance with perfect certainty the amount required as to each specific item to meet the needs of the institutions for a future period covering two years. Circumstances unforseen and which cannot be taken into account many times enter into the question of future ex - penditures which time alone can determine. It is for rea - sons of this nature that we have grouped the expenditures </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF in total sums with the view of enabling us in directing and providing for future expenditures and the actual neces - sities of the institutions to have a degree of elasticity whereby if a saving can be effected with respect to one item and extraordinary demands arise which require a greater expenditure than anticipated as to another item; then, the loss in one will equal the gain in the other so that in the end we will be enabled to meet all proper demands without incurring deficiencies as to some particular item to be met and provided for by future legislation. It may also be suggested that were all of the sums or totals esti - mated as the required expenditures of the several different institutions merged into a grand total for all institutions, to be used wherever occasion arises to meet the reason - able and necessary requirements as to the expenditures of each institution, this would give us greater opportunities for meeting extraordinary demands in one instance by our ability to curtail in others and thus with more certainty meet the requirements and actual necessities for the entire biennial period out of the aggregate amount thus provided for. In concluding our statement regarding legislative ap - propriations for future needs of the institutions under the control of the Board, we beg to respectfully state and sug - gest with earnestness and sincerity that in arriving at the amounts required to meet the wants and needs of the in - stitutions we have in all instances most carefully and thor - oughly considered every factor entering into the question in order to reach correct conclusions ; and we have fixed the different amounts estimated and requested as neces - sary at the lowest sums which seem to us consistent with the proper conduct of the work and the carrying out the ob - jects and purposes of the institution. It is to be hoped that our recommendations regarding these matters are under - stood as being presented not with the view of having the im - pression arise or prevail that the amounts determined upon are given with the view of having them reduced under the belief, as is too frequently the case, that requests are made for appropriations in excess of the actual needs for which requested with the view that they will be cut down to some </seg>
            <seg id="p051">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 51 extent in any event. In the biennial report of the super - intendents of the different institutions are estimates made by them of needed appropriations which far exceed in amount the sums asked for by us. Our conclusions have been reached after a survey of the entire field and a care - ful study and revision of the estimates as thus made by the different superintendents. In this connection we de - sire to say that in our judgment the superintendents in making these requests have acted with sincerity, consider - ation and discrimination and from their viewpoint feel an actual necessity for the appropriation of the sums re - quested. It is to be said also that it may be very true that much larger sums than have been requested by this Board could be used wisely and judiciously and would be of ma - terial benefit in carrying on and advancing the work in this branch of the state's business. We, however, have felt that appropriations may be swollen to the point of being burdensome to the tax-payer and it is preferable to ask for the lowest sum which seems reasonably consistent with the proper discharge of the work and to keep buildings and improvements in suitable condition and repair, and enlargement of capacity gradually rather than to under - take too much during any one biennium. A reduction of the amounts asked for would, we fear, seriously hinder, if not actually cripple the usefulness of these different insti - tutions. DETAILED STATEMENT OF ESTIMATED APPROPRIATIONS For the Biennium Beginning April 1, 1915, and Ending March 31, 1917. NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH, BF.TARICE, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 5,000 Salary of assistant physician 1.800 Salary of steward 2,400 Salary of chaplain 200 Wages of teachers 6,000 rVajres of employees 35,000 Maintenance 92,500 Repairs and improvements 12,500 Total 4155,400 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 52 Extraordinary Expenses: New school building with auditorium $ 40,000 New dairy barn and silo 5,000 New refrigerator and ice plant New refrigerator and ice plant 3,000 Additional land, 80 acres @ $120.00 9,600 9,600 Total $ 57,600 Grand total $213,000.00 GIRLS' I.NIUSTRIAL SCHOOL, GENEVA, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 3,000 Salary of matron 1,000 Salaries of three family managers and teachers 3,840 Wages of employees 7,700 Maintenance 40,000 Repairs and improvements 4,000 Total $ 59,540 Extraordinary Expenses: New laundry equipment Septic tank and sewage disposal $ 2,500 3,000 Total $ 5,500 Grand total $ 65,040.00 NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, BURKETT, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Farm machinery building and bakery $ 5,000 New refrigerator and ice plant 3,000 Total $ 8,000 Grand total $221,020.00 Grand total Salary of commandant Salary of adjutant Salary of surgeon Salary of matron Salary of engineer Salary of night engineer Salary of farm manager Salary of book-keeper and stenographer... Services of chaplain Wages of employees Maintenance Repairs and improvements ... $ 3,000 1,800 2,400 1,000 2.04C l,20« 1,200 1.08C 80C ... 36.00C ... 137.50C ... 25.00C i Total ... $213,02C ixtraordinary Expenses: </seg>
            <seg id="p053">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 53 ASYLUM FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA, INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 5,000 Salary of assistant physician 8,000 Salary of pathologist 3,000 Additional medical staff — -3 physicians... 6,200 Salary of steward 3,000 :{,000 Wages of employees 116,000 Maintenance 280,000 Total $416,200 Extraordinary Expenses: Septic tank for sewerage $ 4,000 Grand total $420,200.00 STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses : Salary of superintendent $ 3,600 Salary of assistant superintendent 2,200 Salary of steward 1,600 Salary of chaplain 520 Salary of physician 1,200 Salary of matron 600 Wages of employees 32,000 Maintenance 63,000 Repairs and improvements 10,000 Equipping and running trades' department 2,000 Machinery and farm equipment 500 Musical instruments and music 500 Total $117,720 $117,720.00 HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 3,600 Wages of employees 10,800 Maintenance 33,000 Repairs and improvements 2,000 Total $ 49,400 Extraordinary Expenses: Hospital and laboratory equipment $ 450 Superintendent's residence 3,000 Central heating plant and laundry 10,000 10,000 Land and septic tank for sewage disposal 2,500 Water supply and fire protection 300 Additional lands 2,800 Total $ 19,050 Grand total $ 68,450.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 5,000 Salary of assistant physician 3,000 Salary of pathologist 3,000 Salary of steward 3,000 Salary of second assistant physician 2,400 Salary of book-keeper 1,800 Salary of matron 1,200 Services of chaplain 300 Wages of employees 80,000 Maintenance 180,000 Repairs and improvements K.OOO Total $285,200 Extraordinary Expenses: New building for housing inmates and employes $ 30,000 Grand total $315,200.00 ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 3,600 Salary of chief surgeon 4,000 Salary of head nurse 1,800 Salaries of two assistant nurses 2,40 Salary of matron 1,000 Salary of stenographer 1,040 Wages of teachers 4,800 Wages of pupil nurses 6,480 Wages of employees 12,500 Maintenance 44,000 Hospital supplies 7,000 Office, library, school supplies, etc 3,000 Repairs and improvements 8,000 Total $ 99,620 Extraordinary Expenses: Furnishing new building $ 6,000 Grand total $105,620.00 Grand total STATE PENITENTIARY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of warden $ 5,000 Salary of deputy warden 2,500 Salary of chief clerk 1,800 Salary of steward 2,400 Salary of physician , 2,400 Salary of chaplain 1,200 Salary of matron 1,000 Wages of guards and employees 43,320 Maintenance 112,000 Repairs and improvements 5,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 55 Office and contingent School and reformatory Paroles and discharges 3,000 2,300 4,000 Total $185,920 Extraordinary Expenses: Power plant and industries $118,000 Grand total $303,920.00 NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 2,400 Salary of matron 1,000 Salary of physician 1,400 Wages of employees 5,650 Maintenance 23,000 Repairs and improvements 12,000 Total $ 45,450 Extraordinary Expenses: New dairy barn and silo $ 3,500 Grand total $ 48,950.00 SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, MILFORD, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of commandant $ 2,400 Salary of surgeon 1,000 Salary of engineer 1,440 Salary of matron 1,000 Wages of employees 10,000 Wages of nurses and chaplain 2,040 Maintenance 60,000 Repairs and improvements 8,000 Total $ 85,880 Extraordinary Expenses : New laundry building and equipment % 10,000 Grand total $ 95,880.00 INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND, NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 3,600 Salary of matron 1,200 Wages of teachers 11,000 Wages of employees 9,000 Maintenance 19,800 Repairs and improvements 5,000 Total $ 49,600 $ 49,600.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA, NORFOLK, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of superintendent $ 5,000 Salary of assistant physician O_l _* 1 f_j. a. _L_ 3,000 Salary of second assistant physician 2,700 Salary of book-keeper 1,800 Salary of steward 2,400 Salary of superintendent of nurses 1,800 Wages of employees 52,000 Maintenance 100,000 Repairs and improvements 15,000 Total $183,700 Extraordinary Expenses: New buildings and furnishings ing female inmates for hous- $ 60,000 Land 5,850 Total $ 65,850.00 Grand total $249,550.00 NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE Ordinary Expenses: DEAF, OMAHA, NEBRASKA Salary of superintendent Salary of matron $ 3,600 1,200 Wages of teachers Wages of employees Maintenance 35,000 14,000 42,500 Repairs and improvements 7,500 Laundry, manual training and printing office machinery 2,250 Total . $106,050 Extraordinary Expenses: Grading and improving grounds $ 2,000 Furnishing new primary building 2,000 Total $ 4,000 Grand total $110,050.00 HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Ordinary Expenses: Salary of placing out agent $ 3,000 Salary of assistant agent 2,000 Salary of secretary 960 Salary of matron 1,000 Salary of nurse. 960 Salary of physician 1,400 Wages of employees 3,600 Office and telephone 600 Traveling expenses 3,000 Maintenance 18,500 Total $ 35,020 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 57 Extraordinary Expenses: New building and furnishings for home for dependent children, officers and employees % 27,500 Grand total $ 62,520.00 $2,087,720.00 Total estimated ordinary expenses Total estimated extraordinary expenses 359,000.00 Total estimated ordinary and extraordinary expenses $2,446,720.00 BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS Salaries of three commissioners and secretary $ 21,600.00 Employees' wages, office furniture, fixtures, equipment. supplies, books, blanks, printing, stationery, postage, traveling expenses and all other expenses 18,000.00 Total $ 39,600.00 FINANCIAL REPORT We transmit herewith a complete and detailed state - ment of all financial transactions, receipts and expendi - tures including appropriations made by the legislature and expenditures therefrom together with all receipts and dis - bursements from funds derived by the different institu - tions from other sources and in which is shown the bal - ance remaining unexpended at the end of the period cov - ered by this report. The statement includes all of the dif - ferent funds over which we have had control. This report shows in detail the appropriations made by the last legislature and expenditures preceding the time this Board began its work and the expenditures made by it since and until November 30th, 1914, the end of the bi - ennial period, together with the balance of the ap - propriations remaining unexpended December 1st, 1914. Calling attention to the recapitulation of the appro - priations and expenditures made therefrom it is proper to note that of the total appropriation for the biennial period of $2,894,134.38 there was a balance remaining unexpend - ed on December 1st of $900,257.22, or, including the bal - ances in the appropriation made to this Board and for the </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF benefit of the Advisory Board, the total balance un - expended of $905,771.31. It should be noted, however, in this connection that there was appropriated for a reforma - tory $150,000.00 and for a binding twine factory $35,000.00 or a total of $185,000.00 in these two items, none of which has been expended. The expenditures as shown by this statement cover a period of nineteen months of the twenty - four, leaving five months yet to be provided for. We de - sire also to call attention to the distribution statement of expenditures in which disbursements have been divided into numerous classifications and the amount expended by each institution under each classification thereon shown, together with the total expenditures for each of the different classifications shown ; and the total expendi - tures of each of the different institutions as to all of the classifications thus shown. Also attention is called to the recapitulation sheet covering a period of one year from December 1st, 1913, to December 1st, 1914, showing by months the number of employees, the number of inmates, the total population and the total cost of maintenance including and excluding salaries, together with the per capita cost thereof, with explanatory notes. These different financial statements together with the oth - ers more in detail accompanying this report disclose the actual transactions and facts with regard to all expendi - tures and it is believed that they will be quite helpful in determining the actual wants and needs and the necessary reasonable expenditures that are required in order to properly carry on the future work in these several institu - tions. We have given the matter much study with the ob - ject of ascertaining wherever we can where expenses may be reduced without in any wise militating against the effic - ient control and management of the institution under consid - eration. They are helpful in a comparative way in that the different expenditures for the same purpose in the different institutions may be examined and compared, bearing in mind always, however, that the population, the amount re - quired for salaries and wages and local conditions and en - vironment have a very material bearing upon the pro - priety and reasonableness of the expenditures thus made. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 59 Statement of Expenditures From appropriations made by the Thirty-third ses - sion of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska from April 1, 1913, to and including November 30, 1914, covering all institutions and boards under the jurisdiction of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 M 1 z H o 5 E- &lt; H PR 3 E- 3 &gt;■ a z it -: o c — . c •. Q i.C r: — 8 IO 1 eft h Z 3-. M CM — cc" ■ «ft s T X 7-i r; oo c o_ e C-4 «ft li Z \\ ■ft II H 1* §2 I 1 Q c o 9 3 I c 3 S 1- T3 C 3 1 E- t_ e «— FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 1" ooo-hocccoco :© : m G~ "J °. °^ a . °? °. ** ;o . N "i_ 2 -hcJ^ooiooo'CJ : d w S »ot-HONO :o : «c uj . 0_iO^_— •fl"_t^O5 :© 5 tc "* rt" »J c-^os : 10 : ic — S-t! * i m 5*1 - i i " rt not^q-Haioo ; n o __ A oooiffds'fHd : 04 oi -TJ^-h lOO(N0505t-OJO : tp O o c "■■ m^-v t^'tc'Tf'^H' ■ eJ Ho «cn co cc HO &gt;&gt; . -, ooooooneoo : : « **joj ooiedoooinn i • oi .§ « . IONO NO5B00 : S cTa" oJ'H co" t-"co*oT : : o » «-■ . -h-w-h : S &gt;&gt; . ~ BOOO« t-t-OJ : : to Si jt ii w c c s i&gt; oi q q : _. 3 *j* ccdiaiflaidiACO : : 5&lt; rt coot- oor-nten : : « co-^t- -hio&lt;»»h : Tf ST« H ••"••" i s yP3 H 2 &gt;&gt; c J. „ csoooot--^ : ; os os £'t&gt;. . en« &gt;a to cE-13.2- 1 •» o &lt;-i : of o s»^SS^ ; ; » •» — *^&gt; f^ f^ i*^ Q} a ooooooooo csi oi *i *T OOOOOOOOO w CO P C — = o. 1 ill! I I lit I ijJiMldljj! n e- o i « 1 ♦ * O IN &lt;N J S § 4 ce e- ». CO CO O «B O W | 5 o os a&gt; o n co to c M N V C CO CO I O w- •» » Ik as ■* 9&gt; CO e» in I in rt - OJ IO US _ a n N 'E s" ~ g &lt; o n ot h r •w q &gt;o b ■* CO t&gt; 5 00 » o" o t CM &lt;N 3 00 II a: -* in -c c . "" — o a 11 "E2 Co? a.— </seg>
            <seg id="p061">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS HI ■f o -r* tc cm ea co :o : co en : "*; c rt ocnooise :9 o oo-h »i S im^oson:* mm uj . toejo&gt;t- :e- eo JH — • :•" cm • I i s j « « OJ I- t- O °l £ 04 - - I O 2 o o» to rn •»(• ec o » to » ooq S _35 lo'si^diBnoN ec oi t^id id — %'* t-xanoit-oo -^ o&gt; oo in ,g.g . « i- so t-^o^o3_o_e&gt;i p« rt_ "-«ei os_ O c of cSlGiDCQZBcS r* w" CC^^ «0* fn V O» CO i-l 05 HQ 3 .S 00 eo - N O o n &gt;» , _ ooirrxeo : :o : : r-o to — Vo*-" °^ *J "? ~l '■ : "? : : °?^ "? _5- l - &gt; oi oooi-ostd : :oi i : •-&lt; oi ui O»t-rtt- : :© : : f- » oi ■c 2 - us .'* '■P.'P.'l : i«i : : •.I °&gt; ai SS . : :co in 3*-l - ||* £ ! 00 &lt; m - 2 — oi_2 qtoouaoooo : : : : coco _3.Ss&gt; osos'iok : i : I &lt;ioi '&lt;• rt otctr-oit-^f : : ooo) •o m - m^io^oio : : to : 1 o; h h»h : ! si" at t-3 . ; : : : : D. si t&gt; : : : : : X O . S e» : : «■ yffl H 2 o o '£ in a. | 1 3 G at- c F. r. &gt;&gt;,-' _ o«covooo ;ii-o»: : 'iiJSwS t- oq in oj ■* oj o i ■* o» io : ■§ »■ *2 ■§ £ fc - « - ■* en loaio : -i rH t- : c£_«3.2 w OOltO: rt^Ol: a) u £^ o i- &gt;, n eo : c oooooooo -&gt;j©c&lt;ii&gt; to Vh^ OOOOOOCO «5 O ®-* lO ° 08 O O O O © O O O C3 © 00 0J lO *a - r ©©©©©©©© ■^•©^f^" n C Q, ©.©^^ift^©^©^©^©^ O4 O± s o eo oo tr- 1- cc"© i-T i-T ■^•'--r co" ' - m m w4 p4 - — — ■ on 93 01 US C t-. -a - it &lt;=&gt; 5 « I- s 5 g * -8- •s s c.2 i a&gt;3 XT i -2 2 § ! 1 Is s rSS i P | I , :;':::::: so i i ■ i ; ■ ; ■ ■ ■ i o&gt; : ! i : i • S"* :"* ; co«3» c ::«0:::::O«'*:ii :«fe'c-SD ••-&gt;:'■: a en ■ en ■ — o,S'S i I II liSJjj i'Jli &lt; « a Sf.S ?1 &gt; » q oS = S 3 S 1^-2-2 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF , •** coocccco © © -• is a co : -^t- *-* — «g c — cioooooc oowt^o « ; «E S S £ w o, Nooo^-fNic os^tocscs -i : ooeo 3 i 3 o UJ • tOI'lOiNnNN -HCqtCCOCO CO SrHCC-w 3 o oc-«oa so e so»t-o « coco 5 cc s 1a o © o o ■ "•2 U3 t- © CO U3 IC *O 0) £ Cvj 00 O ■*• X O] in O q • CO U3 CN CC CN CN OS — CO OS si -h^jcccoco a fc^ *»** »t i «co" «T '-5 «■»• M « o. «&lt;i ~ I • • ; I o -^t o o o r- o o o oosioh c- 3s *c-^» c i c m Sz, oooaooo OOK«« ® 4f h« "L .S en laoioeieioio i--5inccej» t-^ e» oioi — s M ■|I 3^1 I" c ■x. -T a •M 5^ . co co as c- ■* cr os c-cec-teco S e3 oS « ! o ai H r-' H U - o HCU. MHrt « S I £ CO «- ;_ 2 v=- e* :»- O 2 !§§§^§§g §§Sgg 5 ; SB 2 ! "' X xoo NX 1O o ■gc~2 §£§g2£§ £§S?S £ i S§ s I &amp; "= c'S» H -i •* c-^gfcT t-" N " a-: i = •&lt; •(H . Ht.H :OO*j I - &lt; M «- -S -°«i o iH oorsoco ©cotcTi; So ~ 2 a, SN^ -S*!* ©ococcc'©'©' ©c'os-»io : I aid ~ S&lt; ~* ©©^&gt;tt©©© --smoc-is : : S©^ I "« we ■M •m' 2j ■/. o.s~ 1*1 22 V. V6 v. ££ "4 X kiii - s§g?;§§§ § :§?§ j 5 sii'sii 1 a •a S « -3 t-:-r — K cow M , ■^ cc oo . W«" it" '£ CM M ? Vr y. ~ ■n^ S'SSs i5io«vioe'o © :cc?i© : os t^-» &gt;n "O l*|||f 2 . J5US2S3S2 2 :2§§ | 8 98 8 f ] ■M si i ,•? °'3 I. §§§§§§§ §§g§§ § § 9S S &amp; I- c csocoooo X. I" •M N !| gggg|8g ggggg g g £i *\4 I. •wco ai cc OSM HO 00 oooooco so55e c COO^rCXNN C. X O C O O Cft q«-JO0llNSI 3i -XOC© © N S©cJ_ — S ■M CO i o. "^ rt oo o: 3 £ £ meM« E o. &lt;^ • s - 1 5S «• •7. M M PS H Z H ■ 1 i Jit » -S83 ! i 1 ft •S-S- S "S"S t S-S = |:- S i: |.|||| H £ If f|g a a a cola s'a'a K i5 a § 3-S- 2 ° B 2 , « C wwwwmwmw KJfSooa r « 2 &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p063">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 63 »et-o«oooOR tc xio eo O lii C- CC M -TOO CC ■^ X "^ CO t-" ~m 10" i -TIN .2 a • —I t- v. M ** -= OJrt r: — — _ COOOJO X oo "5 1- o n l"; iff fh o&gt;. ifl I - IS [-" x t - tct- eg 5 *?T3 - o £;-• H s • o. o eS ~ -&lt;" -h" -J eJ o" in* * •M 71 f. *. -r V. «ss OSM n 3s O O X ift W O &lt; C^ -^ i-i rtt-OC — — ■M X V. X llfS x» - y. y: •y. x Mia -T X s^sS I- -/. e- X Zl D 1 r *J o fc &gt;. ■M X S LSIIi ■y.- -■? 'j- X 2 7 O I COW Ol « a o o oox to £ M X X r?» © LS 3 O — !• V y^ «» •» i - a a a O.3 3 — *-z ■ A r.'r.r. a n V .2 : iJii.il if ilif X* "-S-S-S m .M w — Hi--- S£ ? V. S 3 •5* &lt;_ ncesnoot-i KONOMOOOIS SCO«OMOOt-« ©_oo oi_ ■004 ©_©__©_•«•_ ©_ao_©_©_© b © ion t- uSmm?Se$*+m&lt;cc -h* 10" eJ-&lt;^ to- co-. Q] C4 CO t4 c- i raimtiHifif !Vs j§ : K«ixt&lt;i|hil|| j;ii || S &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;.&gt;.&gt;.&gt;. « Si! m ceo £cc al &lt; „ •7 s s a a a a s st.s i o ca;i °2 a » a (B n CB (D -^ _. V" r; ai 0)OiM!»tOt«toJSf . J </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 FIRST BIENNJAL REPORT OF ■■* O!c»oeo«-Ho 3&gt;.oe : as co cm i j ".2 ox«-H©oin«eo6ai state : -w « is •&gt; u S loienreioioiooaa ic -» as as o as o s&lt;! - ! • • | o » di-ioocod^BHO ai^m oi t~ei «J ; 3 -S oet^Noiosi-ao^oote io«5 ccoSx o o c w &lt;n »&lt;•&lt; -vaDmei m c'tc* &lt;c* i f-l » . NniCN CO » Ci ! « D.U „ rt — S &gt;&lt;»&lt;«*• •• *» os we - Jo 0 « oooiooen :n« msid ao« ' m i • — &lt;,; -i!"* ooooodeio i^^ ososm i idio « ! £'*&gt; 2 oococcio:cc«r -woo oc-^oc 71 a. U oj2-h. -^:«cg :xxco * |l-i - • • *! • **&lt; — • ■ ■ — n &gt;« : -•? c ■ w 2 5^ = A _ c«»ooc;j.-»io :li: m -HcrTfi'oc 1 -S5-H52 §?ois§sssn§ !? i s ;§i fl , cf,«3.2 H s«x cctc t-'C^ai &lt; ifli 1^- - - k! OS M 0^^ "»| i| ! k^| | — = §§§§g§gii§ §gg ■ as is ||" *j*r ocooooocoo ooo as oscc is c* — E I l| - - - II, It - — N *m : -3 -° — — c ® :j» :::::::■ : *• : • ■ i ■ £ •&gt; '-3 I Jf i !l*i n \ m '■3 £-5:::::5)6C:Srio«iB* H ! j ! -a o z -S-S-a-S-S-Slsj I g-i S g|s 83 I .2 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 ltlCj KUAKU Uf tUMMlSSlUntKS ti" oo^oo : ( °-^2 od-wi-ld i rtoi . j) S" isisecco : o to i S ™ . o0O2C^e~G : oo^ia i 5 i- 1 " 1 &lt;£ o* oo i 5*1 - ! • ( S3 §§£§ : - SS : _ t. ocfin : d ocx i — rt U3 IS CC «O : 00 C-00' 2-o - *"- N c ~- ev| : °i t "- to o c "-^ "^ to V i u. S m : e&gt;5 i &lt;Nt&gt; © £ — r. — &gt;- O to t- O - - I a 83 § J ootc us t-oo so 5; t-te ■» ° tt" us _- n m « •» •» ® I ] O 2 |t IS M i 89 7, C « O : 0» : : : » r&gt; « « ■» :to : : ON c^gS- •* !• ! j ! f* O500 l- "^ -T — • — as oi oi '"- c-" c-" - - s - - 7 I _ _- i &gt;, -- oom : : -i — -Oot-2 ooio : ; : io« _ 3 °a cooo : : : oo t&gt; !«„- 22S || I £-22^ rf | I j "* g-S .i «► : «• w« H c ; .2 00t~ U3 "O (NO « « » • J X a 5 at H r- HP 11 !] I C SOCCO N MO i °« ddodd d d &lt;c — -g o = co= « ooio 3 o l^^-J^^rt■d to* «&lt;-&lt;" o t. m ■• oo I s I V c-s t- c so &lt;c i -o do 6 • ISO IC In kh ■* jj eJ N "^ . •a mo e&lt; c * 6d » *j «, 00 IO CO I '" e OM 00 t. § 00 00 »-&gt; JJ is £.2 i X.2 : : : • C I BO I . ._» . g j!N« ft sl II i II lirill i &lt; iiiUnitJi o o « «r-S b 5 o a (So v cb3=°"-H&gt; -3 a a .5 5 * .2 o o o&gt; 3 ; ; i s. j 1 j c a •I 2 .12 t-as 1 -2 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ** I i- © © © © © © © x c- 1- :: : -r : » o R „• "5 c -I 9SSOSOOO109S :e i : "^ « •"! T3 ° -. 2 HisioiooiadianuJM © 06 zo ei t 0) S fCi«NOt-iot-j:i»H :: : ■* : xn M o u 5" • oecfflanN teoio :: : © : « ■&gt;* x £ S •»"* "J u5*Tf' : 10" : cT'i* « * a, . -h^ : : : to i~- Jr 3$| - I * • 1 - _ CCOOOOOOOMrOCC • S? O «C O t&gt; « X 5 5^1 Mooooooo-nrooi ou © c- © km « _ _ os xisiouicjiscjicto^t-- © c' © os ci oncc c — x, -* iot-t-t-ONia*N»^a 00 o 10 -* nn o 2-n - a^»eoc^aj i '^3!*j5oo»"9^ oc o « « 1°o "* _, o c rt * meiei'Si**** si 10* oT o"t. ic" oT cc'x* cm" e^" a li • s a- &lt; ac S &gt;&gt; — 'ooooooooTt-ooi-': 000 :misoo_ 33 Ju o Z Isoooooooc^Tras i^ic o ; cc» n - W _ "-"Si odd66d6ci»sa ■&gt;* jo o n i 0^ 00 u. Z 5?™ ~* oooc-oooutc:^occ xl-- o o : -h~*c*i,^ »_- e?S h " •• •*•••&lt; J aS'*?: ** 10 0" : os*«o" to* e Z i&gt;5^. cox is .; o» © -8 5 I J^t£^ W©©O©OO»0-&lt;fX^H©: :"? i^.^^-C _ a2 a nddcdoot-fflnid so : : c-» : ci ui X ? • s &lt;■ " nooooccMKiet- f 10 : is © is ' U ooioaofKN t-se s :m 000 k : 51 C^;T-* 2i-*8* •*" i ©" X*-&lt; OT SJ g , £J-i • i I- .' I • *i ** • — ' c ta |&gt;&gt;_ ! o = oocso = 1010 : : © © T -^" •© _57j"3o» u5ioii5io©u50t--w©'co os-h : : os t*x «o js Sh c J-» 5.2 h " cczicc rfio : i "H* 10* -h" to" g« jf«' i_ i „! 5- I - ©©©oooooooo 00 ©o o © © -« -h E* -- v*^ ©©©©©©©©©OS ©C 10© © © US* &lt;| ~ ° as ©©©©©©©o©©© 30 *© © oi aiio us - S? v; ©©©©•^"XNW©©© ©o c^c^oa^ °1 *■ * O 3 o \ammmiir*'* 13"©"©" ©"to" is" 10" i-T «*«" 13" Sj SO C t-C-i-H IM t- X-H OS S 2 i I : i 1 : : : : i i s : A 9 4 &amp; Jg I j c j»i j i I : S 1 '" B I rain JJ 1 !|iL I 1 »i M § i 1 mm i hSM 1 • 11 T74 SC 0000 CO ri '": od ' ~ c ■ ~ oo"w of C f •W "U A &lt;~- 7- - 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 67 1-1 OniACMXOOlOCCHROlOO t-t- U5 -.2 oeoioo-^osusio n en i« so co 10 oo e to t- - k £ ic«^Ntc»o»« x ie -* tt co ea n oia is I o U J ■ t-Xt-CO-HXrtlfa CC»-IIO ■&gt;*t~rt K5 to -« £ S &lt;S - f-H oia Us I o t- X t- CO -H 00 rt IN BfHUJ ■&gt;*t~rt K5 to Is- cJ-W rt'V O&gt; © a &amp; «&lt;?■£ i- &lt;s«* r r r, i o OTCCVOOOSnCOXS .O | O» ttoi I eo i c 9-* M i" en ■" -*" r?* to «« — __ — -*■ .— - — ' i _ ■• -• -v- *? TsTsi-H Uo«iooo«« to Tfos-H it xm to it- -»^ too S 5— oo rt ■* oo to -h t- 1- oi « oo ■* os us :oo vie a ° 3-e 3 '— - z — :t : CO C4 C4 B.ii K« » : «► •» UC &gt;. _ ogoeoe«oo « — coc ■© oia « _ «-«O5 j o osoJoooiri c iootc't-^oit^ :« c-^oo to T&gt; C _ "-• !oa«nNrtoooD n m a us ci :t- nn ic jT w CO ao a: Olicccto^^f :»t-tcccx :00 ifi^H to &lt;* *- o3 looooooioc : oo :c c- as t- : cm t- oo cc •§ » 00.05 Oi ia co so^ ■** : x t~ x o; n :oo us^h &lt;e OOt-XCCOO :&lt;O ISH &lt;; «!Ui-l : IM :eo t- t- H t- \ t- \ I la-l _• i * - I x^^-S • : : - « Z ■ &gt;&gt; cr OeoCOHCCCNRSIliOO : : Tf °* ooarocsiox : : l^i© tt 3 S en e&lt;edeciodu;rir:cKC« t-^ © e«ocoi-ee«e»ieii! : : eie e» /i t— a; x x t-© I t- Z s!&lt;* ~* 9(C009intcu:nHr&lt;3&gt;.xoo : : etc m ■grf &gt;-• oeoosin •^ WNt^X^HXOCN* &lt;M O cts?" rfei-:" oo oi 3 — S-or- *»•-«&gt;■ | | ao z s-s -I - . L; c; S-r-ji X. v. ::•»•» hB-c ■ i c -" &gt;&gt;r-i ©©©coscOGit-^-^rzoi 1 i ao ?-&gt; I ao **t _-^. ?. "OOa s '©©U2©lO'&lt;f©©to'u5C-o6©l-^ : : OSIC t- l &gt;o©o"ao-. »N-&lt;«t-*x- x ©tc t- O N L~ t- © &lt; *^ -r L S^ Oflj ' ooiooib^cdtciot^xdi* : : osio 5 ©©USClO^CCtOUJt-X©!^ S is. X .•s^s o ; — ■ ' - lit ■ - i s s Z. c o oooooooc c c o oc oo on » i. c 5 Sh^ OOOOOOCCOOOOOOC® Ot-; t* u &lt;u 7?- ° a o'ooo'oooooocc'co'ico ioo io S-^-c ** ***r ooooooxccoooocono ■^•oi^ 1 c ■-£ — to o n m x o a a o u; o c o o t^ o oie^^H u u 5 OJCMOO^C^CSCS©^©©©©!^© 050i|^H 0 O I cc'»'eJ-»i 1 "«o ie*«ooo*uf sJwio «*h~ of T£ i. uC i n - 5 »u; ii i ii i*H 1 iijsiiijl i; ! -^° — o u ««c:-* ■« is ie «• v U5 *» «l X E o. Sl 1i1 &lt;3 ee 41 ciisfc^i:::;;::;! ;;:r2 a jlhljti itf I1J hi! 01 J ; HSiiU * s in a ° &amp; o r; » x •S 00^05 Oi Ifl CO «^'^' ■** 00 h tC n X :00 lO^H (C ■■&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF C 2 ««§§§ §§§ §6o§ § S § -. ° ccoiidoc icoo t-^ m i~ © © 8S rt PStlNCO NlSlS tO 35 00 S © g" . ooiaioiaia tc^m t oo -h S-. o = u.~ -h* o* us in" ■*" &gt;o* J5 a. . in « 5*1 - - i a — ■»■*«■©©© OOO t-O5IN rt t- : ■**-! tD . o ,oo.o. o. o .°. '^°? c ! ® _33 tcoiaos &gt;ooo N0&gt;e ei oi : — 7 «iot-oc c- ia i/i acoo »-• © : gj cc t- us : _, * O5 O U5 O O : O 05 OOfNi C*i O : 'C^h aiot-OC :oos — it-SJ o ■?• : C l C5 *^ *~* "~* '^ *^ "■"* 00 p^ *^ tO • &gt;, _. «t-OOO OO'H !Ot- v u; CC : _, 3°* !C&lt;OOOC: OOO USI&gt;_J O d ': S&gt;«( « tC-HOOO lOOO 00-frt CC 00 : ,£^CC . "^ "^ "** "^ 04 IN TjiiOf, ic c*3 : colj-^ t&gt;"oo' t- i as t) : u &gt; &gt;&gt;— j_ »^^rooo ooo 5o^»-^ »h cc : — «■-"! 2 "5 "? I l. S' Oft o'wo'oo "io'o uicii-H O3 ?o : !i *3 !; S *" ■* rt O00OOO O4I«U5 OSWfl" t- 00 : ■3 t ■" . ««M""" N-H- U5U5-W «C IN i c "t,^ 3.2^ in«^" si i 0) « c -s u b &gt;. &lt;-" PL, H c ooooo ooo ooo ooo *"«J OOOOC OOO OOO O o O °« o'o'o'oo coo ooo ooo — &gt;g OOOOO OOO tC'O'O O O O o^-^-^-^ qo^c^in^ o^t-^o ooo ■*'efeJei'eJ ****** -vtacS i« e io o ■- irst-^ to co t: i 1 f j i 1 1 HI ft IpIII Hi Mil I s i z •«'375 - «'3'5 a -515^ a « £e a 3 b §-° </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 x nL r&gt;v f^\ rvi / w r \jUJ»ini»3oiuii EjXvo ■5 E 0 o I 0 •ScS S ! 8S I S | f 4 V a. 0» : tO!N : 00 3 an O ea &lt;-) ' h. h. eo _ t_ w i - \-\U 3_- OO lO CO t! c 3 "? c ! t t'* *i *o B _- c; idd Hoi od oi c 3'iT ■;1!h oo nc ■* « eg w S 3 * ooo torn o o» ° gg-f S I S a " S 1 I 2 s-s si a - * 2 MO 2 I - &gt;v — . o : to to * to «) . _ ja V O 2 t- : oto oj o&gt; c o T ■jlfs S ! §§ 5 B &amp; | .°j « 00 : •»• o o iv &lt; c?os rt * o—" « -^ o 2 o &amp;«"v i - rt 2 - I * "* a i ! all *»*§ Si!! HI f i« a. cd "* -; at o — •M^tt . ;«. t-.- 1 ; oo_ £ Jon SillS-i^ IS S 8 1 fa-si ■B-; oo on in a. "*£" °« OOOO 0000 ± * fc..- OB »j-r ooom -*t- ' *» c c o. "I 0 - t"*. 0,10 _ ** t ». 5 3o MO con oa^i c cm^K £ O. 05 00 £ S — - 12 ~l Tf| ffi :l!lH 1 I ilia : 1 "511 &amp; £ : \m\ i= I 2«J-s^ ; iMiIil i!1| I i lilif «: z ri ' - -C , , OQ Sow - qq C Vi i BO 3 •a c CO ■5 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF M a H Z M H — &lt; M H •Jl 3 z x 3 n H z f t-Ct- "fOtCNOe^OS^H : MCC CC m ■" c -h itceic Rioe^n^iai-i ooio ■«» .§ v 2 &lt;e o •-&lt; o6i~&lt;co6tcoeii-&lt; os &lt;-&lt; »* »• jj £ hh« Ccct-t-t-&lt;N«et- : t- O uj . -w oj in n n —i -* « ~* io ■* oi oo o £ s$j - i • • j S_, mom ccvxooohs eo ioo io c noK tc^ccoot^iopoo io top &lt;o ™" __ os cock rHoi«-H?:ait*i)6 t* t&gt;o t^ S-si - «► 2 &gt;&gt; 41 Of O OOCXCOOUJt- : (N : IM _ 6 O rt 9«9 p ic p oo c- io ■* ec oo : oo ~ «*jos coco c ai o « -^ oi ■&gt;» os oi:c&gt;i S. W Oft- IC^TT^ft- VM U3:iO^ c'gS'-'" •&lt; o"oi" V : ■* o « 5 rt ■ ■ rt : N : N *! *£§-£ • | * I * J _3°e nen s«nco :-hoo t&lt;! S UK r i .aE.Sa 2 s ? 0 :® ~: t: :° c ; c ;i t s »e oo:oo ai -jj.SliP a-, o^e *«6iooi :»&lt;o t^ oi i oi 5 I^-sJSV SSS 2"222 * S : S I DQ - — OOO OOOOOOOO CC ;t X — ~ — •m^ OOO OOOOOOOO lO iQkO 4&gt; OOO* OOOOOOOO* *-"* t~- OS ."ti 0) *j*r ooo o^rx^oooo -^ c*hn^" c cq, oo^ ooooooosoNoe t-o? *-g i j \t \ \ \\ \ j ! iili j iTTi II i i I i W j S a 'i 10 * _.5E.Sj : i 5 &amp; 'j= 3 a-« : "SVS* :-s-s-S-s-s|_S3-£2 |l J §£ 2 =osaas««as«.5c---2'&lt;c-. .s o ** "a "a "a "a* 3 75 "a "a "a "a " V&amp;" "~ 5 *£ </seg>
            <seg id="p071">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 71 ■HjH SnOSN OC4COt£ : 04 00 rt O&gt; •■2 COOOIOIO-H COO»t-^N i US l^Ol CO ~ . fMt--HIO OSOiaOO rt U5O1 t- " t H n o't-*oo* i «■ io" id' ji a. . -h •«» ■* 99 ■ ~T t&gt; IS* — s « •2 ? 3 O .t: S « - C CD I— I J= S ■§ ° 2 cctooqt- ot&gt;mr: oo o go o _, 05 CO »-i U3 IO 00 t&gt; -^ -; O O — ooosto-H-H eooxcoo to as 2io o» ~_£ iC_t-OSI&gt;X tON" t^ « JJi-l o c "^ •* &lt;o^ .-"■*&lt;*■■» so* «p" eJ !&gt;■ H « . « 5 *° we re I 1 i 1 s Vr &gt;&gt; _, oioooie o^^Ji-" : : -,'■',** -°Vo— &lt; °! c ? c ? l '? u " onon p : t- 5*j— 3Jc'ocJ-&gt;j odoiect^ : : .^iid oioccio» -a-oar-oc 2 : CO -5 io to Tf eg OS CO CO -h : : t- "3 — • » - *3 3 /% -» 1 &gt;, — , oit-ooo oc- 1 * : : : — o © •°otS c "-' 0 . 0 , 0 ."": = !"* t^: : , I ■ oo 0 . 00 , _ 3 2* coco©©^H cdcocft: : : -;©© "-i coco©ia© » o&gt; cm : : : S" 5 ® "^■co co^eg'-i'fl 1 rj'O'OO : : : JJ ~* © g-gS-"" - • « 2* I 1 I I - -a 1 s 1 1: « _^ °° » tc S I! ills 2^-22 1 "S a I . I uNMHia loecin: to os oo : oo c ™_ « 3.2"^ "&lt; t~* 3 n* oo : a -i : -i us : 10 OtT I 00 rH : ** = •»:!•»■ i ■■! ■ = C ©©©O© ©OO© IO © lOt- N — -_ ©SOO© OSO© X © 00&lt;H o o c8 ©©"©©© ©©©©* t- © t-oie- . *r* © O 00 © C*] © © © © to © to CO CO c fc © © co^cft cc -^ ©_x ©^ t^ o aes n 3 o ei**'* ©" eq*io"wio* « b m of pa. — — lOt- N OOiH O C- Cji t- teto « O0CO C4 e\f of M — • — • gg - s : : i : \k i i j !i*J :JJ ! j ! "S'S'S'S's" IS SSS^SlS |§ 2 ooe&gt; o B1 c— 3— £^«^ g a « « « bjj«-3.H g fi.2.£ oos-S 05 '-S 2 isasa^riJl?*"-^ I! 3 3 c - </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 Hi oooocinn •&gt;*■* docdiOH Tf iri lOioco^iao coco ■^.■^. CO CO C&gt;_tD OS as ■- CO aT e» «* 32 _OS i i SOt*D3tCt- W l&gt; OCCCfli'*!]!! IO 00 »a us cc oo -^ as &lt;o*-* ooo&gt;©_ec^so_ o.^*. &gt;aoo 5 00 oT « ee- efr e» «•- -° v o&lt;-i i oot-ccotfi oo ec OOQON«HtO QO N oooooow &gt;ao6 oot-Nt-H was 00_® U3.i-&lt;.CO i^ i «.*. oo to 00 CJ id ao 00 OS 00 — «» •&gt;- » *» I I OOOOKOi^ 1 OS t- OOiOiOnri iooo 5C IN O OS t»_(N p4p4M SO OS C- "-. -- IS 00 t-(M — 5 h CO CO o to" 1 e» •» «» •» E Q Iil|il5 1 _ O O N U3 *h GO CO I 1 C O - L-: IN lC 3S Lt ooco'coioao coc^ lOlfit-C^COCC O» CC C- CO WO 35 1= cooi OOS s J c aa «9- «- m (fr 1 u M ll I ooooco ow oooooo o-^ !DNOiQ«O 1°. c? *-4 of ao as g£ i£$^ o t- OOI HS in*'** Ml i— &lt; ■k = H en 2 5 M- •»■ ~ - c o ■ a 2 Q. ■ i : : : i : :t3 ■2 : «j bo : Ijjl j illt i a 08 M tt.S « "5 5 5 3 3 1 i ■ B D * c 5 eg * </seg>
            <seg id="p073">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 73 •9 t-o ooo ©tec-i os oo&gt; •g c^ tOO "3CO O-HIN CO (N» v 2 **"* t- io o iooo» o6 icto m S ■fl'ej oot-o c-^i-i in «&gt;» u g" - o_tc -^ eo io co ©_to_ io_ ao 5i' rt »* ofco* us" oT-^ J P. . "H« 00 to 00 OS 3". 7-1 o* 00 CO 00 93 OS!M 1O1O o* X •M — ~ sz «o §§g "gas s ss os 00 u5 n io o ic co -r ?i rsx" Ml- -«o (Noooo c- coec o e co*eT w'^h'^h' -h'i&gt;'^' oo* io" H « . 10 • &amp;S - HO t- ■■I' rii o 00 00 O 00 00 t- 00 &gt;&gt; _ O -h OOO Ot-lO C- O-&lt; Jjni OO "?OO otOlO Ol 00CO SO-.'- OO -&lt;OO OK00 00 COCO c "P os ~* eo"'-^ *4 co*oT t^" ur" sis' to 00 os N 00-* teoo_ in 8* ■ - &gt;k -- coos ooo ocot- os . : — U Xh — * — — — OlAOS O _ 3 So: coos odd di&gt;d d :: -" ccos OOO OOstt N : : .K^CO «^» 'J'CO'fl 1 C0«M CO s&amp;4 1 1 os X — i.-: aso oT^ • •! — 13 3SO of-*' B p w V.- » *- &gt;&gt;— • _ oo ooo o-*to i= : : JJ.J, J5 OO OOO OOSC4 IN -,£1. SHooi "Jio 60s u5iot&gt; o I ! 333 S'g osia — . 333 £g OS IO — . -T N -T t- -r x* V Vi ■x. v.-f "gg g§§ §§§ g gg °« oe odd odd d do »j "7" O O O O O O O O O O O 3 o io'cc* eS**e$ -^ u5't&gt;' Eo ■- 100 •-&gt; ia P. — gs gs ■M M gs g2 e*r«r ■M t- x" M o K--. . DO a = 1 its y 1 ill i *i c« C-^ " : » &lt;J E m cs J&lt; °o°;sooo s &lt; s« s |^»- mmw www o w 1 H ■ 5 2 E 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 ■s.=i IP oceisoo itoiOh : mr ia : Oj'^f-n" i C^ CO* *~* '■ co cc ; os os 8 4 © ►• O p © £ © o o 3 to a» o s &amp; o : I 32 ft x £ HO COOOHt-COtCOKO IO 03 OOK^HOUSOONO ftO CO U5ClCXHOlC^Wt»C t- CC O oc &lt;n iM_o_N_o^iff ec oo ej_ P_ei. co c^^pfof e^u?" t-^ cc*^"" ©"^ **" n cc m — _i ■ _c : O ■2 00 H : « »-i : OS I I 41 « ONHrHCCNOtCOlO : |O» 00 ! one^f;i&gt;oeo-* ; «coo ■«•■ OM^rt-O"»t--HM0C : ©&lt;C tc o^t-^^u^cc^e^ cc_ o^ : co t- cc « « M oo oo ~ •» •»■ » S r- 8 Ccct-OICCQOO : : 00 : •** o -&lt;r "? qCONb;f;lO : : t-; : CC O&gt; e* J5 O X oi oi r~ io l~ : : »h : rtl&gt; as "^ OXSXNKCC : :a» : ■*« t- V SNt-eaen : m : cdcm w if^JwS OJ- gf N | * £ &lt; OOHT(-ito : :o O0O0 I ID * odot^Nwoo : : :o o» ri ** (*5 iCC-N««rt : :O IN CO «C O m : : :■ ooo« © •» « V I i : ■* te ec m i i ; - - « &lt; M occoooococ© ©a»&lt;» OOOOOOOOOOO OOO -s&gt; OOCCCCOCOOC OH 'H « (c (c c^c^q o tc o oon oo © CQ ec^Hiacc"o*i£3 ©"ufirT^f" cc'af iri" U s s z 1 1 1 1 1^ i mi i i |iJ li |i|| | y i till MS I Jl ■ i ; X I &lt; 0 ■s s - : i- :_ _o ■ X a I ! : S : o : # C z z z U 00 Uli 11 ! el li o u co I x : o - I a : O~ o £ a © a* ©" SS is C £ »H ft *» -a^ i j. •o c c o E : Sg 1 i "8" * i US «• • x * I i gS I5i &amp; I i I I V I ■ c O </seg>
            <seg id="p075">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 75 ri 5 K- 5" N f. — CO •M *t u-: O_ cc* X •» I -c B 5 Vm^h O to OOOOt-USt-t-;»-&lt; ■^J^ H 3 °-2 "OW 66610 'oioi6-&lt; 0606 « «j £ IN"- 1 O1»t- t-tOlO—l W* C 5 S" - »&lt; tomiN'H -&gt;&lt;nco ■»•« 0 i ■"* co * H ' «-. on oooooot-ooxa coco a 32 on qoooe&gt;j-«;ojNOO uses 0 _oj 10 co 6 6 6 10 cri 6 6 cri oo woo a — -O-. t-00 So^eaMn^a 10 us « 2 -S . c ?. u i cs^ee o» &lt;o en &lt;o os &lt;c us_ &lt;B,&lt;^ ° o c eirH w" e^t*" oTei" c JSJ •► «■ . M &gt;»-^ -» OO OOOO :US005OCn COW ' &lt; JaZ? 2 00 0000 aotcia-v use- e OS _-oa 66 6666 6*Hoio6 61- 0 h ! -*"* &lt;-"- • _- 5"cg .8 - - • 2 a I 8 2 H ! i i M i M M II 2 ' ,^f 2 M ! ! I ! ! I ! ! ! M .- S«5 . Z cl o v ■ ■ ■ * « u -= : : i : ; ; ; • ; • ; i i a ?'" 'S'O oa usco 666us aioioocio 00 q |w n 2 Z 1 c 00 000000000 o«-c — ° eg 66 666666666 6e «.» *r" O O O O O O O O O 00 O 2 *r 00 co-^c^oooooco p^^ P^^. Q I 3 o eo'eJ rSr*ri r* co't^ CO-*" _. o t. ~* « b U I «•; 4* ::::::::: : : 1 1 Id! H! Mh! Mi £ III ifiSs-a-sfS. ; i-g -S'goJ'S'S'S'S-S-l&amp;l l.| ■ «a=«5f=»«osabcu&gt;5 -3 ■s.T.-r. znmxzn&gt;Ob'iS •— </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 o. c a&gt; ■IT It 4 ?£* o t- 1 ■ r. ■a ■ — I m o N i6 - : °V v± 32 e si o as x -T M i Sfr ■* ««• on Ot-; o oi o a o_-w_ M IS X ■ X 8 i ! : •*■ V? j O : O : O_ : m : c ■M rr* t- e -• M i ■a bc o - l&lt;f 2 CTiS rt x o .$ H Cm H Q m ■ ; : ! ■ •» ! Q &lt; 0 ! ; I : 5 ', I. ■8«sn?s IB ri 3 N &lt; o m Wf . I P 5 a §2 If ooo to •* o o O OO lO Ol O S ooo id oo o to lOOO N O t- t^iao 03 — i* t~ io'-h'o" «T a» 1 t- — § o o CO* «* •» 4* ««• s n I 2 a a &lt; o ■ I ijiiiiiliillii I 1 j ■o I * i I W I! </seg>
            <seg id="p077">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 77 Z o B -i D s ■^ ©nrttCNcoeciCH«5ii&gt;- c h ' tt&gt; £ ©t-^COOSt-OJiCOOC-^CD S *- t-'^n"^^^ oTpf cT-^ao'ic'ar , 23( - ~ - _ toNoiic-T.uoneciOKO SS OS Tf f; « N tO &lt;N N ■» tO O _ os ia ao t~ -h »o cc ao os t- © — TJ-h o cc *^ ift ® cc oc oo t&gt; ci ao O_C&lt;I CS^^X r* O5 G5 Oc' H * V-&lt;"t-''^Htc"lO(MS^OrTf t-^aT bS SCIt-O-.KN«*rt»M mo &gt;, _, mmTf^^-i-30-HtD-q-*^ _, &amp; ■»-• os ic oi as oo «o t- e4 td c'S"' cJooos-Tf'ort^'w'ia'-H'Vodt-^ O.5 o -*N IN -• -Q be iftN^H'-jc:oo(CNt&gt;aeo^ CC . 00^C-_«D_Oi a^O_O_^O^t^ C "C « H &amp;aicSt^&amp;*GO*OlClSi£2G£*D C C CC c^l iO CD t- t£) CD O3 iO l&gt; 00 iG lO c . 5 ! : * i - — •a "S-5 fc *" - os t- » -h o^-^sg e^oo oj to in j :k :x £«»3.2 rt c?eaie oTt-^ in tc" od o-^r oo io" S- * "" yyi'Ufcb, CRNXXHICM00 »h : : i :« : : »°&amp;* - i\H\i\ * w *» °^ *^i °i — = — — — "= °« oo i-&lt; io o i&gt; tc io i« oo as i~ ■* IS ! 5 s 5 a j-- OT-iC^OSlOCCCC^J't-'fl'CClft i»- : : • t^ CS 0»Nt-,»«01HlO C-_N »&lt; _jz = _S 3o ~* ei it to &gt;o ■*? *b m if in«o&gt; »"S§ri« o t. o cj os c- Tf oo os us cc ■"» &gt;t &amp; — ?t— -— « CO. IN"-I^HTf(N «W« »H ■= t = - i — - ■i ; il-i Ml i Mi i «iKk«i 1 sills • Hn*&amp;w&gt;*'*t iilifii </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF /. I l 8 !r * /- 1 I i ■c =. ■ M (*• ■- - - - - ••2 ooidc: so t^ioic 06' u ~ . Ht-e oo_ e^to_co_ e&gt;i/ S fc« w **W^ ** cT^^r to" _™&amp;. hosl 1 ; © *-« w 3^1 r " a a 3^ •&lt;*« ; oo &gt;4Na} « os to io : ai iod^ o 00O : O QOOn IN 3 . l °.. J 'v w . °° "t^ "&gt; o,y p4«4 : *-( •-* X * in" m &gt;» • -,. tox : ■*»• 00O : ' X -° a o-&lt; : c*n oao ! oo — o**3&gt; ■*■* i^Soo oco i co " iO eo : ,&lt;N 10 -h : t- ciS- ao"io i &gt;,"ca oo"o" : oo s a- 3-. x : a .• r- m . a O.O o :g K N : &lt;N = c c IO.X, : fit; : 5 a! C2 M B : 3 a, m tJ : cc : co xo .« v&gt; ; •» |_ if. j c S i co co «s ; •- 10 e cia &lt;c • i •§ -2-ofcfe - ■*«. ir" &lt;=&gt;. O^«? * 3 sJllss^ — x s 1 s c ootco — i noo co ■^OO to (N»O00 SO 001CO t- lO-&lt;CO OS :. 2 &gt;. CO tO-* O CO, M -M — O — : Z« 3 " 1 •sc&gt;&gt; a i I 1 i i^^ 1 13 ! 3 I ; i?§« 6 3i| g i o o ° B i. oO O 5 i a i ?! £ i O 0) 0) O 2t3 B </seg>
            <seg id="p079">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 79 A u I22222£r'52 o ; f9 &gt;° : t- oc : : c- ■» o « -* oc t- • *» &gt;o _= 2'««j °?' fl ! o i Tf : c 9 c^«'^ *&gt; :*!1 i^T i : e ?1®T " 9 ■"! :c &lt;* 6* £--■=* 2~2!5~E:5S5' 5S ; "-"O&gt; i-iec ■ ioicixci xo6t~«s :&gt;o « ■- a-:;= SSSSSSSS" 1^ ""* : «' &lt; : C-. X : :N00!O« siO«« : US ~ — -5c- SD^C-^N "^t-^ CO ia : « : ■*)• : tc OS »-t : tC ! t- ■£ ° «► | ; ; ; i I*- - _ 2J^S'2 2 3 2 CC i c n^Ho"rtH"oSe :^ opcooooo :■* ■* "^ Jj— . -.•_« *w*ciooaOftin oointfiHAAocoqac] :os qoi&gt;con :^h a 5 -«..«=.£ oqN»o»«e rtn«e-.t-»r.«Hio ;t- -wtoc-ec :in oo »»£°S3 SSiS^"— N ioim"-&lt; •»* -&lt; :V o&lt;n ioo «o • s ** : : j «» - , i t-MAcooiooifl os t- n^^ : *h x w : us x To ici* oiv* ■ &amp;i i ea ii s X S S ! l 2si£!S"'?S"^'° "*d* t ~ ]r * S ; *^ ; °° « oo •* :-hio «| SJIfi ™ -&gt; : |g 3 a,-^ I . _j ■ ; j Ou a^Og 1 I kflt^NinoioiiNO l: i?i oi tt h lt h -n :o^&lt;r^«c o-^^ft* ; o6 ci z^o sSiSl S?.SS§SS!SSS SSSSSSSS !"38S E:gng S f: M 3 E ►•'s - o"o -^ i/5 a; t- » cc x tc "^-"c o o o i 1 o o? -h rs t- cc ** tc t£ ' it - = «2» 2 [ ~r'2°3l2® t^«&gt;ct&gt;c;cjo6io«wio :&gt;o icaiiooc :i» oi wj? ~ | S S C (C t- C 06 i O iC t- CC«iC-.c;i-WC; ~H ~cl u i-tcic - 5^ 2^* e - - - = l °. ""? 3 : C ? 00 . l -'^ c: . e^ t: ! c -9 = ;'^9 :t » ;c ": saSis :?-IS t_ o-a il-Ctfi lOsgcRooxect^oo cooiccffitcioio :oo :oo gjooot^ :o6|6 "*• £ M S*S a O»-5 « U5 i-i -&lt; •» n » :^ -I «-&lt;«« :£ o H « . So S-zBt SS 00 " 5^ 10 " rt " "^ "^ -h : :« cJin rf m" o — . •» : -n z ■« » : : 1 •» O— **" lOiO^t-cceo^^o «ot-NOffiOia oat-o ir^t^ox -o 05 ~E*r •_• 8 "?*"* l =' : i 00 .' 1 :"* -I^^^^^Soo icohS Sn^eS :S x nS" : |s;&gt;S ofj*-»ni; ■Mc-tccr-oo-. m : -w S 3 us e3«Su; ™ x _" ** : : s s xC5jcsfc&gt; ja.n j u. w &amp;b fc. E- « oa _] a. w c Ci xoucaP. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF cooi-h*i»-'*'Cs~*co ccu3"*r-«j"m~©T(M»coo-«i t "«i' Noon^rirc: o osoc-noicoi&gt;-o; oos-h-woocooooscVi — co--.,-. SJ x eo © co 5 ! •* co_inoo-» is co_ oq f~. ac-_NoaH!oo&gt;t-aio!t-N ooiohxh "I 1 1 a ©UJOOt*niOV f 3!MMHU5 1'NW aiHil OS IC CO C* CO t- — n»^MNL1 H n !C — "I 1 X ~H U5 MO 04 OSLO CO ! T CO COT CO lOHNC-a : r- — egio I x ■ c s xos w X *. Vr SNift'0 6-iiO 10 XOC-Os :"80"Oie":««M"N 1 t- t- »i CO "": -T j'ox' ■X 3. - aJj ■*"1S" jioooooaai- Lot^muj :to«coJ i^oeai ■fl'rtoJi' :«« OS CO ■**■ CO t- CO x-h :ascoco i^hoscoic iamom :t~-"i" MS H a. OSOI-H OS-H &gt;i--' ■M vi- gls »»Hflgoo« fcoxosejxoccioxococo comxi-i :os *j lAO-^COOSOSOSX^^^HOscgic *O^fCDC^ :^f w 00r-00_lO SN^N HNN1.N1iN M -H CO 00 CM t- S CO X ~ 8|?*S WO^HlOM^r-tCgX CH*X" &lt;-« 1-" M HsE r: w « 3 ci « » ?: xu A^ lOkCNiflooo^M os to os : OXCOCO-TCO^fO XX-«"»f :0100!1M1MCOI.OCO B3nON -^I 1 hj a) . Sji - 2J * • » bi~S £ CHWOJN31M1 1 OJ -f t- t-CCX ICO M!C^(M : -* S ■ ojooian^^t- -C 55 N X -ft CC 'M Hi ? O^^hX :^J»»-t i-H-^H onn :i-^ X os oo cc »~h : »-^ x : | o(J ■ '-~~?. Vr coocorti&gt;os t-oi cooeqeo ;co-h ococoio coco co^jcoos : t- So co os o i&gt;- x co os o -h o os la : 06 •&lt;* os t^ *«f X iri co loiotoo ■ to t- CO T» Tf -Tf OS CO U5 O) t-COO4X t-BOMrti'nO COCOIMCO "5 OS CC^CO^^LO^CO C^ :*"4^*«-i 04 CO »-ttN y.z *v. 7&gt; fi * I^hoono^io co o o lo 10 w co r- co : X co cm x lo co co : os x xa-iN^-HrfN osoxloloo^coco :osot- xooos i-w S a) £ si— x -*fOc4oiLOt^coo6 oscococ-osos-^co 1 '* :ot&gt;oi ooscO"^ :oi ;;&gt;;;? ooi^nf oox H-t-ioiUHOt-H :oscot- ocoos'f :-&lt; SBjSS COCCCOOOC-C5SO -HNrtNN ■* i-i :!St-n t-SsiS :O ■ j: -* X *» I y. i#iiJliiii|1iliyt|fiili1 "us esf c*3 &lt;c cc t^" 00 U5 l&gt; C-; C&lt;l OS • irt to © o cc : OS : : : itcoiaw :^ : : : «3=P i Et *H CC t- ■* -&lt; «C 00 00 t-NTft- :rt&lt;3J« ioOSLSlfi 31 C- rt S i t- If- oo w : as co co i^hoscoio *a&lt;NOW : t&gt; C = -*_^ t&gt; tji co oj co c- ec as ccouj^oosieooowfflNX ajoojeo :o: o ;;=■;« «o«s---^«cod'» 'j^ixojsjoodwinooococo coirfo6i-&lt; -oiri _ L_l~ M .i2 if Ss"Sl C0INHH i-l Off m </seg>
            <seg id="p081">THE, BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 81 DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES For the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions for the seventeen months' period, July 1, 1913, to Decem- ber 1, 1914. AMOUNT CLASSIFICATION EXPENDED Salaries and wages of commissioners and employees $19,760.23 Salaries of extra help in office of board 566.25 Salaries of extra help outside of office of board 427.32 Professional or expert services 10.00 Premiums on bonds of commissioners 135.00 Postage 725.14 Telephone and telegraph 238.00 Railroad fare _. 590.53 Traveling expense, outside of railroad fare 109.40 Advertising 115.98 Printing, stationery and office supplies 2,503.07 Towel service 14.00 Furniture and equipment 1,448.78 Electrical supplies 115.28 Painting office rooms 124.73 Painting signs on doors 6.00 Hardware (hammer and saw) 2.25 Notary's commission and bond 8.00 Total $26,899.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATISTICAL STATEMENT Showing number of officers ; number of inmates ; total population ; actual cost of maintenance, less salaries and wages ; salaries and wages ; total actual cost of maintenance including salaries and wages ; all other expenditures ; and grand total expended for each month beginning December 1, 1913, and ending November 30, 1914. Monthly average of the foregoing for year December 1, 1913— December 1, 1914. Monthly per capita cost based on inmates for year De - cember 1, 1913 — December 1, 1914. Monthly per capita cost based on total population for year December 1, 1913 — December 1, 1914. Note — (a) Actual maintenance cost excludes all items paid from general repairs, permanent improvements, new buildings and similar appropriations, (b) Average month - ly population of the month preceding the month named is used throughout on account of the fact that payments, in the main, are made for items of indebtedness incurred by and under the population of the month preceding that in which payments are, in fact, made. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">THE BOARD OF COMMISSION] NERS 8:: «aoeo»eoo-H-»ocoo:oo&gt;© co ■C — •§ en .4 to eo !&gt; in 06 -r © to t-^ -&lt; in z - r COt-tOOCO©-*;OectC-*© CI od -*3 J n •* w w 01 ifl « l* a; l* i- C4 JzS. o. en~o*t^'e»'to"'i&gt;t-";of~©Ti4 K i&gt;r eJ co : : in in I n 00 : : CM to : If »* I '. 1 ; ■iO'Jni5osi:si:o x u , : : t^ o oo tt t&gt; 05 «c f; o ■* in SS , i iodooo^'j t^oot^ori -h ic£ : : ■** » co ■» ■* oo oo n ei m -* X £ 2. : ; oo in^to *i c*a w &lt;m eft ■»* co 05 Q« 3 i-H 1-4 oj i-T-h 1/5 in* 00 t- : : in — : -h 10 • -&lt; oi : a co 10 : r- ■• 1" : I 1 ; : •w 1 - I CO 00 00 1-4 to !O ** O) CO O ■&gt;» O US g 1 c M &lt;£ 1 to eft -* 01 -*(i ** .* *h e-i © e» co to — .r-)£ l ~ l c&lt;»aB ai^Htscooouj-^aicooooco co SrtaT 2 '!!* coi&gt;-CM^Haa«ot*c- &lt;^'coe^ 1^ 1 ■Jj O3 2^ N V » ON « « B N O O O CO H_« 5 3-' ofis'wt-rio'io'aj^'Vio'^'t^ to* w , — w &lt;n i-&lt; 1^- ■* S • .r-rr § 5 S| S co os »i .-H IC —■ — CO CO «9&gt; Wfr . ecKisoaNffioaoH t- w I co 06 o to -^i -^ ~* id t&gt; 10 tj« ajctt -H^oooooxooc^aso o C- iO 00 — cs t&gt; © I Tf CO "T -^ — o o o_ V, * ' I w -, CO 00 O to tO 00 IN SO CO N Ifi OS 00 « „ » m J tooostooooo^icnTfooa-. oo to toot--too6ooo'&lt;r^H'^ic4i&gt; od IC-Ot-OO-^OO-^ft^OTXt* tO "3 * * S^ ' ® M . C *. U5 N H K C if N O O) CJ 3g g- &lt;&gt;ooTii K ioooec-fl ; 'co'eJco'ej''^ ; ' n" u&lt;m (Be w- e» &lt; o c a ! « « If » to t-; l&gt; l~ 00 16 Q 00 to m im" tj in — «, 3 s r»OHNOi«coot-t-a-&lt; 10 h£5 co to : : £ ! i •n" 0 ! I i — . : on OCOOOOIMt-O tCCMCOtOCO O • .V N IO to to ■*» ■&gt;» IO ■&gt;* CO CO ■* to to O"*-l£;~ CO Z H E • sit- : i to -o 1 i o « 1- c 3 i i i i I ' n O) : : 01 ■&gt;» : : in i "ii jtfi I I [I ill I ! £3|3S. i »4 4 , CO CO CO CO O IM N CO ■*• CO tD rt CO •5J £ E &gt;&gt;?i 4« 10 to o m to m Tf tii tt ■fluo a 1 z2j«!.» r. : !!!!!!! i 00 8 1 1 1 ! 1 1 ! I ! ! ! I i &gt;- i i i i : : i i !♦ ! i : : -w : : ; : : ;rt ;■* -a co^,^::;;::^!:!"* ; rt»ne» : : : : : ■* i-h ■"»! e» : Gaos»HTj4 ; : ; :^h 1-41-4 •-; ™ *Hr4 i-4-*:Tf:aj eft r- «Oi -H Tji -* tji jT^h » "tT ■S j..&gt;.-4O&gt;-oj S £ J;£ I * Ulliwilill Hiijj </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF •! i ■i c o 3S CC OS 00 C- CC O CC t- OI N I ■W — -S oaosin.-« wccoio t^Nood «h3j «s_t&gt; ■» o t- us os ia to t- ■»* © OH x -h : ; : : : : :iot-040« S^ K i ioococs — os •»•::: i ! i , -a 1 a, I O&gt;fflO5 W t- tDO»0»t-C-0S "*• g 1 C M 5 I »«OO00N» tCOVOllO^ -.r^H"™ 6 '* 6 ' osoiia-^toccotcccNtoo M 86^^aar c *n°* oi^^-oi^aooino^!C H &lt; S « Z ; » X C C l: i -c C - - C &gt; t'OS «»hOMOh»OHOh o 1-3 5i J tt S OOXNOOSl- :00«05« O tJ'S»'»'5f ffJoiooogNOcc nmhr O U .E — -r * or-ax-xoo »o&gt;- ■* &lt;; O c 5 J •&lt; -- 1 _ qo 10 -^ ao © os x &lt;c 00 c- ao c* Qx 1- o r: — t- 1- rt -t i- rt , £ ooxx x ac x xxx x x ci w — ! «ii »■ c ' w ec ■* 10 t ■*■ » « M eo co t* 1 ! «0 s " u ■;;::::::::: , 2J2 I I I l| jgjd 5 !2S2^ I i ; :2-22 .as 'H tji ■» -w •« .-,* . *3 fc- „ &gt;.^h as 5 fc« Qp-,Pi,S&lt;E^^&lt;i»o!5 Bteoioot-co-efiNN i cc © : i|accao«^c44^NH | &lt;© cc r. 3iL:-ir-du:^^ixc t. oo 3s as ■■* os o c- os iO as as r— —. : p^t- ■» o t- 10 as ia to t- ■«■ o t- oc t)Gie}eieiT*~*r*ar*miB oo V : : : : : : :ior-©ioco o 10 : ; : ; : :io^io«c-» &lt;c 10 : :o6«0»thos n cc : : : : : : : :t-«CTrooiN o oc ;::::: : as ■*• os cc cj &lt;c r* »— I CC » ; : : i : i ssfflos oo c- to © to as t- c-as cc i io &gt;o ■; i;as©©a0(NT!"cco5os4o=e ® ! = . ' 3s as la -h co cc ©' «c cc e4 to © t- -^ sc c 3S«— t^"OS^*OS©OSCC©»-«CO t- t-t 1 •t^t^-v ©t-icasioo«iecLCi&gt; io n ?i ei eS ?S eS ** r* m~*cScS to ei S2S§ggSI§2§i§ g § g ! sdes^N«««dfl^ to in t^ « os ■*»« © cc © ** as © © w* *p — . acx«oxc&gt;s«&lt;o«o cc «c "• l» • ncwooNov . cc i-i »-i as -sj* ic ic l XOCNOOei- :00CCOS&lt;C CC LO OC C 2Jo:qcinin©cc :&lt;Ne4'&lt;cc © ej oc &lt; © r- os oo -h os oo :ccos — Tf cc © « , •~t©..c-^'**.'"iOs c^ to^cc a: h ci to eJcJ-H^Jei [m 'H'ei oi" •» » •» xio^xcaix!cscc-nt&gt; x oo asaso'. as©csasasososas© c- os IO W © CC &lt;O LC LC CC &lt;O -^T IO CO C- IO 00XKOCX0C OOOOX OOOCOS rt 00 o « ec ■* us ■» -^ cc cc N cc cc Tf »h co : i-( ~* 5C i-&lt; I I ! I S'i ! 1 I !~i i I if iii I i I i i I I i ! I = s i s =. : ; : : : : c -3 Oj -3 &amp; 1^^22,-1,1 - illpllllll nil to t-OiOCO o IS isviste ■*» to 10 o6cooi-*oi si pi t-tC"*0OIN O 00 OS ■*• A CC W CD </seg>
            <seg id="p085">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 85 ■O t&gt; U5 ■"«; CO N CM ■"* N IO &lt;-&lt; IN IN I •o_.£ tt 06 «■ o tc o «c ej pi -^ -h t~ C^« ? OOTfTf IO &lt;C OS rt t- 00 00 t- rt a .3 5 2 -3 ,,. : :©'»ioc't~;©«oo't©«e' *cS : : co cc -&lt; -« co © cm co oo r J J : : ■»» sc » ecus OS t- ■** t- -h '-'CD : !»J ~h -J = X *» 1O rt 00 00 OS O — c- 00 |W = I a i i ** ., lONiawoiOKCcont-c- DO , C m qj IO OS -&lt;T O O^ t&gt; 00 W OS »H _ r x c M 6i« 6« ■«ro6ioii:odo6io^HioT»-j 5 3 1) C T * »^rtrtiS»C-!D!eflOCC — ™ tj-- £ &gt; ■^'S.os o-. c-^-wt-oosecc© i2 5^ c 3"T eJcTt-'t^'odaj^H'sO'f'io't^'.-S" e j in CO OS CO •-&gt; © ■« s" t s — ■ s — « — iQQtcmxaoaoooM^ 1 - r , nCtOCOOAOCCA^MC 4&gt; k i&gt; cc oo co tt n o os id tc ■* ■*»• J c (( «C_0_05M_CS_C_0_CC_«C^^H_-H_ I C4 IN CO IO © t-^ • t 00 »" IN" — 0 ' X Z &lt; ■j ij S &lt;;iooiovo»reo&gt;»t-H *3 '5 a* 5^ -h os^o^co^c-^-^cc ■^lo^co^ea oo^ "g^- ? cTt^ioio'sJWoJ^'efM'io'oo' &lt;; o c a ■V © *■ °5 00 CO c- e-i W «o" i « g H z r° o ■•-&gt; C4 '- C- © ©_ IO to" a H 3 5 x M 00 « -f -&lt; CC « OS 00 © .-1 1O O ■ , » SC 00 00 00 tO »H 00 OS OS IN ■* IN 21 -E CO 00 in co U5 &lt; •si I - »• _, ' I CCCOOSlCNC- t-00©IN WC- •q £ E &gt;»« t-C- W» XtCtC tOC- t- tC» CS 00 il It if ill i IJJJI J : 1 4 :- i 2 I ! 1 1 ii I (i j ii »a os-*os : : : : :^&gt;-c»os hhh^ : : : : *-t hh ™ a h« : : :o&gt; « _ .-&lt; OS-HTlf«"^"^1 1,'H • T3 - *Z*-i os i~t i-t «, Jp - Iliilsi-tllll ! ii ii 5 S.! I! SI 8 1 fi s I - - &gt;-. tjB u 5 HI {8. i ti i ■ Hlf| § « c « c «.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 oi in — • S — 7M ■w i-w 1 I1J 5 C : S 5. : E '5. a '5^- : &amp;*§»§ j f1J«J FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF I 00 &lt;3&gt; t- IM -H CM 00 t- CJ IS to ■* *4 N ~0 0»t&gt;^|001lOt»t^H(OX -* •C_i t&gt; r- t~ t&gt; co © t- oo © oi oo oi © c a ;- "0 1 t- gg Z § M .°. a .t N f O Cfl O N CO ■&gt;» 00 .^cS O. CJ (N't-* oor-"u5r-^ 'fee" to" uJV ■*■ t-^ a **■ jj. •* I t — -^is :o :oh : i- x - i : : 00 t&gt; : l&gt; : oa ! &lt;o S^ _. : :cit^ioe4 :ej iejto : oo o icS ! t-oaov :»5 :cm« : t « m =^3 ! j* i i - i • £ A j -J__i_ 5 i c oo « ® * °; ™ °i ■* "?^^ t ~: |^: t '? °i ■* S _oS""**« 6 ' t&gt;t^»oc^o6i&gt;!©o«d-He&gt;i eo oi oaS^Si «ONnoo^o»oenn eo 2 e-3^5^5, aaSS2252S235 S 5 o &lt; -2 « •* o 2 oo N -h ao -h cm to 10 -h ec o oo eo ■«• J Jj k ooid os ci a c ** t-^to k «o^sc_io_co_»_io_tc_t^t- to o&gt; S i * * • * • 5 +■• , m ooeoscoot-oooo^tcmt-o co © 5 i ij , • as ■&lt;!; oo Tf o rt a; io us ■« to oo os o W 'i'5o&lt;»'¥ oJt^iNeot^ootocvioiidcotD co r-^ S "^'7" !B NOOH^MIfiVNtCOO 00 "" -'jj j, jj^ '-j k -^to pk t&gt; i c^oo^'^eo &gt; i^» to to cm to 5s J- t-'to'aTrt'rt'oj'-Joo't-'oJ'od'oo' es 1 p« O OVH «W C «■ -I t» Z — i _ or-ioM^ooion^ot- eo -h *3S «*«ioie!D(oe^r-oot- eoto ■£ CD NMO^OOOOBOOX'J -* t- _ , S »»a»OOOHNMNN 00 O H Z °.-i g rt^^rn^rtrt W-H&gt;-Crtr-C CO -H O J, . J, i Oi 00 -^ IO OJ Oi CO -^ "^ CO Oi Tf * ' I28«li 5 " § I Illlllllllll It * U I i eo : : : : : ** : | B J - — - - : : : :rt rtrt : X *Hf-i^ : : : oi ca "3 «^* 35 -^ -^ -^i «» a. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 87 ■*r os oo -* — cm ec &lt;m oo oo c- ■"f h|(. : i TJ OS t-; &lt;*&gt; t- OC 00 © 00 05 ■"» I?; OS OS t- : •O_pS co us c- o oi oi co oo f us ** oo os us : c"a 1: »-i «0 us i-i os us t- t cc ■f i-i t- oo so : eg .*-» 5J ©^©^ os_co co co ©_ us^ -^ : Jzfi o. od t-" us in i-T to* tc* to* to" to to us" as* c^ : UP 1 X "- 1 "- 1 00 ■_J L_ f : iohihismoxiohh o t, , : :oioa«HiOr&lt;M«n »&lt; oo | 2'xi,, : los^HOseoto^HOs^t-t* -^ t- • JCcS : :H»««^onioieo os io : O« 3 : us" oi" ~- I |_ : i " ' C M« OS l&gt; N &lt;N OS -fl; 00 CO 00 N 00 tO M Igs « O r 9 c M bt» &amp;( cous^oswoseot^oo^HcotH us t&gt;^ o us oj^'SaTC-roB -HtD-^t^uswusij'Osos'^'c* os o os ea .3-*S=5i&gt; Tfooqcq^HOM-uos. » n i^aS^'a oot-^ic«o-^u5u:in-*«« os us ■ m »-fl|o;osecco t&gt;Oieoeo«5 00 a h « a&gt; m t&gt; co tt oi o W cc «i oi cc o x T*O aj 5C t— i-H 5 c be t^t^c-^c^t- 1- c^t- oo oo c- x c*4 t&gt; ! f i - -J -" i *» _ *«^eooeNff.K«t-t- oo 10 o * • OS CO CO IN U5 rH -. CC -flj 00 i-» ■* CO OS N « U°"tiaja»ot «CNOsTfodotocJc^ost-cJ *J us o C— -r-CB COO^-H^tONOlOlCintD CO CO N — * ■-';,;&gt; tOrtlN03CO_tO-fl"05T)&gt;COI^_-&lt; ■«■ US^ 35 u ■— "^ to to* «"«"■* e&gt;f co"co"co"(n'-h"cJ of eo* u&lt;4-i &lt;Klc » m- &lt;» &lt; o c a &lt; 5 I Q z — . — i _ OOOCC^lO^N^-Hrt^C CO N aaS oo « os os o w oi n in co co -v ■«■ »h : : ♦? P»° H«riHNM51NNei«N US N : h£5 3 i to csr-iNcoosus tr coeooo oo os us : i , v ■» us to to to c- oo oo oo os os os o t- : O •*-( -1, -*T i_|i-4i-4i_|i-Hi-4 T _ti-«*-Hi— lr- li-l i-l w-t '. '. Z °n g IN i _ i , -h i-i -h i-h to os oo oo oo rt ■&gt;» cm ot-: : ■i;™E&gt;&gt;g co os co eo eo os co cc co -&lt;)i Tf •&gt;» tt eo ; *otC^ °* i : I 1 1 . . . . TTtT \ I j 1 1 1 M j ! |j i !&lt; ifiji S I j i N I ; ; I ! ; ! i -£3138. | •o S !J j ; ! M :SJ3 ; igggl | ostii^i : : : : : •* ** "* os : °£ u q " OSrt^Tli :^i ;O s » _ »J J ; | ES5f_- - li^i -5$f? = </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF *O OJWCOlO^*S£iaiOSCCIf5u3l«0 05 : ■c_.2 t^t-^?iiNOrFi&gt;oioiffla6c» © co : c"3^ eHiaaonaoORiSHOo -* us : 09 2 £ «&lt;0»8!»mNNfOX'H : o£ g. ---------- «- s -- ill MMMMMMi M \ — X ■« :::::::::::: : : : : &lt;K ; | ; i : : : : : : j •»■:::::::::::••••»- ; : "^ w n CO •«* O 00 00 C— CC OJ C- iO IO U5 t^ C: -T *O s^ KiC x 33 NHMiaHaiaincMioic v ec o» ] In r^C'—'&amp;CgjCJC t"-t-C^NO &lt;^'t*OU3li3o605 'o CC 00 00 «, . a^'SoTC-r' 8 w-Hiooic?:3ixnio«» 10 10 eo 2; &lt; 3 * OHnAXiAnc^iAt^xc: o 10 c- o r* x ONID^^Ht-HOtliOH 00 ® a OJ W eu K ■^o»to-HrteJrimo6eJio-&lt; oi-n o co Z E^f xsxaxKsxiaxe &lt;n ~* r; ac" BsswoK^^^fff ie o &gt;o H «J «■ . •» » M I c/T .*-» m nnciaoN-i | iA«xt«?i c* -^ c- ta ~ ' &lt; i'£««&gt;5f cct^iooooiNeot^t^Mrioo o pi oo &gt;o _] ""'5«Je3^ ONftOHJJBt-SSiOSie •* O5 g 1211-s ;r JJ " s* OS &lt; o c s 00 — . . _ w*«C'&lt;'fl 1 '«''-N00-«"*ec •"I'oo S nil II Q r S O"OT0C— -H00C»in-H&lt;-"O»iO : : (h ! ■ ' S i «i n A ' CO CO CO CC CO « CO CO CC CC CO CC !O CO I I i2j-ii a a i aa o*^* j i j i i Si 1 1 1 Mi] if ifl i ill ! J8 :8= : I 1 1 1 1 i j il i i.-si.-s8.| 1 S^S ! ! i : i^2^S i -fSS ! — — — -!■— — ■ « - - - - - — I J iiiiiiiill IB" </seg>
            <seg id="p089">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 89 CO A ■*&gt;• iS •** -H OS CO © iC&gt; — &lt; *H 100 "U CO l&gt; OS -^J OS V CM iO CO 00 OS © I N •v_£ os co oo os co oi oo oo &gt;o oi -h oi I oo c~Z^ cm ce oo co -* c- ia m &lt;m © © us cm a -3 £ »(-nofflt-oN-HH»us ©_ t,° D, os*Hio'r-"V-H"as©"eM~c*os"co~ ce" | CO _ , ioifinc4^oioaiat^iao o • S _ oi t^ us oi oo oi oi oo o&gt; co cc v co X « !. cc ia B » » « * « » a o a eo. ° D.3 tco*co"&lt;N*io«'to »* J T Iff* «* ■ ., FHaoccooaan^usioa m 00 , C — S N CC N l&gt; iO l&gt; CD l&gt; CO OS OJ ..^^c^cicajbt otccc'c'indiooiiecpiooj &lt;n &lt; u '3drcr« iot-«ooH&lt;iN»ot-e co .3— ■ 5~ 2&gt; w-Hiewonio^-Ht-t-io cc in oc CM M &lt;6 CM a CO p OS I-' s O t~ t~ CO »"^ lO O O ifl 00 i K n o t- cp oo ■«■ t-; co o oo ■* co i&gt; oi w co-^cpNcoco^ooi^iooi -&gt;f 5 c cc o o_o a a a a_o « q o_a^ ©_ — oa * ■^'-T'f re* rf«co"W"» i"" ■»»"«" oo CO &gt; *&gt; » £ «■ I »^ « jj xNxcaHCMc^nato »o r 9*^oja&gt;bc cee*jtoc-^^-TfoscDwoico t- • UC — .-OS rtTO0CC«CC--H(N©U3-HTf — . 3 S ~ "a eZt^t^oiatcaZiat^iB^aS co" &lt;; o c a mm t _, lO C* X OS CO CO (N CO t- CM 00 CM IC 3 35 t-t-ooxaacOHN-"N © Q..2 t-t-t-C-C-C-OOOOTOOCOOOO CO h£S » t- OS 00 CO «H -&lt; t- CO -fl 1 © 00 CO t- . * CO CC C~ 00 OS OS OS OS © ~H © i-l © O«M^-JJ iOCCCCCCCCCC«CCC-t-t-t- CO^ 1 Z °— g oo" ii i 0000© CO IO &gt;O IO C- CO CM © OS 00 •S £ E &gt;»? ©©-*© ©o©o«-&lt;rt© os CM t-H OC e SB M O Sfr c I &lt; go as x H Z I ■ I i I i I i 1 1 i i 1 1 I s I I I I I I I I I j I j I «i :•♦ : :■* :■» -a h^-h : : : : : ;*4 : «h : os-hos : : : :-wos-»os 5 rtOS-H^r : : : inHiin ™ w «■* :■* :o» _o» "3 if ifi ! </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF •o so i&gt; &lt;-; &lt;■&lt;* co oo t-^ © ©^toio -*; r&gt; : c "at eowNWfliQocccMN^ 1^ 1 ic © : : « -3 £ NNNX^aoto t-^c^f-^:o_oo_ co^ co_ : *-_9 p, cc" co"ec~ *&lt;fa&gt;aDtt&lt;z&gt; ia «?" : w •* ** ** : lososao — ccc-oous-»ec t- : i&gt; ' ■ °i ■"! ■* m . °? T °9 °i °9 *i I 4) » ■ ■ -^ ic ?c cc cc -^ -^ ao u; *h os oi : J=?5 : :hh«soi&lt;«in«» n us : Xv ii '■ N rt °° " •* oo us n -1 °o «o. i 3 a. 3 ~*iBia t&gt; ~ e* — x — ' &lt;-&lt; K : : W : &lt;j i _ I «c os to us t- -&lt; to in as ai eo ao I to us n w ' c n « ' *R °^ °i °? "? °? °^ "? °^ *? "^ °J * * ■*- « w '5 o CT ■ «neont-n«»»ooo in us cc in | Pl^l - * * W OiOOlt-iflt-OS^OOiHiOiH j D- OS O 25 OC CC t^ U3 00 «C OS W O 00 CO Cl I lO CC W^ t- a&gt; » ; us oS T-n « Nt^HnujTfio^t-iawia oo *-• 2 5c^ -«»'cc^f^ i r:rccc^i | -^ t^'0"^'!o: 0 w |S, 3 *&gt; _ «c •* t- oo in ■*■ c- -h -h « ao r- co os « ' « i S »• CO O IN US IN U3 5O Ol t^ OS IN t&gt;; tO 00 O O3 - 1 n - • • " oo'osejoo'fl'usidccost^us in tt&gt; oi us *2 we — --a ouso-. c-xoit--*ooeoteiN ■* cc in -h «? "m'S 0) Sfe oooo,use&gt;i_o«ooq»e»i&gt; i e»oi oo_ in_ g ! iSs^-s * Si o Z. — i _ co to : : 33 M3S us co ■&gt;* ■«• ■«"^ 1 « cc us to us us ■* : Q - '- H a us o us co as cc ■« in os t- n us o t- : : • , « oasosoosososooooosoo to os : | *°~! rt " rtrt =■ ! | 01 I «i _ i. i os os os cc to t- -h cc o ■&gt;» oj o n a : : :::::::::::: : : m ■ k* '■ k ! : ! i • • • : i i i iJ^i^o.: s I i I i I i I j i j j I Issaa i * °i iJ ! i i i i IS i*i iS-gih ; ' r* a r* ■*:::: i-i r«i-i : &gt;«..S I _-S: m o to « »&gt; _ ' i aa(ii«ist-Hno^NO </seg>
            <seg id="p091">y I eooo^fOf «eo*e I to r* : : •^ _ -S to t- ■«* oi us ui os c- © © eo i© © to r tt5 a. to-voeiwfaS »h" o : •"A °! 1 *? ■"! °^ *"' P. °? "^ * "? ** "* HtoeQOSt^XFHH&amp;irHOOtO 00 o : r {£ C^."*.' H . O ?. C ~ "I"-* °° o . c ' oo &lt;o. •* n is'Ve^iaK'ofec'M'Vi-r h of n &lt;H ** e» «■ : 1 ! j : ** ' * |«^WNOlNOt-OTfOJN 00 r* « Ob '* Bl » CT * C-hhcChOmOINOiOH CQ »-» &lt;N '-I H ' - &lt;oaaccccixwNxi&gt;'&lt;) 1 i oo a x w a0»»00wNNON*«H» l&gt; OS N 5 * ;s » *j , » o io io a « m «Tf wtoiMoo •» os oo ee jijjjj o i&gt; t~ « tc Tf us eo co ■* to ■* t- »h us C , — c8 CD'fl'OSC^CC'Ti-IOOXCO^lO "^ C- »-l - J (,*]&gt; o_ooo»o«nocciooa co eo 35 J- es"t--'*r-'&lt;I'Locf«c'in'(N''oi'tt&gt;"so" co 10 ov. den c » *» *fr &lt; o c a 4 3 r ooc-cftooososoxooooos t- os •g O.S coeoco'fl'-fl'cccoeococoeoeo «o_ eo 10 atCOlOMCMlCMMMffi O OS i * ,5 COCOU5U5CD«DU5C0 1^ #&lt; «1«10»0 OS "** : O'w g^J COCOCOCOCOCOCOCOCOCOCOCO CO MINI ! j 8 \°i\ Hart* : : : :h »h^h : h k .is . «S : ™ .-i i-i-^f : : :os os s SS _e . .os .1 -w -h .-.-1 . O.S.C S.C : 5 ■- kT,-h OS -&lt; th r-i 5 J; -g "o : s IIIllfi#iflI Ipili </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 ! &lt; 3 x H z M 3 -T 5 a p; c &lt; 5 w Q Z K m oofej FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF octcioo»^(M»doiac-u5 i &lt;n ■» .: "O — •§ c-^h os w eo ** os co u5 *!• co © oj us = s s OHMiaDooaiLaooiOif J* -r a 3 5 &gt;ec»_toooco_x_ao(N -&lt; -^asr- 10 o r t[S a ririaiwtri^rinrfri^ri •&amp; IN* X &lt;N : H •* w- w- : :n — n c n 1- tic x cm ■» to ; k • ; icoiNeo^jiooie^N^ia © in St; K ;:--JNeoi&gt;N-*a6aiweq t~t-^ I g££ ::o -H00^N»t-iN : 2g-3 !•» •* - « » : ! 2 -S i 00 50 to 2; ai ■»! ■» o ci -* o 05 cc 100 00 ao ei * 2 1 c w a, «o 04 o in in -h 00 00 as rt ■» eg t&gt; oj o S! S Oll^^ &gt;O O&gt; IO « &lt;N t- © 00 00 t- (N ■« © « 2 &lt; Ji en q" 55 H ** w *° t" ~ 05 as x cc © ao co bo os c- co ■* as iq wh w © -^j cc t&gt; © 10 Tf x o -St,! SS?2S2gg?i^2ai2 2S » Cb « c =r w "* " "* " w co ■»* Tii co -^ x »* 9 K ■ _ « oiOrtt-at-fooio-&lt;iHO x © us ao g SiiS" 0 ' «&gt;INt&gt;00INlO®»00»-llO tC S O ' Off""!? O) «O -H Tf c&lt;0 lij rt «j OS CO 00 IN « S ni Id i; .S~'C S U5t-ioco-o i co©»too©'&lt;i" p~ 5! i; Ij aS •« 3 «* 5 -1"* ■* °° COt--»-*C0X© NOS OS i_ ( H : 1 _ CO CO -^ X IO © OS Ii3 CO IC U3 U3 ia CO W 3 3 o o»©oaxxxt-c-c-c-E-S oa x i — I &lt;MQor&gt;' asoscD©osasasasa:©as© x as I { :::::••:•• i : *r |*r,i | :::::::::::: : o : o^ : 5 I I ! ! ! I i I ! ! j ij 0 ; 0 *; i i^iff :-i:-f I fty i s IllililtlJll |ppi a **n </seg>
            <seg id="p093">&lt; O C 09 — , -M -h %D X 5O Oi *-• ■** CC t- OS kO sag &lt; X oicceo'f -r O ■*&gt; E-SuS 00 InMNNCNr- t^ « c 'S — s c a B z &lt; OS COCO © OS^OS'-*^^ 00 as 01 "^ w t- -^"* ?o » » &lt;m t&gt; «c : 00 £ jd 1 1| || |s H ! ifs'll i sal ■fl| O IO I&gt; t-; N t&gt; t&gt; 00 CO O « I C-; 00 oi t^ c4 oo o (&gt;i ai i&gt; c^i ei c6 oi i ui 00 MionoiNnciHNHoao &lt; -^ &amp;J o t^ co o^ os c^«^ co^o^o^ cc^«o^ ; t^ o^ mcSeSc£cSefei**meS&lt;B*B 06" eo* _ 111 — X-«-&gt; : : o» 10 co a; ■* « ■-&lt; ■&gt;» o us o «o i ! 10 oo 10 «o us &lt;o oi &lt;-i co c&gt; oi c^ : :c» ot-rtioo^»o fH w n iee»ioto_ e&gt;i 1- CO CO A *6- ! •" ' OS I 5 &gt; c m »&gt; ' _ &lt;? c - be w be i^l in* I «e ■*&gt; o ■«•■*' o&gt; © »o *o *e 00 10 »|^ I ■»); o co eJ ■« o; co ■&gt;» «o 00 0; » w I ac-t*dioia^HodoiH « cm ia co N in ia 00 to c^ r~ m 00 co &lt;o co*oi'5jeJeJ?JiN''^ffi-&lt;rj&lt;N* oT cm" cm © M 53 I- 0 a c ¥ — — -- I ■ OJNMHflSOOOOiOiflO •* C" -r r: r 1; ■* 10 »c 10 10 ic oc c -^ co ifl t- iO CO «0 SO 00 iM W (D iO lO -^ SO cocococococococccoi.'-tocD oa_ » id o t- H z EC SjJjJ "£v- SCO c t-Nt"Ml0010iO«CO«»0 C»l f* Ol f- OS X Oi t- X &lt;3l t* CC i-J CO (N t-; 06 cc o us t- to q6 o 10 1-* o 10 u5 ao t-OOOCiOOOOO^^OlOON X Cl « o x in a^^o^aa x^c^^-^ i^ t^ 8 — « 00 OS </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF i x ■* I ■» - r C4 «» •» M CC 00 tc oo CM SC M N 6t » NiCSiKOlOOiOXNSnK eo^ejoiaiotoeatc^^io t^ioas^c^wioccosoocst- ML0X(0XaNC0-i&lt;ICO10 t^CCU5N^HU5C\JCC00Oli5Ut eJiN'eJiNcJ-H'oJ— " — 'sfeJ t- 00 O r1.s4^si c- mm* &lt; 2 « 1O IN IN O ■W IN v= •»• ! »» Okj;]^t-iOQ09U3IOO t- X 91 K S C M &lt; 2 «1 •* m OS fc -1 v. IN US'* 1 cciciaaoc i o § i S « P. i- x x x r! t - ■2 E -IS-s* 3^s^ 5 s tSv, «W c w. &lt;«- I •» e &lt;; o c » J o ? I "3 3 C - z -J oowxooxoooow t-t~ r- ia 55 e t- H - eel 2^ ■s. SUNN-OCM : : .»« sis « ■SiC £ E- r-t-t-^^xoo»aoi!eto c^i n n w w e^ cj c^i « rr ih n c 4 °O £ w o £ C- IN I | m E c X Cl3^ NISf "ISINIOCOMISUJM eg 3 | c-^» ©_« e^«e^»ic_oo c- tc^ *&gt; ' : : °? °i T °. °. °J °9 °9 x £ c : :■» &lt;N«o«et-eq &lt; w 3S » Ed 55 _ . IT ■J. i H &gt;. 3 B " i« j CO^OSIO — O-. O 00 00 00 IQ IO I \ j j ) I I; j ! j j j i I \i\ii I j I I I I I jj I I ! c3£3S. Tf : : : : : : o» : »h C SE?3 o» — o» : : : :-*rt-wa °c°o rtftHf : : : :»h iHih : t&lt; t. *S . — » -* :t» :o» o&gt; -3 J S isi-g- -„- -li-s i -5 %-5% </seg>
            <seg id="p095">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 95 c-N^Ht-omf^'C^'i- '*c cm : "C ""* t&gt; CD l&gt; v* IC tO © 00 CM 00 | N \G c73^ ■« tj eo cm « co -&lt; co eo to -h o • *• £ *1 t "V lo .. e ''.. o l e i 5C .. c -. e i.' c . '"i a l "^ *• ,*;£ a, ioto*t-*coinie'oocc totc't^-H" od x US" 1 x '-i h e» I *h to o r- ss *r w m as oo 04 cm co c- : S'S „ OWIOCOOJ"* «JOOJ3ST»rt N t&gt; icS IOt-»Xt-OI!OOHfl(OM IO« : -£ o*&gt;- tooH^HMN ec_o^oo eq_io^-^ tc_ »h W _ g-^3 -n'r^Tf' CO" i-T I &lt; &lt; w «■ S- •» X ; : a *&gt; i M I «ot-tc»ootOcvjaiiaNiNU5 M ie — © Z S' c o»«'*1 e J lc . C 5 e ?°? o ? c t l '? o 5 l&lt; ? e i e i a ! T *) _ r °5""tt«j6l 05'^OlCt- : '»0'Hoi50»CO IN &gt;-&lt; «O ■* ,: c8^ - 3aT c 'C ! ' •^ 1 «500iO'fl'Xt-^rt»o»cR tc c- — i — * ''•oSS BiaOHlS«N^^««^i CO O £ tot^co'O'to^oe". us «4 I or « c&gt;i » Z M tc-^t-j-fljt^ia^isooasr-t-icr cm 05 x c-^ t-^ *h co 05 "^ o c*i us cc 3^ co ' ift oi ic T X"O^ t^^'TfX'^t^CO^^OOCOCOCOiOO CO OS _ I _ I j oi jm» 10 »h 00 «; » co 00 oi t&gt; co f; ic » e « 00 Z rj-5«i«oc •Hi~ooHi~:oioa&gt;rio'riai «c oj o x E~~*£ea t-^HCOt-Ni-t^l'OiCOCJ-^Cvl C* X 1-1 ~*'3 4* S^ t^or^-^^x co us en c- 1* c^op^ ?e co_ jr &lt; . - O»Tft0 00Oi0t-«lNN &lt; * OS 00 : « OIMOQCOOOCOOOOh t*Oi : 5 ! Hj£3 ~ , « CM &gt;-" IN Ol CM CO CO CO CO CO CO ** t- » I at " , i I -~ a»o»©etf»-iiQt-cceftc»c-x ■*!- : * ' -!!?l2c&gt;.tn to «O I- 5O «O 5O «D » 5O «C «O 5O O to : , : iO.Ho! X : j s MiMiiiiN! I if !&lt;i I § % M M M M M M N 8 i s |i ' s illit|i-jl|S Hlpl </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF I X -r — n •y s 1-1 X c X n eg v? * a jL..J8 Oi'fointyosFHtc^oiCTO e.^,N ~*_o_io oo ion oo m se o^ »c" irT m" &amp; -&amp; if n t-h" fh c^f -T* A « «.5 E^ mm T OC 6t ■M l°r"l w ■ X t- 73 00 t- O !J 3 . lT3 &amp; I «■ 1 » •» ■S , „ x 1 &gt;-&lt; «e 00 «d oj o ■«• tc ■&lt;» Os Oi tc -h o cc o i m « « jsNN^^mNoiiac-iio t- » -j or « « 5f , cc o» n 06 w -h «&gt; -h -- » t^ cc in -r M x M c B 1 B ■- I BO X S &lt; £ X ■Jl &lt; X a w 2 Tf CS IT? C4 Oi CJ O (C M IC W C- ' O5 -T t&gt; IO W ?C lO CD 00 -H C- OS | O5C(CCCNifl00tO^HWN O^"«1"_ Tf p4 0,00 NlOOftH : :ic 10 © ■&gt;i' 10 10 10 m a&gt; &lt;n *■ i I | «&gt; o» "? «o to © « in to tc &lt; ■si &lt; H z .2 8 Noosowcoicoaoodcaolo © .5 """ T a lNt-at-»t--&lt;ffi tec h oo cc ls ct t&gt; g&gt; |iaootcic-*a5mc~ise&lt;i.HO eg rj W3S HHrtrtHrtOCCHHOOO "^ «O 1 •sCCCCCSOCOCOlO COW CD 6 xze±* §§§§§§§8223$; s § '■ i :::!■■!■••■• ■ :« :^i : :::::::::• : : : '■ m ■ rc " i u | i ] ; j : : | j ; i j I :0; °o, : I E ! M M II ij I i l a I gJs j js \i i Iggga ! 5 2S2^ | i i i3"22 fcllfi </seg>
            <seg id="p097">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 97 &lt; &lt; M BQ H 7. z u z u Q — — ■ w ■o_.S! '. to t-^ to ■* eo ci ■«# \ r-i o : c^^ «ct-ia&gt;occoooo5C«c : i e?, : -°.S ::;:::: : : : : %% k jl • i ; ; ; ; ; ; ; ; ; a &gt; ill |i o&amp;$ \ ; i i : i I I ! I ;•» — •*** : o S *i i -.iiotOMNOXO ■"*!« os r-«wt- oo, c b SI&lt;ci&gt;o«mho "O *! offc ot^cc^ccoi-^r »-h o o t- t,c ojc^csccoscciic x o "^ -^5 B :oot-oe»io |oc •» n so _* K :O^e00Jl0» |O 00 00 t~- 75 &gt;• t^J iiaisifiooxr- ' i-i n .- — 5c" :^^«M«« he » t; 3"^ I:. ij «j _ iioosojccr-ost- e&gt; I te as n c£ g;» « ;5CO0NcctCrtTi| ■*!(-; n e §k w c — •- « oMoe^oo m tt « e-i a = SS75^ J — - « - -I &lt; o c s - *^ , 2 c — i_ I :CKNlOriOe -Wit- i :•— ° Sag «"*U5U5tC5C I in :"Se8 £ °*5 i *• « : o g » ;n&gt;4iaoeiN r- i w ; ■ ■Son 6-w ' " ; « ■• ■* us io w o,^5 | | iJ^ z°^i ! :^ .-#»[] "Mi] » JliS ill i j Jijl lt|li [i| 1 Mi m if n U - p H 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF j. \t? c E u «1 ? I t!!P » ■ it f. i I X I i ■/ I U X -T O«H CO t~ OS OS OS CO SO T eg O O O n 3-. — — ©t- ioos-»t- egeg t- eg I os CO t- OS f eg — O t- SOB IKOJ Hl!'ii-'.» J"»d •i|i:mn| A'|i|HMK t- -^ IO ■« VIOIO XSC !M 00 IO CO — eg .— « 1 OINtt Xi-OCO ■~ Cg IO -*! 1 OS »t- V a. M t-ffj — — CO KdSH.li I"IU s..|Ji:|i:s A*iqjiKt|v *«J**V egx e- — us 5 M — XSO t-oo H-coe SO — SO t-iO© . ■- S » 5 3 8 u MlO -r — IN -him eg ir- ?i %* u E h -T T e -f OiCM-* "2? 1 CO CO CO 00 00 C- HOI L J." 1 1 u. '■■•&gt;l| too o-. CO Cft T ■■I* IO "^ -* -»r ?3 (M CIS 1MOO OSC^XOS &lt;M -H OOOO I" ofeJ 11 eJ i-T t* ec t» riS» CO Cft -^ C- t. M 5C N — (M -HCO IM- M CO ii x i- X meq t- 00 1OTJ NB00IO X-&lt; CM -"CO I OS CO X IO C o I O »»».&gt; CO CON to oo CO1OCMC- £ o S IQQD *T O Cft — —Sin © CIMln.) 4rf,I tio||«|ll -doa i»joi AimuoK 10 cri tOMOl U3MHN — . -1 M K «• T L- .-; O t* CO tC COlO^f 5O OS CO "- OS I CO 00— Tf MCO T» l*: co }»oj mulB.) Ud Jiomui A|i|iuoiv MO -fl 1 OH»» 00 t» 6 6066 t^ d •» ~^eg eo — — h^n io z. cotacviio egco — eg — — ■ ■m » T. ■M I - ■.•; \a CO -T IB i«OC a«o *a ir eg OS C- -h hSsm pn i- eg — 1~ IO — X OcOX CO*A— COC-COOS OSX USJh^I 1 toegso looseg egegost* osco co«^^ OCO X CO »rt ! eg eg os t* t^ egia -^J" "V CO X t- -H co ■-* x eg "1 i:ICl I J*l"i"-'il •s.».t«.\\ p«» s^|jH|BS SO t- OS nxio wee- cj I X 5 5. o eg co — o i- eg ia so io XSC CO O IS co hoc- cgmspio ooso c^ o us coeg-H if^Moo ost- coQio so eg ttso xeoegio enso eg-"x t- CO XT coeg — egc-eg Tf Tf SO 1 ...&gt;U IM1..JI11HK os^o eg — so soeo — — — eg x^so os ;,, is...&gt; |i:tu-iv I«1«X Ht-^r 5,-ao eg so — eg — io eg— ti" 2 S llO|JB|llil«l,I XSO — egx o soo iox eg -t - soos so **tn •t — OSO SO Tf9i»TT l«liij. uoiv iv — meg eg x g * i- lOOOt- X COO icio eg t-egen t-OSflO OST» t- — eo 3— I us ■ SJIIMIMII IO CO S0 *- IA O T, 1-4^ | CO jo 0&gt;c u»K av if o en COX'* — SOiC t-cox CO — O X I* r-XOOt- OSCO Oi 00 I Oi CO iO 00 iOh 00 -^ es ee cMfln t- iA 3 &gt;&gt; i-t *&amp; O t- &lt;X&gt; ■*&gt; s*~.LG Oi 00 00 »-• ift 00 lO &lt;O as os o t- as os © ~h 10 (o MhtC^ X(D 00 .t&gt; OS zd 06 5D x oj oJ e4 *"•»■* t&gt; IBiij.iy .&lt;|qmoK A V CO W^ U t&gt;_ = "3 oc X -&gt;\ 3 O h 4IO1 E [3 jo o.&lt;v uop; '•▼ *• I %f. ffi ik g I e i ]il ffj till :l I i S II ft! |p Z V- — H 51 &lt; u M </seg>
            <seg id="p099">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 99 ■» o ec eg t- o» eg O'H'O'rt eg o to e^ * I t OWN ■VCM ■&gt;* ««O--t t";eOO t--t-;«OO COU5 t"; »» OS £ J www C0tO~ CCtA t- CM "C IMIHI.hI \'J in X C— O tOn A X O OS " O 00 Jl - X t-O 0 0) CO © 00 01 O -* CO ■*!• inii&gt;i nan! 00 OJINt- tOlOtC OINTfCki o&gt; O -H «C -f E 7 5 ci i- u MMiv AminoK r.- 5rfg Jjjj wosfeo &lt;n» t-" "1 fc * 1 00 -*X eg CM too*eM*co [" ■vast- c--h^ •» 2 ~ Vi- •» • _ «&amp; I CO CO -H C- X HtDMH IS 06^-^ in - - t-00 -* tC CM »-i •vio &lt;x — ■» I in eg so in -^ nco&amp;i ■** oo t&gt; hn •^j'Pcc «D — »^ N to i© -V co &lt;e m -HiN Tf -c ec | &gt;.• | &gt; tl .•&lt; 1 V ;.| IN 1-eOT »■*« lON^t OC-" «D«»tC M &gt;X P"»Jt) N t-lOTf lO'fl'O 5OWU3C- ■flilC CO Vtn 00 in os &lt;-&lt; ~h oiooo &lt;a o e4 ui ■*»■» is 5 — ocoo |Mptl.Mly;.| eg C-COtt 00^N iON»^ 00"-" «D«"tCN £ OPT^ ?! r-eoT *M'»1' 1»)«X l'»»Jf) 1 t-'C* io^&gt;o 5OWU3C- ■fljic mvtn oo &gt;.i« eJ 00O5-*"' oTt-^to" uj'-^'Voo r-^oo io°" e»" oo ?=■= fi C-iC Tf in -wo tOrtlOC- 1*J»X 1'IIBJt) oocs-v iOOh ~ : O5 t- tC IN r t- CO CM CC I s ill ■( % ■JtlOt- 00 to O* : t~ oot-^ o x i ■* to co 5s • r; : t~ ••"1 toM ; *- *ua*ii»u*axa gj miMte x :»" -vacate oo» o* i t- i.i Jt *'IM&gt; II" i" osaoo t-- ; t^ cit&gt;r*c^ ooc- ox ■ ■* - UIHl|MI.((lx^ -»CM !C 4rfl||(| ||» J( ..^wjrt.W AMiiu.iiv S xon E :^ aoos «n §;2 i ? -= - . ec_ tot- in -&lt; : «_ to&lt;Mt-t- *»-^ &lt;c w j t- CM C- t* C - 1QOO9 N*C5 &gt;J!l!Jrt.VV A|l| H gj 00 oS £ cJ~ ■ V v. ■* : CM -H . *» | » _ J _• x oier- o :cc t-x^io c-m net : o ' I h *&gt; =t ri oo oc "^ **1 "* ! *» e i e i c ?® WO t-j i-n : »- = ;^ w cgoood -*r ?d oioat^N scc»i o » : t» c £ S 1^ -T s.t in nun. h1\m OO)^ 1 Oi 5C NOOK^ C»J»a x^^ : Oi - « S :t- «« - «^ : « -y,;.J es oi f in* sJx* to us :-&lt; -H"x"»*e» co*cc" n fc i «• N t- WL ■M = i •» --f\- 5l O'fl'tD tj i tot-; c&lt;i to co eg -h CNC CMCOrt iMOicjin oo out- loo "■".I x tctot- o&lt;no ot-«"» -&lt;n nun *r I £ I £ J8OJ O t^ w •*}« CM Kiiili;. i Jrf.i un|iii|ii lIOH imi&gt;X AMIIH.iH »Jld« 3 jd d imimin .ooiw^ -•• &lt;^Mt^ -! =-z- iIoh imox A|i|iu.in n«-h n«-h oj — rt-H ec— « q n in =-^ = *"■ 2 £ \\=^ m in^ac- cc^e-i ionxo o— m as n jsoo Bj|ili;.» jj.i tooiiri do6«5 «5«d t-^ — o oi . -" ** " S» -?--i r~ &gt;c eg •&lt;» ecoiin st-oox xm os -co m t~~c.~ «Ct- -H t-Qt" CMrtrtrt CO-" « U N « Vi s 1 [- 1 ■— CO "^ (M CO *-*_ CM ox to 1 XO O ■* t- — 'O 0, t-NX JO1CO X M 1 — CM T J^ y. H 3 _ i in, ® " c ! c i c i* (: i iHt-e t-M 031-ec ic =!•= u 'rf.iiiitii.&gt;)iiii.'i\ j" « m_o i-i »■«'« xtcom 5 «W| sffs s is.i.i i mi i. &gt;v imoi » «h« rc-W ecofieoT •»•* » » — * I;" - t- imoo X'-tc nx m Xi=;^. ** •—•eg »-^ os . v r «• |2*l •f. 1 l«o.) 2 H-noi icsc otCT»o ego: X ■• os = '^i ego: X ■» t-co t- co Z doj ii.'io.i. A|i|iiio|\- ■* &lt;c^*» ooccin oite-*-^ miri ej t^eg z ?'-~, » ~ - IE"; eg t~ cm &lt; f. « ' i : S i Hi in 3,ii ii s i gij II lit 3g.il =£ a X 13^ \ y *£J III f|«s -| o I : iy H y &lt; i\ ini lit til 1 1*11$ m 2: v. 1- ras : &gt; -= -a: ■/. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT In conclusion we call attention to the several reports of the superintendents of each of the different institutions under our control, which are presented herewith and which in many instances contain much of value in the way of in - formation and suggestions and also much of a statistical nature and which in detail show the work that has been accomplished during the two-year period covered by the reports. We respectfully submit the above for such consider - ation and action as may be deemed worthy and wise. In concluding this, our report in general, we wish to express our appreciation for the many courtesies and acts of kindness and helpful suggestion in the performance of our work received from you, as Governor, and from other state officers with whom we have been associated. We especially appreciate the hearty co-operation and earnest work which has been done by superintendents and other officers and employees in our efforts to reach the highest possible degree of success. BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS, Silas A. Holcomb, Chairman, Howard Kennedy Henry Gerdes. Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 191 Jt. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>