<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska Farm Homes A Comparison of Some Living Conditions of Owners, Part-Owners, and Tenants</title>
               <date value="1923-05">1923-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">May, 1923 Bulletin 191 Nebraska Farm Homes I'AHT-UW NKHS. AND TKNAVTS 1. O. RANK IN PROGRESS home has been moved aside to house the family while a new all-modern g built nn the old site. Rapid progress is being made in such matters h AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AND UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING A &lt; HHI' \KI»&lt;&gt;\ OF SOMK I,IVIN(. l(IM)ITIII&gt;s OF OWNERS. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">v Sl.MMAKY BY IJNKS The home is the center of farm lite. Page 3. Many city housing principles are applicable to the open-coun house, but methods of application need study. Page 4. Houses and grounds of about 1,140 owners, part-owners, and ter ants were studied in 10 Nebraska localities. Page 5. The value per house varies greatly from section to section bu averages »l,800-$2.4OO among owners, $2,200 among part-owners, am rs, anc 11.400 among tenants. Pages 6-9. Part-owners live in the newest houses and tenants in the 1&lt;S houses. Page 9. Owners' and part-owners' houst 6 rooms. Page 8. average 7 rooms, tenants nous Little or no overcrowding of houses, rooms, or grounds is ii Pages 10-14 Three bedrooms per house or one for each person and a ;il usual. Pages 14-17. There are 3 times as many 2-story houses as 1 -story Page 17. Screens cover nearly all the doors and windows, half of porches, and about a sixth of the front porches. Page 18. The kind and dryness of cellar floors varies from area Pages IS and 19. Indoor toilets, bathtubs, furnaces, etc., are found in rath percentages oi the homes. Pages 19 and 20. Most houses are on well drained sites and surrounded t of ample size. Pages 21-24. Size and arrangement oi dooryard and farmstead Pages 24-26. Walks to buildings are about one and a halt' times as fre found in the eastern as in the southwestern Nebraska areas. I HC Tenants' yards are oftener without grass, trees, flowers, and but three-fifths of all houses have windbreaks. Pages 27 and . Fences are most frequently of woven wire and wood or woven wire. Pages 28-30. Fruit trees and home gardens are found on almost all only two-fifths of the owners and part-owners and a quar tenants have small fruits. Pages 31-33. The houses are generally within sight and hearing of Pages 33 and 34. Nearly all the water is furnished by wells. They average from the house but vary greatly in distance from possible soi re contamination. Pages 34-37. Ice supply is important and may easily be more generally tained. Pages 37 and 38. Most homes are still without power or lighting systems. Pages 38-4( Two per cent of all farm houses are fully modern — that is, hav modern water, lighting, and heating systems — and about 12 per cen are modern in one or more of these respects. The percentages ar Increasing rapidly. Pages 41-44. Owners have modern homes in about 3 times as great percentage of cases as do tenants. Pages 44 and 45. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Nebraska Farm Homes I'AHT-()«XKH\ AND TBMAMTS 1 J. O. RASKIN' Importance. — "The farm — best home of the family; main )■&gt;■&gt;■ ot natural wealth; foundation of civilized society; natural 1(1 t II I (I I "1 UIU1 , I "UIIVIUI I\l I 1 \JL V ■ T 1I1UVU »v«. »*.»^ * .»W.MIM» &gt;.'" A good home includes a well-constructed, well - louse in good surroundings. The house and its imine - tundinga are to be considered in this bulletin somewhat lily in the house and in the community, of which that a part, are considered in other bulletins of this series, rmer's home, even more than that of most other classes, ter of both economic and human welfare activities. It lidst of the everyday work of making a living and must c of much that is most vital in the family, community, associated activities of farm people. It is less con- possible for the farm family to depend upon outside such as restaurants, commercial amusement, lectures, aries, fairs, and picnics, but outside contacts should be sought. City housing studied. — Much of the study of housing has special reference to city conditions. Overcrowding, and other health conditions have been given special -owner is a farmer who owns part of the land he operate* rt of it from someone else. A mortgage on a full owner'* t clan* him a* a part-owner. The terms owner and tenant i in the usual sense, which doubtless need not be explained readers. The terms cash, share, and share-cash tenant are tit census and the general public use them. The cash tenant amount of money or products per acre or for the farm; the pays a fixed fraction of the product: and the share-cash share of the crop for part of the land and a fixed sum of nwn&gt; fixed amount of product for the remainder, regardless of the the crop which he happens to raise in a given year. The share - • ■n.-irn in Nebraska is usually mainly a share tenant, paying a fixed n of his crop for the tilled land he rents and a fixed amount of z&lt; ther commodity for the hay and pasture land and sometimes m»nr he farmstead Thr author has relied mainly upon the results of a survey conducted in i p. ration with Drs. C. J. Galpin and W C. Oray of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the United States Department of Agriculture. Some portions are based upon a survey made in cooperation with the Inter - church World Movement. Acknowledgments are also due to enumerators who were employed to do the field work, to tabulators, and to a number of members &lt;&gt;f the faculty of the University of Nebraska, and others who have tnude valuable suggestions at various staKes of the work and supplied photographs. To the Agricultural Editor is due credit for the style fol - li wed in typography and make-up, and for some of the details of literary style. •Eliot. Charles W., President Emeritus. Harvard University. Inscrip - tion used in connection with Union Station, Washington, D. C. * I &lt;»H|-AKI&gt;O&gt; OK SUHK I.IVI&gt;«; IOXU1T1OXS OP OWXKRM. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 attention. The amount of space per person, ventilation, lighting, sewage disposal, and many other necessities and conveniences are reasonably well understood. Some of the minimum standards suggested are open to question and all are easier to state than to enforce upon those who do not realize the need for them or feel financially able to meet them. Many of the lessons learned in the study of city housing are directly or indirectly applicable to the open country but we can - not rely entirely upon city studies to solve country problems of house construction and equipment. The same general results should be sought whether the house is in city or country but the means of obtaining them may vary considerably. Human beings need about the same temperature and water supply and about the same kind and intensity of light in both city and coun - try, but the means of attaining them may be very different. The same is true of water supply, power, equipment, and mini I other things that will readily occur to the reader. Even if city housing problems were entirely solved, whirl they are not, there would still be work to be done in determinii country housing conditions and methods of applying estal principles to them. Some of the things laid dowi less imperatively to be demanded are (1)1 window i 2 in each room with (2) a total window area at lea as great as that of the floor, (3) opening directly yard, or court, (4) the top of at least 1 window per be not less than 7 feet and H inches above the f1&lt;&gt;&lt; provision should be made for cross ventilation in means of transoms, doors, or windows, and (6) th not less than 600 cubic feet of air to each adult and 4&lt;Mt p&lt; under 12 years of age, but this provision depends very upon the rapidity with which air is changed. ( 7 1 No roo exeept bathrooms and closets should have less than M ■quan feet of floor area or (8) be less than 7 feet wide and 8 feet high except attics, which should have at least 5 feet between floor and roof. (9) Passage thru a bedroom should not be necessary to gain access to any other room. (10) Sanitary sewage dis - posal should be provided and (11) dampness should be guarded against, particularly in cellars, which should be floored with not less than 4 inches of concrete with a finished surface. 1 12 1 No basement should be occupied for living purposes without atten - tion to light, ventilation, drainage, and other conditions of sanita - tion. (13) Overcrowding should be avoided, for reasons that will be given special attention later. 1 'For fuller discussion of these point* the reader is referred to the -rur uniri uiblumiuh tn iiicnf ptMnm ine r^aaer 11* reierrea i&lt;» me . books by Veiller listed in the bibliography at the clone at this bulletin. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska Farm Homes 5 Country housing also studied. — Attention is being attracted to e country house. Its architecture, construction, equipment, and dings are more and more recognized as presenting special is which must be solved. The present study will not at- &gt;lish now or different rural housing standards but einp nt as correct a picture of the Nebraska farm house v d as the data at hand permit and make some applica- css clearly established principles to the condi- overed The areas studied. — &lt; &gt;ur discussion in later pages will be based nainly apod the facts obtained by visits to about 1140 farms in 10 localities indicated by Figure 1. As less complete studies e made in the (Jeneva area in central Fillmore County and in FIG. I. WHERE THE FACTS CAME FROM ndicates an area in which tenancy and ownership were compared. About i usually studied in an area. The cruu indicates an area in which the ade in cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement. the sandhill area in Logan County, some of the tables omit one or both of these areas. In such cases the text includes any data not included in the tables if they seem likely to throw additional light upon any phase of the subject. A tenure study. — This study is but a part of a larger one in which tenants are compared with owners and part-owners by means of a socio-economic survey. In view of the differences of opinion held with regard to tenancy, more facts have been sought as a basis of opinion. Tenancy has been compared with owner - ship in its effects on as many as possible of the phases of the wel- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 ions hich m .IK :W 1 VI i.i ver y fare of Nebraska's farm population. The various conipari are being grouped for publication in a series of bulletins of w this is one. Table 1. — Arernye ruin,- of hoitaea: by area* THK HOISK Values. — All the values stated are as of Muck 1, 1930 making them reasonably comparable with those of the teenth Census which are as of January 1, 1920. The a\ value of the houses studied is about $1800 — over $24im&gt; fin - er*, nearly $2200 for part-owners, and about $1400 for te Share and share-cash tenants occupy houses of substantially value, but the cash tenant for some reason falls far behind, in a house worth less than two-thirds as much as the othe ants' houses. Managers have houses a little lower in valu&gt; those of cash tenants. In the 2 southwestern areas the average value per k only about $1500 as compared with $2Oti7 in the eastern Ihe state. The part-owners have houses of higher averau than either owners or tenants in these southwestern Xi areas. This results mainly from the showing of the Can area in Furnas County, where the 7 part-owners stand we! either owners or tenants or any group of tenants, and the agers have houses valued practically as high as those owners who live in these areas. In the Nehawka area in Cass County the owners ami owners have houses of practically equal value— each a littk $4000 — but the tenants' houses are worth less than $ltiiHi oi Tenants Areas ill iastern Nebraska Cm* Gace Clay Fillmorr Polk Thurstoa Southwestern NebnMka Fums* Perkins .mndhill Logan. ! AH Omars I1.S01 ft,4M 2,707 4.043 1,730 1,685 2,644 3.285 2,001 2,712 2,526 3,075 1.035 1.820 1.154 1,255 1.778 2.133 MM ' 1,071 Hmrt- 12.166 4.0*0 2,391 4,500 2:&gt;m 2.476 885 1,543 1,802 2.100 Share- All mh Share ' $1,411 ; $1,504 $1,421 1.557 1,423 1,740 1.S42 1.562 2,109 1.699 1.867 1.283 1.117 1,143 1.113 2.088 2,228 1.411 806 1,012 789 969 997 920 1,554 1,663 1,547 i 1.7M j * 1 1.— ; | Cask I tMl 1,450 1.333 2.000 KHl 2,251) 643 UH MM M.n agen 7 61 .V 1.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Farm Homes 7 well over a third as much an those of the owners and part-owners, while the managers are living in houses worth only about $700 apiece. In the Killey area in Gage County, owners and tenants are living in houses of practically the same value — between $1500 and $1700 — while the part-owners stand nearly 50 per cent above ihein with houses averaging $2400 apiece and 11 share tenants' houses average over $2100 apiece in value. The Walthill averages, in Thurston County, are still lower, being under $2000 for the owners' houses and well under $1000 lor the part-owners' houses, altho the part-owners are operating FIG. 2.- AMPLY HOUSED their two small daughters have an 11-room. 6-bedroom house sur - luntls planted with fruit and shade trees. farms worth more than those operated by the owners. The houses of the tenants are valued at about $800 apiece and those ■ »t' fiiwn of all tenures averaged together in this area at just nver $1000 apiece. In the area about Clay Center and Kairfield in Clay County we find the rather high average of $2500 per house, with owners' houses valued at nearly $3300, part-owners' $4500, and tenants' at $1700. In the Milligan area the average value per house is $2000. Part-owners have houses worth twice as much and the owners' hous.s are worth two and a half times as much as the tenants' </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 a :d...* s .o — «o *o 2 S3 i9 iii © «3 e — — — &lt;e • •• s x a s ?ce*aoeJa •» « «; ai x x s *i r-'^ c ?.?.--- mm 9S s»s x» E V.- Z 1 EP 2 A X AM TIC j. i i 53 - X — * 5 x Z 71 r t osaSNO z i NMO t: r £» I NfNnoM sa 88 5 iS!HS2I is ijj!J!j S ili^!!|jlj l[^ I 4 SgS-8° SS35 -'=. %■ I I -el 1 - </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Farm Homes 9 houses. Thi' only other ana populated mainly by those of foreign stock is that about Stromsburg in Polk County, where the people are largely of Swedish origin. The values in this area averaged much above the average for those of all other areas, standing at $2526, — owners' houses nearly $3100, part-owners' $2500, and tenants' $2,100. Even the tenants in this area are living in houses worth more than the average of all houses in all areas. Age. — The houses studied average more than 18 (18.3) years old; those of the tenants are nearly 20 and those of the owners between 17 and 18 (17.6) years old. The part-owners live in SANITATION AND ' CONVENIENCES FIG. S.— SANITATION AND CONVENIENCES Almtwt all are making at Icmst tome effort to keep the fly menace out of the house. Bathtub* and indoor toilet* are generally yet to be installed. houses 3 years newer even than those of owners but they are largely in the 2 most recently settled areas studied, where all houses are newer. In the 6 longer settled southeastern Nebraska areas, however, the part-owners live in houses nearly 4 years newer than those of the tenants and nearly a year newer than those of the owners. Sixe. — The average number of rooms per house gives no indi - cation of lack of room from the health standpoint in the house of either owners or tenants in any area. More than six (6.4) rooms are available for a household of less than 5 persons. Three of these rooms are usually bedrooms. The 7-room house seems at ■H- -h ■* I r 4=^ t +■ «t^: 1- -h J- J U- JoKMTOM oSSn jjMrr- T[MNT| VZ= «s« -rr^r </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 10 typical of owners and part-owners and the 6-room house of ten - ants. In the southeastern areas there is a strong tendeney to - wards 8 rooms for owners, 7 for part-owners, and ti for tenants. Here the average size is a little greater, the additional rooms going mainly to owners, somewhat to part-owners, but not at all to tenants. Danger of overcrowding.— Housing is regarded as a matter of religion and of morals in many senses of the word as well as physical well-being by at least one English work. 1 It speaks of overcrowding as having led to drinking, gambling, and licentious - ness in England. Of H counties remarkable for drunkenness. 4 were also remarkable for overcrowding and the other 2 had considerable proportions of densely crowded districts. Health is affected by overcrowding which doubtless increases the cases of illness. Death rates from 1903 to 190ti in one Eng - lish district were about 44 per thousand population in 1-room tenements, nearly 22 in those of 2 rooms, and nearly 13 among those of 3 rooms, while in those of 4 or more rooms the death rates were only about H or 7 per thousand population. Each of these figures is based on a population of 14,000 or more and 2 of them are based on populations of over 30,000. Among these same populations the infant mortality was a 200 deaths per thousand births in 1-room tenements, ltiO aim tenements of 2 or 3 rooms, and over a hundred among those 4 or more rooms. 1 These crowded conditions were doubtless soeiated with others, such as insufficient or improper food ; medical attention, so that housing is not the only factor. I'i ably none would doubt, however, that overcrowding was important cause. If overcrowding can cause such results in one country it can in another. If it brings these results in cities we should consider carefully whether it may not do so in the country and should take every precaution to see that we have no such condition in any of our homes at present and that they do not invade the Nebraska farm home of the future. The averages just stated are not enough to prove that there is no overcrowding in any of the houses, as the most extreme conditions may be concealed within an average. To be sure on this point, therefore, we must have clearly in mind the danger of overcrowding and analyze these figures still further and determine to what extent, if at all, over - crowding is present. ■Akien and Hayward. Hollaing. P. An and f.l 'Same. P. 04 and 65. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Farm Homes 11 Kinds of overcrowding. — Writers recognize 3 kinds of over - •rowding: (1) ground overcrowding, (2.) house overcrowding, and (3) room overcrowding. 1 The slightest knowledge of Ne- braska farm condition! would seem to indicate that ground over - crowding never occurs unless from the house being too near other farm buildings. It is never close enough to another human habi- iii result in ground overcrowding. House overcrowding is the occupation of a house by too many people. That it practi - cally never occurs in the areas studied to such an extent as to be markedly dangerous to health is suggested by the average already stated and more definitely proved by figures presented on later FIG. 4. BUILDINGS CROWDED TOGETHER 1 overcrowding &gt;&gt; bad from the health, aesthetic, and financial standpoints. A h mure dangerous if buildinKs are crowded together. page*. Room overcrowding need not occur when 6, 7, or 8 rooms are available for 5 or 6 persons. It probably rarely or never occurs in any of the homes of the areas studied, but this inquiry was not sufficiently detailed to show positively that room over- crowding never resulted, for example, from a desire to sleep in warm rooms and to save fuel by heating fewer sleeping rooms than are needed for the proper accommodation of the members of the household. There is, on the other hand, no very definite re— on to suppose thai such room the homes studied. overcrowding occurs in any of •Ranhore. Harvey 15. Overcrowding Districts, 13-15. Ground overcrowding together; hoiiHe overcrowding i* the c and Defective Hounine In the Rural it* the placing of houses too close jpation of a house by too many people; room overcrowding is the occupation of a room by too many per - sons. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 2 -25,3°- 9999 9999 9999 999 9999 «q«o 0090 9999 ooooe 2 I *•*** — 1 — O 0000 0000 ©oo© nWn-o -r-ONc «■*« — © o 0000 e o e e s s ■ J. .." ■ — 'X — M C x -j ~ ~ c- xoo» 0000 = ;»» x-»« — o 00000 • aot-» X 3: -r -t -♦Woo •i S'«- ■**. ? i. "?*^^:^ *^*^ r : ep ? *! t ~. t ~.*! «^«&lt;d oooo *ti &lt;e-r*ti w«cr-n e4t-t«ao N&lt;tNW 0000 fi^w — OS — O ■r I -'•■■■ ■ X ■ •r M — 535 ,352 h ir\ r^ ■c ■ 1 «•»« — 6 t- - ~i — - x I t-»oi — o ««M- NM- ri 2 •»•••• 33 „, I _«M_ |W- .- X 1- X ■V I — © _ MCNOCJ &lt; K &gt;. t-AeoiA x m\ «W rj 3 -«» o aiesi- e x-»o» — — - 9"="»9 •• •S^t"! ®«r^ qooo oaea oooo -i kommo osatie ~2Jli M «««e ededo "? I— &lt; 999*! t : e &gt; e ' &gt;^ Nnax •»«»)■» * — I 5 10 ""* m«oon6 «t-:«r&gt;»id a&gt;-*ti~6 9999 gjnoa — e ooooo ?i ri = ----- :-=-.? 1 W»&gt;OiOkO s ijiji jjiji in M g :;; Id I hi J £e| I l,| f §J l&amp;k I i^z h^ a *i*k Bjsh usls e&lt;zi£ ails *u«£ hill &lt; 5 £ &lt; s </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Farm Homes 13 Persons per house and per room. — Something more closely approaching overcrowding is found in a few cases when we analyze further the figures entering into the general averages. There is a very unequal distribution of the room available in the houses studied, since some are 2-room houses and others have 1(1, 12, or even lin 2 cases) 14 rooms. In number of rooms, whether in other particulars or not, the absolute health require - ments seem to be met. Special investigation of reported cases of H or 8 persons living in 4-room houses resulted in finding that part of the family was grown or for other reasons was living PCTgor* PIC. K. ROOMS AND BEDROOMS PER HOUSEHOLD household had «. t rooms and 3.2 bedrooms for 4.6 persons. The num- txMlronms varies more nearly in proportion to the number of persons per household he number of rooms elsewhere. While some families have less room than conforms with the general living standards of the community, the lack of room is not sufficiently serious to constitute a health menace. The "2-rooin houses numbered 15, or about 1.4 per cent of all, and were largely but not exclusively occupied by tenants. Ten - ants have naturally considered the housing problem in renting farms and only those with the younger families had taken the 2 - and 3-roaa houses. Houses of this size were occupied by only 2 persons or fewer over 20 years of age per house, indicating that in the case of such small houses there were present only the husband, wife, and their own children below 20 years of age. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 In some east's bachelors are the sole occupants. We shall see a little different state of affairs when we come to consider the 1-bedroom house. The owners and part-owners have larger households than the tenants but their houses, as we have already seen, are enough larger to give them as much or more room per person. The (J-room house is more frequently found among owners and part - owners and the 5-room house among tenants than those of any other sizes. There are so many more houses above those most fre - quent sizes than below them that they are distinctly below the averages which have already been stated. In 5 of the 9 areas in which the number of rooms per house was ascertained the 6-rooni house is found more frequently than any other. In the Walthill area in Thurston County the 5-room house is most frequent, with the 4-room house running a dose second, doubtless because the renting of unimproved Indian land makes it necessary for many men to erect their own improvements on the Indian land or on small tracts which they own largely for this purpose. In the Fairfield-Clay Center area in Clay County, the 7-rooni house is much more frequent than that &lt;&gt;f any other size, while in the Ktromsburg area in Polk County, inhabited largely by those of Swedish descent, the 8-ronni house is the most frequent, with the 7-room house running a close st 6-rootn house a fairly close third. Of all houses in all areas, 1 out of every ."&gt; is 1 out of every li a 5-room house, and marly anotl H a 7-room house, while 1 out of every 7 is ar Only 1 house out of every IK has 3 rooms or less ; 1-room house was found, while about 1 house out 9 rooms or more. Bedrooms. — We have already seen that the av all areas studied and for all tenures has about :{ (3.2) )&gt;&lt;-&lt;! for every four and a half (4.C) persons of about a person on ai half per bedroom. The 3-bedroom house is more frequent than any other, including nearly one-third of the total number. A quarter fall into the 2- bed room class and a fifth into the 4-bed - room class, while about 1 out of every H farmhouses has 5 or 8 bedrooms, negligible numbers have 7 or 8 bedrooms apieee, while the 1-bedroom house at the other extreme appears on l&gt;9 farms or about 1 out of every 15. While there is a distinctly greater correlation between the number of persons per household and number of bedrooms per house than between the number per </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Farm Homes 15 I xizc iiml nge composition of Hi Hedronnw per how \ I 4 k N All tenure. 1.014 69 257 311 207 134 28 S 3 Allan*..... 4.6 3.4 4.2 4.4 4.7 5.1 5.8 6.8 I 7.0 1.4 2.6 2.6 3.2 i 3.S 3.3 1.4 1.6 1.9 2.2 2.2 2.3 e.( 0.5 ' 0.6 0.4 O.t ! 1.4 65 100 93 65 i 14 ! 4 I All agea ....... 4.7 3.3 4.1 4.3 j 4.7 5.2 , 5.9 j T.i I 7.0 2.4 2.3 2.6 2.7 3.4 4.2 :!.:( ver 20 yean. 2.5 1.9 2.4 2.3 2.6 2.7 3.4 , 4.2 3.3 20 yean 1.8 0.9 1.4 1.4 1.8 2.2 2.2 ! 2.5 2.3 nder 6 years 0.4 0.5 0.3 0.6 0.3 &lt; 0.3 ' 0.3 0.» 1.4 li 4 11 40 45 32 20 K 0 0 ,6 0.5 0.8 ! 0.5 1.0 0.0 0.0 l» 41 152 166 82 49 8 1 0 4.2 3.6 4.0 4.4 . 4.3 4.4 4.6 4.0 0.0 2.4 2.5 : 2.3 3.0 2.0 0.0 1.4 1.1 ! 1.3 1.4 1.0 0.0 U 0.7 Of 0.7 0.8 I 0.2 1.0 0.0 ll.T Manager. 8 1 4 2 1 0 000 4.0 3.0 0.0 0.0 j 0.0 0.0 aces 2.0 0.0 0.0 ! 0.0 0.0 ti 20 yeare \'.2 2.0 1.2 1.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 I 0.0 0.0 0.5 1.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 I 0.0 ehold and the total number of rooms per house, this correla - is far from perfect. In other words, while the greater num- bednioms per house is associated with a greater average ■ of persons per household, the number of bedrooms rises pidly than does the number of persons per household. nailer houses we speak of number of persons per bedroom le larger houses we reverse this and speak of the number of bedrooms per person included in the regular household. The ] -bedroom houses have more than 3 persons per bedroom, the 2-bedroom houses about 2 persons per bedroom, the 3-bedroom houses a person and a half, the 4-bedroom houses a person and a ;md S-bt'droom houses at least a bedroom per &lt;|iiarter, 5- person. Part-owners have a little less bedroom space per person than owners, and tenants also have less, but these tenure varia - tions are not very great. It is rather easy to presume that the 1 -bedroom houses are tliose occupied by (1) men who are keeping "bachelor's hall," (2) young or childless married couples, or (3) couples who have I'Mtl.K \.—/l&gt; /,»/,/ All ages 5.1 3.5 4.9 4.7 5.5 «.O 7.S 0.0 0.0 Overdye.™ 2.7 2.2 2.5 2.5 2.7 3.1 3.1 0.0 0.0 I M y.-»rs 1.9 0.8 ; 1.8 1.7 2.0 &gt; 2.4 3.2 0.0 0.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 only small children who sleep in the same rooms with their par - ents. These figures hardly support this conclusion, however, as they show that the 1-bedroom house is occupied by an average of about 2 persons over 20 years of age but that only half of them have children under 6 years of age while they average 1 person per house between 6 and 20 years of age in addition to the 2 over 20 years of age. Perhaps the more probable conclusion is that there are some i cases of bedroom overcrowding and some cases of failure of the FIG. «. A BACHELORS HOUSE Many worse houses are occupied by farm families. In screen**, romtit household conveniences, and window space it rates low but its two bedroom* ami thrti droom* and th other rooms are certainly not overcrowded enumerators to learn that rooms not strictly bedrooms and not reported as such were nevertheless used as sleeping i|iiarters. Of these 1-bedroom houses, 17 are occupied by owners, 1 1 by part-owners, and 41 by tenants. The tenants thus have much more than their share of the 1-bedroom houses and t ho same may be said of the 2-bedroom houses of which the owners have a hundred, part-owners 45, and the tenants 15fi. The 3-bedroom house is more common than any other, includ - ing nearly one-third of all. Among owners the 4-bedroom house is almost as common as the house with 3 bedrooms but ainoni - part-owners and tenants it is the 2-bedroom house which comes second in point of frequency of occurrence. In England, where </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Nebraska Farm Homes 17 housing conditions have long been deplorable in both city and country and demands must consider the necessity for economy, "there was an almost universal desire for 3 bedrooms and many statements were made to the effect that this was the least possible number." 1 These were the expressions of wives of working men living under village and hamlet conditions. They doubtless knew that scores of thousands were living in Britain in 1, 2, 3, or 4-room tenements but feared the effect of such crowding upon both health and morals. It has even been contended that intem - perance is as much an effect as a cause of overcrowding. PER CENT FIG. 7.- DRAINAGE AND SITE me requisite. The hillside site wouki probably have been most frequently chosen had nil the farms afforded all the kinds of Kit Stories. — The 2-story house is almost 3 times as common as the 1-story house in the Geneva area in Fillmore County, in spite of the landscape architect's preference for the lower type of con - struction in a prairie country that the lines of the house may blend readily w it li those of the comparatively level country. Two - story houses are 4 times as frequent among owners as 1-story houses but only twice as frequent among tenants in spite of the fact that tenants in this area have almost as many rooms per house as have owners. Data on number of stories are available only from this 1 area. "Alricn and Hayward. Housing. P. 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 Improvements since 1910.— About 1 Geneva area farm house out of every 7 was built in the decade 1910-1919, or had been improved during that time. The proportion is about 3 times as great in case of houses occupied by owners at the end of the decade, or in 1920, as among those occupied by tenants at that time. Among 10 kinds of improvements, houses and garages are far more frequent than any others on the farms of owners. On the farms of tenants, however, the more frequently reported improve - ments are barns, chicken houses, corncribs, and others of an economically productive kind. FIG. 8. AN EASTERN NEBRASKA FARMSTEAD The lite is well chosen and the buildings are well Kroup Screens. — Screens covered the windows of 19 out of every '2&lt;l houses, the outside doors of 49 out of every 50, the back porches of nearly half, and the front porches of about a sixth of the houses. Owners and tenants show no distinct difference in their use of screens. Every area seems to have reached the stage of almost universal screening of windows and doors, but poiwh screening is much more general in eastern Nebraska, even in the newer Walthill area in Thurston County. The personal annoy - ance and disease danger resulting from the presence of flies, then, are almost sis completely banished as screens can banish them. Some further progress is possible by putting some of the, screens in better condition and by making porch screening more </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Farm Homes 19 general. Then the t-ool pon-h shade may be enjoyed in summer without By danger. The main progress to be made in fly control is in the proper handling; •' stable manure and privies. If the breeding places and sources of contagion are neglected, screening alone is not enough. Rural conditions generally leave much to be desired in this particular. Cave and cellar floors. — The kind of cave or cellar floor varies much from area to area and from owner to tenant. More than half of the eastern Nebraska cave and cellar floors are of con - crete, more than a third of them of dirt, and about 1 out of every 30 of brick. Among the owners the concrete floor is two and ;i half times as frequent as the dirt floor, but among tenants FIG. 9. A SANDHILL RANCH FARMSTEAD Good buildings with an ice and skating pond behind the house, dirt and concrete are almost equally common. In western Ne - braska where it is less difficult to keep cellars and caves dry, no briek floors were found and the concrete floor is much rarer, occurring in only about 3 cases out of every 8, over half having dirt floors. Toilets and power washers — Bathtubs are found in a sixth f the homes and indoor toilets in a tenth. Each is found in almost exactly the same percentage of part-owners' homes as of owners' homes, but in a much smaller percentage of the tenants' homes. The power washer, on the other hand, is found in be - tween 2 and 3 per cent of the homes of owners and tenants alike, altho there is some advantage in favor of the owner. In the southwestern areas.— In southwestern Nebraska also, the part-owners have the newest houses and the tenants the old- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 est, but the general average age in only about two-thirds as great as that in the eastern half of the state. Houses here are a little smaller, the 6-room house being the prevailing size apparently among all groups and exactly the average for owners and part - owners, but the tenants fall a little behind this figure with an average of 5.6. Screens are found on practically every southwestern Nebraska door, just as in the eastern areas, but on only a little over nine - tenths of the windows. The owners and tenants are not very far apart, but the part-owner is distinctly in advance of either of FIG. 10. A SANDHILL FARMSTEAD CENTERED ABOUT A SOD HOUSE A well chosen and well protected location with inexpensive improvement. them with screened windows in 52 out of the 54 cases Screens on the front porch are found only about half as frequently as in the eastern part of the state. Here again the part-owner is distinctly in advance of the owner but he is only slightly ahead of the tenant. The back porch is screened in ;. third of the cases in the southwestern areas and in a half of the cases in the eastern areas. For some reason the part-owner was quite low on this important point with only a fifth of the back porches screened as compared with a third of the owners and nearly two -fifths of the tenants. Bathtubs are found in 1 southwestern Nebraska farm home out of every 7 and indoor toilets in 1 out of every 11, but they are almost exclusively in the homes of owners and part-owners as only 5 tenant homes report bathtubs and 2, indoor toilets. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Farm Homes 21 - s z SIS Ujig" »i£ d i Z i •°»" M5lO (-©■* — I 5^1^-S^ I 1^ 3: 31 l*i^- ■»&gt; £ M ir -i XOMVaow &lt;n \£ t f.y.~ z K3'- ~i e» »W£ 1123- 2 ! o«n «on«o — • — F i ! ! i» ■» a is » &lt;o 91 m u !te^m m r - - -* » f i "t ir . =&gt;. -. =&gt; L i 5 is? 6 I !.* — • »■» oa««e*e g52S"S- jj , © iC M5 31 « © »O — — N I PSS 2SSS2S- C E °. **.*"■. x . *°. *! *i n . T. 8 le««9 x t^ oi w — — « £ fc 5»«5 C4M 09 OS 3 II SSS il=i s i s </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 22 FIG. 11.- A WESTERN NEBRASKA FARMSTEAD Reasonably well grouped buildings in &gt; orotected location. About 1 out of every 5 owners' or part-owners' homes has a bathtub, but the indoor toilet is found in only 1 home out of every 8 among owners and 1 out of every 9 among part-owners. |)l;\l\A«.K. WIMUIKKAKS. S1TKS, AND YIKW Drainage. — The site of the house seems to be almost equally good on the farms of owners, part-owners, and tenants with slight, but only slight, advantages to be credited to the locations of the owners' and part-owners' houses. Practically every farm - house in the southwestern Nebraska areas studied occupies a well drained site. In the eastern Nebraska areas 9 out of every 10 have this advantage, with the proportion distinctly higher than this in most areas, except the area about Stronisburi;, where nearly two-thirds of the sites were level rather than on hillsides or hilltops. This was the only area in which the tenants more generally have well-drained house sites than owners and j owners. In most areas there seem to be only chance differei About three-fifths of all houses have windbreaks — over three - fourths in eastern Nebraska, and a sixth in the southwestern part of the state. In each region they are most common about owners' homes, and more common about tenants' homes than about part - owners'. The differences are not very great except in south - western Nebraska, where the tenants have them only about halt as generally as the owners and three-fourths as generally as the part-owners. Cottonwood, boxelder, and soft maple trees were largely planted and better trees have not replaced them as gen - erally as might be desired. Sit*. — More than a third of the locations are level, nearly a third are on hillsides, nearly a quarter on hilltops, and more than a tenth are in valleys. This is doubtless the order of pref - erence, except that the hillside or hilltop location would always MB </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Farm Homes 23 have been chosen had not so much of the territory studied been too level to supply many building spots that were not level. These figures vary from area to area in such a way as to indicate that topography usually determines the percentages, rather than any other local or any tenure consideration. In the Filley and Nehawka areas, where slopes are sufficiently gentle to make hillside locations possible, and there are sufficient hills (i afford such building sites on most farms, about three-fifths of he locations are on hillsides and one-fourth on hilltops. In the FIG. 12.— A HIRED MAN'S HOUSE han the average so-called "tenant house " oc hi- tenant house" occupied by the hired farm Wiilthill area, on the other hand, where the slopes are much .steeper, half of the locations are on hilltops and only about a sixth on hillsides. This is the only eastern Nebraska area in \\ liich there are marked differences between the locations of own - ers and tenants. Half the owners and but little more than a quarter of the tenants have hilltop locations, while only a fifth tit the owners are located in valleys in this area, as compared with a third of the part-owners and more than two-fifths of the tenants. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 24 tin the southwestern Nebraska areas, on the other hand, there n to be distinct differences in location associated with tenure, each of these 2 areas about a fifth of the owners, less than I third of the part-owners, and about two-fifths of the tenants ve hilltop locations, while more than a quarter of the owners id distinctly less than a fifth of the part-owners and tenants have hillside locations. In the Grant area almost no valley locations are reported but in the Cambridge area they are re - ported by nearly a third of the owners, a seventh of the part - owners, and 2 of the 51 tenants, perhaps because the owners are so largely on the valley lands and the tenants out on the divide lands. A gentle southeast slope is often preferred if available. It gives good air and water drainage without the extreme exposure of the hilltop to cold winter winds, and avoids the steep hillside location's undue washing effect and difficulty in driving or walk - ing up or down steep slopes in work about the farmstead. A valley or pocket location is subject to water and cold air from higher ground. Hillside or hilltop locations may be protected in winter by windbreaks and are often preferred where hills are not high or steep. Fire ana* Cam Fumaa Locan Polk Thuratnr FarowUerer Firm. Arm ririti' \cm Flrmi tow Farm*' Krnr Farm '\ri • ■"" ■■■■ »••• i «. n •■ w.^ i n.tn i) u.to Managen 9 , 0.39 3 0.29 3 0.7 0 0.0 1 0^3 0.16 Size of dooryard. — Size of dooryard was reported for only the Cass, Polk, Thurston, Logan, and Furnas County areas. In the others the question "Size of grounds?" was answered by giving the size of the farmstead including barnyards and lots as well as the dooryard about the house. The grounds about the house average three-fifths of an acre in size but vary greatly from area to area, and somewhat from Tabi-k 6. — Size of dooryoiil : Ciixx. FuriKix. L&lt;&gt;&lt;/iih, /'&lt;&gt;//, Thurxtnii County nit us rotml 880 0.60 Own*™ S10 0.70 I Part-own*™ 68 0.52 T*nanti. all | 263 0.S7 8hare-eaah i 132 I 0.59 ' Share I 87 i 0.56 Cash ! U 0.3* M 0.7R 46 0.01 10 0.72 62 ! 0.M 32 i 0.M 26 0.73 4 0.74 its 3 32 '5 n.si 0.6 0.5 0.4 I 0.4 I 0.S 0.4 5* 26 3 23 I 21 1 ! l.»t I 1.39 0.97 1.15 0.91 0.B2 5.24 125 48 18 58 41 14 3 0.62 0.59 0.73 0.61 0.72 0.38 0.73 127 26 30 B» 26 11 32 0.33 0.26 0.40 0.2K 0.25 0.33 0.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Farm Homes 25 one tenure group to another. They are somewhat above the average in the Cass County area, and about twice the usual size in the Logan County sandhill area. In the Thurston County area, grounds about the house average exactly a third of an acre in size — about half the usual size. Perhaps these small yards in this area result in part from the broken surface of this Missouri River county. The owners in all areas average nearly three-quarters of an acre, part-owners half an acre, and tenants nearly three-fifths of an acre per dooryard. Owners have larger grounds about their houses than either tenants or part-owners in most areas except that about Walthill in Thurston County, where part - owners have about one and a half times as large dooryards as either owners or tenants, and owners even stand very slightly lielow tenants. It is hard to see, however, that the data show very clearly any tendency for either tenants or part-owners to have larger grounds than the others. Cash tenants have much less ground about the house than any other tenure group except managers. This is perhaps for 2 reasons: (1) The cash tenant ■nay feel less inclined to keep land out of crop if the yard is not so situated and fenced as to leave him no choice. (2) Much more important in causing this low average is the fact that more than two-thirds of the cash tenants of the 5 areas are in the one which has much smaller yards than any other. Taiii Sue &lt;&gt;f fmrmutemd: Clay, Fill more, Omf*y and Perkin* Size of farmstead. — Farmsteads average 3 acres in size in the 4 areas in which "Size of grounds?" was answered with the acre - age of all grounds occupied by house, barns, and other buildings, together with all the yards and lots attached to them. The farm - stead varies in size from an acre per farm in the Clay County area to nearly 3 acres in the Gage County area about Filley, ■otal Part-owner* Trnants, mil Sharr-rsah Shmra Cash Manager* Four inu &gt; Clay Fillmor* Gut Perkiaa Farm* Acna Farms Acna Fiiim Acres Faiim Acrea Farms Acm 484 3.05 110 0.9» 126 4.8 126 X.81 1SS 3.87 1*1 3.97 I 81 0.69 59 6.3 44 t.10 27 4.1 •1 2.8* 16 1.14 14 S.8 14 2.2« 47 8.4 28S 2.56 ' 6S 1.10 62 2.1 BH 2.76 4&gt; 4.6 144 2.17 : 46 O.»6 87 2.5 64 2.81 8 *Jt 80 8.82 16 1.S6 14 1.3 11 2.5S :I9 6.0 I 1.4* 2 0M 1 8 2.48 2 U» </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 nearly 4 in the westernmost or Perkins County area about Grant, and over 4 acres in the Fillmore County area about Milligan. The average size in all areas of owners' farmsteads is nearly 4 acres; of part-owners', nearly 3 acres; and of tenants', two and a half acres. Share tenants have a larger farmstead average than other tenants or part-owners, largely because so large a part of them are in the Grant area in Perkins County where all farm - steads are comparatively large. Proper size and arrangement. — The size and arrangement of both dooryard and farmstead must depend largely upon the needs of the individual case. The principles of landscape architecture and farm management should, however, be applied more care - fully than they are. A definite, pleasing, labor-saving plan should be adopted and followed in making changes from time to time. The erection of buildings or placing of trees and fences as momentary fancy or temporary needs dictate without reference to a permanent plan has too often prevailed. The result cannot be either the most satisfactory home or the most efficient use of labor in doing farm work. The most profitable farm investment is a pencil worn to a stub in mapping plans and policies. The house and its grounds should be given the first considera - tion. Its inhabitants are more important than those of the barns, yet neither can do best without the other. The house is there - fore the key to the farmstead and to the entire farm, both in purpose and in location. It should not be subordinated either in appearance or in fact. The farm should be made primarily a place where people live and live satisfactorily. This does not mean that its economic productivity need suffer. It will be stim - ulated by such a motive. A location not far back from the road is usually chosen to avoid loneliness and waste of ground. As viewed from the road, the house is usually in the foreground with the farm buildings farther back and on one side. The lawn is preferably an open grass plot not broken by trees, shrubs, or flower beds but shaded by trees around the edges, along the road. and near the house. Shrubs and flowers are near the house. The summer south winds should carry the barn's flies, odors, and noises away from the house. Winter north winds make less difference in this respect. The whole farmstead may be located on the townward side of the farm bui a more central location is often preferred because saving in daily travel to fields is more important than in less frequent travel to town. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Farm Homes 27 Walks. — Walks to buildings are about one and a half times as frequently found in the eastern as in the southwestern areas, and several times as frequently as walks to roads in both groups of areas. Walks of both kinds are much rarer in the Stromsburg and Milligan areas than in any others, with the exception of the (irant area where only 3 farms have walks to roads and 7 to buildings because the character of the soil and the relative in - frequency of rains make walks less necessary in this area. Grass, trees, flowers, and shrubs. — The dooryards of the east- ern Nebraska farmhouses much more generally have grass, trees, flowers, and shrubs than those of the southwestern areas doubt - less because (1) they have greater rainfall, (2) they are further PER CENT 90 IK IS. THE GROUNDS: WALKS. GRASS. TREES. FLOWERS. AND SHRUBS I). ryanl improvement! are only a little lew generally present on the (rounds of than of owners. from pioneer days and there has been more time for such im - provements, and (3) the grass, at least, is much more needed for the prevention of mud and the growth of unsightly weeds resulting from greater rainfall. The part-owners have more gen - erally provided their dooryards with these adornments than cither the tenants or the owners. The tenant has, in most areas, least frequently reported them, but even he has grass in more than two-thirds, trees in more than four-fifths, flowers in nearly half, and shrubs in more than two-fifths of the cases in eastern Nebraska. In the southwestern areas flowers and grass are found </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 in less than 2 yards out of every 5, while shrubs are present in less than 1 out of every 8. Grass, trees, flowers, and shrubs about the farmhouse are im - portant from many points of view. If properly planted and eared for they add very greatly to the comfort, health, and pleas - ure of the household and to the regard in which it is held by passers-by. Prom properly planted grounds less dust will rise and less mud will be carried into the house. Windbreaks have always been important in Nebraska and dust screens have become increasingly important with the advent of larger and more rapidly moving vehicles. Dust is a menace to pleasure, personal com - fort, and health alike. More and more careful attention will doubtless be given to the effective and artistic planting of grounds as we learn to realize that satisfactory living conditions and association with our fellow beings are the great things to be sought. We are thinking more and more of the farm home as a place in which to live and to live permanently and satisfactorily and less as a place in which we are to have merely the barest necessity's while raising food for the rest of the world or accumulating sufficient resources to enable us to move to town. Yard fences. — A third of the eastern Nebraska dooryards and more than a fifth of those of the southwestern Nebraska areas are without any yard fence whatever. In both these regions this condition is distinctly more prevalent on the tenant farms than on the owner and part-owner farms. This is true of every indi - vidual area without any exception whatever, except that in the Milligan area half the yards of the part-owners and half of thotte of the tenants are without fences. Unfenced grounds have some advantages if properly planted and kept. The expense of the fence and the difficulty of mowing around it are avoided, and a greater opening of hospitality is suggested to the passer-by. These advantages are more than offset, however, by the necessity for excluding farm animals and perhaps somewhat by the desire of the householder for a little more privacy and a little less unlimited hospitality than are sug gested by the unfenced yard. Woven wire fences are those most frequently found especially in the eastern Nebraska areas where they enclose the yards of a little more than half of all the farms studied or about two-thirds of all those which have any fence whatever. In southwestern Nebraska areas, however, woven wire is found as the yard fence </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Nebraska Farm Homes 29 ! x I ■? I 1 1 8=°a b s e; § eie; 3 ei OMONOt-OOflONO I i-i- I _5 H — attCTOQ-* ! E:8 s-s?a&amp; r.S •ot-«t&lt;p 5 i s s^ssss I rirj'i'g ! O &lt;BO — X3OM 8 2'SS3S 3 k: S S I SJ1-K3E * g«-r «'«"«• 9=«C8I M =J3 = = ». ffi »r- w«o eo«-««n««M^n9 8 S^SSSSS :«»i &lt; &lt; « !-«?-»r» -5 PS«3-S-5§«5» t-s.ta^ 5 R a a 55 s ?i 3 - *"• E ll ui^ii'Jm — IO 1O — !iS 2"B8SS t is 6 !:-!;"*" 6^ 6 tfi; * S I -■ . S S2S2SS | SSU-^H-r •&gt; - r. ?\ = r- s ■ ■ ■ i- 1 I J^SgSSSSjp 9 e &gt;r t -*-:«i t :^t-&lt;? 8 a-ssss * i — 5SSSSS srg-fsra" s;a- . I? 5 ~8H-ri=irr' $ i 2 ?5t!? t&lt; -? 8 2*S8S!J ■ 2 I « a si«j«= 5 | £*3IIi iiiii.il ¥ I I I^R 1? H(Z C « O -r-f- I I P s«o»o«ia»8o«o i^^ a SS°8 o S o 85 e 8° 1 | 8a~5-s-s~s»- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 on little mure than a third of all farms. It has a strong com - petitor in barbed wire which occurs on 1 farm out of every 4, while plain wire is reported from more than 1 farm out of every 8, leaving pickets and boards for the very small number of farms not otherwise accounted for. In eastern Nebraska, on the other hand, barbed wire enclosed Ely about 1 yard out of every 13 and the picket fence one out every 35 or 40. The woven wire fence is more generally found on the owner and part-owner farm than upon that of the ten - ant in both eastern and southwestern Nebraska areas. The barbed wire fence is found about the dooryards of the tenants rather than those of the owners, particularly in the Grant area in which it is about twice as frequent as woven wire even on the farms of owners. About the tenants' dooryards in this area it is 3 times as frequent as woven wire, being found in about 3 out of every 5 tenants' dooryards. This westernmost area has fewer unfenced dooryards than the others studied as well as more fenced with barbed wire. Dooryard gates. — In eastern Nebraska, dooryard gates present no very strong tenure features or outstandingly popular type, altho the wooden gate and the woven wire gate are used more fre - quently than those of any other type, and are more frequently reported by the part-owners than by either owners or tenants. A great number of the fences are without gates, particularly on the tenant farms. UARDKNH AND KRl'ITS Gardens. — Gardens are reported by more than 19 out of every 20 eastern Nebraska farms studied and in almost exactly equal proportion by owners and part-owners and by tenants with only less close approach to unanimity. The usual size is about a third of an acre but in case of the part-owner it drops to a fifth of an acre; while among share tenants and managers for some reason the size rises to two-fifths of an acre. Either because of a desire for convenience or because of economy of space the part-owner places his garden spot only about nine-tenths as far from the house as the owner and three-fourths as far as the tenant. In the southwestern areas every part-owner reported a garden and so did every other operator in the Grant area except 2 tenants, but in the Cambridge area only nine-tenths of the own - fs and less than two-thirds of the tenants reported gardens and ey are of importance mainly in the spring before summer </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Nebraska Farm Homes 31 drought interferes with their usefulness. They are distinctly smaller in this area than in the Grant area and distinctly closer to the house especially on the tenants' farms. Fruit. — Small fruits are found on the farms of two-fifths of the owners and part-owners and more than a fifth of the ten - iints. The blackberries, raspberries, strawberries, gooseberries, and currants reported under this head constitute a semiperma - nent improvement that might well be more generally made on the farms of both owners and tenants. On the tenant farm, it should pay the landlord and the tenant liberally for the trouble of co- per CENT FIG. 14.— THE GARDEN. FRUITS. GROVES. AND VIEW Fruits should be more generally present about the home* — particularly of tenants. Windbreaks also should be more generally planted. operating, to establish and maintain enough bushes or plants for household purposes. Their presence should help the landlord to get a much better tenant and perhaps higher rent and the tenant to live much better and more economically. The landlord should always be glad to buy plants and bushes if the tenant will plant and care for them. They will pay the average Nebraska tenant well. His average stay is long enough to bring good returns from small fruits he has planted on the farm after renting it. Very much the same may be said for fruit trees but their advantages seem to be more fully recognized, as they are reported from 1 • ■&gt; times as many farms — 3 out of every 5. They are found on the farms of 19 out of every 20 part-owners, about 3 out of every 5 tenants, and 4 out of every 5 owners. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 &gt; ! i £ «i»- ■•■» ,|!«= •=• zsrs ss 31 Oh-- "?*^ M * I ¥ i j H«S H £-*- • ■• 9 - 5 - S ?■ ; '111 Hil 3SS -^. £ ' ■ te«eoo&gt;o r-x* mm - Mia §S = 5 = ?. t 3 ftP-S «* &gt;= C e e.".».« * 5-s: &lt;&lt; o«et — 8S=5 S8S S --S a f « - T. -, ■« -—?, it r- 5 1 »n I « 8S=5 i ■ BSS9 »=« SS5S 3*2 a 14 1221 3i ii 1 lilt ci' HI &gt;• = I ililpill </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Nebraska Farm Homes 33 In t he westernmost or Grant area in Perkins County fruit trees were reported by a third of the owners and part-owners and a little more than a fourth of the tenants, while small fruits were reported on nearly a third of the owners' and part-owners' fa mis and nearly a sixth of the tenants' farms. In the Cam - bridge area only 1 tenant, 1 part-owner, and 6 owner farms have small fruit ; but nearly half the owner farms, three-quarters of the part-owner farms, and a third of the tenant farms have fruit trees. I'ndoubtedly there is a strong tendency for all the valley farms to have fruit trees but for those located on the divide lands to do without them because of the difficulty of tree culture on the lands in this area. FARM 111 II I&gt;I\(.S AND WATER SUPPLY Farm buildings with reference to the house. — Farm buildings are within sight of the houses of practically all owners, part - owners, and tenants in all areas. Barnyard sounds reach the houses of about half of the owners, part-owners, and tenants, and odors reach the houses of between a fifth and a sixth of owners, part-owners, and tenants alike. ( &gt;ne particular area stands far above all others in percentages reporting that sounds and odors reach the houses, but there is so much variation from area to area on this point as to suggest that the answers to these questions are so much a matter of personal opinion and conjecture on the part of the enumerator that we cannot very well compare the figures for the various areas with one another. It seems safe to conclude that neither owner nor ten - ant has any outstanding peculiarity on this point, or it would have been detected. It is of course undesirable from all standpoints that barnyard odors should reach the house, particularly from the standpoints of personal comfort and sanitation. This evil seems to have been reduced to a minimum by reasonable distance and location with reference to prevailing winds. Common observation seems to re - gard the hog pen as the most frequent offender and the source of the most offensive odors. The desirability of hearing and seeing from the house what is going on about the farm buildings is not so easily denied. The more offensive sights and sounds should of course be either sup - pressed or prevented from reaching the house if possible. Other sights and sounds have the advantages of aiding in relieving the </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 charged against farm life by some and of giving the isehold the solidarity that comes from the members working within sight of one another much of the time. The housewife desires to be able to see the farm buildings in order that she may keep a watchful eye upon the children gather - ing the eggs or doing other work and may note her husband's return from the field and the progress of the barn chores and gauge her preparation of the meals accordingly. Unfortunately it is necessary to choose between the advantage of hedging the house away from the barn with more sightly objects and that tthe organized cooperation of all members of the household ich thoro visibility makes possible. Further, there is the abso - e necessity of being able to reach the farm buildings without iue loss of time and energy and of seeing and hearing what is happening to property that may be so quickly injured or lost and which must necessarily be protected against fire, theft, and other possible causes of loss. Feet from water supply to contamination.— The sources of household water supply averaged 137 feet from the barn and 117 feet from the privy and were almost invariably closer to privies than to barns in the various areas. There was considerable variation in distance from water supply to barns in various areas and great variation in the distance from privies. In the Cam - bridge area for example, the distance to privies was 45.8 feet on part-owners' farms and still less on the farms of both tenants ami owners. In the Grant area still farther west the average distances from source of water supply to privy ranged from 152 feet on tenant farms to 203 feet on owners' farms. Among eastern Nebraska farms the owners' sources of water supply were closer to both these possible sources of contamination than were those of either the part-owners or the tenants, while in the Clay County area the owners' sources of water supply were farther from the barn but closer to the privy than those of either the tenants or the part-owners, but the tenants' water supply was practically as close to the privy as was the owners'. Entirely too many wells are insufficiently protected against contamination from the animals and fowls which have access to the ground immediately about them or even to the platforms and windmills over them, as roaming and roosting places. Such causes of contamination should, of course, be absolutely con - trolled. Pumps which supply water for human consumption should not be primed with water from stock tanks or other </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Nebraska Farm Homes 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 sources open to contamination. Rules are not so easily laid down as to location of wells with reference to buildings. The house - hold water supply should, of course, he as near the house and as far from the barns and privies as possible. The drainage of these buildings should be away from the well rather than toward it, locating them down the surface slope from the well. This is good so far as it goes, but the underground water-bearing sand or gravel layers may have a slope opposite to that of the surface of the soil. Only a good knowledge of the general principles in - volved and of local conditions can give the best results. WATER SIPPI.Y Source of water. — The well is the outstanding source of water supply on Nebraska farms and the cistern the only other source found in a considerable number of cases, especially when we re - member that the reservoir and well cistern are usually only stor - age places for well water. Not a single farmer reports a stream as a source of household water supply and only 1 reports a spring while 3 report city supply which doubtless comes from wells. The well is the only source of supply in about three-fifths of the eastern Nebraska farm homes and three-fourths of the south - western Nebraska farm homes studied, while the cistern is the sole source in only 6 eastern Nebraska homes but is never the sole source in western Nebraska so far as the survey shows. In eastern Nebraska nearly half of the owners, two-fifths of the part-owners, and a little more than a fourth of the tenants have both wells and cisterns, but in southwestern Nebraska the presence of both well and cistern is reported by only about one tenth of the owners, two-fifths of the part-owners, and less than a quarter of the tenants. It is in this part of the state that the cistern is really a reservoir in most cases in which well water is stored nearer the surface so that it may be more easily pumped by hand when the windmill or other power is not in operation to bring it from greater depths without human labor. Palatability. — Water is reported as palatable in about 91 per cent of all cases in both eastern and southwestern areas, but n&lt;&gt; special study was made of the causes of unpalatability. There is little apparent difference in the water supply of owners and tenants except that the owners and part-owners much more fre - quently have both wells and cisterns, especially the owners, in - stead of depending entirely upon well water. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Nebraska Farm Homes 37 Distance to water supply. — The water supply is about 50 feet from the house with practically no difference between owners and tenants on this point. It is only about 20 feet from the house in the Cambridge area and only a little more in the Filley and Clay County areas, but the distance is 75 feet in the Milligan area where it is much closer to owners' than to tenants' houses — 85 feet from tenants', 75 feet from part-owners', and 67 feet from owners' houses. In the Nehawka and Grant areas, however, it is over 120 feet from owners' houses and from a fifth to more than half that far from the houses of tenants and part-owners. FIG. 15.— WATER SUPPLY Distance, surface slope, and underdrainage should all be carefully considered in locating wells, to avoid contamination. Pump in house. — Between a third and a fourth of all the houses studied had pumps within them. The fraction is nearly two-fifths among owners, over a quarter among part-owners, and over a fifth among tenants. In eastern Nebraska the proportions are distinctly higher than in western Nebraska. Ioe supply. — Almost exactly 1 farmer out of every 8 reported an ice supply of some kind — either artificial or natural. Among owners and part-owners about 1 out of every 7 has such an ice supply as compared with only about 1 tenant out of every 10. It is found in exactly a sixth of all the farm homes in the eastern Nebraska areas but in only 1 out of every 35 in the southwestern areas. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 Ice supply is important (1) in keeping many foods more palatable and sanitary — notably milk which shouM figure largely in the farm diet, especially for children, (2) in making possible the use of some food which cannot lend variety to the diet in the absence of ice, and (3) in saving the housewife's steps to cellar, cave, or well in a vain attempt to find a cool, sanitary, summer storage place for the more perishable foods. In the absence of ice some of these advantages may be gained by the use of the "iceless refrigerator" which may be made on the farm. Doubtless such devices or home-made ice would be much more common on Nebraska farms if they were better known. Forms or moulds can be secured for use in making ice en the farm from pure water in winter for storage for summer use. Of course artificial ice made from healthful water may be bought in town as needed but a home supply saves many trips. Ordinary pond ice should never be put into drinking water. We would not drink the pond water and freezing does not purify it, in spite of the popular opinion to the contrary. POWER AND I n.H ris&lt;. Gasoline engines.— About a third of the farms studied ha gasoline engines — nearly two-fifths among owners and pa owners and over a quarter among tenants. The proportions va greatly from area to area, suggesting that the gasoline engi is either not equally needed or not equally understood in differ* parts of the state. The westernmost area studied shows a much more general use of the gasoline engine than any other, as it was found on the farms of two-thirds of the owners, nearly three-fifths of the part-owners and 9 out of every 20 tenants. The next area farther east, however, does not have nearly so many gasoline engines as a number of others still farther east but stands very close to the average of all those in the eastern half of the state. In some areas the gasoline engines are more prevalent among owners than among part-owners but in a considerable number of areas the part-owners stand far ahead of the owners, and one east - ern Nebraska area shows even a larger percentage of tenants than either owners or part-owners reporting gasoline engines. The Clay and Gage County areas stand very low in percentage of farms reporting this source of power while the 2 areas peopled by the descendants of the most recent immigrants stand high. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Nebraska Farm Homes 39 Tliis is especially notable in the Stromsburg area where about 6 out of every 7 part-owners, nearly 3 out of every 5 owners, and 2 out of every 5 tenants reported the gasoline engine. Light. — Electricity on farms is similarly variable. In the Gage County area it is reported from only one farm and that a tenant's farm. The southwestern areas studied stand a little above the eastern areas in percentage of all operators reporting electricity. One of them — the Cambridge area — reported elec - tricity in the homes of a sixth of the owners and a seventh of the part-owners but in less than 1 in every 50 tenants' homes. FIG. 16. KINDS OF ARTIFICIAL LIGHT Kerosene predominates, but other artificial lifrht is increasing in importance. Stromsburg area stands much higher than any other studied The in this particular, as nearly a third of the owners' homes, nearly two-fifths of those of the part-owners and even 4 of the 58 tenant homes have electricity altho in most areas it is found almost exclusively in homes of owners and part-owners, being reported by only about 1 eastern Nebraska tenant home out of every 37. Power lines being built thru the country primarily for other pur - poses are sometimes being made sources of farm lighting current. Kerosene is, of course, the great outstanding source of light in farm homes in all parts of Nebraska. It is either the main source or the supplementary source for use when others fail or in places in which others can not conveniently go in 19 out of every </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 i ||3Va Ulaaafliigg ■* | -^ fl£ j Z * 2 ■* 6± . "33332223333 . | i ! e - ! SSSSSSSXSSS -I . ! |a*8-2" I ii* " - l[- 1 l\ . !|j«j-»— Z358« fil j - j j, JiJjjl s =. l\±_Z Lr , jl I S2-S25* |,=--«.«_Sa55 |= ll *~ o ~~ a - * «A_ Si g*" 8^ | |i||iii»5H=? :l 55252a- 1 r--^ —_- |l g J 8828-2" c \=A If 1 fc £ I I gr-act-t-t-t-aa-K I I j i w»- ; — (- - . a I 1 p5=2=5 ! j |f I""-" T&lt; - g fe I I -&lt; &lt; 2 -5 5 ■; - " * -S ■ ': -: l9C*F9£iI*3 *- &lt; 5 5 e JC ■ 2 _ c I fc 5«-oc - * &lt;: a\ I i jiSHsniH ; j-; fX«S9l I £ 53^S"^" ■ I ?*-.«&gt;•«■!-• t-r-x:irXN t 852S«2° • Jt : $ x X 3: 15 • I 1 J HiHiiiiiiSi! fc "" " "- 1 I |« 1 c B I 9 .-o« r - S I j o«t.«»«i— oil *«' I h ] lAjj: |f &lt; •• • « &lt; : o t- »a »^ oae — m — t- 31 J= c \ • 6 j S2"SS~" ! 88-8-2 I | jwMaaja |^ -H Ui :;;:;;; _. \* |r 2 ' t- 1» r* t- » n « N — — — J •— IH ii- ; M M M NN !!!!!!! -* : i a il 2 ■^ijifeij K Aim fSsM-^ 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Nebraska Farm Homes 41 20 southwestern Nebraska homes and in 6 out of every 7 studied in eastern Nebraska. It is used with equal frequency by owners, part-owners, and tenants in southwestern Nebraska, but in east - ern Nebraska by a little over three-fourths of the owners and part-owners and nearly nine-tenths of the tenants. Acetylene lighting is used by only 2 southwestern Nebraska homes. Both of these are those of Grant area tenants but among 728 eastern Nebraska farms studied 1 of every 20 owners' homes reported acetylene as compared with about 1 out of every 25 tenant homes and only 1 out of every 50 part-owner homes. Gas light is used with about equal frequency in eastern and southwestern Nebraska homes — not far from 1 home in every 8. Next to kerosene it was the most frequently reported source of artificial light. It varies greatly from area to area, none what - ever being reported from the Cambridge area while in the Grant area 2 owners out of every 5 and not far from 1 part-owner and 1 tenant out of every 5 have gas light. In the eastern Nebraska areas it is almost entirely absent except in the Filley, Fairfield- Clay Center, and Stromsburg areas. In the last named it is used by about two-fifths of the owner and tenant and one-fifth of the part-owner homes. MOI&gt;KK.\ WATKIt. HEATING, AND MOOTING SYSTEMS Nebraska compared with rest of country Of all the farms in the United States 1 in every 11 has water piped into the house. In the West North Central states the proportion is 1 in 10, and in Nebraska 1 in every 6. Of all farms in the United States about 1 out of every 14 has gas or electric lights, as compared with 1 in 11 in the West North Central states and 1 in 10 in Nebraska.' What is modern? — Modern water, heating, and lighting sys- tems, all will probably agree, mean hot and cold water in the house, heating by something other than a stove, and lighting by something more satisfactory than the kerosene lamp. There is every gradation from the most unmodern and unsanitary open well from which water is drawn with wheel and bucket and carried to the house, on thru the more convenient arrangement of pump in the kitchen or water piped into the house to the truly modern water system with hot and cold water flowing on one or more floors of the house. The modern water system as reported in the following paragraphs is a more or less variable term but 'Agriculture: Summary of the Census of Agriculture for the United State?, ltll and 1920. P. 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 I means more than flowing water delivered by a pump or pipe that it need not be carried to the house by the housewife, is is indicated by the fact that altho one-sixth of the Nebraska farm houses have "water piped into the house" only 1 out of every 16 farmers reports a modern water system. The principal modern lighting systems on farms are electric, acetylene, and gasoline pressure systems. The principal modern heating system is the hot air furnace, with much rarer steam and hot water systems — so rare in fact as to be practically negli - gible. PER :ent 3 7 b 5 - 3 0 ALL ALL ALL LIGHT WATER HEAT ""'" WATER HEAT /,j-[» HEAT LISHT WATER ALONE ALONE AlONE l /"t HEAT U6H T T FIG. 17. MODERN WATER. HEATING. AND LIGHTING SYSTI This BhowinK. based on 117.758 Nebraska farms. i&gt; improving ra year. About an einhth are modern in at least one of these three rape How many are modern?' — Answers from 1 1 T,T."&gt;~- \ farms indicate that about 14,500, or about 12.2 per ien ern in 1 or more of these 3 respects. About 2 per eel ..d- of every 50 are modern in all having modern water, heating, ■i respects (designated WML or and lighting systems . A little more than another 2 per cent are modern in 2 of the&gt;e :i par- ticulars (WH, W'L, and HL). Just about two-thirds "t those modern in any particular at all were modern only in one par ticular — W, H, or L alone. 'All figure* used in answering the question "How many ar n are based upon tabulation made thru the courtesy of the Nebraska T'epart - ment of Agriculture by the United States Department of Agriculture and the University r,f Nebraska Department of Rural Kconomlcs cooperating, from reports of 117.758 farms made as required by the Nebraska law by precinct assessors in 1921. These figures are rising rather rapidly from year to year. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Nebraska Farm Homes 43 The houses which had modern water systems, including those which did not have modern heating or lighting systems or both, numbered 7,522 or 6.4 per cent of all Nebraska farm houses. Similarly the total number having modern heating and lighting systems each totaled nearly the same percentage of all the farm houses of the state. Different parts of the state. — The farm homes are more largely modern in eastern Nebraska than in the newer central and west - ern parts of the state. If we divide the state into northern, southern, and central thirds we find thai the homes in the central third are more largely modern than those of the northern and FIG. 18. HOMES MODERN IN ALL THREE RESPECTS U one Nebraska farm home out of every fifty is included here but six times as modern in at least one of these particulars. We can localize our statements a little more in terms of the 9 district! shown in Figure 19. Modern conveniences were found in larger percentages of the east central district farm homes than in those of any other section, but the northeast section was a close competitor for first place. In each of these 2 sections the per - centages of farm homes having modern conveniences are one and one-half times as large as in the state as a whole and nearly twice as great as in the southeast section which stands third among the 9 sections. The north central district, which is more largely a sand hill district than any other, is the lowest of the 9 districts but the central district just south of it is at about the average for the mthern thirds. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 entire state, with the south central district excelling the south - western district and both standing below the state average in all particulars and combinations. In the western third of the state the central portion again stands distinctly above the dis- FIG. 19. THE DISTRICTS Tenures. — Owners and part-owners have modern water, lie ing, and lighting systems in their homes in about 3 limes great percentages of cases as do tenants. In fact, the owl percentages are either 2 or 3 times as great in every district a in every combination except that tenants exceeded owners in 1 the combinations in the northwest district and in another of t possible combinations in the central district. Part-owners have these 3 modern conveniences a little more generally than owners in the state as a whole but this varies greatly from district to district and from combination to com - bination of the different conveniences. Share-cash tenants' percentages are a little less than those of either share or cash tenants but the differences among these 3 classes of tenants are not very great. No tenant in either the northwest or north central district had a house which boasted all 3 of these modern conveniences. In Grant, Hooker, Arthur, </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Nebraska Farm Homes 45 and McPherson Counties according to the precinct assessors' re - ports not a single farm house had all 3 even among owners and part-owners, while in Blaine County not a house had a modern heating or lighting system, and in Loup County none had a modern lighting system. From some of these counties come re - poris of the erection of homes since these data were secured which make such sweeping statements no longer accurate. It is even possible that they were not strictly true in 1921 as the equipment may not have been fully reported in absolutely every case. There is no reason, however, to doubt the substantial cor- tm of the figures </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 lilltl.KM.KAI'HY Adams, Thos. The Garden and Agriculture. Garden City Press 1905. From bibliography of Alden and Hayward, "Housing." Alden, Percy and Hayward, Edward E. Housing. Headly Broth ers, 1910. 168 pp. Bailey, Ilena M., and Snyder, Melissa Farrell. A Survey of Farm Homes. U. S. Dept. Agr. Office Home Ec. 1921, pp. 347-355. R printed in The Journal of Home Economics, V. XIII, No. 8, 1921. Baker, Charles Whiting. How to Improve the Hot Air Furnact U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 208, 1918, pp. 7-17, figs. 8 Bashore, Dr. Harvey B. Overcrowding and Defective Housing in Rural Districts. John Wiley and Sons. N. Y. 1915, pp. 92, flgs. 17 Beattie, James H. The Farm Garden in the North. U. S. Dept Agr. Farmers' Bui. 937, 1918, pp. 3-53. fig Behrends, F. G. The Farm Water Supply. Cornell Univ. Agr. Ex Bui. 50, 1922, pp. 121-191, flgs. 64. Ithaca, N. Y Bode, I. T. The Shelterbelt as an Asset on the Iowa Farm. low State Agr. Col. Bui. 108. 1922. pp. 3-16. figs. 9. Ames. Iowa. Bowen, John T. Harvesting and Storing Ice on the Farm. I Dept. Agr. Farmers' Bui. No. 1078, 1920, pp. 3-31, flgs. 22. Breckenridge, L. P., and Flagg, S. B. Saving Fuel in H House. U. S. Dept. Int. Bui. 97, 1917, pp. 5-33, flgs Brewer, L. W. Rural Hygiene. Lippincott, Phila., 1909. Briggs, George Waverley. The Housing Problem in Tex printed from Galveston-Dallas News, 1911, pp. l-9fi, flgs. 34. Broadhurst, Jean. Home and Community Hygiene. J. B. Lip cott Co., Philadelphia. Pwin., 1918, pp. 1-428, figs. 116. Cady, LeRoy. Attractive Farmsteads. Minn. Agr. Ext. I 1919, pp. 1-8, figs. 5. Chance, Sir William. Building By-Laws in Rural Districts. I King and Son, Orchard House, Westminster, London. Chase, L. W. Water Systems. Rpt. Nebr. State Boarc 1909, pp. 353-362. Churchill. Allen L., and Wickenden. Leonard. The House Owner Book. Funk and Wagnalls Co.. N. Y., 1923. pp. xvi-388. figs. 51. Committees. How to Plan, Finance, and Build Your Home. Tin Architect's Small House Service Bureau of Minn., 1920, pp. 7-14 figs. 104. Corbett, L. C. Growing Annual Flowering Plants. U. S. Dept Agr. Bui. 1171, 1921, pp. 3-79, flgs. 66. Cornes, James. Modern Housing in Town and Country. Botsford, 94. High Holborn, 1905. From bibliography of Alden and Hayward "Housing." Crotch, W. Walter. The Cottage Homes of England. P. S. King and Son, 1901. From bibliography of Alden and Hayward, "Housing.' Daniels, A. M. Operating a Home Heating Plant. U. S. Dept. Agr Bui. 1194, 1921, pp. 3-26, figs. 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Nebraska Farm Homes 47 Davenport. Mrs. E. Possibilities of the Country Home. Cham - paign. 111., 1910, pp. 1-12. Davidson. J. B. Farm Buildings. Farm Economy. Better Farm- Association, Kans. City, Mo., 1915, pp. 467-600, figs. 93. Dodd, Helen. The Healthful Farm House, with an introduction by Ellen H. Richards. Whitcomb and Barrows. Boston, 1906. Edwards. Clement. Bad Housing in Rural Districts. Paper in Fabian Tract 101. From bibliography of Alden and Hayward, "Hous- ii, n, W. A. Inexpensive Plumbing for Farm Kitchens. Kans. Eng. Exp. Sta. Bui. 6, 1916, pp. 5-23, figs. 7. Ft-nton, H. H. The Farm Shop. Kans. State Agr. Col. Cir. 16, Fill&lt;-y, H. C. Locating the Farmstead. Distributed by the Uni - sity of Nebraska, College of Agriculture, mimeographed form. \i Frazier, F. F. Sewage Disposal for Country Homes. Kans. State Agr. Col. Bui. 6, 1916. pp. 5-30, ttgs. 6. Freeman, A. W. Good Water for Farm Homes. U. S. Pub. Health Douglas. Healthy Dwellings. Oxford, Clarendon Press, 188H. pp. 1-296, figs. 66. oddard. C. W. How to Build and Maintain Approved Types of Improved Privies for Rural Districts and Towns without Sewer Sys- l Texas State Board of Health Sp. Bui., 1920. pp. 1-10, flgs. 4. Haw, George. Britain's Homes. Clarion Press. From bibliography of Ald&lt;-n and Hayward. "Housing. Heineinan. Wm. Country Cottages, by Home Counties. 1905. From bibliography of Alden and Hayward, "Housing." Johnson. Grace A. The Efficient Kitchen. Oregon Agr. Col. Bui. . 1 !» 2 2 , pp. 1-4. figs. 3. Corvallis, Oregon. Kloeffler, R. G. Electric Cooking. Kans. State Agr. Col. Bui. 9 Kr&gt;-i!-inger, Henry. Five Ways of Saving Fuel in Heating Houses V. B. Dept. Int. Bui. 199, 1918, pp. 5-11, flgs. 1. Lewis, Frank C. Farm Buildings. Purdue Univ. Cir. 100, 1921 pp. 3-144, figs. 130. sden, L. L. Rural Sanitation. U. S. Pub. Health Bui. 94 1918, pp. 7-336, figs. 59. McCormack, E. B. Housing the Worker on the Farm. U. S. Dept Agr Bui. 789, 1919, pp. 3-11, figs. 7. McNair, Grayson B. Illumination for Farm and Town Homes. Kans. State Agr. Bui. 1, 1914, pp. 3-13. Mc\&gt;y, Karl A. Water Supply for Country Homes. Univ. Mo V. I., No. 2. 1913. pp. 3-21, figs. 5. Moore, J. G. The Garden and the Orchard. Farm Economy. Bet ter Farming Assn., Kans. City, Mo., 1915, pp. 211-302, flgs. 44. Mulford. F. L. Beautifying the Farmstead. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui 1087. 1921. pp. 3-55, figs. 66. 1919. pp. 3-15, figs Ser. Bui. 70, 1915, pp. 3-16, flgg. 6. 1917. pp. 8-70, flgs. 26. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 191 Howry, J. L. Lighting Farm Buildings. Minn. Agr. Ext. Bui. 58, 1915. pp. 2-7. figs. 6. Ogden, Henry W. Rural Hygiene. Macmillan, N. Y., 1911, pp. 1-434, figs. 79. Peel, Mrs. C. S. The Labor-Saving House. John Lane, The Bodley Head, London, Eng., 1918, pp. 2-187. pis. 46. Potter, A. A., and Simmering, S. L. Economical Use of Fuel in Home. Kans. State Agr. Col. Bui. 8. 1917, pp. 5-15. Reese, Madge J. Farm Home Conveniences. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui 927, 1921, pp. 3-31, figs. 24. Rich, Edward D. The Sanitary Privy. Mich. State Board Health. Eng. Bui. 8, 1918. pp. 4-9. figs. 13. Richards, Edna K. Lavor-Saving Devices for the HousewilV. Farm Economy. Better Farming Assn., Kans. City, Mo., 1915, pp. 952-985, vf, figs. 2 7. Riley, William A. How to Fight the Dangerous House Fly Unhi Minn. Agr. Ext. Bui. 48, 1920, pp. 48, figs. 7. Robertson, J. W. Conservation of Life in Rural Districts. Associa tion Press, N. Y., 1911. Roe. H. B. Septic Tanks for Rural Homes. Univ. Minn. Agr. Ex Bui. 50, 1920, pp. 1-20, figs. 8. Scott, Chas. A., and Burr, Walter. Tree Planting in Kansas. Ka State Agr. Col. Bui. 11, 1916. pp. 5-29, figs. 6. Unsigned. Farmer's Power and Light Hand Book. \\ trie Co., Inc., 195 Broadway, N. Y., 1919, pp. 2-95. Unsigned. Homes for Workmen. The Southern I »■ Orleans. La., 1919, pp. 1-249. ill Unsigned. Housing in Towns and Country. Par. Garden City Press, 1906. Velller, Lawrence. A Model Housing Law. Press of \\ Philadelphia, 1914, pp. 342. figs. 80. Veiller, Lawrence. Housing Reform. Press of Wm. F. F« delphia. 1910. pp. 213. Warren. George M. Water Systems for Farm Homes. U. S. Dep Agr. Bui. 941, 1918, pp. 3-66. figs. 50. Wharton, G. W. Domestic Needs of Farm Women. I P Agr., Office Sec. Rpt. 104, 1915, pp. 10-100 Wharton, G. W. Economic Needs of Farm Women. U. S. Dep Agr., Office Sec., Rpt. 106, 1915. pp. 10-100. White, Charles E. Successful Houses and How to Build T Wooley. J. C, and Gibbs, W. M. The Farm Septic Tank. Idah Univ. Agr. Bui. 128, 1922, pp. 3-18, figs. 11. M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>